[ Man Grunts ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Man ] And David Beckham gets the ball
yet again for Manchester United.
He's really taking responsibility
every time they have possession.
This is really a reflection of the way
he's been playing and captaining England.
He seems to have matured
so much as a player.
He's dominating
proceedings here...
but hoping perhaps
to get a bit more support...
as he gathers the ball on this
right-hand touchline time after time.
The Old Trafford crowd warming now
to the way Beckham is taking over.
But there's a big question mark
here against Manchester United...
because where is
the goal gonna come from...
to break down Anderlecht?
Will it be Scholes?
Could it possibly be Ryan Giggs?
Would it indeed be Beckham
himself who breaks through?
Because Anderlecht are playing
a very controlled game.
This is Radzinski for them
testing the United defense.
Sylvestre here at left back...
possibly with a chance to break
forward now on the other flank.
There's the ball that
Beckham really wants. Oh.!
That looked like a body check there,
but he shrugged off the defender.
Still Beckham,
plenty in the middle.
It's a decent cross.
And there is Bhamra.!
That's a fine header.
And she scored.!
Oh, it's a goal byJess Bhamra.!
A superb header here,
beating the defender...
and planting the ball beyond
the goal keeper's left hand.
Jess Bhamra makes a name
for herself at Old Trafford.
Have we discovered
a new star here, Gary Lineker?
That's right,John. Could Jess Bhamra
be the answer to England's prayers? Alan?
There's no denying the talent.
Quick thinking, comfortable on the ball.
Vision and awareness:
absolutely magnificent.
I'll tell you what.
I wish she was playing for Scotland.
Do you think England
have found the player...
to relive their
World Cup glory from '66?
Definitely. We've finally found
the missing piece of the jigsaw.
The best thing is,
she's not even reached her peak yet.
Thanks,John. We're joined
in the studio now...
byJessie's mother,
Mrs. Bhamra.
- Mrs. Bhamra, you must be
very proud of your daughter.
- Not at all.
She shouldn't running around
with all these men...
showing her bare legs
to 7 0,000 people!
She's bringing shame on the family.
And you three shouldn't encourage her.!
Jesminder, you get back home now.
[ Panjabi ]
Jesminder,
are you listening to me?
- [ Crowd Cheering On TV]
- [ Panjabi ]
-Jesminder, have you gone mad?
- Mum!
Football, shootball.
Your sister's getting engaged...
and you're sitting here
watching this skinhead boy.
- Mum, it's Beckham's corner.
- Eh.
Come downstairs.
Your sister's going crazy.
[ Woman ] Mum, I can't hang around
all day.! I've gotta go.!
Where are my keys?
I can't find them anywhere.!
I'm sick of this wedding,
and it hasn't even started.
- Mum, can you hurry up?
- # [ Woman Vocalizing ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
She wants to ruin it for me.!
That girl's a first-class bitch.!
Pinky, you've got
so many others.
Yeah, but it was all planned.
Now I've got to get another one.
- Will you get a flamin' move on?
- What's going on?
Get this. Teet's bloody sister has gone
and said she's wearing baby pink now.
Stupid cow. I have matching accessories
and everything.
Oh, Mum, do I have to
go shopping again?
Huh! My mother chose
all my 21 dowry suits herself.
I never once complained.
You girls are too spoiled.
Don't forget my dhania.
Four bunches for a pound.
And more carrots.
I'm making achar.
[ Both ] Oh, Mum,
don't do pickle as well!
Am I asking you two to make it?
# [ Woman Vocalizing ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
# [ Continues ]
- Hi!
- [ Woman ] Oh, Pink.!
- You arrived.!
- Yeah.
What are you doing here? You haven't
left everything till the last minute?
Yeah. One more
day of freedom.
- Where'd you get your contacts?
- Do you like them?
Just thought they went
with my hair, innit?
[ Polite Chuckle ]
My fiance don't like dyed hair.
Still, can't stand here
chattin'all day.
I got to go to Ealing
for my facial. Laters!
- Bye, Pinks.
- Laters.
Why'd she have to get blue contacts?
Now I can't wear mine.
[ Girl ] You're mad.!
I wouldn't be seen dead in that.!
They're all the rage, poppet.
You blow 'em up,
just like a lilo.
Look. This little pump
comes free with it.
Pop it in there, in the valve.
Pump, pump, pump away.
Up it goes. Then,
slip it back in there.
And boom, cleavage.
They're perfect
while you're still growing...
- 'cause they lift you right there.
- Mum!
- God, you're so embarrassing!
- They make more of what you got.
All the girls have bought one...
for their daughters.
Well, look, there's the Fleur.
That's pretty. Hmm?
And the gel bra.
That's a clever one.
No pumping.
It's already in there.
Oh, no, sweetheart,
not the sports bras.
They're so plain.
- They don't enhance.
- No one's gonna see them.
It's not how they look.
It's how they make you feel.
I really liked
that lace Lycra one.
Uh-oh, there's your mate.
Let's make this quick, yeah?
I hope your mate's mum wears a cardi
over her three stomachs tomorrow.
- Shut up. She's old.
- So?
- How are ya,Jess? Hiya, Pinky.
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Together In Panjabi ]
- [ Panjabi ]
May you have a long life,
my daughters.
Everything getting ready
for tomorrow?
Yes, Massiji.
Mum's making the samosas.
Ah-ha! May God keep you
and your husband in endless happiness.
And pray for me... that I get
a lovely daughter-in-law like
you for my Tony. Huh, butai?
- Mum.!
- Thank you, Massiji.
- Okay, bye.
- How was biology?
- Did you do the genetics one?
- The daughter was a carrier.
When she got married, she passed on
the defective gene to her son.
Yeah, I got that too. I hope I got
my two A's and a B for uni.
- Come on,Jess.
- Are you going to the park later?
- Yeah, I'll try.
- [ Both In Panjabi ]
- [ Panjabi ]
- Mum!
[ Gasps, Screams ]
I found it!
Come on,Jess.
- [ Groans ]
- Excuse me. That suit--
- Come on, guys!
- Over here! I got Danny!
- [ Men Shouting ]
- Here you go.!
Over here, over here,
over here.!
- Rubbish! Come on, boys!
- You're such an idiot, man.!
- Hey,Jess!
- Fancy a quick game?
I can't. My mum's waiting,
and my dad's on earlies at Heathrow.
Come on. We really need you.
Come on!
[ Shouting Continues ]
# [ Man Singing, Indistinct ]
# [ Continues ]
Who does she think she is?
Beckham, or what?
Can you chest it like him?
You know, give it some bounce!
Chest it,Jess!
Go on, chest it!
- [ Groaning ]
- Oh!
- Did that hurt, pretty boy?
- # [ Continues ]
[Jess ]
I nearly scored from 25 yards today.
Bent it and everything.
I could've carried on playing all night.
It's not fair that boys never
have to come home and help.
I wonder if I had
an arranged marriage...
would I get someone who'd let me
play football whenever I wanted?
- With whom are you talking to?
- No one, Dad.
Biji along with her grandson are coming
and staying in here for the wedding.
Why don't you put some nice picture of
beautiful sceneries instead of this bald man?
- Dad!
- I'm going to change.
- Come and help me out, okay?
- Okay.
- [ Talking, Indistinct ]
- # [ Indian ]
- [ People Chattering ]
- # [ Continues ]
I help make a beautiful
Rolls-Royce,you know?
Gold, black-like color. I'll get one
for your wedding too if you like.
- [ Panjabi ]
- I just want a little bit.
[ Panjabi ]
It will be
your turn soon, huh?
Do you want a clean-shaven boy
like your sister...
or a proper Sikh with a full beard and a turban?
[ Chuckling ]
It's only our men that have a big engine
and full M.O. T.
- [ Women Laughing ]
- [ Chattering ]
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
[ Mutters ]
Nah, man. The alternator's
gone on the Merc.
Just do the carburetor on the Nissan.
I told you not to bother me.
- It's my engagement, man.
- [ Guests Chuckling ]
[ Panjabi ]
Put it to ''off.''
Put ''off.''
Thank you.
- [ Guests Exclaiming ]
- # [ Indian ]
[ Exclaiming Continues ]
Oh, yes!
[ Whooping ]
- Mmm, he is so tick, man!
- Innit? Innit? I know!
Look! He's taking
his shirt off!.
- Oh, my God.!
- A body like that should come
with an X-level warnin'
- And a lifetime guarantee.
- Yeah, man.
- CallJess. CallJess.
- Oi!Jess!
[ Taunting ]
Jess, who's your friend
with the gorgeous bod?
The one
with the six-pack?
If he looks at me,
I really will faint.
- What? Taz?
- Is that his name?
- Look at that kick!
- [ Karate Yells ]
- He's so fly.
- He's fine.
That guy is so fine.
- Get your girlfriend!
-Jess!
- Go on,Jess. Lover boy's calling you.
- Shut up.
- You know he's just my mate.
We're not all slags like you lot.
- Oh!
Just 'cause she's still a ''V,''
thinks she's better than us.
At least she hasn't got off
with half of Hounslow like you two.
- [ Boys Shouting ]
- Hey.
Who's that goreh
watching her?
[ Shouting Continues ]
Come on,Jess!
Come on! All the way!
It's all yours!
[ Laughing ]
[ Whooping ]
- Hi. That was brilliant.
- Hi.
- Do you play for any side?
- Like who? Southall United Sari Squad?
- [ Laughing ]
- I play for Hounslow Harriers girls' side.
It's closed season at the moment,
but we've got summer tournament coming up.
- You should come along, have a trial.
- A trial?
- Think I'm good enough?
- Yeah.
Watched you a couple of times.
You've gotten really good.
It's up to our coach, but I know
we could do with some new blood.
-Jess, that's brilliant.
- Yeah, nice one.
Do you swap shirts
at the end of matches?
- And get in a big bath together?
- ''Where's the soap?''
Yes, it does,
doesn't it, lads, eh?
- Let's play football.
- Yeah.
- I'm Jules. Hey.
- Oh.Jess.
# [ Woman Vocalizing ]
- Yes!
- # [ Woman Singing ]
- # [ Continues ]
- Look up.
I want two groups.
Three in each group. Let's move!
How do you know she's serious?
I haven't got time to piss around.
She's got balls,Joe.
At least watch her.
Hi.
- Where do you normally play?
- In the park.
- I mean, what position?
- Oh, sorry.
I usually play all over, but up front,
on the right is best.
- Get your boots on.
- I haven't got any.
Join in.
Start warming up.
- Where should I put this?
- Put it over there. Come on.
Jesus.
# [ Woman Scatting ]
Pass it toJules!
- Yes!
- Brilliant.
# [ Continues ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
- Hustle on the right.! Come on.!
- [Joe ] How'd it feel out there?
Brilliant. Really great.
I've never seen an Indian girl
into football.
I didn't even know
they had a girl's team here.
It's all her fault.
I used to play
for the men's club...
and she used to hang around here whining
that there was no team for her to play on.
I wasn't whinin'.
Nah, there was nothin' here
for us girls.
There was, like,
junior boys' stuff.
But when he busted his knee...
he set up the girls' side.
And he's been
on my case ever since.
They made me
start at the bottom.
You can't get
much lower than her.
You're so full of it!
Nah, we get just as many
trophies as the men's side do.
So, does she pass?
- Your folks up for it?
- Yeah, they're cool.
I suppose you'd
better come back then.
I've gotta go open the bar.
Some real work.
- He likes you.
- You think so?
[Jules ]
He asked you back, didn't he?
- How long have you been playing?
- For ages.
But just in the park.
Nothin' as serious as this.
This, serious?
It'll do for now.
I wanna play professionally.
Wow. Can you do that?
I mean, as a job, like?
Sure. Not really here,
but you can in America.
They've got a pro league with
new stadiums and everything.
Really?
Can't believe it.
It's a proper pitch with lights...
corner flags, changing rooms.
The coach likes me.
Really knows his stuff.
Must be gutted he can't play
with his injury and all.
Jules is so lucky.
Her mum and dad
must really support her...
to let her go all the way
to America to play.
I don't even know how to tell my mum
and dad about Hounslow Harriers.
- Whoops.
- Will you both pack it in?
Look at the state
of my fuchsias!
Allen, when are you gonna
realize you have...
a daughter with breasts,
not a son?
- Mum!
- Please!
- No boy's gonna wanna go out...
with a girl who's got
bigger muscles than him.
- Why don't you just leave her alone?
- I'm not gonna give it up.
I'm just saying that I saw
that Kevin last night...
in the high street
with a blonde girl.
And it didn't look like they were talking about
Match of the Bleedin'Day either.
Kevin can shag
whoever he bloody wants.
Honey, all I'm saying is...
there is a reason
why Sporty Spice...
is the only one of them
without a fella.
- Sweetheart--
- See what you've done?
Why don't you just
get off her flamin' back?
If she's more interested
in playin'football now...
than chasing boys, quite frankly,
I'm over the moon about that.
- They're a bit tatty, but they'll do the job.
- Thanks.
Here's a kit.
Don't be afraid to get it dirty.
Can I not wear
my tracksuit bottoms?
No.
- Shit!
- [ Girl ] Put your bum away.
[ Chattering ]
Jess, get changed
over here.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- You've met our captain, Mel.
- Nice to meet you.
So you're up for a proper match?
Chiswick next.
Best defensive record
in the division.
- They're due for a good stuffing.
- Absolutely.
We need some peace up front.
Jules could do with some decent service.
Welcome to the Harriers.
Painters and decorators are in.
[ Girl ]
Do you know how much they cost?
[ Girl #2 ]
Tell me.
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
Jules, take over the warm-up.
Come on, girls. Keep going.
Heads up.
Jess, what's goin' on?
It looks awful.
- It's why I can't wear shorts ever.
- Jesus.
That's a stunner.
I thought I had
a bad one on my knee, but...
yours is gorgeous.
Look, don't worry about it.
No one's gonna care
once you're out there.
- What happened?
- You don't wanna know.
Look.
Two operations later,
and it's still useless.
Yours affect your game?
No, it just looks awful.
I was eight. My mum was
working overtime at Heathrow...
and I was trying to cook
beans on toast.
When I jumped up to the grill
to get the toast...
my trousers caught light,
so my sister put me in the bath...
poured cold water over me
and pulled them off.
- But half my skin came off too.
- [ Inhales Sharply ]
Sorry.
I know.
Put me off beans on toast
for life.
Come on. Mine stopped me
from playing outright.
Yours doesn't.
- No more dawdling.
- Sorry about your knee.
Yeah, yeah. I'm a right
sob story, aren't I?
Come on. I wanna see
some sweat on you.
# [ Man Singing ]
[ Singer Grunts ]
[ Singer Screaming ]
# [ Vocalizing ]
- # [ Continues ]
- Come on, boys.
- # [ Fades, Ends ]
- Hey, Tony.
What are you here for,
fantasy football?
Wow,Jess.
You look like a pro.
It's brilliant. They're a top team,
and the coach is ace.
- Excellent.
- What's that down your leg?
-Haven't you seen a burn before?
-It's disgusting.
- Back off, you wanker!
- Ooh!
- No, it's fine.
- At least I can still skin you alive.
- [ All Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
Come on,Jess!
The skill! The skill!
The skills! Oh, the skills!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Panjabi ]
He was touching you all over.!
Putting his hands
on your bare legs.!
You're not a young girl anymore.
And you, showing the world your scar!
[ Panjabi ]
Jessie, now that your sister
has got engaged, it's different.
- You know how people talk.
- She's getting married, not me.
I was married at your age. You don't even
want to learn how to cook daal.!
I'm not playing
with boys anymore.
- Good. [ Panjabi ] End of matter.
- [ Muttering ]
- I'm joining a girls' team.
- Hah?
They want me to play in proper matches.
The coach said I could go far.
Go far?
Go far to where?
We let you play all you wanted when
you were young. You've played enough.
- That's not fair. He selected me.
- He?
- She said it was girls.
- The coach,Joe.
See how she lies?
I don't want you running around
half naked in front of men.
Look how dark you've become
playing in the sun.
But, Mum, I'm really good.
What family will want
a daughter-in-law...
who can run around
kicking football all day...
but can't make
round chappaties?
Now exams are over,
I want you to learn full Punjabi dinner.
- Meat and vegetarian.
- But, Dad--
- [ Panjabi ] No. This is where you spoil her.
- What have I done--
No. This is how it started
with your niece.
The way that girl would answer back.
And then...
running off to become a model
wearing small, small skirts.
- Mum, she's a fashion designer.
- She's divorced, that's what she is.
Cast off after three years of being
married to a white boy with blue hair.
- [ Sighs ]
- Her poor mother.
She hasn't been able to
set foot in that temple since.
I don't want the shame
on my family.
That's it!
No more football!
Jessie,your mother is right.
It's not nice.
You must start behaving
like a proper woman. Okay?
It's out of order! Anything I want
is not Indian enough for 'em.
I never bunked off school to go
at those daytimers like Pinky or Bubbly.
I don't wear makeup or tight clothes.
They don't see all those things.
- Parents never see the good things.
- Anyone can cook aloo gobi.
But who can bend a ball
like Beckham?
Why don't you just play
and not tell them, eh?
Pinky's been sneaking off
for years to see Teets.
Now they're getting married,
nobody cares.
What your parents don't know
won't hurt.
Why should I have to lie? It's not like
I'm sleeping around with anyone.
- [ Chuckles ]
-Jess!
Jess!
- Hello.
- Hi.
I thought I'd find you
out here playing.
This is Tony. Tony, this is Jules
from the team.
Jess is well made up
with your team.
Yeah, we've got high hopes
for her, especially me.
My mum doesn't want me
to play anymore.
That's bollocks! My mum's
never wanted me to play.
You just can't take no
for an answer.
My sister's getting married soon,
so my mum and dad are totally stressed out.
Anyway, I won't be able to get out of
the house for training and matches.
Come on,Jess! You can't
leave me alone out there.
Joe's got an American scout
coming over.
Don't worry about your mum.
Just say you got a summerjob.
I can put in a good word for you
at H.M.V. with me.
So, now we got that sorted...
you gonna show me what
your fellow can do?
- No, he's not--
- I'm not her boyfriend.
[ Clears Throat ]
Jess, come on.
Are you playin'?
Jessie! Breakfast!
- [Jess ] No, I'm in a hurry.
- [ Panjabi ]
- You can't go to work on an empty stomach.
- Where's my keys?
-Jessie--
- No, I'm late, Mum.
Bye.
- # [ Man Singing ]
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
Yes!
[Joe ]
Get those legs up.! Get up.! That's it.!
[Joe Shouting ]
Keep it coming! Keep it coming!
Keep it coming! That's it!
[ Crowd Shouting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ People Shouting ]
- Cheers.
- Give us a hug then.
- Good night,Jules.
- [ Girls Chuckling ]
Easy, tiger.
[ Chattering ]
Yes!
[ Groans ]
[ Shouting ]
- Where is it?
- [ Girls Chuckling ]
- Oh, no!
- I can't stop!
- Open.
- [ Gasps ]
- Oh, my God!
- Goal!
[ Laughing ]
[ Panjabi ]
Aloo gobi.
# [ Woman Singing In Panjabi ]
[ Pinky Shouts ]
Get off me, man.!
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
Yeah? Mum!
No, no, nothing. I'm--
I'm just at work, innit?
I know Poli's coming
around to do the suits.
SoJess can get
the tube, innit?
Yeah, all right, all right.
I'll pick her up.
I gotta go. Someone's coming.
I'll see you later. Bye.
[ Screams ]
No, my mum and dad
don't got a clue.
They've no idea you've
been playing all this time?
- Nope.
- Where do they think you are?
They think I've got
a job at H.M.V.
- Blimey. That's not on.
- Indian girls aren't supposed to play football.
- That's a bit backward.
- It ain't just an Indian thing.
I mean, how many people
come out and support us?
- Are you promised to someone?
- No. No way.
My sister's getting married soon.
It's a love match.
- What's that mean?
- It's not arranged.
- If you can choose, does that
mean you can marry a white boy?
- White, no.
Black, definitely not.
A Muslim, eh-eh.
- I'll guess you'll be marrying an Indian.
- Probably.
- I don't know how you Indian girls
put up with it.
- It's just culture.
Better than sleeping around with boys
you're not going to end up marrying.
- What's the point in that?
- That's the best bit.
- You should know.
- [ Girls Laughing ]
- Are we ready to go?
- See you slags later.
# [ Man Singing In Panjabi ]
- ?? [ Continues ]
- [Jess ] It's only me.
[ Sighs ]
I'm really starving. I had to work
through my lunch hour today.
Where's Pinky? She was
supposed to pick you up...
so you wouldn't
be late for Poli.
Pinky, why didn't you
pick your sister up from work?
I went, but the manager said
I just missed her.
Okay, okay.
Poli's on her way.
I'll make you girls
some tea.
- All right. Who is he then?
- Who?
You must think I'm shit for brains,
lying about a job and all that.
You can't say anything to Mum and Dad.
I kept Teet a secret for you.
- He's not Muslim, is he?
- Shh!
Look, I've been playing football
for a women's team.
Huh? It's worse
than I thought.
It's a proper tournament.
They're real matches.
What is wrong
with you,Jess?
If you're gonna go to all this bother lying,
do it for something good.
Don't you want a boyfriend
like everyone else?
You're quite pretty.
You do something with your hair...
and put a bit of makeup on,
you'd look all right.
Leave her alone. I never put
makeup on till after I was married.
Jessie's a good girl now.
She helped me wash all the net curtains...
and she made lovely aloo gobi
last week.
Waist: 25.
Under bust: 28.
- Bust--
- That's too tight and rude.
No, Mum. I want my choli
more fitted.
- That's the style, innit?
- Yeah, make it 34 1 /2.
- No, tighter.
- Okay, 34.
- More.
- Eh, how are you going to breathe?
-Jess.
- Why do I have to wear a sari?
It'll just fall down.
Your first sari
is when you become a woman.
- Poli, sari blouse and petticoat.
- [ Panjabi ]
So, bust: 31 .
No, it's too tight.
I want it looser.
- Dressed in a sack,
who's going to notice you, huh?
- [ Panjabi ]
Don't worry.
One of our designs...
even these mosquito bites
will look like juicy,juicy mangos.
- Poli.
- Around the bust: 27. The waist: 27.
Mum, I'll need to buy
different shoes...
to go with the sari
and the suits then.
- Come again?
- She's coming into line now.
I can pay for one pair from my wages.
Can you give me some money for the other?
You need one black and one white
to go with everything.
# [ Woman Singing ]
?? [ Singing In Panjabi ]
Can you change the channel,
please?
It's nearly the end.
- [ Pinky ] Mum, she's back.!
-Jesminder!
You've been gone all day
for two pairs of shoes.
- Come here.
- It's not that late.
I was looking at other things,
too, like handbags.
- Can I see 'em then?
- I'll try them on with the suits.
- Let me see them!
- Come here!
Wait!
Cigarette?
- You been smoking?
- No!
[ Panjabi ]
Cigarette!
- [ Panjabi ]
- No, I've never smoked.
I had to go to the loo, so I went
into a pub with my friend.
- I had a Coke. You can smell my breath.
- [ Panjabi ]
She might be right.
These don't even have a heel.
How will they fall nicely with your sari?
I'll take them back.
Give me the ba--
Football shoes.
[ Panjabi ]
- You can't give them back.
- I've gotta get proper shoes
for the wedding now.
Don't worry. Come over to mine afterwards,
and I'll sort you out.
Come on, girls. Wake up!
God, my mum had a fit
when she saw the boots.
And I smelled like
a bleeding ashtray.
- I had to clean all
the sauce pans after dinner.
- Yak, yak, yak, yak.
Jess, is everything all right?
-Yes, Coach.
-Training not getting in the way
of your little conversation?
- No, Coach.
- Good.
Then I want five more laps round the pitch,
elbows to knees as you go.
Joe, that is totally
out of order!
Hey! I don't remember telling
the rest of you to stop.
Come on. Move it.
You're doing very well.
Just keep it up
for another two minutes.
Good, Mackie.
Good, Sally.
Excellent. Excellent.
-Jess, you can stop now!
- [ Chattering ]
I said stop.
You'll do yourself an injury.
- I'm okay. I've just got one more lap.
- I said stop!
- [ Groans ]
- Come, let's have a look at you.
- It's nothing.
- Sit down.
Let me decide
if it's nothing.
Why didn't you tell me
you twisted it?
I didn't want you to think
I'm not as strong as the others.
That's stupid,Jess.
My dad was my coach. Scouts kept
telling him I was too slight to play.
So he kept pushing me.
That's how I screwed my knee.
Your dad made you?
I wanted to show him I wasn't soft,
so I tried to play injured.
- He was a bit of a bastard.
- You shouldn't say that about your dad.
You don't know my dad.
All right. Come on.
Good. Now put
your weight on me.
There you are.
[Jess ]
Oh, my God.!
Just give them back
after the wedding.
My mum loves them.
She stuck the bows on herself.
- Oh, thanks. You sure she won't miss them?
- Nah.
Listen, I hopeJoe
wasn't too hard on you.
Some of the girls think
he's too strict.
No, he was really nice.
Just really professional.
I love that picture.
It was taken just after
we beat Millwall last year.
[ Gasps ] You've got to see this.
It's wicked.
- [ Man On TV] WUSA Soccer!
- [Jess ] Wow.!
[Jules ]
Yeah. WUSA.
Incredible we don't have anything
like that over here.
[ Woman On TV] Washington Freedom
on the attack. The cross comes in! Goal!
Mia Hamm,
world footballer of the year!
[ Man ] Milbrett makes a run.
She's got Overbeck to beat.
She shoots! Goal! Tiffany Milbrett
scores again for the New York Power!
Lily strikes, saves Millinix!
[ Woman ]
Brandi Chastain!
[ Man ]
Saved! Smith beats the keeper!
Goal for Kelly Smith,
the England international!
Anyway, when are you gonna tell
your parents about your game?
Oh, I don't know.
You can't keep lying.
You're too good.
- [ Mrs. Paxton ] Cooey.!
- Quick, hide the shoes.
- Sweetheart?
- I'm up here, Mum.
Oh, it's hot out there.
- Oh, got company.
- Yeah.
- Mum, this is Jess.
- Hello, love.
Jess.Jess?
Is that Indian?
It's reallyJesminder,
but only my mum calls me that.
Oh, that's nice.
Jesminder.
Lovely.
Ah, well,Jesminder...
I bet your room at home
doesn't look like this, eh?
With all these great big
butch women on the wall.
Thank you, Mum.
I'm not old like you.
Jess, I hope you can teach my daughter
a bit about your culture...
including respect for elders
and the like, eh?
You cheeky madam.
Well,Jess,you're a lucky girl,
aren't you?
'Cause I expect your parents
are fixing you up...
with a handsome young doctor soon,
aren't they?
- A pretty girl like you.
- Mum, stop embarrassing yourself!.
What?
[ Scoffs ]
I'm just being friendly.
You don't mind, do you,Jess, love?
Of course not. Are you a friend
from school or work?
She's a footballer.
She's on the team with me.
Oh.
[ Both Laughing ]
- [ Panjabi ]
- [Jules ] ''Jesminder''!
Did you see
her face though?
- ''Juliette.''
- ''Jesminder.'' What was that?
- Oh!Jesus!
- Are you all right?
- I'm sorry.
- Oh!
Jules, you know Joe.
- Do you like him?
- Nah.
- He'd get sacked if he was caught
shagging one of his players.
- Really?
Sometimes I wish I could find
a bloke just like him though.
You know,
that wasn't off limits.
Everyone I know's a prat.
They think girls can't play as well as them.
- ExceptJoe, of course.
- Yeah.
I hope I end up marrying
an Indian boy like him too.
- What? Shut up!
- I'm sor-- I'm sorry.
[ Panjabi ]
We're not trying to cause trouble.
Wejust felt it our duty to tell you.
- Now it's a matter for your own family.
- [ Panjabi ]
[ Panjabi ]
You know how hard it is
for our children over there.
Sometimes they misjudge
and start behaving like the kids here.
All I know is that children
are a map of their parents.
[ Panjabi ]
- You stupid flippin' cow!
- You ruined your sister's life!
[ Panjabi ]
Happy now?
My whole wedding's been
called off'cause of you!
- Me? Why?
- They saw you...
being filthy
with an English boy.
They're lying.
I wasn't with any English boy.
They saw you today
at a bus stop kissing him!
Why couldn't you do it in secret
like everyone else?
Kissing? Me? A boy?
- You're all bloody mad.
-Jesminder, don't use those swearing words.
I was at the 1 20 bus stop today,
but with Juliette, my friend.
She's a girl. And we weren't
kissing or anything.
- For God's sake!
- Swear by Bubaji.
I swear on Bubaji's name.
[ Sobbing ]
Sometimes these English girls
have such short hair.
You just can't tell.
They must have
made a mistake.
Those parents are just
making an excuse.
We were never
good enough for them.
No, Mum. It's all her fault.
I bet she was with some dikey girl
from her football team.
- She's still been playing.
She ain't got no job or nothing.
- Pinky!
-She been lying.
- Oh, God, why did you give me
two deceiving daughters?
What did I do wrong
in my past life?
- But she's the one that's ruined my life!
- [ Panjabi ]
Don't think I didn't know
you were sneaking out...
with that good-for-nothing
Teetu as well?
[ Panjabi ]
# [ Woman Singing
In Panjabi ]
# [ Continues ]
-Just talk to them!
- I promise I'll go talk to them!
I'll come and talk to your parents,
and if they don't like it--
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Jules, come here to me.
Where's your mate?
I dunno.
This is the second training session
in a row she's missed.
It's not like her.
Did she say she was
unhappy with anything?
Her parents didn't know
she was on the team.
Maybe they found out.
What? She told me
her folks were up for it.
I've been telling her to tell them,
but she won't listen to me.
- [ Doorbell Ringing ]
- [ Pinky ] I'll get it.
[ Panjabi ]
- Yeah?
- Hello.
Thanks,Jess.
I'm sorry to barge in on you like this,
Mr. and Mrs. Bhamra...
but I wanted
to talk to you in person.
I only found out today that you didn't
knowJess was playing for our team.
- No, we didn't.
- I apologize.
If I had known, I would've
encouraged Jess to tell you...
because I believe she's got
tremendous potential.
I think we know better
our daughter's potential.
Jess has no time for games.
She'll be starting university soon.
But playing for the team
is an honor.
What bigger honor is there
than respecting your elders?
Young man, when I was
a teenager in Nairobi...
I was the best fastballer
in our school.
Our team even won
the East African Cup.
But when I came
to this country, nothing.
I was not allowed to play
in any of the teams.
And these bloody gorehs
in their clubhouses...
made fun of my turban...
and sent me off packing.
I'm sorry, Mr. Bhamra.
- But now it's--
- Now what?
None of our boys are in
any of the football leagues.
You think they will
let our girls?
I don't want you to build up
Jesminder's hopes.
She will only end up
disappointed like me.
But, Dad, it's all changing now.
Look at Nasser Hussein.
He's captain of the England cricket team,
and he's Asian.
Hussein's a Muslim name.
Their families are different.
Mum!
We've been invited to play
in Germany this Saturday.
It's a shame you'll miss it.
- Wow, Germany.
- [ Car Alarm Chirps ]
I can see
what you're up against.
But your parents don't always
know what's best for you,Jess.
[ Chattering ]
Everyone here.
We're all in, yeah?
- ?? [ Singing, Indistinct ]
- [ Car Horn Toots ]
- [ Pinky ] You know the score?
- Yeah, call them twice a day.
[ Pinky ]
Trust me, man. I'm an expert.
You take care, all right?
Laters.
My sister's covering for me.
We're supposed to be staying at my cousin's.
- I didn't hear that.
- [ Cheering ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
# [ Woman Singing ]
Hey.!
Cheese!
[ Whistle Blows ]
- [ Man Speaking German On P.A.]
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
Jess! Come on! Cross it,Jess!
- [ P.A. Continues ]
- [ Cheering ]
All right. Good luck.
[ P.A. Continues ]
- Jess Bhamra.
- [ Girl ] Come on,Jess.
[Jules ]
Come on,Jess.! You can do this.!
- [ Cheering ]
- [ P.A. Resumes ]
- # [ Woman Vocalizing ]
- [ P.A. Continues ]
Yeah, Mum, I'm fine. Pinky's fine.
We're all cooking a...
- Pasta.
- pasta.
I'd better go.
Pinky's burning it.
Yeah, okay.
Say hi to Dad, yeah?
Okay. Bye, Mum.
Good. They sound happy.
Pinky will meet someone new, and Jessie
will forget all about this football nonsense.
- Dinner's ready?
- [ Panjabi ]
- But let me wash up first.
- Call her back in Croydon.
I want to speak to them.
- [ Panjabi ]
I said I want
to speak to them!
Okay, Papa.
Oh. I didn't bring anything
for a club.
I didn't know they wanted
to take us out clubbing.
I bet it's to gloat.
Mel, we need some help.
- [ Chattering ]
- Look atJess!
- # [ Woman Vocalizing ]
- [ Chattering Continues ]
- Jess.!
- Oh, wow!
- She look good? Looks good. Yeah.
- [ Murmuring In Agreement ]
Let's get a taxi.
# [ Woman Vocalizing ]
- Hello, darling.
- How's Jules?
I'm fine.
How are you?
- Are you gonna dance with me?
- No.
You've gotta dance with me.
You are such a wuss.
I'm sorry I missed
that penalty, Coach.
It's okay. Losing to theJerries on penalties
comes natural to you English.
You're part
of a tradition now.
Enough about football.
You're dancing with me.
- No.
- You are!
- Go on!
I'm not taking no
for an answer!
# [ Woman Singing ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
# [ Continues, Indistinct ]
- [ Groans ]
-Jess?
- [ Chuckling ]
- Whoa. Steady on there, young one.
[ Chuckles ]
You all right?
You sure?
Oh, God.
[ Groans ]
Oh, my head.
It's too smoky in there.
- Yeah.
- [ Chuckles ]
- # [ Continues ]
- [ No Audible Dialogue ]
That was so brilliant,
the way you came to my house.
You were brave enough
to face my mum.
Your dad can't be
as mad as her.
Your mum's a barrel of laughs
compared to me dad.
I don't need to be
close to my family,Jess.
I don't need you
to feel sorry for me.
You bitch!
Jules.
You all right,Jess?
Is that your mum and dad?
# [ Man Singing In Panjabi ]
[ Muttering ]
# [ Continues ]
[ Mother ]
What haven't we done for these girls, huh?
We bought a car for Pinky.
Jessie wanted computer,
music center, TV, video.
Pinks...
how do you know
Teet's the one?
I just know.
When you're in love
with someone...
you'll do anything
for that person.
Pinks...
do you think Mum and Dad will still
speak to me if I ever brought home a goreh?
- Who?
- No one. I'm just saying.
It's that coach bloke,
innit?
I knew something was up
when he turned up here.
- Nothing's happened.
- You make sure it doesn't, all right?
Look,Jess,you can marry
anyone you want.
It's fine at first when you're
in love and all that.
But do you wanna be the one
that everyone stares at...
at every family do, 'cause
you've married the English bloke?
- He's Irish.
- There'll all the bloody same to them, innit?
Why go to so much grief when there's
so many good-looking Indian boys to marry?
It's not like before,
you know?
Now they wear good clothes,
got flashyjobs.
Even know how to cook
and wash up.
How about Tony?
He's been mad on you for ages.
Hmm?
# [ Man Singing In Panjabi ]
# [ Continues ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Chattering, Indistinct ]
Jess?
- Hi.
Was that
the club chairman?
Yeah.
They told me they're considering me as
the assistant coach for the men's side next year.
That's great.
Congratulations.
Probably won't get it.
Better not to count
on anything.
You deserve it.
- Look, I really--
- I've already forgotten about us.
Yeah, good. Me too.
Your mum and dad didn't look
too pleased yesterday.
I suppose you've come to tell me
you're off the team for good.
It's not fair. I feel like I'm either
going to let the team down...
or really piss them off,
and I don't want to upset anyone.
Why are they so frightened
to let you play?
They want to protect me.
From what?
This is taking me away
from everything they know.
Whose life
are you living,Jess?
If you try pleasing them forever,
you're gonna end up blaming them.
What, like you?
- I'm sorry.
- No, you're right.
I stopped talking to my dad
because we had nothing to talk about.
I spent a year
getting pissed...
trying to forget
about the game...
but I couldn't.
But I can't just stop
talking to them like you.
I don't talk to my dad
because I know what he'd say.
He'd piss himself if he found out
I was coaching girls.
How do you know that?
How do you that he wouldn't be proud
that you didn't just give up?
You should be proud of what
you've given all of us.
Then why are you giving up?
- [ Mrs. Paxton ]Jesmindah, isn't it?
- Jesminder.
Jesminder.
Oh,yeah. I'm sorry.
Do you know I cooked
a lovely curry the other day?
[ Knocking ]
Darling?
Oh,you still not up?
Guess who's come to see you.
It's your Indian friend
from football.
Oh...
Jules has been ever so down
since you lost in Germany.
Maybe you can cheer her up
a bit, eh?
Do you two want some tea? I'vejust made
some cheese straws with real gruyere.
No, that's all right.
Jess won't be staying long.
Oh.
Well, um...
just give us
a shout downstairs...
if there's anything
you two fancy.
All right?
Look, I feel really bad
about what happened.
Yeah, well, you should.
I'm sorry.
I don't want you to be
in a strop with me.
I'm not in a strop.
It was a mistake.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I can't believe you kissed him.
- I didn't.
- Yeah, right.
Jess, I know what I saw.
You knew he was off limits.
# [ Woman Singing, Indistinct ]
Don't pretend to be so innocent.
You knew exactly
how I felt about him.
You told me you didn't like him.
Now you're acting as if you're in love with him.
You don't know the meaning oflove.
You've really hurt me.
That's all there is to it!
You've betrayed me!
[Jess ]
So that's it?
[Jules ]
Yeah, that's it. Bye.
Good-bye, Mrs. Paxton.
What's going on?
That's why she's been
so depressed lately.
'Cause thatJess
broker her heart.
She's in love... with a girl!
[ Sobbing ]
You're jumping to
all the wrong conclusions.
But I heard her!
So--
No wonder she never
looked twice at that Kevin...
or brought any boys home.
[ Sobbing Continues ]
I tried to get her
nice clothes.
We've had some lovely prints in
this summer...
you know, in swimwear
and sarongs, and that.
But she never wants
to go shopping with me.
It was terrible what they did
to that George Michael.
Going on about him
and all his private business...
in the papers like that.
Oh, no!
George Michael
is still a superstar.
And you still listen
to Wham!
- Do you fancy me, Tony?
- I like you, yeah.
- Well, good. Maybe we can go out then, yeah?
-Jess, what's going on?
I just think I need
an Indian boyfriend.
What is going on,Jessie?
You're acting all weird.
Sorry.
You know my coach, yeah?
Yeah.
- I nearly kissed him in Germany.
- [ Chuckling ] Wow!
And that's why you need
an Indian boyfriend.
Well,Jules likes him,
too, and now she hates me.
Look,Jessie. You can't plan who you fall for.
It just happens.
- I mean, look at... Posh and Becks.
- Well, Beckham's the best.
- [ Chuckles ] Yeah! I really like Beckham too.
- Well, of course you do.
No one can cross a ball
or bend it like Beckham.
No,Jess.
I really like Beckham.
What? You mean--
[ Incredulous Scoff]
But you're Indian.
Look, I haven't
told anyone.
[ Chuckles ]
Cor! What's your mum gonna say?
- My sister thinks you're mad about me.
- I am.
I just don't
want to marry you.
[ Men Chattering,
Indistinct ]
I wonder what all those
tossers would say if they knew.
Jess...you're not
gonna tell anyone.
Of course not.
It's okay, Tony.
- I mean, it's okay with me.
- Yeah.
Well, you fancying your goreh
coach is okay with me.
Besides...
he's quite fit.
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Sneezes ]
- Listen, you gotta be back by 3:00.
- I can't keep them at temple all day.
- Yeah. I owe you big time.
- Laters.
- Get back into bed.
- Bring me back some langar.
- We're going to pray to God
to give you both sense...
not bring back food for you.
[ Panjabi ]
# [ Chorus ]
# [ Techno ]
# [ Woman Singing,
Indistinct ]
[ Family Chattering ]
Jessie, it's only me.
[ Panjabi ]
Jessie? Jessie?
# [ Continues,
Indistinct ]
Yes! They don't all
look like lezzies, do they?
Lads! Check out the boobs
on the captain.
[ Taz ]
Geez, man. They must get in the way.
She's lucky she ain't knocked herself out,
running up and down the pitch with them!
- [ All Laugh ]
- Why can't you lot just
see them as footballers?
- [ Scoffs ]
- What?
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Footballer ]
To the side.! To the side.!
Come on.! Move it.!
Down 1-nil. Come on.!
- Over end.!
- Hurry up.! Come on.!
- Come on! Push it through!
- Go on, love!
[ Footballer ]
Mel.!
- Uuh!
- [ Mel ] Go on,Jess.!
[Jess ]
Jules.! Over.!
Jules.!
[ Crowd Cheers ]
- Whoo!
- [ Chattering ]
[ Mel ]
Come on, Harriers.
Me.! Me.!
Over here,Jules!
[ Mel ]
Go on,Jess.!
- Go on.!
- Aah! What are you playing at?
- Piss off, Paki!
- Sod you!
- Number 7. Go away. Go away.
Number 7, come here.
- Did you see that?
What's the matter
with you, ref?
- Violent conduct towards another player. Off.
- [ Girls Protesting ]
[ Mel ]
She fell! Then it's out of order!
[ Crowd Jeering ]
She is so hard!
Aw, man.
Unlucky, Tony, mate.
- Shut up.
- [ Laughs ]
What the hell's wrong
with you, Bhamra?
I don't ever want to see anything like
that from you ever again. Do you hear me?
We're lucky they're not suspending players
in this tournament.
All right! Excellent! We've got Q. P.R.
in the final. Give yourselves three cheers.
- Hip hip!
- [ All ] Hooray!
- Yea!
- Hip hip!
- Brilliant.
- [ Chattering ]
Why did you yell at me like that?
You knew the ref was out of order.
-Jess, you could've cost us the tournament.
- But it wasn't my fault!
- You didn't have to shout at me.
-Jess, I am your coach.
I have to treat you
the same as everyone else.
Look,Jess... I saw it.
She fouled you.
She tugged your shirt.
- You just overreacted, that's all.
- That's not all.
She called me a Paki, but I guess you wouldn't
understand what that feels like, would you?
Jess, I'm Irish.
Of course I'd understand
what that feels like.
[ Sobs, Sighs ]
Jesminder?
[ Mrs. Bhamra ]
Oh, please come. Oh, here he is.
Uh, Tejinder's mother and father
have come to speak to us.
[ All Greeting
In Panjabi ]
- Are you well?
- Thank you, yes. Thank you.
- [ Teetu's Mum ] Um--
- [Jess ] What's happening?
- Teet's mum and dad have come to eat dirt.
- [ Mum Continues, Indistinct ]
Stupid cow. I don't know who
she thinks she is in that sari.
No mother can stand by
and watch her son go through this.
[ Mrs. Bhamra ] Well, our Pinky, she didn't
come out of her room for days. She was crying.
[ Teetu's Mum ] Well, our Teetu also. For days
he has eaten nothing and drank nothing.
[ Car Alarm Chirps ]
[ Conversing, Indistinct ]
Bye-bye.
# [ Man Vocalizing ]
- [ Pinky Squeals ] Thanks, Dad.
- Only too glad.
Mom. I'm getting married!
We'll give them a wedding party
they won't forget their whole life.
- Mla Kya, find out which date
the hall is free.
- I'll do that.
And,Jessie, go and get the old wedding cards.
They're in the extension.
-We'll change the dates by hand.
We'll have chicken, lamb...
-My name is Mohan Singh Bhamra.
and paneer tikka.
We'll show them.
We're not poor people. Hello.
Uh, yeah.Just hold on.
Will Sunday the 25th be okay?
- The 25th?
- There's a cancelation there.
No. That's too soon.
We need more time.
Yeah.Just hold on, please.
25th is only available date.
After that, there is no date
available for five months.
- Oh, please. Don't let me wait that long.
- Okay. Fine, baba.
- Let's just do it before
something else goes wrong.
- But, Dad, the 25th--
- [ Panjabi ] That wasn't for you.
- [ Pinky ] I've gotta do my hair,
my makeup, my nails.
- I'm so excited!
- Thank you.
- [ Receiver Clicks ]
- Your sister needs you.
# [ Man Singing
In Panjabi ]
# [ Continues ]
- [ Footsteps Approaching ]
- [ Door Shuts ]
Mel said you
wanted to see me?
- It's aboutJess.
- I don't want to talk about Germany,Joe.
- Listen,Jules--
- Whatever. I'm over it.
God, I don't even know why I was surprised.
You never think about anyone but yourself.
- Everyone knows you're leaving us next season!
- Nothing's been decided.
Bollocks.
You've already lied about the American scout.
He's never gonna show up, is he?
You can't bear the idea of anyone
else making it because you can't.!
He's coming to the final.
- What?
- He saw you play in Germany.
Oh. I thought--
Don't worry about it.
Jess?
[ Sighs ]
We all missed you at training today.
EspeciallyJoe. He, um--
He told me what happened with your dad.
He did?
Yeah.
He's-- He's worried he's gotten you
into even more trouble.
I'm really in the shit.
My dad hasn't
talked to me since.
- He'll never let me go back
to joining the team.
- But you can't miss the final.
Jess, there's gonna be
an American scout there.
I can't. It's the same day
as my sister's wedding.
Oh, shit.
- Well-- Well, can't you get away for a bit?
- You don't understand.
If you give up football now,
what are you gonna have to give up next?
Don't rub it in, all right? You came here 'cause
you need me if that bloody scout shows up.
Look. I came here 'cause
Joe was worried about you.
I'll just tell him
he's wasting his bloody time.
- The teriyaki sauce is the goalkeeper.
- Goalkeeper.
- The posh French mustard is the defender.
- Defender.
- The salt is the attacker.
- Sea salt.
The sea salt is the attacker.
Now, when the ball is played forward...
the sea salt has to be level
with the mustard.
Hello, darling. Right.
Now watch and concentrate.
- Offside, onside. Offside, onside.
- Offside, onside.
What are you doing?
Well, if the mountain
won't come to Mohammed--
- What?
- Don't laugh. I'm trying to teach
your mother the offside rule.
Well, I've decided that
I've got to take an interest...
or we're going
to lose you.
And this way, we can all
enjoy football as a family.
Right. So don't tell me.
The offside rule...
is when
the f-f-french mustard...
has to be between the teriyaki sauce
and the sea salt.
- She's got it.
- Got it.
Wonderful.
- You read all these as well?
- Yeah.
Oh, do you know what? One of those England
girls' players is a math teacher as well...
and she's happily married
with a baby.
- Hmm?
- [Jet Engine Roaring ]
[ Panjabi ]
Jessie, the A-level results.
Hurry up, Mum!
Good.
Thank you, thank you.
[ Panjabi ]
Jesminder Kaur Bhamra--
B, L, L, B.
You can become a fine,
top-class solicitor now.
# [ Chorus ]
[Jules ] She's not coming,Joe.
Her sister's wedding's on Sunday.
Guess I'm on
my own then.
You'll impress the scout.
No worries.
- How was she?
- A right stroppy cow, actually.
She's really pissed off she can't make it,
and she doesn't know what to do.
# [ Woman Singing
In Panjabi ]
Go on! Kick the ball,
kick the ball, kick the ball!
- Three players comin' behind ya
the whole time hunting you.
- [ Chattering ]
# [ Continues ]
[ All Chattering,
Exclaiming ]
[ Indistinct ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
[ Chanting In Panjabi ]
Yes?
I'm sorry to bother you
like this.
I don't have anything
to say to you, okay?
I appreciate it, and I won't keep you
long from the celebrations.
But I wanted you to know there's a scout
coming to our final match tomorrow.
- So?
- So... it's the opportunity of a lifetime forJess.
Please, Mr. Bhamra.
Don't let her talent go to waste.
Thank you.
What did he say, Dad?
Don't play with your future,
butai.
[ Rhythmic Chanting,
Clapping ]
Wait!
I'm sorry
about the final.
No, I'm sorry,Jess.
Got my results.
Starting university soon.
I won't have time to train and stuff.
Now, that's a shame. I could've
seen you play for England some day.
Jules still has a shot.
She told me about the scout coming.
Sorry I'm letting her down.
I asked that scout
to come for you too.
- He's interested in both of you.
- Me?
Mm-hmm.
Why are you doing this
to me,Joe?
Every time I talk myself out of it,
you come around and make it sound so easy.
I guess I don't want
to give up on you.
- [ Man Singing In Panjabi ]
- [ Laughter ]
So, uh, are you promised to one
of those blokes in there?
- [ Laughs ] Don't be silly.
- [ Laughs ]
I'm not promised
to anyone.
You're lucky... to have a family
that cares that much about you.
I can understand you don't want
to mess with it.
-Joe--
- And I don't fancy being
busted by your dad again.
You better get back.
I hope all goes well
for you tomorrow...
and good luck
with your studies.
Come and see us sometime.
# [ Continues ]
[ Scattered Whoops, Hoots ]
[ Chattering ]
Come on, love. Let's just hope
she fits in the car with that hat on.
You're going to a football match.
It's not Ascot. You look lovely.
- [ Crowd Fawning ]
- Beautiful.
Eyes down. Look sad.
Don't smile. Indian bride never smiles.
You'll ruin the bloody video.
[ Girl ] What does she look like?
[ Girl #2 ]
She looks like a jar ofbloody Ragu, innit?
Where the hell is the flippin' Rolls?
Can anything happen without me?
[ Overlapping Chatter]
# [ Woman Singing ]
# [ Woman Singing,
Indistinct ]
[ Whistle Blows ]
# [ Continues,
Indistinct ]
[ Deejay, Indistinct ]
I'm going to introduce you
to their families.
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Chattering ]
- Tony, what are you doing?
- We can still make
the second half if we leave now.
You're mad! My mum and dad'll go spare!
Anyway, I've just got to put them first today.
- There's so many people in there,
they won't even notice.
- I can't.
Look how happy they are, Tony.
I wouldn't ruin it for 'em.
- What are you going to ruin?
- Nothing. It's okay.
It's the final of her football tournament today,
Uncle.
We can pick up the kit on the way. I can
drive her there and back. It won't take long.
Stop it, Tony.
Dad, it doesn't matter.
This is much more important.
I don't want to spoil the day for you and Mum.
Pinky is so happy, and you look as if
you've come to your father's funeral.
Sorry, Dad.
If this is the only way I am going to see
you smiling on your sister's wedding day...
then go now.
But when you come back,
I want to see you happy on the video.
- [ Overjoyed Gasp ]
- Play well and make us proud.
?? [ Man Singing
In Panjabi ]
# [ Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
Joe!
- What's happening?
- Start warmin' up, Bhamra. Were 1 -nil, down...
with a half an hour
to go.
[ Whistling In Rhythm ]
[ Indistinct Shouts ]
Ref!.
[ Referee, Indistinct ]
[ Both Exclaiming
Delightedly ]
[ Mel ]
Form a wall, form a wall!
Oh!
- Good one,Jenny.!
- Kick it out.! Kick it out.!
- Have you seen Jesminder, Massi?
- No.
Jesminder!
Jesminder.
[ Panjabi ]
[ Gasps, Panjabi ]
Come on,Jules!
[ All Cheering ]
1 all!
[ Laughing ]
[ Girl ]
Over, over.!
- Waagh!
- [ Blows Whistle ]
# [ Angelic Choir ]
# [ Man Singing Aria ]
[ Squeals, Laughs ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Shouting In Panjabi ]
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Chattering ]
- Where does that bit go? Over the shoulder?
- Lift your leg up.
- [ Knocking ]
- Pax and Bham, are you decent?
[Jess,Jules ]
Yes.!
- Oh, is that coach?
- Mm.
- Mm. So who's that?
- Ah, he looks important.
- Yeah.
- I haven't seen him before.
- Look how happy she is though.
- I know.
[ Delighted Squeals ]
[Jules ]
Dad, I can't believe it. It was amazing.!
My eyes just glazed over.
What a game for him to see. It's incredible!
Santa Clara! It's in California.
It's like one of the top teams.
Hah! He thinks that he could give us,
like, a full scholarship...
which means you wouldn't
have to pay nothing.
Oh, it's so amazing. Me and Jess
there together, the pair of us.
# [ Continues ]
Come, Paula.
I'm not blaming you,
but it is the football. It is.
[ Sniffles ]
Come on, darling.
Come on.
I'm off then.
[ Sniffles ] Sweetheart, where are you going
in your-- in your best trousers?
- Out.
- Where? Who with?
I'm gonna meetJess
at her sister's wedding to celebrate.
Wait.
- Uh, I'll take you.
- Oh, thanks, Mum.
[ Arguing In Panjabi ]
# [ Women Singing
In Panjabi ]
[ Mrs. Bhamra Sobbing ]
Oh, my God.
It's so colorful.
Everyone looks brilliant.
Look at the car!
?? [ Continues ]
- Hi.
- You look gorgeous.
- Mum.
- Hello, Mrs. Paxton.
How could you be
such a hypocrite? Hm?
How could you be respectful
here with your lot...
when I know you've been kissing
my daughter in broad daylight?
- Mum.!
- Hmm?
You-- You--
[ Stifled Yelp ]
Take your lesbian feet
out of my shoes!
[ Woman ]
Lesbian?
Her birthday's in March.
I thought she was a Pisces.
- Uh-uh. She no Lebanese. She Punjabi.
- What are you doing?
Do you mind, dear?
But this just happens to be my wedding.
- How could you do this, sweetheart?
-Just get in the car.
[Jules ] What is wrong with you?
What are you talking about?
What the bleeding hell's
going on? Huh?
What's that goreh going on about you being
a lesbo? I thought you fancied your coach.
I don't know
what she was saying.
Jess, don't you want
all of this?
I mean, it's the best
day of your life, innit?
I want more than this.
They've offered me and Jules
a scholarship to go to America.
Yeah, but there's no way Dad'll let you go
and live abroad without getting married first.
-[Jules ] What the bloody hell
were you thinking?
- I saw you with my own eyes.
You were kissing
after your match.
I'm not stupid, you know.
And anyway, look at the clothes you wear.
- Mother,just because I wear
khakis and play sport...
- [ Blubbering ]
does not make me
a lesbian!
Me and Jess were fighting because
we both fancied our coach...Joe.
Joe, a man,Joe?
Yeah, as in male.Joe.
Joe our coach.Joe, man,Joe!
Oh--
Anyway, being a lesbian
is not that big a deal.
Oh, no, sweetheart.
Of course it isn't.
No. [ Chuckles, Sniffles ]
No. I mean, I've got nothing against it.
I was cheering for Martina Navratilova
as much as the next person.
I couldn't understand what
that English woman was saying.
Why was she talking
about kissing?
I think she got confused
like Teetu's parents.
Not so hard when young girls
have such short hair.
Biji, I think we were making
too much of noise.
English people are always complaining
when we're having functions.
[ Panjabi ]
Why did she take
Jesminder's shoes?
[ Overlapping Chatter ]
[ Sighs ]
How'm I gonna tell 'em,
Tony?
I have to now, or I'll end up a solicitor,
bored out of my mind.
Come with me.
[ Chattering Continues ]
Mum, UncleJi, AuntieJi.
We've got something
we want to tell you.
- [ Panjabi ]
- Why is he holding her hand?
You know how we've been good friends
for a long time now.
We'd like to ask
for your blessings.
We'd like to get engaged.
[ Scattered Exclamations
In Panjabi ]
But, look.
There's one condition.
I wantJesminder to go to college first
anywhere that she wants.
Of course, butai.
[ Panjabi ]
Well, we have relatives all the way
in Glasgow and Portsmouth!
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
- Mom, Dad, Tony's lying.
- Lying?
We're not
getting married.
Tony only said that to help me,
but I'm not lying anymore.
- I played in the final today, and we won.
- How? When?
I wasn't going to go,
but Dad let me.
And it was brilliant.
I played the best ever.
And I was happy...
because I wasn't sneaking off
and lying to you.
I didn't ask to be good at football.
Guru Nanak must have blessed me.
Anyway, there was a scout
from America there today...
and he's offered me a place
at a top university...
with a free scholarship and a chance
to play football professionally.
I really want to go.
And if I can't tell you what I want now,
then I'll never be happy whatever I do.
You let her leave
her sister's wedding...
to go to a football match.!
Maybe you could handle
her long face. I could not.
I didn't have the heart
to stop her.
And that's why she's ready
to go all the way to America now!
- [ Woman Panicking In Panjabi ]
- [ Whispers ] She's dead meat.
- [ Tony's Mum, Panjabi ]
- [ Tony ] It's all right, Mum.Just leave it.
When those bloody English cricket players
threw me out of their club...
like a dog...
I never complained.
On the contrary, I vowed
that I would never play again.
Who suffered? Me.
But I don't want
Jessie to suffer.
I don't want her to make the same mistakes
that her father made of...
accepting life
or accepting situations.
I want her to fight.
And I want her to win.
Because I've seen her playing.
She's-- She's brilliant.
I don't think anybody has
the right of stopping her.
[ Sniffling ]
Two daughters made happy on one day.
What else can a father ask for?
At least I've taught her full Indian dinner.
The rest is up to God.
[ Both Laugh ]
# [ Woman Vocalizing ]
Joe.!
I'm going!
They said I could go!
- [ Men ] Oi, oi, oi.!
- I'm sorry. I forgot.
- [ Pants ]
- That's okay now. I'm not your coach anymore.
We can do what we want.
-Joe.
- Your dad's not here, is he?
I'm sorry,Joe.
I can't.
I thought you wanted--
Letting me go is a really big step
for my mom and dad.
I don't know how they'd survive
if I told them about you too.
[ Exhales Sharply ]
I guess there's not much point,
with you going to America anyway.
Is there?
# [ Continues ]
- Mum, it's not perfume, is it?
- No. It's not what you think.
- Go on.
- It was your mum's idea.
It was.
- [ Gasps ]
- Hmm?
- Oh, thank you so much.
- [ Laughing ]
Make sure you keep this
by your bed all the time, huh?
And phone Papu Uncle in Canada
as soon as you land.
At least there's
some family close by.
Excuse me. It's getting really late.
You'd better board the plane.
-Just--
- [ P.A. Announcements, Indistinct ]
Jess.!
Don't worry.
That's her coach.
What are you doing here?
[ Sighs ] They offered me the job
coaching the men's side.
No more pulling pints.
- That's great,Joe.
- Yeah. I turned them down.
- What? Why did you--
- They're gonna let me coach the girls' side.
They want us to turn pro
next year.
- Wow!
- Can't keep losin' all my best players
to the Yanks, now, can I?
That's brilliant,Joe.
You should tell your dad, you know.
I already did.
[ Mrs. Bhamra ]
Are you sure we're doing the right thing?
Whatever God has written
for her will happen.Just relax.
Maybe after they trained you up,
I'll sign ya, if I can afford ya.
- Ah, you wish. [ Laughs ]
- [ Laughs ]
Look. I can't let you go
without knowin'.
What?
That even with the distance--
and the concerns of your family--
we might still
have something.
Don't you think?
# [ Woman Singing ]
Oh, my God.!
Dad, it's Beckham.!
Oh, it's a sign!
Jess, look!
It's Becks!
- I'm back at Christmas.
We'll tackle my mom and dad then.
- Yeah.
Okay. I'd better go.
-Jules. Take care of yourself.
- All right. I'll see you later, mate.
- Have a good time, love. Keep an eye out.
- Oh, and you.
Hey, you two. You're gonna miss this plane.
Ticket. Go. Go.
Bye, dear.
[ Muttering Good-byes ]
- Come on.
- Bye, sweetheart.
# [ Man Singing ]
- Hi.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
Good-bye!
[ Muttering ]
Come on.
Let's have a look.
- Hey, hey!
- Hey! Wow. Look at that.
# [ Continues ]
[ Thudding ]
[ Chattering ]
- Yes!
- [ Muttering ]
- No, no, no.
- Oh, yes, yes, yes.
# [ Chorus ]
?? [ Panjabi ]
Whoo!
[ Bleep ] I forgot the line. [ Laughs ]
[ Sustained Bleep ]
Heh! Wait.
[ Indistinct ] Oh! [ Bleeping ]
[ Bleep ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Woman ]
Excellent. Thank you.
- Laters!
- [ All Laugh ]
# [ Man Singing
In Panjabi ]