[ screaming ]
[ car alarms wailing ]
[ dogs barking ]
[ panting ]
I hate those things.
Oh.
???? [ "reality used to be
a friend of mine" ]
?? Ooo-ooo
ooo-ooo ??
?? Reality used to be
a friend of mine ??
?? May be why the question
that's on your mind ??
?? But reality used to be
a friend of mine ??
?? Reality used to be
[ barking ]
a friend of mine ??
?? Please don't ask me
'cause i don't know why ??
?? But reality used to be
a friend of mine ??
?? I used to be friends
with reality ??
?? She used to be a pal
real close to me ??
?? But she tried to hide from me
what was in store ??
[ howling ]
[ woman ]
stanley, is that --
will you put that back ?
Ummm.
Put that back !
Hey, i just washed
all this stuff.
It's my gear.
Sorry, man.
It's okay.
What's my mom
screaming about ?
She's bummed 'cause i
snaked your last bagel.
Grab a shovel,
man.
No, i just
wanna munch.
You don't wanna help,
that's just fine.
[ stoney ]
uh-huh.
You know, this is
a total waste of time.
Dave, be more of a geek.
There's no way
you're going to the prom.
[ girl ]
you're a disease.
Ahh.
And no one will ever swim
in this stupid pool.
Hey !
Later.
Look, david,
please do me a favor
and stress less, bro.
High school
is over, buddy.
Get into it.
We're losers.
I've decided something, stoney.
I wanna look back on
my high school career,
And think that i started
slowly but i finished
strong, you know ?
High school's almost over
and i don't have
anything to show for it.
I know, me neither.
You should be stoked
though, buddy,
'cause you got through
the last four years without
the full-on melon tweekage.
It's not enough.
I mean, i want my own
page in the yearbook.
Jump off the gym,
splatter on the street
and go for the co-ver.
It's not funny.
I'm not goin' down as
this geek kid from encino.
When i finish this pool,
i'm gonna have the
killer party after the prom.
I'm gonna be the prom king !
And i'm gonna graduate a legend.
[ stoney ]
well, what about me ?
Oh, well you'll
be there too.
Thanks, but robyn sweeney,
she's not goin' to
the prom with you, man.
-i wish she would but she's not.
-What are you talkin' about ?
Robyn sweeney
is mine.
She's become a major babe
and she loves me.
She finds you crusty,
dave.
I'll convince her.
She'll see
the truth.
Truth is...
Life's about greasin'
the do-back, buddy
and weasin' on the buffest.
High school was
interesting, right,
But it was kind of
like a harsh ride.
O-o-o-ow.
We're goin' on to bigger
and better things, buddy.
Stoney, i am on to
bigger and better things.
Count on it !
[ stoney yelling ]
[ stoney ]
oh, wow !
Hey, what's up ?
?? I'm a stoney crusty dude
?? Did you know that ?
Get out, dude.
[ stoney ]
?? I got a mop
on top ??
Watch out !
Excuse me.  could you move.
Me and my friend, david
are comin' through.
Hey, there's robyn.
Hey, robyn.
O-o-o-ow !
Four-wheelin'
over the ferns.
Look, dave, you're gonna
have to mellow out, bro,
on this whole robyn thing.
She always shines ya.
You don't understand.
We have history.
You had pre-freshman
history.  you could've
had her back then.
She hadn't hit
"babehood" yet.
Milk does a body good.
Check her.
[ stoney ]
she's clean, buddy,
And he's got her.
[ chuckles ]
Matt wilson ?
What a jerk.
What does she
see in him anyway ?
[ stoney ]
he's got the buff spikes
chillin' the top of his melon.
Dude, he's checkin'
her cheeks.  ooh !
He's got the serious beak,
his own personal... Oh !
Holding company,
Full of fundage, bro,
That he weases
off of ma--
jor.
[ stoney ]
eighteen inch bi's.
Bye-bye.
Mine are only four.
Besides that.
He walks like this,
right ?
Just like this,
the nugs fully loose.
[ bell rings ]
[ indistinct chatter ]
Hi, matt.
All right, everybody.
Quiet, please.
Settle down, quiet.
We're gonna start
this week's class...
Same place we ended
last week's class.
That's talking about
prehistoric man
in the what ?
Prehistoric man
in the -- ?
Oh, stoney ?
Ice age.
Yes, ice age.
That's right,
the ice age.
Why do we call it the ice age ?
'cause there was a lot of ice.
What do we call
these big chunks of ice,
those big slabs of ice ?
We called what ?
What do we call them ?
Glaciers.
Right.  you are paying
attention.  that's good.
These glaciers, as they
moved down our way,
They're so heavy, cold
and thick that they
freeze the ground water...
And they form
underground -- ?
Glaciers.
Right.  believe it or not,
some scientists believe
that there are actual...
Underground glacial movements
still in this part of the world.
You know what i think
that is, class ?
[ class ]
lame !
Exactly.
Bunco, bogus.
Listen,
please remember...
That most of this hemisphere,
including the ground
i'm walking on,
All of this was under ice
at some point, so i guess...
Finding something frozen,
dug up here or there,
Wouldn't be that uncommon
when you think about it.
So moving right along
on your journey of knowledge,
Let me show you
cro-magnon man.
[ girl ]
woo !
He's dope.
I'd go out with him.
[ class laughing ]
no, no.
I don't think so, ella.
Cro-magnon man, even though
he's not bad-lookin',
He's standin' upright and all,
he was extremely brutal.
He just took
whatever he wanted...
And that included
his women.
That's barbaric !
Indeed.
???? [ radio ]
Stone !
Stoney !
???? [ radio ]
Hey !  come on,
check this out.
That's my lobes.
Feel the ground,
man.
Whoa, buddy,
it's chillin'.
It's not like
chillin', chillin'.
Bro, it is chillin' !
I know.
It's cold !
It's so, uh --
help me.
Check it, buddy.
Oh, buddy !
Dude, i know
what this is, bro.
What is it ?
It's a
mousterian bowl.
No way !
Hey, come on, david.
Be careful with that.
What's a mousterian bowl ?
A mousterian bowl
from the mousterian era.
"prehistoric artifacts
for five hundred, alex."
Don't you ever
watch "jeopardy" ?
Buddy, this is kind of like
prehistoric tupperware, bro.
It's still preserved...
Like smuckers !
Oooow !
[ barking ]
Earthquake !
earthquake !
[ rumbling ]
Ahhhh !
Oh !
Oh god !
oh god !
Nice save, davage.
Stone ?
Yeah.
There's a guy
buried in my pool.
[ screaming ]
Hello, fred.
I'm glad i caught you.
Are you available
for a meeting
sometime this week ?
Ms. Morgan,
open the door !
Mom !
Mom, there's a guy
buried in our pool !
Mom !  mom !
Open the door !
[ indistinct yelling ]
i'm working !
Call 9-1-1 !
call 9-1-1 !
[ scratching ]
[ stoney ]
they never found
jim morrison.
Yeah, or jimmy hoffa.
Or jimmy mahoney.
He was a kid i knew
in cub scouts.
Come on,
let's go.
They never
found him.
David, i know
what this is.
What ?
It's a caveman.
Would you please !
No, i'm serious.
No way !
Whoa.
A caveman !
This is unbelievable !
Do you know what
this could mean for us ?
This could mean --
this could mean fame
or money !
Or popularity !
Far too much
responsibility for me.
Anyways,
i'm already popular.
Yeah, you travel
in large groups
of one, stoney.
Besides, this is
my one chance to make
somethin' out of myself.
You gotta help me dig
him out.  you were here.
You're part of it.
I don't wanna be part
of anything, dave.
i'm happy just to be me.
It could mean money.
You tellin' me you
couldn't use a,
a new scooter ?
Some new bell-bottoms ?
A little fun-dage ?
Wease some older nugs
with a mansion and a pool ?
Soakin' up the rays,
Watchin' all the
"jeop-ardy" you can handle ?
That was the clincher.
Everybody's got a price.
Come on, man.
[ lawn mower motor ]
Steady it !
Give it more gas,
more gas !
Perfect !  hold !
This thing
weighs a ton.
Ahh !
Hey, there's his pits,
bro.
[ david ]
that's his head.
That's his skull.
[ snoring ]
Get off me !
What are you
doin' ?
I don't like mornings.
Ow !  come on,
let's get up.
He's still in here.
No kidding, dave.
He's an ice cube.
We gotta
thaw him out.
Okay.
This has gotta be
our secret, okay ?
You can't tell anybody...
Nobody !
Can i tell
steve kooser ?
No one !
All right ?  nobody !
You understand ?
Yeah, zip...
Thank you.
Dee-do-dah.
???? [ rock ]
????
This is
kind of nice.
You were great.
Hi, robyn.
Hi, dave.
Guess what
i found ?
A life ?
No.  come here.
Guess what i found ?
I don't know.
i have no idea.
Guess ?  guess ?
[ whispering ]
i found a caveman.
A caveman ?
Shh.  yeah.
Oh dave,
you're drowning.
It's cool, right ?
I found a caveman.
All by myself.
I dug him out
of my backyard.
You wanna come check him out
after school ?
Well, uh --
I'm only invitin'
a few people.
I got that
prom thing.
Ten minutes...
Please ?
Dave, i just don't think
i'm ready to handle a --
A caveman.
You're not ?
All right.
I understand.
Bye, david.
[ sighs ]
i love it when
she calls me david.
Hello, david.
Agh.
Goin' somewhere ?
Yeah, i got a date
with your mom.
That's not nice.
It's a joke.
I'm sorry, just kidding.
[ grunting ]
You've been a headache
ever since the third grade.
God !
I know about your stupid
prom-king bullshit.
Forget it.
Robyn wouldn't piss
on your gums if your
teeth were on fire.
- yes, she would.
- [ chuckling ]
Shush !  hush, please !
Showin' your ignorance
again, morgan.
Some of us pump
and some of us slump.
You should
try some pump, morgan.
might clear up your acne.
You're so --
am i ?
N-no, stop.
Stop it !
Why do you
make me do this ?
[ dave ]
what are you writing ?
Hey, what did you write ?
Matt, not the
fire alarm !
Matt !  matt !
God, help !
Oh god !
[ alarm ringing ]
Hey, come here.
Oh, ta-ha-ha.
[ laughing, jeering ]
[ screaming ]
[ sniffing ]
[ grunting ]
[ barking ]
[ helicopter whirring ]
[ screams ]
[ glass smashing ]
Hmm.
[ truck engine ]
[ coughing ]
[ engine revving ]
[ yelling ]
I'll be back.
?? This is our philosophy
all these things
can turn you free ??
???? [ continues indistinct ]
?? Now in this land
of democracy why no one
sets the people free ??
?? Lady liberty rocks away
no truth, no justice ??
?? The american way ????
[ groans ]
?? Clap your hands
and dance ??
????
?? Treaty, oo-oh
treaty, yeah ??
?? Treaty, oo-oh ??
????
[ gasping ]
He melted.
Dave, it just wasn't
meant to happen.
Come on, i'll go
buy you some ho-hos.
Come on.
It's all right.
He melted.
Boris !
[ alarm sounding ]
[ screaming ]
What the --
[ sizzling ]
I can't believe it.
He's alive !
He was practically
an ice cube...
Practically.
I say
we just walk.
No, no way !
Oh, please.
He is ours.
We found him.
What ?
Be hospitable ?
[ sniffing ]
- ooh !
- ahh !  ahh !
How ya doin' ?
Hi, my name is dave.
Come here, come here.
Introduce yourself.
This is stoney.
Stoney, he's my friend.
Uh, this is my room.
It's okay.
it's okay.
Uh, we're
from encino.
It's a pleasure
to make your acquaintance.
And we hope you don't
gnaw on our beaks.
Shh.
I know what
i'm doing, stone.
We go to high school.
High school ?
He doesn't know
what high school is.
what anything is.
Just be
calm and easy.
Calm...
And easy.
Hey, hi.
- [ ringing ]
- [ screaming ]
- get the phone.
- okay.  okay.
[ caveman laughing ]
It's okay.
it's okay.
See, i think
he's calming down.
Calming... Down.
[ phone beeping ]
[ screaming ]
Ugh ?
Fire.
Flameage.
Buddy's into it.
That was kill,
stone.
Look at his eyes.
He likes the blue part.
He's glossy-eyed.
Look, freak
him out.  ow !
Ow !  ooh !
- ugh !
- okay.  ah, ah !
Give it to him.
No !
Ugh.  ugh.
- here, here.  look, here.
-You gotta teach him.
Whoa !  oh.
Hey !
No.
What ?
Did you just --
- i think he just said "no."
- no !
- no ?
- no !  no !
No.  no.
Cool, buddy.
He is so greasy !
Greasy ?  he's a
prehistoric pyromaniac.
We gotta
teach him stuff.
We'll teach him how to wease.
No.  no.
No !
No !  no !
Oh god.
We gotta teach him
how to be normal.
No, uh-uh.
We're goin' psycho
with him, bro.
That's boring, dude,
normal !
Stoney, come on, man.
Hang with me.
We gotta play
this thing out.
If we tell anyone,
if anyone sees him, they'll
take him away from us.
They'll cut him up
into little pieces.
They'll take all the credit,
and we'll still be geeks.
I'm not a geek.
i'm a unique weasel, david.
I'm just underrated 'cause
i live here in encino.
Bud ?
Buddy ?
O-o-o-ow !
Okay ?
He needs a bath...
Big time.
?? I'm too sexy
for my love ??
?? Too sexy for my love
love's going to leave me ??
????
?? I'm too sexy
for my shirt ??
?? Too sexy for my shirt
so sexy it hurts ??
?? And i'm
too sexy for milan ??
?? Too sexy for milan
new york and japan ??
[ growling ]
?? I'm too sexy
for your party ??
?? Too sexy for your party
no way i'm disco dancing ??
????
?? I'm too sexy
for my love ??
?? Too sexy for my love
love's going to leave me ??
?? I'm too sexy
for this song ????
Standing o.
Outstanding.
If i had a bic, bro,
right here.
Don't freak him out.
Let's show him
himself.
Okay.
You wanna see
your mug, bud ?
Check it.
Ugh !
What, dude ?
You should be with
your mug, bro.
You look buff.
Right ?
Hey, can you
say "ba...Uff" ?
Ba...Uff ?
[ laughing ]
I like that.
You know,
you pause too.
We gotta give him
a cool name.
Axl.
Yeah, buddy.
Not axl.
This is serious.
Okay.
We've got the missing link
standing in my bedroom.
Link !  link !
We'll call him link !
Okay, cool.
Maybe we could call him
stoney number two...
Because he's got
my same 'do...
And he's from
the stone age.
I like link better.
Okay, we'll
call him link.
But can i
call him linkage ?
Cool !
Let's see how
smart he is.
No, no.
Come here.
Okay.  okay.
You okay ?
Uh.
Uh, uh, look.
See ?
Ugh.
Ahh ?
Whoa !
Ahh !
Ahh, oow, ooo.
Ooow !
[ chuckling ]
Okay, okay.
Um, link.
Link.
No !
You're link.
I'm dave.  dave !
Dave.  dave.
No, dave, dave.
Dave, dave, dave.
Dave.
Yes !
Okay,
and that's --
That's stoney.
Mm-hmm.
Sto...Ney.
No, no.
Stoney.
Yes !
Ahh !
Okay, okay.
And now you are ?
Dave !
Ahh !
No, no, i'm dave.
You are ?
Buff.
[ sighs ]
no.
It's all right.
You've had a hard day.
[ car horn honking ]
- your parents !
- my parents !
Okay, uh, uh,
take him out back and ring
the doorbell three times.
But, dave --
no "buts,"
just do it !
Follow the weasel,
linkage, come on.
quick, quick, quick.
[ banging, crashing ]
my kitchen !
Busted !
What are you doing ?
I'm cooking dinner.
You're what ?
busted !
I'm cooking dinner.
I thought it might be
a nice surprise.
They're surprised,
all right.
[ ringing ]
What is
going on here ?
Where's the flour ?
I can't find the flour.
Hello, stanley.
Who is this strange boy and
why is he ringing my doorbell ?
It got stuck, sir.
Come in.
Meet your new family.
[ father ]
whose family ?
[ dog barking ]
Boris, get down !
boris !
- boris, get out !
-[ dave ] get down !
-[ link screaming ]
- get out, get out !
Hey, dad.
David,
who is that ?
Huh ?
That ?
Who's that ?
- that was linkavitch chomofsky.
- what ?
Link... Linkav--
doesn't anybody in this house
listen to anything i say ?
What is he
talking about ?
Dad, linkavitch
chomofsky.
Our exchange student ?
He's here.
He's gonna help us
dig the pool.
- yeah !
- [ sighs ]
Why does none of this
sound familiar to me ?
I told you about this
months ago, remember ?
About school giving us
extra credit for college
for housing exchange students,
And learning about
their culture and
you said it was okay.
Now you're gonna
take it back ?
No, no, no, i'm not
gonna take it back.
This is important to me.
this is my life.
It's embarrassing.
He travelled here
all the way from --
- i don't know, estonia ?
- yeah, estonia !
Mom, come on.
You're not buying this ?
Well, i --
dad ?
Actually, i, i,
i think now...
That i, i, i do
recall something.
- see ?
- see, it's about focusing.
You're bogus.
Larry, how could i forget
something like this ?
He's an exchange student.
He's going to be staying
in our house.
You forgot me
in the third grade.
I spent the entire night after
the play in the parking lot.
In the sixth grade, the soccer ?
Okay, where's
he gonna stay ?
[ banging ]
And why is he
attacking the dog ?
He's gonna stay in my room.
He's not attacking the dog.
He's bonding.
- as if !
- shut up !
- you shut up.
- no, everybody shut up.
Larry, it's okay.
I'm tired.
i'm a little hungry.
It's time we decide
what we're gonna make
for dinner.
I assume you'll
be joining us ?
You assume correctly, mr. M.
We practically feed the
entire neighborhood.  why not
part of estonia as well, huh ?
I always eat here
and i like your food.
Great.
[ ringing ]
Stop it !  no.
No, no, no.
[ rings ]
[ dave ]
i can't believe you told
my parents he's from estonia.
[ stoney ]
cow pajamas ?
Those are kind of flaming.
Ooh !
Some betty, huh ?
Betty.
Gonzangas.
Gonzangas ?
Buddy, cones.
I know you've had
a big day, pal.
But tomorrow...
I'm gonna take you
someplace really special.
Taco bell.
Better.
Get the camera.
Congratulations, link.
You're gonna be a senior.
Smile.
?? Wild thing ??
?? You make
my heart sing ??
everything groovy ??
?? Wild thing ??
Oh god,
he doesn't like that.
That's glass.
That hurts your beak.
Stand up straight.
[ stoney ]
poor stone-ager.
He spent a million years
chillin' in a block of ice,
Now he's gotta go
to high school !  agh !
Who's that guy with
the dork squad ?
Oh my god,
he is totally rude.
Totally.
We have got a
major find here.
This guy's our ticket
to fame and popularity.
All we gotta do is get him
enrolled in school and he'll
help us become popular.
That's harsh.
We'll make him famous.
We'll teach him some
stupid pet tricks and
get him on letterman.
You're weasin' off
his gig.
Oh please !
He's a caveman,
for god sakes.
Look at him.
He's practically
a monkey.
We found him.
We can do whatever
we want with him.
We, we, we ?
No, no, no.
You, you, you.
I just wanna be
his friend.
Fine.
Hello, mrs. Mackey.
And what do we
have here ?
Now i'm covered
up to fourth period.
I don't know what to do
with him after that.
I can take him to spanish.
Will you be careful ?
I'll be cool, man.
I promise.
Okay.
What's he doin' ?
[ dave ]
i don't know.
Link, be careful !
Uh, hey, hey --
Hey, link,
how's your melon, bud ?
[ sniffing ]
Whoa !
Excuse me.
Hey, hey, hey !
[ grunting ]
whoa.
Link ?
Is this dude
totally fundamental
or what ?
Did you miss me ?
Always.
Who is this ?
This is
my friend, link.
Link.
He's staying with us.
he's from estonia.
You're kidding ?
This guy is staying with you ?
Uh-huh.
He's thinkin' of
becoming a hairdresser.
Designing crusty mops
for the rich and famous.
Oh.
Ugh.  gonzangas.
No !
Bye, robyn.
Hey, hey, hey.
I think he was saying
he likes your cones.
I'm thrilled.
Get out of my face !
Robyn,
that import is mine.
This is just
in time for prom.
Yeah ?
Is he fine
or what ?
I'm not sure.
He's a looker !
Link.  link !
Link, please,
come sit down.
Who is this dipshit,
anyway ?
His name's link.
He's from estonia and
i think he's jive.
Jive, yeah.
You do ?
Hell yeah,
and i'm not the only one.
Hey, link !
[ coughing ]
[ bell ringing ]
i'll see you
next period.
Watch him.
All right, david.
We got spanish now.
Spanish is like guacamole,
chips and salsa.
La d?A es mi
en hermanos.
The day is beautiful.
???? [ rap ]
The sun isn't shining
all through the night.
????
Link, come on.
Sorry, you guys.
Whoa !
Vale, repitan en espanol.
The cheese is
old and moldy.
[ class ]
el queso est?
Viejo y podrido.
[ teacher ]
where is the bathroom ?
¿¿ d?Nde est?
el sanitario ?
[ teacher ]
good, once again.
You're cute.
Meet me
at blades tonight.
Blades tonight.
Yes, what ?
You can drop him off in front
of blades tonight, right ?
Can david and i
go too, please ?
You smell.
Hey, seniorita.
That hurt my lobes.
I didn't do it.  they
started the whole thing.
Kashmir ?
Rajneesh, is it ?
How many minutes
for the burrito ?
[ kashmir ] two minutes.
[ rajneesh ]
one minute.
Two minutes !
Ah, make up
your melons !
Is it one or two ?
[ rajneesh ]
one and a half minutes.
Okay.
Okay, my friend.
Try and experience...
What i'm about to chirp
in your lobes, cool ?
Hey.
We're going
to discuss grindage;
How to fill the furnace,
pack the cheeks and
stuff the gills.  okay ?
You're used to
eating twigs, right ?
But here in the u.S. Of a-age
we got something called...
The four basic food groups,
and this is not one of 'em.
Oh.
Look at what
we have here.
Dairy group.
Milk duds.  hide these
under your pillow so
your mom doesn't find them.
If she does,
you're tweaked, buddy.
Keep on cruisin'.
Fruit group.
Sweet tarts.
These are killer.
So citrusy, dude,
you'll freak.
Keep on cruisin'.
Uh-huh.
Right, this is
the vegetable group.
Corn nuts !  put 'em
on a pedestal, bro.
Look at that !
Those are kill, huh ?
[ microwave rings ]
Meat group !
Come on, the meat group.
These are my favorite !
Hey, you gotta be equal,
equal, fifty/fifty.
Here.  mmm.
Mmm.
Ooh !  figures.
Hot on the outside,
icicle in the middle.
[ rajneesh ] two minutes.
You like that, right,
'cause you're a caveman.
Cool, buddy.
The beverage !
Icee, bro.
This is what put
this place on the map.
What are you doing,
mr. Stoney ?  no, no !
- you can't do this here.
- you must leave now, please.
-look, kashmir, rajneesh, chill.
-No buds chill !
Link and i are
cruisin' the mountain and
we figured we'd wease ju-uice.
- no weasin' the ju-uice.
- wease the juice !
No !  no weasin'
the juice.
No weasin' the juice.
Hey, just chill,
buds.
No buds chill.
It's okay.
Just chill.
I'll be back.
No buds chill !
[ screaming ]
Oh god, no !
Wait !  stop !
Here we go !
[ screaming ]
Comin' home !
Was that the hottest
or what, bro ?
Are you into it ?
[ stoney ]
?? Joy to the fishes
in the deep, blue sea ??
?? Joy to you and me ??
[ dave ]
stop !
Where did you go ?
You just took off.
Do you know
how worried i've been ?
You sound like
my mom.
You can't
do that to me.
What's on his nose ?
Just chill, dave,
'cause you know why ?
Link and i had a
stoney time at the mountain.
You took him to
mega mountain ?
Are you crazy ?
Yeah, 'cause they're
riding the vapor in reverse.
They are ?
Oh, cool.
uh-huh.
Check out the fresh nugs.
Weasin' the juice.
O-o-o-ow.
Buddy.
[ link ]
check out my cap.
O-o-o-ow !
Oh my god !
You got him
talkin' like you now.
O-o-o-ow.
Gee, link, that
is so beautiful.
Is it old ?
You know, mr. M.,
the way i look at it,
some day...
Your daughter and i
could be married...
And we could
be related.
I count the days.
So, stanley,
how's your mother ?
She's really bummed.
Can you pass the peas ?
Sure.
Thanks.
Mr. Morgan, if you're edged
'cause i'm weasin' on your
grindage, just chill.
'cause if i had
the whole brady-bunch
thing happenin' at my pad,
I'd go grind over there.
So don't tax my gig so
hard core, cruster.
- stanley, speak english.
- dad !
Link, how was your day ?
How are you adjusting ?
He's doin' just great.
We got him enrolled
in all his classes.
Didn't we, pal ?
Yeah.
Ugh.
A success.
[ fly buzzing ]
What's up ?
How was your day, mom ?
Where you goin' ?
- what's he doin' ?
- i think he's tracking a fly.
?? Shoo, fly
don't bother me ??
?? 'cause you belong
to my friend, link ??
Good catch.
Meat group !
[ sniffing ]
He's into munchin' too,
you know.
[ gagging ]
Blades... Finally
part of the elite.
How cool are we ?
We're cool.
David, i even showered.
Check out my --
I got some radical
deodorant on, buddy.
Take a whiff, bro.
?? Oh no
you're invited but
your friend can't come ??
Link, hey !
I am so glad
to see you.
Ugh.
Oh, hon, lose the geek squad.
They're bad for your deal.
Ugh ?
Blades !
Hummer patrol,
barneys incoming.
Robyn.
Get him.
Got him.
Hey, rob--
Robyn !
Good.
That was not cool
at all, you guys.
You could hurt his
pancreas or something.
I like the ketchup
and mustard.
Very avant-garde.
Whoa !
Is that me ?
Betty.
betty ?
Betty, betty nugs.
Betty nugs.
Robyn, don't forget,
We've been
naked together.
Nice body.
Remember when
we were together ?
Did you show this
to anyone ?
No.
That's your copy.
Show anyone you want.
Thanks, dave.
Oh, i get it.
This is like your
old girlfriend in estonia ?
Do you miss her ?
Ugh.
Because i can tell you
from experience,
Long-distance relationships
never work out.
Ugh.
Estonia's a
long ways away, link.
Yeah.
And i'm right here...
So let's work on changing
your mind.
[ voice ]
rad mobile.
Rad mobile
Whoa !
Or not.
You just think i'm
bad for your act,
that's all.
Right, and you think
i'm good for yours.
What ?
Matt !
What are you doin' ?
You're not allowed in here.
Whoa-oa-oa !
Woo !
woo-woo-woo-woo !
Are you deaf, dork ?
Didn't i forbid you
to speak to her ?
I'm sorry.
That's all, link.
It's over.
End of story.
[ yelling ]
[ indistinct arguing ]
I'm sorry.
i'm sorry.
Huh ?
[ link ]
wease some juice !
Hey, you want
a piece of me ?
Oh god !
I don't know you.
I don't like you.
As of now,
i'm all over you.
Did you see that ?
the new kid,
he took it.
Whoa !
Don't just stand there.
Do something.
Stand up for yourself.
Hit him back !
Link, hit him back !
Where you goin' ?
What do you think of your
bulgarian dork bud, now ?
Hmm ?
That was harsh,
matt.
Let's get
out of here.
The stench of losers is
doing damage to my sinuses.
Just stop it, matt.
Don't even come near me.
Hey, watch it.
Why don't you take this,
'cause i don't think
i need it anymore.
Hey !
I can't believe
he got nailed.
He's a pacifist.
A pacifist caveman !
You're mental.
Cavemens aren't like us,
dave.
They fought for food and
survival.  they did not
fight for popularity.
What would he be
fighting for, huh ?
For face.
For us !
To be cool !
Cool, huh ?
He does not know
what cool is.
He doesn't know where he is.
he knows nothin'.
He's gotta learn
how to defend himself.
Against what ?
Against butt holes
like matt.
Come on.
come on.
?? I'm gonna knock you out
mama said knock you out ??
[ tv announcer ]
our airplane's been
going round and round.
[ dave ]
stop !
Hey, stop !
?? Knock you out ??
[ grunting ]
?? I'm gonna knock you out
mama said knock you out ??
mama said knock you out ????
Ow !  hey, link !
[ bell ringing ]
Hey, look !
Hey, dude.
You took it from wilson.
No one's ever done that
before and survived.
Link,
come back here.
Stop !
Oh god.
He is so cool.
?? Matty told hatty ??
?? 'bout a thing she saw ??
?? It had two big horns
and a wooly jaw ??
?? Wooly bully ??
?? Wooly bully
wooly bully ??
?? Wooly bully ??
Hey.
Homeslice.
See you in
mr. Albert's class.
Slicey.
Hello, little one.
We took a vote and
the computer club
feels your presence...
Will be a valuable asset
to our organization.
Computer club.
computer club.
Homeboy.
Why doesn't that happen
when matt hits me ?
Give yourself a
few million years, david.
[ indistinct chatter ]
Link.  link.
link, get down.
All right,
come on.
No, no.
I was just playin'.
[ teacher ]
all right,
cro-magnon man.
What you're looking at here
is a representation...
Of what cro-magnon man's
everyday life
may have been like.
If he was here today, you could
sit next to him, you would
never know the difference.
Stoney, let's move on.
We're gonna look at
the giant sloth.
[ growling ]
Class, this is
saber-toothed cat.
Even though he's
been extinct for
over 10,000 years,
While he was alive
you can imagine that
many a caveman...
Was a tasty meal
to one of these.
[ link screaming ]
There's one now.
Uh-oh.
Let's look at
the mammoth display,
our school mascot.
Look out !
Whoa.
Link !  link,
get out from there !
[ screams ]
Look at him.
He's flipping out.
He knows, dave.
What ?
He knows.
He knows what
happened to him.
We have
to help him.
Link.
Link.  link.
Ow !
Link.
Hey.  hey,
come on, man.
Stop it.
Look, i understand.
Family.
You okay ?
It's okay.
We're your new family.
We're your
new family.
It's okay.
It's all right.
[ stoney ]
he's burnt
from all this.
Seeing as we started
the school year
as total losers,
And now everyone
knows who we are,
I don't think one mistake
is such a big deal.
But you're doggin' him.
Just promise me,
Just a little more mellow,
not so much ?
Stoney !
Dave !
All right.
If it'll make you
feel better, i'll be
more mellow with him.
Robyn sweeney ?
Here.
Again ?
I'm sorry.  i can't get
that parallel parking thing.
Whoa.  parallel parking
is not a thing, understand ?
It's not a feeling,
not a state of mind,
or one of your disco dances.
Yeah.
Get in the car and
don't take it personally.
Okay, mr. Beady.
- linkavitch chomofsky ?
- ugh, ugh.
What are you
lookin' at ?
Ugh.
Get inside the car...
And shoot
your barber.
Contrast this
with hemingway's
"the sun also rises,"
Where the blood sport
of bullfighting...
Is used and
perhaps what --
uh-oh.
Oh god.
Rad mobile !
Boys, will you sit down ?
Class ?
You promised me mellow.
This isn't mellow.
Link !  link !
Dave.
[ dave ]
watch the people !
Grab the wheel !
Okay !
[ dave ]  stone,
tell him to stop !
Okay, stop.
[ stoney ]
didn't phase him, bro.
Oh shit !
All right, link.
Joke's over.  stop !
- he-e-e-ey !
- stop that car, young man !
I'm your teacher.
Both hands on the wheel !
[ applause, cheering ]
Who was that ?
Crosswalk !
crosswalk !
Close call, buddy.
[ stoney ]
hey, buddy !
Hi, robyn.
Hi, dave.
Red light !
[ screeching, honking ]
Boom !
Up on two wheels !
I've never seen
anything like this.
I don't teach that.
I got the license plate.
It's e684-257.
You don't have to write
that i left the keys
in the ignition, do you ?
Ow-o-o-o-o !
[ dave ]
i think he's got
the hang of it.
That concludes our
parallel parking for today.
Class dismissed.
[ robyn ]
link, i think you
just failed driver's ed.
[ stoney ]
hey, link,
wait up.
[ dave ]
where are we ?
Great !
?? Move your body ??
?? Move your body
to the rhythm of love ??
?? Move your body ??
?? Move your body
to the rhythm of love ??
Hola, mi amigos.
Is it okay if i just
chill upon here ?
Orale.
You wanna be a man,
ese ?
Eventually, yeah.
But i'm almost there.
Look at my patch, bro.
Ohh !
Ooh !
Mucho macho.
Ooh.
Oh, this is tequila ?
Wait,
where's the worm ?
The worm's right there,
ese.
Ut-uh.
I'm a weasel.
A weasel, eh ?
You wanna be
a man, weasel ?
- you wanna be a man ?
- then drink like an hombre.
No, i can't.
You're showing us
disrespect.
Ah, you guys --
That's disrespectful,
weasel.
Be a man, ese.
Drink it up.
Drink like a man.
You can do it,
weasel.
Bottoms up.
You can do it.
Andale.
[ howling ]
Wait.
I otra, otra !
Otra vez, otra vez,
otra vez.
Okay, okay,
stop !
Five more, man.
[ chanting ]
weasel, weasel.
[ howling ]
[ chanting ]
weasel, weasel.
Wait, stop.
Dude, do i have
to pay for 'em ?
????
Hey, stone.
Hey.
Where's link ?
Dancin'.
????
Cool,
let's go dance.
No, no.
I'm not good.
Let's not dance.
You are too uptight.
I, i just don't
like to dance.
Hey, weasel.
What's happening ?
Hey.
Dave, enrique.
Hey, man,
You see that
muchacha over there ?
Oh man, yeah.
You see her ?
you see her ?
Don't be lookin'
at her, man !
I'm sorry.
You see her ?
No.
If i see any man
looking at my muchacha,
that man will no longer...
Be recognizable
as a man.
I want you vatos
to have a good time.
Yeah.
See you later,
weasels.
See ya.
?? Feel the rhythm
feel the rhythm everywhere ??
feel the, feel the
feel the rhythm ??
?? Move your body ??
?? Move your body
to the rhythm of love ??
Oh !
Chomofsky.
chomofsky.
Got it.
Chomofsky.
Rabies, distemper,
flea dip.
What is this ?
It's a dog license,
man.
Whoa.
Animal shelter.
What are the
two biggest losers
in school hiding ?
A dog ?
It's not
his license.
Mm-hmm.
Let's get
out of here.
?? Dance ??
?? You know
you really turn me on ??
?? Come on now,
honey ??
?? You know
you really turn me on ??
Hey !
?? Get filled
get filled ??
?? And when
when, oh when you do it ??
?? Uh-uh-uh-oh
that's the song ??
????
[ screams ]
Wow !  wow !
?? Uh-uh-uh-oh
that's my song ??
?? Let's do it
let's do it
you turn me on ??
?? Let's do it
let's do it
come on now, sugar ??
?? Come on and
just stick it to me ??
?? You turn me on
come on now, sugar ??
You're right, ese.
She's not worth it.
- the vato's got the point.
- she ain't worth it, homes !
Come here, vato.
Police.
Immigraci?N.
[ dave ]
let's get
out of here !
Oh shit !
Stone, take robyn.
[ burp ]
Robyn, take stone.
Get him out of here.
I'll meet up
with you guys later.
All right, get out.
[ robyn ]
come on, i'll drive.
Link !
[ making monkey sounds ]
link !
The cops are here.
Get down.
Come on.
We're gonna get busted !
You are busted.
Get down, man.
[ all together ]
stoney is the crustiest vato...
I've ever witnessed.
So don't hush his gig,
buddy.
Ow-o-o-o !
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ stoney ]
eh, buddy !
Bye, guys.
Drive safely.
[ horn honking ]
Nice element
you're hanging out with.
Who are your friends
in the low-rider ?
None of your business.
Go home.
Huh.
What time do you want me
to pick you up tomorrow night ?
It's the prom,
remember ?
You are just like
everyone else.
All you care about
is what people think.
It's really pathetic.
Hey, watch it.
Matt, i'm not going
to the prom with you.
I wanna go with somebody
who's really cool,
Who's not afraid of
being himself or having fun.
Good night.
Who's cooler than me ?
Your phone call.
You got one.
Make it quick.
Thanks.
[ phone ringing ]
Matthew wilson !
Hello.
Robyn ?
Robyn.
Dave, did you guys
get away okay ?
We're in prison.
Look, this is
my one phone call.
I'm using it to ask you
to go to the prom with me.
Just say yes,
okay ?
[ sighs ]
no.
Why not ?
I wanna go
with link.
What ?
Will you ask link
if he'll go with me ?
You want me to what ?
Look, i'm sorry.
I'll tell you what.
We'll all go.
we'll have a great time.
How about that ?
Dave ?
[ stoney yelling ]
Hey !
¿¿ c?Mo est? Usted ?
Muy bonita...
Es la d?A.
Hey, wait.
How was jail ?
Did you meet anyone ?
Hey, wait !
Wait up.
Things just didn't
turn out right.
Ugh.
I mean, i don't
want 'em cuttin' you up
into little pieces.
This is just what's
best for you.
It's best for me too,
all right ?
Here.
For rad mobile.
Yeah.
Put 'em
in your pocket.
Don't look at me
like that.
This is just the way
it's gotta be.
Go on,
get out of here.
Go on.
Go on, leave.
Go.
I'm sorry.
[ stoney ]
hey, hey, hey !
Talk to me, david.
Let me know what's
going on, man.
What are you doin' ?
I'm letting him go.
What ?
I can't handle him
anymore.
He'll be better off
with somebody else.
No, he's not !
Listen to me.
Call him back.
I can't take it anymore.
I'm not kiddin'.
Call him back.
It's time.
I'm serious.
Call him back.
That's harsh.
He's not
my responsibility.
You're the one who weased
off his gig the whole time...
'cause you thought maybe
he'd get you somewhere.
Now the guy gets a little crusty
and you're gonna bag him.
It's not happenin', dave.
That's not how it works
with friends, man.
You don't bag your friends
'cause they get in the way,
no matter what, dude.
Like you care ?  the only thing
you've cared about is nugs,
chillin' and grindage.
I happen to care
right now.
That's convenient.
You came along for
the ride and let me
do the dirty work...
'cause you thought it might
work to your advantage.
Those are desperate words
of a loser.
Maybe matt wilson was right
about you all along.
Take that back.
No, you take it back.
Take it back !
You're a loser.
- [ link ]  family !
- all right.
I'm sorry.
Family.
You can let go,
link.
I'm sorry, man.
It's okay.
I don't know
what got into me.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it,
stoney.
I'm sorry, bud.
Ow !
You look great.
Have a good time.
You deserve it.
[ doorbell ]
[ sniffing ]
If you touch her ?
Ugh.
You think
they're ready ?
I don't know.
Dave ?
Dave, hey.
Hey.
You're not ready.
I, i can't go.
Of course you can.
Just go upstairs,
put something on.
No, really, i can't.
I'm on probation.
I'm grounded.
Hi, link.
You look great.
Hi.
You guys go.
Have a good time.
Go on.
No, no, no.
Come on.
Come on, dave.
Go.
Are you sure ?
Go, have a good time.
go, link.
Get outta here.
Have a good time.
Drive safely.
God, she smells good.
[ dave ]
to link.
May he have a cool time
at the prom.
Totally, bro,
to linkage.
[ sighs ]
there's always college.
Junior college.
[ matt ]
link, get down here.
Give me a boost.
[ grunting ]
Whoa.
[ laughing ]
Gotcha.
[ crashing sounds ]
[ sister ]
dave !
Stoney, come on !
Hey, what are
you doing ?
Give me back
those pictures.
No !
Hey, get back here !
They took the polaroids.
Uh-oh.
Come on.
Those are
our pictures !
[ rumbling ]
[ dog barking ]
[ applause, cheering ]
It's unanimous.
The vote for prom king...
Goes to...
Wait !
What's going on ?
Ugh.
What are you
trying to do ?
Come on, stop it.
This is our school,
right ?
Yeah.
We have a right to know if
somethin' bogus is goin' down...
In our school,
right ?
Yeah.
Right.
This homey right here
has taken you for a ride.
His name isn't
linkavitch chomofsky,
and he's not from estonia.
Matt, will you just
stop this already ?
Shush !
Trust me.
They've all
been lying to us.
But i found out.
I know the truth.
Do you wanna know
the truth ?
Yeah !
Do you want to know
what he really is ?
Yeah.
[ girl ]
tell us the secret !
He's a caveman.
[ cheering ]
No.  no !
Look, he's a freak !
[ applause, cheering ]
- i got pictures !
- no !
See ?
Let me see
those pictures.
Give me back those pictures.
give me those !
- [ matt ] no !
- [ robyn ] dave !
Hmmmm.
What are you doin',
fag ?
[ cheering ]
[ stoney ]
go, go, go !
Watch, watch, watch.
[ link yelling ]
Uh-huh.
Shush !
???? [ "feed the monkey"
by michael muir ]
????
?? Ow ??
?? She likes to feed the monkey
she likes to feed the monkey ??
she likes to funky ??
?? So gather 'round and
let me tell ya all a story ??
?? About a boy
and his monkey ??
?? He's got that kind of monkey
that the girls wanna know ??
?? He likes to take his monkey
every place that he goes ??
????
Ow-o-o-o !
?? Hey, ho
just say the monkey ??
Watch this.
Okay.
?? I didn't really know
how you get so hungry ??
?? I'd like to know
would you be my monkey ??
?? Monkey likes to do
the wild thing ??
?? My monkey don't scratch
my monkey don't bite ??
?? My monkey
don't swing in no tree ??
?? My monkey don't trick
my monkey don't fool ??
?? My monkey
be swingin' with me ??
?? My monkey don't freak
my monkey don't hit ??
?? My monkey don't
wear no cape ??
?? You can tell when my monkey
wants to eat ??
?? 'cause he turns into
a big ol' ape ??
????
[ making monkey sounds ]
[ horns honking ]
????
What you did
was pretty cool.
Who cares about cool
anyway, right ?
Right.
There's one really cool
thing i wanted to show you.
What ?
This.
[ cheering, laughing ]
Oh, dave !
Hey, buddy.
[ alarm ringing ]
[ yelling ]
[ stoney ]
it's your cave nug.
Ugh.
[ screaming ]
- ah-ha-ha-ha-ha !
- ow-o-o-o-o !
[ link, stoney ]
yeah !
Ow-o-o-o !
Oh yeah !
Yeah, buddy.
She is so greasy !
Duh-h-h-y !
Ah !  hey.
Buddy,
ow-o-o-o !
Yeah !
I'll be ba-ack !
?? Wow ??
????
?? Oh yeah, stoners ??
?? What's up, bro
ow-o-o-o ??
?? Buddy, fiesta ??
????
?? Do you need a woman
got the look in her eyes ??
?? Wanna cut me down to size
show me what you're gonna do ?
?
?? It's true ??
?? Who's that gorilla
standing by your side ??
?? Oh no
that must be your bride ??
?? You wouldn't be
with such a fool ??
?? Or your mama too ??
?? There's somethin' over here
i want you to see ??
?? There's a party
but it isn't for three ??
?? Get all this straight
between you and me because ??
?? Oh no
you're invited but
your friend can't come ??
?? Whoa no no
come on, baby
gonna have some fun ??
?? Wow ??
????
?? Heartbreaker, yeah
you came for the show ??
?? But little did you know
you'd end up in the spotlight ?
?
?? Well all right ??
?? Come on, babe, won't you
show me what you got ??
?? Ready or not
i want to ??
?? Here we go ??
?? Oh no ??
?? I'm makin' plans
for the rest of the night ??
?? So tell your father
that he better not bite ??
?? My jaws are bigger
and i'm ready to fight ??
?? So come on, come on, come on
give it up tonight ??
?? Whoa no
you're invited but
your friend can't come ??
?? Whoa, no no
come on, baby
gonna have some fun ??
?? Whoa no
you're invited but
your friend can't come ??
?? Whoa, no no
come on, baby
gonna have some fun ??
?? We're gonna have some fun ??
?? Wow, have some fun, baby ??
?? Oh but you can't come ??
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
?? Wow ????