Hello. My name's
Forrest--Forrest Gump.
Do you want a chocolate?
I could eat about a million
and a halfofthese.
My mama always said
Iife was like
a box of chocolates.
You never know what
you're going to get.
Those must be
comfortable shoes.
I bet you could walk all day
in shoes like that
and not feel a thing.
I wish I had shoes like that.
My feet hurt .
Mama always said
there's an awful lot
you can tell about
a person by their shoes.
Where they're going,
where they've been.
I've worn lots ofshoes.
I bet if I think
about it real hard
I could remember
my fi rst pair ofshoes.
Mama said they'd
take me anywhere .
[Gump]
Shesaid th ey was my magic shoes.
All right, Forrest,
Open your eyes now .
Let's take a little walk around.
How do those feel?
His legs are strong,
Mrs. Gump,
as strong as I've ever seen.
But his back's as
crooked as a politician.
But we're going to straighten him
right up, aren't we, Forrest?
Forrest!
Now, when I was a baby,
Mama named me after
the great Civil War hero
General Nathan Bedford Forrest.
She said we was related
to him in some way.
What he did was,
hetarted up this club
called the Ku Klux Klan.
They'd all dress up in their robes
and th eirbed sheets
and act like a bunch
of ghosts or spooks or something.
They'd even put bed sheets
on their horses and ride around.
And, anyway, that'show
I got my name-- Forrest Gump.
Mama said the Forrest part
was to remind me
that sometimes we all
do things that, well,
that just don't make no sense.
This way. Hold on. Ugh!
All right.
What are y'all staring at?
Haven't you ever seen
a little boy with braces
on his legs before ?
Don't ever let anybody
tell you they're better
than you, Forrest.
If God intended everybody
to be the same,
he'd have given us all
braces on our legs.
Mama always hada way of explaining
things so I could understand them.
We lived about a quarter mile
off Route 17,
about a halfmile from the town
of Greenbow, Alabama.
That's in the county
of Greenbow.
Our house had been
in Mama's family
since her grandpa's
grandpa's grandpa
had come across the ocean
about a thousand years ago.
Since it was just me and Mama
and we had all these empty rooms,
Mama decided to let those rooms out,
mostly to people passing through,
Iike from, oh, Mobile,
Montgomery, places like that.
That'show me and Mama got money.
Mama was a real smart lady.
Remember what I told you, Forrest.
You're no different
than anybody else is.
Did you hear
what I said, Forrest?
You're the same
as everybody else.
You are no different.
Your boy's...different,
Mrs. Gump.
His I.Q is 75.
Well, we're all different,
Mr. Hancock.
She wan ted me to have
the finest education
so she to ok me to
the Greenbow County Central School.
I met the principal and all.
I want to show you something,
Mrs. Gump.
Now, this is normal.
Forrest is right here .
The state require s
a minimum I.Q of 80
to attend public school.
Mrs. Gump,
he's going to have to
go to a special school.
Now, he'll bejust fine.
What does normal mean anyway ?
He might be...
a bit on the slow side,
but my boy Forrest
is going to get the same
opportunities as everyone else.
He's not going to
some special school
to learn how to retread tires.
We're talking about
five little points here .
There must be something
can be done.
We're a progressive
school system.
We don't want to see
anybody left behind.
Is there a Mr. Gump, Mrs. Gump?
He's on vacation.
Eee! Eee! Eee!
Eee! Eee! Eee! Eee!
Well, your mama sure does care
about your schooling, son.
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
You don't say much, do you?
Eee! Eee! Eee! Eee!
Eee! Eee! Eee! Eee! Eee!
"Finally, he had to try.
"It looked easy, but...
oh, what happened.
First they--"
Mama, what's vacation mean?
Vacation?
Where Daddy went?
Vacation's when
you go somewhere...
and you don't ever come back.
Anyway, I guess you could say
me and Mama was on our own.
But we didn't mind.
Our house was never empty.
There was always folks
coming and going.
Supper!
It's supper, everyone!
That sure looks special.
Sometimes, we had
so many people staying with us
that every room was filled,
with travelers, you know,
folks living
out of their suitcases
and hat cases
and sample cases.
Forrest Gump,
it's suppertime! Forrest?
One time, a young man
was staying with us,
and he had him a guitar case.
[Guitar Plays]
# Well, you ain't
never caught a rabbit #
# And you ain't no #
# Friend of mine ##
Forrest,
I told you not to bother
this nice young man.
No, that's all right, ma'am.
I was showing him
a thing or two on the guitar.
All right. Supper's ready
if y'all want to eat.
Yeah, that sounds good.
Thank you, ma'am.
Say, man, show me that crazy
little walk you did there .
Slow it down some.
# You ain't nothing but-- #
I liked that guitar.
It so unded good.
Is tarted moving around
to the music,
swinging my hips.
# Cryin' all the time ##
This one night,
me and Mama was out shopping,
and we walked by Vincy's
Furniture andApplian ce Store,
and guess what?
# You ain't nothin'
but a hound dog #
# Cryin'all the time#
# You ain't nothin'
but a hound dog #
This is not for
children's eyes.
# Cryin'all the time#
Some years later,
that handsome young man
who they called the King,
well, he sung too many songs.
Had him self a heart attack
or something.
It must be hard being a king.
You know, it's funny how you
remember some things,
but some things you can't.
You do your very best now, Forrest.
I sure will, Mama.
I remember the bus ride
on the first day of school
very well.
Are you coming along?
Mama said not to be
taking rides from strangers .
This is the bus to school.
I'm Forrest--
Forrest Gump.
I'm Dorothy Harris.
Well, now we ain't
strangers anymore .
This seat's taken.
It's taken.
You can't sit here .
You know, it 's funny what
a young man recollects,
'cause I don 't
remember being born.
I don't recall what I got
for my first Christmas,
and I don't know
when I went on
my first outdoor picnic,
but I do remember
the first time I heard
the sweetest voice
in the wide world.
You can sit here
if you want.
I had never seen anything
so beautiful in my life.
She was like an angel.
Well, are you going to
sit down or aren't you?
What's wrong with your legs?
Um, nothing at all, thank you.
My legs are just fine and dandy.
I just sat next to her
on that bus
and had a conversation
all the way to school.
My back's crooked
like a question mark.
Next to Mama,
no one ever talked to me
or asked me questions.
Are you stupid or something?
Mama says,
"Stupid is as stupid does."
I'm Jenny .
I'm Forrest-- Forrest Gump.
From that day on,
we was always together.
Jenny and me
was like peas and carrots.
She taught me how to climb.
Come on, Forrest,
you can do it.
I showed her how to dangle.
"A good little..."
She help edme
learn how to read,
and I showed her how to swing.
Sometimes, we'd just sitout
and wait for the stars.
Mama's going to worry about me.
Just stay a little longer.
For some reason,
Jenny didn 't never want to go home.
O.K.,Jenny, I'll stay .
She was my most special friend.
My only friend.
Now, my mama always told me
that miracles happen every day .
Some people don't think so,
but they do.
Hey, dummy !
Are you dumb,
or just plain stupid?
Look, I'm Forrest Gimp.
Just run away, Forrest.
Run, Forrest!
Run away! Hurry!
Get the bikes!
Let's get him! Come on!
Look out, Gump!
We're going to get you!
Run, Forrest, run!
Run, Forrest!
Come back here, you!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Run, Forrest!
Run!
Now, you wouldn't
believe if I told you...
but I could run
like the wind blows.
From that day on,
if I was going somewhere ,
I was running.
That boy sure
is a running fool.
Now, remember how I told you
that Jenny never seemed
to want to go home?
She lived in a house
that was as old as Alabama.
Her mama had gone
to heaven when she was 5,
and her daddy was
some kind of a farmer.
Jenny ?
He was a very loving man.
He was always kissing
and touching her and her sisters.
And then this one time,
Jenny wasn't on the bus
to go to school.
Jenny, why didn't you
come to school today ?
Shh. Daddy's taking a nap.
Jenny !
Come on!
Jenny, where'd you run to?
You better
get back here, girl!
Where you at?
Jenny !
Jenny, where you at?
Pray with me, Forrest.
Pray with me.
Jenny !
Dear God, make me a bird
so I can fly far,
far, far away from here .
Dear God, make me a bird
so I can fly far.
Mama always said
God is mysterious.
Jenny !
He didn 't turn Jenny
in to a bird that day.
Instead,
he had the police say
Jenny didn't have to stay
in that house no more.
She was to live
with her grandma,
just over on Creek more Avenue,
which made me happy,
'cause she was so close.
Some nights,
Jenny'd sneak out
and come on over to my house,
just'cause
she said she was scared.
Scared of what,
I don 't know.
But I think
it was her grandma's dog.
He was a mean dog.
Anyway, Jenny and me
was best friends
all the way up
through high school.
Hey, stupid!
Quit it!
Run, Forrest, run!
Hey ,
didn't you hear me, stupid?
Run, Forrest!
Get in the truck!
Come on!
He's getting away! Move it!
Run, Forrest! Run!
Ha, ha!
Move it! Move it!
You better be runnin'!
Yeah!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Go!
Run, Forrest!
Now, it used to be
I ran to get
where I was going.
I never thought
it would take me anywhere .
Ohh!
Who in the hell is that?
That there is Forrest Gump, Coach.
Just a local idiot.
And can you believe it ?
I got to go to college, too.
Forrest, move it!
Run!
O.K. !
Run, you stupid
son of a bitch! Run!
Run, son of a bitch, run!
Go! Run!
Run! Run! Go!
[Whistle Blows]
He must be the stupidest
son of a bitch alive ,
but he sure is fast.
Now, maybe it's just me,
but college was
very confusing times.
Federal troops,
enforcing a court order,
in tegrated the University
of Alabama today.
Two Negroes were admitted,
but only after
Go vern or George Wallace
had carried out
his symbolic threat
to stand in the school house door.
I take it from that statement...
Earl, what's going on?
Coons are trying
to get into school.
Coons? When raccoons tried
getting on our back porch,
Mama just chased them off
with a broom.
Not raccoons, you idiot. Niggers .
And they want to go
to school with us.
With us? They do?
[TV Reporter]
Shortly after Govern or Wallace
had carried out his promise
to block the door way,
Kennedy ordered these cretary
of defense to use military force.
Here, by video tape,
is the encounter
by General Graham, commander
of the National Guard,
and Govern or Wallace.
Because these National Guardsmen
are here today as
federal soldiers for Alabama,
and they live within our borders.
They are our brothers.
We are winning in this fight,
because we are awakening
the American people
to the dangers that
we have spoken about so many times
that is so evident today- -
A trend to ward military
dictatorship in this country.
And so, at day's end,
the University of Alabama in
Tuscaloosa had been desegregated,
and students Jimmy Hood
and Vivian Malone
had been signed up
for summer classes.
Ma'am, you dropped your book.
Ma'am.
[Chet Huntley] Govern or Wallace
did what he promised.
By being on the Tuscaloosa campus,
he kept the mob...
Say, wasn't that Gump?
Naw, that couldn't be.
It sure as hell was.
[Gump]
A few years later,
that angry little man
at the school house door
thought it'd be a good idea
and ran for president.
But somebody thought
that it wasn't.
But he didn't die.
My bus is here .
Is it the number 9?
No, it's the number 4.
It was nice talking to you.
I remember when that happened,
when Wallace got shot.
I was in college.
Did you go to a girls' college
or a girls' and boys'
together college?
It was coed.
'Cause Jenny went to a college
I couldn't go to.
It was a college
just for girls.
But I'd go and visit her
every chance I got.
#I don't know why I love you#
# But I do #
#I don't know why I cry so #
#I only know I know that... #
Ohh!
That hurts.
# But I don't know why
I love you#
# But I do #
Forrest!
Forrest, stop it!
Stop it!
What are you doing?
He was hurting you.
No, he wasn't!
Get over there !
Billy, I'm sorry.
Just keep away from me.
Don't be such-- Don't go.
Billy, wait a second.
He doesn't know any better.
Forrest, why'd you do that?
I brought you some chocolate.
I'm sorry.
I'll go back
to my college now .
Forrest--
Look at you.
Come on.
[Thunder]
Is this your own room?
Shh!
Do you ever dream, Forrest...
about who you're going to be?
Who I'm going to be?
Yeah.
Aren't I going to be me?
You'll always be you,
just another kind of you.
You know ?
I want to be famous.
I want to be a singer
like Joan Baez.
I just want to be...
on an empty stage
with my guitar, my voice.
Just me.
And I want to reach people
on a personal level.
I want to be able
to say things,
just one to one.
Have you ever been
with a girl, Forrest?
I sit next to them
in my home economics class
all the time.
Oh--
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's O.K.
Sorry.
Oh--
It's all right.
It's O.K.
Oh, I'm dizzy .
I'll bet that never
happened in home ec.
No.
I think I ruined
your roommate's bathrobe.
I don't care .
I don't like her anyway .
Run! Run! Run! Run!
Run! Run!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
College ran by real fast
'cause I played
so much football.
Th eyeven put me on a thing
called the all-America team
where you get to meet
the president of the United States.
President Kennedy met
with the collegiate
all-American football team
at the Oval Office today .
Now the really good thing
about meeting the presiden t
of the United States
is the food.
They put you in this little room
with just about anything
you'd want to eat or drink.
But since, number one,
I wasn 't hungry but thirsty,
and number two, they was free,
I must have drank me
about 15 Dr. Peppers.
[Burp]
How does it feel
to be an all-American ?
It's an honor, sir.
How does it feel
to be an all-American ?
Very good, sir.
How does it feel
to be an all-American ?
Very good, sir.
Congratula tions.
How do you feel?
I got to pee.
I believe he said
he had topee.
Some time later,
for noparticular reason,
somebody shot
that nice young president
when he was riding
in his car.
And a few years after that,
somebody shot
his little brother, too,
only he was
in a hotel kitchen.
Must be hard being brothers .
I wouldn't know .
Forrest Gump.
Now can you believe it ?
After only five years
of playing football,
I got a college degree.
Congratulations, son.
Mama was so proud.
Forrest, I'm so proud of you.
I'll hold this for you.
Congratulations, son.
Have you given any thought
to your future ?
Thought?
Hello. I'm Forrest.
Forrest Gump.
Nobody gives a horse's shit
who you are, pus ball!
You're not even a lowlife ,
scum-sucking maggot!
Get your maggoty ass
on the bus!
You're in the army now !
Seat's taken.
Taken.
At first it seemed
like I made a mistake.
It was only
my induction day,
and I was getting yelled at.
Sit down if you want to.
I didn't know who I might meet
or what they might ask.
You ever been
on a real shrimp boat?
No.
But I been on a real big boat.
I'm talking about
a shrimp catching boat.
I been working on
shrimp boats all my life .
I started out
on my uncle's boat
when I was about maybe 9.
I was just looking
into buying my own boat
and got drafted.
My given name
is Benjamin Buford Blue.
People call me Bubba,
just like one of them
old red neck boys.
Can you believe that?
My name's Forrest Gump.
People call me Forrest Gump.
So Bubba was from
Bayou La Ba tre, Alabama,
and his mama cooked shrimp.
And her mama
before her cooked shrimp,
and her mama before her mama
cooked shrimp, too.
Bubba's family knew everything
there was to know about
the shrimping business.
I know everything
there is to know
about the shrimping business.
I'm going into
the shrimping business for myself
after I get out ofthe army .
O.K.
Gump!
What's your sole purpose
in this army ?
To do whatever you tell me,
Drill Sergeant!
God damn it, Gump,
you're a goddamn genius.
That's the most outstanding
answer I've ever heard .
You must have
a goddamn l.Q Of 160.
You are goddamn gifted,
Private Gump.
Listen up, people!
Now for some reason,
I fit in the army
Like one of them round pegs.
It's not really hard.
You just make your bed neat,
remember to stand up straight,
and always answere very question
with "Yes, Drill Sergeant. "
Is that clear?
Yes, Drill Sergeant!
What you do is drag your nets
along the bottom.
On a good day ,
you can catch over
a hundred pounds of shrimp.
Everything goes all right,
2 men shrimping 10 hours ,
Less what you spends on gas--
Done, Drill Sergeant!
Gump!
Why did you put that weapon
together so quickly?
You told me to,
Drill Sergeant.
Jesus H. Christ.
This is a new company record .
If it wasn't a waste
of a fine enlisted man,
I'd recommend you for O.C.S.,
Private Gump.
You're going to be
a general someday !
Now disassemble your weapon
and continue!
Anyway, like I was saying,
shrimp is the fruit
of the sea.
You can barbecue it,
boil it, broil it,
bake it, saute it.
They's, uh, shrimp kabobs,
shrimp creole,
shrimp gumbo,
pan fried, deep fried,
stir fried.
There's pineapple shrimp
and lemon shrimp,
coconut shrimp,
pepper shrimp,
shrimp soup, shrimp stew ,
shrimp salad,
shrimp in potatoes,
shrimp burger,
shrimp sandwich.
That--That's about it.
Night time in the army
is alonely time.
We'd lay there in our bunks,
and I'd miss my mama,
and I'd miss Jenny.
Hey, Gump.
Get a load of the tits on her.
Turns out...
Jenny had gotten
in to some trouble
over some photos of her
in her college sweater.
And she was
thrown out of school.
# My baby does the hanky panky #
But that wasn't a bad thing,
'cause a man who owns a theater
in Memphis, Tennessee,
saw those photos
and offered Jenny
a job singing in a show.
The first chance I got,
I took the bus up to Memphis
to see her perform in that show.
That was Amber, Amber Flame.
Give her a big hand.
And now, for your listening
and viewing pleasure ,
direct from Hollywood,
California,
our very own beatnik beauty .
Let's give a big round of applause
to the luscious Bobbie Dylan.
# How many roads
must a man walk down #
# Before you can
call him a man? #
# Yes, and how many seas
must the white dove sail #
Her dream had come true.
# Before she sleeps
in the sand? #
She was a folk singer.
# Yes, and how many times #
# Must the cannon balls fly #
# Before they're
fo rever banned? #
Shake it up now .
Somebody get her a harmonica.
# The answer, my friend #
# Is blowin' in the wind ##
This ain't Captain Kangaroo.
Hey, honey, I got
something here for you.
Hey! God damn it!
Hey, you stupid jerk!
I'm singing a song here .
Polly, get out here !
Shut up yourself!
Just shut up!
Forrest! What are you
doing here ?
What are you doing?
- Hey !
- Aw !
What are you doing, Forrest?
Let me down!
- Oh! Ooh!
- Ooh!
Ha ha ha!
You can't keep
doing this, Forrest.
trying to rescue me.
They was trying to grab you.
A lot of people try to grab me.
Just--You can't keep
doing this all the time.
I can't help it.
I love you.
Forrest--
You don't know what love is.
You remember that time
we prayed, Forrest?
We prayed for God
to turn me into a bird
so I could fly far away .
Yes, I do.
You think I could
fly off this bridge?
What do you mean,Jenny ?
Nothing.
I got to get out of here .
Wait, Jenny .
Forrest, you stay
away from me, O.K. ?
You stay away from me, please.
Can I have a ride?
Where are you going?
I don't care .
Get in the truck.
So bye-bye,Jenny .
They sending me to Vietnam.
It's this whole other country.
Just hang on a minute.
Listen, you promise me
something, O.K. ?
Just if you're
ever in trouble,
don't be brave .
You just run, O.K. ?
Just run away .
O.K.
Jenny .
I'll write you all the time.
Andjust like that,
she was gon e.
she was gone.
You come back safe to me.
Do you hear?
# Some folks are born #
# Made to wave the flag #
# Ooh, they're red,
white, and blue #
# And when the band play s
"Hail To The Chief" #
# Ooh, they'll point
the cannon at you #
# It ain't me #
# I ain't no senator's son #
# It ain't me ##
Now they told us
that Vietnam was going
to be very different
from the United States
of America.
Except for all
the beer cans and barbecues,
it was.
Hey, I'll bet there's shrimp
all in these waters .
They tell me these Vietnams
is good shrimp.
After we win this war
and we take over everything,
we can get American
shrimpers out here
and shrimp these waters .
Just shrimp all the time, man.
You must be my FNGs.
Morning, sir.
Oh, get your hands down.
Do not salute me.
There are goddamn snipers
all around this are a
who'd love
to grease an officer.
I'm Lieutenant Dan Taylor.
Welcome to Fort Platoon.
What's wrong with your lip?
I was born with big gums, sir.
Well, you better tuck that in.
Gonna get that caught
on a trip wire .
Where are you boy s
from in the world?
- Alabama, sir!
You twins?
No. We are not relations, sir.
Look,
it's pretty basic here .
You stick with me
and learn from the guys
who've been in country a while,
you'll be all right.
There is one item of G.I. gear
that can be the difference
between life and death--
Socks .
Cushioned sole, O.D. green.
Try and keep your feet dry.
When we're out humpin',
change your socks
whenever we stop.
The Mekong will eat
a grunt's feet
right off his legs.
Sergeant Sims. God damn it,
where's that sling rope
I said to order?
I put in the requisitions.
Well, you call
those sons of bitches--
Lieutenant Dan
sure knew his stuff.
I felt real lucky
he was my lieutenant.
He was from a long,
great military tradition.
Somebody in his family
had fought
and died
in every...
single...
American war.
God damn it, kick some ass.
Get on it!
I guess you could say
he had a lot to live up to.
So, you boys
from Arkansas, huh?
Well,
I been through there .
Little Rock's a fine town.
Now, shake down your gear.
See the platoon sergeant.
Draw what you need
for the field.
If you boys are hungry,
we got steaks burning
right over here .
Two standing orders
in this platoon--
1 --take care of your feet,
2--try not to do
anything stupid,
Like getting
yourself killed.
I sure hope I don't
let him down.
I got to see
a lot of the country side.
We would take
these real long walks.
# There must be
some kind of way #
# Out of here #
# Said the joker
to the thief#
And we were always lookin '
for this guy named Charlie.
# There's too much confusion #
# I can't get no relief##
Hold it up!
Hold up, boys!
It wasn't always fun.
Lieutenant Dan was always
getting these funny feelings
about a rock or a trail
or the road,
so he'd tell us
to get down, shut up.
Get down!
Shut up!
So we did.
Now I don't know
much about anything,
but I think some of
America's best young men
served in this war.
There was Dallas from Phoenix.
Cleveland- -
he was from Detroit.
Hey, Tex .
What the hell's going on?
And Tex was- -
Well, I don't remember
where Tex come from--
Ah, nothing.
Fourth platoon, on your feet.
Y'all got 10 clicks
to go to that river.
Move out.
1, 2! Hup!
Step it up!
Look alive out there .
The good thing about Vietnam
is there was always
someplace to go.
Fire in the hole!
Gump, check out that hole.
And there was always
something to do.
Mount'em up!
Spread out!
Cover his back!
One day it started raining,
and it didn't quit for four months.
We've been through
every kind of rain there is- -
little bitty stinging rain
and big old fat rain,
rain that flew in side ways,
and sometimes rain even seemed
to come straight up
from underneath.
Shoot, it even rained at night.
Hey, Forrest.
Hey, Bubba.
I'm going to lean up against you.
You lean up against me.
This way we don't have to sleep
with our heads in the mud.
You know why we're
a good partnership, Forrest?
'Cause we be watching out
for one another,
like brothers and stuff.
Hey, Forrest,
something I been thinking about.
I got a very important
question to ask you.
How would you like to go
into the shrimping
business with me?
O.K.
Man, I tell you what.
I got it all figured out, too.
So many pounds of shrimp
will pay off the boat.
So many pounds for gas.
We'll live right on the boat.
We ain't got to pay no rent.
We can just work it together,
split everything right
down the middle.
Man, I'm telling you, 50-50.
Hey, Forrest,
all the shrimp you can eat.
That's a fine idea.
Bubba did have a fine idea.
I even wrote Jenny
and told her all about it.
I sent her letters- -
Not every day, but almost.
I told her what I was doing
and asked her what she was doing
and told her how
I thought about her always.
And how I was looking forward
to getting a letter from her
just as soon
as she had the time.
I'd always let her know
that I was O. K.
Then I'd sign each letter
"Love, Forrest Gump. "
# There's somethin'
happenin' here #
This one day, we was out
walking like always,
and then, just like that,
somebody turned off the rain,
and the sun come out.
# I got to beware ##
Ambush!
Take cover!
Get that pig up here ,
god damn it!
Forrest! You okay ?
Strong-arm, Strong-arm!
Hey! We got a man down!
Strong-arm,
this is Leg Lima 6! Over!
Roger, Strong-arm!
Be advised we have incoming
from the tree line at point blue
plus two!
A.K.s and rockets!
We're getting it hard !
Misfire! Misfire !
God damn it!
Get that pig unfucked
and on the treeline!
They got us,
and it hurt .
We're going to move
back to the blue line.
Pull back! Pull back!
Forrest! Run, Forrest!
Pull back!
Run! Run, man!
Run!
Pull back, Gump!
Run, God damn it! Run!
I ran and ran
just like Jenny told me to.
I ran so far so fast
that pretty so on
I was all by myself,
which was a bad thing.
Bubba.
Bubba was my best good friend.
I had to make sure he was O.K.
Where the hell are you?
Bubba!
And on my way
back to find Bubba,
well, there was this boy
laying on the ground.
Tex.
O.K.
I couldn't let him
lay there all alone,
scared the way he was,
so I grabbed him up
and run him out of there.
Every time I went back
looking for Bubba,
somebody else was saying,
"Help me, Forrest, help me! "
O.K. Here. Here .
No sweat, man.
Lay back. You'll be O.K.
I started to get scared
that I might never find Bubba.
I know my position
is danger close!
We got Charlie
all over this area.
I got to have those fast movers
in here now. Over.
Lieutenant Dan,
Coleman's dead!
I know he's dead!
My whole goddamn platoon
is wiped out!
God damn it!
What are you doing?
You leave me here !
Get away .
Just leave me here !
Get out!
Aah! God, I said
leave me here, God damn it!
LegLima, this is Strong-arm.
Be advised your fast movers
are in bound. Over.
Then it felt like something
just jumped up and bit me.
Aah! Something bit me!
Aah! Aah!
You son of a bitch!
Aah!
I can't leave the platoon.
I told you
to leave me there, Gump.
Forget about me.
Get your self out!
Did you hear what I said?
Gump, damn it, put me down.
Get your ass out of here .
I didn't ask you to pull me out
of there, God damn you!
Where the hell
do you think you're going?
To get Bubba.
I got an air strike
in bound right now .
They're going to nape
the whole area.
Stay here !
That's an order.
I gotta find Bubba!
Forrest.
Bubba.
I'm O.K., Forrest.
I'm O.K.
O-Oh, Bubba, no.
I'll be all right.
[Voices Speaking ln Vietnamese]
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Ugh. I'm O.K., Forrest.
[Airplanes Approach]
I'm O.K. I'm fine.
[Lieutenant Dan]
Top smoke. Get it up there .
If I'd have known
this was going to be
the last time
me and Bubba was gonna talk,
I'd of thought of
something better to say.
Hey, Bubba.
Hey, Forrest.
Forrest--
Why did this happen?
You got shot.
Then Bubba said something
I won't ever forget.
I want to go home.
Bubba was my best good friend.
And even I know
that ain't something you can
find just around the corner.
Bubba was going to be
a shrimping boat captain,
but instead, he died right there
by that river in Vietnam.
That's all I have
to say about that.
It was a bullet, wasn't it?
A bullet?
That jumped up and bit you.
Oh. Yes, sir.
Bit me directly
in the but-tocks .
They said it was a million
dollar wound, but...
the army must keep that money ,
'cause I still ain't seen a nicke I
of that million dollars .
The only good thing about being
wounded in the but-tocks
is the ice cream.
They gave me all
the ice cream I could eat.
And guess what?
A good friend of mine was
in the bed right next door.
Lieutenant Dan,
I got you some ice cream.
Lieutenant Dan, ice cream!
It's time for
your bath, Lieutenant.
Harper!
[Man]
Cooper.
Larson.
Webster.
Gump.
Gump!
I'm Forrest Gump.
Kyle.
Nichols.
McMill.
Johnson.
Surprise, surprise, surprise!
Gump, how can you
watch that stupid shit?
Turn it off.
You are tuned
to the American forces
Vietnam network.
This is channel 6, Saigon.
Good catch, Gump.
You know how to play this?
Come on. Let me show you.
Now, the secret to this game is
no matter what happens,
never, ever...
take your eye off the ball.
All right.
For some reason,
Ping-Pong came very natural to me.
See?
Any idiot can play .
So I started playing it
all the time.
I played Ping-Pong
even when I didn't have anyone
to play Ping-Pong with.
The hospital's people
said it made me look
like a duck in water- -
Whatever that means.
Even Lieutenant Dan
would come and watch me play.
I played Ping-Pong so much,
I even played it in my sleep.
Now...
you listen to me.
We all have a destiny .
Nothing just happens.
It's all part of a plan!
I should have died
out there with my men,
but now...l'm nothing
but a god damn cripple,
a legless freak!
Look. Look! Look at me!
You see that?
Do you know what it's like
not to be able to use your legs?
Y-Y -Yes, sir, I do.
Did you hear what I said?
You cheated me!
I had a destiny .
I was supposed
to die in the field
with honor!
That was my destiny ,
and you...
cheated me out of it!
You understand
what I'm saying, Gump?
This wasn't supposed
to happen--
Not to me.
I had a destiny .
I was...
Lieutenant...
Dan Taylor.
Y-You still
Lieutenant Dan.
Look at me.
What am I going to do now ?
PFC Gump?
Yes, sir!
As you were .
Son,
you been awarded
the Medal of Honor.
Guess what, Lieutenant Dan?
They want to give me a med--
Ma'am.
What did they do
with Lieutenant Dan?
They sent him home.
Two weeks later,
I left Vietnam.
The ceremony was kicked off
with a can did speech
by the presiden t
regarding the need for further
escalation of the war in Vietnam.
Johnson awarded 4 Medals of Honor to
men from each of the armed services.
America owes you
a debt of gratitude, son.
I understand you were wounded.
Where were you hit ?
In the but-tocks, sir.
Well, that must be a sight.
I'd kinda like to see that.
# And here's to you,
Mrs. Robinson #
#Jesus loves you more
than you will know #
# Whoa, whoa, whoa #
# God bless you, please,
Mrs. Robinson ##
God damn, son!
After that, Mama went
to the hotel to lay down,
so I went out for a walk
to see our nation's capital.
Hi lary! I got the vets.
What do you want
to do with them?
It's a good thing
Mama was resting,
'cause the streets
was awful crowded with people
lookin'at all the statues
and monuments,
and some of them people
were loud and pushy.
O.K., follow me!
Everywhere I went,
I had to stand in line.
Come on.
Go!
Hey, you're a good man
for doing this.
Good.
O.K.
There was this man
giving a little talk.
And for some reason,
he was wearing
an American flag for a shirt.
And he liked to say
the "F" word...a lot.
"F" this and "F" that.
And every time
he said the "F" word,
people, for some reason,
well, they cheered.
[Feedback]
Yeah! Yeah!
Come on, man.
Come up here, man.
Come on. Come on.
Yeah, you!
Come on. Move, move !
Go on. Let's get up there .
Tell us a little bit
about the war, man.
The war in Vietnam?
The war in Viet-
fucking-nam!
Well--
There was only one thing
I could say
about the war in Vietnam.
There's only one thing
I can say about...
the war in Vietnam.
In Vietnam...
[Feedback]
[Silence]
What the hell are you do--
I'll beat your head in,
you goddamn oinker!
Jesus Christ!
What did they do with this?
Can't hear you!
Can't hear anything!
This--This one!
Give me that!
Speak up!
That's it.
And that's all I have to say
about that.
That's so right on, man.
You said it all.
What's your name, man?
My name is Forrest.
Forrest Gump.
- Gump! Gump!
- Gump!
Forrest!
Jenny !
Hey !