[cheering]
[labored breathing, heart thumping]
[clock ticking fast]
Let's go!
- I'm open, I'm open.
- I don't see it!
- Take your time!
- Run!
- Go, go!
- Let's go!
- [audience] Defense! Defense!
Come on,
man!
- Hustle, hustle!
- Control that ball!
- Bolton! I'm open!
- Set it up! Let's go!
All right, let's go!
Let's move! Let's move!
- Watch the run in.
- Watch the back door!
- Get it!
- [buzzer rings]
[announcer] That concludes
the first half of play
in our final game,
with the West High Knights
leading defending champion
East High Wildcats 47 - 26.
Sixteen minutes remain in the game.
All right! No more X's and O's. OK?
Forget about the scoreboard because
here's a number that matters.
Sixteen. There's 16 minutes
left in this game, guys.
There's only 16 minutes
left in the season.
And for the seniors
on this squad... guys...
...you've only got 16 minutes
left in a Wildcat uniform.
So make them count.
Sixteen minutes to be a team.
Captains!
All right.
Hey, guys.
Now, you heard Coach.
We're all gonna remember
the next 16 minutes
for a long time
after we leave East High.
So it's now or never.
Chad.
- What team?
- Wildcats!
[cheering]
# Sixteen, 16, 16 minutes left
Better get it done
# Sixteen, 16, 16 more minutes
Get ready, game on!
# Sixteen, 16, 16 minutes left
Running out of time
# Sixteen, 16, 16 more minutes
And it's on the line
# Sixteen, 16, 16 minutes left
Got to get it done
# Sixteen, 16, 16 more minutes
till we're number one!
# W-I-L-D Wildcats!
Huddle up! Let's go!
Come on, come on
Ready?
Break!
# W-I-L-D Wildcats!
Now's the time
# Got to get it inside
Down low, in the paint, now shoot
# Score!
- # Gotta work together
- Defense!
# Give me the ball
# Fast break, keep the ball
in control, let it fly from downtown
# Three more
- # Show them we can do better
- # No way!
Come on, boys!
# The way we play tonight
is what we leave behind
# It all comes down
to right now, it's up to us
- # Let's go!
- # So what are we gonna be
# T-E-A-M
Team!
# Gotta work it out
Turn it on
# This is the last time to get it right
# This is the last chance
to make it our night
# We got to show what we're all about
- # Work together
- Time out!
# This is the last chance to make
our mark, history will know who we are
# This is the last game so make
it count, it's now or never
- Hey! That's a foul!
- Oh, dear.
[heart thumping]
- You OK?
- Come on, Troy!
Let's go, buddy!
# Troy
# Right now I can hardly breathe
# Oh, you can do it
Just know that I believe
# And that's all I really need
- # Then come on
- # Make me strong
# It's time to turn it up
Game on!
# Wildcats gonna tear it up
Go, Wildcats, yeah, we're number one
[groans]
Foul!
- Yeah!
- All right!
- What?
- Yeah!
# Let me hear you say
Hey, hey, hey, yeah
I'm tripled-teamed.
I can't get a shot off.
- What do you want to do?
- Let's put in Rocket Man.
Rocket Man?
- Troy, you're two points away from...
- I know.
- Just get me the ball.
- OK.
Rocket Man! Come on!
Come on, Rocket Man! You're in!
- Get in here!
- Go!
- Let's go!
- Move!
Go, go, go! Move!
Yeah! Oh, yeah!
Calm down, OK?
- All right, keep your eyes on me.
- # Game on!
# This is the last time to get it right
# This is the last chance
to make it our night
# We gotta show what we're
all about, team! Work together
# This is the last chance
to make our mark
# History will know who we are
# This is the last game so make it count
It's now or never #
Come on!
Shoot it!
Yes!
We won, dude! We won! You OK?
[gasping]
Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about. Yeah!
I'm pushing.
- You better be.
- I'm pushing!
- Push harder!
- Chad, tree!
Home sweet home.
- I'm saving for a new fuel pump.
- Mm-hm. Save faster.
[pop music plays]
Hey, turn it up, Kels.
- How you doing, girl?
- I'm good!
- Great comeback!
- Thanks.
- Watch that tail. It's dangerous.
- You know it!
- Amazing! We won!
- I didn't think they'd come back.
Hey!
- Congratulations!
- Thanks. Can I fix you a plate?
- I want one of everything!
- Are we celebrating?
What's up, Hoops?
- Back-to-back champions!
- Yeah, thanks.
Coach, got a couple
of empty lockers at U of A?
Hopefully not for long.
Charlie Danforth
will suit up next season.
Front row seat will be fine.
That teamwork I saw tonight, that assist
where you gave up the final shot,
that's the kind of players
I'm looking for.
We're going to see you
in Redhawk uniforms?
- Done deal.
- Amen to that.
- Go have some fun.
- OK.
- Congratulations, Troy!
- Hey! Thanks.
- Yo!
- Hey, dude!
Sweet game!
Hey, Troy. Great house, bro.
Your room is way cool.
Thanks, man. You were in my room?
Well, yeah. I just took a picture. Look.
- I'm doing mine the same way.
- Great.
We should hang out tonight.
Get to know each other or something.
I just gotta grab the championship
trophy I left it in my truck.
- Don't sweat it! I'm on it!
- OK.
Hi!
So, another top-secret hiding place?
You're the second girl I've had up here.
The first was my mom.
She only climbed up here to get me down.
Well, I'm honored.
This place is so cool.
Me and my dad built it.
[Gabriella] That the coach
from U of A down there?
- Yeah. He's at my house.
- Yeah.
Crazy.
I bet he's already got
your name on a locker.
It's always been my dad's dream. Now
I'm going to end up at his alma mater.
Did I just say that?
My mom and I have been talking about
Stanford pretty much since I was born.
And you're already in. That's so cool.
Except she won't stop talking
about it. It's embarrassing.
Come on. She's proud of you.
I'm proud of you.
The thing about Stanford
is it's a thousand and fifty...
...fifty-three miles from here.
I know.
It suddenly seems like the rest
of the school year is coming so fast.
Yeah. I wish it would all just stop.
At least just slow down.
# Can you imagine what would happen
# If we could have any dream?
# I'd wish this moment
was ours to own it
# And that it would never leave
# Then I would thank that star
# That made our wish come true
# Oh, yeah
# 'Cause he knows that where you are
# Is where I should be too
# Right here
# Right now
- # Right now
- # I'm looking at you
# And my heart loves the view
- # 'Cause you mean everything
- # Everything
# Right here
# I promise you somehow
# Somehow we're gonna
# Tomorrow can wait
for some other day to be
# To be, but right now
there's you and me
# Oh, we know it's coming
# And it's coming fast
# It's always you and me
- # So let's make every second last
- [giggles]
# Make it last
# 'Cause right here
# Right now
# Yeah, I'm looking at you
# And my heart loves the view
# 'Cause you mean everything
# Right here
# I promise you somehow
# That tomorrow can wait
# For some other day to be
# To be, but right now
there's you and me
- # You and me
# You and me
# But right now there's
# You and me #
Is this a pirate's wheel?
No.
[laughs]
Very cute.
I haven't played
with Robo-Rob since third grade.
- I'm Robo-Rob. I am...
- Don't break him. Don't break him.
- That's Chad's.
- Sure it is.
Now it's just like kindergarten.
Troy? You have guests.
Don't make me come up there
and get you again. Hi, Gabriella.
We'll be right down, Mom.
She really will come up here
if we don't go down.
Oh, OK.
Right there, right there. OK,
come on through. Come on. There you go.
[sighs]
Wow.
[whistles]
Hey, Troy.
So, when's the big game?
[cell phone rings]
Uh, yesterday.
Oh, well. Good luck.
- Wow.
- She's so sweet.
[boy gasps]
What are you? I mean, who are you?
Good morning, Ms. Evans. I'm Tiara Gold.
I transferred
to East High from London
and I noticed on the board you're
in need of a personal assistant.
Yeah, with finals, prom, graduation,
I need someone tracking
my appointments and assignments.
Most important, I need someone
to run lines for the musical.
- That's a theater term for...
- Learning your role. I understand.
It's best to keep
science and math books together,
since those are
first lessons of the day.
How do you know my schedule?
I took the liberty of checking,
simply to make certain
I'd have your nonfat, no-foam,
soy latte ready for free period.
- One packet of sweetener?
- Organic.
I'll e-mail you my wardrobe choices each
morning so that our outfits won't clash.
If you own any orange, get rid of it.
By the way, like the accent.
It's... sweet.
Troy, my brother.
Can I have your gym locker?
- What?
- Like starting next week.
I'll be running the team next season
and it'll help me out with the guys.
- Yeah, why didn't I think of that?
- I don't know.
[school bell rings]
Tardy again. Later, bro!
Are you serious?
What about her... Hey.
All right, everyone. Settle down.
We are all excited about our Wildcats'
- top-to-bottom championships.
- That would be "back-to-back."
Whatever the case,
it was a grand slam. Well done!
And our student body president
and co-editor of the yearbook,
Taylor McKessie,
has important announcements.
Senior trip committee meets tomorrow
and reports Thursday to prom committee,
headed by Martha.
Pick up your tickets from her.
This year's theme is "The Last Waltz."
But don't be last to pick up tickets.
Graduation committee convenes Monday.
Picture deadline is Thursday
and finals study groups alternate
with all of the above. Questions?
What's the lunch special
in the cafeteria?
New York deli. Anyone else?
Moving on. Ms. Sharpay Evans, four-term
president of the drama club,
spring musicale report.
Well, with prom, finals,
everyone is so busy.
I was thinking
I'd select something modest.
Perhaps even a one-woman show.
A little light on the sign-ups, Kelsi?
No. We're actually doing pretty well.
Well, well, well.
Almost the entire homeroom.
[Sharpay groans]
How inspiring!
I will happily see all of you
at free period to discuss the show
and to make a very special announcement.
[school bell rings]
[chattering]
I'll be retaking my finals two or three
times. I'm moving into the library.
I'm working on my truck every day.
I've got five recipes
for Family Science final.
We've got a yearbook to edit, so no.
Sorry! Jeez. I thought since it was the
last show, everyone would want to do it.
- You're wrong.
- We just don't have time.
Hey. Hey, you guys, listen up.
Kelsi's right. We should do this.
This is our last chance
to do something together.
All of us. Something really fun.
Oh, yippee.
So, what do you say, Wildcats?
No, I still don't think
it's a good idea.
- Guys, come on! It's our senior year!
- Troy.
We're all in this together.
This is our senior year.
I'm in.
What?
- It will be fun.
- Yes!
- Oh, boy.
- How much time will it take?
Yeah. And what the heck
is the show about?
You, Mr. Danforth.
Me?
The spring musicale is all about you.
Hold up. If it's about me, then
can I have my ball back? Please?
- It's about all of you.
- Go!
And all of you will create it.
A show about your final days at
East High. We'll call it Senior Year.
Genius.
Uh-uh-uh! Playing a role is easy,
but being yourself,
now that's a challenge.
Miss Darbus, exactly...
Kelsi will compose,
Ryan will choreograph
- and I will direct.
- Thank you.
Now, I have
some very important news from...
...the Juilliard School
in New York City,
America's preeminent college
for the performing arts.
And for the first time
in East High history,
Juilliard is considering four of you
for one available scholarship.
- Miss Sharpay Evans.
- I'm already packed.
- Mr. Ryan Evans.
- Dance.
- Miss Kelsi Nielsen.
- What? They got my letter?
They certainly did.
And, lastly, Mr. Troy Bolton.
What?
Juilliard will be sending
representatives to observe our show.
So good luck to our four applicants.
Yeah, nice. Nice, guys.
That's pretty funny.
So... who's the big comedian?
- Is there something wrong?
- Yeah. Yeah, I didn't apply.
- I've never heard of Juilliard.
- Well, that may be, Mr. Bolton,
but evidently Juilliard
has heard of you.
And as you create this show,
you must dig deep
and think about your aspirations
and dreams for the future.
Line up, downstage, please.
Let's begin with Mr. Danforth.
Step forward, please.
Your future.
It's easy. It's U of A.
Hoops all the way.
- Yeah.
- Miss McKessie.
I'm going to be the President
of the United States.
Oh.
I'm going to finish
college first, of course.
Martha Cox, you're late.
I'm sorry, I just thought maybe
we could use a few more dancers.
[group gasps, chuckles]
I feel a show coming on already!
Mr. Bolton.
- Mr. Bolton.
- Hmm?
- Your future.
- Oh, yeah, uh...
You know... uh...
I've been thinking about...
Uh...
I think we should stage
the perfect prom.
Golly gee, how adorable.
What do I want?
Gosh, I wouldn't know
where to begin.
But I know where it ends.
Center stage.
A single spotlight.
A huge marquee that reads...
New York deli platter, please.
- How can you think about food?
- Maybe because it's lunch time?
No pickles.
Throw that Big Apple parfait in.
OK, this show is our last shot, Ryan.
Sharpay's meal, please.
Thanks. That's great.
Troy pretended
to know nothing about Juilliard.
- Give me a break.
- He seemed surprised to me.
The theater fairy magically
sent in Troy's application?
Performers can't fool me. They're
deceitful, ambitious and ruthless.
- Aren't we performers?
- Exactly.
- Hmm.
- [scoffs]
# Imagine having everything
we ever dreamed
- # Don't you want it?
- # Maybe
- # Can't ya see it?
- # Kinda
# Imagine first audition
after college I get the lead
- # A part for me?
- # Well, of course
- # Yeah, right, keep talking
- # You gotta believe it
- # You and I, all the fame
- # Sharpay and what's-his-name
- # Sound exciting?
- # Inviting
- # Let's do it then
- # Listening
# Personal stylist
agent and a publicist
- # But where do I fit into this?
- # With you, we can win
- # Win the part?
- # Think bigger
- # Become superstars?
- # That's better
# Don't you see that bigger is better
# And better is bigger
# A little bit it is never enough
No, no, no
# Don't you want it all?
# You want it
You know that you want it
# The fame and the fortune and more
# You want it all
# You want it
You know that you want it
# You gotta have your star on the door
# You want the world, nothing less
# All the glam and the press
# Only giving you the best reviews
- # Say it!
- # I want it all
# I want it
I want it, want it
# My name in lights at Carnegie Hall
I want it all
- # Can't you see it?
- # Yeah
- # They're gonna love me
- [clears throat]
# I mean us
# Red carpet, rose bouquets
Crowd waiting backstage
# I'm with her, don't stop me
I'm not the paparazzi
# Invitations
Standing ovations
- # Magazines
- # Yes, please
# Gonna be celebrities
# Photographs, fan club
Give the people what they love
- # Now you're excited
- # I like it
- # Let's do it then
- I love you!
# Times Square, jetsetter
Sequels pay better
# New York today
Tomorrow the world
- # Sold out shows?
- # Think bigger
- # And the Oscar goes to...
- # That's better
# Don't ya see that bigger is
better and better is bigger
# A little bit is never enough
No, no, no
# I want it all
I want it, want it, want it
# The fame and the fortune and more
# I want it all
I want it, want it, want it
# I gotta have my star on the door
# I want the world
Nothing less, all the glam and the press
# Only giving me the best reviews
# I want it all
I want it, want it, want it
# Radio City Music Hall
We want it all
# Here in the spotlight
we shine, look at who we are
# When Broadway knows your name
- Get out of the way!
- # You know that you're a star
# Oh, dance
- Madison Square Garden!
- They love you.
Thank you! Thank you all!
It's Oprah calling.
Again.
She wants you on the show.
They're going to get back to you.
- You know how fast you were going?
- Officer Chad!
Hey, it's Ms. Evans.
How you doing? Follow me.
# I want it
I- I-I want it, want it
# I want it, I want it
I- I-I want it all, yeah
# I want it
I- I-I want it, want it
- # I want it, I-I-I want it
- # I want it all
# I gotta, ooh, I gotta
I want to, I have to, I want to
# I want it, I want it
I have to have it
# I want it, I have to
- # I want it all
- # I want it, want it, want it
- # The fame and the fortune and more
- # I want it all
# I want it, want it, want it
# I gotta have my star on the door
# I want the world, nothing less
All the glam and the press
# Only giving me the best reviews
I want it all
# Paris, London, Rome, Toronto
# L.A., Sydney, Buenos Aires
# Tokyo, Moscow, Bollywood
# New York City
# We want it...
# All #
[applause]
It's ours, Ryan.
Wait a minute. Miss D said that
there's only one scholarship.
There's two of us.
We're twins. They're going
to have to take us both.
Listen, Kelsi always writes her
best songs for Troy and Gabriella.
So you make certain we get those songs.
How?
Polish her glasses, buy her some
ruby slippers, take her to prom.
I don't know.
Just do it.
- Hey, Tay.
- Morning, Sunshine.
- You going to rehearsals today?
- Uh, do I have a choice?
You got us into this. I don't
understand. You might not be here.
Told anyone you're up for
Stanford's Freshman Honors?
No.
You're gonna hear from them any day.
[cell phone rings]
- Hello?
- Taylor, these things take time.
- Hey.
- [Troy] I need you right away.
- What?
- Look up.
I have to go.
This has two weeks detention
written all over it.
Have fun.
I really need your help.
Which one do you think I should wear?
Because?
Because you're going to have
a pretty dress, so I want to look right.
I've never been asked to a prom, but
this almost sounds like an invitation.
This one.
I've never been to a dance,
much less a prom.
But I was hoping these
might be a good start.
Do you think we're going
to have to waltz?
Because I have no idea how to do that.
All I know is what my dad
taught me when I was a little girl.
I'd stand on his toes, and he'd
waltz me around the living room.
Come here. I'll show you.
- What?
- Come here.
- We're on the roof.
- [giggles]
Come here. You'll love it.
# Take my hand
# Take a breath
# Pull me close
# And take one step
# Keep your eyes
# Locked on mine
# And let the music
# Be your guide
- # Won't you promise me
- # Now won't you promise me
- # That you'll never forget
- # We'll keep dancing
- # To keep dancing wherever we go next
- # Wherever we go next
# It's like catching lightning
# The chances of finding
# Someone like you
# It's one in a million
# The chances of feeling
# The way we do
# And with every step together
# We just keep on getting better
- # So can I have this dance?
- # Can I have this dance?
# Can I have this dance?
# Oh
# No mountain's too high and no
# Ocean's too wide
# 'Cause together or not
our dance won't stop
# Let it rain...
# Let it pour
What we have is worth fighting for
# You know I believe
that we were meant to be
# It's like catching lightning
The chances of finding
# Someone like you
# It's one in a million
The chances of feeling
# The way we do
# And with every step together
# We just keep on getting better
- # So can I have this dance?
- # Can I have this dance?
# Can I have this dance?
- # Can I have...
- # This dance?
# Can I have this dance? #
- So is that a yes?
- In every language.
[says "yes" in different languages]
Yes.
- [school bell rings]
- [gasps] Oh, come on!
Where's our clothes?
- Yo, Rocket Man.
- Oh, there they are.
- Thought you wanted our lockers.
- It's moving day.
Oh, sweet.
- Good job.
- Thanks, man.
Perfect timing, Bolton.
We weren't just given these lockers.
We had to earn them.
Right. Right. Thanks, man.
- Chad, what's the combo?
- What's the combo?
It's like he said.
You got to earn them.
What's that supposed to mean?
Hey, guys! Come back.
What are you talking about?
- Not cool, guys!
- Hey, Bolton! Danforth!
[laughing]
Hey, stop playing games!
This isn't funny, guys!
Chad, up top.
- I got it.
- Spike!
- Let's go! Out!
- Give me my clothes!
- This isn't funny, guys!
- Just give me my clothes, man!
Look out. Coming through.
Hey, those are new jeans!
I need those back!
Arms, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
You're really stressing me out.
I need to breathe.
And I don't know what Ryan is doing.
He's doing some kind of
yoga Fosse thing.
Two, three, four... What are you doing?
...six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, great,
five, six, seven...
Troy, just give me my clothes!
- Yearbook opportunity.
- Photo op.
Smile!
Wow.
- Hi.
- Bold choice, gentlemen.
We all must have the courage
to discover ourselves.
However, at East High,
we will discover ourselves
whilst clothed.
But welcome to our drama club
and our spring musicale.
Yeah, welcome.
The stage crew can use
your help during detention...
...painting sets.
Throw a sheet over them.
Ryan!
OK. All right, guys,
let's go back up to the top.
Jason, why don't you come
down here and help me out.
[engine rumbling]
Fuel pump...
...work in progress.
If my truck falls apart
because I'm spending my time onstage,
it's your fault.
You think I'd be spending any time
at all up there if it wasn't for you?
You know what? I do.
- What?
- You're so good.
I watch you in rehearsals. You love it.
Why is that so hard for you to admit?
It isn't, to you.
But to my dad? To Chad?
Yeah, it's a little hard.
It shouldn't be.
They're happy as long as
we're all talking about U of A.
You chose Stanford. U of A
was sort of chosen for me.
I haven't talked
to anybody about this, but...
...I've had offers from other colleges.
- I'm really listening.
- I get it, Troy.
I still have decisions to make, too.
Like what?
I thought I heard you. I was just making
some snacks inside. Are you guys hungry?
- I interrupted something, didn't I?
- Just talking, Mom.
- Homework.
- OK.
Speaking about homework... come on.
I was joking.
[Taylor gasps]
Compliments of Zeke.
Be careful, they're still hot.
He doesn't know they're gone.
Eat the evidence.
Kissing up to the yearbook editors.
Very smart move.
Chad's hoping for two pages on himself.
Maybe even a third page,
just for his hair.
Hey, what's right is right.
Hoops, by the way, could you take me
after school to check out that tuxedo?
Tuxedo? For what?
For prom.
Honey, if that's
what you call an invitation,
you'll be dancing with yourself.
[chuckles] Ohh.
[school bell rings]
- Yo, yo, yo. It's lunchtime.
- Come on, people. Go!
- You ready?
- Yeah.
It's now or never, man.
The Garden Club is rooting for you.
Mmm.
- OK. I'm going in.
- Go get her.
- Troy, I really just...
- No, we're doing this now.
How long have you been up there?
- Hair's great.
- Don't...
I know. I heard that, too.
- Yes, good.
- Yes. OK.
- Your turn.
- So... Hey.
I was kind of wondering if you'd...
...maybe go with me.
Oh, hey, Chad. They have Tuna Surprise
on the menu. It's good. Really good.
Dude.
Taylor.
Hey, I'm asking you to prom.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you
because it's so loud.
- Did you hear something?
- No.
- Neither did I.
- Excuse me. Excuse me, everybody.
- What are you?
- Yo!
[Chad] Oh.
My friend has something to say.
Taylor McKessie.
Will you please be
my date to the senior prom?
[all] Aww...
- I'd be honored.
- [everyone cheers]
Dude, I need to go shoot
some hoops or something.
You nailed it!
# Guess now it's official
- # Can't back out, can't back out
- # No
# Gettin' ready
# For the night of nights
The night of nights, all right
- # Don't panic
- # Panic
# Now do we have
to dress up for the prom?
# Dude, I don't think we have the choice
# Yeah it's the night of all nights
Got to look just right
# Dressin' to impress the boys
# Do I want classic or vintage or plaid
- # Where's the mirror
- # I think this tux is too baggy
# Too tight
It makes me look weird
# Should I go movie star glamorous
# Sassy or sweet
# Don't know, but no one better
wear the same dress as me
# It's the night of our nightmares
# It's the night of our dreams
# It's too late to back out of it
- # Hey, makeovers, massages
- # Don't know what a corsage is
# Been waiting all our lives for this
- # It's gonna be a night
- # Can't wait
- # To remember
- # Oh, man
# Come on now
Big fun, all right
- # It's gonna be the night
- # I guess
- # To last forever
- # Lucky us
# We'll never ever ever forget
- # Gettin' ready
- # Get ready
- # Get, gettin' ready
# Gettin' ready
# Get, gettin' ready
Go
[man] Hey, you've been in there an hour.
# So, what should I do with my hair?
- # Where's my shaver?
- # I love it
- # I look like a waiter
- # Should I fluff it?
# It's getting later already
Should be there
[doorbells ring]
# Her mother opens the door
I'm shakin' inside
# He's here, it's time
The hour's arrived
# Don't know why
her father's starin' me down
# Where's my purse, lip gloss?
Now I'm really freakin' out
# Then something changes my world
# The most beautiful girl
Right in front of my eyes
- # It's gonna be a night
- # Oh, yeah
- # To remember
- # That's for sure
# Come on now
Big fun, all right
- # It's gonna be the night
- # Here tonight
- # To last forever
- # Forever more
# We'll never ever ever forget
Guys, right here. Guys!
# Who's that girl? She's so fine
# Who's that guy? I don't recognize
# Who's that girl?
She looks so good, yeah
# Guess you never really noticed
But you probably should
# Big fun
- # On the night of nights
- # All right
# The night of nights
Tonight
# Let's dance
# On the night of nights
You know we're gonna do it right
# It's gonna be a night
To remember
# It's gonna be the night
To last forever
# It's gonna be our night
To remember
# It's gonna be the night
To last forever
# It's gonna be our night
You know it
# To remember
For all time
# Come on now
Big fun
# It's gonna be the night
We love it
# To last forever
The rest of our lives
# We'll never ever ever forget
# It's gonna be our night
Oh, yeah
# All together
Say it loud
# Come on now
Everyone, that's right
# It's gonna be the night
Yeah, the night
# To remember
Hear the crowd
# And never ever ever
# Never ever ever never ever
# Never never forget #
Bravo! Brava! Lights, please!
Kelsi, splendid music.
Ryan, your choreography
is quite inventive.
- Thank you.
- And, Jason,
we do not chew gum in theatre or prom.
See me at detention.
Lighting crew needs help.
Excellent work, everyone.
Costumes on the rack.
I will see you all tomorrow.
Kelsi's writing something amazing
for Troy and Gabriella.
A song, most likely.
- Just find out what it is.
- OK.
Hi, Boi! How was I? Thank you!
- Hey Troy, good job, man.
- Dude, stop doing that!
I'm sorry.
Look, there's Sharpay.
Now, you didn't hear this from me,
but she has a secret crush on you.
- A secret crush on me?
- Shhh!
Shhh.
- Should I talk to her?
- Yeah.
OK. All right.
Mr. Zara.
Yo! You can call me
"Rocket Man" if you want to.
How generous.
Mr. Zara, since you have become
such a dedicated presence,
I'm making you an understudy. Miss Gold!
- You as well.
- Nice.
I'm in!
I'm playing "The Understudy."
- Congrats.
- Right. What's up?
"Understudy" isn't a role, you moron.
You go on if one of the leads
can't make the performance.
Well, I hate to break it to you, sister,
but you're one, too.
The difference being I can carry a tune.
Listen, I wouldn't sing with you
if my hair was on fire
and you were the last bucket
of water on Earth.
I wouldn't sing with you
if I were starving
and you were
the last pickle at the picnic.
Want to go to lunch sometime?
Gentlemen, start your engines.
That's what I'm talking about, bro.
Yo, come check out these guitars.
[humming]
What is this?
[gasps]
"Stanford's Honors Program cordially..."
- [screams]
- Oh, my gosh.
Oh, my goodness! "You and 29 students
are invited for early orientation."
Oh, my gosh, that's huge.
Your mom must be so proud.
Taylor, you're the only one that knows.
But you've already accepted, right?
I'm throwing a going-away party.
This is huge!
You can't get rid of me that easy.
We've got a yearbook to do.
- Back to work.
- OK.
- These are Sharpay's yearbook photos.
- Of course they are. Thank you.
This better be good.