(INSECTS TRILLING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in!
(DOOR LATCHES LOUDLY)
What?
What are you doing?
I was just thinking that...
I could sleep in here tonight.
In here? Why? Something
wrong with your room?
Is it too warm? Because I had that
air conditioner completely...
No.
Well, then what?
I just wanted...
Oh. Well...
I don't...
(STAMMERS) Uh,
I'm not feeling well...
I had pork for lunch and I...
Mmm-hmm.
I think it's probably
best if we just... If I...
Mmm-hmm. That's okay.
I mean, I...
I'll just go back.
(SIGHS)
(AIN'T LOVE SOMETHIN' PLAYING)
(ALARM BLARING)
♪ This is for
♪ The people holding hands
♪ And this is for the ones
♪ With broken hearts
♪ What I'm trying to explain
♪ Is in our lives
there'll come a day
♪ When we'll find
those feelings
♪ Lost in the dark
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
♪ The losin', the tryin'
♪ It's that crazy little thing
♪ That we call love
(FORK SCRAPING ON PLATE)
♪ And when it comes to you
♪ If! had to tell the truth
♪ About the mixed-up thoughts
♪ My mind's been thinkin' of
♪ It's like the sunshine
6:00?
Mmm-hmm.
I'm making prime rib for our...
♪ You bring me pleasure
♪ And you bring me pain
All right.
Bye!
♪ Ain't love somethin' ♪
Bye.
Think you can
change your marriage?
Change your marriage?
What do you mean?
Like you mostly eat in on
Fridays and then you eat out?
Or that you're at
each other's throats
and suddenly you're Cinderella
and Prince Charming.
The second one.
No. No.
You married who you marry,
you are who you are.
Why would that change?
Well, if you wanted it to.
No, I think for that to happen,
it would have to be so bad
that somebody was willing to risk
everything just to shake things up
and then it may not
come down your way.
No, change is hard.
Marriages don't change.
Hey, what are you making tonight?
The kids still coming over?
Yeah. Prime rib.
(CHUCKLES) Oh,
they are so beautiful!
Huh, Arnold?
Just what we needed.
Mmm-hmm.
I picked them out.
Show-off.
So what'd you guys
get each other?
Yeah, 31. What gift is that?
Silver? Ivory? Paper?
No, it isn't anything special.
Just an off year.
Oh! We got each other
the new cable subscription.
Oh, great.
It's a lot of channels.
First of all, so many
of you are dealing with,
"Should I open the club face,
or should I do this?"
You can learn to
break like this.
All he's doing is he's
taking the club back.
He doesn't have a lot
of wrist hinge at all.
In fact, in the down-the-line view,
what his swing looks like is,
the head of the club
is outside of the hands here.
Very, very late wrist set.
He gets up into here,
like this,
and then his body
is moving forward
while the club
is going backwards
and that's how you get this real...
(TURNS OFF TV)
Arnold.
(GRUNTS)
Turn off the air down here?
Mmm-hmm!
(STAIRS CREAKING)
Night.
Good night.
♪ More, more, more, give me
♪ More, more
♪ More, oh
♪ More, more, more, give me
♪ More, more
♪ More, oh
♪ Open me up
♪ And what do you find?
♪ Broken heart
♪ And a dusty mind
♪ You can take your time
♪ But I'll never take mine
♪ Write your life down
♪ Then break the spine
♪ I'm taking it down
♪ Taking it down
♪ And turning it around
♪ Turning it around
♪ And making a sound
♪ Making a sound
♪ For the first time
in my days
♪ Oh, howl
♪ Need you
♪ To need me
♪ Need it so, need it so,
need it so bad
♪ And you
♪ You want to move
♪ Along with me
♪ Do you want, do you want
♪ To move along with me? ♪
DR. FELD: I can't
tell you how many...
Shh!
(TURNS DOWN VOLUME)
...questions I get on what
constitutes the perfect marriage.
I see couples who think
their marriages are over.
Who feel like it's impossible
to regain what they once had.
Well, it's not. It's not
impossible-And it's not too late
for anyone who truly wants it
and is willing to try.
(SIGHS)
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
(SIGHS)
What are you...
You eating?
No. I, I...
What? You're just
going to sit there?
Okay.
What do we got?
I want to go.
"Dr. Bernard Feld, Center for
Intensive Couples Counseling."
You want to go to
intensive couples counseling?
In Maine.
Maine.
Only half the day.
Rest of the day you can read,
or look around the town.
$4,000 for a week?
Well, it's intensive.
Have to be gold-plated.
Well, I paid for it.
How?
I used my C.D.
How'd you get
access to your C.D.?
I called Vince.
Oh.
You called my office
without talking to me.
I made a reservation for us.
Well, cancel it.
I want to go.
Have you been
to see Dr. Lesser?
Maybe this has something to
do with that hormonal thing.
I am not crazy, Arnold!
Well, then I don't
know what to say to you.
In all our years together,
never have I...
Have you heard me
ask for anything?
Excuse me? Did we not just get a new
refrigerator because you wanted...
That's not what I mean.
Well, you're a grown woman. You
can go anywhere you want to go.
But I'm not going.
So if you want to go to intensive
couples counseling all by yourself,
I'll see you
when you get back.
Maybe I will.
All right.
You're not going to
get audited over $217.
Well, you're just not.
All right! Call Terri
to make an appointment.
Yes, and thank you. Bye.
(GROANS)
VINCE: You know, Kay called me.
I meant to tell you.
That's nothing. She's just been
acting kind of off, is all.
Off? How? I don't know.
Threatening me.
What does she want? Car?
Vacation, something?
No. Yeah, a vacation.
I'll tell you, when Susan
used to threaten me,
I did what
we all want to do.
Head up to Brewsky's,
not call,
come home late piss drunk,
a big "screw you."
You see how that worked out.
Uh-huh.
If I had to do it again,
I'd be on it with flowers, a card,
dinner, maybe even a necklace.
I'd be in there like the Orkin
Man and kill that thing dead.
Maybe then I
wouldn't be in a condo.
(DOG BARKING)
ARNOLD: The girl
liked those best.
I told her how much
you liked the ocean.
This is your boarding pass.
Oh, come on.
The flight leaves at
10:02 in the morning.
What is wrong with you? What
are you trying to do to us?
I want a real
marriage again, Arnold.
A real marriage? This isn't real
after 31 years? This isn't real?
When's the last time
that you touched me
that wasn't
just for a picture?
When's the last time
you kissed me?
I kiss you every day.
We're not 22 years old
any more, things change.
I could be more...
You know. I could...
Um, this is insane.
The flight leaves at 10:02 tomorrow.
I'm going to be on it.
Your supper's on the table.
You're not even...
You're not even gonna...
Aren't...
So if you're one
of those people
that's looking
for more distance,
well if you're doing this, guess what?
I don't like your chances.
(ALARM BLARING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALARM STOPS)
(SIGHS)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Good morning.
Morning, ma'am.
Let me take this for you.
Thank you.
Where we going today?
To the airport.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
I hope you're happy.
(YOU MAKE IT BETTER PLAYING)
♪ Another day
♪ You're doing fine
♪ Everything's okay
♪ Got all your ducks in line
How far is this place, anyway?
Only a couple of hours.
Couple of hours. That's
enough to put us in Canada.
I'm really glad
you came, Arnold.
Yeah?
Well, you tell me
that when we get lost
and wind up in
downtown Montreal
and everybody's
talking French.
♪ Don't be concerned
♪ Ain't nothing wrong
♪ Watch the table turn
♪ It's your favorite song
♪ It's all right
There's a hotel. Is that it?
Mmm...
No.
We're at the Econo Lodge.
♪ You make it better
♪ Life is good ♪
They were in the car,
under the seat.
Oh! Oh.
What time does this thing
start in the morning?
10:30.
We might as well be on time.
Get our money's worth.
Mmm-hmm.
I'll set the alarm.
I wouldn't give us
too much extra time.
It's probably impossible to
get lost in a burg this size.
Mmm.
Well...
We, we could...
(SIGHS)
I guess I'll go see
how the pull-out works.
(SNIFFS) Uh...
(SIGHS)
Goddamn! How is this
thing supposed to...
I'll do it.
You think there's a building in this
place that does not have shutters?
The whole town looks like it was
built by Hansel and Gretel.
(LAUGHS)
I think it's charming.
That's what they
want you to think.
You think
he did it on purpose?
Picking the most
remote possible...
I mean, you're trapped here.
It's like Alcatraz.
Maybe he just wanted people
to have to get away.
From what? Cell phone service?
I don't even have one bar.
Think you can get a decent plate of
eggs anywhere in this zip code?
Oh, there's a... That
little place looks sweet.
Oh, that place?
I guarantee you that place does not
serve breakfast for under $10.
You're a captive
audience here.
We're only here for a week.
It's like an airport.
We might as well try... A week?
I'll be bankrupt in a week.
Let's go. Come on.
Coffee to start?
Yes. Please.
Is there anything on this menu
that doesn't have lobster in it?
Oh.
See, there are your eggs.
And, look, they have
a breakfast special.
What's special about $11.75?
All right, I'm going to have
a side of two eggs,
sunny side up,
and a side of bacon, crisp.
I'll just give you the special.
It comes with the...
Nope.
The special's $1 more.
And for you?
Yes. I'm just going to have the
fruit and cottage cheese plate.
I have a nervous stomach.
And we're in a tiny
bit of a hurry because...
You got the 10:30 with Bernie.
We'll get you there on time.
Good luck.
There it is.
Oh, nice digs.
Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
If he says one word about
repressed memories, I am leaving.
Kay and Arnold,
I'm so glad you're here.
Well, that makes one of us.
Hmm.
So, Arnold, I take it intensive
therapy was not your idea.
Nope!
You wanted to come?
Yes.
All right.
And Arnold, you?
I thought she was nuts.
We're not in the same tax
bracket as your other patients.
I think you'd be surprised.
Well, even if we were,
all due respect.
I really don't
see the point here.
So, you think there's nothing
wrong with your marriage.
Well, we've been married
31 years, isn't it?
It's not perfect.
But in your opinion,
it works well enough.
But you wanted to come.
You persuaded Arnold?
No. I mean, I paid for it.
With my own money,
from savings.
All right. So this is
really important to you.
Mmm-hmm.
Tell me why.
I want to have
a marriage again.
ARNOLD: Again?
If we don't have a marriage,
I don't know who does.
Arnold. Let's let Kay talk
and you can respond after.
Okay. Fine. "Again."
Arnold used to touch me.
Oh, God.
Not just... You know,
but he would touch my arm
or my shoulder, just to...
Just to, I don't know,
because he wanted to.
And now he doesn't?
And that bothers you.
Do you touch him?
Not really.
He doesn't like it.
Is she right, Arnold? Do you
like it when she touches you?
I don't know.
DR. FELD: You don't know?
I don't think about it.
All right.
(SIGHS)
What else, Kay?
Well, it feels like we live in
the house together like two...
Like two workers
who bunk in the same room.
Except we don't...
We're not in the same room,
but it just feels
like there's nothing
holding us together
except the house.
Nothing holding us together
like 31 years of...
Of what, Arnold?
Marriage.
What does that
word mean to you?
Means we have a marriage license
and I pay all the bills.
Not to mention
our two grown...
You really have
lost your mind.
Let's try to keep the conversation
descriptive and positive.
(SIGHS)
Kay, please continue.
Um...
We don't talk
about anything.
Talk! What is there
I don't know about you?
About Eileen and
the skirts she bought
or if she took back the little
necklace with the tiki gods.
Jesus Christ.
No, I don't mean...
I just mean, I don't...
(SIGHS)
I don't tell Arnold how
I feel about anything.
And I don't know how he feels
about anything either.
I'll tell you how I feel
about this, I hate it.
All right. This is good.
ARNOLD: Good. Yeah.
Good for you.
The more we tear
each other apart,
the more money we have to pay
you to put it back together.
(CHUCKLES) Jesus God. You
people are worse than lawyers.
I understand how you feel.
Yeah?
You two have come here to try to
restore intimacy to your marriage.
So that is
going to be the goal
of our very focused
sessions together.
To find ways to communicate
your needs to one another.
To cultivate intimacy.
And to develop the tools to sustain
that intimacy going forward.
The first step in
rebuilding a marriage
is tearing away
some of the scar tissue
that has built up
over the years.
It can be very painful,
but it's worth it.
I like to think of it...
The metaphor of when you have a
deviated septum and you can't breathe?
You have to break the nose
in order to fix it.
(CHUCKLES)
ARNOLD: Charlatan!
No, he's worse than a charlatan.
He's like one of those...
(SIGHS)
Says he's "honed his method."
The only thing he's honed
is making sure that
if you don't walk in
with
a marriage-destroying problem,
you won't leave without one.
He's like those moisturizing eye
drops that make your eyes dry.
$4,000. That could
have been a new roof!
Did you look at his credentials or
even read that brochure that you...
I mean, my God!
Unbelievable! I'd like to have a
look at this guy's tax returns.
Whoo-hoo.
Oh, don't.
Come on, just don't.
You have to
stop yelling at me.
I'm not yelling!
Who's yelling?
Hey. Welcome back.
I'll have an Arnold
Palmer and a tuna melt.
You sure you're
ready to commit?
I'll have the soup
and salad, please.
Okey-dokey.
$9 for a tuna melt, it's canned
tuna, a slab of cheese and toast.
Feld's probably
getting kickbacks.
(LAUGHING)
I saw a grocery store
near the motel.
We can buy some cold cuts,
eat in the room.
Are you guys
here for Bernie?
Mmm-hmm.
We come back every year.
For a tune-up.
Oh.
In case you're wondering,
we are never coming back.
I mean, if I had ever said so
much as even one unkind word...
Do you want the hard salami
or do you want this kind here?
I don't care.
I mean, my brother, Ralph,
if Angela had ever taken him
to one of these things, whew.
You. I just hope you
remember this next year
when you want to tell me that
I never help and I never...
I'm getting the Limburger,
you don't have to eat it.
And I'll tell you one thing,
we're going to go to Florida and see my
mother next year for the full two weeks.
You have forfeited
your right to complain.
Oh, boy! I was thinking
about you the whole...
Get away from the door!
I'm getting!
(MOANING)
What happened to you?
I had to do that thing
and the handle came off.
Oh, me, too! And it broke,
and that kid, he played bad.
(CLANKING)
(SIGHS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
KAY: It was a course
at the university.
Beginning Accounting.
And Arnold was
the teaching assistant.
What was your first impression
of Kay, Arnold?
She was pretty.
Very pretty.
What else?
She probably shouldn't
major in accounting.
And Thanksgiving passed,
no ring,
and my dad said, "Well, you
picked the wrong horse."
But two days later,
I found it.
He had hidden it,
the ring, in a cinnamon bun.
(LAUGHS)
I was so surprised.
What was holding
you up, Arnold?
Well,
it's not like buying a car.
And that winter,
Arnold threw his back out.
I was helping Brad
paint his room and...
He said he would be more
comfortable sleeping alone.
That hurt like
a son of a bitch.
But then,
his back got better.
It still bothers me
a little bit. But also I...
He snores.
I have that
sleep apnea deal.
So he just stayed in the
guest room after that.
Yeah.
Did you ask him to come back?
No. I didn't think he'd...
No.
Hmm.
So it's been a long time since
you've slept in the same room.
When was the last
time you had sex?
Yeah.
Uh, I have no idea.
Well, let's try
to think about it.
It was four years ago, almost
five years ago. In September.
When Brad moved out
after college.
September 22nd.
I remember thinking,
"He's moving out on
the first day of fall."
We get the picture, okay?
This makes you uncomfortable
talking about this, doesn't it?
Well, sue me because
I don't want to talk
about having sex with my wife
with a total stranger.
You want to talk
about it at all?
What else do you remember
about that day, Kay?
How'd you make love?
How?
DR. FELD: Was it the missionary position?
Arnold on top?
KAY: Oh, yeah.
(SIGHS)
DR. FELD: Was it always
missionary position?
Oh, please.
KAY: Mostly, yes. Mmm-hmm.
Were there particular things
that you enjoyed doing?
Mostly it was the same.
Was your sex life
satisfying for you?
Well, it was fine.
Yeah. All right.
Okay.
I would like to assign
you your first exercise.
What... What kind of...
Tonight, I would like you
to spend a period of time
with your arms
around one another.
(STAMMERING)
Well, what's the... Why?
Because I want you to remember what
it's like to touch each other.
Do you think
you can do that?
Arnold?
Well, maybe that's what...
I mean, forced intimacy...
Is that really...
It's not forced intimacy.
That's what it sounds like.
Oh...
What? We're supposed to be truthful here.
DR. FELD: You are.
Although... So what I'm saying is
that I don't think this exercise,
or whatever you wanna call it,
sounds like something...
It's not forced.
If I do that
just because somebody tells
me to, what is the point?
I don't think I like the idea
of anybody telling me...
I mean, the whole idea of this exercise
thing is totally ridiculous to me.
I'm not a trained monkey!
You're a bully!
What?
Since you got here, all you've
done is make me feel...
Kay? Kay.
...terrible.
I've had it.
Kay!
♪ How do I get the man in you
to see
♪ I'm so much more
♪ Than the mother in me?
Kay. Kay.
Kay, come on.
This is infantile.
I think you're infantile!
Look... Where are you going?
This is insane.
No, it's not!
Where are you going?
♪ I want to be your lady
♪ Oh, I want to get swept away
♪ Let me cry for a change
♪ Don't need no lone survivor
♪ I need someone by my side
♪ We don't have
to make it perfect
♪ Oh, but maybe we could try
♪ Love me for the woman
that I am
♪ And I will love you
♪ For being my man ♪
You can come in.
We don't bite.
What can I get you?
Um...
Would you recommend
the red wine or the white?
Do you like red wine?
Yeah.
Then I'd go with the white.
(EVERYBODY PLAYS THE FOOL PLAYING)
♪ Everybody plays the fool
♪ Sometime
♪ There's no exception
to the rule
♪ Listen, baby
And so,
I was just hoping that,
maybe if...
Trying to get
the old magic back?
Yeah.
Did you ever have it?
♪ How can you help it
♪ When the music
starts to play
You want the audio tour?
It's $4.95.
The thing is
we really don't
have sex, mostly.
At all.
That's it?
(CHUCKLES)
All right. Who in here
is not having sex?
Not me.
Mike, I know
you're not getting any.
(LAUGHTER)
This one's on us.
KAY: Thank you.
♪ Everybody, baby
♪ Everybody plays the fool
♪ Sometime ♪
(LOCK CLICKING)
(SIGHS)
I'm back!
I see that.
(HUMMING)
I went to the museum.
Did you?
Was it interesting?
Extremely.
Of course, if you want to go,
you'll have to do it on your own.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm getting ready for bed.
(WATER RUNNING)
(ARNOLD SIGHS)
Where'd you go
this afternoon?
Oh.
Just around.
I thought you
wanted to do that thing.
But if you don't want to
do it, I sure don't care.
All right,
I'll just go to bed.
I want to do it.
I guess we should do it there.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, I guess
I'll get in.
Maybe this is enough.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Yeah, probably enough.
I was just
getting the light.
(SIGHS)
(BOTH SIGHING)
And then we did
the exercise...
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, that was...
...and we woke up.
Yeah.
And we were
in the same bed.
Yeah, it was...
It was comfortable.
Yep.
This is good.
Really good.
By taking some
time to yourselves,
you were able to
relate better as a couple.
And you both did it
without even trying.
Well, she wanted
to spend time apart.
Yeah. I was so mad.
Mad as a wet cat.
But, you know, it was
nice, wasn't it?
To do something on
your own, you know.
Great, you two.
Really great.
I'm thrilled with the
progress that you've made.
And I think it's going to
make it that much easier
to proceed to
the next step.
Next step. That's great.
Let's get with it.
I mean, we're doing so well, we might
be able to get out of here early.
Okay, next step.
What is it?
Write a poem? Hold hands in public?
Sing a serenade?
Sex.
We're going to talk extensively
about your sexual history.
When it started. What it included.
What it didn't include.
If you had orgasms,
vaginally or otherwise.
If you had issues around
sexuality or performance.
Whether you talked
about sex or during it.
What your fantasies are.
If you ever
acted on fantasies.
Brought toys or sex games
into the bedroom.
Brought sex out
of the bedroom.
And once we've explored
all of those things,
I will give you
your first sexual,
not sex,
but sexual, exercise.
All right?
Let's get started.
Arnold,
would you like to begin?
Do you...
I think we ought to stop
this right now before...
We should just get
our things and go.
I'll go first. I will.
Fine.
Terrific.
All right.
Kay, let's talk about
what you liked sexually.
(STAMMERS)
Was intercourse
pleasurable for you?
Sometimes.
Did you have orgasms?
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Sometimes.
Do you masturbate?
KAY: No.
Not any more.
Why not?
Because at a certain point,
I just...
(SIGHS)
I think I didn't want to think
about sex or about Arnold, even.
It just made me sad thinking
about what I missed and...
What about your fantasy life?
Do you have fantasies?
Mmm-hmm.
What?
My fantasy is that, you
know, we'll renew our vows.
Just a little small ceremony,
on a beach, maybe.
Right.
Maybe with the kids there.
Right. And do you
have sexual fantasies?
Imagine scenarios?
Having sex on a mountain top
or dressed all in leather?
(LAUGHS)
That's funny.
So, no.
I mainly think about Arnold
and things that we've done.
You never have fantasies
about things that
you haven't done ever?
No.
Okay. Okay.
All right. Arnold,
let's talk about you.
What do you enjoy sexually?
Sex.
I'm going to ask you
to get more specific.
Okay, fine.
So you enjoy the actual sexual act?
Intercourse?
Yeah.
Missionary style.
(SIGHS)
Would you prefer that
to, say, oral sex?
I guess so.
Was oral sex an option? Is that
something that you would do regularly?
(STAMMERING)
No, I, I, I, I don't... No.
I was not very... I'm...
(CLEARS THROAT) I was not
comfortable with that.
Giving or receiving?
Huh?
Um, I don't know.
Both, I guess.
Okay. So, now you, Arnold,
would have been open to that.
What does it matter? She just
said it was not an option.
DR. FELD: What about
problems in the bedroom?
Have you ever experienced
erectile dysfunction?
(LAUGHS) No.
Use medications
like Viagra?
No.
As we age,
sometimes, it becomes...
It works.
What would you say
was working in your sex life
when you were sexual together?
(SIGHS)
For instance, would you climax?
Yeah.
Were there things that you
wanted to do, but didn't?
You're kidding, right?
Well?
I mean,
who says no to that?
Right. Then go ahead.
Uh, what,
you want a whole list?
Sure.
Uh...
I'm not really
coming up with anything.
There are no
wrong answers here.
(SIGHS)
Well...
if you could have
anything you wanted
in your sex life with Kay,
what would that be?
Did you have fantasies that you didn't
feel comfortable telling her about?
Of course.
Well, I guess I used to think
about Kay giving me a...
(SIGHS)
Giving me oral...
You know...
At work.
Under the desk.
At tax time.
So, public places.
No, not just public places.
No? Okay.
Good, good. Very good.
What else?
(CLEARING THROAT) A threesome.
With?
The neighbor.
Helen?
No, Carol.
Carol?
Carol with the corgis?
Very good, Arnold.
Both of you.
I am going to give you
your next exercise.
You think we ought to
be sitting for this?
Well,
maybe lying down.
You want to go first?
Do you want me to?
Six of one,
half dozen of the other.
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
Is that all right?
Fine.
Does it feel good?
It feels like
you're petting a dog.
That tickles. Don't...
Sorry. Okay.
Don't go there.
I'm sorry.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
I really don't
see the point of...
I mean, this Dr. Feld...
Mmm-hmm.
...you think he has other legitimate
doctors here who agree with him,
or think he could be
just some sort of a renegade?
You, I mean, well, us,
your average person, you could be being
treated by someone who's psychotic.
Or maybe someone
who's just a very average,
or even
below-average practitioner.
Uh...
(GROANS)
I think we better stop.
What?
You sure?
Yeah, I think I just...
I'm going to bed.
(SIGHS)
(MOANING SOFTLY)
(KAY BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MOANING)
(SHUDDERING BREATHS)
So, last night you had
the touching exercise.
How did that go?
How was that for you?
All right,
let's talk about it. Arnold.
How was it
having Kay touch you?
It was fine, I guess.
Did it feel good?
Did you get aroused?
How did that
make you feel?
Aroused.
What about you, Kay?
How did that make you feel?
Oh, I got aroused, too.
Did you know that, Arnold?
How am I supposed to know what
she's thinking or feeling?
How was it for you, Kay,
when Arnold touched you?
Oh, we didn't
get to that part.
Why not? Why?
Because we just stopped.
We did the exercise.
It was done. We did it.
The exercise was to spend a period of
time touching each other sensually.
It sounds like Kay touched
you and then you stopped.
Did you talk about it?
Whose idea was it to stop?
It was mine, okay. I just wanted to stop.
I wanted...
All right. Okay. I didn't
want to do it any more.
All right.
Well, let's go deeper, then.
Let's not go deeper.
It's not enough to just be here.
You have to try.
I'm not trying? I flew 1,500 miles
up here for this and I'm not trying?
All right. Well, then, let's
just try to figure this out.
Why did you
want Kay to stop?
I wanted her
to stop because...
Were you afraid?
No! What do I
have to be afraid of?
Fear... Hey, re-engaging can be...
I'm not afraid of my own wife.
Fine. Well, that's okay. It's okay.
It's normal to feel fear.
I did not feel fear!
Then why did you stop Kay
from touching you?
Let me tell you something.
I am done with this for today.
I am done.
I'll see you back at the room.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Kay?
What are you doing?
Dr. Feld said
he'd give us a refund.
What percent?
What?
Did he say he'd give us back
the whole payment, or...
Half.
I don't know what you thought
was going to happen here.
What did you...
I mean, there's no
magic pill or wand or...
He's just a guy
with an office.
Mmm-hmm.
It's ridiculous. You come
up here, you spend one week
and you're supposed to, what,
have a new marriage?
It's a setup.
You're set up for failure.
Then you feel bad about failing.
You see that, right?
You can't win.
Why the hell did
you bring us here?
You know how you think you're
always headed towards something?
You think, "When we get married,"
or, "When we have kids,"
or, "When the kids go
and it's just us again..."
You know, there's always
something to look forward to.
And one day, I realized that we are
not going towards anything any more.
And I guess I was
just not willing
to let go of things
getting better any more.
Not yet.
Maybe you just
don't get a choice,
you know?
Maybe you just
don't get a choice.
Don't forget your
razor in the bathroom.
You're back.
Let's talk about that.
ARNOLD: Let's not.
Let's just... I'm back, all right?
That ought to be enough.
It isn't, actually.
What do you want
from me, blood?
You have a lot
of anger, Arnold.
What do you think
you're so angry about?
I'm angry about everything.
I'm angry about being here.
Why? What are you
afraid will happen?
You want to know what? Fine.
What I'm afraid
will happen here
is what probably happens in every
goddamn therapist's office
every time any poor
couple goes in there.
You say whatever thing,
because somebody like you
is dragging it out of them and
then you can't take it back.
There are things in this life
that you don't say for a reason.
Like what?
What would you say?
Uh...
Tell me.
I want to know.
It's worse not knowing when there
are things that you're holding back
you won't say because you think
I'm too fragile or whatever.
No, it's not that. It's...
Something I can't hear.
All right, fine!
All right.
She has a way...
Say it to Kay.
You have a way of saying
that something's up to me
and then when
I make a decision
and it's something
you don't like,
you don't actually
say anything,
but you sure do get
your point across.
Well, can I just say, I don't like...
Is it my turn?
I don't like the way
that we always do
something for Christmas,
or an anniversary,
that's a joint gift for the
house, like a water heater.
You needed
that water heater.
Yes, but you did, too.
You shower.
Why is that
a special gift for me?
Hmm?
And I hate watching golf.
I do. I think it's boring.
And the shows where they
talk about golf, even worse.
It's like being
married to ESPN.
And when you eat ranch chips,
your breath smells.
I like ranch chips.
And I hate it when
you rub up against me,
like you just
expect me to do it.
"Come on, let's go."
Hell, it got to the point I was
afraid to make any kind of move.
If I even so much as
tried to kiss you...
Well, you never kiss me.
You don't want to kiss me,
you just want "it."
Not me.
(SIGHS) You know, he always has
his eyes squeezed tight shut.
It's not me.
You just want "it."
Hell, yes, I want "it." You can
bet your life I want "it."
So screw me for wanting
to have sex with my wife!
And, you know,
it's not pleasant
to do that with somebody
who doesn't want to do it.
But you never saw me...
What?
Go on, Arnold.
I didn't complain
because Kay didn't want sex.
Love. That's what I wanted.
Not just sex.
I wanted you.
Well, what about all those
years I wanted you?
All those goddamn years.
And I didn't cheat.
I didn't go to hookers.
I watched a little porn,
but who doesn't?
I was good.
I did the right thing.
Now you're
bringing me here for...
You're the one
who stopped, not me.
Yeah, for a while I stopped,
yes, but you stopped, too.
You did. You stopped.
Well, you don't just turn
it on and off, you know?
Maybe when it's off,
it's just off.
Off.
(SIGHS)
I want you to do
something for me.
I want you to tell me about
the best sex you ever had.
The time that you can remember
that was the best. Either of you.
Even if it wasn't very good.
Even if it was terrible.
Best time
that you remember.
Well...
Hmm.
Oh.
I remember one time.
Kay was pregnant.
Where were you?
In the kitchen.
She was making soup.
And I came in there and she kept
saying she had to stir her soup.
And pretty soon,
she forgot about that soup.
What do you remember, Kay?
Well,
we were on the floor, and...
And it was slow.
He... He put some dish towels
behind my head
so my head wouldn't bang on...
Wouldn't bump up against
the bottom of the cabinet.
That was... (LAUGHS)
Arnold, what else
do you remember about that?
Just wanting her.
Standing there
in the kitchen.
Happy.
Beautiful.
She had a little apron which was
getting to be too little because her
belly was getting so big.
You were very
attracted to her then.
Yeah, I was, and...
Are you still?
Uh, I don't...
I don't know.
It's been a long
time since we've...
I don't look
like I did then.
No, it's not that.
No. I never could
lose all the weight.
You look fine. I just don't think
of it in that way any more.
About her that way any more.
Well, of course, I...
DR. FELD: No,
it's not "of course."
Sometimes when
a connection is lost,
we forget how to
want one another.
Do you still want Kay?
Well, yes!
Do you still
fantasize about her?
(STAMMERING)
You mean, now?
These days.
I don't know.
I don't... I...
I had one.
I had a fantasy.
Was it...
It was...
It was... It was...
Like you said, it was just us,
and it was really different.
Something we've
never done before.
Something new.
I'm going to ask you to take a
leap of faith and try something.
It is most likely way out
of your comfort zone.
Try to think of
it in terms of...
Remember the metaphor
of a nose breaking?
It's the nose.
(SHUSHING)
Well, you can't break
a nose slowly, can you?
(MEN SPEAKING FRENCH ONSCREEN)
Of course there was a problem
with the popcorn popper.
Oh.
(COUGHS)
Thank you.
I don't see why you can't tell
me what you're planning on.
Because he said
it was fine this way.
It just makes me uncomfortable not to
know what I'm going to be asked to do.
When it's your turn,
you can do what you want.
What if we don't do
the exercise again?
We're moving at
a rapid clip here. Okay.
It's your ball game.
I'll tell you one thing.
You would never get me into a
French movie if we were at home.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(ARNOLD LAUGHING)
This is pretty good.
Oh.
Sorry.
(UNZIPPING)
(KAY EXHALES)
(CHUCKLING)
(GROANS)
I'm sorry, I can't see!
You just need to take it easy.
Watch it with the teeth!
I'm sorry.
Sorry, I didn't mean...
It's all right.
I can't see.
Oh, God.
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Hey, you can hurt someone!
(SOBBING) I'm so sorry!
I can't do this.
Kay. Kay. Kay.
Kay, it's okay.
It's not okay!
It's not okay.
(SIGHS)
Kay, listen.
Kay, this is not a big deal.
I should...
I'm not good at anything.
There's not anything
to be good at!
I don't know how to
be good at anything.
Listen, wait.
I'm not sexy!
Wait. Yes, you are very...
What?
What? Yes, what?
Maybe you just don't have...
Maybe there's just certain things
you're not experienced at.
Kay!
I must have
looked so stupid!
But how did you feel?
Like a fake.
I'm just not... I'm...
I just can't do that.
Well, the whole situation
was just dangerous,
with those cup holders,
and seat backs going forth,
and back and forth
and the cramped space,
the concrete floor, those
people everywhere. (GROANS)
That's not me.
I just can't be
a person who commits
an illegal act
in a movie theater.
It's just... Is that
really who I have to be?
It's not about
being a sex object.
It's about pleasing the man you love.
And letting him please you.
Well, I don't even
know how to do that!
Ultimately, I think
you have to ask yourself,
"Is this person worth more
to me than my pride?"
Oh, yeah. I mean...
Yes.
Kay's putting it
all on the line here.
What are you
putting on the line?
Everything.
He is everything.
But I'm really lonely.
And I think
to be with somebody
and not really with him is...
I think I might be less
lonely if I were alone.
Do you want to be alone?
No!
I don't know.
You wouldn't think
it would be so hard
to just touch
somebody that you love.
But it is. It's really hard.
Okay. You know what?
I'm going to
give you something
that may help
with your anxiety.
You can pick
this up in town.
(BELLS TINKLE)
Hey.
Hi. Hello.
Oh, we got a discount on trade
paperbacks in the front,
if you're interested.
Oh.
Are you looking
for anything special?
Not really.
All right,
just let me know.
(DOOR OPENS)
(BELLS TINKLE)
Do you have
a title, miss?
No, not... I'm just...
I was gonna say if you got
a title, I can look it up.
We're short on
shelf space up here,
so we have a lot of
stuff in the back.
Actually, I'm looking for
Sex Tips for Straight
Women from a Gay Man.
Oh, yeah. Dr. Feld has
us keep those in stock.
Oh. Okay.
Can I give you cash?
Yeah, that works.
Couples come to me
for two reasons.
To help them save
their marriage, or...
Or what?
Or to help them end it.
When one person
is this unhappy,
the marriage has to restore
some sort of equilibrium, or...
Or what? Are you trying to
tell me my marriage is over?
Because I'm not gonna pay you
for one more session
just because you threaten me,
you smug little prick!
Arnold, your wife
is very unhappy.
And I'm not saying
that she'll ever leave.
I just don't want you to have
anything to regret should she...
I'm simply
saying the moment is here
and you have to ask yourself,
"Have I done all I could?"
Have you, Arnold?
Is this the best
that you can do?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry, there's...
Listen, I can... Maybe a little
tip would help, you know.
You want to buy a table?
I need it.
So whatever...
Look, I need this.
Look, I'm really sorry about whatever
is going on in your marriage,
but I don't think the dinner
was going to save it.
I need a table.
I need it, and I'm not going to leave
from right here until I get it.
MIKE: We're going to
need more space here,
so I want you to push it further
against the wall. All right?
All right.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello. Captain Jack's.
I'm sorry to hear that, Mr. Fletcher.
What time was that for?
Uh, all right.
Well, thanks for calling. I do hope
you come and visit us sometime.
Thank you very much. Bye.
All right.
That goes away.
Well?
Got a waiting list.
Got to call them.
You got a waiting list? You will
give me that table, so help me God!
Are you ready?
I'm almost ready.
(ARNOLD COUGHS)
(SIGHS)
You really ready? 'Cause
I don't want to be late.
Yes, I'm really ready.
Very pretty.
Thank you.
You look really nice, too.
Yeah, I do.
You handsome devil.
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, Arnold.
It's gorgeous!
(ELEGANT PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
I just can't get over it!
You like it?
Mmm.
This is just exactly...
A little different
than the Econo Lodge?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Completely different.
That place reminds me of when we
drove down to see your mother,
before we were married.
And we stayed at
that little place...
You know, it was the only
place that was open.
It was a truck stop.
In Albuquerque?
Oh, I remember that.
It had orange walls.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
That was the first
time you said it.
First time you
said you loved me.
In that little motel.
You know,
before you said it...
Well, I didn't want to
be the one who said it first,
but I just...
I had to say it!
So every time we
talked on the phone
I would say it to
the phone after we hung up!
Really?
Yes, I really did that.
I figured if I ever said anything
like that, you'd take off running.
What?
You could have
had your pick.
I didn't think
you'd ever want me.
I never wanted anything more.
(KAY AND ARNOLD LAUGHING)
What I don't get is how he
remembers to talk like that.
"Consider the metaphor
of the nose."
I know.
It must be so hard for him.
I wonder if he talks
to his wife like that.
That would be...
"Mildred, I find it very
interesting that you are naked."
Can I bring you
anything else?
Do you...
No, I'm fine.
Okay. No, just the check.
Unless you want to.
No, check, please.
(SIGHS)
Might get chilly
on the way back.
It's been
getting cold at night.
Well, the thing is, I've...
(CLEARS THROAT)
I don't know how
you'll take this,
but I got us a room.
Here.
You did?
Mmm-hmm.
The front desk has toothbrushes.
I asked them.
I thought maybe just
for a night, it'd be...
You might want to...
So,
after this, we can just...
(FIRE CRACKLING)
Like it?
(GASPS) Gosh!
Oh, my gosh.
Oh!
Look at this.
Look at this!
Here's some strawberries.
You had to get them,
so here they are.
Anyway, you want some?
Huh?
Strawberries.
I'm kind of full.
Yeah, me, too.
And they knew that.
It's a rip off, really.
You spend 15...
That's okay. You know, I think
I would like to have some.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
Do you want to eat them
at the table? Okay.
Or we could eat them in
front of the fire. Okay.
Okay.
Um... Oh.
On. (LAUGHS)
Sweet.
Mmm.
Is it good?
Mmm! It's good.
It's fresh.
Good.
Chocolaty.
Mmm.
You want some? There's
champagne, if you want.
Yeah. I know...
I'm sorry. Go ahead.
No, you go.
There's champagne.
You want some? I think I
would like that, Arnold.
Ohh!
(LAUGHING)
I guess you have
something in mind there.
Mmm-hmm.
I do.
Hold that thought.
What?
Oh. Okay.
(LET'S STAY TOGETHER PLAYING)
♪ Let's stay together
♪ I'm
♪ I'm so in love with you
(LAUGHING)
Come here.
♪ Whatever you want to do
♪ Is all right with me
♪ 'Cause you make me feel
♪ So brand-new
♪ And I
♪ Want to spend
my life with you
♪ Let me say that since
♪ Baby, since we've
been together
♪ Ooh
♪ Loving you forever
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪ Is what I need
♪ Let me be the one
♪ You come running to
♪ I'll never be
I want... I want...
You want to...
All right.
You want to... You want to...
Yeah.
♪ Ooh, baby, let's
♪ Let's stay together
♪ Loving you whether
♪ Whether
♪ Times are good or bad
♪ Happy or sad
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
(SONG FADES)
Look at me.
(STIFLED SOBBING)
You lied.
No.
When Dr. Feld asked you if you
were still attracted to me.
It was when you looked at me.
Just now.
You looked in my face.
That had
nothing to do with it.
That's when you stopped.
DR. FELD: Setbacks are a natural part of the process.
They never feel good, though.
(SIGHS)
I know you feel
like you've failed,
but look where you failed. You
fumbled on the one-yard line.
When you got here, you weren't
even on the playing field.
You were somewhere
in the parking lot.
So I think you're ready to follow
up with a therapist at home.
I can recommend
somebody really good.
I have patients who never
should have gotten married.
And you are not those people.
Even great marriages
have terrible years.
So bad that you're
tempted to just give up.
But don't.
Hold on.
There will come a time when
you'll look back at this moment
as the prelude to
something fuller
and richer than
you've ever dreamed.
(SIGHS)
(TV PLAYING)
Soames!
Yo.
Hey, how was that vacation?
Good!
Yeah. Where was it, Vermont?
Maine.
Maine. That's right.
You said Kay likes the ocean.
So, how was it?
You going to go back?
Um, probably not.
It's a little overpriced.
Yeah. I hear you, but, hey, if it
keeps the missus happy another year,
I'd say it's well
worth the money spent!
Yeah.
Jon Ross came in today.
Mmm-hmm.
You'd think it was the first
time he'd ever heard that
October 15th was the
deadline for an extension.
The guy never filed
on time in his life!
And we have the same
conversation every year.
Every goddamn year.
For 17 years.
Can you imagine that?
KRAIG KANN ON TV: Hi, again, everybody.
School of Golf
is back in session
for another week.
This week, it is Chapter 24,
"It's All About the Putting Stroke."
I'm Kraig Kann. This is the
professor, Martin Hall.
Putting.
We're rolling it tonight.
Well, yes. We all want
to hit it fewer times...
(SIGHS)
EILEEN: So you guys
had fun, huh?
Kind of hard to get
back into the old routine.
Mmm.
What is it?
You look like
you could cry.
No!
Do you still need somebody to take
care of that cat when you go away?
Oh, we already got
the girl next door.
But I don't trust her.
She's not bright.
Well, I could do it.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, gosh, are you sure?
Because I think I might
have a spare key with me.
And maybe
I could stay over.
A night, or two nights.
Well, sure. You do that.
I saw The Caine Mutiny
is on later.
Mmm-hmm.
You want to watch it?
I don't think so.
I'm just going
to go up to bed.
Kay.
I'm just a little tired.
Is it really
all that bad?
It's just expectations.
Like one of those makeovers,
you know?
You look different
for a minute
and then go back
to yourself, right?
Right?
I don't know if I can.
What?
I don't know
if I can go back.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
You sure this is
a gallon can?
Yes, sir, it's a lard can. Just
took it from the pantry, sir.
I suppose you're wondering
why I called this meeting.
As you all know by now, we had an
excellent dessert for dinner tonight,
ice cream and
frozen strawberries.
An hour ago, I sent Whittaker to the
pantry to bring me another portion.
(WHY? PLAYING)
♪ Why?
♪ How many times
♪ Do I have to try to tell you
♪ That I'm sorry
for the things I've done?
♪ Ooh
♪ But when I start
to try to tell you
♪ That's when you
have to tell me
♪ Hey, this kind of trouble's
♪ Only just begun
♪ Yeah
(STIFLED SOBBING)
♪ I tell myself too many times
♪ Why don't you ever learn
to keep your big mouth shut?
♪ That's why it hurts so bad
to hear the words
♪ That keep on falling
from your mouth
♪ Falling from your mouth
♪ Tell me why
♪ This is the book
I never read
♪ These are the words
I never said
♪ This is the path
I'll never tread
♪ These are the dreams
I'll dream instead
♪ This is the joy
that's seldom spread
♪ These are the tears,
the tears we shed
♪ This is the fear,
this is the dread
♪ These are the contents
of my head
♪ And these are the years
that we have spent
♪ And this is what
they represent
♪ This is howl feel
♪ Do you know how I feel?
♪ 'Cause I don't think
you know how I feel
♪ I don't think
you know what I feel
♪ Why?
♪ I don't think
you know what I feel ♪
Kay.
(SIGHS)
(MOANING)
You are beautiful.
(LAUGHS)
You... You...
(GASPING)
(MOANS)
(SIZZLING)
I'm late.
Oh. Okay.
Well, have a nice day.
Okay.
Chicken tonight.
Good.
With potatoes and
maybe some spinach.
Good. No spinach.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay. 6:00?
5:30.
What's the matter?
What'd you forget?
(KAY MOANS SOFTLY)
(KAY GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
Have a nice day.
Arnold!
Arnie!
Hey! Hi!
Carol!
You got another corgi!
I know. This is Emma.
But three's the limit.
I'm done.
How was y'all's trip?
Our trip was...
Our trip was really...
You should come over tonight and
we'll tell you all about it.
That'd be great.
I'd love to.
Yeah.
All right.
I'll see you guys later.
KAY: Okay.
(LAUGHING)
That's not going to happen.
Kay. Arnold.
We are all here
today to witness
the renewals of your
vows of matrimony.
We are thrilled, and I
especially am very thrilled,
to be here and to be a part
of this very special day.
KAY: Arnold,
after 32 years of marriage,
I can honestly say that I love
you more than I ever did.
The day I met you
changed my life.
It made my life.
And now I can't imagine
living my life without you.
It wouldn't be any
kind of life at all.
When I think about spending
the rest of my life with you,
I only regret it
won't be long enough.
So I want to now
make this next chapter
of our lives together
something that
we'll both cherish.
I vow to watch more golf with
you without complaining.
(LAUGHTER)
I vow to watch less golf,
and to buy you good presents
that aren't for the house.
Maybe like jewelry.
Like jewelry.
Jewelry. Yes.
I vow not to cut my hair
any shorter than it is,
'cause I know
you like it long.
Longer.
I vow not to
complain so much.
If I can help it,
because sometimes
there's something
that really needs to
be complained about.
And I vow to go to one
of those sleep studies
like you've been
asking me to go to.
And I vow to take you
somewhere once a year
that's more than 200
miles away from home
and isn't to see
a family member.
Now, on this wonderful day,
I give you
the rest of my life
and I thank God every
day that you're in it.
And I vow to
tell you how I feel,
not just when you ask me.
And I'll tell you
how I feel about this.
I love it. I love you.
(MOUTHING)
(LAUGHING)
We will have the ceremonial
breaking of the nose.
(LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE)
See? That wasn't so hard.
Thank you.
Yes, a big boy.
Congratulations.
(BRIGHT SIDE OF THE ROAD
PLAYING)
♪ We'll be lovers once again
♪ On the bright side
of the road
(LAUGHTER)
KAY: I'm so glad
to meet you!
Finally!
Brad, Brad, Brad!
♪ From the dark end
of the street
♪ To the bright side
of the road
♪ Well, into this
life we're born
♪ Baby, sometimes
♪ Sometimes we
don't know why
♪ And time seems
to go by so fast
♪ In the twinkling of an eye
♪ Let's enjoy it while we can
♪ Won't you help me
share my load?
♪ Help me share my load
♪ From the dark end
of the street
♪ To the bright side
of the road ♪