[ Clicking Sound ] [ Crowd Cheering, Faint ]
[ Rhythmic Clicking ]
[ Crowd Clapping   In Rhythm ]
[ Man ]  SO THIS IS THE WORLD, AND THERE ARE ALMOST SIX BILLION PEOPLE ON IT.
???? [ Guitar ] WHEN I WAS A KID, THERE WERE THREE.
IT'S HARD TO KEEP UP.
THERE.  THAT'S BETTER. THAT'S AMERICA.
SEE, AMERICA STILL SETS THE TONE FOR THE WORLD.
IN INDIANA, CLARK HODD, 13, THE BEST POINT GUARD IN THE COUNTRY.
LAST WEEK HE SCORED A HUNDRED POINTS...
IN A SINGLE GAME.
ERICA SORGI.  YOU'LL SEE HER IN THE NEXT OLYMPICS.
[ Diving Board   Vibrating ]
IN SEATTLE, DALLAS MALLOY, 16.
HER LAWSUIT HELPED PAVE THE WAY FOR WOMEN BOXERS EVERYWHERE.
SHE'S PICTURING HER EX-BOYFRIEND RIGHT NOW. [ Bell Dings ]
IN INDIO, CALIFORNIA, ART STALLINGS.
CHECK OUT WHAT PURE JOY LOOKS LIKE.
IN ODESSA, TEXAS, THE GREAT FRANK CUSHMAN.
THIS APRIL, 26 TEAMS WILL BE FALLING ALL OVER THEMSELVES...
TO SIGN HIM IN THE NEXT NFL DRAFT.
HE'S MY CLIENT, MY MOST IMPORTANT CLIENT.
WHEN ARE YOU GONNA TRY? WHEN ARE YOU GONNA CONCENTRATE? YOU WANNA BE A CHAMPION?
[ Man Continues ]  BELIEVE ME, THERE'S GENIUS EVERYWHERE, BUT UNTIL THEY TURN PRO...
IT'S LIKE POPCORN IN THE PAN; SOME POP--
WHAT THE HECK, COACH? YOU DON'T KNOW DIDDLY-SQUAT ABOUT GOLF!
[ Man ] SOME DON'T. YOU LITTLE SHIT!
I'M THE GUY YOU DON'T USUALLY SEE.
I'M THE ONE BEHIND THE SCENES.
I'M THE SPORTS AGENT. WAYNE, I'M GONNA HURT YOU THIS YEAR.
HOW'RE YOU DOIN'? I'M DOIN' FINE.
LISTEN, DOOR'S ALWAYS OPEN IF YOU WANNA COME AND GET A REAL AGENT.
THANKS. YOU'RE WELCOME, JOHNNIE.
I'M GONNA GO TO A MEETING NOW, AND I'M GONNA TALK ABOUT YOU.
'CAUSE I KILL FOR YOU. I'M AN ANIMAL FOR YOU.
WE GOTTA WIN SUPER BOWLS. I HAIL YOU.
HEY, JERRY, HOW'RE YOU DOIN'? ALL RIGHT.
[ Man ] HOW MUCH IS THIS GONNA COST ME?
YOU AND I BOTH KNOW THERE'S A NUMBER YOU CAN AFFORD.
SO I'M JUST GONNA WRITE IT DOWN, AND WE CAN MOVE FORWARD FROM THERE.
I CAN'T AFFORD THAT. NO ONE SAID WINNING WAS CHEAP.
[ Camera Shutter Clicks ] YOU KNOW THOSE PHOTOS...
WHERE THE NEW PLAYER HOLDS THE TEAM JERSEY AND POSES WITH THE OWNER?
THAT'S ME ON THE LEFT.
INSIDE THAT BUILDING, THAT'S WHERE I WORK.
S.M.I.-- SPORTS MANAGEMENT INTERNATIONAL.
REEBOK CAME IN WITH FOUR MILLION.
[ Continues ] 33 OUT-OF-SHAPE AGENTS GUIDING THE CAREERS OF 1,685...
OF THE MOST FINELY TUNED ATHLETES ALIVE.
- YOU GOTTA BE TOUGH. - I ALREADY HAVE 18 MILLION.
I HANDLE THE LIVES AND DREAMS OF 72 CLIENTS AND GET AN AVERAGE OF 216 PHONE CALLS A DAY.
IT'S WHAT I DO.
I WILL NOT REST UNTIL I HAVE YOU HOLDING A COKE, WEARING YOUR OWN SHOE, PLAYING A SEGA GAME...
WHILE SINGING YOUR OWN SONG IN A NEW COMMERCIAL STARRING YOU,
BROADCAST DURING THE SUPER BOWL IN A GAME YOU ARE WINNING.
I WILL NOT SLEEP UNTIL THAT HAPPENS.
IT'S WHAT I DO BEST. I'LL GIVE YOU 15 MINUTES TO CALL ME BACK.
[ Siren Wails ] I'LL BE HONEST WITH YOU.
I STARTED NOTICING IT A FEW YEARS AGO AND DIDN'T SAY A WORD.
[ Female Reporter ] WAS THE GIRL 16 OR 17?
IN THE QUEST FOR THE BIG DOLLARS, A LOT OF LITTLE THINGS WERE GOING WRONG.
THERE'S NO PROOF OF ANYTHING EXCEPT THIS GUY IS A SENSATIONAL ATHLETE!
THERE WAS NO GIRL! THAT'S BULLSHIT!
ARE YOU CALVIN NACK? CAN YOU SIGN MY CARD?
I'M SORRY, LITTLE FELLA. I CAN'T SIGN THIS PARTICULAR BRAND OF CARD.
ONLY PRO-JAM BLUE DOT CARDS.
I JUST WANTED AN AUTOGRAPH.
LATELY, IT'S GOTTEN WORSE.
[ Sportscaster ] REMO WITH THE PUCK, AND-- OH, HE GOES DOWN!
HI, BABY.
DO YOU KNOW YOUR NAME? UH--
[ Whispers ] STEVE REMO. UH--
[ Wife ] STEVEN REMO. OH, WAIT.  IT'S COMING.
MY NAME IS STEVE REMO. YEAH.
I PLAY FOR CHICAGO. THIS LADY HERE IS MY WIFE.
[ Chuckles ] HI, BABY.
AND THIS IS MY BOY,  AND THIS IS, UH,
UH, UH, WAIT.
MY AGENT.  MY AGENT.
I GOTTA PLAY THIS WEEKEND. IF I PLAY 65% OF MY GAMES, I GET A BONUS.
I GOTTA GET THE BONUS.
OKAY, JESSE. YOU TAKE CARE, LITTLE GUY.
MR. MAGUIRE? YEAH?
THIS IS HIS FOURTH CONCUSSION. SHOULDN'TSOMEBODY GET HIM TO STOP?
- [ Beeper Beeping ]  - IT WOULD TAKE A TANK    TO STOP YOUR DAD.
IT WOULD TAKE ALL FIVE SUPER TROOPER VR WARRIORS...
TO STOP YOUR DAD.
RIGHT?
FUCK YOU.
[ Continues ] WHO HAD I BECOME? JUST ANOTHER SHARK IN A SUIT?
[ Man Talking,   Indistinct ]
WITH THE SKYROCKETING SALARIES, AND YOU ARE ONE OF THE GUYS RESPONSIBLE.
[ Jesse's Voice ] FUCK YOU.
[ Voices Overlapping ]
[ Jerry Continues ] TWO DAYS LATER AT OUR CORPORATE CONFERENCE IN MIAMI,
A BREAKTHROUGH. [ Man ]  I ALREADY HAD 18 MILLION ON THE TABLE.
BREAKDOWN? BREAKTHROUGH.
[ Boy ] I JUST WANT AN AUTOGRAPH. [ Jesse ]  FUCK YOU.
[ Doctor ] DO YOU KNOW YOUR NAME?
[ Jerry ] I COULDN'T ESCAPE ONE SIMPLE THOUGHT.
I HATED MYSELF.
NO, NO, NO. HERE'S WHAT IT WAS.
I HATED MY PLACE IN THE WORLD.
I HAD SO MUCH TO SAY AND NO ONE TO LISTEN.
[ Typing, Beeps ]
AND THEN IT HAPPENED.
IT WAS THE ODDEST, MOST UNEXPECTED THING.
I BEGAN WRITING WHAT THEY CALL "A MISSION STATEMENT."
NOT A MEMO, A MISSION STATEMENT.
YOU KNOW, A SUGGESTION FOR THE FUTURE OF OUR COMPANY.
A NIGHT LIKE THIS DOESN'T COME ALONG VERY OFTEN.
I SEIZED IT.
WHAT STARTED OUT AS 1 PAGE BECAME 25.
SUDDENLY, I WAS MY FATHER'S SON AGAIN.
I WAS REMEMBERING THE SIMPLE PLEASURES OF THIS JOB--
HOW I ENDED UP HERE OUT OF LAW SCHOOL;
THE WAY A STADIUM SOUNDS WHEN ONE OF MY PLAYERS PERFORMS WELL ON THE FIELD;
THE WAY WE ARE MEANT TO PROTECT THEM IN HEALTH AND IN INJURY.
WITH SO MANY CLIENTS, WE HAD FORGOTTEN WHAT WAS IMPORTANT.
I WROTE AND WROTE AND WROTE AND WROTE,
AND I'M NOT EVEN A WRITER.
I WAS REMEMBERING EVEN THE WORDS OF THE ORIGINAL SPORTS AGENT, MY MENTOR,
THE LATE, GREAT DICKY FOX, WHO SAID--
THE KEY TO THIS BUSINESS IS PERSONAL RELATIONSHIPS.
[ Jerry ] SUDDENLY IT WAS ALL PRETTY CLEAR.
THE ANSWER WAS: FEWER CLIENTS.
LESS MONEY. MORE ATTENTION.
CARING FOR THEM, CARING FOR OURSELVES AND THE GAMES TOO.
JUST STARTING OUR LIVES, REALLY.
I'LL BE FIRST TO ADMIT IT. WHAT I WAS WRITING WAS SOMEWHAT TOUCHY-FEELY.
I DIDN'T CARE. I HAD LOST THE ABILITY TO BULLSHIT.
IT WAS THE ME I'D ALWAYS WANTED TO BE.
I TOOK IT IN A BAG TO A COPYMAT IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT...
AND PRINTED UP 110 COPIES.
EVEN THE COVER LOOKED LIKE THE CATCHER IN THE RYE.
I ENTITLED IT, THE THINGS WE THINK AND DO NOT SAY:
THE FUTURE OF OUR BUSINESS.
THAT'S HOW YOU BECOME GREAT, MAN.
HANG YOUR BALLS OUT THERE.
THANKS.
EVERYBODY GOT A COPY.
THERE ARE DANGEROUS ANIMALS IN THE WORLD. SOME WALK ON TWO FEET.
THEY DON'T WANT PEACE. THEY'RE NOT CAPABLE OF LOVE.
SOCIETY-- AND THAT MEANS YOU AND YOU-- NEED PROTECTION FROM THESE WARPED MINDS.
???? [ TV ]
BOOM.
HI, THIS IS JERRY MAGUIRE. DID THOSE MANUSCRIPTS GET--
[ Man ] THEY'VE ALL GONE OUT. OH, THEY DID?
WOULD YOU LIKE ME-- OH, NO, NO. THAT'S FINE.
THANK YOU.
[ Phones Ringing ] I COULD CONNECT YOU, IF YOU'D LIKE.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
[ People Chattering,   Phone Ringing ]
[ Man ] FRONT DESK. HOW MAY I HELP YOU?
ALL RIGHT! HEY, FINALLY SOMEBODY SANE.
[ Man ] GOOD WORK, MAGUIRE! [ Man ]  YEAH, YEAH!
YEAH! [ Cheering ]
[ Man ] UNBELIEVABLE. UNBELIEVABLE.
[ Cheering Continues ]
OH, YEAH.
[ Sighs ] [ Jerry ] I WAS 35.
I'D STARTED MY LIFE.
HOW LONG DO YOU GIVE HIM?
'BOUT A WEEK.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Cheering Continues,   Whooping ] [ Sighs ]
YOU'RE WITH THE SPORTS PEOPLE ON THE PLANE? YEAH, I'M JERRY MAGUIRE.
S.M.I. BOBBI FALLON, B.P.I.
I'M PRODUCING THE COKE COMMERCIALS FOR THE PLAY-OFFS.
GOOD LUCK WITH THAT. [ Chuckles ]
[ Baby Crying ] OH, HI.  HI.
MY SON IS REALLY ALLERGIC TO THE MATERIAL IN THE BLANKETS,
AND I WAS WONDERING-- THAT'S ALL WE HAVE, OKAY?
[ Coughing ] [ Gasps ]
- [ Coughing Continues ] - [ Both ]  OHH!
I'M SORRY IF I WAS RUDE JUST THEN.
THAT'S OKAY.  WE'RE IN IT TOGETHER NOW.
WHY IS IT SO EASY TO TALK WITH YOU? TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FIANCEE.
MORE CHAMPAGNE? I DON'T THINK WE'RE AT YOUR PITCH YET.
TELL ME HOW YOU PROPOSED. HONEY, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT? YOU WANT SOME JUICE?
[ Baby Continues Crying ]
THANK YOU. BUT WE'RE HIKING UP THROUGH THE POOLS.
I GOT THE RING IN MY POCKET, AND--  [ Laughs ] I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS.
I'M LAGGING, YOU KNOW, AND SHE SAYS TO ME-- GET THIS--
"HURRY UP, KLUTZ."
IT BOTHERED ME SOMEWHAT, YOU KNOW?
I GOT QUIET AND SHE GOT QUIET.
AND I DECIDE, I'M NOT GONNA PROPOSE.
THE MOOD IS NOT RIGHT. WHY BE IMPULSIVE?
NOW, AT THIS POINT I KNOW SHE KNOWS...
THAT I WAS GONNA PROPOSE AND DIDN'T, AND SHE KNOWS I KNOW.
SO WE CHECK BACK INTO THE PRO BOWL HOTEL. HOW SAD.
NO.  BUT WAIT. LITTLE DO I KNOW...
THAT MY ASSISTANT HAS ASSUMED  THAT I'VE NOW PROPOSED.
SO SHE'S GOTTEN A LOUNGE BAND TO ACTUALLY PLAY "HERE COMES THE BRIDE"...
WHEN WE WALK BACK IN. I LOVE THAT SONG.
ALL THE FOOTBALL GUYS ARE IN THE LOBBY, WATCHING.
THERE'S EVEN AN ESPN CREW.
SO I TURNED TO HER, SORT OF GRANDLY SAY,
"WELL, THIS IS ME, KLUTZ,
ASKING YOU, GODDESS OF ROCK CLIMBING, TO MARRY ME."
I TOOK OUT THE RING.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T MUCH LIKE BIG SCENES,
BUT, UH,
SHE SAID "YES" RIGHT THERE IN THE LOBBY.
SOME OF THE TOUGHEST MEN IN FOOTBALL WEPT LIKE BABIES.
WE'RE GETTIN' MARRIED IN FEBRUARY.
[ Woman ] OH, JERRY, YOU TWO ARE GONNA BE MARRIED FOREVER.
[ Baby Crying Continues ]
WHAT'S WRONG, MOM?
FIRST CLASS IS WHAT'S WRONG, HONEY.
IT USED TO BE A BETTER MEAL. NOW IT'S A BETTER LIFE.
[ P.A. Announcer ] MR. WATERS, MR. CHARLES WATERS, RAY!
YOUR PARTY IS WAITING FOR YOU AT THE INFORMATION GATE... RAY!
ON THE UPPER CONCOURSE. COME ON, BUDDY!
HIGH FIVE! RAY!
OH, GOD.  RAY! EXCUSE ME.
CAN I HELP YOU?
JERRY MAGUIRE.
I WORK IN YOUR OFFICE.  I WAS ON THE JUNKET.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE. DOROTHY BOYD IN ACCOUNTS.
YOU HAVE THE SIDE-MIDDLE CUBICLE WITH THE POSTER OF ALBERT EINSTEIN'S FACE...
MORPHED ON SHAQUILLE O'NEAL'S BODY.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
WH-WHAT DID YOU LOSE HERE?
MY SON, MY MIND. [ Moans ]  RAY!
RAY!
- LISTEN, WHILE I LOOK--   DOROTHY? - HUH?
WHILE I GO LOOK FOR HIM, WHY DON'T YOU GRAB THIS CURIOUS GENTLEMAN HERE?
- HEE-HEE! - OH.  OH, THANK GOD.
OH.  OHH!
YOU SCARED ME.  YOU SCARED ME.
DON'T DO THAT AGAIN, EVER! OKAY, MOMMY.
EVER, EVER,EVER! OKAY?  EVER!
DOROTHY?  TAKE CARE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
I LOVED YOUR MEMO,
BY THE WAY.
- YOU DID? - YEAH.
THANKS.
UH, ACTUALLY IT WAS JUST A MISSION... STATEMENT.
I THINK, IN THIS AGE, OPTIMISM LIKE THAT IS A REVOLUTIONARY ACT.
- YOU THINK SO? - OH, YEAH.
I APPRECIATE THAT BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW IF I SHOULD WRITE IT.
I MEAN, IT WAS 2:00 IN THE MORNING.
I DON'T KNOW. SOME OF THE STUFF, I JUST-- WHOO!
NO.  THAT PART ABOUT HOW WE SHOULD EMBRACE WHAT IS STILL VIRGINAL IN OUR ENTHUSIASM--
UH-- NOT RIGHT NOW, HONEY.
AND FORCE OPEN THE TIGHTLY CLENCHED FIST OF COMMERCE AND GIVE A LITTLE BACK...
- FOR THE GREATER GOOD? - UH-HUH.
GOD, I WAS INSPIRED, AND I'M AN ACCOUNTANT, YOU KNOW?
- ONE, TWO, THREE, SWING! - I MEAN, TO RESPECT YOURSELF   ENOUGH TO SAY IT OUT LOUD?
TO PUT YOURSELF OUT THERE LIKE THAT, SO OPENLY, SO NAKEDLY?
I DON'T KNOW. IT GOT ME. SWING!  WHOO!
SWING! IS THIS BOTHERING YOU?
- WHOO! - NO, THIS IS, UH, GREAT.
WHOO! TH-THIS IS GREAT.
ONE, TWO, THREE, SWING!
DO YOU NEED A RIDE? ARE YOU OKAY? WHAT?
- DO YOU NEED A LIFT? - OH, NO.
OH.  [ Laughing ] YEAH, I'M SURE THAT WOULD JUST MAKE YOUR DAY.
TO DRIVE US ALL THE WAY OUT TO MANHATTAN BEACH, MAKING THAT LEFT ON TINY WATERLOO STREET,
PLAYING CHICKEN WITH TRAFFIC, YOUR LIFE FLASHING BEFORE YOUR EYES.
I'VE OBVIOUSLY HAD TOO MUCH COFFEE, HUH? [ Laughing ]
IT'S NO PROBLEM. UH, UM, OH,
THERE'S MY SISTER LAUREL TO PICK US UP.
THANKS. SURE.
RAY,
DOROTHY,
A PLEASURE.
BYE.
[ P.A. Announcer ] RACHEL ADAMS, PLEASE PICK UP THE WHITE COURTESY PHONE.
- HEY, RAY.  HEY, YOU.   I'M DOUBLE PARKED.  LET'S GO. - HI, AUNT LAUREL.
OH, SORRY, HONEY. IS THIS EVERYTHING?
THESE THREE? COME HERE. LET ME SEE YOU.
DOROTHY?
MAN, WHOEVER SNAGGED HIM MUST BE SOME CLASSY BABE.
[ Panting ]
DON'T... EVER... STOP... FUCKING ME!
[ Moaning ] SOONER OR LATER, I WILL HAVE TO STOP.
OH! NEVER BEEN BETTER! [ Grunts ]
NEVER BETTER!
NEVER BETTER! [ Screams ]
OHH!  OH. [ Sighs ]
OPEN YOUR EYES.
IF YOU EVER WANT ME TO BE WITH ANOTHER WOMAN FOR YOU,
I WOULD DO IT.
I'M NOT INTERESTED IN IT. THERE WAS A TIME, YES, IT FELT NORMAL FOR ME.
BUT IT WAS A PHASE, A COLLEGE THING,
LIKE TORN LEVI'S OR LAW SCHOOL FOR YOU.
WANT ANYTHING FROM THE KITCHEN? I'M GONNA GET SOME FRUIT.
[ Sighs ]
I DON'T THINK WE NEED TO DO THE THING WHERE WE TELL EACH OTHER EVERYTHING.
JERRY, THIS IS WHAT INTIMACY IS.
OH, DON'T FORGET-- TOMORROW WE HAVE DINNER WITH WADE COOKSEY.
I KNOW ABOUT THE BACHELOR PARTY.
YOUR BUDDY DOOLER WORKED HIS ASS OFF TO MAKE YOU A TRIBUTE FILM.
ALL THOSE GUYS FROM THE OFFICE ARE COMING. EVERYBODY LOVES YOU.
JUST CALM DOWN, RELAX, ACT SURPRISED...
AND HAVE AN AMAZING TIME.
OHH, NO! [ All Shouting ]
OH!  OH!
[ All Laughing ] OH, MY GOD. ALL RIGHT.
YOU!  YOU! SORRY.
CONGRATULATIONS, JERRY!
- JERRY! - GOT YOU, MAN!
ETHAN VALHERE. HEY.
- OLD COLLEGE BUDDY,    CONGRATULATIONS. - THANK YOU.
FOR YOU. THANK YOU.
AND THIS IS FOR YOU, THE FINEST CIGAR...
MY CLUB HAS TO OFFER.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT, MAN.
EVERYBODY LOVES YOU.
PISSES ME OFF.
WHETHER YOU'RE COUNTRY, REDNECK OR A FREAK,
YOUNG OR OLD,
FROM MOSCOW, LONDON OR MEMPHIS,
[ Woman's Voice ] JERRY MAGUIRE...
[ Normal Voice ] WILL STILL BE THE KING OF ROCK AND ROLL TO ME.
JERRY, JERRY, JERRY. LITTLE BLACK BOOK.
WHEN I THINK ABOUT JERRY, MY HEART STARTS POUNDING.
- OH. - I KNOW JERRY PRETTY WELL.
- [ People Laughing ] - HI, JERRY.  REMEMBER ME?
WE'RE STILL ON FOR LUNCH TOMORROW? YEAH.
- HE WAS NO SLOUCH IN BED. - THIS IS THE FUNNIEST THING   I'VE EVER SEEN IN MY LIFE.
- YOU GUYS ARE CRAZY.   I'LL SEE YOU LATER. - IT'S PROBABLY A GOOD IDEA...
THAT JERRY GET MARRIED; HE WON'T BE ALONE.
- HE CANNOT BE ALONE. - HE-HE CAN'T BE ALONE.
- HE'S ALMOST PHOBIC. - JERRY IS GREAT AT FRIENDSHIP.
HE'S JUST REALLY BAD AT INTIMACY.
[ Women's Voices ] HE CAN'T BE ALONE. HE CAN'T BE ALONE.
- HE CAN'T SAY "I LOVE YOU." - ARE YOU LISTENING, JERRY?
LIES, LIES, LIES. HE'S AN AGENT.  HE LIES.
- I LOVE YOU TOO. - HEY, LOVE YOU TOO.
LOVE YOU TOO. LOVE YOU, JERRY.
- I LOVE YOU, MAN. - [ Woman ]  I LOVE YOU.
?? GOT A POCKETFUL   OF RAINBOWS??
- I LOVE YOU. - I LOVE YOU.
[ Kisses ]
?? MR. HEARTACHE??
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]?? I FOUND A WAY   TO MAKE YOU WEEP????
GOOD MORNING, JENNY. SORRY I MISSED THE BACHELOR PARTY.
GOOD MORNING, JERRY. MARCEE'S ALREADY IN YOUR OFFICE AND SHE'S LATE...
FOR HER PLANE BACK TO PHOENIX. THANK YOU, WENDY.
- MARCEE. - JERRY, I'M GLAD TO SEE   YOU FINALLY MADE IT.
ROD IS VERY, VERY UPSET. TYSON! [ Child Roars ]
NO. OKAY, MOMMY.
- TYSON, HELLO. - HELLO, JERRY.   LONG TIME NO SEE!
WHAT DID I SAY, TYSON? HOW CAN I MAKE YOUR LIFE BETTER?
JERRY, THIS IS HUMILIATING, AND I'M PREGNANT AND I'M INCAPABLE OF BULLSHIT.
- WHERE IS OUR OFFER   FROM ARIZONA? - CRONIN'S OKAY FOR LUNCH?
THIS IS ONE OF OUR AGENTS, BOB SUGAR.  HE NEEDS TO LEARN TO KNOCK. PLEASURE.
YOU'VE CALLED OUR HOUSE, RIGHT?
I-I'M SORRY TO INTERRUPT YOU GUYS.
NOW, I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU DO FOR YOUR FOUR PERCENT,
BUT THIS MAN, MY HUSBAND, HAS A WHOLE PLAN, AN IMAGE.
WHEN YOU PUT HIM IN A WATERBED WAREHOUSE COMMERCIAL, YOU'RE MAKING HIM COMMON,
WHEN YOU KNOW WE DESERVE THE BIG FOUR-- SHOE, CAR, CLOTHING LINE, SOFT DRINK.
I KNOW ABOUT THE FOUR JEWELS OF THE CELEBRITY ENDORSEMENT DOLLAR.
- WOW. - I MAJORED IN MARKETING, BABY,   AND SO DID MY HUSBAND.
- WE CAME TO PLAY. - [ Loud Crash ]
THE DIRTY MAN IS BACK! HA, HA, HA, HA!
[ People Chattering ]
HEY. HEY, BUDDY.
YOU OKAY?
- FINE.  WHAT'S UP? - CAME HERE TO LET YOU GO.
- PARDON ME? - I CAME HERE TO FIRE YOU,   JERRY.
IT'S REAL. YOU SHOULD SAY SOMETHING.
IT WAS THE FUNNIEST STORY. [ Laughing ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Group ]?? HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU?? OH, SHIT.
?? HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU??
A CROWDED RESTAURANT, SO THERE WON'T BE A SCENE.
?? HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU????
[ People Whooping,   Cheering ]
YOU... UNGRATEFUL, UNCTUOUS--
YOU DID THIS TO YOURSELF. YOU SAID "FEWER CLIENTS." YOU PUT IT DOWN ON PAPER.
JESUS CHRIST! WHAT ABOUT ME?
YOU KNOW WHAT I WENT THROUGH, KNOWING I WAS GONNA HAVE TO FIRE MY MENTOR?
CARRYING THAT AROUND IN MY HEAD FOR A WEEK? COULD YOU GET PAST YOURSELF?
- YOU'LL LOSE. - YOU WANTED SMALLER.
OH, I'M OVER IT. NOW I WANT ALL MY CLIENTS AND YOURS TOO.
WHATEVER.
- [ Phone Beeping ] - [ Busy Signal Beeping ]
[ Grunts ]
WENDY, BRING ME MY NUMBERS.
[ Phone Beeping ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Busy Signal Beeping ]
[ Rings ]
THIS IS CUSH. CUSH!  IT'S SUGAR.
LOOK, I'M CALLING YOU FIRST'CAUSE YOU'RE THE MOST IMPORTANT GUY IN SPORTS.
I WANNA KNOW ONE THING: HOW DOES THAT FEEL, TO BE A LEGEND?
I JUST WANT TO PLAY FOOTBALL. IT'S ABOUT TO GET BETTER.
DAD!  IT'S ONE OF THE AGENTS.
WENDY, CUSHMAN'S LINE IS BUSY. YOU KEEP CALLING HIM'TIL YOU GET THROUGH.
AND PLEASE BRING ME MY NUMBERS!
J.J., WHAT'S UP, KID? YEAH, BOY.  HAVE YOU TALKED TO MAGUIRE?
HOMEBOY HAD A MELTDOWN OR SOMETHING.
I WANTED TO TELL YOU I WAS TALKIN' TO DORITOS ABOUT YOU, AND THEY'RE VERY INTERESTED.
MARTINEZ. HOLD ON. TALK TO RICK, OKAY?
MARTINEZ,HOMBRE. ¿¿ COMO ESTA?
CARLO, RIGHT NOW YOU'RE PAYING 25% OF YOUR ENDORSEMENTS TO S.M.I.
I WOULD CUT MY COMMISSION BY SEVEN PERCENT.
I DON'T WANNA SAY IT WAS DRUG-INDUCED, BUT THE GUY COMPLETELY FREAKED OUT.
YOU WANT A GUY LIKE THAT REPRESENTING YOU GOING INTO THE DRAFT?
I'VE SAID MY PIECE. HOW'S YOUR MOM?
I'M GONNA MAKE THIS DECISION EASY FOR YOU, OKAY?
JUST WHAT DOES YOUR HEART TELL YOU?
I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
[ Phone Ringing ] I CAN'T BELIEVE THEY FIRED HIM.
HE'S GONE.
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
THEY FIRED JERRY MAGUIRE. DID IT AT CRONIN'S.
S.M.I. THIS IS CLEO.
HEY. LISTEN TO ME. S.M.I. REPRESENTS--
I THINK YOU'RE MAKING A BIG MISTAKE. THAT'S HOW I FEEL.
I'M CONCERNED ABOUT YOUR FAMILY, YOUR FUTURE.
IF YOU STAY HERE, I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
JERRY, I'M SORRY. I HAVE A LONGSTANDING RELATIONSHIP WITH S.M.I.
DO YOU THINK MAGUIRE KNOWS WHAT IT'S LIKE TO BE A BLACK GUY?
BOB SUGAR? HE'S, UH, HE'S A--
HE'S AN ENTERTAINING, FUNNY--
HE SAID I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO BE A BLACK PERSON? I'M MR. BLACK PEOPLE!
[ Laughs ] LIKE I SAY, I MEAN, DON'T MAKE IT HARDER THAN IT IS.
I'VE GOT TO BE HONEST WITH YOU. THIS IS VERY PERSONALLY DISTRESSING FOR ME.
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU SINCE WE WERE WITH THAT STRIPPER IN LAGUNA BEACH.
YOU REMEMBER HER NAME? I DO.  IT WAS APRIL.
THAT'S MY JOB-- TO REMEMBER THE NAMES OF SCANKS YOU BANG ON THE ROAD.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE MONEY. I DO IT ALL FOR YOU.
HELLO, MERILEE? THIS IS JERRY MAGUIRE STILL HOLDING FOR KATARINA.
- I'M TALKING ABOUT MONEY.  HO! - I GOTTA TELL YOU.   IT'S BEEN A GREAT DAY.
ARE YOU IN OR OUT? IT'S NOT SHOW FRIENDS. IT'S SHOW BUSINESS.
YOU ARE IN. THAT'S GOOD. HE CAN'T DO SHIT.
JERRY, I WANT TO CRY FOR WHAT THEY DID TO YOU AT S.M.I.
I-IF WE WEREN'T RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF THE ACURA DEAL,
YOU KNOW I'D GO WITH YOU.
OH, JERRY!  OH, GOD! [ Phone Clicks ]
CALL WAITING.  WHO COULD BE CALLING ME NOW?
[ Beeps ] HI!  KATHY SANDERS.
- IT'S STILL ME, KATHY. - [ Wailing ]
[ Kathy Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing ] KATHY! WHY ARE YOU CRYING?
OH.  [ Laughing ] SO YOU'RE IN.
ROD?  ROD, ROD, JERRY MAGUIRE. HOW ARE YOU DOING?
JERRY MAGUIRE! [ Laughing ] HOW ARE YOU DOING?
HOW AM I DOING? I'LL TELL YOU HOW I'M DOING. I'M SWEATING, DUDE!
I'M SWEATING MY CONTRACT.  I'M SWEATING BOB SUGAR...
TELLING ME I'M MISSING THE BIG ENDORSEMENTS BY BEING WITH YOU.
THAT'S HOW I'M DOING. I'M SWEATING! YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
THAT'S WHY I'M CALLING.
NO, I HEAR THAT YOU HEAR WHAT I'M SAYIN', BUT DO YOU TRULY HEAR WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
I HEAR WHAT YOU'RE SAYIN', DADDY.
MAYBE THE BEST THING IS THAT WE GET TOGETHER IN PERSON.
ROD, I'M SORRY. WOULD YOU MIND HOLDING? I JUST GOT SOMEONE.
DIDN'T YOU TELL MY WIFE, "MORE PERSONAL ATTENTION"?
DID YOU NOT TELL MY WIFE, "MORE PERSONAL ATTENTION"?
I SAID, "MORE PERSONAL ATTENTION." GOOD!
YOU GOT EIGHT CALLS. WE'RE GETTING STARTED ON MY LIST OF THINGS YOU NEED TO KNOW!
TAKE NOTES IF YOU WANT TO!
I WILL KILL FOR YOU. I WILL MAIM, RAPE AND PILLAGE FOR YOU.
I AM A VALUABLE COMMODITY!  I GO ACROSS THE MIDDLE!
I SEE A DUDE COMING AT ME, TRYING TO KILL ME,
I TELL MYSELF, "GET KILLED, CATCH THE BALL."
BOO-YA!  TOUCHDOWN! I MAKE MIRACLES HAPPEN!
I NEED TO KNOW-- ARE YOU IN OR OUT?
I'M FROM ARIZONA, JERRY! I BROKE ARIZONA RECORDS! ROD.
I WENT TO ARIZONA STATE. I'M A SUN DEVIL, MAN!
- YOU WANT ARIZONA DOLLARS. - EXACTLY!
I UNDERSTAND. I'M SITTING HERE WITH AN ANT PROBLEM.
I GOT ANTS GOIN' UP AND DOWN MY HALLWAY!
MY BROTHER TEE PEE'S ROOM IS FLOODED WITH-- LOOK AT THIS!
ROD! WE GOT A FLOOD IN TEE PEE'S ROOM!
- SAY HELLO TO JERRY MAGUIRE. - HELLO, BROTHER MAGUIRE.
H-HELLO, TEE PEE. JERRY, MY HOUSE IS FALLIN' APART!
NOBODY'S LOOKING OUT FOR ROD TIDWELL!
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE  WE GONNA LIVE IN A YEAR!
AND I'M SUPPOSED TO BE A SUPERSTAR, MAN!
ROD, I NEED A DECISION FROM YOU. ARE YOU IN OR OUT?
YOU'RE GONNA BE SO HAPPY YOU STAYED WITH BOB SUGAR,'CAUSE I AM THE TERMINATOR!
- I AM A ROLE MODEL, JERRY! - [ Phone Lines Beeping ]
I HAVE A FAMILY TO SUPPORT. HEAR ME?
???? [ R&B ] I WANNA STAY IN ARIZONA.  I WANT MY NEW CONTRACT.
BUT I LIKE YOU. YES, I LIKE YOU, JERRY.
MY WIFE LIKES YOU. YOU'RE GOOD TO MY WIFE.???? [ Louder ]
- I WILL STAY WITH YOU. - THAT'S GREAT.  I'M VERY HAPPY.
ARE YOU LISTENING? YES.
THAT'S WHAT I'M GONNA DO FOR YOU. GOD BLESS YOU, JERRY.
THIS IS WHAT YOU'RE GONNA DO FOR ME. YOU LISTENING?
JERRY? YEAH, WH-WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU, ROD?
JUST TELL ME, WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU? IT'S A VERY PERSONAL,
VERY IMPORTANT THING.
HELL, IT'S A FAMILY MOTTO.
ARE YOU READY? I'M READY.
WANNA MAKE SURE YOU'RE READY.
HERE IT IS.???? [ Volume Down ]
SHOW ME THE MONEY. OH-HO-HO!???? [ Volume Up ]
GO!???? [ Rapping ]
HEY!  HEY!
MONEY! [ Laughing ]
JERRY, DOESN'T THAT MAKE YOU FEEL GOOD JUST TO SAY THAT?
SAY IT WITH ME ONE TIME, JERRY. SHOW YOU THE MONEY.
NO, YOU CAN DO BETTER THAN THAT, JERRY.  SAY IT WITH MEANING, BROTHER!
I GOT BOB SUGAR ON THE OTHER LINE. I BETTER HEAR YOU SAY IT!
- SHOW YOU THE MONEY. - NOT SHOWYOU!   SHOWMETHE MONEY!
SHOW ME THE MONEY. YEAH!  LOUDER!
- SHOW ME THE MONEY. - THAT'S IT, BUT YOU   GOT TO YELL THAT SHIT!
SHOW ME THE MONEY! I NEED TO FEEL YOU, JERRY!
SHOW ME THE MONEY! YOU BETTER YELL!
[ Yelling ] SHOW ME THE MONEY!
SHOW ME THE MONEY!
- DO YOU LOVE THIS BLACK MAN? - I LOVE THIS BLACK MAN!
- I LOVE BLACK PEOPLE! - [ Continues Yelling ]   I LOVE BLACK PEOPLE!
- WHO'S YOUR MOTHERFUCKER? - YOU'RE MY MOTHERFUCKER!
- WHAT YOU GONNA DO, JERRY? - SHOW ME THE MONEY!
UHH!  CONGRATULATIONS. YOU'RE STILL MY AGENT.
[ People Chattering,   Phones Ringing ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
WELL... DON'T WORRY.
[ Chuckling ] DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT GONNA DO WHAT YOU ALL THINK I'M GONNA DO,
WHICH IS JUST FLIP OUT!
LET ME JUST SAY...
AS I... EASE OUT OF THE OFFICE...
I HELPED BUILD--
I'M SORRY, BUT IT'S AFACT!
THAT THERE IS SUCH A THING...
AS MANNERS,
A WAY OF TREATING PEOPLE.
THESE FISH HAVE MANNERS.
IN FACT, THEY'RE COMING WITH ME.
I'M STARTING A NEW COMPANY, AND THE FISH WILL COME WITH ME.
YOU CAN CALL ME SENTIMENTAL.
THE FISH, THEY'RE COMING WITH ME.
[ Water Sloshing ]
COME ON.  COME ON. YOU COME ON.
COME HERE. HOW IS THAT?
OKAY.
IF ANYBODY ELSE...
WANTS TO COME WITH ME,
THIS MOMENT WILL BE THE MOMENT OF SOMETHING REAL...
AND FUN AND INSPIRING...
IN THIS GODFORSAKEN BUSINESS,
AND WE WILL DO IT TOGETHER.
WHO'S COMIN' WITH ME?  WHO'S COMIN' WITH ME?
WHO'S COMING WITH ME? [ Man Coughs ]
WHO'S COMING WITH ME BESIDES FLIPPER HERE?
THIS IS EMBARRASSING.
ALL RIGHT.  WENDY?
- SHALL WE? - AH, JER, I'M--
I'M THREE MONTHS AWAY FROM THE PAY INCREASE.
I--
OKAY.
I WILL GO WITH YOU.
[ People Murmuring ] DOROTHY BOYD, THANK YOU.
[ Whispering ] RIGHT NOW?
DON'T DO IT. SHH!
[ Dorothy ] BYE.
[ Water Sloshing ]
WE'LL SEE YOU ALL AGAIN.
SLEEP TIGHT. BYE.
[ Jerry ] LET'S SEE HOW THEY DO WITHOUT US.
[ Elevator Bell Dings,   Doors Close ]
[ Chattering Resumes,   Phones Ringing ]
I'LL JUST-- OH.  THANK YOU.  IT'S--
I KNOW THIS IS A BAD TIME, BUT YOU WILL HAVE A MEDICAL PROGRAM?
OH, SURE, YES. MEDICAL.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I--
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT WHAT YOU DID THERE, DON'T-- DON'T PANIC.
WE'RE GONNA BE OKAY.  WE'RE GONNA BE GREAT.
WE'RE GONNA BE...GREAT.
[ Bell Dings,   Doors Open ] YES.
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Doors Open ]
[ Doors Close ]
I WONDER WHAT HE SAID.
MY FAVORITE AUNT IS HEARING IMPAIRED.
HE JUST SAID, "YOU COMPLETE ME."
[ Women Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Woman ] WE'VE ALL GOT A PROBLEM.
WE'RE ALL STUCK IN SOME KIND OF PATTERN.
IT'S TRUE. I THINK HE WAS MAKING AN EXCELLENT POINT.
FIRST OF ALL, WE HAVE COME HERE TO SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER...
AND WE DON'T EVEN LISTEN TO ONE ANOTHER.
WOMEN ARE-- ARE TAUGHT NOT TO SEE EACH OTHER AS GOOD PEOPLE.
WE SEE EACH OTHER AS THE ENEMY. WE'RE COMPETITION FOR MEN. WE'RE COMPETITION FOR--
IT'S TRUE.  WE ARE-- WE HAVE THIS TERRIBLE COMPETITION GOING ON.
I REALLY HATED WOMEN.
AND THEN I MET YOU GUYS,  AND YOU'RE LIKE ME.
AND IT'S IMPORTANT BECAUSE I KNOW YOU CAN BE MY FRIENDS.
WHAT ABOUT MEDICAL? OF COURSE, MEDICAL.
YOU ARE A SINGLE MOTHER. YOU HAVE GIVEN UP THE RIGHT TO BE FRIVOLOUS.
IF YOU HAD READ WHAT HE WROTE, YOU WOULD HAVE LEFT WITH HIM TOO.
AND I CAN ALWAYS TAKE THAT JOB IN SAN DIEGO.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MUCH THOSE WELL-CHILD EXAMS COST? OF COURSE.
[ Both ] A HUNDRED AND FIFTY DOLLARS.
- THAT'S JUST WHEN HE'S WELL. - WAIT.  WHERE IS RAY?
ASLEEP IN THE LIVING ROOM. THAT'S WONDERFUL.
THE NEXT TIME YOU DECIDE TO LECTURE ME,
DON'T LEAVE MY LITTLE BOY IN THAT ROOM WITH THAT DIVORCED WOMEN'S GROUP.
SO I FINALLY, FINALLY GOT IN TOUCH WITH MY ANGER!
[ All Cheering ] YOU GO, ALICE!
[ Cheering, Laughing   Continue ]
WHAT'S HER PROBLEM? SHE QUIT HER JOB TODAY.
MY GOD.  WHAT DID I DO?
FUNCTION, FUNCTION,  FUNCTION.
FORWARD MOTION IS EVERYTHING.
CUSH SAVES ALL.
YOU GO TO TEXAS. YOU KEEP ONE SUPERSTAR, AND THEY'LL ALL FOLLOW.
THERE'S NO REAL LOYALTY. NONE.
THE FIRST PERSON WHO TOLD ME THAT, JERRY MAGUIRE, WAS YOU.
I THINK I WAS TRYING TO SLEEP WITH YOU AT THE TIME. WELL, IT WORKED.
I WILL NOT LET YOU FAIL.
YOU ARE JERRY MA-FUCKING-GUIRE.
THAT'S RIGHT. KING OF THE HOUSE CALLS. MASTER OF THE LIVING ROOM.
OKAY, OKAY. THIS IS WORKING. THIS IS WORKING.
YOU ARE NOT A LOSER.
WHO SAID ANYTHING ABOUT LOSER?
MISTAKE. I MEANT SOMETHING ELSE. WHEN DO YOU WANT TO LEAVE?
[ Airplane Engines   Roaring ]
[ Footsteps ]
MATT? I'M IN THE BACK DEN, JER.
HEY, YOU LIKE A BLOODY BEER, JERRY? I'M FINE.
BEER AND TOMATO JUICE. HUH?
I'M FINE.
LISTEN, I'M HERE TODAY. WE SPENT A LOT OF TIME TOGETHER, MATT.
YOU KNOW HOW MUCH I CARE ABOUT YOU, YOUR SON.  YOU KNOW I'M A STRAIGHT SHOOTER.
I'M QUITE CONCERNED, BECAUSE IF YOU STAY WITH S.M.I.,
YOUR SON-- WE DECIDED TO STAY WITH YOU.
[ Laughs ] OH.
OKAY.
I'M NOT REALLY A HUGGER, YET... I CAN'T LET GO.
[ Laughing ] I TOLD MYSELF,
"HE SHOWS UP,  WE STICK WITH HIM."
- [ Laughing ] - [ Matt ]   HEY!
- HEY, JERRY.   HOW'S IT GOING? - HEY!  CUSH.
HOW ARE YOU, CUSH?  HOW ARE YOU?
REMEMBER KEITH? YEAH, KEITH. HOW'RE YOU DOIN'?
I WANT HIM TO GO NUMBER ONE IN THE DRAFT, AND I WANT HIM TO PLAY.
IT'LL EITHER BE DENVER OR SAN DIEGO TRADING UP TO TAKE HIM.
- HE'LL GO NUMBER ONE. - I'LL EITHER SURF OR SKI.   I DON'T CARE.
- DENVER'S WHERE HE SHOULD BE. - I'LL GIVE IT EVERYTHING.
YOU KNOW I DON'T DO CONTRACTS.
BUT WHAT YOU DO HAVE IS MY WORD,
AND IT'S STRONGER THAN OAK.
???? [ "Bitch"      By Rolling Stones ]
?? I WAS SO--???? I WAS SO TIRED??
?? CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT???? CAN'T--????
?? JUST CALL ME ANGEL   OF THE MORNING???? ANGEL--????
[ Country ]?? SHE HAD FAITH   SHE HAD BELIEVERS????
?? BREAKIN' HER HEART   AND I'M FREE???? AND I'M FREE??
[ Singing Along ]?? FREE FALLIN'?? [ Laughs ]
?? YEAH, I'M FREE-EE-EE??
?? FREE FALLIN'?? WHOO!
?? YEAH, I'M FREE??
[ Phone Rings ]
?? FREE FALLIN'???? HELLO?
- DOROTHY?   JERRY MAGUIRE. - HI.
- IS AVERY THERE? - UH, SHE HAD TO FLY   TO ATLANTA.
- SHE HAD A MEETING   AT THE NFL OFFICE. - THE PLAYHOUSE ROCKS.
WAIT.  OH, GOD. JERRY!
HELLO?  HELLO? GO SIT BY CHAD. SORRY.
THAT WAS MY SON AND THE NANNY.
- WHAT ARE THEY ALL DOING   IN OUR OFFICE? - NANNY?
I PREFER "CHILD TECHNICIAN."
DOROTHY?  HELLO? YEAH, I HAD THE CALLS TRANSFERRED TO MY HOUSE...
SO I COULD GO OVER SOME OF YOUR STUFF.
THAT'S FINE. DOROTHY, WE ARE BACK.
WE ARE SO VERY, VERY BACK.
I RE-SIGNED CUSH. WE'RE SET!
I AM SO HAPPY FOR YOU.
HAPPY FORUS! HAPPY FOR US.
OKAY.  HAPPY FOR US.
[ Jerry ] ROD, BEING AT THE DRAFT WITH ME IS A GOOD IDEA.
NOBODY'S SHOWING UP AT MY HOUSE! NO, ROD, GET ON THE PLANE,
MEET US AT THE GATE. WHY NOT?
GOOD. WE'LL SEE YOU THERE. GOD BLESS YOU, JERRY.
AVERY'LL MEET YOU AT THE "B" GATE AT 4:15. DON'T BE LATE.
JERRY, DO YOU KNOW THE HUMAN HEAD WEIGHS EIGHT POUNDS?
DID YOU KNOW THAT TROY AIKMAN, IN ONLY SIX YEARS, HAS PASSED FOR 16,303 YARDS?
DO YOU KNOW BEES AND DOGS CAN SMELL FEAR?
OH, I PUT TIDWELL ON THE SAME FLOOR AT THE MARRIOTT MARQUIS.
HE DOESN'T SMOKE, DOES HE? I DON'T KNOW.
DID YOU KNOW THE CAREER RECORD FOR MOST HITS IS 4,256 BY PETE ROSE,
WHO ISNOT IN THE HALL OF FAME?
DO YOU KNOW THAT MY NEXT DOOR NEIGHBOR HAS THREE RABBITS?
I CAN'T COMPETE WITH THAT.
OKAY.  SO DID WE GO OVER EVERYTHING?  YES? YUP.
BACK ON TUESDAY, RIGHT? [ Sighs ] YEAH.
HEY, RAY, HAVE A GOOD TIME AT SCHOOL.
- WISH ME LUCK. - LUCK!
?? THAT'S THE WAY IT'S GONNA BE   LITTLE DARLIN'??
?? WE'LL BE RIDING ON THE HORSES   YEAH??
?? WAY UP IN THE SKY   LITTLE DARLIN'??
-?? IF YOU FALL, I'LL     PICK YOU UP, PICK YOU UP??? - HEY!  ROD!
HOW'RE YOU DOIN', JERRY? WAI--
CUSH! HOW ARE YOU, MAN? HEY!
[ Cush ] JERRY, WE SHOULD REALLY BE SELLIN' THESE.
THIS IS MY AGENT. YOU MIGHT WANT TO GET HIS AUTOGRAPH.
- MAN, MY HAND'S   GETTING TIRED.  - EXCUSE ME.
- HEY, WHAT'S HAPPENIN'? - ARE YOU HOOTIE?
NO, I AM NOT HOOTIE.
NO, PUNK.
[ All Shouting ] CUSHMAN, WHAT'S IT GONNA BE, SAN DIEGO OR DENVER?
UH, SURF OR SKI?
[ Shouting Continues ]
HE'LL EITHER SURF OR SKI. [ Female Reporter ] GO TO DENVER!
[ Male Reporter ] SAN DIEGO! I'LL EITHER SURF OR SKI.
[ Reporter ] CUSHMAN, RIGHT HERE! HEY!
[ Sighs ]
ROD, AT LAST... I FIND YOU.
WHAT AM I DOING HERE? I FEEL LIKE I'M FIVE YEARS LATE FOR THE PROM.
COME WITH ME. NOBODY GIVES A DAMN ABOUT ME BEING HERE.
WE'RE GONNA GO DOWNSTAIRS AND WALK THROUGH THIS LOBBY.
I WANT EVERY MEDIA GUY, EVERY PLAYER'S REP, EVERYBODY...
TO SEE YOU FOR WHAT YOU ARE--
THE BEST-KEPT SECRET IN THE NFL.
THE MOST COMMANDING WIDE RECEIVER IN THE GAME.
YOU ARE FAST, FIERCE, WILDLY CHARISMATIC.
YOU ARE THE MAN. YOUARE THE MAN.  ARE YOU READY?
LET'S GO.  LET'S WALK.
YOU ARE THE GREATEST, FIERCEST.
YOU ARE THE MAN.
LET'S DO IT.
HI.  HOW'RE YOU DOING? TOM, HOW'S IT GOING?
WHERE'S CUSH? HE'S UPSTAIRS.
IT'S GOOD YOU WERE ABLE TO HANG ONTO CUSHMAN. SAN DIEGO OR DENVER?
WE'LL KNOW TOMORROW. I WANT YOU TO MEET ROD TIDWELL RIGHT NOW.
HOW'RE YOU DOING? 110 RECEPTIONS, 1,550 YARDS LAST YEAR.
HOW ARE YOU? MEET ROD TIDWELL.
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
[ Voices Overlapping ]
GENTLEMEN, I WANT YOU TO MEET ROD TIDWELL. HEY!
110 RECEPTIONS, 1,550 YARDS LAST YEAR. THAT'S RIGHT.
HI, JERRY. ROD, FEELING GOOD?
FEELING GREAT, BABY.
I'M GONNA TALK ABOUT ROD TIDWELL, WHO IS THE FIERCEST WIDE RECEIVER IN THE NFL.
HEY. NICE TO MEET YOU.
I CAME ALL THAT WAY JUST TO WALK THE LOBBY.
YEAH.  MIGHT HAVE EVEN WORKED TOO.
YEAH?  SHIT, LET'S DO THAT SHIT AGAIN.
[ Giggles ] HEY, HEY.
THEY'RE SHOOTING A REEBOK AD DOWN THERE. WHERE ARE MY ENDORSEMENTS?
I DIDN'T GET NO LOVE FROM CHEVY.  I DIDN'T GET NO LOVE FROM PEPSI.
I DIDN'T EVEN GET NO LOVE FROM THAT LITTLE ENERGIZER BUNNY.
I AIN'T GETTING NO LOVE FROM NIKE. ROD.
OBVIOUSLY, I AIN'T GETTING NO LOVE FROM REEBOK.
DID I EVER TELL YOU ABOUT MY REEBOK STORY? ROD.
GOTTA GET BACK TO CUSHMAN. OH, YOU GOTTA GET BACK TO YOUR GOLDEN PAYCHECK.
WAIT JUST-- I'LL BOIL IT DOWN FOR YOU.
FUCK REEBOK. ALL THEY DO IS IGNORE ME.
ALWAYS HAVE.  ALWAYS HAVE.
YOU KNOW WHAT WAS GREAT ABOUT YOU DOWN THERE?
FOR FIVE MINUTES YOU UNLOADED THAT RATHER LARGE CHIP...
THAT RESIDES RIGHT THERE ON YOUR SHOULDER.
YOU LET PEOPLE IN. OHH.
YOU WERE BRILLIANT.
BRILLIANT? BRILLIANT.
REALLY? NOW, TAKE CARE. I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
YOU'RE LOVIN' ME NOW, AREN'T YOU?
I'M NOT ABOUT LOVE. I'M ABOUT SHOWING YOU THE MONEY!
I WAS JUST TESTING YOU, JERRY!
BUT TO HEAR YOU SAY THAT MAKES ME LOVE YOU, BABY!
YOU KNOW? JERRY, COME BACK!
[ Camera Shutters   Clicking ]
- HOW WAS YOUR FLIGHT?  - GOOD.  HOW WAS YOURS?
GOOD. [ Cush ] WHAT SIZE ARE YOU?
TWELVE AND A HALF. GRAB A COUPLE PAIR OF THEM NEW SHOES BY THE DOOR.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Cush ]?? IT'S OKAY TO EAT FISH??
??'CAUSE THEY HAVEN'T GOT   NO FEELINGS??
CUSH?  MATT? WE HAVE A DECISION TO MAKE.
?? SOMETHIN' IN THE WAY????
SAN DIEGO JUST CAME IN WITH A LAST-MINUTE SCENARIO.
- IT'S BIG. - WELL, HE'S GOT TO   GO NUMBER ONE.
HE STILL GOES NUMBER ONE, BUT SAN DIEGO WANTS TO TRADE UP WITH DENVER AND THEY WANT HIM BAD.
WHAT HAPPENED TO DENVER?
THIS STUFF TENDS TO HAPPEN THE NIGHT BEFORE A DRAFT. PEOPLE GET CRAZY.
- SAN DIEGO, MATT-- - [ Phone Rings ]
SAN DIEGO IS CRAZY TO THE TUNE OF 7 YEARS FOR 30, SIGNING BONUS OF 8.
SHOULD I UNPLUG THE PHONE? REPORTERS.  THEY BEEN CALLIN' ALL NIGHT LONG.
BE FRIENDLY AND SAY, "NO COMMENT."  WE'LL TELL THE WORLD IN 12 HOURS.
TALKIN' AND SAYING NOTHING, MAN, IT IS AN ART I HAVE NOT MASTERED.
WELL, THEN LET ME DO IT. [ Ringing Continues ]
IF IT'S FOR YOU, IT'S A PLEASURE.
- [ Low Voice ]   THIS IS CUSH. - HEY.
IT'S SUGAR. IS MAGUIRE THERE? JUST SNIFF IF HE'S THERE.
- [ Sniffs ] - OKAY.  ALL RIGHT, BUDDY,   JUST REMEMBER.
YOU'RE SWIMMIN' WITH THE BIG BOYS NOW. LET YOUR DAD DO THE TALKING.
I'M THE ONE THAT GOT YOU THE DEAL YOU NEEDED.
THIS IS BUSINESS, NOT FRIENDSHIP. YOU GOTTA BE STRONG.
YOU'RE GLOBAL NOW, WORLDWIDE.
OKAY, BUDDY? I'LL SEE YOU LATER. BYE.
[ Chuckles ] NO COMMENT.
[ Hangs Up Receiver ]
[ Chuckles ] HE'S GOT IT ALL WRONG.
HEY, IT'S CUSH ON THE BIG TV AGAIN. I'M SICK OF ME ALREADY.
I GOT "CUSHLASH."?? CUSHLASH??
?? CUSHLASH, CUSHLASH    CUSHLASH, CUSHLASH????
[ Laughs ]
NOW, MATT, BEFORE I GO BACK TO DENVER,
WE SHOULD PUT SOMETHING DOWN ON PAPER.
SOMETHING THAT SAYS, "HEY, I'M WITH JERRY MAGUIRE." NOT RIGHT NOW.
DO I KNOW EVERYTHING THERE IS TO KNOW HERE, MATT?
[ Chuckles ] YOU FELLAS AREN'T TALKING WITH BOB-- BOB SUGAR, ARE YOU?
APPARENTLY, DENVER WANTED TO DEAL WITH HIM INSTEAD OF YOU.
SAID WHO?  SUGAR?
[ Chuckling ] I'M LEARNING AS I GO HERE.
SO YOU EMPOWERED BOB SUGAR TO DEAL WITH DENVER BEHIND MY BACK?
I'M SORRY.  I, UH--
- I LOVE MY SON. -ILOVE YOUR SON.   ILOVEYOUR SON!
I BROUGHT DENVER TO 20 MILLION. DENVER DEALS WITH ME ALL THE TIME!
YOU LISTENED TO SUGAR!
BOB SUGAR, MATT, IS A CHILD.
YOU LET THAT SNAKE IN THE DOOR?
OKAY, HEY, MATT. THIS IS A ROOKIE MISTAKE.
YOU WANT DENVER. I'LL FIX THIS WHOLE THING UP FOR YOU.
YOU DIDN'T SIGN ANYTHING WITH SUGAR, RIGHT?
MATT...
TELL ME YOU DIDN'T SIGN.
TELL ME YOU DIDN'T SIGN,
'CAUSE I'M STILL SORT OF MOVED BY YOUR "MY WORD IS STRONGER THAN OAK" THING.
WE SIGNED AN HOUR AGO.
YOU WERE IN THE LOBBY WITH THE BLACK FELLA.
[ Cush ] I'M SORRY, JERRY. I JUST WANNA PLAY FOOTBALL.
WHAT DO I DO? HOW DO I SPIN THIS?
OH, HONEY, IT'S SPUN.
WHAT DID I DO TO YOU?
IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU, ISN'T IT?  SOOTHEME. SAVEME. LOVEME.
COULD YOU STOP MOVING? I HAVE TO FINISH MY JOB.
EVERYTHING IS ON THE FUCKING RUN WITH US. EVERYTHING!
JERRY, YOU AND I ARE SALESPEOPLE. WE SELL.
IT'S NOT "LOVE ME."  IT'S NOT "TRUST MY HANDSHAKE."
IT'S "MAKE THE SALE," "GET IT SIGNED."
THERE SHOULDN'T BE CONFUSION ABOUT THAT.
JUST JUMP RIGHT INTO MY NIGHTMARE. THE WATER IS WARM.
SO HONESTY IS OUTLAWED HERE? I CAN'T BE HONEST?
- I WOULD PREFER LOYALTY. - WHAT WAS OUR DEAL WHEN WE   FIRST GOT TOGETHER?
BRUTAL TRUTH, REMEMBER?
I THINK YOU ADDED THE "BRUTAL."
JERRY, THERE IS A SENSITIVITY THING THAT SOME PEOPLE HAVE.
I DON'T HAVE IT.  I DON'T CRY AT MOVIES.
I DON'T GUSH OVER BABIES. I DON'T START CELEBRATING CHRISTMAS FIVE MONTHS EARLY!
I DON'T TELL A MAN WHO JUST SCREWED UP BOTH OUR LIVES, "OH, POOR BABY."
THAT'S ME, FOR BETTER OR WORSE.
BUT I DO LOVE YOU.
- AVERY. - NO.
IT'S OVER. DIDN'T HEAR IT.
THERE'S SOMETHING MISSING HERE, DON'T YOU THINK?
- YOU HAVE NEVER BEEN ALONE. - LISTEN TO ME.
- YOU CAN'T BE ALONE. - IT'S OVER.
NO ONE HAS EVER DUMPED ME.
I'M NOT TRYING TO MAKE HISTORY HERE.
I DID THE 23-HOUR NOSE ROUTE TO THE TOP OF EL CAPITAN...
IN 18 HOURS AND 23 MINUTES.
I CAN MAKETHISWORK.
NO.
OH, JERRY.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
I DIDN'T EVER WANT TO HURT YOU.
OH!  OHH!  OHH!
I WON'T LET YOU HURT ME, JERRY.
I'M TOO STRONG FOR YOU. LOSER!
OH, FUCK.
ROLL WITH THE PUNCHES. TOMORROW'S ANOTHER DAY.
TAXI!
YOU LOVIN' ME NOW, AREN'T YOU?
VERY MUCH.  TAXI!
IS IT MY IMAGINATION, OR DIDN'T WE ARRIVE IN A LIMO?
THE QUESTION I HAVE TO SAY IS THIS, AND I HOPE THIS DOESN'T COME OFF...
LIKE I'M A SHRINK. [ Sobs ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
MAN, I'M JUST A BIG DISAPPOINTMENT.
- LOOK AT THIS.  JERRY.  - CAN'T CHANGE IT.
EVERYBODY CRIES ON THIS SHOW. CAN'T CHANGE IT.
YOU MAD YOU TESTED POSITIVE? QUIT DOIN' BLOW!
UPSET ABOUT YOUR BABY GIRL?
WHY'D YOU LEAVE THE MOTHER? I KNEW HER.  SHE WAS ALL RIGHT.
PEOPLE, LIKE THE MEDIA, DON'T UNDERSTAND...
WHAT KIND OF PROBLEMS AND PRESSURES 54 MILLION COME WITH.
THIS IS SOME BULLSHIT. WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' WITH ME, ROD?
[ TV ] BUT I'M STILL POOR IN LIFE.
WHAT? [ Jerry ] DON'T YOU EVEN SEE?
[ TV ] I DON'T HAVE NOTHING! I'M FINISHED.
I AM FUCKED.
TWENTY-FOUR HOURS AGO, MAN, I WASHOT.
NOW... I'M A CAUTIONARY TALE.
SEE THIS JACKET I'M WEARING? YOU LIKE IT?
'CAUSE I DON'T NEED IT, BECAUSE I'M CLOAKED IN FAILURE!
I LOST THE NUMBER-ONE DRAFT PICK THE NIGHT BEFORE THE DRAFT!
WHY?  LET'S RECAP.
BECAUSE A HOCKEY PLAYER'S KID MADE ME FEEL LIKE A SUPERFICIAL JERK.
I HAD TWO SLICES OF BAD PIZZA, WENT TO BED AND GREW A CONSCIENCE!
WELL, BOO-FUCKING-HOO.
[ Groans ]
I GOT A SHELF LIFE OF TEN YEARS, TOPS.
MY NEXT CONTRACT GOTTA BRING ME DOLLARS THAT'LL LAST ME AND MINE A VERY LONG TIME.
I'M OUT OF THIS SPORT IN FIVE YEARS.
WHAT'S MY FAMILY GONNA LIVE ON?  HUH? [ Slurps ]
WHAT YOU GET ME. SO I DON'T WANT TO HEAR YOUR SHIT, JERRY.
I DON'T WANNA HEAR YOUR "NAH, NAH, NAH!
I LOST CUSH, AVERY AND SHIT."
I'LL HAVE ANOTHER DRINK, PLEASE.
ANYBODY ELSE WOULD'VE LEFT YOU BY NOW.
I'M STICKING WITH YOU. I SAID I WOULD.
IF I GOT TO RIDE YOUR ASS LIKE ZORRO, YOU'RE GONNA SHOW ME THE MONEY.
YOUGONNA SHOW ME THE MONEY.
???? [ Headphones: Jazz ] WE TOGETHER ON THIS. KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
WE GONNA BE ONE. UHH!
THE BOTH OF US! YOU KNOW?
OH, MY GOD.
[ Answering Machine ] YOU HAVE NO MESSAGES. [ Beeps ]
[ Phone Beeping,   Ringing ]
HE'S COMING OVER.
- TONIGHT? - HE JUST LOST HIS BEST CLIENT.   I INVITED THE GUY OVER.
DOROTHY, THIS IS NOT A GUY, IT'S A SYNDROME:
EARLY-MIDLIFE-HANGIN'-ON- TO-THE-BOTTOM-RUNG...
DEAR-GOD- DON'T-LET-ME-BE-ALONE...
I'LL-CALL-MY-NEWLY-LONG- SUFFERING-ASSISTANT-WITHOUT- MEDICAL-FOR-COMPANY-SYNDROME.
- IF, KNOWING ALL THAT, YOU   STILL WANT HIM TO COME OVER-- - HONEY, HE'S ENGAGED.
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME IN MY PROFESSIONAL LIFE I'M PART OF SOMETHING I BELIEVE IN.
OKAY.  BUT HE'D BETTER NOT BE GOOD-LOOKING!
[ Doorbell Rings ]
HI.
I'M JERRY MAGUIRE.
OH.  [ Chuckles ] HELLO.
YOU ARE... JUST THE WAY I PICTURED YOU.
I'M HER DISAPPROVING SISTER LAUREL.
HONESTY.
[ Groans ] MMM. THANK YOU.
THANKYOU. [ Chuckles ]
DOROTHY!
DOROTHY! YOUR... BOSS IS HERE.
HELLO.
OH, CAREFUL.
HEY, YOU.
- HI.  THANKS FOR   INVITING ME OVER. - SURE.
WHERE'S, UH--
WHERE'S THE LITTLE GUY?
HE'S SLEEPING. OH, YEAH.  SLEEPING.
I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE HOME.
YOU KNOW, I JUST-- THAT, UH, ALONE THING IS NOT MY, UH, SPECIALTY.
- OH, MY GOD. - OH, YEAH.  OH, MY GOD, UH--
WELL, I BROKE UP WITH AVERY.
[ Chuckling ]
IT'S JUST, UH--
THAT--  GOSH, YOU KNOW, THAT'S TOO BAD.
NO, IT'S-- IT'S BETTER,
BECAUSE WE'RE STILL GONNA BE FRIENDS, AND--
YOU KNOW, IT'S BETTER NOW THAN LATER. SURE.  SURE.
YOU KNOW, I MEAN, I'M--
- I'M DYIN' HERE, AREN'T I? - YEAH, IT'S A REALLY BAD CUT.
WELL, JUST THINK IF I'D GOT HER THE RING SHEREALLYWANTED.
[ Laughing ]
- YEAH. - WHY DON'T YOU HAVE A SEAT.
YEAH. I'LL, UH--
I'LL GET SOME ALOE VERA FOR THAT CUT. [ Toy Squeaks ]
- DO YOU HAVE SOMETHING   TO DRINK? - SURE.
- I HEARD. - NO KIDDING.
I LOOKED OVER AND SAW THE SHADOW OF TWO CURIOUS SHOES IN THE DOORWAY OF THE KITCHEN.
THIS GUY WOULD GO HOME WITH A GARDENING TOOL RIGHT NOW, IF IT SHOWED INTEREST.
DON'T USE THOSE. USE THE FROSTED GLASSES.
THANK YOU. YOU'RE WELCOME.
I WARMED UP SOME OF THAT CHICKEN WITH SALSA FOR YOU. OHH, THAT'S THE GIRL I LOVE.
I'M NOT GONNA SAY ANYTHING, JUST THIS:
YOU HAVE ALWAYS BEEN VERY RESPONSIBLE WITH RAY.
I DON'T THINK IT'S RIGHT FOR HIM TO WAKE UP AND HEAR SOME STRANGE MAN'S VOICE IN THE HOUSE.
SOMEDRUNKENSTRANGER.
OH, AS OPPOSED TO TEN ANGRY WOMEN?
WHOA! OWW!
LEAN FORWARD. OKAY, I'VE GOT IT.
OHH. STILL EDIBLE. CHANGE YOUR SHIRT.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
HI, JERRY.
HI, RAY.
AREN'T, UH, YOU SUPPOSED TO BE IN BED?
YEAH. YEAH.
[ Whispers ] ALL RIGHT.
I WON'T TELL.
THE HUMAN HEAD WEIGHS EIGHT POUNDS.
[ Ringing ]
[ Phone Beeps ] JERRY MAGUIRE.
[ Ringing Continues ] I THINK IT'S THIS ONE.
[ Rod ] YOU SHOULD BE DREAMIN' ABOUT ME, BABY.
MY AGENT SHOULD BE THINKING ROD TIDWELL.  THAT'S WHEN THE BIG DOLLARS ARE GONNA FLOW.
THAT'S WHEN WE TRULY WILL MATERIALIZE THE "KWAN." WHO IS THIS?
WHO ISTHIS?  YOU ARE SPEAKING TO THEROD TIDWELL.
I NEED TO SPEAK WITH MY AGENT. I NEED TOBEMY AGENT.
MY AGENT AND I SHOULD BE ONE. ARE YOU A FOOTBALL PLAYER?
AM I A FOOTBALL PLAYER? I'M A SCHOOLTEACHER ABOUT TO WHOMP YOUR ASS!
PUT JERRY MAGUIRE ON THE PHONE!
ONE MORE THING: YOU DON'T HAVE THE LUXURY OF FALLING FOR SOME DROWNING MAN.  BE PRACTICAL.
- "PRACTICAL"? - HIGH TURTLENECK SENSIBLE   OR LOW V-NECK SEXY?
TURTLENECK, TURTLENECK. COME ON. DON'T TELL ME TO BE PRACTICAL.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT OTHER WOMEN MY AGE ARE DOING RIGHT NOW?
THEY'RE OUT PARTYING, TRYING TO GET A MAN, TRYING TOKEEPA MAN.
NOT ME, LAUREL.
I'M TRYING TORAISE A MAN.  THIS ONE.
I'VE GOT A 24-HOUR-A-DAY REMINDER OF ROGER FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE.
I'VE HAD THREE LOVERS IN FOUR YEARS.
- THAT'S NOT BAD. - AND ALL OF THEM   RAN A DISTANT SECOND...
TO A GOOD BOOK AND A WARM BATH.
LOOK AT ME, LAUREL.
I'M THE OLDEST 26-YEAR-OLD IN THE WORLD.
- NOW, HOW DO I LOOK? - GOOD.
YEAH?  THANKS.
[ Rod ]  SEVENTY-TWO PERCENT OF NEW BUYERS ARE AFRICAN-AMERICAN!
IAM AFRICAN-AMERICAN.  MAKE THE CONNECTION. YOU TALK TOO MUCH.
NO, NO, NO! TALKING IS ONLY A PRIMITIVE FORM OF COMMUNICATION!
FUN TALKING TO YOU. BYE, ROD. J-JERRY!
[ Laurel ] MAKE A SANDWICH. [ Dorothy ]  GOOD IDEA.
HAM SANDWICH? I JUST WANNA SAY ONE THING:
YOUDOLISTEN TO ME. WELL, I LOVE YOU.
MAYO? YEAH.
[ Jerry ] OPPRESSION... AS A RELIGION.
MY DADDY WORKED FOR THE UNITED WAY FOR 38 YEARS.
YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAID WHEN HE RETIRED?
"I WISH THEY'D GIVEN ME  A MORE COMFORTABLE CHAIR."
38 YEARS HE SAT IN THAT-- WAIT, WAIT, WAIT. AND THEN MY DAD DIED.
MY MOM TOOK ME TO THE ZOO, AND I LOVE THE ZOO--
NO, WAIT, WAIT,'CAUSE I WANNA TELL YOU MORE ABOUTMYDAD.
NO, LET'S GO TO THE ZOO.
[ Sighs ] OKAY.  OKAY.
NO, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW, IT'S JUST MY WHOLE LIFE I'VE BEEN TRYING TO TALK, I MEAN...
REALLYTALK.
BUT NO ONE WANTS TO LISTEN TO ME. YOU KNOW THAT FEELING?
THEY JUST LOOK AT YOU-- LET'S GO RIGHT NOW.  LET'S GO TO THE ZOO.
RAY, THE ZOO, YOU KNOW--
THE FUCKIN' ZOO'S CLOSED, RAY, I MEAN--
[ Whispers ] YOU SAID "FUCK."
YEAH, I DID. I, UH--  IS THAT--
I WON'T TELL.
WELL...
NOW I'M GONNA HAVE TO TAKE YOU TO THE ZOO.
[ Plates Clattering,   Laurel, Dorothy Chattering ] I GOTTA GO TO BED.
MY MOM'S COMING. I GOTTA GO TO BED. W-WAIT--
[ Chattering Continues ] I HEAR MY MOM.  I GOTTA GO TO BED.
HEY, THANKS FOR LISTENING. SURE.
WHEW.  OKAY.
DRINKS, FOOD, AND I CALLED YOU A CAB.
GOOD IDEA.
AND WE SHOULD KEEP OUR VOICES DOWN. I HAVE A LITTLE BOY ASLEEP.
RIGHT.
OUR COMPANY.
YEAH.
OKAY.  OKAY.
LOOK, UH, A LITTLE, UH,
A LITTLE SPEECH BEFORE I GO.
DO... NOT... WORRY... ABOUT YOUR FUTURE.
YOU AND YOUR SON--
WE--ARE JUST FINE.
YOU STILL HAVE A JOB.
BUT LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING...
ABOUT JERRY MAGUIRE, OKAY?
YOU COME AFTER ME, AND YOU... WILL... LOSE.
YOU KNOW, BECAUSE I AM A SURVIVOR.
I'M A SURVIVOR.
DOROTHY BOYD, YOU ARE WITH THE LORD...
OF THE LIVING ROOM,
THE, THEKINGOF THE KINGDOME,
AND I... AM...
DRUNK.
WE MEET AGAIN.
[ Gurgling ]
[ Sighs ]
HERE.
THE TRUTH?
SURE.
I CARE ABOUT THE JOB,
OF COURSE,
BUT MOSTLY I JUST WANNA BE INSPIRED.
ME TOO.
WHAT YOU WROTE INSPIRED ME.
OHH-- NO, NO, NO.  NO, HEY.
I'M WORKING WITH YOU BECAUSE OF THAT MEMO.
I LOVED THAT MEMO.
IT WAS A MISSION STATEMENT.
[ Car Horn Honking ]
WELL-- [ Snickers ]
SORRY ABOUT THE HAND.
HUH?
DO YOU KNOW THAT FEELING, UH,
YOU'RE NOT... [ Grunts ]
COMPLETELY EMBARRASSED YET,
BUT YOU GLIMPSE TOMORROW'S EMBARRASSMENT?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT, BOSS.
OH, SHIT. YOU SAID "BOSS."
- YEAH, I DID. - NOW I FEEL LIKE   CLARENCE THOMAS.
NO, DON'T FEEL LIKE CLARENCE THOMAS.
NO, NO, I DO. I FEEL LIKE CLARENCE THOMAS.
I'M, LIKE, HARASSING YOU RIGHT NOW.
WELL, I MAY NOT SUE. [ Laughs ]
- GOOD EVENING. - GOOD EVENING.
LOOK, DON'T WORRY, OKAY? I MEAN, DON'T--
WE'RE GONNA BE OKAY, BECAUSE I AM GONNA TAKE MY ONE CLIENT...
AND WE ARE GONNA GO... ALL THE WAY.
'CAUSE, HEY,
I'M BACK.
[ Engine Starts ] D-- DON'T WORRY.
[ Laughs ]
[ Whistle Blows ] [ Man Shouting ] FRISCO!  RAZOR!  RAZOR!
[ Continues Shouting,   Indistinct ]
- HUT!  HUT! - [ Grunting, Yelling ]
[ Whistle Blows ] [ Jerry ]  WAY TO GO! GOOD CATCH!
- GOOD CATCH. - [ Rod ]   HEY, MAN, YOU CAN'T--
[ Men Chattering ] [ Man ]  ALL RIGHT! GOOD JOB!  GOOD JOB!
WE GOTTA TALK ABOUT HIS CONTRACT, DENNIS.
MEET ME AT THE CROCODILE, 8:00.
YOU BET.
[ Whistle Blows ]
THANK YOU.
[ Jerry ]  TELL ME YOU GOT LOST LAST NIGHT, BECAUSE I KNOW YOU WOULDN'T DO THAT TO A FRIEND.
SOMETHING CAME UP. YEAH, WELL, IT'S OKAY.
TEN MILLION DOLLARS FOR FOUR YEARS.
IT'S EARLY. YOU'RE STILL DREAMIN'. TEN FOR FOUR, IT'S A DEAL.
LOOK, THE GUY'S GOT AN ATTITUDE PROBLEM.
- I CAN HELP YOU WITH THAT.   HE LISTENS TO ME. - HE'S A SHRIMP.
"SHRIMP"?  ROD TIDWELL BROKE EVERY RECEIVING RECORD YOU HAD LAST YEAR.
I WANT A PROTOTYPICAL WIDE RECEIVER, JERRY-- SOMEBODY WHO'S 6'3", 220,
NOT SOME GUY WHO'S 5'10" AND BITCHES IN THE LOCKER ROOM.
DENNIS, I'M ASKING YOU...
FOR A FAVOR.
I INTRODUCED YOU TO YOUR WIFE.
WE'VE SPENT CHRISTMASES TOGETHER, HOLIDAY CHEER.
[ Chuckles ] DENNIS-- JERRY, YOU'RE REACHIN'.
I-I'M ASKING YOU FOR A FAVOR!
DON'T DO THIS TO ME. WE HAVE HISTORY, DENNIS.
OH, YEAH, WE GOT HISTORY, ALL RIGHT, JERRY.
YOU DROVE THE PRICES UP ON ME FOR YEARS.
- IT'S YOUR TURN TO SPEND SOME   TIME AT THE BACK OF THE LINE. - NO, NO, NO, DENNIS, DON'T--
[ Sighs ]
I STARTED TALKING WITH DENNIS WILBURN ABOUT YOUR RENEGOTIATION THIS MORNING.
[ Shower Running ]
TALKING?
JERRY RICE. ANDRE REED.
CHRIS CARTER. I SMOKEALL THESE FOOLS!
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH. YETTHEYARE MAKIN' THE BIG, SWEET DOLLAR.
THEY ARE MAKIN' THE KWAN.
AND YOU'RE TALKING.
"KWAN." THAT'S YOUR WORD?
HELL, YEAH, THAT'S MY WORD.
YOU KNOW, SOME DUDES MIGHT HAVE THE COIN, BUT THEY'LL NEVER HAVE THE KWAN.
- WH-- WHAT IS-- - IT MEANS LOVE, RESPECT,   COMMUNITY AND THE DOLLARS TOO.
THE ENTIRE PACKAGE.  THE... KWAN.
GREAT WORD.
- TOWEL? - NO, I AIR DRY.
UH, LISTEN, ROD.
I-I SAY THIS WITH GREAT RESPECT FOR YOU,
BUT THOSE PLAYERS YOU MENTIONED, ROD,
THEY'RE MARQUEE PLAYERS, AND THIS DEAL, WE'RE--
Y-YOU KNOW, WE-- M-M-MARQUEE?
HERE'S WHAT I'M SAYING. THIS IS A RENEGOTIATION.
WE WANT MORE, SO LET'S GIVE THEM MORE.  LET'S SHOW THEM YOUR PURE JOY OF THE GAME.
- LET'S BURY THE ATTITUDE   A LITTLE BIT AND SHOW THEM-- - WAIT.
- YOU'RE TELLIN' ME TO DANCE. - NO.
I'M SAYING TO GET BACK TO THE GUY WHO FIRST STARTED PLAYING THIS GAME.
REMEMBER WAY BACK WHEN, WHEN YOU WERE A KID?
IT WASN'T JUST ABOUT THE MONEY, WAS IT?
WAS IT?
WASIT?
DO YOUR JOB.
DON'T YOU TELL ME TO DANCE! FINE.
HEY.  HEY! FINE!
I AM AN ATHLETE!  I AM NOT AN ENTERTAINER!
- FINE! - THESE ARE THE ABC's   OF ME, BABY!
I DO NOT DANCE, AND I DO NOT START PRESEASON WITHOUT A CONTRACT.
FINE, FINE!  FINE!
JERRY, TALK TO ME. BREATHE.
BREATHE, JERRY.
I AM OUT HERE FOR YOU.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO BE ME OUT HERE FOR YOU.
IT IS AN UP-AT-DAWN, PRIDE-SWALLOWING SIEGE...
THAT I WILL NEVER FULLY TELL YOU ABOUT.  OKAY?
JUST, GOD, HELP ME.
HELP ME, ROD.  HELP ME HELP YOU.
HELP ME HELP YOU.
HELPMEHELPYOU.
I'M SORRY.
YOU ARE HANGIN' ON BY A VERY THIN THREAD.
[ Continues Laughing ]
AND I DIG THAT ABOUT YOU!
[ Giggling ] NO CONTRACT?
"HELP ME, HELP ME,   HELP ME!"
THAT'S MY-- THAT'SMY MAN!
HEY, I'M HAPPY TO ENTERTAIN YOU.
"HELP ME!   HELP ME!"
[ Laughs ] I'LL SEE YOU IN LOS ANGELES.
JERRY! COME ON, MAN!
HEY!  SEE, THAT'S THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN US.
YOU THINK WE'RE FIGHTIN', AND I THINK WE'RE FINALLY TALKIN'!
UNLESS YOU LOVE EVERYBODY, YOU CAN'T SELL ANYBODY.
DENNIS WILBURN CALLED FROM ARIZONA...
TO SAY HE'S FAXING IN THE NEW OFFER FOR TIDWELL ON THURSDAY MORNING.
HE SAID YOU'D BE HAPPY. GLAD.
WELL, DID HE SAY "HAPPY" OR "GLAD"?
GLAD.  HE SAID GLAD.  GLAD.
GLAD'S GOOD. YEAH.
GLAD'S GOOD. YEAH, WE COULD SURE USE THAT COMMISSION.
HERE, I DID A RUNDOWN ON WHERE YOU STAND FINANCIALLY.
WELL, I SUNK MOST OF WHAT I HAD INTO THIS CONDO, YOU DON'T HAVE TO EXPLAIN.
WHICH DEVALUED AND--
LOOK, THE OTHER NIGHT, UH-- I WANT TO APOLOGIZE.
YEAH.  WHAT HAPPENED THERE?
WE'RE TWO PEOPLE WORKING TOGETHER. WE CAN'T HAVE ATMOSPHERE.
NO, I'M REALLY RELIEVED YOU SAID THAT.
THE OTHER NIGHT I WAS LONELY...
AND I FELT YOU UNDERSTOOD SOMETHING.
- BUT LOOK, WE'VE GOT A COMPANY   TO THINK ABOUT HERE. - YES.
I WILL NEVER TAKE ADVANTAGE OF YOU IN THAT WAY AGAIN.
-GOOD. -YOU WALKED OUT ON A JOB FOR ME,  AND THIS IS HOW I REPAY YOU?
CAN THIS BE RIGHT?
EXACTLY.
I KNOW THIS IS ONE OF THOSE TIMES WHEN YOU NEED TO BE ALONE WITH YOUR THOUGHTS...
AND THINK ABOUT EVERYTHING THAT'S GONE WRONG AND HOW TO FIX IT AND, YOU KNOW,
JUST BE ALONE.
ALONE.  ALONE, ALONE, ALONE.
ALONE.
- YOU WANNA GO OUT TO DINNER? - I KNOW A GREAT PLACE.
THE GUY'S AN UTTER LOSER SO I BROKE UP WITH HIM, AND THEN HE STARTED STALKING ME.
WHAT'S THE CURRENT DEFINITION OF STALKING?
[ Woman ] COMING OVER UNINVITED. [ Women Laughing ]
"COMING OVER UNINVITED." SO, LIKE, ROMEO UNDER THE BALCONY IS A STALKER?
EXACTLY. OH, STOP.
WHAT? [ Women Exclaiming,   Chattering ]
ILOVEGUYS LIKE THAT. I WOULD DATE SOMEBODY THAT WAY.
I WOULD TOO. I WOULD DATE ANYBODY, FOR THAT MATTER.
HE'S ALWAYS JUST COMING OVER UNINVITED-- EXCUSE ME.
LADIES?  LADIES? [ Chattering Quiets ]
GOOD EVENING, I-- I'M LOOKING FOR DOROTHY BOYD.
SHE'S IN THE KITCHEN.
LAUREL. JERRY.  HI.
WHERE YOU TAKIN' HER TONIGHT, HUH?
[ Chattering Continues,   Faint ] YOU'RE THE NANNY, IS THAT--
- AU PAIR. - A-AU PAIR, IS IT?
YEAH.
JERRY! WHOA!  RAY!
- RAY. - HE LIKES YOU.
MY GOODNESS. LOOK, RAY, I GOT SOME GIFTS FOR YA.
DO YOU LIKE PRESENTS? YEAH.
GOOD, GOOD. ALL RIGHT.
HERE'S THE ARIZONA CARDINALS.
THIS IS THE TEAM THAT ROD PLAYS FOR.
DROPPING YOUR LAUNDRY OFF, JERRY?
WOULD YOU LIKE, UH, A HAT?  STEELERS? FOR ME?  WOW.
GOT SOME THINGS, YOU KNOW. GOT IT IN GRAY TOO.
[ Ray ] THANKS, JERRY. YOU'RE VERY WELCOME.
OH, MY GOODNESS, LOOK WHAT I'VE GOT HERE. THIS IS AN ENERGY BAR.
THIS WILL KEEP YOU UP ALL NIGHT.
SEE, THAT'S NOT A GOOD IDEA. I'LL TAKE THAT.  YEAH. AUNT LAUREL'LL EAT THAT.
HEY.  LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE GOT A FAN.
WOW. THAT'S MORE THAN A DRESS.
THAT'S AN AUDREY HEPBURN MOVIE. YEAH.
I GUESS I GOT A LITTLE REVVED UP AT THE IDEA OF AN EVENING AMONG ADULTS.  NO OFFENSE, BUDDY.
- JERRY, DID YOU MEET CHAD?   CHAD, JERRY.  JERRY, CHAD. - YEAH, WE DI--
AM I DRESSED OKAY? I DIDN'T REALIZE--
[ Women Chattering ]
CHAD, DON'T LET HIM STAY UP TOO LATE.
TONIGHT I'M GOING TO TEACH RAY HERE ABOUT JAZZ.
- GOOD.  THAT'LL PUT HIM    TO SLEEP EARLY. - [ Women Giggling ]
- I WANNA GO TOO. - OH, NO, NO, SWEETHEART.
YOU STAY HERE WITH CHAD, OKAY, AND BE GOOD? GIVE ME A KISS.
LET'S GO. EXCUSE ME.
LET'S GO. HMM?  OKAY. GOOD NIGHT.
- GOOD NIGHT. - GIVE ME A HUG.
[ Women Continue   Chattering, Faint ]
HEY!
GO AHEAD. I'LL MEET YOU AT THE CAR. OKAY.
JUST FORGOT THE KEYS. NO BIG DEAL.
THAT IS THE FIRST TIME I HAVE EVER SEEN HIM KISS A MAN JUST LIKE A DAD.
WASN'T THAT JUST THRILLING? HE MUST REALLY HAVE BEEN NEEDING THAT.
TAKE IT EASY.  DON'T CRY AT THE BEGINNING OF A DATE. CRY AT THE END, LIKE I DO.
YOU ALL RIGHT? ALL RIGHT. OKAY.  OKAY.
AND DON'T BE A SHOULDER FOR HIM TO CRY ON EITHER. THAT'S ALL I'M GONNA SAY.
KEYS, KEYS. OH, KEYS. OKAY.
[ Sighs ] OH, DEAR.
?? SHE'D LET YOU   IN HER HOUSE??
?? IF YOU COME KNOCKIN'   LATE AT NIGHT??
?? SHE'D LET YOU   IN HER MOUTH??
?? IF THE WORDS   YOU SAY ARE RIGHT??
[ Customers Chattering,   Laughing ]
?? IF YOU PAY THE PRICE???? EVER SINCE YOU'VE MET ME,
I'VE BEEN-- BLE-EA-EAH! RIGHT?
[ Blubbering ]
IT WAS LAZINESS, YOU KNOW, MY BREAKUP WITH AVERY.
THAT THING YOU SAY-- "IT'S NOBODY'S FAULT." IT'S ONE OF THE GREAT LIES.
SOMEBODY IS ALWAYS TO BLAME.
YOU GO FOR IT LIKE YOU DO A JOB.
WORK AT IT.
BUT MAYBE LOVE SHOULDN'T BE SUCH HARD WORK.
YEAH, YEAH, MAYBE SO.
I MEAN, IT'S NOT EVERY DAY YOU SAY GOOD-BYE TO A WOMAN LIKE THAT.
A SONG FOR THE LOVERS?
NO, THANK YOU. OH, NO.
NO, NO. WE WORK TOGETHER.
THIS IS LIKE AN OFFICE MEETING. BUT THANK YOU. THANKS.
BUT I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
IT WASN'T LIKE MY MARRIAGE TO ROGER WAS ANY GOOD EVEN BEFORE--
???? [ Mariachi ] BEFORE?
????
???? JERRY. WHAT?
???? LET'S NOT TELL OUR SAD STORIES.
???? [ Continues ]
????
???? I'LL BE BACK IN JUST A SECOND, OKAY?
???? [ Ends  ] [ Applause ]
????
?? I REALIZE YOU'RE   SEEING SOMEONE NEW?? NO, THEY STING.
LET CHAD CATCH THE BEE IN THE GLASS. NO, HE WON'T HURT HIM.
???? [ Continues ] YOU'VE GOT SUCH A GOOD HEART, BUDDY.  I LOVE YOU.
?? YOUR TEMPERAMENTA L   MOODY SIDE??
?? THE ONE YOU'VE ALWAYS   TRIED TO HIDE FROM ME??
?? ME ESTOY MURIENDO   POCO A POCO FRENTE A TI??
?? ME ESTAS ROBANDO   TODO AQUELLO QUE TE DI????
WELL, THIS... WOULD BE GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.
I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW. BIG DAY. I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
WELL, GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.
OOPS.
LET ME FIX THIS.
GOOD IDEA. [ Laughs ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
I THINK YOU SHOULD NOT COME IN.
OR COME IN.
DEPENDING ON HOW YOU FEEL.
SAME TO YOU. NO.
I HAVE TO GO IN.
[ Gasps ] I LIVE HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL COME IN.
GOOD.
ARE YOU SURE WE WANNA DO THIS?
OH, HELL, YES. YEAH.
[ TV, Indistinct ]
HEY. HI.
HOW IS HE? DID HE HAVE A GOOD NIGHT? YEAH.  HE'S ASLEEP.
GOOD. HOW'D IT GO WITH SPORT BOY?
STILL GOING.
ALL RIGHT.
CHAD.
HOW ARE YOU?
TREAT HER RIGHT.
YEAH. SHE'S, UH...
SHE'S GREAT.
YEAH.
AND, UH,
I KNOW THIS MIGHT BE A BIT AWKWARD, BUT, UH, I WANT YOU TO USE THIS.
OH, LOOK--  GOD. CHAD.
OH, NO, NO, NO.
THIS... IS MILES DAVIS AND JOHN COLTRANE.
STOCKHOLM, 1963.
TWO MASTERS OF FREEDOM PLAYING AT A TIME BEFORE THEIR ART WAS CORRUPTED...
BY A ZILLION COCKTAIL LOUNGE PERFORMERS...
WHO DESTROYED THE LEGACY OF THE ONLY AMERICAN ART FORM:
JAZZ.
I PUT SOME MINGUS ON THERE TOO.
NO BARRIERS,
NO BOUNDARIES.
CHAD, I GOT IT.
???? [ Tape Deck:      Jazz ]
????
???? [ Continues ]
???? COME HERE.
????
???? [ Continues ]
YOU KNOW THIS IS GONNA CHANGE EVERYTHING.
PROMISE?
???? [ Continues,      Tempo Change: Rapid ]
????
???? WHAT IS THIS MUSIC?
]???? [ Continues, Faint
[ Dorothy ] OHHH! [  Laughs ]
[ Continues Laughing ] [ Jerry Whispering ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
-???? [ Loud Rock ]  - I LOVE GETTING UP    IN THE MORNING!
I CLAP MY HANDS AND SAY, "THIS IS GONNA BE A GREAT DAY!"
???? [ Continues ]
GREAT.  YOU REALLY NEEDED TO DO THIS.
???? [ Electronic Guitar Riff ]
[ Liquid Dripping ]
I'M GETTING HIM UP, SO DON'T WORRY.
WHAT?
JUST WAITING FOR THE COFFEE. I DON'T CARE ABOUT--
JUST TELL ME ONE THING. NO.
[ Sighs ]
WHY ARE YOU ACTING LIKE THAT? BECAUSE I'M WORRIED...
THAT YOU'RE PUTTING ALL YOUR FAITH IN THIS GUY WHO,
BECAUSE OF THE WAY THINGS ARE GOING, MIGHT NOT HAVE AN EMOTIONAL MARBLE IN HIS HEAD.
LAUREL, PLEASE. IF I START TALKING--
[ Laurel ] YOUPLEASE. SO WHAT DOES THAT MAKE ME FOR TAKING THE OPPORTUNITY?
[ Laurel ]  MEN ARE DIFFERENT PEOPLE WHEN THEY'RE HANGING ONTO THE BOTTOM RUNG.
MAYBE IAM TAKING ADVANTAGE.
DOES THAT MAKE ME A BAD PERSON?  HUH?
ALL I KNOW IS I FOUND SOMEONE AND HE WAS POPULAR AND CHARMING...
AND NOT SO NICE TO ME,  AND HE DIED, OKAY?
SO WHY SHOULD I LET THIS GUY GO WHEN EVERYTHING IN MY BODY SAYS...
THAT THIS ONE ISTHEONE.
TAKE IT EASY, ALL RIGHT? I WAS JUST LOOKING FOR A FEW FUN DETAILS.
OH.  WELL, WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'RE INTERESTED IN THIS ONE LITTLE DETAIL--
YEAH.  WHAT? I WAS JUST ABOUT TO TELL YOU...
UH-HUH?
THAT I LOVE HIM.
I DO!  I LOVE HIM!
AND I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU THINK.
I LOVE HIM FOR THE-- FOR THE MAN HE WANTS TO BE,
AND I LOVE HIM FOR THE MAN THAT HE ALMOST IS.
I LOVE HIM, LAUREL.
I LOVE HIM.  I LOVE HIM.
HI, JERRY!
ACT NATURAL.
HI.
TELL ME HE'S NOT THERE. HE'S NOT THERE.
OH, GOD.
EASY, LADIES, EASY.
- COFFEE, JERRY? - OH, NO, THANKS.
WE BOTTOM FEEDERS,  WE PREFER CEREAL FIRST.
[ Ray ] LET'S HAVE APPLE JACKS.
APPLE JACKS?  APPLE JACKS, IT IS.
DOROTHY.
?? THAT'S THE WAY   IT'S GONNA BE?? GOOD MORNING, DARLING.
?? LITTLE DARLIN'??
MORNING.
?? WE'LL BE RIDING   ON THE HORSES?? WHAT'S GOING ON, JERRY?
WELL, A LOT, ACTUALLY. WE'VE GOT A BIG FAX TODAY.
???? [ Continues ] WE NEED THIS COMMISSION, BUDDY.
NEED THIS COMMISSION. MILK?
YEAH.?? IF YOU FALL??
?? I'LL PICK YOU UP   PICK YOU UP???? CHEERS.
THAT WAS REALLY GREAT OF YOU THIS MORNING.
LOOK, LET'S JUST ROOT FOR A BIG OFFER...
SO WE CAN MOVE OUT OF THIS ROOM AND INTO A REAL OFFICE.
[ Giggles ] YES.
WOULD YOU MIND? THANKS A LOT.
SHIT.
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST--
ONE-POINT-SEVEN FOR THREE YEARS?
MAN, WE OWE MORE THAN THAT! THIS IS HOW THE GAME IS PLAYED.
NOW I'M GONNA GO BACK TO THEM. AND SAY WHAT?
- "PLEASE REMOVE YOUR DICK    FROM MY ASS"? - MARCEE.
I'M SORRY, I'M JUST A LITTLE PREGNANT RIGHT NOW. THAT'S OKAY.
I FEEL LIKE CRYIN', JERRY. I FEEL LIKE BUSTIN' THE ROOM UP. I KNOW.
ROD, LET'S NOT TAKE THIS EMOTIONALLY.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL WITH THIS PROBLEM, OKAY?
WHAT ARE YOU SO CALM ABOUT? WHAT DO YOU MEAN, "ROLL WITH THIS PROBLEM"?
"DON'T TAKE IT  EMOTIONALLY"?