Hey Rahul! Want to be
friends?
She's just like her
father. lsn't she?
Tina's very critical Rahul.
She doesn't have much time.
We tried our best.
She had severe internal bleeding.
We couldn't do anything.
She knew there would be
complications in her delivery.
She also knew how much you
wanted this child.
She loved this baby more
than her life.
l want my daughter to now me.
Who her mother was,
what she was like.
l want her to be able to answer
all these questions herself.
l am leaving these 8 letters
for her...
...1 each of her 1st
8 birthdays.
These letters have everything
that l want to tell my daughter.
These letters are going
to be her memories.
You are very bad.
Rahul, Want to be friends?
Promise me you will never cry.
Anyways, you look very bad
when you cry.
Also promise me that...
...you'll name our daughter
Anjali.
l am sorry Rahul.
l am really sorry.
Don't go.
Promise me you'll name
our daughter Anjali.
Hi! l am Anjali...
...and you're watching
channel Anjali.
l am going to grow up
and be a V.J...
...you know just like
Neelam.
Hey cut cut cut.
Ooops l'll be back
after the break.
My hobbies are eating
chocolates,...
...beating up boys,
irritating granny...
...and reading mom's letters.
Hey l'm late.
l have to get ready and
go to meet papa.
l'll be back next week
same time, same place.
Watch me.
Hi, Anjali, listen to me.
Look.
Look... l'm only...
...2 hours late.
Right.
- Okay. Sorry. l was busy.
So was l.
l haven't even watched
television today...
...because l had to come
to do your shopping.
l can't handle everything.
l'm your daughter not your wife.
Why?
lf l can be both your dad
and mom...
...why can't you be both...
Okay.
What?
- Felt bad?
A bit.
Sorry
- Okay.
That is why one says...
...there is only one god
in many forms.
No matter what form,
he knows our devotion.
lt is important to keep
this bond with god.
She speaks so well, doesn't she?
So, that's all for today.
Now we'll have...
l got this gift for
St. Valentine's day.
Rupa!
- Me?
Rupa will chant the
divine hymn.
Me?
Chant Rupa.
The divine hymn...
l forgot it.
What?
What are you saying Rupa?!
Can you believe that sisters?
She has forgotten the divine hymn.
My dear if you don't pay
attention to prayer...
...what will you teach
your children.
The way we think and
the things we say...
...have a deep impact
on our children.
Granny.
Speaking of children...
Namaste. - Hi, sexy!
Who taught you that?
- Papa.
Go get ready for your
School function.
Granny... the letter.
When is your birthday?
- Tomorrow.
So?
Come on, hurry up.
Yes, there are our seats.
- Come sit.
Come Mr. Khanna, sit.
Good evening ladies
and gentlemen.
Welcome to the
Just one-minute competition.
lt's a strange competition. Children
have to talk on the stage...
.. and the topic is given right
there in some strange bowl.
On the spot sir, on the spot.
Stop it Balbir, control yourself.
- Never mind. lt's ok.
Every student will be given only
one minute. Just one minute.
Just One Minute?
Only one minute to speak?
Exactly. Very unfair.
But yet our Jassu wins
every year.
She's so talented you know.
Best of luck Jaswinder.
- Same to you.
Our Jaswinder is the best.
Actually Anjali is also
taking part.
She'll come second.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
- Oh welcome!
Our first contestant is
Jaswinder Singh.
Oh! My sweetheart.
My topic is Prayer.
Every morning we pray
to the lord.
Papa says prayers will
keep god happy...
...and he will protect us.
Mummy says that by praying
Grandma will get impressed...
...and will leave the big
house for us in the will.
Prayer... yes, my favourite
actress's name is Puja...
...and even my best friend's
name is Puja.
Wow! My daughter is
the best.
Next we have Anjali Khanna.
Pick your topic.
Second!
Your timer starts now.
Say!
Mother!
l am sorry.
Mother...
A mother is someone
who loves us so much,...
...that we sometimes can't
understand it.
A mother is someone who makes
us realise how good we are,...
...there is no one better
than us.
Her happiness is in our
laughter...
...and sorrow in our
sorrow.
She is someone we can't
live without,...
...she is everything.
Only we don't have her.
But we have papa, and
he is quite nice too.
Then you give me a hug.
That's number one!
Rahul, you remember
Mr. Shama? He had phoned.
Who?
Our neighbour in Delhi.
He has sent a proposal.
For whom?
Me.
Shut up.
He said the girl is
sweet and beautiful...
...but l refused flatly.
l did the right thing, didn't l?
- Yes.
l did the right thing?
l was right?
Yes mom.
Well l must have done
the right thing.
l never do anything wrong.
So what if the girl is
sweet and beautiful.
Everyone is beautiful these days.
Who wants to get married?
Mr. Sharma has gone mad.
Keeps sending me proposals.
Why doesn't he get himself married
and just leave me alone.
What's wrong mom?
l just find this family
incomplete.
Why? You are there.
l am there...
...Anjali is there, l don't
find it incomplete.
When l go out with my
friends,...
...they all complain about
their daughters-in-law.
l can't even do that.
This is a big problem.
So you need a daughter-in-law
to complain about.
No son.
l just want you to be happy.
l am happy mom.
So you won't marry again?
Mom, we live once, die once,
get married once,..
...and love once.
We don't do these again.
You are fine, but what
of Anjali.
Why? What's happened to her?
You don't feel she needs
a mother?
She's okay.
She's just fine.
She's got something which
even l don't have.
Her mother's letters.
Happy Birthday Anjali.
My dear, Anjali.
You are 8 years old today.
l'm sure you look just
like your dad.
That same smile, those
same eyes.
No. l look like you.
Does your father still go
Old habits die-hard.
Today you are a big girl and
you will be able to understand...
...what l have to tell you.
Today, l will tell you a story...
...about your father, me and
Anjali.
Anjali?
You're late again.
Can't wake up so early.
Can't wake up or were
you scared.
Rahul Khanna is never
scared.
But loses to Anjali Sharma
everyday in Basketball.
Don't want to play?
What's the point, you
will lose again.
l won't lose today.
- You say that everyday.
We'll see.
lf you can't play
atleast don't cheat.
Don't call me a cheater.
Anjali, don't call me
a cheater.
Rahul is a cheater.
He is a cheater, cheater.
l am not a cheater.
- Cheater.
Stop screaming like a girl.
- Hey! Don't call me a girl.
You're right, you're not a girl.
Atleast better than those
girls you run after.
Excuse me! l don't run after
them, they run after me.
Wow! Rahul's so cute.
- Yes.
He's so sweet, he's so
handsome.
Not as handsome as you,
you have a better moustache.
Was that a joke?
- What if it was?
l don't like jokes.
- l don't like you.
Shut up.
Rahul and Anjali have
fought again.
Rahul and Anjali
have fought.
have fought again.
''What sort of a boy is this?''
''What sort of a girl is this?''
''What do l do with him?''
''What do l say to her?''
''He fights with me!''
''She irritates me!''
''He troubles me''
''She gets upset''
''He is crazy''
''She is crazy''
''But he is your best friend dear''
''But she is your best friend dear''
''Oh my! Oh my! this boy.
Oh my! Oh my!''
''Why does he play these pranks?
Ask him please, why''
''Sometime he fights with me,
sometime he quarrels with me''
''Stay away from him''
''This boy is crazy''
''Crazy... Crazy...''
''Oh my! Oh my! this girl
Oh my! Oh my!''
''Why does she play these pranks?
Ask her please, why''
''Sometimes she fights with me''
''Sometimes she irritates''
''Trouble her, but only
from a distance''
''This girl is crazy.
Crazy... Crazy...''
''Only she understands
what she says''
''No one else can
figure that out''
''She's like this
and she's like that''
''No one can figure her out''
''So run for your life,
she is surely upto some mischief''
''This girl is crazy.
Crazy... Crazy...''
''This boy is crazy.
''He teases us
as he comes by''
''He does not listen''
''Look, look, he is crazy
beware of him''
''He is weird and yet
he is dear to me''
''This boy is crazy.
Crazy... Crazy...''
''This girl is crazy.
Crazy... Crazy...''.
Oh God! Just look at
this room. Filthy.
These girls will drive
me crazy.
Hey! What is this mountain
on your head?
These are rollers, Rifat bi.
Rollers don't impress boys.
You can take that from me.
Then how do they get impressed,
Rifat bi.
Oh god! What are you wearing?
Come on tell us.
- l don't know.
Tell us please.
- No!
Tell us.
Okay! Boys get impressed by
a girl's mannerisms,...
...her walk, her talk...
- And?
And l don't know.
You girls talk to much.
Come on, clean up this mess.
God! What do l do with
this girl, Anjali, what is this?
What are you wearing?
lt's cool Rifat bi.
Cool? Try to be feminine once
in a while atleast.
Not like them but...
Rifat bi, you say the
same thing everyday.
You know, l beat Rahul
in basketball again.
Stay away from that boy.
Why? He is my best friend.
He is my buddy.
When best friend becomes
boy friend,...
...one doesn't even get to know.
- Rahul? Please.
Yes, yes. l know all about that.
Here l've got you some pudding.
Don't tell anyone.
Oh! Thank you Rifat bi.
- Leave me, mad girl.
No short skirts in the
college please.
Good morning Ms. Briganza.
Good morning boys,
Nice colour Piyush.
l'll complain to your
parents that...
...you wear short skirts to
college in order to excite the boys.
Excuse me!
l said no short skirts
in college please.
Oh! Ms. Briganza.
You said something Malhotra?
Oh! l was just saying, that short
skirts are not allowed in college.
What? But this is the
latest fashion...
...infact, some girls don't
even wear skirts these days.
Don't tell me Ms. Briganza.
- Yes!
And am l not looking
nice today?
You're very queet. Queet?
Cute.
You're very cute.
But if you expose like this,
then these youngsters...
What do you mean by these youngsters.
Am l not young?
You're... young. Very young.
But you wear very boring
clothes.
l Know. Till Mrs. Malhotra
was alive...
...l would occasionally wear
fancy clothes.
Really?
But now there is no point.
- What do you mean?
Mr. Malhotra... Ms. Briganza...
Mrs. Malhotra.
Happy friendship day.
Sharma. Always scaring me.
What are you doing now.
- lt's a friendship band sir.
Besides being your student,
l am also your friend now.
Oh! Good!
Sir, you look very happy today.
What do you mean?
- Just generally.
Oh! Generally. Well, my daughter
is coming home today.
Your daughter?
- Tina.
- She is coming back from London.
- From London?
She was studying at
Oxford University.
Oxford University?
We used to all live there.
But when Mrs. Malhotra died,
l couldn't stay there anymore.
- So l came back to my country.
- Tina didn't come back with you?
No. She had to finish
her education.
But l miss her, so l told her
to complete her final year,...
...in our college, after all
we are no less than Oxford.
Yes Sir!
You'll take care of Tina, won't you?
- Of course sir.
Happy friendship day.
- Thank you sir.
Who? Rahul?
Yes! l'm the first girl for whom
Rahul has tied a friendship band.
lsn't it exciting.
- Of course.
You know l am tying a friendship
band only for you.
Really Rahul?
- Really Sonia.
That is because you're the
nicest...
...and most beautiful girl
l've known.
Really Rahul?
- Really Sonia.
Oh Rahul! You are telling
the truth, aren't you?
Really Tanya.
- My name's Sonia.
See! l got so lost in
your eyes, l forgot your name.
l just can't believe this Rahul.
- Trust me.
Oh Rahul!
- Oh Sonia!
These fell off.
- You cheat, you liar.
Hey come on... Tanya...
What's your name?
Sonia.
- Go away! Wasted my half-hour.
You don't get tired running
after these stupid girls.
Hey! l don't run after...
l know. Can't you find one girl
with beauty and brains?
Beauty and brains?
Where will l find
such a girl?
l'm only passing my time with these
girls. l haven't found her as yet.
Her?
Her.
l'm looking for a girl who
makes something happen.
Makes what happen?
Makes something happen
in my heart.
Makes what happen?
Something happens.
You won't understand.
When she walks, the
world looks on.
And when she stops, time stops.
And when she smiles...
She, she, she. What will you
do when you find her?
What will l do?
- Yes.
l'll kneel down in front of
her, spread my arms and say...
...Hey! Whoever you are...
l love you.
- Sorry?
Don't be. l love you.
Excuse me.
Tina!
Tina.
Hi! l'm Anjali and you are...
Rahul.
Tina! Right?
- How do you know?
This morning the principal...
Ya! ya! Don't take that old slob's
name first thing in the morning.
So Tina! Your first day in
college?
Yes. She just got back from London.
- How do you know?
Rahul, this morning the
principal...
l just told you not to talk
about that baldy.
Baldy!
- So Tina...
- Where were you studying in London?
- Oxford University.
Ox... How do you know?
Rahul, this morning the
principal...
Yeah! yeah! Let the
Baldy be.
We have this grouch of
a Principal. She's his fan.
Grouch?
- Grouch is right. But forget him.
Tell me how is your
first day in college?
Great.
Good morning Archana.
Feroze... cut your hair.
Short skirt... Oh god.
There's groucho.
Morning Sir.
Short skirts are not allowed
in college, you know that?
You know l just got back
from London...
...and haven't had the time
to unpack.
Sir, it's Tina's first day here,
she's just gotten back...
...from London and hasn't had
the time to unpack.
- She wore whatever she could find.
- And how do you know that?
Sir, l've known Tina
since childhood.
Since childhood? Really?
Really Papa.
- Really Pa... Papa?
Mr. Malhotra l need you here.
Not there sir, in the
staff room.
He's an old slob, a baldy,
and a g...
Great? Good?
Grouch. But he's not
all that bad.
Happy friendship day.
We've only just met,
friendship is a far thought.
So... something happened?
No, she's not my sort.
- Why?
She's not lndian enough.
She's born and brought up in England.
And these London returns
are little weird.
A girl should be one you can
take home to your mother.
No. She's not my type.
She's not my type.
You won't find anyone this way.
Why? You're there.
Me? Just shut up.
lf l don't find anyone else,
l'll marry you.
See. Anyway no one will
marry you.
Here, this is for you.
What's this?
This is our college sweatshirt.
Cool?
Thanks.
Anjali... May l ask you something?
Sure.
Why is everyone staring at me?
Why the boys are staring,
you know!
And the girls are wondering
what the boys are staring at...
...and that is why even they
are staring at you.
And look if you have any
problems,...
...just come to me or
to Rahul.
Rahul? The one who yesterday...
Yeah! He's my best friend and
we sort of rule this college.
This is Rahul.
We have a rule in this college.
We make every newcomer sing.
You know Do Re Me...
Rahul, she's the principal's
daughter.
So! We can't break our rules
for anyone. Right?
But Rahul?
- Shut up,
You have to sing a song for us,
for this college, in Hindi.
Hindi?
Why you forgot how to speak
Hindi in London, is it?
Sorry! One minute.
Rahul how can she sing
a Hindi song?
Why? She's the principal's
daughter.
lf he can't teach her
then how will he teach us,...
...and you shut up.
So, Tina, you will sing
a song in Hindi...
...and fast because we don't
have much time. Right?
Living in London and studying
and growing up there...
...has not made me forget
my roots...
...and you don't forget that.
Hey! You're sitting in my place.
- Oh! l'm sorry.
No it's okay. Hey Adi move.
Good morning class.
Good morning Ms. Briganza.
Today we are going to start
a new lesson - Romeo & Juliet.
An eternal love story.
Before we begin, l want to
ask you all -...
...What is Love?
Tina? You tell us,
What is love?
Me? l don't know.
You tell us, what is love?
Love?
Anyone?
Rahul... What is love?
Love is friendship.
lf she can't be my best friend,
l can't be in love with her.
Without friendship there is no love.
Love is friendship.
Thank you for sharing
that with us Rahul.
Love is friendship.
So! Want to be friends?
Oh my head! My feet.
Oh Sorry Mr. Malhotra,
Ms. Briganza here.
l hope l didn't disturb you...
...and even if l did
l'm sure you don't mind.
Of course not Ms. Briganza.
l called to tell you that
the rehearsals are complete...
...and our college will
come first tomorrow.
Rest of the teams don't stand
a chance. You know what l mean.
This is all because of
you Ms. Briganza.
And it's all for you Malhotra.
Really Ms. Briganza?
Really Malhotra.
Oh Ms. Briganza.
Oh! l have fallen.
And the next college is
our college... St. Xavier's.
What! Oh my god.
They can't make it?
Ms. Briganza, there is a
curfew in their area...
...and they can't leave.
Now what do we do?
Mr. Malhotra let me think
please. ldea...
ldea.
You have to do this or else
you both are going to fail.
Bur Sir, how can we sing and dance.
We don't know anything.
You know these students,
they will skin us alive.
Of course it's a good idea.
Nothing will happen to you.
The students who were
going to perform today...
...have recorded a tape of
their rehearsals.
l'll play that tape and
you just have to move your lips.
Like in the films. Okay.
lt won't work.
What do you mean it won't
work. Of course it will work.
My name is Chin Chin Chu.
Moonlit sky, you and me,
Hello Mr. how do you do?
Anjali, you don't have any concern
for the reputation of your college?
Come on Rahul, it is for
the college.
Come on, help us Tina.
- No, l'm not coming.
What are you saying?
Why are you asking her?
Let's go.
What do l play?
This must be it.
'' You are a foreigner,
You are a foreigner,
You won't be here with us
for long...''.
Looks like, l have put the
wrong tape.
Joe music off.
Lights off.
''l found someone''
''l found someone?''
''What's come over me?''
''Why do l feel so lost?''
''Either l was insane earlier
Or l've just become so.''
''Dreamy eyes and unkempt hair,
What have you done to yourself.''
''l found someone...''
''l've lost my heart...''
''What can l tell you my friends...''
''l am all shook up...''
''l've found someone...''
''l don't know
what's happened to me?''
''People have begun
calling me Romeo.''
''And why is that so?,
We should also know.''
''What's happened to you?''
''Till yesterday l was
quite fine.''
''My heart was filled with
happiness divine.''
''Then why are you upset?
What are you disturbed about?''
''Have you lost something?''
''l have found someone...''
''Who is this disguised
as a cloud?''
''Who has come and taken
over my heart?''
''l would like to say it
but l can't name it.''
''Don't name it but say
something.''
''Give us a slight clue.''
''lt's in my eyes
lt's in my heart''
''What can l tell you friends...''
''l've found someone...''
''l don't know what's happened to me''
''Why am l so lost''
''Either l was insane earlier
or l've become so now''
''Dreamy eyes and unkempt hair''
''What have you done
to yourself''
''l've found someone...''
''l've lost my heart...''
''What can l tell you my friends...''
''l'm all shook up...''
''l've found someone...''.
Anjali, what's wrong?
Don't know why, l am
missing mom today.
How can you say this when
l am here for you?
Stupid, tears don't
solve anything.
Anjali how long have
you known Rahul?
From the first day at college.
You know what l did?
l defeated him in arm wrestling.
Eversince we've been
best friends.
Rahul is your best friend,
isn't it?
l am Rahul's best friend.
Aren't you in love with him?
Hi! Shall l go?
- Where?
Today's Tuesday...
Rahul goes to meet his
relatives every Tuesday.
But l'll stay if you want.
No, you go Rahul. You'll get late.
- l have some time.
No Rahul you'll be late,
go, go, bye!
God please see that l don't fail
in my exams this time as well
l am a bit weak in Chemistry.
So, you take care of it.
Hey! Look forward.
So, your relatives
stay here?
Yes, here... here... here...
So, Rahul Khanna comes
to the temple every Tuesday.
Yes.
- How sweet.
Why did you lie at college then?
Actually boys don't go to
the temple. So!
But you do...
- Yes.
You come every week?
How sweet...
- Don't call me sweet.
Actually my dad used
to say that...
...don't tell this to
anyone at college.
He says that a Man should
bow to 3 women...
...to mom-to one's mother,
to the Goddess Durga... and...
And?
- And...
Wear it. What do they say,
cool, you'll look cool.
l was just trying. Don't
know, how they wear all this.
There's nothing wrong in looking
girlish once in a while.
Here, your mother's letter.
You were missing her, weren't you?
And listen, take this too.
- What is this?
Present.
Hey Tina.
Rahul... what are you doing
here at this hour?
Actually l couldn't sleep and l
thought even you won't be asleep...
...and would be thinking of
me, so l came...
Do you like flowers or chocolates?
- What?
l haven't got either,
l was just curious...
Got chocolates too...
...don't you think
it's too hot out here?
Okay! lf you insist.
Hey sit down... feel at home.
lsn't this the novel where the
butler murders the married couple?
Why are you wasting your time
reading such a thick book, ask me!
Rahul, you didn't finish
your story.
This couple goes on a holiday and
leave their butler behind...
Later one finds out the
butler is...
Not this story...
- Then?
The one you were telling me
at the temple.
Which temple? l don't know
any temple.
The story about a man bowing to
three women,...
...one's mother, the goddess
Durga, and...
- And?
- And...
Papa?
- Groucho...
Shut up. Rahul, papa's coming...
Congratulations.
- Shut up Rahul, go from here.
No... not from there,
go from there.
Rahul!
And.
l'll climb this ladder
and catch the culprit.
What is it?
- Torch.
Throw it.
- Okay.
Groucho...
Who hit me?
A ghost! l'll become a ghost as well.
The ghost will also get scared of me.
Where has the ladder gone?
Malhotra!
Why are you sneaking into
your own house?
Rahul, what are you doing?
- l was on my way to see you.
Me? Why?
Hey look, a shooting star.
Where?
- Not down here, up there!
They say if you make a wish on a
shooting star, your wish comes true.
You believe that?
- Let's try. Come on.
''You came close to me''
''Smiled ever so sweetly.''
''You gave me dreams.''
''These days my heart is neither
awake nor asleep''
''What should l do?
Somethings happen in my heart.''
''Oh! What a feeling this is!''
''What is this unquenchable thirst?''
''l know not, this drunken stupor
of love that's consuming me?''
''No one knows, why one loses
one's peace, when in love''
''What should l do?
Somethings happen in my heart.''
''My prayers have been answered''
''God knows when and how
l fell in love.''
''l wonder how,
l found peace in turmoil.''
''l sit alone, weaving memories.''
''What should l do?
Somethings happen in my heart...''.
Butler's the killer...
Hey! Look at that.
Hi guys! How do l look?
Just like Tina, right?
Here? Okay.
l'm mad, aren't l?
l wanted to look beautiful
like you,...
...but l don't even know
how to.
You are beautiful, Anjali.
You're lying.
Didn't you hear them
laughing?
Those people are...
-...idiots like me.
Actually you're the most beautiful,
because you're very special.
Atleast you're not like those
girls, l keep running after.
You know, you can have
any boy you want.
Anyone?
- Anyone.
But he has to be cockeyed.
Where did you get this
lipstick?
From that girl 'Babli' in
our class.
l'll bash her nicely.
Love is strange,
love is weird.
lt's unaware of happiness
and pain.
Papa.
Rahul.
- Papa?
What papa?
You can't keep secrets from me.
But Rahul? Couldn't
you find anyone else?
Come on papa.
Actually, l would have felt
as bad,...
...even if it were someone else.
Why?
Because l'll have to share
your love with him.
l love you papa.
That is the problem.
l love you too.
Have you told him as yet?
l just feel that Rahul
and Anjali...
Tina, Rahul only loves you...
...and Anjali is his best
friend, nothing else.
No papa.
Somewhere hidden in this
deep friendship is deep love...
...and l don't want to come
in the way of this love.
The whole college knows that...
...Rahul and Anjali are just
friends and nothing else.
Go tell him that you love him.
But l don't even know,
if he loves me.
Don't keep matters of the heart
a secret. Go and tell him.
l love you.
l really love you.
l never thought l'd say
this to someone,...
...but l really love you.
l hope l can get myself
to say this to her...
l wanted to say it to her
so often...
...but couldn't get the
courage...
...and whenever l meet her
l decide to, but... somehow...
Tell whom?
- Tina. who else?
Let's do this again.
l'll be Rahul you be Tina.
l love you.
l love you too.
She'll say the same thing,
won't she?
Ya.
- Come here.
Shall l tell her?
Shall l go right now?
''O! my Lord, love comes with
so much pain.''
''The heart felt remains in
the heart...''
''...and does not escape
from one's lips.''
My first love is incomplete Rifat bi.
My first love is incomplete.
l love you.
''You did not remember me,
there's nothing more left to say.''
''The heart cried and the eyes welled up
There's nothing more left to say'.'
''You did not remember me
there's nothing more left to say''
''The heart cried and the eyes welled up
There's nothing more left to say.''
Mother!
''l gave you all my joys,
gave you all my smiles.''
''Your locks enticed me, bidding
messages of faithfulness.''
''You couldn't care for my love.
There is nothing more left to say.''
''You did not remember me
there's nothing more left to say.''
Anjali... Anjali.
Rahul you look ahead,
l'll look there.
Anjali... Anjali...
One minute.
Where are you off to?
Home.
- What?
l got a letter from mom.
My father's not well...
...and there is lots of work
in the new house.
Have you gone mad? You got
a letter and you're leaving?
You're not going anywhere.
- Rahul, l have to go.
How can you go in the middle
of the term?
Rahul please...
- Go after this semester.
Rahul l have to go.
- You can go after the final exams.
Rahul l might not come back
even for the final exams.
l'm not coming back Rahul.
You are leaving college,
leaving me...
...and you didn't even tell
me about it.
Rahul please...
- l don't want to know.
Rahul l'm going.
- So go.
Rahul l'm not coming back.
- l don't care.
Anjali don't go.
Who'll l play basketball with?
You used to lose everyday, anyways.
But why are you going?
My parents need me...
- And l don't?
Now you irritate Tina. You've
bothered me enough.
l'll fail.
- Then fail.
Anjali...
Stop chasing those stupid
girls now.
l'll miss you Anjali.
- l'll miss you too.
That day l realised that
perhaps...
...l had come between
Rahul and Anjali.
Perhaps, l had come between
two friends...
Anjali's silence told me
everything.
And that day l was sure...
that she loved your father.
Perhaps even l couldn't
love him as much.
Anjali neither called nor wrote.
She had gone away from
our lives. Forever.
You father used to say -
'Love is friendship'.
Yes. l became his friend but
could never be his best friend.
Your father is alone now
but won't say anything.
He needs a friend, he needs
love...
that friend is Anjali,
that love is Anjali.
Get Anjali back into
your father's life.
Return Anjali her first love.
Anjali and Rahul are made
for each other.
This is the truth and
this is my dream.
Will you fulfil your mother's dream?
Get Anjali back in Rahul's life.
Get Anjali back in your
father's life.
Make my dream come true.
Happy Birthday!
Give me five.
This is Malhotra speaking,
using STD on my personal line.
Are you all coming tomorrow?
Yes! As soon as we reach Delhi,
we'll take the Faridabad train.
The one at 4 O'clock?
- Yes! What are you doing?
Me? l was just... nothing.
No... sorry not you.
These Mumbai butlers
are something else.
Okay then, l'll pick you
up tomorrow.
Sure? You forgot last time.
Last time... this time
l'll be there
...by the way, the requirements
for the death anniversary...
Yes! l am getting it all
with me. Don't worry.
Okay then, bye.
- Bye.
Hi Guys!
This is Neelam and you're watching
your favourite show, The Neelam Show.
Like always we are going to
do something new...
We are going to play a game.
Would you all like to play
this game?
lt is said that this game gets
matters of the heart to the fore.
l will say a word...
...and you have to say the first
word that comes to your mind.
But you get no time
to think.
We'll start with you, Clouds?
Sorry. Times up. Clouds?
Rain.
Beautiful?
- Neelam.
Thanks!
Heart?
- Love.
Okay... Love?
-Seema.
What? You love me?
- Yeah!
This game really works.
You saw how real feelings came
rushing out. Now you try this game...
...and we'll be back
after a break.
Stupid game, stupid Neelam.
- Don't call my Neelam stupid.
Okay! Let's play your game.
Okay! Ready, start, go... Sexy?
- Granny.
Papa play seriously.
- Okay.
Clouds?
Papa you can't take so long.
l'm having water. Okay, now
we'll start. Tell me.
Clouds?
- Air.
Mad?
- You.
Home?
- Us.
Love?
- Friendship.
Anjali?
- Sharma.
Sharma?
Who is Anjali Sharma?
Who is she?
Nobody.
Papa, it's my birthday...
Okay. Anjali Sharma studied
in college with me.
ln your College?
She was my friend.
- Friend!
My best friend.
Her name's very nice,
what was she like?
She was unlike any other girl.
She was like one of the boys.
All the other girls spent
time on make up...
...but Anjali played
Basketball.
She wore clothes like me.
Yeah! really.
Anjali was mad. Dressing
up and looking beautiful...
...was just not her scene.
Enough or do you still
want to hear more?
Papa where is she now?
- l don't know.
Anjali, l can't believe that
you are getting engaged.
By the way, Guruji has come
to fix the wedding date.
Show me that one.
How much will you adorn yourself,
Aman's getting impatient.
Tell him to wait, this
bride will take sometime.
''Your groom has been
waiting for long''
''Don't delay anymore
come soon''
''l've come to your doorstep
l've come to take you away''
''l've come to exchange
my heart for yours''
''My every heartbeat has a message
for you... listen to my heart''
''The Bridegroom has come home...''
''Why's the bride shy?...''
''The Bridegroom has come home''
''Oh! dear heart you can't make
excuses... no more''
''Now the bride will have
to go with her groom''
''What's her vermilion
whispering to her?''
''l've got hooked in
his net of love''
''Dear friends, how
did this happen?''
''Tell me, tell me''
''Oh my darling! Your friends
too have a crush on me''
''They won't have much to say
Ask them''
''Go, go, dear liar
Why do you make self praises''
''Your love has something to say
Will you listen to my heart!''
''He is innocent and oblivious. l've
done him a favour by accepting him''
''Someone please convey to him''
''She teases me deliberately l've given
my heart in return of her favour''
''Do convey to her''
''You're not aware of heartbreak''
''Your love has something to say
Will you listen to his heart''
''With henna on your hands
bedecked with jewellery''
''Teary eyed you will make us all,
and leave in the morning''
''We will miss you lots,
We will miss you lots''
''l've come to your doorstep
l've come to take you away''
''l've come to exchange
my heart for yours''
''My every heartbeat has a message
for you... listen to my heart''
''The Bridegroom has come home''
''Why's the bride shy?...''.
This is the old address.
Where do l get the new one from?
What Grandpa, you can't even
do this much for me?
l can do it for you but...
- Really!
The college principal can't even
do this much.
One minute... She would definitely
know where Anjali Sharma is.
l'm sorry. l had promised
Anjali that...
...l would not give her
address to anyone.
We were hopeful that...
l understand sir, but l made
a promise to Anjali.
Rifat bi, l'm also Anjali,
you won't tell me either?
Sir, she's getting engaged
today...
...and her wedding is within
this week.
Her Guruji will finalise
the date today.
The preparations for the
wedding are under way.
You have come very late.
l am also going by
tomorrow afternoon's train.
This marriage cannot happen.
Mummy said so.
Guruji, we need to finalise
the wedding date.
Yes dear.
This is Aman's horoscope.
- Yes.
Aman wants to go to
London this month.
lf you could find a date this
month itself?
This month?
- Yes Guruji.
Sir, if you would have
come earlier...
Yes, but we didn't know...
Anjali's stars have a negative
influence right now.
Until it changes she
cannot get married.
What about next month Guruji?
- Not even next month.
Not before December.
l had heard of God's grace,
today l've seen it.
The child's prayers
have been answered.
Anjali's wedding is
postponed to December.
Anjali, can l ask you something?
- Yes.
Are you happy?
What sort of a question is that?
Of course l'm happy.
l've got engaged.
Aman's really nice, he
loves me a lot and...
But do you love him?
Anjali...
l have already loved mom.
l'm not sure l can do
it again.
Just think of this
as a compromise.
Compromise?
l never thought that my daughter would
marry out of compromise and not love
l'm your mother and l want
you to be happy too.
But a home based on a compromise
is a house, not a home.
The rest is upto you.
Oh! l can't handle this
religious stuff... Yes l can.
Today Guruji is going to chant
hymns and read the sacred book.
Wow! How exciting. This
Guruji will get a...
Why? He has delayed my wedding.
l can't stand these hymns any more.
Even God gets fed up with
so many hymns.
Why? Don't you want to ask
God for anything special?
l've got you...
what more could l ask for?
Well l do want some kids but that
l'm afraid l'll have to do myself.
Behave yourself!
Aman l saw you bare bodied,
exercising this morning.
What are you saying?
- Kammo... even in your old age?
Old!... old must be you.
Don't trouble him.
Do you have a brother?
My Gurpreet is also very pretty.
- What are you saying?
Forget Gurpreet,
My Jaspreet is Ms. Chandigarh.
Ms. Chandigarh or Ms. Sector 11.
Okay come on now, Guruji
has started.
Okay, bye Aman.
Anjali, there is a call for you.
Thanks a lot mother-in-law.
- Welcome son-in-law.
Hello!...
l love you.
Huh... Aman!
- Listen, l have a problem.
What?
- Don't leave me like this.
Aman l don't know who is
on the line.
And anyway you are going to
Shimla for your summer camp.
You're going to Bombay as well.
For 24 hours and you're
going for a month.
Aman, l go there every year
to teach singing and dancing.
Those kids are part of my life.
Even they are a part of
your life.
Only l'm left out.
Why do l get the feeling, you
don't love me?
Because l don't.
And that you don't want to marry me.
- Right, l don't.
Hey! Any tantrums this time...
...and l'll drag you by the
hand to the marriage pandal.
You'll force me?
- lf need be.
You have the guts to do it?
Try me.
l'll stay here with
your aunts.
You go to Shimla
for your Summer Camp.
Summer Camp!
Shimla!
Summer Camp? Shimla?
No way. Too much snow there.
Papa, it's a summer camp.
- Whatever... ls this okay?
Yes. Papa they teach singing
and dancing there...
...and you know l am fond
of that.
Since when have you been fond
of singing and dancing?
l've said no means no.
Papa not fair.
- Let her go.
All kids go to camps. She'll also...
- Mom! l'll handle this okay.
But Rahul try and understand.
l'll also go with her...
Papa l want to go, l want
to go, please papa.
No Anjali.
Shut up. l said no. Now
neither of you will go.
You felt bad? l'm sorry.
lt's okay.
This doesn't mean you're going.
l'm going to the conference.
We'll talk when l get back.
Papa.
- Now what?
You haven't worn your pants.
lt's okay, you wear it
if you want to.
Driver take out the pant... the car.
Anjali... How will we make
your father come to the camp?
Oh Granny! Remember when dad was
in London and l fell sick.
Yes my baby.
Granny. Papa left everything
and came back immediately.
Oops sorry!
- Don't worry about it man, it's okay.
lndian Exporters Conference,
good evening!
May l speak to Aman Mehra please?
Whom shall l say is calling?
- Anjali.
lndian Exporters Conference,
good evening!
Hello! Can l speak to papa?
- Papa?
Your father's not a film star.
Tell her his name.
Sorry. May l speak to
Mr. Rahul Khanna please?
Whom shall l say is calling?
- Anjali.
Certainly, Anjali.
Quickly tell him we're going
and put the phone down.
Hi! Rahul Khanna.
Hello! Aman, l can't hear you.
- l can hear you. Tell me?
Hi sweetheart!
l'm really missing you.
Listen, l'm off to the camp tomorrow.
Where to?
- Summer camp.
Again summer camp. l said
no once to you, didn't l?
Listen. l'm feeling very...
give me a kiss.
This is your mother speaking.
- Look. l don't like these jokes.
My mother passed away
10 years ago.
Why is everyone trying to
pronounce me dead today?
No summer camp, no summer
camp. Understood?
Aman why are you screaming?
That's because l've told you,
you're not going.
lf you say one more thing,
l'll get home and... slap you.
Aman you've gone mad.
Anjali?
Your dad's gone mad.
- Anjali?
Hi! l'm Rahul Khanna.
- Aman Mehra, how're you doing?
l guess because of the same
name she got confused...
Bet you, my Anjali is
prettier than yours.
No! My Anjali is very beautiful.
l'm sure but not as
beautiful as mine.
My Anjali is my 8-year-old daughter.
Shit! You're right.
Your Anjali is prettier.
Dear Papa, How are you? Sorry
we left without informing you...
...but you know how much l love
singing and dancing.
Don't miss me too much.
Love Anjali.
That's not possible for me to do...
Good Morning kids.
l am Col. Almeida, the camp manager.
l'll now measure your height
and weight.
24 - very nice, 30 - very good.
80 - very... what child is this?
Hey! Who are you?
Me? l am Granny.
- Whose Granny?
Anjali's. Who are you?
Col. Almeida. Camp Manager.
No grannies', mummies' and
daddies' allowed on this camp.
So l should've let Anjali
come here alone?
What?
Have you seen Ms. Anjali?
Ms. Anjali!
What?... What?
The British flag in lndia...?
l'll sort him out. Almeida...
You have no shame?
You've hoisted the British flag.
l love England.
My father was an English tailor.
He made this flag.
Britishers went away and
left you behind.
You fool, you should teach
the kids ''My Bharat is the best''.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
Hey! What's your name?
Sorry. What's your name?
- Anjali.
Hey that's my name too. Hi!
Why is your name Anjali?
Perhaps my parents liked
the name.
Why is your name Anjali?
- Perhaps my parents liked you.
Where is this Almeida?
Namaste.
Almeida...
l need your blessings mummy.
- Almeida.
Stop following me.
- Where is the kitchen?
l want to see how you cook food.
- And where is the prayer room?
- Puja has not come on duty today.
Prayer room, where one prays
to the lord.
We don't do that here.
What? There is no prayer
to the lord.
Lord? Who is the Lord?
Counting stars?...
London Bridge is falling
down, falling down... up.
Dear God, How are you?
Please keep papa happy and see that
he doesn't miss me too much.
You know he can't do anything
without me. Okay.
Caught you.
All prayers for papa,
nothing for mama?
Why ask God for anything for mummy?
Why?
- She's with him.
Whatever she wants,
she can ask for it herself.
Hey! Now go to sleep.
Sweet dreams.
Miss you papa.
Hi guys! Welcome to the
Neelam Show...
...and today we are coming
to you live.
There's so much noise here,
so check it out...
Hi Guys! This is Neelam and
you're watching...
... The Neelam Show.
Like always we're going to do
something new and different.
Today's theme is love messages.
Messages anyone?
l have a message.
- We've got one here.
Whom is your message for?
- Superna.
Who is Superna.
- My girlfriend.
Your message?
Look Superna. Don't call me.
l've found someone else.
Hey! Another message.
l want to give a message too.
Like the one he gave...
- And his message is for...
For Anjali.
l love you Anjali.
Why have you left me and gone?
You know l feel lost without you.
Come back or else... just come back.
Please come back.
Who is Anjali?
She's my 8-year-old daughter.
She's gone to some camp in Shimla.
Neelam can you tell her to come
back? She'll listen to you.
Anjali... Papa really loves you.
Come back soon. He misses you.
Come back home. Okay.
Mr. Khanna, meeting for tomorrow
at 11am is confirmed.
Ooops, Mr. Khanna forgot to tell you,
the fax has arrived from London.
Hi Rahul! Party at my place
tomorrow. See you there.
Papa... aachoo.
- Cold...?
Are you feeling okay?
Yeah. Why?
No. You're looking... beautiful,
that's why... Saree.
l didn't know about Tina.
l'm sorry.
How could you know? You just
disappeared.
We changed our residence.
- You changed your friends as well?
When l needed my friend the most,
you were not there.
You didn't marry again?
Couldn't find you... or else would
have married you.
We live once, die once, get
married once and love...
Only once.
You didn't get married either?
Couldn't find you.
Hey! Look a shooting star.
- Still believe in it?
No. You?
- No.
What did you wish for?
Granny.
What news?
- Bad news.
They are behaving like they're
meeting for the first time.
Good night Rahul,
Good night Anjali.
Now what do we do?
You have any idea granny?
The solution now lies in
prayer and devotion.
Oh Granny. Now you only
tell me what to do?
What are you doing?
Have you gone mad?
ls this what l have taught you?
Big boys don't fight, she's a girl.
- Why are you fighting?
She hit me first.
l just said that girls can play
Basketball and he said...
Boo girls can't play Basketball.
He said the truth and you
fought with him.
Why! ln college Ms. Anjali beat
you everyday in Basketball.
Shh! Quiet! Not everyday,
sometimes.
Rahul, you lost everyday.
- Remember Anjali, you lost everyday.
- No Anjali.
Yes Rahul.
Don't lie in front of
the kids.
What l'm lying?
- So am l lying? Liar.
What?
The truth is you could only
Hey! don't call me a cheater.
That's what you are... a cheater.
Anjali, not cheater.
- Rahul is a cheater.
l challenge you right now,
let's play.
Don't be silly Anjali.
Why? Are you scared Rahul?
Rahul Khanna is never scared
of anyone.
We will see.
- We will see.
l'm sure Rahul will win.
- We will see!
You'll lose again Rahul.
l've been practicing for
8 years, l won't lose.
Listen, be careful
with your saree.
Don't hit me.
What was that!
Hey! lf you can't play
atleast don't cheat.
Hey! Don't call me a cheater.
That's what you are -
a teacher... cheater.
''There is a strange girl,
she is a dream...''
''ls she for real or a story''
''Look at this mad one,
she's not changed''
''She is still the same
crazy one''
''There is a strange boy,
he is a dream...''
''ls he for real or a story''
''Yes, yes, this mad one has
not changed''
''He is still the same
crazy one''
''We were close and yet so far
those were strange circumstances''
''Those were strange times
when you were so close''
''Where are you lost, l'm right here
if only you would look''
''l was lonesome even in a crowd''
''You were forever in my memory''
''lf someone stops me now
my heart will brim over''
''l can't stand steady
only you can help now''
''There is a strange girl,
she is a dream...''
''ls she for real or a story''
''Yes, yes, this mad one has
not changed''
''He is still the same crazy one''
''You gave me dreams''
''l am neither awake
nor asleep''
''Somethings happen in my heart...''
''Somethings happen in my heart...''.
Mamata here's your letter.
All your mothers are
complaining that...
you all are not writing to them and
l have complained to your mother...
...that you don't say anything.
Everyone is going to write
home, in front of me.
Here pass these on.
Anjali, come on write a
letter to your mom...
lf you were here, you'd be proud of
Anjali being your daughter.
Because she's so nice.
She has to be, her name's
Anjali after all.
But the best thing about
her is that...
...she looks just like you.
The same eyes, the same face.
l don't find this family
incomplete anymore...
Hello kids! Good morning.
Are you ready?
Say cheese.
Taking photographs without me?
Anyway l'm here now.
My saree looks nice?
- Beautiful.
Shall l sit there?
- Come sit please.
No not there, a little higher.
Where is he sending me? Higher.
Little higher. Yes.
- Shall l sit here?
How do l look?
- Fantastic, beautiful.
What happened?
l don't know. Something
is missing. Something wrong.
Okay now?
lt's perfect. Shoot it.
Excuse me. Now one of
just the 2 of you.
No Mr. Almieda, enough.
Anjali, just one.
Colonel, please colonel, really.
- Come on Anjali.
Wow! How can anyone look
so good?
Yes! Anjali is looking
very nice here.
Really, l didn't even
notice her.
Liar. She's not here so you...
- What to do mother-in-law?
Aman, Since the wedding is
in December,...
...why don't you go back
to London for a while?
l'm not budging from here.
- Why?
l don't trust your daughter.
She's taken forever, to agree
for the marriage. Till we don't...
Tie the knot...
- Yes!
Tie the knot,
l'm not going anywhere.
You love her a lot don't you?
No... Yes.
But l get the feeling
she doesn't love me.
She doesn't, right?
Hey! Mother-in-law...
she doesn't right?
Aman, you've gone mad.
She didn't answer.
Today we are going to play
a new game.
lt's called Dumb Charades.
ln this game there are 2 teams.
This is team A.
And this is team B.
One team will secretly tell
1 or 2 members of the other team...
...the name of a film.
The players have to act
out the film.
And make their teammates
guess the name of the film.
You can't say anything.
Simple! We'll start with team A.
Yes! But how do l do this?
Now look, it's like...
You can't say anything.
Cheating...
This is cheating,
you are a cheater.
Come on! Can't you do this much.
Come on.
Yeah! Everybody yeah!
She's doing it.
''The Colourful One''.
Yeah! That's right.
- ''The Colourful One'' yes.
You were really sexy!
- Thanks.
No, no, no,
l can't do this.
Come on granny...
At this age kids! No. no.
Even l don't see Hindi films,
you know.
l like ''Gone with the wind''.
- Shut up!
Okay son.
But she's my mom.
You go there.
- Where?
Go there...
- Why?
Becuase l'm telling you that's why.
- Granny gone mad.
Yeah! Now bend.
- Bend.
Like this?
Mummy... Madhuri...
''How Are We Related''
lt's my turn.
There's no such film.
There is papa.
- No there isn't.
There is.
- But l haven't seen any such film.
But, hey wait a minute.
Ofcourse, it's a film.
l've seen it myself.
But what is the name
of the film.
Three... three words.
Yes l've understood there
are three words, what else?
Rahul, what are you doing?
- Your son has gone mad.
Rahul l can't understand anything,
what are you doing?
What is it?
l love you...
Do it again...
l love you.
You couldn't do that much?
- No.
l wish you would've,
we would have won.
Come on kids, hurry up get into
the barn...
Hey give me that, thanks.
Have you gone mad?
l'm feeling very cold.
Come with me. l'll take you
to a place.
No music.
l love you.
Hey! l love you too.
Almeida you can't even
fix a leakage. Go on, go up.
Mom, did Anjali come here?
- Her she is.
No... not this one,
the other one.
Here hold this and help.
l want to talk with you.
You call this sty a summer camp?
Hi guys!
Hey, l know you from somewhere.
Telephone man.
What's up dude.
What're you doing here?
ls that your Anjali?
This is my Anjali.
And this, is my Anjali.
You're just like Michael Jordan.
You're too good.
l'm not that good.
l've been beaten.
l don't believe it... Who won?
Anjali.
- Your Anjali.
No, your Anjali.
- My Anjali...
She played basketball?
Tell me, what kind of a girl
was she in college?
She was the life and pride
our college.
Everyone came to her with
their problems.
Well, nothings changed.
Even l've come to her with
my problem.
What problem do you have?
My problem is that
l love her too much, you know.
l know.
What kind of friend are you?
You didn't even come
for our engagement.
You're engaged?
Yes, but with great difficulty.
The wedding is in December,
hopefully.
Hey! Tell your friend...
lf she doesn't marry
me in December...
l'll... marry this basketball.
We live once, we die once,
we get married once and
love...
Men are very weak...
They make principles but
don't realise that...
...no principle can override
the heart.
And we remind these stubborn
weak men that...
...bonds of the heart are based
on feelings not principles.
But these bonds are created...
...by telling the other person
about one's inner feelings.
Tell him what you feel Anjali.
Sometimes saying what one feels
can break one's heart.
But by not saying it you won't,
be happy.
Congratulations and
celebrations,...
...we wish Ms. Anjali a
happy wedded life.
Congratulations and
celebrations...
Anjali, you didn't even
tell me.
Aman told me that you
are getting married.
Are you happy?
You are happy, aren't you?
Having heard this, are
you happy?
l'm very happy.
Then how can l be happy?
l don't understand.
Somethings happen Rahul,
you won't understand.
Somethings happen Anjali...
Uncle, May l ask you something?
- Sure.
Why are you marrying Ms. Anjali?
What? Why? ls something wrong?
Yeah! lt's simple.
You're so handsome.
What happened?
- So good-looking.
Oh! Thank you so much.
But Ms. Anjali is not
that good looking.
You're right. She's dark,
fat and short.
You know, you can get anyone.
Anyone?
- Yes!
Then will you marry me?
- Me? No, no, no...
Why am l that bad?
Then you'll have to find
me a nice girl.
Found her.
- Who?
She.
This MTV one? Hi!
This is the Neelam Show... Yo!
Then what about this Anjali?
You'll have to find someone
for her too.
Found him.
- Found him?
Shall l tell you?
- No, no, no...
Please, let me tell you.
l want to leave tonight itself.
Goodbye Mr. Almeida.
You're leaving?
Please don't go.
You gave this to Tina when
she was beginning a new life.
Today you are going to begin
a new life...
...and l am sure, you and Rahul will be happy.
Start preparing for the wedding.
l don't want to wait anymore.
But Guruji said that there is no
auspicious date before December...
Mother, dates don't bring
happiness, destiny does...
...and no one can change that.
Look! Aman's here and
that too on a mule.
Bindya... Panditji has come. Leave
everything and look after him.
You are Rahul, right?
- Yes, Anjali and l...
l know.
Anjali is getting married today?
Yes. She decided to get married
so suddenly that...
...l didn't get any time to
prepare...
Yes, l'm coming.
Please sit, l'll just be back.
Anjali!
They say if you make a
wish on a shooting star...
...it comes true...
The auspicious time is running
out, please call the bride.
Anjali.
The auspicious time is almost
over, please call the bride.
Anjali, let's go.
l'll drag you to the marriage
pandal, l told you so didn't l?
You know, l always wanted to see
that love in your eyes...
...that l have in mine.
Today, l've seen it,
but it's not for me.
You're mad Anjali.
You've always loved him.
Ever since you've known love,
understood love,...
...You've loved only him.
Rahul is your first love...
...and no one understands
first love more than l do.
You were going to give this
all up for me? Stupid!
How can l come between
this love...
...that was never mine
in the first place?
And anyway, someone told
me that...
...l'm so handsome,
l can get anyone.
Aman l...
- What are you saying...?
Go...
www.moviesubtitles.org