Surprise!
Alex! Do not interrupt me
when I'm daydreaming!
When the Zebra is in the
zone, leave him alone.
Come on Marty, just wanted
to wish you a happy birthday!
Hey man, thanks.
I got something stuck in my
teeth. It's driving me crazy!
- Can you help me out here? Please?
- You came to the right place, my friend.
Doctor Marty tedious is in the house!
Please hop on top of my sterilized
examination table, if you may.
I don't see anything.
Okay, just don't talk with your mouth open.
Right here.
- What a hack is this doing in there?
- Happy birthday!
Thanks man. It was behind
the tooth! You're all right.
It's hardly on a shelf yet.
Here, check it out.
Look at that, look at that.
Look at that, it's snowing.
Ten years old, ha!
A decade!
Double digits. A big 10.
- You don't like it?
- No, no. It's great!
You hate it. I should have
gotten you the Alex alarm clock.
- That's the one, that's the big seller.
- No, no. The present is great, really.
It's just that another year's come and gone
and I'm still doing the same old thing.
Stand over here, over there. Eat
some grass. Walk back over here.
- I see your problem.
- Maybe I should go to law school.
You just need to break out
of that boring routine.
- How?
- Rock the old that,
get out there, who knows
what you're gonna do!
Make it up as you go along!
Add limb, improvise, on the fire!
- You know, make it fresh!
- Fresh? Okay.
- I could do fresh.
- Works for me.
CENTRAL PARK ZOO
Here come the people Marty.
Oh, I love the people!
It's fun people fun time!
Let's go Gloria!
Up and down and open!
- What day is it?
- It's Friday! Feel tricky.
Yes, it's future day,
let's... get up and go!
Ten more minutes.
Come on Melman,
Melman, Melman!
Wake up! Rise and shine!
It's another fabulous morning
in the Big Apple! Let's go!
- Not for me. I'm going in sick.
- What?
I found another brown spot
on my shoulder. Right here!
- See? Right there! You see?
- Melman, you know it's all in your head.
Phil. Wake up, you funky monkey.
Oh I'm gonna be fresh.
Straight up the ground.
Tasting fresh.
Freshelicious.
Zip lock fresh!
Ladies and gentlemen,
children of all ages.
The Central Park Zoo proudly presents...
Show them the cat!
Who's the cat!
...The King of New York city, Alex the Lion!
... Alex the Lion!
It's showtime!
Gather around people,
big show about to start!
Check out the Zebra take
a cannon, that's right!
Just smile and wave, boys.
Smile and wave.
- Kowalski, target report.
- We're only 500 feet from the main zoo line.
- And the bad news?
- We've broken our last shovel.
Right. Rico, you're on lead of patrol.
We need shovels and five more popsickle sticks.
We don't want to rescue another cadet.
- And me, Skipper?
- I want you to look cute and cuddly, private.
Today we're gonna blow this dam.
Yeah! You don't see that on animal planet!
Well show's over, falks!
Thanks for coming!
I hope you thought it was fresh!
I'll be here all week.
In fact I'll be here for my whole life 365 days a year,
including Christmas, Hanaka, Helloween!
Please don't forget to never stay on a pet.
And tip your cabman, cause it's gross.
You, quadropaint.
Sprecken Sie English?
- I sprecken.
- What county is this?
- Manhattan.
- Damn! We're still in New York.
- Aboard! Dive, dive, dive!
- Hey! You on the docks! Wait a minute!
- What are you guys doing?
- We're digging to Antarctica.
- Anhootica?
- Can you keep a secret, my monochromatic friend?
Do you ever see any penguins
running free around New York city?
Of course not. We don't belong
here, it's just not natural.
This is all some kind of
wackdown conspiracy.
We're going to the wide
open spaces of Antarctica.
To the wild!
The wild? You could actually
go there? It sounds great.
Hey! Hold up!
Where is this place?
- Tell me where it is!
- You didn't see anything.
- Right?
- Yes, sir.
Sorry. No, sir.
And now appearance of the day.
The King of New York city, Alex the Lion!
Thank you! Thank you very much!
You guys are great.
You're great prowl.
Give me something here. Thank you.
Thank you! Oh well, thank you!
Underpants!
Everybody get home safe.
This is the life.
That's the spot.
Oh, I'm in heaven.
- Whoo, it's Marty's birthday!
- Open it, just open it!
- What is it? What is it?
- Come on, open it up!
Yeah! Thermometer! Thanks.
I love it Melman, I love it!
Yeah, I wanted to give
you something personal.
You know that was my
first rectal thermometer.
Happy birthday to you!
You live in a zoo.
You look like a monkey.
And you smell like one too.
I say...
Well done, you guys are just
embarrassing me! And yourself!
What are you talking about?
We've worked on that whole week.
Let's go, let's make a wish baby cakes.
- Come on, what did you wish for?
- No, can't tell you that.
- Come on, tell!
- No sirrey, I'm telling you!
It is bad luck! You want some bad luck?
I'll blow it out, but if you wanna be safe...
Ah, Marty would you just tell us?
- I mean really, what could happen?
- Okay.
- I wished I could go to the wild!
- The wild! Wow!
I told you it was bad luck!
The wild? Are you nuts? That is
the worst idea I've ever heard.
- Sounds amatory.
- The penguins are going, so why can't I?
- The penguins are psychotic.
- Come on, just imagine going back to nature.
- Back to your roots, clean air, wide open spaces!
- Well I hear they have wide open spaces in Connecticut.
- Connecticut?
- Yeah, what you got to do
is you gotta go over Grand Central.
And then you gotta take
the metro north train. North?
So one could take the train?
Just hypothetically.
Marty, come on! What would
Connecticut have to offer us?
- Lion disease.
- Thank you, Melman.
- No, no, really I just wanna...
- You certainly don't have this in the wild,
this is highly refined food. Thing
that you do not find in the wild.
You ever thought it might be
more than life and stake, Alex?
He didn't mean that baby.
No, no, no.
Doesn't it bother you guys that you don't
know anything about life outside of the zoo?
- Naa.
- Nope.
Well I mean come on,
that's just one subject.
You have a little smutz
right there in your mouth.
Thanks guys. Thanks for the party.
It was great! Really.
- What's eating him?
- Maybe you should talk to him, Alex.
- You know go off for there and get him a little pep talk.
- Hey, I don't get snow globe, I can't talk that.
- Alex.
- I can see where this is going.
It is getting late. I guess I'm gonna...
- Come on, he's your best friend.
- All right, all right. Okay.
- Good night Marty!
- Good night Gloria.
What a day.
I mean it just really,
really I mean I tell you,
just doesn't get any better than this, you know.
It just did! Even the star's out.
I bet if I could find a star like that in the wild.
Helicopter.
Marty body, listen. Everybody
has days when they think
the grass might be greener somewhere else.
Alex, look here.
I'm ten years old, my life is half over.
And I don't even know if I'm black with
white stripes or white with black stripes.
- Marty, I'm thinking of a song.
- Alex please, not now.
Yes, it's a wonderful song.
I think you're familiar with it.
Oh no!
I'm not listening.
- Start spreading on new.
- I don't know you.
- I'm leaving today.
- He's funny.
Come on, you know,
you know the words.
- Two little words.
- New York.
- New York!
Shut up! Shut up!
I am sleeping here!
- We're not all that turtle you know!
- I'm not give turtle right off, pal!
- Yeah, you won't run on, you stripes!
- You mess with him, you mess with me, coward!
See? Mr. Grumpy Stripes.
- We make a great team. Two of us.
- We sure do. No doubt about it!
What are you gonna do? Just going
running off to the wild by yourself?
- No.
- Good.
- You and me! Let's go.
- What?
The wild! Come on,
you and me together!
It's a straight shot down
Fifth avenue to Grand Central.
We'll grab a train,
we'll head north!
- We'll be back by morning, no one will ever know!
- You're joking, right?
Yeah! I'm joking, of course
I'm joking! Give me a break!
How do you think we're gonna get a train?
Don't do that, you really
had me worried there.
- Well, I guess I'll hit the sack.
- Yeah, me too. I'll need the rest of my voice for tomorrow.
It's seniours day, you know.
I have to roar extra loud.
Give them a little jaw! You
know what I'm talking about?
Good night, Alea.
- They forgot to turn off the ambience again!
- Don't worry, that's cool.
You know, I got it.
Much better.
Come on now baby. My little fillet.
My little fillet with a little fat
around the edges, I like that.
I like a little fat on my stake,
my sweet juicy stake.
- You are a rare delicacy.
- Alex? Alex. Alex!
- What?
- You suck your thumb?
- What is it, Melman?
- Okay, okay.
You know about the blood infection,
and I have to get up every two hours.
Well I got up to pee, and I
looked over in Marty's bed,
which I usually don't do, I don't know why
but I did, and this time I looked over...
- What Melman, what's going on?
- It's Marty. He's gone.
Gone?
What do you mean, gone?
How long has he been working on this?
Marty? Marty?
- He wouldn't fit down there.
- Marty? Marty? Marty?
This doesn't make any sense.
Where would he go?
- Connecticut!
- He wouldn't.
Oh no! What are we gonna do?
We gotta, we gotta call somebody!
Hello? Get me missing animals!
And hurry! We've got a lost Zebra,
probably on the way to Connecticut
by now, and we're gonna need...
- Hello? Hello?
- Wait a second. We can't call the people.
They'll be really mad! They'll get
Marty transported for good!
- You don't bite the hand that feeds you.
- I know that's right.
- We gotta go after him.
- Go after him?
He's not thinking straight. We gotta stop him
from making the biggest mistake of his life!
He's probably out there
lost and cold. Confused.
Poor little guy.
- Melman, come on!
- You know, maybe one of us should wait here,
in case he comes back.
- Oh no, not now.
This is an intervention Melman, we all gotta go!
- What's the fastest way to Grand Central?
- You should take Lexington.
- Melman!
- Okay. We should take Lexington.
- What about the park?
- No, park goes two ways, you can't time the lights.
I heard Tom Wolf is speaking at Linkoln's Center.
Well of course we're going
to throw a poo at him!
I knew we should have taken park.
- Are you sure this is the fastest way to Grand Central station?
- I don't know, that's what Melman said!
Hey you guys! That room has
little things you can wash up and look!
Free mint!
This isn't a feel trip, Melman!
This is an urgent mission
to save Marty from throwing
his life away! Where's the train?
Ah! Here it comes.
What did Marty say to you?
I asked you to talk to him!
I did! I don't understand!
He said: Let's go!
And I said: What are you crazy?
And he says: I'm ten years old!
And then that he has
black and white stripes...
What you gotta do, is you go
straight back down West 42nd.
It's now on your left
after Vander building.
You hit the Chrysler building,
you've gone too far.
Thanks a lot, officer.
Hey! Wait for the light! Freak.
Yeah, that's right. Zebra.
Right in front of me.
- Can I shoot it?
- Negative.
Than I'm gonna need some back up.
- Oh! Next loss of the game.
- I don't know what even to do.
Did that just say Grand Central
station? Or Grand Constipation?
This is it!
Grand Central station!
It's grand and it's central.
This is an emergency situation! Don't panic!
Chill out! It's not
that big emergency.
How do you like that!
Lady, what is wrong with you?
- Get a grip on yourselves people!
- What a bad kitty!
Damn, I missed the express!
Looks like I'm gonna have
to take the Stanford local.
- I got him!
- He's got him!
He's got him!
I got something for you!
I'm okay, I'm okay.
What are you guys doing here?
- Oh, I'm so glad we found you.
- We were so worrying about you!
Don't worry, I'm fine, I'm fine.
Look at me, I'm fine.
You're fine? Oh, he's fine! Oh, great.
Hey, you hear that, Marty's fine.
That's good to know.
Cause I was just wondering...
How could you do this to us, Marty?
I thought we were your friends!
What's a big deal! I was
gonna back in the morning!
Don't you ever do this
again. Do you hear me?
- Do you hear him?
- Guys, we're running out of time!
- Oh Melman, you broke their clock?
- Don't you ever ever do this again!
Come here!
We've been randed up, boys.
Cute and cuddly boys.
Cute and cuddly.
If you have any poo, fling it now!
It's the men.
- Good evening, officers!
- No, no, you don't talk now, okay?
You're not so good with the putting the words
together and their coming out, good thing.
You can thss!
Hey! How you're doing? Yeah!
You know what, everything's cool,
we just have a little situation here.
Little internal situation. Actually
my friend just went a little crazy.
It happens to everybody.
The city gets to us all.
- Just went a little cuckoo in the head.
- Hey! Don't be calling me cuckoo in the head!
Just shush!
I will handle this!
I got him!
Would you get a kind of break?
We're just gonna take my little friend to
your home and forget this ever happened.
All right? No harm no ballet.
Oh, no, no, no. Hey, it's cool!
It's me, Alex. Lion from the Zoo.
What's the matter with him?
Wow! I feel really really weird.
Hey! I love you guys.
I love you so much.
Last night event at Central Grand station
was an example of animal rights
have been shouting for years.
The animals clearly don't belong in captivity.
Now they're to be sent back
to their natural habitat,
where they will live their lives in the
freedom they used to freely desire.
- Hey, little help.
- He's awake! He's awake!
Oh, man!
Oh my head!
Where? What?
I'm in the box!
Oh no! No no!
Not the box!
Oh no, they can't transfer me! Not me!
I can't breathe.
Darkness creeping in.
Can't breathe.
I can't breathe!
Walls closing in around me!
- So alone, so alone.
- Alex!
- Alex are you there?
- Marty?
- Yeah! Talk to me, body!
- Marty! You're here!
- What's going on? Are you okay?
- This doesn't look good, Marty.
- Alex? Marty? Is that you?
- Gloria! You're here too!
- I am loving the sound of your voice!
- What is going on?
- We're rolling in crates.
- Oh, no!
- Oh, sleeping just knocks me out.
- Melman!
- Is that Melman?
- Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I often doors off
while I'm getting a hemorrhoid.
Melman, you're not getting a hemorrhoid.
- Cat skin?
- No! No cat skin!
- It's a transfer! It's a zoo transfer!
- Zoo transfer! Oh, no.
I can't be transferred, I have an
appointment with doctor Goldberg at 5.
- Melman.
- My prescriptions have to be filled.
- Calm down, Melman.
- No other zoo can afford my medical care!
- Melman!
- I am not going nowhere.
Easy Melman. It's gotta be okay,
we are going to be okayze.
No Marty, we're not gonna be okayze.
- Now because of you we're ruined!
- Because of me? I feel to see how this is my fault.
- You're kidding, right Marty?
- You! You kicked off the people!
You bit the hand Marty,
you bit the hand.
I don't know who I am,
I don't know who I am.
- I gotta go find myself in a wild!
- Hey! I did not ask you to come after me.
- Did I?
- He does have a point.
- What?
- I did say we should stay at the zoo,
but you guys!
- Melman, just shut it!
You're the one that suggested this
whole idea to happen in the first place.
- Alex, leave Melman out of this please.
- Thank you, Gloria. Besides Alex,
it is not my fault that we're transferred!
- Melman, shut it.
- Does anybody feel nauseous?
- I feel nauseous.
Melman, you always feel nauseous.
SHIP TO KENYA WILDLIFE
PRESERVE AFRICA.
- Progress report.
- It's an older code Skipper, I can't make it out.
You, higher mammal.
- Can you read?
- No, Phil can read though. Phil!
Ship to Kenya. Wildlife preserve Africa!
Africa. That ain't gonna fly. Rico!
I was the star in the greatest city on earth!
- A King loved by my people!
- Let's just be simple!
- And you ruined everything!
- Love? If the people loved you,
it's only because they didn't know the real you!
- Don't make me come up there, I'd get the wooping on both of you!
- I thought I knew the real you!
- Let's talk about this calm!
- They cancel each other right after you!
- Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
Hey listen! You're gonna
have to be patient!
- Status.
- This time, Skipper
I don't know the codes!
- Don't give me excuses! Give me results!
Navigation!
All right, let me think.
And shut him up!
I did it!
Let's get this tin can turn around!
Guys?
Gloria! Melman! Marty!
- Alex!
- Marty?
- Marty!
No! Wait! Come back, Marty!
Don't go.
Marty? Melman? Gloria?
Marty! Melman! Gloria!
Marty!
Melman! Gloria!
Hey anyone! Hello!
Marty, Melman, Gloria.
Marty, Melman, Marty.
Marty, Melman, Gloria, Marty,
Melman, Marty, Marty, Melman.
Hey! Help!
Get me out of this thing, somebody! Hello?
Get me out of this thing right now!
- Hello? Somebody?
- Melman!
- Alex? Is that you?
- Melman, I got you!
Hang on, hang on, I got you.
Melman! I got you, body!
Wait a second. Wait right there.
- Aha!
- Alex, what are you doing?
Getting you out of the box!
- Relax.
- Alex?
Giraffe quarterback!
- Wait! Wait! Come on! Wait!
- Here comes Alex!
- Hold still!
- Wait! Wait! Wait!
- No! Come on! Come on!
- Here I come!
- Look! Look!
Look, look! It's Gloria! It's Gloria!
Oh hey, it is Gloria.
Gloria!
All righty boys, fun is over.
- Gloria!
- Alex!
- Marty?
- Marty!
You know, I don't really have
anything on me right now.
I'll have to get you later.
To you too!
Marty! Marty!
Alex!
- Marty!
- Alex!
- Al!
- Marty!
- Alex?
- Oh shoot, we were nice team.
- Marty! I'm gonna kill you!
- Hey! Hold on! Hold on!
Look at us! We're all here
together safe and sound.
Yeah, here we are.
Where exactly is here?
- San Diego.
- San Diego?
White sandy beaches, cleverly
simulated natural environment,
wide open enclosures, I'm telling
you this could be the San Diego zoo.
Complete with fake rocks.
Wow! That looks real.
San Diego? What could be
worse than San Diego?
I don't know, this
place is crack I like it!
Oh, I could hang here, I could hang here.
- I'm gonna kill you, Marty!
- Take it easy! Take it easy!
- And then string you!
- Calm down!
Then take you up and clone you!
And kill all your clones!
- Can we take a time out?
- And then, I'll never talk to you again.
Stop it! Look, We're just
gonna find the people
get checked in and have
this mess straighten out!
Oh great, this is just great. San Diego.
How I have to compete with Shamu.
And a smug little grin!
I can't top that. Can't top it!
I'm ruined! I'm gone!
I'm out of the business!
- It's your fault, Marty! You've ruined me!
- Come on, Alex. Do you honestly think
I intended all of this to happen?
You want me to say that I'm sorry?
Is that what you want? Okay, I'm...
- He just shushed me!
- Marty look, just gotta be just a little bit more...
- Shush!
- Don't you shush me!
Do you hear that?
Don't you hear that?
- I hear it now!
- When there's music, there's people.
- We go right to the head.
- A sidewalk will be nice.
- Yeah, what a dump!
- We shall call it the San Dilemo zoo!
First they tell you hey! We gotta
this great open plan thing.
Let me handle it for a while!
Next thing you notice
close in your hair, and everybody's
plugging everybody.
This boy has got a gross on it!
This way guys, come on!
Oh, no!
Okay, let's make a good
impression on the people.
Smiles everyone, let's get it together.
Is that the best you can do, Melman?
- Oh, I'm not smiling, it's gas.
- Okay well great. Let's make gas look good.
- It's not people. It's animals!
- California animals!
This is like a puppy party!
I like to move it move it!
You like to...
Move it!
I like to move it move it!
You like to...
Move it!
I like to move it move it!
You like to move it move it!
She likes to move it move it!
We like to...
Move it!
Hi there, Julian with the word!
Original King Julian, what a des man!
I like my jam, I love to move my body!
When you move your body,
you move it nice and sweet and sassy.
- What kind of zoo is this?
- I just saw 26 blink hoco violations.
- I'm loving San Diego, this place is off to Shizam!
- Twenty-seven!
What kind the bad chimps at it?
Wait, where's Alex?
What happened to him,
he was right behind us. Were he right behind us?
- I don't know where he's at, but he's missing one hack of a party!
The Foosa! The Foosa!
The Foosa are attacking!
I hate spider webs.
Yeah, thanks a lot, guys.
Thanks for waiting up.
I really appreciate it.
Hey hi. We just got in from New York
and we're looking for a supervisor,
because we've been sitting on
that beach back there for hours.
And nobody's even bothered to show up.
I don't know how things
normally run around here,
but obviously there's been some
sort of major screw up, which is cool.
So if you just point us towards,
we've been straight to offices, or just...
Well how do you do?
Spider! Spider on my back!
- Maurice, did you see that?
- He scared the Foosa away.
Get it! Get it! Get it!
Where did he go?
King Julian, what are they?
What are they!
They are aliens. Savage aliens
from the savage future.
They've come to kill us!
And take our women!
And our precious meadows!
Get up, Mort. Do not be near
the King's feet, okay?
Shh! We're hiding. Be quiet
everyone. Including me.
Shh! Who's making that
noise? Oh, it's me again.
- Come on boys!
- Stop it! Enough!
I think you got it.
I thing she got it.
- Is it still on me? I hate spiders.
- That's okay, he's gone.
They are savages!
Tonight we die.
The feet! I told you!
Didn't I tell you about the feet?
He did tell you about the feet.
- Wait. I have a plan!
- Really?
I have devised a gunning test.
To see whether these are savage killers.
No!
- Hi there!
- You let me handle it.
Alex handles it.
Marty does nothing.
Hi there!
- Oh, sorry. No, no!
- Oh Alex, what did you do?
Stop, stop. It's okay.
It's okay. I'm just a
silly, just a silly lion.
Oh, you poor little baby, did
that big mean lion scare you?
He did? He's a big bad
old puddy tad, isn't he?
Come on, mama hold you.
They are so cute from a reasonable position.
You're sweetest little thing,
I just wanna dump him in my coffee.
- They are just a bunch of pansies.
- I don't know, there's still something
about that one with the crazy
hairdo that I find suspicious.
Nonsense, Maurice! Come on everybody!
Let's go and meet the pansies!
Presenting your royal highness our illustrious
King Julian the 13 self proclaimed
Lord of the Lemur etc. etc.
Hurray everybody.
He's got style!
What's he like, King of the kiwi pigs?
I think it's a squirrel.
Welcome, giant pansies! Please
feel free to bask in my glow!
- Definitely a squirrel.
- Yep, a squirrel.
We thank you with enormous gratitude
for chasing away the Foosa.
- The Hoosa?
- The Foosa.
They're always annoying us by
trespassing, interrupting our parties,
and ripping our limbs off.
- Yes, sounds good. Look, we're just
- We're just trying to find where the people are.
- Oh, my! What big teeth you have! Man!
Shame on you, Maurice! Don't you see
that you've insulted the freak?
- You must tell me, who the hack are you?
- I'm Alex. The Alex.
- And this is Gloria, Marty and Melman.
- Say just where are you giants from?
- We're from New York and we...
- All hail the New York Giants!
New York Giants!
What are we doing, some
sort of inbreeding program?
I say we just gotta ask these
bozos where the people are.
Excuse me, we bozos
have the people of course.
- Hey, the bozos have the people!
- Oh. Well. Great! Good!
They're up there.
Don't you love the people?
Not a very lively bunch though.
- So do you have any alive people?
- No. Only dead ones.
I mean if we had a lot alive people here,
it wouldn't be called 'The Wild', would it?
The wild?
Hold up there a second.
You mean like the living in mud hut?
Wipe yourself with leaf type wild?
Who wipes?
Would you excuse me for a moment?
Get me out of here!
We gotta get out of here!
- Alex!
- Help!
- What are you doing?
- I'm swimming back to New York!
I know I can't swim, but I have to try!
- You can't swim!
- There are more chances!
Nature! It's all over me! Get it off!
I can't see! I can't see!
I can see!
Okay look, there's obviously
just been a little mistake.
I'm sure the people didn't dump us here on purpose.
As soon as they realize what happened,
they will come looking for us, right?
Yeah, right.
You know something?
I bet they are already on their way.
250 KILOMETRES PLUS SOUTH
Well boys, it's gonna be
ice cold sushi for breakfast.
Rico!
Well, since I'm doomed to die
on this forsaken island,
I, Melman Mankowitz being of
sound mind and on sound body
have divided my estate equally
among the three of you.
- Oh, sorry Alex.
- Hey! On the train. Nice work, Melman.
No, it's not on the train, it's a grave.
- You sent Melman to his grave, are you happy?
- Oh, come on. This is not the end.
This is the whole new beginning!
- This could be the best thing that's ever happened to us!
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
- This is not the best thing that's ever happened to us!
- Yeah! You've abused the power of the birthday wish
and brought this bad luck on all of us.
Why did you tell your wish?
You're not supposed to do that!
Wait a minute, I didn't want to tell you. Remember?
You guys made me tell you.
Besides, this isn't bad luck, this is good luck.
Look around. There's no fences,
no scedules, this place is beautiful!
Okay, I've got to stop this.
This is your side of the island,
and this is our side of the island.
That is the bad side where you can jump
and skip around like a magical pixi horse.
And do whatever the hack you
wanna do all day long. And this,
this is the good side of the island, for those
who love New York and care about going home.
- Come on.
- No, no. Back, back. Back!
- You know what, this isn't good.
- Okay! You all have your side,
and I'll have mine. And if you
need me, I'll be over here.
On the fun side of the island.
Having a good old time!
This is the fun side! This is the fun side!
We're all gonna have a great time
surviving until we go home! I love
this side! This side is the best!
That side stinks! You're on
the Jersey side of this pool!
- Well now what do we do?
- Don't worry Melman I have a plan to get us rescued.
Can't wait to see that look on
Marty's face when he sees this!
Just look at him, he's helpless without us.
Shut up, Spolden!
I've been standing here for hours man!
How long do I have to pose like this?
She is finito!
I define any rescuable within a
million miles to miss this baby!
When the moment is right, we will
ignite the Beacon of the Liberty!
And be rescued from this awful nightmare!
What do you think? Pretty cool, ha?
How's the liberty fire going, Melman?
- Great! Idiot.
- I heard that.
Why can't we just borrow some of Marty's fire?
That's wild fire! We're not
using wild fire on Lady Liberty!
- Now rub, Melman!
- I've been doing, I can't!
I can't! I can't do it!
I can't do it!
Fire. Fire!
Fire! Fire!
- Fire!
- No, no!
Fire!
Jump! Alex, jump!
Don't worry, cats always
land on their... face.
What kind of cat are you?
You maniac! You burned it up!
Darn you! Darn you all to hack!
Can we go to the fun side now?
Everybody calm down!
Come into this cave.
Everybody please calm down.
You over here and you over there.
FASTEN SEAT BELTS
Calm down people, okay?
Now presenting your royal highness
bla, bla, etc. etc. Hurray, let's go.
Now everybody! We all have
great curiosity about our guests.
The New York Giants. Yes, Willy.
- I like them.
- I like them, I like them.
I liked them first before
I even met them I liked them.
- Yes, yes.
- You have them compare to how much I like them.
Ah shut up, you're so annoying!
Now! For as long as you can remember
we have been abduct and
eaten by the dreaded Foosa.
The Foosa!
The Foosa are attacking!
TO SERVE LEMUR
It's a good book!
- Please, please. Maurice.
- Shh! Quiet!
Come on yo, they ain't
attacking us this very instant.
So my genious plan is this.
We will make the New York Giants
our friends. And keep them close.
Then with Mr. Alex protecting us, we will be safe
and never have to worry about
the dreaded Foosa! Ever again!
I thought of that!
I thought of that! Yes! Me!
Hold on, hold on everybody.
I'm just thinking now.
I mean does anyone wonder why the
Foosa was so scared of Mr. Alex?
I mean maybe we should be scared too.
What if Mr. Alex is even worse than the Foosa?
I'm telling you that dude
just gives me the hibichivis.
Maurice, you did not raise your hand.
Therefore your speech coming will
be taken from the record.
Does anyone else have the hibigibis?
No! Good. So shut up!
When the New York Giants wake up,
we will make sure that
they wake up in paradise.
Now who'd like a cookie?
HELP
Al, Melman and Gloria are over
there having a good time.
- It's fun side for one more.
- No thanks.
Look, I've been thinking.
Maybe if you give this place
a chance I don't know.
- You might even enjoy yourself.
- Marty, I'm tired. I'm hungry.
I just wanna go home.
Could you just give it a chance? Think about it.
It really isn't the fun side without you.
HELL
NO SOLICITING
- Shh! It's him! Who is it?
- It's the pizza man. Who the hack do you think it is?
- Yes? Can I help you?
- Can I come to the fun side?
- Beg your pardon?
- I've been kind of a jerk, Marty.
But I've been thinking about
what you said and... I'm sorry.
Welcome to castle del Voir! Take
a load off! Hey, watch your feet.
WILD SWEET WILD
- Alex!
- Me castle is you castle!
- Very impressive.
- Hey, have a drink!
- It's on the house!
- This is sea water!
Oh, you don't swallow it. It's just
temporary till the plot is done.
Hey, you all look hungry. How would
you like some of nature's goodness?
- You have food?
- The fun side special, coming up!
See weed on a stick!
- Sea weed?
- On a stick!
You don't love it till you try it!
- So good.
- Well thanks!
Does kind of hit the stomach, does it?
Well maybe I could use a little lemon.
No, it's great.
It's really great.
- Does it get any better than this?
- But it does! Check this out!
- Wow! Would you look at that.
- It's like billions and billions of helicopters.
- It's a shooter star. Make a wish! Quick!
- How about a thick juicy stake?
You know what Alex? I promise you I'm gonna
find you a stake tomorrow that kills you.
- Thanks, Marty.
- It's getting late. I guess I'm gonna...
I think I'm gonna hit the sack too.
Sweet dreams everyone.
Alex!
- What are you doing?
- 27, 28, 29, 30.
Thirty. Thirty black and
only twenty-nine white.
Looks like you're black with white stripes
after all. Good night to us all. Good night.
You see Maurice. Mr. Alex
was grooming his friend.
He's clearly a tender loving thing.
How can you have the
hibijibis for Mr. Alex. Look at him.
- He's so cute. And flashy.
- I don't think he was grooming him, Julian.
- Looked more like he was tasting him to me.
- Suit yourself, no matter. I don't care it.
Soon we will put my excellent plan to action.
All we have to do is wait
until they're deep in their sleep.
How long is this going to take?!
ANTARCTICA
Well this sucks.
Wake up, Mr. Alex.
Rise and shining.
Wakey, wakey Mr. Alex!
Wake up, Alex!
You suck your thumb?
What a hack is going on?
What is this?
Don't be alarm, giant freaks.
While you're asleep,
we simply took your
little corner to heaven.
- Welcome to Madagascar!
- Madawhoa?
- What?
- Not whoa. Gascar.
- Marty. It's...
- It's just like my meadow. Back at the zoo.
- No fellow. That is the real deal right there.
- I think that is not a bad view.
I mean that's the thing that
you were always looking at,
but it's actually there,
that's like the real version of...
How about a run?
Let's get our blood pumping,
get those lungs breathing at all
this fresh air, who's with me?
Ah, no. I really I don't
think I can. You're at!
Hey! Wanna play around?
- Got you there!
- Come here!
Hey, stop that!
Hey, you're crazy!
Okay Marty, I'm at.
- I'm at, you win.
- Come on, Alex. Get in the groove.
I haven't eaten in two days.
My blood sugar is real low.
- I just don't have the energy.
- I don't think that's your problem.
First of all that's not
how you run in the wild.
Let's go man! Put your rubber to the roll!
You just have to let up that inner lion!
- Now, who's the cat?
- Marty, I really don't...
You are! That's who!
Come on, here we go!
That's it. Now let's
build up some steam!
- You're the cat.
- Who's the cat?
Who's the cat?
I'm the cat!
Surprise!
You're at! You're at!
Can't you get. Cat's too quick.
I feel like a mile high for straw me,
I'm rye I'm the fly from the Deli in the sky!
- Let's go wild!
- Now you're talking!
Man, I feel... great!
Marty, Marty, Marty!
Like you said baby, it's...
- Crack a like it! Ain't that right, Melman!
- Oh, yeah! Yeah!
I'm in heaven!
You see, Maurice Alex is now a friend
and the Foosas are nowhere to be seen.
It could be said that my plan is
working in a very good kind of way.
Alex, you gotta try something!
- I feel good! I feel like a King again!
- King?
Yeah! You should see that!
Come on Alex, why don't
you show him some yawn?
- No, I really don't think I can... Okay.
- Ladies and gentlemen, primates of all ages,
the wild proudly presents
the King! Alex the Lion!
Eat that, fellows!
Yeah! The King is in the house!
If he's a King, then where's his crown?
I've got the crown. Got the very
nice one! And it's still on my head!
The roar man, the roar!
Wow! I've never heard that one before!
Yeah go wild man, come on!
Bring up the wild!
Excuse me,
you're biting my butt!
- No, I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
- Alex, what did you do?
- He bit me on the butt!
- No. I didn't. Did I?
- You kind of did.
You just bit me on the butt!
What a hack is wrong with you?
- Why did you bite me?
- Man, that's because you are his dinner?
- What?
- Excuse me?
That's dumb. Dumb, dumb, Maurice.
What is the simple bite
on the buttocks among friends?
The party is over, Julian.
- Your brilliant plan has failed.
- What are you talking about?
Your friend here is what we call a
deluxe model hunting and eating machine.
- And he eats stake. Which is you.
- Get out of here.
Okey dokey, Maurice.
I admit it, the plan failed.
All is lost! We're all doomed.
The Foosas will come back and
goblbe us with their mouths!
- Because we are all stakes.
- I'm stake! Me, me, me, me!
Mr. Alex cannot stay here.
He belongs with his own kind.
- On the Foosa side of the island.
- By the power invested in me,
by the law of the jungle,
bla, bla, bla, bla.
- Be gone!
- What? Come on.
- Do I look like a stake to you?
- Yeah.
See, I told you I don't look like...
- Wait, wait, what did you say?
- Oh, yeah!
- He's going savage.
- Run for your lives!
Marty, run!
- A bullseye. Excellent shot, Maurice.
- Thank you.
Marty? I'm so sorry, Marty.
What is wrong with me?
Oh, no. What have I done?
It's true. I'm a monster.
I gotta get out of here.
Foosa Territory
1 Mile
What have I done?
This is a nightmare!
It's all my fault.
- Now because of me we've lost Alex.
- What are we gonna do?
We're gonna find the way to help him,
that's what we're gonna do.
Come on, we are New Yorkers, right?
We're tough. We're greedy.
We're adoptable!
And we are not going to lay
down like a bunch of Melman!
- No, we're not.
- Oh, Gloria!
That was not me, okay?
That was the boat. The boat!
The boat? The boat's come back for us!
Come on guys, we're gonna flag it down!
- Here it is!
- Over here!
Come on, give me a lift!
Come on, lift me up, lift me up!
- Help! Help! Help!
- Over here!
My head. My head. Guys.
You have no idea how much this hurts.
Look! It's turning!
It's coming back!
- Yes, this way!
- Come on, baby!
You guys flag down that
boat, I'll go get Alex!
Hold on then. You cannot
go back there by yourself.
Come on, I know Alex. When he hears
we're rescued, he'll snap right out of it!
- The people are coming, they can help us.
- Melman's right. The people will know what to do.
Now come on, we gotta flag down that boat.
- Now this is more like it!
- You! Where are the people?
We killed them and ate their livers.
Got you, didn't I? Just get
them all the people down.
They are on the slow light boat to China.
Hey! I know you two.
Where's that psychotic lion?
- And my monochromatic friend?
- Marty, he's right...
Where did he go?
He was right behind us.
He went back for Alex,
he's gonna get himself killed.
Boys, my monochromatic friend is in danger.
Looks like we have a job to do.
Captain's log. Bargain
the hostile environment.
Kowalski, we'll need to win the
hearts and the minds of the natives.
Rico, we'll need special
technical equipment.
We're gonna face extreme peril.
Private probably won't survive.
Alex, come on Alex!
Come on to here, we can go home!
Alex!
- Alex.
- Marty?
Step out of it, Alex. Boat came
back. We can get out of here!
We can go back to civilisation and
everything will be just like it has to be!
Stay back. Please.
I'm a monster.
Alex, you're no monster.
You're my friend.
We're a team, you and me, remember?
I don't wanna hurt you.
Alex, I can't leave without you.
Alex, I'm thinking of a song.
It's a wonderful song.
I'm sure you're familiar with it.
Start spreading the news.
I'm leaving today.
We are a great big part of it.
Come on, you know the words.
Two little words!
Please don't make me sing this by myself.
You really don't wanna hear
me sing this by myself.
Alex?
Come on here for a minute.
Hey Alex, little help.
Help me!
Alex!
Help me! Anybody help me! Somebody!
- Melman?
- That's right, baby.
Run!
- What's the plan?
- This is the plan!
This is the plan?
Foosa hold!
Foosa ha!
Foosa uh!
Come and get it!
- There's too many of them, Skipper!
- It's been a real pleasure serving with you, boys.
- Alex?
- That's my kill! Mine.
Alex hungry.
Alex eat.
Pss!
It's showtime.
Thanks for not giving up on me, Marty.
Man, you almost gave me a heart attack.
You can't just come up
here and sneak upon me.
We're getting out of here.
Guys, just go with me on this.
Like I said it's showtime.
My kill! They're all mine!
- That's the king of the beast!
- Please leave us Mr. Lion.
Beauty and savagery beyond comprehension!
I am too young to die!
And you!
Are you maximalist?
You better run for your lives!
- Somebody call a cop!
- He's psychotic!
This is my territory! Understand?
I never ever wanna see you on my turf again!
Yeah! You're the cat!
I did it! Give me some love!
The plan worked!
The plan worked! I'm very clever!
I'm the one, baby!
Come on, time to robot!
I am a very clever king.
I am supergenious.
I am robot king of the monkey kin.
So, what's for lunch?
- Close those eyes!
- Why do I have to close my eyes?
- Do it!
- They're closed.
- Higher!
- Yes, sir.
- No peeping!
- All right, they're closed.
Rico.
Open that hatch.
Fire in the hole!
Now chew!
Chew like you mean it.
- And?
- Well?
- Pretty good, right?
- There's always plan B.
This is better than stake.
I love it! I love it!
The kitty loves the fishy.
Can I propose a toast?
Now he may be a pain
in the butt at times,
trust me, I know.
But this cat, who to me without a doubt,
he has heart as big
as his stomach! To Alex!
To Alex!
Enough!
Well, what do you guys think?
Shall we head back to New York?
I don't know, Marty.
I mean this is your dream.
- You're sure you wanna leave?
- I don't care where we are.
As long as we're together,
it doesn't matter to me.
Well, in that case. Yo, Rico!
I'll take three hundred orders! To go!
Yes, yes. But before you leave,
I have an announcement to make.
So shut up everyone please. Thank you.
After much profound
brain things inside my head,
I have decided to thank you
for bringing peace to our home.
And to make you feel good, I'm gonna
give you this lovely party gift.
No, I couldn't. Really I can't take your crown.
That's okay, I've got a bigger
crown. It's got a gecko on it.
Look at them shake!
- Bye, little fuzz buggots!
- Thanks for everything!
Okay, bye-bye now.
Bye-bye! See you later, crocodiles.
Maurice, my arm has died, wave it for me.
Faster, you nodding it like a monkey.
You know, by the time we get back to New York,
it's gonna be the middle of the winter.
So I was just thinking, why rush?
Maybe we could make a
few side stops along the way?
- Maybe Paris?
- You just read my mind!
- Let's think, Spain.
- What about Fiji?
Cool! Canada, can we? Cheap meds.
You know, I wouldn't mind coming
back here for a visit sometime.
- Yeah, I can do that.
- You can say that again.
Skipper,
don't you think we should tell
them that the boat's out of gas?
Na, just smile and wave boys,
smile and wave.