Love is blind
As far as the eye can see
Deep and meaningless
Words to me
Easy, lover
I need a friend
Road to nowhere
twists and turns
But will this never end
Well, my dear
you know that he pleases me
But short time solutions
ain't no resolution
There ain't no release for me
Too mch of something
Is bad enogh
Bt something's coming over me
To make me wonder
Too much of nothing
Is jst as tough
I need to know the way to feel
To keep me satisfied
Unwrap yourself
From arond my finger
Hold me too tight
Or left to linger
Something fine
Bilt to last
Slippedp there
I gess we're running
Out of time too fast
Yes, my dear, you know
He soothes me
Moves me
There's no complication
There's no explanation
It's just a groove in me
Too mch of something
is bad enough
Bad enogh
Bt something's coming over me
To make me wonder
If too mch of nothing
Is jst as tough
Jst as tough
I need to know the way to feel
To keep me satisfied
What part of "no"
Don't yonderstand
I want a man
not a boy
Who thinks he can
Well done, girls.
Foarte bine.
Despre ce vb?
Nici mãcar nu te uitai, Cliftord.
... Ba da, mã uitam.
- Nu minþi. Chiar nu te uitai.
I sensed the vibes.
I have an excellent vibe sensor here.
... Right.
... He doesn't love us anymore.
Yes, I do love you
like a wildebeest...
loves tive lionesses
chewing at his legs.
Hello, I'm Piers Cuthbertson Smythe.
Today I'm spending
the tirst ot five days...
with the Spice Girls.
Elton!
Good to see you.
- Great glasses, Elton.
... Thank you very much.
Girls, we've got to go.
Sorry, Elton.
Any second now, the Spice Girls
will be stampeding down this corridor...
in a trenzy of chaos and energy...
which ot course
has become their hallmark.
What, chickens? How many?
I thought you said they'd
be coming down this way.
I never said that.
- You want me to cut?
... I think that would be wise.
Don't worry about tans here.
They're all round the tront.
They're sorted.
Come on and do it
... Girls, it's Andy.
- Not up the skirts, thank you.
What was that you said, Clitford?
Do what your mama said
- Bye!
- Let's go. Come on.
Hands oft my flutfy toys.
- Nobody come in my bit.
- Don't touch my wardrobe.
Can we get changed, everyone?
We're gonna be there in 15 minutes.
Dennis, Albert Hall.
We're heavy and rolling.
Come on and do it
Don't care how you look
It's just how you feel
Horoscopes.
I don't believe star signs.
You wouldn't,
because you're an Aquarian.
- Aquarians don't believe in anything.
... I don't believe that either.
Oh, no!
I can't tind my boots.
I think I've lost them.
It's always the same.
I never know what to wear.
It must be really hard tor you,
Victoria...
trying to decide whether
to wear the little Gucci dress...
the little Gucci dress...
or the little Gucci dress.
Exactly.
I know. Why don't you wear
the little Gucci dress?
Good idea. Thanks, Emma.
... There they are!
... What?
You're wearing my boots, Geri.
Oh, yeah.
I don't know how that happened.
Typical Leo, that is.
Borrowing stutt without even asking.
That's Capricorn.
Don't you be starting
on Capricorns.
- That's it. You've had it.
- Have them back!
I don't want them.
Get ott!
- Excuse me!
... What?
- What do you think ot this one?
- It's great.
Now hear this.
There's a press conference coming up.
That means smiling at the cameras
and answering a lot ot dumb questions.
That is all.
It really is tremendously exciting.
We're breaking the news right now.
Next Saturday, 8:00, for the
tirst time ever, the Spice Girls...
are gonna pertorm live for the
very tirst time at Albert Hall.
- Are you excited, girls?
... Very excited.
We're working with a new band.
It's gonna be tantastic and will be
broadcast live throughout the world.
How many countries
are we talking about?
... Millions.
- Or maybe even more.
Do you have a message
for the multitude ot f ans out there?
Yes.
Goes out to the people in France.
They're huge in Portugal.
To all the people in Leeds......
Northerners!
I don't have an idea what that means,
but it's gonna be great.
I'm excited.
My mum's excited.
They are adorable.
Yohaven't even shaved for us,
have yo, Jonathan?
- I got what you want.
... Shut up and watch this.
These are the Spice Girls.
I've seen them.
- I like the blond one.
... No.
- Sporty.
- Yeah, Sporty one's good.
This is what our movie
should be about.
They're young, they're cute,
they're hip, they're wacky.
... But can they act?
- What act?
Did anyone care
it Marilyn Monroe could act?
All they cared
was she in focus.
I just got an idea,
and you're gonna love it.
I can see it very clearly.
It's the Spice Girls.
There's tive ot them.
- And they're singers.
- I love it. We pitch this atternoon.
- Yes, Chiet?
- How are the girls, Clifford?
Ready for show time on Saturday?
Just going to rehearsals.
They're hot, Chiet.
They've got tire in their eyes
and great big shoes on their teet.
I'm telling you, Chief,
they're raring to go.
Well, remember that now
is the dangerous time.
They've had a lot of success
very quickly...
so get ready for the backlash.
When the speeding melon
hits the wall...
it is Christmas tor the crows.
Of course it is.
Do you want me to go atter
the paparazzi, Chiet?
I could start kicking asses,
if you like...
stir things up a bit.
There's no need
tor any stirring.
Put a couple ot cats
among a tew pigeons.
Leave the pigeons alone.
Watch the feathers fly.
Get some blood on the walls!
Sorry, Chiet. Just an idea.
There will be time tor that
soon enough.
Remember, the drummer
who is without sticks...
has no backbeat.
Absolutely.
Right, puss?
... What did he say?
- I haven't a clue.
But I know that he's right.
Drummer?
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
I'm giving you everything
All that joy can bring
- This I swear
- I give you everything
And all that I want from you
Is a promise
you will be there
Say you will be there
Now, remember, the camera
is the window to the soul.
... Window to the soul.
... Through the eyes, obviously.
What I want to do is take my audience
on a journey into the mind's eye...
of the Spice Girls...
tocus on their deeper subconscious.
... Deeper subconscious.
- That's it, Enzo. Got it? Great.
Track.
- I think we'll need a longer lens.
... BAFTA, BAFTA.
- Hold on. What's going on?
- What are you doing?
... Sorry, my tault.
... Sort your fingers out.
- You left your boxing gloves on?
... Let's do it once again, please.
That was absolutely pertect
without being actually any good.
Once again, then.
Hi, Nic.
Please, let's keep
the momentum going.
Obviously atter a short break.
Are you all right?
Look at that emotion,
that real, raw emotion.
Come on, boys.
Capture that magic.
Quickly!
How are you feeling?
Oh, all right,
except my back's done in...
my tront's done in,
my insides are wrecked...
and I haven't seen my feet tor weeks,
but I hear they're really f at too.
- They are. Not.
- How's baby?
How would you teel being carried around
all day in a nice, squishy water bed?
Very lucky, I think.
It kicked.
When's it due?
... Last week.
- You want to charge it storage.
So how's Trevor?
- He's gone. Trevor's lett me.
... I don't believe it.
... Sound running.
- Excuse me.
Would you mind
not tilming, please?
... Cut.
- I knew Trevor was irresponsible.
... But he's now gone and proved it.
- What a complete...
What I want to do with this documentary
is show the real Spice Girls.
I want to break through
the show business side.
I want to crash right through it
and reveal the truth.
That's fine, as long as you crash
through the showbiz f acade on schedule.
Don't get in anybody's way.
Yes, well, a smile costs nothing.
Don't worry, Nic.
It'll be all right.
- Oh, no.
... What?
- I think I am getting broody.
- Oh, no.
Just wait till you lot
start having kids.
That will be really weird.
How my Gloria gets her clothes
so dirty, I'll never know.
Bless her.
My poor back.
I don't know how you can have
any more ot them kids.
- You've got six already.
... Is it six?
They're so cute when they're little,
then they grow up to be real bleeders.
Thank God tor boarding school.
I only see mine once a month.
- Our Terry goes to me...
- Cheers.
He goes,
"Ma, I wanna be a singer."
I said, "Lad, go to college,
get yourselt a proper job."
Does he listen? No.
They never do, though, do they?
I mean, you know.
Darling, kids today
don't know how lucky they are.
Brucey, Demi...
will you turn
that bloody racket down?
Hate to interrupt.
There's a small matter
ot an extremely live gig on Saturday.
- All right. We're coming.
... I don't want to.
- Take care.
- Jools, we're coming.
I need a wee.
I'm giving you everything
All that joy can bring
Yes, I swear
Last time
that we had this conversation
I decided we should be friends
- But now we're going rond in circles
- Quick! Baby Spice. Get the shoes.
- Which one's Baby?
... The blond one.
Now you tell me
that you've fallen in love
Well, I never, ever thoght
that would be
This time
you gotta take it easy
Throwin' far too much
emotions at me
Bt any fool can see
They're falling
Posh one.
- Which one is her?
- The one that looks posh.
I'm giving you everything
All that joy can bring
Yes, I swear
I'll give you everything
And all that I want from you
Is a promise you
Will be there
Say you will be there
If you
Pt two and two together
You will see
what our friendship is for
Across to Geri. Hips. Very good.
Very nice. This is a good bit.
If you can't work this equation
Then I guess I'll have to
show yothe door
There is no need
to say yolove me
It'd be better leftnsaid
I'll give you everything
On this I swear
Just promise
you'll always be there
Look at that, Brad!
"Spice Girls set
to conquer the globe."
Why is it that I
can't pick up a paper...
without seeing them
all over the front page?
... You told us to write that story.
- I know.
As long as they sell newspapers...
we're gonna have to keep
writing about them.
Well, I'm sick ot them.
We need a new angle, Brad.
Who cares it the Spice Girls
get to number one yet again?
Who cares if they climb to the top
ot Mount Everest on an ostrich?
Or it they tind a cure
tor déjà vu.
Not me.
Or it they tind a cure
tor dèjà vu.
- Not me.
- I got a better idea.
You try this tor size.
"Spice Girls...
live show cancelled."
That's not bad.
"Spice Girls tall out."
"Spice Girls split up."
Think how many copies of the paper
we'll sell with a headline like that.
... I like it.
- I can make it happen, Brad.
Me, Kevin McMaxtord.
I put them up there.
I can bring them down!
... Yes.
... Who's gonna help me, Brad?
Who is gonna help me
take on Girl Power...
and bring it crashing
and whimpering to the ground?
I'll find someone.
I just wish
you wouldn't get so upset.
Now hear this.
It is dangerous to store moisturizing
cream in the retrigerator...
as it can be mistaken
tor mayonnaise.
That is all.
Check.
- What do you mean, check?
- I mean check.
... My bishop's got your king.
- Where?
There. You either got to move it
in front or move it out of the way.
I'll move that tairground horse
to there. Sort that out.
- You can't do that.
... Says who?
Says Mr. Chess. It's been
in the rules tor thousands ot years.
I'm gonna break the rules
and set this f airground horse tree...
amongst all these little
square tields like that.
I'm gonna slap you in a minute.
It's obvious to us that
the Spice Girls are movie stars.
We've worked on this idea
tor months.
- Graydon?
... Can we turn otf our cell phones?
Respect tor the writer.
This is the ultimate tale.
Five girls, tive lives, one story.
As old as time itself
but as tresh as newly cut grass.
That's fresh.
The girls play tive sisters...
whose parents disappeared
during the January Harrod's sale...
and were never seen again.
Ripped trom today's headlines.
Now they live at home,
struggling to support...
an elderly grandmother who sutfers
trom some mysterious wasting disease.
I've got tears.
Their only hope at breaking
the cycle of poverty...
lies with the middle sister,
Melanie C...
who's convinced she could be
an Olympic ski...jump champion...
it only she could overcome
her tear ot heights and snow...
and could just get her hands
on a pair of skis.
That's amazing.
That's tantastic.
... What do you think?
- I think it stinks.
Ot course it stinks,
but it's a start.
We're cooking here.
This is a stew, a gumbo.
A jambalaya, it you will.
We're just jamming.
Okay, here's another idea.
Crocodiles.
If you want tickets to the Spice Girls'
first-ever live gig, you're too late.
Bt they're with me now on Srgery.
Welcome, girls.
... There's Sporty, Scary, Ginger...
... Turn it otf.
- I will.
- What's it like to be Baby Spice?
You think I'll always be seen as
Baby Spice, the sweet, innocent one...
even when I'm 30?
You love it really, Emma.
You play up to it all the time.
No, I don't.
... You do. You're doing it now.
- I'm not.
You see, the thing about you...
is you've got this dead-cute smile
so you can get away with anything.
Hello, ladies and gentlemen.
Four horrible murders...
perpetrated by the same...
ruthless psychopath.
Each victim riddled with a hundred
machine gun bullets by this maniac.
But who is it?
Protessor Schutzmann?
Father Conan Murphy?
Lady Matilda Davenport?
Or Miss Emma Bunton?
The murderer is...
Father Conan Murphy.
I am really ted up with people thinking
all I do is talk about clothes.
People are really shallow.
They judge you on what you look like.
Exactly.
I think it's the same with fish.
I mean, look at this.
You've got the spotty one
that's wacky.
You've got the tlutfy one
that's cute.
Then you've got
this ugly loser one...
that reminds me
ot my ex...boyfriend Steven.
Did you know that the largest tish
in the world is the manta ray?
Then there's the little ginger one...
that is tull of useless intormation...
about manta rays.
I don't get it.
Why do people stereotype us
all the time?
The trouble is we're all
getting really predictable.
... I should stop being loud and lairy.
- Yeah, right.
Fat chance.
Hold it there.
Give it to me.
Why don't we give each other
new characters?
Like what?
I tell you what.
What about Bricklayer Spice?
Sexy. Come on, energy.
- Or Trainspotting Spice.
- Smashing.
What about Sporty-but...l-am...actually
interested...in-other-things Spice?
Go tor it. Come on.
Or Cheesed-otf-with...cheesy
photo-session Spice.
... And again.
- Let's go do our own thing.
Take it from me
You know I mean
what I'm saying
Yobetter watch out
You better wisep
To mind games he's playing
He may have the looks
He may have the charms
But where does he go
What does he do
When he's not in your arms
Keep your headp high
Don't you know
you are the sperfly
And that ain't no lie
Because it's Satrday night
You got a feeling it's right
Don't you know
we'll get so high
Bye!
Get down
Get deeper and down
Saturday night
Get down, deeper and down
Hello, Mr. Bond,
or can I call you James?
Want that shaken or stirred?
That's it.
I'm otf. I'm going.
I'm so sporty!
Telling on a superstar
That's what you are
My mummy's my best triend.
I'm just too posh.
When are Liverpool
gonna win the cup, like, eh?
Are we tinished yet?
Ah, blah, blah. Girl Power.
Feminism.
You know what I mean?
Oh, no.
I feel as though I'm being strangled.
How do you feel?
Really uncomfortable.
I just nearly tell otf these shoes
and sprained my ankle.
These things are really tight.
They're going right up my bum.
- These are really comty, actually.
- Don't even think about it.
I'm ott.
I'm getting these oft.
- I need some plattorms.
- How can you wear this stutt, Geri?
Yes! I got just the man
tor the job.
He did the Fergie
toe...sucking pictures.
He got the Teletubbies
taking a poo.
He can get you a picture ot Clinton
tucking his T-shirt into his underpants.
He sounds great,
but where the hell is this guy?
I'm here.
How do we know
you're any good, pal?
8:45... You snitting your socks
betore putting them on.
8:55... You in the litt,
picking your nose.
Another bogey breaktast.
He's good.
You again...
behind the bike shed with
Eileen Winters, when you were 12.
He's very good.
He's gone.
Stand back, man
Thank you very much
I need somebody
with the human touch
Now hear this.
Atter using the showers...
could people please pick up
the clumps ot hair in the plug holes.
It's unhygienic
and can lead to flooding.
Can't Clitford
just tell us normally?
Next up: publicity party......
beautiful people, reporters,
interviews...
lots ot finger food...
have tun.
That is all.
- They're here. Don't look.
- I'm not looking.
I hate these parties.
Everyone dresses so over the top.
If you notice, they all ask you
how you are and don't even care.
Well, I should be at the tootie now,
and it I'm not there and they lose...
You know him?
... Sorry.
... Do you know who I am?
Who are you?
Piers Cuthbertson Smythe.
I'm with the Spice Girls.
Your name is not down,
you're not coming in.
You said they'd recognize you.
Yes, I go to all the shows,
but Gucci, Pucci, Prada and Fendi...
I was very disappointed
with their spring collections.
As for McQueen and Galliano,
I could go either way on them.
What do you think about manta rays?
Oh, yes, marvelous designer,
Manta Ray.
I love Manta Ray.
These are Manta Ray's shoes,
these are his glasses.
Bob, we've gotta sort your hair out.
In tact, I'm gonna do your hair tor you.
What's wrong with the hair?
Everybody's always going on about it.
It's not as if we wanna be threatening
to a man's masculinity or anything.
... Ot course not.
- Or be dominating.
The tunny thing is when we meet men,
sometimes they get nervous...
and don't know what to say.
... I'm just gonna go to the toilet.
- Hello, Trish.
I've been talking
to a Spice Girl.
I know.
Now, Bob, I think you look great.
What the hell have you done?
Nicola! Remember me? Piers, yes.
We're with her.
We have to get in.
- Spare ticket?
... We have a ticket.
And tonight is the night
When three become one
Thank you.
Look, I've got something
really important to ask you.
But if you don't wanna do it,
it's all right.
... What is it?
... I was thinking.
One ot you could be godmother
to the baby...
but then I thought, I love you all
and you're all my best mates.
I want you all to be godmothers.
One condition: It's got to be
a Liverpool supporter.
Hang on a minute.
Do godmothers get stretch marks?
I'm sorry to interrupt, but it is
interview and photo time now.
- Do we have to go?
- Yes, you do. It's your job.
... See you. I'm so sorry.
- Sorry, Nicola. See you.
Girls, it's publicity
tor Saturday's show.
- Hi, I'm Barnaby.
- Oh, hi.
Are you a part
of the Spice phenomenon?
No, I'm just nobody.
Excuse me a minute.
So we're on a wide...angled lens.
Running.
Tonight I'm going to be asking
the big questions.
How are relationships molded...
in this strange,
kaleidoscopic world...
the Spice Girls inhabit?
Let's tind out.
So, do you have any time for boys?
Boys? Doesn't ring a bell.
I think with boys, you should
be able to just wheel them in...
then they're there, and that's it.
- Really?
... And order them like a pizza.
I'll have a deep-pan, six foot...
green eyes, pair of loafers
and no socks.
And no cheese.
But you do like boys,
don't you, Geri?
Come on. Is the Pope a Catholic?
Apparently he is, yes.
Here at home, church leaders
have reacted with shock today...
to report that the Spice Girls...
have cast dobt on the religious
conviction of the Pope.
That's more like it!
A Vatican spokesman said
the pontiff was hurt and confsed....
by the suggestion
that he might not be Catholic.
We asked the Bishop ot Candleford
what he thought ot the report.
It's a terrible suggestion,
almost blasphemous.
Ot course the Pope's a Catholic.
Otherwise he wouldn't have been invited
to become pope, would he?
I'd like to know what evidence the Spice
Girls have to support these allegations.
I really would.
Here we go.
The backlash has started.
When the rabbit ot chaos is pursued
by the terret of disorder...
through the fields ot anarchy...
it is time to hang your pants
on the hook of darkness.
Whether they're clean or not.
Why Milan, Clifford?
Just a TV special... ltalians,
screaming kids, thesal thing.
Are we there yet?
Come on, come on
Do you wanna be in my gang
my gang, my gang
I'm the leader
What the hell is this?
I'm the leader of the gang
Yeah
No way.
Cliftord, what is going on here?
Clitford?
Stop.
What are you stop?
We didn't agree to have this lot
dancing with us.
I know you said
it was going to be tacky...
but this is tacky.
Hey, Bobby Charlton,
why have they stopped?
They're stopping because
these clowns suddenly appeared.
I don't doubt you, my triend, but they
should be on another show or a zoo.
Look at his muscles. It looks as though
he's got terrets burrowing under there.
I know. I'm sorting it out.
Over here.
... You think that's real down there?
- Looks like rolled up socks to me.
You carry on like this,
I take the girls back.
You're taking the girls back?
What about the contract?
Contract? Ha!
In my bed I've got two teddies,
a rabbit, two dollies.
One's Susan.
She's got a bad eye.
The boys stay here.
The girls go, I sue you.
A.C. Milan? No.
You're a bit weak in your midtield.
Then I've got a green girafte
which I won at a tair.
It was the only one lett,
and I telt really sorry for him.
So you want to play hardball?
What do you want, tisticutf s?
Then there's Buzz, Woody, the alien,
and a flutfy pink hot-water bottle.
There's just not enough room tor you.
... Your mother.
- My mother?
Your mother.
Hey. Your mother!
Your big f at mother,
and your brother-in...law.
And your mad cousin.
And your next door neighbor's goat!
- Now I kill you.
- Go tor it.
Boys, boys.
Calm down. Have you not heard
of the word "compromisation"?
What?
Crazy, crazy.
Come on, come on
I said
Do you wanna be in my gang
My gang, my gang
I'm the leader
I'm the leader of the gang
Yeah, yeah
But there's no one
like the girl I am
I can take you
High as a kite
every single night
I can make you
jump ot of bed
- Now, that looks better.
... We agreed on a compromise.
Who'd ever believe it
... What on earth's that?
- That's the compromise.
Do you wanna be in my gang
my gang, my gang
Hey, Bobby Charlton!
Was that really worth it?
I'm so glad we got the morning off.
- First one in a month, Clifford.
- Are we there yet?
- I'm dying for the loo.
... So am I.
Clitford,
can we stop the bus?
Dennis, pull over.
We've got a crisis.
The girls need to go
to the bathroom again.
- I'm bursting to go wee.
- Come on. Move.
- Geri, I've borrowed your shoes.
- Mind the spider!
You see?
Doesn't matter how successful you are,
sometimes you have to pee in the woods.
I don't understand how all the toilets
can break down at the same time.
It's not my tault
they keep breaking down.
It's hard to get a plumber to your
house, and that stays in one place.
But you try calling one out to a bus
that's moving around the countryside.
... It's impossible.
- Can't you do something about them?
... Like what?
- Fix them.
Listen.
I love these girls
and I'll do anything for them...
but I won't do that.
I don't want to go any turther.
I'm scared.
Why does the countryside
have to be so bloody muddy?
Something just brushed past me,
and I'm not joking.
It was only a disgusting beast
that wants to eat you.
... Oh, pack it in, Mel.
- It weren't me.
I think we're lost, you know.
Spiders are everywhere.
Whose idea was this?
What's that?
... Oh, my God! Run for it!
... I can't move!
Get oft!
You've done it now.
Geri, go and say something to them.
Go on.
Say something good, Geri.
What do you want with us?
Yeah.
Sorry, but they've all sold out.
... Oh, my God.
... What is it?
What's his name?
Is that three or tour "K"s?
Four.
Gosh, you're tat.
Ew, he wants you to snog him.
He wants you, G.
They want a picture.
Smile.
... What do you mean, aliens?
... Aliens trom outer space.
They had these
little squidgy f aces.
And really cheap green coats.
You're obviously under massive stress.
I think you need some time ott.
I'm going to stand up to the chiet,
be assertive.
I'm gonna ask him...
no, tell him...
the girls are going to
have the morning otf.
- The answer is no, Clifford.
... Chiet?
- The girls cannot have the morning ott.
- Of course not.
The tact that they've
been working really hard...
and they're at the point
ot exhaustion is...
- Irrelevant.
Without sacrifice
there is no success.
Without pain
there is no pleasure.
And without something
there is no nothing.
Very assertive, Clitford.
You better go and tell them.
- I know.
... Go on, then.
I'm going on, then.
... See you, Clitford!
... Hold on.
... Where are you going?
... Going home to sleep.
- See you tomorrow atternoon.
... Sorry. There's been a change ot plan.
The schedule's too tight.
No morning ott.
Oh, nice one, Clittord.
... You nearly had us there.
... You're not good at telling tibs.
I'm sorry.
There's too much to get through.
- You're not joking, are you?
- Oh, no.
You see, we've got to
see Nicola in the morning.
The baby's overdue.
Baby's are allowed to be overdue.
You're not.
Please, I'll buy you
a milk chocolate Magnum each.
... Okay.
- Get back.
Look, Clitford,
you can only push us so tar.
- Yeah, right.
- You just better watch it, mate.
From now on, there's no more
Mr. Nice Spice.
Where are they going?
... What do you think?
- I don't know, mate.
Fooled you.
See you in the morning.
Don't forget my Magnum.
Now hear this.
You are about to enter Dance Camp.
You will be under the instruction
ot the toughest...
dance teacher ot all time,
Mr. Step.
Right, you horrible lot!
Left, right, lett!
Don't give me that "Julie Andrews high
on a hill'' type claptrap. Chop, chop.
I'm your mother now,
and I don't mean Superior.
Take that sweet out ot your mouth...
... Shimmy, shimmy.
... Are you the dance teacher, Mr. Step?
That is correct.
I'm going to show you
my "pas de bra.''
That won't apply to you.
Pay attention.
One, two, one.
Mother!
- We can't dance like that.
- Yes, I know.
I've seen your videos.
That's enough.
Shall we do our own thing?
I don't even understand them,
they seem so strange.
That's it.
We're gonna get tit, fit, fit.
One, two,
one, two, three, four.
Never give up on the good times
Gotta believe
in the love you find
Never give up on the good times
Sharp turn right. March!
Living it up is a state of mind
Love it.
Make your mothers proud ot you.
What sort ot men are you, anyway?
Left, right.
Right then, Spice Girls,
regimental chant.
We're the Spice Girls, yes, indeed
Just Girl Power is all we need
Pick it up!
We know how we got this far
Strength and courage
and a Wonderbra
Cold this work with only one
Right wheel!
Just with me I'd have no fun
Would this work with only two
Lett wheel, go down.
We need more for what we do
Would this work with only three
Three's a crowd, bad company
Wold this work with only four
No way, girl, we need one more
Listenp
Take my advice
We need five
for the power of Spice
Give itp, give it out
Take a stand, scream and shout
One, two, three, four
Five Spice Girls
Get in there.
Posh Spice, where are you going?
- There's a spider in there!
- Get out ot those tubes.
Come on. Get up that ramp.
Get hold ot that rope.
That is correct!
That is not correct.
I'II give you not correct.
Lights otf.
... It's not even dark yet.
- And you, Melanie.
It's pathetic that we can't
even sleep in our own rooms.
I don't know what we're making such
a tuss for. It's only an old house.
A big old house.
A big, very old, haunted...
big old house.
I had this horrible dream
last night.
I dreamt we were all doing
the live show.
I went on stage.
I was just about to open my gob,
and nothing came out.
Something
even more weirder happened.
... You didn't have a head?
... How did you know?
I have the same dream.
No way.
I had exactly the same dream,
but mine was much, much worse.
You see, I had a head
but there was no makeup on it.
Oh, no.
I just don't understand.
So what does it all mean?
Probably our subconscious minds
so we don't have to deal...
with our inner anxieties
when we're awake.
Like we're all gonna be scared
of this live show.
And that we might not
be able to sing.
And it's gonna be
a complete disaster.
Oh, no.
Let's just stay here together.
Yeah, squash up.
I'm going to sleep now.
I am. See you.
I hate you, McMaxtord.
I really, really hate you.
I hate you!
Look at that! More stories!
More evil harpoons trom the press!
I wouldn't let it
bother you, Cliftord.
Just chill out.
Yeah, the press
can just tlick otf.
Makes me wanna strangle something!
If we took any notice of all that press,
we'd go mad like you.
I just can't take it anymore!
It's all lies!
I'm simply not like that!
Bring me a straitjacket!
Yes, you can laugh!
You can laugh!
He is so uptight,
he's gonna have a heart attack.
- Maybe he's not getting enough bacon.
- Could be.
Do you know what would be pertect?
It he tancied Deborah.
- Yeah!
- I reckon he's got a chance with her.
... She hasn't had a boytriend in months.
- He doesn't tancy her.
The body language is all wrong.
He doesn't even look at her.
But that doesn't matter.
Men don't like showing their emotions.
That is true.
But apparently there's these animals
in the jungle or the rain forest.
Anyway, when the male's courting
the temale, he goes and pees on her.
- Oh, no!
... Geri, do you have to?
But it's his way of showing
that he f ancies her.
And the thing is,
they get it on afterwards and mate.
Call me old-tashioned,
but I preter a bunch ot tlowers.
- Here's where we get "high concept.''
- Eight miles high.
A Royal Air Force stealth bomber is
hijacked by extraterrestrial terrorists.
Inside the pilot's pocket
is a computer disk...
with a virus encoded on it that is
so deadly, it could destroy the world.
The British prime minister
has absolutely no choice.
He has to call in
the Spice Force Five.
Can you see the merchandising?
Action tigures?
Crack operatives in their own tield.
There's the martial arts expert.
Counterespionage agent.
Goal!
Explosives expert.
Oh, no!
Master ot disguise.
Wonder Woman
You're a Wonder Woman
Girl Power!
Equalization between the sexes, hmm?
And...- oh... Victoria.
- Then what? Back to reality.
- Absolutely.
Oh, hell, yeah.
Why not?
What kind ot reality
are you interested in? I'm open.
Competition winners.
The chance to make those
f antasy tigures become a reality.
Dreams come true.
The stuft of tairy tales.
So, how's it teel to have won the trip
round London with the Spice Girls?
- It's great.
... I expect your friends are jealous.
- Yeah.
... I'm sure they are.
- How's that sound?
- Planes, dogs, trattic.
We won't be using this bit anyway.
Don't worry about it. Come on.
I hate that.
Couldn't get a word in edgewise.
They treat us like bloody kids.
Okay, kids,
welcome to the Spicebus.
- Cool.
... Girls, competition winners.
Balloons, cakes,
sandwiches, tun, tun.
- Do you want a Polaroid?
- It's Jack and Evie, isn't it?
... Do you want something to eat?
- Ready? Smile.
Why do they have loads ot
tish paste sarnies at parties?
- No one likes them.
- I know.
It must be great
being a Spice Girl.
- It's good.
- lt'd be better it it wasn't tor...
our f ascist slave driver
bossing us about all the time.
Let's just escape
trom this place!
Don't worry, she does this all the time.
She is mad.
Yes!
When I say "go, '' we go.
... Go!
- Grab some crisps.
- Where are we going?
... Just go with the flow.
Take it easy, girls.
... Mind telling me where they're going?
- They're being spontaneous.
I told them before,
it they want to be spontaneous...
they'd have to
clear it with me first.
... Let's go.
- Can we have a ride on your boat?
Quick! There's an aquatic
adventure happening here!
What we need now
is a really serious speedboat.
- Dennis, tollow them.
... I'm on the trail.
My boy lollipop
Yomake my heart go giddy-p
You are as sweet as candy
Yo're my sugar dandy
Uh-oh
My boy lollipop
The Spice Girls at sea.
What an extraordinary combination
ot Girl Power and horsepower.
Can't this thing go any taster?
My heart told me so
I love you
I love yoso
But I don't want you to know
Faster! Come on!
I need you, I need yo
I need you so
And I'll never let you go
Deborah, can you please explain
what the hell is going on here?
... They're having tun. Rock 'n' roll.
- No, it's not.
Rock 'n' roll is staying up all night
and getting completely ott your f ace...
and throwing television sets
out ot hotel windows.
I don't remember
any mention ot boats.
You're my lollipop
Enzo, they're dancing.
Can we have them dancing, please?
I can hear singing.
Can you get what they're singing?
... Don't you remember being a kid?
... What?
You know, talling over in
the playground, scraping your knees.
Deborah,
what planet are you trom?
Hold on!
Water on the lens, Piers!
Here they come.
Stop!
Oh, my!
There is a child in the water.
I want a close...up of...
... All I'm getting is you shouting.
- Shush then.
Turn it round! Quick!
Don't worry! I'II save her!
At last, a real drama.
Sorry.
Get oft!
I'm trying to tilm.
I got a loud splash there, Piers.
Just great!
Parents lend us their kids,
and we drown them.
- That was so brilliant!
- Wicked!
That was not supposed to happen!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, we're fine.
... You mean, I got wet tor nothing?
- Help!
... What?
... This dress is dry-clean only!
Do they have sharks
in the Thames?
... Oh, shut up!
- They're coming.
... Whose idea was this?
... Yours.
... Can we do it again?
- No!
- Vicky, do you wanna wear this?
- I'm not that desperate.
Are you all right?
Do you realize what'll happen
if any of this ever gets out?
And more drama
concerning the Spice Girls.
Today, two young
competition winners...
had a dramatic escape when they fell....
from a speeding boat
on the river Thames.
This report from James Platt.
Take it easy, Clitford.
Would you like a Rescue Remedy?
I think it's time tor a chat.
Look at this.
Front page news again.
Suppose the whole lot of you
had been drowned?
- We weren't though.
- Speak tor yourselt.
What did you think
you were doing?
- We were just having fun.
... What?
You know, tun,
like "ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.''
Look, we're old enough to take
responsibility for our own lives.
You don't have a life.
You have a schedule.
You are part of a well-oiled
global machine.
There are people working
their butts ott tor you!
- People like Deborah.
... Can you leave my butt out ot this?
Just don't be
so uptight, Clittord.
Uptight? You've got
a live gig here tomorrow.
It's my job
to see that you turn up.
My bum is on the line here!
Could you please leave butts and bums
out ot this tor one minute?
Some things are
more important than gigs.
... Like what?
... Like self-respect and our treedom.
Yeah, and triendship.
What are you saying?
You don't want to turn up here tomorrow?
Maybe we don't!
- What did you say that tor?
... I don't know.
Listen, you.
It's up to us whether we turn up
to this gig or not tomorrow, all right?
Okay, stay at home.
That's tine.
- Fine!
- We can't let the f ans down.
- He didn't mean that.
... Didn't I?
... Can we please stop arguing?
When you know exactly
what is supposed to be happening...
could somebody
please let me know?
Great, Clittord.
Now look what you've done.
... That's just too bad.
- It is, because you know what?
- I'm going home now. See you!
- Bye!
Can we just stop all this?
It's doing my head in!
Emma!
I hope you know
what you're doing...
'cause if you're looking tor a tight,
you're gonna lose!
What do you think?
No, I don't want to hear what you think.
... What do you think?
- I think you detinitely lost.
I think...
I think I may have just started
the breakup ot the Spice Girls.
It's tine, Chief.
Everything's tine.
... Oh, no, it isn't.
- No, it isn't.
How bad is it?
Imagine how bad
it cold possibly be.
- Yes?
- Well, it's worse than that.
- Oh, dear.
- Don't get upset, Chief.
... Oh, dearie me.
- You're getting all emotional, Chief.
Look, the show will go on...
even it I have to
round up four triends...
and personally
dress up as Victoria.
Let us hope
it does not come to that.
- I won't let you down.
- You'd better not.
Remember: The headless chicken
can only know where he has been.
He cannot see
where he is going.
Do not be that chicken, Clitford.
Chicken. Right.
Things are moving.
The girls have had a row with Cliftord.
They might not
turn up tor the show.
Something strange is happening.
What is it?
Something's happening to my f ace.
I think you're smiling.
That you'd be like this.
I'm sorry.
Sorry that you ever left here.
Sam, for old time's sake.
Yeah, sure, for old time's sake.
So there we go, girls.
That's six coftees.
- Thanks, Brian.
- One pound tifty.
... Can you put it on the slate?
- What slate?
The "we'll pay you back when
we're rich and f amous" slate.
Call me old-f ashioned
and sentimental, but no.
Do you think I'm
the Salvation Army?
It was worth a try.
How's the musical career going?
You got any deals?
- Not quite.
... But we've got this new song.
What is it? Flip-flop?
Or hip-hop?
... Funk?
- Hip-hop?
Funk? Where have you been
tor the last ten years?
I don't know the music scene now.
I can't make head nor tail of it.
Anything goes these days.
You just do what you want.
I'm a jazz man,
and I'm telling you...
jazz is due tor a comeback.
Brian, they've got
this great song.
- Do it tor him.
... He's not interested.
Of course he is.
You are interested, aren't you?
Sit down and shut up and listen,
'cause we're gonna do it anyway.
... Let's do it.
- Ready?
One, two, three.
Hit it!
I'll tell you what I want
What I really, really want
So tell me what you want
What you really, really want
I wanna, I wanna, I wanna
I wanna, I wanna
Really, really, really wanna
Zig-a-zig-ah
If you want my fture
Forget my past
If yowanna get with me
Better make it fast
Now don't go wasting
my precios time
Get your act together
We cold be jst fine
If yowanna be my lover
yogotta get with my friends
- Gotta get with my friends
- Make it last forever
Friendship never ends
If yowanna be my lover
Yohave got to give
Taking is too easy
But that's the way it is
Slam your body down
and wind it all around
Go on, Mel!
- If yowanna be my lover
- What'd you think?
Not bad. Just needs
a wee bit more jazz in there.
I think it'll make the Top 20.
It's great!
I love it!
- It's so sad.
- That's what I was thinking.
We used to live in there.
Now look at it.
- What are you doing here?
... What are you doing here?
Same as you.
This all seems like
ages ago, doesn't it?
It just shows you, you can't go back.
Nothing's the same.
... I wonder whatever did happen to Brian.
- We owe him tor a couple ot cottees.
- Yeah.
... Let's go and get some chips.
... I'm not paying for cotfees.
... Bacon butties tor me.
... You don't care what you eat, do you?
- No, I don't.
I wonder it we've changed a lot
since we've been f amous.
... I don't think I have.
- Nor have I.
I just think we worry
about difterent things.
In the old days it was,
"Where's our next meal coming from?''
And now it's,
"Where's our next single going to?"
And like,
is it all gonna be over soon?
Melvin B, Emma...
Melvin C, Victoria, Geri.
You have been tound guilty
ot releasing a single...
that is by no means as kicking
as your previous records.
Nor does it have such a wicked,
dirty, tat bass line.
You are sentenced
to having your next record...
enter the charts
at number 179...
betore dropping straight out
the tollowing week.
Furthermore,
you are sentenced to 20 years...
of having to appear
on cheesy chat shows in Taiwan...
talking about how
you used to be tamous.
And may God have mercy
on your lip gloss.
Call Hootie and the Blowfish.
You know what's happened? We haven't
got time tor our triends anymore.
Like Nicola.
We're supposed to be
godmothers to her baby.
We haven't even spent
any time with her.
Why don't we
take her out tonight?
- Yeah, and go really mental!
- Yeah!
Hang on. We've got a show tomorrow.
What are we gonna do about that?
It Clittord tinds out we've
been out all night, he'll go berserk.
What are we waiting tor?
- Come on, Vicky!
... I can't run in these heels!
Thought I'd tind you here.
Sorry, there's only room tor
one depressed personality in here.
At least you're still alive.
That's the bit
that depresses me.
It it makes you feel any better,
I've got a degree in politics...
philosophy and economics,
and I spend my entire lite...
worrying about whether Mel C
is wearing the right Nike Air Max.
By the way,
did you sort them out?
Yes.
Mind you, I'd rather
be us than the girls.
Fame is...-
Fame is such a tickle thing.
... What can I get you?
... Gin and tonic, please.
Just a minute.
- Can you make that a double?
... Yes.
- You know what happens now, don't you?
... What's that?
We both sit here
getting more and more selt-pitying...
telling each other tragic tales
of lost lovers...
then deaden the pain by having
a night ot tull-on passion...
and end up completely ruining
our protessional relationship.
Well, I'm up tor it,
it you are.
Time, ladies and gentlemen.
- You all right, Nicola?
- Fine.
It's the last time I'll be going out
tor a while, so I'm gonna enjoy it.
- I love this song!
- That's 'cause we wrote it!
- Let's go for a dance.
- No. I'll watch you.
- Carry on.
... Take care, Nicola.
Come on!
Could somebody please tell me
exactly what is the dress code here?
The race is on
to get out of the bottom
The top is high
so yor roots are forgotten
Giving is good
as long as yo're getting
What's driving yo
is ambition I'm betting
I said
Who do yothink yoare
I said who
Some kind of sperstar
You have just got to
Swing it, shake it, move it, make it
Who do yothink yoare
Trst it,se it, prove it, groove it
Show me how good you are
You're swelling out
in the wrong direction
Yo've got the bug
Superstar, yo've been bitten
Yor trmpet's blowing
for far too long
Climbing the snakep the ladder
But you're wrong
Nicola!
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Sorry.
- Can we sit there?
... Can you get out of the way?
I think the contractions
have started.
- Maybe it's something you ate.
- I don't remember swallowing a baby.
... It's tor an emergency.
- The baby's coming.
- Now don't panic.
- Don't panic!
I'm not panicking.
- What do you do in an emergency?
- Call my mom!
We need an ambulance.
- I don't think there's enough time.
... Okay, we don't need an ambulance!
Dennis! We've gotta
get to the hospital!
What happened?
- We're having a baby.
- What? All ot you?
... Just get there!
- Come on!
Round them up!
We're gonna hit the trail!
... Ow! That was a contraction!
- Cuddle.
Deep breathing,
that's the thing.
Not you, Victoria! Her!
...Does anyone know how to deliver a baby?
-Don't look at me.
... I know all about home delivery.
- Yeah, right.
I read it in a book.
The tirst thing to do is, uh...
- Put your legs together.
... Too late.
... Should've done that nine months ago.
... Don't make me laugh.
Do not make her laugh, because
it'll just shoot out like a cannonball.
Seriously now, what it
the baby comes out right now?
It's not gonna go very tar.
She's still got her tights on.
Stay up there.
We're not ready tor you yet.
That's it! Push!
- I am pushing!
... Are you sure she should push?
What else is she gonna do?
It I push any more,
I'll turn myselt inside out!
... What's going on?
... She's pushing!
- How dilated is she?
- Not very.
- She only had one gin and orange.
... Just calm down, girls.
You're in tor a long wait.
This is going to take a long time.
Oh, that's nice.
It's all right.
We're here.
Mama, I love you
That's catchy. Hmm.
Excuse me.
Are you the Spice Girls?
Some of them.
My son's banged his head.
He's unconscious.
I was wondering it you could
talk to him, try and wake him up.
- We can do that.
- Sorry about this.
Malcolm, the Spice Girls
have come to talk to you.
Isn't that wondertul?
Hello, Malcolm.
It's Geri.
- I'm Melanie C.
... And I'm Victoria, Malcolm!
Stop it.
Well, what should we do now?
I don't know.
Maybe we should just talk to him.
... What are we gonna say?
- Maybe you should take your top ott.
Shut up!
It was just a joke.
There's not much point.
He's got his eyes shut.
Not now.
- How are you teeling?
- Bad. Where are the girls?
I don't know.
I have no idea.
How about trying to tind out?
Come on! Chop-chop!
Hurry it up!
It's amazing how much pain
mothers have to go through.
No wonder my mom
thinks I'm so ungratetul.
... I hear it's like passing a football.
... That's nothing.
My mom said when she had me, it was like
passing a block ot flats with balconies.
Hello?
Hi, Deborah.
We're in hospital.
We're tine. It's Nicola.
She's having a baby.
No, we can't leave her.
Oh, no.
I've got to go. Bye.
I can't believe it.
I cannot believe it.
They're waiting for a friend's baby?
- It's called loyalty.
- No, it's called insanity.
The whole world is waiting tor
their show, and the girls aren't here.
They're doing it to spite me.
They're trying to make me crack.
But I won't.
I won't.
I spy with my bionic eye...
something beginning with "H.''
... A hospital.
- Shut up, Geri.
I'm otf duty now, Helen.
Everything all right?
Fine. Doing anything
nice tonight?
- I'm going to see the Spice Girls show.
- That'll be nice, Gladys.
Oh, I better get a move on.
See you all later.
Hopetully.
Listen, this is silly.
Don't wait tor me. You gotta go.
Nicola, we said we would stay,
so we're gonna stay.
- I think this is it.
... Yeah, it is.
Push down, Nicola.
Very good.
Hi, Clitford. I don't know
what time we're gonna be there.
The world can wait.
This is more important.
It's about friendship and commitment,
but you wouldn't know about that.
I'll speak to you later. Bye.
It can't take this long
to have a baby!
This is the '90s.
He's about to crack up
at any moment.
The sense ot tension,
ot impending doom, it's......
... Are you getting that sweat on his lip?
... Sound running.
- That's beautitul.
- I could put a little bit more on.
Clitford, five minutes.
Have you got five minutes?
All right, seeing as there's
nothing else going on around here.
... Graydon, tetch.
- Come on.
Okay, here's the story.
It's the girls' tirst live pertormance.
They are major stars.
It's only minutes
until curtain up.
All hopes ot the Spice Girls'
live triumph are surely dashed.
Oh, my God! It's coming out!
I think I'm gonna taint.
... No, you're not.
... Slap me!
... Oh, my God!
- Is it a boy or a girl?
... It's a beetroot!
- It's a girl!
With hands like that,
she'll make a great goalie one day.
Now that is Girl Power.
Hey, you just...
I do believe he's got a camera.
- You're that reporter, aren't you?
- Emergency!
... I don't believe you!
... Get him, Melanie!
I'm late tor the theater!
The curtain's already gone up!
He crashes to the ground.
And now the girls come face to face
with their tabloid tormentor.
The evil reporter has been unmasked,
and in that moment...
Damien's whole worthless life
tlashes betore his eyes because...
the girls have made him realize that
he's been living a meaningless lie.
Do you know what, girls?
You've made me realize...
I've been living
a meaningless lie.
It's his character's
one defining moment.
There isn't a dry seat
in the house.
- I'm wet already.
- I don't buy it.
One minute Damien is this big,
threatening monster...
the next he's some weeping wimp.
That's the power
ot Girl Power, man.
- So that's the end?
... No.
Damien goes after the really
big evil boss, McMaxford.
... What about the girls?
- They've gotta get to Albert Hall.
They've been at the hospital
for 12 hours.
He's not here.
I don't believe it.
Just when you need him.
Now it's a race against time.
- So there's gonna be a chase?
... Those are the rules.
Out ot the way, girls.
- What are you doing?
- Fasten your seat belts.
Hey! That's my bus!
What are you doing?
Get out ot the way!
Come on!
What are you doing?
What's the matter?
Are you blind?
Put your foot down!
Sunday drivers.
It's only Saturday.
Okay, now the Spicebus is racing
across London, through Trafalgar Sqare.
Pigeons are flying up.
Guys are diving into fountains.
And as it zooms down the Mall
past Bckingham Palace...
Prince William
is looking through a curtain.
He turns to the Queen, man,
and says, 'Oi, Granny, look!
It's the Spice Girls!
They're on telly in a minute!''
And the Queen says,
"Oh, you're right.
Isn't that the Posh one driving?"
- There's the Queen.
- Hi, William.
- Hi, Charlie.
... Hello, Harry.
... Suddenly they're on top ot the bus.
- Why?
- The rules!
... Yeah, the rules.
And there they are,
standing together in gale force winds....
holding on for dear life.
Emma slips, but Geri grabs her.
But then Geri slips.
Mel B grabs her, bt she slips,
so Mel C grabs her!
Is that tour?
No, there's one driving.
They're standing on top of the bus,
whiplashing back and torth...
about to be turned into Spice Jam!
- Oh, my God!
- And?
Two old nuns in a Mini Metro
pull up right in tront ot them.
The braking tmbles the girls
back inside the bus.
That was close.
- Is everyone all right?
... Victoria!
Sorry!
Now they're coming
to the Tower Bridge.
Yor attention, please.
The bridge will shortly be lifted.
The road is rising in tront ot them
to let a boat through!
The bridge is going up!
They can't believe it!
Oh, my God!
I don't believe it!
Are they crazy enough
to try and jump the gap?
Hold on to your knickers, girls!
Hey, baby,
these are the Spice Girls!
Of course they're gonna go tor it!
Up it goes.
A tive-ton London bus sailing
through the air at 80 miles an hour.
... It's incredible!
- It's expensive.
Not necessarily.
Just when you think they're safe,
they discover the bomb.
What bomb?
That bomb.
- Why?
- Those are the rules.
I've had enough ot the rules!
Are you trying to kill them?
- Stop it!
- They've suttered enough!
- Please!
- All right! All right!
They run up to the Albert Hall,
up the steps...
and then they hurtle down the corridor
and burst through that door right there.
You lied to me.
Now, now.
Hey, that's enough of that!
- Come on now!
- Where are they?
I'll rewrite it.
Spice Girls!
- Let's go!
- Quick! We're late!
Clitford's gonna be mad.
- Oh, no!
- Coppers.
Stay calm.
It'll be all right.
Is there a problem, Otficer?
Dangerous driving,
criminal damage...
tlying a bus
without a license, and...
frightening the pigeons.
- Go on, Emma.
- But what do I say?
I'm really sorry, Otficer, but we were
late tor a show, so we were in a hurry.
We didn't hurt anybody
and we're just really sorry.
We promise never, ever
to do it again.
Shall we cut?
- What's the matter with him?
... It's the very essence of documentary.
Silence. Silence.
This is marvelous.
Okay...
so this is the plan.
The band starts up,
the tans go wild...
the lights come on
and I walk center stage and hang myselt.
By the way,
this is my good side.
My tinal words are...
"The Spice Girls...
I hate them!"
... What are you doing sitting around?
... We've got a show to do.
- Let's do it!
... Where are the mikes?
- Where are the clothes?
- And where are the bacon butties?
... I love those girls.
... Great.
I love those girls!
Damn.
Well, that's ruined a perfectly
good ending to this documentary.
Everything's under control.
Then let us enjoy this triumph
while we can...
before the hounds ot catastrophe
break tree ot their shackles...
and slobber chaos
all over our taces once again.
- Ciao, Chiet.
... What did he say?
Does it matter?
You know that thing you do when you've
been really horrible to someone...
and you want to make it
all right again?
And you have to,
you know, say stutt.
- Apologize?
... That's the one.
... I want to do that.
- You want to apologize?
Right. So, what do you think? Do we
still have a protessional relationship?
Ot course we do.
Why ever not?
Just a minute.
I love you.
Let's go crazy now!
The marvelos Spice Girls!
Gonna make this movie?
Have we got a deal?
... We've got a deal.
... Yes!
When yo're feeling
sad and low
We will take yo
where you gotta go
Smiling, dancing
Everything is free
All yoneed is positivity
- Colors of the world
... Spice up your life
Every boy and every girl
People everywhere
... Slam it to the left
- If you're having a good time
... Shake it to the right
- If yoknow that yofeel fine
Chicas to the front
Go rond
Hi Ci Ya hold tight
Yellow man in Timbktu
Color for both
me and yo
Kng-fu fighting
Dancing Queen
Travel, space, man
And all that's in between
- Flamenco
- Lambada
- But hip-hop is harder
- We moonwalk the fox-trot
Then polka the salsa
I'm worried about my character.
It's unreal. Do you know what I mean?
I know I'm supposed to be the baddie,
but why do I hate the Spice Girls?
- There's no reason.
- He's a caricature sort ot.
Sort ot this evil,
grotesque symbol...
about how power corrupts
and perverts.
Yeah, but why can't
I have a sotter side?
The kids are gonna start hating me,
attacking me in the street, like.
Look, as an artiste,
a good kicking...
could be the highest compliment
you'll ever get.
They want me to play
their road manager.
I'm on a mobile phone
getting angry all the time.
Well, I don't want
to end my career.
Fat or stupid or lazy...
That's all I get ottered, Alan.
- The sort ot character people ignore.
- They don't want my Scottish accent.
That's tine, doing a silly accent.
But the chest wig...
... Where's Mel B?
- This comedy chest wig.
- Hi, Mel.
... Hello.
... Are you all right?
- I've gotta wear this chest wig.
- You're Mel B?
... No, C.
Just call me Sporty.
It's all right.
All right, sweetheart.
That's that saying
from the tilm you did.
That was really good.
What was it called?
- That was brilliant.
- I've torgotten, but you were good.
I think we'd all like to say
a big thank you tor being in this.
We needed a serious actress
in this movie to give it some depth.
- We didn't want it to be...
- Superticial.
Could I ask about my chest wig?
They want me to wear this......
Graydon, can I speak to you
about our characters, please?
I was thinking, in one scene
I'd like to be really angry...
and maybe slap someone like...
like Victoria.
... Sure. Why not?
... Emma.
And you know what? I don't wanna be
on an exercise bike all the time.
Well, I've got this little catchphrase
that I'd really like to say.
I'd go up to somebody and I'd go,
"I'm not trom London, you know!''
'Cause you really are
trom London, right?
- I get the joke.
- Does he not know that I'm from Leeds?
Oh, you lot,
someone's watching us.
Oh, yeah.
Look at all those people in there.
- Hi.
... Hello.
Look at them two snogging
at the back there.
I bet you didn't see any ot our tilm.
And look where your hand is.
Go on! Go on!
Look at the mess they've made
with the popcorn. That's what I do.
I always wonder
why people sit there...
at the end of the tilm
and watch the credits go up.
It's probably the sad anticlimax.
It's all over. Back to reality.
... That's it.
- I know where they're gonna go.
They're gonna go down the pub
and then they're gonna go to the chippy.
Hey, you. No, not you. Behind you.
I like your dress.
- Is that a new Gucci one?
... C&A, mate.
Some people are watching this on video.
Is there nothing on telly, then?
Yeah, but you know what
they're wondering now, don't you?
What happened to
the bomb on the bus?
Elvis was
A coola shaker
Marley, Ziggy
Melody Makers
She's a Bond babe
Kick some ass
Doctor No
This girl's got class
Charlie's Angels
Girls on top
Handbags, heels
Their pistols rock
Baby Love
are so glam qeen
Sing the blues
A love supreme
'60s Twiggy set the pace
Way back then she had the face
That's all in the past
Legends bilt to last
But she's got something new
She's a Power Girl
In a '90s world
And she knows jst what to do
'Cause the lady is vamp
She's a vixen, not a tramp
She's a dadadadada dada
Come on, fellows, raise your bets
'Cause yoain't seen nothin' yet
She's the top of the top
She's the best, yes
Jackie O
We loved her so
Sorry, Mr. President
As far as we know
Norma Jean had
a seven-year itch
Some like it hot
to a fever pitch
Sandy Denny, summer love
And Grady's T...birds
to the moon above
That's all in the past
Legends bilt to last
But she's got something new
She's a Power Girl
In a '90s world
She's a downtown
Swinging dude
Scary, Baby
Ginger, Posh
Sporty, yes
Now that's your lot
We're the Spice Girls
Ready to go
Ladies and gents
can you please take your seats
And we hope that you
enjoyed the show
Thank you very much.
Translation And Subtitles By
Captions, Inc. Los Angeles