Captioning made possible by
Polygram video
See them
Tumbling down
Pledging their love
To the ground
Narrator: A way out west
There was this fella,
Fella I want
To tell you about,
Fella by the name
Of jeff lebowskl,
At least that
Was the handle
That his loving parents
Gave him.
But he never had
Much use for it himself.
This lebowskl,
He called himself the dude.
Now dude, That's a name
No one would self-Apply
Where I come from.
But then, There was
A lot about the dude
That didn't make a whole
Lot of sense to me,
And a lot about
Where he lived, Likewise.
Along with the
Tumbling tumbleweed
Narrator: But then again,
Maybe that's why I found the
Place so dern interesting.
They call los angeles
The city of angels.
I didn't find it
To be that exactly.
But I'll allow there
Are some nice folks there.
'Course I can't
Say I seen london,
And I never
Been to france,
And I ain't never seen no
Queen in her damned undies
As the fella says.
But I'll tell you what,
After seeing los angeles
And this a-Here story
I'm about to unfold,
Well, I guess
I seen somethin'
Every bit as stupefyin'
As you'd see in any
Of those other places,
And in english, Too.
So I can die
With a smile on my face
Without feeling like
The good lord gypped me.
Now this here story
I'm about to unfold
Took place back
In the early nineties,
Just about the time of
Our conflict with saddam
And the iraqis.
I only mention it 'cause
Sometimes there's a man,
I won't say a hero,
'Cause what's a hero?
But sometimes
There's a man,
And I'm talking
About the dude here,
Sometimes there's a man,
Well,
He's the man
For his time and place.
He fits right in there,
And that's the dude,
In los angeles.
And even if
He's a lazy man,
And the dude was
Most certainly that,
Quite possibly the laziest
In los angeles county,
Which would place him
High in the running
For laziest worldwide.
But sometimes
There's a man,
Sometimes...
There's a man.
Wow, Lost my train
Of thought here.
But... Ah, Hell.
I done introduced
Him enough.
George bush: All for
A collective action.
This will not stand.
This will not stand,
This aggression
Against kuwait.
Here on the range
I belong
Drifting along
With the tumbling
Tumbleweed
Aah!
Where's the money,
Lebowskl?
I want that money,
Lebowskl.
Bunny says you're
Good for it.
Where's the money,
Lebowskl?
Where's the fucking
Money, Shithead?!
Well, It's, Uh, Ohh,
It's down there somewhere.
Let me take another look.
Don't fuck with us!
Your wife owes money
To jackie treehorn,
That means you own
Money to jackie treehorn.
Ever thus to
Deadbeats, Lebowskl.
No, No, Don't do that...
Not on the rug, Man.
See?
See what happens,
Lebowskl?
You see what happens?
Nobody calls me
Lebowskl.
You got the wrong guy.
I'm the dude, Man.
Your name's
Lebowskl, Lebowskl.
Your wife is bunny.
My... My wife...
My wife bunny?
Do you see a wedding
Ring on my finger?
Does this place look
Like I'm fucking married?
The toilet seat's up,
Man.
What the fuck
Is this?
Obviously,
You're not a golfer.
Woo?
Yeah?
Isn't this guy supposed
To be a millionaire?
Woo: Fuck!
Yeah, What do you think?
He looks like
A fucking loser.
Hey, At least
I'm housebroken.
Fucking time wasted.
Thanks a lot,
Asshole.
La la la la
La la la la la
La la la
La la la la
La la la la la
The man in me will do
Nearly any task
And as for compensation
There's a little
He would ask
Take a woman like you
To get through
To the man in me
The storm clouds
Are raging
All around my door
I think to myself
I might not
Take it anymore
Take a woman
Like your kind
To find the man in me
But, Oh
What a wonderful feeling
Just to know
That you are near
That sets
My heart a-Reelin'
From my toes
Up to my ears
The man in me
Will hide sometimes
To keep from being seen
But that's just because
He doesn't want to
Turn into some machine
Take a woman like you
To get through
To the man in me
Whoo!
I'm throwing
Rocks tonight.
Mark it, Dude.
This was a valued rug.
Ahem. This was a...
Yeah, Man, It really
Tied the room together.
So this was
A valued, Uh...
What tied the room
Together, Dude?
My rug.
Were you listening to
The dude's story, Donny?
What?
Were you listening
To the dude's story?
I was bowling.
So you have no frame
Of reference here, Donny.
You're like a child
Who wanders in
In the middle of a movie...
Walter, What's
The point, Man?
There's no reason...
Here's my point, Dude...
There's no fucking reason...
Yeah, Walter,
What's your point?
Huh?
Walter, What
Is the point...
Look, We all know
Who is at fault here.
What the fuck are
You talking about?
Huh? No, What
The fuck are you...
I'm not...
We're talking about unchecked
Aggression here, Dude.
What the fuck is
He talking about?
My rug.
Forget it, Donny.
You're out of your element.
Walter, The chinaman
Who peed on my rug,
I can't go
Give him a bill.
So what the fuck
Are you talking about?
What the fuck
The chinaman is not
The issue here, Dude.
I'm talking about drawing
A line in the sand, Dude.
Across this line,
You do not...
Also, Dude, Chinaman is not
The preferred nomenclature.
Asian-American,
Please.
Walter, This isn't a guy
Who built the railroads here,
This is a guy...
What the fuck
Are you talking...
Walter,
He peed on my rug.
He peed on
The dude's rug.
Donny, You're
Out of your element.
Dude, The chinaman
Is not the issue here.
So,
Who... Who...
Jeff lebowskl.
The other
Jeffrey lebowskl,
The millionaire.
That's fucking
Interesting, Man.
Interesting.
Plus, He has
The wealth, Obviously,
And the resources,
Uh, So that
There's no reason...
There's no
Fucking reason
Why his wife
Should go out
And owe money
All over town,
And then they come
And they pee on
Your fucking rug!
Am I wrong?
No.
Yeah, But...
Ok, Then. Ahem.
That rug really tied
The room together,
Did it not?
Fuckin' a!
And this guy
Peed on it.
Donny, Please.
You know, This
Is the fucking guy...
I could find this
Fucking lebowskl guy.
His name is lebowskl?
That's your name, Dude.
This is the guy
Who should compensate me
For the fucking rug.
His wife goes out
And owes money
All over town,
And they pee on my rug?
They pee on
Your fucking rug.
My fucking rug.
Walter:
That's right, Dude.
They peed on
Your fucking rug.
This is the study.
As you can see,
The various commendations...
"Jeffrey lebowskl."
Honorary degrees,
Etcetera.
Hmm, Very impressive.
Oh, Please feel free
To inspect them.
Hmm? Oh, No, I'm
Not really that...
Oh, Please, Please.
That is the key to
The city of pasadena,
Which mr. Lebowskl
Received 2 years ago
In recognition of
His various civic, Uh...
Oh, That's
The los angeles
Chamber of commerce
Business achiever award,
Which is given...
Oh, Not necessarily
Given every year.
Hey, Is this, Uh,
Is this him with nancy?
Yes, Indeed,
That is mr. Lebowski
With the first lady, Yes.
It was taken when...
That's, Uh, Lebowskl
On the left there?
Yeah, Of course.
Mr. Lebowskl on the left...
So he's a cripple...
Uh, You know,
A... A handicapped guy?
Mr. Lebowskl
Is disabled, Yes.
Uh, This picture
Was taken
When mrs. Reagan was
First lady of the nation,
Yes, Yes.
Not of california.
Pope john.
Uh, In fact, He met
Privately with the president,
Though unfortunately,
There wasn't enough time
For a photo opportunity.
Oh, Nancy's pretty good.
Oh, Wonderful woman.
We're very happy...
These are, Uh...
Oh, Those are mr. Lebowskl's
Children, So to speak.
Different mothers, Huh?
Racially, Pretty cool.
Ha ha ha ha.
They're not literally
His children.
They're the little
Lebowskl urban achievers,
Inner-City children
Of promise
But without
The necessary means for...
Necessary means for
A higher education.
So mr. Lebowskl
Is committed
To sending all
Of them to college.
Excuse me.
Thank you. Thank you.
Far out.
Think he's got room
For one more?
One, Uh...
Oh. Ha ha ha.
You never
Went to college.
Please,
Don't touch that.
Yeah, No, I did,
But, You know,
I spent most
Of my time, Um,
Occupying various
Administration buildings,
Uh, Smoking a lot
Of thal stick,
Breaking into
The r.O.T.C.,
And bowling.
To tell you
The truth, Brandt,
I don't remember
Most of it.
Oh.
Hmm.
Ok, Sir, You're a lebowskl,
I'm a lebowskl,
That's terrific.
But I'm very busy,
As I imagine you are.
What can I
Do for you, Sir?
Uh, Well, Sir,
It's, Uh,
This rug I have.
It really tied
The room together. Uh...
You told brandt on
The phone, He told me.
Where do I fit in?
Well, Uh, They were...
They were looking
For you, These 2 guys.
Uh...
I'll say it again.
You told brandt on
The phone, He told me.
I know what happened.
Yes? Yes?
Oh, So you know that
They were trying
To piss on your rug?
Did I urinate
On your rug?
You mean, Did you
Personally come
And pee on my rug?
Hello! Do you
Speak english, Son?
Parla usted ingles?
I'll ask you again.
Did I urinate on your rug?
No, Like I said,
Woo peed on my rug.
I just want to
Understand this, Sir.
Every time a rug
Is micturated upon
In this fair city, I have
To compensate the person...
Come on, Man,
I'm not trying
To scam anybody here.
Uh, You know,
l... I was just...
You were just
Looking for a handout
Like every other...
Are you employed,
Mr. Lebowskl?
Uh, Wait, Let me...
Let me explain
Something to you.
I am not mr. Lebowskl.
You're mr. Lebowskl.
I'm the dude. So that's
What you call me,
You know, Uh, That
Or, Uh, His dudeness,
Or, Uh, Duder, Or, You
Know, Uh, El duderino,
If you're not into
The whole brevity thing.
Are you employed, Sir?
Employed?
Ha ha.
You don't go out
Looking for a job
Dressed like that,
Do you, On a weekday?
Is this a...
What day is this?
Well, I do work, Sir.
So if you don't mind...
No, I do mind.
Uh, The dude minds.
This will not stand,
You know.
This aggression
Will not stand, Man.
I mean, Your wife owes...
My wife is not
The issue here!
I hope that
Someday my wife
Will learn to live
On her allowance,
Which is ample,
But if she does not,
That is her problem,
Not mine,
Just as the rug
Is your problem,
Just as every bum's
Lot in life
Is his own
Responsibility,
Regardless of who
He chooses to blame.
I didn't blame anyone
For the loss of my legs.
Some chinaman took them
From me in korea.
But I went out
And achieved anyway.
Ha ha ha.
I cannot solve
Your problems, Sir,
Only you can.
Oh, Fuck it.
Yes, That's your answer.
That's your answer
To everything.
Tattoo it
On your forehead.
Your revolution is
Over, Mr. Lebowskl!
Condolences!
The bums lost!
My advice to you is to do
What your parents did!
Get a job, Sir!
The bums will always lose!
Do you hear me,
Lebowskl?!
The bums
Will always lose!
How was your meeting,
Mr. Lebowskl?
Ok. The old man told me to
Take any rug in the house.
Well, Enjoy,
And perhaps we'll see you
Again sometime, Dude.
Yeah, Sure, Uh, If I'm
In the neighborhood,
You know, And, Uh...
I need to use the john.
Blow on them.
Huh?
Go ahead, Blow.
You want me to blow
On your, Uh, Toes?
Uh-Huh. Ha ha ha.
I can't blow that far.
Are you sure
He won't mind?
He really doesn't
Care about anything.
He's a nihilist.
Oh, And that
Must be exhausting.
You're not blowing.
Our guest has to be getting
Along, Mrs. Lebowskl.
Oh, You're bunny.
I'll suck your cock
For $1,000.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Wonderful woman.
We're all... We're all
Very fond of her.
Very free-Spirited.
Brandt can't watch,
Though,
Or he has
To pay 100.
Ha ha ha.
That's marvelous.
Uh, I'm just gonna
Go find a cash machine.
Whoo! Ha ha!
Slamming them
Tonight.
You guys are
Dead in the water.
Walter: All right!
Way to go, Donny!
If you will it,
It is no dream.
You're fucking
20 Minutes late, Man.
What the fuck is that?
Theodore herzel.
Huh?
The state of israel.
If you will it, Dude,
It is no dream.
What the fuck you
Talking about, Man?
The carrier. What's
In the fucking carrier?
Hmm?
Oh, Cynthia's dog.
I think
It's a pomeranian.
I can't leave him
Home alone
Or he eats
The furniture.
I'm watching it
While cynthia
And marty ackerman
Are in hawail.
You brought a fucking
Pomeranian bowling?
What do you mean,
"Brought it bowling"?
I didn't rent it shoes,
I'm not buying it
A fucking beer,
He's not taking
Your fucking turn, Dude.
Man, If my
Fucking ex-Wife
Asked me to take care
Of her fucking dog
While she and her boyfriend
Went to honolulu,
I'd tell her to
Go fuck herself.
Why can't she board it?
First of all, Dude,
You don't have an ex.
Secondly, This is
A fucking show dog
With fucking papers.
You can't board it.
It gets upset.
Its hair falls out.
Walter...
The fucking dog
Has fucking papers.
Over the line!
I'm sorry, Smokey,
You were over the line.
That's a foul.
Bullshit.
Mark it 8, Dude.
Uh, Excuse me, Mark it
Zero. Next frame.
Bullshit, Walter.
Mark it 8, Dude.
Smokey, This is not
'Nam, This is bowling.
There are rules.
Hey, Walter, Come on,
It's just...
Hey, Man, It's smokey.
So his toe slipped
Over a little.
You know, It's
Just a game, Man.
This is a league game.
This determines
Who enters
The next round-Robin.
Am I wrong?
Smokey: Yeah,
But I wasn't...
Am I wrong?
Yeah,
But I wasn't over.
Give me
The marker, Dude.
I'm marking an 8.
Smokey, My friend,
You're entering
A world of pain.
Walter, Man.
You mark
That frame an 8,
You're entering
A world of pain.
I'm not...
Look, Dude,
This is your partner.
Has the whole world
Gone crazy?!
Am I the only one
Around here
Who gives a shit
About the rules?!
Mark it zero!
They're calling
The cops, Man.
Put the piece away.
Mark it zero!
Walter, Put
The piece away.
Walter...
You think I'm
Fucking around here?
Mark it zero!
All right,
It's fucking zero.
You happy,
You crazy fuck?
It's a league game,
Smoke.
You can't do that, Man.
These guys, You know,
They're like me.
They're pacifists.
Smokey was a
Conscientious objector.
You know, Dude,
I, Myself,
Dabbled in pacifism
At one point,
Not in 'nam,
Of course.
And you know he's got
Emotional problems, Man.
You mean,
Beyond pacifism?
He's fragile,
Very fragile.
Huh. I did not know that.
Well,
It's all water
Under the bridge,
And we do enter
The next round-Robin.
[Police siren]
Am I wrong?
No, You're not wrong.
You're not wrong,
Walter,
You're just an asshole!
Ok, Then.
We play quintana
And o'brien next week.
They should be pushovers.
[Siren stops]
Man, Will you just...
Just take it easy,
Man.
You know, That's your
Answer for everything, Dude.
And let me
Point out something.
Pacifism is not... Look
At our current situation
With that
Camelfucker in iraq.
Pacifism is not something
To hide behind.
Just take it easy, Man.
I'm perfectly calm, Dude.
Yeah, Waving
The fucking gun around?
Calmer than you are.
Will you
Just take it easy?
Calmer than you are.
[Answer machine beeps]
Dude, This is smokey.
Look, I don't want to
Be a hard-On about this,
And I know it
Wasn't your fault,
But I just thought
It was fair to tell you
That gilbert and I will be
Submitting this to the league
And asking them to
Set aside the round,
I don't know,
Maybe forfeit it to us.
So, Like I say, Just thought,
You know, Fair warning.
Tell walter. I'm sorry.
[Beep]
Mr. Lebowskl, This
Is brandt at, Uh,
Well, At
Mr. Lebowskl's office.
Please call us as
Soon as it's convenient.
[Beep]
Mr. Lebowskl,
This is bill selliger
Of the southern cal
Bowling league,
And I just got
Uh, An informal report
That a member of your team,
A walter sobchak,
Drew a firearm
During league play.
[Knock on door]
If this is true,
Of course,
It contravenes a number
Of the league's bylaws
And also article 27
Of the league...
Man: Dude.
Hey, Monty.
Dude, l... I finally got...
I got the, Uh,
The venue I wanted.
I'm performing
My dance quintet,
You know, My cycle,
At crane jackson's
Fountain street theater
On tuesday night,
And, Well, I'd
Love it if you came
And gave me notes.
I'll be there, Man.
Uh...
Dude, Uh,
Tomorrow's
Already the 10th.
Far out.
Oh. Oh, All right, Ok.
Just, Uh, Just slip
The rent under my door.
Bill selliger:
...Serious infraction
And examine your standing.
Thank you.
[Beep]
Mr. Lebowskl,
Brandt again.
Please do call us as
Soon as you get in,
And I'll
Send a limo.
I hope you're not
Avoiding this call
Because of the rug...
Ha ha ha...
Which, I assure you,
Is not a problem.
We need your help,
And, Uh...
Well, We'd very much
Like to see you.
Thank you.
It's brandt.
[Beep]
We've had some
Terrible news.
Mr. Lebowskl's in seclusion
In the west wing.
Mr. Lebowskl.
Funny...
I can look back
On a life of achievement,
Challenges met,
Competitors bested,
Obstacles overcome.
I've accomplished more
Than most men
And without the use
Of my legs.
What...
What makes a man,
Mr. Lebowskl?
Dude.
Huh?
Uh, l... I
Don't know, Sir.
Is it being prepared
To do the right thing?
Whatever the cost?
Isn't that what
Makes a man?
Mmm, Sure, That
And a pair of testicles.
You're joking.
But...
Perhaps you're right.
You mind
If I do a "j"?
Bunny...
[Crying]
Excuse me?
Bunny lebowskl,
She is the light
Of my life.
Are you surprised
At my tears, Sir?
Fuckin' a.
Strong men also cry.
[Clears throat]
I received this fax
This morning.
As you can see,
It is a ransom note.
"We have bunnie."
Written by men who
Are unable to achieve
On a level field
Of play.
[Reading to himself]
"Gather one million dollars
In unmarked,
Nonconsecutive twenties."
Weaklings.
"Await instructions."
Bums!
"No funny stuff."
Bummer.
Huh?
This is a bummer,
Man.
That's, Uh,
That's a bummer.
Brandt will fill you in
On the details.
Mr. Lebowskl
Is prepared to make
A generous offer to you
To act as courier
Once we get instructions
For the money.
Why me, Man?
He believes the culprits
Might be the very people
Who, Uh...
Soiled your rug,
And you're in
A unique position
To confirm
Or disconfirm
That suspicion.
He thinks the
Carpet pissers did this?
Well, Dude,
We just don't know.
[Singing hotel california
In spanish]
Fucking quintana.
That creep
Can roll, Man.
Yeah, But he's
A pervert, Dude.
Yeah.
No. He's a sex offender
With a record.
He did 6 months at chino
For exposing himself
To an 8-Year-Old.
When he
Moved to hollywood,
He had to go
Door-To-Door
To tell everyone
He was a pederast.
Donny: What's
A pederast, Walter?
Shut the fuck up,
Donny.
So...
How much
They give you?
20 Grand, Man.
And, Of course, I still
Get to keep the rug.
Just for making
The hand-Off?
Yeah. They gave, Uh,
Dude a beeper.
Now, So whenever
These guys call...
What if it's
During a game?
Oh, I told them if it
Was during league play...
What's during
League play?
Life does not
Stop and start
At your convenience,
You miserable
Piece of shit.
I figure, Uh...
What's wrong
With walter, Dude?
I figure
It's easy money.
It's all
Pretty harmless.
She probably
Kidnapped herself.
Huh?
What do you mean, Dude?
Rug pee-Ers
Did not do this.
Look at it.
A young trophy wife
Marries this guy
For his money.
She figures he isn't
Giving her enough.
You know, She owes money
All over town.
That fuckin'...
Bitch.
It's all goddamn
Fake, Man.
It's like lenin said.
You look for the person
Who will benefit,
And, Uh, Uh,
You know...
I am the walrus?
You know,
You'll, Uh, Uh...
You know what
I'm trying to say.
I am the walrus.
That fuckin' bitch!
Oh, Yeah.
I am the walrus.
Shut the fuck up,
Donny!
V.I. Lenin. Vladimir
llyich ulyanov!
What the fuck
Is he talking about?
Fucking exactly
What happened.
That makes me
Fucking sick.
What do you care,
Walter?
Those rich fucks.
This whole
Fuckin' thing.
I did not watch
My buddies die
Facedown in the mud
So that this
Fucking strumpet,
This fucking whore...
I don't see any connection
To vietnam, Man.
Well, There's
A literal connection.
No, Walter, Face it,
There isn't any connection.
Your roll.
Have it your way,
But my point is...
Your roll.
My point is...
Quintana: Are you ready
To be fucked, Man?
I see you roll your way
Into the semis.
Dios mio, Man.
Liam and me, We're
Gonna fuck you up.
Yeah?
Well... You know,
That's just like, Uh...
Your opinion, Man.
Let me tell you
Something, Pendejo,
You pull any
Crazy shit with us,
You flash a piece out
On the lanes,
I'll take it away from you
And stick it up your ass
And pull
The fuckin' trigger
Till it goes click.
Jesus.
You said it, Man.
Nobody fucks
With the jesus.
8-Year-Olds, Dude.
[Bowling ball hits pins
On cassette]
[Hit, People cheer]
[Hit]
[Music plays]
La-La la-La-La-La
La la la
La-La-La-La
La la
La-La-La-La-La
La la la la
La la la
La-La-La-La
La la la la la-La
The man in me will do
Nearly any task
And as for compensation
There's little
He will ask
Aah!
Take a woman
Like you
To get through
To the man in me
The storm clouds
Are raging
All around my door
I think to myself
I might not take it
Anymore
Take a woman
Like your kind
To find
The man in me
But oh-Ohh
What a wonderful feeling
[Pager beeps]
Just to know
That you are near...
[Beep beep]
[Yawning]
[Groaning]
Ohh, Man.
[Beep beep]
Ohh!
Ohh...
[Beep beep]
They called about
80 Minutes ago.
They want you
To take the money,
Drive north on the 405.
They will call you
On the portable phone
With instructions
In about 40 minutes.
One person only. They
Were very clear on that,
Or I'd go with you.
One person only.
What happened to your jaw?
Oh, Nothin',
You know.
Here's the money.
And the phone.
Please, Dude, Follow whatever
Instructions they give.
All right.
Her life is in your hands.
Oh, Man,
Don't say that.
Mr. Lebowskl asked me
To repeat that.
Her life is in your hands.
Oh, Shit, Man.
Her life is in
Your hands, Dude.
Report back to us
As soon as it's done.
Where the fuck
Are you goin', Man?
Take the ringer.
I'll drive.
What? The what?
The ringer.
The ringer,
Dude.
[Tires squeal]
Have they
Called yet? What the...
What the hell is this?
My dirty undies,
Dude.
Laundry.
The whites.
Walter, I'm sure
There's a reason
You brought
Your dirty undies, Man.
That's right, Dude.
The weight.
The ringer
Cannot look empty.
Walter, What the fuck
Are you thinking, Man?
You're right, Dude.
I got to thinking.
I got to thinking
Why should we settle
For a measly fuckin'
20 Grand...
We? What the fuck we?
You said you just wanted
To come along.
My point, Dude, Is
Why should we
Settle for 20 grand
When we can keep
The entire million?
Am I wrong?
Yes, You're wrong.
This isn't
A fuckin' game, Man.
Oh, But it is a game.
You said so yourself.
She kidnapped herself.
I said I thought...
[Telephone rings]
[Ring]
Dude here.
Man, German accent:
Who is this?
Dude the bagman, Man.
Where do you want us to go?
Us?
[Whispering]
Shit!
Yeah, You know,
Me and the driver.
I'm not handling the money,
Driving the car,
And talking on the phone
All by my...
Shut the fuck up!
Dude, Are you
Fuckin' this up?
Who is that?
That is the driver.
I told you...
[Dial tone]
Shit!
What the fuck's
Goin' on?
Walter!
What the fuck is goin' on?
He hung up, Man!
You fucked it up!
Her life was
In our hands, Man.
Easy, Dude.
We're screwed now.
We don't get shit.
They're gonna kill her.
We're fucked, Walter.
Nothing is fucked,
Dude.
Come on, You're
Being very undude.
They'll call back.
Look,
She kidnapped...
[Telephone rings]
You see? Nothing's
Fucked here, Dude.
[Ring]
Nothing is fucked.
They're a bunch of
Fuckin' amateurs!
Hey, Walter, Will you
Just shut the fuck up?
Don't say peep while I'm
Doin' business here, Man.
Ok, Dude,
Have it your way.
But they're amateurs.
Fuck.
Dude.
Ok, We proceed.
But only if there's
No funny stuff.
Yeah, Yeah.
So no funny stuff, Ok?
Just tell me where the fuck
You want us to go.
That was the sign, Man.
So all we gotta do
Is get her back,
No one's in a position
To complain,
And we keep
The baksheesh.
Yeah, Terrific, Walter,
But you haven't told me how
We're gonna get her back.
Where is she?
That's the simple part,
Dude.
We make the hand-Off,
I grab one of 'em,
Beat it out of him.
Huh?
Yeah. That's
A great plan.
Walter, That's
Fucking ingenious,
If I understand it
Correctly.
It's a swiss
Fuckin' watch.
That's right, Dude.
The beauty of this
Is its simplicity.
Once a plan
Gets too complex,
Everything
Can go wrong.
If there's one thing I
Learned in 'nam, It's...
[Telephone rings]
Dude.
You're coming
To a wooden bridge.
When you cross
The bridge,
You throw the bag
From the left window
Of the moving car.
You're being watched.
[Dial tone]
Fuck!
What'd he say?
Where's the hand-Off?
There is no fuckin'
Hand-Off, Man.
At the wooden bridge, We throw
The money out of the car.
We throw the money
Out of the moving car.
No, We can't
Do that, Dude.
That fucks up
Our plan.
Well, Call 'em up and
Explain it to them, Walter.
Your plan
Is so fuckin' simple
I'm sure they'll
Fuckin' understand it.
That's the beauty of it.
Wooden bridge, Huh?
I'm throwin' the money,
Walter.
We're not fuckin'
Around, Man.
Ok, Dude,
Bridge is comin' up.
Give me the ringer,
Chop-Chop.
Fuck that, Walter.
I love ya,
But sooner or later you're
Gonna have to face the fact
You're a goddamn moron.
Ok, Dude.
No time to argue.
Hey, Man.
The bridge.
Hey, Walter! Hey!
Walter, Hey!
There goes the ringer!
What the fuck?!
Here, Dude, Your wheel.
At 15 mph, I roll out.
I double back, Grab one,
And beat it out of him.
The uzl.
Uzl?!
You didn't think I was
Rolling out of here naked?
W-Walter, Please...
15, Dude. This is it.
Let's take that hill!
[Uzl self-Firing]
[Tire blows]
Whoo-Hoo-Oo.
Aah... Aah.
We have it!
[Gasping]
We... Have it!
Aw, Fuck it, Dude.
Let's go bowling.
[Portable phone rings]
[Ring]
[Ball hits pins]
Ah.
[Ring]
Etz chaim he, Dude,
As the ex used to say.
What the fuck is that
Supposed to mean?
What the fuck are we
Gonna tell lebowskl?
Huh?
Oh, Him. Uh...
[Ring]
Well, Uh, What exactly
Is the problem?
The problem is...
What do you mean,
What's the...
[Ring...]
There was no...
We... We didn't, Uh...
They're gonna kill
That poor woman, Man.
What the fuck are you
Talking about?
The poor woman...
That poor slut
Kidnapped herself.
Come on, Dude,
You said so yourself.
Man, I said I thought
She kidnapped herself.
You're the one who's
So fuckin' certain.
That's right, Dude.
100% Certain.
They posted the next round
For the tournament.
Donny, Shut the fuck...
When do we play?
This saturday.
Quintana and...
Saturday? Well, They
Have to reschedule.
Walter, What am I
Gonna tell lebowskl?
I told that fuck down
At the league office...
Who's in charge
Walter... Of scheduling?
Burkhalter.
I told that kraut
A fuckin' thousand times
I don't roll
On shabbos.
He already
Walter... Posted it.
Well, He can fuckin'
Unpost it!
Who gives a shit?!
They're gonna kill
That poor woman, Man.
What am I gonna tell
Lebowskl?
Come on, Dude,
Eventually she'll get tired
Of her little game
And, You know,
Wander on back.
How come you don't roll
On saturday, Walter?
I'm shomer shabbos.
What's that, Walter?
Yeah,
And in the meantime,
What do I tell
Lebowskl?
Saturday, Donny,
Is shabbos,
The jewish day of rest.
That means I don't work,
I don't drive a car,
I don't fuckin' ride in a car,
I don't handle money,
I don't turn on the oven,
And I sure as shit
Don't fucking roll!
Sheesh.
Shomer shabbos!
Walter,
How am I gonna...
Shomer fucking shabbos.
Oh, Fuck! That's it!
I'm outta here.
Oh, Come on, Dude.
Dude! Dude!
Look, You just tell him...
Tell him we made the drop,
And everything went,
You know...
Oh, Yeah,
How'd it go?
Went all right. Dude's car
Got a little dinged up.
Walter, We didn't make
The fuckin' hand-Off, Man.
They didn't get
The fuckin' money!
And they're gonna...
They're gonna...
They're gonna kill
That poor woman.
That poor woman
Hey, Walter, If you
Can't ride in a car,
How do you get around
On shammos?
Really, Dude,
You surprise me.
They're not gonna kill shit,
They're not gonna do shit.
What can they do to her?
They're a bunch
Of fuckin' amateurs,
And meanwhile,
Look at the bottom line.
Who's sittin' on
A million fucking dollars?
Am I wrong?
Walter...
Who's got a fuckin' million
Fuckin' dollars
Sitting in the trunk
Of our car?
Our car, Walter?
And what do they got?
My dirty undies.
My fuckin' whites.
[Telephone rings]
[Ring]
Say, Dude.
Where is your car?
[Ring]
Who's got your
Undies, Walter?
Where's your car, Dude?
You don't know,
Walter?
[Walter clearing throat]
It was parked
In a handicap zone.
Perhaps they towed it.
You fuckin' know
It's been stolen.
Well, Certainly that's
A possibility, Dude.
Oh, Fuck it.
[Ring]
Donny:
Where you goin', Dude?
I'm goin' home, Donny.
[Ring]
Phone's ringing, Dude.
Thank you, Donny.
[Ring]
[Ring...]
Uh...
Yeah, Uh...
Green.
Some, Uh, Brown or...
Rust coloration.
And was there anything
Of value in the car?
Oh. Uh, Yeah.
Uh... A tape deck,
Some creedence tapes,
And there was a, Uh...
Uh, My briefcase.
In the briefcase?
Uh, Uh, Papers.
You know, Um,
Just papers.
Uh, You know,
Uh, My papers.
Business papers.
And what do you do,
Sir?
I'm unemployed.
[Home telephone rings]
My rug was
Also stolen.
Your rug was in the car?
No, Here.
[Ring]
Separate incidents?
Answering machine:
The dude is not in.
Do you find them much,
These stolen cars?
Sometimes.
Wouldn't hold out much hope
For the tape deck, Though.
Or the creedence.
Well, What about, Uh...
[Answering machine
Beeps]
The briefcase?
Woman: Mr. Lebowskl,
I'd like to see you.
Call when you get home,
And I'll send a car for you.
My name is maude lebowskl.
I'm the one
Who took your rug.
Guess we can close
The file on that one.
[Heavy door
Opens and closes]
[Woman chanting breathily]
[Chanting continues]
Huh.
[Chanting reverberates
In room]
[Heavy thud]
[Mechanism rumbling]
Woman: Elfranco,
Ay'dame abajo.
I'll be with you
In a moment, Mr. Lebowskl.
[Breathy chanting resumes]
Does the female form make you
Uncomfortable, Mr. Lebowskl?
Uh, Is that what this
Is a picture of?
In a sense, Yes.
My art has been commended
As being strongly vaginal,
Which bothers some men.
The word itself makes
Some men uncomfortable.
Vagina.
Oh, Yeah?
Yes, They don't like hearing it
And find it difficult to say,
Whereas without
Batting an eye,
A man will refer to
His dick or his rod
Or his... Johnson.
Johnson?
All right, Mr. Lebowskl.
Let's get down to cases.
My father told me he agreed
To let you have the rug,
But as it was a gift
From me to my late mother,
It was not his to give.
Now...
Your face.
As for this kidnapping...
Huh?
Yes, I know all about it,
And I know that
You acted as courier.
Let me tell you something.
The whole thing stinks
To high heaven.
Yeah...
Right, But let me
Explain something
About the rug.
Do you like sex,
Mr. Lebowskl?
Excuse me?
Sex. The physical act
Of love. Coitus.
Do you like it?
I was talking
About my rug.
You're not interested
In sex?
You mean coitus?
I like it, Too.
It's a male myth
About feminists
That we hate sex.
It can be a natural,
Zesty enterprise.
However, There
Are some people...
It is called satyriasis in men,
Nymphomania in women...
Who engage in it compulsively
And without joy.
Oh, No.
Oh, Yes, Mr. Lebowskl.
These unfortunate souls
Cannot love
In the true sense
Of the word.
Our mutual acquaintance
Bunny is one of these.
Listen, Maude,
Um, I'm sorry if your
Stepmother is a nympho,
But, You know,
I don't see what this
Has to do with, Uh...
Do you have any kahlua?
Take a look
At this, Sir.
Hmm?
Oh, I know that guy.
He's a nihilist.
[Reading title card]
HI.
[German accent]
Hello. Meine dispatcher says
There's something wrong
Mitt deine kable.
Yeah, Come on in.
I'm not really sure
Exactly what's really
Wrong with the cable.
Zat's why they sent me.
I am an expert.
The tv's in here.
You recognize her,
Of course.
Bunny: Oh, That's
My friend sharl.
She just came over
To use the shower.
The story
Is ludicrous.
Meine nommen is karl.
Ich bin expert.
You must be here
To fix the cable.
Maude: Lord, You can imagine
Where it goes from here.
He fixes the cable?
Don't be fatuous,
Jeffrey.
Little matter to me
That this woman chose
To pursue a career
In pornography
Nor that she has been
"Banging" jackie treehorn,
To use the parlance
Of our times,
However,
I am one of the 2 trustees
Of the lebowskl foundation,
The other being my father.
The foundation takes
Youngsters from watts and...
Shit, Yeah,
The achievers.
Little lebowskl
Urban achievers, Yes,
And proud we are
Of all of them,
I asked my father about
His withdrawal of $1 million
From the foundation account,
And he told me
About this abduction.
But I tell you,
It is preposterous.
This compulsive fornicator
Is taking my father
For the proverbial ride.
Yeah, But my...
I'm getting to your rug.
My father and I
Don't get along.
He doesn't approve
Of my lifestyle,
And, Needless to say,
I don't approve of his.
However, I hardly wish to make
My father's embezzlement
A police matter,
So I'm proposing that you
Try to recover the money
From the people
You delivered it to.
Well, Uh,
I could do that.
If you successfully do so,
I will compensate you
To the tune of 10%
Of the recovered sum.
A hundred...
Thousand. Yes.
Bones or clams
Or whatever you call them.
Yeah, But... But, Uh...
What about my, Uh...
Your rug, Yes.
Well, With that money
You can buy
Any number of rugs
That don't have
Sentimental value for me.
And I am sorry about
That crack on the jaw.
Oh, Th-That's fine.
That doesn't even, Uh...
Here's the name and number
Of a doctor
Who will look at it
For you.
You will receive no bill.
He's a good man,
And thorough.
Th-That's thoughtful,
But...
Please see him, Jeffrey.
He's a good man,
And thorough.
Oh, Well...
All right.
So he says, "My wife's
A pain in the ass.
"She's always bustin'
My friggin' agates.
"My daughter's married
To a real loser bastard,
"And I got a rash
So bad on my ass
"I can't even sit down.
But you know me, I can't
Complain." [Laughs]
Ah, Fuckin' a, Man.
I got a rash, Man.
Fuckin' a.
I gotta tell you,
Tone, Man,
Earlier in the day, I was
Really feeling shitty, Man.
Really down
In the dumps.
Lost a little money...
Hey, You know what?
Forget about it, Huh?
Forget about it.
Yeah, Fuck it, Man.
I can't be worried
About that shit.
Life goes on, Man.
Home, Sweet home,
Mr. L.
Tony: Hey, Yo. Look.
Who's your friend
In the volkswagen?
Huh?
Yeah, He followed us
Here.
When did he start foll...
Aah!
What the fuck?!
In the limo, You son
Of a bitch. No arguing.
Hey, Careful, Man.
There's a beverage here.
Hey!
Start talking
And talk fast,
You lousy bum.
We've been frantically
Trying to reach you, Dude.
Where's my goddamn
Money, You bum?!
W-Well, We...
l... l... I...
They did not
Receive the money,
You nitwit!
They did not receive
The money!
Her life
Was in your hands!
This is our concern,
Dude.
No, Man,
Nothing is fucked here.
Nothing
Is fucked?!
No, Man.
The goddamn plane
Has crashed
Into the mountain!
Look, Man, Come on.
Who are you gonna believe,
Those guys or, Uh...
We dropped off
The damn money.
We?!
I.
The royal we.
You know, The editorial.
I dropped off the money
Exactly as per...
Look. Man, I've got certain
Information, All right?
Certain things have
Come to light, And...
You know, Has it
Ever occurred to you
That instead of, Uh,
You know, Running around,
Uh, Blaming me, Given the
Nature of all this new shit,
Th-Th-This could be
A lot more, Uh...
Uh, Uh, Uh, Complex?
I mean, It might not be
Just such a simple, Uh,
You know?
What in god's
Holy name
Are you blathering
About?
Well, I'll tell you what
I'm blathering about.
I've got information, Man.
New shit has come to light.
And... And, Shit, Man...
She kidnapped herself.
Well, Sure, Man.
Look at it. You know,
A young trophy wife...
In the parlance
Of our times, You know...
She, Uh, Uh, Uh, Owes
Money all over town,
Including to known
Pornographers.
And that's cool.
That-That's cool.
I'm saying,
She needs money, Man.
And... And, You know,
Of course they're gonna say
They didn't get it,
Uh, Uh, Because
She wants more, Man.
She's gotta feed the monkey.
I mean, Uh...
Hasn't that ever occurred
To you, Man?
Sir?
No, Mr. Lebowskl,
It had not occurred
To me.
That had not occurred
To us, Dude.
Well, Ok, You know,
You guys aren't privy
To all the new shit, So...
Uh, You know. But...
Hey, That's what you...
That's what you pay me for.
[Slurping]
Speaking of which,
Do you think that you could, Uh,
Give me my 20,000 In cash?
My concern is... And I gotta
Check with my accountant...
But this might bump me
Into a higher tax, Uh...
Brandt...
Give him
The envelope.
Oh, Well, If you've already
Got the check made out,
Th-That's cool.
We received this
This morning.
Since you have
Failed to achieve,
Even in the modest task
Which was your charge,
Since you have
Stolen my money,
Since you have unrepentantly
Betrayed my trust...
I have no choice
But to tell these bums to do
Whatever is necessary
To recover their money
From you, Jeffrey lebowskl.
And with brandt
As my witness,
I will tell you this:
Any further harm
Visited upon bunny
Will be visited tenfold
Upon your head.
By god, Sir, I will not
Abide another toe.
I hear the cottonwoods
Whisperin' above
That wasn't her toe, Dude.
Whose toe was it,
Walter?
How the fuck should I know?
I do know that nothing
About it indicates...
Man, The nail
Polish, Walter.
Fine, Dude.
As if it's impossible
To get some nail polish,
Apply it
To someone else's toe.
Someone else's...
Where the fuck
Are they gonna get...
You want a toe?
I can get you a toe.
Believe me,
There are ways, Dude.
You don't wanna know
About it, Believe me.
Hell, I can get you a toe
By 3:00 this afternoon,
With nail polish.
These fuckin' amateurs.
Walter...
They send us a toe,
We're supposed to shit
Ourselves with fear.
Jesus christ.
Walter...
Now, The point is...
They're gonna kill her,
Walter,
And then they're gonna
Kill me.
Dude...
That's...
That's just the stress
Talking, Man.
Now so far we have
What appears to me
To be a series of
Victimless crimes.
What about the toe?
Forget about
The fucking toe!
Excuse me, Sir,
Could you please
Keep your voices down?
This is a family restaurant.
Oh, Please, Dear.
For your information,
The supreme court
Has roundly rejected
Prior restraint!
Walter, This is not
A first amendment thing.
If you don't calm down,
I'm gonna have to ask you
To leave.
Lady, I got buddies who
Died face down in the muck
So you and I could enjoy
This family restaurant!
All right,
I'm outta here.
Hey, Dude,
Don't go away, Man.
Come on, This affects
All of us, Man.
Our basic freedoms!
I'm stayin'.
I'm finishing my coffee.
[Water gurgles through
Overflow drain]
[Telephone rings]
[Snorting inhalations]
[Ring]
Answering machine:
The dude is not in.
Leave a message
After the beep.
Thanks, Man.
Mr. Lebowskl, This is
Duty officer rolvaag
Of the lapd.
We've recovered
Your automobile.
It can be claimed at the
North hollywood auto circus
There on victory.
Far out, Man.
Far fucking out!
[Banging]
H-Hey!
This is a private
Residence, Man.
Ah, Nice marmot.
Aah!
[Marmot squealing]
Aaaahhh!
Ve vant the money,
Lebowskl.
Aah!
[Whimpering]
You think
Ve are kidding
Or making with
The funny stuff?
There are things
You haven't dreamed of,
Lebowskl.
Ja. Ve believe
In nothing.
He believes in nothing,
Lebowskl, Nothing.
And tomorrow
Ve come back
And ve cut off
Your chonson.
Excuse me?
I said we'll cut off
Your johnson!
Just think about that,
Lebowskl.
Ja, Your viggly penis,
Ja, And maybe we stomp on it
And sqoosh it, Lebowskl.
[Glass shatters]
Man: It was discovered
Last night in van nuys
Lodged against
An abutment.
Oh, Man, Lodged where?
You're lucky she
Didn't get chopped,
Mr. Lebowskl.
Oh, Man!
Must've been
A joyride situation.
They abandoned
The vehicle
Once they hit
The retaining wall.
Oh, My
Fucking briefcase!
Man, It's not here.
Shit!
Yeah, I saw that
On the report. Sorry.
You gotta get in
On the other side.
The side-View was
Found on the road
By the car.
You're lucky they left
The tape deck, Though,
And the creedence.
Aw, Jesus!
What's that smell, Man?
Probably a vagrant
Slept in the car
Or maybe just used it
As a toilet and moved on.
Hey, Man...
Are you gonna find
These guys or, You know,
I mean, You got any
Promising, Uh, Leads or...
Leads?
Yeah. Sure.
I'll just check
With the boys
Down at
The crime lab.
They, Uh, Got
4 More detectives
Working on the case.
They got us
Working in shifts.
Ha ha ha!
Leads.
My only hope is that
The big lebowskl kills me
Before the germans
Can cut my dick off.
Now, That is just
Ridiculous, Dude.