(drumroll)
(rousing orchestral fanfare playing)
(fanfare ends)
(horn honking)
(engine revving)
(horns honking)
(horn honking)
(second horn honking)
(tires squealing)
(bicycle bell tinkles)
(horns honking)
(horn honks)
(second horn honks)
(tires screech)
(engine revving)
(tires screeching)
(shouting in Hindi)
(indistinct chatter in Hindi,
woman speaking over P.A.)
That's my train.
Wait! Wait...!
(The Kinks'
"This Time Tomorrow" playing)
¢Ü This time tomorrow ¢Ü
¢Ü Where will we be? ¢Ü
¢Ü On a spaceship somewhere ¢Ü
¢Ü Sailing across an empty sea ¢Ü
¢Ü This time tomorrow ¢Ü
¢Ü What will we know? ¢Ü
¢Ü Will we still be here ¢Ü
¢Ü Watching an in-flight
movie show? ¢Ü
¢Ü I'll leave the sun behind me ¢Ü
¢Ü And I'll watch the clouds
as they sadly pass me by ¢Ü
¢Ü Seven miles below me ¢Ü
¢Ü I can see the world
and it ain't so big at all ¢Ü
¢Ü Oh... ¢Ü
(train bells dinging)
¢Ü This time tomorrow ¢Ü
¢Ü What will we see? ¢Ü
¢Ü Fields full of houses ¢Ü
¢Ü Endless rows
of crowded streets. ¢Ü
(sighs)
(quietly): Shit.
Ow.
(inhales deeply)
(snores quietly)
Wake up, Jack.
(chuckles)
Have you seen Francis?
(glasses clinking)
Hello, Peter.
- (Peter chuckles)
- (knocking at door)
Good afternoon. Whitman?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
May I see your tickets, please?
Thanks.
There's no smoking, please.
(train car chugging)
Welcome aboard.
(speaking in Hindi)
Sweet lime?
- Yes, please.
- Sure, I'll have one.
- Sounds good.
(inhales softly)
Let's go get a drink
and smoke a cigarette.
I want to start by thanking you both
for being here. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you.
You're the two most important
people in the world to me.
I've never said that before, but it's true,
and I want you both to know it.
I love you, Peter.
Thank you.
I love you, Jack.
I love you, too.
How did it get to this?
Why haven't we spoken in a year?
Let's make an agreement.
- To do what?
- Okay.
A: I want us
to become brothers again
like we used to be,
and for us to find ourselves
and bond with each other.
Can we agree to that?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- B: I want us
to make this trip
a spiritual journey,
where each of us seek the
unknown, and we learn about it.
Can we agree to that?
- Sure.
- I guess so.
C: I want us
to be completely open
and say yes to everything,
even if it's shocking and painful.
Can we agree to that?
Now, I had
Brendan make us an itinerary.
Who's Brendan?
My new assistant.
He's gonna place an updated
schedule under our doors
every morning of all
the spiritual places
and temples
that we need to see
and expedite hotels
and transportation and everything.
How's he gonna do that?
I had him bring a printer
and a laminating machine.
Where is he?
In a way, it actually
doesn't matter.
He's in a different compartment
on another part of the train,
but we never see him- ever.
That's more or less it.
Three, please.
Does that sound okay to you?
It sounds good, sure.
Yeah, it sounds good.
Do you have any questions?
- I do.
- Okay, go ahead.
What happened to your face?
I only remember
certain details,
but from what I've been able
to reconstruct,
it was raining, I was going
about 50 miles an hour
as I went into a corner,
did some wrong steering,
wheels went out from me,
and I suddenly, whoo,
skidded off the road,
slammed into a ditch
and got catapulted
50 feet through the air.
Little particles
of glass and debris
were stinging my face as I flew.
And for a second,
there was just total silence.
Just...
(imitates wind)
Then bam! The bike crashed
to the ground,
exploded and caught on fire,
and I smashed into the side
of a hill with my face.
I was driving home.
I live alone right now.
Anyway, two joggers ran up
and started digging out
all the dirt that was
jammed inside my mouth
and my nose and my ears.
My brain had stopped,
my heart had stopped,
so technically I was dead
at this point.
They did all the procedures
exactly right,
as a result of which
I'm still alive.
- Boy.
- Wow.
The first thing I thought
of when I woke up was,
I wish Peter and Jack were here.
Have you heard anything from Mom?
No.
Have you?
Me neither.
Fuck.
(mutters)
What's that?
Some kind of Indian muscle relaxer.
I got it at the pharmacy
next to the train station.
What's that?
You don't need a prescription here.
A type of Indian flu medicine.
It's got a tranquilizer in it.
PETER: What's that?
Strongest Indian
painkiller you can get.
It's for my face.
Be careful with that.
You only want to take one drop.
(woman speaking German)
- (speaking German)
- Shh.
I also lost a tooth.
You want to read a short
story I wrote in France?
(muffled): How long is it?
What?
- How long is it?
Never mind. Forget it.
You can save it till after dinner.
You know,
maybe right before
whenever you're about
to take out your tooth,
you should say something
like, "Please forgive this."
Because it's, actually,
it's kind of...
Can... you... back away a little?
You just spit in my eye.
When was the last time you
were in America, by the way?
I don't know.
The funeral.
In other words, a year?
I have to tell you,
I support this relationship
not working out.
May I take your order, please?
Let's see.
Do we want meat or fish?
I'm gonna have the chicken.
Jack, you want to try the fish?
I bet that's delicious.
And, Peter, the lamb?
A chicken, a fish and a lamb?
How does that sound?
Who wants a soup?
Raise your hand.
Are those Dad's glasses?
Yeah.
You still have
his prescription in here.
How can you see in these?
Three soups.
WAITER: Soup.
Could you not order for me, please?
What?
Order for yourself.
(women arguing in German)
(laughing)
What part are you on?
Nothing.
It reminded me of something
not related to it.
How's Alice?
She's fine.
She actually started
this company
where she makes these
little clay pots.
They're quite popular.
We sent you one.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
I want that stewardess.
(women arguing loudly in German)
(mutters)
These Germans are bothering me.
(speaking German)
Ladies! Please keep it down.
Lower your voices. Thank you.
Did I... raise us?
Kind of?
Hang on- I'm gonna ask this guy
if he can get me a power adapter.
She's pregnant.
Alice.
Really?
- You're kidding.
- No.
Uh, how long?
Seven and a half months.
So it's gonna be
born in, like,
six weeks or something.
I think so, yeah.
I'm trying not
to get too caught up
in it right now.
Don't tell Francis.
Brendan got the wrong voltage.
Your soup, sir.
Please forgive this.
(tooth clinking)
Hmm.
Is it supposed to be sad?
I think so.
Well, I'm not too crazy
about the part
where I start screaming
at the mechanic.
That never happened.
The characters are all fictional.
May I take your dessert order, sir?
Let's see.
Do we want sweets or fruit?
I'm gonna have the pudding.
Jack, you want to try the cake?
And, Peter, what looks good to you?
The cookies?
He's gonna order for himself.
The cookies.
Excuse me, I'm...
(clears throat)
Has he been rooting around
and taking things?
Maybe.
I think he's still in mourning.
Well, I probably
am, too, but there's
something kind of unethical
about it, isn't there?
Legally those glasses
belong to all three of us.
(medicine dripping)
I'm gonna take this bed,
because I'm the oldest
and my ankle's fractured.
Peter, you don't mind climbing
a ladder as I recall,
so why don't you set up shop
topside?
And, Jack, you're a little bit
of a lone wolf.
Why don't you bunk out next door?
How does that sound?
Oh, sorry.
- I-I was...
- FRANCIS: Stand up.
Brendan, this is Jack.
- Good evening.
- And this is Peter.
Hello, Brendan.
Nice to meet you.
Let's update me.
How's everything going back there?
- Pretty good.
- What does that mean?
I never heard back.
So try again.
What are you waiting for?
Well, I left a message.
Why are you smiling?
What do you think
he looks like
under all that tape and everything?
FRANCIS (muffled):
Brendan, what did I tell you?!
Well, I don't know
about his face,
but I think his brain
might be pretty traumatized.
Damn it!
Come down to this spot over here.
Call her again
right now
and keep calling
every ten minutes
- until you get through.
- Okay.
This is urgent.
We're almost there.
- Okay.
- And once again,
so we're explicitly clear,
I don't want you
to mention this
or discuss it with anyone.
In other words, it's a surprise.
Okay.
Did you find me a power adapter?
Not yet.
JACK:
How long are you gonna stay here?
What do you mean?
He said till the end of the month.
Uh-huh.
Why do you ask that?
I'm just trying to know so
I can figure out my plans.
What plans?
I don't know yet.
Anyways, I've got my own
ticket, just in case.
Don't tell Francis.
Well, I'm not gonna stay here
with just me and him.
(door opens)
Is that one of Alice's pots?
FRANCIS: Oh.
We should order some more of these.
I'll tell Brendan.
Okay.
He has this disease where
his head is shaved,
except he doesn't
have to shave it
because he can't grow any
hair in the first place.
Don't... talk about it
around him, though.
It might offend him.
(window opens)
Are these Dad's keys?
Yeah.
You've got his car keys, too?
Where's those nuts at?
(buzzing)
(knocking on door)
I got it, I got it, I got
it, I got it, I got it.
Good evening, Mr. Whitman.
How can I help you?
Is it possible for us
to get some more
of those Savoury Snacks, please?
Of course.
Can I offer you anything else?
Um... I don't think so.
I'll be right back.
I forgot something.
(knocking on window)
You want to smoke a cigarette
with me in the bathroom?
You're crazy.
What's your name?
Jack. What's yours?
Rita.
You're beautiful.
Don't come into me.
Jack's got his own return ticket.
He says he might leave early.
What are you talking about?
Don't tell him I told you.
Brendan's got all the tickets.
There's a whole itinerary.
Where is he going?
Air Italiano?
What the fuck is this?
I'm keeping his passport.
In fact, give me yours, too.
I want to keep
all the passports
so nothing happens to them.
I'm keeping mine.
No. I want to keep
them all together.
Why are you standing there?
I'm waiting for you.
Mr. Whitman,
the whole point
of us coming
out separately
is so no one sees us together.
Jack.
Right. I get it. Okay.
Good night, then.
Go back to your compartment.
Move over, please.
Where are the Savoury Snacks?
Huh?
Did you just fuck that Indian girl?
What?
Sweet Lime.
Of course not.
I went for a walk.
Something just happened.
- Shh!
- Who's he talking to?
No one.
He's got the code
to his ex-girlfriend's
answering machine,
and he's checking her messages.
What? When... When did
he confide that to you?
Just now.
Why am I not a part of this?
I've never liked that girl.
Me neither.
Anyway, I never trusted her.
I don't feel good about myself.
FRANCIS:
Okay. Let's make another agreement.
On the spiritual journey,
it's crucial
that we don't splinter
into factions
or not include somebody
who has advice and may know better.
- Can we agree to that?
- Okay.
- What did you find out?
- Nothing.
Good.
She put this in my suitcase.
(all sniffing)
Is that her?
Mm. That's her.
How did she gain access
to your personal belongings?
She came to see me in
France for 24 hours.
Could she be gaslighting you?
What's gaslighting?
Okay, hang on a second.
Let's make another agreement.
From now on,
if you want to talk to her
or check her messages,
you speak to us first.
Day or night. Anytime.
Can you agree to that?
I think we should destroy that.
Jesus!
Okay. All right.
Let's check the itinerary.
Give me a little light.
Okay, here we go.
Train stops first thing
tomorrow morning
for an hour and 45 minutes,
which is just enough time
for a quick visit
to Temple of a Thousand Bulls,
probably one of
the most spiritual places
in the entire world.
Wow.
Power adapters!
Can I get a power adapter?
Yes, yes, yes.
Do you have a power adapter?
No, no.
No power adapter.
Use battery.
Do you have these in, say,
a ten-and-a-half medium?
These all size.
Take off shoes and try.
PETER: Yeah, like that. That's good.
Pepper spray. What ingredients
does this have in it?
I don't want to kill
anybody or anything.
No, no.
Not for killing.
Spray in face.
Okay. Spray in face.
(hissing)
Most rare, from desert.
Very poisonous.
How much you want for him?
(bells ringing, people chanting)
This is incredible.
(bell dings)
Ring it.
(ringing)
Take some of these
rupees and put them
on this thing in front
of the deity here.
(inhaling, exhaling deeply)
Is that my belt?
Can I borrow it?
Well, no, not right now.
I was looking for that earlier.
(grunts)
- Ask first... next time.
- Right.
Where's my passport?
I got pickpocketed.
My passport got stolen.
Calm down.
- It's not stolen.
- No, yes, it is.
- It's gone.
- No, it's not.
I have it.
I'll be right back.
You stole my passport?
Peter, where are you going?
I'm going to go pray
at a different thing.
I hear you're leaving early.
What are you talking about?
I thought we made an agreement.
That's why you stole my passport?
Well, no, but I think
we have a chance
to make this kind of a
life-changing experience,
and I think we need it.
In other words,
I don't want you to leave.
He's going to have a
kid in six weeks.
- Who?
- Him, Rubby.
- He doesn't want you to know.
- "Rubby"?
Yeah, you know, Rubby.
- Yeah.
- (chuckles)
Why doesn't he want me to know?
JACK:
Because we don't trust each other.
Wow, right?
- Yeah, amazing.
- Great, thanks.
Let's get a shoeshine.
Oh, hit it.
Hey. Hey, come back here!
- What?
- The kid just left...
- Who?
- He just...
(shouting): Get him!
- He left his shoeshine kit.
- He...
Well, now he can pay
for this building.
Those are $3,000 loafers!
Yeah, but he only got one of them.
Yeah, but that's...
We're in an emergency here.
I got my face smashed in,
Jack's heart's been
ripped to shreds,
and Rubby's having a child.
Let's get into it.
You told him?
It's okay.
Okay, that's what
we're here for,
to start trusting each other.
I don't get it, by the way.
Why aren't we celebrating?
'Cause I don't want
to talk about it.
Well, why not?
(sighs)
I guess because
I always expected
eventually I'll get divorced,
so having children...
really wasn't part of my plan.
Okay, but you're never
gonna do better than Alice,
and what's the point
in getting married...
Why'd you expect to get divorced?
I don't know.
I love Alice.
Maybe it relates
to how we were raised.
I was gonna save this
for later in the itinerary,
but I think it's time.
There's a ceremony I want
us to do where we each
take one of these peacock feathers.
We're gonna go off
into the wilderness
and meditate for...
Damn it, I gave them to Brendan.
That's all right, we'll
do it after the next stop.
Those guys are laughing at us.
Where?
I love it here.
These people are beautiful.
They're playing cricket
with a tennis ball.
(boys laughing)
- (bicycle bell dings)
- Hello.
- How do you do?
It's great.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
It's so well-written.
You remember everything so clearly.
Peter getting all frantic
getting the car started,
you with the suitcase.
The characters are all fictional.
Well, anyway,
I think it's the best thing
you've ever written.
Thank you.
Here are the peacock feathers,
plus some instructions
from the guru.
What's in that box?
He bought a snake.
It's got a skull and crossbones...
Let's update me.
Anything?
She got the message, yeah.
And?
What? That's it.
That's it.
She got the message.
You're satisfied with that?
Well, she knows you're coming.
Does she want to see us?
But she's your mother.
Happy birthday...
from last year.
I can't accept this.
It's too valuable.
It's got one
wrong initial,
but you can paint over it.
It's from me and Jack.
(knocking)
Yes?
RITA: Would you like tea?
Okay.
Thank you.
(folk rock)
¢Ü You talk like Marlene Dietrich ¢Ü
¢Ü And you dance
like Zizi Jeanmaire ¢Ü
¢Ü Your clothes are
all made by Balmain ¢Ü
I got to get off this train.
¢Ü And there's diamonds
and pearls in your hair ¢Ü
¢Ü Yes, there are ¢Ü
¢Ü You live in a fancy apartment ¢Ü
¢Ü Off the Boulevard Saint-Michel... ¢Ü
What's her name again?
Rita.
(Peter mumbles)
What'd you say?
There's a hole in it.
He escaped.
No, he didn't.
How?
(all yelling, gasping)
PETER:
Now-Now you believe me, assholes?
We think a snake might
have gotten on board.
¢Ü But where do you go to,
my lovely ¢Ü
¢Ü When you're alone
in your bed? ¢Ü
Don't go in there, Rita.
(snake hissing, Rita gasps)
FRANCIS: You got him!
(woman speaks German)
(speaks Hindi)
I'm kicking you off
at the next station.
Please don't do that.
We're very sorry.
It won't happen again.
I know it won't.
What's that smell?
Voltaire Number Six.
Do you have
a prescription for these?
A prescription?
I almost died.
Give me a second.
¢Ü Where do you go to,
my lovely ¢Ü
¢Ü When you're alone
in your bed? ¢Ü
¢Ü Tell me the thoughts
that surround you ¢Ü
That animal's deadly poisonous
and you brought him onto my train.
We didn't know.
It was an accident.
We're just trying
to experience something.
It's very important to us.
(indistinct radio transmission)
(speaks Hindi)
You're confined
to your compartment
until further notice.
Is our snake getting confiscated?
(music playing)
Do you think it's working?
Do we feel something?
- I hope so.
- It's got to.
Do you trust me?
(loud thumping)
Where are we?
(door squeaks)
(speaking Hindi)
(clanking)
(indistinct chatter in Hindi)
Brendan, what's going on?
I don't know. I guess
the train's lost.
What'd he say?
He says the train's lost.
How can a train be
lost? It's on rails.
Apparently we took a wrong
turn at some point last night.
That's crazy.
How far off course are we?
Nobody knows-we haven't
located us yet.
What'd you just say?
What?
What you just said.
Say it again.
We haven't located us yet.
Aah!
Is that symbolic?
"We... haven't
located... us... yet."
Where's those feathers at?
In the envelope
I gave you this morning.
Meet me on top of
that thing out there.
The guru told me
when the moon turns...
Do you trust me?
I hired a private detective
to track down Mom.
She's living in a convent in
the foothills of the Himalayas.
We'll be there in six days.
How is that possible?
I guess she became a nun,
apparently.
You know what she's like.
A nun?
Apparently.
Did you talk to her?
No, I didn't.
Does she know we're coming?
I think so.
How do you know she wants to see us?
She probably doesn't.
But maybe she does.
Why didn't you tell us sooner?
Because I'm trying
to protect you
from all the painful emotions
this is probably gonna stir up.
Well, aren't you kind of
doing that right now?
Yeah.
I'm scared, too.
She's obviously suffered
some kind of mental collapse
and we've got to go get her
and bring her back home.
Actually, it's in the itinerary,
but I put it under "T.B.D."
(laughs)
Why are you laughing?
You didn't tell us
'cause we never
would've come here
if we knew about it.
I'm gonna hold this in
for a little while.
(train whistle blowing)
You gonna drink that whole
bottle of cough medicine?
That's a dumb way to get loaded.
Let's look at the itinerary.
Fuck the itinerary.
(sighs)
You know, I think I'm gonna have
to get that belt back after all.
Because it cost me $6,000
and it was made special for me.
We'll get you a different present.
I don't think so.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means there's been too much
Indian giving over the years.
(knocking on door)
These guys are driving me crazy.
Is there an empty compartment
I can move into?
No, there isn't.
We're fully booked.
I really want to kiss you
right now. Can I?
No.
No?
But we already... did it.
I have a boyfriend.
You do?
Actually, I just broke up with him.
Or I'm about to.
(bell buzzes)
I really need someone
to talk to right now.
And I feel like you might be
very important to me in my life.
All right.
(bell buzzes)
(knocking on door)
What did I tell you?
Get back in your room.
- What's happening?
- What do you mean?
- I rang the bell.
- I'll be right there.
(chattering, music playing)
(dinging)
(music playing)
(razor buzzing)
Is that Dad's razor?
Yeah.
Can I say something?
What?
You don't have permission
to take his property
that belongs to all of us
and use it for yourself
as if it's yours.
Jack agrees with that.
Right, Jack?
Plus, Dad would've hated it.
Why?
That's my opinion.
I knew him well.
That's a terrible thing to say.
Well, I don't mean it to be.
I just don't want you
to get the feeling
that you're better friends
with him than we are
or something weird like that.
And, also, you can't
leave your wife
just because she's pregnant.
Jack agrees with that, too.
Right, Jack?
Stop including me.
I was his favorite.
He told me that with blood all
over him laying in the street
right before he died.
How is that supposed
to make us feel?
I want my passport back.
Francis?
Yeah?
Here's your belt.
(growls)
(grunting)
Fuck. Stop!
- You don't love me!
- Yes, I do!
I love you, too, but I'm gonna
mace you in the face!
Stop!
(screaming)
(all screaming)
I had to do it!
Jack! (groans)
You maced us!
Stop including me!
(screaming)
(glass breaks)
BRENDAN: I'll find us a hotel.
Next train's in 24 hours.
This just came in.
Why are your eyes all red?
Why is your head so bald?
Because I have alopecia.
Oh, yeah.
That's like albino, right?
Not really.
Jack maced us.
Was I just mean to Brendan?
He's not coming back.
He just quit.
He did, didn't he?
Can we at least get our snake back?
It's dead.
You killed him?
Your fake tooth's gone.
Fuck.
(mutters in German)
What did you say?
Shame on you.
Did you get maced, too?
No, I'm crying.
What's wrong with you?
Let me think about that.
I'll tell you
the next time I see you.
Sure, tell me then.
Thanks for using me.
You're welcome.
Good-bye, Rita.
FRANCIS: So long, Sweet Lime.
(metal clangs)
(rocks clang against metal)
"Dear boys..."
WOMAN'S VOICE: Bad timing.
This morning I received the
details of your travel plans
in a document sent to me
from a man named Brendan.
Unfortunately,
I cannot receive you now.
A neighboring village requires
our urgent assistance
due to an emergency,
not to mention the recent
arrival of a man-eating tiger
in the region.
I suggest you come
in the spring
when you'll be safe with me.
You must know how sad I am
to experience this long separation.
I hope you'll eventually
understand and forgive me.
God bless you and keep you with
Mary's benevolent guidance
in the light of Christ's
enduring grace.
All my love, your mother,
Sister Patricia Whitman.
FRANCIS:
That sounds like bullshit to me.
- JACK: Me, too.
- PETER: Obviously.
She's trying to sell us
a vacuum cleaner.
(soft music plays)
Let's get high.
I'm sorry.
Me, too.
I wasn't trying to aim
for your face.
Doesn't matter,
it's already demolished.
Let's just go home.
She doesn't want to see us anyway.
You don't think so?
Not even on some primordial level?
No.
FRANCIS:
She's been disappearing all our lives.
We weren't raised
to be treated like that.
It's just not done.
Maybe this is how
it's supposed to happen.
It could all be part of it.
Maybe this is where the
spiritual journey ends.
You read the instructions,
right?
Okay, let's do it.
I'm gonna go over here.
Yeah, g... that's good,
get on the rock. Yeah.
- Yeah. Yeah, okay.
- Peter, you get... Yeah.
- Everybody ready?
- Yeah.
- Ah! Oh!
- Shalom.
(all chanting gibberish)
Okay, that's it.
That's it.
Okay.
(quietly): Well, all right.
Which direction did yours go?
What do you mean?
Your feathers.
Mine blew towards the mountains.
That's not right- it's
not supposed to get blown away.
You're supposed
to blow on it... (blows)
And then bury it.
I didn't get that.
I still have mine.
You guys didn't do it right.
I asked you
if you read the instructions.
You did it wrong.
(sighs)
I tried my hardest.
I don't know what else to do.
I don't think Dad
would have hated it.
Did he really say
you were his favorite?
I don't know.
I could barely understand him.
He wasn't really breathing.
I wonder if the three of us
could have been friends
in real life.
Not as brothers but as people.
Well, we probably would've had
a better chance, I guess.
Let's make another agreement:
We'll all come back here
in the spring when...
We're never coming back here.
Let's just find an airport
and go our separate ways.
Wouldn't it sound great
if you could hear a train
going by off in the
distance right now?
- Not really.
- Probably be annoying.
(boy shouts in Hindi)
Look at these assholes.
That's gonna tip over.
(yelling)
Go!
(boys shouting)
Get the little one.
Francis!
(grunting): Grab him!
Don't let go of me.
PETER: He's all tangled up.
(grunts, gasps)
Hang on, hang on.
I got you.
(loud grunt)
PETER: I can't get him out!
(boy shouts)
- (loud snap)
- Peter!
(thunder rumbling)
(amplified heartbeat)
He's all bloody!
(amplified heartbeat
accelerates)
- (heartbeat stops)
- He's dead. He's dead.
- He's dead?
- The rocks killed him.
You're bleeding like crazy.
FRANCIS: Peter! You okay?
I didn't save mine.
(panting)
What's his name?
(animal bleats)
(bell tinkling)
(speaking Hindi)
- Papa! Papa!
- Hey!
(boy speaks
frantically)
(man speaking Hindi)
(train whistle blowing
in distance)
(speaking angrily in Hindi)
(quietly): No.
(people speaking Hindi
in distance)
(quiet chatter in Hindi)
(men speaking Hindi)
(many women wailing)
(women continue wailing)
(men speaking Hindi)
(man speaks Hindi)
Thank you.
(woman speaks quietly)
(speaks Hindi)
(birds chirping)
(man singing in Hindi
in distance)
(speaks Hindi)
(baby cries briefly)
(long sigh)
(wind whistling)
PETER:
Can you explain that I almost had him?
I lost him when
we went off the rocks.
He was too slippery.
I had him the whole
rest of the time.
I want them to know that.
(bus idling)
What you doing in this place?
Well, originally, I guess,
we came here
on a spiritual journey,
but that didn't really pan out.
(door opens)
(music playing quietly,
indistinct chatter)
We're invited to the funeral.
Okay.
(guitar strumming
mid-tempo intro)
¢Ü Where you going? ¢Ü
¢Ü I don't mind ¢Ü
¢Ü I've killed my world
and I've killed my time ¢Ü
¢Ü So where do I go? ¢Ü
¢Ü What will I see? ¢Ü
¢Ü I see many people
coming after me ¢Ü
¢Ü So where are you going to? ¢Ü
¢Ü I don't mind ¢Ü
¢Ü If I live too long ¢Ü
¢Ü I'm afraid I'll die ¢Ü
¢Ü So I will follow you ¢Ü
¢Ü Wherever you go ¢Ü
¢Ü If your offered hand ¢Ü
¢Ü Is still open to me ¢Ü
¢Ü Strangers on this road
we are on ¢Ü
¢Ü We are not two,
we are one ¢Ü
¢Ü So you've been
where I've just come ¢Ü
¢Ü From the land
that brings losers on ¢Ü
¢Ü So we will share
this road we walk ¢Ü
¢Ü And mind our mouths
and beware our talk ¢Ü
¢Ü Till peace we find,
tell you what I'll do ¢Ü
¢Ü All the things I own,
I will share with you ¢Ü
¢Ü And if I feel tomorrow
like I feel today ¢Ü
¢Ü We'll take what we want ¢Ü
¢Ü And give the rest away... ¢Ü
(orchestral classical music
playing quietly)
I can't believe you just said that.
Why not?
It's the truth.
He didn't really mean it.
I think you're all
equally grief-stricken.
Let's just leave it at that.
When does Mom get in?
She's going straight there
from the airport.
I want to pick up the car.
We're already late.
Tell the driver
- to take a right.
- We don't have time.
- Let's do this later.
- No. I want to get it now.
Uh, excuse me?
I'm sorry, uh, we're gonna
need to make a stop first
at this address.
Go ahead- I'll be right behind you.
I think we should wait for you.
Why?
Francis.
Tell them we'll be there
in five minutes.
(bell buzzes)
MAN: Hey, hey...
Hey.
Yeah, we're here to pick up
Mr. Whitman's car.
No, Mr. Whitman's car is not ready.
What do you mean, it's not ready?
No, we're waiting for...
a part.
- A part?
- Yeah.
Uh, I left a message
with his secretary.
No, no, no, that's crazy.
This car's been here
for three months.
He can't wait any longer.
He'll have to wait another week.
Uh, I left a message.
Yeah, he didn't get the message.
Mr. Whitman is dead.
You understand?
Jimmy Whitman?
Yeah.
What happened to him?
He got hit by a taxi.
And it killed him?
Yeah.
His change was scattered
all over 72nd Street.
Oh, you're his sons.
Right. And we're gonna
take this car
to his funeral, which
we're late for, right now.
Where are the keys?
Peter, we'll come back
later and get the car.
It's not ready, right?
It's not ready.
- (no audible dialogue)
- (indistinct chatter over radio)
(engine sputtering)
(backfire)
The battery's dead, too.
FRANCIS: There it is.
That's the other one.
We found it.
We're still waiting for a part
to come in from Stuttgart.
Where's a battery charger?
What are you doing?
- This one's mine.
- No, it's not.
We need to take it home and
enter it in the inventory.
I'm taking this suitcase.
You going somewhere?
I don't know.
Where's the goddamn battery charger?
Ah, aha!
Guess he didn't read
my book in time.
What do you mean?
In time for what?
The envelope's never been opened.
Oh, you mean when
he was still alive.
WOMAN (over speaker):
Phone call for a Francis Whitman.
Hello.
ALICE: They want to start.
Send the car back for us.
The battery's dead.
They can only wait ten minutes.
There's another service after us.
Okay, well, we might not
make it, then.
I guess just...
tell 'em to go fuck themselves.
Hold the line.
No, you're going to start
when they get here,
not one second before.
Is that perfectly clear?
Try to be quick.
Okay.
- Wait a second.
- Yes?
I spoke to your mother.
She's not coming.
She didn't get on the plane.
Why not?
I don't know. I'm sorry.
Will you tell Peter and Jack, so
they don't expect to see her?
Yeah.
ALICE: I'm sorry.
Thanks, Alice.
Thank you.
- RECEPTIONIST: You're welcome.
- (shouts)
Put it in second.
Put it in second!
Pop it!
(horn honking)
Watch it, asshole!
What do you want?
Are you kidding me?
Fuck, no.
You get back in your car right now.
Get back in that car!
This isn't gonna work.
- Let's put the cover back on it.
- Let's go.
FRANCIS: Come on. Steer it in.
Let's go.
Who called?
Alice.
What'd she say?
They're waiting.
Mom there?
Not yet.
(chanting in Hindi)
(chanting continues)
(flames crackling)
Hey...
hey, help him up.
You okay?
(music playing softly)
(footsteps)
(bus horn honking)
(bus approaching)
(brakes hissing)
(praying in Hindi)
Let me help you.
(Indian pop song playing)
¢Ü ¢Ü
(whistles)
(metal detector warbling)
Whitman.
The flight boards in 25 minutes.
Let's set aside the next ten
minutes to use as free time.
Do a little shopping,
have a snack,
make a phone call, and then
we'll meet in the bathroom
next to that statue over there
at about a quarter after,
get cleaned up,
brush your teeth,
have a shave or what have you,
and in our last five minutes
we'll sit quietly in
that little shrine over there,
say a prayer and think about
everything we've been through.
(indistinct P.A. Announcements
in Hindi)
Three, please.
(sighs)
I love the way this country smells.
I'll never forget it.
It's kind of spicy.
Who's he talking to?
I think he's trying
to rehire Brendan.
He said he's gonna
offer him a 50% raise
plus some medical benefits
to help with his albino disease
or whatever it's called.
How'd it go?
He's gonna think about it.
He's gotta get hired
back, because otherwise
I'm probably just a bad person.
And in some ways I
feel like Brendan
might be my...
friend maybe.
I'll be right back.
He didn't really kill
our snake, did he?
I mean, it's gotta be
against his religion.
I bet he just sent him
out into the desert, which is...
actually closer to his
natural habitat.
Who's he talking to?
Probably checking his
ex-girlfriend's messages again.
I thought we made an agreement.
Why didn't you stop him?
What'd you find out this time?
She's gonna meet me in Italy.
Oh, man, that's terrible.
I know.
I'll be right back.
Let's look at the itinerary.
(woman speaking on P.A.,
indistinct)
Is that from Sweet Lime?
Who's he talking to?
I didn't say that.
I didn't want... Hello?
Alice, I guess.
It's a boy.
It got born already?
It's gonna be a boy.
She had a sonogram or something.
It's a boy?
That's incredible!
- Wow!
- Yeah.
Why were you yelling?
She's angry 'cause I didn't tell
her I was coming here.
Ever?
Until just now?
Yeah.
But I explained everything.
It's actually kind of lucky
'cause I got this vest.
It can work with either one,
but I think it's better for a man.
(chuckles)
Here, he can inherit this.
It's from me and Jack.
Thanks.
Can I use those scissors?
(jet passes overhead)
I guess I've still got
some more healing to do.
You're getting there, though.
Anyway, it's
definitely gonna add
a lot of character to you.
What should we pray for now?
(engine roar drowns out
conversation)
¢Ü ¢Ü
(wind whistling)
Didn't you get my letter?
I told you to come back
in the spring.
Should we go?
Of course not.
Welcome, my beautiful boys.
Francie, Peter, Little Jack.
What happened to your face?
I smashed into a hill
on purpose on my motorcycle.
I'm sorry to hear that.
There's so many things
we don't know about
each other, aren't there?
Who's this?
That's Oberoi.
He got us here.
(both converse in Tibetan)
Whoa, whoa, wait a second.
What are you saying to him?
I'm telling him
to lock up your horses.
There's a tiger.
Really? We thought
that was bullshit.
You call that bullshit?
He ate one of the Sister's brothers.
(brothers laugh)
I'm not kidding.
¢Ü Praise him ¢Ü
¢Ü Praise him, praise him
in the morning ¢Ü
¢Ü Praise him
when the sun goes down ¢Ü
¢Ü Love him, love him ¢Ü
¢Ü Love him in the morning,
love him in the noontime ¢Ü
¢Ü Love him, love him. ¢Ü
(bell tolling)
What do we want for breakfast?
Jack, you'll like
the porridge,
Peter, fresh mango, and
cornflakes for you, Francie.
Now who wants scrambled
eggs? Raise your hand.
What's on fire in that
hideous little flowerpot?
Alice made that.
Oh, it's darling.
Tell her I said so.
Okay.
You want one?
Of course I do.
¢Ü Everybody knows ¢Ü
¢Ü But don't play with me ¢Ü
(music box tinkling)
¢Ü 'Cause you're playing
with fire ¢Ü
¢Ü Your mother, she's... ¢Ü
PETER: Mom?
Uh-huh?
There's one last thing.
I want to tell you about my son.
What son?
The one I'm gonna have next month.
Well, you should be with Alice.
You should have been
at Dad's funeral.
So that's why you came here.
We came here because we miss you.
I miss you, too.
But why didn't you
come to Dad's funeral?
Because I didn't want to.
Why are we talking this way?
What's wrong with us?
We should be celebrating.
What are you doing here?
I live here.
These people need me.
What about us?
You're talking to her.
You're talking to someone else.
You're not talking to me.
I don't know the answers
to these questions
and I don't see myself this way.
Listen.
I'm sorry we lost your father.
We'll never get over it,
but it's okay.
There are greater forces at work.
Yes, the past happened,
but it's over, isn't it?
Not for us.
I told you not to come here.
Maybe we could express
ourselves more fully
if we say it without words.
Should we try that?
¢Ü ¢Ü
¢Ü Well, you've got
your diamond ¢Ü
¢Ü And you've got
your pretty clothes ¢Ü
¢Ü And the chauffeur drives
your cars ¢Ü
¢Ü You let everybody know ¢Ü
¢Ü But don't play with me ¢Ü
¢Ü 'Cause you're playing
with fire ¢Ü
¢Ü Your mother,
she's an heiress ¢Ü
¢Ü Owns a block
in St.John's Wood ¢Ü
(thunder crashing)
¢Ü And your father'd be there
with her ¢Ü
¢Ü If he only could ¢Ü
¢Ü But don't play with me ¢Ü
¢Ü 'Cause you're playing
with fire ¢Ü
(snake hissing)
¢Ü Her old man took
her diamonds ¢Ü
¢Ü And tiaras by the score ¢Ü
¢Ü Now she gets her kicks
in Stepney ¢Ü
¢Ü Not in Knightsbridge anymore ¢Ü
¢Ü So don't you play with me ¢Ü
¢Ü 'Cause you're playing
with fire ¢Ü
¢Ü So don't you play with me ¢Ü
¢Ü 'Cause you're playing
with fire ¢Ü
(tiger growling)
¢Ü So don't you play with me ¢Ü
¢Ü 'Cause you're playing
with fire. ¢Ü
All right, let's make an agreement.
A: We'll get an early start
tomorrow morning
and try to enjoy
each other's company here
in this beautiful place.
B: We'll stop feeling sorry
for ourselves.
It's not very attractive.
C: We'll make our plans
for the future.
Can we agree to that?
- Sure.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
To be continued.
(birds chirping)
Good morning.
She's gone.
What?
I was still asleep,
but Oberoi saw her go.
Peter.
What?
She's gone.
Who?
She's gone?
Where?
They couldn't say.
They just said she
goes away sometimes.
She left our breakfast
in the doorway.
Whoo!
Zip!
Pshew!
I'm working on a new short story.
I wrote the ending, but I
don't know how it starts.
Read us what you got.
"'Whatever happens
in the end,' she said,
"'I don't want to lose
you as my friend.'
"He looked into her eyes.
"'I promise I will never
be your friend,
"no matter what, ever.'
"Her voice cracked.
"'If we fuck, I'm gonna
feel like shit tomorrow.'
"'That's okay with me,' he said.
"He lifted her shirt over her head.
"'I love you,' she said.
"'I never hurt you on purpose.'
"He nodded.
'I don't care.'
He would not be going to Italy."
That sound okay?
Yeah. It's hard for me
to judge the ending
without knowing the rest of it.
I like how mean you are.
Well, the characters are all...
Thanks.
That's our train.
Hurry!
Dad's bags aren't gonna make it!
(chuckling)
(rock song playing)
¢Ü I know a man,
he's a powerful man ¢Ü
¢Ü Got the people in his power
in the palm of his hand ¢Ü
¢Ü He started at the bottom
and he worked his way up ¢Ü
¢Ü Now he's never gonna stop
until he reaches the top ¢Ü
¢Ü It's the same old story ¢Ü
¢Ü It's the same old dream ¢Ü
¢Ü It's power, man, power, man,
and all that it can bring ¢Ü
¢Ü If you want your money,
better stand in the line ¢Ü
¢Ü But you'll only end up
picking up ¢Ü
¢Ü The nickels and dimes. ¢Ü
(knocking on door)
Good morning. Whitman?
Uh-huh.
May I see your ticket,
please?
Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
Sweet lime?
Why not?
Why don't you hang onto mine?
It's safer if you keep them.
Let's go get a drink
and smoke a cigarette.
¢ÜJe m'baladais sur I'avenue
le coeur ouvert a I'inconnu ¢Ü
¢ÜJ'avais envie de dire bonjour
a n'importe qui ¢Ü
¢Ü N'importe qui et ce fut toi,
je t'ai dit n'importe quoi ¢Ü
¢Ü II suffisait de te parler,
pour t'apprivoiser ¢Ü
¢Ü Aux Champs-Elysees,
aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Au soleil, sous la pluie,
a midi ou a minuit ¢Ü
¢Ü II y a tout ce que vous
voulez aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Tu m'as dit "J'ai rendez-vous
dans un sous-sol avec des fous ¢Ü
¢Ü Qui vivent la guitare
a la main, du soir au matin" ¢Ü
¢Ü Alors je t'ai accompagnee,
on a chante, on a danse ¢Ü
¢Ü Et I'on n'a meme
pas pense a s'embrasser ¢Ü
¢Ü Aux Champs-Elysees,
aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Au soleil, sous la pluie,
a midi ou a minuit ¢Ü
¢Ü II y a tout ce que vous
voulez aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Hier soir deux inconnus
et ce matin sur I'avenue ¢Ü
¢Ü Deux amoureux tout etourdis
par la longue nuit ¢Ü
¢Ü Et de I'Etoile a la Concorde,
un orchestre a mille cordes ¢Ü
¢Ü Tous les oiseaux du point
du jour chantent I'amour ¢Ü
¢Ü Aux Champs-Elysees,
aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Au soleil, sous la pluie,
a midi ou a minuit ¢Ü
¢Ü II y a tout ce que vous
voulez aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Aux Champs-Elysees,
aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Au soleil, sous la pluie,
a midi ou a minuit ¢Ü
¢Ü II y a tout ce que vous
voulez aux Champs-Elysees ¢Ü
¢Ü Aux Champs-Elysees,
aux Champs-Elysees... ¢Ü
(song fades)
(melodic Indian music plays)
¢Ü ¢Ü
(music fades)
(train whistle blows)
sub2srt by ¿­³ë(Yeolno)
http://nfou.net/