Ha Ha Ha Ha!
Money, money, money!
Hey!
You got a date with justice, One-Eyed Bart.
- Too bad, Sheriff.
I'm a married man.
One-Eyed Betty!
I think you dropped something, mister.
Jessie?
- Give it up, Bart.
You've reached the end of the line.
I always wanted to go out with a bang.
Oh no!
- The orphans!
Hate to leave early, but our ride is here.
It's me or the kiddies, Sheriff.
Take your pick.
Ride like the wind, Bull's-eye!
Hold 'em steady.
Woody, hurry!
No ...
Glad I can catch the train.
- Now let's catch some criminals.
To infinity and beyond.
Reach for the sky.
- You can't touch me, Sheriff.
I brought my attack dog
with a built-in force field.
Well, I brought my dinosaur
who eats force fields dogs.
Evil Doctor Pork Chop.
That’s Mr. Evil Doctor Pork Chop to you.
Buzz, shoot your laser on my badge.
- Woody, no, I'll kill you.
Just do it.
You're going to jail, Bart. Ah, watch out!
Mom!
- No, no, no. Just keep playing.
Just pretend I’m not here.
Oh, no, Molly!
- No, it's ok, Mom.
It's a 50 foot baby from outer space.
And she's on a rampage!
Run for your lives!
Does the red light mean it's going?
Come on say "Happy Birthday" to Molly.
Happy birthday.
- Oh. Charming.
Look how tall you're getting.
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue.
Good work, Buzz.
Ok places, everyone. Come on, come on.
Get in position.
- Wait, I can't find my other eye.
All right, whose foot's in my face?
- It's mine, give it back.
You saved our lives.
We are eternally grateful.
Buzz, mind if I squeeze in next to you?
Yes. No.  I mean, why would I mind if
I squeeze .. squeeze in next to .. you?
Is it hot in here?
- Oh, here they come.
Sarge, you got it?
- Mission accomplished.
- Hooray!
Careful. Careful.
All right guys. We've got one shot at this.
Everybody ready?
- We're ready, Woody. Let's do it.
Ok Buzz, make the call.
Target is on approach.
- Just like we rehearsed it guys.
Hello. Hello.
Anyone there?
Molly, stay out of my room.
- I wasn't in your room.
Then who was messing with my stuff?
- It wasn't me.
Well, that went well.
- He held me! He actually held me!
Uh, this is just sad.
- Who we kidding? The kid's 17 years old.
- We ain't ever getting played with.
Guys, hey, hold up. We need a staff meeting.
Everyone, a staff meeting.
Oh, not again.
- Oh come on. Sling, gather everyone up.
Uh, we are together, Woody.
Ok. Uh, first off ... we all knew
"Operation Playtime" was a long shot.
More like a misfire.
- But we've always said this job
isn't about getting played with
it's about ...
- Being there for Andy.
We know.
But we can try again, right?
I'm calling it guys. We're closing up shop.
- What?
Andy's going to college anyday now.
That was our last shot.
We're going into attic mode folks.
Keep your accessories with you at all times.
Spare parts, batteries ...
Anything you need for an orderly transition.
Orderly? Don't you get it? We're done!
Finished. Over the hill.
Hey, hey, hey. Come on guys. We all
knew this day was coming.
Yeah, but now it's here.
- Look, every toy goes through this.
No one wants to see ...
Hey Sarge! What are you doing?
- War's over folks.
Me and the boys are moving on.
Moving on?
- You're going AWOL?
- We've done our duty.
Andy is grown up.
- Let's face it ...
When the trash bags come out,
we army guys are the first to go.
Trash bags?
- Who said anything about trash bags?
It has been an honor serving with you.
Good luck folks.
You're gonna need it.
- No, no, wait, wait, wait.
We're getting thrown away?
- No. No one's getting thrown away.
How do you know?
- We're being abandoned.
We'll be fine, Jessie.
- So why did Sarge leave?
Should we leave?
- I thought we were going to the attic?
Oh I hate all this uncertainty.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on a minute. Quiet!
No one's getting thrown out, ok?
We're all still here. I mean, yeah,
we've lost friends along the way ...
Wheezy and Etch and ...
- Bo Peep.
Yeah, even, even Bo.
All good toys who've gone
on to new owners.
But through every yard sale,
every spring cleaning ...
Andy held onto us.
He must care about us
or we wouldn't be here.
You wait. Andy's gonna tuck us in
the attic. It'll be safe and warm.
And we'll all be together.
- Exactly.
There's games up there and books and ...
- The racecar track.
The racecar track, thank you.
- And the old TV.
There you go, the old TV. And those
guys from the Christmas decorations.
Well, they're fun, right?
And some day, if we're lucky, Andy
may have kids of his own.
And he'll play with us then, right?
We'll always be there for him.
- Come on guys ...
Let's get our parts together, get ready
and go out on a high note.
I'd better find my other eye.
- Where'd you leave it this time?
Some place dark and dusty.
Come on. Let's see how much
we're going for on eBay.
Don't worry, Andy's going to take
care of us. I guarantee it.
You guarantee it, huh?
- I don't know, Buzz.
What else could I say?
Well, whatever happens, at least
we'll all be together.
For infinity and beyond.
Can I have your stereo?
- No.
- Why not?
Can I have your computer?
- No.
Your video games?
- Forget it, Molly.
Ok Andy, let's get to work here.
Anything you're not taking to college ...
either goes to the attic, or it's trash.
Mom, I'm not leaving til Friday.
- Come on, it's garbage day.
Mom!
- Look, it's simple.
Skateboard: college.
Little League trophy: probably attic.
Apple core: trash.
You can do the rest.
- Why do you still have these toys?
Molly, out of my room!
- Three more days and it's mine.
Molly! You're not off the hook either.
You have more toys than
you know what to do with.
Some of them can make other
kids really happy.
What kids?
- The children at the daycare.
They're always asking for donations.
- What's daycare?
- Sh Sh Sh.
Mom!
- No buts. You choose the toys
you want to donate, I'll drop
them off at Sunnyside.
Poor Barbie.
- I get the Corvette.
Andy, come on. You need to start
making decisions.
Like what?
- Like, what are you going
to do with these toys?
Should we donate them to Sunnyside?
- No!
- Maybe sell them online?
Mom, no one's going to want those old toys.
They're junk.
- Fine. You have til Friday.
Anything that's not packed for
college or in the attic ...
is getting thrown out.
- Whatever you say, Mom.
What's happening?
- We're getting thrown out, you idiot!
That's what's happening!
You need a hand?
- I got it.
Here. So you gonna miss me when I'm gone?
If I say "no", will I still get your room?
No.
- Then, yes, I'll miss you.
I can't breathe.
- This can't be happening.
Quiet! What's that sound?
Andy!
That's not trash.
That's not trash!
Think, Woody. Think, think, think.
Buster, come here boy. Come here.
Ok boy, to the curb.
Heeyah!
No, Buster! No!
Get up, Buster.
We're on the curb!
- Oh, I knew it come to this.
Pull everyone! Pull!
It won't rip!
Oh for goodness ... It's triple-ply,
high-density polyethylene.
There's gotta be a way out.
- Oh Andy doesn't want us.
What's the point?
Point, point, point!
Push! Push!
- I can hear the garbage truck!
It's getting closer.
Buzz! Jessie!
Andy threw us out.
- Like we were garbage.
- Junk. He called us junk.
How could he?
This doesn't make any sense.
- I should have seen this coming.
It's Emily all over again.
- The Sarge was right.
Yeah and Woody was wrong.
- Wait a minute. Hold on.
This is no time to be hysterical.
It's the perfect time to be hysterical.
- Should we be hysterical?
No. Yes.
- Maybe, but not now.
Yee haw! Fellas, I know what to do.
What the heck?
Oh, we should have done this years ago.
- Jessie wait. What about Woody?
He's fine, Buzz. Andy's taking him to college.
Now, we need to go.
You're right. Come on.
Buzz?
- Woody.
- What's going on? Don't you know
this box is being donated?
It's under control, Woody. We have a plan.
- We're going to daycare.
Daycare! What, have you all lost your marbles?
Well didn't you see? Andy threw us away.
- No, no, no. He was putting you in the attic.
Attic? So how did we end up on the curb?
- That was a mistake.
Andy's mom thought you were trash.
- Yeah, after he put us in a trash bag.
And called us junk!
- Yeah, I know it looks bad.
But guys, you gotta believe me.
Sure thing, college boy.
- Andy's moving on, Woody.
It's time we do the same.
Ok, out of the box.
Everyone, right now!
Come on Buzz, give me a hand.
We gotta get this thing.
- Woody, Woody.
We need to figure out what's best for everyone.
Oh great, great. It'll take us
forever to get back here.
Oh it's all right, Barbie.
You'll be ok.
Molly and I have been growing
apart for years.
It's just .. I can't believe she
would throw me away!
Welcome to the club, Toots.
- Ok, everyone listen up ...
We can get back to Andy's
but we gotta move fast.
We'll hide under the seats
til we get back home.
- Get it through your
vinyl noggin Woody ...
Andy doesn't want us anymore.
- He was putting you in the attic!
He left us on the curb!
- All right, calm down, both of you!
Ok. Fine, fine. Just wait until you
see what daycare's like.
- Why? What’s it like?
Daycare is a sad, lonely place for
washed up old toys who have no owners.
Quite the charmer, aren’t you?
- Oh, you'll see, as soon as we get to daycare
you'll be begging to go home.
Can anyone see anything?
- There's a playground.
- Wow!
We hit the jackpot, Bull's-eye.
- So much for sad and lonely, huh?
Ok calm, down guys.
Let's keep this in perspective.
Perspective? This place is perfect.
- Woody, it's nice.
See? The door has a rainbow on it.
Hey, there.
- Wow. I haven't seen you in ages.
I just wanted to drop these old toys off.
- Is this Bonnie?
Look how big you are.
- Say hi, Sweetie.
Hi.
- Hey, how are your kids?
Molly and Andy?
- Not kids anymore.
Andy's going to college on Friday.
- What?
Can you believe it?
- You sure they won't miss these?
No, they never get played with.
Do you see any kids?
- Where's she taking us?
Look.
- Wow.
- What? What is it?
I can't see.
Ok, everyone recess. Come on.
So now what do we do?
- We go back to Andy's.
Anyone see an exit?
- Exit, schmexit.
Let's get played with.
- Careful these toys might
be jealous of new arrivals.
I want to see.
- It's my turn.
New toys!
Howdy, glad to meet you.
- Buzz Lightyear at your service.
Oh, thank you.
May I? Oooh.
The Claw.
Well, hello there.
I thought I heard new voices.
Welcome to Sunnyside, folks.
I'm Lotso, hugging bear.
But please call me Lotso.
Buzz Lightyear. We come in ...
First thing you gotta know about me,
I'm a hugger.
Oh, look at you all. You been
through a lot today haven't you?
Oh, it's been horrible.
- Well, you're safe now.
We're all cast-offs here.
We've been dumped, donated ...
yard sales, second-handed
and just plain thrown out.
But just you wait, you'll find being donated
was the best thing to ever happen to you.
Mr. Lotso, do toys here
get played with everyday?
All day long. Five days a week.
But what happens when the kids grow up?
- Well now, I'll tell you.
When the kids get old, new ones come in.
When they get old, new ones replace them.
You'll never be out-grown or neglected,
never abandoned ...
or forgotten.
No owners means no heartbreak.
Yee haw!
- It's a miracle!
- And you wanted us to stay at Andy's.
Because we're Andy's toys!
- So you got donated by this Andy, huh?
Well, it's his loss, Sheriff.
He can't hurt you no more.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now let's get you all settled in.
Ken? Where is that boy? Ken!
New toys.
- Far out. Down in a jiff, Lotso.
So, who's ready for Ken's dream tour?
Let's show our new friends
where they'll be staying.
- Now folks, if you wanna
step right this way ...
Hi. I'm Ken.
- Barbie.
Have we ever met?
- Uh uh. I would have remembered.
Love your legwarmers.
- Nice ascot.
Come on, Ken. Recess don't last forever.
- Right on, Lotso. This way, everybody.
You got a lot to look forward to, folks.
The little ones love new toys.
What a nice bear.
- And he smells like strawberries.
Folks, if I could share ... Here at
Sunnyside we've got just about
anything a toy could ask for ...
Spare parts, super glue and enough fresh
batteries to choke a hungry, hungry hippo.
Think you're getting old?
Well, stop your worrying.
Our repair spot will keep you stuffed,
puffed and lighted up.
And this ... Well, this is where I live.
Ken's dream house.
It has a disco, it's got a dune buggy and
a whole room just for trying on clothes.
You have everything.
- Everything, except
someone to share it with.
You need anything at all,
you just come talk to me.
Here we are.
Well, thank you, Big Baby. Why don't
you come meet our new friends?
Poor baby. We were thrown out
together - me and him.
Abandoned by the same owner.
But we don't need all
this at Sunnyside ...
We own ourselves.
We're masters of our own fate.
We control our own destiny.
Oh, watch out for puddles.
Here's where you folks will be staying.
The Caterpillar Room.
Look at this place!
- Wow!
Holy moley guacamole!
- Jackpot, baby!
Hello.
- Hello.
It's so beautiful!
Huh? What the ... ?
Oh, hey, little guy.
How long's it been since you all
got played with?
It's been years.
- Well, just you wait ...
in a few minutes, that bell's gonna
ring and you'll get the playtime
that you've been dreaming of.
Play. Real play. I can't wait!
Now, if you'll excuse us,
we best be heading back.
Welcome to Sunnyside, folks.
- Thank you. Bye.
Will I see you again?
- Oh, I'll see you tonight ...
In my dreams.
- Ken, let's get a move on.
Barbie, come with me.
Live in my dream house.
I know it's crazy. I know we just met.
Ah heck, you don't know me from GI Joe ...
but when I look at you,
I feel like we were ...
- Made for each other?
Yay!
- Yes!
- Ken?
- Coming, Lotso!
It's so exciting!
Sounds like kids to me.
- Oh, I want to get played with.
Why can't time go faster?
- How many are there out there?
- Oh, they sound so sweet!
Look everyone, it's nice here, I admit.
But we need to go home.
- We could have a whole new life here, Woody.
A chance to make kids happy again.
- Why don't you stay?
Yeah, Woody stay with us.
- Come on, Woodster.
You'll get played with.
- I can't. No. No.
Guys, really, no!
I have a kid. You have a kid - Andy.
And if he wants us at college
or in the attic ...
Well, our job is to be there for him.
Now I'm going home.
Anyone who wants to join me is welcome.
Come on, Buzz.
Buzz?
Our mission with Andy is complete, Woody.
What?
- What's important now is that we stay together.
We wouldn't even be together
if it weren't for Andy!
Look under your boot, Buzz. You too, Jessie.
Whose name is written there?
Maybe Andy doesn't care about us anymore.
- Of course he does. He cares about all of you.
He was putting you in the attic. I saw ...
You can't just turn your back on him now!
Woody, wake up! It's over!
Andy is all grown up.
Ok. Fine. Perfect.
I can't believe how selfish you all are.
So this is it?
After all we've been through ...
Bull's-eye, no.
You need to stay.
Bull's-eye, no. I said stay!
Look, I don't want you left alone
in the attic, ok?
Now stay.
Bonnie?
I ... I gotta go.
Bonnie, you in here?
Come on, Come on ...
No, no!
What? What the heck?
Ah, that's better.
Bonnie!
Oh, there you are.
Come on, Honey. It's time to go home.
No, no, no, no ...
Reach for the sky.
Bluebells, cockleshells, eeny, miney ...
You're my favorite deputy.
Bonnie!
- Coming!
Oh, great!
Oh, it's gonna be ok, Bull's-eye.
- Woody's going to college with Andy.
It's what he always wanted.
- Ah, he's crazy.
College is no place for a toy.
- Toys are for playtime.
Oh speaking about playtime ...
They're lining up out there!
How many?
- There must be dozens.
Oh, I can hardly wait!
- Places, everyone.
At last I'm going to get played with.
Uh Rex ...
- Come to Poppa.
There's a snake in my boot.
I'd like to join your posse boys, but
first I'm gonna sing a little song.
A sheriff!
Move over, Mr. Prickle Pants.
We have a guest.
You want some coffee?
It's good for you but don't drink too much
or you'll haveta .. haveta ...
Be right back!
Hey. Hello. Hi, excuse me.
- Sh!
Can you tell me where I am?
- Shhh!
The guy's just asking you a question.
- Well, excuse me, I'm trying
to stay in character.
My name's Buttercup.
You've met Baron Von Shush.
- Sh!
Hello, I'm Trixie.
Guys. Hey. Guys, look.
I don't know where I am.
- We're either in a cafe in Paris ...
or a coffeshop in New Jersey.
I'm pretty sure I just came back
from the doctor ...
with life-changing news.
- We do a lot of improv here. Just
stay loose, have fun. You'll be fine.
- No, no, no, no. I ...
Who wants lunch?
I have the secret ingredient.
Jelly beans.
Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
- Poisoned?
Who would do such a mean thing?
Agh! The scary witch! Look out!
She using her witchy powers.
I know where to hide.
She'll never find us in here.
What's wrong?
Agh! She found us! We need a spaceship
to get away from the witch!
You're doing great.
- Are you classically trained?
Look, I just need to know
how to get out of here.
- There is no way out.
Just kidding. Door's right over there.
- Well, Cowboy. You just jumped
right in, didn't ya?
I'm Dolly.
- Uh, Woody.
Woody. Really? You're gonna stick
with that? Cause now's your chance
to change it. New room and all ...
That's coming from a doll named Dolly.
Who's the new guy?
- Are you a real cowboy?
Well, actually ...
- Of course he's not, Pea Brain ...
He don't even have a hat.
- I do too have ...
My hat!
- Told you.
I found a spaceship!
- Showtime!
Quick. Get in. Strap in your seatbelts,
close your tray tables.
Hold on, it might get a little bumpy.
Three, two, one. Blast off!
Yee haw! You saved us, Cowboy!
You're our hero!
I got a kink in my slink.
My tail! Where's my tail?
Someone need a hand?
Where's my nose?
- Here it is.
Here's your arm.
- Gimme that.
- Honey, the mustache?
I don't recall playtime being
quite that strenuous.
Andy never played with us like that.
- We're just gonna have
to make the best of it.
But these toddlers, they don't
know how to play with us.
- They're too young.
And they're sticky.
- We should be in the Butterfly Room.
With the big kids.
- That's right.
- You said it.
We'll get this straightened out.
I'll go talk to Lotso about
moving us to the other room.
Blast. Try that one.
It's locked.
- Same here.
Try the windows.
- Uh negatory.
It's a Fenster-Sneckler 380.
Finest child-proof lock in the world.
We're trapped!
- Wait. Did anyone notice the transom?
Oh great. How do we get up there?
All right, everyone. On three!
One ... two ...
- Three!
Let go!
Go!
He did it!
- Yes, sir!
Way to go, Buzz!
They think they had a fun playtime.
- Sh. They might hear you.
Ok, now you start.
- I ...
- Love ...
- You!
See? That time I said "love".
Ok, now me first.
- Ok, ok, ok.
I ...
- Love ...
- You!
You see what I mean?
It changes every time!
You are so smart.
- Come on, Romeo. You're late.
I'm going to miss you.
All right. Place your bets.
Come on, everybody.
- Any splits?
Here we go.
- Come on.
That's it. No more bets.
Come on, right here.
- Come on, duck!
I won!
Stretch takes the round.
- You lost.
Ok, minimum bet: five monopoly.
Coyotes wild.
Change of two double A's.
Hey, what do you guys think of
the new recruits? Any keepers?
Oh please ... landfill!
Cowgirl? Dinosaur?
- Toddler fodder.
But that, that, uh, space guy ...
He can be useful.
He ain't the sharpest knife in the
place where they keep the knives.
Neither are you, Chunk.
You got a little piece for yourself,
didn't you, Ken?
Hey, lay off, Twitch!
Barbie's different.
- Oh, Mr. Softy over here.
What do you expect from a girl's toy?
- I'm not a girl's toy! I'm not!
Why do you guys keep saying that?
- All them toys are disposable.
We'll be lucky if they last us a week.
Well, well. Looky who we have here.
Let me go!
- Take him to the library.
No!
1225 Sycamore.
Woody, what are you doing?
I gotta get outta here.
- You're leaving?
But didn't you have fun today?
- Well, of course I did.
More than I've had in years.
But, you see, I belong to someone else.
- Who's "Ydna"?
I believe it's pronounced "Ydnay".
- Guys, it says Andy.
He's my Bonnie.
And he's leaving soon.
I gotta get home.
- Where's home?
Elm Street. 234 Elm.
Do you have guys a map?
We're on it, Cowboy. Trixie?
I'll fire up the computer.
Unhand me you, cowards.
I demand to talk to Lotso.
Zip it, Buck Rogers.
You won't talk to Lotso
til we say you can ...
Ken, what's going on here?
Why is this toy tied up?
Uh, he got out Lotso.
- Got out?
Oh no, no, no, no, no, no!
This isn't how we treat our guests.
FAO my Schwartz! There you go. I'm so sorry.
Lotso, there's been a mistake.
- A mistake?
The children in the Caterpillar Room are
not age-appropriate for me and my friends.
We respectfully request a transfer
to the Butterfly Room.
Well, request granted.
- But Lotso ...
Hush now, Kenneth. This toy showed initiative.
Leadership. Why I say, we've
found ourselves a keeper.
Hear that everyone? We got a keeper!
We're calling you up to
the big leagues, son.
From now on you'll have anything you want.
Excellent! I'll go get my friends.
- Whoa, whoa. Hold on there, boss.
Those Caterpillar kids need
someone to play with.
But my friends don't belong there.
- Oh none of us do.
I agree, which is why for the good,
of our community ...
We ask the newer toys, the stronger
ones, to take on the hardships the
rest of us can't bear anymore.
I guess that makes sense.
But I can't accept.
We're a family. We stay together.
A family man, huh? I understand.
Put him back in the timeout chair.
Unhand me!
Bring in the bookworm.
Ah! Here it is.
It was filed under "Lightyear".
Let's see here ...
Accessories, maintenance ...
Oh, here we go. Remove screws
to access battery compartment.
What are you doing?
Let go of me.
To return your Buzz Lightyear action figure
back to its original factory settings,
slide the switch from 'Play' to 'Demo'.
Stop! No, no, no!
What was that?
- Sounds like it came from the hall.
I'll see what it was.
What do you see? Anything?
- No, just a dark hallway.
Wait, wait, I see Andy.
- What?
That's impossible.
- No, no. I really see him.
In his room. Ohh! My other eye!
The one I left behind!
This is so weird. He's packing up.
Uh oh. Here comes Buster.
Out of the way. Get away!
Ok. Andy's out in the hall.
He's looking in the attic.
Wait, there's Mom.
Why is he so upset?
Oh no. Oh, this is terrible!
He's looking for us.
Andy's looking for us.
He's looking for us?
Andy does want us! I just knew it!
- I think he did mean
to put us in the attic.
Well, then Woody was telling the truth.
- Holy cow!
- And you didn't believe him!
Hey, you didn't believe him first.
- Guys, we gotta, we gotta go home!
Lotso!
- Hey there. How are you all
doing this fine evening?
Thank goodness. Have you seen Buzz?
- There's been a mistake. We have to go.
Go? Why? You just got here,
in the nick of time too.
We were running low on volunteers
for the little ones.
They just love new toys,
now don't they?
Love? We have  been chewed,
kicked, drooled on ...
Just look at my pocket book.
Hmm, well here's the thing, Sweet
Potato, you ain't leaving Sunnyside.
Sweet Potato?
Who do you think you're talking to?
I have over 30 accessories and I
deserve more respect ...
Ah, that's better.
Hey! No one takes my wife's mouth,
except me!
Give it back, you furry air freshener!
Come on guys. We're going home.
- Whoa, there Missy!
You're not going anywhere.
Oh yeah? Who's going to stop us?
Buzz, you're back. Buzz?
Watch out!
Prisoners disabled, Commander Lotso.
Buzz, what are you doing?
- Silence. Minions of Zurg.
You are in the custody of the Galactic Alliance.
- Galactic Alliance?
Good work, Lightyear. Now lock 'em up.
Yes, sir.
Where do you think you're going?
Buzz, we're your friends.
- Spare me your lies, Temptress.
Your emperor is defeated and I'm immune
to your bewitching good looks.
Hey, Mungo. Get your paws off my wife.
Let go of me, you drooling doofus.
- Not him. I think this potato needs
to learn himself some manners.
Take him to the box.
- Hey, put me down, you moron!
Where are you taking me to?
Bad baby. Bad baby.
Ken, what's going on?
- Barbie. I told you to
wait in the dream house.
What are you doing with my friends?
- Get in.
Barbie, wait.
- Don't touch me!
We're through!
- Barbie, I ...
And give me my scarf back.
- Ow!
Lightyear, explain our overnight accommodations.
- Sir. Yes, sir.
Prisoners sleep in their cells.
Any prisoner caught outside their cell,
spends the night in the box.
Roll call at dusk and dawn.
Any prisoner misses roll call,
spends the night in the box.
Prisoners do not speak unless spoken to.
Any prisoner talks back,
spends the night ...
... in the box.
We get it!
At ease, soldier. They're neutralized.
But remember, they'll say anything
to make you doubt yourself.
Don't worry, Commander.
Any doubt I had ...
got pounded out of me at the Academy.
Listen up folks. We got a way of
doing things here at Sunnyside.
If you start at the bottom, pay your dues,
life here can be a dream come true.
But if you break our rules,
step out of line ...
try to checkout early,
well, you're just hurting yourself.
Woody! What did you do to him?
- You all get a good night's rest ...
You got a full day of playtime tomorrow.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
1225 Syca ...
Who is Velocistar237?
That's just a dinosaur toy down the street.
That's nothing. Let me just take care of that.
Just a dinosaur ...
All right. Sycamore. Ok. Enter.
Please don't be far. Please. Please.
Right around the corner?
It's right around the corner!
- Yay!
Look at me! I'm big toy on campus!
Hello. I'll see you at the Sock Hop.
- Ok, Potsie.
Hey, wait, listen ... If any of you guys
ever get to Sunnyside Daycare ...
you tell them that Woody made it home.
- You came from Sunnyside?
But, how'd you escape?
- Well, it wasn't easy.
What do you mean "escape"?
Sunnyside is a place of ruin
and despair.
Ruled by an evil bear who
smells of strawberries.
Lotso?
- The guy may seem plush and
huggable on the outside ...
but inside, he's a monster.
- But, how do you know that?
Chuckles. He'll tell you.
Yeah, I knew Lotso.
He was a good toy. A friend.
Me and him, we had the same kid. Daisy.
I was there when Lotso got unwrapped.
Daisy loved us all.
But Lotso ... Lotso was special.
They did everything together.
I've never seen a kid
and a toy more in love.
One day we took a drive.
At a rest stop, we had a little playtime.
After lunch, Daisy fell asleep.
She never came back.
Lotso wouldn't give up.
It took forever, but we finally
made it back to Daisy's.
But by then, it was too late.
Something changed that day inside Lotso.
Something snapped.
- She replaced us.
Come on.
- No, she only replaced you.
She replaced all of us.
Didn't she?
She don't love you no more.
Now, come on!
We were lost. Cast off.
Unloved, unwanted.
Then we found Sunnyside.
But Lotso wasn't my friend anymore.
He wasn't anyone's friend.
He took over Sunnyside and
rigged the whole system.
So, how'd you get out?
- I got broke.
Bonnie found me. Took me home.
Other toys, they weren't so lucky.
It ain't right what Lotso done.
New toys, they don't stand a chance.
But my friends are in there.
- You can't go back.
Returning now would be suicide.
- But what about your Andy?
Isn't he leaving for college?
Quiet, musical hog! Knock it off!
Oh, Bull's-eye. I miss Woody too.
But he ain't ever coming back.
Rise and shine, campers!
- Commander Lotso, sir.
All quiet. Nothing to report.
- Excellent, Lightyear.
Come on. We need you back at Star Command.
- Wait! What have you done with my husband?
Big Baby.
Sweet heart!
It was cold and dark. Nothing but sand
and a couple of "Lincoln Logs".
Uh, I don't think those were "Lincoln Logs".
You all get ready.
You got a play date with destiny.
Uh, hello?
- You shouldn't have come back, Cowboy.
They've cracked down hard since you left.
More guards, more patrols. You and your
friends ain't ever gonna get outta here now.
I made it out once.
- You got lucky once.
Want my advice? Keep your heads down.
You'll survive.
- Yeah, for how long?
I've been here years.
They'll never break me.
There's only one way toys leave this place.
Poor fella.
Trash truck comes at dawn.
Then it's off to the dump.
- Look, I appreciate your concern, Old Timer.
But we have a kid waiting for us.
Now we're leaving.
If you'd help us, one toy to another,
I'd sure be grateful.
Well, if you're gonna get out, first thing
you gotta get through is the doors.
Locked every night.
Inside and out.
Keys are left on a hook in the office.
- Got it. What else?
Lotso's trucks patrolling all night long.
Hallway, lobby, playground ...
- Yeah, yeah. What about the wall?
8 feet high.
Cinder block. No way through it.
You go over or under.
That's it? Doesn't seem so bad.
- It's not.
Your real problem's the monkey.
The monkey's the eye in the sky.
He sees everything.
Classrooms ...
Hallways ...
Even the playground.
He can unlock doors, sneak past guards ...
climb the wall, but if you
don't take out that monkey ...
you ain't going nowhere.
Do you want to get out of here?
Get rid of that monkey!
Recess. Come on, kids.
Hey guys.
- Woody?
- Woody!
Thank goodness!
- You're alive!
- Of course I'm alive.
My hat. Wait. Where's Buzz?
Lotso did something to do with him.
- He thinks he's a real Space Ranger again.
Oh no!
- Oh yes. Return of the astro nut.
Woody, we were wrong to leave Andy.
I ... I was wrong.
Jessie's right, Woody. She was wrong.
No, no, it's my fault for leaving you guys.
From now on, we stick together.
But, Andy's leaving for college.
College! Flag down the mailman!
We gotta get you home before
Andy leaves tomorrow!
Tomorrow? But that means ...
- That means we're busting out of here.
Tonight.
- What? Impossible!
There's no way out of here.
- No, there is a way out.
One way.
Slinky Dog?
- Present.
Green guys? Cowgirl?
Here.
- Horse?
Piggy Bank.
- Yup.
Tyrannosaurus?
- Here.
Barbie?
Potato Head?
Hey! Hey! Super Troop Man. Wake up!
Impossible.
Little late for a stroll isn't it,
Potato Head?
That's Mr. Potato Head to you smoothie!
You ascot-wearing pink nosier!
You're not a toy!
You're an accessory!
You're a purse with legs!
Take him back to the box!
- No, not the box!
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
I like ascots.
Ok check.
- Good work, Lightyear.
All right. Resume your ...
uh ... space guy thing.
Yes, sir, well-groomed man.
Ken? Ken?
What do you want?
- I can't take it here, Ken.
I want to go to the Butterfly Room.
With you.
Yeah, well, you should have
thought of that yesterday.
- I was wrong.
I want to be with you Ken, I do,
in your dream house.
Take me away from this!
Take me away!
Darn it, Barbie. Ok, but things
are complicated around here.
You gotta do what I say.
- I will Ken. I promise.
Wait! I'll do anything!
I'll change your diapers!
Get the tape!
And this is where the magic happens.
Look at all your clothes!
I can't believe you never
brought me up here!
Tennis whites. Mission to Mars.
- Check this out.
Kung Fu Fighting. Canvas Hero
with matching sports pennant.
Flower Power. Oh, Ken!
No one appreciates clothes here, Barbie.
No one.
- Ken, would you model
a few outfits for me?
Just a few.
Go get the key!
- Where is it? Where is it?
Where's the key? Where's the key?
Bingo.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
I told you, keep your hands off of my stuff!
Make a move, Porky.
No fighting. Break it up.
You can't hit each other.
That's my job.
Help! Prison riot!
Get the tortilla.
Ready?
- Ready.
Uh, Barbie?
No more games, Ken.
What did Lotso do to Buzz?
And how do we switch him back?
- You can't make me talk. You can't!
But I'd like to see you try.
Let's see ... Hawaiian surf trunks.
Oh, Barbie, those are vintage!
It's ok. Go ahead, rip them.
I don't care. They're a dime a dozen.
Ooh, glitter tux.
Who cares? Who cares?
Those things are tacky.
Ooh, a Nehru jacket.
- Barbie, not the Nehru!
This is from what? 1967?
The Groovy Formal Collection, yes!
- What a shame.
Oh no! No! No!
There is an instructional manual!
Lotso switched Buzz to demo mode.
- Where's that manual?
I don't know why this couldn't wait
until morning Ken, but here you go.
What's taking so doggone long?
So, how do we fix Buzz?
What are you looking at, Feathers?
Yeah, fly away, you coward.
Uh oh.
Well, that's just great.
Oh give it up. No one can hear you.
What?
- I said, no one can hear you.
- He said, "no one can" ...
Shh. Be quiet.
- Woody, you're back.
Stop him! Don't let him get out!
- Star Command: I've been taken
hostage by my own prisoners.
Quick.  Open his back, there's a switch.
- Unhand me Zurg scum!
The Galactic Court will show you no mercy.
It's not working. Why is it not working?
Where's the manual?
Here we go. There should be a little
hole under the switch.
- Little hole ... Got it!
To reset your Buzz Lightyear,
insert paper clip ...
Rex, use your finger!
- What?
- Ok. Now what?
Let's see. Caution do not hold button
for more than five seconds.
It's not my fault.
Starlog, I've awakened from hyper
sleep on a strange planet.
Now what did you do?
- I just did what you told me.
I am surrounded by unknown creatures.
Friend or foe?
Amigos. We're all amigos.
I must have crashed and
my memory's been erased.
Has anyone seen my spaceship?
- We gotta switch him back.
How do we do that ?
- I don't know, this part's in Spanish.
We don't have time for this. Come on, El Buzzo.
- My ship has landed well.
Good luck, Cowboy.
Here they come.
Come on, Buzz.
What took you so long?
- Things got complicated.
Where's Potato Head?
- We haven't seen him.
Buzz.
My desert flower.
Did you fix Buzz?
- Uh, sort of.
Behind you. Someone's coming.
You would not believe what I've
been through tonight.
Darling, are you ok?
- I feel fresh, healthy ...
It's terrible.
- You've lost weight.
And so tall.
Ah, you're a sight for detachable eyes.
All clear.
Come on. Come on.
We're almost there.
Back up. Back up.
Come on.
Miss, you are the prettiest
flower in the room.
And together, we'll fight evil.
Woody!
Come on, we're almost there.
- After you.
Buzz, come here. Give me a lift.
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
Open.
- Way to go, Buzz. Come on.
Is it safe?
- I guess I'll find out.
Woody, are you ok?
- Yeah, come on down.
But not all at once.
- What did he say?
I think he said, all at once.
- No. No, no, no, no, no!
Thanks Jess.
- You're welcome.
Almost there guys.
Slink, you think you can make it?
I might be old, but I still
got a spring in my step.
He did it!
- All right, Slinkykins!
Ok, climb across.
You lost, little doggie?
Well, well, look who's back.
I'm sorry, Cowboy. They broke me.
What are y'all doing?
Running back to your kid?
He don't want you no more.
- That's a lie.
Is it? Tell me this Sheriff ...
If your kid loves you so much,
why is he leaving?
You think you're special, Cowboy?
You're a piece of plastic.
You were made to be thrown away.
Speak of the devil.
Now, we need toys in our Caterpillar Room
and you need to avoid that truck.
Why don't you come on back
join our family again?
This isn't a family, it's a prison.
You're a liar and a bully.
And I'd rather rot in this dumpster
than join any family of yours.
Jessie's right.
Authority should derive from
the consent of the governed,
not from the threat of force.
If that's what you want.
Barbie, wait!
Don't do this, Lotso!
She's a barbie doll, Ken.
There's a hundred million just like her.
Not to me there's not.
Fine. Then why don't you join them?
Oh Ken!
- Everyone listen. Sunnyside can be cool
and groovy if we treated each other fair.
It's Lotso. He's made us into a pyramid,
and he put himself on top.
Anyone concur with Ken?
I didn't throw you away, your kid did.
Ain't one kid ever loved a toy, really.
Chew on that when you're in the dump.
Wait. What about Daisy?
I don't know what you're talking about.
- Daisy. You used to do everything with her.
Yeah, then she threw us out.
- No, she lost you.
She replaced us.
- She replaced you.
And if you couldn't have her,
then no one could!
You lied to Big Baby and
you've been lying ever since.
Where'd you get that?
- She loved you, Lotso.
She never loved me!
- As much as any kid ever loved a toy.
Mama.
- What? You want your mommy back?
She never loved you! Don't be such a baby!
Push them in. All of them.
This is what happens when
you dummies try to think.
We're all just trash waiting
to be thrown away.
That's all a toy is.
Hey, stop it! Put me down, you idiot!
No, no, wait a minute! Baby, wait!
He's gone.
- Holy cow.
Come on. Hurry.
Oh for crying out loud!
- Come on.
No!
- Woody!
Oh boy. Incoming!
Come on.
Barbie, no!
Woody!
No!
Can you hear me? Is everyone ok?
Of course not, you imbecile!
We're doomed!
Everyone, go to Buzz. Come on.
We all here ? Slinky? Rex?
Against the wall, everybody. Quick!
- Miss, where are you?
They'll never make it.
Look out!
Anyone see him?
- Over here, y'all. I found him.
Buzz, are you ok?
Buzz? Buzz?
That wasn't me was it?
- Oh Buzz, you're back.
Yes, I'm back.
Where have I been?
Beyond infinity, Space Ranger.
- Woody!
So, where are we now?
- In a garbage truck on the way to the dump.
Hold on! We're going in!
Have you got all your pieces?
- The Claw.
My babies!
- Hey guys! No! No!
No!
Hang on.
Woody, what do we do?
- We'll be ok if we stay together.
It's a magnet. Watch out!
Don't worry, Slink.
We'll get you down.
I don't wanna take a look at this.
Quick, grab something metal.
You heard the guy.
It's not working.
Help! Help me! I'm stuck!
Help please! Help!
- Woody!
Thank you.
- Don't thank me yet.
Go! Go!
Thank you, Sheriff.
- We're all in this together.
Right guys?
Guys?
- Woody, down here.
Woody, look, I can see daylight.
We're going to be ok.
I don't think that's daylight.
Run!
Sheriff, the button. Help me.
Come on.
Go! Go! Hit the button!
Hurry!
Just push it! Push it! Push it!
Where's your kid now, Sheriff?
No! No!
- Lotso!
Buzz, what do we do?
You know all that bad stuff
I said about Andy's attic?
I take it all back.
- You're darn tootin'.
You said it.
Oh darling, you were so brave.
You saved our lives.
- And we are eternally grateful.
My boys.
- Daddy!
Hey, where is that furball Lotso?
Yeah, I'd like to loosen his stitching.
Forget it, guys.
He's not worth it.
Hey!
- Whatcha got?
- I had me one of these when I was a kid.
Strawberries.
Hey buddy! You might wanna
keep your mouth shut.
Come on, Woody. We gotta get you home.
- That's right, college boy.
Wait, what about you guys?
I mean ...
Maybe the attic's not such a great idea.
We're Andy's toys, Woody.
- We'll be there for him ...
Together.
I just hope he hasn't left yet.
- Wait a minute. Wait, I'll check.
Andy's still packing.
But he's almost done.
He lives halfway across town.
- We'll never get there in time.
Come on, Buster.
- Honey, you've got everything?
Yeah, just a few more boxes in my room.
- Ok, come on!
Ok. All clear.
Oh, there you are!
Buzz ... this isn't goodbye.
Hey, Woody. Have fun at college.
- Yeah, but not too much fun.
Woody, take care of Andy.
- Yeah.
- He's a good kid ...
Tell him to get a haircut.
- Sure thing.
Jessie, you'll be ok in the attic?
- Of course I will.
Besides, I know about Buzz's Spanish mode.
My what?
You know where to find us, Cowboy.
Did you say goodbye to Molly?
- Mom, we've said goodbye like ten times.
Mom, it's ok.
I know. It's just ... I wish
I could always be with you.
You will be, Mom.
Hey, aren't you going to say goodbye to Buster?
Of course I am. Who's a good dog?
Who's a good doggie?
Get the rest of your things.
- Ok Buster. Now don't let Molly near my stuff.
Hey, Mom. So, do you really think
I should donate these?
It's up to you, Honey.
Whatever you want to do.
Don't go in there! The bakery is haunted!
Are you crazy? You'll wake up all the ghosts.
Look out! The ghosts are throwing pies.
Mom!
- Andy?
- Hi.
- Wow, look at you.
I hear you're off to college.
- Yeah, right now actually.
So, what can we do for you?
- Uh, I have some toys here.
You hear that, Bonnie?
- So, you're Bonnie?
I'm Andy.
Someone told me you're
really good with toys.
These are mine, but I'm going away now ...
So I need someone really special
to play with them.
This is Jessie. The roughest, toughest
cowgirl in the whole west.
She loves "critters", but not more
than her best pal, Bull's-eye.
Here.
This is Rex, the meanest, most terrifying
dinosaur who ever lived.
The Potato Heads. Mr. and Mrs.
You gotta keep them together,
because they're madly in love.
Now Slinky here, is as loyal as
any dog you could want ...
And Hamm ... he'll keep your money safe ...
but he's also one of the most
dastardly villains of all time
... Evil Doctor Pork Chop.
These little dudes are from a strange
alien world - Pizza planet.
And this is Buzz Lightyear,
the coolest toy ever!
Look, he can fly and shoot lasers.
He's sworn to protect the galaxy
from the evil Emperor Zurg.
To infinity and beyond.
Now, you gotta promise to take
good care of these guys ...
They mean a lot to me.
My cowboy!
Woody? What's he doing in there?
There's a snake in my boot.
Now, Woody ... he's been my pal for
as long as I can remember ...
He's brave, like a cowboy should be ...
and kind and smart, but the thing
that makes Woody special ...
is he'll never give up on you. Ever!
He'll be there for you no matter what.
You think you can take care of him for me?
Ok, then.
Oh, no! Doctor Pork Chop is
attacking the haunted bakery!
The ghosts are getting away!
Woody'll stop them!
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
Thanks, guys.
Look, Mommy!
They're all playing together.
Come on. Let's get some lunch.
So long, partner.