(CHATTERING)
Your breakfast, sir.
Pork bellies.
I have a hunch something very exciting
is going to happen
in the pork belly market this morning.
Will Miss Penelope be dining
with you this evening, sir?
Yes. Yes, she will.
-Good morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
-Morning, Folsey.
-Morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
-Morning.
Morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
-WOMAN: Morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
-Morning.
MAN 1: Morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
MAN 2: Morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
Good morning.
-Good morning, Mr. Winthorpe.
-Morning.
Pork bellies. I knew it. I knew it!
-Good morning, Mr. Duke.
-Morning, Mr. Duke.
WOMAN: Good morning, Mr. Duke.
When do we sell?
I just cannot believe
how stupid these scientists are.
"The eternal question."
There is no question.
The answer's obvious.
I don't care
about heredity versus environment.
In fact, I'm sick and tired of hearing it.
I care about how much money
we can get for our pork bellies.
Winthorpe put in a sell order
for 76 and a quarter.
His charts say
that's as high as it's gonna go.
It'll never get that high. Let's sell now.
Patience, Mortimer.
Let's see ifWinthorpe's right.
Winthorpe's wrong. It's topped out.
I saywe sell now.
Just anotherfew seconds.
The market's closing.
We won't get the order in.
Wejust made an extra $347,000.
Get me Winthorpe.
Well, of course I never had an instant
of doubt in my mind, Mortimer.
Oh, yes, I'm sure a lot of people
went belly-up on that one.
I'll see you at the club.
(WHISTLING)
Morning, Mr. Duke.
Merry Christmas! Merry Christmas!
Thank you very much.
Vietnam did this to me,
but I'm not bitter, thank you.
Merry Christmas! Happy Hanukkah?
Yeah, how're you doing?
Spare a poorwar veteran
some change?
I'm on my knees for life.
I have no money to give you.
Please, anything. A quarter.
Anything, just a couple of dollars.
Anything, a quarter, a nickel, please.
Hey, man, I really don't appreciate this.
I don't care what it is.
Smoked ham, anything. Some crackers.
Thanks a lot.
How'd you like a stump up your ass?
Stay out of here!
You got a lot of soul. I appreciate it.
Listen to this.
"Expect this stagnation to continue
"until the Department of Agriculture's
January crop report."
Exactly as we thought, Randolph.
Wrong. Quite wrong. Untrue.
They've given this genetics fellow
the Nobel Prize.
The man doesn't know
the first thing about human nature.
Randolph. We're about to make
millions of dollars in frozen orangejuice
and you're talking to me
about human nature.
Money isn't everything, Mortimer.
Oh, grow up.
Mother always said you were g
She meant it as a compliment.
Ezra, right on time.
I'll betyou thought
I'd forgotten your Christmas bonus.
There you are.
$5. Maybe I'll go to the movies
by myself.
Half of it is from me.
Thank you, Mr. Mortimer.
Gentlemen.
Looking good, Louis.
Feeling good, Todd.
We need a fourth for squash today,
Louis. Are you interested?
No can do. I'll be having dinner
with Penelope tonight.
Oh, lucky you.
It's not luck. Todd.
(MOCKING)
Randolph, Mortimer.
Winthorpe, my boy,
what have you got for us?
Well, it's that time ofthe month again.
Payroll checks for our employees,
which require your signatures.
And no forgetting to sign the big ones.
We seem to be paying some
of our employees an awful lot of money.
Can't get around
the old minimum wage, Mortimer.
$50,000 to Clarence Beeks!
Who the hell...
(CLEARS THROAT)
I meant to ask you about that.
I went through personal records
thoroughly and there doesn't seem to be
a Clarence Beeks
employed with the firm.
(COUGHING)
Clarence Beeks. Oh, yes, of course.
He's doing something top secret for us.
Research.
How is Penelope?
Neverforget
she's our grandniece, Winthorpe.
You'd better make
an honestwoman of her.
Well, I'll certainly try, sir.
Actually, the wedding invitations
go out this week.
Good. Good work, Winthorpe.
Don'tworry about this, Winthorpe.
I'll take care ofthis one personally.
-Goodbye, Winthorpe.
Winthorpe is a very steady young man.
We're lucky to have him
managing ourfirm for us.
Oh, hogwash. Exeter,
he's the product of good e
It's got nothing to do with environment.
With his genes,
you could put Winthorpe anywhere
and he's gonna come out on top.
Breeding, Randolph,
same as in race horses.
It's in the blood.
Hey, baby, what's happening?
How you doing?
Once you have a man with no legs,
you never go back, baby.
I knowwhatyou're thinking.
You seen Porgy and Bess?
We can make it, baby. Me and you.
You bitch!
Who's that? Who's there?
Whatyou want?
Police. We've had some complaints
about con men
pretending to be blind and crippled.
Oh, I'd love to help you, man,
but I ain't seen nothing
since I stepped on that landmine
in Vietcong back in '72.
Itwas rough, very painful.
You were in Nam? So were we. Where?
I was in Sang Bang, Dang Gong.
I was all overthat place,
basically a lot of places, a lot of places.
What unitwere you in?
I was with the Green Berets,
Special Unit Battalion's
Commando Airborne Tactics
Specialist Tactics Unit Battalion.
Yeah, itwas real hush-hush.
I was Agent Orange.
Thatwas my name, Agent Orange.
Special Agent Orange, thatwas me.
Airborne, huh?
I can see! I can see!
I have... I have legs.
I have... Oh shit, look at this.
Man! I can walk.
Jesus, praise Jesus.
I appreciate this. Oh, this is beautiful.
I can't believe... Thank you.
I just don't knowwhat to do. It's...
Glory be to God. Praise Jesus.
Look at me.
This is too much. I can't believe it.
You're beautiful.
Listen, I can't thank you.
First Moses, now this. God, Jesus...
Oh, baby, look at me.
I'm so happy. Oh, God.
Look at me, this is too much.
What a happy day. What a happy day!
Really, I appreciate it, y'all.
Okay now. All right. Look at this.
I can walk. I don't knowwhat to say.
I'll be all right. Take it easy.
You're beautiful,
both ofyou all, the two ofyou.
How're you doing?
-Oh, I'm sorry about that, man.
-Stop, thief.
-Help, help!
-What are you talking about, man?
Don't shoot. Take it, take it.
Please don't kill me. I'm getting married.
-Hey, I don'twantyour bag, man.
-Help! Help!
Help! Help!
Help!
He's in there. After him.
-Excuse me.
-Watch out. He probably has a weapon.
WINTHORPE: Stop him. He has
my briefcase. Stop him! Stop him!
He's inside. That boy's crazy.
-WINTHORPE: He's escaping. Get him.
-Shit.
MAN 1: Look at him.
MAN 2: Get out ofthe way.
Get him. He's getting away.
There he is. That's him.
Get him. Get him.
He's underthe table.
Somebody go underthere.
Somebody get down there.
Right there. Right there. There he is.
Is there a problem, officers?
What in heaven's name
is going on here?
He tried to rob the payroll, Randolph.
He attacked me in broad daylight.
I didn't do nothing, man.
This guy bumped into me.
I did not. You knocked me down
and tried to grab my briefcase.
-Yeah, but itwas an accident, man.
-An accident, really?
What's going to happen to this man?
We're gonna book him
on assault, attempted robbery
and resisting arrest.
Well done, Winthorpe.
Hey, man, I'm innocent.
This guy bumped into me.
I was trying to give him his briefcase
back to him.
Shit, I can't be going tojail
'cause some asswipe ain'twatching
where he's going.
Officer, I would like to press
full charges.
People like this are
a menace to decent society.
You're from a broken home, of course?
Itwas broke. So what?
You have a history ofjuvenile arrests,
I presume?
Drug abuse, reform school,
state prisons and all that?
I ain't talking to this guy.
I want a lawyer.
Is there a lawyer in the house?
(CLEARS THROAT)
That man is a product
of a poor environment.
There's absolutely nothing wrong
with him, I can prove it.
Of course there's
something wrong with him.
He's a Negro!
Probably been stealing
since he could crawl.
(POLICE RADIO CHATTERING)
Given the right surroundings
and encouragement,
I'll bet that that man could run
our company
as well as youryoung Winthorpe.
Are we talking
about a wager, Randolph?
I suppose you think Winthorpe,
say if he were to lose hisjob,
would resort to holding up people
on the streets?
No, I don't thinkjust losing hisjob
would be enough forWinthorpe.
I think we'd have to heap a little more
misfortune on those narrow shoulders.
If he lost hisjob and his home
and his fiancée and his friends,
if he were somehow disgraced
and arrested by the police
and thrown in jail, even,
yes, I'm sure he'd take to crime
like a fish to water.
You'd have to put him
in the wrong surroundings, of course,
with the worst sort of people.
I mean real scum, Randolph.
We've done it before.
This time it's in a good cause.
How much do you want to bet?
-The usual amount.
-Why not?
You're so brave, Louis.
Someone has to take a stand
against criminals like that.
But he could have killed you.
In such a situation,
you have no time to think.
Instinct takes over.
It's either kill or be killed.
Did Louis tell you what he did today?
Mr. Louis was kind enough
to share this afternoon's excitement
with me, Miss Penelope.
You're so hot-tempered, darling.
I would have groveled on the ground
and begged for mercy.
(WHISPERS) I wantyou, Louis, now.
-Coleman.
-Sir?
I think we'll take our drinks
in the living room, by the fire.
No dessert, sir?
You have it.
Thank you, sir.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Oh, hello, Mr. Duke, sir. Awhat?
A scientific experiment.
Well, not at all, sir. No, I...
It all sounds very
original.
Well, it's your house, sir,
and I work foryou.
I shall make
the necessary arrangements.
And a very good night to you, sir.
What a scumbag.
Mumsywants to have a party for us
right after New Year's.
January 2nd, is that good foryou?
A-okaywith me, hon.
Darn nice of her, too.
Oh, heck. 2nd of January.
Can't do it, boo.
-Oh, Louis.
-It's the day the crop reports come out.
What do those stupid old crop reports
have to do with Mumsy's party?
Well, it's the busiest time ofthe year
in the office, sugar puff.
It'sjust not fair. Why can'tyou
make them do it another day?
Oh, no.
The Department of Agriculture
gets those estimates
from all overthe country.
Pork bellies, soybeans,
frozen orangejuice.
I suppose
I'll just have to ask Todd to take me.
Now, waitjust a minute. Ifyou think
I'm going to let that playboy...
Just teasing, Winthorpe.
-You know something, Witherspoon?
-What?
We are going to make a great couple.
We're going to have a great life.
-Excuse me, sir.
-What is it now, Coleman?
Will you be needing me any more,
this evening, sir?
No, I think I have everything I want.
Good night, sir.
See, I had to keep the dude
undertight surveillance, man.
That's why I'm wearing
these bummy clothes.
I had to make sure
the dude had his payroll
before I made my move.
-Tell us how you cut him.
-Hey, I ain't cut him with no knife, man.
Butyou told me last night
you cut the dude.
It's with these I cut him.
I am a chain belt in kung fu.
Bruce Lee was my teacher. Watch this.
(YELLING)
That's called
the Quart of Blood technique.
You do that, a quart of blood will drop
out a person's body.
Tell how you beat on the cop.
Wasn't no cop, man.
Itwas cops. Plural. Nine, ten cops.
I beat the shit out often cops
and had to change
mywhole strategy around.
Yo, when they broughtyou in here
and booked you,
-you was crying like a pussy.
-Yeah.
That's 'cause as one ofthe cops fell,
he threw tear gas in my face.
And that's the kind of shit
they use on crowds, man.
And I still walked in here like a man,
so get out of my face, all right?
I mean, you beating up on a man,
you putting a man in the hospital.
How come I don't see no marks on you?
-Yeah.
-'Cause I'm a karate man, all right?
Karate men bruise on the inside.
They don't show theirweaknesses.
Butyou don't know that 'cause you're
a big Barry White-looking motherfucker.
Now get off my back, all right?
I wish my bitches'd hurry up
and get here.
I ain't got no time to be sitting
inside this cell with you...
Where is your bitches,
Mr. Big-Time Pimp?
Yeah.
Didn't I tell you that the phone
in my limousine is busted
and I can't get in contact
with my bitches?
Yeah, the phone in the limo is busted.
What are you, ignorant?
Hey, look, sit down, all right.
It ain't cool being nojive turkey
so close to Thanksgiving.
Hey, now...
You boys don't knowwhatyou're doing,
I can see that already.
Do you knowwho you're fucking with?
Back the fuck up. Back up.
Do you knowwho you're fucking with
in cell number 4 on the ninth floor?
-Billy RayValentine?
-Yes.
Move it.
-You made bail.
-I did?
COP: Where are you going?
What do you think? You crazy?
Get up there.
You don't knowwho
you're messing with, boy.
You stay still.
May I suggest using
a night stick, Officer?
Get out of here.
Mr. Valentine?
Could you spare us a moment?
Hey, man, don't I know you two guys?
Step inside, nice and warm in here.
Whiskey, all you want.
Hey, look, man, I ain't falling
forthe same trick twice, all right?
Whatyou gonna do, get me in the car
and have me arrested for stealing it?
Why should we do that, Mr. Valentine?
We're the ones who bailed you out.
Say, man, who are y'all?
Whaty'all wantwith me?
We want to help you, Mr. Valentine.
My brother and I run
a privately funded program,
to rehabilitate
culturally disadvantaged people.
We'd like to supply you
with a home ofyour own, a car,
a generous bank account,
and employmentwith our company.
We're going to startyou
at $80,000 a year.
$80,000?
Excuse me.
This is a practical joke, right, bro?
Then these dudes are
a couple offaggots then, huh?
Well, what's my next move, man?
Thank you, you've been helpful.
What about the police and the payroll?
We've had
the charges dropped, Mr. Valentine.
You're a free man, Valentine.
We can stop right now
and you can walk out on us forever.
No. No, I believe I can hang out
with you fellas for a little while.
Excellent. I'm Randolph Duke.
How you doing, Randy.
What's happening?
-My younger brother, Mortimer.
-Hey, Morty! What it is? How you doing?
Billy RayValentine, Capricorn.
Randy, that's like Randy Jackson
from the Jackson 5, right?
-Yes. Yes, I suppose so.
-Yeah, yeah.
Here we are, William.
How you doing?
Hey, Randy, Morty.
This is nice. I like this.
-William...
-Billy Ray.
William, this is Coleman.
He'll look afteryour day-to-day needs.
Can I relieve you ofthose, sir?
You get a glass, I'll give you a sip, man.
-Perhaps your coat, sir?
-Yes, this is my coat.
Coleman is here to take care ofyou.
He is your servant.
-May I take it?
-Get out of here, man.
Valentine very badlywants
to take a hot bath
and to get into something comfortable.
Don'tyou, Valentine?
Jacuzzi, sir?
You see, man, I knew
you all was faggots, man.
You'll be Jacuzzi nobody.
It's a whirlpool bath, sir.
I think you'll enjoy it.
(EXCLAIMS)
Bubbles, man.
Say, man, when I was growing up,
we want a Jacuzzi,
we had to fart in the tub. This is bad.
(VALENTINE SINGING)
-What's he doing in there?
-He's singing, sir.
They're very musical people,
aren't they?
-What shall I do with his clothes, sir?
-Send them to the laundry.
He'll have to have something
to wear back to the ghetto
after I've won our bet.
Well, William, what do you think?
I like it, Randy. It's very nice.
I like the way you have the mirrors
and stuff hooked up overthere.
It's very pretty. I like that.
I like that mirror.
-I don't think he understands, Randolph.
-Oh, but, Morty, I do understand.
-William.
-Yes.
-This is your home.
-Right.
It belongs to you.
Yeah, all this is mine. I like my home.
It's very nice.
I have very nice taste in houses.
Everything you see in this room
is yours now.
-This is my stuff?
-Your own personal property.
-Yeah, my own personal shit.
-You understand?
This is mine. Yeah, I like that.
Yeah, you knowwhat I like most
about my place, Randy?
The curtains, man. Look at the curtains.
It's beautiful the way
I got this place set up, man.
This is something else. I like it.
The cabinets and whatnot.
Beautiful. I suppose you're gonna
just give me this TV set forfree, Randy?
-That's right.
-Everything in here is mine, huh?
-Oh, I guess the stereo's mine free too?
-Absolutely.
This is too much for me, man.
You know, I can really dig this, Randy.
You knowwhy?
This kind ofthing happens to me
everyweek.
This is your house.
These are your personal possessions.
You will only be stealing from yourself.
Look, firstyou throw
my ass in jail, right?
Then you go and drive me out here
and start running some garbage to me
about this is my house,
this is my personal rug.
And then you go and tell me
this is my personal slave too.
I understand how you feel, William,
but the fact remains, all this is yours.
You may do with itwhateveryou wish.
This is my stuff and my place, huh?
I can do what I want
with this stuff, right?
This is my vase here, right?
This is Billy Ray's vase, right?
I own this vase.
And I can play like
Harlem Globetrotters shitwith it, right?
Okay, you want
Meadowlark Lemon shit, right?
Hey, man, I'm sorry about that.
Perfectly all right, William,
itwas your vase.
That's a cheap vase, man.
Thatwas a fake, right?
I think we paid $35,000 for it.
But I seem to remember
we estimated its value
at $50,000 forthe insurance company.
(RANDOLPH LAUGHING)
You see, Mortimer? William has
already made us a profit of $15,000.
You want me to break something else?
ALL: No.
Excuse me.
I just hope we're not pushing our luck,
using Mr. Beeks forthis,
as well as forthe crop report.
We are involved in a very important
scientific experiment, Mortimer,
and Mr. Beeks has always
proven reliable.
(GONGING)
Excuse me. Sorry.
Hello, Todd. Gents.
Gentlemen. There is something rotten
in the Heritage Club.
Something that has never raised
its vile head
in the 208 years ofthe club's history.
There is a thief,
and he's sitting here among us.
Not an ordinary thief like the man
Winthorpe had the guts
to stand up to yesterday.
No, this man is a hundred times lower.
I'd like to introduce Mr. Beeks
of Lyndhurst Security.
Thank you. I'd like
to ask you gentlemen to all stand up.
I'd like to ask you to place
your left hand on the shoulder
ofthe man to your left.
I would now ask you
to place your right hand
in the coat pocket
ofthe memberto your right.
And empty the contents
ofthose pockets onto the table.
Thank you.
You may sit.
We marked three $50 bills with red X's.
Less than 10 minutes ago
those bills were stolen
from a coat in the cloakroom.
One of our operatives
witnessed the theft.
Now, wait a minute. I've never seen
this money before in my life.
Randolph, Mortimer, this is outrageous.
What are you doing?
I haven't done anything wrong.
Oh, Winthorpe.
I'm glad your parents are not
alive to see this.
What? No, wait, now this is
totally preposterous. This is insane.
I have no reason to steal.
No, wait, I'm not a thief.
I demand a fair hearing.
You can at least grant me that.
Someone planted that stuff on me.
(PHONE RINGING)
(WHISPERING)
You realize you're making
a grave mistake.
Boy, are you two going to be sorry.
Do you knowwho I am?
Yeah, Winthorpe, Louis III.
I know, I know.
I'm permitted two phone calls.
Just point me to the phone.
-Take offyour clothes.
-Now, wait a minute, I know my rights.
Take offyour clothes.
You are making a career decision here.
Now, you'd betterthink about it,
because it's something
thatyou're going to have to live with
forthe rest ofyour life.
Strip, you little shit,
before I tearyou a new asshole.
Did you hearwhat this man said to me?
Now, I have witnesses.
This man is physically threatening me.
Winthorpe.
Louis III.
All right. One gold watch.
One alligator skin wallet.
Master Charge,
American Express Gold Card.
Visa, Diners Club Carte Blanche.
Two tickets.
-La Boheem.
-La Bohème. It's an opera.
It's an opera.
One cellophane bag.
That's not mine.
I've never seen that before in my life.
That's PCP, phencyclidine. Angel dust.
You ever seen
what this stuff does to kids?
You are looking at three to five,
mandatory, Louis.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHOUTING)
What's happening, Terry?
Give me a bottle
ofyour best champagne.
You got a lot of nerve,
showing yourface around here
after all this time.
Look, man, I gotyour money.
I gotyour poor, measly $27
with interest.
Billy Ray, honey. Is thatyou?
Who you think it is?
Terence, get the lady some champagne.
In fact, champagne for everybody,
courtesy of Billy RayValentine.
-ALL: All right!
-All right!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
That's sweet ofyou.
A toast to Billy Ray, huh?
VALENTINE: Well, I'm a sexy man.
I'm very sexy, see.
And people will come
and say, "Billy Ray, you're so sexy,"
and not understand my sexuality.
-I know.
-I'm a very sexy...
You was in the tank last night,
bragging on your limousine.
You're the motherfucker
I was gonna carve.
Yeah.
Motherfucker? Moi?
Thatjust happens to be
my limousine outside.
Why don'tyou go take a look at it?
Right outside?
Yeah.
You took care of him, baby.
-I was gonna kick his ass.
-Were you going to?
I should have kicked it,
but I'm a peaceful man.
Look, ladies, it's about time
for me to get home.
But if any ofyou ladies want
to drop by my house for cocktails,
there's plenty of room in my limousine.
-Limousine!
-Come on, everybody.
(ALL CHATTERING)
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
-You're looking so fine, Billy Ray.
-Thank you very much.
Hey, yo, cuz, ifyou gonna vomit,
the bathroom's downstairs.
No, it's downstairs, man.
Shit!
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
That's a Persian rug.
It's Persian, from Persia.
Hey. Hey, what is this?
What is this shit here?
Hold up! Hey, who's been
putting out their Kools on my floor?
Who has been putting out
their Kools on my floor?
Hey, hey, hey. Hey, hey.
Have you people
ever heard of coasters?
Would you like me to prepare some
more hors d'oeuvres forthe guests, sir?
Fuck them.
Hey, Coleman, there was more people
in this room here before.
Where'd they go?
I believe some ofthem
have adjourned upstairs, sir.
To my bedroom?
I've been waiting foryou, Billy Ray.
Putyour clothes on and get out of here.
Yeah, that's my girl, right overthere.
Can I have
everybody's attention please?
(MUSIC STOPS)
Get the fuck out!
MAN: Okay, now, see here.
COLEMAN: Good night, sir.
-Good night, madam.
-Man.
-I hope you enjoyed it.
-Dude ain't nothing.
Thank you.
Itwas a stone groove, my man.
You are the most righteous...
Yeah, right. Just get the fuck out, man.
Let's go. Shit, come on.
Hurry up.
And be quiet out there.
My neighbors are asleep, theywork too.
Well, your...
Yourfriends seemed
to enjoy themselves, sir.
I thought itwas a great success.
Itwasn't no friends of mine, Coleman.
Itwas a bunch offreeloaders,
treating my house
like itwas a goddamn zoo.
Why don'tyou retire, sir,
and I'll straighten up?
You've got a big day
ahead ofyou tomorrow.
Yeah, yeah, I think I will
retire.
Good night, Coleman. Thanks, man.
Good night, sir.
Let's go, Winthorpe.
(PHONE RINGING)
-Excuse me.
-I'll see you later, we'll have lunch.
Howwould you like to make
a fast hundred?
I just got out.
Hey, come on.
What are you trying to do,
entrap me right here
in the middle ofthe police department?
-You guys must be getting desperate.
-No, no, no. This is for...
Is thatyour purse?
Yes.
That's a nice purse.
Thank you.
Darling, I'm so glad to see you.
Louis, you're making a scene.
The good news is I'm innocent.
I've never even done anything vaguely
resembling this. Really. It's the truth.
Louis, you look awful. I'm so ashamed.
Those clothes and those shoes
and you've been fighting and...
And you smell.
I smell?
Penelope, do you realize
where I've been since yesterday?
They beat me up and stole my clothes.
Those men wanted to have sexwith me.
Can we discuss this
somewhere else, Louis?
One ofthem tried
to bend me overthis...
I mean, ifthis place is indicative
ofthe state of correctional institutions
in this country,
they might as well let
all the convicts out.
It's farworse on the inside.
Stealing from yourfriends
at the club, Louis?
Heroin, Louis?
Have you lostyour mind?
Motherwants me to call offthe wedding
and so does Todd.
Todd? What does Todd have
to do with it?
You've been fired from Duke & Duke.
They're preparing charges againstyou
for embezzlement.
Embezzlement? I've never stolen
anything in my life.
How could the man I loved,
whose children I wanted to have
and breastfeed, be a heroin dealer?
Itwasn't heroin,
itwas angel dust, PCP, and...
Listen, Penelope,
I swearto you, on my honor,
with almighty God as mywitness,
I am not an angel dust dealer.
Oh, Louis.
(WINTHORPE GRUNTING)
I've been looking everywhere foryou,
baby. Listen, Louis...
-Would you...
-I'm hurting, baby. I just need a shot.
-Please...
-Louis.
Who is this person?
I've never seen this woman
before in my life.
Don't say it, Louis.
Come on, baby, just a dime bag.
I'll do all those things you like.
You lying, filthy, disgusting creep.
Todd was right aboutyou. I neverwant
to see you again as long as I live.
Grand! Great! Thanks a lot.
Itwas ajoke.
Yourfriend said itwould getyou off.
You mean,
someone told you to do this to me?
Yeah, and he paid me
a hundred bucks, too.
He's right overthere.
So let me get this straight,
I'm gonna give you $20 forthe cab,
and you're gonna give me $50
when we get to your house?
That is correct.
My butler, Coleman, will give you $50,
and drive you anywhere in the city
you wish to go.
You don't exactly look like
the type that has a butler.
You know, ifyou're hustling me...
Hustling you? Hustling you?
You don't think they give these
tojust anyone, do you?
I can charge goods and services
in over 86 countries around the world.
Yeah? Well, I don't take credit cards.
You'll see what a mistake all this was.
Yes?
Coleman, could you please let me in?
I'm having trouble with my key.
Who are you? What do you want?
Coleman, just unchain the door
and let me in. I'm in no mood forjokes.
Coleman? There's no Coleman here.
You've made a mistake.
Excuse me, for a moment.
Coleman! Let me in!
Ifyou don't go away,
I shall be forced to call the police.
Hello. I'll be making a cash withdrawal
forthe amount of $500.
Well, in fact, we'll make it $1,000.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, Mr. Winthorpe,
but the IRS has frozen your accounts.
What are you talking about?
You know me.
You're a heroin dealer, Mr. Winthorpe.
Itwasn't heroin, itwas angel dust, PCP,
and I never even had my hands on it.
Regardless, it's not the kind of business
we want here at First National.
May I see your credit cards please?
-I've been ordered to repossess them.
-What?
Now, wait a minute,
what am I supposed to live on?
I mean, what's going to happen to me?
Roger.
Why is someone deliberately trying
to ruin my life?
Tell you what.
Forget about the $50, okay?
I'm just real tired. I'm going home.
You've got to believe me.
You must believe me.
I have been framed.
You can'tjust leave me here.
I've got enough problems, Louis.
Come on, come on.
Listen! Wait! Wait.
I have over $150,000 in that bank.
Butyou don't care
because you helped them do this to me.
Get offyour knees, Louis.
Give me your hand.
Soft hands.
And a manicure.
You haven't done a hard day's work
in your life, have you?
I'm gonna regret this, but...
Come on. Get in.
I'm going to get to the bottom ofthis.
This is about a grave, grave mistake.
Hey, that lookjust like
the dude that had me busted.
Sir?
Right there,
he looked just like the mother...
I mean, he looksjust like
the gentleman that had me busted.
To whom are you referring, sir?
Right there. The dude right overthere.
-Right overthere.
-That's my car.
Coleman! Coleman, that's my car!
That's my car! That's my driver.
There's some strange shit
going on here, Coleman.
You don'twant to be late
foryourfirst day atwork, sir.
(BELLS CLANGING)
I mean, what am I supposed
to do in here?
What theywant from me?
-I'm sure they'll tell you, sir.
-Yeah, what if I can't do it?
Just be yourself, sir.
Whatever happens,
they can't take that away from you.
Excuse me, my name is...
Yes, Mr. Valentine, they're waiting
foryou in the last office down the hall.
William, my boy. Right on time.
Come in, come in.
Sit down.
No, thanks, guys.
I already had breakfast this morning.
This is not a meal, Valentine.
We are here to try to explain to you
what it is we do here.
We are commodities brokers, William.
Now, what are commodities?
Commodities are agricultural products.
Like coffee, thatyou had for breakfast.
Wheat, which is used to make bread.
Pork bellies,
which is used to make bacon,
which you might find in a bacon
and lettuce and tomato sandwich.
Then there are other commodities
like frozen orangejuice and gold.
Though, of course,
gold doesn't grow on trees like oranges.
-Clear so far?
-Yeah.
Good, William. Now,
some of our clients are speculating
that the price of gold
will rise in the future.
And we have other clients
who are speculating
that the price of gold is going to fall.
They place their orders with us
and we buy or sell their gold forthem.
Tell him the good part.
The good part, William, is that,
no matterwhether our clients
make money or lose money,
Duke & Duke get the commissions.
Well, what do you think, Valentine?
Well, it sounds to me
like you guys are a couple of bookies.
I told you he'd understand.
It doesn't take a genius
to figure outwhat happened.
It's the same guy
who tried to rob the payroll.
No doubt about it, that's him.
He planted the drugs on me.
Rahim, Mohammed, Larry.
How you guys doing?
RAHIM: Hey, how you doing?
LARRY: Hey, how you doing, baby?
You know those people?
He was wearing my Harvard tie.
Can you believe it? My Harvard tie.
Like, oh, sure, he went to Harvard.
I mean, if he's being driven around
in my car,
he could actually be living in my house.
Maybe he's even taken my job.
You know, for all I know,
right at this moment
he could be fondling my fiancée.
And Coleman.
Afteryears of service, this betrayal.
I don't understand it.
There's going to be retribution.
Oh, he's going to pay.
-The things that I am going to...
-Shut up, Louis.
Listen, taxis cost money,
food costs money
and rent costs money!
Now, you want me to help you out,
I expect a lot in return.
These were here when I moved in.
Put them on ifyou want.
Look, I cannot begin to tell you
how much I appreciate this...
Ophelia.
Ophelia. You realize that
that's the name...
I know, I know, I know.
Hamlet's girlfriend.
He went crazy, she killed herself.
This is not Shakespeare, Louis.
Look, I'm 24 years old.
I'm from a small, miserable little mining
town you probably never heard of.
The only thing I've got going for me
in this whole big, wide world
is this body, this face,
and what I got up here.
I don't do drugs
and I don't have a pimp.
This place is a dump,
but it's cheap,
it's clean and it's all mine.
I've saved 42 grand
and it's in T-Bills earning interest.
I figure,
I got three more years on my back.
I'll have enough to retire on.
You're a prostitute?
I'm talking about
a business proposition, Louis.
I help you getyourself back on yourfeet
and you pay me, in cash, five figures.
That's the deal
and it's not subject to negotiation.
Understood?
By the way,
food and rent are not the only things
around here that cost money.
You sleep on the couch.
It's hit rock bottom. Come on, let's buy.
Mortimer Duke here.
Buy 200 May belly contracts at 66.8.
Put them on my personal account.
That's a big mistake, man.
Valentine, something very important
is going on here. Justwatch.
All right, butyou all gonna get
reamed on this one.
Why shouldn'twe buy now, William?
Price is going to keep going down.
Randolph, this isn't Monopoly money
we're playing with.
This is Randolph Duke.
Hold that belly order a moment.
Tell mejustwhy you think the price
of pork bellies is going down, William.
It's Christmastime. Everybody's uptight.
Could we please buy now, Randolph?
All right, ifyou want to lose money,
go ahead.
What are you trying to say, William?
Okay. Pork belly prices
have been dropping all morning.
Which means everybody's sitting
in their office
and they're waiting forthem
to hit rock bottom
so they can buy cheap and go long.
So people that own the pork belly
contracts are going bat shit.
'Cause they're thinking,
"Hey, we're losing all our damn money
"and Christmas is around the corner.
"And I ain't gonna have no money
to buy my son
"the G.I. Joe with the kung fu grip,"
okay?
"And mywife ain't gonna wanna...
"Mywife ain't gonna make love to me
'cause I ain't got no money," right?
So they sitting there
and they panicking.
They screaming, "Sell! Sell!"
'Cause they don'twant to lose
all their money, right?
They out there, panicking right now.
I can feel it.
They out there. They panicking.
Look at them.
He's right, Mortimer, my God, look at it.
I'd wait till you get to about 64,
then I'd buy.
You'll have cleared out
all the suckers by then.
Do you realize how much money
hejust saved us?
Money isn't everything, Randolph.
Advise our clients interested
in bellies to buy at 64.
Mr. Valentine has set the price.
Well done, William. Verywell done.
Come on, Randolph,
we're gonna be late.
Yo.
Mortimer dropped his money clip.
You can count it. It's all there, all of it.
Thank you, William.
It's all there, man, count it.
I'm sure it is, William.
Thank you and keep up the good work.
All right, Randy. All right.
Nice try, Mortimer.
(MORTIMER SCOFFS)
(SINGING)
What do you think, huh?
Thatwas great, thatwas really great.
-WOMAN: That's perfect.
-TODD: Witherspoon.
...and she stepped on the ball.
Oh, my God, I don't believe it.
-There you are.
-I think I'm going to be sick.
Don'tworry, I'll handle this, pookums.
Todd, Harry, Andrew, Philip.
I realize this looks completely awful
but I justwanted to assure you,
my friends,
that I am completely innocent.
I'm going to fight this thing till the end.
Someone is out to get me
and I knowwho it is.
The important thing is
that I can rely on you,
my friends, as characterwitnesses.
I'm going to be defending myself
and, well, I wondered
ifyou could see yourway clear
to perhaps advance me
a small loan until the hearing.
Frankly, Winthorpe,
and I think I speak for all of us,
I think it shows incredibly bad taste
foryou to come here
and embarrass us all like this.
I believe I'm still a member ofthis club.
Nobodywants to buy
your drugs here, Louis.
Nowwhy don'tyou just go away?
Burned my fingers, man.
I beg your pardon?
Man, thatwatch is so hot, it's smoking.
Hot? Do you mean to imply stolen?
-I'll give you 50 bucks for it.
-50 bucks?
No, no, no. This is a Rochefoucauld,
the thinnestwater-resistantwatch
in the world.
Singularly unique, sculptured in design,
hand-crafted in Switzerland
and water-resistant
to three atmospheres.
This is the sports watch ofthe '80s.
$6,955 retail.
You got a receipt?
Look, it tells time simultaneously
in Monte Carlo, Beverly Hills, London,
Paris, Rome and Gstaad.
In Philadelphia, it's worth 50 bucks.
Just give me the money.
How much forthe gun?
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
So this snail is standing
in front ofthe Cadillac salesman, see,
and he looks up at the salesman
and he says,
"How much is that Cadillac?"
The snail says, "I want
a big S put on each door, a big S,
"and on top ofthe car,
I want another big S
"so everybody can see it."
So the salesman says,
"Butwhat do you want that for?"
He says, "Well, you see,
when I drive down the avenue,
"I want everybody to say
'Look at that S car go."'
"Look at that S car go."
I'm considering going long
on April wheat.
What do you think, Valentine?
I can think ofthree real good reasons
why you shouldn't do
something like that, Judge.
One, the Russian wheat harvest isn't
going to be as bad as everybody thinks.
And two...
And three, judging from all thesejewels
around your girlfriend's neck here,
I think you'll need every penny
you've gotjust to keep her happy.
(WHISPERS)
103. That's it, you're staying in bed.
The man has moved into my house.
He's stolen my job.
I have to do something.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Stay here.
It's 10:00. Here's Johnny.
Listen, baby, I'm sorry.
My mamajust came in from out oftown.
Can we do it nextweek?
Flowers for me?
Thanks.
(COUGHING)
What are you doing?
You've got company.
Business is business.
I'll go for a walk or something.
The fresh airwill do me good.
Lay down.
I'm sorry you had to cancel
your appointment.
What are you doing?
Ophelia, I can't tell you
how good that feels.
You've been so kind to me.
I'm just protecting my investment.
That's all.
Shut up and go to sleep.
99 and a half. You're not getting
out of bed, though, until it's normal.
I feel fine
and I've inconvenienced you enough.
You have work to do and so do I.
Nobodyworks on Christmas Eve.
I'm gonna go shopping
and then I'm gonna come back
and make you a nice quiet dinner.
Now, read your paper.
Christmas, huh?
I'll give him a Christmas present
he'll neverforget.
(JINGLE BELLS PLAYiNG)
(ALL CHATTERING)
William, where've you been?
The party's already begun.
I have some work to finish
in my office, Mr. Duke.
It's Christmas Eve and William wants
to keep working, Mortimer.
I'll think ofyou in Stockholm,
when I accept the Nobel Prize.
The wager has two parts as I recall.
Something about
a second party turning to crime.
Didn'tyou say you had
some work to do, Valentine?
Yes sir. I was wondering about this
$10,000 check to Mr. Clarence Beeks.
I'll take care of it, Valentine.
I don't seem to recall
any Clarence Beeks
working forthe firm, Mr. Duke.
Itwas before you joined us, Valentine.
We did manage to stay in business
for 47 years before your arrival.
Have a drink, William. Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Mr. Duke.
-What?
-Merry Christmas.
Oh, oh, Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Justwhat do you think you're doing?
Randolph! Mortimer!
Come in here quickly!
I've finally caught him!
-Who are you?
-I've caught him red-handed.
Winthorpe, is thatyou?
I'm making a citizen's arrest.
This man is a drug dealer.
Look. Look, here in his office drawer,
he's got all the bad drugs here.
Marijuanajoints, pills, Quaalude,
Valium, yellow ones, red ones,
cocaine grinder, drug needles.
He's the pusher, not me.
Really, I just came in and caught
this man planting this stuff in my desk.
It's obviously some primitive attempt
to try to frame me.
Frame you? Boy, ifthat isn't
the pot calling the kettle black.
This man's obviously a lunatic.
I'm calling security.
Put that phone down.
Hello, security, Merry Christmas.
You try to rob me, plant drugs on me.
You steal my house, my car, my job.
You know, I ought to kill him right now.
Hey, look, man,
this is a big misunderstanding, all right.
I don't know nothing aboutyour house
and your car and yourjob, really.
Could you put the gun away?
Will you ask the Dukes?
Put that gun away at once, Winthorpe.
Have you lostyour mind?
Freeze, slime ball.
RANDOLPH:
I realize this whole experience
must have been
rather unsettling foryou.
Winthorpe, don't leave. We can explain.
Yeah, you'll be sorry.
You'll all be very, very sorry.
(WINTHORPE SHOUTING)
Poor, deluded creature.
We caught him pilfering at our club,
embezzling funds, selling drugs.
Now he's dressing up like Santa Claus.
Very sordid business.
I can't believe Winthorpe
would fall to pieces like that.
It's none of my business,
but that guy belongs behind bars.
-He's unemployed, Valentine.
-It's no excuse, Mortimer.
He's flat broke, obviously hungry.
Oh, but he has money
to buy drugs, right?
Listen, you can't be soft
on people like that.
Take it from me. I know, Randolph.
RANDOLPH: Pay up, Mortimer,
I've won the bet.
Here, $1.
We took a perfectly useless psychopath
like Valentine,
and turned him
into a successful executive.
And during the same time,
we turned an honest, hard-working man
into a violently deranged
would-be killer.
Now, what are we going to do
about taking Winthorpe back
and returning Valentine to the ghetto?
I don'twant Winthorpe back
afterwhat he's done.
You mean keep Valentine on
as managing director?
Do you really believe
I would have a nigger
run ourfamily business, Randolph?
Of course not. Neitherwould I.
I do think we should hold off
on switching them back, though.
Until we get that crop report,
New Year's Eve, don'tyou?
Absolutely. No sense
rocking the boat until then.
If Mr. Beeks does
whatwe paid him to do,
we should have a very happy New Year.
Indeed.
Hey, Winthorpe! Winthorpe!
(GRUNTING)
Hey.
Hey, Winthorpe. Hey, yo, Winthorpe!
Winthorpe. Yo.
Sorry about that.
No, no.
Hey, taxi!
(WATER DRIPPING)
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
(GUN CLICKS)
(GUN FIRING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Hi, Louis. Merry Christmas.
Louis. Louis, when you get out,
I have a big surprise foryou.
Excuse me. The doorwas open...
I'm sorry to botheryou,
but I'm looking for a Louis Winthorpe.
Does he live here?
Wait here a minute, I'll be right back.
Louis. Louis, it's him. It's Valentine.
Louis. Louis.
Louis.
Itwas close,
but he's going to be all right.
Now, make sure he gets plenty of rest.
And for God's sake, no excitement.
-Thanks, Doc.
-Not at all.
-Merry Christmas.
-Merry Christmas to you.
-I'll let myself out, Coleman. Thank you.
-Thank you, Doctor.
-Merry Christmas.
Itwas a dream.
I dreamt the whole thing.
Itwasjust a bad dream.
Good morning, sir. Merry Christmas.
Coleman, I had
the most absurd nightmare.
I was poor and no one liked me.
I lost my job, I lost my house.
Penelope hated me.
And itwas all because
ofthis terrible, awful Negro.
(YELLS)
Oh, dear!
(CHOKING) Itwas the Dukes.
Itwas the Dukes.
You're a dead man, Valentine!
Look, Louis.
Itwas an experiment.
They used us as guinea pigs, man.
Dukes used us as guinea pigs.
To see how our lives would turn out.
They made a bet.
-I'm afraid it's true, sir.
-I believe him, Louis.
The Dukes ruined my life over a bet?
For how much?
A dollar.
$1.
Fine, that's the way theywant it.
No problem.
You know, you can'tjust go around
and shoot people in the kneecaps
with a double-barreled shotgun
'cause you're pissed at them.
Why not?
It's called assaultwith a deadlyweapon.
You get 20 years forthat shit.
Listen, do you have any better ideas?
Yeah, you know, it occurs to me
that the bestway you hurt rich people
is by turning them into poor people.
You have to admit, sir,
you didn't like ityourself a bit.
NEWSCASTER: And now forthe news.
Under heavy security,
the crop estimates
for next year's orange crop
are being delivered from Miami
to the Department of Agriculture
in Washington, DC.
Louis. Louis, that's him.
That's the guy
who paid me to talk dirty to you.
In charge of security
is Mr. Clarence Beeks,
head of Lyndhurst Security.
-Clarence Beeks!
The Dukesjust gave that guy 10 grand.
Ten grand? I saw an outlay
in the payroll to him for $50,000.
Mortimer said itwas for research.
Yeah, research on how he can get
his hands on that top secret crop report
two days before it goes public.
My God.
The Dukes are going to corner
the entire frozen orangejuice market.
Unless somebody stops them.
Or beats them to it.
Eggnog?
WOMAN: Duke & Duke,
may I ask who's calling?
Duke & Duke, I'm afraid he's busy.
Can you hold please?
May I help you?
Just a moment, Mr. Beeks,
I'll put you right through.
Operation Strange Fruit proceeding
according to plan.
I anticipate penetration and acquisition
at 2100 tomorrow. Hold on.
Fuck off!
-When can we expect delivery?
-I will be leaving DC by train.
We'll rendezvous at 2400 hours
at the Hilton hotel,
parking level D, section 4.
-That's the orange section.
-Orange, I like that. Very good.
The final payment is due on delivery
in cash.
Jesus, hey!
Happy New Year!
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
Ever make itwith an ape?
Harvey, haven'tyou had
enough to drink?
Are you kidding,
it's not even New Year's Eve.
Come here, kiss this beautiful ape.
Come on, give me a little.
Come on, just a little.
MAN ON PA: Harrisburg express.
Stairway C.
-What?
-It's my turn to drive.
-No, it isn't.
-Yes, it is.
Well, I'm sure you think it is, but it isn't.
MAN 1: No, don'tyou remember?
This morning, you drove
the shipment of anchovy paste.
MAN 2: Yeah, I drove the anchovy paste,
butyou had the videotape recorders
this afternoon.
Well, I just...
I backed them up about five feet.
We have to take turns.
Sometimes it's longer,
sometimes it's shorter. It's my turn now.
-No, it isn't.
-Yes, it is.
No.
-Merry New Year.
-Happy New Year.
In this country,
we say, "Happy New Year."
Thank you for correcting my English,
which stinks.
I am Nanga Eboko,
exchange student from Cameroon.
(SINGING GIBBERISH)
Beefjerky time.
-You want some beefjerky?
-No, please.
There's plenty, you know.
This animal's being routed
through to New York.
Its care and feeding instructions
are on this bill of lading.
Okay, gotcha.
Now, I doubt ifyou'll have any problems,
but ifyou do,
there's a tranquillizer gun
in the first-aid kit.
Oh, yeah?
Say, have you guys been drinking?
No, sir. Not us.
There's enough drunks
on this train already.
Happy New Year.
Oh, that's kind ofyou, son.
And a happy New Yearto you, too.
Could I offer
either ofyou two gentlemen
a weejolt of Irish whiskey
to usher in the New Year?
Not for me, pal.
I do not drink. It is against my religion.
I always say, religion's a fine thing,
taken in moderation.
-Beefjerky?
-Oh, no, son, thank you very much.
No, it gives me the wind,
something terrible.
We are moving! We are moving!
New York, here we come!
Come in, my child, join the party.
Let me see now,
you would be from Austria. Am I right?
-No, I am Inga from Sweden.
-Sweden?
Butyou're wearing lederhosen.
Ja, for sure, from Sweden.
Please to help me with my rucksack.
Oh yeah, sure, why not?
(GROWLING)
I'm hungry, man.
I have got to get something more to eat.
Well, maybe there's some pretzels
in the bar car.
(CHATTERING)
You're welcome!
-Who is that?
-Open the door, man.
I'm dressed as a baggage handler.
You can imagine
how embarrassed I was
when I saw that there was someone
at the party
with the same costume I had.
Monkey? Monkey?
I'm a fucking gorilla, you clown!
(GIBBERING)
I certainly hope there's
enough space on the train for me.
Nanga, Nanga Eboko, from Cameroon.
Do you remember me?
It's Lionel Joseph.
Lionel, from the African
Education Conference, right?
Yes, aye, man.
I was director of cultural events
at the Haile Selassie pavilion.
I rememberthe pavilion.
We had big fun there.
(SINGING GIBBERISH)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLARING)
Now thatwe are all here,
we will have a picnic,ja?
Yeah.
You will help me get my rucksack down
forthe Swedish meatballs.
-Rememberthe one we did?
-Yeah.
(BOTH SINGING GIBBERISH)
-The memories.
-All day long I could tell those stories.
-Those were the good ones, man.
-The good old days, man.
There you are, sweet pea.
So the train will be pulling
into Philadelphia soon.
Will you be getting off at
the City of Brotherly Loves, Mr. Beeks?
Yeah, I will, butyou won't,
Winthorpe.
-See ifthis one's empty.
-Hey, back off.
I'll rip outyour eyes
and piss on your brain.
-Excuse me.
-You got it.
All right. On yourfeet. Up, let's go.
Bunch offucking weirdoes!
We're going to take a little walk.
And don't try anything funny
orthe whore loses a kidney. Let's go.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
-No, I'm from Sweden.
-Hey, beat it.
Hey, I'm King Kong. I'm the biggest,
baddest boy in thejungle.
Get lost, you maggot.
Hey, who is that guy,
yourfather or something?
BEEKS: All right, hold it right here.
-WINTHORPE: Oh, honestly, Beeks.
-This is as far as we go.
No more cockamamie cigar smoke.
No more Swedish meatballs
there, tootsie.
And no more phony Irish whiskey.
No more goddamn jerky beef.
The party's over.
The party's over. Hey, come on.
What do you mean, "The party's over"?
It's not even 10:00, you dummy.
Hey, come on. Loosen up, man.
It's almost New Year's Eve.
(GROWLING)
Hey, look what happened to me, huh?
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
Sometimes, they look so human,
it gives you the creeps.
Boy, that other one's
getting kinda horny, ain't he?
Think we ought to hit him up
with the tranquillizer gun?
It's New Year's. Let them have theirfun.
(BEEKS GRUNTING)
That black one must be the female.
-Where is he?
-Beeks. Are you there, Beeks?
I'm over here.
That's far enough.
Did you get the report?
Let's see the money.
Okay, toss it over.
RANDOLPH: Thank you, Beeks.
Wonderful news. Wonderful.
Beeks, Happy New Year.
My life savings, sir. Try not to lose it.
Lose it? Coleman, in a couple hours,
you're going to be the richest butler
that ever lived, man.
I worked real hard forthis, Louis.
Hope you knowwhatyou're doing.
-Thank you, Ophelia.
-What are you doing?
MAN ON PA: 1031...
-That's us, Louis.
-...en route to New York and Boston.
Coleman, would you please.
Thank you.
I could use a stiff drink.
Would you care tojoin me?
-Good morning, Mr. Duke.
-Wilson.
Keep the change.
Think big, think positive.
Never show any sign ofweakness.
Always go forthe throat.
Buy low, sell high.
Fear, that's the other guy's problem.
Nothing you have ever experienced
can prepare you forthe unbridled
carnage you're about to witness.
The Super Bowl, the World Series,
they don't knowwhat pressure is.
In this building,
it's either kill or be killed.
-That's right.
-You make no friends in the pits
-and you take no prisoners.
-No prisoners.
One minute you're up half a million
in soybeans, and the next, boom.
Your kids don't go to college
and they've repossessed your Bentley.
-Are you with me?
-Yeah.
We've got to kill the motherfucker...
We've got to kill them.
We wantyou to buy as much OJ
as you can, the instant trading starts.
Don'tworry ifthe price starts going up,
just keep buying.
But, gentlemen,
they're gonna broadcast
the crop report in an hour, what if...
Let us worry about that, Wilson.
Yes, sir.
-How's the ulcer, Harry?
-Pretty good. How's the hypertension?
Hasn't bothered me in months.
(BELL RINGING)
Let's kick some ass.
(ALL CHATTERING)
WINTHORPE: Well, this is it. The last
bastion of pure capitalism left on Earth.
Here in New York they trade everything,
gold, silver, platinum,
heating oil, propane, cocoa and sugar
and, of course,
frozen, concentrated orangejuice.
Now, the people on the phones
are taking orders
from brokerage houses
all overthe world.
The runners then hand
those orders to the traders in the pits.
They're trading cotton overthere.
And that's the silver pit.
Now the Dukes' trader is going to be
buying like crazy right from the opening.
VALENTINE: We'll be waiting
until he drives the price up?
Right. I can'twait to see his face when
they broadcast that genuine crop report.
OJ trading opens at 9:00.
VALENTINE: Let's go kick some butt.
WINTHORPE: Let's go.
(BELL BUZZING)
-102 bid for...
-MAN: Sold!
Hey, hey. The Dukes are trying
to cornerthe market.
-They know something, I can feel it.
-Let's get in on it.
200, taken.
-MAN: 130.
-200, 200.
Louis!
Notyet, almost.
MAN 1: 220, take them.
MAN 2: 209.
-Yeah, yeah, got them.
-MAN 3: 139.
Now! Sell, 200 April at 142.
(LOUD CHATTERING)
That's not right.
How can the price be going down?
Something's wrong. Where's Wilson?
VALENTINE: Sell, sell, sell.
What are they doing here?
-They're selling, Mortimer.
-Why, that's ridiculous.
Unless that crop report...
God help us.
I told you we shouldn't have
committed everything, you asshole.
We've got to get Wilson
and tell him to sell.
MAN ON TV: Ladies and gentlemen,
the Secretary of Agriculture.
Ladies and gentlemen, the
orange crop estimates forthe next year.
After calculating the estimates from
various orange-producing states,
we have concluded the following.
The cold winter has apparently
not affected the orange harvest.
Consumers can expect
orange and orange juice prices to fall...
RANDOLPH: Wilson,
for Christ's sake, sell.
-Buy them.
-Sold!
Selling!
Selling. Sell.
Sold!
36!
25!
Selling.
All right. I'll buy. 15.
Wilson, where are you going?
You idiot.
Get back in there at once and sell, sell.
But I... I'vejust... I've...
(BUZZING)
-5.
-Yeah, 200. Thank you, brother.
-100.
-Yeah, thatwas 100.
-So did you get the hundred?
-I got that.
-Five with you, man, five.
-Louis, thatwas 100 lots.
Hundred?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Happy New Year.
-Winthorpe.
-Valentine.
-Hey, how'd you all make out today?
-How could you do this to us,
after everything we've done foryou?
Oh, see, I made Louis a bet here.
Louis bet me
thatwe couldn't both get rich
and putyou all in the poorhouse
at the same time.
He didn't think we could do it. I won.
I lost.
-$1.
-Thank you, Louis.
-Afteryou.
-Certainly.
Margin call, gentlemen.
Why, you can't expect us to...
You know
the rules ofthe exchange, Mr. Duke.
All accounts to be settled
at the end ofthe day's trading,
without exception.
You know perfectlywell,
we don't have $394 million in cash.
I'm sorry, boys.
Put the Duke brothers' seats
on the exchange up for sale at once.
Seize all assets
of Duke & Duke commodities brokers,
as well as all personal holdings
of Randolph and Mortimer Duke.
My God, we're ruined.
This is an outrage.
I demand an investigation.
You can't sell our seats.
A Duke has been sitting
on this exchange since itwas founded.
We founded this exchange. It's ours.
-It belongs to us.
-My God.
Mortimer, your brother's notwell.
We'd better call an ambulance.
Fuck him! Now you listen to me.
I want trading reopened, right now.
Get those brokers back in here!
Turn those machines back on!
You and your Nobel Prize, you idiot!
Where's Beeks?
Where in hell is Beeks?
-Beeks!
-Yeah, I forgot all about that guy.
(SHIP HORN BLARING)
Okay, one male gorilla.
Hey, wait a minute.
There's two ofthem in that cage.
One gorilla, two gorillas. Big deal.
The whole bunch is getting sent
back to Africa.
It's a big scientific experiment.
What do I know?
Anyway, take a look, they're in love.
-Hey, Coleman!
-COLEMAN: Yes?
What shall we do about lunch?
The lobster orthe cracked crab?
-What do you think?
-Can'twe have both?
Why not?
-Demitri.
-Sir.
-Lobster and cracked crab for everyone.
-Extra primo good, Mr. Coleman, sir.
Looking good, Billy Ray.
Feeling good, Louis.