Girls, your mother and
I are getting divorced.
Don't cry. I know you're
upset, I know you're confused.
I don't know what
your mother told you,
but let me explain it
from my side,
in terms you can understand.
You got your
doll, right?
doll there.
Yeah.
You got your doll, you like
your doll, right? Yes.
You love your doll. Yeah.
Yes, you love the doll.
But what if
I told you
that was the only doll
you're allowed to play with
the rest of your life?
How would you feel?
Sad.
You'd feel sad!
Of course!
Because there's a lot of
other dolls on your shelves.
And if you play
with the other dolls,
you can't have
that doll anymore.
Even though that
doll doesn't really
want to play with
you at this point.
You're both
living a lie!
There's other
dolls you like,
and they're making
new dolls every year.
You want a
stewardess doll?
BOTH: Yeah.
What about a slightly overweight
cocktail waitress doll?
BOTH: Yeah.
What about a doll
who happens to be
best friends
with your main doll'?
BOTH: Yeah.
It could happen, right?
What about a doll you only play
with one day and never see again?
BOTH: (EMPHATICALLY) Yeah!
What about a doll where your
friend's playing with the doll,
and he needs you to kind of
man up with the other doll.
You don't even want
to play with that doll,
but you do it because your
friend's playing with that doll.
You don't wanna sit there and
leave the other doll unattended.
BOTH: Yeah.
So that's why me and Mom
are getting divorced.
Monogamy isn't realistic!
BOTH: Monogamy
isn't realistic!
Again!
BOTH: Monogamy
isn't realistic.
Again!
(KISSING)
(MOANING)
AMY: I never do this.
This is so weird for me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I really like
these ones.
Oh, no!
Shit! That's your dick? Uh-huh!
Too big! Your dick
doesn't end.
Why doesn't your dick end?
(CHUCKLES)
Have you ever
fucked someone before?
Where is she buried?
That looks like the whole
cast of Game of Thrones.
Come here.
You know what?
I'm, like, really shy, Uh-huh.
So we should probably
do this first
so I feel
comfortable with you.
Yeah, all right.
A little warm-up. I know.
Yeah, a little warm-up.
You taste
like mango.
Just stop talking, okay?
Just, like...
Just do the alphabet.
Just hang up
at the top.
Everything important
is up at the top.
Yeah, that's good.
Okay.
(INHALING SHARPLY)
(MOANS)
(suoruwe)
MAN: Hey,
you like that, right'?
(WHISPERS) Amy?
Hey.
I think it's
my turn, baby.
Amy, seriously,
my turn.
Muffin, remember you
said you were gonna...
(CONTINUES SNORING)
MAN: Okay.
AMY: Hey, guys, I'm Amy.
Don't judge me, fuckers!
Pm just a sexual gin, okay?
I am fine. S am in control.
This is clearly
not my first rodeo.
The key is to never
ever let them sleep over.
I got a couple of ticks
to The Black Keys,
Thursday, if you want... Ooh...
Thanks. Bye!
AMY: All right, good night.
All right, bye.
Good night.
Oh...
I guess I do love pussy.
(CHUCKLES)
AMY: Look, (have a great job
and my apartment is sick,
and my friends and
family are awesome,
and Tm sort of
seeing someone.
This dude is not him.
This guy is who
I'm seeing. Kind of.
He's hot, right?
He is great, but it is like
fucking an ice sculpture.
(suoruwe)
Okay, so 3 broke
the sleepover rule.
Where am Y?
Scarf ace poster. Ugh!
Please don't be a dorm room.
There she is.
Buenos dias, baby.
0h, my God!
You look like
an angel.
What time is it?
MAN: It's like 7:30
in the morning.
I didn't know if I should
let you sleep or not.
Or make you breakfast.
I chose breakfast.
Where am I?
Oh, you're in
Staten Island, sugar!
What?
(FOGHORN BLOWING)
AMY: Fuck!
NOAM: What's up, buddy?
Help me out, dude. Come on.
Noam, watch out.
Good morning.
On! Amy!
There she is,
my princess.
What happened? Did
church let out early?
Ha-ha.
(CHUCKLES)
NOAM: Hey! Amy,
where are you going?
This isn't
Planned Parenthood.
Oh, my God.
Shut up!
You have to tell me
everything about last night.
I went on your lnstagram.
That guy is like, so hot.
He looks kind of like
a white Drake. No.
He was like
a Puerto Rican Gollum.
I'm not talking
about it.
AMY: Do you have to pee?
Yeah, totally.
(TINKLING)
AMY: Did you hear Johnny Depp is
coming into the office today?
NIKKI: Oh, yeah.
I'm all overthat.
Which version
of Johnny Depp
would you most
wanna have sex with?
Which one does it
for you the most?
Because I can't
stop thinking about it.
For me, 'Ks
Pirates of the Caribbean.
I love a fully
made up, long hair,
almost feminine-looking
Johnny Depp.
Not almost. He looks like a
beautiful woman in that movie.
Yeah. Who would be yours?
I'm thinking, like, an Edward
Scissorhands Johnny Depp.
You would get
totally cut up.
Yeah, but he'd feel
so bad about it
that he'd be like,
"I'll never leave you."
And I would get,
like, a sick haircut.
Yeah. Yeah.
But also, guess what?
Willy Wonka, bring it on.
Oh, my God, totally.
Right?
Yeah. I would
fuck the shit
out of Willy Wonka
Johnny Depp.
DIANNA: Okay, my babes,
I want your undivided.
I've been looking
at your pitches
and these are
my thoughts.
Nikki.
Why are you smiling?
I'm not smiling,
I'm just very nervous.
DIANNA: Stop smiling.
Stop smiling.
That's even more.
Nikki.
The more nervous I get,
the more I smile, so...
Stop smiling.
Stop it. Stop it.
Nikki, shut it down. Come on.
Bring it down, bring it down.
That's it.
I'm sick of your
ginger nonsense.
I don't wanna see
those gnashers. No.
Stop it.
What's this?
BRYSON: That's our
new intern, Donald.
I thought we were getting
a chick, but he's here.
Okay.
Welcome, Donald.
Welcome to S'nuff where we are
teaching the strong-willed man
how to dress,
think, eat, fuck.
Do you like the
magazine, Donald'?
Oh, yeah, it's pretty much all I read.
Good answer.
Look, this is ours. This is ours.
Right? We made this.
What's our demographic?
ALL: Every-fucking-one.
Thank you.
You can go now.
Yeah, thank you.
It's a big opportunity.
Right, pitch me.
Pitch me hard. Schultz?
So I was thinking
of something called
the "S'nuff Guide to
Beating Off at Work."
Where to do it,
how to do it,
how not to
get caught.
How to get caught.
SCHULTZ: Makes it more fun.
I already started
the research, you guys.
(CHUCKLING)
DIANNA: Bryson?
Okay, I got one.
"You're not gay.
She's boring."
DIANNA: Good.
Yeah?
Fantastic! I can see it.
Thank you.
Okay. I have
another to pitch.
Maybe a cover,
I don't know.
Uh...
"You call those tits?"
That's good. Yeah.
And then maybe like a
"Where are they now?" piece
about the kids Michael
Jackson gave settlements to.
DIANNA: Good.
Ooh...
I want to know.
That's good, yeah.
I play ice hockey with one of them.
I'll get an email.
DIANNA: Yeah, that's good.
Right. So, assignments.
Schultz, you're on
the Ryan Phillippe piece.
Oh! What?
Yes! Crash
was epic.
I was thinking I would take a
stab at the Phillippe piece.
No. Ryan, I tell you, he's
in a major funk right now,
and he will respond
much better
to a male who is neither
attractive nor masculine.
Blam! That's me
right here.
Bryson, I've got
a red mark by your name.
Why would that be?
Yes, okay.
I am pitching
Dr. Aaron Conners.
He works with
some of the Knicks.
He's this incredible, young
sports physician on the rise,
and he just created
this revolutionary
knee insert that cuts
recovery time in half.
He's about to perform it
on Amaﬂe Stoudemire.
It will be the first time it's
ever been done on a pro athlete.
If we get this,
we'll have access
to the biggest
names in sports.
LeBron, Durant,
Blake Griffin.
I've heard of this guy. He did
D'Brickashaw Ferguson's knee, right?
YES.
Yeah, and Metta
World Peace's too.
Yeah. Thabo Sefolosha owes his
whole career to this guy.
Are these
real names?
What's that, Amy?
Your thoughts?
AMY: I'm sorry, I just...
I don't know why we treat
these athletes like heroes
just because
they can skate fast
or kick a ball in a net.
I just think it's weird.
No offense.
I just think that
sports are stupid,
and anyone who
likes them
is just, like,
a lesser person.
And has a
small intellect.
Killer. I want you
to write the piece.
What?
0h, no, I literally
can't stomach sports.
Yeah, I know. Your
opposition is perfection.
This really feels
like a Bryson article.
Yeah, this feels like a "me" article.
Ipﬂchedit
Yeah, you pitched it.
I'm giving it to Amy.
What are you saying? You
giving me some attitude here?
This isn't a fucking
medical journal.
I can do opposition,
I can do sexy.
I want that.
I want that hatred.
I'm giving it to Amy.
Don't sulk at me.
I'm not sulking.
This is my decision.
I'm giving it to Amy.
Sure. Fine.
BRYSON: I can do sexy though.
Sorry?
Huh? Nothing. I'm fine.
DIANNA: What?
I'm just having fun.
(CHUCKES DRYLY)
DIANNA: Nikki,
I want you to research
whether garlic makes semen
taste any different.
Oh... Um...
How am I supposed to get the...
DIANNA: Thank you.
You inspire me.
It tastes the same.
Am?-
I'm not trying
to punish you.
Does it feel
a little like I am'?
No, no,
I appreciate the...
I know you want to branch
out and cover more,
and you do know
I'm looking for a new
executive editor,
don't you'?
I do know that, and I'm
very, very interested.
Hmm. I'd love to be considered.
Especially my dad's
house isn't selling
and my sister and I
just had to put him
in this assisted
living place,
and you would think it was like
the Waldorf. It's so expensive.
Is this your one-woman
show right now'?
Because I ain't
got a ticket.
You know, just
eviscerate the piece.
I'm giving you an assignment.
Right, yeah.
Hmm? And, Amy, if you would
teach this about this.
So, does she have
a foreign accent
or is she just
awesome?
Don't talk to me
for two weeks.
AMY: That's my sister Kim.
She's cute, right?
Well, back off! She's
totally married as fuck!
Our dad's MS has
gotten really bad,
so he can't live
by himself anymore.
We're cleaning out his house.
KIM: There's your box.
That stuff's Goodwill,
that stuff's eBay,
and the stuff
up front is trash.
AMY: This stuffs eBay?
KIM: Yeah.
Iwanna go
through this.
No, don't go
through it.
That's stuff we can
make money off of.
Why are they here?
KIM: They're picking me up.
Hey, Mother, look,
we got a croquet set!
Great job, sweetpea!
He calls you Mother?
That's not creepy.
Yeah, it's
his choice.
Have him call
you Stepmother.
It's more accurate.
I've raised
that child!
Mom, lfound
a glove.
Hey, buddy, how you doing? Good.
What are you
studying in school'?
I'm learning
about space
and all the
celestial objects
and how there are
planets and
solar systems,
and sometimes there could
be multiple universes
but people don't know
how to describe that yet,
but it's a new theory,
and I'm so excited to see if
they figure it out or not.
Great.
See you around.
Okay.
Why is he dressed
like Colonel Sanders?
He got to dress himself
and that's what he chose.
That's what the inside of his
heart looks like. Be nice.
Can you just be
real for a second?
If you just met
that dude at a CVS,
you'd have a real
problem with him.
Can you just
pretend to like him?
I am pretending.
Ooh, I like
Tom's sweater.
He's doing the
To Catch a Predator look.
Amy!
What?
TOM: Amy, what's up?
Hey! Looking sharp.
Looking sharp, man. Thanks.
TOM: Nice to see you.
AMY: Nice to see you'
I was reading
your article about
how to talk your girlfriend
into a three-way.
You read that one? Yeah.
Wow!
Would you do that? No.
No.
That got off
the table quick.
Yeah.
Lei him do
what he wants.
You guys should
make a sex tape.
I would.
Uh...
I did high
school theater.
I think I'd be pretty good.
(LAUGHING)
AMY: This nursing home is nice.
KIM: Yeah.
Ifs too nice and
it's too expensive
and we should've
put him in a shithole.
We did. I mean,
it's a shithole.
It's just the nicest shithole.
Yeah.
Places where the nurses don't
fuck the patients are expensive.
That's what
you're paying for.
It's not the food,
sister.
Ew!
"Condoms ribbed
for his pleasure"?
(Gas PS)
I better hold on
to these.
Is this coke?
No. Dad didn't
love coke.
He was just a
full-blown alcoholic.
(SNORTING)
(GASPS)
No. It must just be from
a Halloween costume. Oh.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
KIM: Moving on.
AMY: Let's just...
Amy, don't touch it.
These are
his memories.
No, don't do that!
Toss it away.
What? He needs
his wallet.
We've got so much stuff to go through.
Please stop...
Oh! He loves
that poster.
I know.
Kimberly! Stop it!
Stop it! Girl!
Come on!
Not cool, girl!
That felt good.
It's not right.
Alaska.
No. Don't throw
away his snow globes.
These are his memories. He got
one of these everywhere he went.
Does he have one for every
one of ou r teachers?
I don't see them.
He didn't fuck
all our teachers.
He fucked all
of my teachers.
No, he never
fucked Mr. Hecht.
I did.
I'm just kidding.
(LAUGHS)
You know,
he wouldn't, but...
(GAS PS)
Oh, man!
Look at this.
AMY: Morn was
so fuckable then.
She had
the best tits.
When she would lay down,
they would just stay put.
Mine are just like,
"See ya!"
(CHUCKLES)
My titties are
like, "Peace!"
KIM: Dad was
such a dick.
(SIGHS)
I don't really
see it that way.
Can we mix it up
a little bit?
Will you talk
dirty to me?
Come on. Come on!
Amy, no. It's not
something I do well.
I'm not really
verbal, okay'?
I'm more physical
in how I communicate.
You're gonna be great at it.
I'm gonna sound stupid.
I don't wanna sound stupid.
You're not gonna sound stupid.
Clear your mind and say
whatever pops in it, okay?
Just try it.
Say anything.
All right.
I'm gonna give you
my full pecker. Yeah.
Okay.
Because of
the pecs,
but "pecker" is
kind of like my dick.
Yeah, I got it. I understood
what you meant by "pecker."
(GRUNTING) I'm gonna
fill you with protein.
I'm gonna give you
the protein you need
to survive when
you're making muscles.
I'm gonna put my
green drink in you.
Yeah. Beta-carotene
and vegetable mix.
Can it not be
about protein
or energy
or nutrition?
Can you just talk
about sex stuff?
All right. Yes. Just sexy stuff.
Talk to me.
There's no
"F, in "team"
but there's an
..l.. in "Win...
Can't spell "victory"
without "T-R-Y."
Winning isn't everything.
It's the only thing.
Okay, these are
just sports phrases.
Are these Nike slogans?
Please just...
You want the "Just do it"?
Do you want that one?
No! Just have sex with me
and say some dirty shit.
(SPEAKING IN MANDARIN)
What is that?
Talking to you dirty in Chinese.
That's what I'm doing.
What? I've been studying
Mandarin in my off time.
(SPEAKING IN MANDARIN)
"Do you need to go
to the bathroom?"
Please don't speak Chinese
or whatever during sex.
Okay, no problem.
I'm sorry. I don't mean
to be so picky.
You look discouraged
and you're doing great.
I told you I wasn't
gonna be any good at this.
Can we try
something else?
Yeah. Talk about
the first time you saw me.
Okay?
That's easy. I remember
it like it was yesterday.
Yeah?
I was just getting
done in the gym.
You were leaving that
pizza place, remember?
Yeah.
And you were holding on to that box.
(MOANING) Mmm-hmm.
And you walked out. You
were wearing those jeans.
0h' God! They looked
so good from behind.
Uh-huh!
Oh!
From behind...
Yeah, yeah.
...you looked like a dude. What?
Oh!
(GRUNTING)
Don't move! Don't move at all!
Anything!
Ah! You're moving
your arm.
Fudge ripple
ice cream!
Ah!
(GRUNTS)
Oh! Yeah!
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Oh...
That was great.
We gotta make that part of our program.
For sure.
Really onto something.
(SIGHS)
STEVEN: Amy, don't forget
to hydrate, babe.
We went verbal!
The boys make
the noise!
NOAM: What's up, brother?
Yes, I'm loving it.
Rastaman! Digging it with the rolling bag.
Mixed messages.
Come back over here.
I love you on Glee.
How's it going? Amy,
what's happening?
You got a new sign?
Yeah, I'm working
a couple of ideas out.
Yeah. I'm going to
visit my dad.
Oh. How is he'?
We put him in an assisted
living facility.
I don't know how
nice it is, actually.
Oh. I know exactly
how you feel.
The car I take
a shit in,
they towed it.
Yeah.
Sucks. Sorry, man.
All right. I'll see you later.
I'll see you later.
I'll be here.
Hey, I'm digging
that back camel toe.
NORMAN: What a
ridiculous statement!
You're talking about the most
talented player on all levels.
None of these bums
are the equal of Babe Ruth.
Norman, Babe Ruth was awful.
Stop it!
How can you
negate facts?
Just be nice to him.
I am nice to him.
He's not nice to me.
Babe Ruth was a superhero.
He was Superman!
Easy to be a Superman when
you never played against
a black guy
your whole life.
What does white/black
got to do with it?
Every 12-year-old kid in the
Dominican Republic right now
can probably
beat Babe Ruth.
Blah, blah, blah!
GORDON: Before 1947,
it's one big asterisk. Norman!
Can you just keep a low
profile for two weeks, here?
GORDON: Oh, I'm sorry.
I don't want to offend
any of these people
fucking each other with Viagra
day and night, God forbid.
Can you just be
nice and make friends?
After T300...
After dinner,
it turns into Caligula
around here. Trust me.
Please.
It's a madhouse.
Ifs like the Playboy
Mansion, for Christ's sake.
This place?
Yes.
(SIGHS)
You got my Mets stuff?
Yeah.
Am?-
I'll bring it by.
Amy. Look at me.
Amy?
Kim made me throw
a lot of it away.
Kim made you? Your little sister?
Yes.
She's mean as a dog.
Jesus!
I tried. I'm so sorry.
What do I care? It's all
memorabilia, anyway.
I'm memorabilia
at this point.
Don't say that.
ANN". Dr. Gunners'?
Hi. Hey.
Hi.
Amy Townsend.
Aaron Gunners.
Great to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you so much
for letting me come in.
No worries.
Um, so...
How does
this work?
0h, uh, today is really
just to go over schedules.
Okay.
AMY: If that's cool.
Yeah, that's great.
Uh, I have never
been interviewed
for a magazine.
(KNOCKING)
Hey . AARON". Hey , Lemon .
Sorry, I don't mean
to interrupt.
Did I leave my
sunglasses here'?
I don't know.
Did you?
I was sitting...
Oh, here they are.
Did you just drive
40 minutes back here
to look for
your sunglasses?
Yeah, of course.
You think I'm gonna give
Sunglass Hut
another $30 for these?
You crazy?
Hey, how you doing? Hi.
Wait, your watch costs
more than my apartment.
Oh, this thing?
That was a gift.
We watching
Downton Abbey later?
Uh, if I get out of here on
time, yeah, we could watch it.
If not, let's do it tomorrow.
LEBRON: What?
I'm watching it tonight,
because I'm not gonna go to
practice in the morning,
and all the guys are talking
about it and I'm left out.
Hey, do what
you gotta do.
Can you validate
my parking, please?
I don't validate. You
should talk to Cheryl.
Okay, take care.
Nice meeting you.
AARON: Bye, LeBron.
Thanks, buddy.
LEBRON: Cheryl, can you
validate my parking, please?
Tall! Yeah, I know, right?
Do you know
who that was?
A basketball player.
He's LeBron James. He's kind
of "the" basketball player.
Oh, yeah. I think lsaw one
of his soda commercials.
Yeah.
Do you follow sports?
Oh, my God.
Sports? I love them.
Who are your
favorite teams?
I like smaller teams.
Not the big leagues.
I like the Long
Island Mediums.
The Acorn Pine Cones.
Haven't heard of them. The
Fire Island Penguins.
I like the Cincinnati
Thunder-Wizards.
You can stop.
The Orlando...
Blooms.
You can stop.
You don't follow sports.
I'm sorry, I don't.
I don't know
anything about sports.
You know what? That's okay, though.
Don't be embarrassed.
I'm sorry. No, don't
be embarrassed
because I actually didn't follow
sports until I got thisjob.
Really?
Yeah.
0h, my God! You have no idea
what a huge relief that is.
I was assigned this.
This was not
even my pitch.
Right. So you're
doing the article on me?
Mmm-hmm.
AWGSOMG.
I think they're kind of weird
and it's just strange.
Grown men wearing jerseys with
another man's name on it.
Like, are you in jail?
Are you his bitch?
Right. Kind of
like that one?
That's different,
because it's in a frame.
I think sports brings
people together.
It kind of forms
a community.
That's what I'm saying.
Right. Yeah. Obviously.
I'll tell you another thing
that's great about this job,
is that I get to
work with athletes,
which means that I
work with a lot of...
Black people?
...injuries.
What did you just say?
Did you say "black people"?
No.
Do you have a problem
with black people?
(CHUCKLING) No.
I love black people.
I prefer black people.
Do you have
black friends?
Endless black friends.
Can you show me pictures of your
black friends on your phone'?
You want 10 see pictures on
my phone of my black friends?
Amy, you gotta have
a lot of them.
I have so many. I'm deciding which
one, because there's so many.
Oh! Here we go. Oh, great.
Let's see it.
You're gonna be eating yourwords.
Oh, good.
You ready?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Okay, get ready.
Black friend.
AARON: That is you
and a white friend,
and that is a black
waiter pouring your water.
Let me find another one.
Oh. My phone died.
Um, I'm gonna let you
get back to doctoring.
Oh, thanks.
I'll talk to your...
Cheryl.
Cheryl about when we can meet again.
Yeah.
Great.
DANIEL RADCLIFFE: No,
we're not going into the park.
We've been in
the park already.
Sorry I'm late.
No, it's okay.
It's a wonderful film
Daniel Radcliffe is in.
What is this movie?
Radcliffe is
a dog walker,
but he's got a chip on his
shoulder, a real edge.
Sundance loved it.
I need help
with my dog.
I can see that.
I would love to be the one
to help you with your dog.
What's your technique?
I put them on
a leash and walk them.
You talk a big game.
That's because
I walk a big dog.
MAREMQMEY.
She looks lime...
Am?-
What's up?
Is that wine
in a box?
Mmm-hmm.
I have red, too.
STEVEN: You have red, too?
Is this guy
ever gonna shut up?
Please watch
the movie.
Stop. That's not right.
Don't do this to me.
Why is he yelling?
Listen, you always
do this to me.
You show up to these places,
you put me in a situation.
I'm a big guy.
Everybody wants to fight the big guy.
Yeah, you are.
Hey, Mark Wahlberg,
shut your bitch up.
Mark Wahlberg? Me?
Who else looks like Mark Wahlberg?
Your girl?
Mark Wahlbergs, like, 150 pounds.
I'm 250, lean.
I look like Mark Wahlberg
ate Mark Wahlberg!
Your muscles aren't
the fucking problem.
It's your
yapping girlfriend.
Just say "Fuck you." Yeah?
I will fuck you,
all right?
I will enter you!
You're gonna
"enter" me?
Did you hear
what he said?
What are you talking
about right now?
(WHISPERING) I'm just
trying to intimidate him.
You're talking
about raping him.
You're not about that life, champ.
I can see it.
Oh, I am about that life!
MAN: No, you're not.
No,no,no. I will get
crazy up in here.
You like movies?
We'll make a movie.
We'll make Mama
Said Knock You Out
starring my fist
and your dick hole.
MANI Oh, Shit!
What the fuck is
wrong with this dude?
He wants you.
Babe, your threats, I'm telling
you, they're super gay.
Too sexual?
Yeah.
This has to be the corniest,
muscled white dude
I've ever seen
in my fucking life.
Okay, Koko B. Ware,
you know what?
You're being
an asshole, all right'?
You know what I do with assholes?
I lick them.
What the fuck?
He wants
to fuck you.
My pooch has been
hurt more than enough.
I will make sure no one ever
hurts your pooch again.
TOMEI: I/ike when you're
taking control of your dogs.
RADCLIFFE:
I thought you would.
I'm back.
What did I miss?
Amy, what did I miss?
They pre-butter it.
Who's Brody?
What?
Who's Oli?
Who's Brody?
Why do you have
my cell phone?
Why are you smiling?
I got a little
high outside.
Like, barely
at all high.
Okay, while you were
outside getting high,
I was putting your phone
on silent for the movie,
and when I did that,
I noticed you have
all these guys
in your phone.
There's Brody. There's a guy
listed as "Hot as Balls."
Who the fuck is
"Hot as Balls"?
Stop smiling!
I'm not smiling.
Those are
guys from work.
Can we just
watch this movie?
You know what?
No, I can't.
Because as I was
turning off your phone,
lgot a picture
of somebody's dick.
Itwas mine.
Fuck you, Tone-Léc. You want to
take it to the parking lot? Fine!
You can't find me? I'll be
the closest one on Grindr.
That's 93Y-
Steven, please. lam not
in shape for this.
Stop walking like the Hulk.
I can see that you're mad.
You are being crazy!
Am I? Because I think you owe
me an explanation for this.
Do I have to worry
about you with other guys'?
I'm so high
right now.
Can we please talk about this tomorrow?
I'm too fucked up.
Amy, you're always
fucked up.
Answer the question. Are you
hooking up with other guys?
We never said we
were exclusive.
Fuck, Amy! "Exclusive"?
It's not high school.
You know, every single guy I
work outwith, every single guy,
says that all
you're gonna do
is mess with my
emotions and hurt me.
You guys talk
about that at the gym'?
Fuck, Amy! Do I have to worry
about you with other guys?
Yes, I hook up with other guys.
(GROANS)
I don't go to
the movies with them.
That's, like,
our special thing.
This is so
fucking stupid.
You know what
the sad part is'?
I was gonna ask
you to marry me.
Really?
I didn't even think
you liked me very much.
Why are you making me
feel bad about this?
You can sleep
with other girls.
It's like every
guy's dream.
It's not this
Yeah, this guy's
got a dream,
and it's us
making it!
Getting married,
moving out to the
countryside, having a family.
Three boys and
two more boys.
Enough for a
basketball team.
And I'll develop a CrossFit
program and patent it.
And I'll rule
the CrossFit world.
With you by my side.
You can be my
Cross?“ Queen.
That's my dream.
Hey.
Can I leave?
Or, like, can you leave?
I just, like...
I'm very high,
and I just kind of need
this interaction to be over.
You serious?
Fuck you, Amy.
You are not nice.
I'm totally nice.
Maybe you should consider
changing your ways.
My "ways"?
Mmm-hmm.
You would love
having a family.
You sound
like Steven.
I wish I could
break up with you.
Having a family is fun.
That's fun?
Yeah.
They're having
a boys' lunch.
Here?
AMY: Hi!
Hi, ladies.
Urn, we're gonna have two mimosas.
Okay.
Mmm-mmm.
No, you're right. Hold the orange juice.
No orange juice.
It's sugar.
So, champagne?
Ooh! Okay.
No, no.
No champagne for me.
Uh, yeah, we'll have
two champagnes.
Two champagnes.
Thanks.
Okay. We'll
see you in a bit.
Oh, my God. He's dying to fuck me.
Mmm-hmm.
Wait, why aren't
you drinking?
Have a drink with me.
Wait. No!
You're pregnant?
I'm pregnant.
Ugh!
Goa!
Tom's the father.
Ew!
(LAUGHS)
God. They look like
they're on a speed date.
Say "Congratulations."
(SCOFFS)
We're telling Dad.
I'll tell him at the
new nursing home.
The one that's cheaper.
It's not okay.
You're telling him.
GORDON: Kim,
are you serious?
Oh, my God.
Congratulations!
You're pregnant.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my God.
Come here, come here.
GORDON: Oh!
My God! Oh, my God.
I'm tingling right now. I feel high.
(LAUGHING)
GORDON; I feel high!
That's incredible.
KIM: Thank you.
I'm finally gonna
be a grandfather.
You're already
a grandfather.
Not yet.
You're already
a grandfather.
Allister.
What's that?
What about him?
That's your grandson.
Allister? (LAUGHS)
No, I mean, Allister's
your step-child
and my step-grandkid,
lguess.
But I'm talking
about your kid.
Our bloodlines!
That's... Yeah.
I was the first
person on my block
to own a television set.
That's really not
relevant right now, Norman.
It's not relevant.
Come on, that's more
like Tom's kid.
Ifs Tom's kid,
who you help with.
Dad, you love Allister.
GORDON; I like Allister.
I care for him,
I fear for him.
I know what happens to a kid
like that in the schoolyard.
We had a kid
like that. Stewie.
We used to beat him
mercilessly.
Oh!
Some of the beatings
I almost feel bad about.
That's gonna
happen to this kid.
I'm trying to protect him, trying
to teach him how to be a man.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You were the
worst father ever.
Come on.
I wasn't a bad father.
Mom did everything
when we were growing up.
You wouldn't understand
because you weren't there.
So, now your mother's a saint?
Of course she's a saint.
Of course, because once you
die, everybody's a saint.
Dad, just shut up.
We were talking about
this yesterday, right?
About Allister.
KIM: Amy?
No! He's lying.
Amy'?
Amy, come on, you said
he's the kind of kid
who drops his
pants to the floor
when he pees
in the urinal.
AMY: No, you said that!
GORDON: That's funny to guys.
AMY: I said he
pees sitting down.
(LAUGHS) That was funny.
AMY: Itwas a joke.
I cannot believe
that you guys
are teaming up
against me again.
Oh! No! I'm on your side!
I'm on your team.
You're not on my team!
Sorry if I'm excited more about my
grandkid than some step-grandkid.
They're both your
grandkid, God damn it!
What the...
Kimberly, come...
Is that your wife?
What is this speech
you have to make
for Doctors
With Borders?
"Without."
Without Borders.
Ifs "Doctors
Without Borders."
on. Right.
Yeah, it's Doctors
Without Borders.
It's a really
good organization.
Basically, we go to places
with the most conflict,
places with the
biggest disasters,
and we go in
and help people.
So, you help
people by choice,
and that's
what you like'?
Yeah. It's great work. It's very
rewarding, helping these people.
Wow!
What's your story? Are you a
Division One athlete or something?
Me? No, no. I was on the
Xbox that I was playing,
and then I got really high
and tripped on my bong.
Are you high?
Yeah.
(GUFFAWS)
Wow.
So high.
I think you got your
new article right here.
Here we go.
All right.
So, this is our Sports Medicine
and Performance Center.
Wow.
This is where most
of our athletes come
and do the
rehabilitation.
What does this do?
Come on.
So the HBM shows
how your muscles
are working
and moving,
so your rehab is
most effective.
It could help you with
your gait, your posture.
My gait?
(MACHINE BEEPS)
Mmm-hmm.
AMY: Okay.
So, just walk
normal for a second.
AMY: That looks pretty good.
Okay, okay.
Just walk naturally
for one second, please.
AMY: Like this'?
I walk like Beyoncé. People
always think I'm her.
We share on Instagram.
Is that how you walk down the street?
AMY: MMm-hmm.
No, this is how I walk.
I think the screen's doing different
stuff than what I'm doing.
What we can do with this,
is we could show
how you can, um, fix your
posture and your gait.
I really wouldn't
do a Hitler march.
Just walk the way you
walk down the street.
AMY: Like this'?
AMY: All right.
Sorry, I'm listening.
Okay. We good? You good?
All right. Thank you.
Wait, who is this? Watch the screen.
Who is this?
Who? Kevin Spacey at end
of The Usual Suspects.
I didn't see
that movie.
Oh. He's
Keyser Siize.
That's not important.
It's not a spoiler. Oh.
So why don't you pick up
the speed a little hit?
That's good.
Get a nice jog going, there.
You can speed it up a little
bit faster, if you want.
(BEEPING)
AARON; Ah.
There you go. See how that's working out?
That's great.
See how your legs are lighting up green'?
You can go
a little faster, actually.
Don't lean forward like that when you run.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
You want to lean
back a little bit.
See how that's
lighting up green?
There you go.
See, that's real nice.
See how you're
landing on your heel.
You're stepping
too far back.
So you want to land on
the ball of your foot.
There you go.
See, that's real nice.
(PANTING)
How do you stop? Can you
make sure this thing stops?
(MACHINE POWERS DOWN)
Oh.
Whoa, whoa whoa.
Are you all right?
You're hyperventilating.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Can you get this off?
Yeah, here you go.
Look at me.
Deep breath in.
Blow it out like you're blowing
out a birthday candle.
(EXHALES SLOWLY)
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
That's good, that's good.
Slow it down. Slow it down.
(BOTH EXHALE SLOWLY)
You're just
hyperventilating.
You're all right.
You're okay.
Just take your time.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
You all right?
I'm hungry.
Okay.
I haven't eaten
much today.
Okay.
I basically had,
like, Lay's potato chips.
Stopped at a Starbucks,
had, like, one
red velvet yogurt.
And two scones. They
were, like, super small.
And then just
some Chipotle,
but that stuff
runs through you.
So you had breakfast,
lunch and a snack?
Yeah, that's it.
Okay.
Let's go get some food.
Yeah.
Yeah?
Let's do that.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
AARON: Um...
My dad, um,
is a rheumatologist
and my mom is
a college professor.
They're great. They put a
lot of pressure on me.
I was their
only child, so...
Or maybe they didn't
put a lot of pressure on me.
I just put the
pressure on myself
because they did so
much great stuff, but...
No, they put
pressure on me.
You knew what? Can we not
put this in the article?
Is that all right? This doesn't
need to be in the article.
I don't know why I'm saying any of it.
They're great.
Aaron's parents are great.
I won't put any of that in the
article, if you don't want.
Is that all right?
Yeah.
Just off the record.
Okay. Um...
Just so you know,
if you want me
to keep something
out of the article,
if you want it to
be off the record,
you have to
tell me before.
Oh, really?
Yeah. This can
be retroactive.
I won't put your parents
in the article. Okay.
This article is
gonna be killer.
Yeah, it's gonna
be a bummer.
(LAUGHING)
I read some
of your stuff.
Oh, my God.
No, they were really good. No.
AARON: When I
started reading...
There was one thing, and I
was, like, "I don't know."
And then lstarted reading it
and I thought it was...
I was, like, "This is actually
really funny and smart."
It's satirical.
Thank you.
It was good.
I have other stuff that I've
written for other places.
That's just the kind of stuff
they want at this magazine.
Can I read some of it?
Yeah, you can read... You
can read some of my stuff.
Do you want to
go get a drink'?
Yeah.
Yeah? Okay.
Can I get the check, please?
He understood.
Don't do...
Don't do the
symbol and yell.
Just do one
or the other.
What do you mean?
You can mouih the word
"check" really loud
and not make noise.
And that's
kind of the best.
What do I do?
Watch.
Check.
Okay, let me try.
Okay.
(YELLS) Check?
(LAUGHS) No!
No.
Am I not doing that right? No!
(YELLS) Check!
Oh, my God!
Could we get
the bill, please?
We'd like to pay
for the food.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Okay, first kiss. This girl
named Jennifer Jennifer.
Her name was
Jennifer Jennifer?
Jennifer Jennifer.
And she was
very cute.
It was a Halloween party,
seventh grade.
She was shorter than me, she had
to stand up on a stone to kiss me.
Itwas like a Norman
Rockwell painting.
It was very cute.
Oh! And you see these teeth?
Yeah.
Look at these teeth.
They're fake,
they're porcelain.
Ron Gardner,
seventh grade.
I got brand new Air Jordans.
He wanted them.
Yeah?
He punched me in the
face and knocked out
my teeth and
stole my shoes.
No! You're getting a
lot of info from me.
This is all off the
record, by the way.
All off the record. AMY: Yeah,
off the record. Totally.
Hey, today
was really fun.
Yeah, it was great. I was a
little nervous about it.
Yeah. But no, this
was a lot of fun.
No, this was great.
Um... If you want to maybe
come by tomorrow...
Are you coming?
Oh!
You going downtown?
Sweet. Uh...
AARON: Hi. Sorry.
Uh, two stops.
Just one stop.
You want to give
him your address'?
(STUTTERS)
Spring and Washington.
AARON: So, this
is where I live.
Uh...
It's pretty sweet. Do you
want a drink or anything?
AMY: No, thanks.
AARON: No? All right.
Uh...
This is the kitchen.
Umm...
It's a pretty
sweet place.
I've been here
for about a year.
You know what? Let's get
some tunes on in this place.
Holy shit.
(REMOTE CLATTERS)
Hi.
(KISSING)
So we're gonna
do this now?
We are gonna
do this now.
Okay, that's...
Is that okay?
That's cool, yeah.
Whoa!
Do you own this place?
Are you renting it?
I own it.
Cool, that's
really nice.
Oh, shit.
Yeah.
We're doing this
right now?
We are doing
this right now.
We are off
to the races.
Yeah, it's happening. Okay.
All right.
That's nice.
Oh, man.
Oh, God!
0h, my God!
Good for you.
Yeah, thank you.
I didn't see
this for you.
Uh , yeah'?
Mmm-hmm.
(BOTH SIGH)
Okay.
I'm gonna head out.
Oh, no.
Thank you.
Why don't you
stay over?
Yes. No, I'm not gonna
stay here. I just...
You have an
early day, I bet.
No, it's fine.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Are you comfortable?
No. No, I'm not.
I don't really
like to spoon.
Oh.
Okay. Yeah, sorry. Can we...
If I stay here,
can we just sleep
in a realistic position?
Sure, yeah.
Because I'm
a light sleeper,
and if I feel you
move or sweat or breathe,
I'll wake up
and just lay here
resenting you
all night.
So, yeah, can we...
Actually, could we put
this pillow in between us?
That'll be good. Put
the pillow between us?
Yeah, that's not
your main pillow
that you use, is it'?
No.
Okay, cool.
Let's kind of
get that in there.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm sorry
I'm nit-picking,
but you're breathing on me
pretty hard right now.
Yeah, it's like
a strong wind.
What do you
need me to do?
Breathe up towards the sky
and not at me. (SIGHS)
Yeah, you got it.
Sorry, it's
just a lot.
Like this? Are you
feeling better?
Let me see. Do it and I'll
tell you if I can feel it.
I'm still getting
a little bit of a wind.
Oh... Jesus.
Do you want me
to go home?
I can sleep at home.
No, this is
so worth it.
(SIGHS)
Nikki, just hurry up
and get here.
When you're
writing an article,
do you always use
a tape recorder?
No.
Um, when you're
writing an article,
what are the 10 biggest
mistakes you could make?
Plagiarizing, getting
drunk, fucking someone.
Have you ever seen any kind
of article about a fetish
where guys like to
masturbate to hockey fights?
That's not a thing.
Not a thing.
Then Why'd it
work for me?
We're in the middle
of something, so...
Yeah. Seriously, right?
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Okay, so, that
actually brings me
to an interesting
line of questioning.
You know what? Uh, they're
gonna want you to just do
a bunch of web stuff
because you're younger.
Everyone has a boner for young
people on the Internet, okay?
They think you have the key to it.
DIANNA: Amy!
That's why we'll do anything
we can to help you here.
Right, but when you're
writing an article...
Sorry, talk to me
about it later.
Just write
them all down.
I'll be
helpful later.
Okay.
I like you, Amy. I do, you know?
You're clever, but
you're not too brainy.
You're pretty-ish and you're not gorgeous.
You're approachable.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I want this promotion
for you, Amy, you know'?
I want you to
help me to help you.
I need to go up there,
to the men upstairs.
I need you to provide
me with the ammo
to get them to know that you
can handle their workload.
Can you handle
their load, Amy?
I can handle all their loads.
That's it.
Nikki.
Hey. Where have you been?
Sorry, I was
getting a smoothie.
Can you sit, please?
I slept at the doctor's
place last night.
Oh, my God, because you
were blackout drunk?
No, that's the thing. I was dead sober.
I had like two drinks.
Three, max.
Four, now that I'm tallying.
But I was sober.
So you barely drank?
Barely.
Because you're on
antibiotics or something?
No, lspent the
night on purpose.
I don't understand.
When you think
about the sex,
are you just
kind of like...
No. I'm like...
So, you're like...
No, that's not what I'm doing.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, my God!
He's calling.
Why would he call?
You guysjust had sex.
It's probably a mistake.
It's a mistake.
He's butt-dialing you.
Hello.
AARON: Oh.
Hey, there. It's Aaron.
Oh. This is Amy.
I think you
butt-dialed me.
No, ldialed you
with my fingers.
What's she saying? What did she say?
(SHUSHING)
He called me
on purpose.
Hang up. He's obviously
sick or something.
Yeah, what's up?
I was calling to say I had a
really good time last night.
I was wondering if you wanted
to, um, hang out again.
Will you say
that again, please?
I was wondering
if I could see you again.
You know what? I'm
gonna call the police.
Hold on, hold on.
I'll just talk
to you about it
tomorrow at
the interview.
Okay? Oh, yes! She said yes!
okay, We-
All right, I'll
talk to you then.
Oh! Man!
That's pretty
cool, man.
I didn't get 10 hear the
whole conversation, though.
We're gonna
talk about it
when we see each
other tomorrow.
That's great, man.
Yeah, she's got
a sexy voice.
Did you guys
make love?
Yeah.
Oh!
Whom!
My boy got intimate. Yeah.
Sexual intercourse!
Whoa!
Do you want to just
announce it to everybody?
My boy got a girlfriend.
Man, it's been forever!
Yeah. I'm not gonna lie.
It's been a while.
Yeah, it's been
six years since Sheila.
And that only lasted five weeks.
Yep.
There was Debbie.
Debbie didn't even
tell you where she lived.
Yeah, she thought
I was a psycho.
She kept calling
me "Dexter."
What I'm saying is,
you got to go for it.
You need to focus if you want
to take it to the next level.
Right.
You have to. You got
to give it everything
if you want
this one, man.
It like, when I lost the
Championship in 2011,
I worked on my
game twice as hard,
worked on my
post-up game,
and we wound up winning
the Championship, twice.
Yeah. Yeah.
I don't feel like
that applies to me.
But I appreciate
the thought.
Aaron, you have to take a risk.
You have to. Yeah, you're right.
Ifs like, when I decided
to go back to Cleveland,
I wasn't totally sure they was
gonna welcome me back, man.
But they did.
They welcomed me back
with open arms
and an open heart.
Yeah, they did. Again, I feel
that applies more to you.
I don't even
live in Cleveland.
But, again, I
appreciate the thought.
Cleveland, Ohio?
You're talking about the home of
The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.
Or maybe we go down lo Canton to
the Pro Football Hall of Fame.
Did you know Superman
was created in Cleveland?
Yeah, I know Superman
was created in Cleveland.
You've told me that
a number of times.
You ever seen a Cuyahoga sunset?
No.
Do you know Cleveland's
great for the whole family?
Yes. Yes, I do. You tell
me that all the time.
You randomly just text me that.
And what's wrong with that?
Which is weird. It's weird.
I got free texting.
Why are you trying to always
sell me on Cleveland?
When are you gonna
come to Cleveland?
(STAMMERING) I'll come
when I have the time.
I just don't have
the time right now.
I'll come when I have the time.
I've just been really busy.
You visit me in
Miami all the time.
Yeah, but that's
Miami. I mean...
What's the difference between
Miami and Cleveland?
It's the same.
You're right,
it's the same.
Exactly.
Okay, so you had the salmon.
That's about 14 dollars.
What are you doing, man?
You had two Cokes.
Dude, are you trying
to split the bill'?
Look, I told you those
refills weren't free.
No, no, no, we're
not splitting the bill.
Pick up the check.
Why do I have to
pick up the check'?
Because you're
LeBron James.
Listen, don't look at
me no differently now
just because
I got a little money.
Look, I don't know how
long this could last.
Anything can happen.
Right.
I'm not about to
end up like MC Hammer.
Listen, you
owe $32.43.
You know what?
I'll pay it, but you got to pick
up a check every once in a while.
No, don't pay
the whole thing.
Just pay your part.
Ifs better for our friendship.
Equals forever.
All right, fine.
All right.
I'll put my
credit card in.
Put a credit card in,
we'll split it.
That's what I'm talking about.
(SIGHS)
Fuck you.
I think I left my wallet.
Ifs right
in the car.
(UPTOWN GIRL PLAYING)
(AARON HUMMING)
No, no, no...
AMY: So that was disgusting.
Yeah.
Why Billy Joel?
Why Uptown Girl?
I love that song.
That's probably the worst
Billy Joel song.
I'm pretty sure
Billy Joel hates that song.
Oh, he shouldn't.
It's great.
Okay.
So, uh,
off the record,
do you wanna maybe
go grab some dinner?
Um...
Actually, Aaron,
I think you're so great,
but I'm a writer.
I'm your writer,
you're my subject,
and from now on, we need to
just keep it professional.
Okay.
You know'?
Yeah.
Okay.
I think we really
like each other
and we should
start dating.
No, I'm saying...
I'm confused.
Am I not communicating
this right?
No, I hear you. I'm
just saying I disagree.
Do you like me?
Yeah.
Yeah, see,
I really like you.
So we should
be a couple.
(STAMMERING)
No! I have plans.
What are your plans?
Dentist.
Is that true?
No.
Then let's go out.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I'm sorry. My dad's
place is calling.
Hello?
Well, why didn't
someone help him?
What is it?
My dad fell. He lives in assisted living.
I need to change.
Okay, I'm on my way.
What hospital
is he at?
TEMEMBE: Oh! Sit still, Gordon.
Dad!
GORDON: Hey, baby.
AMY: What happened?
Nothing.
He's supposed to
ring his call button
if he wants to get
out of his chair.
He has fallen.
Where's the doctor?
They are ignoring
my pages.
If I wanted,
I could treat him.
I was a doctor
in my country.
Yeah, I'll let you
know if the wound
gets invaded
by evil spirits.
Are you in pain, Dad? No.
AARON: Can I take
a look at it, please?
Oh, God, Dam!
It looks a lot worse
than it actually is.
Who's this Moondoggie?
Hi, I'm Dr. Conners.
Your daughter and I just
officially started dating.
No. Not officially.
Not at all.
Welcome to a
very large club.
You are gonna be
getting stitches today.
Not a chance, Buster!
Dad, let him do it.
What's the point?
Just leave it.
What do I have to look
like Kate Middleton for?
I don't give consent.
Here we go.
No consent!
AMY: Shut up, Dad.
AARON: I need you
to stop moving.
GORDON: Ah! lfeel
like a pincushion.
(AARON HUMMING UPTOWN GIRL)
What is he humming?
Billy Joel.
Uptown Girl.
That's the only thing that saves you.
I like Billy Joel.
I saw him in Nassau Coliseum,
Nylon Curtain Tour.
Oh, Nylon Curtain Tour?
That's awesome.
I saw him with Elton John in Shea Stadium.
It was great.
Of course you did.
Nothing better than down-lo-earth,
blue collar Billy Joel
with Elton John,
the Queen of England.
Hey, Amy tells me that you're a Mets fan.
Is that right?
I'm a supporter of the
New York Metropolitans.
That is correct.
What about it?
Would you like to
hear some trivia?
GORDON: Distracting me
like I'm a young girl
getting her ears
pierced? Go ahead.
Can you name nine
major league teams
that don't end
with the letter "S"?
Child's play.
The Jazz. Utah Jazz.
You got the Miami Heat.
You got the White Sox.
What's up?
I shouldn't be
telling you this,
but I think he's hoarding
his pain medication.
No, I got it.
Ease up, Martha Stewart.
Hey! Water aerobics.
You coming?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
I'll be right there.
Meryl is wearing
a two-piece.
(SMACKS ups)
The guy died three years ago
and nobody alerted him.
Thank you so much.
Hey, no problem.
My dad's really
not a bad guy,
but you caught
him on an off day.
No, no, no.
He was fine.
You know what? What I'll do is,
I'll check up on him next week.
And I told him about
this immune suppressant...
Will you please
come home with me?
Uh...
Forget it.
No, no, no. No!
You know what?
Hey, you know what?
Let's, um...
Let's get food. Do you
wanna get some food?
Do you wanna
get some raviolis'?
Raviolis?
I'm serious.
Yeah. Do you wanna
get some raviolis?
I know a place
that's around here.
They have
great raviolis.
I'd love to
get raviolis.
Just go to the ravioli place.
Just get them.
Yeah.
Yeah?
(BREATHING SHARPLY)
Stop doing that.
Why are you
breathing weird?
I'm not
breathing weird.
(BREATHING SHARPLY)
What's going on?
I like him SO much.
Yeah?
(STAMMERING)
Why do I feel so scared?
Because you've
always dated dummies
you weren't at risk
of actually liking.
Can we get a drink? No!
No, we can get one drink.
Stop it!
No, I...
What?
I've been dating
for fucking 90 years.
Something
always happens.
Why not this time
that I really care?
What do you think
is gonna happen'?
What if I forget
to flush the toilet,
and there's a
tampon in there?
Okay.
And not like a cute,
"Oh! lfs the last day."
Like, a real tampon.
I'm talking, like,
a crime scene tampon.
Like the Red Wedding,
Game of Thrones.
0h, my God!
It's like a Quentin
Tarantino, Django.
Like a real
motherfucker of a tampon.
There'; like,
an ear on it.
(LAUGHING)
You know what
I mean, though.
There's deal-breakers,
you know?
I know.
Why?
Hey, look who's here!
This does not
seem safe.
Hi! Whoa!
Oh, my God.
Always here.
Is Amy crying?
Yeah, she's in love.
Oh, with Steven?
No! No!
I love Steven.
He taught me this workout
to get me a beach bod.
You look amazing. TOM:
Thank you so much.
You'll be really
ripping it up.
(ALL CHEERING)
That was cool.
And there he is!
It's LeBron.
LeBron!
I'm LeBron James, and welcome
to the Big Apple Jam Fest.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
So, are you guys
ready to have some fun?
ALL: Yeah!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
The Knicks
City Dancers!
Whom!
They're just gyrating.
They're not.
No, no, no. These girls work really hard.
I treat them.
You treat them?
Yes, I do.
lwork with them.
They get bad injuries. I bet.
The pole isn't
always greased right.
You're gonna lose
us the right to vote!
How long is this?
I don't know.
I'm just asking.
Another hour, maybe.
Okay.
Whom!
Dr. Gunners.
Do you mind taking a
look at my ankle?
I think I rolled it.
Oh. Yeah. Yeah, sure.
I'll see you in a sec.
Hey!
Hey.
YOU were So great.
Everybody flipped out
when you came out here.
It was really cool to see.
Thank you.
Seriously,
what's the deal?
What's your
intentions?
My intentions?
Yeah, with my boy.
Like, what's your plan'?
Oh, I don't have
a plan with Aaron.
No, we've just been dating for six weeks.
We're just hanging out.
Okay.
Keeping it cazh.
So, you get butterflies
when you hear his name?
Excuse me?
When you're
looking at clouds,
do you see his face?
Do you hear
his name
when you listen
to the wind?
Um...
YES.
I really have to
ask you a question.
Don't hurt him.
AW: So we did it. Okay?
We fell hard for each other.
Welcome to the whitest
couple in America.
(SIGHS)
How did no one mug us that day?
Look at his hat.
Now we're kissing on a rock.
Do you know how
many homeless people
have taken a dump
on that rock?
Subway kissing? E w!
I love how tall he is.
Whoa! Easy, dude.
I'm a working man, too.
All right,
I get it.
Hey, Noam.
Hey, guys!
Whoa! Inside sex!
I'm digging that.
AMY: Even my dad likes him.
My dad doesn't like anyone.
He thought Mother Teresa
was M! oi shit.
That's my "Aaron 's apartment" toothbrush.
I have two toothbrushes.
I hope this love montage
ends like Jonestown.
Ooh! I think this is where
Woody Alien met Soon Vi.
Okay, e65'!-
That was a dare, okay?
I was dared to do that.
So what's up with you and Amy?
How's that going?
Amy? Things are
going awesome, man.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah. lfs going
real good.
I mean, I really,
really like her,
but she's got
some issues, you know'?
I mean, that's gonna happen.
AARON; Yeah.
Like, last night we
went out drinking.
You? Yeah, lwent out drinking.
And she...
I don't drink.
I got hammered.
And then she drank a lot,
but she barely got...
(SNEAKERS SQUEAKING)
But she didn't
get drunk at all.
You use
protection, right'?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. She's got
little bowls of condoms
all around
her apartment.
Condoms?
I'm not talking
about condoms.
I'm talking about
protection, like a lawyer.
Like a nondisclosure
agreement, you know'?
No penetration
without representation.
Yeah, you're right.
What happened?
Nothing, man.
Listen, I'll tell
you one thing.
You don't wanna
have a baby mama.
The next thing
you know,
you're paying
for a Ferrari.
You're getting her a big
house, a big mansion.
She's gonna want to
start a jumpsuit line,
and you're gonna
have to pay for it.
You wanna
go through that'?
You gotta convince
one of your friends
to say he's the dad
and raise the child.
Who wants to
go through that?
Kid end up
being 67",
your best friend only 5'2".
Mmm-hmm.
Eighteen years later,
the kid comes
and he writes
a book about you
saying how much of
a jackass you are.
Eighteen years, man.
18 years.
Your baby mama's car and
crib is bigger than his.
You could turn on
the TV any given Sunday.
Win the Super Bowl
and drive off in a Hyundai.
She was supposed to get the
shorty Tyco with your money.
Then she went to the doctor,
got Iipo with your money.
What are you
talking about?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
It's Kanye.
You're quoting
Kanye West to me?
You know what?
Amy's not like that.
Amy's not like that at all.
She's awesome.
And this is
gonna be great.
I think she's cool, and I don't
think I have to worry about that.
All right.
Oh!
Did you
let me do that?
Did I just score on you?
Yes! You are my bitch,
LeBron James!
But not really.
Not really.
You gotta admit, that was a good shot.
Come on, man.
I scored on
LeBron James.
I'm never playing
basketball again.
Lunch is on
you, buddy!
LEBRON: Where are
you going, Aaron?
AARON; Whoo!
Aaron?
Lemon .
Whom!
God damn it!
How's work?
Work's great,
actually.
I think I'm gonna
get that editorjob.
Aaron's been kind of pushing
me to think bigger.
Can I just
do this, please?
Aaron was telling me
about this acupuncturist.
She's supposedly amazing.
She helps a lot of his
patients with pain management.
I really want herto take a look at you.
Will you do that?
I have no desire
for an Oriental woman
to touch me
above the waist.
Don't say that.
That's disgust...
It's Asian.
Just say Asian.
Why does Aaron
all of a sudden
know everything
about everything?
He's a doctor.
He knows something.
He's a sports doctor. He's not
a real doctor, let's face it.
A real doctor
tries to cure diseases.
He's trying to get courtside
seats for the playoffs.
You're saying sports doctors
aren't real doctors?
Yeah. When they say, "What
do you wanna focus on?"
"I wanna focus on MS."
"What do you wanna focus on?"
"I wanna focus on cancer."
"What about you?"
"Whatever gets me closest
to men's locker rooms."
Okay.
"I want giant, athletic
penises close to my face,
"while I'm pretending
to look at their knees."
He's a good doctor,
and he does a lot with
Doctors Without Borders.
He's a great guy.
I'm not saying
he's not a good guy,
but he's got
about a month left
before you give
him the boot, right'?
What does that mean?
He's a reaction from the
muscle-bound Knucklehead,
so now you go for
the nerdy brainiac.
I know the way your
pattern works, Amy.
It's my pattern.
No, Dad,
lreallylike him.
I want you to be nice to him, and
I want you to take it seriously.
Will you do that'?
I think we have
a real shot.
That's great.
You sound like
a Lifetime movie.
One of the happy ones,
not the murder ones.
Don't you want
me to be happy? I mean...
You're building him up, and you're
gonna let yourself in for a big fail.
He's gonna
break your heart.
I'm leaving.
AMY: I'll talk to you later.
I'll tell Temembe
to come get you.
GORDON: Amy,
don't leave like this.
I don't like it when you don't
talk to me for a while.
Thank you so much
for doing this with me.
No, lwanna be
doing this with you.
Ifs the only one I've ever
done that we've framed.
WENDY: It looks great.
It seems like a
regional thing.
Girl!
Hey.
Hi.
Hey, I'm Aaron.
I'm Kim. So nice to meet you.
Ifs really nice
to meet you.
You're Tom? Pleasure
Hey, Amy.
How are you'?
Congrats on trapping my
sister with your seed.
Well, not all sex ends with a
ﬂush and a cry. (CHUCKLES)
Sometimes you get this. (LAUGHS)
That's killer.
KIM: Come on in!
I'll get you
guys a drink.
Anything that
you want.
I haven't been to a
baby shower in years.
We're so glad
you made it.
Yeah. Hey,
congratulations, man.
So I hear that you
work with athletes.
Yeah, I'm a physician
and a surgeon.
Mostly work with
the Knicks right now.
ALL: Ooh. TIM: That
sounds very cool.
Yeah, yeah.
And other athletes.
Really?
Like, which ones?
Specifically,
which athletes?
Uh... Tom Brady.
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Yeah.
Any other athletes
that you, uh, work with'?
Uh... Jay Cutler.
ALL: Whoa! Yeah, lwork with him.
Do you guys
follow tennis?
ALL: Yeah.
Roger Fewer.
Whoa!
Robert Griffin.
Chris Paul. CP3.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Alex Rodriguez.
Fuck that guy!
TOM: lagree.
KEVIN: Yeah.
KEVIN: Fuck him.
TOM: Piece of shit.
Clayton Kershaw.
ALL: on! (LAUGH)
Amy, he's great.
LISA: Yeah, where
did you find him?
(STAMMERS) Work.
Well, you two are
really cute together.
You two would have
the most perfect babies.
I could just eat you up.
You know'?
Yeah, it seems a little early
for this kind of talk.
It's not.
If anything,
it's late.
My life did not begin
until I had kids.
Your life has not begun.
Yeah, you know, I'm pretty
happy right now, so...
LISA: Aaron, do you
want a family?
Um... Yeah.
I think I'd like
to have two kids
by the time I'm
40 at least, right?
Yeah.
Oh, that's great.
Two is tight.
It's tight.
WENDY: If I were you,
I would start thinking
about having them
as soon as possible.
Just breathe. Just breathe.
It's fine.
He wants to have kids. Amy.
Right now. People
talk about that.
Not really.
It's fine.
I don't know anyone
that talks about that.
He's great.
It's normal.
I think Aaron's great.
I really like him.
Can you tell the members of
Heaven's Gate in there to relax?
No, he's too nice.
He's not too nice.
Yes, he is. He's too nice for me.
You know it.
No, Amy.
He's the perfect amount
of nice that you deserve.
Yeah, but there's deal-breakers
across the hoard with him.
Like the sex is good.
It's really good.
It's great, but it's not the
best I've ever had. You know?
Right. You don't want
best-sex-that-yowve- ever-had guy.
No, you wanna stay with the
best-yowve-ever-had guy.
No, you don't.
That's a creepy guy.
You don't wanna
be with that guy.
Best-sex-that-yowve-
ever-had guy is in jail.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
But I've been thinking about
maybe reaching outto him.
(LAUGHS) Stop.
Amy, breathe. It's fine.
He's great.
You're ridiculous.
ALLISTER: Mother.
I'm not ready for.“
lfl kiss the belly
hard enough,
will the baby feel it?
You wanna try?
I think that the
baby did feel it.
No.
Kim's great, man.
Oh, yeah. She's really awesome.
Kim's the best.
I'm glad I finally
got to meet her.
Yeah, and Amy's great,
too, by the way.
I just love her.
But keep her away
from those pro athletes.
You know what I mean?
(LAUGHING)
Wait, what does
that mean?
Um...
No. “was a 'yoke.
Like, that she'd
sleep with them.
I don't get
the joke angle.
No, not that
she would, but...
Those are the kinds
of jokes she tells.
Like, "I'm loose! I'm a
whore!" or whatever.
That's my
girlfriend.
No! I know.
It's not myjoke.
Those are the kind
of jokes she tells,
which I'm not
for at all.
I'm always like, "Don't
tell these kinds of jokes."
And then she does,
and I'm like,
"There she
goes again."
But I'm
just like...
Just forget
I said this.
Just drag that
one to the trash
and empty
the trash.
The game is “Skeletons
in the Closet."
Okay.
We all have
to admit things
we've never
told anyone before.
KAT: No! Wendy!
Yes!
Yes, we have to.
WENDY: We have to do it.
KAT: Okay, okay.
Sometimes, after
Kyle falls asleep,
I get up and eat Skinny
Cow ice cream pops.
No!
LISA: No, you don't.
You should be asleep!
I know! Sometimes
I have the whole box.
LISA; What?
That's like a whole regular-size ice
cream if you eat the whole box.
I know.
Your turn.
Okay. Um...
Last week, I let my
six-year-old watch Glee.
(ALL GASP)
LISA: I know. I know.
Too SOON!
KIM: That show is very racy.
There were some homosexual undertones.
I will say that.
There were two girls
kissing in this episode.
And I haven't even explained
to them what gay people are.
Uh, they're people.
Okay, okay.
Amy, your turn.
Um...
I don't know how I'm gonna follow these.
They were so good.
You guys are
really brave.
Thanks for trusting.
Um...
Onetime, I had
sex with this guy,
and we couldn't
find the condom.
So, three days later, I found out
it was attached to my cervix.
It had been kind of
pounded up there.
And so I googled
what do I do, right'?
So it said just
kind of bear down.
Just fish it out.
Make your finger a hook.
So I just hooked
my finger like this,
and then just
kind of beared down,
and just got it
out of there.
I let Tim and his brothers tag
team me on Christmas morning.
And you know what?
It was wonderful.
I like her.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
AMY: Hi.
Hi.
How are you'?
Can you come over?
No, Pm working.
Is this about
the baby shower'?
'Cause I'm sorry
I wasn't nicer
to The Real
Housewives of Hell.
No, it's fine. It's fine.
It's not about that.
What's up?
Um...
Dad died.
He was hoarding his medication
and his heart gave out.
Amy'?
Are you there?
NOAM: A little change? A penny?
A nickel? A ruble?
Crowdfund this.
Come on, help me out.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Thank you.
(STAMMERING)
I had a black boyfriend once.
Your mother
must be proud.
Yep.
And I'd
do it again.
AMY: (CLEARS THROAT)
Hello.
Thank you
for coming.
Gordon David Townsend.
Not that great of a guy.
He was
kind of racist,
and homophobic.
He was a drunk.
He once
apologized to me
for missing a
volleyball game
that he was at.
He had made signs
with my name on them.
When I was 11,
this kid,
Brandon Lipinsky...
Remember Brandon?
He stole my bike.
And he maybe was
just borrowing it,
but our dad
went over there
and beat the shit
out of Brandon's dad,
and his grandpa,
and Brandon.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
I bet he
personally offended
everyone here.
Right?
Raise your hand if our
dad ever offended you.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah.
He was an asshole.
When I asked him
to tell me the story
of how he proposed
to our mom,
his response was
"who?"
(ALL CHUCKLE)
I know he was joking,
he loved her
a lot. But...
He was really sick
for a really long time.
Which isn't fair
because I don't
think anyone else
was more alive than him
when he was younger.
He thought it was payback.
He thought it was karma.
And that's why
he got sick,
but I don't think so.
I think he was
the greatest dad.
He always made me
feel loved and important.
I know he fucked up.
(SHUDDERS)
I know he probably
hurt everyone here.
But raise your hand if he was
one of your favorite people.
He was my
favorite person.
Thank you.
You all right'?
This makes me wish they'd
found my father's remains.
Hey.
Mother, can we go
to La Poubelle now?
Yeah. Sure, honey.
How about a
piece of pizza'?
So Mom doesn't have to take
you to a French restaurant.
Pizza has
gluten in it.
Who gives a shit?
I'm sorry. I'm just kidding.
We're just...
I'll putAllister
in the car.
Can we have
one second?
I'm joking-
I'm not in the
mood today.
I'm not in the mood
for the jokes today.
Thoughtyowd be
in a great mood.
You don't have to pay for
Dad's nursing home anymore.
What are you doing?
What?
Don't push me
away today.
I'm pushing
you away?
YES.
You've been running away from
this fucking family forever.
Amy, lam not
a crazy person
because I got married,
and got pregnant
with a child.
That's what people do.
Why are you even here?
You didn't even like him.
I did everything.
You don't get to pretend
today like you gave a fuck.
I think that's
enough for today, Amy.
We ought to go.
Hey. Hey.
YOU Okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
You ready to go?
Yeah, let's go.
I just want you to know,
I really care about you, okay'?
And I love you.
Thank you.
What?
Are you seriously
saying that to me today?
You're gonna say
that to me, seriously,
for the first time
right now?
They're putting dirt on
my dad's body behind you.
Today is the day
you say that? Let's go.
Is that bad?
Yes, that's bad.
Bad timing.
Sorry about
that. Sorry.
Is this us?
We're way
down there.
Is this us?
No.
Can he pull up?
Do we have his number?
Is this us?
Sorry about
that. Sorry.
(sum-nus)
Hey.
How's it going,
sweetheart?
I'm getting by.
Mmm-hmm.
Thank you for coming the other day.
That was really nice.
I can't believe
he's gone.
I'm literally
just sitting here
waiting for him to call.
It feels like
a dream or something.
Are we still
talking about this?
That was
eight days ago.
I'm over it.
It was hard,
but I'm over it.
All right.
Best way to grieve...
Don't do it.
Don't.
Do not grieve?
No.
I've got good
news for you.
You know that story, that Mr.
Doctor Boring Sports Guy?
Well, I cut it.
I know you weren't in love
with that piece anyway.
No, no, no. I was very
in love with that.
I love that piece.
There's nothing happening.
There's no tension.
There's no sex appeal.
He's a bore.
Did you see the pictures?
We did a photo shoot.
Look at him.
Personally, I don't
like his odd bird face,
but we tried
everything.
We tried a ball.
He's supposed to
be a sports guy.
I don't think he'd ever
touched a ball before.
Not that kind, anyway.
And there he is. Look
at him standing there,
stiff as a scarecrow.
These guys,
they're hot, right'?
We even got him wet!
Would you fuck that?
Sure.
You would? I wouldn't
fuck that with your dick.
No. We decided
to go with
"Ugliest Celebrity
Kids Under 6."
Let's get this
done, Amy.
Orwe are not
talking promotion.
MMm-hmm.
Good girl.
Almost ready?
AMY: Yeah,
I need two seconds.
How you feeling about
Amar'e's surgery tomorrow?
I don't feel any
pressure at all, you know?
If it doesn't work, it's
just the end of his career.
But (CLICKS TONGUE)
I feel fine.
I can't breathe in this.
AARON: You look great.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Is that a formal dress?
Or what is it?
Yeah. It's like...
There's flowers on it.
It's shiny, kind of...
Is it too short?
No, no, no.
These people...
They're real conservative.
AMY: Okay, so...
It's like more gown...
Oh, yeah. A gown?
Do you want me to just
go into my gown closet?
No, no.
AMY: Would you grab my tiara?
It's right next to my pearls.
Forget I said anything.
I didn't mean anything.
I know nothing about fashion.
You look beautiful.
You're crazy hot.
Let's go.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
AARON: You look beautiful.
I look like a dickhead. Why didn't
you tell me this was so fancy?
Come on, it's nice. You look really nice.
I'm serious.
Congratulations.
Maybe we can talk a little
later about another charity.
Yeah. Yes, please.
Ifs Arnold,
from Somalia.
Good to see
you, Arnold.
Do we need a...
Right, tables.
Enjoy the day.
You've earned it.
Oh! Thank you,
buddy. Thanks.
Dr. Conners,
welcome.
Hi. How are you?
Do you mind if I grab you just for
a minute? To go over some things.
I'll be right
back, okay'?
Okay.
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine. Okay.
WAITER: Would you
like some more wine'?
AMY: Yeah,
thafd be great.
Hey, it's a luncheon.
It's wine.
I'll have some more.
(APPLAUSE)
TONY ROMO: Thank you.
Thanks, everyone.
Pm Tony Rome.
Soccer?
Football.
Tet! you what, 1 don't get
cheered in New York very often,
so this is a rare
treat for me this evening.
AMAR'E: Dallas suck!
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's Amafe Stoudemire
if you guys do not know.
He's been following
me around all week.
Anyway, we're here today to talk
about our esteemed recipient.
No athlete wants to
go under the knife,
but when you do, you feel
comfortable with Dr. Conners.
He's not just changing
professional athletes
and the way they
look at medicine,
he's also changing the world.
And he's helping everybody.
From pandemics,
to war-tom regions,
to extreme
poverty situations,
they fee! safe in his hands.
To our MVP and
to my good friend,
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
Dr. Aaron Conners.
Good luck.
AARON: Hey,
look at this.
Look at this. Very nice.
Very nice of you guys.
It's very sharp.
I'll be doing the surgery
tomorrow with this, Amar'e.
And, remember, don't eat
anything after midnight.
I'm hungry!
But I really...
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
I really want to thank the actual
heroes from Doctors Without Borders.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
Sorry.
Mark Twain said, "Be careful
about reading health books.
“You may die of a misprint. “
(RINGING)
Shit.
Hello?
DIANNA: Amy, it's Dianna.
Hi, Dianna.
We really need to talk.
Actually, it's a really bad time.
Is there any chance...
No, I don't want to
hear that It's a bad time.
Yeah, but maybe
in an hour?
You can be replaced within
the hour by 90 other girls,
who graduated from places better
than whatever state school
you blew your way through.
(SIGHS)
I'm stepping out.
Thank you very much.
For fucks sake!
AARON; Um...
This...
This organization came
into my fife at a time
when I was looking to
truly make a difference.
DIANNA: Which of these
can we live without?
"We Forgive You,
Lance Armstrong“,
“The inventor of the
Pussy Magnet“, Mmm-hmm.
and “Are you Gay or
is She Just Boring?"
What do you think?
(SIGHS)
...is a family.
And it's a family that I'm very,
very happy to be a pan' of.
Thank you guys very much.
R's very nice of you.
Thank you.
Hey!
Hey. I was just
coming in to watch you.
Yeah,
you missed it.
Shit. I got a phone call.
How'd it go?
Look, Amy, I know you're going
through a lot right now,
(STAMMERING) but I really
needed you in there.
Instead, you're out here,
smoking weed.
No, I didn't come out here to smoke pot.
I came out because...
Because Dianna called.
Amy, I really, really
needed you out there.
You were my lifeline.
You knew that.
I really can't take you seriously
when you're holding that.
Why did you carry
your award out here'?
You don't have
to carry it around
like Anne Hathaway
at an Oscar party.
Can you put it down?
So I can...
That's crazy, Amy.
You knew I wanted to
do that speech to you!
(SIGHS) Yeah,
I'm so sorry.
I really didn't
want to miss it,
but I'm afraid I'm gonna
lose my job right now.
But it doesn't matter!
You shouldn't
have your phone on
in the middle of
my speech anyway.
That was just so
disrespectful, Amy.
All right, goodbye.
No, Amy! Whoa, whoa, whoa! What
are you talking about, "goodbye"?
What? I'm leaving!
We're fighting. We're not
gonna talk for a while.
That's how this works.
What are you
talking about?
No! We're just
having a fight.
What are we doing?
What do you want?
Why are you with me?
I love you.
WhY do you keep
Saying that?
Because I mean it! I love you!
I'm crazy about you!
What do you
want me to say?
We're just having a fight.
You insulted me,
and we'll talk about it,
and we'll work through it.
What's wrong with you
that you want to be with me?
I'm a drinker.
I don't care!
I've been with
a lot of guys.
I don't care!
How many?
I don't know.
How many girls
have you slept with?
I've slept with
three women.
Me, tOO.
I have slept with
three women, too.
How many guys?
What, this year?
This year?
Fuck this. I'm not
talking about this.
Come on. Don't say "fuck this."
Don't follow me.
Amy!
I'm tired.
Iwanna go to sleep.
You can go to your apartment.
It's nicer than mine.
No. Look, my parents had a
saying, "Don't go to bed angry."
We're angry, let's resolve this.
Okay?
Your parents
weren't that happy.
They're very haPPY-
Fine. You wanna
talk about it?
You want to get into it? Yes!
Let's get into all of it right now.
Yes, please.
Okay, let's do it.
Okay.
I'll start.
You go down
on me too much.
What?
Yeah.
It's selfish.
No, it is actually selfish,
because you act...
Don't look
like I'm crazy.
You act like
it's for me,
but really, it's just to
show how great you are.
Like, you're always
helping people.
So I shouldn't go
down on you as much?
Don't try and
spin this as a way
to not go down
on me as much.
That's ridiculous.
Of course, I want you to
go down on me that much.
So take it
down a notch?
No, keep going
down on me.
Forget this whole part
of the argument, okay'?
Forget that.
I'm so glad
you apologized.
I didn't apologize!
Wow!
I did not
apologize.
Are you serious
right now?
I've been through
a lot this year,
and of course I'm gonna have
some ups and downs,
but that's why I need
to stop and then say,
"Am I gonnajust
follow the river
"or am I gonna make
decisions in my..."
You're sleeping!
You were just asleep.
No, lwasn't.
Okay, good.
Because I am not even close to done.
Okay.
I have a lot of thoughts and I'm
thinking very clearly right now.
I'm so glad that I feel comfortable
enough with you to talk like this.
This is the time
when you have to look
at yourself and say...
(SNORING)
"Am I living the
best life I could?"
"Am I the best
version of myself
"that I could
possibly be?"
That's why I need
to stop and then say,
"Am I gonna just follow the
river or am I gonna..."
Wake up, Aaron!
You're totally sleeping!
Mmm-mm.
You said we were
gonna stay up
until we figure it out,
like your parents.
I'm listening.
AMY: What did I just say?
You said, "Wake up."
Amar'e.
What's up, Doc'?
How you feeling, buddy? Good.
You ready to do this? Yeah.
We're gonna do this.
It's gonna be great.
AWGSOMG.
You met Rachel?
Yes.
We've been acquainted.
Okay. What do we have here?
This is just a little more
sedative to relax you.
Hey, the good stuff.
Yeah.
Okay. Oh, whoa!
All right, buddy.
Okay. So, we're gonna be replacing
your cruciate ligament.
And, um...
Uh, do you want a coffee?
Hey, could we get a coffee?
I can't. I'm not supposed
to drink before...
Right. Don't
worry about it.
Just one coffee,
for me. Um...
Are you okay, Doc?
Me? I'm great.
I'm great. Yeah.
Me and Amy got into
a little bit of an argument,
but I think
I'm doing okay.
Yeah, this is gonna
go really well.
She really lit
into me last night.
Wow.
AARON: Like really...
A side of her I've
never seen before.
It got dark, fast.
It really fucked me up.
Are you sure
you're okay?
AARON: I'm good' I'm good.
We're gonna
get this going.
AMAR'E: Okay. Perfect.
(CLATTERING)
I'm gonna mark the knee that we're
gonna do the surgery on, all right?
Doc, this is the
wrong knee.
I'm marking this as
not the knee to do.
This is not the knee.
Not this knee.
Are you sure
you're okay, Doc?
Amar'e, I'm great.
This is gonna go great. This is the
bad boy we're gonna split open.
You know what?
This is a bad idea.
Amar'e, you're nervous.
Everyone gets nervous.
I don't think
you get it, Doc.
We need to
reschedule this.
AARON: No, no, no.
We're not doing that. I'm gonna
get you back out on the court.
We gotta get you
back out on the court.
I wanna see you
play. Okay?
I'm here for you, okay?
You're nervous,
I'm nervous.
Amy was acting like
a psycho last night.
I don't know what I did.
I really,
really like her,
but she's like
a fucking demon.
She's like the
fucking Exorcist.
I said, "You gotta let me go to sleep.
I have a surgery."
And you know what she said?
She said,
(MIMICKING DEMONIC VOICE)
"NO!"
I'm taking a rain check.
No, no, no.
I'm out of here.
(SPITTING)
(HEART MONITOR FLATLINES)
Hey, Amar'e.
Mr. Stoudemire,
where are you going?
I've gotta get out of here.
RACHEL: Amar'e!
Watch your head.
Oh!
(THUDDING)
(METALLIC CLATTERING)
Oh, Shit!
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey.
AARON: Hey.
How'd it go'?
Have you just been watching
TV and smoking pot all day?
No. I got up and
had some cereal.
At some point.
They canceled
my surgery today.
Amar'e didn't feel comfortable
with me performing it
because I was
too tired,
so he fled.
He was on a lot
of anesthesia. He fell.
And when ltried to help
him, he called me a witch.
Is he okay?
You know, and itwas because
of all this shit last night.
Which was crazy.
“Was bad.
Yeah.
You know, I've been
thinking about all that
and I was walking
over here,
and I was just thinking, maybe...
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Can I say something?
(STAMMERS) It does bother
me that you smoke pot,
and that you
drink a lot,
and I do care that you
slept with a lot of guys.
It makes me feel
unsafe or something.
Okay, yeah.
Yeah, you should be with a
girl who you feel safe with.
That's not what I'm saying.
Ifs very clear. That's fine.
It's obvious.
You should be with one
of those cheerleaders.
Amy, that's not
what I'm saying.
Just go be with
that kind of girl.
A little Texan with
huge hair and big tits.
And then, when
you get married,
she wants to be
more conservative,
so shejust gets
smaller fake tits put in,
but they still
look amazing.
The thing about
cheerleaders is that
they bring
people together
and they make
people happy.
Unlike you and your
friends at your magazine
who sit there and judge
people from afar
because if you don't try,
then you can't fail.
That's why you're
threatened by cheerleaders.
That's me.
You really got me.
(SIGHS)
All right.
You know what, Amy'?
Um...
You know what?
We're...
I have to do the
surgery in two days.
Let's just take
those two days off.
And then...
I'll do the surgery and then we'll
come back and we'll work this out.
I think you're right.
That's good.
I know we're
done here.
"We're done"? What are
you talking about?
Amy, that's not
what I'm saying.
And you know what?
It's fine.
It's not fine. lfs
fine that we're done.
Because don't need to
talk to you anymore,
because the
interview is over.
Because your
article got canceled.
My boss said you
were too boring.
(CHUCKLES)
All right.
You win.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey.
How you doing?
So great.
It's fun, right'?
This is the best.
I love this.
So, are you gonna work at the
magazine after the internship?
Honestly?
Yeah.
Probably not.
Why? You're so good
and you have energy.
Yeah, I know,
but being around
all these photographs,
I think I wanna
do photography.
Yeah, I can see that for you.
Pictures and...
I love that stuff, like the
photo shoots for... Yeah.
BARTENDER: Hey!
Last call for alcohol!
I gotta get
out of here.
Oh. You wanna
get out of here?
Yeah, okay.
Let's go.
Okay.
(GLASSES CLINK)
Cool.
Shit, Donald.
Ifs so nice to hang with
you outside the office.
This is great.
I really like you.
You're great.
(MOANING SOFTLY)
Okay, maybe let's
next-phase it up, you know?
Okay.
I know just
what you mean.
Ooh.
Oh!
Hey.
When did you
get here?
Yeah, let's get
that going.
(DONALD MOANS SOFTLY)
Shit.
Yeah. Shit!
Just feel me.
Feel me.
Okay.
You like that?
Grab my tits.
Grab them,
feel them.
I feel like I'm the
one with the tits
in the equation,
but this is cool.
You wanna lick them?
You wanna lick them? Yes, you do.
You wanna lick them.
Are you there?
Yeah.
Now I'm there.
Yeah, suckle it.
(MOANING)
Shit.
I don't have
a good angle.
What?
DONALD: Youlejust gonna stay
really still for me, okay?
Stay really still. Yeah?
What is that?
(MOANS)
(SNORTING)
Ah!
Yeah.
What is that?
It's Adderall.
I have ADHD,
so it just helps me
with my education.
ANN: Oh, Okay.
Okay, this so great, but...
Cradle my bunch!
Your what?
Cradle my bonch!
I'm gonna take a rain
check, but how about...
You wanna get on top?
You wanna take charge, Daddy?
You wanna take
charge, Daddy?
I think it's
Mama's turn.
Sure, Daddy.
DONALD; Yeah.
All right,
this is great.
I just want
you to know
my safe word
is "pineapple."
All right. Got it.
(MOANING)
AMY: Okay.
Hit me.
Hit you?
Yeah, lwantyou
to hit me.
Okay.
Are you serious?
In the face!
Hit me!
I'm hitting you!
Hit me hard.
Oh! Fucking
do it already!
Hit me!
I'm hitting you!
Why don't you take a little
arthritis medication
and then try again?
You pathetic
childless MILF.
Hit me like this!
Ow!
(GRUNTS)
Fuck!
Shit!
Pineapple! Pineapple!
Donny, what's going
on back here?
Mommy!
"Mommy"?
Mommy, my 9Y3-
He is 16 years old!
Fuck!
So,
you had
quite a night.
I'm So...
Am?-
Listen, we've
all been there.
0h, yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
I once fucked three-quarters
of Pink Floyd.
Yeah.
Dark side of
all their moons.
Am?-
You're a very
strong writer.
I will go so far
as to say
that you are my
most valuable writer.
Thank you.
I reread your latest draft of the Dr.
Conners piece,
and I have to confess,
I spoke too soon.
It is very good.
Really?
It really is.
Yeah, it's very good.
Thank you. You won't
regretthis, Dianna.
I know you said, don't...
I won't regret what?
I'm not gonna
publish it here.
No, no, no.
Amy, you're fired.
Amy, how could
you not get that'?
You are so fired.
My love, I can't have
one of my employees
having sex with
someone underage
and beating them up.
You know? One or the other,
but not the combo.
See what I'm saying?
Hey, Dianna,
we just, um...
Oh...
You're
doing it now'?
Sorry. Should we come back,
or did it already happen?
Everyone knows?
Did what
already happen'?
Amy fucked Donald.
Amy... I didn't fuck Donald.
I tried...
You tried?
He's 16.
0h, my God!
Can you get out,
you guys'? Go, please.
BRYSON: His safe
word is "pineapple."
Fuck you!
Fuck you, Schultz!
Can you go? You want to line
up the winners you fucked?
Hey, congrats. Nice.
AMY: The girl you fucked
while she was quarantined
for we don't even know what.
I'm sorry about that.
That's so inappropriate.
Anyway, nice news. I know
you're close with Nikki.
She got the
Executive Editor position.
Oh, that's great.
NIKKI: Thanks, Amy.
That means the world.
Although, I can
turn down the position
if you want me to.
AMY: Okay, yeah.
Please don't take it.
I'm serious.
I'm kidding.
NIKKI: You're funny.
Congratulations.
You scared me.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
She's great.
I mean she's...
She looks
like an idiot.
Okay.
Go.
I'll go.
(WHISPERING)
Amar'e. Hey, buddy.
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
How'd we do?
We did great.
You get some sleep.
Did it go
Tom Brady good?
It went better
than Brady good.
Have you seen
his wife, Gisele?
Yeah, I have.
She's hot.
Look, you're on a
lot of medication right now,
so why don't you just
gel some sleep, all right?
Isn't she like a
Victoria's Secret model?
I don't know.
I think so. Yeah.
I'm gonna be right here.
I'm gonna be on this floor.
So, if you need anything,
you let me know, okay?
I follow her
on lnstagram.
Okay.
You should go to sleep.
Okay, buddy?
Oh!
AARON: Are we
gonna do this again?
All right.
Yeah.
AMAR'E: I love you.
AARON: Oh, I love you too, man.
It went great.
(SNORING)
AARON: Okay.
Okay.
And he's asleep.
(DOG WHIMPERING
OVER TELEVISION)
Everybody's left
a dog in a hot car
at some point
in their lives.
I don't think
that's true.
I trust you with
my hot doggie.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
LEBRON: Hey, Aaron, this is LeBron.
I'm at the gym, man.
I think I pulled something.
You pulled something?
You need to come down.
It hurts like a mother.
Yeah, hey.
I'll be right over.
Hurry up! Just sit tight,
LeBron!
Hey.
YOU Okay?
I'm not okay, Aaron.
I'm concerned about you.
So you're not hurt?
LEBRONI No.
This is your intervention.
What? My intervention?
For what?
You ruined
things with Amy.
This is aboutAmy?
LEBRON: You've
been so sad lately.
It's scaring me.
BRODERICK: Aaron.
We're concerned about you.
You've helped us, and now
we're gonna help you.
Come on, man.
Sit down.
MARV:
It started and it is on.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Did I miss
anything?
Now, I know that relationships
can be terrifying,
but you don't just bail out
at the first sign of trouble.
It's obvious.
Aaron, choking
under intense pressure.
I did not choke, Marv.
Look, if he's not happy and she's
not the right one for him,
then, obviously,
it's just not meant to be.
Sometimes, the right person happens
to be sitting right in front of you.
Chris Evert
hitting on Aaron hard.
LEBRON: Chris,
don't hit on Aaron.
LeBron, don't be
a cock-blocker.
Evert is still
at it and, frankly,
it's making me
uncomfortable.
BRODERICK: You know what
I think the issue might be?
You're probably focusing
on her problems
instead of looking
in the mirror.
Aaron is playing
the blame game.
Thank you, Marv.
BRODERICK: I bet you're
not the easiest person
to have a relationship with.
Broderick, cutting
deep with his insights.
He is on fire.
His best work
since WarGames.
AARON: You guys
don't understand.
I tried. She didn't
want to be a part of it.
You can't just run
when you get scared.
AARON: She pushed me away.
Aaron is fearing
engulfment and intimacy.
You know what?
You're not helpful, you're not
helpful, you're not helpful.
And you are really not helpful, Marv.
Really not helpful!
Marv Albert apologizes.
Bye.
LEBRQN: Aaron.
AARON". Goodbye, Lemon.
LEBRON: Aaron!
I thought you said he
would look at my hip.
Yeah, if things
would've went better.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Hi.
Hey.
KIM: This isn't working
for you anymore.
I know.
I'm sorry.
I know you're sorry.
No.
No, I'm really sorry.
I want you to know that I act
like everything
you do in your life
is so wrong and stupid.
But it's just because I don't
think that I can have that.
I'm not okay.
I'm not okay, Kim.
I know what I am,
I know who I am,
and I'm broken.
Mother, Dad needs you.
KIM: We're talking
right now. What's going on'?
I don't know,
he's just yelling.
KIM: Okay. Is it okay?
Yeah.
What you got there?
My drawings
for Minecrafl.
For what?
Minecraft.
It's a game where you can
build a whole virtual world,
and put whatever
you want in it,
and make it big or
small or whatever.
Let me see.
Yeah.
AMY: If it's a video game,
why is it in a notebook?
Oh, I draw it out
first to plan it,
so I know what to build
and what to put in it
instead of just
winging it.
What's this?
Oh, this is our house.
Here's my bedroom,
here's the baby's room.
What's that rectangle?
It's the mattress for you and Aaron
to stay in once the baby's born.
That's for me?
You and Aaron. Yeah.
That's really cool,
Allister.
Thank you.
But you know what?
I don't think
Aaron's gonna be
around much anymore.
So...
Oh. You don't
like him anymore.
I like him more
than anybody.
He's my best friend.
Then we should
have him come over.
Yeah. Yeah.
We should.
The baby's
room is pink.
It's a girl?
It's a girl!
(LAUGHING)
That's amazing.
Congrats.
That's so cool.
No, it's not.
Ifs not. It's the worst
thing in the world.
It really sucks.
She's doomed.
No, she'll be fine.
She's got us.
She'll be fine.
I miss Dad, too.
I know that.
Come here.
AMY: I got you.
(KIM AND AMY LAUGHING)
AMY: I'm uncomfortable.
(ALL LAUGHING)
KIM: Receive.
Receive the love.
Get out of here!
Too much intimacy.
Love overload.
I'm exiting this hug.
NOAM: Urban Outfitter,
help me out.
AMY: Hey, Noam.
NOAM: What's up, Amy?
AMY: A gift.
Booze, pot, drugs,
and a place to live!
Amy, you are
the best.
You got it, man.
Oh, God, I gotta
give you something.
How about a reach-around?
No, it's okay.
Oh, I don't need a reach-around.
Thanks, man.
"The most important play of the
season is about to take place
"and there isn't a scoreboard,
fan, or cheerleader in sight.
“The man on the spot
is Aaron Gunners.
“And his arena
is a silent, antiseptic
“operating room on
a Tuesday morning
“where he's about to sew
Amara Stoudemirefs
"battered $20 million
knee together.
“Time is ticking.
“Pressure builds
and he goes for it.
“I, on the other hand,
just woke up.
"Still drunk with dried
cheese under my fingernails
“leading me to believe
that I ordered fries
“before passing
out on the ﬂoor.“
“Life hurts.
“But spending time
with Dr. Conners
"showed me that you
can't play scared.
"And maybe every
drunken night,
"accidental ride on
the Staten Island Ferry
"and awkward sexual encounter
were just practice for this...
“The main event.“
MARV: Since the beginning
of training camp,
Knick fans have wondered
when do they get back
their number one'?
Well) the answer is tonight.
Amar'e Stoudemire is back
in action for the Knicks.
Hi, everybody.
I'm Marv Albert
and welcome to sold-out
Madison Square Garden
where Knicks fans are
holding their breath
to see if Amafe Stoudemirew
surgically repaired knee
will bring new hope
as they tip off another season
looking to get back
into the playoff picture.
It's the Knicks and the Nets,
coming up next.
How you doing, man?
You doing good?
I'm gonna ask
you a question.
How are you feeling?
How's the knee feeling?
Feels good.
Feels great.
Ifs okay?
It's awesome.
Taxi!
What is going on?
MARV: Amafe Stoudemire
is checking in.
And it is a standing ovation.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING) ANNOUNCER:
Introducing, for the Knicks
number one...
Amare Stoudemire.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
Why are we stopped?
Sometimes on these
short trains, you know,
it doesn't touch
that third rail.
You know, where
the electricity is?
So the red
signal comes on
and the power
just shuts off.
Really?
No, not really.
I don't fucking know.
Do I look like
I work for MTA?
I don't know.
What, I got MetroCards
in my fucking purse now?
What the fuck, man?
You ask me
some stupid shit.
I'm sorry.
I don't work here.
Don't lean into me.
MARV: Pierce,
off the drive.
It is blocked by Stoudemire!
And he comes up with the ball.
Under four to play
here in the first.
Smith. Finding Stoudemire!
Beautiful play!
That gets the crowd going.
Hey , Dr. Sonnets.
Oh. Hey.
Amar'e looked
great tonight.
Yeah, he did.
I'm happy for him.
Actually, he's
looking for you.
He said to meet
him out on court.
On court?
Yeah.
Right now?
Right now.
Okay.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Amy?
You're really good!
(UPTOWN GIRL PLAYING)
Hey.
(MOUTHING)
Come here.
Hey.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
No, no, no. I'm sorry. No.
You were really,
really good.
As it turns out, lam in
terrible physical shape.
Yeah, I saw that.
Could you see that'?
I am sweating more than
I am proud of. Yeah.
No, no. I know. Hey.
What?
I really missed you.
I missed you.
(SONG CHANGES)
Oh, shit. I have
to dance more.
What?
Amy, you really
don't need to do that.
Why is there a mat?
Oh, shit. These guys.
Jeez!
AARON'. No.
No, no, no.
Amy! Amy!
Bad idea!
AARON: Honey!
Honey! No! No!
No! Amy!
No!
(MUSIC STOPS)
Amy? Amy? Amy.
Honey. You okay?
(GASPS)
Did I get it?
Did you get
the basket?
Did n go m?
Oh, of course not.
You didn't get
enough height.
No?
No.
I thought I got
a lot of height.
No, no. Zero height.
No height, huh'?
Usually when people hit
trampolines they go high,
but, for some reason,
you went down.
You went straight
down. Hard.
I really wanted
to impress you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I wanted to show
you loan work hard
and put myself
out there, you know'?
I got that.
And not be
afraid to fail.
No. I got the metaphor.
'Cause with the dance,
I wanted to show you us.
Yeah, I got the metaphor.
It's like I really wanna try.
Yeah.
I wanna try with you.
I wanna try, too.
I love you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I love you, too, Amy.
CHEERLEADERS: Aw!
(ALL CHEERING)