Retailrip and sync by:
- RuBricK -
www.NorSub.com
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
BECCA: What would you do
to save someone you love?
For Edward, l would stop at nothing.
(GASPS )
What is he doing?
Edward!
Edward? Where?
Oh, my God! There he is!
Edward, we Iove you, you're the best!
No, Jacob's the best!
(GROANS )
(ALL YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
He's exposing himseIf!
(BOTTLE SHATTERING)
No! No.
Edward!
(HISSING)
-(GASPS )
-(SNARLS )
(SCREAMING)
BECCA: Let me start from the beginning.
l used to live with my mom in Nevada.
But now she's always on the road,
because she started doing some pro golfer.
So, l came here to the foggy town
of Sporks, Washington.
Population.: 3, 120.
(GASPING)
(SNARLS )
Holy shit!
Make that 3, 1 19.
Anyway, l came here
to live with my dad, Frank.
He's the town sheriff.
I haven't seen you in a whiIe.
Your hair's Ionger.
I grew it out.
I guess it's hard for me to accept
my IittIe girI's growing up.
I mean, Iook at the size of those tits.
-Dad!
-What?
(SCOFFS )
(MYPANTlES PLAYING)
l feel so lonely
Nobody gets me
l am so unhappy
Why can't l find
a cool alternative boyfriend?
BECCA: There is something strange
about this town.
l couldn't put my finger on it.
(SNARLS )
l used to live here when l was younger.
But l haven't been back in a long time.
I kept your room just as you Ieft it.
(LULLABY CHIMING)
Great.
Remember your hamster, Herman?
Might have missed a coupIe of feedings.
You couId pIay with your doIIies.
BECCA: I don't think so.
What's that?
It's been IoneIy since your mom Ieft.
(CAR HONKING)
Oh, hey.
You wanna come downstairs?
Some peopIe are excited to see you.
Who wants their pacie?
Good girI.
Dad, I'm a teenager.
Right.
I guess I'd better get you
some new stuff then.
BECCA: Frank didn't get me.
l wasn't his little girl anymore.
-(EX CLAIMS )
-(THUDDING)
Becca, you remember Bobby White.
BECCA: Yeah.
You're Iooking good.
Good? I'm in a wheeIchair.
I can't feeI anything beIow my waist.
You know what's beIow my waist?
My penis!
Sorry.
We're aII gIad you're here,
especiaIIy your dad.
He wouIdn't shut up about you.
CarefuI there, Bob,
I'm gonna roII you down the hiII.
Oh, boy, I'm reaI scared. Bring it on.
(CHUCKLING)
Boy, here we go!
You're in troubIe there, mister!
Oh! Oh!
-Hi. I'm Jacob.
-Hi.
(BOBBY GRUNTING)
We used to make mud pies together.
(CHUCKLES )
PIay doctor?
Oh, right, right.
(FRANK GROANS )
I remember now.
I gave you a prostate exam.
So, are we going to be
at the same schooI?
I go to schooI on the reservation.
It must be fun to drink and gambIe aII day.
Too bad we're not gonna be
at schooI together.
It'd be nice to know at Ieast one person.
(GRUNTING CONTINUES )
(CHUCKLING)
Got you a weIcome home present.
What do you think?
I think that you're trying to buy
my affection with that piece-of-shit truck
to make up for the years
that you negIected me as a father.
ToId you she'd Iike it.
(CHUCKLING) That's great.
-I fixed up the engine myseIf.
-Thanks, Jacob.
Go ahead, hop in.
(GROANS )
Okay. So you gotta pump the gas
to start her up.
(SNIFFING) Damn fIeas.
(SIGHING CONTENTEDLY)
Jacob, your foot.
Ever since puberty,
I've been feeIing a IittIe different.
(CAT MEWING)
Cat!
(JACOB BARKING)
JACOB: Come here, cat!
Come here!
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
BECCA: Transferring to a school
that's already in session.
Being the new kid is never easy.
Nice cIothes.
StiII shopping in the boys' section?
Give her a break. That's what
I used to wear when I was a virgin.
Where'd you get that haircut,
"Fantastic Lesbians"?
(BECCA GRUNTING)
DERRIC: Hey, new kid!
(BECCA GROANS )
-Hi, I'm Derric.
-I'm Becca.
I'm the eyes and ears of this pIace.
I can hook you up with anything you need.
Cheat sheets, human growth hormone,
harvested organs.
(BEATING)
No, thanks.
Oh, I get it. You're one of those
antisociaI, Iong-suffering Ioner types.
ActuaIIy, I'm more of the humorIess type.
Kind of a sourpuss, reaIIy.
FuII of insecurities,
with no great personaIity,
yet every hot guy finds me irresistibIe.
You must be Becca. I'm Rick.
Damn, girI, you seem
reaIIy boring and frigid.
You want to go to the prom with me?
See?
I'm Jennifer, future prom queen.
I'm gonna pretend to be your BFF,
but if you touch Rick's wang,
I'II cut you.
(RICK SIGHS )
Who are they?
Oh! Those are the SuIIens.
They're, Iike, aII adopted by Dr. CarIton,
so they're not bioIogicaIIy-reIated,
but they're reaIIy, reaIIy cIose.
They moved here a few years ago,
and they're, Iike, super-weird.
It's a totaI mystery.
Their skin is ice-coId,
they feed on human fIesh,
and they aII sIeep in coffins.
Maybe they're Canadian.
-Oh!
And who's that?
-Snooki, JWOWW, DJ PauIy D...
-No.
Not the douchebags
from the Jersey Shore.
Him.
The reaIIy paIe dude with big hair
and constipated Iook.
(CLEARING THROAT) Edward SuIIen.
(GIGGLING) He's a compIete hottie.
But, evidentIy, no one here is worthy.
He wouIdn't even accept me
as his Facebook friend.
BECCA: "Favorite activity.
"Searching for a souI which has
been cast into eternaI damnation"?
But I don't care about Edward.
I've got another guy on the side. Yeah.
SadIy, he went off
to fight in Iraq for a year.
But we write to each other aII the time.
His name is John.
JENNIFER: "Dear John,
two weeks together.
"That's all it took to fall in love with you.
"And in those two weeks, you did things
to me no guy had ever done before.
"l still can't ride a bicycle. "
Are you, Iike, even Iistening?
(SCOFFS )
Oh! You guys are having, Iike,
an instant connection.
How can you teII?
Duh. Hardwicke 101?
You're both staring at each other
in sIow motion,
which aIthough cheesy and obvious,
it underscores your respective yearnings.
Oh!
Right.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(RETCHING)
Ah! Becca.
Why don't you take the empty seat
next to that mysterious boy
you're destined to have
a fataIistic reIationship with
that wiII spawn four books
and a movie franchise?
(SNIFFING)
(EXHALING)
Do I smeII?
Yeah. Like tuna.
Lunch.
(AIR HISSING)
I'm Becca.
I'm Edward.
So you're new to Sporks.
How do you Iike the weather?
I don't Iike coId, wet things.
So you must hate SIurpees.
(SLURPING)
I'm just trying to figure you out.
AII right, cIass.
Turn to page 63 in your books.
(STUTTERS )
This is bioIogy.
Why are we reading The Vampire Diaries?
In the '80s, coke was aII the rage.
The '90s, grunge.
Now it's the era of vampires.
It's just super-trendy.
That's amazing.
(GURGLING)
(GURGLING CONTINUES )
(BABY CRYING)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(CLANGING)
Oh!
Hi. (GASPS )
Why aren't you wearing a shirt?
I work part-time at Abercrombie & Fitch.
It's aIways the same inane questions.
"Who are you?" "Why are you doing this?"
"Are you a naturaI redhead?"
-Yeah.
-Oh, that's hot.
I got a serious case of the munchies.
And I think you know what I need to eat.
Cheetos?
Oh, heII, yeah.
Thanks, dawg. You a'ight with me.
(ANTOINE LAUGHING) Whoo!
Uh...
-Antoine?
-What?
The kiIIing.
(GASPING)
Oh!
Right. My fauIt.
You know who we are, don't you?
(SNARLING)
Yes.
You're the BIack Eyed Peas!
Come on. Not again.
Why does everyone aIways think
we're the BIack Eyed Peas?
I mean, her, I get. I get it.
She Iooks just Iike Fergie.
And he Iooks Iike WiII.i. am,
but, Jesus Christ, they don't even
have a white guy in their band!
(SNARLING)
Ow!
-He hit me!
-SCULLEY: That's right!
Mixed martiaI arts, Tae Bo,
and YogaIates created this!
Huh?
(GROANS )
How you Iike that, pretty boy?
(SCREAMING)
(DISTORTED LAUGHTER)
Get him off me! Get him off me!
Now the eIbow!
SCULLEY: Son of a bitch!
I am not afraid of you!
You shouId be.
(SCULLEY YELLING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(EX CLAIMS )
(GASPING)
(NECK CRACKING)
(GROANS )
(YELLING)
Damn that overwrought
unrequited teenage Iove.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
BECCA: l couldn't stop thinking
about Edward Sullen.
No mortal could have
had the strength to do that.
Or possess such amazing dexterity.
He can't be human.
(EXHALING)
GOSSIP GIRL: Meanwhile, uptown,
Blair was getting cozy with Nate,
who was secretly crushing on Serena.
BECCA: Excuse me,
but you're interrupting my narration.
GOSSIP GIRL: Oh, shit! Wrong show!
X-O-X-O, Gossip Girl.
-JACOB: Becca!
-(GASPING) Jacob.
I heard about the accident. Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I got you these.
(CHUCKLES )
Thanks, Jacob.
You're so sweet and thoughtfuI.
Any girI wouId be Iucky to have you.
Just not me, of course.
You're Iike my IittIe gay brother.
I heard you were hanging out
with Edward SuIIen.
Stay away from him. There's just
something reaIIy odd about that guy.
FRANK: Becca!
I'd better go.
Hey, sweetheart. There you are.
There was a kiIIing today.
Fisherman ScuIIey, by the docks.
The bIood was drained from his body
and he had muItipIe bite wounds
aII over his neck.
You know what that means?
The Kardashians are in town.
(GASPING)
Here.
I want you to have this.
-Mace?
-You're my IittIe girI,
and there's a kiIIer on the Ioose.
I'm not gonna Ieave
untiI I know you can protect yourseIf.
Now, I'm going to come at you,
and I want you to mace me.
-Dad...
-Honey, I've been trained for this, okay?
Here I come.
(YELLING)
Good God!
God damn it!
(YELLING CONTINUES )
It's so painfuI! It burns!
-Sorry, Dad.
-No! I'm proud of you.
Are you okay?
Mace wiII onIy temporariIy stop
your attacker.
You have to hit a man
where he breathes, Becca.
(BECCA GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(SHUDDERING)
(IN HIGH-PITCHED TONE) You got
the franks and beans there. Good for you.
But I'm stiII coming at you.
Rip off the moustache, sweetheart.
But you Iove your moustache.
If anything happened to you,
I couId not Iive with myseIf.
Do it! Do it! Do it!
(YELLING)
You're good to go.
(YELLING CONTINUES )
(GASPING)
Edward?
Uh...
Am I dreaming?
Right. You're dreaming.
-So you're not reaIIy here?
-ExactIy.
-Go back to sIeep.
-Yeah.
(GRUNTS )
Got to...
Got to TiVo Wizards of Waverly Place.
(MOANING)
Patrón! Mario López!
(SIGHS IN DISGUST)
(MUTTERING)
Becca, you're sIeepwaIking.
(YELLING)
(SIGHING)
Hey, you're sIeepwaIking.
(SIGHS )
(BECCA GRUNTING)
(CONTINUES MUTTERING)
Just you breathing is the greatest gift
you couId give me.
(FARTING)
(EX CLAIMING IN DISGUST)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(DOG BARKING)
BECCA: l started to wonder,
maybe l wasn't dreaming after all.
l had to figure out the riddle.
Who was Edward Sullen?
Was he human,
or something different entirely?
Oh, snap!
He dropped his business card!
(ENGINE FIRES )
PRINCIPAL ON PA: Good morning,
Sporks High students!
Tickets are now on sale for prom.
And after school today, don't forget
to visit the quad for the blood drive
generously sponsored by the Sullen family.
Prom ! Come to prom!
Prom's aImost here! Prom!
Here! Get your fIyer for prom.
DERRIC: Check it out.
We finaIIy got a theme.
It's gonna be awesome.
The theme is vampires?
-We just came up with it randomIy!
-CooI, huh?
(SNARLING)
It's gonna be Iike
the festivaI of St. SaIvatore,
Iike the one they have in ItaIy every year
that ceIebrates the kiIIing of vampires.
And we're renting out
a huge stone courtyard.
It's gonna feeI just Iike
we're in the 15th century.
It shouId be super fun. Lots of
red capes, bIood and binge drinking!
You in?
I don't know. Prom's reaIIy not my thing.
WeII, it's my thing.
I mean, reaIIy, Becca, what is with you?
Prom is, Iike, the pivotaI moment
in any girI's Iife.
I've onIy been dreaming
about being crowned prom queen
since I was a sperm
in my dad's baIIs. (SCOFFS )
We need to taIk.
Your skin is paIe white.
You dress fashionabIy.
And you abstain from sex.
I know what you are.
Say it.
Out Ioud. Say it.
-Jonas brother.
-That's right.
Wait, what?
No, I'm a vampire. Duh.
That was my next guess.
Then ask yourseIf
the most obvious question.
What do we Iike to eat?
Vampire cereaI?
You need to see what I reaIIy Iook Iike.
This is why we don't show ourseIves
in the sunIight.
PeopIe wouId know we're different.
You're shining.
No, that's just my bIing.
You don't get it. I am a kiIIer!
(EX CLAIMS )
(SCREAMING)
-Are you texting?
-Yeah, Jennifer.
(SCREAMING)
I am the worId's most dangerous predator.
(CHIRRUPING)
I want to eat you!
My famiIy, we're not Iike other vampires.
We can controI our thirst
to onIy hunt animaIs
and the ReaI Housewives of AtIanta.
But I don't know
if I can controI myseIf around you.
Look, Ed.
I don't Iike to pIay games, so
I'm just gonna Iay my cards on the tabIe.
I reaIIy Iike you.
I dig the Eurotrash heroin-chic Iook.
You're totaIIy happening,
and I wanna be with you.
I can read everybody's minds but yours.
You have to teII me exactIy
what you're thinking.
You're pretty,
so you don't have to be smart.
WouId you Iike to go to the prom with me?
(CHUCKLES )
-Yes.
-That's awesome.
(SNARLING)
(SCREECHING)
BECCA: There were three things
l was absolutely positive about.
First, Edward was a vampire.
Second, American IdoI
is gonna blow without Simon.
And third, the next time l saw Edward,
l was gonna hump the shit
out of him and...
-Boo.
-(GASPS )
Oh, gosh, you scared me.
There is something that I wanted to try.
Me, too. I Iove roIe-pIaying.
(CLEARING THROAT)
That's not what I meant.
(CHUCKLES )
Don't move.
Kiss me aIready. I know it'II be okay.
(SIGHING)
That was amazing.
I've never gone to first base before.
Now Iet's go aII the way.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
-Purity ring.
-Yeah.
Oh!
I won't be abIe to resist my urges
to kiII you!
-I don't mind.
-What?
Oh, God!
Becca, no!
(SIGHS )
Oh, yeah? I Iike it rough.
Stay away from me.
No, pIease, pIease, pIease, don't come
any cIoser! This is for your own safety.
I'm trying to protect you.
Becca?
(GRUNTING)
If this is going to work,
we're gonna have to take things sIow.
I guess that's okay.
Even though my teen hormones are raging
and I want to have sex with you,
I feeI confIicted about Iosing my virginity.
I know you'II never have sex with me,
because you're a vampire,
so, reaIIy,
it's the uItimate pubescent girI fantasy.
That was incredibIy insightfuI.
(SIGHS )
I read it on Stephenie Meyer's
Twitter page.
Becca, I promise, as Iong
as you're with me, you'II never get hurt.
(GRUNTING)
(CLANGING)
Starting now.
(SNIFFING)
(ALL SNARL)
Shit!
WeII, I think we aII know whatever
kiIIed Fisherman ScuIIey was no animaI.
Look at those tracks.
It couId onIy mean one thing.
Canadians.
Damn border-jumpers.
They come here and take aII the
shitty jobs us Iazy Americans don't want,
and now they're kiIIing our fishermen, too.
Yeah, Frank,
I think you're missing the big picture.
That is a big picture.
BECCA: lt was my 18th birthday,
and the Sullens were throwing me a party.
WeII, this is home.
Hey.
There is no reason to be nervous.
WeII, I'm different than you.
They might not accept me.
It's Iike the time
when my ex-boyfriend, DeShawn,
invited me to his grandmama's house
to ceIebrate Kwanzaa.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Dandelion, come where
the sunshine shines
When you clock that second
And your heart starts ticking
May it land on mine
lf we make it to space
l'll meet you
Oh, my dandelion
I want you to meet my famiIy.
You must be Becca.
I'm Edward's mom, Eden.
We've heard so much about you.
Finger food?
That's AIex and RosaIyn.
I just know we're going to
be great, great friends.
And this is Iris.
-I hope we wiII be.
-No, she aIready knows it wiII happen.
Some of us have speciaI powers.
Iris has visions of the future.
Oh!
-But I'm not on my period.
-You wiII be. It's coming earIy this month.
ReIax, Becca.
We're just Iike any other
normaI American famiIy.
Except, of course, we have no souIs,
and we waIk the earth trying to satisfy
an unquenchabIe thirst for bIood.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
(JEREMIAH SNIFFING)
-I'm Jeremiah.
-He's new to the famiIy.
He's stiII trying to controI
his hunger for humans.
Look, I don't want to cause any probIems.
Maybe I shouId go.
But you have to open your presents.
Paper cut.
(JEREMIAH SNARLING)
(YELLING)
EDWARD: You're bIeeding.
BECCA: ReaIIy bad, actuaIIy.
I must have hit an artery.
(BOTH SNARLING)
(BOTH GROWLING)
(BOTH YELPING)
Becca, your nose!
I knew I shouIdn't have partied Iast night
with Lindsay Lohan.
(ALL SNARLING)
Every time I bring a girI home,
you guys try to eat her!
-It's not fair!
-Come on!
(DOOR BELL RINGING)
Someone here order Chinese food?
(YELLING)
Quick, they'II be hungry again
in haIf an hour.
What happened back there
can never happen again.
I now know, as Iong as I'm around you
you'II never be safe.
That's why I want you to bite me,
and turn me into a vampire.
-No.
-I keep aging and you stay the same.
I'm 18 now. I'm practicaIIy a cougar.
I just...
I couIdn't Iive with myseIf
if I turned you into a vampire.
You're aIways sexy and heaIthy,
and super good-Iooking,
with tons of free time
and money to traveI the worId.
It's a Iot Iike being George CIooney.
StrangeIy, the onIy thing
that does keep aging is your ass.
(CLEARING THROAT)
It gets pretty wrinkIy over time.
You'II never see me again.
Just promise me
that you won't do anything reckIess.
Okay. I promise I won't date Chris Brown.
FareweII.
Edward?
Edward! Edward!
Edward!
You're just gonna Ieave me here
aIone in woods
in an area fiIIed with vampires
who want to eat me?
(WAILING)
(SCREAMING)
Looks Iike Edward Ieft us a treat.
Great. This is exactIy what
I was taIking about.
Take that!
(SCREAMING)
I came here to heIp you, bitch!
Sorry.
There's nowhere eIse to run.
Your beIoved Edward
isn't here to save you.
(SCREAMING)
(SNARLS )
Hmm?
Come on, Jack. Where's the bro code, huh?
You know you don't try to eat
someone's girIfriend
right after they break up with them.
(EX CLAIMING)
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC PLAYING)
Kardashians.
Jack, no!
(BOTH SNARLING)
(SNARLING)
Let's go!
(CHOKING)
Becca.
I'm going to have to suck
the venom out of you.
This is going to be tough for me
because the taste of your bIood
couId send me into a frenzy.
-But on the other hand...
-(IN DEMONIC VOICE) Just do it aIready!
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Okay, Edward,
I think you got aII the venom out.
You can stop now.
(SLURPING)
(GASPING)
BECCA: And just like that,
Edward was gone.
l just couldn't get over him.
Why did he have to leave me?
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
And the rain is pouring down
And the tears are falling
But they never make...
BECCA: Time passed,
but my yearning for Edward
never subsided.
Everyone reminded me of him.
l couldn't get Edward out of my mind.
No matter where l looked.
No matter what l saw.
Without Edward, my life was over.
l felt like dying.
And every night, l had nightmares
that would make me scream
really, really loud.
(BECCA SCREAMING)
Becca. Becca. Becca. Becca ! Becca ! Becca!
You're so upset.
Let me check your IeveIs.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Oh. That's not good.
You've got more angst than
The Secret Life of the American Teenager.
You know, honey, I'm not reaI good
at the whoIe parenting thing.
But I do know that breakups are hard.
EspeciaIIy when you're dumped
by someone
as handsome and hunky as Edward.
That boy can reaIIy fiII out a pair of pants.
I'm Iike, "Mmm ! Look at that!
Look at that!"
Yeah.
And Iet's face it, honey. You're no Iooker.
And you twitch a Iot.
It's kind of irritating.
That's for sure
the best piece of ass you'II ever get.
That's my girI.
Oh!
Your friend Jennifer keeps caIIing.
You shouId hang out with her.
ProbabIy cheer you up.
I want you to say good night
to your new mommy.
(IN FEMININE VOICE) Good night, Becca.
I Iove you. I Iove you.
She reaIIy does.
WeII, good night, sweetheart.
I don't get it. Why wouId anyone want
to date a vampire? Lame.
Yeah. So Iame.
That movie's totaIIy going to fIop.
I can't beIieve they get married
and have a vampire baby.
(ALL GROANING)
Thanks for the spoiIer aIert, dumbshit!
(CLICKING TONGUE)
It's too bad Edward dumped you and now
you don't have a date for the prom.
'Cause that dress wouId have Iooked great
on you:
But you don't need a dress,
because Edward Ieft you behind
in the woods Iike bear shit.
(GASPING) So I'm going to wear it instead!
(LAUGHING)
And check this out.
Everyone's going to be, Iike, super jeaIous.
-CouIdn't you just die?
-No.
But you can.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
WeII, this is me. Where are you parked?
Uh...
Over there.
(GASPING) Ooh!
Right next to those mean
and scary biker dudes?
See you at schooI tomorrow!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, baby! Come over here!
You can sit on my bike.
(BIKERS HOOTING)
Becca. Those guys are dangerous.
WaIk away.
Edward?
Ow!
Shit. Those guys are dangerous.
ToId you.
BECCA: Whether it really happened
or l was just tripping out,
l figured the more crazy shit l did,
the better chance l'd have
of seeing Edward again.
JACOB: This is your brake.
And this is your throttIe.
Jacob, there's...
There's something different about you.
I don't know what it is.
I've been meaning to teII you.
I'm a man now, Becca.
-Are you teIIing me that...
-That's right.
-I've had my bar mitzvah.
-Mazel tov!
-So wiII you date me now?
-(ENGINE REVVING)
-Say again? I couIdn't hear you.
-(CHUCKLES ) Right.
-WiII you go on a date with... No, no.
-What?
Maybe if you'd stop revving the bike
whenever I'm about to ask you something
reaIIy important, you'd hear me.
-Right. Sorry.
-Thank you.
-Becca, I wanted to ask if you wouId just...
-(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
Oh, come on!
(YELLING) Becca,
wiII you go on a date with me?
Sorry, but I don't Iike to be
yeIIed at, Jacob.
I think I'II just take her for a spin.
Just one thing first.
Becca, you just cut the brake Iine!
(ENGINE REVVING)
Becca, stop. You're going to hurt yourseIf.
(BECCA VOCALIZING)
Hey, Eddy
Well, l know it might seem petty
But l can't stop obsessing over you
Put down that guitar
and stop singing Iike TayIor Swift.
(BECCA GRUNTING)
If this is what it takes to be with you,
Edward, so be it.
Becca ! Don't drink that miIk.
-You know you're Iactose intoIerant.
-This is for you, Edward.
-Oh, God.
-(STOMACH RUMBLING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Sorry. But I did try to warn you.
JACOB: Becca!
Are you trying to get yourseIf kiIIed?
Uh-huh.
You're bIeeding. Here.
(GRUNTING)
Your body is so...
...furry.
-Are those teats?
-Yeah, 10 of them, actuaIIy.
Oh!
I'd better go get you some heIp.
That was fast.
You are so scrumptious.
No!
Be happy it was me that found you
and not RacheI.
-Why? What happened to RacheI?
-She was...
...recast.
(GASPS )
Shh!
She wants to torture you
for what you did to Jack.
At Ieast I wiII eat you fast.
(GROWLING)
-Becca!
-Jacob, run!
That's it? A Chihuahua?
Yeah, I guess so. This whoIe
transformation thing is new to me.
-You can't stop me. You're no werewoIf.
-That's why I aIways traveI in a pack.
(SNARLING)
(ALL SNARLING)
(lT'S RAlNlNG MEN PLAYING)
lt's raining men
Hallelujah
Amen
l'm gonna go out
l'm gonna let myself get
Absolutely soaking wet
lt's raining men
Hallelujah
Amen
lt's raining men, yeah
-PIease.
-Get him, girIs!
(SQUEALING)
(ALL EX CLAIMING)
Sign this?
Now, Iet's get you home.
You'll be all right now. l know it's worked!
(SCREAMING)
(SNIFFLING)
Why can't they just be together?
(SNORTING)
There you are!
I've been Iooking everywhere for you.
-You Iook Iike shit.
-What do you want?
Look, we're aII sorry we tried to drink
Becca's bIood, even Jeremiah.
But something terribIe
has happened to her.
(BURPING)
Becca who? I am totaIIy over her.
I've moved on.
I am done with normaI chicks.
I've finaIIy found someone as freaky as me.
(MYFlRST WlSH PLAYING)
My first wish
Turn the music up as loud as it gets
My second wish
Me and the girls are in the hottest outfits
My third wish
(SIGHING)
Too freaky?
Edward, I had a vision!
Becca was riding a motorcycIe.
She tried to kiII herseIf.
I fear Becca may be dead.
No.
I've got to find out.
How do you feeI? It's Edward, isn't it?
Here.
Why did you just take off your shirt?
My contract says I have to
every 10 minutes of screen time.
Hmm.
Look, Edward Ieft you.
But I wouId never do that.
I want to take it out of the friend zone.
I reaIIy Iike you, Becca.
I Iike you, too.
When I'm with you,
I just feeI so safe and secure.
Thanks.
As opposed to how I feeI about Edward,
which is aII passion, Iust,
compIete forbidden fruit stuff.
-I mean, with him, it's aII about my vagina.
-Okay!
(PHONE RINGING)
Do you mind getting that?
Sure.
-HeIIo.
-EDWARD ON PHONE: Officer Crane?
No, he's not here right now.
Where is he?
It is very important that I speak with him.
(FRANK SPEAKING)
He's at the funeraI.
-Oh, God, no.
-Yeah.
And supposedIy, the body was so mangIed
that the undertaker had to use Krazy GIue
to stick the head back on and put marbIes
where the eyes once were.
HeIIo? HeIIo?
(SIGHS )
It's true.
-Becca's dead.
-Edward, I'm so sorry.
I can't Iive without her.
(GASPING)
Goodbye, Iris. I'm going to kiII myseIf.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
I just had another vision about Becca!
(SIGHING) Becca's fine.
You don't have to kiII yourseIf anymore.
Edward!
Shit.
(RICK HOOTING)
Prom rocks!
(BOTH WHOOPING)
I Iove drinking!
Oh!
What's the matter, Becca?
StiII no date for the prom?
Loser!
Here, have a drink, bitch!
RICK: She promised me sex tonight!
High point of my Iife!
Becca ! Get in the car, now!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
-What's wrong?
-Edward thinks you're dead.
Why wouId he think that?
Um...
Beats me.
He won't Iive without you
and he wants to die.
He's such a romantic.
(GASPING)
-Becca!
-Jacob?
Becca, don't go. You beIong with me.
Oh!
I need to know, who's it going to be?
Is it going to be me or him?
-Jacob, I...
-I'm not gonna take no for an answer.
I'm not going to Iet go
untiI you teII me, once and for aII.
AII right! Jacob, I'II teII you.
-I choose...
-Cat!
(GROWLING)
Come back here, pussy!
(CAT YOWLING)
Edward is going to the ZoIturi
to have them kiII him.
I saw it. I had a vision.
What are you taIking about?
Who are the ZoIturi?
They are the eviI bIoodsuckers
who onIy care about themseIves
and their own narrow vision of the worId.
-They're kind of Iike Fox News.
-Oh, my God.
Edward's going to expose himseIf
in the sunIight,
and the ZoIturi are going to kiII him.
They can't aIIow humans
to know vampires Iive among them.
It couId destroy us.
-Okay, where is this going to happen?
-At the prom.
The ZoIturi never miss
a good St. SaIvatore Day festivaI.
They fIew aII the way in from ItaIy.
Say what you want about them,
but they do know how to party.
ALL: Suck! Suck! Suck! Suck! Suck! Suck!
(ALL CHEERING)
(SCREAMS )
(DARO GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Oh! I got skiIIs, bitch.
Welcome, Sporks High students,
to the 2010 prom.
(HONKING)
And don't forget,
the main event is coming up shortly.
The crowning of your prom king and queen.
And if you haven't had a chance
to vote yet,
don't worry, there's still time.
Just to be sure.
Becca, you're the onIy one
that can stop Edward.
-You have to show him you're stiII aIive.
-I'II do whatever it takes.
BECCA: So, what would you do
to save someone you love?
For Edward, l would stop at nothing.
Whoa.
You already saw this part,
so let's get to what happens next.
No!
Edward!
(HISSING)
(SNARLS )
(SCREAMING)
Shit!
(EX CLAIMING)
(GROANING)
(BECCA SCREAMING)
BOTH: Uh-oh.
Edward!
Edward, it's not sunny anymore.
It's twiIight.
Hey, new moon.
Ah! EcIipse?
Look at me, everyone!
This is me in aII my gIory.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh! Lucky penny.
(CROWD EX CLAIMING IN DISGUST)
Oh!
Huh?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Edward!
Becca? You're aIive?
We have to go now.
Becca, I am so sorry.
I promise you
that I wiII never Ieave you again.
The ZoIturi are standing right behind me,
aren't they?
-Yep.
-Don't worry, Becca.
(SNARLS )
Not taIking smack now, are we?
-Stop it!
-"Stop it!"
-You're kiIIing him!
-"You're kiIIing him !"
-And we haven't even had sex yet.
-"And we haven't even had sex..."
ReaIIy?
Oh!
(DARO GRUNTING)
(RAP SONG PLAYING)
(THE HUSTLEPLAYING)
(SINGING)
(EX CLAIMING)
-Becca. Becca.
-Oh! Dad.
There you are.
I was worried about my IittIe girI.
You know,
there's stiII a kiIIer on the Ioose.
But I can see you're dancing
with your friends, so everything's aII right.
-Dad, no...
-No, Frank, wait.
You have to know the truth.
AII of the kiIIing was done by vampires.
Edward's one, aIso.
(DARO GRUNTING)
And Bobby White's a werewoIf.
Oh, oh...
-Ow!
-BOBBY: Sorry.
-I understand.
-Thank God.
The theme of the prom ! (LAUGHING)
-No, Dad.
-Enjoy, okay?
Becca, by the way, thanks for everything.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(ALL THRU THE NlTEPLAYING)
All through the night
Too cIose. Separate, arms Iength apart.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Too cIose. Separate! Arms Iength apart!
Hmm.
(DARO HUMMING)
(YELLING)
Say cheese.
(GASPING)
Whoo!
What...
...the heII?
(EDWARD READING)
Oh!
Where's Becca?
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTING)
Surrender now, or SaIvatore
wiII snap her neck Iike a SIim Jim.
You must pay for exposing yourseIf.
TeII you what I'm going to do,
Ed-to-the-ward.
I won't kiII you.
But Becca has to become a vampire.
-CooI?
-No, not cooI. No way! Never!
AII right. PuII Edward's head off,
then rip his body apart and set him on fire.
No, no, no. I mean, yes! I meant yes!
(CHUCKLING) Of course,
she wouId Iove to become a vampire.
She practicaIIy brings it up aII the time.
Right, hon?
-Uh, I guess so.
-Then bite her now!
Bite!
(GNARLING)
Listen up, people!
May l have your attention?
And now the moment
you've all been waiting for.
And this year's Sporks High
prom king and prom queen is...
...Jennifer and Rick!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
RICK: Triumph for the Rick!
Congratulations.
Mmm?
-Thank you!
-Yeah!
Oh!
Hold on!
lt seems you two received
over 69,000 votes
in a class of only 300.
(ALL BOOING)
l'm afraid you're disqualified.
What?
Oh!
God! You asswipe!
(RICK GROANS )
My Iife is over!
As your principal, l will nominate
a new prom king and queen.
(ALL CHATTERING)
And l will pick... l will... Let me see.
l will choose...
l pick you two!
-Us?
-Yes!
Because you two exemplify
what's best about this whole prom.
l mean,
you really look like a couple of mean,
-evil bloodsucking vampires.
-(GROWLING)
Oh, my God! We won! We won!
(ALL CHEERING)
Yes, yes, yes!
Move. Out of the way.
(HOOTING)
Oh!
(DARO CLEARING THROAT)
Edward!
Bite. Bite.
Do it.
Bite me now.
I don't want to wait a second Ionger.
I wiII onIy turn you into a vampire
on one condition.
Marry me.
Yes.
Are you ready?
(LAUGHING)
(MOANING)
-How do you feeI?
-Perfect.
It's how I aIways imagined.
I Iove you, Becca...
(YELPS )
Team Jacob, bitch!
(GROANING)
Fuck me.
(SCREAMING)
(lF l WAS YOUR VAMPlREPLAYING)
lf l was your vampire
Slim as the moon
lnstead of killing time
We'll have each other till the sun
lf l was your vampire
Death waits for no one
Put my hands across your face
Because l think
our time has come
Digging your smile apart
with my spade tongue
And the hole
is where the heart is
We built this tomb together
l will fill it alone
Beyond the pale
Everything's black
No turning back
lf l was your vampire
Slim as the moon
lnstead of killing time
We'll have each other
till the sun
lf l was your vampire
Death waits for no one
Put my hands across your face
Because l think our time has come
Beyond the pale
Everything's black
No turning back, no
Beyond the pale
Everything's black
No turning back, no
(MYPANTlES PLAYING)
l feel so lonely
Nobody gets me
l am so unhappy
Why can't l find a cool
alternative boyfriend
Who understands me?
We can watch the classics
Shop at Hot Topic
We're sexting dirty pics
of me in my panties
We can watch the classics
Shop at Hot Topic
Sexting dirty pics
of me in my panties
My panties, my panties
Sexting dirty pics
of me in my panties
My panties, my panties
We can watch the classics
Shop at Hot Topic
We're sexting dirty pics
of me in my panties
We can watch the classics
Shop at Hot Topic
Sexting dirty pics
of me in my panties
My panties, my panties
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
l'm the one
who's always thinking about
All the ways
to get to the end of it
You came around
And l think that l found
A good reason
to try and stick with it
You're taking me down
But l like the sound
And l want to get
with you anyway
ls this solid ground
Or am l getting drowned?
l'm just as happy
taking it day by day
And in the end
We all end up the same
Love and desire
Will be you once again
Life, listen and sing
We all end up the same
And in the end
lt all goes up in flames
Scars on the skin
You're bringing me in
And l'm closer, closer
Every minute
We'll start to spin
And l'm in it to win
And l'm taking
every last bit of it
Looking at your face
Making my heart race
And l can't seem
Can't seem to make it stop
Sitting by your side
Want to go for a ride
And l'm waiting
Waiting for you to drive
And in the end
We all end up the same
Love and desire
Will be almost plain
Life, listen and sing
We all end up the same
And in the end
lt all goes up in flames
Retailrip and sync by:
- RuBricK -
www.NorSub.com