Previously on Chicago Fire...
You're getting paid. Three quarter salary.
Any of us would take that deal.
How about you, Kelly?
Would you take that deal?
- I need something.
- The last one.
- Yeah.
- I mean it.
Didn't we have an agreement
when we first moved in
that we wouldn't get in
each other's business?
This is serious what you're doing.
I'm not doing anything.
Is there anybody back there?
Keep walking.
Sweetheart, do you remember your Uncle Matt
from Thanksgiving a couple years ago?
You're so grown up.
- Remember me?
- I remember.
Do you want to have lunch?
You're a good man.
- Ready?
- Ready.
- You sure.
- Yeah.
Look at you.
All lit up like a Christmas tree.
What? No!
I wanted to talk to you about my brother.
He ain't cut out for your crew.
Want to buy out, gotta drop 10k.
- I don't have it.
- [Tires squealing]
Leon! Oh, my God, Leon!
What the hell did you do?
Where is he?
- Where's Leon?
- Where's my money?
Okay, look...
I have a grand, but...
Leon.
Flaco, listen, man...
The deal was for ten grand, chum.
I... I can make payments.
You know how this works.
I give you a break, word gets out,
and everybody wants a break.
And I spend half my
day explaining to people
why they ain't gonna get one.
So no breaks.
Do you have the money or not?
No, I don't.
No!
[Door slams]
Hey, yeah... is Renee Royce there?
[Chuckling] Leave... leave... what?
Word? Uh, yeah, sure.
Yeah, go for it. Leave word. Thanks.
Good morning, ladies.
Peter Mills, it's the saddest thing.
The Christmas lights at the north gate
- got blown down.
- What?
We are gonna have to
do something about that.
The fireman that saved Christmas.
[Laughs]
You think if I asked him to
my cousin's Christmas party,
he might take it the wrong way?
Family functions are usually
reserved for serious suitors,
so shouldn't you be asking Casey?
I just need a date so that my cousin
doesn't make any more comments
about how I'm gonna die alone.
So you afraid Casey will say no?
Bitch, please.
Hey, hey, Cruz, you give me a hand here?
- In a minute.
- Okay.
You said ten minutes.
Yo, I don't even want to be here.
Why you calling me? Come on inside.
So a bunch of fat firemen
can make jokes about my face?
Look, this is a daily police bulletin.
We get one of these every day.
That's what "daily" usually means.
"Expect increased violence
in neighborhood Humboldt Park
due to an escalating gang conflict."
Leon, this is some serious business
you're getting wrapped up in.
I don't know how else to say
it, man... I'm worried about you.
Then pay Flaco his buyout
and be done with it.
Oh, but you don't got ten grand, right?
So why are we still talking?
Look, just keep your
nose out of my business
before you get my ass kicked again.
Leon, man.
Leon!
[Grunts]
[Station alarm blares]
Engine 51, truck 81, ambulance 61.
I was deep-frying eggplant.
I turned my back for a minute
and there were flames everywhere.
I... I tried to beat it
out with a towel, I...
Let these two take care of that hand.
Truck 81 is on the scene.
[Smoke alarm beeping]
Aah... turn off that smoke detector.
All right, let's do a quick walk-through,
open some windows, get this place vented.
[Beeping stops]
Holy moly. These folks must be
the 1% I keep hearing about.
Oh, you guys!
This priceless piece of
artwork has been destroyed.
Oh, wait. Never mind.
It's supposed to look like that.
- All right?
- Thank you.
Probably need a new countertop,
but everything else is okay.
Oh, my God, thank you.
Thank you so much.
Truck 81, are you available
to assist at a pin-in accident?
Truck 81 responding.
Pack her up. We got another call.
[Siren blares, horn honks]
Come back. Somebody stop them!
Ma'am, what's the problem?
My diamond necklace was sitting right there
on my dresser, and now it's gone.
And one of those firemen took it.
[Siren fading]
What's the matter, Hermann?
Matthew Casey. How about that?
What are you doing here, Griffin?
I'm with Internal Affairs Division now.
- What's the I.A.D. doing here?
- C.P.D. too.
What the hell's going on?
A woman on Green Street
said somebody walked off
- with her diamond necklace.
- What?
This is a joke, right?
No joke, Lieutenant.
- My men aren't thieves.
- All the same,
we're talking about a
$50,000 piece of jewelry.
That's a class 2 felony.
Casey, the police need to take statements
from you and the men.
And I'm gonna need you
to fill out a form too.
Basic stuff... where
you worked in the fire,
who you worked with, if
you saw the missing item
or anything else at all suspicious.
Can I have a minute?
Man!
I know what you're gonna say.
On my best day, I'd have to fight the urge
to choke that guy out.
Today's not my best day.
The possible theft of a $50,000 necklace
supersedes any concerns
about your personal feelings
toward Ted Griffin.
Chief, you know as well as I do,
none of my men took that necklace.
I hope not, 'cause I don't
want to see any of them
lose their job and face criminal charges.
And I don't want to see their Lieutenant
get a black mark on his record,
so let's just play this one by the book.
Good.
- Yeah, stop right there.
- Go ahead, lover boy.
Yeah, go break her heart, huh?
Never thought I'd see the day.
[Chuckling]
[Knocks on door]
Uh, hey.
Um, does Renee Royce live here?
Renee, there's a fireman here for you.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Thanks, Ray. Hi.
Uh, don't mean to interrupt.
I know you said you worked
from home on Fridays, and...
And you just pictured me
all alone answering emails
in my underwear?
- Well, I am now.
- Mm-hmm.
Wow, these are, um, gorgeous. Thank you.
How about dinner tomorrow night?
No interruptions this time, I promise.
Okay. All right.
- Okay.
- I'll see you then, Royce.
- Okay, Severide.
Wait, so what, exactly,
do you have against Mills?
Not a thing. He's adorable.
He's like a harmless little puppy dog.
Yeah, a puppy dog with a
little wolf blood in him.
- Hey, what's up, Chief?
- Hey, Chief.
Sit.
Uh, Chief, is this about
the diamond necklace
Dawson stole at the residence...
Hey.
Someone from another shift apparently
just told your field chief
that sometime in November,
four units of toradol
went missing from your rig
during your shift.
What? Who's saying this?
I bet you it was Lowell.
Don't you worry about who said it.
And why are they waiting
till now to say anything?
That's probably because
they heard I.A.D. is
sniffing around our house.
They want to cast the
blame if any more narcotics
turned up missing.
You know some junky
probably stole it off the rig
when we were busy saving his friend.
That may be so. But it's on you, Dawson.
So the two of you knock
your heads together,
get back to me with your official version
about what happened by
the end of the shift.
Yeah, we'll figure it out, Chief.
You better.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
We saved this lady's house.
Where does she come off
accusing us of stealing...
It's not like it's without precedent.
Back in the day, I worked
with Pat "The Pinch" Osbourne.
Had fingers like flypaper.
The roof could be caving in on us,
and Pat would take a moment
to rescue the silverware.
So... what's the deal with the Lieutenant
and the guy from I.A.D.?
Bad history. They went
through the academy together.
- And... there was an incident.
- What kind of incident?
The kind that ends with Griffin
getting his face punched in.
Wait, why did the Lieutenant hit him?
He was talking trash about Casey's family.
Um, but, see...
we don't talk about that.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, guys, here we go.
Here we go!
Hey, Lieutenant.
Lieutenant, check this out.
The people with all the artwork...
Sandra and Richard Vaughan...
they're selling their entire
art collection at auction.
I already finished my Christmas shopping.
No, no, no, no. Think about it.
You don't sell your art collection.
Your children sell your art collection
after you die, or...
you sell it if you need the money.
- Otis, I have things to do.
- The diamond necklace...
it's an insurance scam.
So this woman nearly burned down her home
in some elaborate scheme
to get firefighters in there
so she could accuse 'em
of stealing a necklace?
No. She didn't set the fire.
But when it happened, she
saw an opportunity to cash in.
Yeah. You should write that down.
[Sighs] Okay, I will.
- All right.
- Shay, your ride's here.
There you go. Thanks.
- Great.
- Yeah.
[Chuckles] You going to the prom, Hermann?
Hey, this is the flagship
for Caesar limousine.
- Your chariot awaits, ma'am.
- Ooh.
This guy, he's liquidating his company.
I can only afford one vehicle to start,
but I figure I roll the profits
of this one into the next,
and then the next, and before you know it,
I have a whole fleet.
Airport runs, weddings, prom season.
- Really, Hermann?
- Hey...
I was smart enough to bring my own mechanic
to the negotiations.
Severide got the guy to
knock $1,500 off the price.
You're gonna have to
spend some of that money
to fix this charging issue.
And you definitely need
to replace the timing belt.
And I thought I replaced
every vial I gave you,
but I must have lost count.
Hey. How can they bust
you for something that
somebody said happened a month ago?
It's their word against yours.
If it were my ass on the
line, I'd put up a fight.
But Dawson's the P.I.C.
It's her ass on the line.
Well, I don't know what to tell you.
No, you're right.
It's not your problem.
You got what you needed.
That... Shay.
Shay.
[Station alarm blares]
Truck 81, ambulance 61...
Capp, move this thing, will you?
You got it.
[Engine sputtering]
Oh, please, please start.
[Engine starts]
- Yes!
- Be advised.
Reports of multiple gunshot
victims, Humboldt Park.
Humboldt Park. As predicted.
[Siren]
Everybody back up. Give 'em some room.
Hey, Shay, let's get a "C" collar on her.
Get her in the back of
the ambo and start an IV.
- Just the one?
- The other two are DOA.
It was a drive-by vehicle to vehicle.
Girl was hit by a stray.
Shooters are long gone.
Check these two, just in case.
I'm on it, Lieutenant.
What color was it? The car, what color?
Was it an SUV, a Sedan... what?
Hey, come on, man, my partner heard you say
you saw the other car.
Not really.
I mean, it all happened so fast, man.
- Yo.
- Yo?
Leon, I left you, like, four messages.
- Busy day.
- Yeah, no kidding.
We just got a call on a
drive-by on Pulaski and Augusta,
and your boy Flaco was behind it.
Yo, can I call you later?
Are you with him right now?
Mm-hmm.
It don't matter. I'm gonna do the talking.
There's gonna be retaliation,
Leon, and I know you know that.
You gotta put some daylight
between you and Flaco.
[Locker shuts]
Listen, Leon...
I know you think you don't
got a way out of this life,
but you do.
I can help you.
Not right this minute,
but I can help you get out.
Just say the word.
You want my help, just say so.
So.
There you go, sweetie.
Get in there. Have a seat.
You're gonna catch a cold out here.
[Sighs]
Okay, James, I'm gonna
take your blood pressure.
- Is that okay?
- Will it hurt?
I do it every time, and you always ask me
- if it's gonna hurt.
- You never know.
I don't know, it's just
too soon to ask Casey.
This isn't the first time
his relationship with hallie flatlined.
And if it somehow gets revived again,
and she finds out that
I asked him on a date...
Won't you regret it if
you don't ask him, though?
[Sighs] It's gotta be Mills.
He's just the more appropriate choice.
I guess you're right.
Oh, for your dress, there's
this new shop on damen.
No way.
I sprained my credit
card Christmas shopping.
I'll just recycle something.
Oh, 110 over 60! James...
you're like a triathlete.
You're good to go,
sweetie. We'll take you in
and get you your meds, okay?
Oh, James, that reminds me.
Did you steal any
toradol from us last time?
I'm totally kidding. [Laughs]
Give me a minute.
Quick question. [Clears throat]
Saturday... what are you doing?
Depends. What do you got?
Um, my cousin, the poster child
for better homes & gardens,
throws this really super-fancy
Christmas party every year.
String quartet, plum pudding,
nutmeg sprinkled on the eggnog.
It's so perfect you want to vomit.
Sounds awesome. And you need a date?
Yeah. I mean, I just need a friend
to bring along, really.
Oh. Then maybe you should ask Mouch.
If you're up for a date,
tell me what time to pick you up.
7:00?
Great.
Yeah, I need a new dress.
Chief, are you just gonna
let these pretend cops
violate our civil rights?
Yeah, don't they need to show
us a warrant or something?
They are well within their authority
to search firehouse property.
Even our personal lockers?
You mean the department's lockers.
Besides, it shouldn't bother you
if you're not hiding something.
Griffin, can I have a moment with you?
Locker room, guys. Come on.
What? You want to punch me again?
When's the last time I.A.D.
searched an entire house?
A firefighter stole a $50,000 necklace,
and it's my job to find out who.
But don't blame me if you suddenly regret
assaulting a fellow classmate.
Regret it? I'm glad I did it.
You weren't the first idiot to
make a crack about my family.
You're the last.
No one's brought it up again
since I laid your ass out.
- Sucker punched.
- You saw it coming.
The only ones who saw it were your buddies.
None of whom had the integrity
to say what really happened.
By the way... how is your mom?
Hey! Hey!
Oh, whoa, whoa.
Casey blood sure runs hot, don't it?
Do your job.
Remember that one call we
went on at D and University?
- Which one?
- We got a block away,
and we realized the jump
bag was sitting on the curb.
I think that's when the vials went missing.
Damn, girl, you wear that
dress, I'll be your date.
I don't know. I feel kind of naked.
It's perfect.
Excuse me. Ring this up.
Oh, no, I need to think
about this one for a minute.
Thank you.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. Why?
You seem more worked up over
this toradol thing than I am.
No, I'm not worried.
Ambo 61, what is your location?
Ambulance 61. We're at Armitage and Damen.
Take in a working fire.
1100 block North Hamlin.
Okay, I'll take the other one.
[Station alarm blares]
Engine 51, truck 81, squad
3, battalion 25, ambulance 61.
House fire, 1100 block...
This house was supposed
to be taken out of service.
You never made that request.
So now you guys are
gonna have to sit tight...
until these men get back.
[Engine starts]
That address is Humboldt
Park again, isn't it?
[Siren blaring]
This is Battalion Chief
Boden at 1140 North Hamlin.
We responded to a call of a
gang shooting into the building.
They torched it and
fled before we got here.
Who's inside? Another gang? Any civilians?
You know as much as I do.
Could be gang members inside.
I count six mailboxes.
That fire has reached the structure.
Help me!
Mouch, Otis on the aerial.
Get ready to vent the roof.
Hermann, Mills, Cruz, with me.
Be careful.
[Gunshots]
Get clear! Get clear! [Voices scream]
I got you, Hermann.
This is the Chicago Fire Department.
Lay down your weapons.
We are trying to help you!
[Gunshots]
Cruz! [Speaking spanish]
We're not the police. You're gonna die
if you stay in there.
Let us help you!
I'm coming in.
- Cruz!
- Don't shoot!
[Speaking spanish] Cruz!
[Speaking spanish] Don't shoot!
You the Kings?
Insane Kings. I'm Leon's brother.
Where is he? Where is he? Where is he?
- That's the shooter!
- Get over here, you punk.
Take a look at him.
Hey, we're in! Let's go!
Take the infrared.
Mills, catch up with Cruz.
Hermann... you okay?
I'm gonna crack one of those
punks upside their head.
No. You're gonna sit this one out.
Severide, let's go.
Here you go. Put your arm around me.
You're doing fine. Keep going.
Come on, just take it
easy. You're almost there.
All right, here we go.
- Hey, somebody take this guy.
- We got him.
- We got you.
- Shay! We got you, sir.
Here you go. [Chatter on police radio]
[Coughing] Help us!
We got a woman and a
kid on the second floor.
Front, center.
We'll get 'em.
Help us.
Fire department. Call out!
Help!
[Coughing] Help us!
Let's go.
My little one. I don't know where he is.
Severide'll find him, but we need to go.
You don't understand, I need to find him.
Ma'am, we need to go right now.
Marco!
Hello! Anybody in here?
Anybody in here?
- All clear.
- Clear!
Come on. Come on, buddy.
- We're gonna find him.
- Marco!
- Ma'am!
I got him!
Get this guy out of here!
Cruz, hold up. I'll be back!
Come on, buddy. Up. I got you.
Fire department!
Clear the door!
Anybody in here? Call out!
[Woman coughing]
Come on.
[Coughing]
Got two minors, smoke inhalation.
Get 'em to the ambulance.
- Here we go.
- What do we got?
First and second floor are clear.
- My leg!
- Watch your step here.
Mills, where's Cruz?
He's still up there.
This is Cruz on three. All clear.
Headed up to four now.
Cruz, wait for me. I'm coming up.
Move away from the door.
Fire department. Call out!
[Man coughing] Leon!
Leon! [Coughing]
Thank God.
Yo... help me...
[Coughing] Help me!
[Coughing]
Please!
Please! Ahh!
This is Cruz up top.
All clear.
Hell of a job you did out there, Joe.
Hey... we missed one.
Don't beat yourself up about it.
You hadn't gotten us through that gauntlet,
we might have missed them all.
Casey. Hey. You're not gonna believe this.
So I ordered a background check
on Sandra and Richard Vaughan...
- Otis...
- And they are leveraged
up to their eyeballs.
It's one judgment after the next.
They're staving off bankruptcy.
They're in financial ruin.
And Mr. Vaughan...
investigated twice for wire fraud.
236 subscribers are gonna hear
about this on my next podcast.
Well, Lieutenant Casey.
Four-hour call, huh?
That was... pretty convenient.
It's insurance fraud.
The woman with the diamonds? They're broke.
What do you do off-shift,
drive around in a van solving mysteries?
Ugh.
[Knock on door] Lieutenant Casey.
You're up.
What is it you're hoping for, Griffin?
Toss the room. Search him.
Seriously? Come on.
It's all yours.
It was extremely careless on our part.
You leave a bag of full medication
on a curb at a college campus,
you're asking for trouble.
And you are gonna be so much
more careful in the future, right?
- Yes, sir.
- Absolutely, Chief.
Hmm.
Okay.
Just write down what you told me.
Don't sign anywhere until
you bring these back,
because I have to witness your signatures.
If you would like Mouch
to go over it with you
as your union representative,
you do have that right.
You want us to sign it in blood,
or will blue ink suffice?
Don't you drag your heels now.
No, we'll get it right back to you, Chief.
Shay... one moment.
What is it, Chief?
Nothing.
Go on.
[R&b music playing]
♪
- Skinny margaritas.
- What?
Skinny on the calories, not the alcohol.
Ah! Ahh.
You have a really nice place.
Mmm, thank you.
Guess it pays to work in...
- foreign financial...
- International finance law.
Yes, it does.
But I want to hear about you
and how you fight fires every day.
It's not every day.
On 24, off 48.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- I didn't know that.
- Uh-huh.
And then what do you like to do
on your off days?
I repair boats up near Monroe Harbor.
Um, do you go out to the lake much?
Yeah, more in the summers, but...
Mmm. I haven't been out in a while.
I'll take you some time.
Oh, will you now?
Any time you want,
Royce. Just say the word.
Hmm.
What?
Who was she?
What do you mean?
The Renee that ruined my name.
She was my fiancée.
[Knocks on door]
- Evening, ma'am.
- Can I help you?
I just wanted to apologize
on behalf of truck 81
for your missing item,
and to let you know we're going
to get to the bottom of it.
Well, I should hope so.
This is a thermal imaging camera.
It's a really great piece of technology.
It helps us see through the thickest smoke.
Okay.
We all carry them, and
we leave them recording
the whole time we're on a call.
I'm actually on my way to
drop all our cameras off
with the police so they
can review the footage,
and see exactly what
happened the entire time
my men and I were inside your home.
So don't worry.
Okay. Is that it?
Yeah.
Great.
So maybe you should leave now.
Son, you're a slob.
Got something.
Oh, yeah. Oh, boy. Gimme that. Gimme that.
Oh, false alarm.
Just an adorable pair
of kitty cat cufflinks.
It's the maneki-neko, a
Japanese good luck charm.
And those were a Christmas
gift, if you don't mind.
Hey, domo arigato, Mr. Roboto.
That doesn't even make sense.
Chief Boden, have you been
able to locate Lieutenant Casey?
I'm right here. [Cell phone rings]
Griffin.
Is that a fact?
That's very interesting.
No, thank you.
The diamonds slipped down into
a heat register, apparently.
Mrs. Vaughan just found 'em.
You gotta be kidding me.
What a surprise.
Less paperwork for me. Hallelujah.
Let's go.
Do say hi to your mom for me.
Door's that way.
[Door shuts]
All right... so what'd you do?
Nothing.
I just told her we recorded the whole thing
on our thermal cameras, you know.
Wait, thermal cameras don't record.
Oh. That's good.
Ooh.
Casey, you have a visitor
in the briefing room.
Chris. This is a nice surprise.
Merry Christmas.
Yeah, Merry Christmas.
Almost done shopping.
I couldn't remember if you're a large
or extra large, but there's
a gift receipt in there.
Oh. That's really sweet.
Thank you.
Since we saw you at the cemetery...
Violet's been pretty flipped out.
"Why doesn't Uncle Matt
ever come to see us?
Does he not like us? Do you not like him?"
And she shouldn't have to
be asking those questions.
And...
that's on you and me.
Absolutely it is, yeah.
I feel like she's been without her Uncle,
and...
I've been without my brother for too long.
Yeah, I want nothing more than for us
to be in each other's lives.
The last time we talked about it...
I know. I remember the conversation.
[Sighs]
[Exhales]
So you're still defending her.
I'm not gonna turn my back on her.
Don't you miss dad?
Yeah, something...
Excuse me one second. I need to steal him.
Bye.
- Drink?
- Oh, thank you.
Oh, I can't wait to show you this room.
Okay.
Ooh.
- Wow.
- It's nice, right?
- Yeah.
- Ahem.
Oh, and hey, I promise I won't let my aunt
corner you again like that.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. She's fun.
Yeah, she's better when you're drunk.
Oh, better learn how to keep up, buddy boy.
Yeah.
[Both chuckle]
I mean... are we just here as friends,
or... is this a date?
I can't. I mean...
No, yeah. I get it.
It's not a good time.
Because it's worth doing right.
Right?
Oh, sorry. Don't mind us.
Ahem.
Uh, you ready for dessert?
I'm ready for dessert.
This is crazy, bro.
I was just up there,
like, ten minutes before
it all went down.
Flaco sent me to get shorty. Otherwise...
I don't know.
Somebody's gotta be up
there looking out for me.
Joe, you okay?
I can't.
I can't do this. I can't do this.
I...
[Breathing unsteadily]
You're up early.
You know I love you, right?
Okay, what's going on?
I love you because I know
you'd stick your neck out for me
the way I have for you.
Of course I would.
And I did that to get you over the hump.
Which you totally did.
And then I found these in the trash.
Those are ol... they're old.
I perjured myself for you, Kelly.
Shay...
I'm out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What do you mean?
I mean I'm out. We had a deal...
we wouldn't get in each other's business,
but I can't hold up my end.
So I'm out.
Shay, it's okay. I got it.
- I got it.
- No, you don't got it!
I'm not gonna sit here and watch you...
just fool yourself.
I'll get the rest of my stuff later.
Shay, hey, please don't go.
Please don't... please don't do this.
[Door opens, shuts]
[Breathing unsteadily]
[Cell phone vibrates]
This is Matt Casey.
Leave it here and I'll call you back.
Lieutenant, it's Joe Cruz.
Um... Casey, man, I need to talk to you.
It's really important. I, uh...
I, um...
[Whistle blowing]
Here we go.
I'll make my brother get the
rest of your stuff tomorrow.
And you are totally welcome to stay with me
as long as you want.
Thanks.
You gonna tell me what he did?
No. You gonna tell me how your date went?
Nope. He's good.
Thank you.
[Dispatch chatter over radio]
Come on, give me something.
[Chuckles]
Well, I was right about Casey.
He's still into Hallie.
And I'm an idiot.
[Whistle blows]
[Door buzzer]
Hi, mom.
Tomorrow night, you and me are gonna have
- a few margaritas.
- Heh!
A few pitchers, you mean.
Yeah, well, that was implied.
[Horn blaring]
[Both gasp]
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -