It's gonna be another
boring, beautiful day today
in Los Angeles with a high of 70.
[Ben Harper's "Walk Away"]
♪ with so many people
to love in my life ♪
Hey, Bram.
Can I have two?
How 'bout an egg
and some cereal, huh?
Two eggs for you,
yeah, Gracie?
Eggs are gross.
Eggs are not gross.
Eggs are just
un-hatched baby chickens.
[Clucking]
Ugh.
Oh.
[Sighs]
[Banging]
Damn it.
You okay?
All good.
I'll just have some cereal.
- Here you go.
- Thanks, baby.
♪ we've tried the good-bye ♪
♪ so many days ♪
♪ we walk in the
same direction ♪
♪ so that we could never stray ♪
Mr. Bram, sir.
Here's your list.
Now what do I say?
Bring oranges and staples only?
Amazing.
Love you.
Good morning.
Good morning. You stink.
Or is it you? You stink.
You stink.
[Birds chirping, dog barking]
He's a good kid.
They're all good kids.
Got to go to work.
[Sighs]
[Poignant music]
♪
Bye.
Be safe.
Bye, you.
[Chuckles]
Love you.
You take care of them, okay?
[Door opens, closes]
New transportation
passes are required
by the fifth of the month,
so be sure to pick yours up.
What about you, Carlos?
What are you gonna do
when this is all over?
Go see my family.
Yeah, and bore them to death.
Come on.
This is supposed
to be a fantasy.
Sully's got a better answer.
I'm gonna leave this garage,
you idiots, and never come back.
I'm gonna grab the kids, hit
the the Santa Monica pier,
and eat in-n-out
burgers till we puke.
Doesn't anybody want
to go somewhere exotic?
Australia? Thailand?
Just a lot of
stupid daydreaming.
Come on. My pop says this
will all be over by Christmas.
Pop's been drinking
too much moonshine.
Parker's got something good.
I know it.
You all right, Parko?
My brother got sent up.
Factory.
Word came in last night.
This is the worst part of it,
you know?
It's families.
Husbands separated from wives.
Parents from children.
Thank God we can take
a lot worse if it wasn't for that.
Rat bastards.
[Both grunting]
Why don't you come with me?
I'm not that guy.
But uh, you do something for me?
Contacts.
My mom and my brothers.
I just want to make
sure that they're okay,
that they know that I'm okay.
Hey.
Good luck, hermano.
Careful.
[Engine starts]
[Suspenseful music]
♪
Oh, no, no.
You're kidding me.
♪
[Sighs]
[Dog barks]
- Morning.
- ID, please.
Yeah.
Destination?
Santa Monica gateway.
Parts delivery.
What are you carrying?
Fuel cells.
[Barks]
You're clear.
♪
[Whistles]
You're late, Sully.
Payment's in the van.
Go on, check it.
Here's your Santa Monica ID.
Give me your LA one.
You'll be my 38th run.
You've got nothing to worry about.
You're gonna want to put that on.
Hop in.
[Sighs]
♪
Two kind of guys roll through here.
Guys running to something,
guys running from something.
Which are you?
I'm going to find my son.
We were separated
during the arrival.
How old?
He turned 12 last week.
Mm.
You have entered the exclusion zone.
Remain inside your vehicle
until otherwise directed.
What's it like in Santa Monica?
About the same,
but with a beach.
Come in.
Hold. That's good.
Okay, we're a go for scan.
ID.
- [Barking]
- All right, let's go.
Los Angeles drivers
to Containment Area.
[Suspenseful music]
♪
Scanner's are infrared?
My box kills x-ray and thermal.
They won't see shit.
_
Santa Monica drivers
to your trucks.
How do we know the replacement
drivers won't sell us out?
They'll never know
we were here.
[Buzzer blares]
[Exhales]
Spider's got you co...
[Explosion]
[Groans]
[Grunts]
[Men groaning]
[Buzzing]
Freeze!
Hands where I can see them!
- Do it now.
- Keep your hands up.
Get 'em up! Move!
On your knees!
Move him out!
- [Buzzing]
- Put your hands
behind your head!
[Suspenseful music]
♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
[Dog barking]
Come on, Minnie.
[Dog barks]
[Stirring music]
♪
_
- Move along.
- Sorry.
[Siren wails]
- Get down!
- Shit! What is this?
- You! Come here.
- What are you doing?
I haven't done anything!
You can't do this! Please!
[Siren wails]
All right, Minnie.
Hi.
You can't bring the dog.
[Whining]
With thousands of full- and
part-time jobs available,
there's more than one
way to be the best.
Right here.
Right through here.
Thank you.
Hi, are you Heloise?
I am.
What can I do for you, dear?
I heard you make insulin.
You are correct.
Come on.
Certain conditions are
deemed unworthy for treatment.
Diabetes is one of them.
Reps are culling
weakness from the herd.
Existing supplies of
insulin are nearly gone.
And no one's making any
home-brewed solutions.
That is, except Old Heloise.
In 1922,
this Canadian guy figured out
how to extract insulin from
the pancreas of a canine.
You made insulin from a dog?
When an artist
finds herself in doubt,
she should consult
with the old masters.
I need to see
what you have to trade first.
This has to be kept cold.
It's way too hot in here.
And it's cloudy.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm not buying your shitty insulin.
Oh, I believe you already did.
- That's...
- A trade is a trade.
Put it down.
Let's go, right now.
Right now.
Put it down.
I'm just leaving.
Come on.
Put your hands up.
Let her go.
[Dog barking]
Are you damn crazy, lady?
One of those drones
finds you with a gun,
they're going to kill us all.
Then let me go!
Let her go.
[Chickens squawk]
Shit, sorry.
[Dog barking]
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're gonna stay right there.
All right, relax.
Stand back.
[Dog barking]
Come on, Minnie.
- Anyone need oranges?
- I have canned tuna.
What's the expiration?
One orange per?
Two.
How about one and a half?
I'll take two cans.
My mom made tortillas.
Oh, my God, best in LA.
Here, give her these.
I don't think this is a fair trade.
- All right, who's got coffee?
- Yeah, right.
What the shit is this?
You need oranges, Jackson?
This market is mine.
No trading goes on without
me getting my beak wet.
You should report me
to the Red Hats.
Your backpack.
Your backpack, shit-heel.
[Tense music]
♪
[Yells]
[Grunting]
Your beak's wet.
- Five-oh.
- Let's go.
Hey, you over there.
[Indistinct chatter
over PA and radios]
Hey!
Where's my phone call?
Let me out of here!
Don't waste your breath, brother.
These collaborating assholes
cannot do shit for you.
[Man yelling in distance]
Let me out!
I want my phone call.
Step back.
I need to call my wife.
[Sighs]
He's two hours late.
He'll be here.
Your father's never late.
Everyone home before dark.
That's his rule.
- [Door opens]
- Katie?
Hi.
Did you get it?
I'm sorry.
My source didn't pan out.
What? How?
It just didn't, Maddie, but
I'll figure something else out.
Hudson needs insulin.
You still have the last batch?
It'll be gone in a week.
Okay, we got a week.
- Hey.
- I'm bored.
Do you want to go upstairs
and play with your cousin?
- Yeah!
- Okay, go, go, go, go.
What are we gonna do?
There's no one
to buy from anymore.
I'm gonna find you some.
I promise.
I need you to stay here
with the kids right now.
Where are you going?
I have work tonight.
Will never came home.
Mom, you can't go out
this close to curfew.
I'm going to be just fine.
I promise, all right?
I'll be back.
I hope Will's okay.
[Door closes]
[Coyote howls]
Katie. Jesus,
what are you doing here?
Was Will at work today?
- Of course he was.
- He didn't come home.
It's too close to curfew.
You shouldn't be here, honey.
Do you have any idea
where he might be?
Will went out on a delivery
this afternoon.
- I figured he went home after.
- No.
He didn't call you?
He didn't say anything?
If you know something, please...
I don't know where he is.
Sorry.
Carlos. Please.
Get home safe.
Please.
[Mechanical buzzing]
[Loud siren]
[Ominous mechanical whirring]
[Screaming]
[Gunfire]
Get off me! Let me go!
You got the wrong guy.
Get off! Oh.
Let me go.
No, please. Get off!
[Engine starts]
[Exhales]
Mom!
Hey, hey.
It's okay, it's okay,
I told you I'd be home.
I'm home.
Where's dad?
I...
I don't know.
Here I thought your only
talent was drinking my bourbon.
[Laughs]
Is this a new project?
This was my mother's place.
I would oversee so much
it didn't make sense
to keep a place of my own,
so I stay here with her.
Always wanted to restore
it to a former glory,
just never had the time.
Now it's all I got.
You looking for work?
What's wrong?
Uh...
Will's missing.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
He, um, he went to work yesterday
and he hasn't come home.
The Red Hats didn't come by?
What's my reality?
Are you sure he didn't...
Oh, no, no, no.
He didn't walk out on us.
Look.
Guys like me and Will,
we knew we had to go to
ground after the arrival.
But that doesn't mean
there isn't a list.
That someday our resumes
won't catch up with us.
What do I do right now?
Hey.
Check the hospital.
I'll make some calls.
Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay. Okay.
Dr. Green on nine.
Excuse me.
What's going on?
There are no free beds.
That's what's going on.
There was an explosion at the
Santa Monica gateway yesterday.
An explosion?
The proxies are saying
it was a gas leak.
Gas leak, my ass.
It was the Resistance.
Those terrorist pricks
wounded at least ten people.
Thank you.
Who knows how many
more they killed?
Excuse me,
can you close that, please?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Excuse me?
Um, I'm looking for my husband.
What room is he in?
I'm not actually sure that he's here.
You're looking for someone
who might not be here?
I haven't seen him in a day
and there was an explosion,
so he might have been brought in.
Do you have a name, do
you have any idea where...
- Will Sullivan.
- Where the hell is a doctor?
Or anyone that can get me
some answers around here.
Excuse me, sir?
Can you... No, no, no.
Get your hands off of me.
- Okay, how can I help you?
- No way.
Do you realize how long
we've been waiting out there?
We've been out there for six hours.
My wife and I have been waiting
out there in a room full of...
[Arguing continues]
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry,
I'm looking for my husband.
I know that you guys
are super busy but I...
Okay, fine, fine,
what is his name?
Will. Sullivan.
[Sighs]
Sullivan.
Burn unit, third floor.
He's not here.
If I ever see you back here again,
I'll report you to Homeland.
Thank you for your help.
[Line rings]
Hello?
Did you know about the party?
Why didn't you tell me?
You weren't on the guest list.
Was my friend invited?
He wasn't invited but he went anyway.
Was it him and the...
when... the party?
Try to calm down.
Another group picked up
your friend after the party.
He had a better time than most,
but he's with those people now.
Our hope is
they'll bring him home
after they're all
done catching up.
Any idea why he'd go
there in the first place?
I don't know.
He didn't tell me anything.
Okay.
It's the 12th time I've laid
my head in this shit hole.
Just waiting for them to come
and take me up to The Factory.
Go and work for those bloody rabs.
You ever seen one?
No one ever sees them.
[Gate buzzes]
Everybody. On your knees.
Hands behind your head,
fingers interlocked.
Will Bowman.
I'm looking for Will Bowman.
Are you Will Bowman?
Sullivan.
Aah!
Not anymore.
Where are you taking me?
Oh, come on.
Who am I going to tell?
You're going to the GZ.
Where?
The Green Zone.
You look relieved.
I can think of
worse places to be going.
[Chuckles]
All right, big man.
[Siren wails]
Hold it there.
[Indistinct instruction]
[Dramatic music]
♪
[Dance music playing]
♪ ♪
You behave.
Upstairs.
♪
Hi, Will.
How you doing?
You a scotch guy?
Bourbon.
Ah, should have guessed.
You're originally from Georgia, right?
[Pours drink]
Sorry about all this.
I hope you weren't
treated too poorly.
Come on, Captain Lagarza,
we don't need those.
Sorry.
Alan Snyder.
I'm the Proxy Governor
of our little block here.
Why am I here?
To turn crisis into opportunity.
Even the most successful men
make two or three critical
mistakes in their lives.
It's what they do
afterward that defines them.
I'm not standing here
with Billy Sullivan,
auto mechanic
from Hollywood, am I?
No.
I'm standing here with
Special Agent William Bowman,
former army ranger,
Gulf War II in Afghanistan,
former FBI fugitive
hunter extraordinaire.
I understand you bagged
something like 50 fugitives
in your stint with them?
I'm good at finding people.
Impressive.
But I'm even more
impressed that you managed
to hide your identity
from us for so long.
Military law enforcement
guys like me,
they all went missing
after your friends came.
You protected yourself
and your family.
I can respect that.
What was it exactly
you were doing in the
Santa Monica exclusion zone
when that IED exploded?
You think I'm with the Resistance?
You wouldn't be here if we did.
Then why am I here?
Because our hosts are
tired of the insurgency.
They've blown six IEDs
in the last month alone.
They're getting bolder,
more dangerous.
You and I, we both know
that guys like yourself,
guys with your training,
you're a, uh,
rare breed these days.
And that makes you
especially valuable.
You want me to collaborate.
I want to give you your
old job back, my man.
That is, head up
special task force,
infiltrate the insurgency,
and bring us their leader.
This character
they call "Geronimo."
Sorry to interrupt, Alan,
but it looks like it's starting.
You're gonna want to see this.
[Ominous music]
♪
All right, here we go, everybody.
[Rumbling]
[Boom]
[Gasping]
[Distant explosion]
It's breathtaking, isn't it?
They put on that show
a couple times a month.
Yeah, I've seen it from my house.
Not like this.
I thought it might give
you some perspective.
The most important day in
human history is coming, Will.
I just want you and your family
to be on the right side of it.
And when I tell you to piss off?
- Why don't you give us a minute, sweetie?
- Yeah.
You have committed crimes
that must be punished
in accordance
with Occupational Law.
If you can't help me, then you
and your wife and your children,
well, I'm sorry but
you'll all be sent to The Factory.
How do you do it, Snyder?
Slap on a suit and smile
and dick over your own kind?
I'm doing what anybody
with a brain would do
in this situation.
I'm taking advantage
of my opportunities.
[Tense music]
[Screeching tires]
Maddie, go get Hudson.
- Who is it?
- Right now, right now.
We're leaving.
Bram, Bram, Bram, Bram, Bram, wake up.
- What? Mom, what?
- Wake up, wake up.
Go get your sister.
We're leaving. We're leaving.
Gracie!
Up and at 'em, sweet girl!
Grab your bag, it's ti--
[Exhales sharply]
I'm sorry.
Okay. I'm okay.
- Daddy!
- Hey, baby.
Come here.
[Chuckles]
Oh.
Hey.
What's everybody doing up so late?
God, Will. We were so worried.
I'm okay. Here.
Take this big girl.
Where were you?
I was out on a delivery,
had a little fender bender.
Got stuck out after curfew.
Homeland picked me up.
No matter what I said or did,
they wouldn't let me
make a phone call.
Just released me now.
I'm sorry.
Come on!
It's okay, I'm home.
I didn't mean to worry you.
It's all right.
No problem.
Ah.
[Grunting]
[Both panting]
[Crying]
[Giggles]
So they know?
We're not the Sullivans.
What do you want to hear?
I want to hear the truth.
You've got all the answers.
You tell me.
Do you know how scared I was?
How we all were?
I called in some favors and
they said you'd been picked up
trying to leave the block.
I went after Charlie.
No.
This thing is a cancer.
It's bad enough he's gone,
but to see you every day
hating me for it.
I don't hate you for it.
I should have picked him up.
He's my son, too.
I know.
I know, I know, I know.
Baby. Shh, shh, shhh.
Love, we have
two other children.
I know.
And you know what they do
to the families of criminals.
You don't have
to worry about that.
Proxy Snyder offered me a job.
To work for him?
What does he want you to do?
He wants me to
hunt down the Resistance.
To collaborate?
I saw a dozen people
murdered the other day,
and so the Resistance
can accomplish what?
Do they even know
who their enemy is?
Love, you sound
like them right now.
I'm trying to do something
to help us, to...
If you do it, you're putting
a target on your back
and on mine and
on those children.
As far as the
Resistance is concerned,
collaborate and you die.
I'm not sending our kids
to a labor camp.
Well, thank God you've
got it all figured out.
Well, what would you do?
[Door slams]
[Quiet clanging]
Hey.
Yeah?
Is that bacon?
[Sizzling food, rustling]
Snyder?
Good morning.
Hungry?
It's Katie, right?
Right.
Proxy Alan Snyder,
Los Angeles Block.
What are you doing in my house?
Cooking breakfast.
I also made some coffee.
One of the little luxuries
we took for granted
before our current situation.
Mommy?
Oh, man, is that bacon?
It is. Let me guess.
Bram and Grace?
Yeah. Aren't you...
Proxy Snyder.
Bram, take Grace upstairs.
Wait, wait.
Don't leave without breakfast.
[Exhales]
Move, Grace. Come on.
This is a big moment
for your family.
You're going to
have access to things
that were
previously unavailable.
For instance, your children
will be assigned private tutors.
You'll also be afforded
certain other luxuries,
round-the-clock security
from Homeland among them.
Which we'd need
as Collaborators.
Look. I know it may not seem it,
but our hosts are here
for our benefit.
Come out there with me, Snyder.
Not the Green Zone, the flats.
Let me show you a few things
and then tell me
if you still believe that.
There need to be
some controls in place,
otherwise it'd be anarchy.
But all of this, it's temporary.
Once they've satisfied
their needs, they'll leave.
Everything will go back to normal.
What needs?
I wanted this to be more
of a surprise, but um...
Your bar? The Yo... Yo...
Yoknapatawpha.
We called it The Yonk.
The Yonk.
I like that.
So, I've convinced our hosts
that they've undervalued
recreation a bit.
They've agreed to
re-opening some places.
We'd like The Yonk
to be among the first.
Hm.
Only thing is,
I'm going to need
an answer before I leave.
You want my help?
We want our son back.
We were separated
during the invasion.
He's in the Santa Monica Block.
Good things come to the loyal.
We help them, they help us.
You help me, I help you.
Gotta go.
[Huffs]
Where have you been hiding that?
Special occasion.
[Chuckles]
To new jobs.
To old jobs.
Mm.
Oh.
I'm with you.
I got to go to work.
Hey. Hey.
Come here.
Be safe.
You bet.
Okay.
Don't finish it.
Just might.
[Mechanical buzzing]
[Bicycle clicks]
Hi, grandma.
I'm here for breakfast.
You're a bit early.
I came hungry.
Come with me.
Oh, put your bag down there.
Thank you.
It's okay.
- [Knocking]
- Here we are.
And there you go.
Go ahead.
Tell them.
You have someone on the inside.
Who?
Me.
How's that?
The Occupation just hired
my husband to hunt us down.
[Dramatic music]
♪
_
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com