[Woman Vocalizing]
[Glass Cracking]
[Vocalizing Continues]
[Sizzling]
[Computer Voice] Stasis interrupted.
Fire in cryogenic compartment.
Repeat.
All personnel report to...
emergency escape vehicle launchpad.
Deep space flight will commence...
in "T"minus 20 seconds.
[Siren Wailing]
[Vocalizing Continues]
[Breathing Heavily]
[Alarm Blaring]
[Vocalizing Continues]
[Wind Gusting]
[Bell Tolls]
An E.E.V.'s come down.
Get down to the beach.
There may be others.
Now!
Talk to me.
All right, all right.
Let's get it going.
Keep it together.
Come on. Right.
Right. Here we go, Mr. Dillon.
Give us strength,
O Lord, to endure.
We recognize that we are poor sinners
in the hands of an angry God.
Let the circle be unbroken...
until the day.
- Amen.
- [All] Amen.
Thank you, gentlemen.
This is rumor control.
Here are the facts.
As some of you know...
a 337 model E.E. V...
crash-landed here at 0600...
on the morning watch.
There was one survivor...
two dead and a droid that was
hopelessly smashed beyond repair.
The survivor is a woman.
[Overlapping Chatter]
I just want to say that I have taken
a vow of celibacy.
- [Man] So have we all.
- That also includes women.
- Yes.
- We've all taken the vow!
- [Man] Shut your gob, Morse.
- [Morse] I'd like to say, that I for one...
do not appreciate company policy
allowing her to freely...
intermingle with inmates
and the rest of the staff.
What brother means to say is we view
the presence of any outsider...
especially a woman,
as a violation of the harmony...
a potential break
in the spiritual unity.
We are well aware
of your feelings in this matter.
You will be pleased to know
that I have requested a rescue team.
Hopefully, they will be here
inside of a week...
and evacuate her A.S.A.P.
[Man] Don't give us that.!
What's her medical status?
She doesn't seem
too badly damaged.
She's unconscious. Can't give you a more
specific diagnosis at the moment.
- Will she live?
- I would think so.
Look. It's in
everybody's interest...
the woman doesn't come out of the infirmary
until the rescue team arrives.
And certainly not without
an escort, right?
Sir.
Gentlemen, we should all stick
to our set routine...
and not get unduly agitated.
- Right.
- Correct?
All right.
Thank you, gentlemen.
- All right.
- [Man] Better get here sooner.
- There ain't gonna be much left.
- Everybody's dead.
[Clattering]
What's that?
It's just a little cocktail of my own mix.
Sort of eye-opener.
[Breathing Heavily]
You the doctor?
My name is Clemens.
I'm the chief medical officer here.
- Here?
- Fury 161.
It's one of Weyland-Yutani's
backwater work prisons...
it grieves me to say.
Do you mind?
This is basically a stabilizer.
I really ought to shave your head.
We have a big problem with lice here.
And when you're feeling better,
I'll give you some clippers...
- and you can tend to
your private parts yourself.
- How'd I get here?
You crash-landed in an E.E. V.
Evidently separated from your mother ship
before you hit our atmosphere.
You have any idea
how long you were in hypersleep?
Coming out the way you did
can be a jolt on your system.
Yeah, I'll be sick
for a couple weeks.
- Indeed.
- [Inhales]
[Exhales]
Where are the others?
They didn't make it.
- What?
- They didn't survive.
I have to get to the ship.
- I have to get to the ship.
- You're in no condition for that.
You wanna get me some clothes,
or should I just go like this?
Given the nature of our indigenous
population, I would suggest clothes.
- [Clears Throat]
- None of them have seen a woman in years.
Neither have I for that matter.
This used to be
a 5,000 convict facility...
but it's been reduced
to a custodial staff of 25.
- Why?
- Keep the pilot light on.
The pilot light for what?
[Loudly] Blocked furnace.
Natural methane.
We have a foundry,
Lieutenant Ripley.
The inmates forge lead sheets
for toxic waste containers.
How do you know my name?
It's stenciled
on the back of your shorts.
[Men Yelling, Indistinct]
[Man]
Release the cable.!
- Where are the bodies?
- We have a morgue.
We put them there until
the investigative team arrives
in about a week, I think.
[Clattering]
- There was a droid.
- Disconnected.
There were bits and pieces
of him all over the place.
We put what was left
on the rubbish tow.
The corporal was impaled
by that safety support.
He never knew what hit him.
And the girl?
She drowned in her cryo-tube.
I don't think she was conscious
when it happened.
I'm... sorry.
[Sobbing]
[Exhales]
- [Gasps]
- What's the matter?
- Where is she?
- In the morgue.
I have to see her.
I have to see what's left of her.
Is there any particular reason that
you're so insistent?
Yes. I have to be sure how she died.
I hate to be repetitious about such
a sensitive subject...
but it is perfectly clear
that she drowned.
Was she your daughter?
No. She wasn't.
Um...
could I have a moment
alone, please?
Yes, of course.
[Deep Breath, Exhales]
[Quietly]
Forgive me.
What's she doing?
Okay?
No.
We have to do an autopsy.
- What?
- I told you...
we have to make sure
how she died.
And I told you, she drowned.
I'm not so sure.
l- I have to see inside ofher.
You're disorientated.
Half your system's still in...
I have a very,
very good reason.
Well, perhaps you'd like to
share that reason.
Possible contagion.
What kind exactly?
- Cholera.
- Cholera?
There hasn't been a case
of cholera reported for 200 years.
Please.
[Cutting Skin]
[Yawning]
Everything's in place.
There's no sign of infection.
- No indication of disease.
- The chest.
Open the chest.
Careful.
[Bones Cracking]
[Sobbing]
Lungs.
Flooded with fluid.
Ergo, she drowned.
Now, since I'm not
a complete idiot...
would you like to tell me
what we're really looking for?
Mr. Clemens.
Superintendent.
I don't believe you've met
Lieutenant Ripley.
What's going on, Mr. Clemens?
That's right, sir.
- Well, first...
- [Clattering]
the lieutenant is feeling much better,
I'm happy to say.
Second, in the interest
of public health...
- I am performing an autopsy.
- Without my authority.
Well, there didn't
seem to be time.
But it's turned out all right.
- There's no sign of contagion in the body.
- Good.
But it might be helpful if Lt. Ripley didn't
parade around in front of the prisoners...
as I am told she did in the last hour.
It might also be helpful...
if you kept me informed as to
any change in her physical status.
Or would that be asking too much?
- We have to cremate the bodies.
- Nonsense. We'll keep their bodies on ice...
- till the rescue team arrives.
- On ice.
There is the public health issue.
The lieutenant feels that there is still
a possibility of a communicable infection.
I thought you said
there was no sign of disease.
[Clemens] It would appear
that the child drowned.
But without the benefit
of proper laboratory tests...
it's impossible
to be absolutely certain.
I would consider it unwise...
to tolerate even the possibility
of an unwelcomed virus.
An outbreak of cholera
would look extremely bad on a report.
- Would it not, sir?
- [Clears Throat]
We've 25 prisoners in this facility.
All double "Y" chromos.
All thieves, rapists,
murderers, child molesters. All scum.
Just because they've taken on religion,
doesn't make them any less dangerous.
I try not to offend their convictions.
I don't want to upset the order.
I don't want ripples in the water.
And I don't want a woman walking around
giving them ideas.
I see. For my own personal safety.
Exactly.
I will leave the details of
the cremation to you, Mr. Clemens.
They may use the furnace, but I want
everyone back in lockup by 2200 hours.
[Assistant]
Recorded, sir.
- Ah, Christmas has come early, Murph.
- What do you mean?
- Any dead ox is a good ox.
- You're bloody right.
Smelly bastard's all covered in lice.
There's only seven of the friggin' things
left, and then we're done with them.
God, I hates hosin'
these bastards down.
I always get shite
all over me boots.
- Sure we're gonna hose
these things down, Frank?
- Yeah.
If you had the chance,
what would you say to her?
- What do you mean,
if I got the chance?
- You know.
- If you got the chance.
- You mean, casual like?
Yeah. I mean, how would you put
it to her if you bumped into her
in the mess hall or somewhere?
No problem!
[Grunts]
I've never had any problem
with the ladies.
I'd say to her, "Good day, my dear.
How's it goin'?
Anything I could do to be of service?"
- Then I'd give her the look,
you know... up and down.
- [Grunts]
And I'd give her the wink,
the dirty smile.
- She'd soon get the picture.
- Yeah, right.
And then she'd say, "Kiss my ass,
you horny old fucker!"
I'd be happy to kiss her ass.
I'd be happy to kiss her
anywhere she wants. [Smacks Lips]
- Yeah, but treat 'em mean,
keep 'em keen. Right, Frank?
- Told you before, Murph.
Treat a queen like a whore
and a whore like a queen.
You can't go wrong.
What do you think killed Babe?
Beats me. She just keeled over.
- How old was she?
- The charts say 11.
In her prime. Never mind.
- We'll chop her up later
and throw her in the stew.
- Right.
Hey, Frank.
What's this?
[Clattering]
"We commit this child...
"and this man
to your keeping, O Lord.
"Their bodies...
"have been taken
from the shadow of our nights.
"They have been released...
"from all darkness and pain.
[Gurgling]
"The child and the man...
"have gone beyond our world.
"They are forever eternal...
"and everlasting.
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust."
[Dillon]
Why?
Why are the innocent punished?
Why the sacrifice?
Why the pain?
There aren't any promises.
Nothing's certain.
Only that some get called,
some get saved.
She won't ever know
the hardship and grief...
- for those of us left behind.
- [Squealing]
We commit these bodies
to the void...
with a glad heart.
[Squealing]
For within each seed...
there is a promise of a flower.
[Gurgling]
And within each death...
no matter how small...
there's always a new life.
[Gurgling]
A new beginning.
[Growling]
- Amen.
- [Gurgling]
[All]
Amen.
[Squawking]
[Man] I'll tell you,
it's fucking weird.
The only one to survive
that crash is a woman.
What trouble can she become?
She's already changed everything.
[Chattering Continues]
[Water Running]
What the fuck are we supposed to...
[Continues, Indistinct]
[Men Chattering, Overlapping]
- I mean it.
- [Chattering Continues]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Okay.
There's a lot of talk going around that
we've got some disharmony here?
Any you guys want to tell me
what the problem is?
[Sniffs]
Come on.
Speak to me, brothers.
All right. I'll tell ya.
I don't mind the dark.
I don't mind the bugs.
I don't mind wanderin' around in some
cold, wet, damp tunnel for a week at a time.
I don't mind anything.
But I mind Golic.
That the way you feel about it?
Yeah. The guy's crazy
and he smells bad.
- [Snickering]
- I ain't going out with him anymore.
You got anything to say for yourself?
Well, he's going with you.
Golic is just another poor,
miserable, suffering son of
a bitch just like you and me.
- 'Cept he smells worse.
- And he's crazy.
Knock off the shit!
You got a job to do.
I don't want to hear
another word about Golic.
Okay?
Uh-oh.
As I thought, Mr. Aaron.
- As I thought.
- You called it, sir.
I just wanted to, uh, say thanks for
what you said at the funeral.
My friends would have
appreciated it.
Yeah, well, you don't
wanna know me, lady.
I'm a murderer
and rapist of women.
Really?
Well, I guess
I must make you nervous.
- You have any faith, sister?
- Not much.
Well, we've got a lot of faith here.
Enough even for you.
I thought women weren't allowed.
Well, we've never had any before...
but we tolerate anybody.
- Even the intolerable.
- Thank you.
That's just a statement of principle.
Nothing personal.
You see, we've got
a good place to wait here.
And until now, no temptation.
What are you waiting for?
Huh!
[Chuckles]
We're waiting for God to return...
and raise his servants to redemption.
[Clemens] Dillon and the rest
of the alternative people...
embraced religion, as it were,
about five years ago.
- Tempt you?
- [Ripley] I'm on medication.
- Hardly.
- What kind of religion?
Some sort of apocalyptic, millenarian,
Christian fundamentalist, uh...
- Right.
- Exactly.
Point is, when the company wanted
to close the facility down...
Dillon and the rest of the converts
wanted to stay.
And they were allowed
to remain as custodians...
with two minders...
and a medical officer.
And here we are.
How did you get
this wonderful assignment?
How do you like
your new haircut?
It's okay.
Now that I've gone out
on a limb for you with Andrews...
damaged my already less-than-perfect
relationship with that good man...
and briefed you...
on the humdrum history
of Fury 161...
can you not tell me what
you were looking for in the girl?
You attracted to me?
In what way?
In that way.
Very direct.
I've been out here a long time.
So have I.
Yech!
Hey, Spike.
Spike? Spikey!
Are you down there?
What are you doing?
[Yelling, Indistinct]
I really appreciate your affections...
but I am aware that they...
deflected my question.
In the nicest possible way, of course.
[Ripley]
You're spoiling the mood.
I have a job to do. Hmm.
I just want to know why we had to
cremate the bodies.
And now that I'm in your cot...
you think I owe you an answer.
I think you owe me an answer.
Being in my bed's got
nothing to do with it.
[Sighs]
I had a terrible dream in hypersleep.
And I had to be sure what killed her.
Anyway, I made a mistake.
Possibly.
[Sighs] And now I've made
another mistake.
Really? What's that?
Fraternizing with a prisoner.
Physical contact.
It's against the rules, isn't it?
Definitely. When was this?
I think you know.
I'm not a prisoner.
You have a bar code
on the back of your head.
[Sighs]
That does deserve an explanation.
But I don't think
now is the moment.
Sorry. We are rather
spoiling things, aren't we?
- [Intercom Buzzes]
- [Assistant On Intercom] Mr. Clemens.
- Mr. Aaron.
- Superintendent Andrews
would like you to report...
to vent shaft 22
on the second quadrant now.
- We've had an accident.
- Something serious?
You could call it that.
One of our prisoners has been... diced.
Sorry. I have to go.
Official duties.
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
- Who was it?
- Murphy.
How do you know?
That's his boot.
I gave him the assignment, sir.
He was a wanker.
No apologies, Mr. Aaron.
It wasn't your fault.
Well, not much to say, is there?
- Death was instantaneous.
- No shit.
I take it he was pulled
into the fan.
A sudden rush of air,
I'd imagine, except...
Right. Almost happened to me once.
I've told him so many times,
"Stay away from the fans."
Nobody bloody listens.
Except the fan was blowing.
- What's that?
- I don't know.
I want to see you in my quarters
in 30 minutes, if you please, Mr. Clemens.
Have you got any ideas?
[Beeping]
Here you are. You know,
wandering around without an escort...
is really gonna piss
Superintendent Andrews off.
Will you tell me
about your accident?
One of the prisoners has been killed.
- Really? How?
- Hmm.
In the air shaft.
Poor soul backed into a nine-foot fan.
I found something
at the accident site...
just a bit away
from where it happened.
A mark. A burn.
Rather like the one you found
on the girl's cryo-tube.
Look. I'm on your side.
I want to help, but I need to know
what's going on...
or what you think is going on.
If you really wanna help...
find me a computer
with audio capabilities...
so I can access this flight recorder.
We don't have anything
like that here.
- [Sighs] Well, what about Bishop?
- Bishop?
The droid that crashed with me.
I can point you in the right direction.
I can't join you.
I have a previous engagement.
This'll clop you up.
Golic, don't fidget.
What's all this shit?
It's not properly wrapped.
- What the hell does he ever do right?
- Eat.
- He got that down pretty good.
- Golic!
- You light a candle for Murphy.
- Plus thousands.
[Golic]
He was special.
- [Bangs]
- Never complained about me once.
I loved him.
Is it true what they say?
His head split into a million pieces?
- [Man] Okay. Who's got the matches?
- [Door Slams]
- Sit down, Mr. Clemens.
- Thank you.
- Sugar?
- Uh, no thanks.
- Milk?
- Just a little, please.
Thank you, Mr. Aaron.
Listen to me, you piece of shit.
You screw with me
one more time, I'll cut you in half.
I'm sorry.
I don't think I understand.
At 0700 hours, I received word
from the network.
I may point out this is the first
high-level communication...
this installation has ever received
to my knowledge.
They want this woman looked after.
- They consider her to be very high priority.
- Why?
I have no idea.
But why did you let her
out of the infirmary?
This accident with Murphy
is what happens...
when one of these dumb sons of a bitches
walks around with a hard-on.
I'm a doctor. You're the jailer.
We both know exactly what you are.
- Sit down.
- I think it might be better if I left.
I find you...
unpleasant to be around.
You do? Isn't that lovely?
Consider this, Mr. Clemens.
How would you like me to explain
your sordid history...
to your newfound friend?
For her personal
edification, of course.
Now sit the hell down.
I don't like you.
You're unpredictable.
Insolent. Possibly dangerous.
You question everything!
If I didn't need a medical officer...
- I wouldn't let you within
light years of this operation.
- I'm eternally grateful.
Keep your sarcasms to yourself.
Now, is there anything I should know?
- About what?
- About the woman.
Don't play with me, Mr. Clemens.
You spend every second you can with her.
And I have my suspicions not all of
your concerns with her are medical.
Has she said anything to you...anything
about where she's from, what her mission is?
What the hell she was doing in an E.E. V.?
She told me she was part of a combat unit
that came to grief.
Beyond that, I assume it's all classified.
I haven't pressed her for more.
- That's all?
- That's all.
- You're sure?
- Yes.
- Nothing more?
- No.
Get out of here.
[Door Shuts]
[Raining, Thunderclap]
[Grunts]
[Thunderclap]
[Grunting]
- [Screams]
- Shut up, you fuckin' bitch!
- Shut up, you bitch!
- Nobody's gonna hear you.
- Goddamn it, let go of me!
Damn you! No!
- Hold still! Shh! Shh!
- [Indistinct Yelling]
No.! Goddamn it.!
[Yells]
[Grunts, Groans]
You okay?
Now, you son of a bitch.!
Take off. I gotta reeducate
some of the brothers.
We've gotta discuss
some matters of the spirit.
- Aah!
- Uuh!
Cigarettes!
Okay. Let's do it.
[Man] This is like 10 city blocks.
[Man Chewing Loudly]
- How many?
- This makes 176.
Can't you chew a little quieter?
I'm trying to figure out
how big this compartment is.
I can't think with all this
goddamn noise you're making.
- You're not supposed to swear.
- I'm sorry.
- Now, we've encircled
this entire compartment once...
- Hey.
What?
What the shit is doing that?
- You're swearing.
- Shut up.
It's all right to say "shit."
It ain't against God.
What the hell is going on
with the candles?
Must be the wind
from one of the vent shafts.
Backwash from the closest
circulating unit.
If all the candles go out,
how we gonna know where we are?
Somebody will just have to
go back and relight them.
I guess I'm nominated.
Watch your step, brother.
Okay, who are the comedians?
[Liquid Dripping]
[Screeches]
[Man Yelling]
[Both Yelling]
- Quick, grab it. Here.
- Help me! Help me!
Go! Fuckin' go!
Go, go, go! Quick! Run!
[Both Yelling]
Gimme that!
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Clattering]
[Yells]
Get this fucking thing off me.!
Oh, fuck! [Yells]
Let me go.! [Yells]
No!
[Screaming]
[Beeping]
[Squishing]
[Arm Whirs]
Hey.
Ah, Ripley.
Hi, Bishop.
How are you feeling?
My legs hurt.
Hey, listen, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I'm just a glorified toaster.
How are you?
I like your new haircut.
Bishop, can you access data
on the flight recorder?
No problem.
[Beeping]
Golic?
- I am home.
- What happened on the Sulaco?
Why were our cryo-tubes ejected?
[Computer Voice]
Stasis interrupted.
Fire in cryogenic compartment.
- Repeat. Fire in cryogenic...
- What happened?
What started the fire, Bishop?
Can you hear me?
The fire was electrical.
It was in the subflooring.
Did the sensors pick up anything moving
around on the ship prior to separation?
It's very dark here, Ripley.
I'm not what I used to be.
Just tell me. Does the recorder
indicate anything?
Was there an alien on board?
Yes.
Is it on the Sulaco or did it
come with us on the E.E.V.?
It was with us all the way.
Does the company know?
The company knows everything
that happened on the ship.
It all goes into the computer
and gets sent back to Network.
And they want it.
I hurt. Do me a favor.
Disconnect me.
I could be reworked, but I'll never be
top of the line again.
I'd rather be nothing.
You're sure?
Do it for me, Ripley.
[Whirring]
[Sighs]
[Men Chattering]
It wasn't me! I didn't do it!
[Chattering] It wasn't...
It was the dragon.
Feeds on minds. It was...
- Nobody can stop it.
- What about Boggs and Rains?
But they got s-slaughtered like pigs.
It wasn't me!
- It wasn't me!
- Stark raving mad.
I'm not saying it was anyone's fault,
but he should have been chained up.
You called it, sir.
Mad as a fucking hatter.
Keep him separated from the rest.
I don't want him causing a panic.
- Clemens, sedate this poor idiot.
- Yes.
Not until we know about the brothers.
No, now, pull yourself together.
Talk to me now.
- Now, where are Boggs and Rains?
- It wasn't me.!
[Andrews] Hopeless. You're not gonna
get anything out ofhim.
- It wasn't me.
- We'll have to send out a search team.
I'm afraid we'll have to assume
there's a very good chance...
this simple bastard has murdered them.
Now, you don't know that.
He's never lied to me.
He's crazy, he's a fool,
but he's not a liar.
He's telling the truth.
I'd like to talk to him
about this... this dragon.
- It was a dragon.
- [Andrews] You're not talking
to anyone, Lieutenant.
I'm not interested in your opinion...
because you are not
in full possession of the facts.
This man is a convicted multiple murderer,
known for particularly brutal crimes.
Isn't that right, Mr. Dillon?
Yeah. That part's right.
Then I'll talk to you. It's important.
When I have finished
with my official duties...
I will be quite pleased
to have a little chat, yes?
[Andrews] Let me see if I have
this correct, Lieutenant.
It's an eight-foot creature of some kind,
with acid for blood...
and it arrived on your spaceship.
It kills on sight
and is generally unpleasant.
And, of course, you expect me to accept
all this on your word.
No, I don't expect anything.
- Quite a story, Mr. Aaron.
- Right, sir. It's a beauty.
- Never heard anything quite like it, sir.
- Expect not.
Tell me, Lieutenant,
what would you suggest we do?
Well, what kind
of weapons have you got?
This is a prison.
It's not a good idea to allow prisoners
access to firearms.
What keeps them from killing you?
Fear. There's no way to escape.
With the arrival of the next supply ship,
the company will eliminate them.
This is a maximum security prison...
and you have no weapons of any kind?
We have some carving knives in the abattoir.
A few more in the mess hall.
Some fire axes scattered about the place.
Nothing terribly formidable.
That's all?
We're on the honor system.
- Then we're fucked.
- No, you're fucked.
Confined to the infirmary.
Quarantined.
Mr. Aaron will escort you.
I think you'll be safe from any large,
nasty beast while you're there, right?
Yes, that's a good girl.
- [Intercom Buzzes]
- [Aaron] Let's all report to the mess hall.
Superintendent Andrews wants a meeting.
Mess hall, right away, people.
Isn't there any way off of this place?
Some way to escape?
[Laughs] No. Supply ship comes
every six months.
- And that's it?
- Mm-hmm.
Fuck.
They are sending somebody
to pick you up quite soon, I gather.
Really. [Clears Throat]
What's soon?
I don't know. Nobody's ever been
in a hurry to get here before.
Do you want to tell me
what you and Andrews talked about?
No.
- You'll just say I'm crazy.
- [Liquid Swishing]
- That's a bit uncharitable.
- [Inhales, Coughs]
How are you feeling?
[Sighs] Not so hot.
[Clears Throat]
Sore throat.
Sick to my stomach.
Pissed off.
Well, that's understandable
given the circumstances.
Perhaps I should give you
one of my special cocktails.
[Golic] I don't know why everybody
blames everybody for everything.
Nobody's perfect, only human.
I don't know a perfect human.
There's no such thing
as a perfect human.
In an insane world...
a sane man...
must... appear... insane.
That's very profound, Golic.
Thank you.
You married?
- Me?
- You should get married, have kids.
Pretty girl. I used to know
lots of them back home.
They used to like me.
For a while.
You're gonna die too.
- Are you?
- What?
Married.
[Ripley] Why?
- Just curious.
- No.
- How about leveling with me?
- Could you be more specific?
When I asked how you got assigned here,
you avoided the question.
And then when I asked about the prison
I.D. tattooed on the back of your head...
you ducked me again.
It's a long, sad story...
and more than
a little melodramatic.
Try me.
- [Liquid Swishing]
- If you insist.
After my student years...
despite the fact that I had become...
secretly addicted to morphine...
I was considered
to be most promising...
a man with a future.
And during my first residency,
I did a 36-hour stretch on an E.R.
So, I went out and I got
more than a little drunk.
Then I got called back.
Boiler had blown on a fuel plant...
and there were 30 casualties.
And 11 of them died.
Not as a result of the accident...
but because I prescribed
the wrong dosage of painkiller.
I got seven years in prison
and my license reduced to a 3-C.
At least I got off the morphine.
I'm sorry.
I think I was let off lightly.
Did you serve your time here?
I got to know
this motley crew quite well.
So when they stayed, I stayed.
Nobody else would employ me.
So, do you still trust me with a needle?
[Gasping]
[Alien Screeches]
- [Yells]
- [Whimpering]
[Hissing]
- [Growls, Hisses]
- [Yells]
[Whimpering]
Magnificent.
[Dillon] Give us strength,
O Lord, to endure.
We recognize we are poor sinners
in the hands of an angry God.
Let the circle be unbroken
until the day. Amen.
- [All] Amen.
- [Dillon] What the fuck is happening here?
What the fuck is this
bullshit that's comin' down?
We got murder. We got rape.
We got brothers in trouble.
I don't want no more bullshit
around here!
Now, we got problems,
we stand together.
Yes. Thank you, Mr. Dillon. All right.
Once again, this is rumor control.
Here are the facts.
At 0800 hours,
prisoner Murphy...
through carelessness on his part...
was found dead in vent shaft 17.
He seems to have been
sucked into a ventilator fan.
[Panting]
At about 2100 hours...
prisoner Golic reappeared
in a deranged state.
Prisoners Boggs and Rains are missing.
There seems to be a good chance that
they have met with foul play...
- at the hands of prisoner Golic.
- [Sighs]
We need to organize
and send out a search party.
Volunteers will be appreciated.
[Panting]
I think it's fair to say that
our smoothly running facility...
has suddenly developed
a few problems.
I can only hope we are able to all
pull together over the next few days...
until the rescue team arrives
for Lieutenant Ripley.
It's here! It got Clemens!
- Stop this raving at once! Stop it!
- I'm telling you it's here!
Aaron, get that foolish woman
back to the infirmary!
- [Andrews Yells]
- [All Chattering, Yelling]
[Man]
Move it.!
Out of my way.!
Fuck!
[Dillon]
We give you thanks, O Lord.
Your wrath has come, and the time
is near for us to bejudged.
The apocalypse is upon us.
Let us be ready.
Let your mercy be just.
- That thing was massive.
- Amen.
- [All] Amen.!
- I saw it.
- Yeah, I know.
What the fuck do we do now?
Who's in fucking charge?
Organize. We got
to organize, right?
Right. Well, I guess
I'm next in line.
- 85's gonna be in charge.
Jesus, give us a break!
- Don't call me that.
[Aaron] Okay, look. There's no way
I can replace Andrews.
He was a good man. I know you guys
didn't appreciate him.
Aaron, we don't want
to hear that shit now.
Hey, sister, what about you?
You're an officer.
How about showing us
a little leadership?
Forget fucking Shirley Temple.
You take charge.
- Right.
- You run things here anyway.
No fuckin' way.
I'm not the officer type.
I just take care of my own.
[Man] Well, what does
this fucking beast want?
Is this mother
gonna try for us all?
- Yeah.
- Well, ain't that sweet?
- So how are we gonna stop it?
- [Clears Throat]
- We have no weapons. Is that correct?
- Right.
I haven't seen one
exactly like this before.
Moves differently.
But the others
were afraid of fire...
Not much else.
- Can we seal off this area?
- No chance.
The installation's 10 miles square.
- There's 600 air ducts
running to the surface.
- What about video?
I see these closed-circuit monitors
everywhere. We could try to find it that way.
The video system hasn't worked in years.
Nothing much works here.
We've got a lot of technology,
no way to fix it.
- What 85 is trying to tell you is...
- Don't call me that!
we ain't got no entertainment center,
no climate control...
no video system,
no surveillance...
no freezers, no fucking ice cream...
no rubbers, no women, no guns.
All we got here is shit!
Oh, what the hell are we
even talking to her for?
She's the one
that brought the fucker.
Why don't we just get her head
and shove it through the fucking wall?
Sounds good to me.
[Dillon]
Morse.
Why don't you shut the fuck up?
Hmm.
Right.
Right. What are we going to do?
- What's this?
- Um...
that leads from the mess hall
to the infirmary.
It's a ventilation shaft.
Then we go in there, flush it out.
Hey. Hey, look, there's miles and miles
of tunnel through there.
It won't go far.
It'll nest in this area.
Right around...
- here.
- How do you know that?
It's like a lion.
It sticks close to the zebras.
Zebras? Oh, right.
But, look. Running around down here
in the dark... Are you kidding?
Once you get out of this main shaft,
there's no overheads.
- Don't we have flashlights?
- We've got thousands of'em, but no batteries.
- I told you, nothing works.
- Torches?
Do we have the capacity
to make fire?
Most humans have enjoyed that privilege
since the Stone Age.
No need to be sarcastic.
Never been used. They were gonna
dump a lot of nuclear crap in there.
Never got around to it.
It's clean as a whistle inside.
This the only way in or out?
That's right. Walls are
six feet thick, solid steel.
Really knew how
to build these babies.
You're saying we get
something in there...
there's no way it can get out?
That's right. No fucking way.
[Whistles]
This is where we keep it.
I forget what the stuff's called.
- Quinitricetyline.
- I knew that.
Right. I've got to get these section
arrangements organized with Dillon...
for the paintbrush, uh...
- So, um...
- David.
- Yeah. You can get
these drums organized.
- Right, 85.
And, uh, don't call me that.
What's this "85" thing?
A couple of us sneaked a look at
his personnel file the day he arrived.
It's his I.Q.
I saw a drum of this stuff...
fall into a beachhead bunker once.
The blast put a tug
in dry dock for 17 weeks.
Great stuff!
All right. Let me get this straight.
You want to burn it down
and out of the pipes...
force it in here, slam the door...
- and trap its ass?
- Right.
And you want help
from us y-chromo boys, huh?
You got something better to do?
Why should we put our ass
on the line for you?
Your ass is already on the line.
The only question is...
what are you gonna do about it?
[Chattering]
Look at this.
There's only one of these fucking batteries
in 2,000 that works.
- Hey, it could have been a lot worse.
- Yeah.
We might have got
the paintbrush detail.