Typical of Victor Von Doom
to build a 30-foot statue
of himself.
Well, it's obviously aimed at first-time visitors
to create feelings of smallness...
inadequacy.
Good thing
it ain't workin'.
Reed, what are we doing here?
This guy's fast-food, strip-mall science.
This wasn't our first stop,
in case you forgot.
Besides, Victor's not that bad.
He's just a little... larger than life.
- Hi, Reed Richards and Ben Grimm-
- Executive elevator. Top floor.
What's it take to get
a smile around this joint?
[ Woman ]
Von Doom Industries, at the forefront
of aerospace technology
and biomedical engineering-
The unparalleled leader
in government defense systems
[ Reed ]
My research suggests
that exposure to
a high-energy cosmic storm...
borne
on solar winds...
might have triggered the evolution
of early planetary life.
In six weeks
another cloud...
In six weeks another cloud...
with the same elemental profile...
will pass Earth's orbit.
A study, conducted in space...
could fundamentally advance
our knowledge...
about the structure
of the human genome...
cure countless diseases,
extend human life
give kids a chance to live longer,
stronger, healthier-
Turn it offPlease
- I don't think I've explained my proposal fully.
- No, I think you have.
Same old Reed- always stretching,
reaching for the stars...
with the weight of the world
on his back.
But dreams don't pay the bills,
do they?
You remember,
when we were in school...
we talked about working together.
Well, that's what
I was about to explain.
The storm is deadly
but the shields
on your station's control room
are designed to protect
any occupants inside
So, it's not just my money you want.
It's my toys.
Tell me, if NASA doesn't trust you,
then why should I?
That's my job-
to stay a step ahead...
to know what other men don't.
- I can't take this.
- Ben, this is business. Just work.
He's right, Ben-
It is just business.
I think you both know
my director of genetic research
Susan Storm
One more thing he's got.
- Hey, Susie
- Hey.
Oh, it's so nice to see you.
How's Debbie?
- Great.
- Uh, how have you been?
- Never better.
- This isn't gonna be a problem, is it?
- Oh, not at all.
- No, l-
- Good
Then you are just in time...
to hear the great Reed Richards...
ask me for help.
You made a lot of folks at M.I.T.
Feel like a junior high science fair...
so you'll excuse me
if I savor the moment.
You back this mission...
and I'll sign over a fair percentage
of any applications-
The number is 75,
and its applications and patents.
- What about his firstborn?
- Ben.
[ Laughing ]
Come on.
Twenty-five percent of a billion is enough
to keep the lights on a while, isn't it?
Maybe even pay off your fourth mortgage
on the Baxter Building.
Deal?
Well, then, to our future.
Together.
It's funny how things turn out,
isn't it?
Hilarious.
He knew about NASA.
Maybe he made the call to shut us down.
Ben, think about all the people
we can help if this works. Huh?
Look, we got what we wanted.
That's enough.
A few days in space. It'll be great.
What's the worst that can happen?
If Reed's right, this little trip
could double our stock offerings.
And if he's not?
Reed's always right.
Good thing he doesn't always know
what he's got.
[ Beeps ]
Reed, you should know those solar winds
have been picking up speed.
- I factored them into my coordinates.
- Right.
Of course you did.
In theory.
- It's a little different once you're out there.
- I can assure you-
When are we leaving?
I'll be scheduling the launch.
You can call me in the morning
for resources and crew.
- I think I remember the number.
- It's been changed.
[ Ben Clears Throat ]
I was hoping Ben
could pilot the mission.
We already have a pilot
on our payroll.
But you're welcome to ride shotgun.
Remember my brotherJohnny?
##[ Rock ]
##[ Man Singing ]
- ##[ Continues ]
- Can't do it. Cannot do it.
External S.R.B.'s,
orbital system engines.
- It's just like the shuttle you flew-
- No!
- I cannot take orders from the underwear model.
- Oh, come on, now.
That wingnut washed out of NASA for
sneaking two Victoria's Secret wannabes...
into a flight simulator.
- Youthful high spirits.
- They crashed it into a wall.
A flight simulator.
When have I ever asked you to do something
you absolutely said you could not do?
Five times.
- I had it at four.
- Well, this makes five.
##[ Continues ]
##[ Ends ]
[ Woman On PA]
Attention, all personnel
Commencing launch sequence
in six hours
[ Ben ]
I miss you already, Debs.
[ Man ]
Captain on the bridge!
Digital camera- $254.
Memory stick- $59.
The look on your hard-ass
former C.O.'s face...
when he finds out he's
your junior officer- priceless.
- [ Zipper Zips ]
- [ Chuckles ] Thank you. That's so sweet.
I can handle this ship.
I can even handle
Mr. Blond Ambition.
But I don't know if I should be flying
or doing Swan Lake in these suits.
Who the hell came up with these?
Victor did.
The synthetics act as a second skin,
adapting to your body's individual needs.
See, now that means it keeps
the hot stuffhot and the cool stuff cool
Wow. Fantastic.
Material made from self-regulating,
unstable molecules.
I've been working on
a formula for this.
Great minds think alike.
- Here you go, Ben.
- Thanks, sweetie.
Reed
[ Von Doom ]
E TA until cosmic event, nine hours
If you're good, maybe next time
Daddy'll let you drive.
You keep talkin',
and there won't be a next time.
Long way
from the projection booth...
at the Hayden Planetarium,
isn't it?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
We can monitor the cloud's approach
and observe the tests from here.
Is it safe?
The shields on the station
should protect us.
- "Should"?
- What's the matter, Ben?
Getting paranoid in your old age?
Let's start loading those samples.
Get your suit ready, Ben.
So I see you're still doing
all the heavy lifting.
Maybe you should have stayed in the lab.
Fieldwork never suited you.
He does the talkin'.
I do the walkin'. Got it?
So, take a walk, Ben.
Actually, if you'll all excuse me,
I need to borrow Susan...
for a moment
Sure.
Please tell me your guy's not trying
to rekindle things with my sister again.
Of course not.
It's strictly business.
Yes, well, his eyes
say differently, don't they?
Hey. Two hearts
got busted last time.
Maybe she's not over it either.
Wow, Dr. Phil, that's deep.
Let's think about that.
You got Victor-
more money than God, stud of the year-
and you got Reed,
world's dumbest smart guy...
worth less than a postage stamp.
That's a real toss-up.
Don't trouble your tiny little mind.
Don't wander off now, boy.
- [ Beeping ]
- [ Computer ] Securing air lock chamber
Surprised I agreed to Reed's proposal?
I understand the business reasons.
Well, when you're
looking at your future...
it doesn't hurt
to find closure about the past.
Susan, every man dreams he'll meet
a woman he can give the world to.
In my case,
it's not just a metaphor.
[ Beeps ]
[ Computer ]
Opening viewing station shield
[ Beeping ]
That can't be right.
[ Computer ] Event threshold
in T-minus nine minutes, 47 seconds
[ Reed ] That's impossible
It should be seven hours
We've been together
two years now.
It's been a good two years, Victor.
The company's accomplished so much.
Right. Of course. The company.
But I've come to realize...
that all the accomplishments in the world
mean nothing without someone
to share them with.
- Um-
- I've lived my life unafraid of taking big steps.
- Now it's time to take the biggest step of all.
- Victor-
If it helps,
think of this as a... promotion.
Victor, l-
I have four words.
Four little words that can change
our lives forever.
[ Reed ]
The cloud is accelerating!
We've got minutes until it hits,
not hours.
- Victor, that storm is deadly We need to abort
- Get a grip, Reed
We didn't come all this way to lose our nerve
at the first glitch. Just close the shields.
- Ben is still out there.
- So reel him in.
We came here to do a job,
so let's do it Quickly
Victor, Reed's right.
We have less than six minutes.
- Ben, get inside now!
- What's going on?
I ain't done arrangin'
your flowers yet, egghead.
[ Reed ]
Ben, turn around
- [ Ben ] Guys, I'm not gonna make it.
- You gotta jump!
It's the only way!
- What are you doing?
- Closing the shields.
- You can't just leave them out there.
- Watch me.
You can't help them
any more than I can!
I can try.
Come on, Ben! You got this!
Johnny, get ready to close the portal.
[ Groaning ]
[ Yelling ]
- [ Beeping ]
- [ Groans ]
[ Groans ]
- You okay?
- Oh. Yeah.
Ben! Ben!
Ben!
[ Monitor Beeping ]
Wake up Ben
Hey, rise and shine, big boy.
How you feeling?
- [ Groans ] Where am I?
- Back on Earth.
We're in quarantine.
Victor's medical facility.
Reed? Sue?
Oh, they're fine.
Everybody else is fine.
What's wrong with me?
I swear to you, Ben, they've done
everything humanly possible.
The best plastic surgeons in the world
are here, Ben. You had the best.
- Give me that mirror
- I don't know if that's a good idea.
- They said the shock alone-
- I said, give me that goddamn mirror!
Okay, Ben.
Just be strong.
Unfortunately, the doctors just
couldn't do anything to fix your face
[ Yells ]
Hey. Nice do.
[ Chuckles ]
Likin' the grandpa look.
What?
[ TV: Reporter ] You've been charged
with moving science a little too fast
[ Von Doom ]
By whom, my competitors?
[ Door Closes ]
Danger is always part of this
- How's she doing?
- Stable.
And her vitals are strong.
Blood panels show no irradiation.
Good.
- You'll step up this protocol-
- Every four hours, yes.
We know what we're doing.
- Another day of observation, and you're all clear.
- [ Door Opens ]
[ Cart Squeaking, Rattling ]
She's allergic to orchids.
Put the sunflowers by her bed.
They're her favorites
[ Door Closes ]
Well, Victor
the bank would like
to congratulate you...
on the fastest free-fall
since the Depression
- We can't even give your stock away.
- Ned, I can turn this around.
You're going to have to, Victor,
or we pull out.
- You have a week.
- You're enjoying this, aren't you, Ned?
One week.
Whoa, whoa, whoa
Where do we think we're going?
I don't know if we've noticed, but the sickest
runs this side of the Alps are right outside.
Yeah, I've noticed. But there are rules here.
You can't leave until we-
Until we've finished the tests. I know.
I've never been good with rules.
You let me know
how those come out.
- Do you wanna help me with the zipper?
- This is not a ski resort.
Not yet.
Luckily, Grandma still sends care packages.
It's amazing.
- For an 80-year-old woman, you'd be surpri-
- You are trouble.
Mmm "Trouble"is my middle name
- Oh, you're hot.
- Why, thank you. So are you.
- And I'm not afraid to cry.
- No, I mean you feel a little feverish.
I've never felt better in my life.
My God, you smell good.
- When do you get off work?
- 4:00, but l-
Tell you what. You meet me at 4:01
at the top of the mountain.
That'll give you
a minute to freshen up.
This is yours. That's mine.
[ Whispers ]
Nurses!
[ Monitor Beeping ]
How long was I out?
Hey. Three days.
I was worried about you.
How are you feeling?
Solid.
Uh, it was a close one, though, huh?
What was that about?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
I've been going over the figures again and again,
and they all add up.
I just don't understand.
Maybe I should've aborted-
Reed, it was a freak of nature.
You couldn't have possibly predicted it.
- Let it go.
- [ Exhales ]
You know, you live through
something like this...
it really makes you appreciate
having the right woman in your life
- Yeah, you and Debbie are perfect.
- I'm not talking about Debbie.
What? Come on.
She's got a good thing with Victor.
- He's smart, he's powerful, he's successful-
- Maybe you should date him then.
Ben, she ended up
with the right guy.
Things worked out for the best.
Do I have to do everything myself?
##[ Rock ]
##[ Man Singing ]
You should stay to the right.
The left might give you trouble.
- I think we should drop, like, 10 more feet.
- Good.
Last one down
springs for room service!
Whoo-hoo!
##[ Continues ]
My future wife!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo!
You're losing!
All right, no more kid stuff.
Check this out!
##[ Continues ]
- You're on fire!
- Thanks! You're pretty good too!
No! You're on fire! Look!
##[ Continues ]
- Whoa!
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Whoa-ohh!
Care to join me?
I can only stay for one drink.
I have to meet Victor.
Oh. Wouldn't want
to keep Vic waiting.
Reed, what are you doing here?
I thought-
Great!
Uh, maybe you can join us
- How's the IPO now?
- It's fallen.
We're looking at low 20s.
It's a good number, considering the fallout from-
From Reed's disaster?
Get me on the am shows,
Larry King, cover of the Journal.
Gonna have to do something
about this scar.
Make sure they only shoot me
from my left side.
Actually, uh, the scar's tracking well.
People seem to think
it humanizes you.
[ Chuckles ]
And that's a good thing?
[ Gasps, Sighs ]
Maybe you should get some rest.
Later.
First I have some unfinished business.
A deal that needs closing.
Sir, I have always wondered-
Why Sue?
You could have any other woman
in the world
That's why. Because I could
have any other woman.
- [ Laughing ]
- No, let me tell the story! Let me tell the story!
- [ Gurgling ]
- Oh-
[ Gasps ]
- [ Gurgling Continues ]
- Wow.
- [ Ben Exhales ]
- You all right?
[ Sighs ]
Bad shrimp.
I think I'd better go lie down.
Excuse me.
[ Groans ]
Oh, God.
[ Ben Groans, Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Reed ]
So, are you feeling better?
Yes. Thank you.
Good.
That's, uh, good.
You always had a way with words.
Uh-Wow.
I should be going, 'cause, uh...
I have to meet Victor.
I'm really happy for you and Victor.
You're really happy
for me and Victor?
I can tell you guys are enjoying
what was the best part of our relationship.
- Which was?
- Passion.
For science.
You are such a dork, Reed.
You never got it,
and you never will.
- What did I say?
- Unless it's explained to you in quantum physics.
I just wanted
to let you know that I was-
It's been two years, and all you can say
is you're happy for me and some other guy?
Victor may be a lot of things
but at least he's not afraid
to fight for what he wants
It's nice to be wanted
sometimes, Reed...
to be seen and heard.
Look at me.
I can't.
- What do you mean, you can't? Look at me!
- Sue, look at your hands.
[ Gasps ]
Hey! You guys-
Hey. You are never gonna believe
what just happened to me.
What?
Oh. Well, I can explain this.
[ Crackling ]
[ Grunting, Exhaling ]
It has to be the cloud.
It's fundamentally altered our D.N.A.
Let's not jump to conclusions.
We need a massive amount of evidence
before making that leap.
Whoa! Guys, look
[ Fingers Snap ]
Now, picture that, but everywhere!
It was everywhere!
What?
The cloud has fundamentally
altered our D.N.A.
[ Cackles ]
Cool!
- And you know what, guys? I think I was flying.
- We need to find Ben.
- [ Groaning, Screaming ]
- [ Monitors Beeping ]
- [ Heart Beating Rapidly ]
- [ Ben Roaring ]
I said cut it out, Johnny.
- Still getting the hang of it.
- Hey, Ben! It's Reed!
- Stop.
- All right.
- All right?
- Yes!
- God! What's wrong with you?
- God! What?
- Sue, do you know the code?
- [ Roaring, Groaning ]
Hey, Ben! Open up!
- You all right, Ben?
- Hey, does somebody have keys to these doors?
[Johnny ]
Anybody?
Just break the glass
It can't be that thick
[ Lock Pad Beeping ]
[ Beeps ]
That's gross.
[ Thudding, Crashing ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Reed ]
Ben?
Look! Look, look, look, look!
What is that thing?
What's going on?
What happened in here?
- Are you feeling all right?
- I'm fine. Just a few scrapes, that's all.
Ben did this He's had some kind of
reaction to exposure from the cloud
We all have, um, different symptoms
Symptoms?
- Victor, um, I should have-
- Just find him.
Anybody got any ideas
where the big guy's going?
[ Reed Sighs ]
He's going home
[ Train Passing Overhead ]
- [ Men Laughing, Chattering ]
- ## [ R&B ]
[ Glass Shatters ]
- [ Dial Tone ]
- Oh, you gotta be kiddin' me.
[ Grunting ]
- [ Beep Tones Overlapping ]
- [ Growls ]
Little buttons! Hello, Operator?
[ Line Rings, Clicks ]
- [ Woman ] Hello?
- Debs? It's me.
Ben? Are you all right?
You sound a little different.
- Uh, listen, I need you to come out front.
- Out front?
- You're home, baby?
- [ Sarcastic Chuckle ]
- Yeah.
- [ Laughs ]
I got a surprise for you.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, I got a little one for you too.
Ben?
Where are you?
I'm over here.
Don't come any closer for a sec, okay?
It's gonna-
It's gonna be a bit of a shock
Honey, what's going on?
Debs...
remember w-when we used to say...
together forever,
no matter what?
Yeah?
Baby, you're scaring me.
- Oh, my God.
- Deb.
It's me. It's still me.
It was the accident.
- Let me explain.
- No! Don't touch me!
- Debs!
- [ Horn Honks ]
[ Cab Driver ]
What are you doin', lady?
Hey! I'm callin'the police!
[ Woman ]
Everybody all right?
- [ Man ] I saw him! It's that guy over there!
- [ Dog Barking ]
[ Man ]
What the hell's going on out there?
[ Grumbling ]
Oh, yeah, Ben.
A few days in space. It'll be great.
What's the worst that could happen?
Hey, little guy.
[ Chuckles ]
You're not afraid of me, are ya?
[ Cooing ]
[ Grumbles ]
Perfect.
Thanks.
[ Muttering ]
- [ Water Splashes ]
- Hey!
- [ Gasps ]
- You think you got problems?
You take a good look, pal.
Huh. How bad could it be, right?
- I don't think you-
- [ Muttering Continues ]
[ Sighs ]
Okay, pal, take it easy.
No, no, no. Don't go out there.
I said stop, you fruitcake!
No, no, no. Come closer.
That's further! Come closer!
I said stop! No, no, no!
Whoa!
[ Grunting ]
[ Ben ]
Feet!
[ Grunts ]
[ Horn Honking ]
Whoa!
- [ Shouting, Chattering ]
- Come here!
[ Horns Honking ]
- [ Shouting, Chattering ]
- All right.
Calm down.
You wanna be scared?
[ Shouts ] Fine!
[ Screams ]
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Coughing ]
- Give me a couple tow trucks.
- Get back! Get back!
Get back in your vehicles!
We'll tell you when you can go!
- What are we gonna do now?
- We're not gonna get past these guys.
But you could.
[ Grunts ]
Sorry about the truck, pal.
Come on.
A little help here
You wanna hit the button, sir?
- Stuck.
- [ Grumbles ]
Sue, your clothes. Lose them.
Oh. Right.
This is so wrong.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Sue ] What?
[ Gasps ]
Oh!
- Wow. You've been working out.
- Shut up!
All right.
[ Grunting ]
All right, freeze!
Now, just, uh-
just put the man
in the seat down!
Do it!
Any more great ideas? Why don't you strip
down and have 100 people stare at you?
- Sue
- What?
Oh. Hmph!
I'm gonna need therapy.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
- Excuse me Coming through
- [ Gasping, Shouting ]
Right now, uh,
just back away from him
And, uh, I want you
to put your hands
on your head right-
[ Horn Blasting, Siren Wailing ]
954 approaching scene.
- I still can't believe you made me do that.
- We got through, didn't we?
Just find Ben.
- Stay back of the bridge!
- [ Shouting, Chattering Continues ]
Ben! Ben!
Mom! Mom?
[ Screaming ]
[ Whimpering ]
- Whoa!
- [ Whines ]
[ Groaning ]
- Stay here, okay?
- [ Grunting ]
Coming! Hold on!
- [ Shouting ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Grunting ] No, you-
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Whimpers ]
- [ Grunting Continues ]
Don't.
- No!
- [ Screams ]
[ Continues Screaming ]
[ Yells ]
[ Continues Grunting ]
- Hang on!
- [ Onlookers Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
- Huh?
- I got ya.
[ Yelling ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Officer On Bullhorn ] This is the police!
Get down on the ground!
[ Woman ]
Don't shoot! He's a hero!
- Get down on the ground now!
- [ Shouting, Chattering ]
- [ Onlookers Cheering ]
- Ben!
Whoo-hoo!
I swear to you...
I will do everything in my power...
until there is not a breath left in me-
You're gonna be Ben again.
- How 'bout this guy?
- I don't know
I tell you what-
I never seen nothin'like him before
I told you I felt fine.
Where are your ears?
- There are some folks outside
that want to talk to you.
- We're not going public.
- We're scientists, not celebrities.
- It's too late, son.
Look.
- When a New York Fire Department ladder truck...
- See that?
Became part of the tragedy.
But the rescue itself is not the story
One of the four stretched
to an amazing length-
That's what they're calling you-
the Fantastic Four.
- Cool!
- No, wait! Where are you going?
- I'm gonna go talk to 'em.
- No!
- We should think this through.
- That's great. Brainstorm.
Where is it? Left?
[ Sue ]
Get back here right now! Johnny!
- Settle down!
- [ Reporters Clamoring, Shouting Questions ]
Do you believe this?
- Which one of you is the leader?
- That would be me.
No, seriously.
Okay, son, you're on.
Uh...
during our recent mission
to the Von Doom space station...
we were exposed to
as-yet unidentified radioactive energy.
- What happened on the bridge?
- How can you stretch?
- Is it true you can fly?
- Yeah, I'm working on it. It's actually difficult-
No, actually, we do not know
much more than you do at this point.
Uh, sir, Larry King just canceled.
Apparently there's a bigger story.
NASDAQ was up 9.9-
Bravest-
Actually, here they come now.
You had to see it
to believe it, folks The man-
named the Fantastic Four-
We will be going directly to our lab
to diagnose our symptoms.
[ Reporter ]
Symptoms? Is this some kind of disease?
No! No, no, no.
It's not a disease.
Symptoms? If having special powers
is a disease, then, yeah, we got it bad.
Excuse me.
That thing doesn't look so fantastic.
Ben Grimm is a genuine American hero.
What he means is,
every team needs a mascot.
- [ Laughing ]
- A new day is dawning.
The day of the Fantastic Four!
[ Clamoring, Shouting Questions ]
Look- Look, we went up to space
to find a way to understand D.N. A... .
Cure disease, save lives
Well, now it's our D.N.A.,
our "disease," our lives on the line.
Thank you.
No more questions.
This is how you turn things around?
These freaks on the front page...
your company's in the obituaries?
- I was planning to use the publicity-
- The board's in agreement
- The bank's lost enough already.
- Wait a minute.
It's too late, Victor.
Do you know how much money
I've invested in this company?
Victor, stop.
This isn't a negotiation.
It's a notification
We're pulling out
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Is all that for you, Dr. Richards?
I'm afraid so.
Come on, Ben. Smile.
They wanna like you, bud. Say hi.
[ All Gasping ]
Uh, don't do drugs!
[ Cheering Resumes ]
- [ Grumbles ]
- [ Bell Dings ]
Welcome back to the Baxter,
Dr. Richards.
I've got the usual for you.
- Good to have you back, sir.
- Thanks, Willie.
We had a tough year.
Yeah, like, nine straight.
- [ Bell Dings ]
- [ Pulleys Creaking ]
[ Thuds ]
[ Creaking Continues, Stops ]
Either we're moving
really fast or not at all.
[ Alarm Buzzes ]
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Doors Slide Open ]
I'll take the stairs.
[ Bell Dings ]
How come Ben can't turn it
on and off like we can?
That's what we're here to find out.
- If it happened to him-
- What? You mean, like, we won't
be able to turn it off either?
- That would save time. Ha!
- You wanna walk around on fire
the rest of your life?
- Is that a trick question?
- Grow up.
Come on. Am I the only guy
who thinks this is cool?
We should stay here until we can
define the extent of our changes...
and figure out how to reverse them.
Whoa.
[ Sue ]
Believe it or not, he lives here
[ Reed ] But I have to warn you,
it's gonna be a little crowded in some areas
[Johnny Laughs ]
So, what do you think?
I don't know, Reed.
I think you might be bringing
your work home with you.
[ Laughs ] Come on. Let me show
you guys where you'll be staying.
Busy guy.
[ Crowd Chattering ]
- Hi, everybody.
- Mr. Von Doom!
Would you like to comment
on the recent failure of your I.P.O.?
[ Female Reporter ]
What about the rumors of a takeover?
God, I was so worried about you
Victor
- I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to call.
- Please.
No apologies
I've arranged for your things
to be moved to one of my condos.
- You'll have round-the-clock care.
- Thank you.
That's very generous of you, but I think
I should stay here with my brother...
until we get a handle on things.
Susan, I think you should
let my doctors have a look at you.
[ Reed ]
Victor
What are you doing here?
I'm starting to wonder
the same thing.
- How much do you know
about what happened to you?
- Not much.
- We need to run tests
to see the extent of the damage.
- You let me know what I can do.
We're all in this together now.
Victor, wait
I just wanted to say I'm sorry
the mission didn't go as planned.
Didn't go as planned?
It was a catastrophe
You ruined the lives of four people
With all due respect, we're both to blame.
I told you to abort.
Abort?
I put my company, my name,
billions of dollars on the line.
- I will not let you make me look like a fool.
- If we could understand-
I don't want to understand it!
This isn't one of your science projects!
I just want to fix it, fast!
- [ Heavy Footsteps ]
- [ Ben ] Is there a problem?
[ Sighs ]
No.
- [ Bell Dings ]
- No problem, Ben.
Just pay your damn electric bill
and get to work on finding a cure.
[ Bell Dings ]
Whoa!
Wow!
He's heating up from his core.
And his vitals are completely normal
If we're going to identify
the source of the mutation
we need to isolate
your recombinant D.N. A... .
So we can activate
positional genomes.
- Huh?
- We have to do a physical
to see what got zapped.
Oh. Why didn't you just say so?
[ Reed ]
His internal organs are completely solid
[ Heart Beating ]
How bad is it?
You know, I used to smoke.
[ Beeping ]
[ Reed ]
It's not invisibility per se
You should be able to bend light
around other objects, even people
if you could control
your emotional state better.
- Excuse me?
- If you had more self-control,
you could locate the trigger.
Can you remember
your exact emotions on the bridge?
Anger.
Rage. Frustration.
Okay, is there any way to duplicate
that feeling? Some memory or-
I'm sure I can
come up with something.
- You feel anything?
- Nope.
Okay.
[ Stammering ]
It's hotter than I anticipated.
- Johnny, back it down.
- I can go hotter!
[ Sue ]
Johnny, just back it down!
[ Groans ]
Johnny, back it down right now!
Johnny!
- [ Alarm Buzzes ]
- Ohh!
[Johnny Laughing ]
Buzz-kill!
You guys are crampin'my style!
Johnny, you were at 4,000 Kelvin.
- Any hotter, and you're approaching supernova.
- Sweet!
No, not sweet.
That's the temperature of the sun.
Not only could you kill yourself.
But you could set fire to Earth's atmosphere
and destroy all human life
Got it.
Supernova- bad.
How's that coming?
Oh, I'm so sorry.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. Fine.
- You sure?
- Yep.
I, um-
[ Chuckles ]
You probably thought that was
some form of latent hostility.
What in the world
would give me that idea?
I mean, you broke up with me, right?
- [ Chuckles ] Are you kidding?
- No
I distinctly remember
you walked out my door, ergo-
I was ready for the next step.
You weren't. Ergo, I walked.
It was a little more complicated
than that.
I just wanted
to share an apartment.
What was so complicated about that?
- There were a lot of variables to consider.
- No, there weren't
There was you and me.
No variables, no math.
It was actually the simplest thing in the world.
- But like always, Reed, your head got in the way.
- No, it didn't.
Then what was it?
Did you feel anything when I left?
Do you feel anything right now?
[Johnny ]
Hey, guys!
I think we have a serious problem.
Thank you.
- How are you feeling?
- Fine. I'm good.
Thank you for
coming out to see me.
- You said it was urgent, so-
- It is.
There's, uh, something
we need to talk about.
Something I need
to ask you.
Victor, wait a second. Um, I appreciate
everything you've done for me...
- but I think it's a bad
idea for us to get involved.
- Just listen.
What are you doing?
[ Chuckles ]
I didn't bring you here...
to talk about us.
Please, this is business.
[ Clears Throat ]
I need to know, how close is Reed
to finding a cure?
He's been working
'round the clock.
- The data needs to be
tested and analyzed before-
- Same old Reed.
All analysis, no action.
[ Chuckles ]
Wasn't that the problem
with you two?
If the molecules aren't stable, it could
make us worse- maybe even kill us.
Then why is Reed
dragging his feet?
Maybe he likes having
his prize specimen under a glass.
It's ironic,
isn't it?
You're finally the perfect woman for him
because you're his science project.
- Please don't make this a personal matter.
- I think you already have.
Victor, we can't do anything
until the research is ready.
"We"?
[ Rumbling ]
Don't forget who
you work for, Susan.
So get to work
and do your job.
I wish my wife
would disappear.
[ Von Doom ]
So, what's the prognosis?
Your tissue, your organs, your entire
biophysical structure is changing
Every system is still
functioning somehow
And it's changing into?
I don't really know.
Some kind of organic metallic alloy.
Stronger than titanium
or carbon steel.
Harder than diamonds
Like the shields
Reed said would protect us.
[ Exhales ]
How long?
At this rate, the infection could be
complete in two, maybe three weeks.
What do you mean, complete?
I wish I could tell you.
I can't pretend to know
what we're dealing with here.
- I'll have to notify the C.D.C.
- What?
- The Center for Disease Control
- I know what it is.
If this thing is contagious,
we may have a big problem on our hands.
I'm talking about an epidemic here
[ Laughs ]
Look at me.
I have a life. I'm the... face
of a billion-dollar company.
We need to keep this confidential.
Victor, this disease is progressive,
degenerative. I have to notify someone.
- [ Choking ]
- That's terrible news.
I think I'll get a second opinion.
Our uniforms were exposed
to the storm, like us
so they can transform like us...
becoming invisible, changing size on demand
or remaining impervious to flame.
You guys look like an '80s rock band.
[ Laughing ]
You know, Ben,
this material stretches.
- I'm sure I can figure out a way to make it fit.
- [ Stammers ]
I wouldn't be caught dead
wearing that.
I love these costumes! They're missing
something, though. Needs, like, spice-
- They're not costumes.
- You can't use your powers in public, Johnny.
You guys are worse than NASA.
[ Sue ]
Johnny-[ Scoffs ]
Maybe it's missing a utility belt.
[ Chuckling ]
If we can build a machine to recreate
the storm, we can reverse the polarity.
- And reverse the mutations.
- Curing countless diseases, not just ours.
But we're the focus,
right, Reed?
- Reed?
- Yeah, of course. Of course.
And you're sure you can
control this thing?
- Because last time it didn't work out so well.
- With the right amount...
of energy we can stabilize
the storm.
Maybe tie in
to the city grid.
You know, you really
need a janitor.
I bet this is what it looks like
inside your head.
- Oh!
- Sue!
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Sue Chuckles ]
- [ Reed ] That's okay
- My fault.
- No problem.
- Hi.
[ Doors Close ]
[ Elevator Gears Whir ]
- Did it just get really hot in here?
- Yeah. It-Yeah.
It's weird.
Yeah, it's-Whoo.
Whoo!
- Is this your floor?
- No. I was gonna- It's broken or somethin'.
- You guys goin' up?
- Is it hot in here?
Yes.
Listen, I'll call you
about that drink, okay?
- Good-bye.
- Bye-bye.
I'll talk to you later.
Bye.
[ Sighs ]
It's like a sauna in here.
It's been like this
all day.
There you go
There's your change
Can I help you, buddy?
- Oh, my-
- It's Sue Storm!
- It's the Invisible Woman!
- Hey, you're right!
Sue Storm! It is you!
Listen, my kid loves you!
[ Shouting, Chattering ]
I can't believe
I'm doing this again!
All right, I'm here. Let's make this quick.
I got places to go today.
- [ Grumbles ]
- Oh, wait. [ Laughs ] I don't go anywhere.
Johnny, it's imperative that we
stay inside for the foreseeable future.
I know, I know, Reed, but when you
said that last time my brain hurt a week
Johnny, it's too dangerous
for you to be in public.
You've been saying that for years.
What worries me
is that our powers are evolving.
I know I know!
I am so close to flying, guys, I can taste it
- You can't fly.
- Yet.
- Johnny, can you put that napkin out?
- Oh, Jesus.
What's going on?
How you gonna cure us?
I'm gonna build a machine
to re-create the storm.
The cosmic rays will travel
from this generator to this chamber
What, no pop-ups?
If I can reverse the wave signal-
It'll return us back to normal.
- Huh.
- Right But what are the risks?
Even a small miscalculation could
increase our symptoms exponentially.
- [ Metal Crunches ]
- Or perhaps even kill us.
Now, dying- that's bad, right?
I say wejust let sleeping dogs lie, guys
- So, how long till this
contraption's up and runnin'?
- It's hard to say.
- How long, Reed?
- I don't know-
You don't know?
- You don't want this to get worse.
- Worse than that?
Guys, look, we're gonna
be stuck here for a while
So let's just try and get along
##[ Rock ]
##[ Man Vocalizing ]
- Ohh!
- You could knock!
Sorry!
##[ Continues ]
##[ Ends ]
Johnny!