DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
Well. We are ready.
- Can you manage?
- May have to ask?
To make some money!
Ocupaþi your positions.
Now it's up to you, Han.
Come to you.
Come on, tego, move it up!
Ending the road.
I moved up, frãþioare!
Yes, there are sharp!
Shit!
Come on!
Hold on!
- Give me your hand!
- Do not go!
You can jump!
Jump!
Letty, jump!
You catch me!
Go!
~ ~ Fast and Furious
Translation and adaptation: Felixuca, Xander
Comments on
www.desprefilme.info
Police sent in crews Baricola.
I am very interested in you.
That will strike a signal
which will lead directly to us.
I say get out
tomorrow at first hour.
Me I will.
And if you catch me ...
I will not care to fall one
besides me.
I did a good race.
It's time to go back to Japan.
I and some uste
that can help you.
You saw it somewhere on Letty?
Here you are.
You said that Rio is very
well this time.
Police trying to catch us.
I guess I did a good job.
They are a safe target.
I do not want to be
around you will catch me.
"Drive or die", I remind you?
Dom, how long do this?
And now out of the blue
It appears that you too dangerous?
Be serious.
Find a solution you always do.
Freeze!
Damn!
- I do not know anything!
- Give me a name!
David Park is the type that you want!
Please!
Federal Bureau of Investigaþii
E in miff.
Yesterday was his birthday free
and an idiot he reported.
Perfect.
Sorry I am late.
Receive continuous reports
ta about the Olympics in the middle, O'Conner.
Prove me that reangajarea
no it was a gre and ealã.
I have a name.
- David Park.
- Just so?
That's all you got?
David Park?
If you ask the street
find a 50 by David Park.
- It's Korean, not Chinese.
- That's All.
Park recruiting drive
Braga Card.
If you catch him on the Park,
and catch them on bãieþii heaven.
PANAMA, PANAMA ciudad de
You talk.
Dom.
Mia, you told me not to call here.
It's  Letty.
He was killed .
We are gathered here to
of a lead on the last road
on our sister, Letty.
Let us recall the words Psalm 23.
The identification of the facial
they have recognized Toretto.
In ten minutes or
after crossing the border.
Not understand.
I thought that I would come.
I told you not to come.
We supravegheaþi if you find ...
There will.
Relax.
Look at you.
Letty was not left to destroy.
Although it is a fucking curse.
When he came back, was always here,
working at it day and night.
It was weird.
Like the people that you come back.
I want to see the site of the accident.
Just what I was on the phone
Deputy director Lawson.
If in 72 hours
not doing any progress in Braga
will close.
I know that are new
but that is the reason ultimatum?
Because the past two years,
and the three agents infiltraþi
returned in plastic bags.
He walked over border more heroin
Escobar than ten years.
It is the largest national threat
and we have no even a picture with him.
We do not have fingerprints.
Not even a facial description.
How we David Park?
There is someone important
the organization's Braga?
I searched the name
all databases.
We have 500 results.
Park is unimportant.
It's a ragamuffin, in my opinion.
No Park, Braga and would provide
to that stuff.
Check the data traffic.
Changes illegal.
Illegal racing. Search
history. I find it.
It would be good to you a.
What do you think? We found the Chevrolet
Toretto's in his old garage.
I will arrest.
With your car you doubt me about this.
It's right in front.
You saw something there.
Were residual traces on the asphalt.
Traces that could be left only
of nitromethane.
There is one man
selling you something in the U.S..
None of what you do
will not bring back, Dom.
If you have Letty you so request,
no, I beg you
to and from everything behind.
Before too late.
Already too late.
I love you.
persons arrested:
David Park.
Gentlemen's time Toretto.
Michael Stasiak are the FBI.
Can be a little talk?
Hello. Here in Forsyth samples.
Stasiak I need to sign me
some urgent autorizaþii.
Thanks.
Reduce the list of results
for David Park 50.
Investigating the mark and model
inilor me and all involved.
Tyler, I was sent something?
Want to come with me?
Toretto.
When you back in town?
And I am looking for a car which
did you make changes.
Reservoir nitromethane. Size 44.
Continental Tires.
What makes you come here?
There is your territory, and efu '.
Not me and involve me in this.
Say hello to your sister for me.
He brought a guy.
David Park.
A green Ford Torino.
Please let me go.
Good afternoon.
Tell me why did you bring me here, Brian.
I know that I did not arrested Dom.
I even did the reverse.
I do not want to be involved in this
stay away from him.
That's all you can say
after five years?
Suddenly I started to care
what happens with me.
What I did was gre º it.
I'm sorry. He was the most difficult
thing that had to do it.
And I'm sorry, Brian.
I'm so sorry that you came in
my home and you pretend to love me and you.
I'm very sorry
that you destroyed my family!
I'm sorry that you were so hard!
I minþit.
I minþit the Dom,
I minþit everyone.
I am the best.
That's why I recruited feds.
Maybe you minþi sure.
Maybe you're not the good kind
claiming that it is bad.
Maybe you're the bad guy
who claims that is not good.
You think of that?
Every day.
I always wondered ...
Why did you left my brother
to go that day?
I do not know.
Damn.
Hi.
We received results for David Park.
Analyze all possibilities.
What have you found?
Man of 46 years owner of a
Scion's 2006 fine for imprudenþã.
No.
- And a Chevrolet Tahoe in 2001.
- No.
Two Mini Cooper,
Peugeot 607, a Toyota hybrid.
No.
A Senator in'98. One of the'95 Sebring.
One of the'98 Nissan 240.
Changes illegal.
That is, 240's with illegal modifications.
Would lead you to something.
A green Turin.
Nitromethane.
- Who was your car?
- I do not know. I'm just an intermediary.
I do not know! I swear!
A wait. I do not know anything, man.
I swear.
I'm just a man link.
I can not you just entered in races.
That's all we do.
What curse?
Get him, Dom.
God, this is all I know.
Raises it.
I will arrest O'Conner?
Damn!
Shut up!
Letty was and my friend.
You have been a friend to anybody.
You can discutaþi
about it later?
Letty headed for Braga
when things went wrong.
Please.
I'll catch, Dom.
Let me do my job and raises him.
I will kill this Braga ...
and everyone will stand in my way.
I let go.
O'Conner!
If you'll ever release
one of my witnesses ...
- Enough!
- Take your hand!
It is enough.
- He finished O'Conner!
- I said that's enough!
Stasiak, go to cureþi.
What? He hit me first!
We are not in kindergarten!
So I go at once!
Bleeding on my floor!
O'Conner, you know the difference between
a police and a criminal?
- What is it?
- A decision and gre ita.
Control your exit irile, son.
Fun fun.
I eazã up.
You are good. Lieutenant
of Braga, Ramon Campos,
Tomorrow will race in a neighborhood
Korea to form a team.
Have chosen and provide three
in previous races.
Our informant, Mr. David Park,
was courteous and he entered and us.
O'Conner ...
Your turn.
Let me guess.
As tigãtorul occupy the post.
These are cars
imports were confiscated.
- And to me.
- Choose one.
Nr. 2206.
A your car without equal.
Nr. 3148 and i. ..
2765.
Okay, you want?
All three.
It is a standard transmiþãtor.
ª efu 'wants you to where you always are.
Want to bet on it?
Uiþi What are you, stupid?
I do not know. You tell me.
Drive it like you are Dwight.
But Dwight is already in the team.
Must be quickly
like to work for Braga.
We have a problem?
No.
- You are one of the Park to offer?
- Yes.
Follow me.
See you later, you idiot.
And you.
Right on! Get banu!
I could þin to you all day.
With all sure why you are here.
I give good ...
are available on all roads.
Every corner of every street is
an idiot who organizes races.
Not what you look like Braga.
Braga wants and someone who would sell
bunicuþa like to be behind the steering wheel.
People who drive and your car
"ten seconds" does not line up right
but go to the limit and get
in places where nobody has ever passed.
You give real.
What do we carry?
How many money to give Braga,
should not you know.
You do that and give real.
A true driver's exact tie
Why is your car.
Listen, "and really oferule"
no one commits to attend
the race.
You are the head?
Talk to the head now?
It appears that you look like a head and?
My job is to find
and the best offer. Period.
At that race as a pan
receives the information.
The so-good?
Yeah, so okay.
No, it's not good.
Who will block the streets?
Nobody.
That 's the idea.
Wait
to download the route.
start on the route indicated.
Ten .
New .
Eight .
Seven .
And six .
- Sure you want to do this?
- Many have changed.
- Four.
- You are right.
Three .
Two .
One .
start.
Viraþi right.
You  8 km to the destination.
What you seem ass me?
Trash in the ghetto.
Deadites driving.
Come on!
Viraþi right.
Shit!
Ouch.
Reconfiguring  route.
Go straight ahead.
- Reconfiguring route.
- Shut up!
May you  4 km to the destination.
Oops, you have seen.
May you  7.2 km to the destination.
- Can return.
- Jokes are
May you  6.7 km to the destination.
I'm sorry,
me and inuþo.
May you  1.6 km to the destination.
Guess who came back, Dom.
Come on!
To move your car!
Asshole!
May you  400 meters
to the target.
Too soon, Dom.
Injection
Still have remained a novice.
You've reached the destination.
Bye.
Now you know you can not beat me
right.
I do not knew that there is no rule.
- That I call "driving"!
- Fuck!
Go cry to mommy.
Now working for Braga.
When the GPS I will indicate the route,
to follow.
Driving license.
What driving?
Put your finger.
Mobile number.
Footprint is to Campos.
Number
is for me.
Asshole!
Listen here: horses always power bat
me and inile import.
You know what I say? Always!
Girls, let's go
with "daddy" Dwight!
"Daddy" like Dwight
to remove your shoes.
Dwight likes his feet.
Down shoes.
What beauty.
Dwight likes him more
President picioru that.
What do? I did nothing?
Dwight has never done anything!
Staþi! Where plecaþi?
What I did?
You are arrested for distribution
of methamphetamine.
What? Dwight does not achieve any
of shit, frãþicã!
Dwight does now.
Not mine!
I know that will not accept any
as evidence, right?
Nor needed.
A Corona.
Too bad for Dwight. To be arrested
just when the team entered ...
How unfortunate.
I wish I could say
you are surprised to see you here.
What you stop me to say
that the police are you?
The same me that you stop me
to say why you're here.
- How you doing, boys?
- What are you doing?
- Okay. We distraþi?
- Yes.
Come to have fun and better.
What do you make your car?
Was hit soundly.
Will be ready.
I heard that you just exit it
in limbo.
Yes.
Can you know the one, Jim Garcia?
No. It's a great place.
Many names, many faces.
And you
you looking great world.
That may not be profitable
for business.
Depends on how things are concerned.
If you are caught
go to jail.
Years heavy.
I do not know how others are and provide
but I, you see police lights
in the mirror,
not stop me.
Teþi your knowledge?
See the sor'mea.
Understand.
- You are lucky.
- Why?
Still breathing.
For the ladies that I loved and
for the ladies that we have lost.
Cheers.
How's Braga?
It is of us.
She grew up on the streets.
It's faithful people.
Now big cocky.
And the head efilor.
I see all the guys ã º tia?
Whatever die for Braga.
Including you?
Especially me.
Enjoy the party.
Take drink, women.
Any want.
Braga is mine.
I will put organization on Earth.
Cheers.
Are you interested in something that your car?
I just admire bodywork.
You are one of those who
put before me and inile women?
I am one of those who appreciate
a body to move,
regardless of the brand and model.
Your car is yours?
It's your car's Fenix.
One can see
at the meeting.
It will open you up.
Now ...
I know what you like me and initially,
tell me how I like women.
Everything starts with the eyes.
Must have eyes to see that
lies beyond.
To see the good in someone.
20% angel 80% devil.
Realistic.
Not to forbid the least
Vaseline under your fingernails.
You are not you a.
I know.
I have a small gift for you.
A dirty glass.
Just what I always wanted.
I took last night from the club.
Has two sets of fingerprints.
Processes them.
Some are of Campos.
But others could be his Braga.
You'll have to get over Interpol.
To contact individual agencies?
It could take weeks.
Well.
UNLOADING Coordinates
Yes.
You are the third breach of rules
road in less than three streets.
More easily, O'Conner.
Sure, Dad.
Signal
Latitude / longitude
It stopped.
I lost.
- It destroyed emiþãtorul.
- We are like that.
- He destroyed.
- We like you to know that yet.
Send the helicopter.
I head north,
3356.
Everything is in order.
base, are Angeles 5.
No receive signal  objective.
Do not found it.
Damn!
Overdraw
This is not good. They have not said anything
I will tuck into a truck.
No kidding.
Where do we go?
No matter.
Just to enjoy the journey.
Welcome in Mexico, boys.
Border and helicopters are rooms
you will scan the heat signature.
But you can direcþiona satellite
to secure some points.
We can not tolerate
strecoare to an error,
so that I will have to follow
instructions without deviation.
Do you have any questions?
Fenix that I will be here.
We will meet there.
Well. Let us Sync.
Good luck, gentlemen.
Go with God.
Direcþionarea satellite active.
Înaintaþi to north
menþinând speed.
stay close to the Fenix.
He will lead you.
FRONTIER USA - MEXICO
We detected a heat signature
north, the narrow Legardo.
Thermal sensor in the Mexican
will visit some 45 seconds.
Go to the video camera.
Manual control.
Middle room to
location data.
Grãbiþi sure. Have been detectaþi.
Shit.
Toretto, come back as a group.
Resume detection is heat.
Do not see anything.
Disappeared.
Send some helicopters in the area.
base, we are at 40 seconds
the narrow Legardo.
Send  helicopter.
May you have 30 seconds.
3233 North, West 11649.
drain time.
must plecaþi there
before you send ground crews.
15 seconds.
The objective is
3 km away.
no longer have time.
should I exit now!
base, we are at 3233 North,
West 11649.
We have visual contact.
Send ground crews.
Neglijenþi.
Very neglijenþi!
What do?
Come on!
I exit!
Come on, man!
Come here.
Do not touch me.
Do not touch me!
I said do not touch me.
- Labele Get off me.
- Calm down, frãþioare.
What are your tovar President?
Hey, and head.
What did you say?
I said that only poponarii
using nitromethane.
Have you looked under my hood?
Talk to you.
Got something to say?
70 in Plymouth.
A call Letty.
Hey!
Where is my money?
Somebody has destroyed your car.
I ruined your car.
I remember you face them?
Because I do not remember me.
Last time I saw her
burn.
Now what?
I would like to follow.
Get, Dom!
Get up!
Get the hell in your car!
Let's go!
Grab it Now!
What are you, trình?
Get in touch with agencies
in several countries.
Unfortunately most
must manually process the prints.
O'Conner you search on line five.
You should see this.
Thanks.
Says O'Conner.
- Where are you?
- Got stuff.
"You got the stuff"
or "we have stuff"
What  speak
Cameras for monitoring traffic
in the area
recorded images
with you and Toretto, together.
Listen, O'Conner.
Teaching and merchandise on Toretto.
I think the idea is to catch it
on Braga. Now we have a chance.
Brian, time has elapsed.
teaches everything. Obviously
O'Conner
So you like 60 million dollars.
You need a doctor.
You can find a place
to hide ã º tia.
I know my part.
Garage and INI OF MA
502, drunk driver.
It raises your car 48 hours.
In the back, where find place.
You are sure?
Yes. Last
they will find
is their garage
ma and the initial high. Believe me.
When you have your car thrown into the air,
exploded and mine.
Yes?
Yes.
Now you are you owe to your car
"10 seconds".
Really?
Yes.
Now we're even.
That's your idea
to keep me away from him?
- I do not knew who to call.
- It's my brother. Sure.
Glonþul is not here.
I will clean the wound and I sew.
It will hurt.
I'm sure you'll do it gladly.
A little.
- Do you?
- Yes.
It's spicy. Take care.
A I love you.
Dom, how are you?
You should say your prayer.
Thank you, Lord,
bless you for
this table.
For food, family
and friendship.
Do you wonder why
I let go of Dom.
Maybe because at this time
I respect more than I respect
myself.
What I learned from that is Dom
nothing matters unless you
a code of honor.
And that code is yours, Brian?
Him now.
Envelope with evidence
CALLS RECEIVED
LETTY
Shit!
Hey, Dom ...
- When were you going to tell me?
- Dom ...
I use the agent as Letty.
- Let me explain you.
- When?
Ends, Dom!
- I understand.
- Do not understand?
Stop!
Dom, stop!
Please, stop it up!
He did it for you, Dom!
He did it for you.
Letty came to me to make you exempt
in exchange for his arrest Braga.
Just wanted to go home!
I'm sorry, Dom!
I'm sorry!
It would be good to have an explanation
very good.
You violated a direct order.
- Where is the merchandise?
- In security.
Safely.
We can use that stuff to show
Press
I am caught
several kilograms of heroin
Braga but will send a shipment
next week
and the one that will follow.
Let's use it to remove the Braga
cartel and his millions of dollars.
and suggest how to do this?
Through an exchange with Braga.
We are not that really.
Not and can allow
refuse to exchange.
Do you have any plan?
There is a price.
If it arrested Braga
is exempt on Toretto.
- Yes.
- I'm Dom.
just thinking of you.
When I gave you my phone number
I hope to call.
But not in this situation.
What  situation
You are in life?
Do not take it personally.
I'm just business.
I  and me some "business"
to do.
Put him on the phone Campos.
They are.
To do so, and provides Braga
people's loyalty?
Ucigându-and give you
We can find others.
is more profitable for business.
I want to make a change.
Braga not negotiable.
Okay.
Then it explains how he disappeared
cargo of 60 million dollars.
I know sure that this
is not profitable.
What?
six million and ice money,
livraþi by Braga staff.
I hate to draw me.
I assume the risk of
if not and he had something to lose.
There will never accept.
either treat me with Braga,
times you do it.
When and where?
With all and have occupied positions
in the perimeter.
Be carefully.
Maximum stay in alert.
Nobody  not move up until you
O'Conner gives no signal.
When you give,
and you know what to do.
When we catch this guy
will leave here
Free as a bird heaven.
- That you have said?
- A so we understood.
and still believe in
Inherited Christmas?
Yes.
Here.
In case things get out bad.
- Like the old days?
- Yes.
You dropped something.
- That want, right?
- No, Dom.
It's harmless.
Do not you worry about him.
And we're very sorry
Letty for ...
Where's our stuff?
You mean stuff
who was here?
You see when you see Braga.
He was so understanding.
Do not you worry.
Braga is keep the word.
IDENTITY CONFIRMED
Two million.
You will receive the remainder
when you recover what is mine.
- Stasiak.
- We have a result.
Fingerprints belonging to them
Braga's.
just waiting for confirmation
do.
have to ask you something.
Ro and isei in your car
when trying to exit the gate?
Order that all agents
to intervene.
We have confirmation. Main Suspect
wearing a gray suit.
To intervene.
Sir, no O'Conner gave us yet
signal.
I just received confirmation.
Do it!
Arestaþi main suspect
in the gray suit. Repeat.
in the gray suit.
I Think what you think
and me?
Not Braga.
Shit!
- Dispose of weapons!
- FBI!
Down!
Clear out of here!
Get outta here, Dom!
Get outta here.
Fuge!
Campos Braga is the!
Come on.
Approaching the main objective.
Suspect is secure.
Let's go.
Stand up.
He was always
right under your nose.
Now Braga fled.
Toretto is certainly now
over border.
Any idea how many of the problems, O'Conner?
I'm just busy.
There is the first offender
You have I left to escape.
Now you're suspended
and are subject to internal investigations.
What will happen to Braga?
Stop your concerns.
We know where Braga?
Satellite tracking has shown us
home that is in Tecato, Mexico.
Mexico is not in our jurisdicþia.
The truth is
that superiors will be so for ocupaþi
with conferinþele Press
captures about drugs
that can act
without-and give them out.
Park start
to do what is right.
Everyone is looking for you.
I'm right here.
I'm glad to see that you have adapted
and you got the injection electronics.
Informer know now
and to me the ini.
Come with you.
I 'm
to bring anybody back.
I know.
Click on that pedal.
How do I get to say goodbye
only from your brother?
Do not do it.
FRONTIER USA - MEXICO
5 Kilometers
I thought that you were coming.
You saved my life.
I want to return the service.
This will help
to get to Braga.
Dom.
It's suicide to go there.
I have no choice.
I think you loved her very much.
Go with God.
This is the limit
My jurisdicþiei.
Yes. And here begins my.
Welcome to the house of God.
Do not worry you, father.
Everything will be fine.
great.
For Holy Church.
- Thanks.
- For less.
Be blessed.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
No you're forgiven.
Arestaþi want to go?
Right here
We have that option.
This will not escape with the money.
Frãþioare, two of us ...
Two of us are not so different.
No you're a hero.
You're right.
That's why you come back
abroad.
But Fenix is mine.
Sure.
Shit!
If we are lucky, we move
about three kilometers.
You know where to go?
Want to your loan
My GPS?
Where are your friends?
They intend to appear or what?
Premiums are fixed what you wanted.
Stop it up.
You stop your car.
Are behind.
Dom, take it to the tunnel!
To go through the tunnel!
Clear it away, Brian.
I know where are the tunnels?
You are sure?
I'm fine.
You might hurt.
Now you're in my world!
This is the end of the road.
Now what?
- End of the road.
- No.
Faster!
Get me outta here!
Gay.
Let me see.
Apply pressure there.
You'll be fine.
You must go.
No longer run.
You need to ask you something.
If I would like tigat race
do not you be stretched a trap, right?
You hit your head.
Do not make me laugh.
Ridicaþi sure.
Please take a seat.
Get up, sir Toretto.
I listened to the testimonies
and we took into account
clemenþã the call to Mr. O'Conner
on behalf of Mr. Toretto
because of its direct contribuþiei
in arrest
well-known drug dealer
Arturo Braga.
Nevertheless,
this court considers
that an act as not compensated
an entire lifetime and acts gre ite.
and therefore
are obliged to give sentinþa
maximum imposed by law.
Dominic Toretto,
you're sentenced to 25 years
prison
in the maximum security prison
from Lompoc
without possibility
release conditioning.
And session ended.
Subtitles for Felixuca and Xander, edited by fjfo