Quickly!
What'd he say?
How would I know? Just run!
Hurry, run or we won't get away!
Leave that! Let's go!
Japan 90's
This is the third boatload of illegal immigrants
...
to land in Wakasa Bay in 6 months
Tokyo Shinjuku District
I'll take you to a nice restaurant
No, it's OK, maybe next time...
Come on, it's OK...
30,000 for both of you, OK?
No... you're so rich and still you haggle...
Stop, don't run!
You can't escape
Where do you think you're going? Oh no...
Let go, let me go!
Let go! Stop resisting!
Let me go!
Northeastern China
Hey, little brother-in-law Hi
Can I get through?
Yes
Don't fool me
I'm not, it's frozen solid!
You little rascal
Who's your brother-in-law? My sister hasn't
said yes to you yet!
Let's go, let's go...
Where are you running off to?
My tractor's been destroyed by you!
That's the one
No way, just from this scar
You can prove my wife is a Japanese orphan?
What do you know?
Those days, getting cowpox vaccination was a
big deal
Only the Japanese children could afford such
luxury
You're great Auntie
Just go along with it
and say they are your children
Then they can claim to be descendants of
Japanese orphans
And go to Japan legally
Goodness, that's not possible
It would be illegal Yes
It can work!
It can work? Oh, no way
Look, I can't have given birth to so many!
It's not like making buns you know!
Sure you can! Auntie Liu next door has 1 2!
Please auntie, say we are yours!
Let us have the chance to go!
Yes, give us a chance...
Steelhead
Are you romancing me, or that machine?
Come up
My aunt in Tokyo wants me to go over. Should
l?
Will you come back?
Why wouldn't l?
You're worried I won't be back? Can't bear to
see me go?
Shameless!
If you don't want me to...
Follow your dream!
Once I make enough money, I'll be back
Mail's here
No need to look, nothing for you
It's connected
Thanks
Jie, have you found her?
No, she has moved
How can she just vanish?
That's the thing
What about her aunt?
She died last month
Died? How did she die?
We are at the scene of the shipwreck
People of different nationalities are being
taken away by the police
That's it, he must have been caught
Another one, poor sod
Jie, I've walked for two days
Thank God, I thought you didn't make it
Come on in
Some tea, hurry
Let me introduce you
This is my brother from home, Steelhead
This is Lao Gwei, Dai
That's Auntie Hao and her daughter Mae
Also just arrived. Now helping us to clean and
cook
Hu and Fang
I said slow down... slower
Don't choke
God, he stinks
When he's eaten, take him for a bath
You have to hurry, we're closing soon
Understood
Come
I'm surprised they have bathhouses here, just
like home
This is the old area, some houses don't even
have toilets
Idiots! Shut up!
So sorry
Japanese mobsters, stay away
Why are there so many louts here?
Tokyo has really gone to the dogs
That's right! Ain't that the truth!
Damn it, if they had balls come to China
See if I don't chop him into pieces
How is life?
Fine, just tiring
She moved away
After her aunt died
I've looked everywhere
You should give up
We'll talk after you get some rest
Come on, get up Coming
Move faster, or you won't get work
Takadanobaba
How've you been?
Same as before
Is there any work?
I don't understand English
Big brother... Wait
Any work?
You're lucky, a foundation job
Guaranteed a week, 6,000 yen a day
Great!
Can my two buddies go with me?
Sure
But, 6 times 7 is 42,000
First, fork over commission of 4,200 each
Sure, sure, no problem...
Go on then
Plastics with plastics, glass with glass
Separate the flammable from the inflammable.
Don't be lazy!
Damn it, I thought it was foundation work
Isn't all the land here foundation?
In 20 years, this'll all be full of villas
Stop talking and get to work!
Separate them properly! Plastics with plastics!
What's that guy doing?
Treasure hunting!
Treasure hunting?
Hey, hey...
That's mine!
The crane!
Hey! Stop! You're crushing him! Hey!
Someone's trapped underneath
Quick, call the police!
They're calling the cops!
Illegal workers better run!
There's still someone there!
Run! Run!
Hurry up and help! Come on!
Run! They're calling the cops!
Thanks
Run! Run!
Brother Steelhead, eat while it's hot
I'm Hong Kong Boy
You saved my life, I'll repay you 10 times
I have a plumbing job in a few days
10,000 yen a day, I'll leave you a spot
Make sure you keep your word
A little token, please take it
Telephone cards
No, I can't
It's nothing
How do you sell these?
Very cheaply, at a tenth of the price
Get me 20 of those
No problem, coming right up
They're fake! You have to use them at green
pay phones
The red ones have a detection system. Never
use those
How are you, big brother?
Fine
Brother Tai Bo, please give me another 20
cards
Is 20 enough?
It's for a friend
Look at you, didn't I ask you to work with me?
There's a lot going on here! You can get
anything you want!
We are now at the Sanwa-kai headquarters...
...for the funeral of Mr lwaida Jiro
All major mob heads are here
Police are being very cautious...
and have sent a large contingent
We also hear from a reliable source...
that the mob leaders will...
sit down and elect...
a new head for Sanwa-kai today
Excuse me
Togawa Taro, 2 votes
Muranishi Koichi, 5 votes
Muranishi Koichi is the new leader
The new leader is here!
Boss... Boss...
Our new leader, Muranishi Koichi
Sub-head, Eguchi Toshinari Enter
Kurata
Do you know what I do?
I'm a police officer
You ask me to crawl down a sewer?
Don't you know lwaida Jiro is dead?
I haven't even had time to celebrate...
and you want me to do this?
We received a citizen's complaint
Then you should tell them
It's the illegal workers who clean the sewers
A Japanese would never do such a dirty job
If his toilet was blocked
Shit would just pile up to his ass
OK, all right
After this, I'll buy you some drinks
Lead the way
The number of illegals has gone up in the past
2 months
The brass needs to clean things up
He's the Chinese interpreter
I see
I studied some Chinese in college
But I'm not fluent. Can you understand me?
I can follow you
Because I'm also Japanese
Oh... he really does understand me?
Forget it
Watch your step
OK
Stay where you are!
Cops!
Steelhead, run! Go!
Cops! Run!
Don't run!
Stop!
Round them up for questioning
Show your lD
Take out your lDs
Keep quiet!
Can you speak Putonghua? Speak it!
What's happening?
I can't understand them
Aren't you the interpreter?
They are speaking in dialect
Besides Beijingnese, Cantonese, what else is
there?
Several hundred others!
Oh really?
How much do you earn a day?
8,000 yen
8,000?
He said only 8,000
What's your point?
This kind of work pays at least 1 5,000 yen
It's too little
Is my Chinese OK? Can you understand me?
Yes I can
Get them out of here
Don't arrest me, please
Run! Run!
No running!
Stay where you are!
Watch out! Over there!
Help... I can't swim
Give me your hand
Steelhead, run! Hurry!
Don't run
Wait
Run
Doesn't anyone guard the place?
The Japanese don't steal, so they think others
won't
Fools!
Come, take this
3,000 is too little!
This is worth nothing, get the LVs
and the Guccis
They're at department stores
Steal these, they're the hottest
I'll give you 20 percent of the market price
All these are stolen goods
The Southeast Asian buyers
All come here to buy
Some customers order in advance too
The harder it is to steal, the higher the price
Come, freshly grilled
Have it while it's hot So slow!
I'll tell you who they are
The crew cut is from Vietnam
The effeminate one behind you is from
Shanghai
Those on the other side... the loud ones
...are from Fujian
The people here...
...are capable of doing anything
Do they work with each other?
They're all in different gangs, so probably not
Don't listen to him
This year, everyone is under the same sky
Money is king! No money, no brethren
Get lost if you have no money!
Don't talk rubbish!
Let me show you something
Come over, come on
You eat first... come over
I'll show you a trick, just a slip of paper
You spend nothing, but you have cigarettes
And you have spare change
Steelhead
I see an aggressive streak in you
It'd be a waste if you don't take short cuts
I don't want to be deported
Deported... you scared? Stop the
nonsense
Just ignore him
I'll bring you back
Come back and play again, right?
I'll wait outside
Are you new?
Get yourself some food
Lily Yes
Go
Be careful
I'm drunk, Lily takes care of me
If you get drunk, I'll take care of you
Give me your money
I have no money
Hand over your money!
Let go... What are you doing?
Mito-san
Let me go...
What are you doing?
You... what are you doing?
Help! Help!
Help! Help! Run!
Help...
Thank you... thank you
Are you OK?
Oh, it's you
I hit the jackpot today
Mito-san
Sister
Mito-san, your head is bleeding! Come and
help
I'm pissed off
No, don't drink any more
Give me a drink! Sit down first...
I can't calm down without booze
Wang, bring the first aid box
Right away
Come... sit
Here's the box
I don't know how to thank you
Money's the most practical, please take it
I still need to return this money to you
Thanks
I'm looking to hire someone
Why not come and help me?
It's OK, I have work
Let me get you a drink
Wang, bring some food
What would you like? I'll go prepare it
Anything will do OK
No need to be curious
They're all working students
I purposely opened this bar at a quiet location
I wanted to keep things simple
Kabuki-cho is too uncivilised
Zunaku is a hostess bar
It's yours?
Yes!
If you're lonely or troubled
Just come here for a drink
This place is meant to sooth sorrows
I envy her
I too would like a man to search the world for
me
You don't have a man?
No good man!
Good men like good women
Wrong! Good men like bad women
So you're a bad woman looking for a good
man
Right! You're so right!
Ah, problems, everyone has their problems
Are you doing OK at work?
I'm doing OK
That's good. Don't rush yourself
When people are in a hurry, they stray from
the path
What do you want?
You're obstructing justice, you're under arrest
Reject the Anti-yakuza bill, protect our rights
Can you please elaborate on...
how the Japanese mafia can co-exist with
other legal organizations?
They don't exactly co-exist
It is a long and complicated story
Can you give us a simplified explanation?
It's rather difficult...
Tell the branches to burn all papers
And cease operations Yes
No one is to use any violence
Don't give the cops any excuse to hold us
Understood
Move out! Yes!
Hurry up! There's no time!
Hurry!
Sir, times have changed
Sanwa-kai cannot survive on old rules
We need radical changes
Togawa Taro from Togawa-gumi...
will never accept your suggestion
Perhaps, but Togawa-gumi is pushing things
The cops will use this as an excuse to arrest
us
We can't treat him as the enemy
We can't have Sanwa-kai in disarray
And we certainly cannot anger Togawa Taro
I understand
Welcome
Good evening, Eguchi-san
Please come in
Here you go
Who is that man?
Big shots!
Look, look
The one in red...
is Gao, the Taiwan gang's leader
The fiercest in Shinjuku
I think the tall guy beside him
is probably a mobster
Jie, is that her?
Surely not
Isn't it?
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't go
Nakajima, take the things in
I can take them
No need
Nakajima, do you need to move some stuff?
Thank you
If it's not enough, there's more inside
That man just now
Seemed quite taken with you
He is from my village
Under the circumstances, I didn't dare greet
him
I didn't want to embarrass you
Yuko
We've been together so long
Why would I discriminate against the
Chinese?
Some people discriminate against foreigners
I think that's too extreme, and naive
Don't you agree, Nakajima?
Many Chinese have come to Kabuki-cho
They're creating a mess there
Actually, they are no different from us
Just trying to make a living
Do you know how many Chinese...
helped to build Kabuki-cho after the war?
Never mind
Yuko
If you meet your friends again
Just make contact with them
I won't mind
I've been keeping this for a special occasion
Tonight, it's bottoms up!
Come!
Ah... Enough, enough...
What's up?
Waiting is such torture
Now we have the answer, great!
Come, let's paint the town!
Good, paint the town!
Stop! What are you doing?
Don't run!
Come down!
Run!
My papers! My papers!
Squat down!
I can't go back
Since I'm on the road of no return
I should make life better for myself
I'll make some money and make myself legal
I can't live in the shadows forever
You mean...
You want to skirt the law?
What do you think?
My problem is I'm a coward
I just want a pushcart to sell Tianjin chestnuts
That's my biggest ambition
Every dream needs money
Excuse me, brother Tai Bo
My buddy Steelhead has a deal for you
Let's sit and chat
What's to talk?
20 cards? 50?
2,000 now, 1 0,000 next month
Can you move that much?
I have people
Good! Just show me the money!
Remember, it's 1,000 for 8 cards
If they bargain, just throw in a couple free
Phone cards... phone cards...
1,000 yen for 10
If you want to make more, sell fake cards!
To pose as tourists, you must behave like
them
What do you think? Beautiful?
Remember, look for the expensive stuff!
Hong Kong Boy, come over
This is good
Look at this, this one... it's good
PACHlNKO
I've secretly rigged this machine
I'll teach you a special way to play it
It will spit out tens of thousands of yen every
day
It's steady income
We've to get 600,000 yen to go into business
Is it risky?
Isn't being an illegal worker risky?
Let's go for it, here's 30,000
I'm in!
Here's my 30,000
Jie, go and change the presents
OK
Sorry... there's no problem
Let me do it
Calm down, why are you so flustered?
Thanks
Have you seen this kind of card before?
I think so
Sir, are you not well?
I'm fine... I'm fine...
Are you sure? Yes, I'm fine
Please wait Thank you
You can take a seat over there
It's fine... really
Why are you so nervous?
He's really unwell... Iet it go
All right?
Jie... Jie...
Come here
What's going on?
There's a delivery for you, go take a look
For me? What is it?
OK... quiet down
Jie, we all discussed it
You're too timid for a life of crime
We pooled our money and got you a cart
You can sell your chestnuts
Work hard Go have a look
Tasty chestnuts, sweet and fragrant!
Sweet and fragrant!
30 percent is Fate, the rest is a battle
You can only win if you love a good fight
Check it OK
Is this what you wanted? Yes
OK, I'll keep this one
Looks great
Such a coincidence... shopping?
My day off today, just looking around
I've been doing this recently
This is for you
For real?
Of course, it's for real. It's from Takashimaya
I mean are you really giving it to me?
Oh... boss, give me a bag
Thanks!
Don't put it here, over there!
Do you have it? Two twos, any takers?
No Three fours
Quiet... quiet...
Steelhead's brought a woman back
No way!
And she's quite pretty
They're coming
It's very lively in here
Let me help you
Thank you
What? Seen a ghost?
Yes, two in fact
A male and a female
You!
Can't ever say anything nice!
Let me introduce
She's Lily, a special friend of mine
How are you? Sister in law!
That's Auntie Hao How do you do?
Pleased to meet you
Miss Lily
You and Steelhead look like a couple!
Auntie Hao, what are you saying...
Attention! Marry now, bridal chamber next!
The banquet comes tomorrow
Hear, hear!
You people are impossible
Making noise all day long
You've destroyed my perfectly good place
Get out, all of you, or I'll call the cops!
Get out!
What did he say?
He... he said you're rude and noisy
He wants you to go, or he'll call the cops
Move? Are you kidding...
Lao Gwei It's new year and he
wants me to move!
Hush...
I'm sorry
Please...
What's this?
Please
This won't work next time
Remember, sort the garbage!
This is a broken shack, what's he so pissed off
for?
Don't you agree?
What did he say?
You must have got him in trouble...
...by not sorting the garbage
This place is a garbage dump! What do we
need to sort?
That's right! Hey!
You can't blame him for being mad, it's his
property
If we piss him off, he'll go to the cops
Who suffers? We do
Hey, we have to learn Japanese...
if we want to blend into their world
We're living in their home, we should build
links
We need to communicate more
You're right
Why don't I start a Japanese class
and teach you all for free?
Fantastic, count me in OK!
Me too... I want to as well...
OK, no more talk
It's new year, time to eat!
Yes, new year! Let's eat!
Lao Gwei, speak softer
You're the loudest, tidy up!
Why so late tonight?
Business has been good
Really? Look
Let me show you some magic OK
Which hand?
This one
Nothing
That... that one
Also nothing
Where is it? Where is it?
I think, it's in your ear...
How can it be? Let me see
It's really there
Really How would I know?
I'll give it to you OK
Who are you?
He's my father
How do you do?
I'm also Chinese! It's the New Year
A gift from me
You're also Chinese?
Come, have a cup of tea!
Come... Sure...
How about my cart? No worries!
Go on home
Why?
Just go
I told you to go home! Why?
I said go! Go home!
Dad...
Who do you think you are?
You dare touch my daughter?
I didn't, we're just friends
Friends?
Weren't you just holding her hand?
Don't misunderstand
Misunderstand?!
We're just platonic friends
Teach him a lesson!
No, please listen to me
I really have no designs on her
Beat him!
Don't...
Jie
Dad, stop it!
Stop hitting him!
Is Jie back?
No Come... eat while it's hot
Give me the cold one, have the hot one...
Auntie, leave some for Jie
Of course... of course
Oh... mother!
What's wrong? Who?
He's bleeding
It's Jie! Jie!
What happened?
Come... sit here...
Who beat you?
Uncle Tak...
Who is this Uncle Tak?
An old China hand
He has yakuza support
We always try to avoid him
and try to ignore him
I told you to leave his daughter alone
Why didn't you listen?
Where are your ears? Can you hear?
He's taken my cart
Let's go
Get the cart back!
Steelhead, don't mess with these people
He really has yakuza support
If we don't look after our brothers
Does that mean I should also look away...
if any of you are in trouble in future?
Those without balls can stay and eat!
I'll be back
What do we do now?
Steelhead...Steelhead
Which one?
The one at the back
What are you up to?
You don't understand? Are you a foreigner?
You looking for trouble?
Shouldn't be
Chinese are forbidden
You asshole
You want to die?
What's going on?
What's with the noise?
This guy
Are you Uncle Tak?
Who wants to know?
Give me back the chestnut cart
And you injured my friend, I want you to
apologise!
What? Say that again!
Apologise! Return the cart!
Beat him!
Hong Kong Boy!
Apologise! Return the cart!
Apologise! Return the cart!...
Quickly! No way...
Where is he? There!
Don't hit me... don't hit me...
Where's the cart?
The back alley...
The cops are here
Cops!
Stop... don't run!
Here
It's stuck Move that
Let's go!
The police!
Don't run, I'm not arresting you
Don't run!
You saved my life
I wanted to thank you
I'm Kitano, I've been looking for you...
...to thank you
My cellphone number
Call me if you need help
Kitano-san
Go!
Not here, that way
It's been tampered with
Damn it!
Put it back
Delicious chestnuts!
Thanks
Jie Thank you for coming
Jie
Can you look after the pachinko for me?
I need to take a piss OK
I really need to go... hurry Let me
turn out the fire
It's that machine I know
Hurry OK
You bastard, you've got balls! You,ve got guts!
You dare tamper with my machine?
I don't understand...
I said you've got balls!
Messing with my shop!
I didn't... you got it wrong...
I sell chestnuts
You look familiar, you come often?
I already told you I sell chestnuts
I think you're here to make trouble
I'm not!
You have a death wish
Do you have partners? Quickly!
Take him away!
I really don't know
Look, that's my cart
You really sell chestnuts?
Yes, I sell chestnuts Then there's
nothing to fear
Keep a look out
Take him inside
Don't run...
Don't be afraid!
Why are you crying?
Why try to run?
I really didn't...
Bring him inside...
Who's your leader?
Oh, he shit his pants?
Then answer quickly!
Who's your leader?
How many of you are there?
Where do you live? Tell me and I'll let you go
Just my luck... What?
I said I'm really ill-fated!
You?
I'm the unlucky one!
Keep him down!
Just your luck?!
You're ill-fated?
There's trouble
Jie's being held by the Taiwan gang!
What?
Let's go!
What? Still not talking?
No!
Fine then! Drag him over here!
Put him down!
I gave you a chance
Now you'll regret it!
Jie
There's quite a few of you!
You the leader then?
Tell your people never to step foot in Shinjuku
again
If I ever catch any of you again
I guarantee
It will be much worse than this
Jie... it's OK
How are you doing?
Hang on
Hand... give me back the hand
You want his hand?
Sure
You want the hand?
Here!
Quickly, let's go home
Let's go!
Go, quickly!
Perhaps... I should have killed him!
Auntie Hao, the doctor is here
Quickly... come in
The doctor is here
This is unacceptable!