Look at yourselves.
Unplug from your chairs,
get up and look in the mirror.
What you see is how God made you.
We're not meant to experience the
world through a machine.
Surrogates
14 years ago
What you're telling me is -
a monkey is operating this arm
with nothing but his thoughts?
Absolutely.
There are 100 sensors,
each listening to a different brain cell
or neuron.
Physicaly disabed people
will be able to operate
fully synthetic bodies.
It provides a tremendous amount of hope for the future.
11 years ago
Because of the technology that
we have, at a time of war
we're going to start seeing this more and more.
As manufacturing capacity expanded for military/industrial use
Surrogates became affordable to the general public
Causing a revolution in how
in how we live.
The ability to leave your home
without risk of disease or injury
To have perfect looks without trips to the gym
or plastic surgery
There is no question that at some
point they will be persons like anyone else
They will not be human, but that they will be part
of our community?
There is no question
in my mind.
The decision came down 5 to 4
That the Supreme Court ruled in favor
of the use of surrogates in daily life.
Right now, we are witnessing an
event
That is of an evolutionary significance
7 years ago
According to VSI, the industries
leading manufacturer,
over 98% of world population
uses a surrogate in all
facets of their daily life
We're in the midst of profound changes that are things
that were once unimaginable have become inevitable
Since the global embrace of surrogacy
crime rates have dropped
to record lows
We have witnessed and incredible
reduction in violent crime
communicable disease and discrimination.
Problems that have plagued
societies for centuries
solved almost overnight.
We are the creators.
We will be making them
Do everything for us.All in one machine.
3 years ago
But there is a minority who
actively oppose Surrogates
And are moving to limit their use.
Many people will see this
as the invasion of the inhuman.
They've established reservations or
Surrogacy free zones
in major cities around the country.
They are led by Zaire Powell
or as he is better known
to his followers
The Prophet.
Those machines walking around out there
They're a lie.
You have been sold a lie.
Presend Day
You're going to love Tosca
-Alright, but don't tell me how it ends.
- The way they all end.
Everyone dies.
I'm so glad you could
come back east for a visit.
Well... anything for a break from exams.
We're almost there.
Listen... thanks for lending it to me.
Have a wonderful time.
I love you.
I love you too Dad.
You know Armando
I'm not really in the mood for opera
Four Point?
You read my mind.
Get lost meat bag
I'm agent Peters.
This is Agent Greer... FBI.
Yeah... some jackass on a motorcycle
wiped out a bunch of units
So what do you need us for?
Well I was going to file just a vandalism report
but it turns out this unit's unregistered.
Looks like it's going to need new optics
No shit
The memory chip is completely fried.
Whatya got on the girl?
Registered to a
Cameron McAllister.
He file a report?
No, that's just it, no calls, no nothin'
Come on.
Let's go talk to
our operator.
Cam?
Maybe nobody's home.
My Surries in for an upgrade
and they gave me this crappy loaner.
Could you?
Certainly.
Cam?
Cam's a good tenant you know,
pays the rent on time, never leaves the apartment.
Cam?
[Screams] Oh my God!
Don't touch anything, please.
I'll call it in.
- You're sure this is Cameron McAllister?
- Yes!
This is Agent Peters, we
tracked down the operator.
Yeah
Better send a coroner
Connection interrupted.
Have you ever seen anything like this?
Morning
Where's your....
In the... charge room.
You pull another all nighter?
Yes I did
Why don't you think about taking a break?
- A break?
- Mmmmhmmm
I got some vacation time saved up
How about Hawaii?
Lisa said she got an amazing deal
Hawaii would be great
She had this totally buff Surrie in Maui,
She took it surfing, parasailing, deep sea diving.
You know that rental place on Boilston?
I was thinking about US.
You and me going away some place together.
And leave our units at home?
Are you kidding?
- We could take a drive out to the Cape? We haven't done that for a while...
- Could talk about this another time?
You now I should get to work, the shops
been really busy, everyone wants me to look for somewhere and...
Yeah... I was just thinking that...
Ummm...
It just feels like we...
- Haven't really spent much time together lately.
- We're together every day.
Surrogates...
Not the same...
It's better.
College West, San Diego.
Yo Canter?
He's been in there all weekend.
He's gonna miss the Psych final.
Jesus!
Someone call the cops!
We are confronted by an unprecedented situation.
Two people have died while
connected to their stim chairs.
According to the pathologist,
their brains were liquefied in their skulls.
What ever happened to
their surrogates, killed them.
Sir?
- How's it even possible?
- We don't know.
I'm imposing a total media blackout.
No one in this office is going to be responsible
for setting off a nationwide panic.
The public cannot be allowed to get the idea
that using a surrogate can be fatal.
Tuxedo boys last moments.
Get lost meat bag.
- Looks like we got ourselves a witness.
- Mmmmhmm.
Hang on...
- What is that?
- Exactly...
- Some kind of weapon.
- Anything yet?
Hang on to yourself, I think
we may actually have a homicide here.
Come here and look at this.
- Are you serious?
- No we don't know that for sure.
Yeah but what if it is a homicide?
When was the last one?
This could be huge.
- Yeah, Lee go.
- We got your next of kin.
I hope you're sitting down.
The kids father is Lionel Canter.
As in the inventor of surrogates, Lionel Canter.
Jarid Canter, son of Dr. Lionel Canter was found dead
In his Southern California
dormitory this morning
Cause of death
remains unknown.
A college sophmore, Jarid
was the only son
of the man known around the world
as the father of surrogacy.
The Former Chairman of VSI
Shaped it into one of the largest
corporations in the world.
However, a split between
Canter and his VSI partners
Over the direction of the company
Led to Canters firing
seven years ago.
Publicly humiliated and forced out
of the company he helped to build
Canter has since remained
absent from the public eye.
Dr. Canter's expecting you.
He actually lives here?
I didn't say that.
You'll be speaking with
one of his surrogates.
I work for Dr. Canter.
His private elevator is this way.
Please, wait in here.
What a nice place.
It should be.
It's a piece of every surrogate they sell.
Dr. Canter?
That's right.
You're with the FBI?
Yes we are.
This way.
I can't help but notice the similarities between
your surrogate... and the
one your son Jared was using.
I never really knew
Jarid as a child.
He grew up with his mother in California
Who kept him from me.
When he went to college I encourage him
to borrow my surrogates whenever he wanted.
How did you managed to do that?
A Surrie has to be coded
to your neural signature.
I am not exactly your
average VSI consumer.
This was just a way for me
to spend time with my son.
It's a felony to inhabit a surrogate
registered to another operator.
No offense Dr. Canter.
We're just trying to straighten out our facts.
What is this?
- Some kind of Good Cop, Bad Cop routine?
- No sir.
- You tryin' to handle me?
Because I'm not going to be handled.
Dr Canter...
- I know how you must feel.
- Do you?
Yes, sir.
I lost a son myself.
Do you have any idea why
someone might want to harm Jared?
No.
Or yourself?
Oh my God.
If it was me they were after...
I'm responsible for my sons death.
Well... I guess the interview's over.
[Sobbing]
No!
Robotic surrogates combine
the durability of machines
With the grace and beauty
of the human form
To make your life safer
And better.
Whether you're....
Get ready to live your life without any
risk or danger.
You can live your life
without limitations.
And become anyone you want to be.
From the comfort and
safety of your own home.
VSI, where it all began.
Do what you want.
Be what you want.
Agents Greer and Peters?
I'm Victor Welsh.
VP of corporate relations.
Please Sit.
- Thanks for taking the time to see us.
- No problem.
You uh... You must know Andy Stone?
Our immediate superior.
Do give him my regards.
- We're from the legal department.
- Hope you don't mind if we sit in.
Not at all.
The two of you might be interested in a free software
upgrade we're offering all law enforcement officials.
Better night vision.
Improved pursuit capability.
You have any idea how a surrogates
head would explode from the inside?
Mr. Welsh isn't qualified
to answer that question.
What do the operators say?
Not much.
They're dead.
If you're trying to imply a link between VSI
products and an operators accidental death...
I'm not implying anything.
I just want to know how an operator
can be killed by signals from it's surrogate.
This idea itself is absurd.
If it were possible it would defeat
the entire purpose of surrogacy.
Surries have jumped from bridges...
Been shot....
Even... blown to bits without the
least bit of harm to their operators.
The failsafes always kick in.
I can assure you VSI's products have the most
stringent safety standards in the industry.
What about a human head?
What would cause one of them to blow up?
Agent Greer...
We're not doctors.
Honey...
I don't know WHAT you are.
I mean for all I know you could be some big fat dude
sitting in a stim chair with his dick hanging out.
Interesting technique.
I hate lawyers.
[Click]
What are you doing?
Mr. Steinberg?
Seth Steinberg?
Hello.
Sorry.
I was in the can.
Agent Peters, I'm Agent Greer with the FBI.
Really?
You know with any chip this damaged...
Every circuit must have fired off at once.
Kablooey!
Have you ever seen anything like this before?
Last week a truck load of GI Joes
did come back for re-conditioning.
And a couple of the
Surries were missing optics.
Mind if we take a look at them?
Here we go.
No bullet holes?
No blast damage?
No scratches.
No dirt. No mud.
Mind if I check out the identity chip?
- Heh. Yeah.
- Why not?
Didn't come back with one.
I'm down!
I'm down.
Damn things aren't free Polaski!
Take the snipers from behind this time.
Yes sir!
Back online.
Follow me.
- Keep an eye on Bravo Company.
- Go kick some ass sir!
Agent Greer you're wasting
your time with these questions.
Why on earth would the Defense Department want to develop
a weapon that could wipe out our own troops?
So no such weapon exists...
If it did, I'd know about it.
And the soldier that we saw?
We routinely remove motherboards
and optics for analysis.
Now if you'll excuse me.
I've got to move a Peace Keeping operation.
- Check your screen
- What?
Myles Strickland.
Who?
Myles Strickland, beat that!
I did a run on criminal records
Guess what I found?
He's already in the system.
He was arrested a month ago
for multiple counts of armed robbery.
And what's really weird about this...
After he was busted...
They let him off.
Someone on the inside's protecting him.
But I put out an APB anyway.
Visual matching.
- Cameras caught your guy.
- Where?
Dorchester, Gore Park and Adams.
Not far from the reservation.
Boston PD is on its way.
Stay here.
Keep tabs on him.
Wait a minute where are you going?
Dorchester.
It wasn't too difficult.
I put his face in the system and... Bingo!
We found him in an alley.
K33 over there brought it to my attention.
Thanks Jerry.
He's one of our best watchers.
He's semi-retired.
So he gets to work out of
his beach house in Maine.
- Pretty sweet huh?
- Yeah, it's a nice setup you have here.
Yeah, we can access every
Surrie on the grid here.
Touch a button.
I can tap into anyone's feed.
It's kinda like being inside Gods head.
[Burps]
Ooooooh Boy... I felt that one coming.
My name's Saunders by the way.
Jennifer Peters.
Yeah... Yeah you are aren't you?
- Can I ask you a question?
- Hmmm?
Why no surrogate?
Me?
[Laughs]
They've been trying to puppet me for years.
But they ain't built a machine
that can handle this big puppy yet.
[Alarm Sounds]
Excuse me a second...
We have an assault and
battery in progress.
I need warrants to shut
them down immediately.
Charlie 4639er.
Sierra 7855
Let's see if they have a
security camera in the hotel...
Looks like there is one.
Warrant recieved.
Agent Peters...
Watch this.
Boom.
Since when have you been
able to cut off operators?
It's brand new software.
I call it buffering.
Let's me disconnect anyone
from their surrogate.
Well that can't be legal?
Ahhh... It's a grey area.
They don't ask, we don't tell.
It's pretty cool huh?
Awww C'mon.
Relax, we're the
good guys.
Suspect on a bike heading east of
South Hampton up a mile from the Res'
Greer, be careful, you're heading straight towards
Dread territory.  We don't have jurisdiction to fly over there.
It's restricted air space.
Greer are you there?
Freeze!
What was that?
Agghhh!!!
Fire! Fire!
I ain't done nothin'!
Give me the bag.
Throw it over here.
Now!
You're an abomination.
Oh god.
Maggie.
Maggie!
Lionel Canter is on the phone.
He's called for Greer a half dozen times.
I can't deal with this right now.
- He's pretty upset.
- Just tell him someone will call him back.
Peters!
You gotta believe me
I tried to stop him.
Well you didn't try hard enough.
You're done for the day.
Clock out.
Oh you're kidding!
God.
Tom?
Oh my God!
Call an ambulance!
Myles Strickland is it?
Why are you...
What's goin' on?
Who was it?
Who gave you the weapon?
And paid you to use it?
I don't know!
Myles you can't lie to me.
I'm not lyin'.
I swear to God sir, I'm not lying.
He never told me his name.
We talked on disposable cell phones.
I never saw
his face.
I couldn't tell you who he
was if my life depended on it!
A Police chase through Dorchester concluded
with an FBI helicopter crash landing
inside Bostons' Dread Reservation
Residents of the Reservation are outraged
over what they're calling
a gross violation of their territorial sovereignity.
Human Coalition Leader, The Prophet
responded in a statement made earlier today.
They've attacked us.
Declared War on our way of
life and left us with one option:
Revolution!
We did not throw the first stone.
But we will throw the last.
Hi.
Hey.
How's the headache?
Still there.
- Thanks for being here.
- Of course.
Imagine a World where
children are always safe.
a world where every child
and every parent is secure.
Make every childhood a happy one.
Surrogates for kids.
Exclusively from VSI.
Where it all Beg...
- Knock Knock.  Hey.
- Andy.  Hi.
Oh my gosh.
- I haven't seen you forever.
- I know.
I should let you guys talk.
- Will you be okay?
- Mmmhmm
See you tomorrow morning.
Bye.
How bad?
The doctor said you're
lucky to be alive.
Good thing you unplugged.
You gotta go get him.
Stricklands got that weapon.
You just get a court order...
There won't be any court
orders, you've been suspended.
For what?
- Tom, you violated our treaty with the Dreads.
- Forget the Treaty!
He killed 5 cops!
Look... I'm gonna take care
of this case myself personally.  Alright?
Now... I'm afraid the bureau won't be able to supply
you with a new surrogate until after the official inquiry.
Same goes for your
gun and your badge.
Don't think about this now.
He killed 5 cops Andy.
Take some time to heal.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Sorry I'm late.
That's ok.
Wow... You look a lot
like your synth.
Yeah
Should we go?
How long has it been since you've
been out without a Surrie?
I can't even remember.
I can't believe they didn't give
you something for the axiety.
Greer?
- Look... This isn't gonna work.
- I'm fine.
I have an idea.
Come on... This is
a really bad idea...
It's gonna be alright.  I'm sure
we'll find you something decent.
Now we're gonna have you
back on your feet in a sec.
Sync looks good.
It's responding well to signal, right?
It feels numb.
It's only a base model.
It comes with vision and hearing.
If you want other senses
they're extra.
Of course if you like seeing your own
face when you look in the mirror, no problem.
I'll just scan your head, cast the thermo plastic
and you're good to go
in less than an hour.
Hey no charge on the improvements.
I'm sure you wouldn't mind taking yourself back
5, 10 years, huh?
What do you think of that?
- Hmmm?
- I think we're done here.
Greer.
Tom.
Tom you can't come out
here by yourself.  It's not safe.
- I'm fine.
- Let me take you home.
I'm not going home.
Tom.  We gotta forget the case.
Stone is going to run things his way
and as far as we're concerned, it's over.
It's not over until we
get that weapon back.
Then you gotta let me help you.
I'm not gonna let you win.
Take care of yourself Peters.
Death came to Myles Strickland
As death comes to all men.
But for Myles
It's not an ending.
It's a new beginning.
When you sacrifice your
own personal desires
for a greater cause, a greater good.
You never die.
You never disappear.
That is what it means to be human.
There is no alternative
You can try to escape by
living through a puppet
Through a machine.
But deep down inside, you
know you're living a lie
Here, inside these walls
We understand the truth.
We sacrifice many modern
pleasures and conveniences
to feel truly connected.
Not with machines
But with ourselves.
This is the human condition.
This is what gives life meaning.
My friends.
Soon the day will come
when surrogacy must end.
That day, I promise you
Is close at hand.
The day... we get a second chance.
Excuse me.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah
I'd like to speak to
The Prohet for a minute.
You and everybody else bud, no.
You some kind of cop or somethin'?
You have no jurisdiction here.
Can I talk to you
about Myles Strickland please?
Enough.
It's different when you actually feel the pain.
Isn't it?
What happened to Strickland?
Was he a friend of yours?
He had a weapon.
A very dangerous weapon.
My people will do
anything to get this back.
[Laughs]
Well... if I happen to come
across such a weapon
I promise to have it
delivered to your door.
Show him to the gates.
Gently.
Agent Greer.
May I offer you a ride?
You'll have to excuse my appearance.
It's not safe for me to
use my usual surrogates.
Dr. Canter.
This is one of VSI's newer models.
How long have you been following me?
Long enough to know you're getting
nowhere solving my sons murder.
You lost a child Agent Greer?
How?
Car accident.
It was just an accident.
I'm sorry.
I can think of no worse tragedy
than a parent outliving a child.
All I can tell you
is that the man who killed your son is dead.
His name was Myles Strickland.
Lived on the Res'.
He was killed by his own people.
And that's it?
Case solved?
One man didn't act on his own.
Whatever killed my son
was an extraordinary
sophisticated technology.
Far beyond the capabilites of the Dreads.
We're talking about a
billion dollar weapons project.
Who do you know spends money like that?
Focus on the weapon, where it came from.
Mmmm do me.
How was it?
- Hey Maggie?
- No, thank you.
Come on... it'll take the edge off.
Tom?
Honey?
I thought you were still in the hospital?
Yeah...
I can see that.
What happened?
Tom I don't want you going out
without your Surrie ever again.
- Tom?
- You look very nice, Sexy.
Ok... Don't start.
I'm sorry, those guys...
They're friends of Brigettes, she
brought them over, she wanted to go to this party...
I didn't even want to go.
How long have you been jacking?
I don't.
I don't do it Tom.
And what does it matter if I did?
Why are you being like this?
Okay go have a good time.
Tom stop it!
Tom?
Tom, what was that?
- What?
- What you want from me?
I want you...
...My wife.
I am your wife.
And you won't see it.
No. God.
No you're not.
Not...
Not... this.
Not this... thing...
This...
I just want you.
And I want the woman that's in that room.
My wife.
Things have changed Tom.
You're... No you've changed.
You're just scared.
You're just scared...
We could go talk to somebody...
Maggie...
Maggie your my wife.
Agent Greer?
Is that... Is that you?
Yeah.
- You look... You look terrible.
- Thanks you too.
The chips completely fried.
What do you got on the girl?
Come on...
Let's go talk to her Op.
We can we access any Surrie in the grid.
Touch of a Button, I can
tap into anyones feed.
Transfer to remote operator.
I wish I could help.
This thing killed 5 cops.
One of my men.
Almost put me in the ground.
I know it's a weapon.
I want to know what kind.
- You're asking me to compromise highly
classified information...
- I know where it is.
Where is it?
Right...
Is called an O.D.
Overload Device.
The idea was to end
the battle with one shot.
Giving the software virus straight to the CPU.
Disables the Surries instantly.
We didn't know the virus would
defeat the built in failsafes.
...kill the operators.
Who makes it?
VSI.
After the test
the project was scrapped.
Every unit was destroyed.
Except this one right?
Where is it?
Right now it's in the hands of the Human Coalition.
- How long have they had it?
- A day...
Maybe two.
This is out of your hands.
Military will handle this.
- You called for us?
- Take this to
the federal building downtown.
A woman will meet you there.
Agent Jennifer Peters.
You're to give it to her... and her alone.
Peters.
What are you doing?
Just a background check on VSI.
Structural stuff.
Those are internal financial records.
Talk to Jenkins in corporate.
6th Floor.
Don't forget the cheek bones.
Okay, honey.
Face off.
Maggs.
Hiya Tom.
Those ugh... Smile muscles need to set.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I'm sorry about last night.
I'm at work Tom.
- I didn't come here to argue.
- Good.
See I feel like I've gone crazy.
It's...
I just...
I love you.
I love this smart, beautiful
Intelligent, funny
Woman... And...
I can't sleep.
And when I do... I have these dreams that are...
And I can't stop
thinking about him.
Tom... don't...
Don't you ever think about him?
Of course I think about him Tom.
You say you don't sleep?
You say you have nightmares?
That girl who you say
is funny and charming and whitty...
And has a great smile...
she doesn't smile anymore.
I don't believe that.
The only reason I can get up in the
morning and get out of the house
Is because THIS is who I am now.
- That's okay, honey.
- No, no.
- No.
- Maggie.
- NO!
Maggie wait.
Brothers and sisters gather
close and prepare yourselves.
The day of the resurrection is upon us.
The day we make history.
The day we launch the revolution!
We all know what we're looking for.
Remember...  Do not fire
unless absolutely necessary.
Biologicals here.
Over there!
- Cease fire!
- Hands on your head.
- Cease fire.
My God.
I couldn't figure out why
the cops let Strickland off.
So I started going
through the payroll records.
You won't believe this.
- For the last 16 months...
- He was working for us.
That's right.
Which means Stones
gotta be dirty.
Looks like he hired Strickland to kill Canter.
Hey Tom.
I thought you were on leave?
Oh yeah... I am.
Actually I was just suspended.
Another investigation,
I'll just clear my desk out.
You should be home.
Recuperating Ok?
Not walking around here in the flesh...
I was at home then I came
here to clean out my desk.
And you know... before the
medication kicks in... Hopefully...
I can find a box...
And... Oh...
Victor Welsh wanted me to say hello.
I'm sorry?
Victor Welsh, VSI, the good looking kid?
Very excited you coming over there, finally
moving into the private sector
You must be excited.
Why don't you come into my
office, you're not looking too sharp.
Yeah Yeah... I got a minute.
It's a good move for you.
It's a really good group over there.
Smart.
Talented.
Great legal department.
Great working environment.
You gotta be happy with those
first year stock options huh?
What are you talkin' about?
Myles Strickland, the guy I was chasing...
The guy you hired to kill Canter.
- Tom you got it all wrong.
- You gave him the weapon.
VSI makes them.
They give one to you, you give it to
Strickland so he can go out and kill Canter.
The only problem is, he
killed his son by mistake.
- Something is wrong with you.
- Why are you doing this?
Money? Is that what it is?
You need help.
This is Stone.  That son of a
bitch Greer disabled my unit!
Stop him!
Go... Go!
Jesus.  No wonder VSI
wants Canter dead.
He's in bed with The Prophet.
He's funding the
Anti-Surrogacy Movement.
He's given them names.
Crazy bastard invents surragotes and
does everything he can to destroy them.
It doesn't connect Stone to the murder.
We need to link him to the weapon.
He needed codes to use it.
I want you to look for access codes.
You get the codes... You nail Stone.
Good job Agent Greer.
Thank you.
This is Agent Peters.  I found Greer.
He's been in an accident at
Market and Hanover.
- FBI!!!
- Get out of the car!
He's gone.
Scanning for identity chip.
He doesn't have one, he's a meatbag!
There's and exit in the back!
Hey! Where you going?!
HEY!!!
Bobby it's Greer.
I need a remote shutdown.
Agent Peters has been hijacked.
You gotta disconnect her.
Bobby?
Hello Bobby?
Peters.
Have you gone insane?
Why don't you put the gun down? huh?
What are you trying to prove?
She's grabbing into the entire 3rd network!
Maggie get offline right away, as
soon as you get this message.
Something is going to
happen to the surrogates.
- She'll only speak to you sir.
- Why don't you just move in and take her down huh?
She has a human hostage.
Uh... the slob Saunders...
Peters?
Peters it's me Andy Stone.
That's far enough Stone.
I know who hired you to kill me.
I hope my old partners
at VSI paid you well.
Did you feel even a second of remorse
when you found out you murdered an innocent boy?
Canter?
I don't believe it.
Ok... How about you tell me something Doctor. Huh?
What did you expect VSI to do?
Just stand by while you tore
down everything they built?
You left us no choice
but to take you out.
You created the technology, you changed
the world and now want to destroy it?
So what?
So you can take us backwards?
So we can all live like Dreads?
So we can live like
human beings.
Really Doctor?
You should learn
how to live with your regrets.
Now give me the gun.
That's for my son.
I need to see your boss.
I need to see Dr. Canter right away!
Oh good... Listen to me... I
gotta to see your boss.  Dr. Canter he...
Device connected.
Over here officers, this way.
Warning!  Commencing Upload.
Hello Tom.
Nice to finally meet you.
In the flesh.
Now... Lie on the floor, face down.
It's a little different when you have
to kill somebody with your own hands.
You're going to have to squeeze the trigger.
You don't have a machine to do your dirty work.
Feel that?
An accelerated pulse, the
heightened awareness...
Savouring each breath
as if it were your last.
That what you've been missing.
That's what everbodys been missing.
- So you kill millions of people?
- I changed the course of human
history when I invented surrogates.
Now I'm going to change it back.
You can't change what's been done.
You and I know that
better than most people.
My son's death will not
have been in vain.
Not if it heals mankind.
Heals mankind?
That what you want to do?
You want to kill everyone?
- And that's going to heal mankind?
- They're already dead.
They died the minute they
plugged into those machines.
This is not the solution.
- That's the way it is.
- That's not the way it is!
I had a vision.  I was going
to empower the powerless.
To enable other like me to walk, to feel.
- To live a normal life.
- Listen to me! They're going to call you
a murderer!  That is what you're doing!
Surrogacy is a perversion.
It's an addiction.
And you have to kill the
addict to kill the addiction.
Upload Complete.
You're too late.
What I've done can't be stopped.
Now you're going to be witness
to the rebirth of humanity.
That's my gift to you.
No! NO!
Selecting All Surrogates.
How do we make it stop?
Bobby it's Greer.
Tom Greer.
How do we shut
this thing down?
All Database Selected.
Jesus... He's trying to kill everyone.
Listen... That thing has just uploaded a virus into the system
that's going to kill anyone who's using a surrogate.
It's already started.
Bobby we need to
unplug everyone... Now!
Think!
Uh.... Uh....
I... Ok... Move over to
the terminal on the left!
Type in password:
RED253
We can't unplug them
but maybe we can buffer the operators.
Oh God... Ok... we've got 10 seconds!
Ok look... there are three passes.
Type in Tango in the first.
Xray in the second.
772 in the third.
Hit Enter.
HIT ENTER!!! What
happe... Ah.. Shit!
SHIFT and Enter!
Uh... Ah...
Uh... You just saved about
billion lives there.
Ok... Now we gotta keep
the surrogates from getting fried.
Please go back to the first
terminal hit the Enter key.
Hit the Enter key please!
Good... Now press Yes.
So that's it?
Everyone's safe?
- What?
- All the people?
Yes... Yes... Of course yes.
All the operators are safe.
But if you don't press abort, all the
surrogates are going to be destroyed.
We don't have a lot
of time man... Hit Yes.
Hi? Hello?  Hit Yes Greer!
Greer I'm talking
about ALL the surrogates!
Wha... What are you doing?
Greer??!!
For God's sakes what
are you waiting for?!
Press the friggin' button damnit!
Freeze!!!
Transmit Complete.
Excuse me.
Bare with us as we're still trying to piece
together exactly what has occured today
There has been a total systems
failure of the central surrogate grid
In every major city on the eastern
seaboard, possibly in the entire United States...
...describing an identical failure
in those cities this is unbelievable...
...no reports of human casualties
the damage appears limited only to surrogate units...
...thus far, no statements from VSI.  They have
not responded to requests for information...
...Paris, London, Beijing
all reporting the same thing...
...there is still no official word when or if surrogate services can be restored.
It appears, at least for now, that we are on our own.