[PA BEEPS]
PILOT [OVER PA]:
Ladies and gentlemen...
...we are beginning our descent
into Berlin Tegel...
...where local time is 8:30 a.m. And the
temperature is a cool minus four degrees.
Morning.
Did you sleep?
No. I'll sleep at the hotel.
You'll do great.
You always do.
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN
OVER PA]
What's the purpose of your visit?
We're here for a biotechnology summit.
I'm giving a presentation.
Mr. And Mrs. Harris, welcome to Berlin.
MARTIN:
Danke schon.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER:
Next, please.
"I'm giving a presentation"?
Well, she asked.
- Oof. Welcome to Berlin.
MAN: Taxi.
Taxi.
Martin, get in the car. Let him do that.
[GROANS]
Oh, ya-ya.
[DRIVER SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
What do you think he's saying?
No idea.
Look. Isabel Kronenberger is showing
here on Saturday.
Oh, yeah.
Remember when we saw her
in Chicago?
[CHUCKLING]
Yes.
Why don't I meet you there on Saturday
after my lunch with Professor Bressler?
Yeah.
If you promise.
I promise.
- Welcome to the Hotel Adlon Kempinski.
MARTIN: Thank you.
You check in, honey.
I'll take care of this.
Have you stayed with us before?
- First time in Berlin.
RECEPTIONIST:
If there's anything else I can do for you...
How much do I owe you?
DRIVER:
Thirty-seven, sir.
Welcome to the Adlon Kempinski Berlin.
How may I help you, madam?
- Dr. And Mrs. Harris, the Eisenhower suite.
- Of course.
MARTIN: Wait, wait.
- Everything okay, sir?
- Is this everything from the taxi?
- Yes, sir.
I'm afraid, Mrs. Harris, but the Eisenhower
suite may not be available right now.
What do you mean "not available"?
There have been changes,
security reasons.
[PHONE RINGING]
But we confirmed two weeks ago.
Would you allow me
to answer the phone?
MARTIN:
I'll go to the airport. I'll be back, okay?
[RECEPTIONIST SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Oh, please.
Excuse me, driver?
Is there another route?
Oh, come on.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Look out!
- No!
[GINA SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[GASPING]
[METAL CREAKING]
[SIREN APPROACHING]
[CROWD SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Hello? Hello?
[MUFFLED]
Can you hear me?
[EMTS SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[DEFIBRILLATOR CHARGING]
[DEFIBRILLATOR ZAPS]
[LIZ LAUGHING]
[LIZ MOANING]
[RESPIRATOR PUMPING]
[BOTH SPEAKING IN
MUFFLED GERMAN]
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Dr. Farge?
Dr. Farge. Dr. Farge.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
I don't speak German.
FARGE:
Are you English?
American.
You have been in an accident.
Accident?
Can you tell me your name?
Your name.
Martin. Martin Harris.
Dr. Martin Harris.
Where's my wife, Liz?
- Is she hurt? Is she hurt? Where is she?
- Calm down.
It's all right, Dr. Harris.
You were the only passenger.
The taxi you were in went into the river.
Your heart stopped for several minutes.
It's Thursday, November 24th.
You have been in a coma for four days.
Thanksgiving.
But my wife, she's in Berlin with me.
Where is she? Why isn't she here?
We couldn't find any identification
with you, Dr. Harris.
No, no, no.
- Please, calm down.
MARTIN: Aah.
Where can we reach your wife?
Does she have a cell phone?
Of course she has a cell phone. It's...
Uh...
I can't remember.
Can you tell me what you do remember,
Martin?
Bits and pieces. Arriving at the airport.
Getting in a taxi with Liz...
...but I don't know how I got here.
There are no rules with severe trauma
of this kind.
Memories get lost or fractured.
Most of them return,
although it's unlikely...
...you will ever fully recall the events
around your accident.
In the meantime, let us see
if anyone has filed a report...
...looking for a Martin Harris, okay?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- Okay.
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN ON TV]
ANNOUNCER: From London
with Kevin Spencer and Diana Bailey.
Good evening.
Welcome to the BNI World News.
Here are today's top stories.
The Prime Mini...
[TURNS TV OFF]
Clothes. For you.
MARTIN: Has anybody been
looking for me? My wife?
Meine Frau?
[CHUCKLING]
Come here, you.
It's beautiful. Just beautiful.
LIZ:
I'm glad you like it.
She gave it to me as a gift.
In Paris. On our honeymoon.
[CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS]
Prince Shada arrived in Berlin today for
this year's biotechnology global summit.
The personal attendance
of the flamboyant prince...
...has fueled speculation that the summit,
now in its 10th year...
...will witness the announcement
of a major scientific breakthrough.
With the world's leading researchers
convening...
...at the luxurious Hotel Adlon
in Central Berlin...
- Hotel Adlon.
...the field of biotechnology...
...steps into the forefront
of the media spotlight.
I'm here for the summit.
Nurse.
You have to realize the risk.
Doctor, I've been gone for four days.
My wife is out there in a city
she doesn't know. She'll be terrified.
I need to find her.
Sign this.
It releases you from my care.
And here's my card.
Any nausea, dizziness, difficulty with
speech, you contact me immediately.
- Do you understand?
- Thank you.
Welcome to the Hotel Adlon Kempinski.
How may I help you?
Yes, hi. I'm a guest of the hotel.
I lost my room key. I need a new one.
- What room are you staying in?
- The Eisenhower suite.
- And may I have your name?
- Martin Harris. Dr. Martin Harris.
And may I please see some ID,
Mr. Harris?
There's been a situation.
I've lost my passport.
I'm going to need some ID, sir.
If you get someone to escort me
to my room, I can prove it.
Just give me a moment.
[MAN AND RECEPTIONIST SPEAKING
IN GERMAN ON PHONE]
- Excuse me. Do you have an invitation?
- No.
I mean, yes. My name is Dr. Martin Harris.
I'm on the list.
- Let me check.
- I saw my wife go inside.
I'm trying to find her.
Herr Strauss?
- Dr. Martin Harris?
- Yes.
Yes. There you are. I'm Herr Strauss,
head of the Hotel Security.
Do you have any identification?
Passport, driver's license?
No, I don't, but...
- You would know him, he's over there.
- Professor Bressler!
STRAUSS: Sir, please.
He knows me.
He can confirm who I am.
- Lf you will be patient, sir, no problem.
- I'm being very patient.
Thank God. There she is. That's my wife,
over there by the buffet table.
I have been missing for four days and she
has no idea what happened to me...
...so I need you to take me to her
right now.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- The lady in the dark dress.
- Okay.
[GIGGLING]
Excuse me, madam.
Your husband is here.
Liz. Oh, Jesus.
Excuse me. Do I know you?
But, Liz... What's wrong?
I'm sorry.
I was in an accident. I was in a coma.
They didn't know who I was.
I said I'm sorry.
Oh, you must have me confused
with someone else.
MARTIN:
Liz.
It's me, Martin.
Your husband.
This is a misunderstanding.
I don't know this man.
- Okay.
- Martin.
This is my husband.
You are Dr. Martin Harris?
Last time I looked.
Yep, still me.
What's going on here?
Is this some kind of a joke?
Joke about what?
Because it's not very funny.
- Do you know this man?
- No.
Who the hell are you?
I'm her husband.
Okay. Okay.
Would you mind just getting him
away from us, please?
- Liz. Liz, stop this.
MARTIN B: Hey.
- Gentlemen, please, please, please.
- Get your hands off me.
MARTIN B: Back off.
- What's going on?
- Tell me.
- Back off!
- What's this all about?
MARTIN B: Why don't you take a walk?
STRAUSS:
Gentlemen, please.
- Don't touch me.
- Come on, come on!
If you don't leave now,
we have to call the police.
Call the police! Call the goddamn army!
That's a good idea!
What's happening?
You're embarrassing me. Please.
- Get him out of here.
- Liz!
- I must apologize. Have a nice evening.
- I was hurt!
- Liz! Why are you doing this to me?
MARTIN B: You okay?
Can you believe this?
Right there.
That's Liz. And I am...
I must've been outside.
I can't remember.
Well, as you can see, you are not there.
OFFICER: Immigration confirms the arrival
of a Dr. And Mrs. Harris...
...on November the 20th at 7:40 a.m.
- Yes.
At 8:50, she checked into their suite
at the hotel...
...followed by Dr. Harris
at 3 in the afternoon.
- What?
- Danke.
Wait. He's... He's not Martin Harris.
I am Dr. Martin Harris.
The man upstairs is pretending
to be me.
And this impostor,
did he also steal your wife?
He must be forcing her or something.
Well, why? Help me. Why?
For God's sake,
just do an Internet search.
There are over 400 Martin Harrises
in the United States, sir.
We already checked.
Rod. Rodney Cole,
a colleague at Langemore in the States.
A dear friend.
He can verify who I am.
Please, call him. It's 001...
[OFFICER DIALING]
[MARTIN SIGHS]
...508-146-2595.
RODNEY [ON RECORDING]:
This is Dr. Cole. I'm having an...
Sorry, answering machine.
Please, leave a message.
Professor Bressler. Talk to him.
He's the reason I'm in Berlin.
He invited me over to the summit
to discuss my thesis.
- You know Professor Bressler?
- Yes.
Well, we haven't actually met,
but we've been speaking on the phone...
...e- mailing, dozens of times.
[GUARD SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
- Why don't you arrest him?
STRAUSS: For what?
Entering the country legally?
Presenting all the correct documentation
and sharing a hotel suite with his wife?
Excuse me. With your wife.
She is my wife.
Herr Strauss? I found a Dr. Martin Harris
at Langemore University.
Yes. Thank you.
That's what I've been trying...
Okay.
Wait, please, wait.
You're going to arrest me?
I demand to speak to my embassy.
Unfortunately, it's your Thanksgiving.
The embassy's closed until Monday.
Herr Strauss,
can I have a quiet word, please?
Okay.
Listen...
...you're probably right. L...
The accident.
I, uh...
I haven't been remembering things
very well. I'm confused.
This is my doctor
at the hospital here in Berlin.
He warned me that this sort of thing,
this was gonna happen.
I need to go back there now.
I'm so embarrassed.
So now you are saying
that you are not Dr. Martin Harris?
I don't know.
[GUARD SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
Wait, stop. Stop. I've changed my mind.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
- Need passport.
- Please.
Please?
Police. Very bad.
[RINGS]
RODNEY [ON RECORDING]:
This is Dr. Cole.
I'm having an out-of-office experience
right now. Please, leave a message.
[BEEPS]
Rodney, it's me, Martin.
Listen, I'm in Berlin
for the summit, but...
It's Liz. She's...
l... I don't know what she's doing...
...and there's another man involved.
It... She... She...
I'm in trouble, Rod. We...
[OPERATOR SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Shit.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[FOOTSTEPS STOP]
[IN GERMAN]
[BELL TOLLING]
MAN: He says he doesn't care
if she saved your life.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
The bitch cost him 20,000 Euros.
The insurance won't cover the cab
as she had no license.
[MAANGER SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
He says illegal immigrants
are destroying German society.
So I'm guessing he doesn't know
where she is.
No one knows where she is.
Well, thank him for his time.
MARTIN:
Excuse me.
Hey, American.
I'm sorry we couldn't help you.
You know where she is, I can tell.
Look, I just wanna thank her.
She saved my life.
I thought maybe I could give her
some money. I just wanna thank her.
Please.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
You remember me?
- I was in your taxi.
- I don't drive taxi.
MARTIN:
I was in your taxi.
We crashed.
I need to know,
where did you pick me up?
- Where was I going?
- How did you find me?
Your friend, Biko.
[IN GERMAN]
[WHISPERS]
Just leave me alone.
MARTIN:
Please, help me.
Just leave me alone.
Thank you for saving me.
Excuse me.
I need to find Professor Bressler's lab.
I have an appointment at 12:30. I'm late.
- Your name, please?
- Dr. Martin Harris.
Wait here, please.
The professor knows who I am.
We scheduled this appointment
weeks ago.
MARTIN B:
Drake, the English botanist...
...who wondered how it manages
to reproduce...
...as it doesn't appear to attract
any insects.
Yes. One wonders how plants are
developing firm, unlike m...
[IN GERMAN]
- Bressler.
- This lab is restricted. Who are you?
This man is not Martin Harris.
I am Dr. Martin Harris.
So, what is this?
There are two Martin Harrises, huh?
MARTIN B:
No, let me explain.
This man showed up at my hotel last night
claiming to be me.
- The police were called.
- I called the police, son of a bitch!
He checked himself out of a hospital.
- He was in an accident.
- Professor.
[IN GERMAN]
Ja. Danke.
We talked, you and I, on the phone.
We discussed
alternative forms of propagation.
I told you about my father,
a schoolteacher, his passion for science.
We talked about your children...
...about how much time you've spent
with them since you lost your wife.
Two girls, right?
You told me their names. And I...
I just can't...
I know them. I know them.
- Laurel.
MARTIN B: Laurel, Lily, twins.
Ten years old.
About the same age I was when I told
my father I wanted to be a botanist.
Do you remember, Professor?
We talked about that on the phone...
...how I'd never seen my father
this happy.
No, that wasn't you.
Don't you remember? We spoke
about how brave our wives were...
BOTH:
To marry scientists.
- I told you about our...
- Our honeymoon in Paris.
My wife and I. And how she wanted to visit
all the museums.
- All I wanted to do was go to the...
BOTH: L'Ecole Polytechnique.
BOTH: But she insisted. And that's how
I first saw Leonardo's Vitruvian man.
Wow.
This is not happening.
STUDENT:
[IN GERMAN]
Moment, Moment.
I don't know who this man is,
but he has taken everything from me.
You have to arrest him.
Go on, arrest him.
I don't believe I need to do this.
[LIZ'S LAUGHTER ECHOING]
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
MARTIN:
No.
[IN GERMAN]
My friend, he...
...looks...
No, he finds people.
FARGE:
Martin.
The mistake was mine.
I should never have let you leave.
- What's happening to me, doctor?
- Confusion...
...memory loss,
complete or partial loss of identity.
These are common stages in recovery.
A person can awaken from a coma...
...convinced of a reality
that was previously only fantasy.
We are going to sedate you now...
...do another MRI,
try to find out what's going on, okay?
If I'm not Martin Harris,
why do I know so much about him?
Perhaps he was someone
you read about...
...or met once in passing.
Do you know what it feels like
to become insane, doctor?
It's like a war
between being told who you are...
...and knowing who you are.
Which do you think wins?
[MACHINE THUMPING]
[BOTH MOANING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOUGE]
[THUMPING STOPS]
Hello, Martin. This won't take very long.
[GRUNTS]
[DOOR OPENING]
[IN GERMAN]
GRETCHEN:
SMITH:
[GRETCHEN GRUNTS]
[NECK SNAPS]
[DOOR CLOSING]
[GRUNTING]
[ALL SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
It's okay. I'm feeling much, much better.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[RINGING]
MAN [ON TV]: And now with us,
Rebecca for the weather.
Hello?
REBECCA [ON TV]: So it's going to be
a cold night here in Central Berlin...
...with an overnight low
of three degrees...
...and a high probability of more snow
throughout tomorrow.
And now to the West,
to the Ruhr Valley.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
- Herr Jurgen?
- Yeah?
You met her?
She looked after me in the hospital.
She was kind to me too.
I'm sorry. She's dead.
Come. Come in.
Thank you.
Drink?
No, thanks.
I was a former member of the Stasi...
...the Ministry for State Security.
- East German secret police, huh?
- Yes.
Proudly.
[COUGHING AND GAGGING]
Excuse me.
I cannot drink any longer,
but I like to forget that.
We Germans are experts at forgetting.
We forgot we were Nazis.
Now we have forgotten 40 years
of Communism, all gone.
But it's not just history that's forgotten,
it's people too.
Please tell me more about
Nurse Gretchen Herfort.
Quite a story.
For a moment,
they had me convinced I was crazy.
But when they came to take me,
when they...
...killed your friend, I knew.
I'm not sure how I can be of service.
I need you to help me prove I'm me.
May I?
Please.
It's a gift from my father.
I always have it with me.
These mean anything to you?
No. It's my wife's writing.
So they mean something to her.
That's my schedule for this week.
I wrote it from memory.
Your wife's involvement in this.
There must have been something in
the past, a new friend, an acquaintance?
No, no, no.
Unexplained absence?
No, no. There was nothing.
I would've known.
Men always like to think.
It's not Liz. I know her.
Yet she does not know you.
Look, whoever's been doing this,
they've been planning it for some time.
They have passports, credit cards,
family photos, for God's sakes.
I mean, this takes preparation,
doesn't it?
They have detailed knowledge of my
research, my relationship with Professor...
As well as the fact that you were going
to have a random accident...
...that would allow a stranger
to seamlessly take your place?
These people may be good,
but they are not God.
A little confirmation would be nice.
Somewhere there's proof.
They can't have thought of everything.
The question is,
why would they want to take your place?
What could they gain from being you?
What does your wife gain
by denying you exist?
Do you believe me?
In the Stasi, we had a basic principle:
Ask enough questions and a man who
is lying will eventually change his story...
...but a man who tells the truth
cannot change his...
...however unlikely his story sounds.
- Do you believe me?
- I believe...
...you are telling the truth, Dr. Harris.
I'll start by calling your colleague
at Langemore.
As you say, it's Thanksgiving,
and there's the time difference...
...so it may take time to make contact.
Then there is the question of...
Oh, of money. Of course.
Unfortunately, yes. Money.
Of course. Here.
Here's everything I have.
I'll pay you in full as soon as I can.
- For expenses.
- Sure.
I'll need 24 hours.
Call me tomorrow afternoon.
And go find your taxi driver.
See if she'll talk to me.
She was there at the beginning of all this.
Perhaps she knows something.
I've already tried.
There may be details we've overlooked.
That's what I was really known for,
details.
MARTIN:
Gina?
I know why you ran away
from the accident.
You're an illegal.
If the police had picked you up,
they would have deported you.
Look, I want you to have this.
- What if I don't want it?
- It's worth at least 5000 Euro.
Feel the weight of it.
Go on. It's the real thing.
"E.H. To M.H."?
Elizabeth Harris, my wife, to me, Martin.
Special gift.
Okay, Martin Harris.
What do you want?
There's someone
I need you to speak to.
- I'm not talking to the police.
- He's not the police. I promise you.
I just need you to tell him
what happened.
Anything,
everything you can remember.
And I need a place to crash tonight.
[CHUCKLES]
Please?
Sentiment,
it's always the first thing to go.
OFFICER [IN GERMAN]:
Brandt.
Jurgen?
I picked you up from the Adlon Hotel.
You wanted to go to the airport.
You were in a hurry.
That's it?
But I'd just arrived.
Doesn't make sense.
She didn't recognize you?
How long have you been married?
- Five years.
- Five years?
I know it sounds crazy, but it's true.
This is it.
Sorry, no elevator.
I know, not the Adlon Hotel.
[WOMAN SHOUTING IN GERMAN]
[NEIGHBORS SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
The walls are made of cardboard,
but it's home.
I have to work tonight.
You can sleep in there.
I have extra mattress.
MARTIN:
It's quaint.
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[COUGHING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MAN SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
MARTIN:
Would you mind if I took a shower?
You could try. I'm not sure you will fit.
The light is broken. You need to leave
the door open if you want to see anything.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
- I'm sorry. I just... I'm sorry.
- I give you a place to stay.
- That does not give you the right to...
- You're right.
They're good, the drawings.
You want to know?
This is me.
Two thousand
two hundred fifty-eight Euros...
...and counting.
I get to 4000, I can buy papers
so I can get the hell out of here.
Sell the watch.
You'll get more than you need.
I plan to.
[THUMPING]
[NEIGHBORS MOANING
AND GRUNTING]
[WOMAN SHOUTING]
[MAN SHOUTING]
[WOMAN MOANING]
Ohh.
How do you sleep?
Eh. He never goes for very long.
This guy, Jurgen.
He's absolutely no danger to you.
Okay.
[KNOCKING]
Hello.
You got company.
Do you have the keys?
Bring it back to my place,
leave the keys on the TV...
...and don't forget to reset the meter.
- You're the best.
- I know. Come.
Yes, I sleep with every American
you send my way.
No need to explain.
[BIKO LAUGHING]
[SHOWER RUNNING]
[KNOCKS]
GINA:
Biko! You're going to be late.
[GINA YELPS]
[GINA GRUNTING]
[SHOWER RUNNING]
[GRUNTS]
[CLATTER]
[SCREAMS]
Shh.
[CREAK]
[GLASS BREAKS]
Jones?
[GASPING]
[SMITH YELLS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
Biko? Biko?
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[GASPS]
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?
[GINA PANTING]
Biko's keys.
Give them to me.
Come on, you can't stay here.
This one!
[CAR DOORS CLOSE]
Are you all right?
That guy,
he killed a nurse in the hospital.
- What?
- He killed a nurse.