ANNOUNCER:
The following program
is brought to you
in living color on NBC.
(fanfare plays)
♪♪
(gunshot)
(man grunts)
(groans)
Why do you stop me?
Because I do not want to pay
for the stupidity of my brother.
(grunts)
Only you think it is stupid
to kill the white man.
I know that if you scalp
a white man,
the Bannocks will be blamed.
But we must kill them.
And drive them out.
No, Lagos.
They are too many and too wise.
We'll never drive them out.
I don't like them
any better than you do.
But we have to learn
to live with them.
You talk like a woman.
All right, brother,
soon-to-be chief of my people,
you handle the white man
your way, I'll handle him mine.
You make me ashamed
to call you brother.
(theme song playing)
I'm glad you brought him here.
You remembered what I read to
you about "love thy neighbor."
I had to, when I found
he was still alive.
I couldn't let even a white man
to die in the sun.
I'm glad he lives.
I'm not sure I am.
(horse approaching, neighing)
So, you would rather
leave our village
and live here like an outcast.
What are you doing here, Lagos?
You should never have taken that
Shoshone woman as your wife.
You, too, are
the son of a chief.
Your place is with your people.
My people turned me away.
This is my home now.
Did you move the body
of the white man
I killed this afternoon?
No.
I did not move him.
Why?
I went back to take the scalp
so I could give it
to our father.
This one would
have made him proud.
You would say the same
about any white man's scalp.
LAGOS:
That was not any white man.
That was the owner
of all this land
that once belonged
to our people.
You mean, the white man
whose scalp I saved
is the owner of the range
called the Ponderosa?
That is what I mean.
I left the white man
where he fell.
I know this kind of woman.
If the white man lived,
she would have you take him.
You might even
have brought him here.
I will look inside,
to make sure.
This is my place.
I say there is
no white man inside.
You will not look.
HATOYA:
I'm sorry you visit our home
only on such an errand.
There is no white man here.
I believe you even less
than I believe my brother.
You'd better leave.
Now, Lagos.
(hoofbeats receding)
He is still bleeding.
Will you change the bandage
while I get some fresh water?
No.
I can't touch him now.
Stop that.
You've done enough.
Our father who art in Heaven,
hallowed be thy name...
That's enough!
...thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
on earth as it is in Heaven.
Well, Pa ain't setting traps
at this hour.
Don't worry about Pa--
he can take care of himself.
Yeah, well, he's gone
awful close to Bannock country.
Yeah, and them Indians have been
acting up out there lately, too.
Well, they're
getting hungry, Hoss.
Can't hardly grow anything
up in those mountains.
Hunting gets worse every year.
Pa doesn't go into
Bannock country by himself.
Yeah, but...
Adam, our property runs
right up there in them
foothills--that's pretty close.
Well, he took
his blankets with him.
Maybe he's gonna
sleep overnight.
(horse approaching)
Hi, Ike.
Howdy, boys.
Where's your pa?
HOSS: You're up sort of late,
ain't you, Ike?
What do you want with Pa?
I, uh, I brung him a present.
I've got something
to talk to him about
that I figure won't keep
much longer--where is he?
ADAM: Well, you must have just
missed him on the way over.
He, uh, he's been out setting
traps in that foothill country
right near your place--
we expect him back any minute.
Dad-gumit! If I'd have known
he was going out that way,
I could've saved
myself the trip.
Yeah, what'd you bring him?
Well, uh... let me show you boys
while we're waiting here.
Where'd you get that?
Turned it up with my plow
just yesterday.
It's an Injun skull.
That must be 200 years old.
Yeah. They show up
every once in a while
all over the valley.
Guess there's
no question about...
who originally
lived on this land.
That was then, not now.
How come you'd bring it to Pa?
I can't figure him wanting
a human skull around the place.
Who said anything
about a human skull.
That's an Injun skull!
(laughs)
Ike, I wouldn't, uh,
use those words with Pa.
You, uh, you know how
he feels on the subject.
Yeah, well, he knows
how I feel about it, too!
I got no kick about Injuns
rolling around under my land,
but I'll be dad-burned
if I want any live ones
squatting on top of it!
Your land?
Yeah, my land!
Your pa give it to me
to homestead.
Now, Ike, I don't think
there are any Indians
living on your land.
Well, they're...
awful durn close to it, anyhow!
Your pa's got to do
something about it.
(sighs) We'll give him
your message, Ike.
No, Hoss, I'll give it
to him myself.
I'll, uh, set with you fellas
for a while
and, uh, wait for him.
All right, you can set a while,
but no more talk
about Indians, all right?
Suit yourself.
Now, Ike, it's liable
to be a long wait.
As a matter of fact,
it may be all night.
(quietly):
Oh.
If it is, you can sleep
in the bunkhouse. (sighs)
And I think
we can do without this.
♪♪
(grunting in pain)
(Ben exhales)
(labored breathing)
(labored breathing continues)
His fever is worse.
BEN (weakly):
Why...
why did you try to kill me?
My husband did not
try to kill you.
He found you lying wounded
in a clearing
and brought you here.
It was an Indian that...
tried to kill me, I know that.
You're Bannock.
I am a Bannock.
But I did not try to kill you.
- Perhaps I should have.
- Matsou.
(panting):
I... I didn't...
I didn't mean to accuse you.
I know you've...
you've cared for me.
I'm grateful for your help.
You would have died if he
had left you where you fell.
What is this place?
Where are we?
This place is on your land.
No villages or settlements...
Indian villages on my land.
This is not a village.
Hatoya and I live here alone.
Why are you not
with your village?
I am a Bannock;
she's a Shoshone.
When we married,
neither tribe would accept us.
Where did you find out
about the Bible?
I lived with a man of God
and his wife for three years,
in a white man's town
to the west.
Then I met Matsou.
And we will stay together,
no matter how many times
we have to move.
Who said...
said anything about moving?
We do not stay
where we are not welcome.
BEN:
You are...
you are welcome.
We would still be intruders
on white man's land.
You'd not be intruders...
if I gave you land.
You would give land
to a Bannock?
If you came in peace.
Our people have not signed
a white man's peace treaty.
Put me on my horse, and...
I'll... I'll try
to find my way home.
You are not
well enough yet to travel.
I must, I must,
I must get to a doctor.
We will get him home.
It will take all of God's help.
All right, Hatoya,
I'll hold him on his horse.
You pray.
LITTLE JOE:
Pa!
- What happened?
- Where'd you find him?
MATSOU:
He will need a doctor quickly.
He's badly hurt.
Come inside, both of you.
I'd like to know more
about what happened.
Don't let them red devils
go in the house
after what they done to your pa.
They probably tried
to kill him theirselves.
They brought him home,
didn't they?
Now, shut up.
How did it happen?
We found him wounded
in a clearing.
We tried to care for him,
but the fever is very bad.
He recovered enough
to tell us where he lived.
We brought him here.
Do you mean my father
was in Bannock country?
No.
No, he was on his own land.
That's where we found him.
You see? I told you.
I told you them heathen devils
was sneaking around
on your land.
ADAM: It's a lucky thing
they were there.
Now, keep your mouth shut, Ike.
Thank you very much
for what you did.
You'll need rest and food.
You ain't asking them to stay?
It would be better if we leave.
Your father is a strong man
and very brave.
We both hope he is better soon.
No, please, please, I...
I want you to stay.
Well, I ain't staying
in no house
where they ask Injuns in
and they make 'em welcome.
Why don't you leave?
All right, but don't you forget
that I got a big bone to pick
with your pa when he gets
better, if he ever does.
(door closes)
It's a very, very poor way
to say thank you.
I'm sorry.
If you will just make yourselves
comfortable here, I...
I'll be right back.
We shouldn't have come here.
It was a mistake.
No, Matsou, it was God's will.
If we hadn't brought the white
man home, he would have died.
He's a good man.
He's promised to let us live
on this land.
I never believed
in any white man's promises.
(footsteps approaching)
He's resting more easily now.
How long did you have
to pack him?
Pa's a pretty heavy fellow.
Not far.
We had to take him
from his horse.
The wound was opening again.
Why don't the two of you
get some sleep
while we wait
for the doctor to get here?
I am sure my father would like
to see you before you leave.
Thank you.
How you feeling, Pa?
A lot better than I did.
That's all we can do
for him for now, boys.
I want you three to take turns
making sure
that he stays in bed.
Don't you worry, Doc,
I'll make sure he takes orders.
He'll stay in bed, Doc,
I'll see to that.
Look, I'm sorry about
that wild ride coming over, Doc.
You can take it easy going back.
Yes, indeed, I certainly will.
I don't know how Mr. Cartwright
got hurt or why you helped him,
but one thing
I do know for sure--
if you hadn't helped him
when you did,
he'd be far beyond all help now.
We can't spare men
like Ben Cartwright.
Thanks, Adam.
I'll see you tomorrow, Ben.
Now, you rest, you hear? Hmm?
That's an order.
Thank you, Doctor.
LITTLE JOE:
See you in a little while.
Boys, you mind if I have a...
few minutes alone
with my friends?
Not at all.
You stay in bed, Pa.
I'll be back in a minute.
(door closes)
I don't even know your names.
You have heard them before,
but in your fever.
My name is Hatoya,
and my husband is Matsou.
I'll remember them.
And I haven't forgotten
what I told you
about that piece of land.
We didn't ask for it.
I know you didn't.
I've been thinking about it.
I want you to have
a big piece of land,
enough for a farm.
What would we do
with such a piece of land?
You'd farm it,
raise crops, animals...
live off the land.
(whispers):
How?
I know nothing of such things.
The red man knows more
about hunting and fishing,
the white man knows
more about farming.
If we put what we know together,
there will be more than enough
for us all.
This will never be.
There is no way to begin.
You offer us a farm...
but I know nothing
of such things.
So I say... keep your farm.
Let me ask you a question.
Would you come
to live as a farmer
on your own land
if I and my sons
and the... the settlers in the
valley would teach you,
help you with the things
you do not now know?
It would be so wonderful,
Matsou.
It would also be difficult.
It might not work.
I might not learn.
I've... I've talked too much.
I never believed
such an offer could be made.
The white man always takes.
We will talk and pray
and let you know our decision.
(door opens and closes)
HATOYA: But I have lived among
them in the white man's town.
I know them better than you do.
Perhaps you do not know me
well enough.
I know you very well, beloved,
and I believe we can do
this thing together.
Why can't we stay here?
I could stay here, anywhere,
alone with you forever, Matsou.
But what of our sons
and daughters
who will be coming
if God wills it?
Would you keep them alone, too?
We can go back
to the tribe someday.
They won't always be at war,
and I am a son of a chief.
The youngest son,
and with no great love
for his brother Lagos,
who will be the next chief.
That is true.
This is a chance to have
a better way of life
than we have ever known,
for us and for our children.
I don't know
that it will be better.
I only know that it will
be very different,
and it is this difference
that frightens me.
Frightens you, Matsou?
You have told me
that nothing frightens you.
I spoke those words
as a warrior and a hunter,
and they were true.
And I was raised to be
these things and not a farmer.
You have also told me
that our people
and the white man must learn
to live together in peace.
But you are asking
much more than that.
You are asking me
to put down my bow and arrow
and pick up an ax and a plow.
You are asking me to eat bread
instead of meat,
to wear cloth
instead of leather,
to live in a house
instead of a wickiup.
You are asking me
to stop being an Indian.
And I don't know if I can do it.
♪♪
HATOYA: "I shall lift up
mine eyes unto the hills,
from whence cometh my strength."
I do not know
that I can do it well...
or even that I will
not fail completely.
But I will try, my dearest love,
if you will stand beside me.
No, can't do it, I tell you.
I couldn't hardly believe my own
two ears when I first heard it.
Can't believe it now.
Well, you might as well believe
it, Ike, 'cause it's true.
Well, then, I, I think
you're going out of your mind,
or else that Injun banged you
real good on the head
before he stuck
his knife into you.
(Ben laughs)
Well, whichever way it is,
I ain't going to have
no Injun for a neighbor
and you ain't got
no right to make me.
Now, look, let's just simmer
down and talk some sense, Ike.
I don't want to simmer down!
Now, you listen to me.
The night that you was hurt,
I come down here to get you
to run off two savages
that sneaked on to your land,
and they was squatting
in a stinking tent
right next to my boundary.
Now I find out those same two
savages has been given a farm
by you right next to my land,
and you ask me to simmer down.
Now, those two "savages" saved
my life.
Yeah, more like they stuck
their knife into you first.
A-All right, now, if you have
to give 'em a reward,
give 'em whiskey or money.
Don't give 'em land.
Well, don't you think
that Indians
at least have a, a call to share
the land in this valley?
No, not next-door to me.
What have you got
against Indians?
I sure would like to know.
Well, I sure would like
to tell you.
I don't like 'em because
they're bloodthirsty savages.
They're worse than wild animals.
They're twice as dangerous.
And I don't like 'em
'cause they're heathens.
'cause they won't work,
and they can't work,
and because they're dirty,
and they stink,
and they're sneaky,
and they're drunks,
and they're thieves,
and God knows what else.
Most of all, I don't like 'em
'cause they scare me.
I hate 'em.
What is it about them
that scares you?
They got long, black hair...
And red skins.
Yep.
Yeah.
I'm not going to try
to answer you, Ike, not now,
but someday somebody's going
to have to answer
for people
who think like you do.
There's nothing wrong
with the way I think.
Well, I'm not going
to argue that point either,
but neither am I going to back
down from what's my right to do.
Now, I promised Matsou
and Hatoya that piece of land,
and I mean for them to have it.
Yeah, well,
why put 'em next to me?
It's not just
a piece of land, Ike.
It's-It's treating them
like people.
I have no intention
of giving them
some worthless scrap
up around the rocks.
They've already got that.
I want to give 'em a piece
of land that they can work,
a piece of land
that they can farm.
And that land next to yours
is the best I have,
and it's my intention
to give it to them.
If you put 'em
on that piece, I move out!
Well, that's a decision that
you're gonna have to make, Ike.
I'd think about it a long time
before I made the move.
Now, look, all... all I'm
asking you to do is...
is give those two a chance.
I don't want you to...
be a friend,
just be a decent neighbor.
Well, I'll tell you what kind
of neighbor I'll be.
I'll treat 'em
just like they wasn't there.
I won't talk to 'em.
I won't answer 'em.
I won't help 'em.
I won't let them help me.
I won't go on their land,
and if they put a foot
on my land, I'll kill 'em.
Ike...
You do anything out of line...
you'll answer to me.
All right, Hoss, let her go!
(horse neighs)
♪♪
Look at me, Hatoya.
Months of work,
and I am now nothing.
Not an Indian...
and certainly not a white man.
- Never mind it...
- (Matsou sighs)
Eating bread at a table.
What a thing for a warrior.
It is only when you're tired
that you get this way.
We've done so much,
and we've come so far.
We're not only at peace
with the white man,
- we've made friends.
- And enemies.
Our close neighbor,
Ike Daggert, is an enemy.
He is difficult, but I noticed
that the other settlers
have no love
for Mr. Daggert, either.
(door opens)
I enter this house in peace only
because you were born my brother
and I owe you something.
The feather of the chief--
why do you wear it?
Our father died two days ago,
full of hatred for the white man
and scorn for his youngest son.
I am sorry.
I loved him.
And I've had no love for you,
but I hope you will be
a better chief than he was.
I tell you one thing, Matsou,
we no longer will sit
in the mountains and starve
while this valley
is full of plenty.
We no longer
will sit in the mountains
and talk about peace treaties.
Tomorrow, the Bannock braves
go on the warpath,
and this valley
will be full of death.
I have known you would do this.
I also know that you are wrong.
You are the one who is wrong.
You do not belong here
and never will.
As chief of our tribe,
I ask you to come back.
The day of the lance is upon us.
You were once a great warrior,
until this woman
turned you soft.
Come back to the tribe;
you are needed.
I am needed here, Lagos.
Hatoya is with child.
And I rejoice
for the both of you.
Bring her with you.
The ban will be lifted--
if she carries your child
she will be welcome.
It is mostly for the child
that I will stay.
If you stay,
then you will die here
like the white men
you are trying to imitate.
I give you till tomorrow
to think on it.
I wait no longer.
Are you sorry now
about the child?
You know I prayed
for that child...
to your god, as well as to mine.
But would you go back
if it were not for that?
If it comes to dying...
I'd rather die as a warrior
fighting with my people than...
then as a farmer
living among strangers.
Then you would go back.
I might.
But the child is
not only important for us,
but for the future
of our people.
I will stay,
for my little wife...
and for my child.
What will you do
about your brother?
In the morning,
I'll ride to Ben Cartwright.
The settlers have to be warned.
Even though he's your brother?
I still remember the teachings
of my father, Hatoya.
When a decision is made,
it must be kept...
even against a brother.
Hey, Mat!
(laughing)
Congratulations!
I just heard the wonderful
news about Hatoya.
I only heard about it myself
three days ago.
Oh, you know the way that kind
of news travels--women talk.
Wonderful to see you.
You don't get over
this way often enough.
Yeah, why don't you bring
your pretty wife with you?
Yeah, I'm-I'm digging her
up a present.
It's-It's a cradle.
Ain't been slept in since
Little Joe jumped out of it.
Save your welcome until you
hear the rest of my news.
The Bannocks are going
on the warpath.
Oh, how do you know that, Mat?
Because my brother is now chief
of the Bannocks, and he told me.
You mean they're
planning a raid?
No, more than a raid.
It will be war.
How soon is this to start?
MATSOU:
Any moment.
Maybe we ought to get word
to Fort Bradley.
You know the way they are.
They're not going to do anything
until after there's an incident.
You'd better warn the settlers.
Get ready to ride
into the valley.
All right, Pa.
It is good to warn the settlers,
but, uh,
I came to warn you first.
- That's very good of you.
- No, no, no, no.
My brother has two people
he hates.
One of them's me because I won't
go back and join him.
The other one is you, Ben.
Well, why should
your brother hate me?
It was my brother
who tried to kill you
that time we brought you home.
The people of this valley
are getting to owe you
more and more, Mat,
especially me.
Why don't you
and Hatoya stay with us here,
till this thing blows over?
Oh, thank you.
I would like to bring Hatoya
here, for the sake of the child.
I...
I will stay on my land.
Good. You do that.
Adam, better get word
to Ike Daggert.
Right.
Ike Daggert is my neighbor, Ben.
I will take care of warning him.
Mat, I don't want
you to take that chance.
Don't step foot on his land.
I don't like Ike Daggert, Ben,
but I am not afraid of him.
You have enough country
to cover.
I will warn the Daggerts
on the way home.
(chanting war cries)
(chanting continues)
(speaking native language)
Why don't you bring that danged
gun right into bed with us?
You pay it more mind
than you do me.
Martha, I told you
a hundred times.
When you got red Injuns
for next-door neighbors,
got to be ready for trouble,
especially at night.
Bah!
You've been saying
that for months.
Staying up late, sneaking around
with your danged gun,
and they haven't so much as set
foot on your danged place.
That's 'cause I scared them good
and proper to begin with,
and I kept them scared
every chance...
(rustling)
(mutters):
What's that...?
I heard something out there.
Yep, you certainly got
them scared, all right.
I'm going to go see
what that is.
(rustling)
Ike Daggert.
- Daggert.
- (rifle cocking)
Ike Daggert.
(screaming)
(speaking native language)
(groans)
(yelling in native language)
(horse whinnying)
The Lord maketh His face
to shine upon thee
and be gracious unto thee.
The Lord lift up His countenance
upon thee
and give thee peace.
Amen.
HOSS:
WOMAN:
Amen.
Thanks, Ben.
Quit it!
You quit that, I said!
What is it, Ike?
What's the matter?
I won't stand it.
I won't stand for no heathen
saying prayers
at my wife's grave.
Now, you quit it!
- Ike!
- Stop, now...
She ain't no heathen.
She knows as much
about the Bible as you do.
IKE: What are they doing here,
anyway?
- They're trying... -It was
Injuns that killed my Marthy.
They're trying
to pay their respects,
just like the rest of us now.
Ain't got no more respect
for the dead than a coyote.
Quit it!
I want to tell you
how deeply sorry I am
that my people killed your wife.
I tried to warn you.
Don't you talk to me, you Injun.
I understand how you feel.
I am sorry.
You dirty, rotten, lousy,
stinking savage!
Ike!
- Ike! -Ike, come on!
- Come on, Ike.
LITTLE JOE:
Stop it.
MAN:
Here.
BEN:
Ike!
(screams)
(onlookers murmuring)
There, you savage.
You killed my wife,
I killed yours.
An eye for an eye.
An eye for an eye, Ben,
an eye for an eye.
That's in the book.
BEN:
Ike!
An eye for an eye.
It's in the book.
♪♪
It's Ike Daggert.
You can hardly recognize him.
Pa, Pa, come out here.
What's the matter?
That's Injun work, Pa.
You don't reckon,
you don't reckon Mat...
Let's get him into the house.
He sure done a job on him.
Yeah.
Wonder why he didn't finish it.
He didn't want him to die.
IKE:
Help me.
(Ike mumbling)
Aah!
(groaning)
- It's all right, Ike.
- (Ike shouts)
It's all right, Ike.
You're with me.
Ben?
Ben Cartwright?
It's me, Ike.
(Ike panting)
Ain't, ain't so easy
to kill Ike Daggert, you...
(groans)
He left me...
left me alive on purpose,
so's I could suffer.
Who, Ike, who?
(Ike groans)
The... the Injun...
your friend...
the one you tried to make
into a white man--Matsou.
Know why... why he left me...
left me alive, Ben?
He wants you, wants you to meet
him in the cave, north fork.
He wants Ben Cartwright or...
or otherwise...
every settler in the valley
will get what... what I got.
(mumbles)
Just didn't understand
what we were trying to do.
What are you gonna do now, Pa?
Mat wants to see me,
I'll go to him.
I've got to try
to bring him to his senses.
I owe him that.
He's gone too far now.
Ike Daggert killed his wife.
Pa, we can't let you
take the risk.
Anything I've ever done has had
some risk attached to it.
I'll go up by the north trail.
If I'm not back by morning,
you come for me.
Pa...
Here, you forgot this.
Eh, that won't bring me back,
or Mat either.
Mat!
Matsou, it's Ben Cartwright.
I didn't think you would come.
I got your message
from Ike Daggert.
He said you wanted to see me.
I'm here.
Then you saw what I did
to Ike Daggert?
I saw.
Aren't you afraid?
No, Mat, I'm not afraid.
(grunting)
You know about rawhide.
It shrinks in the sun,
it gets tighter and tighter.
I know.
Why did you come here
last night?
To see if I could help you.
All right, go ahead, help me.
Give me back the wife that I
loved and the child she carried.
Will tying me like this...
bring her back?
No...
but I think
that making you suffer enough
will ease some of my pain.
I guess you're right.
I just wanted to help you,
not hurt you.
Help me?
You held my arms, Ben.
You let that madman shoot Hatoya
right before my eyes.
Do you think
if you hadn't held my arms, Ben,
he could have done that?
I say you killed Hatoya
just as surely as if you had
pulled the trigger.
Does it hurt?
Yes, it hurts.
Good... good.
It will get worse.
(Ben panting quietly)
Is it bad?
It's bad.
You're a strong man, Ben.
I thought you would be
screaming by now.
Our Father who art in Heaven...
What did you say?
...hallowed be Thy name.
Stop that.
Thy kingdom come...
Stop that, Ben!
(mumbling prayer)
Stop it!
Ben!
You shouldn't have
done that, Ben.
You shouldn't have prayed.
(groans)
Is that what made you let me go?
I meant to kill you.
But I fail here, too.
I failed at everything.
I lost my wife.
My brother, Lagos, is dead.
I failed being a white man.
I failed being an Indian.
No, Mat.
You didn't fail.
I don't think
you could ever fail.
I wanted to kill you, Ben.
It was important for me
to kill you,
and I couldn't do it.
If I couldn't torture you
into hating me,
then I couldn't kill you.
Can you forgive me
for hurting you?
I did that
before you cut me loose.
I will help you home, Ben.
No, I'll be all right.
Mat...
Are you going home...
to your people?
Yes.
Now, you'll be back?
Yes, we will be back.
There he is.
Pa, you all right?
Yeah.
Pa, did he do this to you?
I'll get him.
No, no.
Let him alone.
He's going home.
Back up in the mountains?
Yeah.
There's a new chief
of the Bannocks now.
ANNOUNCER: This has been
a color presentation
of the NBC Television Network.