Hello. I'm James Michener.
And those peaks are part
of a majestic mountain range
we call the Rockies.
Granite giants that have been
a part of this land forever,
that symbolize our nation's
strength and freedom.
I suppose my primary reason
for writing the book
Centennial
was to ask us, you and me,
if we're aware of
what's happening right now
to this land we love,
this earth
we depend upon for life.
It's a novel, of course,
and its characters
and scenes are imaginary.
But there were French trappers
from Canada,
like the man who called
himself Pasquinel.
There were mountain men
from Scotland like the man
named Alexander McKeag.
There was a silversmith
in St. Louis like
Hermann Bockweiss,
an Army officer
like Maxwell Mercy,
a militia commander like
Frank Skimmerhorn,
a Texas trail boss
like R.J. Poteet,
and certain background
incidents and characters
are real.
In the 1820s and '30s,
the mountain men did hold
an annual rendezvous
in the Rockies.
In 1851, there was
a great convocation
at Fort Laramie
that saw 10,000 Indians
gather to approve a treaty
with our government.
In 1864, there was a massacre
that is to this day
one of our nation's
greatest tragedies.
And the same decade
did see the great longhorn
trail drives north from Texas.
The cattle would bring
a need for a town.
A town like the one
I call Centennial.
This is the story
of that town.
It's a big story
about the people who helped
make this country what it is,
and the land that makes
the people what they are.
And it's a story about time.
Not just as a record,
but also a reminder.
A reminder that during
the few years allotted
to each of us,
we are the guardians
of the earth.
We are, at once,
the custodians
of our heritage,
and the caretakers
of our future.
Stay with us for
the great adventure
of the American West.
NARRATOR: When the Earth
was already ancient,
of an age
incomprehensible to man,
an event of basic importance
occurred in the area
which would later be
known as Colorado.
One billion, seven hundred
million years ago,
an irresistible power broke
through the crust of the Earth
to form a basement rock.
That rock would endure
to this very day.
Upon it would be built
the subsequent mountains.
Across it would
wander the rivers.
Brawling, undisciplined,
violent arteries of life
that are part of an endless
cycle of building up
and tearing down,
of stripping away old deposits
and laying down new rock,
using the same material
again and again.
By the year 15,000 B.C.,
the major characteristics
of the land around
what was to become Centennial
were fairly well determined.
Some miles northwest
was a chalk cliff,
beds of limestone infinitely
older than the Rockies.
To the west and slightly
to the south was
a gemlike mountain valley
where nuggets of gold had
been raked from the crevices
of the rocks by a glacier
and hidden
at the bottom of a stream.
Another special place
was on the western bank
of a wandering, muddy stream
where Centennial was to be.
A small underwater cave that
might never have been found
except for a murder
committed over 11,000 years
after its creation.
And finally
there is the river.
A sad, bewildered
nothing of a river,
a sand bottom of
wandering afterthought.
Its name is as flat
as its appearance.
The South Platte.
Yet for a while
it was the highway of empire.
It was the course
of stirring adventure
and the means whereby
the adventurers lived.
And so the stage is set,
the land has become
a home for living things.
One of the most loveable
and stubborn of all creatures
came to thrive
in the streams of Colorado.
One of the most deadly
and terrifying took refuge
in its rocky sanctuaries.
The horse returned to
the vast plains that were
its place of origin.
And a version of the bison
trekked from Asia
to roam the area that would
one day be Centennial.
This shaggy beast would
become the center of culture
for the American Indian,
a nomadic people
that migrated from Asia
12,000 years ago
and stayed to develop
a primitive social order
and a deep appreciation
of the land.
In the year 1756,
a sliver group of a tribe,
who referred to themselves
only as Our People,
faced a major crisis.
The Indians surrounding them
had horses,
making them more mobile
in their hunting
and more powerful in war.
War between the various tribes
on the plains was
a kind of dangerous game
that seldom resulted in death.
What was important
was a display of courage.
Bravery was shown by
touching or striking an enemy
with hand or weapon,
a practice later to be
known as counting coup.
But the bravest act of all
was for a warrior
to stake himself out
to face his enemy.
Held to the ground
by bison thongs
and his own pledge
to fight so long as
his strength lasted.
Because of its bold disdain
for the enemy,
this act would
almost certainly end
in the warrior's death
and was practiced only under
desperate conditions.
(SHOUTING)
For Our People,
the year 1756
was such a time,
because they had no horses
and they knew they could not
survive long without them.
(IN ARAPAHO)
My father...
I am your father.
My real father,
where is he?
He is not coming.
Why? Where is he?
Listen to me.
Only the rocks
live forever.
(IN ENGLISH)
Only the rocks
live forever.
(IN ENGLISH)
Gray Wolf. My father.
I am your father now.
NARRATOR: This young Indian
was nine years old when
he first encountered death.
It was a thing
he could not fathom,
but he would learn
to face it without fear.
You didn't get any horses?
No.
Then my father
died for nothing.
Sun-at-Noon
staked himself out.
He counted many coup.
I am proud
he was my brother.
You can be proud
he was your father.
And we should both hope
to die such a death.
Only the rocks
live forever.
NARRATOR:
He was called Lame Beaver,
and he was destined
to become a great leader
at a time when a force
the Indian could not imagine
was moving slowly
inexorably toward him.
A force that would change
his way of life forever.
(PASQUINEL SINGING IN FRENCH)
(GROWLING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(YELLS)
(LAUGHING)
(SINGING)
NARRATOR: As the century
was drawing to a close,
Lame Beaver had
lived half of it
and seen many things,
and now he had been told
that he would see a god.
He's no god. He's a man.
He moves more like a bison,
like he owns the prairie.
And the wolves
ran from him.
Maybe they're fresh
from another kill.
Maybe they had
reason to fear him.
His skin is different.
Ute skin is
different, too.
He's a man.
We should talk with him.
No.
He must have killed
many Pawnee to get here.
He may kill us
if we go to him.
We'll wait till dark,
then we'll see
what his medicine is.
(WOLF HOWLING)
NARRATOR: It was but one of
many coups for Lame Beaver,
but it was the beginning
of a new era.
In that moment of
mutual terror and trust,
a treaty was ratified between
the Indian and the white man.
A treaty that would change
forever the nature of life
in the American West.
He was a coureur de bois.
One who runs in the woods.
A small, powerful Frenchman
who wore the red knitted cap
of Quebec
and called himself Pasquinel.
He brought with him
blankets from Canada,
bright cloths
from New Orleans,
silver from Germany
and beads from Paris.
With the coming of spring,
he had traded goods
with the Arapaho,
the name by which
the other tribes
referred to Our People.
He pressed his pelts
into bales weighing
100 pounds each.
And through that ingenious,
silent language of the plains
that is older
than speech itself,
Lame Beaver let him know that
he was welcome to come again.
He also let the trader know
the gift he would most like
to have next time was a gun.
For he had seen
its awesome power
and knew it was
the weapon of the future.
And the white man agreed
to bring him one.
Then the Arapaho warned him
about the Pawnee.
Pasquinel had crossed
their land in safety
coming in,
but the Arapaho insisted
they would not let him leave
with anything of value.
Not even his life.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
NARRATOR: Heading eastward,
he found the river impassable
and was forced
to portage his pelts.
Selecting a hiding place
for his canoe
among a stand of cottonwoods
near the river's edge,
he covered it with brush
and set out on foot
to carry the first two
of his 100-pound bales
the distance of
over seven miles.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SINGING IN FRENCH)
(WHOOPS)
Satisfied that the bales
were properly concealed,
he calculated the hours
of daylight remaining
and turned back into
the heart of Pawnee territory
for the rest of his pelts.
(HORSE SNORTING)
You come.
I follow.
I, Rude Water.
Pasquinel.
Gun?
Oui. Gun.
NARRATOR: Like Lame Beaver,
Rude Water's primary interest
was in the weapon
the trader carried.
The Pawnee had met
white men before,
spoke some of their language,
and knew well
the power of the gun.
You come from where?
St. Louis.
St. Louis
where sun rise.
I was with
Lame Beaver.
How long you
with Lame Beaver?
Your people must have told you
when I came through.
I saw them follow me.
You stay long time. Why?
Trade beaver.
Trade gun?
Non.
Trade bracelets and beads.
For you.
And your wife.
I have four wife.
You smart man.
We be friends, Pasquinel.
You give me gun,
we be good friends.
No. I need gun.
I could take.
Not if you're my friend.
And not if you want to learn
how to use the gun.
You smart man.
Next time you come,
you bring me gun.
The gun is worth many beaver.
We have plenty beaver.
I bring gun.
NARRATOR: The reception
and the parting
were so friendly
that Pasquinel knew
Lame Beaver's words were true.
He would have to fight.
(SCREAMING)
(GUN FIRING)
(LAUGHING)
By damn, he's stubborn,
the Pawnee.
(RUSTLING)
(MAN WHISTLING)
(GROANS)
Pawnee.
Cheyenne.
(IN FRENCH)
Pull it out.
(IN CHEYENNE)
No!
I will do it.
Bite.
The tip has caught on bone.
I cannot work it free.
(IN FRENCH) Push it in,
twist it and pull.
You would die.
Then cut it off
beneath the skin.
(HORSE SNUFFLING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
All the Cheyenne
will hear of Pasquinel.
(ALL WHOOPING)
(SNAKE RATTLING)
Beaver! Much beaver!
We trade. You trade gun?
Trade? Yeah, sure.
We trade gun.
(GRUNTS)
These my peltries!
They stole them from me!
Get the rest of those pelts.
Sink those canoes.
NARRATOR: His canoe,
his rifle, his store of goods,
and his pelts were gone.
After two years of work,
all he had was
a knife on his hip
and an arrowhead in his back.
BUTLER: It's lodged
in bone, all right.
The shaft's cut off
well below the surface.
Hurt?
Non.
That?
I can move it.
But if you can stand
that kind of pain,
it's not doing any damage,
I'd leave it alone.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Will you be going back?
As soon as I can
find a license holder
to supply me.
To the Pawnee?
I have no war
with the Pawnee.
Just the pirates.
Thank you, Doctor.
I'll pay you
as soon as I find someone
to finance my next round.
Tell me,
what's it like out there?
Violent.
There is a wind that
never seems to stop.
Sometimes you swear
you are going insane.
And storms like
you have never seen,
screeching and booming
with their thunder.
And hail. Hail
the size of hen eggs.
They can kill
whole flights of birds.
In the spring,
tornadoes that tear apart
everything in their path.
And in the winter,
snow squalls
that kill everything
that is unprepared.
And in between the storms,
it falls silent.
So quiet you are certain
you are going mad
and you pray for the storms
to come back again.
And then when they come
back again, you pray
for them to stop again.
I tell you, it is a land
fit only for the savages,
and you have seen
what they are like.
But I have seen worse.
I have seen much worse.
They are very curious
how slowly a man can die.
And if you survive
the Indians and the elements,
there are the animals.
Wolves that run
in whole packs,
and snakes that strike
from me to you
and plant their fangs
to pump their poison.
You find that amusing,
monsieur?
(CLEARS THROAT) Just wondering
why you're going back.
Because I am a simple man,
monsieur.
Without a profession,
without an education,
I know only the woods.
You know what I think?
Qu'est-ce que c'est?
I think you found a treasure.
A treasure?
What they fought
for in France.
What my people fought for
in the colonies.
Freedom.
Do you know what I think?
What?
I think that you are more
dangerous than the Pawnee.
Talk like that
could change everything.
(LAUGHING)
BUTLER: I wish
I could go with you.
I'm glad
you think you cannot.
Perhaps...
What?
I have a patient,
a merchant, a silversmith,
who has a trading license
with the governor.
Oui?
Well, I was just thinking
that perhaps we three could
form a partnership.
He's just recently
from Munich.
His name is Bockweiss.
Hermann Bockweiss.
You like it?
If I were a Cheyenne chief,
I could not live without it.
(EXCLAIMS)
That is what
I want to hear.
You see, Richard?
This is a man
who knows good work.
I know nothing about silver
but I know the Indian.
And you cannot
make enough of this.
And this, and this,
and that
is the pièce de résistance.
Do you know the meaning
of the pipe?
It's smoked for peace,
isn't it?
And war.
And anything between men
that needs to be sanctified.
To many tribes
on the plains,
this is their most
sacred possession.
They believe that the pipe
gives them a communion
with the spirit world.
When they exhale the smoke,
they see it as
a breath of prayer.
The living breath
of the spirit.
The Great Spirit.
Monsieur Bockweiss,
with this pipe
you can become immortal.
That would be nice,
Monsieur Pasquinel,
but quite candidly,
I would just as soon
it made me rich.
(LAUGHING)
Papa?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I did not know
you had company.
Oh, it's all right.
You know Doctor Butler.
Ja. Hello, doctor.
Lise.
And this is
Monsieur Pasquinel.
My daughter, Lise.
Monsieur.
(GREETING IN FRENCH)
I guess we should
know your first name,
should we not?
I'm sorry.
Don't be. I have none.
Just Pasquinel.
You're from France?
Quebec.
Canada? How fantastic!
I've always been
so curious about Canada.
I hope you will
do us the honor
and come to dinner tonight
and tell us all about it.
Thank you, but...
Of course you will.
Lise, take him
to the house
and pour him
whatever he likes.
The doctor and I
will be right in.
Ja, Papa.
Monsieur?
I only brought him
to discuss a business
proposition, Hermann.
But the city has
only 500 or 600 men,
Richard.
Most of them married
and maybe none of them
as strong as that one.
At any rate, if I were
a cautious man, I would not
have come to this country.
And if I were not a romantic,
I would not have had
such a lovely daughter.
Please sit down.
Merci.
Claret?
Fine.
You like the house?
It's grand.
The Chouteau family
built it,
but it was...
They wanted
something larger.
Larger?
Why would anyone want
a house larger than this?
A house says a lot
about a person.
Merci.
But it doesn't make a man
bigger than he is.
Shall we sit?
Would you be more comfortable
if you were sitting?
No. No, I'm fine.
What brought you
to St. Louis?
The river.
I mean, what reason?
Oh, beaver.
You're a trader, then?
Oui.
I should think that would be
a very lonely profession.
Profession? No, no.
(LAUGHING)
It is work.
And when a man works
he is always alone,
n'est-ce pas?
Ja.
(STAMMERING) Ja,
I suppose that is true.
Shall we sit?
I would so love
to hear about Canada.
I don't think that
you would like Canada.
No? Why not?
Because they only have
little people.
It's true.
Little people like this.
Everyone.
I am the tallest man
in the whole country.
I do not need
to be laughed at.
Cried about, then?
Poor Lise Bockweiss.
The fairest woman
in all St. Louis,
with hair like wild honey,
whose eyes are like
a mountain lake.
What a pity she's so tall.
And that Pasquinel,
if he wants to hold her,
he should take an axe and
chop three or four inches
off her legs.
It is fine to be tall.
If I were tall,
I would rule the world.
But since I'm not,
I am satisfied to rule
where I am at the moment.
Monsieur Pasquinel...
Non. Pasquinel.
No monsieur, no Henri,
no Jean Pierre.
Just Pasquinel.
I think I should
look about dinner.
Do you still want me
to stay for dinner?
You were invited.
Oui, but to talk about Canada.
To get where we're going,
it does not matter
how we stand.
It matters how we move.
And you, mademoiselle,
you move very well.
BUTLER:
So, what do you think,
Hermann?
I think it is
a dangerous enterprise.
He must come and go
through how many tribes?
Pawnee, Cheyenne, Arapaho,
Dakota, Comanche, Ute.
Several thousand Indians
and one white man alone.
His chances for survival
cannot be good,
but you think he's worth
the risk of investment.
When I pushed that arrowhead
deeper in his back,
I know it hurt.
And I know a little bit
about pain, Hermann.
A man doesn't learn
to bear it like that
without a lot of courage.
I think
he'll bring back pelts.
(DOG BARKING)
You killed
three Pawnee.
I killed three thieves.
And if your braves
attack me now, I kill you.
Two guns.
Oui.
For me?
One for the man
who said he was my friend.
Which man
speaks to me now?
I sorry we fight last year.
This year we be friends.
(IN PAWNEE)
Get the other gun.
(IN ENGLISH)
Now I have two guns.
(IN PAWNEE)
Bring the red beard.
And two white men.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Parlez-vous français?
(IN ENGLISH)
Just smile.
You teach them
how to shoot yet?
You kill anybody?
This my brother.
My brother.
Regardez.
(IN PAWNEE)
He says they're brothers.
Do they look like
brothers to you?
(IN PAWNEE)
If they are brothers,
she is my brother.
(ALL LAUGHING)
He said
if you're my brother,
she's his brother.
I speak some Pawnee.
(IN ENGLISH) You speak
at the wrong damn time.
I might have
made their eyes believe,
but not their ears, too.
Sorry.
(IN PAWNEE)
The brothers speak
different tongues.
Are the Pawnee
and the Cheyenne brothers?
The Pawnee
and the Arapaho? No.
They speak the tongues
of different tribes.
Brothers speak
the same tongue.
He said different tribes
speak different tongues.
Since we don't speak
the same tongue,
we cannot be brothers.
He lies.
He said...
I speak that much
in any language.
No, no.
You're the one who lied
when you told me
I could pass in peace
last year.
I carry the arrow
of a coward in my back.
A Pawnee arrow.
Now we are brothers.
This is true.
We are brothers like
the Arikara are brothers
to the Pawnee.
Different,
but from the same family.
Now, I know you didn't
send your braves
to kill me last year.
That is why I came back
in friendship as I promised.
And I brought this
to prove my friendship.
After we smoke it,
I will teach you
how to shoot a gun.
We'll bring you
more guns next year
if you keep your word.
I understand about family
like the Arikara and Pawnee.
I glad you understand
about last year.
You can travel in Pawnee land.
But for every
five pelts you take,
you must give me two.
One.
Last year you said one.
It is still one.
But we will take
your pelts to St. Louis,
get more goods
then you can get on the river.
We?
Unless you have
a better offer.
Him word good?
Same as you?
Same as me.
Maybe I keep him here.
Make sure you come back
from St. Louis.
Non. We go together,
we come back together.
How I know for sure?
Because I am Pasquinel.
I come to you unafraid.
Scotland?
Aye.
How long?
Oh, a year.
Didn't take you long
to get caught.
I was about
to escape.
I could see that.
Bringing the Indian along
on the leash as a guide,
were you?
I would have
gotten away.
Then I apologize for
spoiling your plans.
No.
No. I owe you my thanks
for saying what you did
without kenning
anything about me.
And I think
you should ken
I've killed a man.
(LAUGHING)
How do you ken
you'll see the men
who took your pelts?
They went
to the Mandans.
They should return now.
Never without an answer,
are you?
Nor you a question.
We camp here
three, four days.
No more.
McKEAG: You laughed today.
PASQUINEL: I hope so.
When I told you
what I'd done.
And now you want
to tell me again.
It is a hard thing
to live with.
I've never told
anyone before.
Do you mind?
I'm not a priest.
I'm not a Catholic.
It was an awful thing.
The reason
I left the Highlands.
Had to leave, actually.
You see, he was a laird,
and a tyrant he was,
sinful as the devil himself.
He thought because he owned
the land, he owned the people
who worked it, too.
He thought he could
do with them whatever
he willed.
Never bothered me
that much, but...
My sister.
Well, if you're a wee bit
of a lass like her,
a man like that
is a hard thing, I suppose.
She never told me before,
mind you, what...
What he'd tried to do to her
when he'd come on her alone
a time or two.
When I found him with her,
saw how he was hurting her
and how she was crying...
Well, I just could not
help myself.
I had to get him
away from her.
And when he unsheathed
his sword, I lashed out
with my walking stick,
a big, knotted thing it was,
and I caught him full force
on the side of the head.
And he... He just lay there.
And Meg, she was
crying even harder.
Dear God, it was
such an awful sight to see.
And then I had to leave
because I knew
what would happen
if they found me.
Him being a lord and me
just a woodsman's son.
I was sorry for doing it,
and sorry for having
to leave my home
and my family.
But I ken
I did the right thing.
Didn't I?
Pasquinel?
McKEAG: How can you tell?
Hmm.
You go.
They don't know you.
Hey there,
passage to St. Louis?
I have pelts.
Sure.
Get your pelts ready.
(GUN FIRING)
(INDIANS ULULATING)
(MAN GROANING)
You did not tell me!
You did not tell me
you were going to kill them!
That's one question
you didn't ask.
But why did you do it?
They tried to kill me
last year.
How can you be sure
they were the same men?
The one that was
going to crush your skull
with the club, I know,
and the grinning one,
he would have smiled
watching it.
I know him and the others.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What?
Bad companions bring bad luck.
It doesn't even turn
your blood a wee bit
to see what those butchering
savages are doing with
their hatchets out there?
When they find the boat,
no one in St. Louis
will accuse us, will they?
What white man would believe
that another white man
would lift his scalp?
Have you?
You're as much a heathen
as they are.
Worse, maybe.
Because you ken
the wrong in it.
Do you know where the Indians
learned to take scalps?
From the English.
That's right,
from your fellow Britons.
They paid tribes up north
to bring back scalps
to prove that the enemy
had been killed.
And the enemy
were my countrymen.
One was my father.
Now think about this.
The one thing the white man
is most afraid of,
the one thing that has
branded the Indian a "savage"
is a practice invented
by the white man.
(LAUGHS)
You don't think
that's funny, huh?
Well, you won't think
this is funny, either.
You should know, ken,
that the coureur de bois
ends up a scalp.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You perhaps, and me, too.
(DONKEY BRAYING)
Whoa, whoa.
Still wobbles.
Wait.
Good as new.
Better.
You never told me
how you were caught
by the Pawnee.
I thought you never
asked questions.
I was just wondering
if you were taken
by surprise.
Like now.
What?
I think
there are only three.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Don't!
I have one arrow
in my back already.
I don't want to start
a collection, n'est-ce pas?
What do we do?
What you always
do with Indians.
Get ready to kill
or be killed
and hope it doesn't happen.
That'll just make us
better targets.
And let them see
our faces show no fear.
The old man
who taught you the Pawnee,
did he teach you Ute?
No.
The Utes are always
welcome in our camp.
Join us.
(IN UTE) You go.
No, we stay.
Trade beaver.
Ute no trade beaver.
You go.
Cheyenne trade beaver.
Arapaho trade beaver.
Pawnee trade beaver.
You come,
you see, you trade.
No trade.
When sun comes, you be gone.
What do we do now?
Sleep.
Tomorrow
we fight for our trade.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Don't fire.
(GUN FIRING)
You were way high
both times.
I hit what I wanted.
Yeah, the wind.
If you give an Indian
a fair chance,
you can avoid killing.
They're going
to charge again.
We'll give them this one
and then they'll be gone.
Years to come they'll sit
around the campfire and talk
about the coup they made
on the two white men
and the whistling lead.
And you'll sit in Scotland
and talk about the tomahawks
and lances.
(LAUGHING)
Non!
(GROANS)
(UTE ULULATING)
Get it out.
It will hurt like hellfire.
No question that.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
The smell is bad.
Begone with you.
I'm bound to die.
I said begone.
(GROANS)
I'm cold.
You need the air.
I tell you I'm dying.
It's rotten.
McKEAG: It's rotten.
You think that will work?
Can you cut it off?
If you have no arm,
how can you fire a gun?
If you cannot fire a gun,
how can you hunt?
If you cannot hunt,
how can you...
You ask too damn
many questions.
There are worse places
for a man to die.
You will not die.
(SCREAMING)
I'm sorry, mon ami.
Out here, half a man
is no man at all.
Arapaho!
(DOG BARKING)
Pasquinel.
Your gun.
(IN ARAPAHO)
We smoke.
NARRATOR: And so, once again,
Lame Beaver and Pasquinel
smoked the calumet and talked.
About the Pawnee attack
and the Cheyenne who had
saved Pasquinel's life,
and that fateful moment
when each held
the other's life
in his hands
and didn't take it.
(ARAPAHOS CHANTING)
(DRUMS BEATING)
(IN ARAPAHO)
Bad scar.
What?
Aye. Aye bad.
Does it hurt?
(IN ARAPAHO)
Hurt?
(IN ENGLISH)
It still hurts.
I cannot move my arm
away from my body.
The skin...
The scar is so tight.
You'll use it, though.
By damn, you'll use it.
Same thing, your shoulder.
I don't know.
I know.
(GROANS)
Use it!
Take your gun, by damn,
and use it!
Why?
You could do the hunting
for the next few weeks.
I could be dead tomorrow!
I'll get more plants.
(IN ARAPAHO)
Can you use this?
What?
Can I use it?
Aye, I can use it.
But not with that wound.
My arm?
With my arm this way? No.
No, I cannot shoot now.
Did he wrap your gun this way?
Pasquinel?
Pasquinel, he wrapped it.
Buffalo hide.
Pasquinel, he wrapped
your gun to make it strong.
My shoulder? The same?
Yes. That's what he means.
Pasquinel, he said,
"Shoulder."
Aye.
I suppose that is
what he was saying.
(ALL WHOOPING)
I shoot.
You shoot well.
Très bien. Now you load.
Is it dry enough?
We'll soon see.
Lame Beaver just hit
the limb on that tree.
McKEAG: It's still there.
He'll take it off
next time.
There won't be a next time.
(GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(IN ARAPAHO)
Flower.
(IN ENGLISH)
How you say in English?
Flower.
Flower?
Aye.
A wee braw flower
for a wee braw lassie.
(LAUGHS)
Braw flower?
Aye.
Oh, pretty. I suppose
you'd best say pretty.
Pretty?
Aye.
Pretty flower.
If you're going
to learn English,
you'd best learn it
the way the English
speak it.
That way people
won't be turning up
their nebs at you
like they do at me
from time to time.
Turn up their nebs?
Aye, nebs.
Oh, nose. Nose.
You'll learn
to call it nose.
Nose.
And these are your ears.
Ears.
And your hair.
Hair.
And your eyes.
Eyes.
And this?
Lips.
You're beautiful.
Beautiful?
We'd better get back.
Beautiful.
Means pretty?
Aye.
Like the flower?
You think I'm pretty?
We'd better go.
Red Beard,
I think you pretty, too.
Clay Basket, I...
We have to go.
You teach me more?
(STAMMERING)
I'll teach you more tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
I know tomorrow.
Tomorrow will be beautiful.
Aye.
(GIGGLES)
(BIRDS CAWING)
Your father is quite a chief.
No. He's not
a chief.
Well, he got
all those horses
and did all those things
and he's not a chief?
He did not want
to be a chief.
Why?
(SPEAKING ARAPAHO)
(IN ARAPAHO)
Why isn't he a chief?
Aye. Why isn't he a chief?
He doesn't like feathers.
What?
What about feathers?
(IN ENGLISH)
He doesn't like them.
I don't understand.
A long time ago,
my father got horses
for Our People.
Aye, the first horses
for your tribe.
But he could not
keep the horse he wanted.
Why not?
It was given to a chief.
But he got them himself.
You told me, 19 of them.
Aye.
How could the chief
take the horse
your father wanted?
He was chief.
Oh, so now your father
won't be chief.
Never.
I see.
It isn't the feathers
he doesn't like,
it's the men who wear them.
Tell your mother
there are men like that
in every tribe.
(SPEAKING ARAPAHO)
And tell her
I think your father
is the chief anyway.
A big chief.
(SPEAKING ARAPAHO)
(GIGGLES)
Pasquinel.
(SPEAKING ARAPAHO)
(IN ARAPAHO)
Tell Pasquinel my heart
is sad to see him leave.
(IN ENGLISH) Pasquinel,
my father sad you go.
Well, mon ami, I see
you have her English
as tongue-tied as your own.
(LAUGHS)
Tell him that I sad to go,
but I come back
when the leaves change.
Red Beard, too?
Red Beard,
are we partners?
Aye.
They are sad to leave, too,
but they will come back
when the leaves change color.
Will they bring their wives?
Ask them!
(IN ARAPAHO)
I don't know how to ask that.
Comprends?
He wants to know
about our wives.
Wives?
If they'll come with us
next time.
No, no, no. My wife,
she stays in Montreal.
(IN ARAPAHO) Pasquinel,
his wife stays in Montreal.
Montreal? Is it far away?
Far away. Far enough.
(LAUGHING)
(IN ARAPAHO)
Montreal is many miles north.
(IN ENGLISH)
And you, Red Beard?
I have no wife.
What did he say?
He said he has no wife.
A man must have a wife
to give him
the best gifts of all.
He said a man must
have a wife to give him
the best gifts of all.
Tell him he has
a beautiful family
and he should be
proud of them.
(IN ARAPAHO)
Your family is beautiful.
Now we go.
Good hunting.
It will be good
because of Pasquinel.
Mon ami.
Six bales, mon ami.
Our share will
make us rich men.
Is it true what you said?
Qu'est-que c'est?
About having a wife.
Is she in Montreal?
Non. Detroit.
Even good friends shouldn't
know everything about a man,
n'est-ce pas?
All right.
No more questions.
(SINGING IN FRENCH)
LAME BEAVER:
Clay Basket.
(IN ENGLISH)
They will return.
Pasquinel is a brave man.
But I do not believe him,
what he says about his woman.
He will need a good woman
when he returns.
I would welcome him
into my family.
You hoped I would
say the Red Beard?
Yes.
No.
It is Pasquinel
you will marry.
When I am gone,
he will take care of you.
But Father,
you will not go
for many years.
There are many changes.
The Pawnee are trading
for more guns.
The Utes are coming
out of the mountains
to live like us,
and these white men,
they're only the first.
More will come
to trade for beaver
and with them
they'll bring change.
What kind of change?
I don't know.
Pasquinel, he will know
and he will protect you.
Pasquinel,
he can be trusted.
(GRUNTING)
Make sure Bockweiss
gets these pelts.
JOE: Pasquinel!
Joe Bean. Kentucky.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Well, I'm doing all right,
but not that good.
How far up
did you get?
La Cache la Poudre.
The big mountains?
That's some doing.
Any trouble?
Well, there's always trouble,
n'est-ce pas?
In the high mountains
there are the Utes,
but still the worst
are the Pawnee.
That's where I met my partner
on the Missouri.
He was taking on
a whole war party
all by himself.
A whole war party?
Nine braves were stealing
peltries from a pirogue
called the Sainte-Geneviève.
The Genevieve. I heard tell
another boat picked her up.
All the men
had been massacred.
The Pawnee were
already lifting scalps
when I saw him
right in the middle
attacking them all.
I dropped three
from long range
with my rifle,
but he was right in the middle
with just his knife.
Hand to hand?
By the time I tried to
reload for the fourth,
he had killed the last one.
Regardez.
A tomahawk right there.
And still he continued
fighting with only one hand.
I was wondering
why you partnered up.
I guess that tells
the whole story.
Joe Bean. Kentucky.
What is it they call you?
Alexander McKeag.
Where you from?
Scotland.
And La Cache la Poudre.
MAN: Pasquinel!
(LAUGHS)
Whiskey!
Whiskey for my friend
Joe Bean from Kentucky,
and my partner.
Where've you been,
Pasquinel?
I've been to
the other end
of the river
and now I'm going
to drink my way back.
(ALL CHEERING)
(MEN SINGING)
You Pasquinel?
Pasquinel, oui.
What are you drinking?
Nothing you buy.
Then you're in
the wrong place,
because today,
I buy everything
this man sells.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah, with blood money.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Do I know you?
I know you.
You're a liar and a coward.
I know we have
never met before.
You murdered my brother.
Your brother?
And three good men
that ride the Saint Genevieve.
Oh, The Sainte-Geneviève.
It was attacked by the Pawnee.
Pawnee nothing.
It was you and
that burr-tongued
partner of yours.
Why would we attack
white men and scalp them?
What for?
You know damned good
and well what for.
My memory fails me.
Why don't you tell me?
Why didn't you
wash the furs?
Because what belongs
to another man is
of no interest to me.
Now, I want to
buy you a drink,
in honor of
your brave brother.
And if he was
an honest trader,
he was my brother, too.
You go to hell!
In due time.
Joe Bean!
Here is to new profits
and to new partners.
Are you sure you're
completely healed,
Alexander?
Aye.
I just can't imagine
an experience like that.
How about you,
Pasquinel?
That arrowhead
bother you at all?
No.
What arrowhead?
The one the Pawnee planted
in his back last year.
The one that brought me
to the good doctor
and brought us all together.
For many years.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
How long could a man survive
in a land like that?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Only the rocks live forever.
What?
It's a saying of
the Indians on the plains.
"Only the rocks live forever."
None of us will live forever,
so it matters not
how long you live, but how.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
They tell me you have
a wife in New Orleans.
New Orleans?
(SCOFFS) This town...
I'd better get back
to the Indians.
Here.
The ingots have melted.
That is how you
shape them, huh?
Ja. The molds.
When you're on the plains,
you have a woman there?
An Indian woman?
I mean,
I have heard some men do.
It's a natural thing,
I suppose.
How long does it take?
Until they cool.
Tomorrow these will be ready.
So, then, you do not?
What's that?
Oh, the Indian woman? No, no.
McKeag is the only one
who shares my canoe.
He sounds like
quite a fellow.
But he does not
say much, though,
does he?
That's why I let him
share my canoe.
It seems to me
a man with a good business
like you ought to marry.
What you file off,
you use again?
Ja.
I have been planning
on it again myself.
What's that?
Get married.
Oh.
But a good woman
is not an easy thing to find.
A woman like Lise?
Lise.
Ja, ja,
my Lise is a fine woman.
You have noticed, ja?
It'd be hard for
a man not to notice.
I'm glad to hear you say that.
It's easy to say...
You're buffing.
Is that right?
Ja.
And these tools here,
they're for the etching?
Ja.
Such small tools
in such big hands.
What you do is
really remarkable.
Pasquinel,
let me be frank.
I sell a piece like this
for a lot of money.
I'm going to be
a very wealthy man.
I can afford to be
very generous with Lise.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH)
I don't understand.
You would have
a fixed home here.
A fixed home is something,
Pasquinel.
(LAUGHS)
Monsieur Bockweiss,
why would Lise want me?
I will never be anything
but what I am, a coureur.
Damn it,
do not play dumb with me.
You know she is
interested in you,
and so do I.
Now, I am telling you
that as your partner
I would be very happy to...
That is, should you
at some point in time
wish to join my family,
I would have
no objection whatsoever.
You are a good father,
monsieur.
Hermann.
Hermann,
you are a good friend
to suggest that
something like that
would be possible.
We could have the wedding
before you go back
to the plains.
You said, "In time."
And you said none of us
lives forever.
The Indians know
more about life than
any of us maybe, huh?
Huh?
Perhaps.
NARRATOR: At the end of
the 18th century,
the Indians of
the Great Plains were
sovereigns of their world.
The horse had allowed them
to ride into a new life
in the formerly forbidding
heart of the open grasslands.
While Lame Beaver
continued to refuse
all offers to sit
among a council,
he was respected above all
other members of his tribe
because they remembered
it was his courage that
first gave them the horse.
A man's wealth
and his family's
social standing
were now determined
by the amount of
horses he owned.
And every young Indian boy
knew that if he became
a skilled warrior and hunter,
he would acquire
many horses of his own
and live a life of
dignity and respect
like the old man
called Lame Beaver.
Lame Beaver was
53 years old as the century
was drawing to a close.
By the standards
of his time,
he was already old.
Not even the new power
the gun brought him
as a warrior and hunter
could replace other powers
he would be losing soon.
He knew his time
was almost over,
but he had no way of
knowing that an ancient
culture at its zenith
had little more
time left than he.
(ARAPAHOS CHANTING)
(DRUMS BEATING)
The Plains Indians
of the year 1800 were
a contented people.
The horse had been
their salvation,
the buffalo was the basis
of their existence.
From its many parts
came almost everything
necessary to daily life.
It provided food,
clothing, shelter, weapons,
and a source of industry
that kept bodies strong
and minds healthy.
It was a time to be enjoyed.
There was no need to worry
about the future,
and the young people could
take pride in the past.
(IN ENGLISH)
Father, tell me
about the horses.
How you were
the first one to get them.
(IN ENGLISH)
That was a long time ago.
Did you really visit
the sun before you
raided the Comanche?
Could a man do
something like that alone?
I wish I could have
seen you bring them
into camp.
Was it exciting, Mother?
(IN ENGLISH) It was
the most exciting thing
we'd ever known.
BLUE LEAF: The bravest thing
any warrior had ever done,
and he was only 17 summers.
He walked far to the south
where the Comanche
were hunting buffalo.
Our people could not
follow the buffalo
as far as the other tribes
and we were not
as powerful in war
because we had no horses.
Your father knew that
we must get horses
or our tribe would die,
but no other warriors
would go with him
because they knew
if they were caught
by the Comanche,
they would die
a terrible death.
Man Above,
I am one of Our People.
Help me.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(SHOUTING)
(YELLS)
(WHOOPING)
(YELLING)
(MEN WHOOPING)
(WHOOPING)
(SHOUTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Comanche!
(SPEAKING ARAPAHO)
BLUE LEAF:
It was so bold and so daring
that even the Comanches
saluted him for his courage.
(ALL WHOOPING)
When I saw him
return to camp,
I knew it was
the greatest thing
I would ever see.
He had brought the horses
no one else could get,
the horses we could
not go on without.
He had given us our lives.
And I have never known
a prouder moment
than when he put me
on one of them.
The one he would
give to my brother,
so that we could
share a life together.
And you were
only 17 summer.
The other braves
must have...
We need new lodge poles.
They'll last another season.
They've been dragged
for many miles.
They're growing short.
Maybe we could use new ones.
Maybe? Look at them!
We should have traded for them
when we were in the north.
Trade for what, a horse?
I'd never trade a horse.
I'll find poles.
The best poles.
(GROANS)
BLUE LEAF: What is it?
Are you all right?
Leave me alone.
Blue Leaf.
I'm not angry with you.
Clay Basket thinks it's her
because she asked you
to tell the story.
No. I just broke
another tooth. See?
Does it hurt?
What hurts is getting old.
Each year for you is
another one for me, too.
Remember when we had
no horses?
We moved so slowly then,
only with the dogs.
We moved so slowly,
and life seemed so long.
LAME BEAVER:
I remember when I was a boy,
I thought I'd never grow old.
I thought I'd never be
old enough to be a warrior.
(IN ENGLISH) Sit.
When your body must work,
make it work.
When it needs rest,
give it rest.
Where is the river?
Have you looked around you?
Yes.
Then take a second look.
A longer look.
I don't see anything.
What are those?
Just swallows.
(LAUGHS) That's right.
But swallows must
have water every day.
Doves, too.
So you watch for them.
If their mouths were empty,
they were flying toward water.
If they had mud in them,
they were flying from water.
Do you know
which way the water is?
That way.
You saw the mud
in their mouths from here?
You didn't ask me that.
You only asked if I knew
which way the water is.
Look closely
at everything.
Watch the animals
to learn their secret ways.
The deer will teach you
how to go without water
for a long time.
The hawk will teach you
how to strike swiftly
without missing.
The coyote, how to keep
from being captured.
The rattlesnake,
how to keep from being seen.
Which one teaches you
how to make fire?
Only man.
And he is the most
dangerous animal
you will ever know.
More dangerous
than a mountain lion?
Much more.
Why?
Because he knows
what you know.
LAME BEAVER:
That was a long time ago.
A lifetime ago.
You've made my life
a good one.
Tomorrow I'll make us
the best tepee in the village.
I'll find poles in
the Blue Mountain.
Poles that are
tall and straight.
The Blue Mountain?
The Utes are there.
I'm not afraid of the Utes.
Just because a man
breaks a tooth
is no reason to change
the way he lives, is it?
No.
There have been Ute here
hunting beaver.
Over there.
We can take them.
We're here for lodge poles,
not scalps.
Is that the man
who raided the Comanche
for horses talking?
A man of many coups?
It is a man who lived
long enough to tell
the stories himself.
We'll wait here
in the shadows
until they leave,
then we'll find our poles
among the tall spruce.
NARRATOR: It was
in this mountain valley
that Lame Beaver made
a discovery that
would have an impact
on the whole world
a half a century later.
But at the time
he had no way of knowing
the value other men
might put upon
the shining rocks
he held in his hand.
What is it?
Bullets
I don't have to melt.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
SEÑORA ALVAREZ:
Will you give up
trading now?
No, señora.
But with a family...
It's all that I know.
Merci.
Well, perhaps you might
learn to be a silversmith.
After all, we have
the finest teacher
here in St. Louis.
(LAUGHS)
He would make a good pupil.
But I cannot
get him interested.
Because it's a talent
that I don't have.
Señor, you must have
a very special talent.
Lise could have chosen
any man in the city
and she chose you.
Because she wanted
someone to look up to.
Papa.
Excuse me, Pasquinel.
Oui.
I'll be right back.
Alexander,
will you dance with me?
Oh, I cannot dance.
I will teach you.
It is my wedding.
Monsieur Pasquinel?
Oui?
I say it is very exciting
to know you are
civilizing the Indians.
Civilizing them?
Well, I pray to God
I'm never guilty of that.
But that is what you do,
is it not?
No, no.
You introduce them
to our ways?
I am a trader.
Gracias.
I trade beaver, madame.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH)
Surely you are too modest.
You must admit that you are
an emissary for our cultures.
And if the Indian is to learn,
he must learn
from men like yourself.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Monsieur, you may ask
my father-in-law, I am not...
I'm not a modest man.
But there is nothing
I can teach the Indian
that he needs to know.
Why is that?
Because he lives
with nature.
He's been taught
to become a part of nature.
Yes, but still they are
totally uneducated.
No, no, no.
Uneducated in our world,
but not in theirs.
Well, are they so different?
What time is it?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
The time, do you have it?
It is ten of four.
Is that important to you?
Is that important
to any of you?
Well, I thought you asked.
I did. But an Indian wouldn't.
He has no clocks
because he sees no need
to schedule his life.
And he does not believe that
what a man does in a day
by so many hours
is a real measure
of his worth.
No, no.
He does what he does.
It takes as long as it takes,
and no one does it
better than the Indian.
No, no one here can
teach the Indian anything
that is important to him.
You may be forgetting
one thing, my son.
They are heathens.
They build no churches,
they write no sacred books,
but everything about
the Indians centers
around his religion.
A pagan religion.
Sacrifices, bloodletting.
Didn't Christ himself
die on the cross,
and wasn't that God's will?
That was a unique act,
Pasquinel.
To save the world.
Theirs is a unique world.
It needs no saving.
Just relax.
(STAMMERING) I cannot.
Of course you can.
Just glide with the music
and listen to the rhythm.
(STAMMERING)
I'm sorry, I cannot.
All right, Alexander.
Oh, thank you.
To friendship.
Did Pasquinel tell you
that there would always be
a room here for you
whenever you are
in St. Louis?
Oh, no, I...
That's one "no"
I will not accept from you,
Alexander McKeag.
Our home is your home.
Unless you have plans
of your own you're not
telling us about.
No.
No, you will not
accept our offer?
Or no, you have
no plans of your own?
No, I... I mean, I...
Alexander,
I think there's something
you're keeping from us.
No.
There must be
someone somewhere.
Well...
I knew it.
Here or in Scotland?
Here.
In St. Louis?
No.
Where then?
Can you keep a secret?
Forever.
Me, too.
Alexander,
that's not fair.
It's just I don't suppose
I should be telling others
till I've had a chance
to tell her first.
That's fair.
And I know whoever she is,
she'll be as happy
as I am today.
I'd better go
rescue Pasquinel.
He takes a bit of that
from time to time.
Now he will have both of us
to take after him.
SEÑORA ALVAREZ:
Is it true they have
more than one wife?
Señora?
I've heard they keep
more than one wife.
Is that true?
If they need them,
and if the woman
needs a husband.
And if the other wives
are happy for it.
They work hard.
More hands
makes the work easier.
I don't know.
I don't think I understand
that kind of thinking.
People understand
what they want to understand.
Like me.
I don't understand
why you're dancing with
that skinny Scotman
when you could be
dancing with me.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Regardez, McKeag,
regardez.
Fascinating man.
Why?
Because he fights Indians?
Because he understands them.
He should, my dear.
He's part Indian himself.
Oh, yes. Didn't you know?
He's Mandan.
He's from Montreal.
By the way,
I have heard that
he has a wife there, too.
(ALL CHANTING)
(DRUMS BEATING)
Do you know why they dance
in a circle?
When I was little,
I thought it was to keep
warm by the fire.
All of life is a circle.
The dancers start there,
the south,
which represents the source
from which we are born.
Then we move to the left,
through youth,
toward the sunset in the west.
And night falls
as we draw close
to the cold north,
where the white hairs are.
To show us that all life is
night and day, good and bad.
Father, I know.
If we live on,
we find the source of light
to the east,
and with it
we find understanding.
The understanding that
teaches us now to prepare
for the end of life.
Then we return
to where we began.
Giving back our life
to all life,
our flesh to
where it started from.
Think about this.
And the more you think
about it, the more meaning
you'll find in it.
Mother?
St. Louis ends here.
We've said goodbye.
I know, but...
Make certain this old man
keeps working.
I'm going
to make him a god.
God Bockweiss, who makes
his silver pipes in heaven
but only for Pasquinel.
I will be working.
Come back.
I always come back.
Bonjour, mon ami.
It looks like
a great year for beaver.
Are you all right?
I did not think
I would feel this way.
I think that is natural.
Especially now,
since you're going
to be a grandfather.
What? What?
That's wonderful.
BOCKWEISS: Does he know?
I could not tell him.
Lise.
I want him back.
He should not be going.
He will always be going.
Do you not know that, Papa?
If he has a family...
He'll always be going.
That is what he is,
what he does.
I do not want
to change that.
I've heard there were others
who have tried.
Those are unfounded rumors.
They are lies.
Perhaps.
All I know is that I love him
and I want him
to know how much.
If he comes back and sees
I did not try to stop him,
I think he will know.
I want you to know
I do not understand
that kind of thinking.
Maybe we only understand
what we want to understand,
huh, Papa?
(GASPS)
Lame Beaver.
I'll get you,
I used to watch your mother
on mornings like this.
You're even more beautiful
than she was then.
I don't think so.
No, this is my work.
Not today.
Have I ever told you
why we named you
Clay Basket?
(CHUCKLING)
Many times.
We were in the north,
following the bison.
A Dakota trader
brought out a splendid
basket made by a Cree.
It looked like it was woven,
but it was made of clay.
And your mother loved it.
She wanted it
above all other things.
Father, I know the story.
You must not forget it.
You must not forget
that I bought that basket
for your mother
with a bison robe.
A robe she'd worked on
for many months
to make it soft.
It was a good robe,
and I traded it
for the basket.
The clay basket
your mother loved so much
and for which you're named.
Father...
And all the other stories,
too.
The ones your mother
painted on the robe for me,
the ones we told you
about our life together,
about the wild duck that
lived in the cottonwoods,
and the tame elk that stayed
in the camp in the north,
and all the other stories.
You must not forget them,
or they will die.
Father, where's Mother?
I've looked for her.
She's gone to be alone.
Why?
To think.
To make herself ready.
Oh, no.
That's why you told me
again about the dance, too,
isn't it?
You are my child.
You must remember
everything,
or your children
will never know
how it was with us.
You're going to war?
The Pawnee have
stolen a child.
She must be returned.
Let the young men go.
The young men are
afraid of the Pawnee.
You can't go.
The girl may be dead.
Why should you die, too?
We must know.
And the Pawnee must know
that Our People will not
let them do
such things to us.
Father...
If I've been a good father,
you know the end
must come for us all.
And you remember what I said
about the white man Pasquinel.
When I'm gone,
he'll take care of you.
You don't have to go.
What about Mother?
Who'll take care of her
if you go?
Your mother is a woman.
She knows her end
as well as I know mine.
Oh, Father.
Who is Man Above?
Man Above is a creator.
Higher than all people
and all the universe.
He has no beginning
and no end.
Is he good?
He is all good.
Then why do we fight
other men?
Because there is
evil in men, too.
You pray every morning?
Our tepees face
the morning sun
to remind us we must
give thanks every day.
What if there's no reason
to give thanks?
Then the fault
is in yourself.
LAME BEAVER:
I'll pray with you tomorrow.
GRAY WOLF: No.
You must meet the morning sun
and the great silence alone.
It prepares your mind
to face the day.
It makes you thoughtful
in all things.
Man Above,
I have done
all I can do.
(SINGING IN FRENCH)
The charge will be
heaviest there.
I will wait there
for the great chief
Rude Water
and I will shoot him dead.
The Pawnee will panic,
and we'll have the girl.
Go now.
Man Above is with us.
Go!
(SHOUTING IN PAWNEE)
(ALL WHOOPING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
(ALL CHANTING)
(DRUMS BEATING)
Mother, your things.
They are mine no more.
Your basket!
(SCREAMS)
Get away!
PASQUINEL: Burial.
Up there?
So the spirit can escape
into the wind and the clouds.
He was a great warrior.
How do you know?
The ponytail.
They kill a great man's
favorite horse
so his spirit
won't have to walk.
The stake and the thongs.
He died in combat,
as brave a death
as possible.
McKEAG: And it just
stays up there like that?
Nature will claim it
in time.
As she does everything.
Mother.
Mother?
You don't have to
stay out here.
It must be.
There's room on my robe
in your brother's tepee.
He did not ask me in,
and it's not
your right to ask.
He won't want you
to stay out here.
He has no choice.
I do.
And I'm staying with you
wherever you are.
No, sweet one.
You have a life to live.
And mine is over.
He didn't have to
kill himself that way.
leave you like this.
We talked.
I knew what would come.
It was this way
for my mother, too.
But why?
It makes no sense.
Does it make more sense
for us to grow old
and burden those who need
their strength to survive?
I can't leave you.
I won't leave you.
You must stay warm
and you must stay well.
And when the white man
comes,
you must go with him
as your father said.
And you must
have his children,
and you must remember
all the stories
so they will know
who they are.
You remember who you are.
You are the daughter
of a very brave man.
A man of many coups.
He was a fool.
He was what I said.
And what you will say
to your children
and they to theirs.
In that way,
he will go on living
and bring meaning
to their lives as well.
That's all
we can ever do.
Any of us.
(SOBBING) Yes, Mother.
Yes.
Rude Water dead.
Dead? How?
Arapaho make war.
Big devil Lame Beaver
stake self out,
shoot Rude Water.
Lame Beaver?
What happened to him?
We kill him.
But his medicine strong.
He count many coup
before he died.
That scaffold by the river.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH)
How long ago this fight?
Just before snow.
Not long.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH)
We should have
started earlier.
You think you could've
stopped them?
I could've tried.
You give Lame Beaver gun?
I trade gun for beaver.
Same as Rude Water.
You trade yellow bullets, too?
Yellow bullets?
Only reason Lame Beaver
kill Rude Water.
Well, that looks like...
It is.
(IN ARAPAHO) Mother.
Mother?
(IN ARAPAHO) Mother?
(IN ARAPAHO)
Go back.
Back.
Bonjour, mon ami.
Another long night
for you, too, huh?
Sweet savior.
Damn.
It's Blue Leaf.
How could that happen?
What's she doing out here?
She is no longer
the wife of a warrior.
She has no right
to a tepee of her own.
What?
It's their law.
Without a son or a brother
willing to take her in,
she has no home.
She is allowed to keep
is what she has on her back.
That's bloody inhuman!
She knew
it would happen.
What about her daughter?
Oui, the girl,
she would know.
Know?
About the gold.
Where her father found it.
That's not what I meant.
I meant what did
they do to her?
She is young and strong,
she'll bear the grandchildren
of a great warrior.
She'll have plenty of men
after her.
She could even have
a husband already.
What should we do with her?
Leave her.
They will lay her to rest with
her sewing kit and awl cases
like they did him
with the weapons.
Let's find the girl.
What's her name?
Clay Basket.
Oui, Clay Basket.
She is with my father now.
It is good.
And you?
You're all right?
Aye.
Clay Basket,
I gave your father
the gun.
Do you know
where he got
his bullets?
Pasquinel.
Ask her.
(IN ARAPAHO) Do you know
where your father got
the bullets for his gun?
(IN ARAPAHO) Bullets?
Aye.
Where? Ask her where.
(IN ENGLISH) I make.
You? You made the bullets?
(IN ARAPAHO) Bullets.
(IN ENGLISH)
Aye. I make bullets.
The yellow ones?
Yellow?
Like these.
No.
But they came
from the gun.
My father's gun?
Oui.
They came
from your father's gun.
Where did he get them?
I not see.
I not know.
But he say to me...
Oui? He said?
(SPEAKING ARAPAHO)
He just told her
how much it meant to him
and to the tribe for you
to give him the gun.
That's all?
(IN ARAPAHO)
That's all
he said to you?
He told me
you would come back.
(IN ENGLISH)
He told her we'd come back.
And when you did,
he wanted me to go with you,
if it pleases you, Pasquinel.
What?
He told me it would
make him proud if I would
belong to Pasquinel.
What did she say?
McKeag?
He told her
he wanted her
to go with you.
Avec moi?
To be your wife.
Pasquinel, I wonder...
I mean,
since you're already...
since there's no way...
Mon ami, I don't think
you understood what she said.
Her father told her
to go with me.
He know I would
take care of her.
I heard.
But Bockweiss
asked you first...
Bockweiss is in St. Louis.
What about Lise?
He'll take care of her.
He will always
take care of her.
Tell her I am proud
to have her for my wife.
For the gold,
you mean.
That's it, isn't it?
The gold.
You think she knows
where it is.
Tell her.
(IN ARAPAHO) Pasquinel,
he doesn't want me?
Pasquinel says
you make him proud.
Red Beard?
Aye?
(IN ENGLISH)
Arm good?
Aye. My arm is fine.
NARRATOR: The Indians said,
"Pasquinel,
he can be trusted. "
It came to be
a passport of safety for
the coureur de bois
and his partner
Alexander McKeag.
But McKeag began to wonder
how much the Indians had
really known about Pasquinel.
Had they confused
courage with honor?
Still, the young Scot
could not leave
the only friend
he'd ever known
and the only woman
he'd ever wanted.
He only knew
one thing for certain.
It would be a hard winter.