Sorry, Bullock.
You abide me beside you,
20 paces or so?
Yankton's man is among us.
Even under the circumstances...
he may try you to confirm we're allied.
If he does...
your nod would advance the cause.
All right.
Yeah, you fat fuck, you're alive.
Let me die.
What is that, "thank you" in whale talk?
- Drink this.
- No.
Drink it.
Get up, get the doc,
and tell him he's got a live one.
Tell him, too,
his rupture patient left here...
to convalesce at his own fucking place.
You gave him a shoulder to lean on
as he was getting the fuck out.
Next time he opens his eyes, he's
gonna think he died and went to heaven.
Cocksucker!
Yeah, San Francisco cocksucker, Wu.
Your mortal fucking enemy.
- Swearengen.
- Wu.
Swearengen.
Yeah, I make these
as burnt-up whores...
that I smelt on the char this morning
with your San Francisco rival...
turning the fucking spit.
- Swearengen fucking knows.
- Swearengen know.
I know about the burnt-up whores,
I know about the San Francisco...
cocksucker setting a match to them.
Now, here's the part
you gotta listen to, Wu.
- Chung Kuo.
- Is "China."
- Chung Kuo, "China."
- Yeah, Chung Kuo, "China."
Celestial whores in the fire. What?
Their spirits are fucking...
nothing, if their bones
don't get back home? Is that it?
And do you come to me
to back your move...
against your
San Francisco cocksucker rival?
Am I getting
the fucking drift to you, Wu?
- Swearengen!
- Swearengen fucking gets it!
Swearengen doesn't give a fuck!
Back to Chinks' Alley, Wu.
Fall to your fucking prayers.
I can use the plate
if you want to leave that.
Why don't I back him?
'Cause Hearst is
in the other Chink's corner.
Meaning Wu has to lose.
Wouldn't be the worst thing.
Backing a loser to Hearst.
Let him pick me up from the canvas
after, dust me the fuck off.
I raise the great man's hand...
murmur, best as I can through split lips:
"Your man beat my man's balls off,
Mr Hearst."
But Hearst's Chink...
bossing that alley
ain't to my fucking taste.
So what if something delays
the battle of the Chinks?
Say, during that interval I get to show
my ass a few times to Mr Hearst.
Meanwhile, that pain in the balls,
Wu, is sketching up a storm...
and drawing fucking little pictures of
himself brandishing the lash...
driving from a delivery ship a quota
of Chinks to be blown to pieces...
by dynamite working
in the mines for Hearst...
at half the fee per Chink that Hearst
is paying the San Francisco cocksucker.
Now, by this time, Hearst
has seen my ass so many times...
he knows I'm no long-term threat.
So, some brief opposition
of our interests...
ain't gonna make him
feel like he needs...
to engage me in a death struggle,
say, by opposing local elections.
Those circumstances
we can risk backing Wu...
and the great man figures:
"I am damaged by neither outcome.
"Why not retire to a neutral corner...
"and test my import against the locals?"
What delays Wu going after
the other Chink?
- Or the other Chink going after Wu?
- That, too.
Well, if the other Chink can
be dissuaded, Wu, we can put on ice.
Well, how do we dissuade
the other Chink?
I suppose laying eyes on him
would be the first step.
My only question is,
push comes to shove...
wearing them Chinese dresses...
how well can you ladies fight?
You're staying, Adams.
Cheyenne and Black Hills
Telegraph Company.
Telegrams for delivery.
Mr Blasanov. On our day of grief.
Our acquaintance
is established, Blasanov...
and for my part, our friendship.
- Thank you.
- You needn't announce yourself...
every morning, and your purpose.
May I suggest, as well, that rather than
you delivering your telegrams upstairs...
interrupting the rest, or secret
depravities, of well-armed guests...
I could distribute them
in these pigeonholes...
to be collected by the guests
at their leisure?
I am not permitted.
A man must put bread on his table,
Mr Blasanov, I well understand.
Suppose, to compensate you for lost
gratuities, I were to pay you $5 a day?
Cheyenne and Black Hills
Telegraph Company...
requires personal delivery by Blasanov.
I am not permitted.
Yet avarice is numbered among
the sins, and stupidity omitted.
- No Gem whores at the railings today.
- Why not?
Al won't permit them on the balcony.
He lets them on, they'll be leaping off.
Very dramatic we get,
at the passing of the fucking young.
Yesterday was a terrible day.
Do not even fucking ask me
to account for my coming here...
advising you how to answer Ellsworth.
You haven't changed your opinion,
have you, Trixie...
as to my accepting
Ellsworth's marriage proposal?
My new opinion is...
few choices, as are ours to make...
others should stay
the fuck out of the process.
Quiet like that since the boy's accident?
Cheyenne and Black Hills Telegraph.
Telegram for Mr Wolcott.
- How are you today, Mr Blasanov?
- Thank you.
- Telegram for Mr Jarry.
- Yes, I am he.
Thank you.
You've packed your things.
Thrown them, it looks like.
What is it you wish to say?
That I'd hope in the throes of this day
you'd not make any final decision.
I can't bear to stay.
The minister's here
to discuss the service.
Reverend.
Mrs Bullock, my deep sympathies...
which I conveyed
to your husband last evening.
Thank you.
You wish to discuss William's service.
I suggested to Mr Bullock that
we hold service in front of the house.
That would be fine.
As to the substance of the service...
do you wish psalms,
a reading, my words...
hymns, chosen speakers in memoriam,
a second reading...
- Let the service be brief.
- Yes.
Certainly.
Do you wish to provide me
a detail or two of William?
I don't want that.
Do you have a favourite reading?
Did he?
- You choose something.
- Certainly.
And you'll announce that
the burial is private?
I will.
Will there, then, be a passing-by
of the casket after the service?
No!
- Certainly.
- Thank you, Reverend.
My condolences, Sheriff.
My deepest sympathies.
The answer is yes, Commissioner.
What you wanna know.
Having to do with Mr Swearengen
speaking with your voice.
Yes. That's all, now.
My reluctance to intrude
nearly kept me from coming at all.
Mose Manuel made it through.
- Thank heavens.
- The doc fixed Con's rupture, too.
Go shoot some dope.
Thank you, sir.
It's been a hell of a trying evening.
I have a cheque for $50,000...
I'd like to cash with you.
I show that courtesy to people
who gamble in my joint.
I wish to afford you, Mr Tolliver,
a chance to show...
my colleagues in Yankton that you are
not blinded by parochial rivalry...
as to what the greater good requires.
You'd deliver the 50 to Swearengen?
Who'd no doubt prefer the cheque,
to have the bribe on record.
So, this ain't you just being a twitch...
who likes rubbing people's noses
in their losses.
Shall we transact our business
in the cage, Mr Tolliver...
where I was attacked the other day,
and you failed to come to my aid?
I see you made it
through the fucking night.
Jesus fucking Christ.
This is gonna be a pleasant fucking day,
them wailing and gnashing their teeth.
Will they be allowed
to pay their respects?
- By who?
- By you, most importantly, as always.
And should you,
in your greatness, consent...
will he let them in his fucking house?
I won't object...
but it's yours to keep them she-apes
from disgracing me.
As to Bullock's feelings,
get the Jew to find them out.
Should I ask about you also?
What the fuck
would I wanna go there for?
Shut the fuck up!
Hot!
I mean I know what it's supposed to
be, but I ain't fucking used to it.
Well, maybe wait a little.
Yeah, I'll wait a little bit
before I fucking get in.
Did it ever occur to you strange...
bathing in a tub you've dirtied,
coming out thinking you're clean?
- You need a bath, Jane.
- And I'm gonna fucking take it!
I'm raising a general fucking question.
If you want boots different
from your regular...
No, I do not.
I will clean my fucking regular boots.
- Shouldn't you do that before your bath?
- No! Turn around!
Don't go!
Dumb fucking luck it must have been
me living this long...
without your fucking guidance.
I don't like new boots, either.
I ain't afraid of newness...
it's the blisters give me pause.
God, I burnt my fucking snatch!
- Or funerals.
- Or funerals, what?
Any more than I like new boots.
- I don't like funerals.
- I do! I do! I can't get to enough of them!
Trixie.
He'd have me ask, might the whores...
pay the dead boy their respects?
The service is outside the home.
All in the camp are welcome.
They'd be sure to keep to their place.
Why did you go to him?
Now, hold to this counter
as I reveal this, Mr Star.
I've lived most of my life a whore,
and as much as he's her misery...
the pimp's a whore's familiar.
So, the sudden strange or violent
draws her to him.
Not that I wouldn't learn another way.
- You look fucking mournful.
- Even more.
Sad day, gentlemen,
on which commerce must intrude.
Says who that it must?
Because of the death
of the Sheriff's son.
You need to ask,
you don't deserve an answer.
I should say
that even in his hour of grief...
Sheriff Bullock conveyed to me
his reliance on you as his proxy.
And, as his proxy...
I don't do business on the day
of my godson's passing.
I'm compelled to wonder,
Mr Swearengen...
if this show of grief is a pretext
to some other purpose.
What a type you must consort with...
that you not fear beating
for such an insult.
If Montana, for example...
had sweetened the terms
in annexing this camp...
and you'd delay the closing
of our business not for piety...
but to pursue your other negotiations...
Leave here with your
sick fucking ghoulish thinking.
I'll have further instructions
within the day.
If not honour...
practicality dictates granting Yankton
further counter.
You come back here offering
one more dollar than that 50...
you'll find yourself facedown
in the horseshit.
But you would entertain
enhancement of the offer...
other than cash?
I do not discuss business
on this day. Silas.
You're buying yourself
a fucking bum's rush, Commissioner.
When Mr Swearengen says go,
he means it.
All right. All right.
I'm not without imagination.
A counter without currency
is in the offing.
Go over there with that guy.
You do remember me, Andy?
Three times we worked together.
Memphis, and on the river,
and in Kansas City.
And we were meant to here,
but you fell ill.
I've changed.
You're bound to resent my presence
in the camp.
Well, see, I haven't changed...
or changed the rules which,
against your having gone soft-headed...
are fucking inviolate against you
running a game in my territory...
without prior arrangement,
and on my fucking terms...
set and agreed in advance.
I'm not running a game, Cy.
I fucking schooled you, Andy Cramed,
to the variety that can be played.
I don't practise deception anymore.
The opening pronouncement
of a dozen we both can name.
I was nursed last fall
in the plague tent...
and saved to be born anew
and preach the risen Lord.
The Lord risen, or the wheel,
or the shell and pea...
in this camp, for you, it's by my leave.
- I will suffer any indignity...
- Which I still have not heard you solicit.
Interference with God's work,
I will not suffer.
Then you'd best be moving along, Andy.
'Cause absent tribute,
even as His employee...
you don't get to fucking operate.
Don't let me find you trying, Andy.
Or it's into the woods once more,
only this time...
left nailed to a tree.
I don't know what you'll understand
of my speech, and I don't give a fuck...
or what terrorizing them human bonfires
this morning intend towards...
the Chinks still under your thumb.
A white man's son is dead,
that you will be doing business with.
On the day of his son's burial...
the smell of burning flesh
ought not offend his nose.
The only showing you need make
that you've understood our chat...
is a stop to them fucking fires.
And you might want to put off
other violence while you're at it...
as a decency to the day,
you heathen fucking cocksucker.
Jesus fucking Christ!
There will be no violence between you
and Wu, while the grieving goes on.
My God, act civilised even if you ain't.
I am a civilised person.
Then take your civilisation
and get the fuck out of here!
He got the fucking message.
- Wait on Wu if you want.
- Wait until what?
You wanna go to the fucking service
or fucking not?
Don't have to ask us twice.
What the fuck I wanna go for?
What price will you take for your hotel,
Mr Farnum?
- Why do you ask?
- Because I wanna buy it.
Do you, sir?
- I presume as agent for other parties?
- Presume away.
Is it warm in here?
- To me it seems chilly.
- Chilly, is it?
Richardson, Mr Wolcott finds it chilly!
Not around. I'll see to it, sir.
If you are chilly in 10 minutes time,
pray for my immortal soul...
because some fatal mishap
will have befallen me.
Short of which, I will not fail
to dispel the chill now afflicting you.
Cocksuckers.
Think they can take away everything!
Oh, cocksucker.
Found it outside dead,
under the window.
- Well, why'd you bring it inside?
- Poor little finch.
Throw it out and wipe your hands.
If a bird taps on a window
or crashes into one...
that means that there has been a death!
We know there's been a death.
We know now, but that bird
crashed into the window...
and died a while ago, before we knew...
for all we know.
I've shined me and Al's,
but I ain't doing yours.
Oh, well, I got me some new boots.
They pinch bad,
but they got that factory shine still.
Johnny, you can't wear
nothing new to a funeral...
especially not new footwear.
I ain't never heard that.
Maybe because when
they was telling it to you...
you was too busy listening to that
bullshit about birds flying into windows!
To be kept till after
the after-funeral fuck rush is over.
Fucking confiscated paraphernalia.
Boots on a bar?
What is the fucking matter
with you, Dan?
Give me a fucking whiskey bottle.
I'm sprinkling it...
at the fucking doorways.
Or would you rather
evil traipse past this fucking threshold?
Must have brought that
from the other side.
I've wished, sometimes,
only to play checkers...
or to occupy myself some other way...
than having to see
and feel so much sadness.
Or feel, every moment,
how difficult things are to understand...
or to live with.
I've sometimes felt
I couldn't live with them...
but I find I can, Sofia. I've found I am.
Even when I think I'm not, or that I can't.
Can you look to me now, Sofia?
Can you try?
I will be so grateful
if you will trust me with your sadness...
and I will trust you with mine,
so that even when we are sad...
we will be grateful for
how much we love each other...
and know that we are...
in the world as much in our pain...
as in our happiness.
Thank you, honey.
Shall we dress now,
and say goodbye to William Bullock?
...that no one that's turned in a needle...
try eating the dope
or shoving it up theirselves...
as I will be checking eyes
for signs before we fucking leave.
And no being drunk, either, Jenn.
And wash your fucking mouth.
You got seven kinds of cock breath.
Yeah.
Underarms clean, cunts braided?
- They're ready.
- You are accountable.
Why not come?
Make them accountable to you?
Shut the fucking door behind you.
William Bullock...
beloved son of Martha and Seth...
called to God age 11 years...
as we are called by his passing.
Let us bow our heads.
From Psalm number 23.
"The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
"He maketh me lie down
in green pastures...
"He leadeth me beside the still waters.
"He restoreth my soul...
"He leadeth me in the paths of
righteousness for His name's sake."
"Oh that my words were now written.
"That they were graven
with an iron pen and lead...
"in the rock for ever.
"For I know that my Redeemer liveth...
"and He shall stand
at the latter day upon the earth.
"And though after my skin
worms destroy this body...
"yet in my flesh I shall see God.
"Whom I shall see for myself...
"and my eyes shall behold...
"and not another."
From Psalm 121.
"I will lift up mine eyes unto the hills...
"from whence cometh my help.
"My help cometh from the Lord,
which made heaven and earth.
"The Lord is thy keeper...
"the Lord is thy shade
upon thy right hand.
"The sun shall not smite thee by day...
"nor the moon by night.
"The Lord shall preserve thee
from all evil...
"He shall preserve thy soul."
Let the people come
and say goodbye to William.
"...preserve thy going out
and thy coming in from this time forth...
"and even for evermore."
At the request of the family,
the burial is private.
On their behalf, at their request,
I thank you all for coming.
Let them see him.
Those who wish to pay final respects...
to the corpse of William Bullock
are invited now into the Bullock home.
The girls are gonna be awhile.
They're viewing the corpse.
- Get Wu now, please.
- At the icehouse.
How should we set up the shifts?
- What does he mean?
- You know, guarding Wu.
Bring Wu here.
Put him in one of the whores' rooms.
Didn't make sense when he said it.
That's the first place
Wu's people would look.
"Put him on ice."
It's a figure of speech, Johnny.
Like, "Got you by the balls."
Up you go, little lady.
We picked flowers
in William's graveyard.
Me and Trixie.
"Trixie and l" is how
that's supposed to go, I think.
Yes, Ellsworth.
Yes, to the question you've asked me.
- Swearengen.
- Swearengen!
Now, Wu. Swearengen.
Swearengen!
Mr Wu, why don't you just come with us
like a gentleman?
Seems to me, Wolcott,
last your eyes had that unsettled look...
matters got grave for some young girls.
What does it? Do you know?
Or does the water
just come on you quick?
- "Be ye afraid of the sword!"
- Jesus fucking Christ!
"For wrath bringeth
the punishments of the sword."
Get him the fuck out of here!
You're a desperate man,
aren't you, Tolliver? Desperate.
You feel your position weakening.
And what I do, situation like that,
instead of murdering helpless women...
- I get on my hind legs and fight.
- Mr Wolcott.
I have nourished a suspicion
that we might pass each other...
in the telegraph office.
I, of course, would be communicating
with Yankton.
I wonder, would your messages
be sent to Helena?
Mr Hearst is not a partisan
in territorial rivalries, Commissioner.
Oh, God, I want to believe that.
The great man himself
will allay your doubts.
He joins us within the week.
Does he, for a fact?
I would hope, sir, that by that time,
Yankton's answer to my telegram...
would authorise me to offer,
and I would've heard accepted terms...
of annexation of this camp,
such that a huge banner...
would be hung across
the thoroughfare...
"Welcome, George Hearst,
to Deadwood of Dakota territory."
I don't envy you the interval,
Commissioner.
Ain't it the idle hours that try us?
Ain't they what lead us sometimes
to the cliff, sometimes fucking over?
I may have to ask Mr Hearst
if that's his experience, too...
or, of any of those that he may know.
Let me ask you something.
You think you're giving me a treat,
drooling on my fucking nuts?
- Because I happen not to enjoy it.
- Sorry.
It's a strange fucking sensation.
Distracts me from my hard-on.
Fucking caskets.
Bring out the dunce
in the entire fucking community.
I took some fucking beating
after my brother's fucking funeral.
Smacks coming
from every fucking angle.
Still dizzy from the smack from the left,
here comes a smack from the right.
Brain can't bounce around fast enough.
Headache I fucking had
for three fucking weeks.
Fuck fault is it of mine
if my fucking brother croaks?
Ain't even my fucking brother.
Fucking people take me in,
I didn't ask them to fucking take me in.
Fucking flopping like a fish on the dock,
my brother, the perch.
Fucking falling sickness.
Let the old man beat you
because he's sad...
he has his load on.
I did better in the orphanage,
if that fat-ass Mrs Anderson...
hadn't turned out a fucking pimp.
Anyways, how was the funeral?
- Did you carry on, disgrace yourself?
- No.
- Everyone was sad, I expect.
- But it was pretty, too.
Shut up.
Do you dye your hair?
Whatever will let us live...
as we are now.