( theme music playing )
Man:
HOLD IT, NOW KEEP
THE TENSION ON IT, BOYS!
GOT TO PULL
IT TO THE LEFT.
THAT'S IT!
( pigs squealing )
( barking )
WASH-EE.
EAT-EE.
HIS DOG
THEM EAT-EE TOO.
OR, EAT-EE HIM YOURSELF,
YOU LEERING HEATHEN.
( men chattering )
( urinating )
IS THIS FOR ME?
BROUGHT IT FOR YOU.
GET OUT.
POINTED THE GUN
AT HIM!
BOOM, SHOT HIM
RIGHT THERE!
THAT'S THE GUY
OVER THERE.
HIM AND WILD BILL
GOT THE GUY RIGHT
IN THE EYE.
YOU TOUCH THAT
HOTEL'S KITCHEN, SETH?
I'LL MEET YOU.
MEN LIKE MR. SETH BULLOCK
THERE RAISE THEIR CAMP UP.
YEAH, FELLA TO BE
PUT IN THAT BOX
MIGHT ARGUE WITH YOU,
REVEREND.
MR. BULLOCK
DID NOT DRAW FIRST.
AND I POINT TO HIS
COMMISSIONING ME
TO BUILD THE DEPARTED
A COFFIN
AND SEE TO HIS
CHRISTIAN BURIAL.
WELL, ANY IDEA
OF THE DEPARTED'S NAME?
IN HIS EFFECTS I FOUND
A LETTER ADDRESSED
TO TOM MASON.
WELL, I KNOW
A TOM MASON.
BUT THAT FELLER
KEEPING COOL IN THE CREEK,
THAT AIN'T HIM.
WHICH, HAVING PRAYED,
I DECIDED TO OPEN.
THE SENDER, MRS. WALTER
MASON WRITES,
"I'VE ASKED YOUR BROTHER NED
TO BEAR THIS TO YOU."
FROM WHICH I CONCLUDE
THE DEPARTED'S NAME IS NED.
NED MASON, HUH?
PERHAPS THE TOM MASON
YOU KNOW IS THE DEAD
MAN'S BROTHER?
IF HE IS IN CAMP
HE SHOULD BE NOTIFIED.
NO, I AIN'T
SEEN TOM AROUND.
COFFEE!
MORNING, AL.
I'D LIKE SOMEONE
TO TELL ME WHAT IN FUCK
IS GOING FORWARD
IN THIS CAMP?
TIM DRISCOLL'S
CHECKED OUT.
I CAN TELL YOU
THAT MUCH.
- LEFT YOUR HOTEL, HAS HE?
- MOVED TO WU'S PIGSTY.
- WHAT WAS THAT
SHOOTOUT ABOUT?
- AT SUN-UP?
- YEAH, FUCKING SUN-UP!
- FAR AS I HEARD, AL,
HICKOK AND ONE
OF THEM HARDWARE GUYS
YOU'RE RENTING TO,
THREW DOWN ON THE FELLA
BROUGHT WORD IN
OF THAT SQUAREHEAD
FAMILY'S MASSACRE.
SUSPECTED HE WAS
IN ON THE KILL.
WHAT'S IT TO HICKOK
OR THAT HARDWARE GUY
EITHER
HOW THEM SQUAREHEADS
COME TO DIE?
I COULDN'T AGREE
WITH YOU MORE.
( leg dragging )
IF YOU DON'T STOP DRAGGING
THAT FUCKING LEG...
COFFEE?
I MIGHT HAVE
ONE CUP.
DID YOU KNOW ONE
SQUAREHEAD LIVED?
LITTLE SQUAREHEAD GIRL.
THEY TOOK HER TO THE DOC'S.
- WHAT CONDITION?
- I DON'T KNOW, AL.
IF SHE WAS TO LIVE,
WOULDN'T SHE HAVE
A STORY TO TELL?
( snorts )
WAKE UP.
- HOW'S THAT LITTLE ONE?
- SHE'S STILL AMONG US.
I'M ASKING YOU WHAT
HER PROSPECTS ARE?
IF HER WOUNDS
DON'T FESTER,
SHE MIGHT CAN HAVE
A FIGHTING CHANCE.
GOOD.
NONE OF THAT
TO HIM.
OH, HE'S ALL RIGHT.
NOT A WORD.
- MORNING.
- MORNING, BULLOCK.
I WAS WONDERING
HOW THAT CHILD FARED.
IFFY.  TOUCH AND GO.
I'M NOT OPTIMISTIC.
HAS SHE SPOKEN?
SHE'S NOT CONSCIOUS.
BE SURPRISED
IF SHE EVER IS.
I'D LIKE TO HEAR
WHICHEVER WAY IT GOES.
IF YOU SEE BILL HICKOK,
OR THAT SORE ASSHOLE,
CHARLIE UTTER,
COULD YOU TELL HIM
I LOOKED TO THE STOCK?
SURE, I'LL LET HIM KNOW.
YOU'RE WRONG
NOT TO TRUST HIM.
HE FORMED A PARTY THAT
FOUND THAT LITTLE ONE
AMONG ALL THE DEAD
OF HER FAMILY.
DIDN'T HE?
AND DIDN'T HE ALSO
SHOOT A MAN HE SUSPECTED
IN THE MURDERS?
AND IF I WERE
TO CONFIDE IN HIM
WOULD HE
CIRCULATE MY OPTIMISM?
I MEAN, WOULDN'T HE SAY,
"WHEN THE LITTLE ONE SPEAKS,
YOU'LL SEE I WAS RIGHT.
NOT THE SIOUX
KILLED HER FAMILY,
BUT ROAD AGENTS"?
AND SUPPOSING
IT WAS ROAD AGENTS,
AND THEY HEAR HIS TALK,
WHERE'S THE LITTLE ONE
STAND THEN?
YOU GOT A DARK
TURN OF MIND.
I SEE AS MUCH MISERY
OUTTA THEM MOVING TO JUSTIFY
THEIRSELVES
AS THEM THAT SET OUT
TO DO HARM.
Charlie:
SAME DEAD ROACH
IN THE SAME DAMN BISCUIT.
HE STUCK TO
HIS POSITION.
- MORNING.
- MORNING, MONTANA.
YEAH.
- JOE?
- MUCH OBLIGED.
- YOUR FRIEND ASKED ME TO SAY
SHE'S LOOKED TO YOUR STOCK.
- THANKS.
SHE'S BACK NOW WATCHING
OVER THAT CHILD WE FOUND.
FAR AS HER CHANCES,
THE DOC'S NOT OPTIMISTIC.
FROM THE LOOK OF HIM,
THINK THAT DOC'S BEEN WRONG
ONCE OR TWICE IN HIS LIFE?
MAYBE ONCE
OR TWICE.
WE'LL LIKELY BE BY
YOUR TENT LATER.
GET BILL HERE OUTFITTED
WITH SOME PROSPECTING GEAR.
YES, SIR.
DON'T DO THAT,
CHARLIE.
- DO WHAT?
- TRUMPET MY INTENTIONS.
HERD ME LIKE
A DAMN STEER.
AIN'T YOU HERE
TO PROSPECT GOLD?
IF YOU'RE JUST GONNA GAMBLE,
BILL, LET'S GET IT SET.
I'LL ARRANGE APPEARANCE
MONEY FOR YOU.
THAT AIN'T GAMBLING.
IT'S SHILLING FOR THE HOUSE.
IT'S GETTING YOU A REGULAR
DAMN SOURCE OF INCOME.
SO'S THIS DON'T
WIND UP LIKE CHEYENNE.
WHAT OFFER SHOULD WE MAKE
AT THE PURCHASE OF THAT LOT?
BARBER NEXT TO US
PAID 600 FOR HIS LOT
10 DAYS AGO.
- SELLER'S MARKET.
- MM-HMM.
I'D SAY WE'RE
WELL BOUGHT AT 750,
WE DON'T GO PAST 1,000.
UH, MAY I, UM,
JOIN YOU?
WELL, MR. BULLOCK,
AFTER THE EVENTS
OF LAST NIGHT,
FOR AN INK-STAINED
WRETCH LIKE MYSELF
FINDING YOU
AND MR. HICKOK HERE
IN THE SAME DINING ROOM
IS LUCK INDEED.
I DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT
LAST NIGHT'S EVENTS.
ALL RIGHT,
FAIR ENOUGH.
I NOW POCKET
MY NOTEBOOK, SIR.
THE SAME WRETCHED
BISCUITS.
MRS. GARRET.
I HOPED YOU
SLEPT WELL.
AS IT HAPPENS,
I DID NOT.
I'M VERY SORRY.
DO YOU REQUIRE
THE DOCTOR?
YES.  PLEASE.
CERTAINLY, MA'AM,
OF COURSE.
SORRY YOU'RE
POORLY AGAIN.
THAT IS MRS. ALMA GARRET.
WHOSE HUSBAND,
I'M TOLD,
STANDING AT THE BAR
AT SWEARENGEN'S SALOON
PURCHASED A GOLD CLAIM
LAST NIGHT FOR $20,000.
WE RENT OUR LOT
FROM AL SWEARENGEN.
I'M NOT SURPRISED
TO HEAR IT.
TIM DRISCOLL,
THE CLAIM'S SELLER,
LIVES HERE
IN THIS HOTEL.
HE, UH...
MUST BE SLEEPING IN.
DO YOU MIND?
MORNING, BOYS!
- GOOD MORNING!
- ELLSWORTH.
NAME'S ELLSWORTH.
I HEAR YOU BOUGHT
THESE DIGS.
BROM GARRET,
HOW DO YOU DO?
MY CLAIM'S
NEXT ONE OVER.
I SEE.
YOU CLEANING UP
ANY YELLOW?
DAY'S YOUNG!
HOW ARE THINGS
RUNNING AT YOUR CLAIM?
MADE MY QUOTA FOR WHISKEY,
PUSSY AND FOOD.
THEN YOU BEST GET ON DOWN
TO THE GEM, ELLSWORTH.
FURTHER EFFORTS'LL ONLY
BENEFIT THE FARO DEALERS.
THIS EXACT SPOT SHOWED A FISTFUL
OF NUGGETS TWO NIGHTS AGO.
WELL, DON'T WEAKEN,
PILGRIM.
NUGGETS ARE NOTHING.
SHE'S USUALLY GONNA
SHOW YOU SOME FLAKE.
THANKS FOR
THE ENCOURAGING WORDS.
SHE HASN'T EVEN
SHOWED ME ANY FLAKE.
OH, HELL.
Johnny:
"WELL, I DOUBT THAT,
REVEREND," I SAY,
"THE TOM MASON I KNOW
IS NOWHERE NEAR HERE."
BUT WHAT I WAS THINKING
IS DAMNED IF AL DIDN'T
CENTER SHOOT THE BULL'S-EYE.
IT WASN'T SIOUX
KILLED THEM SQUAREHEADS.
BUT IT WAS
PERSIMMON PHIL,
TOM MASON AND THAT CROAKER
HEADED FOR HIS COFFIN.
WHO'S PROBABLY SOME
FUCK-UP YOUNGER BROTHER
OF TOM'S NAMED NED.
LISTEN TO ME,
GO GET DOC COCHRAN.
AND I NEVER TIPPED
THE THUMPER TO NONE OF IT, AL.
PLAYED IT DUMB
AS A PILE OF ROCKS.
GO GET THE DOC.
SAY I WANT HIM TO SEE
TO THE WHORES.
ALL RIGHT, AL.
'SCUSE ME, FELLA.
MR. SWEARENGEN.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
- SOL STAR.
- SETH BULLOCK.
RENT ON LOT FOUR.
LOT FOUR?
THE HARDWARE BOYS,
HMM?
HERE, I WANNA BUY YOU
FELLAS A DRINK.
HOW'S BUSINESS
ON THAT LOT?
HELL OF A SPOT,
ISN'T IT?
ANY MORE FOOT TRAFFIC
YOU'D HAVE TO CALL
IT A RIOT.
NOW, I'M TURNING
BACK SLOW.
NOTHING IN HAND
BUT THIS WHISKEY BOTTLE.
I HEARD YOU'RE NOT A MAN
I WANT MISTAKING
MY INTENTIONS.
WHO SAYS THAT?
I'D LIKE TO ASK 'EM
WHAT THEY MEAN.
- A FELLA DREW ON
SETH THIS MORNING.
- NEVER HEARD DIFFERENT.
NO ONE MISTOOK
HIS INTENTIONS.
LET'S LEAVE IT
ALL ALONE.
I AM STUPIDEST
WHEN I TRY TO BE FUNNY.
THERE YOU GO, FELLAS.
AND THESE ARE
STILL FREE.
SORRY FOR HITTING
A NERVE, HUH?
WE'D LIKE TO MAKE AN OFFER
ON THAT LOT WE'RE RENTING.
SELL MY BACK TEETH
FOR THE RIGHT MONEY.
WOULD 600
GET THE JOB DONE?
I GUESS BEFORE I MADE
A PRICE I'D WANT TO KNOW
IF YOU BOYS
- HAVE UNNAMED PARTNERS?
- WHY?
I THINK SPECIFICALLY
WILD BILL HICKOK.
DIDN'T YOU ACT TOGETHER
THIS MORNING?
WE JUST MET WILD BILL.
WHAT BUSINESS
OF THAT IS HIS?
YOU MEAN WHAT BUSINESS
OF MINE IS THAT?
DON'T TELL ME
WHAT THE FUCK I MEAN.
NOT A TONE
TO GET A DEAL DONE.
CAN WE SORT IT OUT
ANOTHER TIME?
THIRSTY PEOPLE COMING.
SURE.
YOU AND ME WILL FIND
OUR PROPER STRIDE.
- ALL RIGHT.
- GOOD LUCK ON
THE DAY'S TRADE.
WON'T WISH YOU LUCK.
I CAN TELL YOU AIN'T
THE TYPE THAT NEEDS IT,
SOL STAR, RIGHT?
THAT'S A JEWISH NAME.
- MINE ISN'T, BUT NICE
TO MEET YOU, SON.
- PLEASURE.
MARKED YOU
FOR AN EARNER THE MINUTE
YOU COME IN MY SIGHT.
JEW BASTARD.
AH, TWO WAYFARERS
WHEN I'D HEARD YOU WERE THREE.
HOW YOU DOING, AL?
SHALL WE ALL?
LET'S DRINK UPSTAIRS.
I CAN BE PERSUADED.
WILL YOU HAVE A WHORE,
TOM, OR YOU STILL STAYING
TRUE TO THAT HEIFER?
IT'S OVER
'TWEEN ME AND HER.
OLD TOMMY WENT SWEET
ON A BUFFALO DOWN
BY YANKTON.
WHERE'S BROTHER NEDDY,
ANYWAY?
FUCK IF I KNOW,
THAT FUCKER.
I'LL TAKE HER.
PICK ANOTHER.
I DON'T LIKE
THAT SON OF A BITCH.
THANK GOD YOU DIDN'T
LET HIM SEE IT.
CALLS ME
LOOSE WITH A GUN.
WAS HE THERE?
WE'LL JUST GET THE LOT
BOUGHT AND HAVE NOTHING
TO DO WITH HIM.
BUY THE LOT AND THEN
WE'LL GIVE HIM WIDE BERTH.
I'VE ACTED ON YOUR COMMISSION,
MR. BULLOCK.
- BUILT A COFFIN
AND DUG A GRAVE.
- THANK YOU.
WILL YOU JOIN ME,
NOW FOR THE BURIAL SERVICE?
Charlie:
ALL I WAS SAYING,
BILL,
IS TILL YOU START
YOUR PROSPECTING,
IF YOU'RE GONNA GAMBLE,
LET'S GET YOU PROTECTED
A LITTLE.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU WERE SAYING.
THE EXTRA BUSINESS
YOU BRING A JOINT,
INTERRUPTIONS YOU STAND FOR
OR FOLKS WANTING TO GLAD-HAND,
THAT ALL DESERVES
COMPENSATION.
DON'T SHOP ME
TO THOSE PLACES,
CHARLIE.
( knocking at door )
E.B. FARNUM,
GENTLEMEN.
MR. UTTER'S ROOM
IS READY.
CLEAN
AND THOROUGHLY AIRED.
THE PREVIOUS GUEST
WAS IRISH.
NO TIP NECESSARY, SIR.
I OPERATE THE HOTEL.
I'VE REPLENISHED
YOUR SUPPLY OF MEDICINE.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I'M VERY GRATEFUL
FOR YOUR ATTENTION.
I ONLY WISH MY SYMPTOMS
WOULD SUBSIDE.
IF I WERE TO TELL
YOU THAT I WOULD SEE
TO YOUR REQUIREMENTS,
WHETHER YOU HAD
SYMPTOMS OR NOT,
DO YOU SUPPOSE
THAT WOULD HELP
YOU TO HEAL?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
I BELIEVE YOU DO,
MADAM.
I BELIEVE WE
UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER.
THERE ARE PEOPLE
IN THIS CAMP
IN GENUINE NEED
OF MY ATTENTION.
MAKE THIS ADEQUATE
TO YOUR PURPOSES
FOR THE NEXT
SEVERAL DAYS.
WELL, THANK YOU,
DOCTOR.
( Tom moaning )
LISTEN TO TOM
CARRYING ON IN THERE.
BAD LUCK HE WASN'T
HERE YESTERDAY.
YEAH, WHAT'D WE MISS?
SQUAREHEAD FAMILY
I COULD'VE TIPPED YOU TO
- HEADING BACK TO MINNESOTA.
- WELL OFF?
WORTH STILL TRYING
TO CATCH, ARE THEY?
SIOUX ALREADY
CAUGHT UP WITH THEM.
DID THEM LAST NIGHT
ON THE ROAD TO SPEARFISH.
HEATHEN COCKSUCKERS.
SO WE MISSED A GOOD
SCORE THERE, DID WE?
KEEP LYING
AND I'LL MURDER YOU
IN THAT CHAIR.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENED, AL.
AND THIS IS THE GOD'S
HONEST TRUTH.
WE COME ON THAT FAMILY
BY ACCIDENT.
NOBODY WAS TRYING
TO HOLD OUT YOUR END
OR ANYTHING OF THE SORT.
OR TO CONCEAL
A GODDAMNED THING.
THAT'S YOUR END,
RIGHT THERE.
WEIGHED TO THE OUNCE.
MY PROBLEM WAS WE DIDN'T
CLEAR THIS WITH YOU.
AND YOU KNOW
HOW YOU GET, AL.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW
THAT YOURSELF.
BUT MY PROBLEM
WAS BRINGING UP
THE SUBJECT.
BUT, UH...
THAT'S ALL WEIGHED
OUT THERE.
YOU KNOW WHY I GET
HOW I GET?
YOU WANNA SEE OVER THE JOB,
YOU DON'T LIKE LOOSE ENDS.
- I APPRECIATE THAT.
- DON'T LIKE MESSES,
THINGS DONE HALF-ASS,
BAGS OF SHIT
LEFT TO HOLD.
THERE'S NO LOOSE ENDS,
I'LL GUARANTEE YOU.
'CAUSE I GOT A WHOLE
OPERATION HERE TO CONSIDER.
( moaning and pounding )
( chuckling )
LISTEN TO TOM.
ONE OF THE SQUAREHEADS
LIVED.
- NO.
- NO?
I'M SAYING THAT'S
PRETTY HARD TO BELIEVE.
I BELIEVE YOU,
BUT WE SEEN TO 'EM
PRETTY GOOD.
THEY BROUGHT IT TO CAMP.
IT'S AT THE SAWBONE'S.
IS IT TALKING?
CAN IT SPEAK ENGLISH?
WHEN WE WAS SEEING TO 'EM,
THEY WAS ALL SCREAMING
IN SQUAREHEAD.
WHERE'S NED MASON?
THAT'S A FUCKING STORY
RIGHT THERE, AL.
IF YOU KNEW
THE FUCKING PROBLEM.
WHEN IT COMES
THE SQUAREHEAD'S TIME,
HE SPOOKS
AND RUNS OFF.
TOM'S AND MY HANDS
AS FULL AS THEY WAS,
DOING WHAT WE
HAD TO DO,
SO GOD KNOWS WHERE
HE GOT OFF TO.
THAT'S YOUR CUT THERE.
THAT REFLECTS HE'S OUT.
- THERE'S NO CUT THERE-
- HE CAME HERE.
( sighs )
NO.
SAY NO AGAIN,
I'LL MURDER YOU
WHERE YOU SIT.
HE SWORE HE'D HEAD
TO CHEYENNE.
YEAH, BUT HERE'S CLOSER,
ISN'T IT?
ALL YOU COCKSUCKERS
GO FOR THE EASIEST CHANCE.
SO, WHERE IS HE NOW?
WHERE HE IS NOW IS HE
STIRS THE WHOLE CAMP UP
LAST NIGHT WITH
HIS MASSACRE STORY
TILL I'M GIVING LIQUOR
AWAY AND CUNT AT HALF PRICE
JUST TO KEEP
MY CROWD CONTROLLED.
PARTY MAKES UP
FROM NUTTALL'S TO RIDE
BACK OUT TO SPEARFISH.
WILD BILL HICKOK
AND THOSE TWO GUYS
WALKED PAST YOU DOWNSTAIRS
SAVE THE SQUAREHEAD KID,
TELL NED TO STICK AROUND
TILL THEY SEE WHAT THE KID
HAS TO SAY ABOUT HIM.
WILD BILL HICKOK?
AND NED THROWS DOWN.
AGAINST WILD BILL HICKOK?
AGAINST HICKOK
AND THIS OTHER COCKSUCKER
WHO DRAWS ALMOST AS FAST.
SO IT'S A TOSSUP
WHO BLEW NED'S HEAD OFF.
CHRIST, AL...
I'M REALLY
SORRY FOR THE BOTHER.
SO YOU LET NED RUN,
YOU LEAVE A SQUAREHEAD ALIVE
AND ME TO CLEAN UP
THE MESS AND THOSE ARE
THE ONLY LOOSE ENDS?
I WANT YOU
TO HAVE MY SHARE.
I SWEAR TO FUCKING
CHRIST, AL.
I DON'T WANT
YOUR FUCKING SHARE.
I DON'T WANT THAT KID
TELLING PEOPLE IN ENGLISH,
OR SQUAREHEAD
OR DRAWING PICTURES
IN THE SHIT WITH TWIGS
ABOUT HOW IT WASN'T INDIANS
THAT KILLED HER PEOPLE
BUT WHITES!
THIS CAMP COULD
BE UP FOR GRABS.
GOD KNOWS WHAT THESE
COCKSUCKERS ARE UP TO
OR WHAT I'M GONNA HAVE
TO DO ABOUT IT.
JUST WHEN I NEED TO KEEP
MY HEAD CLEAR
YOU GIVE ME THESE BAGS
OF SHIT TO HOLD!
I SHOULD CUT
YOUR FUCKING THROAT, PHIL!
PLEASE DON'T
CUT MY THROAT.
LET ME HELP YOU
STRAIGHTEN THIS OUT.
THAT SNATCH
IS BRANDED!
WHAT HAPPENED?
TIPPED OVER.
I'M HELPING HIM UP.
PUT YOUR IRON AWAY NOW, TOM.
NOT YET!
BRANDING AT THE FLAG!
- ( loud knocking )
- Johnny: DOC?
YOU'LL GET ME
IN DUTCH WITH AL!
JUST ANOTHER
DAMN MOMENT!
DON'T PUT ANY PRESSURE ON IT,
JUST LAY IT ON LIGHT.
IT LOOKS LIKE
I'M PRESSING,
I'M NOT.
I'M NOT PUTTING
ANY GODDAMNED PRESSURE!
THAT'S VERY GOOD.
Johnny:
DOC!
I GOTTA GO.
I EXPECT CARE FOR THEM
WHORE'S BUSINESS AREAS
IS A BIG DAMN PART
OF YOUR INCOME.
THIS IS WHAT
YOU WANT ME TO DO?
AH, YES.
AND DON'T
LET ANYONE IN.
BELIEVE ME, ANYONE TRIES
GETTING IN HERE
WHO'S NOT YOU IS GONNA BE
DAMN FUCKING SORRY.
ALL RIGHT.
I MAY NOT
LET YOU BACK.
OUR CHRIST,
AS HE WAS CRUCIFIED
ADDRESSED THE THIEF
WHO WAS HANGING BY HIS SIDE.
"VERILY I SAY
UNTO THEE, THIS DAY
SHALT THOU BE
WITH ME IN PARADISE."
YOUR WAYS ARE NOT
OUR WAYS, O LORD.
WE ABIDE THE JUST
AND THE UNJUST ALIKE
UNDER YOUR TEARLESS EYE.
TEARLESS NOT BECAUSE
YOU DO NOT SEE US,
BUT...
BECAUSE YOU SEE
WHAT WE ARE SO WELL.
LAMB OF GOD, WHO TAKEST
AWAY THE SIN OF THE WORLD,
SEND YOUR ANGELS TO WELCOME
THIS BODY INTO PARADISE.
LAMB OF GOD, WHO TAKEST AWAY
THE SIN OF THE WORLD,
GRANT THIS SOUL
ETERNAL REST.
AMEN.
THAT'S A REAL GENEROUS
PERSPECTIVE, REVEREND.
AND DON'T WE NEED ALL
THE GENEROSITY WE CAN GET?
THEY BUTT INTO
OTHER PEOPLE'S BUSINESS
AND MAKE THE BUSINESS
OF OTHERS THEIR OWN,
THESE BOUGHT-OUT
NO-GOOD COCKSUCKERS.
WHAT, HICKOK
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT?
FUCKING BIGSHOT
THAT HE IS.
BIG FUCKING SHOT
WHEN HE'S STANDING
IN FRONT OF YOU.
ONE IN HIS EAR
FROM BEHIND, I'D LIKE
TO SEE
- HOW FUCKING TOUGH HE WAS.
- THAT'S RIGHT.  COCKSUCKER.
- ( knocking )
- ANYWAY, REST HIS SOUL.
THAT'S ALL.
CONDOLENCES, TOM.
HE'S GONE, JOHNNY.
I DON'T THINK
YOU EVER DID MEET HIM.
AH, NO.
DOC'S HERE.
FUCK HICKOK!
AND WHAT HE DID
TO YOUR POOR BROTHER, HUH?
THIS IS FESTERED
BECAUSE YOU WON'T TAKE
A FLAME TO YOUR NEEDLE.
I DO, DOC, EVERY TIME
BEFORE I USE IT.
- STOP LYING.
- ANYWAYS, I'M QUITTING.
THEY SAY YOU'RE LOOKING
TO A LITTLE ONE, DOC.
- HOW'S THAT UNGUENT WORKING?
- IT'S NICE AND COOL
ON ME, DOC.
I'M TRYING JUST A LITTLE
BIT MORE LANOLIN IN IT.
HEY, GIVE ME
A DOLLOP OF THAT!
HOW'S THAT PUSSY
LOTION FEEL?
SHOULD I TRY
SOME ON MY ASS?
AL.
WILL SHE LIVE?
LET ME LOOK
AT YOUR BELLY.
Woman:
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU CARED, DOC.
WILL WHO LIVE, AL?
NORWEGIAN KID.
HOW MANY CHILDREN
YOU CARING FOR?
I'M NOT OPTIMISTIC.
I SEE.
WHERE ARE YOU
IN YOUR MOONS?
- 'BOUT TWO WEEKS ALONG.
- SHE SPEAK ENGLISH?
WHAT'S SHE GOTTA SAY
FOR HERSELF ANYWAY?
SHE HASN'T SAID A WORD
OR BEEN CONSCIOUS
FOR A SECOND.
OH, TOO BAD.
SHE COULD SETTLE
WHO KILLED HER PEOPLE,
ROAD AGENTS OR SIOUX.
I DON'T KNOW
NOTHING ABOUT THAT.
DOES THAT HURT?
- LITTLE BIT.
- IF SHE DOES SEE,
THAT'S THE POINT.
SHE COULD SETTLE IT.
I DOUBT SHE'LL
SETTLE ANYTHING.
I DOUBT WE'LL EVEN KNOW
WHAT LANGUAGE SHE SPOKE.
GIVE THESE GIRLS
A GOOD GOING OVER, DOC.
LOOK TO 'EM LIKE
THEY'RE YOUR OWN.
DON'T TELL ME MY JOB
OR HOW LONG TO DO IT IN.
I CAN SEE TO THEM
AND I CAN SEE TO THE WAY
I'M GODDAMNED ABLE,
AND THAT IS ALL I CAN
GODDAMNED DO!
OH, WHAT'S YOUR TIME
OF THE MONTH, HUH?
ARE YOU POORLY, DOC?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME,
I KNOW WHAT I AM.
WHAT I'M NOT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
DOC ASKED ME
TO SEE YOUR PATIENT.
WHAT FOR?
WHAT DO YOU
KNOW ABOUT IT?
WHO THE FUCK
ARE YOU?
HEY, DON'T YOU
FUCKING IGNORE ME!
YOU DON'T WANT
TO INTERFERE WITH ME.
- THINK I'M SCARED OF YOU?
- SURE YOU ARE.
IF I TAKE
A KNIFE TO YOU,
YOU'LL BE SCARED WORSE
AND A LONG TIME DYING.
I AIN'T SCARED
TO DIE.
OF NOBODY.
GET AWAY FROM HER!
LE-- LEAVE--
LEAVE THAT LITTLE
ONE ALONE!
- LEAVE HER ALONE!
- HELLO.
LEAVE HER!
LEAVE--
LEAVE HER ALONE,
YOU COCKSUCKER!
DO IT TO ME
IF YOU HAVE TO!
WHY WOULD
I DO IT TO YOU?
( sobbing )
DID YOU HURT HER?
NO.
NO, DOC.
BUT SHE'S BETTER
THAN YOU THOUGHT.
HER EYES ARE OPEN.
( sobbing )
I FELL APART.
I COULDN'T LOOK OUT
FOR THE LITTLE ONE.
FUCKER LOOKED AT ME
AND I FELL APART
IN FRONT OF HIM.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT THE FIRST.
NO, I'M NOT THE FIRST.
WHO SAID I WAS
THE FIRST?
YOU THINK HE'S
THE FUCKING FIRST?
I'VE BEEN FUCKED
PLENTY!
AND TOUGHER FUCKS
THAN HE WAS
AND LITTLER
THAN HER BY PLENTY!
THEY FUCKED ME PLENTY!
SO YOU CAN GO FUCK
YOURSELF!
( sobbing )
GO ON, HEAD OUT.
I'LL LOOK AFTER HER.
WAS HE A ROAD AGENT?
WAS HE AMONG THEM
THAT DID FOR HER FAMILY?
HE OWNS THE GEM SALOON.
THEN WHAT'S IT TO HIM
IF SHE CAN OPEN HER EYES?
YOU GO ON AHEAD.
DOES ROAD AGENTS
WORK FOR HIM?
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF HER.
I'M SORRY.
I APOLOGIZE.
YOU GOT NOTHING
TO APOLOGIZE FOR.
YOU GOTTA GIFT
FOR THIS.
YOU CARED
FOR HER REAL GOOD.
- DON'T BE MEAN.
- NO.
YOU GOT A GIFT.
E.B.:
MR. GARRET?
HOW WAS YOUR DAY
AT THE DIGS?
IT WAS A MIXED EXPERIENCE,
MR. FARNUM.
MY CLAIM RETAINS EVERY
BIT OF ITS PROMISE,
BUT I'M AFRAID
I'VE INJURED MY BACK.
ALL THAT TWISTING
AND TURNING.
IT'S WRENCHED AT LEAST
AND I FEEL WORSE.
I MAY NOT BE CUT OUT
FOR THIS SORT OF ACTIVITY.
OH, MANY AREN'T.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
PERHAPS I SHOULD RECONSIDER.
WHAT, SIR?
I REFER TO YOUR OFFER
ON MY GOLD CLAIM.
MY OFFER?
LAST NIGHT, MR. FARNUM,
BEFORE WITNESSES
AT THE GEM SALOON
YOU OFFERED 16,000.
I SEE.
I'M PREPARED
TO RECONSIDER.
I HAVE A CONFESSION
TO MAKE, MR. GARRET.
I HAVE A WEAKNESS
FOR SPIRITS.
YOU SAYING YOU WERE
DRUNK LAST NIGHT?
I MUST'VE BEEN, SIR.
I BLACK OUT AND NO MEMORY
AT ALL OF MY ACTIONS.
PLEASE IGNORE ANY OFFERS
MADE WHILE IN MY CONDITION.
AND YET YOU DIDN'T
SEEM DRUNK.
I SUPPOSE THAT'S WHY
I'M SUCH A DANGER TO MYSELF.
JESUS CHRIST ALMIGHTY, AL.
FAR AS THAT SEWER-MOUTH
FRIEND OF HICKOK'S
PLAYING NURSE,
YOU CAN TIP HER OVER
WITH A FEATHER.
BUT A LITTLE GIRL?
IT'S HARD
ON MY CONSCIOUS.
WE COULD LET HER SPREAD WORD
THAT FOLKS GOT ROAD AGENTS
TO FEAR MORE THAN INDIANS.
BREED MISTRUST, ONE WHITE
FOR ANOTHER
THROUGHOUT THE CAMP.
THAT'D BE ANOTHER OPTION.
IS HE READY?
TOM'S READY,
BUT HE'S AWFUL DRUNK.
I DON'T TRUST HIM
TO PULL IT OFF.
NOT A BANK JOB.
HE WALKS UP TO THE COCKSUCKER,
PUTS ONE IN HIS EAR.
HE KEEPS RUNNING
THAT MOUTH LIKE HE IS,
HICKOK AIN'T GONNA
LET HIM GET CLOSE ENOUGH.
- ( knocking at door )
- WHO IN FUCK IS IT?
THEM HARDWARE GUYS IS ASKING
FOR YOU DOWNSTAIRS.
TELL 'EM I'LL BE
FUCKING DOWN.
POUR COFFEE DOWN TOM,
'CAUSE HE IS GOING OUT
TONIGHT TO MURDER THAT
SON OF A BITCH.
WHERE DO YOU
AND ME STAND?
WE'RE ALL RIGHT.
WHAT ARE YOU
SUPPOSED TO DO?
NOTHING.
DON'T EVER SAY
NOTHING TO NO ONE.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU
CAN UNDERSTAND ME,
BUT IF YOU CAN,
DON'T SHOW IT.
( mumbling )
IF YOU GOTTA TALK,
TALK LIKE THAT.
( horse neighing )
Sol:
SEE IF THIS MAKES
SENSE TO YOU, SETH.
I DO THE TALKING.
FINE WITH ME.
SOME PEOPLE
DON'T GET ALONG.
THEY HAVE BUSINESS TO DO,
THEY FIND A WAY AROUND IT.
DON'T TALK TO ME
LIKE I'M FIVE.
- BOYS.
- EVENING.
SOL'S GOT MY PROXY.
ME AND HIM,
WE SHOULD TALK
WITHOUT YOU?
THAT'S WHAT IT MEANS.
WHAT'S YOUR PARTNER
SO MAD ABOUT ALL THE TIME?
- HE'S NOT MAD.
- HE'S GOT A MEAN WAY
OF BEING HAPPY.
FAR AS OFFERING
ON YOUR LOT,
WE'D PROBABLY
GO 750.
YOU'D PROBABLY GO
1,000.
SAY WE WOULD.
DOES 1,000 GET
IT DONE?
MY CONCERN, SOL.
YOU DON'T MIND
IF I CALL YOU SOL?
- PLEASE DO.
- MY CONCERN, ANYTHING CAN
HAPPEN UNDER A TENT.
A HARDWARE OPERATION CAN TURN
INTO A GAMBLING JOINT,
- AIN'T THAT RIGHT?
- THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
SELL TO YOU BOYS OUTRIGHT,
I COULD BE INSTALLING
MY OWN EVENTUL COMPETITION
IN A PRIME LOCATION,
WITH THE A NUMBER ONE
MAN KILLER IN THE WEST
HOLDING AN UNNAMED
PIECE OF THE ACTION.
WE MET HICKOK BY COINCIDENCE.
HE'S NOT AN UNNAMED PARTNER.
SO YOU SAY.
BUT A CAMP LIKE THIS,
NO LAW
OR ENFORCEABLE CONTRACT.
YOU GOTTA WATCH
A MAN A WHILE
TILL YOU SEE WHAT
HIS WORD COUNTS FOR.
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME COMPANY?
NO.
SAY WE VALUE THE LOT
AT 1,000,
YOU BOYS GIVE ME 500
AND WHATEVER YOU SHOULD
PUT THAT TENT TO
BETWEEN NOW
AND THE FIRST SNOW.
I'M IN FOR HALF THE NET.
COME OCTOBER,
WE FINISH THE DEAL KNOWING
EACH OTHER BETTER.
SETH WON'T ACCEPT IT,
MR. SWEARENGEN.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD
HIS PROXY.
JUST UP TO A POINT.
SEE, THAT AIN'T
MY SENSE OF PROXY.
THAT'S WHAT I'D WANT
THESE FEW MONTHS FOR
TILL WE AGREED
WHAT THINGS MEANT.
I'M TELLING YOU,
WE'RE A HARDWARE OPERATION.
YOU HEARD MY OFFER.
HE DIDN'T WANNA DRINK
AND HE DIDN'T WANNA FUCK.
ANYONE OR JUST YOU?
WE PAY 500 NOW.
HE GETS 50% OF OUR NET
TILL THE FIRST SNOW.
- THEN WE BUY OUT THE REST
OF HIS INTEREST.
- NO.
IT'S A GREAT LOCATION.
HE WANTS TO BE SURE
WE DON'T TURN TO GAMBLING
OR THAT HICKOK'S WITH US.
- I WON'T BE PARTNERS.
- WE WOULDN'T BE AFTER
OCTOBER.
I WON'T BE PARTNERS.
TRIXIE.
SEE, YOU GOT TRIXIE
ALL DISTRESSED.
- SHE WANTED
TO GIVE YOU A RIDE.
- 1,000, NOW!
IF ANYONE IN THAT TENT
OR THE BUILDING WE PUT UP
TURNS A PLAYING CARD,
OR POURS A DRINK,
OR OFFERS A WOMAN'S
SERVICES, YOU GET TITLE BACK
AND KEEP OUR MONEY.
WHAT MAKES YOU TALK TO ME
IN THAT TONE OF VOICE?
I'M MAKING
A COUNTER-OFFER.
YOU COME INTO CAMP,
RENT MY LOT,
WITHIN SIX HOURS,
YOU BLOW IN A GUY'S EYE
WITH WILD BILL HICKOK
BACKING YOUR PLAY.
NEXT DAY I'M SUPPOSED
TO SELL YOU THE LOT,
PUT YOU IN BUSINESS
WITHOUT ASKING WHO YOU ARE
OR WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE?
FAR AS WHAT HAPPENED
IN THE STREET
WITH BILL HICKOK
BEING INVOLVED,
THAT WAS A TURN
OF EVENTS.
A WHAT?
IT WAS A TURN
OF EVENTS.
OH, A TURN OF EVENTS.
YOUR PARTNER CALLS
IT A COINCIDENCE.
SO WHAT WITH THIS COINCIDENCE
AND TURN OF EVENTS
STARING ME IN THE FACE
AND FIVE OTHER THINGS
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE PAYING
ATTENTION TO,
I STILL MAKE YOU
A SENSIBLE PROPOSAL
AND YOU ANSWER
BY INSULTING ME
IN MY OWN JOINT.
SETH DIDN'T MEAN
TO INSULT YOU.
YOU DON'T KNOW
NOTHING ABOUT THIS.
YOU WEREN'T HERE,
YOU DON'T HAVE
HIS PROXY.
SO DO WHATEVER YOU PEOPLE
DO WHEN YOU'RE NOT RUNNING
YOUR MOUTHS OFF
OR CHEATING PEOPLE OUT
OF WHAT THEY EARN BY
CHRISTIAN WORK.
- YOU DON'T WANNA
BE TALKING THAT WAY.
- DON'T TELL ME HOW TO TALK
IN MY OWN FUCKING
PLACE!
AND HERE'S MY COUNTER-OFFER
TO YOUR COUNTER-OFFER.
GO FUCK YOURSELF!
COME HERE, SETH.
Sol:
SETH.
GET HIM AWAY
FROM ME.
MISTER.
THE BEST BATH
AND BLOWJOB YOU EVER HAD'S
NOT 12 STEPS
UP THEM STAIRS.
Trixie:
MISTER!
Brom:
I MAY AS WELL
CONFIDE IN YOU, ALMA.
OF COURSE.
I'M BEGINNING TO FEEL
WE'VE BEEN DUPED.
OUR GOLD CLAIM
MAY BE WORTHLESS.
I'M BEGINNING
TO THINK THAT EVEN
SWEARENGEN'S
NAME SHOULD BE ADDED
TO THE CONSPIRATORS' LIST.
- HOW DISAPPOINTED
YOU MUST BE.
- I KNOW.
I TOLD YOU I'D BELIEVED
I'D FOUND A FRIEND IN AL.
AS I NOW LOOK BACK,
AL NOT ONLY PRESIDED
THE SALE,
HE FACILITATED
MY INVOLVEMENT
AT EVERY TURN.
WELL, I SUPPOSE
A COMMUNITY SUCH AS THIS
ATTRACTS A CERTAIN
KIND OF MAN.
I'VE MENTIONED TO YOU
EXCHANGING HELLOS
WITH WILD BILL HICKOK
IN THE HOTEL HALLWAY?
YES, YOU SAID HE SEEMED
VERY FRIENDLY.
IN THE HALLWAY AND ON
THE STAIRS.
DO YOU SUPPOSE
WE MIGHT ENLIST HIM
TO OUR CAUSE?
DO YOU THINK THAT THAT'S
THE SORT OF THING HE DOES?
FOR A FEE, A PERCENTAGE
OF THE MONIES RECOVERED,
I'D SAY THAT'S
EXACTLY HIS LINE.
HMM.
I MAY WELL INCLUDE
THE NAME OF AL SWEARENGEN
WHEN WILD BILL
AND I CONFER.
Sol:
THIS CAMP IS
A GOING CONCERN.
WE COULD SECURE
OUR FUTURES HERE.
- HARDWARE COULD
JUST BE A START.
- CAMP NEEDS A BANK.
CAMP ALSO NEEDS A BANK
IS EXACTLY RIGHT.
SETH.
IF YOU SEE ALL
THESE POSSIBILITIES
WHY GET SIDETRACKED
BY THAT SALOON-KEEPER?
WE JUST WANNA
BUY HIS LOT.
WHAT ABOUT WHAT
HE CALLED YOU?
I BEEN CALLED
WORSE BY BETTER.
GET IT IN WRITING
FROM THAT SON
OF A BITCH.
WE BUY THE OTHER HALF
IN OCTOBER.
- JUST LEAVE IT TO ME.
- ( Charlie groaning )
( Urinating )
- EVENING.
BILL AND ME DIDN'T
MAKE IT TO YOUR TENT TODAY.
TOMORROW'S ANOTHER DAY.
PROSPECT.
HIS EXPRESS PURPOSE
COMING TO THIS CAMP.
MAKE A STAKE
FOR HIS NEW WIFE.
HIS IDEA.
DON'T SUGGEST
BUYING A SHOVEL
OR A SIFTING CRADLE.
HUH-UH.
( flatulence )
AH, UH-OH.
AH.
ANYWAYS,
HAVE A GOOD EVENING.
WHAT'S YOUR SECRET,
BULLOCK?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU GOT SOME
OF BILL'S QUALITIES
BUT THEN YOU GOT
SOMETHING HE'S MISSING.
GET ALONG WITH PEOPLE,
TURN A DOLLAR,
LOOK OUT FOR YOURSELF.
HE DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DO THAT.
YOU SEE WHAT I'M SAYING?
I LIKE TO KNOW YOUR SECRET
SO'S THEN I CAN TELL IT
TO BILL.
I DON'T KNOW
ANY SECRETS.
DON'T TELL ME
IF YOU DON'T WANT.
FIND OCCASION
AND TELL HIM YOURSELF.
HE LIKES YOU.
JUST DON'T
WAIT TOO LONG.
- HOW YOU FEEL?
- ONE MORE SHOT,
AND I'LL BE READY
TO TAKE THAT COCKSUCKER.
MAYBE ONE MORE CUP
OF COFFEE.
I'M OUT FOR A COUPLE.
GO GET YOU SOME
MORE AMMO WILD BILL.
THAT KINDA LOOKS
DOWN TO TURN.
- YOUR NAME'S JACK?
- YEAH, THAT'S CORRECT.
WHAT ARE YOU IN THE GAME
FOR, JACK?
WHAT AM I
IN IT FOR?
IF IRRITATING ME'S
THE JACKPOT, YOU'VE GOT
THE JOB DONE.
MONTANA.
- EVENING.
WHAT'D BE YOUR OPINION
FAR AS ME GETTING
ANOTHER 50?
YOU WANT ANOTHER 50
IN CREDIT?
Bill:
IF THAT'S ALL RIGHT
WITH YOU?
YEAH, I SUPPOSE SO.
- PLAY POKER?
- I'M NO GOOD AT IT.
YOU LET THAT
SLOW YOU DOWN?
FELLA IN THE FAR
CORNER TO YOUR RIGHT
INTENDS ME HARM.
WHEN HE MAKES HIS MOVE,
WOULD YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THE MAN WITH HIM?
YOU BET.
SEE THE FELLA'S I MEAN?
YES, I DO.
THANKS, MONTANA.
WOULDN'T WANT
THE WATER
GETTING NO DEEPER
THAN THIS, MR.HICKOK.
FAIR ENOUGH.
STAND AWAY
FROM ME, SOL.
DON'T BE TOO STUPID,
JACK.
I RESTORED
OUR BOSOMS!
- THEY THROW YOU OUT?
- NO, THEY DID NOT!
I LEFT ON MY OWN STAND.
I CHOOSE
TO BE OUT HERE.
WELL I WAS DRINKING DOWN
BY THE GODDAMNED CREEK
OUTTA MY OWN
FUCKING FREE WILL.
WHERE'S BILL?
INSIDE,
LOSING AT CARDS.
I'D GO GET HIM
BUT HE'D ACCUSE ME
OF HERDING HIM
LIKE A DAMN STEER.
SOMEONE I NEED
TO GO KILL.
WHAT, WHO?
YOU ARE NOT MY TARGET,
BUT KEEP BOTHERING ME
AND I'LL ADD YOU
TO THE LIST.
WHO WE TALKING
ABOUT, DAMN IT!?
GREASY-HAIRED
LIMEY COCKSUCKER
THAT RUNS
THE GEM SALOON.
WHAT THE HELL
YOU WANNA KILL HIM FOR?
FOR SHOWING ME
TWO DIFFERENT THINGS
BETWEEN THE COWARD
AND THE LAPSE
OF MOMENTARY FEAR.
LISTEN, JANE!
YOU LISTEN TO ME!
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I GUARAN-FUCKING-TEE
YOU HAVE AT THAT MAN
AND YOU WON'T COME OUT
OF THAT JOINT ALIVE.
NO!
THE SUN AIN'T ROSE
ON THE DAY I PAY HEED
TO WHAT YOU SAY!
( sobbing )
OH.
OH, WHAT IS THIS?
OH, OH.
HE SCARED ME,
CHARLIE.
I AIN'T BEEN SCARED
LIKE THAT
SINCE I WAS
A LITTLE GIRL.
OH.
OH, JESUS.
JANE, WHERE YOU GOING?
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, DOWN THERE
IS DOC COCHRAN'S OFFICE.
IF THAT LIMEY COCKSUCKER
COMES FOR THAT LITTLE GIRL,
I GOT HIM TRIANGULATED.
IF HE COMES FROM
THAT WAY I GOT HIM,
AND IF HE COMES
FROM THAT WAY...
I GOT HIM.
HERE I GO.
NO WORDS, AND NO GUN
TILL YOU'RE ON HIM.
HERE I GO.
REVENGE FOR MY
FUCKING BROTHER.
THE MAN'S GUN NEVER LEFT
HIS HOLSTER, MR. HICKOK.
HE MEANT ME HARM.
YOU KILLED MY BROTHER,
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
AND NOW I KILLED YOU.
HE WAS GOING
FOR HIS GUN.
- I SAW IT.
- Tom: A REVENGE SEEKER.
I GUESS HE DID
MEAN YOU HARM.
YOU'RE HALF FUCKING
BLIND, AIN'T YOU?
SOMETIMES IT'S
A FUCKING BLESSING.
WHAT THE FUCK
YOU LOOKING AT?
LIKE HE'S
A FUCKING ADONIS.
( knocking at door )
YOU GO ON AWAY FROM HERE
FOR A LITTLE WHILE, DOC.
- I WON'T.
- GO ON.
YOU GO SEE
ABOUT THE WHORES.
NO.
YOU KNOW I'LL COME
THROUGH YOU IF I HAVE TO.
LET ME REMIND YOU
OF SOMETHING, DAN.
IF YOU KILL ME...
THEN YOU ARE UP TO YOUR
ELBOWS IN SNATCHES,
JUST LIKE YOU WERE BEFORE
I CAME TO THIS DAMN CAMP.
TAKING CARE OF 'EM.
NURSING 'EM,
DAY IN, DAY OUT.
TAKING HEAT FROM AL
EVERY TIME ONE OF 'EM'S
POORLY.
UP TO YOUR ELBOWS.
BETWEEN THAT
AND A SLIT THROAT
THAT AL WILL GIVE ME
IF I LEAVE THAT CHILD ALIVE,
I THINK YOU KNOW WHICH ONE
I'M GONNA CHOOSE.
YOU JUST GO AHEAD
AND DO WHAT YOU'RE GONNA
DO 'CAUSE I'M NOT MOVING.
JESUS CHRIST.
YOU'RE PITTING ME
AGAINST AL.
SO THE FUCK BE IT.
WELL, I AIN'T
GOING IT ALONE.
YOU'RE COMING WITH ME
TO MAKE THE CASE.
JESUS CHRIST.
HAVE WE BEEN ASLEEP
AT THE SWITCH?
- WHAT'S WRONG?
- WHY'S HE GOT HIS ARM
ON THE DOC?
YOU WITH THAT UGLY FUCKER
OF YOUR OWN FREE WILL?
( whispers )
YES.  YES, I AM.
I'D RATHER BE LUCKY
THAN SMART.
WORD FOR WORD
WHAT THE HARDWARE GUY SAID.
- THE HARDWARE GUY?
- THE HARDWARE GUY.
DIDN'T YOU JUST TELL ME
THE HARDWARE GUY WAS STANDING
NEXT TO HICKOK?
THE HARDWARE GUY SAID
SOMETHING LIKE,
"HICKOK'S RIGHT.
HE WAS GOING FOR HIS GUN.
- I SAW HIM
GOING FOR IT."
- SOMETHING LIKE.
MY TOOTH WAS PAINING ME
SOMETHING AWFUL,
BUT I AM CERTAIN THAT
WAS THE GIST OF IT.
GET SOME DOPE
FROM JOHNNY.
Man:
THANKS AN AWFUL LOT,
MR. SWEARENGEN.
MY TOOTH'S ABOUT
BROUGHT ME TO MY KNEES.
TELL ME ONE THING.
WHEN THAT IDIOT MADE
HIS MOVE, DID HE TIP IT?
TOM DIDN'T
SAY BOO, AL.
HICKOK MUST'VE
JUST SMELLED HIM.
AL, YOU'RE NOT GONNA
BELIEVE WHAT HAPPENED.
WHAT?
LUNATIC THAT
RUNS WITH HICKOK
JUST ABSCONDED
WITH THAT CHILD.
MUST BE UNDER
HIS PROTECTION.
COME HERE.
YOU'RE SURE THAT GIRL DOESN'T
KNOW WHAT YOU LOOK LIKE?
AL, I'M CONFIDENT THAT GIRL
DON'T KNOW WHAT I LOOK LIKE.
BUT NO, I CAN'T GUARANTEE
THAT TO A MORE CERTAINTY.
I KNOW YOU GOT
YOUR WHOLE OPERATION HERE
YOU GOTTA CONSIDER.
AND YOU DON'T NEED
TO BE WORRIED
OR TROUBLED ABOUT THE--
WELL, AS FAR AS THAT GIRL
RECOGNIZING ME,
NO MATTER IF IT'S THE SLIMMEST
OF THE SLIM POSSIBILITIES.
SO WHAT YOU WANT ME TO DO?
YOU WANT ME
TO JUST STAY OUTTA CAMP
UNTIL YOU DEAL WITH ALL THIS?
WHY DON'T I DO THAT, AL?
HOW 'BOUT YOU HAVE JOHNNY
CHECK UNDER THE ROCK
AND I'LL PUT MESSAGES
UNDER THE ROCK.
AND THEN I'M GONNA
CHECK UNDER THE ROCK
EVERY DAY AND SEE IF YOU
WANNA SEND MESSAGES TO ME.
ERR ON THE SIDE
OF CAUTION?
THAT'S, UH--
IS THAT A PLAN?
ALL RIGHT.
HEY AL, THINK I GOT TIME
TO PUT MY BRAND
ON A LITTLE SNATCH
BEFORE I GO?
( groaning )
NO LOOSE ENDS NOW.
Al:
GET UP HERE!
BRING THE SLED.
( door slamming )
* ROW, ROW,
ROW YOUR BOAT *
* GENTLY DOWN
THE STREAM *
* MERRILY, MERRILY...
GOD DAMNIT!
* ROW, ROW,
ROW YOUR BOAT *
* GENTLY DOWN
THE STREAM *
- * MERRILY, MERRILY
- * ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT
- * LIFE IS BUT A DREAM
- * GENTLY DOWN THE STREAM...
( continue singing
in the round )
( female singing in creek )