( theme music playing )
( hawk cries )
( wind howling )
( arrow whistling )
( whinnying )
WHOA!
( groaning )
AH!
( speaking Sioux )
( hooting )
( groaning )
( shouting )
( both groaning )
( grunting )
MAY I SAY, DAN,
EVER SINCE I RESUMED
DRINKING ALCOHOL,
I CANNOT FOR
THE LIFE OF ME
FIGURE OUT WHY
I EVER GAVE IT UP.
- TAKES THE EDGE OFF
THE TOUGH ONES.
- OOH.
TAKES THE EDGE OFF.
WELL PUT.
AND MAY I SAY, DAN,
THAT I OFTEN FIND YOU
THE SOURCE OF MANY
WELL PUT AND WITTY THINGS
THAT YOU SAY.
THANKS.
THE HICKOK MURDER,
EXONERATION
OF THE COWARD McCALL,
STAIN ON THE ESCUTCHEON
OF THE CAMP.
DOC, LIBATION!
I WONDER IF HE THOUGHT
I SAID "LIVE PATIENT?"
( gasping )
COULDN'T GET IT UP.
GIVE HER
A DOLLAR TO WAIT.
BUT HE JUST KEEPS
GETTING SICKER.
SHUT UP!
COME TALK TO ME
AFTER, DOC.
MY BACK HURTS SO BAD.
( gasping )
WILL YOU KEEP
A GIRL COMPANY?
I WILL,
BUT I'M EXPENSIVE.
( laughing )
OH, I KNEW THAT
LOOKING AT YOU.
I'M JOANIE.
ELLSWORTH.
FIRST VISIT TO
THE BELLA UNION,
ELLSWORTH?
YES, MA'AM.
MY LEISURE TIME'S USUALLY
SPENT AT THE GEM.
WHAT FILLS THE REST
OF YOUR TIME?
WELL, MA'AM, I'VE GOT MYSELF
A WORKING GOLD CLAIM.
WELL, SIR,
IS THAT A DAMN FACT?
YES, MA'AM, A HELL OF
A WORKING GOLD CLAIM.
AND IF WE KNEW
EACH OTHER BETTER,
I WOULD THROW FUCKING
IN THERE SOMEWHERE.
IF YOU DID,
I WOULD TRY TO CATCH IT.
A WORKING, FUCKING
GOLD CLAIM, JOANIE.
AND THANK YOU FOR ALLOWING ME
MY FULL RANGE OF EXPRESSION.
- ELLSWORTH.
- WHAT?
DO YOU SHOOT CRAPS?
NO, I DON'T.
BUT I'M A LETHALLY
QUICK STUDY.
COME ON.
JOEY?
I'M SICK, BOSS.
I AIN'T RIGHT.
KEEP YOUR VOICE DOWN.
WALK THIS WAY.
I WOULD NEVER'VE
MADE NEBRASKA.
I GOT FEVER.
MY BACK'S HURT
SOMETHING AWFUL.
ALL RIGHT, SON, LAY UP
TILL YOU GET BETTER.
( coughs )
HERE'S THAT
LIST YOU GIVE ME.
YOU HOLD IT FOR AWHILE.
FELLA WHO COULD READ
SAID ONE OF THE ITEMS
WAS FOR SMALLPOX.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING SHOWING
THAT LIST AROUND?
WELL, WHEN I GOT
POORLY BY BUFFALO GAP
I WANTED TO SEE
IF I COULD FILL
THE LIST THERE.
THAT'S A BREACH
OF GODDAMNED TRUST!
HAVE I GOT SMALLPOX,
MR. TOLLIVER?
HOW DO I KNOW?
MAYBE YOU GOT YOURSELF
A DOSE.
NO, I-I WOULDN'T.
I'M VIRGIN.
THAT'S HOW COME
I JUMPED WHEN YOU TOLD
ABOUT NEBRASKA PUSSY.
ANYWAY, GO LAY UP.
JOEY DIDN'T
MAKE NEBRASKA?
COME DOWN WITH WHATEVER
AILED ANDY CRAMED.
I WONDER IF JOEY WAS
AFTER A REMEDY FOR ANDY?
MAYBE WITHOUT EVEN KNOWING.
AIN'T YOU CLEVER,
EDDIE?
WAS I BEING CLEVER?
I THOUGHT I WAS WORRYING
ABOUT THE PLAGUE.
WHY DON'T YOU CONCENTRATE
ON RUNNING IN THE BONES
ON JOANIE'S MARK?
A WELCOME DIVERSION.
WOMAN LIVES
IN YOUR FUCKING HOTEL,
BUT YOU CAN'T FIND
PRETEXT FOR PRESSING
THE OFFER ON HER CLAIM?
I CAN'T OUT FLANK
TRIXIE, AL.
THE WHORE GUARDS THAT
WIDOW LIKE A MOTHER HEN.
SHE'S DOSED HER
WITH OPIUM PRIMING HER
FOR YOUR APPROACH.
- BE THAT AS IT MAY--
- E.B., PUT THAT OFFER
IN YOUR POCKET.
- YOU KNOCK ON
THE WIDOW'S DOOR.
- BUT TRIXIE'LL ANSWER.
TRIXIE ANSWERS,
YOU TELL HER I WANT
TO TALK TO HER.
TRIXIE LEAVES,
YOU GAIN ENTRY,
BROACH THE SALE.
CAN YOU CIRCUMNAVIGATE
THE CHILD
- OR MUST I MAP
THAT FOR YOU, TOO?
- ( mumbles )
WHAT?
- ( knocking at door )
- NOTHING.
COME ON IN, DOC,
HIM AND ME ARE FINISHED.
DON'T PLAY THAT SHIT
WHERE YOU MAKE ME DRAG
YOUR WORDS OUTTA YOU.
DECLARE,
OR SHUT THE FUCK UP!
I SAID SOMETHING
STRANGE IS GOING ON
IN THAT HOTEL ROOM.
IT'S BAD WITH THAT
FELLA DOWNSTAIRS, AL.
PLAGUE, IS IT?
SMALLPOX.
WOULD LAND
IN MY JOINT.
YOURS WASN'T
THE FIRST.
NO DECEIT
TOO PROLONGED.
NO ERRAND
TOO DEMEANING.
GET OUTTA HERE!
NO REBUKE TOO VILE.
AL SWEARENGEN'S A CUE
AND FARNUM MERELY IS...
A BILLIARD BALL.
Man:
HOWDY.
SHIT!
QUAGMIRE OF PISS
AND BULLSHIT!
WHAT?
AL WANTS
TO SEE YOU, TRIXIE.
ALL RIGHT.
HE WANTS YOU
OVER THERE NOW.
I'LL BE THERE WHEN
I GET THERE, E.B.
HOW IS MRS. GARRET
ANYWAY?
HUNKY-DORY.
( moaning )
MY BOSS WANTS ME.
I'LL BE BACK
QUICK AS I CAN.
THIS PASSES.
ALL RIGHT.
PLACE YOUR BETS,
GENTLEMEN.
PLACE YOUR BETS.
NEW SHOOTER
COMING OUT!
THE WINNER'S SEVEN.
WHAT YOU HEAR
ON THAT VACCINE?
HE'S HAD A CASE
BREAK OUT AT HIS PLACE.
Cy:
LET'S GO TO THE CAGE,
OR SHALL THE THREE OF US
LEAP UP ON TABLES
AND SHOUT QUESTIONS
ACROSS THE ROOM?
WHAT ABOUT THE VACCINE?
THE BOY NEVER
MADE NEBRASKA.
- HE TOOK SICK.
- WHERE IS HE NOW?
- IN THE BACK HERE.
- HOW LONG HAS THAT BEEN?
YOU DON'T WANT
TO PURSUE THAT TONE.
YOU SAT ON NEWS,
NO ONE WENT AFTER THE MEDS,
NOW I'M ASKING THE DURATION.
AND I'M SAYING QUESTIONS
IN THAT TONE AND POINTING
YOUR FINGER AT ME WILL GET
YOU TOLD TO FUCK YOURSELF.
SHOW ME THE ROOM
WHERE THE BOY IS.
PLEASE, JOIN US.
( cheering )
HOW LONG THEY BEEN
PLAYING THIS WITHOUT ME?
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- IT'S LAUNDRY DAY, MADAM.
- I'VE COME
TO REPLACE THE LINEN.
- LEAVE IT AND GO.
ARE YOU ILL?
LEAVE THE ROOM.
OF COURSE.
( sighs )
( groaning )
- BREATHE.
- ( rasping )
WE SHOULD CHAT
THIS ALL OUT.
SURE.
WHY DON'T WE DO
SOMETHING TOGETHER?
US AND SEVERAL OTHERS?
YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
LIFT UP.
THERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT, LIE DOWN.
IF I HAD
THAT MUG ON ME,
I BELIEVE I'D CUT DOWN
GETTING TOLD
HOW BUTT FUCKING
UGLY I WAS
BY NOT STARING AT
FUCKING STRANGERS.
SORRY-LOOKING CABIN
EVEN IN THIS SHITHOLE CAMP!
PASSERS-THROUGH HAS
A RIGHT TO MAKE INQUIRIES?
A LEAVE-TAKER HAS IT.
( inhaling )
I CARRIED THAT
FUCKING CHILD!
NO, NOT IN MY BELLY, BUT
NONE OF THAT
FUCKING BLOOD IN ME.
FUCKING COCKSUCKER!
IT'S JANE CANARY CALLING
FOR DOC FUCKING COCHRAN!
YOU FUCKING
IN THERE?
I BELIEVE
I'LL FUCKING WAIT!
TRIXIE'S UPSTAIRS.
E.B.'S WAITING FOR YOU
IN THE KITCHEN.
QUIT DRINKING A FEW HOURS.
WE'RE HAVING A GET-TOGETHER.
WHOM DO YOU MEAN?
BUY SOME FUCKING FRUIT
OR THE LIKE, HUH?
I TOLD YOU SOMETHING
STRANGE WAS GOING ON.
ARE YOU PREPARED NOW
TO TELL ME WHAT IT IS?
IF THAT WIDOW WAS HIGH
I AM A MONKEY'S UNCLE.
HOW MUCH FRUIT?
HOW MANY'S A FUCKING
GET-TOGETHER?
NOW ONE THING I CAN
TELL YOU, JOHNNY...
RIGHT NOW AIN'T
A GOOD TIME TO ASK.
HI, AL.
YOU TOSS THE PLACE?
I KNOW WHAT'S
IN THIS ROOM.
HOW'S THE WIDOW?
YOU GIVING HER
THAT DOPE?
I GIVE IT
TO HER REGULAR.
AND SHE TAKES IT?
SHE GOES BEHIND
WHERE SHE DRESSES
TO SPARE THE CHILD SEEING.
WHEN SHE GOES BEHIND
WHERE SHE DRESSES TO SPARE
THE CHILD,
DO YOU SEE BILLOWS
OF DOPE SMOKE RISING?
SHE SAYS
SHE EATS IT.
- DOES SHE ACT HIGH TO YOU?
- I CAN'T BE SURE.
I NEVER SEEN
A RICH PERSON HIGH
BEFORE.
NEXT PIECE OF DOPE,
TRIXIE...
YOU GO BEHIND THE SCREEN
WITH THE WIDOW.
YOU WATCH HER
PUT IT IN HER MOUTH,
YOU WATCH HER SWALLOW.
AFTERWARDS, YOU LOOK
DOWN HER FUCKING YAP
AND YOU VERIFY
SHE'S GOT NOTHING
ABOVE OR BELOW
HER FUCKING TONGUE.
I'LL FIND
A GOOD REASON.
YOU BEING FUCKING
CLEVER WITH ME?
HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO DO THAT
AND NOT AROUSE
HER SUSPICION?
ONLY SUSPICION YOU
GOTTA WORRY ABOUT IS MINE
OF IF YOU'RE GIVING IT
TO HER AT ALL.
WHY WOULDN'T I?
I'D RATHER TRY TOUCHING
THE MOON THAN TAKE ON
A WHORE'S THINKING.
ONLY KNOW THIS, TRIXIE,
THAT WIDOW BETTER
BE MUDDLEHEADED
NEXT TIME FARNUM
SEES HER OR YOU PAY.
- CAN I GO BACK?
- PLEASE.
TRIXIE AND ME CHATTED
ON THE SUBJECT
- OF THE WIDOW
TAKING DOPE.
- I SEE.
- TRIXIE'S GONNA
MAKE SURE SHE DOES.
- GOOD.
YOU FIND PRETEXT
TO DETERMINE TRIXIE
AIN'T LYING.
OH.
( woman gasping )
DAMSEL IN DISTRESS.
WILL YOU WANT ME BACK
FOR THE GET-TOGETHER?
HOW THE FUCK COULD WE
DO IT WITHOUT YOU, E.B.?
TRUTH ISN'T
IN YOU.
MAKES TWO OF US.
DOLLY WAS WITH
THAT DRUMMER.
'FRAID HE GIVE
HER PLAGUE.
FUCKING PLAGUE!
* ROW, ROW, ROW
YOUR BOAT *
* GENTLY DOWN THE STEAM
* MERRILY, MERRILY,
MERRILY, MERRILY *
* LIFE IS BUT A DREAM
* MERRILY, MERRILY,
MERRILY, MERRILY *
* LIFE IS BUT A DREAM.
IT'S LOVELY.
VERY LOVELY.
I NEED YOU TO DO
SOMETHING FOR ME.
AND I KNOW YOU CAN.
WHEN FARNUM'S HERE,
SO WE CAN BUY YOU
TIME TO GET WELL
YOU HAVE TO FAKE
BEING HIGH.
* ROW, ROW,
ROW YOUR BOAT *
- * GENTLY DOWN
THE STEAM... *
- YOU CAN DO IT, ALMA.
LOOK AT ALL
THE PRACTICE YOU'VE HAD.
* MERRILY, MERRILY, MERRILY,
LIFE IS BUT A DREAM *
( shudders )
YOU BETTER HAVE A PAYING
DWARF UNDERNEATH YOU!
AM I DYING?
TURN OFF THE FUCKING WATER
AND TELL ME WHAT YOU DID.
- I KNOW YOU
DIDN'T FUCK HIM.
- NO.
YOU SUCK HIS PRICK?
HE DIDN'T WANT
TO SHOW IT TO ME TILL
HE HAD A HARD ON.
THAT'S WHAT YOU CALL
A MISTAKE OF YOUTH.
YOU MUG IT UP
WITH HIM?
- A LITTLE.
- FRENCH LOCK OR NORMAL?
NORMAL.
SO ANY HOOPLE-HEAD
WHO DRANK
FROM THE SAME GLASS
THIS GUY DID
WOULD HAVE AS MUCH RIGHT
TO SIT THERE WEEPING AS YOU,
EXCEPT I CAN'T KICK HIS ASS
AND SEND HIM OUT TO WORK.
MY MOM DIED OF IT
WHEN WE WAS COMING OUT.
AND THAT'S WHEN
DADDY GAVE US UP.
WELL, THAT SAD STORY
MAKES ME BELIEVE
MAYBE YOU WAS EXPOSED
AND AIN'T A CANDIDATE
FOR IT NO MORE.
STICK TO HAND JOBS
A DAY OR TWO IF YOU LIKE.
THESE SHEETS
NEED CLEANING.
I JUST PROVIDED
NEW LINENS.
AND NOW THEY GOT
SICK ON 'EM.
TAKE THOSE
TO THE CHINAMAN.
SHOW YOU WANT
A CLEAN EXCHANGE.
SAY, "FOR MR. FARNUM, WU.
SHEET FOR FARNUM."
- HELLO.
- HELLO, MR. STAR.
- MAY I HELP WITH
THOSE SHEETS?
- I GOT 'EM.
HOW IS MRS. GARRET?
- STILL NOT RECEIVING.
- YOU DO TELL HER I'VE ASKED
TO CALL?
ON COMMISSION
FOR MR. BULLOCK.
HOW'S BUSINESS
AT YOUR STORE?
BRISK.
OH.
JESUS CHRIST!
YOU JUST SHIT
YOURSELF!
I TAKE IT YOU'VE BEEN
OUT ON A HOOT.
I'VE BEEN DRUNK
AWHILE, CORRECT.
WHAT THE FUCK
IS THAT TO YOU?
QUESTION WAS WELL MEANT,
LIKE IF YOU WAS
A FARMER I WOULD ASK YOU
HOW THE FARMING WAS GOING.
I DID LOSE MY FUCKING
BEST FRIEND, YOU KNOW?
I KNOW.
ANYWAYS, I AIN'T HERE
TO TEACH YOU ANY MANNERS.
I WAS WONDERING
ABOUT THE CHILD.
SHE'S FINE.
AND WHAT ELSE?
AND SHE'S STAYING
WITH THAT WIDOW,
AND THE WHORE FROM THE GEM
IS WITH HER, TOO.
WHAT THE FUCK IS A WHORE
DOING WITH HER?
THE WIDOW HAS HEALTH
PROBLEMS OF HER OWN.
AND TRIXIE'S
TAKING CARE OF HER.
TRIXIE BEING
THE FUCKING WHORE?
YOU HAVE HIGH STANDARDS
AS APPLIED TO OTHER PEOPLE.
I AIN'T JUDGING ANYONE.
I WAS SEEKING INFORMATION!
WELL, ARE YOU
ADEQUATELY INFORMED?
YES, I AM,
YOU COCKSUCKER!
'CAUSE I AM
IN THE MIDST
OF A SITUATION.
OH, SMALLPOX?
WHAT THE FUCK
IS THAT TO YOU?
FELLA IN THE WOODS I SEE
TO SAY HELLO TO HAS IT.
UNLESS HE CAUGHT IT
FROM A TROUT.
I FIGURED SOME IN THE CAMP
COULD BE DOWN WITH IT, TOO.
WHAT WAS HE DOING
IN THE WOODS?
SOMEONE THREW HIM THERE.
ANYWAYS, HE'S BETTER NOW.
AND HOW DO
YOU FEEL?
WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- HOW DO YOU FEEL?
- WHY?
I TAKE IT THAT YOU'RE
FEELING WELL.
- AM I WRONG?
- NO, YOU'RE NOT
FUCKING WRONG!
THAT'S ALL I WANTED
TO FUCKING KNOW!
I WILL LAY YOU OUT
AS SOON AS LOOK AT YOU!
THIS IS MY POINT.
YOU BEEN CARING
FOR A SICK MAN
WHO DOESN'T SEEM
TO HAVE GOTTEN YOU SICK.
AREN'T YOU A WISE
FUCKING OWL?
BEING AS YOU HAVE
A GIFT FOR IT,
AND I'M GONNA HAVE
SICK PEOPLE UP TO MY HIPS,
I WAS WONDERING IF YOU MIGHT
WANNA COME BACK TO CAMP.
MY BEST FRIEND DIED.
AND HE AIN'T
COMING BACK!
NOW WILL YOU
HELP ME?
YOU CAN DO YOUR DRINKING
OFF WORK, LIKE I DO.
E.B.:
MADAM?
YES?
HOW ARE YOU?
BETTER, MR. FARNUM.
THANK YOU.
I'M GLAD.
HOW ARE YOU?
VERY WELL,
THANK YOU.
EXCUSE ME.
- I BROUGHT MORE LINENS.
- HMM.
I'D HEARD
SOMEONE THREW UP.
( sighs )
WELL, APPEARS
LUCK PINCHES OUT
AT THIS GAME EVEN
QUICKER THAN PROSPECTING.
IT CAN COME BACK
THAT QUICK, TOO.
NEVER WEAKEN,
SAME AS AT THE CREEK.
YOU WANT TO STOP FOR
A WHILE, ELLSWORTH?
WE CAN STOP.
OH, WHAT IF
MY LUCK COMES BACK?
WON'T BE HERE
TO REAP THE BENEFITS.
Joanie:
WELL, MAYBE IT'LL
A WAIT FOR YA.
OF COURSE, TOO,
MAYBE IT WON'T,
RIGHT, JOANIE?
MAYBE YOU SHOULD STOP
FOR AWHILE, HONEY.
YOU NEED TO PISS?
EXCUSE ME.
DID I SAY THAT
TOO POLITE, CY?
GO HEAD OFF NOW.
Cy:
EDDIE, TAKE OVER
THE GAME.
PUSH THEM BONES
MY WAY, WILL YA?
PLACE YOUR BETS, GENTLEMEN.
PLACE YOUR BETS.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S WARM
THE WORLD BACK UP NOW.
Eddie:
NEW SHOOTER COMING OUT.
SEVEN, THE WINNER.
THE WINNER IS SEVEN.
YOU SURE YOU DON'T WANT
TO GET ON ME, YOUNG MAN?
WELL, I MIGHT
HAZARD A 20.
ALL RIGHT, NOW!
DO NOT DETAIN ME.
Eddie:
SEVEN, THE WINNER
IS SEVEN.
HOT SHOOTER!
YOU CAN'T KEEP
AN OLD MAN DOWN!
WAGONS,
WESTWARD BOUND!
- IT'S A SEVEN.
- YOU BETTER GET
ON ME NOW.
I GOT A MEETING TO GO TO
AND I GOT A HOT HAND HERE!
HAH!
MONEY'S OUT FRONT,
HONEY.
OKAY.
SPOTS ARE COMING OUT
ALL OVER HIS BODY.
THAT DON'T DECIDE
HOW IT ENDS.
JOEY WAS CHERRY.
I KNOW.
HE DIDN'T WANT US
TO DO IT TILL HE KNEW HOW.
YOU'D DO BETTER
IF THE TRICKS
DIDN'T THINK LOOKING
AT 'EM MADE YOU CRY.
WHOA, NOW.
IT'S JOHNNY BURNS,
REVEREND.
MR. BURNS.
- HOW ARE YOU?
- THERE'S A MEETING
AT THE GEM.
MR. SWEARENGEN THOUGHT
YOU'D WANNA COME, TOO.
AT HIS SALOON?
YES, SIR.
MAY I ASK
THE MEETING'S PURPOSE?
WELL, HE DON'T GET
INTO THAT WITH ME.
ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU.
TELL MR. SWEARENGEN
I WILL BE THERE.
HE'S HAVING ME
GET FRUIT.
I KNOW THAT MUCH.
FINE.
THE THREE RED HANDS
ON THE PONY'S FLANK
WAS THREE MEN KILLED
HAND TO HAND.
THE RED CIRCLE WAS
ONE KILLED ON HORSEBACK.
THE WHITE LINES
ON THE PONY'S LEGS
WAS TIMES THAT HE'S
A'COUNTED COUP.
WITH THEM, WHETHER
YOU MEAN TO KILL YOUR MAN
AFTER OR YOU'RE JUST
SHOWING OFF,
YOU HIT 'EM WITH A GUN BUTT
OR A STICK OR A CLUB.
THAT'S COUNTING COUP.
THAT'S WHY HE COME
FOR YOU INSTEAD OF
PICKING YOU OFF WITH AN ARROW,
LIKE HE DID YOUR HORSE.
CHARLIE.
AH, THERE YOU ARE.
THAT WAS ONE BAD HOMBRE
YOU GOT BY BULLOCK.
BILL'S DEAD,
CHARLIE.
OF YOUR OWN SEEING?
YEAH.
I HEARD IT SPOKE OF
TWO DAYS AGO,
BUT AS OFTEN
AS HE WASN'T BEFORE,
I HOPED HE WASN'T
THIS TIME, TOO.
I WAS AFTER
THE BASTARD WHO DID IT.
ANYTHING BROKE?
NO.
CAN YOU RIDE?
YEAH.
LET'S GET
THAT COCKSUCKER.
WE SHOULD
DIG A GRAVE.
I'D AS SOON NOT WASTE
THE FUCKING TIME.
IT WON'T TAKE LONG.
YOU AIN'T DOING
HIM NO FAVOR.
I MEAN HIS WAY
TO HEAVEN'S ABOVE GROUND
AND LOOKING WEST!
WELL, LET'S
DO THAT, THEN.
DON'T YOU WANT TO TAKE
HIM OVER THE RIDGE?
THIS HOLE IN THE GROUND
AND PUT HIM UP THERE WITH
HIS HEADLESS BUDDY?
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT YOU
NEARLY GOT KILLED FOR.
INTERFERING WITH HIS
BIG FUCKING MEDICINE,
BURYING HIS FUCKING BUDDY
OVER THE FUCKING RIDGE!
TRIXIE DID HER WORK
AND THEN SOME, AL.
MUST'VE PUT A DOUBLE
HANDFUL OF THAT DOPE
DOWN THE WIDOW'S MOUTH.
DID YOU HAPPEN TO OFFER
ON HER GOLD CLAIM?
THE MOMENT WAS WRONG.
THE DOPE HAD MADE
THE WIDOW RANDY.
LUSTFUL LOOKS,
HEAVY BREATHING.
OUTTHRUST CHEST.
THE FULL CATALOG.
ONLY HOPE YOU COMPORTED
YOURSELF AS A GENTLEMEN.
THERE WAS A CHILD
IN THE ROOM.
PEACHES AND PEARS
ON THE FUCKING BAR.
SPOON IT OUT AMONGST
YOURSELVES.
FIRST THING TO SAY IS...
PLAGUE'S IN
THE FUCKING CAMP.
SMALLPOX.
PLAGUE IS SPREAD
BY RATS.
Al:
I WAS RAISED
CALLING IT PLAGUE
BUT DOC WANTS
THAT IN RESERVE
IN CASE OUR LUCK HOLDS
AND THE RATS DECIDE
TO DESCEND ON US,
TOO, HMM?
- ( laughing )
- BUT WHATEVER YOU
FUCKING CALL IT,
THE POINT IS FOR
NO ONE TO RAISE
THEIR FUCKING DRESSES
OVER THEIR HEADS.
YOU-- YOU WAIT
IT OUT.
YOU OUTLAST
THE COCKSUCKER.
I'VE OUTLASTED SEVERAL
FUCKING OUTBREAKS.
IS IT PRETTY?
NO, BUT IT PASSES.
SO, WE NEED A PLACE
FOR THEM TO GET IT.
TO CARE FOR 'EM
AND TO KEEP 'EM OUTTA SIGHT
SO PEOPLE DON'T GET
FRIGHTENED AND DISGUSTED.
MR. BULLOCK AND ME
HAVE LUMBER LEFT
FROM PUTTING
OUR BUILDING UP.
TENT'S A BETTER
IMPRESSION.
EMPHASIZES IT'S
A PASSING PHASE.
AS FAR AS A VACCINE,
ONE PLACE WE KNOW HAS IT
IS FORT CARNEY.
HOW DO WE KNOW THAT?
OFF THE FUCKING ISSUE,
TOM.
Doc:
BISMARCK
AND CHEYENNE
PROBABLY GOT IT, TOO.
SO WE SHOULD SEND
TO ALL THREE PLACES.
AND AS TIME'S A FACTOR,
STAGECOACHES AIN'T
THE RIGHT CONVEYANCE,
SO I SUGGEST THREE GROUPS
OF HORSEMEN, HUH?
FIVE RIDERS TO A GROUP,
FEND OFF THE DIRT WORSHIPERS.
60 BUCKS A RIDER,
$10 IN ADVANCE, 50 ON RETURN.
E.B.:
WOULD BE THREE TIMES
FIVE TIMES 60.
$900 AT THE WORST.
ASSUMING THEY
ALL SURVIVE.
Al:
ADD IN, FOR THE VACCINE
AND PAYING THE DOC,
I WOULD SAY $1,500
IS THE TARGET.
I'M IN FOR FIVE.
- Cy: 500.
- A.W.: TWO.
- TWO.
- YOU FUCKING
KIDDING ME, E.B.?
150.
50 FROM
BULLOCK AND STAR.
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
E.B.:
150 HITS THE TARGET.
I ASSUME THEY'LL BE
A PUBLIC ANNOUNCEMENT
IN "THE PIONEER."
YEAH, GET A JUMP ON
THEM PANIC-MONGERS.
CAN YOU GIVE ME
FIVE MINUTES, DOC,
AFTER THE MEETING
ADJOURNS?
GIVE SOME
POSITIVE ANGLE TO IT.
VACCINE'S ON IT'S WAY
OR LOOKS LIKE IT'S
THE MILD TYPE.
IT WOULD ALSO BE USEFUL
TO AVOID APOCALYPTIC
PREDICTIONS.
NIP THAT SODOM
AND GOMORRAH SHIT
IN THE BUD, HUH?
AND STIGMATIZING
THE AFFLICTED.
WHERE WILL WE LOCATE
THE PEST TENT?
I BOUGHT A LOT AT THE END
OF CHINK'S ALLEY YOU CAN USE.
GONNA BUILD A JOINT
IN FUTURE, CATERING
TO THE CELESTIALS, AIN'T YOU?
YOU CLEVER COCKSUCKER.
THEY ARE THE FUCKING
DEGENERATE GAMBLERS
AMONG ALL THE RACES.
I'LL SEE TO RECRUITING
THE RIDERS.
Al:
$10 A RIDER ADVANCED MONEY.
IF I CAN GET
YOUR JOHN HANCOCK
FOR THE RECEIPT
OF THE 150...
Al:
FRUIT'S UP HERE,
ANYBODY DIDN'T GET ANY.
( groaning )
OH, FOR CHRISSAKE.
Doc:
ALL RIGHT, REVEREND.
SOMEBODY GET ME SOMETHING
TO HOLD HIS JAW OPEN.
HERE YOU GO, DOC.
FRUIT SPOON, DOC.
NOT A FUCKING
METAL SPOON, JOHNNY!
HE'LL BREAK EVERY
TOOTH IN HIS MOUTH.
HERE YOU GO, DOC.
DOC, I WON'T SAY
IT'S PRISTINE.
ALL RIGHT, REVEREND.
YOU'RE DOING BETTER,
REVEREND.
YOU EVER SEE HIM
DO THAT?
Doc:
HE'S ALL RIGHT.
USED TO HAVE A FUCKING
BROTHER GIVEN TO THAT.
WE'D MAKE
PENNIES OFF IT
WHEN IT'D COME
OVER HIM IN THE STREET.
HEY, REVEREND,
YOU COULD'VE
JUST SAID "AMEN."
QUITE THE CIVIC FIGURE,
CY.
THAT'S ME, THAT'S
WHAT I LIVE FOR.
HOW HEALTHY WE LEAVE
THAT PROSPECTOR?
HE'LL BE BACK.
FUCKING JOANIE.
GOT A CRACK
OUT OF TURN.
YOU STILL GOT AN AWFUL
SMOOTH HAND, YOUNG MAN.
YEAH.
PRACTICE MAKES
PERFECT, HUH?
YEAH, CY.
AND YOU GIVE A GOOD
HAND JOB YOURSELF.
FIND OUT FROM JOANIE
HOW EXPOSED THAT REDHEAD GOT
TO THE KID.
ANYTHING ELSE YOU WANT ME
TO ASK YOU HER FOR YOU?
EDDIE, IF I TALK
TO HER RIGHT NOW,
I'LL BREAK HER
FUCKING JAW.
AND IF WE KEEP TALKING,
I'LL BREAK YOURS, TOO.
I TAKE IT I SUFFERED
SOME SORT OF CONVULSION
OR SEIZURE.
PERHAPS BROUGHT ON
BY IRREGULAR HOURS.
OH, I SEE.
I SUSPECT YOU WILL
SOON BE HANGING UP
YOUR SHINGLE IN
COMPETITION WITH ME?
- NO, OH NO, NO, SIR.
- MM.
HOW DID YOU FEEL BEFORE
THE SPELL COME ON YOU?
I NOTICED A PECULIAR
SMELL IN THE AIR,
AS IF SOMETHING
WERE BURNING.
IS THIS FIRST TIME?
NO, THE FIRST EPISODE
OCCURRED SEVERAL DAYS AGO.
AFTER THE SERVICE
FOR MR. HICKOK.
AND ANY OTHERS BETWEEN
THAT ONE AND THIS?
NO.
FOLLOW MY FINGER.
HMM, PERHAPS
I JUST NEED GLASSES.
MERRICK NEEDS TO SEE
YOU ABOUT THE ARTICLE.
PRESCRIBE THIS MALINGERER
A CAN OF PEACHES
AND SHOW HIM
THE FUCKING DOOR.
AM I CLEAR TO ASSIST YOU
TO TEND TO THE SICK?
YOU ARE CLEARED,
REVEREND.
WHAT THE FUCK'S
WRONG WITH YOU?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU BETTER FIGURE IT
THE FUCK OUT.
'CAUSE THIS FREE-RIDE
SHIT'S COMING TO A QUICK
FUCKING HALT.
FREE RIDE?
WHAT WOULD
YOU CALL IT?
I EARN MY WAY.
( laughing )
HOW?
POSING IN EXPENSIVE DRESSES
AND BREAKING UP CATFIGHTS?
TAKING TROUBLE
TO STEER THE TRADE?
THAT DON'T PAY
THE FREIGHT, HONEY.
YOU'RE HERE TO CREATE
A FUCKING ATMOSPHERE.
FUCKING ATMOSPHERE YOU
CREATE LATELY, "I'M SAD."
THEN ON YOUR BAD DAYS,
"OH, I'M SO SAD."
OH.
WHAT IS IT,
SWEETHEART?
I GUESS
IT'S COMING HERE.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH COMING HERE?
YOU NEVER LIKED
THE RIVER THAT MUCH.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH
A FRESH START?
HOW IT FEELS WHEN
THERE ISN'T ONE.
WELL, SHIT.
STAY HERE, I'LL BRING
YOU BACK A FUCKING
LOLLIPOP.
SORRY I CRACKED
ON YOUR PLAY WITH
THE PROSPECTOR.
ME AND EDDIE TURNED IT
INTO A LONGER CAMPAIGN.
IF HE DON'T GET PLAGUE,
IT'LL ALL HAVE A HAPPY END.
MY WORRY'S YOU.
AND MY CONCERN'S
FEELINGS OF FUCKING
AFFECTION.
SHUT UP, CY.
WORK ON BELIEVING IT,
JOANIE.
THAT'S THE WAY
I ALWAYS WANT TO TOUCH YOU,
JUST LIKE THAT.
DON'T MAKE ME
DO IT DIFFERENT.
A.W.:
"TWO CASES OF THE SMALLPOX
HAVE BEEN DIAGNOSED IN OUR CAMP
BY DOCTOR AMOS COCHRAN."
HEY, DOC!
GET THE AMOS
OUTTA THERE!
SCRATCH AMOS.
"AT DR. COCHRAN'S SUGGESTION,
A PEST TENT,
ENDOWED BY THE GENEROUS
RETAILERS OF OUR FINE
COMMUNITY,
IS BEING ERECTED
FOR THE AFFLICTED
ON THE SOUTH END,
AND RIDERS DISPATCHED
TO SECURE A VACCINE."
MAYBE YOU
SHOULD ADD THERE,
"THEY'RE ALREADY PROBABLY
ON THEIR WAY BACK."
EXCUSE ME.
"'THE PIONEER' HAS BEEN ASSURED
OF THEIR IMMINENT RETURN."
THAT'S CATCHIER.
"THANKS ALSO TO
THE AFOREMENTIONED MERCHANTS,
THE VACCINE WILL BE
DISTRIBUTED GRATIS."
FREE GRATIS.
FREE GRATIS
IS A REDUNDANCY.
DOES THAT MEAN
REPEATS ITSELF?
THEN LEAVE GRATIS OUT.
WHAT LUCK FOR ME, AL,
THAT YOU HAVE
SUCH A KEEN
EDITORIAL SENSE.
FREE.
DISTRIBUTED FREE.
PERIOD.
IT WILL TAKE ME SOME
TIME TO RESET THE TYPE.
YEAH, HURRY UP.
EXCUSE ME.
AL.
THANKS FOR NOT PUTTING
THE STINK ON ME BEFORE
WITH THE OTHERS
OVER THAT FORT CARNEY
BUSINESS.
SURE.
I'M BACK.
YOUR ROOM HAS
BEEN RE-RENTED!
FUCK YOU AND FUCK
THE ROOMS YOU RENT.
I'M CALLING ON
THE WIDOW AND THE LITTLE
ONE IN HER CARE.
AND IF I WAS YOU,
OR ANY COCKSUCKER WITH YOU,
I WOULDN'T
TRY TO STOP ME.
- BE BRIEF.
- BE FUCKED!
HER GUTTER MOUTH
AND THE WIDOW IN
AN OPIUM STUPOR.
A CONVERSATION
FOR THE AGES.
HEY, FUCK-NUT!
WHAT YOU GOT
IN THAT SUITCASE?
MILLINERY SAMPLES.
IF IT CONCERNS
YOU AT ALL.
MILLINERY SAMPLES,
AIN'T THAT JUST PERFECT!
SOME WOMEN...
TAKE THE TROUBLE TO MAKE
A DECENT APPEARANCE.
WELL, FOR YOUR
INFORMATION, MR. MILLINERY-
SAMPLE-SUITCASE COCKSUCKER,
YOU'RE STAYING IN
THE FORMER ROOM OF SOMEONE
YOU AIN'T FIT
TO LICK THE BOOTS OF!
WILD BILL HICKOK.
I PAID $2
A DAY EXTRA.
HAD YOU ANY CONNECTION
TO WILD BILL?
GOOD LUCK WITH YOUR
FUCKING DAY SELLING HATS.
IT'S JANE!
OH MY GOD.
HELLO, JANE.
LOOK AT YOU.
LISTEN TO YOU.
OH MY GOD IN HEAVEN.
I'M TRIXIE.
I THINK I'VE SEEN YOU.
AT THE GEM.
YEAH.
MAYBE THAT'S WHERE.
YOU LOOK LIKE SHIT.
OH, OWE YOU A PENNY.
I'M BETTER.
I WAS SO SORRY TO HEAR
ABOUT MR. HICKOK.
YEAH.
YOU OUGHTTA GET
YOUR HUSBAND OUTTA
THAT CREEK.
AS SOON AS I FEEL
JUST A LITTLE BETTER.
ANYWAYS, I'M GLAD
TO SEE THIS LITTLE ONE
IN GOOD CONDITION
AND TALKING, TO BOOT.
COME SEE HER
ALL THE TIME.
NAH, I'M
FUCKING DRUNK.
I MIGHT BE SEEING
TO SICK PEOPLE.
BUT I'M GONNA KEEP
THIS EXACT RECOLLECTION
OF YOUR LOVELY MUG.
AND PUT A PENNY ASIDE
EVERY TIME I CURSE.
AND THAT IS
MY PROMISE TO YOU,
AND ME TOO.
WE'LL SEE EACH OTHER
AGAIN DOWN THE ROAD.
- GENTLEMEN--
- WELL, LET'S SEE IT.
OR SHOULD I SAY,
MY FELLOW AUTHORS?
Jane:
I'M DONE IN THERE!
WHERE WOULD THE DOC
HAVE GOT TO?
SOUTH END
OF CHINAMAN'S ALLEY.
THEY'LL GET ME THERE.
I THINK MAYBE IT SHOULD
HAVE A QUESTION MARK.
"THE PLAGUE
IN DEADWOOD?"
THE TYPE IS SET.
YOU'RE READING
THE DEFINITIVE EDITION.
LET'S RUN IT.
NICE WORKING WITH YOU.
- TAKE HIM
RIGHT OVER HERE.
- ( man coughs )
IT'S ALL RIGHT
TO BREATHE,
JUST TURN YOUR HEAD
AWAY FROM HIM.
( muffled )
OKAY, DOC.
ALL RIGHT.
ROLL HIM OVER
ON HIS SIDE.
TURN HIM
BACK THIS WAY.
THAT'S IT.
ALL RIGHT,
THANK YOU, FELLAS.
BYE, DOC.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, SON.
IT'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
Jane:
HEY!
HEY, SOMEBODY!
ARE YOU SURE
YOU'RE UP TO THIS?
OH YES.
I'M RIGHT WHERE
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE.
( man coughing )
( panting )
HERE'S ANOTHER ONE
FOR YOU.
SO I SEE.
YOU ALREADY BEEN EXPOSED,
YOU WANNA FOLLOW HIM IN?
I MIGHT.
"'THE PIONEER' WAS ASSURED
OF THEIR IMMINENT RETURN."
I'LL BELIEVE IT
WHEN I SEE IT.
"IMMINENT RETURN" IS ONE
OF MY CONTRIBUTIONS
TO THE FUCKING ARTICLE.
THE IDEA FOR THAT PHRASE.
"PEST TENT BEING
ERECTED AT THE SOUTH--"
WHAT ABOUT THAT
FUCKING TOLLIVER
BUYING UP PROPERTY
ON THE Q.T., HUH?
WE'RE LUCKY HE WAS
STRUGGLING WITH THE SHIT
WHEN HE MADE THE OFFER
TO LOAN OUT THE LOT.
NONETHELESS, IT SAYS THE MAN
SEES THE POSSIBILITIES
OF THE THINGS.
I MEAN, TO COME UP
AT THIS FUCKING JUNCTURE
WITH THE IDEA
OF CREATING AN EMPORIUM
FOR THE FUCKING CHINKS
TAKES BRASS FUCKING BALLS,
AND A LONG-TERM VISION
FOR THE FUTURE.
MERRICK.
MERRICK WANTED
TO PUT HERE "GRATIS."
NOW IS THE IDEA
TO INFORM YOUR READER
OR MAKE HIM FEEL LIKE
A FUCKING DUNCE?
I HAD HIM PUT "FREE."
DON'T SEE WHY HE DOESN'T
HAVE NEWS OF THE BASEBALL.
THAT NEW LEAGUE STARTED
A TEAM IN CHICAGO.
DIFFERENT PATH TAKEN
AT CERTAIN FORKS
IN THE ROAD,
WHO KNOWS WHAT KIND
OF A JOINT WE'D BE IN NOW?
OF COURSE, TRUTH IS,
AS A BASE OF OPERATIONS,
YOU CANNOT BEAT
A FUCKING SALOON.
AH!
( blues music playing )
* I'M TAKEN DOWN
WITH THE FEVER *
* AND IT WON'T
LET ME SLEEP *
* I'M TAKEN DOWN
WITH THE FEVER *
* AND IT WON'T
LET ME SLEEP *
* IT WAS ABOUT 3:00
* BEFORE HE WOULD
LET ME BE *
* I WISH SOMEBODY
* WOULD COME AND DRIVE
MY FEVER AWAY *
* I WISH SOMEBODY
* COME DRIVE
MY FEVER AWAY *
* THIS FEVER I'M HAVIN' *
* SHO' IS IN MY WAY. *