Fixin' toward a bloody outcome, boss.
Absenting myself don't change your fuckin' instructions
Parp
Slainte
Whoop goggle
Whoop goggle, boop boop.
Parp
Hey!
Get the fuck out!
He come at me with his foreign gibberish.
You get the fuck out while I let you get the fuck out.
You too, you get out that way.
Leave him be or you'll be riding the Goddamn sled with him.
Get out!
Parp…
Either of you cocksuckers want to talk funny at me?
Good day, Sir.
Good day
Wu's out of camp.
Store him in our corner of the icehouse
Will you look this over?
Certainly.
Words that doing the wrong jobs,
piling on too heavy, or at odds over meaning
I'll mark my suggestions
Nothing showy is the main thing
I understand
Shall I gather my school supplies?
I'm much obliged
That's better, isn't it?
Mm
Over here?
I will apologize, Mr. Ellsworth, for what I am about to ask
She wants to try it on the ceiling
A coverlet, dark red, is packed with the linens in the gray leather trunk
Back at the hotel
It's...
near time in any case to take Sofia to school
The settee is best sited with its spread upon it,
would be your mother's idea
Mr. Ellsworth will help you gather your things, Darling, for school
Young lady
Goodbye
Bye
Will I bring you back a sandwich or a glass of milk?
Just the coverlet, thank you
I'd sooner be hanging from those hustings \Nthan stand on 'em giving a speech
Nuttall's bartender's no hand at it either
We both may get pelted with refuse
Morning
Good morning, Sofia
Good morning
Will we bake bread again today?
Is it your vote we should?
Yes
And Mr. Bullock for Sheriff, and Mr. Star for Mayor
And I will put the bread in to bake
If I'm to believe what I read, you're heavily scheduled today
Yes
As to your meetin' with Hearst,
if the chance comes up natural,
stomp on the cocksucker's foot
Morning
Yes, Ma'am
Off to the Bella Union like the moth to the fucking flame
Miss Stubb's didn't name her destination
I'm telling you where she's going
And why don't you look for honest work?
Miss Stubbs holds what I'm doing for honest
She no more needs a watchman than she does a fucking balloonist
And why should the young of this camp
have to scurry past your man-toad figure to receive an education?
The time they come for schoolin', I'm in back and out of sight
Exposin' them to being terrified only when they use the privy
Go get your load on, Jane
Do not instruct me how to spend my day…
or to itemize for you my crowded itinerary…
you tub of blubber and guts!
I've got 10 minutes yet to be out front!
Might I give over the little one to you here?
Of  course
When next we meet, young lady,
I will be on the eye for warm bread
Wants a coverlet from storage-Mrs. Ellsworth-to consider atop the day bed
Framing of a dream
He's saying that to you, Seth
Mr. Ellsworth, no doubt on some menial domestic errand
Sheriff!
Forgive my raucous tone
Mr. Swearengen
May we have a word?
Once I've see 'em to school, I meet Hearst
Very much what I'd have us speak of
Can we plant beets again today?
Yes
"Thank you…Thank you for the introduction, Sheriff."
Sheriff
Morning, Charlie
Morning
Miss Bullock
Good morning, Mr. Utter
Morning there, little one, in your lovely go-to-school outfit
Good morning
Did the evening pass in quiet?
The morning got a little busy
Cornishman killed in the Gem
His buddies come babbling to our office
Dority kill him?
The complainants can't speak right so I had to have them play act
But I'm guessing no
They up in the office still?
Down in Hearst's shafts
We'll  say goodbye
Goodbye
Goodbye, Sofia
Goodbye there, little one
Goodbye
Thank you
Hi Dorothy
Good morning, James
Good morning
Nice thing, ain't it?
The children?
Will you attend the evening speeches, Richardson?
If you let me
Of course I will
How else are you to vote with intelligence?
I intend no lengthy remarks
My tenure as Mayor speaks for me
Will they have the Jew merchant instead?
Well, let them then and welcome
I caught you, Richardson
Stuffin' spitbacks in your vile maw
"Let tomorrow's omelets go empty."
Is that your fuckin' attitude?
You hurted me
Shhh!
Wash and stack, shit monkey
Or ready yourself for worse
Florence Nightingale
Florence Nightingale is a nurse
I know that, ya ignorant cocksucker
Joanie Stubbs is a cocksucker
I know that, you ignorant fuck
Don't be sweatin' all over the gentleman's money
And thank you for that rasher of shit
Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us
And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil,
for Thine is the kingdom and the power and the glory,forever and ever
Amen
Morning, Tess
Morning, Joanie
Git
I can take him that
I got it
How's Cy?
I don't know yet, Tess
It's none of your business anyway
Your only business is how you start the fucking day
I'm clean
Before you go to sleep, how are you supposed to start?
I said I'm clean
You answer my Goddamn question
My snatch is clean
Is the rest of your body clean?
Yes
What's next?
The room where I receive, and that's fucking clean
Well what's next after that?
God damn you, Joanie
What's next, Lila, if you ain't too fucking high?
Our room where we rest
Which don't it fuckin' stink in here?
It does, Lila, like a hogwhore's cunt.
And I ain't loaded not to smell it
Why don't you go, girl?
Why don't you get to the muck where you're fuckin' headed anyway?
Go on. Git
What are you doin' sittin' back there?
Oh, please let me stay
When I come back tonight, you better all be sweet for me to fuck
Or have your damn bags packed, 'cause I'll throw every one of you out
Move, Tess, move
you know she's going to let her stay
Come  on in, Honey. How are you?
I'm all right
Was the Doc by?
Brightened my early mornin'
Another day on the right side of the ledger far as puss
How's the action outside?
It's quiet
Either clown upright to tell you what the action was?
I  didn't ask.
I guess you'd stopped in on the whores
Well, you might have mistook, Cy, pickin' Tess over Lila to see to 'em
Lila's on the needle
Well, Tess ain't pickin' up the bit
Maybe she's unsure of her place,
you in and out of our lives
Well, fresh water
You're not leaving yet, are you?
Right here, Cy, on the side table
Act like a fucking baby, don't I?
"Oh, don't go."
Where's my Good Book, honey?
just next to you, in the bedfold
I've been scooping out rain gutters for a month
My fingers are bloody with sandin'
You do recall you're only the transactions beard?
You return to Star. A sorry run at the tables,
you can't support the loan he made you
Well, what if he don't foreclose?
Oh, you beg him to buy you out. You may harm yourself
You're up all hours, "What have I fucking done?" Or the like
"Maybe I should fucking end it."
Star ends owning that house is the necessary fucking conclusion
Coffee!
Ready
That croaker seen to?
At Wu's icehouse, under a tarp, in our corner
Will you pour it without scalding me, huh?
Breakfast?
Bacon and eggs
You know you could have said that before I went down
You get in the kitchen
I liked living in that place
Why do I give a fuck?
So why not force this morning's murder outside?
You told us not to
As he stank of a put-up job,
I wanted to find out if we were meant for the venue
Well, whoever put the job up can't be any too smart,
'cause them Cornish work for Hearst
Murder a Cornish and you buy Hearst for an enemy
You're a fucking miracle, Johnny
It's close to a mortal certainty he ordered the murder himself
Hearst?
Shut up!
He stages a murder in my fucking joint
Wants Bullock to show his ass before he'll bless his fucking candidacy
What does he require of the weather?
Jesus Christ
That's it-how you clean a fuckin' bloodstain, hey
What if we stretched out the payments?
I cannot fucking make it
What the fuck was in my head to sign that note?
Take it easy
Take it easy, Mr. Adams
Take it off me
Can't  you?
Ain't there some way to take it off?!
Oh God!
I'm in crisis too, needing awfully to piss
Why not cork up and go on stage with that tragic fuckin' minstrel turn?
Are you alone?
Yes, Miss Bernhardt, I am
Al wants Star to take over that house
Why?
Keep my ruddy color not askin' Al his reasons
Disarray…
in your room
Your last day when you left, disarray
I sat on the bed
I won't have it
Did you hear me, Shaunessy?
My last day I sat on the bed for three hours
I had a glass of water
Yes yes yes Very likely
Uh, 1-F, $2
The book, please
Ink on the floor
Pen near blunted, possibly broke
Binding's damaged.
I won't stand for it
Give that back to the gimp
What the fuck you trying to pull with Adam's fuckin' house?
Star needs to move into that
He's a candidate for office
He can't whore-fuck no longer with impunity
Who says I want to live in that house?
You ain't
You're installing at fucking Shaunessey's
The fuck if I'll live in that shithole
Shaunessy being richer by 50 for his common wall with Star's home-to-be
and the passage he cut through it,
so you and the Jew can fall upon each other away from prying eyes
Fuck you, Al
Fuck Shaunessey's
And fuck the passage into Adam's fuckin' house
Loopy cunt!
The wrist business on Adam's house loan,
Adams being nothing but his fucking stalking horse
from the gambit's fucking beginning
You sign to take those over,
we'll move in your 12 possessions
You will be free to come and go by your own front fucking door,
and as you lay in your beddy-bye,
I'll pop from the wall
like Grandma Groundhog in a storybook
and attend to your Johnson,
as he'd not see you jeopardize your Mayor's campaign
whore fucking in your place of business
And I'll have installed
in room 3-fucking-C or the like
of Shaunessey's adjacent shitbox
that he's paid Shaunessey to cut a hole through
to ease my fuckin' fucking you
Swearengen has?
Who the fuck was I just talking to?
I don't know. You said you'd just gone to piss
Man of the hour
Quick prick-suck, Bullock?
Sally forth to meet the great man with unencumbered thoughts?
What happened in here this morning?
Charlie Utter says a man was murdered,
one of Hearst's workers
I'd spare you the particulars till after your meeting concludes
Why
Why ask why?
Why not honor the meeting's purpose?
Speak as a candidate of your hopes for the camp
and its future,
confine yourself to generalities
Suppose Hearst…
was this murder's architect?
Suppose the workers were thieves or
organizers?
Why  kill 'em in camp before witnesses?
Maybe as message to me his domain includes my fucking joint,
and to test your willingness
to bend to his fucking will before he backs your candidacy
What we know, fucking Bullock, is
if when you two meet,
Hearst does ask you to go easy,
and you, for love of his type, say "Fuck yourself,"
no more illumination can come to us,
because you will have muddied the fuckin' waters
Is why I'd hoped you'd skirt the topic
Has the body been eaten?
The Cornish croaker? Wu's out of fucking camp
Don't let it get eaten
Oh, absolutely
till your further full investigation
As for your meeting with Hearst,
may I offer a fervent Godspeed and hopes
for your fucking self-control?!
What am I, Lord,
that I'm so helpless?
Bullock.
He ascends, Richardson,
to be dug at
and sifted and shoveled
till his crucial vein is exposed
Then Hearst will empty him out
Much anticipated, Mr. Bullock
some good solid talk between us
What do you drink?
No
thanks
I believe I won't either
I'm told that you operate a hardware concern
I'm partnered with Sol Star
Ah, candidate for Mayor
as you are for Sheriff
And an officer
of the Deadwood bank
Sol's chief officer,
yes
And you are an officer too
Yes
The bank capitalized, as I understand, by Mrs. Alma Garret Ellsworth…
Formerly quartered in this hotel and who has struck
so rich in these hills
Way back second to you
Extraordinary,
the story of that woman's adventures
Do you suppose that its future chapters might be written…
elsewhere than the hills?
What are your intentions?
As to Mrs. Ellsworth's holdings, I would shape those to the lady's preferences,
and be pleased and grateful if you told her
Do you need a handkerchief, Mr. Bullock?
No
Unfortunate incident this morning at Swearengen's saloon
Do you know about it?
No
One of my workmen was killed in a drunken shootout
How will you deal with that, Sheriff?
Depends
what it was about? Who makes complaints?
Mmm
My worker was Cornish
They are a clannish people
I suppose another Cornish might complain
I'd need to hear what he said then
He may also indict the sunrise
For men of that sort,
events such as these are as natural
Anyways
May we speak of your ambitions?
Another time
I would want to support them, you see?
I would want to back you
to thank you
for taking her my message
I never said I'd take her your message
Are you saying now that you won't?
You stay out of our fuckin' affairs
Oh…
affairs of that sort are not my interest, Mr. Bullock
My only passion is the color
Excuse me
Bullock,
how did you like Mr. Hearst?
What are you doin'?!
You piece of shit
How have I given offense?
You told him
Call the law
The Sheriff's killing the mayor
In the thoroughfare,
if I fucking need you
Bullock?
Bullock…
Bullock!
Why are you beating Farnum in Mr. Hearst's hotel?
How are you , Sir?
I am well, Mr. Swearengen,
and how are you?
Bullock!
Shall I have him seen to, Sir?
He seems to need that
My place, Sheriff?
Boys!
E.B.'s had an accident
Under your supervision,
and then inform us on his further transport
Yes
Give the poor fuck your shoulders, boys, huh?
Sheriff!
Much experienced at the enterprise, Sir
I haven't a doubt
And once he's situated, may you and me speak?
Of course
You saw fuckin' nothing
Jesus, Joseph and Mary
Mrs. Ellsworth?
No
You must drink this
I will not awaken that demon, Doctor
This has nothing to do with demons, Mrs. Ellsworth
This has to do with allaying the pain to get you through
Leave the demons to God and trust the pain to me
"A lady should not choose a man
who chews tobacco."
"It robs his pocket,
soils his clothes…
and makes a chimney of his nose."
Good, peek
if one of 'em sees you, they give up attendance forever
I suppose you didn't come to peek in
I came to shit in the privy,
which is where you're supposed to be during school hours
How does it feel to take one sitting up?
"The Jews burn sacrifices upon an altar of stone."
Altars of the kind in the sentence
are spelled "T-A-R,"
It's not so important always to be right, Mary,
or to be first
"Indians are sometimes very cruel."
I'm pulling out as a candidate
No, you aren't
He'll use knowing to try to control me,
have his way in the camp's affairs
He asked me to get her to sell
Oh, best leave the camp entirely as penance for having a prick
You were right about the killing
He didn't want it pursued
Bleeding?
He stopped
Put him up on the fucking bed then
No grand gestures, fucking Bullock,
till I've had my talk with Hearst
Do no fucking withdraw
And no more beating up on Farnum that has to run against Star
It's no certainty
Hearst knew one Goddamn thing about Bullock putting it to the widow
Hell of a beating for E.B. to take if he's innocent
Oh, he's still way ahead of the game. Nonetheless,
we must now assume that Hearst does fucking know
As going mad in front of him,
Bullock might have tipped him as to the state of things
How are you gonna go at Hearst?
Don't I yearn for the days
a draw across the throat made fucking resolution?
Why, Dan,
by composing my thoughts, tropes and gambits
for the talk between us that is yet to come
Will you excuse me?
Sure
Is she dying?
She's not in imminent danger
The baby?
Your wife is still with child
I saw the blood on the floor
There wasn't as much blood as I'm sure it seemed to you
Mrs. Ellsworth must remain abed,
And she must take the medicine I've given her,
her fear of it notwithstanding
And you must remain strong at her side
I have to collect the child May I ask you to st
I'll stay here till you come back,
and then I'll go collect Trixie to help you
Thank you, Doctor
Who the fuck are all these people?
Guess the stages are gonna be crowded
Headed to collect the Missus?
I just beat Farnum
Meeting Hearst,
I got the idea someone
had told him bidness of mine
Figured it was Farnum?
If it'd been me, I'da
gone ahead and killed him
I wonder now
if I might have mistook
Fuck Farnum anyway
If I tipped Hearst myself, is what I'm wondering now
Ah
And of my temper generally,
I'm wondering about
far as running for office
Maybe you just don't want to speak tonight
I know
I don't want to speak
wondering if I ought to withdraw
Talking against my own interests
being if you pull out, I won't have to speak from the audience
far as conversing with your rival,
what's your best fuckin' experience?
Harry Manning?
Huh
I guess that once the two of us talked to him
When he killed Bummer Dan by mistake
And that was high fucking water
So you'd hold me as fair calling Harry fucking outright
dimwitted?
You think better than the Sheriff with a shortish temper,
which in certain Sheriffing situations is a plus,
camp be better with Harry?
Anyways
You gonna have dinner with us?
May be my last fucking meal if apoplexy takes me
off my nervousness
What if you won?
I won't
I'm only in it to make myself known
Say you're fucking elected, Harrry,
am I entitled to the fucking livery abandoned
by the Nigger Hosteteler leaving its stock to starve?
Well, I know you've took up its care
And do you as Sheriff
hold my fucking labor speaks for me,
my diligent fuckin' efforts the last six fuckin' weeks?
Well, uh, I'd hold with the law, Steve,
whatever statute applied
Well, oughtn't a "statue" have to do with justice
and not just to bait back a fled fucking nigger
looking to steal what a white man's worked for?
Well, Hostetler ain't come back
Why think he ever will?
Because it's my family luck
over centuries
to get repeatedly fucked up the ass
And here in this fucking camp
is where the chain gets fucking broken
And I'm askin' if you as Sheriff
will stand with me?!
Yeah, I ain't Sheriff
I got problems enough today without
kiting checks on tomorrow's
That was a wiggle
worthy of a fucking reptile, Harry
Bullock took a position?
I ain't asked Bullock!
Fool that I am,
I figured I'd give you first crack
on the basis of our friendship
But I guess I was mistaken
I've got an idea
Instead of running for office and tending bar
why don't you just tend bar and let everybody punch you in the face?
Hello, Jane
Yeah, hello
Several of the children's parents have told them you scouted for Custer
I can't hear you!
Severa of the children's parents have told them you scouted for Custer
Not that the arrogant bastard ever heeded others' counsel
Shall we fashion a story about your experiences, Jane,
for the children to hear?
Do you talk this low when you're teaching the children?
Shall we fashion a story about your experiences, Jane,
for the children to hear?
Uh, I best say no
My funds just now all go for liquor
I see
I fine myself
for swearing amongst the young
And just now,
I need my money for booze
We'd tell your story to avoid those
Does that Mose Manuel horrify the children?
No
Gives 'em bad dreams at night?
No, the children like Mose
I expect he pisses you off
No
Well, he irritates the hell out of me
Oh, I was just going, Sheriff
I thought I left a bottle in here
Must've left it in the shitpile outside
Goodbye, Jane
Good afternoon
How was your meeting with Mr. Hearst?
We needn't be afraid is the main thing
She'll not be
of a sudden taken
or the like
The Doctor's guaranteed it
So
when we're with her,
we needn't be worried
Do you want to keep it?
May not be a matter of my choosing
As I suppose we both fucking know
I'm asking…
if all the way down,
you want to bring it into the world
I want it very much
Or if an accident befalling
or fate intervening or
however you want to fucking put it,
might find a small part of you relieved
I want my baby
Then you're gonna lay down
and be spoiled
and put off proving what else you can do
until after you've popped out this kid
"Voters of the camp,
do you see come before you
some swollen and dissolute stranger?
Do not mistake
It is I, E.B. Farnum!"
Lie back, E.B
"Beaten past recognition by
a candidate for another office
Lie the fuck back
and listen
I need your truthful reply
Lie, I will know it,
and death will be no respite
I told Hearst nothing
of Bullock and the widow
I will profane your fucking remains, E.B
Not my remains, Al
Gabriel's trumpet will produce you
from the ass of a pig
You told me not to tell him,
and I didn't
I believe you
My pain is such
that gives me no solace
Well, try not to blame Bullock for presuming it was you,
considering your fucking history
Anyways,
tonight's speeches are fucking canceled
Nurse your fuckin' wouds
Thank you
I do not mean here
All right
Let me collect myself
Cock...suckers !!!
Say what you have to say…
Again for Merrick, Dan
Gratis
Uh, I'm due no special thanks, Al
Facilitating presentation of the candidates
is the honor and privilege of the press
That's off, the presentation
Is Farnum incapable of speech?
Does Star refuse to take advantage?
Other factors at play
But surely Bullock and Harry Manning still can take to the hustings
I got to notify the parties
I'm an interested party too, Al
And I require explanation
Jesus Christ
How interested are you?
Enough to bleed to keep the business from being a fucking puppet show?
I can imagine bleeding,
if first I've been made to understand
No one asked if you could imagine bleeding,
or if you'd have tumbling or somersaults or cartwheels
to bring you into the lists
Drink and fuck on the house,
but do not attempt to detain me
In what state?
We ain't in a state, Shaunessy
What condition?
The room?
How much
disarray?
No fucking...
disarray
But you nearly had brain on your walls
Oooh!
You see me empty, Sir,
do not pause and inquire,
simply assume
and refill
Would you
rather we spoke in private?
No, fuck, no
I'd rather the gentleman stay
Captain Turner
I'd rather the Captain stay
Brings home I consort with my betters
I'll not dissemble, Sir
Today's events have gave me pause
Hmm
Tell me what you mean
The beating of Farnum most recently
How is Mr. Farnum?
Worse for wear,
not that I'd care
if he weren't in your hire
Where does the Sheriff get off
taking off on one of your own?
I don't consider Bullock came here to beat Farnum.
He and I had appointed to meet
In my joint this morning,
another of your workers was gut-shot, Mr. Hearst
Yes, I know
Now this wasn't some hooplehead bullshit
This had the feel of a put-up job
I fear a plot against you
I have learned to accept, Mr. Swearengen,
that events sharing some effect on my interests
does not make them part of a plot
You ain't the center of the universe,
in other words
Exactly
Don't that lead you to despair?
No, Sir
You're stronger-minded than I
Bullock
beating Farnum seems more likely some
expression of a private feeling of his own
That leaves the bloodshed in my bar,
Sir
How do you account for that?
Nor are the Cornish well-loved as a race
Oh, not you through the Cornish
Maybe the Cornish themselves were the object of the violence
Well, they do tend to
aggregate and organize to
further their financial interests
Unions
Have you strong feeling on that subject?
I don't give a fuck about unions, Mr. Hearst
Nor do I have any objection to the killing of the Cornish as high-graders
aggregating organizing cocksuckers. But
bloodletting on my premises
that I ain't approved
I take as a fucking affront
It puts me off
my feed
How do we know when
you are off your feed?
You'll start to see me tearing things down
Speeches tonight are canceled
Unless the insult's cured by tomorrow,
there'll be further tearing down
Fuck the fucking elections,
and fuck the agreement with Yankton
Let the camp return to its former repute :
unstable and unsafe for commerce
I'm a great believer in those
Oh, stability, Sir, and commerce?
I can fucking imagine
Think of all they've helped you accomplish
Shall I perceive you then
as dangerous to my interests?
As capable of inconvenience and
of some damage and debt to those that would
act against my interests,
I cannot fucking argue with dangerous
Different from powerful though,
which speaks to potency longer term
I'd not have myself called powerful in your company
or the Captain's
Then I'll hope that your insult is cured
to spare the camp any danger
of however brief a duration
And to look for one fucking instant out of the other end of the telescope
once placated…
I'm meek as a babe
Dead
You will want to converse with
those friends of yours, Captain Turner,
who argues with the Cornish
Perhaps they'd care to pay another visit to the saloon
I think I'll want to hear the talk
Fucking pagan
Tell your God to ready for blood
Would you rather I didn't introduce you from the audience?
Is it all so hard to remember?
No, I,
uh,I think I got it
Unless you don't wanna
Ought we to start soon for the hustings?
Five minutes
Adams may default on that house
Asks me to assume his note
That's a very pleasant house
Uh, I-I'd…
never thought of myself as a homeowner
It's very very spacious
It's Albert Swearengen
The speeches
are postponed
Is Farnum turned for the worse?
I'd borrow the Sheriff a moment
Evening, Jane
Mrs. Bullock asks me to
author with her to give the children
an account of my scouting for Custer
I think I'd like to hear that story myself
"Custer was a cunt.
The end."
Yo,
a piss puddle
Must not have seen that
when seating myself
Why are you drinking so much?
I drink what I'm able
If that comes to much
That's the day's affair and the liquor's
You returning to the Bella Union?
Not tonight
As residence and workplace
is my meaning
Thos girls need looking out for
And who will look out for you
against that gut-stabbed cocksucker,
weaving schemes
from his coming to Jesus?
I don't know
Why is everybody fucking whispering all of a sudden?
I said I don't know
Do you mind…
if I stay here tonight?
I'd be glad if you would
I don't know why you started sleeping outside anyway
Every day takes figuring out all over again how to fucking live
Night, Jane
Yep
Pain-in-the-balls Hearst
Running his holdings like a despot,
I grant, has a fucking logic
It's the way I fucking run mine. It's the way I'd run my home if I fucking had one
But there's no practical need for him to run the fucking camp
That's out of scale
It's out of proportion,
and it's a warped unnatural impulse, this fucking cocksucker!
Sorry
Shall I go back down with you?
It won't be just now
He'll be wanting to marshal his cutthroats
Do stay in hailing distance
Subs: nikou3131
www.forom.com