- That's good.
- How's Bullock doing?
I don't discuss my patients, one with another.
Bleeding through his fucking ear?
He was bleeding through it pretty
fucking good out there in the thoroughfare.
Tell me about that other department.
Inform that fucking lunatic
next you see him
I'm fit as a fucking fiddle
and ready to play on.
Inform me, Al, to what mark
in your piss-pot did you fill?
The volume was adequate.
I didn't check the mark.
Any discharge of gleets,
burning or soreness?
I got your suit back from Mr.
It's kind of, like,
aromafied from that solvent.
Why don't you let it cure in the air for
a while, huh, Johnny?
Not on the balcony.
Not on the fucking balcony.
Gleets, burning, soreness?
He's come back to my hotel.
Bullock.
Upstairs to the widow.
I can't say if they're in rut.
I didn't linger for the song of the bedstead.
Let me go check
on those fucking whores.
No more in that department.
That fucking discussion is over.
I was relieved Mr. Star and Mr.
Utter weren't more badly injured.
Yes.
I hope my coming to your store
caused no awkwardness.
It was kind of you bringing that
basket for my family.
May I ask if you had been aware their
arrival was so imminent?
No.
She had written that William
seemed entirely recovered,
but no mention of intending to travel.
He's handsome...
Your brother's son.
He's a fine boy.
I would so like to see to your injuries,
however superficially.
My proposal would be we leave the camp
immediately,
or remain and sever connection.
A choice for me to make?
Yes.
I don't seek to absolve myself.
I don't believe i'm to be relied
upon for good judgment.
Or even for an account of your own feelings?
I only know
that for us to stay and not sever connection
would add lying to her humiliation,
- renew her humiliation daily.
- Yes, I understand.
- You say I must choose immediately?
- Tonight.
I'd need some part of tonight to consider.
- Yes.
- Others are involved for me as well.
I'll come back in a few hours.
Be very careful in the interim, Mr. Bullock.
All right.
Be careful.
...two, fucking three.
Easy.
A lovely family, the Bullocks.
Grand.
Looked forward all this while,
and meet them with my load on.
Easy does it.
- Easy!
- Two, fucking three!
Thank you, Mr. Utter.
- Okay.
- Much obliged, Mr. Merrick.
I got him.
Look the fuck out.
I ought probably to get some weapons.
Why?
What?
Why would you?
Maybe you didn't notice
Bullock was without his gun.
No, I did.
Perhaps with the ringing in your ears,
you didn't hear Mr. Bullock say he'd
get his old weapon back.
You think maybe a new one might be useful
to Bullock arranging his old one's return?
And more backing his position?
May I have a word with Sol?
Sure.
- Will you mind if I hang around awhile?
- Fuck, no.
Self-deluding, interfering motherfucker.
I'm sorry you got shot.
A man like me gets used to it.
If it had came to it,
i'd have seen to dissolving the partnership,
sending your mother the proceeds.
Why would i expect otherwise?
- And I know you would do the same.
- What are you thinking of?
Along with any funds I might forward.
From the afterlife, you mean?
Any funds I would send subsequent,
I know you would administer in their interest
- Martha and the boy.
- Yes, you're correct.
What are you fucking thinking of?
What we've built and been through,
you don't get to walk away
without saying why.
You know why.
That don't mean you don't have to say it.
I'm sick of knowing and you not saying.
- I love her.
- Good! you fucking said it.
And now I get to tell you you're wrong.
You  loved her these
months and stayed.
It ain't love that'd make you run, but shame.
Now let me ask you this,
you think shame would end
when you cleared the fucking camp?
It's shameful either way, Sol.
It's life either way, Seth.
I'm sorry you got shot.
Well, i am too, but I like being loaded.
I like telling you what the fuck I think,
you cocksucker.
I  know you will see to their interests.
Yes, I will, you cocksucker!
And I like saying "cocksucker."
What the fuck do you think of that?!
Want a fast blow-job?
What?
Quick open air blow-job.
Uh, no, thank you.
- Bullock.
- Charlie.
Maybe Mr. Star will want one.
Thanks for going against orders.
I'll tell you,
I got such a fucking ringing in my ears.
Thanks for taking my back before.
Oh, you're welcome.
Hey, I'll bet your wife and son
are overtook by that lovely
home you built them.
Ah, and what did that boy say about a
creek in his own front yard?
And that's a fine appearance he makes.
And if you don't mind my saying,
she is one striking woman, Mrs. Bullock.
Sense of dignified and upright.
Thank you.
Anyways, where the fuck you headed?
To get my things from Al Swearengen.
Maybe for a word with Dan Dority too.
Gave me this fucking headache.
To the Gem then.
Jesus Christ.
I'm faint.
A faintness come over me.
Oh, Jesus.
That's a lightheaded fucking sensation.
Did you want to go to your place?
Oh, maybe I should.
Maybe that's the fucking prudent course.
Give me some weight.
Come on.
Yeah, to not keel forward
and drown in fucking horseshit.
How are you feeling?
Things are a little wavy-like before my eyes.
Fuck the Gem. Gem'll fucking wait.
For what it's worth,
Yankton's afraid of Bullock.
Well, say no more.
Refrain from explaining yourself.
Till congress approves, nothing's to say
the hills get made part of Dakota.
Far as that, Montana's got pull Dakota don't.
Montana's got silver for bribes.
Thieving indian agent's all fucking
Dakota's got.
It ain't fucking fresh money to the game.
And how does that argue for bullock
living or dying?
Yankton thinks Bullock's Montana's man.
On what basis?
He was favorite of a judge in Helena
that wanted him in politics.
They figure he's a stalking horse
here for the judge's interests.
Then Yankton's got their
head up their fucking asses
if they think Bullock's
anybody's man.
Hell, Bullock himself don't even
know whose man he is.
In the thoroughfare,
as I readied to stab the cocksucker,
did you have no impulse to hint at this?
The moment didn't seem right.
Over time, your quickness
with a cocky rejoinder
must have gotten you
many punches in the face.
Depends what you call "many."
There's another fucking clever one.
To Yankton's thinking,
Would Bullock dead
curb Montana's interests
or incite them
to a stronger expression?
- I don't know.
- If he's spoiling to mix it with us further,
they may get a chance to find out.
He will leave with me,
if tell him that's my wish.
As to what our life would be,
that's another question.
I would say, ma'am, it might be like
living atop a volcano.
- That's been done, Miss Isringhausen.
- Certainly.
And with a good deal of
excitement, I should think.
A sense of high adventure every day.
And, of course, danger.
As to excitement, would you possibly...
add happiness?
Why not, Mrs. Garrett?
Please don't be angry with me, ma'am.
No.
We do love each other.
Our being together ought not to seem
so outlandish a proposition...
No, ma'am.
... except for every other single thing.
Oh boy.
Yeah, there you go.
Thank you, thank you, Bullock.
All right.
I'm next to completely collected.
Three separate occasions I've been shot at,
hit, and fought on.
And  now, a miss takes my equilibrium.
Anyways.
You want to get to the Gem, huh?
- Yeah.
- Why?
I told you why.
Well, i mean why just this instant,
say, different from later a little while,
when a friend could back your play?
I mean,
someplace you need to get to after that?
I got the elements stored in the back.
I hope to Christ you do.
Come in.
Don't anyone bolt for freedom.
I kept accumulating them secret
so Cy wouldn't think I was proceeding.
Well, well, well.
- There's the wallpaper you sent, Maddie.
- Yes, ma'am.
Ladies, why don't you put your attention
to some of the lighter furniture,
and we'll hire some great
minds to do the heavy lifting?
Roll up your sleeves, Doris.
hard work dispels worry.
I pray to God your shoulder pain's
like some sharp-toothed creature's
inside chewing at it and gnawing.
How did I give offense?
No one needs feeling as good as you'd
feel otherwise.
I say from fucking experience.
And I didn't need the fucking activity today
and the fucking crises.
I prefer sucking prick is the fucking
short of it.
I would settle for a vigorous hand-holding.
You are a funny fucking Jew.
...and type that insinuates himself.
General principle,
I believe in fostering people's
tries at improving theirselves,
and I think you all also
know at I got a special fondness
for Joanie Stubbs.
And if those things wasn't true,
in this camp at this precise juncture,
I, Cy Tolliver, would not have backed
an exclusively high-end whoring operation
at the far fucking end of the camp
without concealed access for its trade.
But, be that as it may,
and wishing Joanie godspeed,
this congregation gathers so that
I can assure each of you
that our operation here, the Bella Union,
is organized exactly
to capitalize on what this camp is ready for
and for what it's going to become.
I want each of you to take one of these...
as a gesture of optimism and good will.
Keep your fucking distance!
Remain on your side
of the street!
Do not interfere with me in any way!
Chinese cocksuckers!
Jesus.
Well, you are an entangled inebriate,
are you not?
This happens to be a rig and contraption
of my own devising
against repeated accidental falls
that has temporarily malfunctioned.
Very well knotted.
I'm back in camp, Cochran,
'cause I'm dying
and I need a place
to breathe my fucking last,
and not for no human aid or consolation.
Jesus Christ, you're bad with your hands!
If I wasn't practically fucking dead,
I'd reach that knife and cut myself free.
And I just farted. so what?
Don't you disarm me, you cocksucker!
Lift me up so I can cut myself free.
All right. you ready?
All right now, give me that hand.
Now...
step inside
and let me examine you,
even if you are past help.
Enhancing my understanding
may allow others the benefit of your
mortal illness.
Do you mock me, cocksucker?
No.
Come on inside.
All right, there we go.
Promise when I'm dead, you'll plant me
with a view of where Bill is.
He couldn't have meant that, not possibly.
Well, I shouldn't have thought so.
You don't believe he imagines
were he and I to go,
I'd leave Sophia behind?
I can't be certain, Mrs. Garret.
I didn't hear him speak.
Because others rescued her and nursed her,
is the idea that she belongs to the camp?
Are we some sort of vicious,
filthy outpost of brook farm?
She's been with me
for seven months.
She's a part of my life as I am of hers.
He couldn't have.
I will not!
Jane, for me, the female breast
has long ago lost all mystery or allure.
open your goddamn blouse.
I'm keeping my eyes shut,
but I'll know every fucking move you make!
I'll have you further promise
that you won't forage in my remains
after i'm dead,
as you obviously don't scruple from
that type of sick behavior.
I promise.
All right, sit up if you're not too drunk.
Your liver runs from your
chin to your genitals,
so I suggest you quit drinking.
I will when you do, you ugly son of a bitch.
Nature is a forgiving mistress,
and you might could have some time to fill
before she collects her due.
As if I'd credit any opinions of yours
on the subject of health.
Well, if you do care to sojourn among us,
Charlie Utter has put aside
a room for you at the freight building.
Does he have any animals in there?
Fort Cooper...
on the Butterfield Stage route.
I know that fort.
- On the Brazos. - That's where I found him.
I was 13,
and he had to send me back.
But we had...
a good talk before I left.
Probably I'd have come looking for him again,
but next year was the war.
Robert was cavalry.
No way to locate where he was.
The fucking war had everyone all over
everywhere.
We wrote.
Less after my father passed
and I headed to Montana.
I had letters when he married,
when they had their boy.
And we'd threaten visits.
When I finally did come to Fort Quitman
where Robert was posted and...
met Martha and William,
Robert wasn't there.
He was following back some raid
across the Rio Grande.
I had let it wait too long.
He got shot and killed in Mexico
and was buried there.
Fucking Mexico.
I went down,
found him
and brought him back.
Wrong to let him lay there...
unless you're a Mexican.
My bowels are in an upheaval.
I'll walk off to pass wind.
Don't ever say I'm not a fucking gentleman.
Fuck you two!
No. 10...
ruled me off, the round-eyed toads.
Cocksucker.
My concern, past your physical well-being,
is what the dispute portends.
Yeah, I don't know.
Is it settled between you two
or still unresolved?
I don't fucking know.
Your ribs are hurting, ain't they?
Yeah, they fucking hurt.
Well, I always believed,
of His sufferings on the cross,
His busted ribs would have hurt Him the worst.
Hey, Adams? cutthroat friend, huh?
And I thought you was in Florida
having your belly rubbed by a seminole.
- What the fuck?
- You aren't going to believe what happened to me, boss.
If Kate Hogranch is part of this story
and fucking that half-breed,
go ahead and try me.
That's not the stop that detained me.
I'm past my fill of this shit.
Next time don't fucking catch up.
Guess the day of the Samaritan's passed.
Stopped  help stranded sisters.
Hi.
Severe reprimand.
Them two seem disputatious as well, huh?
Storm clouds gather.
Think you about got her clean there, hoss.
Another fucking clever one.
You know I bet when you and your
partner's out on the trail,
When you ain't greasing poles
and choosing who's going to be rider,
I bet you and him just bust each other's guts
with your little fucking funnies.
Well, we do laugh some about you.
Let's hear a belly giggle now, you cocksucker.
No.
God damn it!
Christ, that's one country ass-kicking!
Shut your fucking mouth!
Oh, he just 12-pointed slippery Dan.
Next one is to your head, Dan.
Do not doubt me.
Well, that's just fucking great.
That's fucking beautiful.
Feels like a cannonball up my ass.
Fella in Livingston went sweet on me.
Finnish fella from Finland,
hardly spoke fucking english.
Brought me flowers and
some dry food they like there.
And, uh, one night,
he takes my arm and he starts in
and he, uh, whispers in his finland accent,
"I want to suck your cock."
What do you fucking
think of that?
Uh, oh, I missed the end part, Jane.
Uh, can't practically hear fuck-all.
A fucking bullet near creased my ear.
It didn't do your face no fucking
favors neither.
- Yeah.
- Put him to sleep.
I got to go.
No, no, no, wait, wait, wait.
Uh, wait.
- Let me get weapons.
- For what?
I told you, we was
involved in a falling out,
and I guess hostilities
may be about to resume.
You going to tell me now who it was with?
Swearengen.
The limey cocksucker
nearly did for the little one?
Why the fuck was you withholding
that information?
In the futile hope
of preventing you roiling the fucking waters.
How is that little one the limey
cocksucker nearly killed?
Still in the care
of the widow Garret?
I'll have my badge and gun back.
Well, go get the fucking weapons
for us to back him, Charlie.
Let me just wake my fucking watchman.
Alcoholic encephalopathy.
Um... wet brain.
$5.00.
Anything else I can do for you, boss?
Keep up.
Just save your fucking words, Al.
Don't waste your precious time.
You got any orders, you just send
Adams and he can deliver them.
- Dan--
- You chose!
You took his fucking part!
As was right and fucking proper at the time.
Yeah, but you pointed the fucking gun at me.
And persuaded you I'd use it in order
that I didn't need to.
Dan?
Where you or me would have
slammed that hoople up,
planted him back and twisted the cocksucker
till all the points of that buck's
rack showed out his chest,
and then done it twice more in case the fuck
mistook the first for accident,
what did Adams do?
He fucking walked away.
Different man from you and me.
Whatever looks ahead
of grievous abominations and disorder,
you and me walk into it together like always.
As you'd never say to Adams?
As I'd never say to Adams.
Send fucking Dolly up, huh?
Yeah, sure thing, boss.
When I first came to this camp
and for many years before,
I depended on spirits of laudanum.
May I ask against what indisposition?
Various indispositions.
The remedy was invariable.
Caring for Sophia has been a great joy
and a great freedom.
To give up her care
in love's name or any other
the selfishness of that...
i'd be too afraid.
Ain't never seen a man killed like that.
By God, I'll tell you what, Johnny,
there would have been a hell of a lot more
than two tines sticking through
that cocksucker's chest
if it had been me or al impaling him.
Jesus Christ!
Either Al got god
or Dolly just stuck her thumb
back up his ass.
Now, I'm halfway thinking
this exaggerates the condition
rather than alleviates it.
If I might should query the doc,
but then that cocksucker will
only ask after gleets.
Oh my God.
Take it out.
Take it out. Remove your fucking thumb.
Why,
if I was moving forward to get away from you,
would you have fucking pursued me?
When I stopped, pressed on yourself
to drive your thumb into my intestine?
Sorry.
Is it a river of blood,
or what the fuck's pouring out of it now?
Nothing.
Close the ass-flap.
The entire area of my fucking asshole
is now one gigantic fucking throb.
I have no idea what's transpiring in there.
- Shall I suck your prick?
- Please.
Does he want to fucking die?
I understand that has its fucking appeal,
but not going out a fucking cunt
taking others fucking with you.
Dulled faculties!
Your fucking stupid fuck of a stupid
fucking partner.
Wants to die?
Help me, Trixie.
Even this now gives me no pleasure.
Swearengen!
Be down in five minutes
with my gun and badge!
Start down now, you limey cocksucker!
Allow for getting stuck
crawling out from under the bed.
That Bullock's a fucking strategist, ain't he?
Sets terms to publicly humiliate me,
and my penalty if I don't comply
is he walks into the bar downstairs
and takes 15 bullets in the chest.
And that ain't no hooplehead, you know.
Bullock, he's one of those
special fucking cases.
You don't know what in fuck's
going on in their mind.
And he's big with Montana.
Big.
I heard that today.
Because the news earlier from Yankton
and the fucking commissioners
wasn't adequately confusing.
Not to mention
the fucking telegraph coming in
and four whores that I don't
know who the fuck they work for.
Three minutes!
Shut the fuck up!
I suppose I do fucking understand.
So fucking confused and disgusted
and wanting it to end
and looking for the blessing
of a quick way out.
Sets himself to a higher fucking
standard than our natures,
- And he wants execution 'cause he's failed.
- One minute!
What the fuck happened to two?
Talk about one person
fucking up another person's entire fucking day.
Wait.
I had best go over.
You linger awhile.
Do not think of thieving, huh?
Johnny,
produce that coal-oil-stinking suit.
Unless you'd rather get it for me.
I wish the fuck you two would
let me finish this the way I prefer.
Well, we wish to fuck you would find
something else to wish for.
Jesus Christ! I'm unarmed.
He's coming. He's detained.
- Getting dressed.
- Ain't it always a trial
picking out the gown best
conceals you fucking pissed yourself?
I recommend the six-shooter,
being this rifle's first recoil's
liable to knock you unconscious with pain.
Thank you.
Selfish cocksucker.
That's not to say should the situation
deteriorate,
you boys wouldn't open fire
from concealment, huh?
Hardware Jew at less
than full force,
now they'll be fucking quaking.
I regret the delay. I was sequestered.
Have been, one thing and another,
since last we met.
I also apologize for the stink.
Welcome change
from your usual odor of skunk.
I offer these,
and I hope you'll wear them a good long
fucking time in this fucking camp,
whosever fucking thumb we're under.
And where it come to me
just a few moments ago
that the reverend
Smith,may he rest his soul,
he was found on the road,
apparently murdered by heathens
just some months ago.
What he said on the subject of you,
"Mr. Bullock raises a camp up,
"and I hope he'll reside with us
"and improve
our general fucking atmosphere
"for a good long fucking time,
"even with all the personal complications
"and fucking disasters
that we all fucking have,
"and where, running away
"solves absolutely fucking nothing."
Did you find my hat?
Dolly!
Would you look
for the sheriff's hat?
Remember the reverend's half-dead face,
that cock-eyed look like he was the
victim of a lightning stroke, hmm?
May she sail it down or would
that be degrading?
- No.
- Toss it, Dolly.
I wish her aim
was as good with her thumb.
When the opportunity offers itself,
please return this to Mr. Bullock.
Yes, ma'am.
- Mr. Bullock.
- I don't want to talk about it.
As a practical matter,
self-censorship of the rigor which
obtains from this camp
so muzzles the press
as to make the first amendment
- a hollow superfluity.
- Thank you.
She can situate me.
All right.
The man says he's finished,
needs to get to his claim.
Four hours work, he's earned two bucks.
Says he wants to take it in pussy.
No, you want cash, Elmer,
to convert to pussy
at the Gem or Bella union.
All right, Joanie.
And let it be known in camp,
close to pussy as two bucks
will get a man in here
is a deep whiff walking past.
Hey, can I, uh, get one of those
and keep my money?
Have at it.
Fan some at him, Rosie, as he's leaving.
Mother, it's the ocean!
There's a rodent-looking creature
lamping one of your barrels.
Pay him no heed. That's the mayor.
You're tenacious, Merrick,
I'll fucking give you that.
Just tell me how it began.
After the conflict's genesis,
I'd lay it at cunt's doorstep.
Now, has cunt one "n" and two "t"s
or the other way around?
Jeez, Al.
You solicited the true account.
Within the limits of decency.
You want the decent truth, huh?
I choose to believe that
truth and decency need not be at odds.
Oh, you'll hear no argument from me.
Let it help me accumulate capital
or, at worst, not interfere,
the story is true and decent.
I would define as true and decent
in such endeavor, the facts rendered fully
within social standards and sensibilities
without bias or abridgement.
Why do I imagine a snake
swallowing its tail, huh?
Which is to say
the economic motive is but one strand
in the social tapestry my exemplary
account would weave.
Ass-fucking the dirt worshippers being another,
huh, as a pleasure beyond gain?
Now, now, now, now, I, uh...
Wait, was that your heathen imitation, huh?
Jump up and down a few times
and shout out "whoops,"
as in, "whoops, that ass-fucking hurts."
A more elevated perspective
would construe our conduct as white men
to be enacting a manifest destiny.
Whereas the warp, woof and fucking weave
of my story's tapestry
would foster the illusions of further
commerce, hmm?
"Tonight, throughout Deadwood
"heads may be laid to pillow
assuaged and reassured,
"for that purveyor for profit
"of everything sordid and vicious,
Al Swearengen,
"already beaten to a fare-thee-well
"earlier in the day by sheriff Bullock
"has returned to the sheriff
"the implements and ornaments
of his office.
"Without the tawdry walls of
Swearengen's saloon the Gem,
"decent citizens may pursue
"with a new and jaunty freedom
"all aspects of
christian commerce.
"In which connection, we
particularly recommend..."
There you throw in the names
of a few businesses
gave you good-sized adverts, huh?
May I come in with my boots?
Of course.
You haven't slept?
I waited for you.
To show the boy when he awakes,
I've got these back.
I saw that you installed a bundling
board in the bed upstairs.
I did.
I hope you don't mind that I removed it.
No.
"A full fair-mindedness
requires us also to report
"that within the Gem,
on Deadwood's main thoroughfare,
"comely whores,
decently priced liquor
"and the squarest games of
chance in the hills
"remain unabatedly
available at all hours,
"seven days a week."
Resynchronisation : Bigmac
Corrections : Nicephorus et KB
Transcript : RaceMan