( theme music playing )
Ellsworth:
HE'S DOWN THAT HOLE
FOR A FACT.
PITIFUL AS
YOU PURSUED IT,
YOU BETTER HOPE
HE AIN'T GOT SPACE ENOUGH
TO ROLL AROUND
HOLDING HIS SIDE,
AND BUST A GUT LAUGHING...
TELL ALL THE OTHER
WOODCHUCKS AT THE CLUB
THIS AFTERNOON.
HE MIGHT NOT EVEN
CALL IT AN ESCAPE.
MIGHT JUST CALL IT
HIS "MORNING'S ENTERTAINMENT."
Dan:
HEY!  HEY, ELLSWORTH!
HEY, DAN DORITY!
( whimpering )
WHERE'S
THE GREAT PROSPECTOR?
I GUESS BROM
SLEPT IN THIS MORNING.
SUPPOSE HIS ENTHUSIASM'S
ON THE WANE?
THAT'S ALWAYS
POSSIBLE.
HE SHOWS UP, YOU TELL HIM
I QUIT WAITIN'.
- SURE WILL.
- SEE YA AT THE GEM.
ALWAYS POSSIBLE.
( yells )
GO ON!
Reverend:
"THE EARTH IS THE LORD'S
AND THE FULLNESS THEREOF,
THE WORLD, AND THEY
THAT DWELL THEREIN.
FOR HE HATH FOUNDED IT
UPON THE SEAS,
AND ESTABLISHED IT
UPON THE FLOODS.
WHO SHALL ASCEND
INTO THE HILL
OF THE LORD?
- ( sneezing )
- OR WHO SHALL STAND
IN HIS HOLY PLACE?
HE THAT HATH
CLEAN HANDS,
AND A PURE HEART;
WHO HATH NOT
LIFTED UP HIS SOUL
- UNTO VANITY,
NOR SWORN DECEITFULLY.
- ( sneezes )
HE SHALL RECEIVE
THE BLESSING
FROM THE LORD,
AND JUSTICE
FROM THE GOD
OF HIS SALVATION.
LIFT UP YOUR HEADS,
O YE GATES
AND BE YE LIFTED UP
YE EVERLASTING DOORS,
AND THE KING OF GLORY
SHALL COME IN.
WHO IS THE KING
OF GLORY,
THE LORD OF HOSTS?
HE IS THE KING OF GLORY.
SELAH."
( man yells )
LET ME SEE THEM TITTIES!
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
( men hooting )
PULL THAT SIGN A LITTLE
TO THE RIGHT.
NO, NO, NO.
THAT WAY, THAT WAY.
( whispers )
"EVERYONE PROUD IN HEART
IS AN ABOMINATION
TO THE LORD.
THOUGH HAND JOIN IN HAND,
HE SHALL NOT BE UNPUNISHED.
- ( sneezing )
- BY MERCY AND TRUTH
IS INEQUITY PURGED.
AND BY THE FEAR OF THE LORD,
DO MEN DEPART FROM EVIL.
A MAN'S WAYS
PLEASE THE LORD
WHEN HE MAKETH
EVEN HIS ENEMIES TO BE
AT PEACE WITH HIM."
AMEN.
THANK YOU.
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
MAY WE EDIFY
MY READERS,
MR. BULLOCK?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT "EDIFY" MEANS.
- CAN WE TALK ABOUT
LAST NIGHT'S GUNFIGHT?
- NO.
WE CAN'T TALK
ABOUT LAST NIGHT'S
GUNFIGHT EITHER.
- WHAT THE FUCK?!
- E.B.: ALL'S I CAN
SPECULATE, AL,
IS WHOEVER THESE
BELLA UNION PEOPLE ARE,
THEY BOUGHT
ARTIE SIMPSON'S PLACE
ON THE QUIET.
PRE-ARRANGED
TURNIN' IT
INTO A JOINT.
THIS NO-GOOD
FUCKING JUDAS!
- HEY, FUCKNUT!
- JUST TAKE IT EASY, AL.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
HATCHING THIS?
I MADE A PRACTICAL
GODDAMN BUSINESS DECISION.
NO CHANCE
FOR ME TO MATCH
THEIR FUCKING OFFER?
YOU COULDN'T HAVE.
YOU'D HAVE KILLED ME
BEFORE YOU'D MATCHED.
BUT IT'S BETWEEN
YOU AND THEM NOW.
DRIVE CAREFUL,
COCKSUCKER!
- DON'T THINK I HAVEN'T
TAKEN PRECAUTION.
- ( gun cocks )
DON'T THINK
I DON'T KNOW YOUR MIND!
- I HATE TO PRESS YOU
ON THAT LOT, MR. SWEARENGEN.
- I AIN'T READY TO SETTLE YET.
- WE'RE ANXIOUSTO BUILD.
- IF YOU WANT AN ANSWER NOW,
IT'S NO.
TWO.
SAME FOR ME,
ONLY BETTER.
YEAH, THREE
TO THE DEALER.
THE DEALER DRAWS...
TRENCH MOUTH.
OPENER BETS.
WELL DAMN,
WILD BILL.
EVEN A STOPPED CLOCK'S
GOTTA BE RIGHT SOMETIME.
COMMON LAW
JUST SAYS YOU GONNA
WIN ONE SOONER OR LATER.
BUT I'M GONNA KEEP
PUSHIN' MY LUCK.
WHAT DO YOU GOT THERE?
$8.
ARE YOU READY
TO STAND ANY MORE CREDIT
TO WILD BILL, TOM?
I DIDN'T HEAR HIM
ASK FOR ANY.
YOU WANT ME TO JUST
BET EIGHT, BILL?
COVER MY CALL.
AW, BILL, I CAN'T
LET YOU PUT YOUR GUN UP.
THAT COLT'S WORTH
MORE THAN MY RAISE
BY A GOOD 40 BUCKS.
- ARE YOU TAKIN' THE BET?
- I TELL YOU WHAT,
I'LL ADD
40 BUCKS TO MY RAISE,
TO MAKE THE BET FAIR.
AND THEN 50 MORE,
IF YOU'LL
PUT UP A SET.
( laughs )
POT'S RIGHT.
WOULD A NINE-HIGH STRAIGHT
DO THE TRICK?
POT TO
THE CLUB FLUSH.
WELL, THAT'S ONE IN A ROW
FOR YOU, WILD BILL.
WHO'S HUNGRY?
WHAT IN THE HELL DAMN
TIME IS IT ANYWAY?
SURE YOU WANNA
QUIT PLAYING, JACK?
THE GAME'S ALWAYS
BETWEEN YOU AND GETTING
CALLED A CUNT.
MEETING ADJOURNED, FELLAS,
TAKE IT OUTSIDE.
THAT DROPPED EYE
OF YOURS
LOOKS LIKE THE HOOD
ON A CUNT TO ME, JACK.
WHEN YOU TALK,
YOUR MOUTH LOOKS LIKE
A CUNT MOVING.
I AIN'T GONNA GET
IN NO GUNFIGHT
WITH YOU, HICKOK.
BUT YOU WILL RUN
YOURCUNT MOUTHAT ME...
AND I WILL TAKE IT
TO PLAY POKER.
Tom:
I'LL TOTE UP ACCOUNTS,
MR. HICKOK.
WE'LL DO WHATEVER
BUSINESS WE NEED TO
NEXT YOU'RE IN.
ANYONE WANTS TO,
CAN FIND ME AT
THE GRAND CENTRAL.
- Jane: SHE'S WARM, ISN'T SHE?
- Charlie: SHE AIN'T TALK YET,
NEITHER.
THAT'S BESIDE THE POINT,
YOU SHUT UP!
SHE WILL GET A FEVER,
BEIN' WOLF BIT.
THE REASON WE RISKED
BRINGIN' HER INTO CAMP.
YOU DON'T NEED TO FEAR
THE SALOONKEEPER.
- HE'S NOT A DANGER
TO HER NO MORE.
- HE'S NOT?
SALOONKEEPER WORRIED
THAT THE LITTLE ONE
SAID ROAD AGENTS
KILLED HER PEOPLE--
WHO THE ROAD AGENTS
MIGHT SAY THEY WORKED FOR.
MEANING HIM?
HE TOOK A DIFFERENT
APPROACH TO THE PROBLEM.
SHE WOULD
DO BETTER INDOORS.
I TOLD JANE SHE COULD
TAKE MY ROOM WITH
THE LITTLE ONE,
AND I'D MOVE
BACK IN WITH BILL.
I WILL NOT STAY
IN NO FUCKIN' HOTEL!
THEY WON'T GIVE ME A ROOM!
YOU TWO KEEP
YOUR VOICES DOWN.
WHAT'D I SAY
ABOUT NOISE?
HE SNORES THE WHOLE
FUCKIN' NIGHT!
SNORING'S PAST
A PERSON'S CONTROL.
I WAS A FIELD NURSE
DURING THE WAR,
AT SHILOH
AND SECOND MANASSAS.
THAT WAS
A GOOD DEAL
OF VIOLENCE.
IS THAT WHEN YOU
GOT YOUR CALLING?
YES, IT WAS, SIR.
OUT OF THAT CRUCIBLE--
OUT OF ALL THAT HORROR,
TO COME TO GOD'S GRACE.
A MAN'S HEART
DEVISETH HIS WAY,
BUT THE LORD
DIRECTETH HIS STEPS.
HE DIRECTETH
ALL OUR STEPS,
MR. BULLOCK.
ALL OF US.
IF YOU'RE PREACHING
AT ME, REVEREND,
YOU NEED
TO PUT SOME MORE
LIGHT ON THE TEXT.
IF I AM
PREACHING AT YOU, SIR,
I DO YOU A DISSERVICE.
GOOD MORNING,
MR. STAR.
REVEREND.
Seth:
DID WE GET THE LOT?
CAN WE START BUILDING?
- THE REVEREND'S COME TO HELP.
- WE'RE STILL HANGIN' FIRE.
- WHAT'S THE DAMN HOLDUP?
- NEW GAMBLING OUTFIT
COME INTO TOWN.
- TIME WASN'T RIGHT
TO PUSH HIM TO A DECISION.
- I GOT ALL THE LUMBER CUT.
- AND I WARNED YOU
THAT WAS PREMATURE.
- YOU SAID 98%
AFTER YOUR LAST CONVERSATION
WITH THAT SON OF A BITCH.
98 IS NOT 100.
GOD DAMN IT!
- GOOD DAY, SIRS.
- Sol: GOOD DAY, REVEREND.
Jane:
I SAID THEY'D FIND
A WAY TO STOP ME.
IF IT'S RAISING ROOM RATES,
YOU HAVE TO GO AHEAD
AND RAISE 'EM.
RATES AREN'T THE ONLY FACTOR.
THERE'S A WAITING LIST
FOR OCCUPANCY.
YOU UNDERTAKER-LOOKING
SON OF A BITCH.
THIS LITTLE GIRL'S DOCTOR
ORDERED HER TO LIVE INDOORS,
AND I'M ASSIGNED
TO CHANGE HER DRESSINGS!
A SAD STORY, THAT'S NONE
OF MY AFFAIR, "MADAM,"
IF I GUESS
YOUR SEX CORRECT.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM,
INNKEEPER?
MR. HICKOK.
LITTLE ONE TOOK
FEVER IN THAT WAGON
LAST NIGHT, BILL.
AND I THOUGHT JANE AND HER
COULD STAY IN MY ROOM
AND I'D MOVE
BACK IN WITH YOU.
E.B.:
I'M NOT IN OPPOSITION, SIR.
JUST THE OPPOSITE.
WHO WOULDN'T
WANT TO ACCOMMODATE
A SICK GIRL?
BUT THE SIMPSON HOTEL'S
CLOSED ITS DOORS.
IF MR. UTTER'S VACATING,
SHOULDN'T THESE PEOPLE THAT HAVE
BEEN TRYING ME ALL MORNING
GET FIRST CALL?
ISN'T THAT
SIMPLE FAIRNESS?
HE DON'T GIVE
FUCK ALL FOR FAIRNESS!
HE JUST DON'T WANT ME IN HERE.
HOW 'BOUT IF
HE STAYS IN HIS ROOM
AND THE LADY
MOVES IN WITH ME?
THAT WAY NO ONE'S
VACATING NOTHING.
THAT WOULD OUTFLANK
THE CHECKOUT ISSUE.
BUT IT MIGHT RAISE
QUESTIONS OF DECORUM.
- WITH WHO?
- NO ONE OF CONSEQUENCE,
I SUPPOSE.
LET HER IN.
I'M GOING TO GET
SOME BREAKFAST.
THERE WILL BE
A RATE ADJUSTMENT!
GOOD MORNING.
I'VE HEARD THE STORIES, MADAM,
I TELL YOU THAT AT FLAGFALL.
YOU ARE HERE
ON SUFFERANCE.
KISS MY ASS!
COCKSUCKERS.
WHERE WERE THEY
WHEN DAN AND ME WERE
CHOPPING TREES
IN THIS GULCH?
HANDS ALL BLISTERED,
BUCKTOOTH FUCKING BEAVERS
ROLLING AROUND IN THE CREEK,
SLAPPING THEIR TAILS
IN THE WATER
LIKE WE WAS HIRED
ENTERTAINMENT.
I'D HAVE PAID A NICKEL
TO SEE YOU CHOPPING WOOD.
YEAH.
DON'T THINK I WASN'T
BLOW FOR BLOW WITH DAN.
I CAN PLAY THAT SHIT
WHEN I HAVE TO.
BUT I'VE BEEN
TO CHICAGO TOO.
HOW DO I LOOK?
LIKE CHRIST CRUCIFIED.
Al:
GUESS THIS AIN'T
A HOTEL NO MORE.
COME SEE US TONIGHT
WHEN WE OPEN,
WE'LL FIND YOU
A PLACE TO LAY DOWN.
AND SOMEONE TO KEEP
YOUR FEET WARM.
I'M AL SWEARENGEN.
I OWN THE JOINT
ACROSS THE STREET.
- Man: THE GEM?
- THAT'S IT.
CY TOLLIVER, AL.
ED SAWYER,
JOANIE STUBBS.
YOU PEOPLE MUST'VE
TRAINED WITH THE HEATHENS.
YEAH, YOU KNOW, YOU COME UP
ON US UNBEKNOWNST.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
IN CAMP, AL?
THIS YEAR, SINCE MARCH.
I WAS HERE LAST YEAR TOO,
BUT THE FUCKING CAVALRY
DROVE US OUT.
PUT ALL THE WHITES OUT,
DIDN'T THEY?
DEEP FUCKING THINKERS
IN WASHINGTON PUT FORWARD
THAT POLICY.
THIS YEAR THOUGH, SO MANY
SOLDIERS DESERTING TO PROSPECT,
GAVE UP THE GHOST,
LET US ALL BACK IN.
AND OF COURSE,
CUSTER SORTED OUT
THE SIOUX FOR US,
SO NOW WE'RE ALL AS SAFE
AS AT OUR MOTHERS' TITS.
DID A JOB FOR OUR SIDE,
DIDN'T HE, AL?
Al:
HOW ABOUT THAT LONG-HAIRED
FUCKING BLOWHARD, HUH?
I'LL TELL YOU THIS, SON,
YOU CAN MARK MY WORDS,
CRAZY HORSE WENT
INTO LITTLE BIGHORN,
BOUGHT HIS PEOPLE ONE GOOD,
LONG-TERM ASS FUCKING.
YOU DO NOT WANT TO BE
A DIRT-WORSHIPPING HEATHEN
FROM THIS FUCKING
POINT FORWARD.
- PARDON MY FRENCH.
- OH, I SPEAK FRENCH.
WELL, HERE WE ARE,
SETTLING THE WORLD'S PROBLEMS.
AND I'VE BEEN WONDERING, CY,
UM, PERHAPS WE SHOULD
TALK ABOUT
OUR AREAS OF OVERLAP
SO WE'RE NOT
AT EACH OTHER'S THROATS.
- GIVE ME
A FOR INSTANCE, AL.
- UH, WOMEN.
WOULD WE WANT
TO AGREE ON RATES?
WELL, FAR AS PUSSY, AL,
WE'LL WANT TO LET THE MARKET
SORT ITSELF OUT.
SOUNDS TO ME LIKE I'M
UP AGAINST SPECIALTY ACTS.
HOW ABOUT TABLE GAMES?
ANY OVERLAP THERE?
WE'LL BE FEATURING
CRAPS, AL.
I PLAYED THAT
IN CHICAGO.
I DON'T
OFFER IT MYSELF,
GETS THESE HOOPLE-HEADS
CONFUSED, HMM?
THAT'S ONE AREA
OF OVERLAP AVOIDED.
- WHAT ABOUT FARO?
- WE'LL HAVE IT.
THAT DECISION
HARD AND FAST?
I DON'T SEE OVERLAP
BEING A PROBLEM, AL,
EVEN WHERE WE DUPLICATE.
WE'RE OFFERING
DIFFERENT ATMOSPHERES.
YOU'RE A PIONEERING TYPE,
A TRAILBLAZER TYPE.
YOU'RE GONNA DRAW
A TRAILBLAZING ELEMENT.
MEANING I GET THE ONES
THAT DON'T WASH?
MUST CUT THROUGH THE STINK
THOUGH WHEN THEY WALK IN WITH
THOSE SACKS FULL OF GOLD.
OH, THE MONEY SPENDS,
DEFINITELY.
ANYWAYS, THANKS FOR
THE NEIGHBORLY VISIT.
YEAH, GOOD TO MEET YOU.
VERY GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
YOU'RE OPENING
AT 8:00, HUH?
THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE AIMING AT.
8:00.
GOOD FOR YOU.
WOULDN'T SET
A FIRE RIGHT AWAY.
COME TO CASE US
THOUGH.
HE WOULD SET A FIRE.
THE WAY YOU TELL IT,
MISTER,
THE MAN DIDN'T SELL YOU
THAT CLAIM HOLDING A GUN
TO YOUR HEAD.
FRANKLY, MR. HICKOK,
BEING A NOVICE
IN THESE MATTERS,
I WAS DUPED.
AND NOW
THE SELLER'S DISAPPEARED.
YOU CHECKED INTO HIS ROOM.
IT SOUND LIKE
YOU'RE UP SHIT'S CREEK.
THE SELLER HAD ACCOMPLICES,
GENTLEMEN.
MEN OF-- WHAT PASSES
FOR POSITION IN THIS PLACE.
I WOULD PAY A HANDSOME BOUNTY,
IF THEY WERE BROUGHT TO MAKE
RESTITUTIONS.
SORRY YOU LOST
YOUR MONEY, MISTER.
BUT I AIN'T FOR HIRE
TO ROB IT BACK.
I MAKE NO TERMS
AS TO METHOD.
YOU DON'T FIGURE
A GOOD TALKING-TO
WOULD DO THE TRICK?
I'M NOT LEAVING CAMP
WITHOUT MY MONEY.
MISTER, THAT FELLA YOU SAID
HAD MY ROOM BEFORE ME?
A MAN NAMED TIM DRISCOLL,
YES, PURE CHARLATAN.
FRESH STAIN ON THE FLOOR
WHEN I MOVED IN.
HE MAY HAVE CHECKED OUT
SHORT A USEFUL AMOUNT
OF BLOOD.
IT WOULDN'T SURPRISE ME
IN THE LEAST.
THAT WOULD MAKE
THESE ACCOMPLICES
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
DANGEROUS PEOPLE
TO DEAL WITH.
YES, I QUITE TAKE YOUR POINT--
NO HONOR AMONG THIEVES.
WELL...
THANKS FOR YOUR TIME.
I'LL PURSUE MY REMEDIES
IN SOME OTHER FASHION.
I DON'T THINK
HE TOOK YOUR POINT...
QUITE.
I THINK HE QUITE
MISSED IT.
I BELIEVE
I'LL PASS OUT, CHARLIE.
I GUESS YOU WERE
PLAYING POKER ALL NIGHT, HUH?
YES, SIR.
WHEN WE WAS COMING INTO CAMP
I SAW THAT MONTANA FELLA
YOU SEEM TO LIKE.
BULLOCK HAD MY BACK
AGAIN LAST NIGHT.
WELL, HE WAS SEEING
TO THE RESULT THIS MORNING.
MAN HAS AN ACTIVE
CONSCIENCE.
WHAT WOULD YOU THINK OF US
AND HIM AND HIS FRIEND
- HAVING DINNER TONIGHT?
- WHY?
PEOPLE GOTTA EAT,
DON'T THEY, BILL?
AND MAYBE YOU'D ENJOY
SITTING WITH SOMEONE
WHO WASN'T LOOKING
TO BEAT YOU AT CARDS.
OR BLOW
YOUR FUCKING HEAD OFF.
TRUE ENOUGH.
MARK ME DOWN
FOR A YES.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHO DID THEIR LEGWORK.
YOU HIT THE NAIL
SQUARE, AL.
WHOEVER WENT BETWEEN THEM
BELLA UNION PEOPLE
AND ARTIE SIMPSON
WOULD BE A PRIME SOURCE
OF INFORMATION.
DO NOT REPEAT
BACK TO ME
WHAT I JUST SAID
IN DIFFERENT FUCKING WORDS!
I WANNA KNOW
WHO CUT THE CHEESE.
I'LL TELL YOU THIS
FOR OPENERS--
WE ARE GONNA SET OFF
AN AREA ON THE BALCONY.
AND GOD HELP
WHOEVER DOESN'T USE IT,
BECAUSE THE NEXT STINK
I HAVE TO SMELL IN THIS OFFICE,
AND WHOEVER DOESN'T ADMIT TO IT
IS GOING OUT THE WINDOW,
INTO THE MUCK,
ONTO THEIR FUCKING HEADS
AND WE'LL SEE HOW THEY LIKE
FARTING FROM THAT POSITION,
OKAY?
"I HATE TO PRESS YOU
ON THE LOT, MR. SWEARENGEN."
WOULDN'T THAT
BE A SETUP?
IF THEY WERE ALL
OF THE SAME FUCKING PARTY?
YOU THINK THEM
HARDWARE GUYS AND HICKOK
MIGHT BE THE ADVANCE PARTY
FOR THEM SALOON OPERATORS?
YOU DID THE SAME FUCKING THING
I TOLD YOU NOT TO.
GET THEM TOO, SAY I'M READY
TO CONCLUDE ON THEIR OFFER.
STOP AT WU'S ON THE WAY.
TELL HIM EITHER HE FEEDS
HIS PIGS PERSIMMON PHIL TONIGHT,
OR I SERVE THEM
RAW LOIN OF ORIENTAL.
I THOUGHT YOU FORGOT
ALL ABOUT THAT, AL.
I THOUGHT IT JUST SORTA
SLIPPED THROUGH THE CRACKS.
THE FARO DUDE
AT THE NEW JOINT,
DOPE-FIEND.
TALL GUY,
SKANKLY RED BEARD.
YOU WANT ME TO GET NEXT
TO HIM, MR. SWEARENGEN?
LET ME TAKE A FEW DOLLARS,
I'LL GO PLAY AT HIS TABLE.
STOP HUSTLING.
I'LL GIVE YOU DOPE WHEN YOU
BRING THAT COCKSUCKER HERE.
HE'S AS GOOD AS
STANDING IN FRONT OF YOU,
MR. SWEARENGEN.
NO.
STICK AROUND.
HELP ME MEASURE
WHERE THEIR LOYALTIES LIE.
THESE HARDWARE GUYS?
THE BURDEN FALLS
ON ME, ALMA.
THAT MUCH IS NOW CLEAR.
DO YOU THINK THERE'S
ANY POSSIBILITY
THAT MR. HICKOK
MIGHT RECONSIDER?
NONE.
NOR WAS I SURE THAT,
IF HE'D AGREED,
THE MAN BEFORE ME
AT THAT BREAKFAST TABLE
WAS EQUAL TO THE TASK.
PROMISE ME ONE THING
THEN, BROM.
DON'T ASK ME
TO AMEND MY PURPOSE.
THAT BEFORE SEEING
MR. SWEARENGEN,
YOU TAKE YOUR WALK.
TO CLEAR MY HEAD
AND REFLECT?
IF ONLY TO PERFECT
YOUR ARGUMENTS.
I SEE.
I ACCEPT
THE SUGGESTION
AND A FEELING
FOR ITS AUTHOR.
THANK YOU.
IF I'M STOOPED WHEN
NEXT YOU SEE ME, ALMA,
IT WON'T BE WORRY
WEIGHING ME DOWN BUT BAGS
OF OUR RECOVERED GOLD.
TAKE YOUR WALK, DEAR.
IT'S HICKOK, ALMA.
- UNCONSCIOUS.
- I SEE.
I TAKE THIS AS PROOF
MY RESERVATIONS WERE
WELL FOUNDED.
( door closes )
TOO CONSIDERATE
TO DISTURB US?
WOULDN'T HAVE TRUCK
WITH THAT...
ROOM CLERK GHOUL TO GET
LET INTO CHARLIE'S,
I'D RATHER SLEEP
IN THE FUCKING HALLWAY,
THAT'S THE KIND OF MAN HE IS.
AW! I OWE YOU
ANOTHER FUCKING PENNY.
I OWE YOU ANOTHER ONE.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU
EVER SHOULD LEARN ENGLISH,
EVERY MIND FOUL.
SPARE YOU KNOWING
HOW IGNORANT PEOPLE ARE.
BUT THEN I COULDN'T
TELL YOU ABOUT BILL...
SLEEPING IN THE HALLWAY
OUT OF THOUGHT FOR OTHERS.
AND I KNOW SOME OTHER
FUCKING STORIES TOO--
OWE YOU
ANOTHER PENNY.
Seth:
LOOK AT
THAT JACKASS.
HELP YOU
WITH ANYTHING?
I TELL YOU WHO'S BEING DONE
A FAVOR AT THIS EXACT MOMENT.
OR WOULD YOU CARE
TO TAKE A GUESS?
A FAVOR
IN THIS TENT.
I'D GUESS IT'S YOU
DOING ONE FOR YOURSELF,
CONSIDERING
THE QUALITY GOODS.
THE FAVOR HERE'S BEING DONE
FOR WILD BILL-FUCKING-HICKOK.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
'CAUSE IF I'M OUT
PROSPECTING IN THE HILLS,
THEN HE AIN'T GETTING
HIS JUST DESSERTS--
AT THE POKER TABLE,
OR OTHERWISE.
DON'T ASK ME WHAT I MEAN
BY THE LAST PART.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I SAID YOU'D DO
BETTER NOT ASKING.
GET OUTTA HERE.
I'LL BUY THIS ONE.
WHAT'S THE PRICE
ON THAT?
YOU AIN'T
BUYING NOTHING.
I KNOW YOU.
- WHERE I KNOW YOU FROM?
- CAN'T HELP YOU
WITH THAT, PARTNER.
YOU FOLLOW HIM AROUND.
HEY!
( groans )
THAT TENT'S
SHUT TO YOU.
DON'T COME
BACK THERE.
FUCK YOU...
AND ANY PLANS I MIGHT'VE
HAD TO BUY SOMETHING,
OR PROSPECT.
I'D BE LOUSY
AT RETAIL.
I GUARANTEE YOU
THAT MUCH.
WOULDN'T HAVE
THE PATIENCE FOR IT.
I'M NOT SURE HOW MUCH
FUTURE HE'S GOT.
ANYWAYS, I WANT
TO TELL YOU FELLAS,
SEVERAL DAYS I'LL BE
GOING BACK TO CHEYENNE--
TO TRY AND SECURE
A MAIL ROUTE.
I OPERATE A FREIGHT BUSINESS
OUTTA THERE.
YOU NEED RESUPPLY, I'LL BE
BRINGING SEVERAL WAGONS BACK.
THAT'S GOOD TO KNOW.
AND, UH, I WAS, UH,
HALF WONDERING TOO IF...
IF YOU'D WANT TO JOIN
BILL AND ME FOR DINNER.
TONIGHT
OR SOME OTHER TIME.
LET'S DO IT TONIGHT.
I FEEL LIKE I SHOULD'VE
BRUNG POSIES.
AFTERNOON.
CAN I HELP YOU
FIND SOMETHING?
MR. SWEARENGEN
WANTS TO SEE YA.
I ONLY HOPE YOU UNDERSTAND
ME BEING SHORT WITH YOU
- OUT IN THE STREET
THIS MORNING.
- YOU HAD A LOT ON YOUR MIND.
I HAD A LOT OF WHAT'S LEFT
OF MY FUCKING MIND,
THESE NEW INTERESTS
COMING IN.
I'D ONLY HOPE YOU UNDERSTAND,
AND SEE MY THINKING
IN NOT SELLING YOU
THAT LOT OUTRIGHT.
WHAT'S YOUR
THINKING TODAY?
GETS DEAD SET
AT THE FUCKING POINT,
WHICH I LIKE
IN MOST SITUATIONS.
DO YOU KNOW THESE
NEW SALOON INTERESTS?
- ARE YOU ACQUAINTED
WITH THEM AT ALL?
- NOPE.
NOT THEM
AND NOT BILL HICKOK.
AND ALL WE WANT TO DO IS
RUN A HARDWARE BUSINESS.
I HAVE GOT
TO BE SATISFIED.
SEE, I'M THE SIMPLE-TYPE
COCKSUCKER
THAT WHEN HE SEES LIGHTNING,
READIES FOR THUNDER.
AND TAKES THE THUNDER IF IT
COMES FROM THE SAME STORM.
WHY WOULDN'T YA,
MR. SWEARENGEN?
THANK YOU FOR SAYING THAT,
EVEN IF YOU DON'T
FUCKING MEAN IT.
WHAT WOULD MAKE YOU
COMFORTABLE SELLING
TO US?
1,000.
PLUS RIGHT OF FIRST REFUSAL
ON ANY FURTHER SALE.
ACCEPTED.
AND RIGHT TO BUY BACK
AT THE ORIGINAL PRICE,
- PLUS THE COST OF
YOUR IMPROVEMENTS.
- ACCEPTED.
NO GAMBLING
ON THE FUCKING PREMISES.
NO ASSOCIATION OF ANY KIND
WITH THESE BELLA UNION
COCKSUCKERS.
- ACCEPT--
- WE CAN'T SELL 'EM
OUR GOODS?
NO.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THAT?
ACCEPTED.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
OR, THEY COULD BUY
YOUR WARES
IN YOUR NORMAL COURSE
OF YOUR NORMAL
FUCKING BUSINESS.
I'D GUESS IT'S
OKAY TO TRANSACT
WITH THESE COCKSUCKERS.
- WE CAN SELL
THEM OUR WARES?
- YOUR NORMAL WARES.
NO GAMBLING,
WHORING OR WHISKEY
ON THE FUCKING PREMISES
IS THE CHIEF FUCKING POINT.
AGREED.
I SPIT IN MY HAND.
WILL THAT DRIVE YOU
SCREAMING INTO THE HILLS?
THE THOUSAND
WOULD BE NICE.
Sol:
20, 40, 60, 80, 100.
A HAPPY OUTCOME.
20, 40, 60, 80, 200.
...A SHOOTING
EXHIBITION.
THAT IDEA FOR
MR. HICKOK HAS BEEN
HAD AND ACTED UPON
BY A FEW PEOPLE
BEFORE YOU.
AND, THEN AFTERWARD,
WE CUT THE BULLETS OUT
AND THE FUCKING PLAYING CARDS
HE WAS USING AS TARGETS.
THAT'S THE POINT
I WAS TRYING TO GET TO.
HOW ABOUT THE TREE BARK
BEHIND THE FUCKING
PLAYING CARD TARGETS, HUH?
HELL, YEAH, WE'LL SELL
THE FUCKING BARK.
- WHAT DO YOU SAY, FELLAS?
- WE GOT OUR LOT.
HOORAY FOR YOU BOYS.
TWO DAYS FOR ME
TO GET THE WORD OUT.
10¢ TO WATCH,
AND WE'LL CHARGE
FOR THE SOUVENIRS.
AIN'T TAKING YOU UP
ON THAT, MISTER.
- ANOTHER 20 FOR YOU
ON THE QUIET.
- NO.
AND THE TALK
BETWEEN US IS OVER.
SOAP!
SOAP WITH
A PRIZE INSIDE.
SOAP!
GOT THAT MAN
TO SELL, HUH?
NEVER HAD TO STRAIN SO
TO SPEND $1,000.
WILL YOU LET US
OUTTA DINNER?
YOU'D AS SOON
NOT DO IT, HUH?
WE'D LIKE TO GET
TO BUILDING.
WILL WE SEE YOU TOMORROW
FOR BREAKFAST?
SURE.
MAYBE WE'LL CATCH BILL
COMING BACK FROM CARDS.
WELL, CONGRATULATIONS
TO BOTH OF YOU.
THANKS, MR. UTTER.
- THANK YOU.
- GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE IN BUSINESS.
HUH?
MY GOODNESS.
MY HEAVENS.
MY GOODNESS GRACIOUS.
HEAVENS TO BETSY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, HIRAM,
EVER SEEN A CRAPS LAYOUT?
- MY FIRST.
- SHALL I SHOW YOU
HOW IT WORKS?
I MIGHT
COULD FOLLOW.
I DO READ
AND CIPHER.
WELL, YOU'RE WELL
IN ADVANCE OF THE PACK.
TELL ME
WHAT THIS SAYS.
C-O-M-E.
IT SAYS "COME."
YOU REALLY CAN READ,
CAN'T YA?
I WASN'T
RAISED TO LIE.
( softly )
I'M LIABLE TO BE
KILLED, EDDIE.
HE'S ON MY SCENT
AND CLOSING.
CURIOUS TACTICS,
YOUR COMING HERE THEN, E.B.
TO REMIND YOU SECRECY
IS OF THE ESSENCE.
AL SWEARENGEN'S
A DANGEROUS MAN.
LET HIM DOUBT
THOSE HE'S TRUSTED,
THIS CAMP WILL
RUN RED WITH BLOOD.
ARGUES FOR RAISING
YOUR ROOM RATES,
AT LEAST MAKE THE GAME
WORTH THE CANDLE.
I WONDER HOW CAVALIER
YOUR ATTITUDE WILL BE...
WITH A PIG GNAWING
THROUGH YOUR VITALS.
BET ON ME
SCREAMING FOR MERCY.
I TURNED DOWN
YOUR OFFER TO BUY
AND POINTED YOU
TO ARTIE SIMPSON.
THE WHOLE DAMN EXTENT
OF MY INVOLVEMENT.
AND I'M STARING
STRAIGHT AT EXTINCTION.
HE MAY GET YOU ANYWAY, E.B.,
BUT IF YOUR NERVE GOES,
HE'LL GET YOU SURE.
NOW, DOPE IS NOT MY OWN
PREFERRED FORM OF RELAXATION,
BUT I DID TRY THE SHIT
AND BELIEVE ME...
I NEARLY CONVERTED.
JIMMY SAID YOU'D DO RIGHT
BY ME, MR. SWEARENGEN.
EVERYTHING...
THAT GOES ON
AT THAT PLACE.
I'LL GIVE YOU
A DAILY REPORT.
YEAH.
HE'S THE TYPE
I'D WANNA KNOW ABOUT.
JUST LEFT YOUR JOINT.
JUDAS GOAT-LOOKING FELLA.
HEY, YOU SEE HIM?
COYOTE-MOVING TYPE?
- YOU SEE HIM?
- THE SHORT GUY?
YEAH, WITH HIS PAWS ALWAYS DAMP
LIKE A JUST SHIT FUCKING TURD.
THAT'S THE TYPE
I WANNA KNOW ABOUT.
COMINGS, GOINGS,
ANY DEALINGS WITH YOUR BOSSES.
I'LL KEEP A SPECIAL EYE
ON HIM.
- AL?
- YEAH.
THAT CHERRY NEW YORK DUDE
- IS DOWNSTAIRS
ASKING FOR YA.
- NO GOOD.
CHARLIE HIM
THE FUCK OUT.
HE KEEPS TALKING
ABOUT THE PINKERTONS.
DAN DORITY,
THOUGHT YOU WERE DEAD.
YES, I DIDN'T GO
TO THE CLAIM THIS MORNING.
YOU SHOULD'VE
TOLD HIM.
I'VE HAD HIM HERE
THE LAST SEVERAL HOURS
IN TEARS.
DAN, LOOK!
- HE'S ALIVE.
- THANK GOD.
Brom:
YES, I CHOSE NOT
TO GO TO THE CLAIM.
WHISKEY, BROM?
SNATCH?
FRANKLY, AL, I'M HERE
TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
AND I'M NOT
TO BE DISTRACTED.
THEN PROCEED, MY SON,
SPEAK FRANKLY.
WE NEEDN'T REACH
THE QUESTION OF WHETHER
MY CLAIM
HAS "PINCHED OUT,"
AS THE SAYING GOES.
OR WHETHER IT WAS A SHAM
PROPOSITION TO BEGIN WITH.
LET'S JUST SAY, I'VE LOST
FAITH IN THE PROPERTY.
- Al: HAVE YOU?
-AND I WANT MY $20,000 BACK.
IN THE HEAT
YOU'VE CONFUSED ME
WITH TIM DRISCOLL.
I THINK WE'RE BOTH AWARE,
AL, THAT DRISCOLL'S
NO LONGER IN CAMP.
AND BECAUSE I BELIEVE YOU
COLLUDED WITH TIM DRISCOLL
AND PERHAPS WERE IN CAHOOTS
WITH OTHER PARTIES AS WELL,
I REQUIRE SATISFACTION
FROM YOU.
IT'S THE HEAT
AGAIN, BROM.
I DON'T COLLUDE
AND I DON'T CAHOOT.
AL, ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH THE PINKERTON AGENCY?
- WHY?
- PURSUING ITS
BUSINESS INTERESTS,
MY FAMILY'S HAD
SEVERAL OCCASIONS TO
ENGAGE THE PINKERTONS.
WE MAINTAIN
FRIENDLY RELATIONS.
I'D PREFER WE TWO
SETTLE THIS AS GENTLEMEN,
BUT IF NEED BE,
THE PINKERTONS CAN BE MADE
A PARTY TO OUR DISPUTE.
HAS HE ASKED YOU
TO RECONNOITER THE RIMS
WITH HIM AT ALL?
NEVER.
DID HE ASK TO
AND YOU REFUSED?
DIDN'T GET AROUND
TO IT, AL.
I THOUGHT HE WAS IN
FOR THE LONG HAUL.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT SPECIFICALLY?
THE GOLD YOU FOUND
WASHED DOWN FROM SOMEWHERE,
THAT'S THE LAW OF GRAVITY.
AND YOUR CLAIM RUNS
RIM TO RIM THE WIDTH
OF THE FUCKING GULCH,
SO THE ORIGINAL DEPOSIT
THE GOLD YOU FOUND
WASHED DOWN FROM
IS LIKELY ON YOUR CLAIM ABOVE,
NEAR ONE OF THE RIMS.
THAT'S WHAT YOU FEEL
I SHOULD RECONNOITER?
FIRST PLACE THE PINKERTONS
WOULD LOOK.
UNLESS I'M
FUCKING WRONG.
NO, THAT'S HOW
THEY OPERATE.
SO IF HE ASKS YOU,
WOULD YOU RECONNOITER
THE RIMS WITH HIM?
AL, I WAITED OUT THERE
ALL MORNING FOR HIM--
- IS THAT A YES
OR A NO?
- YEAH.
I'D BE HAPPY TO RECONNOITER
THE RIMS WITH HIM.
AND IF DAN'S AND MINE
GOOD FAITH RECONNOITERING
DON'T SHOW THE SOURCE
OF THE GOLD,
DO YOU THEN MAKE
RESTITUTION, AL?
OR DO I HAVE RECOURSE
TO THE AGENCY?
IF AT THAT POINT YOU ASK,
YES, I'LL MAKE RESTITUTION,
ALL RIGHTS AND WRONGS ASIDE,
'CAUSE YOU'VE GOT ME
BY THE FUCKING BALLS.
LET ME GO HOME
AND CHANGE.
UH, DO I NEED
CLIMBING GEAR?
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO BRING A PICKAXE.
GOODBYE, THEN.
MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
AN ACCIDENT.
AIN'T THIS
A PRETTY PICTURE?
I CAN'T WAKE PEOPLE
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
PASSED OUT
IN THE PUBLIC HALLWAY.
HE NEVER KNOCKED
ON THE DAMN DOOR.
BY THE TIME I LOOKED OUT
HE WAS SNORING.
DID YOU WANT ME
TO DRAG HIM IN
BY THE DAMN HEELS?
I SAY LEAVE HIM WHERE HE IS
AND GO ABOUT YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
HE'S UP.
I HOPE YOU'RE HAPPY.
CONGRATULATIONS,
COCKSUCKER.
DINNER'S BEEN
CANCELED, BILL.
ALL RIGHT.
THEM TWO FELLAS GOT
THEIR LOT BOUGHT
AND THEY'RE STARTED
RIGHT AHEAD
WITH THE BUILDING.
SURE.
I WAS THAT SHOCKED SEEING
YOU SLEEPING OUT HERE, BILL.
FIRST SAW YOU
MAYBE AN HOUR AGO.
DIDN'T WANT TO DISTURB ME
AND THE CHILD, CHARLIE.
HE MUST'VE SOUGHT ENTRY
TO YOUR ROOM, WHEREVER
THE FUCK YOU WERE AT.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW WHERE
THAT GODDAMNED INNKEEP WAS!
HE COULD'VE LET BILL IN.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
LET ME SLEEP, ARE YA?
I'D WOULD HAVE
LET YOU SLEEP AS LONG
AS YOU WANTED.
( sighs )
- HOW'S THAT LITTLE ONE?
- GOOD.
SHE'S NAPPING.
MORE THAN I CAN
SAY FOR YOU.
ARE THOSE HARDWARE BOYS
LOOKING FOR EXTRA HANDS?
IN A ROUNDABOUT WAY.
I DON'T AGREE
WITH THIS PLAN.
RECONNOITERING THE RIMS
IS EXACTLY THE SORT OF
DUE DILIGENCE THAT FATHER
WOULD ASK IF I'D DONE.
NOR DO I SEE THE NEED
TO INVOLVE YOUR FATHER.
IT WAS MY MENTION
OF THE PINKERTONS, ALMA, WHICH
BROUGHT AL SWEARENGEN AROUND
AND THE PINKERTONS
CAN'T COME INTO THIS
UNLESS FATHER DOES AS WELL.
I WOULDN'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE TO LOOK FOR THEM.
OUGHT WE POSSIBLY TO TAKE
A DIFFERENT VIEW OF THIS?
CONSIDER
WE'VE HAD AN ADVENTURE
COSTING US $20,000
AND LET MATTERS
REST THERE.
LET THEM REST?
YES.
IF YOU STILL WANT
TO SEE MORE OF THE WEST,
LET'S GO NOW
AND SEE IT.
OR ELSE RETURN
TO NEW YORK.
I DON'T THINK
WE SHOULD LINGER HERE.
I HAVE NO ABIDING AFFECTION
FOR THIS CAMP.
BUT I WON'T LEAVE
WITHOUT MY MONEY.
WHY DO YOU TAKE
THAT MEDICINE?
YOU KNOW WHY,
TO RELIEVE MY HEADACHES.
THE OTHER DAY I HAD
A WHOPPER OF A HEADACHE
AND I SAMPLED A BIT.
I WOULD HARDLY CALL
THE DULL, NUMB,
FLOATING FEELING
I EXPERIENCED "RELIEF."
PERHAPS THE SEXES EXPERIENCE
THE MEDICINE DIFFERENTLY?
IN ANY CASE, I, UM...
HOPE YOU FEEL BETTER.
THANK YOU.
( people chatting )
( E.B. clearing throat )
E.B.
THANKS FOR COMING.
WHISTLE--
( whistles )
AND I'M UNDERFOOT.
LOYAL AS A DAMN DOG.
I TELL YOU WHAT, AL,
YOU GOT A HELLUVA NICE
TURNOUT DOWNSTAIRS.
HELL OF A NICE
MONDAY CROWD.
E.B.:
JESUS CHRIST
ALMIGHTY!
- GO AHEAD IN, E.B.
- I'M NOT IN DUTCH,
AM I, AL?
GO AHEAD IN.
Man:
MR. HICKOK?
I'M NATHAN GORDON.
I COME UP FROM
MURFREESBOROUGH AND...
- HOW ARE YOU, NATHAN?
- FINE.
SEE, I'LL TELL YOU
THIS MUCH, MR. HICKOK,
AND I'D SAY THE SAME
TO THE ANGELS IN HEAVEN.
AS A STAGE PERFORMER,
YOU CANNOT ACT
A SINGLE DAMN LICK.
I'D CALL THAT
A FAIR JUDGMENT.
I SAW YOU ON A STAGE
IN HARTFORD, CONNECTICUT.
AND I'D HAVE BET U.S. CURRENCY
THAT YOU'D BEEN STRANGLED
AND KILLED,
AND YOU JUST DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WAS DEAD YET.
WAS YOU BORN PATIENT,
MONTANA,
OR DID YOU CULTIVATE IT?
I GUESS I'M PATIENT
FOR LABOR.
NOW WHY TELL HIM
THAT TYPE STORY?
WHY I SAW HIM PERFORM
WITH BUFFALO BILL CODY
AND TEXAS JACK OMOHUNDRO
ON A STAGE IN HARTFORD,
CONNECTICUT.
WHO GIVES A FUCK?
YOU THINK HE WAS
PUT ON EARTH TO HEAR YOU
RUN HIM DOWN?
I'M ALL RIGHT, FRIEND.
NO, WHY DON'T YOU GET
OUTTA MY SIGHT
BEFORE I DO SOMETHING
I'LL FUCKING REGRET?
I'LL TELL WHATEVER KINDA
STORY I FEEL LIKE TELLING.
THAT'S RIGHT,
TELL IT WALKING.
ANYWAYS, ME AND SOL ARE SURE
GRATEFUL YOU AND MR. UTTER
ARE TAKING
THE TIME TO HELP.
Man #2:
GO AHEAD ABOUT
YOUR WORK, MR. HICKOK.
HE WON'T
BOTHER YOU NO MORE.
CHARLIE ENCOURAGES ME
BEING IN YOUR COMPANY.
HE FEELS YOU'RE
A POSITIVE INFLUENCE.
NO REASON
YOU'D REMEMBER ME
BUT I SAW YOU MARSHAL
AT ABILENE.
SAW YOU BLOW ONE
COCKSUCKER'S HEAD
RIGHT THE FUCK
OFF HIS NECK.
I ALSO SAW YOU...
DEAD CENTER THREE BULLETS
ON AN ACE OF SPADE
PLAYING CARD AT
25 GODDAMNED PACES.
SOME OTHER LOUDMOUTH
LIKE THIS LOUDMOUTH
I JUST SORTED OUT,
SAID YOU'D DOCTORED
THAT PLAYING CARD
BEFORE YOU EVER TACKED IT
TO THAT TREE.
- AND DID YOU
SORT HIM OUT TOO?
- GODDAMNED RIGHT.
WELL, THANKS
FOR ALL THAT HELP.
NOW IT'S TIME
YOU MOVED ALONG.
I SORTED HIM OUT
PROPER.
GOUGED OUT THE BOTH
OF HIS FUCKING EYES.
- charlie: ALL RIGHT, FRIEND!
- MOVE ALONG, I'M TIRED
OF LISTENING TO YOU.
YOU'RE TIRED
OF LISTENING?
- THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
- OH.
I GUESS EVERYBODY'S
TALKING TO ME NOW.
GET THE FUCK
OUTTA HERE!
ALL RIGHT, I HEAR YOU,
WILD BILL.
YOU DON'T NEED
TO INSULT ME TWICE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
I HOPE YOU GET
WHAT'S COMING TO YOU
AND I HOPE IT'S SOONER
RATHER THAN LATER.
I HOPE THEY
SORT YOU OUT!
AND I GET TO SEE IT!
I HOPE YOU'RE GUT SHOT
AND DIE SLOW!
AND I HOPE THEY
GET YOU IN THIS CAMP!
HAND ME-- HAND ME SOME
OF THEM PEGS, WOULD YOU?
HEY, WANT SOME
PEGS, BILL?
I'M GONNA
DESERT YOU.
PLAY SOME POKER.
DRINK SOME WHISKEY.
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
SEE YA LATER, CHARLIE.
ALL RIGHT, BILL.
READY, LIFT.
OH, THERE WE GO.
FOR HAVING NOTHING
TO DO WITH HIM,
THESE HARDWARE COCKSUCKERS
SURE SEEM TO BE JOINED
TO HICKOK AT THE HIP.
YOU MADE YOUR JUDGMENT
ON THAT SITUATION.
AND I BELIEVE YOU
JUDGED CORRECT.
NO CONNECTION
BETWEEN THEM AND HIM?
OR BETWEEN ANY OF THEM,
AND THESE NEW SALOON PEOPLE?
YOU SAW IT LIKE THAT
AND I DID TOO.
TO THE BEST OF THE BOTH
OF OUR THINKING.
- WHICH WAS
IMPORTANT TO ME.
- WHICH WAS?
- WHAT?
- WHEN YOU SAID
"WHICH WAS,"
I DIDN'T FOLLOW
WHAT YOU WERE ASKING.
I WASN'T
ASKING NOTHING.
I WAS SAYING.  I DIDN'T
HAVE FULL INFORMATION
SO YOUR IMPRESSION
ON THIS WAS IMPORTANT.
SOMEONE I COULD TRUST.
WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
- MY PALMS ARE DAMP.
- THEY'RE ALWAYS DAMP.
- YES, SIR.
- SO IS SOMETHING WRONG?
NO, NO.
WELL, THE GREAT PROSPECTOR'S
FOUND HIS SECOND WIND.
YOU TELL ME, AL.
HAVE YOU A DOUBT
OR MISGIVING?
YOU TELL ME.
GENERALLY, IF I HAVE
A MISGIVING OR A DOUBT,
I KILL THE COCKSUCKER I HAVE
A DOUBT AND MISGIVING ABOUT.
BUT THESE ARE SPECIAL
CIRCUMSTANCES.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN BY
"SPECIAL CIRCUMSTANCES."
IF I WANT TO, I CAN BURN
THE WHOLE FUCKING CAMP DOWN.
- YES, YOU CAN.
- CUT YOUR THROAT FIRST,
AND THEN BURN DOWN
THE WHOLE FUCKING CAMP.
- YOU CAN--
- SO I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE FUCK YOU MEAN.
I MEAN, SHORT OF
BURNING IT ALL DOWN,
YOU GOTTA TRUST SOMEONE.
- WHAT WERE YOU
DOING OVER THERE?
- WHERE?
- AT THE BELLA UNION?
GET AN IMPRESSION,
SCOUTING.
LISTEN TO ME,
LISTEN TO ME.
I WAS THE GO-BETWEEN,
IT WAS ME.
BUT WITHOUT
MALICIOUS INTENTION.
WELL...
I CONFESS
TO BEING WINDED.
OH NO, DAN.
NO.
MOTHER.
SIMPLE GREED.
ONE LESS HOTEL IN CAMP,
SHORTEN UP THE ROOM SUPPLY.
NO CONSPIRACY,
NO BETRAYAL.
IF YOU'RE GONNA MURDER ME,
I'D APPRECIATE A QUICK DYING.
AND NOT GETTING ATE
BY THE PIGS--
IN CASE THERE IS
RESURRECTION OF THE FLESH.
STAY FRIENDLY
WITH THEM COCKSUCKERS.
WITH THEM
BELLA UNION PEOPLE?
CAN'T HELP YOURSELF,
CAN YOU?
( wheezing )
YOU FELL, BUT YOU'LL
BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA
TAKE CARE OF YOU.
HOLD ON A SECOND.
NO HOLLERING.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU.
NOW, HUSH.
( grunts )
( piano music playing )
TINA AND MOLLY CAN BE QUIET
IF YOU WANT HIM KEPT COMPANY.
THAT MAN'S ALREADY
DOING ALL HE WANTS TO.
IF I SEND HIM ANYONE,
IT'D BE YOU.
ARE YOU LOADED, LEON?
WELL ON THE PATH,
MR. TOLLIVER.
THAT MAN AT THE GEM
HAS GOT SOME SERIOUS SHIT.
I KNOW WHEN YOU
MAKE YOUR FIRST REPORT
ON US TO HIM,
YOU'LL REMEMBER
TO SAY THANKS.
I HOPE YOU'RE NOT
TOO FUCKED UP TO DEAL
THE DEUCE FOR US, LEON.
OPIUM AIN'T BEEN
MADE YET, MR. SAWYER,
THAT CAN FUCK ME UP
THAT BAD.
I'LL TUG HIS REINS.
- I HOPE OUR HERO WINS.
- COUNT ON IT.
IF BILL COMES,
I'M GONNA MOVE YOU
TO THAT NICE PALLET
OVER THERE,
ONLY 'CAUSE HE'S FAR TOO BIG
FOR IT AND SO TOO WOULD I BE.
SO IF YOU
WAKE UP ON THE PALLET,
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
AND HIM AND ME BEING
WHERE WE ARE
IS THE CIRCUMSTANCES
OF THE ROOM, PERIOD.
AND THE GROWNUPS
ARE JUST SLEEPING.
BUT DON'T BE AFRAID TO--
TO-- TO WAKE ME UP.
ALL RIGHT.
SWEETHEART,
GO TO SLEEP.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
NOT TOO FUCKING
DEEP, HUH?
I WON'T.
TRUST.
HELL OF A WAY
TO OPERATE, HUH?
LEARNING AT ALL THE INS
AND OUTS OF GETTING KILLED.
NOT TOO FUCKING DEEP.
EVERY FUCKING BEATING
I'M GRATEFUL FOR.
EVERY FUCKING
ONE OF THEM.
GET ALL THE TRUST
BEAT OUTTA YOU.
THEN YOU KNOW WHAT
THE FUCKING WORLD IS.
( knocks at door )
AL, OPEN UP,
IT'S ME, IT'S DAN!
YOU'RE GONNA WANNA
HEAR THIS, OPEN UP!
COME IN, SIT DOWN.
- WELL, IT'S A MIXED REPORT.
- YOU JUST TELL ME, IS IT DONE?
OH, IT'S DONE.
YEAH, HE'S GONE.
SO WHAT'S THE MIXTURE?
HE WENT OWNING ONE HELL
OF A FUCKING GOLD STRIKE.
WHERE'S THE DUDE NOW?
SPLATTERED AT
THE BOTTOM OF THE RIDGE.
RIDE BACK OUT.
BRING HIM BACK IN AT DAWN.
ALL RIGHT.
TRIXIE!
YOU WANT
THE OTHER FOOT?
YEAH.
PLEASE.
( country ballad playing )
* KICK OFF YOUR HIGH HEELS
* CAREFUL WHERE YOU STAND
* DON'T YOU MOVE TOO CLOSE,
I'M A TWISTED LITTLE MAN *
* HEAVEN HELP ME,
I KNOW WHAT I AM *
* DON'T YOU MOVE TOO CLOSE,
I'M A TWISTED LITTLE MAN. *