( theme music playing )
Reverend:
MY DARLING WIFE...
( panting )
I HAVE $68 PUT BY--
OUR BELLY CLEAVETH
TO THE EARTH.
I HOPE TO BE HOME
SOON, AMANDA.
I'ŐLL HELP WITH
THE CIDER PRESSING.
( groaning )
OUR SOUL IS
BOWED DOWN TO THE DUST.
TELL JOHNNY TO BREW SOME COFFEE,
OPEN SOME PEACHES.
- AL KNEW THEY WAS COMIN'Ő.
- WELL, HE KNEW SOMETHIN'Ő
WAS COMIN'Ő.
I'ŐD ABOUT DECIDED HE JUST
COULDN'ŐT SLEEP WITHOUT TRIXIE.
AM I RIGHT IN BELIEVING
THAT I SAW YOU LAST YEAR
IN THE HILLS?
HE AND HIS MEN WOULD REQUIRE
SOME RESUPPLY AND RESPITE.
I'ŐLL MAKE YOUR FEELINGS KNOWN
TO THE OTHER OPERATORS.
I AND MY FELLOW OFFICERS
WOULD BE GRATEFUL NOW
FOR THE USE OF THE BATHHOUSE.
MR. BURNS HERE
WILL STEER YOU.
THE CAMP WILL
WANT A PARADE.
A PARADE IS ALL RIGHT.
UNLESS YOU WANT A GIRL
TO SPONGE YOU WHILE
WE CONVERSE?
THOSE ARE THE DAYS
TO MY FUCKING LEFT.
IT CAN'ŐT BE DONE.
YOUR MOST VICTORIOUS
SMILE.
I HOPE YOU
CHARGE SOMETHING
FOR YOUR SERVICE.
HI, DOC.
THE FUCKIN'Ő MAGISTRATE DON'ŐT
GO BACK TO YANKTON ALIVE.
COMMON ROOM.
SWEEPIN'Ő.
WHAT YOU GOT
IN YOUR TOTE SACK?
LETTUCE.
ALL RIGHT.
I MAKE THIS STIPULATION.
OF YOUR FUCKING BOOT.
( whispers )
ALL RIGHT.
HERE'ŐS YOUR GODDAMN BOOT.
HELP ME PUT IT ON.
WHAT THE FUCK
ARE WE TALKING ABOUT?
OH, FUCK YOU, AL!
I'ŐLL SEND SOMEONE OVER
TO PICK HIM UP.
I MADE JEWEL
A BRACE AND A BOOT.
I'ŐM WORKING ON MY DEPLOYMENTS
AND FLANKING MANEUVERS.
HOW ABOUT THAT OTHER ONE?
TRIXIE'ŐS FINE.
TRIXIE?
ARE TRYING
TO WASH OUR SHIRTS
IN GODDAMN FECES!
IT DEMANDS CAPITAL.
( chuckles )
GENERATING FROM THE INTEREST
ON THE PREVIOUS DEBTS?
ALMA...
YOUR SPIRIT TO UNDERSTAND
IS ALWAYS PAINFUL FOR ME.
AFTER YOU GOT ME OUT OF DEBT,
I GOT MYSELF BACK IN.
.
MY DAUGHTER BECOMING
A GARRET RAISED ME IN
THE LENDER'ŐS ESTIMATION
AND CONSIDERABLY MORE.
ALL RIGHT, DADDY.
I'ŐLL HAVE THAT IN WRITING
BEFORE I HELP YOU.
AND YOU'ŐLL
HAVE NO SUCH THING.
GET AWAY FROM HER!
WHY, THANK YOU, SIR.
( sobbing )
PLUS $2 SOME-ODD
FOR MRS. GARRET TO GIVE
THAT GIRL.
( sobbing )
I'ŐLL GIVE HER
THE MONEY LATER.
SETH.
.
I'ŐM ASKING FOR YOUR HELP
THEY LOVE--
TO HAVE THEIR
PICTURES TAKEN.
- SHOULD I STAY WITH HER
AT THE STORE?
- PLEASE.
AND BILKING YOU LOSE,
NEEDING TO RUB AGAINST
YOUR BETTERS.
FIRST-RATE THINKING.
AND WIDEN SUSPICION
TO INCLUDE YOURSELF?
SHOOT CRAPS,
MR. BULLOCK?
I KNOW WHAT'ŐS
IN THE TILL.
WERE YOU BULLIED, MR. BULLOCK,
WHEN YOUNG AND INCAPABLE?
MY OLFACTORIES ARE KEEN
TO THE SMELL OF SHIT.
AS TO HER COMPLICITY
IN HER HUSBAND'ŐS MURDER...
I SUPPOSE YOU'ŐD BEST
TAKE YOUR SWING.
GENTLEMEN,
WATCH THE FELT.
( distant drum corps
playing )
( whispering )
PLEASE...
- SEE TO MY FATHER.
-( marching band playing )
( gunshot )
- FUCK THAT MONKEY NOISE!
- ALL RIGHT, ENOUGH!
TAKE JURISDICTION
ON THIS CORPSE!
Man:
BACK OFF, OLD MAN.
( band continues playing )
AT ONCE ATTACKED
FROM ALL FOUR SIDES.
LAST SEEN ON HIS PERSON
WHEN HE RODE INTO BATTLE...
CAPTAIN.
AND NOW RECLAIMED
BY WHITE MEN!
ARE GONE, DRIVEN OFF.
...TO THE PROGRESS
OF THE UNITED STATES...
GOTTA TAKE OFF
THE FUCKING BADGE.
NOT CERTAIN I TAKE
YOUR INFERENCE.
.
AND IF I DO,
I'ŐM NOT SURE I LIKE IT
LEAVE IT THERE,
YOU BOUGHT-OUT
SON OF A BITCH.
UM, "THE SIOUX
AND CHEYENNE...
WE'ŐLL WORK SOMETHING OUT.
BUT, OF COURSE, YOU'ŐRE
BUYING FOR FULL-GROWN MEN.
I DON'ŐT THINK
I KILLED HIM.
NOW, THAT'ŐS THE MESSAGE
YOU WANT ME TO TAKE UPSTAIRS.
YOU OUGHT TO PIN THAT
ON YOUR CHEST.
YOU JUST TELL HIM.
OR TO MAKE
YOUR FUCKING WAY?!
( crowd chattering )
YOU WISH YOU
COULD AMEND, SETH.
WHAT KIND OF A MAN
HAVE I BECOME, SOL?
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
THE DAY AIN'ŐT
FUCKING OVER.
DID I SAY
SOMETHING FUNNY?
THAT COCKSUCKER
CLAGETT'ŐS BAGMAN.
MODERATION
IN ALL THINGS.
THANK YOU,
THANK YOU, SIR.
- Soldier:MUCH OBLIGED.
- GOOD LUCK.
WHICH WE AIN'ŐT.
ARE WE SURE
WE CAN'ŐT TEMPT YOU?
CASH COMPENSATION,
UNRECORDED.
MR. BULLOCK.
WHY ARE YOU HERE,
MR. BULLOCK?
- HE NEEDS PROTECTION.
- PROTECTION FROM WHOM?
AND THE CAMP SHERIFF CAN BE
BOUGHT OFF FOR HALF A CAN
OF BACON GREASE.
MAY I HAVE
A WORD, GENERAL?
WE ALL HAVE
BLOODY THOUGHTS.
I QUITE
UNDERSTAND.
.
IF I WERE SHERIFF,
I'ŐD HAVE YOU HANGED
Joanie:
I BROUGHT THESE.
HI, SWEETHEART.
SEEMS HE WILL.
MR. BULLOCK WAS
MY AGENT IN THIS.
TILL HE SOLD ME
TO CY TOLLIVER.
OH.
EVENING.
( whispers )
GOOD EVENING,
MR. BULLOCK.
UM, UH-- SOPHIA.
YOU GO WITH MISS STUBBS
FOR DINNER, OKAY?
I'ŐVE ASKED GENERAL CROOK
TO SEE TO HIS SAFETY.
WE'ŐLL DEAL
WITH THAT THEN.
MARRIED.
YES.
IF YOU'ŐD-- IF YOU WOULD BE
MORE COMFORTABLE BEHIND
THE SCREEN...
( whispers )
WOULDN'ŐT THAT
DEFEAT OUR PURPOSE?
( sighs )
GIVE YOU TIME
TO MAKE UP WHICH SIDE
YOU'ŐRE ON, ADAMS.
IF THE COCKSUCKER
WOULD EVER SHOW UP.
FOR THAT WHICH I DO,
I ALLOW NOT FOR...
BUT SIN THAT
DWELLETH IN ME.
SHUT THE DOOR.
JESUS CHRIST.
TO KNOW YOUR-YOUR--
YOUR OMNIPOTENCE?
IT HURTS SO BAD."
( breathing heavily )
THY WILL BE DONE, AMEN.
( moaning )
DEAL OUT DEATH
WHEN CALLED UPON?
( choking )
( choking gasp )
YOU CAN GO NOW,
BROTHER.
I GOT THOSE OTHER TWO GUYS
WAITING UPSTAIRS.
JOIN 'ŐEM.
GET THE SLED
FOR HIM, HUH?
-( piano playing )
-( crowd chattering )
TELL ME WHAT YOU MEAN
UPSTAIRS, HUH?
AND HIS BUTLER.
- WHICH HE'ŐD BE...
- Al: WHEREVER HIS
ALLEGIANCE MAY LAY.
LIVING AS WE ALL DO
IN DOUBT, PLEASE PROCEED.
WILL NO LONGER
WEIGH UPON YOU.
WHAT MAN COULDN'ŐT
THAT BE SAID ABOUT?
( gagging )
- ( blade slices )
- ( groans )
WHEN YOU TAKE THAT
FUCKING GUN OFF ME.
BOTH OF THEM.
NO, I STILL
OWE YOU THE TWO.
-( gunshots )
-( bugle playing )
I DON'ŐT BEGRUDGE HIM
AN UNCOMFORTABLE JOURNEY.
AND AFTER THAT,
HE'ŐS ON HIS OWN.
OR IS THAT ONE OF
YOUR FUCKING HERESIES?
HE PASSED.
WAITED TILL I GOT HIM
OFF THE SLED, HUH?
THANKS FOR
SEEING HIM THROUGH.
IS A GOOD WAY TO HEAR
GOD LAUGH.
( thumps )
IT'ŐS BEEN
A BUSY NIGHT.
DOC, I'ŐM GONNA BE
A FEW MINUTES, HUH?
SEE THIS MAN GETS
HIS SHINE, HUH?
NO STIFFNESS
OR NUMBNESS.
UH, LET ME SEE YOU
MOVE AROUND A BIT.
THAT'ŐLL GIVE YOU
A SHINE.
HEY, DOC.
GIVE ME A WHIRL.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO, I WON'ŐT, UM-- NO.
.
YEAH, I'ŐM...
I'ŐM GONNA GET TO THAT
YOU'ŐD JUST AS SOON
AS SEEN HIM DEAD.
NO.
PRODUCE IT.
I KNOW WHERE IT GOES.
( bugle playing )
( drums playing )
HEY, GENERAL!
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
WOOH!
HA-HA-HA-HA-HA!
BESIDES
WHATEVER'ŐS GOING ON
BETWEEN THE TWO OF YOU.
YEAH.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
( piano playing )
( giggling )
? WE'ŐLL UNDERSTAND IT ALL
BY AND BY. ?