" Tell Him Something Pretty "
Quit your Goddamn knockin'.
I'm comin'
Casket's come with your name on it
Why tell me in the middle of the night?
Body's inside
Evidently not mine
But I'd as soon make delivery
You'll find out where when I decide.
Good night
I don't like your tone of voice
Who are you, Mr. Utter, for me to care
what you like or don't?
I'm the guy that the next time you see me,
you'd better take a different fuckin' tone with
Given what's in store, I'm not sure I'll ever learn
what price I'd have paid for not complyin'
Oh, I guess someone lookin' hard might could find you in there
somewheres, peekin' from under the covers to make a fuckin' threat
Their quality apart, Claudia, failing reception,
our efforts are lost to the void
I understand
Don't say so! Please!
I lose my thought
This camp is in mortal danger
The man Hearst is a murderous engine
My friend Swearengen, aware their combat is unequal,
feels the appeal of the gory finish
Others I've just come to know stand candidates in the elections,
whose results they know may be moot
What, one is disposes to ask,
in fuck ought a theater man to do?
Of a certainty, our debut's postponement is necessary
But unless of one's own volition,
certain is it too that one would not be canceled
To prevent that, if need be, even off the boards,
one would take steps of one's fuckin' own!
Why did you bring me here?
I don't know, child
What's the point Al having us leave
I.O.U.s
when Wu can't read fuckin' English?
Wu gets back, he'll take Al the I.O.U.s for interpretin',
find out Al did the rightful thing while he was gone
That's big point with Al, ain't it?
When he ain't lyin', Al's the most honorable man
you'll ever meet
Johnny, balance up against this fuckin' Chinese sign
while I lay my rack on your shoulder
Why?
Just shut the fuck up.
Get this meat inside
What are you gonna do?
Murder
Where the fuck you been?
I fuckin' vouched for you!
We're camped up at the Spearfish Meadows,
as not to tip Hearst off till Swearengen can deploy us
I mean, I rode into town to tell you,
but I fell one saloon short
Come on
Lots of Chinks in that meadows up there
Is the railroad comin' to camp?
To have kept our claim, we'd have had to leave here, you and I,
so that thugs we'd have had to engage could counter Mr. Hearst's thugs
without having the further responsibility of defending us
So…
we are to sell, Sofia, so that we may stay
To be fair to Mr. Hearst-which is more than he deserves-
the price he is paying assigns a great worth to our holdings,
which lacking expertise
of our own and others now being absent
who might have provided it,
as a practical matter makes refusal absurd
But how I hate to give that man what he wants
Your hair has survived my diatribe
If we left, we wouldn't be able to see Mr. Ellsworth
And we are not leaving
Your fuckin' throat's gonna be at risk, Hawkeye, in case you don't
fuckin' realize, which wouldn't bother me except mine's gonna be too
Advancing your interests, Mrs. Ellsworth,
mine and all others,
what we do here seems natural and proper
Mr. Newman, I ask you to ready payment
to the officers of Mrs. Ellsworth's bank
We'll receive it where we can put it in her safe
May I hope, Madam, you do not subscribe
to this insulting and juvenile precaution?
I do not find the precaution juvenile, so many having
been murdered with whom you've had dealings in this camp
At least you acknowledge the insult
I acknowledge the pretense to civility-
in a man so brutally vicious-as vapid and grotesque
Have the gold seen to her bank, Newman.
Have its purity assayed
Let her or her seconds choose the man
When that tedium is completed,
have the documents witnessed as though we were all of us Jews
And bring the business back to me
Excuse my absence, Mr. Star, as I hope you'll forgive
my thoughtless aspersion on your race
You stand for local office, but some contests being countywide
I await wires from the other camps
You've changed your scent
Can't shut up! Every bully I ever met
can't shut his fuckin' mouth…
except when he's afraid
You mistake for fear, Mr. Bullock,
what is in fact preoccupation
I'm having a conversation you cannot hear
Oh see, that's just Miss Stubbs now answering my message
I sent her by secret thinking, requesting
unguent for my bruises
Hello hello, Miss Stubbs
Joanie : Hello hello, yourself. Hello, Sofia
Sofia : Hello, Miss Stubbs
I'm just going to the center.
I wondered if you needed anything
Oh, I've let her in on it
You needn't tell a stretcher how it is you come to appear
You told?
Asked for unguent by secret thinking for
the beating she was giving my hand
That's my purpose in the center.
Stopped to ask if you needed aught else
If I did, I believe you'd already know
Hit her a good one for me
I will
Come in!
I  was looking for Mr. Hearst
Who do you think you're talkin' to?
Candidly, of late, I'm at pains to be certain
which voices are within me and which without
This one is without, telling you to come in
Of course
What is it, Mr. Hearst?
I've sensed for some while we owed each other a talk
Let the outcome be grim or worse,
I'll at least be relieved that it's past
May I look at the addressee?
How will you know to whom
it is to be delivered if you do not?
Oh dear
Well, I'll be on my way then
Must have shook 100 hands in Sturgis
When you declared for Sheriff, Harry, I feared you'd be
a poor campaigner and derelict in your duties here
You've held your end up
and more
Ache in my hand and wrist,
the deep-set dirt defies me
Well, if sweeping, you don't raise your usual simoon,
it's a paltry price to pay
Fuck if you saw that comin'
I have something to show you, Harry
The Finster Model 60 steam pumper fire wagon
120-gallon boiler?
Three brass nozzles
Nickel-finished firebox?
I believe that to be the case
Did the hats come?
Is that a checker in Steve's mouth?
You don't want to look after him, just say so
Who says I don't?
Only he kibitzes my moves
Where are you goin'?
Takin' him to vote for Bullock
This may require my supervision
I'll vote just before lunch
And  I'll go once you've relieved me
You don't expect me to believe you didn't
steam this open
and reseal it for me to open again
I didn't wanna know
This motherfucker!
For my complicity in his shooting, he orders my death
You did read it
Be quick then, please
Your complicity's mostly in your noggin, E.B
It's the whore he wants dead
By what vile method then?
Is Trixie to be drawn and quartered and set aflame?
Say he'll have my answer in an hour
Al
E.B
I can't, Al
I can't engage him in further conversation
When I hear his voice, I see the inside of his skull!
Phantoms grin out at me, oozing gruesome goo
Slide this under his door then
Would you rather I tell him?
Only decide quickly
Fear is every man's portion
Did he send for you, Joanie?
What's happenin' here, Con?
Well, not knowin' Mr. Tolliver's, uh,
present state of feelin' towards you is why I ask
Then why don't you stay the fuck out of it, Con?
I wasn't fuckin' dreamin'.
It is Joanie Stubbs
I got "Stay the fuck out" written on
a stone tablet in my bedroom
How you feelin', Cy?
I get around all right
Your color's better
Is that a fucking fact?
My color's better, Stupid
Stupid, this is Joanie Stubbs
Hi
What's your name, Honey?
Go ahead and tell her your name
Janine
Hi, Janine
Hi
Go ahead now, Jan-nee-nee-neen,
and finish your Latin lessons and your Greek
The thirst this girl has for knowledge,
she's barely time to suck a prick
She's pretty
What the fuck do you want?
I've been thinking about you is all
Help me understand cunt, Lord
Saying the other night you oughtn't come inside
that school, Cy, don't feel I don't wish you well
Buy some lines in the paper, Joanie.
Let the public know
I know you meant that for me in your way
What?
Meant me well
If it's Christmas, where's the fucking snow,
or the fucking harp music or the like?
If it wasn't for you, I'd have died a long long time ago
Some happiness has come into my life now,
and I'm grateful I didn't
My lines are women, liquor
and rigged games of chance.
Are you playing?
What do you think of all this trouble Hearst brought?
Does a girl have to drive cattle
for you to eat her pussy?
You voting, Leon?
Against the opium ordinance
What the fuck are you looking at?
That whore's gotta die
Jen?
Hearst won't stand for an empty coffin
Likely, he paid most attention to Trixie's tits and snatch,
so Jen'll adequately pass
Jesus Christ
I know. You like her
She's a nice girl
All right
She's learning to read
Spend some time with her, and let me know when you're done
You'll scare her
I've done it once or twice, Johnny
She won't know that's what I'm there for
She won't need to.
You scare her no matter what
Oh, just give me a fucking knife then.
Just give me the fucking knife
Fucking  Trixie!
Don't get me started
What are you doing?
Going for a stroll to the polls
One vote for Star buys a hand job
Repeaters get a suck
Trixie
I'm through staying inside.
If something's to happen let it happen to me
You  selfish cunt!
No one asked you to put me up
That's right. That's right
My fucking choice! I'm not fucking afraid
I guess maybe I'm not either
Not to die
Well, ain't you clever?
Ain't you fucking clever, you deep thinkin' fuckin' Jew!
Sol : Why bother with your boots then, Trixie,
if you're going to be on your knees?
Trixie : Let go of me!
No!
Let me walk out by myself !
The fuck if I will!
At least I can say I threw you out
if you'd rather die than live with me!
Use just half till you see how you stand it
It itches bad
I'm saying use just half till you see
I wanna talk with you
No, I mean it, Jen. I wanna talk
Pure conversation
Nothing for you to be alarmed about
Four and five deep to vote, Boss
Eyes up or predominantly down when Hearst's goons
glare upon 'em?
Uh, I want to go check again
Good. Good.
Never opine short of certainty
What is this, Jen?
A wall?
On the surface, yes, it is
But inside, many creatures go about their lives,
such as ants
They got a whole operation going
They got soldier ants and worker ants and whore ants
to fuck the soldiers and the workers,
right inside that wall, baby ants
Everyone's got a task to hew to, Jen
You understand me?
Jesus Christ's fucking sake
We'll talk about this later
I can't
Give it to me then
No
Give me the fucking knife
She ain't stole or been quarrelsome
or set the bedding afire
Get out of my fucking way, Johnny
It ain't fair to fucking kill her
Since when did that begin entering in?
I won't let you pass, Boss
Johnny
I won't.
I won't let you
You're willing to die in her stead?
If I got to…
preferring you'd handle things different
Make sure the whore don't leave.
Let Johnny cool down, then knock him the fuck out
What's gonna happen?
What's gonna happen is I'm gonna go look and see if, perchance,
I mightn't be the owner of another fucking knife
Richardson!
I can't remember
Come here.
Give it to me
I don't suppose you gonna go vote
stocking-footed
I  forgot
Ain't those them?
You gonna vote for Mr. Bullock now
Even though he beat Mr. Farnum,
'cause he took you-know-who by his ear
Like some others ain't brave enough to do
Anyways, Harry Manning gives me splinters
How's he do that, child?
Raising the windows after he's ate
Richardson…Richardson, you're right about that
South had that man's gas to load in their cannons, shoot,
wouldn't be no free niggers nowhere
Noah hisself would have throwed him out the boat
Now that's for us talking now
Don't you be saying what I say to you outside these rooms
First you back, you're gonna clean your mess up, Richardson.
You hear me?
Yes, Ma'am
Okay. Go on on.
You look fine
Thank you
Remember who gave it to you, boys.
Vote democratic
Look what broke out their cage-a monkey
Right to vote shall not be abridged or denied…
on account of race or color or
condition of previous servitude
15th amendment to the U.S. Constitution, ratified 1870,
law of the land thereafter, including territories
They got something about niggers not waiting their turn?
Not that I'm aware of
Oh, you ain't aware of it
Then I guess you'll want this white man voting first
What's a few minutes more?
The nigger was before him
Yes
No he wasn't
I guess you're blind and stupid
I believe I'll vote later
Fuck if you will.
Get your nigger ass back in line
You'd better be walking him home afterwards
You'd better see to that yourself,
'cause if he don't make it,
you'll be eating your spuds running
till I hunt you the fuck down
And that ends that
What your shit-stirring started
Will you drop your fucking ballot?
Ain't it wonderful, Steve?
Sorry for all the commotion, Miss Stubbs
That's all right, Mr. Utter
Uh, I got something at the jail for you and the other one
'Cept right now I'm pretty agitated
Well, I got time
Maybe you'll calm down as we walk
All right
How do you make your way, Star, not sometimes buying silence
by punching her in the fucking mouth?
She thinks Hearst is going to want her dead
She thinks you'll kill one of these others
Oh, Jesus Christ
Al :Jesus Christ
Sol : Is it true?
I already fucking did
Is that true?
Don't waste your Jew's time wondering
what's true and what ain't
You go over there, tell fucking Hearst
the whore Trixie has been killed,
and then tell Joan of Arc that
instead of flames lapping at her tippy-toes,
you'd have her live to fuck in the morning
And after to you tell fucking Hearst,
before you tell that loudmouth cunt,
tell your fucking partner I need him here
Don't talk about her that way
Oh, I fucking recant.
Off you fucking go.
And don't neglect fucking Bullock.
Water comes to a boil
Unlucky fucking mutt
You remember Hawkeye
How many has he got?
Ride from Cheyenne winnowed the wheat from the chaff
How many, Adams, of the promised 23?
Almost 18, Mr. Swearengen, camped in Spearfish Meadows,
ready to join in the issue
What does he mean by "Almost 18?"
17 normal size and a short one that's hell with a knife
Turn me loose
Ain't that Mr. Wu?
In there, Wu
Go with him to get the men, station in Cochran's Alley
Send word you're positioned with the midget
That went off well
Hello, hello
What  happened, Jane?
Nothing out of the ordinary
The bank lady took her child to Ellsworth's grave
and I got drunk
How long you been here?
Many years.
Or is it a day or two?
What's important is you get to keep asking me questions
so I don't get to ask you one
Go ahead
Why in fuck, with me asking you in to play hot hands with me and Sofia,
you stood there instead looking like you just did murder?
Well, you didn't.
I'd come in if you'd asked
Bullshit!
How can you say we've been sending secret thought
messages and pretend you didn't know?
Well, anyways
Anyways, what?
Anyways, I've just finished my business at the center
Who gives a fuck?
I saw you, and then I went to the Bella Union,
and I talked to Cy real quick, and then I went and saw the voting-
Is that so?
Oh, so did you go see Cy real quick?
Did you pay a quick call on Cy?
Did they stick some quick pricks in you?
It wasn't like that, Jane
Who gives a fuck?
Not me
I saw at the voting what I guess you knowed about
Mr. Utter all these years, and Mr. Hickok musta knowed
What he's like in a tight-one he didn't even need to be in
Yeah, he's okay in those
I want to be that to you
Even when we don't get along
You got that part down perfect, me and him
What, the "don't get along"?
Of course we had years of practice
He sent us this
That's Bill Hickok's robe you got there,
that's whose that is
Warm
I, in no way, wish to impugn his veracity, but
I would have Mr. Swearengen understand that for her try on my life,
I ought to see that the whore has paid with her own
All right
Wherever the viewing will impose least
You'll go there?
Of course
I feel very safe in this camp
This fucking place is gonna be a fucking misery
Every fucking one of them, every fucking time I walk by,
"Ooh, how could you?  How could you?"  With their big fucking cow eyes
The entire fucking gaggle of 'em is gonna
have to bleed and quit before we can even hope for peace
What's the fucking alternative?
I ain't fuckin' killing her that sat nights with me sick and
taking slaps to her mug that were some less than fucking fair
I should have fucking learned to use a gun,
but I'm too fucking entrenched in my ways
And you ain't exactly the one to be leveling criticisms
on the score of being slow to adapt
You fucking people are the original slow fucking learners!
How was she, pal?
Good, wonderful
I don't mind a small pair of tits
You sure you're done?
You look the sort could turn right around
and drop the hammer again
I will if it's free
See you later, Pal
C'mere
Did it seem like Hearst ordered the interference?
Huh-uh
Being stupid on his own, that strong-arm was
Or if you want, I could say "Yes."
Tea, Mr. Utter?
Tea got kick to it too, a little, don't it?
Would you rather coffee?
Oh, no no no
I ought to get familiar with tea
Uh, Much free liquor as them Pinkertons poured against you,
Sheriff, it seemed like strong support for you and Star
My election's countywide, Charlie
That's what's fucking worrisome, fucking countywide aspect
Mr. Star
I'm sorry for barging in, uh
What is it, Sol?
Uh, everything
Mr. Langrishe
Making bold to ask after your health, Sir
I was shot in the shoulder
So one understood
But the wound seems healing clean
And your back, Sir?
Oh, deprived of your Turkish artillery treatments,
my back is as it was
Please blame my dereliction
on the demands of readying our theater
I had been blaming your choosing old friends
over new acquaintances
Please, sit down
One prays always, Sir, as one's store is depleted by time,
new acquaintances may become one's friends
As your friend, I ask if you believe that fate has not chosen
for your encounter with your deepest destiny
the place where you now find yourself, while decreeing for some-
my friend Swearengen included-quite otherwise?
Your proposition is that this place at this hour
will show all of Mr. Swearengen?
Yes
And Mr. Bullock, who took me by the ear?
I only hazard my impression that,
less possessing his character than possessed by it,
he is also someone for whom the outcome must be soon
Whilst imagining for you, Mr. Hearst, the earth entertaining
some larger purpose to be told you elsewhere and at another time
Why do you say so? In those words, I mean-"The earth speaks"?
A vestige of childhood tales in which not only humans spoke,
but other creatures too
Mountains and streams
I imagine she speaks to me still, the earth,
what's inside her, how to get it out
Comprehending such a language can cost a man
his own kind's sympathies
Arguing perhaps for a more solitary life
Sad anointing
The mountain I must go up on, Mr. Langrishe,
I have ascended before
It's in Montana, and I came down it with silver,
suspecting there was copper too, and now I'm told that's true
Do I understand you to say you're leaving us?
For the Anaconda, yes
But first, I'll have the election returns, and then one last visit
with your friend to see the cunt who shot me dead
Good day, Sir
Box her in my office
Send Jewel up to clean up the mess?
If I'm having her boxed in my fucking office,
don't I want the blood left for the cocksucker to see?
And when that's over, if we're still alive,
I'll clean my own fucking mess up
Look in on Johnny, see if he's grown the fuck up
Sturgis is a landslide
for Harry Manning
970 votes for Harry Manning, 68 votes for Mr. Bullock
Heavy turnout among the bivouacked military
"Within the hour," Hearst said 20 minutes or so ago
Didn't you tell him?
I have not as yet, no
How do you think you might enjoy private life?
Sturgis?
970 votes for Harry Manning, 68 votes for Mr. Bullock
Put her in?
Don't I want to put my dress on her first,
you fucking moron?
I'm sent to check on Johnny.
I'll come back and put her in
She's, uh, putting Jen in her dress
Johnny
Then I'll do the boxing
We show united in the prelude when he's making
his entrance and the fucking like
Comes to viewing the body, I stand for virtue alone
The deception failing, I'll make a pass
at him with my blade
In the aftermath, play the lie as mine,
knowing I speak of you in heaven
Others owe thought to the future-their thinking
straightforward don't come that naturally to
Fuck you, Dan! Fuck you!
You got my condolences
As sorrowful as the passing of Jen is,
you know that Al, he didn't have no choice
Bullshit
Feeling how he feels about Trixie, is what I'm saying
Come on, Johnny, you side with your feelings
Right or wrong, you side with your feelings
Now can you come to yourself in time
to be of some fucking use?
You don't chew your cabbage twice, do you, Mr. Newman?
I guess I don't have to set big blocks of time aside for
this future collaboration between us that Mr. Hearst outlines here
You don't want to crack too fucking wise
I don't want to be talking to you at all, Mr. Newman,
but that seems to be the way the hand lays
I tell him you agree?
Yeah, you tell him I agree,
and I appreciate the chance at a new friendship
A few nails in the box, Dan, would do me for pretext
All but sucked your prick,
you'd have me be your fucking quartermaster
The rising tide of fucking chinks, Janine?
The ragtag collection by the hardware store:
I'd put in Swearengen's camp
Good dope today, am I right, Leon?
Last two or three days have been good
You are a fucking beauty, Leon
Lifts me up to be with you
Jesus!
What the fuck did you do to me, Sir?
I believe I fucking stabbed you
Gentlemen
Any word yet on how the other camps have voted?
Is it as Sheriff, Mr. Bullock, you divide us?
Need anyone divide us inside?
Are you sure you still hold office?
If I'm beat, it owes to Yankton's whore
buying cavalry repeaters in Sturgis
Why, Sir, then you must protest; camp in Yankton;
protest and demand justice; grab the legislators by their ears
Ain't you hear to confirm a croaker?
In here?
Mr. Newman and so many of his cohorts
as he deems appropriate will precede us
You don't mind if I go in alone?
Not at all, Sir
Hearst moves his operating headquarters to Lead,
I get to see to all his other-than-mining interests here in the camp
Congratulations, Sir
Thank you, Leon
If those are your last words here on earth,
you tell the Lord you went out stupid
He's dead
Oh, not yet, honey
See how the blood still pumps a little out his leg?
When they're dead, that turns to seep
Do you believe I will leave without seeing?
Well, I was hesitant to presume
What do you want done with that body?
It's Mr. Swearengen's affair now
The body at my fucking freight office,
what you want down with that one?
You'll be wired instructions
Has she family ought be notified?
I don't notify fucking family
I guess especially not hers
She has a sister, whores in Gunnison
Jen's sister, you could write to, care of the Yellowbird
I'd take that fucking scrub brush
I wonder if, the other day, you took my not publishing
the news that you'd been shot for a failure to observe,
or lay it correctly to a judgment on my part
that suppressing the news would better serve the camp
I've stopped reading your paper, Merrick
I'll have my people here start another one-
to lie the other way
Hop down
I'd like to take a last look around
If I'm quick enough about this, Janine,
maybe me and Mr. Hearst will get to hear the Lord judge Leon
You want to get a listen too?
Huh?
No, Charlie
Yes, Mr. Bullock?
You've looked at your last body
You're done tipping your fucking hat
Get out of here or I'll drag you out by the ear
Oh, Please.
Please don't
Drive on
Tell fucking Con to take care of that asshole
You done fucking good
I did fucking nothing
That's often a tough one, in aid of the larger purpose
Which is laying head to pillow,
not confusing yourself with a sucker?
Far as I ever get
'Cause that's gonna be a project tonight
Did she suffer?
I was gentle as I was able,
and that's the last we'll fucking speak of it, Johnny
Wants me to tell him something pretty
[ The end? Let's hope it's a "to be continued" ] :)
Synchro : Nikou3131
www.forom.com