( theme music playing )
I'ŐM THERE BUYING GIRLS
TO BRING OUT TO THE CAMPS.
I'ŐLL FUCKIN'Ő FIND
THAT OUT SHORTLY.
OR IF YOU'ŐRE
NEVER GONNA BE ABLE
TO FUCKIN'Ő OPERATE IN PEACE.
FARNUM'ŐS SLITHERED
HIS WAY ACROSS HERE.
I DON'ŐT KNOW.
?
VENTURE OUT,
SALLY FUCKIN'Ő FORTH, HMM
- MAYBE I WILL.
- BUT NOW COME BACK TO BED.
( mocking )
( laughing )
I WAS GODDAMN THERE.
BUT IT'ŐLL HELP ME
WALK BETTER.
YES.
FUCK AL.
YOU DRAGGIN'Ő
YOUR LEG IS YOURS.
DON'ŐT-- DON'ŐT
APOLOGIZE TO ME.
LET ME HOLD ONTO
THIS FOR A WHILE.
THANK YOU.
UH, CAREFUL, CAREFUL,
CAREFUL, CAREFUL!
OF THIS PRECIOUS CARGO.
THE FINEST
PHOTOGRAPHIC APPARATUS
MANUFACTURED IN THIS COUNTRY.
IN SERVICE OF
THIS FINE APPARATUS.
OH, GOD!AGH!
OH, GOD,
YES, CAREFUL, CAREFUL.
OH.
( laughs )
SORRY.
MIGHT UPSET
THE CHILD.
AHA.
I'ŐLL TELL YOU
ONE THING--
IN MY CAPACITY
AS FIRE MARSHAL.
I TAKE GREAT PLEASURE
IN YOUR COMPANY.
I FEEL THE SAME.
I KNOW I'ŐM TOO DAMN
OLD FOR YA.
BUTTON!
OH MY GOODNESS.
I CAN'ŐT BE...
- HOW DO YOU DO, SIR?
- HOW DO YOU DO?
MYWARD.
AND MY HAT.
FINE MANNERS.
( chuckles )
REVEREND SMITH.
UH-HUH.
HOW YOU FEELING?
AS YOU SEE.
- UPRIGHT?
- HE WAS UPRIGHT, YES.
HIS NAME ESCAPES ME.
CERTAIN LINIMENTS
AND...
ARE YOU NOT WELL,
MINISTER?
OR EXCESS OF ENERGY.
BUT YOU'ŐRE PUTTING
THE TENT DOWN.
WHEREVER YOU FIND YOURSELF,
HE WILL SHOW YOU THE PATH.
COULD YOU HELP ME
TO PRAY?
LORD,
TO UNDERSTAND
THAN TO BE UNDERSTOOD...
TO LOVE THAN
TO BE LOVED...
AND THE REST
I FORGET.
YEAH, I'ŐVE NEVER SEEN AL
WARM UP TO ANYBODY SO QUICK.
.
ADAMS IS
THE MAGISTRATE'ŐS BAGMAN
IN TURN, HIS WARMTH
IS COUNTERFEIT.
FIX ME A CUP
OF COFFEE.
MORNING.
TAKE A TABLE
OUT OF THE TRAFFIC, HUH?
JUST THAT
AFFECTIONATE.
IF NOT, THEY COULD
ALWAYS BE CHANGED.
LET ME FUCKING POUR.
HE'ŐS GOTTA MAKE SOME
DISTANCE BEFORE SUNSET.
I'ŐM KNOCKED UP.
NO ENVELOPES
AND TO FUCK HIMSELF.
- I'ŐLL KNOW.
- YOU TRAVEL SAFE.
YANKTON.
BACK AND FORTH
BETWEEN HERE AND YANKTON.
2,000.
I PUT HIM IN A ROOM
ABOVE THE PRIVY.
( chuckles )
UH, ALWAYS A LITTLE
SKETCHY ABOUT ME.
OH, THAT WOULD BE
MY ROOM KEY.  SOPHIA?
- ROOM SEVEN.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
- Sophia: THANK YOU.
- YOU'ŐRE WELCOME, LITTLE ONE.
OH MY GOODNESS,
WHAT'ŐS THAT BEHIND YOUR EAR?
DON'ŐT YOU EVER CLEAN
BEHIND YOUR EAR?
DOES CARING
FOR SOPHIA PLEASE YOU?
AS IT HAPPENS...
YES.
THERE'ŐS SOME TALK
THAT YOU DID BROM IN.
THEY HAVE RAISED
THE POSSIBILITY.
BUT HE WOULD VERIFY
THAT I WASN'ŐT THERE.
I DIDN'ŐT MEAN
TO UPSET YOU.
I SUPPOSE HERE,
AS WELL.
IN CERTAIN CIRCLES.
MR. ELLSWORTH
BEING THE EXCEPTION?
NEARLY AS MUCH AS
I'ŐD LIKE TO WASH.
DADDY.
AH.
I'ŐM GLAD TO SEE YOU.
I AIN'ŐT SEEING THE CAMP
BURNED TO THE GROUND.
WELL, I'ŐLL SEND
ONE OF MY BOYS OVER
TO PICK UP THE IRON.
THIS AIN'ŐT THE GODDAM
N DAY OF JUDGMENT, TOM.
WHEN ANY VIOLENCE CREATED
MAYBE BUSINESS OPPORTUNITIES;
BUT FIT FOR THE CAMP.
SHOW IT TO YOU,
WONDER IF YOU'ŐD PUT IN A WORD?
-( knocks on door )
- YEAH?
COME ON IN.
YOUR HABIT GET THE BEST
OF YOU AWHILE, SON?
OH, THE LEFT EYE'ŐS PERFECT,
AND THE RIGHT'ŐS COMING BACK.
BE THAT AS IT MAY...
AHEM, WELL...
I MAY BE ABLE TO COME UP
WITH SOME MORE DETAILS.
HE SAID TO TELL YOU
WHAT I SEEN.
AND NOW IS HE HOLDING
THE STRINGS ON YOU?
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY
THAT I'ŐD STOLE HIS PROPERT
Y AND FUCKED HIS ACTION UP.
OR YOU'ŐLL WISH YOU'ŐD HAVE
GOT DROWNED IN THAT BATHHOUSE.
ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME BACK, SON.
I-- OR...
YES, I WILL.
JESUS CHRIST.
THAT TOO,
IS-- IS TRUE ENOUGH.
STAPLETON.
LIKE I KNOW ANYBODY
NO MORE.
HE CAN BE SHERIFF
FOR ALL I CARE.
AND NO FUCKING
PAPERWORK.
WELL, I DON'ŐT EVEN
KNOW IF HE CAN WRITE.
IF HE WAS SWORN IN
UNDER YOUR ROOF.
AWFUL GRATEFUL, AL.
AND IF I GOT 'ŐEM,
THEY WOULDN'ŐT BE APPLIED
TO BUILDING NOTHING.
ANYWAYS...
WOULD YOU WANT
A FREE FUCK?
WOULD YOU TAKE IT
FROM ME, FREE?
( door opening )
OH, YES.
WELL, I JUST STOPPED
FOR A MOMENT.
OH, YES.
- I'ŐLL LOCK UP.
- OH, YES.
KISS MY NECK OR TITS
IF YOU HAVE TO KISS SOMETHING.
LET ME KISS YOU.
WELL, YOU'ŐRE
A GODDAMN JEW FOOL.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
WITHOUT THAT PUTRID APRON
AROUND YOUR MIDSECTION.
- NO.  LET'ŐS DRINK.
- ( laughs )
OUR HEALTH
COMMISSIONER.
WHISKEY.
YOU WERE AT THE TABLE
WHEN HICKOK WAS KILLED.
MY WIFE AND CHILD ARE
TO JOIN ME FROM MICHIGAN.
HE MISSED
THE SWEARING IN TOO.
THEN WHY THE FUCK
DIDN'ŐT HE COME DOWN?
AT WHOSE MYSTERIOUS
PLEASURE YOU SERVE.
A CANDID MOMENT.
THY CIRCUMCISION
BECOMES UNCIRCUMCISION.
THY... UNCIRCUMCISION...
WHO BY--
BY LETTER AND UH...
YEAH.
I WANT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING ABOUT THE LAW.
PLEASE, PLEASE, TAKE A SEAT.
'ŐCAUSE YOU'ŐRE ONE OF THOSE
PAINS IN THE BALLS WHO THINKS
THE LAW CAN BE HONEST.
I DON'ŐT WANT IT.
HELL, I DO LOTS OF THINGS
I DON'ŐT WANT TO DO.
'ŐCAUSE MY PARTNER'ŐS
FUCKING THAT WHORE.
ANYWAY--
HE'ŐS BACK OPEN.
- HOW WAS YOUR
TALK WITH AL?
- CONGRATULATIONS.
GOOD SPORTSMANSHIP,
BULLOCK.
OR PERIL OR SWORD?
I AM PERSUADED THAT...
NOR-- NOR ANGELS,
FROM THE LOVE OF--
OF GOD!
AND--
AND JESUS CHRIST
OUR LORD.
WHO SHOULD BE ABOUT
LOOKING FOR A PLACE.
- VERY WELL.
- I'ŐM SETH BULLOCK.
MR. BULLOCK.
- HOW DO YOU DO, SIR?
- HOW DO YOU DO?
- MY DAUGHTER SAYS THAT
THE DINNER HOUR IS EARLY.
- 6:00 IS FINE.
- Sol: YES, SIR.
- REMARKABLE.
HI, DOC.
- ( chuckles ) OKAY.
- SIT DOWN.
EXCEPT THAT
I LEARNED THIS IN LATIN--
HAVING SAID THAT...
AND DIFFERENT FROM THE...
I THOUGHT WE MIGHT TRY
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
LET'ŐS.
SAUCY WORDS, DOC.
GOOD THING YOU'ŐRE
HANDY WITH THE SNATCH.
SHE'ŐLL BE KICKING UP
HER HEELS IN NO FUCKING TIME.
I WILL LEAVE YOU NOW
TO PURSUE ANOTHER EXCUSE.
GET THAT JEW
OVER HERE.
WE SHOT HIM.
FRESH BAKED BREAD
AND RHUBARB PIE TO COME.
- YOUR REPAST AWAITS
YOUR MOUTHS.
- THANK YOU.
THANK YOU,
MR. FARNUM.
HE HAD SOMETHING
TO DO WITH IT.
AS HER ADVISOR,
I MEAN?
I THOUGHT, BUTTON,
THAT YOU WERE OUR ENTIRE
PREOCCUPATION.
A CHEAT, A BROAD TOSSER
AND A CLIP.
OR SHE'ŐS HIS PIGEON.
WHEN YOU'ŐVE GROWN
A FULL HEAD OF HAIR.
BRASS, THAT WOULD BE...
TO GULL YOUR OWN
FLESH AND BLOOD.
( saloon piano playing )
- MR. SWEARENGEN.
- YOU OWE ME $5.
IF YOU ASS-FUCKED HER,
YOU OWE ME SEVEN.
- IT WASN'ŐT TO DO WITH YOU,
IT WASN'ŐT BUSINESS.
- TRIXIE!
DON'ŐT THINK
I DON'ŐT UNDERSTAND.
TRUSTED EACH OTHER
ENOUGH TO TELL HALF
THE FUCKING TRUTH.
EVERYBODY NEEDS THAT.
IT BECOMES
PRECIOUS TO 'ŐEM.
OR SHE PAYS.
FIVE.SEVEN
FOR AN ASS-FUCK.
YOU GET BACK TO WORK.
YOU SLEEP TONIGHT
AMONGST YOUR OWN.
ANOTHER FUCKING BOTTLE.
AND ARGUED
MORE IMPORTANT MATTERS...
I DIDN'ŐT KNOW
HIM AT ALL.
MY WIFE AND SON
WILL BE JOINING ME SOON.
THEIR PASSIONS RULE.
OR SECURITY OR THE SECURITY
OF HER HOLDINGS.
I'ŐM A PRACTICED
AND INVETERATE LIAR.
IF WE DIDN'ŐT HATE THE
M TOO MUCH TO BE CURIOUS
ABOUT THE WORLD...
WE'ŐD WONDER WHAT
THEY'ŐD HAD TO SAY.
HAND THAT STICK TO A CAPTAIN
OF THE FLOATING TABLE, CY.
WITHDRAWN
WITH APOLOGIES.
ARE WE THAT FAR WEST
THAT WE'ŐVE WOUND UP
IN FUCKING CHINA?
LEON, LEON, LEON.
THIN IT OUT, LEON.
PRUNE THE PATTER DOWN, HMM?
FOR THE JOANIE STUBBS
CONSTRUCTION FUND.
MIND IF I SHOW JOANIE
MY PEACOCK, EDDIE?
YOU NEVER KNOW HOW
THAT SHIT'ŐS GONNA SHAKE OUT.
( cheering )
HE'ŐS LOOKING
TO ROOT AT HER CLAIM.
I GUESS SHE TOLD HIM
WHERE SHE'ŐD BEEN.
AND I USED POOR
FUCKING JUDGMENT.
COLD ENOUGH WORLD
WITHOUT GETTING GONE AGAINST
BY YOUR OWN.
NOW, HOLD
ONTO THAT, HUH?
YOU SHUT THE FUCK UP, HUH?
GIMME THAT!
COME HERE.COME ON.
IS WHERE THIS
WARRANT'ŐS FROM.
SLOW THE FUCK UP.
BEHIND IT SHE RAN
A WHOREHOUSE, HUH?
NOW, I'ŐLL TELL YOU
SOMETHING YOU DON'ŐT KNOW.
( grunting )
JUST SPIT IT OUT.
ANYWAYS.
( Western music playing )
? BRING BACK MY HO-CAKE,
YOU LONG-TAILED NANNY-O ?
YOU LONG TAILED NANNY-O. ?