Previously on Hatfields & McCoys...
All this to-do over a pig.
This is about honor,
about lyin', and murder.
I'm Johnse Hatfield.
I know who you are.
You spent the night under a Hatfield roof?
You're not my daughter anymore.
They're trying to kill you.
I'm going there to rescue my bride.
Uh!
I'm gonna shoot you dead, come dark!
My brothers have got Johnse.
Please, Mr. Hatfield, hurry!
Hurry up.
Stop.
See, I want to just shoot you myself.
But I got to humor my brothers.
In a couple of minutes,
when the sun comes up,
I'm gonna give you this pistol.
Now, will you do the honorable
thing and kill yourself?
Why in God's name would I do that?
Shame and remorse.
Bullshit.
No, you all,
you just want to save yourselves
from doing a murder.
And I ain't ashamed of loving Roseanna.
So he won't die by his own hand.
Will he eat poison?
To hell with this.
Guns down.
Now.
I said now.
Do what he says,
or I'll scatter your brains
all over this place.
The rest of you kneel down
there next to your brother
and pray as if your lives depend on it,
on account they do.
Are you deaf, McCoy?
I said to kneel.
I kneel for no man.
And I pray only to God,
not you.
You're a brave man, Jim McCoy.
Your daddy should be proud.
All right, Skunkhair, torch it.
You know, we should've burnt
down this shithole years ago.
Whoo!
This is none of your business.
Get off me!
You're a damn fool for riding into McCoy hands.
None of that matters now.
Roseanna's carrying my baby.
She saved my life.
I'm gonna marry her.
Roseanna's what?
Did you know about this?
Johnse, she's a McCoy.
She betrayed her own family.
She'll betray ours too.
That ain't true.
You know, I ain't...
I ain't taking this.
No, you'll take it.
Stop it!
You'll take it and like it.
Stop it, please!
Anse, Anse!
Hey, that's enough.
That is enough.
That is... that is enough!
You don't touch that boy
no more, Anderson Hatfield.
You will never marry a McCoy.
You leave this house to go after her.
You don't come back.
Now, you make your choice.
Make it now.
Stay or go.
Whoo!
- Whoo-whoo-whoo!
I'm up.
Come on, come on.
Go, squirrel.
Come on, Sammy.
Ah-ha!
- Whoo!
Now we got a competition on our hands, boys!
One apiece.
Robert E.
Here.
Jefferson, Jefferson.
That's the family discount.
Give me that.
- No.
How much you had already?
- No, I ain't had nothing.
Give it to me.
- I ain't had nothing.
Stop acting like that.
Quit hitting me.
Hey, Robert E., take over.
Nancy.
Hello, Johnse Hatfield.
Hey.
How ya been?
I been fine.
You know,
I should've called on you.
I really didn't mean you no harm.
I just... I guess what happened
was kind of an accident.
I guess it was.
But don't you worry about it none.
I just been all messed up
in my mind about Roseanna.
How is she?
Poorly.
Doctor says she took down with a cough.
She's been spitting up blood.
They think she might lose the baby.
Lose it?
Or not.
Who knows?
Hey, will you...
would you tell her that I asked
after her and the baby?
Would you do that for me?
I'll pass it along...
Next time I see Roseanna.
Hey, grandpappy.
That ain't funny.
Yeah, it is.
Hey, don't let it eat you up.
Hey, speaking of eatin',
have you tried this pickled okra?
Delicious.
It's a damn pepper.
Bullnose red hot.
You son of a bitch.
If you weren't my brother,
you'd be dead right now.
Come on, now.
Let's dance.
Right there, son.
This competition's still open, ain't it?
If'n you don't mind wasting a bullet.
I ain't wasted one yet.
How you gonna beat that,
fog eye?
Good luck.
Hey, hey, toe the line.
You're over the damn mark.
Yeah,
Judge should've caught that.
Just do what you do, son.
What he does is miss.
Oh, Cap.
You missed complete.
No, he didn't.
Hit the nail on the head.
Right on the gol'dang head.
You see where that went.
Hey, settle down, boys.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
This here is a shooting contest.
This here is a shooting contest,
boys.
Get up.
Look at this.
Watch McCoy put his head down.
Hatfield's a-tremblin'.
Devil Anse couldn't meet the old man's eye.
Randall McCoy looked away
like a lonely girl seeing
a hard prick for the first time!
You watch your filthy mouth,
Hatfield.
Might be some rowdy-do.
Whatever happens, Cotton,
you stay right here.
Keep these horses peaceable.
Hah!
Yeah, McCoy flinched.
Skipped off a step.
Hatfield, he shit himself.
You can smell it yet.
How'd you see it, Ellison?
Seems to me both men behaved gentlemanly.
If anyone looked off,
they both did together.
Let's go.
That is for owing me almost
a whole greenback on my heirloom fiddle
for a year, you thieving prick.
Johnse was right.
You hit like a old woman.
Maybe we should get you a bonnet and a dress.
No more.
I am hell on earth!
You're a damn stinkhog.
That's enough now.
You take him, Ellison.
Hatfields, stay out of this.
Get in there.
Come on, bud.
Come on, get him.
Yeah, that's the way.
How many more do you need?
Let him sit there.
Aw, we ain't done with you yet.
Aww.
Ah!
Go on, there, get him!
Go take your dancing lessons.
You're going dancin'!
Take this.
Stick 'em.
Ellison!
Hold on, little brother.
Just keep holding on.
Anse, Anse.
Where's...
Where's Cotton?
Cotton, come here.
Let the law handle it.
You get well.
We'll look after the rest.
Cotton, you comfort your daddy.
Can we go home now?
Levicy, get him to a bed at the house.
Johnse, Captain, get his legs.
Gonna get him in the wagon.
Levicy, get a blanket.
Gonna get him up there...
He was always angling for peace,
throwing water on fires that others started,
letting people have their way,
and now...
now maybe killed for it.
What did Ellison say to you?
Asked for Cotton.
We got 'em!
Sherriff holed 'em up!
We got them bastard McCoys.
We got 'em, Anse.
Sheriff,
you can't let them take us.
How's your brother, Anse?
Still alive...
Barely.
I need you to hand over your prisoners, sheriff.
I understand how you feel,
Anse.
But these boys broke Kentucky law
on Kentucky soil and are obliged
to be tried by Kentucky justice.
Yeah.
Well, I'll take 'em anyways.
Anse, give me a minute.
I want to go on a record about all this.
I wish you would, Judge.
Explain to your brother howsomever he and you
and the other Hatfields feel...
and I know that's awful...
this business requires to be done legal.
Sheriff,
you acknowledge the victim
was a West Virginia citizen.
That's the essence of the case determinative.
That's why West Virginia law prevails.
Now, you can dispute the matter
here or later in court.
It's your choice,
you son of a bitch.
You're likely to lose in either venue.
Yah.
You abscond with these boys
over my strenuous objection.
Easy, easy.
Damn.
He gon...
he gonna die?
Should've already.
Oh, my lord.
Obtained a directive from Judge Tobias Wagner
instructing the sheriff to
recapture and restore the boys
to his lawful custody.
Sheriff.
The law...
Ain't worth a bucket of spit.
They-they were kidnapped illegal.
So why can't we kidnap 'em back the same way?
No, Hatfields will have 'em heavily guarded.
Could turn into a bloodbath.
Sweet Jesus,
what have they done?
Jim, you go with Perry to Pikeville
and get this letter toé sheriff maynard.
Calvin, you stay here with
your mother until I get back.
Poppy,
you ain't going over there.
Alone he'll do me no harm.
It's Poppy.
Where?
Right there.
Right... you see him?
- Yeah, I see him.
He's coming to get us.
- There he is, Poppy.
I come unarmed to ask you for my boys.
You got my word.
I'll turn 'em over to the law in Pikeville.
Your boys stabbed my brother.
They stabbed him over
and over again, then shot him.
Penalty for that's the same in Kentucky
as it is in West Virginia.
How is Ellison?
I pray he recovers.
You still believe in praying?
I do.
Well, then we'll leave it to the almighty.
If my brother survives,
you can have your boys,
and we'll let Kentucky law take its course.
If he dies...
If my brother dies,
your boys will stay here not long before justice
will be done on 'em.
Is there anything I can say or give you
that'll move you from that?
No.
I'd like to see my sons.
I don't think so.
Then let their mother see 'em.
We'll send for her.
Devil Anse Hatfield,
I rue the day I saved your life.
May God damn your eternal soul.
That might be, Randall.
But I don't recall God saving your ass that day.
We saved each other,
'cause that's...
'cause that's what men do in war.
This all here,
this all sits the way it sits,
'cause of us and nobody else.
If you feel the need
to bring up God one more time,
whose side he sits on...
You won't be making a ride home.
Yah.
Hey.
I hope you and all of your kin
and friends and babies
come and try to rescue 'em
so's we kill you all at once,
not drag it out.
Jim.
Shut up.
What, where's he going?
What's he doing?
He's leaving us.
What?
He's leaving.
Poppy!
- Poppy!
- Shut up.
Poppy!
Poppy, we're here!
Shut up.
Poppy!
What are you doing?
Cutting the boards.
What for?
There's a possibility.
There's a possibility of uncle Ellison dyin'.
Jim said we'd want a coffin.
Don't you cut no boards.
I tell you when you can cut any boards.
Yes, sir.
Now you better do your job and get 'em back.
We just have to get up a posse.
We have a written finding
here from Judge Tobias Wagner
stating you're legally entitled
to enter West Virginia
in hot pursuit.
West Virginia's sovereign
and has armed Hatfields swarming all over.
You cannot abide by this.
If'n Ellison Hatfield dies,
Devil Anse has so much has said
he'd kill my sons.
Ellison dies,
your sons are murderers.
Just made some enemies,
sheriff.
Get out of my way.
Reverend Garrett.
Captain Anderson Hatfield sent me to fetch you.
He promised Randall.
Ellison?
Passed over Jordan singing with the angels.
Oh, dear God.
Ma.
I'm to fetch you to your boys.
Where are they?
They're in a safe place where they can visit
with their mother.
I'm to bring only her.
I gave my word.
Ride to Pikeville.
Tell your father where I am
and what has happened.
All right, ma.
I've come to see my sons.
They're inside.
It's very Christian of you to do this, Anse.
Save it for your congregation,
preacher.
Please, Captain Hatfield.
Let me take 'em back to Kentucky with me.
Please.
You'll get 'em back.
That much I can promise you.
Mama.
I brought some food from home.
Is Poppy here?
Is he coming?
I've got apples from the yard tree and cheese,
the one you like, bud,
bread your sister baked...
Is pop comin' back?
Some chicken.
From the first book of kings...
- Hold on, reverend.
Mama, we...
We saw Poppy riding away.
When's he coming back?
When's he getting us out of here?
You can't imagine the pain that comes
with giving birth to a child.
But I welcomed that pain over and over
so that I might have each of you.
I love you all
and will always love you.
But what about Poppy?
He will always love you too.
I meant...
'Any who escape the sword of hazael
'will be put to death by Jehu.
'And any who escape the sword of Jehu
'will be put to death by Elisha.
'But I shall spare 7,000 in Israel.
'All the knees that have not bent before baal.
All the mouths that have not kissed him.'
All right.
Whoa, whoa.
Hickory tree there.
Tie 'em tight now.
Johnse.
Is that too tight?
You're shooting phamer there
when the time comes.
You reap what you sow.
You're shooting Tolbert.
Mm.
Tolbert first.
Bud.
You boys understand what's gonna happen here?
You understand why?
Make yourselves ready.
Aim!
Harden your hearts.
Oh.
'Surely thou shalt slay the wicked, o God.
'Depart from me therefore,
ye bloody men.
'Do not I hate them that hate thee, o lord?
'I hate them with perfect hatred.
I count them mine enemies.'
Same family that killed
your brothers killed my pap.
Somebody ought to do something about it.
I don't see your sister.
Roseanna's ailing.
Still laid over at aunt Betty's.
Can't travel none.
She lose the baby?
No, it come, a girl,
but it's sickly.
Likely to perish?
I pray not.
But likely.
Likely.
Baby's daddy,
Johnse Hatfield...
Folks are saying he was amongst
them that killed your brothers.
I pray he wasn't.
Likely was.
Likely.
Tolbert...
Phamer...
And bud...
Having been handled with such
manifest injustice and cruelly murdered,
when they stand before the lord,
he will wash away their sins
and take them to the promised land.
People forget.
Hatfields killed our pap too.
Honest soldier coming home from war
doing no harm.
That's another item goes on Hatfield's account...
Shut up.
Come on.
Which reckoning is past due,
which bill needs collectin'.
Come on.
I'm accepting donations,
reward money for the capture or killing
of the murderous Hatfields.
McCoy family thanks you.
Do not let this atrocity go unpunished.
Jesus will be smiling on you and your family.
Thank you.
It ain't fitting you remain here
just sitting days on end.
I know he's revenged.
I miss my daddy.
My brother was always about the work of life.
He'd...
He'd not...
He'd not want you lingering about his remains...
Not when...
not when there's chores to do.
A lot of strange faces in town.
Man hunters, Randall,
here to bring your sons' killers to justice.
They ain't here for justice.
They're here to try and collect
the bounty we're offering.
Ma'am.
This here Devil Anse
Hatfield's loggin' enterprise?
Devil Anse won't be back till tomorrow mornin'.
If you're looking for work,
he only hires men he know:
His neighbors, his kin.
Well, right now, I believe
I got business with you.
What's that?
You got that funny streak
of white in your hair, Tom.
Guess that's why folks call you Skunkhair.
My friends call me that.
Well, no reason we can't be friends, Tom.
Don't get testy.
I'm just doing my job.
You got a prize on your head,
Mr. Skunkhair Tom Wallace.
You got the wrong man.
I didn't do nothin'.
Kentucky courts say otherwise.
You must've crossed the tug and got lost.
This here West Virginia.
I'm in the right place, Tom.
McCoy family's gettin' indictments for them
that murdered their three boys,
already posted rewards.
What the hell?
How much?
I don't recollect exact.
Couldn't be more than two bits or so for you.
You son of a bitch.
Shut it down.
Take 'em off.
All right.
Hey, Selkirk, come here.
Come here.
Where you been?
You been drinkin', hmm?
No, sir.
No?
You sleepin'?
Yes, sir.
I'm a hold back 25¢?
25¢?
Ugh.
Anse!
They scalped him,
like Indians done it.
He's my best friend since we was little.
Jim.
He was my best friend.
Randall McCoy done this.
Thought we'd leveled the scales.
Uncle Anse,
I found these in the logs
underneath Skunkhair.
$750 for you.
Seeing as how you was the outlaw leader.
What in tarnation?
Am I in there, French?
Well, I'll be damned, Lark,
you and me both.
They're after me too.
Hell, Selkirk,
you're worth more than me,
McCoy defector that you are.
$600?
That's uncle Wall.
Uncle Wall wasn't even in that shootin'.
This is out of hand.
Greedy bushwhackers
and bloodsuckers by the dozens
are gonna come after us.
Just keep your guns handy.
Cap.
Yes, sir.
Take care of Skunkhair here.
Everybody else get back to work.
'Lias.
Come on.
- Anse, a word.
Reckon we ought to stock up on supplies and ammo.
We need to take to them hills if a posse comes.
Nobody knows these hills like us.
Set up lookouts along the tug.
We won't get caught unawares again.
Uhhuh.
What do you hear of Roseanna?
I once had a daughter Roseanna,
who's now dead to me.
How's Sally holding up?
Poorly.
How would you expect?
Women are fortunate to enjoy
special consideration, hmm?
If I curled up in a ball
every tragic turn of events,
I'd never get any work done.
Quit talkin' like an imbecile.
You never lost your sons.
Mr. Cline?
Not now.
We're busy here.
Not too busy to pay me the $250 bounty owed me
on Mr. Skunkhair Tom Wallace.
Should I have brung his ears too?
Put that abomination away.
I'm owed the bounty.
There were no conditions imposed.
We are not Savages.
It is our duty to bring
the Savages in for justice.
Avoiding unnecessary wear
and tear on their corpses.
Had to get me out of West Virginie quick.
Couldn't strain my horse toting a whole carcass.
What's your name?
Frank Phillips.
You the one they call 'Bad Frank'?
Not to my face.
And not twice.
Do not come back for more
reward money, Mr. Phillips.
I will not be a party to atrocity.
Any event,
we got our indictments
against the murderers,
and we're sending deputies
across the tug.
No doubt they'll handle things just fine.
Ma'am.
I'd like to see Roseanna.
See our baby.
Even if she weren't too sickly,
she'd not want to see
the murderer of her brothers.
I didn't...
I didn't murder 'em.
I raised my rifle.
I shot over their heads.
You can ask Alex Messer.
I built a cabin for me,
Roseanna,
and the baby to live at.
It's a... it's a real nice one
with an oilpaper window.
You built a cabin for your whiskey business
and to consort with whores.
God damn it.
I took a chance coming here.
They got a reward out for me.
Please.
A man...
A man's got a right to see his own child.
You got no rights here.
Now, get yourself off my porch and gone.
I got my rights!
I'm tellin' you that!
God damn it!
Come on, girl.
Fft, fft, fft.
You see him?
Yeah.
I got him.
Shoot him.
Just be quiet, Parris.
Did you get him?
No.
Identify yourself.
I said identify yourself.
Bounty hunters.
Worst kind of trash.
Cap, get your paper and quill.
Time to put Randall McCoy on notice.
Found these horses ground-tied
a few miles out of town.
Figured I'd bring 'em in for the sheriff.
Letter pinned on there is addressed
to the lawyer Cline and you,
Mr. McCoy.
'My name is Nat Hatfield.
'I am not one individual but many.'
This is as good as a confession.
'We hereby notify you
that if you invade our state
'to take or kill Hatfields,
we will charge it to you.
Your hides will pay the penalty.'
Devil Anse Hatfield is threatening to kill us,
like he done these men.
We got it in writing.
We appreciate your help,
Mr. Miller.
Let me get these horses over to the sheriff.
Hey, Cotton,
give us another bottle.
Cotton, give us a bottle.
I love Johnse Hatfield so much.
Why don't he see that?
On account of you're a whore.
Better than some McCoy bitch.
Cap, put down the whiskey,
make like nature calls.
Get my drift.
All right, I'm gonna find me a tree to water.
That's good.
You know, I knew this boy once 30 years ago.
Could hold his hand over that fire
for two minutes and take the pain.
Do you know who that boy was,
Cotton Top?
That was your old uncle Jim Vance.
No.
Yes, God's truth.
William 'Cap' Hatfield.
Yeah?
Button your dick,
you vulgar bastard.
I'm arresting you for the murder
of Tolbert, phamer, and...
Miller?
Miller, come on, wake up.
Another one of your deputies
what's gonna fix things for ya?
A tele-scop...
Scope.
- Scope.
It's a telescope.
Telescope.
For a gun, latest thing.
You shoot a target at 100 yards,
makes it the same as 25.
You joshin' me?
Hard to miss at 25 yards.
Yep.
Ordered it near six month ago.
Just arrived by push boat.
Take a look, little brother.
That is one fine purchase.
I figure to use it on old Devil Anse.
Hey, give me that.
Come on.
Take that.
You see him?
Get on the ground behind me.
Don't even breathe.
I got you this time.
Oh, God.
Hey, Anse!
I do believe we got ourselves a real McCoy!
Cap done shoot 'em dead!
You saved your pappy.
I'm proud of you, son.
You are good, boy!
Mama, are you sure you won't eat some?
No, thank you, sweetheart.
I'm fine.
There's something you've been wanting to tell me?
What is it?
Your nephew Parris has been killed.
Good lord.
Poor Parris.
Got to do something about it,
Randall.
Got more detectives and family
coming back dead every week.
You can't keep poking a mad bear with a twig
and making it madder.
We need a big stick,
someone prepared to execute our indictments.
Pa...
Let me do it.
I'll get my brothers' killers.
I'll be his right hand.
I can fire a gun, pa.
I appreciate it, boys,
but the only success we've had
in capturing any of our fugitives
has been with Bad Frank.
I do not like that man.
That man is a Savage.
He's the only one equal to the task.
Can this bad man, the Savage,
can he bring me my boys back?
We got a paying customer for ya.
Bye, Miss Nancy.
Easier seein' president Chester A. Arthur
than passing through these woods
to get your 'shine.
What you want, Nancy?
Purchasin' whiskey for my brother's birthday.
Though I did hear you paid
a visit to my aunt Betty.
I don't much like aunt Betty.
When you gonna stop tryin'
to win over my relations?
Only one I care about,
your cousin Roseanna,
mother of my baby.
Little Sarah Elizabeth is frail and ailing,
and so is Roseanna.
Folks don't expect the child to live much longer.
I'm truly sorry, Johnse.
Without the baby, I fear
you'll lose Roseanna too.
After all that happened, I...
it seems like she don't want you anymore.
What am I supposed to do?
You don't deserve these hard times, Johnse.
You truly don't.
Hah!
Ho, ho, ho.
My lady...
Uncle Wall,
I'd like you to marry us,
me and Nancy McCoy.
Jesus H. Christ almighty, boy.
You gone plumb crazy?
No, sir.
What about the McCoy woman
you already knocked up?
Yes, sir, well,
that is a sad chapter.
That seems over with... Roseanna,
though, not by my choosin'.
You know,
it's different with Nancy.
There ain't no one opposed.
Do your ma and pa know?
You know,
I ain't askin' this time.
Please, uncle Wall.
Me marrying a McCoy could help end
all this dying between our families.
By the power vested in me
by the state of West Virginia,
I now pronounce you man and wife.
Jefferson, come over here and sign this thing.
Right there.
Let me sign.
Shut up.
You sure you want to do this,
sis?
Smile, little lady.
It's your wedding day.
Man and wife now.
And I expect no more trouble
between us, not ever.
I sure hope you know what you're doin', boy.
I don't know how to tell
y'all this but just say it.
Just come on out with it, Wall.
Yesterday I married Johnse and Nancy McCoy.
What?
You married 'em?
Well,
it was damn sure reluctantly.
I can tell you that.
Harmon McCoy's daughter?
Oh, my God.
Well, he was lookin' to be lost to us.
This time,
he just may have succeeded.
Well, Anse,
he thinks it'll make peace
between you and Randall.
He does, huh?
Somebody want to tell me how a son of mine
could turn out to be so goddamn dumb?
Cap.
Yeah?
Get your horse.
Go fetch your brother.
No matter how you fortify it,
Anse,
this place is too close
to the tug and open to attack.
As long as that peckerwood Perry Cline
keeps putting up bounties,
the wolves are just gonna keep on comin'.
Oh, Wall, I think we sent Kentucky a notion
of how we deal with bounty hunters.
Damn it, Jim.
All I'm sayin' is,
y'all would be better off
deeper in the mountains.
Just to be safe, Anse.
Well, I'll take it under advisement, Wall.
And don't you let Johnse bring
his new McCoy hussy with him.
I'll bring him home, mama.
When you do the trick with me,
are you picturing Roseanna?
Tryin' not to.
Tryin' but failin'?
I need more time, I guess.
I'll give you time, Johnse.
I can wait a long time for what I want.
Anybody the hell in there?
That's my brother.
Jefferson.
You got to hide me.
Why we got to do that?
Can't let me hang, sis,
not for no fight that I can't even remembers,
'cause I was drunk
and feels terrible about poor Fred Wolford.
Fred Wolford?
The mailman.
We was at a barn dance,
drinking, arguing,
went out back,
commenced to scuffle.
I just give him... I give him a little cut,
and he tried to shoot me.
So I wrenched that gun around,
and I made him shoot his own damn self.
Oh, hell.
He died this morning.
Now they all out there looking for me.
They got a reward out.
Come here, brother.
You gonna be all right.
All right.
We'll feed you.
You can spend the night here.
You're gonna be safe here,
Jefferson.
For the night.
As long as I'm here.
I don't look like the girl
Johnse romanced no more.
Will he still want me lookin' like this?
Too late to worry about that.
I didn't want to stir the pot,
but here it is.
Johnse's gone and got himself married
to your cousin Nancy.
Did you hear me?
Johnse Hatfield
married Nancy McCoy.
Mr. Phillips,
good to see you.
Equally good to see the two of you.
Expect you know why I called
this meeting here this morning.
Y'all are lookin' for someone to lead a posse
across the river,
and I'm the only gun handler around here
who's man enough for the job.
You're awful full of yourself, ain't ya?
I wouldn't call it that.
I wasted some years of my misspent youth
a'ridin' with Jesse and Frank.
Once got to witness wild bill kill a man,
so I seen better than me,
though not many.
And I can't help but see
what you got to choose from.
I didn't realize you'd once been an outlaw.
Oh, that, of course,
was before I was saved,
long prior to my being washed clean of sin
by the blood of our lord and savior Jesus Christ.
You sure don't act Christian.
I'm a warrior for God,
Mr. McCoy,
a fighter of evil,
right and ready to take on your demon murderers.
I heard you were a Pinkerton man.
I was,
till I got shot in the back by Hatfields,
left me with my limp,
another reason that warrants my hiring.
I bear Devil Anse Hatfield and
all his kin a personal grudge.
Now, let me get this straight.
Now, Randall wants his governor
to make our governor arrest us
and cart us over to Kentucky?
It's called extradition, Elias,
and I don't think our governor
Wilson will agree to it.
Well, I got my own ace in this poker game.
My friend John Floyd works
with Windy at the capital now.
Yes, sir, our new assistant secretary of state.
John will help out.
It's Cap and Johnse.
How do we handle this boy,
'vicy?
Well, not by pushin' and pullin' him.
That's what drove him into
the arms of another McCoy.
You want to untie this knot...
You get her to hate him.
Take your hat off in here.
So...
How's the married man?
Doin' just fine, uncle Wall,
just fine.
So marriage suits you then,
huh?
Yes, sir,
right down to the ground.
She must be one sorry-ass cook.
You choosin' a ham supper over
a comely McCoy bride.
She ain't McCoy no more,
is she?
She's Hatfield,
Mrs. Johnse Hatfield.
Hatfield ain't just a name on a piece of paper.
Don't expect to bring her
around here like the last one.
Things get spoke that ain't for McCoy ears.
Well,
I didn't bring her here, did I?
Don't sass your father.
Your horndog philanderin' helped make this mess.
Mama, please, you know what?
I get enough grief at home.
Truth be told,
I need to get away for a bit.
It ain't her, you know.
Nancy treats me fine.
It's just...
Her gol'dang brother is turning
my honeymoon into misery.
Jefferson McCoy?
I heard he killed the mailman the other day.
Got a gol'dang reward up too.
You're harborin' a McCoy
with a price on his head?
Nancy says it's just for a while,
says it's her duty to protect him.
Well, loyal sis.
How much is the reward?
I don't know.
$100 maybe.
Well, we just want you to be happy, son.
Why don't you take a little time
away from home, hmm?
Wouldn't hurt none.
Go huntin' with your pa.
It's true; I ain't been huntin' for a spell.
You up to goin' with me, Johnse?
That'd be nice.
I don't know.
Yeah, might as well.
Shit, better than watching
my layabout brother-in-law
drink up all my whiskey profits,
right?
Amen to that.
I believe that's a Jefferson McCoy.
Who's sayin' that?
Johnse Hatfield's uncle Jim Vance
and his little brother Cap.
Where's... where's Johnse?
Out huntin' with his pa.
So what you doin' here?
Doin' a little hunting ourselves.
Well...
Not much huntin' around here.
Place is all shot out of deer and such.
Oh,
there's still critters here.
And one critter in particular
has a handsome reward on his head.
Nancy!
What are you doing to my brother?
Nancy, do something!
They gonna take me in!
Get off!
You get back in that cabin,
Miss McCoy.
You get yourself dressed proper.
Get off him, you old coot!
What the hell you gonna do?
Nancy!
Damn it.
I'll show you.
Come on.
Get 'em, Nancy!
Get off me, you...
you bitch!
You good for nothing bitch!
Let go!
You want to do some whippin'?
Here's some whippin', girl.
Don't let him do that to you!
Yeah, bet you like that,
don't you, you mean little...
Get off of her, Vance!
Stop it, Jim.
He's gettin' away.
Come on, Cap.
We're gonna lose him.
Stabilize me.
I ain't drowned!
Come on.
- You Hatfield morons!
Come and get me!
Goddang pecker-pullers!
What's the matter with you?
Can't swim?
Go ahead, shoot, you fog-eyed,
half-blind bastard!
Here I am!
You one-eyed ape, it's 1/2 mile!
Yeah!
A hole in the head.
You did good, boy.
Nancy?
Jesus.
Somebody bashed you?
Oh, my God.
Jim Vance beat me like I was a mule, worse.
Uncle Jim?
He did disgusting things to me.
Him and Cap come in here and take Jefferson.
Now, you tell me true whether you had anything
to do with that.
I swear to you I didn't.
Nancy, I swear it.
Well, then you go,
and you get after 'em,
and you bring my brother back here.
You go on and do that.
You do that for me.
Damn it.
Get!
I can't, Nance.
Can't or you won't?
I can't.
It's already been played out.
I seen my... my brother Cap down the road.
Jefferson tried to run.
Cap had to shoot him.
Jefferson's killed, Nancy.
Oh.
No.
Now I ain't got no one.
Hey, hey, hey.
All of 'em dead.
Now I ain't got nobody.
Now my brother's dead.
You got me.
You st...
- No!
You still got me.
- Stop it, damn it!
Come here.
- Don't touch me!
Stop it!
I don't want you here!
No!
Hey.
No.
Damn it.
Get out of here.
Get!
Get out of here!
Why you want to be on the posse?
I don't like Hatfields.
Were you in the army?
I tried to enlist, both sides.
There was something awry with my genitals.
It prevent you from riding a horse?
Oh, not anymore.
And I'm a fine shot.
I can hit a rat's ass at 40 yards.
You leave word where to find
you when it comes to that.
Next.
My name is Ransom Bray.
I am armed and ready to ride.
And I'll take on your fight
and anyone or anything
you put in front of me.
Mr. Phillips, I ain't here to just join a posse.
I want to be your personal deputy,
'cause I work hard,
and I wouldn't say...
got any law enforcement experience?
Well, I... I want to learn the occupation,
'cause I know I'd be good at it.
I ain't gonna give you no guff.
All right, look,
you take me on,
and I'll even split my wages with you.
Well, sir,
let me talk to Mr. Cline and Mr. McCoy about you.
Lady upstairs wanting to talk to you.
Gentlemen, I'll be back.
Man downstairs said you had something to tell me.
How would you like to know
where Selkirk McCoy is,
traitor that killed his own kin?
What would you want in return?
For you to kill Jim Vance,
man that did this to my face...
worse than that,
killed my brother and my pap.
Jim Vance is on the list.
Sooner or later we gonna get every damn one.
Not just get 'em, kill 'em.
You can demonstrate on Selkirk.
He's workin' down in
beckleyville using a fake name.
Want me to kill him too?
Makes me no never mind.
It's Jim Vance I hate.
And just one other thing.
Just leave Johnse Hatfield be...
for now.
Ready?
Up.
Selkirk McCoy, the kin killer.
Yes, sir, I believe that's you.
Well, you got me wrong, sir.
Name's bidwell.
Stop the horseshit.
You're Selkirk McCoy,
and we damn well know it.
Don't... don't kill me.
Don't kill me.
I give up.
You got me dead to rights.
A man who'd shoot his own cousins,
I don't expect he'd let himself get taken alive.
Make your play.
I ain't wearin' no gun.
My hands are up.
I won't deny a man his right to defend hisself.
I'll count to five,
and you go for it.
One, two...
Aaron, you tell him I'll surrender!
Three.
I'm gettin' down on the floor.
I'm helpless.
I surrender.
You got a witness right there.
He knows I give myself up.
Yeah,
real-life Judas Iscariot.
Don't do it, Mister.
It ain't right.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe he ain't worth the price of a bullet.
That's right.
No, sir.
Hit me, Cap.
Ooh.
It's me.
Open the damn door.
He's alone.
Hey, sugar.
You insane, boy?
That's right, Johnse.
Don't give up.
Whoa.
Come on, Johnse.
Yeah!
- You shut up.
Why'd you do it, uncle Jim?
What the hell?
Do what?
Get your money, Cap.
Let's get 'em.
All right, now.
Get off him.
I'm gonna kill you!
You monster!
Nancy says you damn near raped her!
That's a lie!
That bitch came at me first.
That's my wife you're talking about, God damn it.
Johnse, sit down.
You're drunk.
Sit, sit.
The only way I could come here was liquored up.
I hate goin' up against my family like this.
Uncle Jim's right about Nancy comin' after him.
She started whippin' him with a cow's tail.
Pret'near took my eye out,
she did.
I had to jerk that thing out
of her hand to save myself.
I'm sorry, Johnse.
Well... You know.
You hear about Selkirk?
That Bad Frank prick hauled
him off to Pikeville jail.
How did he know where he was,
Johnse?
Selkirk was incognito.
Only us Hatfields knew where he was.
I am foursquare Hatfield,
front and back, dawn to dusk.
Yeah, well, that's why
emotions are runnin' so wild,
because there's a spy amongst us.
Whoa.
Papers come through.
It's official.
'Special deputy,
state of Kentucky,
Mr. Frank Phillips.'
Sent by governor Simon Buckner.
You should be very pleased,
Mr. Phillips.
Men, should you meet resistance,
you'll use no more force
than is necessary to prevail.
We are not infidels like the Hatfields.
We embody the law.
Let us pray.
Dear lord,
may you be with us today and bless our endeavors.
Amen.
Years past,
you'd have lead the charge
and fixed this mess yourself.
Today you best leave it to the younger men.
He killed my boys.
This is my fight.
Your sons can ride in your stead.
With dignified regard,
Mr. McCoy, you ain't deputized.
He's right, Randall.
You're the one who insists this all be legal.
Yah.
Let's ride!
Our boys will be fine.
I thought you were goin' off with 'em.
Mm, they reckon I'm too old and shaky.
I'd slow 'em down.
They're young men.
We should pray for their safety.
You ever get tired of praying, Randall?
Seems like it so rarely works.
It's not ours to question God's will.
That's what faith's for.
Don't be fearful, mother.
Gets awful dark in these woods at night.
We could use some of Tom Edison's
electric lightnin' bulbs.
There's so much I wanted to give you,
so much, Sally.
But all I brought you is pain in this life.
Others have, but not you.
You always believe what you say,
Randall.
That is a rare quality,
and I admire you for it.
That why you married me?
I married you, because one day,
you're gonna buy me that electric double boiler.
Where's the guards?
I don't know.
Maybe waiting to ambush us.
There ain't nobody here,
Mr. Phillips.
Food on the stove,
plates on the table.
Let's wait till they get back.
Devil ain't comin' back.
Heard us comin' and gone deep in the hills.
Least we got him on the run.
Now, we got others to go fetch.
Wake up, frenchy,
you lazy son of a bitch.
Don't kick me, Lark,
you asshole.
Lark Varney!
French Ellis!
Come on outside!
We'll give you one chance!
Well, who are you?
Deputy marshals out of pike county!
We got warrants!
Toss out your guns and come on out!
We're lookin' for Devil Anse Hatfield!
Either one of you mush-heads
know where he went to?
Hey, that you, Ransom Bray?
Hey, I know you!
Yeah, I'm friends with the fella
that's humpin' your sister
Ruth-Anne back home!
Thought maybe I'd look her up myself,
but the line's too long!
Ah!
I think they killed me,
frenchy.
I'm g... I'm gutshot.
Tell us where the Hatfields run off to,
and we'll spare you!
Hey, Lark.
- Come on out!
They shot me, frenchy.
Come on.
Drink some of this.
You got to stay with me, Lark.
Okay, I'm freightin' you out.
Okay.
- Okay?
You put up a good show,
and I'll make a run for it,
circle behind 'em.
Okay.
- Okay, come on.
Come on.
All right, we're comin'.
Hold your fire.
Lark will tell you about the Hatfields.
All right,
you break to the right,
and I'll go left, okay?
All right, I quit this fight!
Here's my gun!
Hell, if I'd have known y'all was comin',
I'd have put my Sunday best on.
French, you're under arrest for your part
in the illegal execution
of the sons of Randall McCoy.
How you know my sister Ruth-Anne?
McCoy boys.
Calvin, Jim, I see y'all were
takin' up your daddy's war.
Jesus, you already got Alex and Charlie?
You know, that other fella I don't recognize.
I mean, y'all just round up
anybody you come across?
All you need to know is,
this here warrant has your name on it.
Yeah, reckon I'm gonna hang,
be a big disappointment to my family.
Well, take us straightaway to Devil Anse,
you won't have to ride in the cage.
How do you know my sister?
Hell, everybody pass through bluefield
gets a pork job from Ruth-Anne Bray.
What the hell?
Made one damn remark too many.
He was takin' us to Devil Anse!
He don't know where Hatfield is!
French Ellis was always a fat liar.
How do you know him?
We was in school together,
the one year I went.
The way I fire asswipe morons is,
I put a bullet in their goddamn heads.
Won't happen again.
Apologize.
We got to do this right.
Politic!
No more trail justice,
you hear?
I might want to be sheriff one day.
Hey.
I picked up our ammo and our winchesters.
Good.
Dumb McCoy's raiding all the push boats;
Didn't think to check the mail wagon.
Yeah.
- Is it true?
Governor Wilson in there?
Next best thing.
He sent his boy John B. Floyd.
No, no, no.
John, now,
I want you to understand this.
Now, what we got here is Lark Varney,
French Ellis,
Skunkhair Wallace,
all of them dead.
Then we got Alex Messer,
Selkirk... pliant men...
about a half dozen others kidnapped.
I hear you, Wall.
It's hard to know how many of our relations
they've buried in unmarked graves.
Why, you have governor
Wilson's complete support, Anse.
He's doin' everything he can.
Well, it's pretty clear it ain't enough.
I petitioned the U.S. district court
for writs of habeas corpus
on our imprisoned citizens.
Now, governor Wilson has had a heated exchange
of telegrams with governor Buckner.
Heated exchange?
Yes, sir.
Hear that, Wall?
They had a...
They had themselves a heated exchange.
Mm.
Give me troopers at the border, John,
troopers at the border,
so when McCoy tries it again,
you stop his ass.
John, John, what these son'
bitches are doin' is illegal.
Ain't no out-of-state lawman
got the right to invade
another sovereign state to abduct citizens,
warrant or no damn warrant.
I sent an official requisition to Kentucky
calling for the arrest of Frank Phillips
and 23 members of his posse.
Kentucky ain't gonna do nothin'.
But if they try to invade West Virginia again,
Mr. McCoy's posse can be arrested here.
Mmhmm, by who?
Ah, hell, deputize us.
Give us a few Cannon,
we'll ride into Pikeville,
end this shit right now.
Sir, you are talkin' about
startin' another civil war.
That's not talk, John.
That's what we already got.
So you tell the governor...
He steps in, or I will.