Everybody get a move on!
We're loading on the run!
Head for the tree line!
Fall back!
We'll make our stand on the ridge.
Cover your backs!
Come on, let's go!
Don't stop!
Here they come!
Come on!
Come on, let's go!
Come on.
I'll cut them damn buttons
off, randall.
Makes you a target.
At least I can stay warm at night.
How are you still keeping
your britches up?
Nature provides.
Over here!
Take cover and reload!
You're gonna lose that arm.
I'll give the arm.
Just want to live.
Here they come!
Don't shoot!
Hold fire.
Yankee cavalry coming.
Company strength.
This could be it, anse.
Best make your peace.
Yeah, well, I never courted
god before, randall.
I doubt he'll hear me now.
On the left!
Can't hold this.
Get the boys back to the line.
Tell them to leave the pistols
with me.
Soldier, on your feet now!
Move!
We're moving out!
Them that's got sidearms,
put them in this sack here.
Come on, let's move!
Go on.
I'm a faster runner than you are.
Hey, anse.
I'll pray for you.
We're moving out!
Make it stop.
Make the hurt stop.
Oh, oh, hey.
Make it go away.
That's it.
Yeah, that's good.
I'll take some of them
biscuits and beans.
Got your sidearms back for you.
Well, I'll be.
How many yanks you kill, devil anse?
How'd you get away, captain?
Damn miracle.
Anse.
What do you think you're doing?
Well, I ain't stayin' to watch
the boys we just saved
die for a lost cause.
Lost?
You don't believe that.
I do.
Come on, what do you think
would happen
if every soldier decided for himself
when the war was lost?
Be shorter wars for sure.
Don't make a cause no better,
randall,
when good men die for it in vain.
From here on out,
I fight only from home.
We're your home.
You can't just twist things
to suit yourself.
This is desertion.
I don't look at it that way.
I figure I deserted my family
when I signed up.
You'd be wise to come with me.
You took an oath, anse.
We swore "death before dishonor."
Nothing changes that.
What if I'm on that firing squad
that has to put you down?
Well, if it comes to that,
don't flinch.
This is wrong.
I can't let you do this.
You take care of yourself, randall.
Many thanks for today.
God hates deserters.
You ought to buy your dog
a drink, uncle jim.
And a little of this.
And a little of that.
Smell good too, don't you?
Damn dog.
You get that coat off a dead yankee?
No, I did not.
You find it in an outhouse
somewheres?
No, I did not.
Where'd you get it then?
I wore it throughout the rebellion.
My nephew,
"devil" anse Hatfield,
proudly serves these here
confederate states of america,
as does your brother randall.
Yet you dare come in here
and wear that
goddamned bluebottle jacket,
you son of a bitch?
Near as many around these parts
are fighting and dying for the union.
As for me, war is passed,
but I ain't got another jacket.
Howsomever, being as how I'm
getting a little hot in here,
I will take it off.
Put it on my charge.
You're gonna throw that damn
yankee jacket on the floor,
and you're gonna piss on it.
I'm going on home.
Don't much care for
the perfumed stank in here.
Can't even pay for your drink.
What kind of a damn man are you?
The kind who, you wanna come after,
you'll find ready, Jim Vance.
Unlike your kinfolk here,
i'm not afeard of no man
on account of he uses his dog
for a whore.
Leave it now, uncle jim.
Do you bluebellies know
the penalty for thievery?
Please, sir.
We were just really hungry.
That's all.
Please.
Please, sir.
We were just-
I don't want to hear it.
You just keep walking.
I got a good plan for you boys.
Quit your lollygaggin'.
Git.
Oh, my god!
Where you taking 'em, uncle jim?
Anse Hatfield, you're back!
Hold up, you bastards.
Guarding the home front, I see.
Yep.
You know nothing gets by old jim.
I caught these yankee shit heels
a'pilfering corn.
He meant to take your life, nephew.
I never.
We was just hungry.
I saw murder in his eye.
Please, sir.
Don'm t hit lekill me.
On your way, yankee bill.
Go on.
And I'd hurry it up.
And I thought you was letting him go.
So did he.
After you blew out
the other one's brainpan,
what choice did I have?
Yep.
Don't want to leave no witnesses.
Died unafraid,
how a man should die.
That's a damn shame.
That yankee piss pot
should've suffered.
Yeah, well, you hate 'em so much,
how come you didn't sign up
to fight 'em?
Fighting on others' terms
is how you lose,
and losin' is intolerable to me.
Well, I'm back now
and still head of this family.
I ain't gonna be no problem.
Good.
Then you'll understand
when I tell you
to get these bodies off the road,
somewhere no one ever finds 'em.
Yeah.
It's gonna be like it was before.
Lookit Mr. Howls over there,
all smilin'.
He's glad you're back too...
With all your fine plans.
Get the bodies off the road.
What were you doing in there anyhow?
Not even home yet and you get
yourself into a drunken fight,
you shiftless fool.
I'm hidin' out at the still
till this ruckus with Jim Vance
blows over.
You'll drink yourself to death
up there.
I ain't going up there to die.
I'm going up there to stay alive.
Ain't right.
Come home from the army,
breedin' me like I was cattle,
then you take off again?
No, you've got your duties
as a husband and father.
Kids, mind your mama while I'm gone.
We will.
Levicy.
Anderson?
I'm done with the war.
You ain't going back?
I've given enough.
I'm back for good, darling.
Lord, you lived through it.
How's our little boy?
He's an angel now that he's asleep.
Ngobbi
oh, my god, look at you.
You'll want to know
that we got at least 60 bushels
of corn in last year,
so we ain't starvin',
and this year promises to be
just as good,
so you don't have to worry none,
and johnse, you will not recog-
We'll get to all that come morning.
Hey!
Ain't that martha McCoy?
'Lias.
Miss McCoy.
Suppose you heard about my harmon.
He's up at that still over
a month, drinking.
Says if'n he stops now,
he'll throw a fit and be helpless
when Jim Vance come to kill him.
Ma'am, your yankee husband
was a traitor
to more than just my uncle jim.
There's lots of folks around here
can't forgive harmon's betrayal
and might-
Might want to kill him,
even some of your own kin.
But your uncle Jim Vance is
the only one my harmon accused
of fornicating with his hound dog.
Well...
That's a poor choice of words.
I'll admit, hidin' out was prudent.
I can't survive being a widow.
My uncle tends to go his own way.
But next time I see him,
i'll do what I can.
Nancy, sit down.
I hear ya!
Ya ain't getting me,
you son of a bitch!
Pappy?
"Dear randall,
"our fortunes are bitter.
"Your brother harmon
was done murdered,
"it is said by Hatfields.
"The rest of us barely scrape by.
"If you are still alive,
dear husband,
"i pray that you come home
to us soon.
Your loving wife, sally."
It's over!
The war is over!
General lee surrendered!
- Praise the lord!
- The war is over!
Thank you, thank you, jesus.
Now, I'll be damned.
Won't be over for some.
War was a goddamn waste.
I don't intend to waste the peace.
Who's there?
Now turn around.
Randall?
Sally, it's me.
You've aged some.
Yankees done it.
Treated us worse than animals
in that prison.
I didn't want to give up on
you, husband, but I think I did.
First we log my ten acres here-
Run from the ridge across
and outside that hill.
Then?
We take the money from that.
We buy 20 more acres.
Then what?
Buy 40 more.
It's like wiping your ass
with a wagon wheel.
Ain't never gonna end now, is it?
Mr. Hatfield.
I'm a cousin of randall McCoy,
an attorney.
My name is Perry Cline.
I studied law at the offices of
ethan mckibbin in louisville.
Passed the bar last october.
I apologize for any unpleasantness
we're about to have.
Just state your business, mr. Cline.
Now, I know you believe
you own this stand of timber
and have the right to cut.
Whereas, in fact, in the eyes
of the law, you do not.
Where in thunder did you get that?
My daddy bought this parcel
off of bucky hand in 1859.
I got the deed in a box at home.
I believe you, Mr. Hatfield.
But he sold my cousin rutherford,
whose estate I administer,
the timber rights beforehand
on june 22, 1858.
Signed and witnessed, see?
Well, bucky was a friend
of my family.
He'd have told us if we'd not
bought the timber with the land.
You'll force me to sue, mr. Hatfield.
You'll be liable for damages
and the cost of all my timber
you have cut to date.
You will lose.
That a threat?
I reckon it's safer you sue.
Without they hear different
from a judge,
my relatives might think you
just tried to bamboozle me.
Well...
I've informed you of my rights.
We'll see what the law
has to say about it.
I bid you good day.
I'm prepared to do my duty
as your wife,
but I ask that you spill
your seed outside of me.
I could not bear another birth.
Alas and did my savior bleed
and did my sovereign die
would he devote
the sacred head
for such a worm as I
at the cross, at the cross
where I first saw the light
and the burdens of my heart
rolled away
it was there by faith
I received my sight
and now I am happy
all the day
alas and did my savior bleed
and did my sovereign die
would he devote
Well, then, take care.
Now, good see you again.
Nice to see you.
Randall, good to see you.
Now, take care.
Thank you so much.
Randall!
Oh, now, stop fighting.
Sally.
Sally, you come talk with me.
Come on, johnse.
Come on.
Come on now.
Hard to reconcile you
in the lord's house.
Yeah, well, levicy dragged me
here to-
It's good to see you, randall.
I feared- I feared you dead.
Times I felt like I was.
Rest of the company-all lost,
all dead, except me.
Our men are home now, sally.
Yours is.
Mine is only half home.
I mean to enter
the election day contest,
and I would value your opinion.
Go ahead.
Elderberry?
There's nothing sweeter.
It's terrible bad
what happened to you-
Prison and all.
If there's anything I can do
to help out.
You propose now to ease
your conscience for deserting?
Or for my brother's murder?
Your uncle Jim done it.
If'n he was here,
i'd say it to his face.
Jim swears he had nothing
to do with harmon's death.
And you believe that?
Well, I have no knowledge
to the contrary, randall.
And uncle jim, he-
He swore before god.
And what use do
Hatfields have of god?
Well, you keep that, and you try it.
Let me know if'n it set up and-
Thank you.
I don't understa...
Mornin'.
There's something I'd like
to show you, Mr. Cline.
Court's about to convene.
Yeah, well, I think
you'll wait for this.
Ellison, 'lias, show lawyer
cline our evidence.
You recall that hamish was
witness on your bill of sale
in '59 but somehow died,
got himself buried in '57.
You recall that?
I am somehow made a victim
of a fraud.
How is not clear to me-
Maybe you oughta should just
fetch the sheriff.
Perchance he can help you
track down the scoundrel
what sold you a bill of goods.
Obviously this changes things,
mr. Hatfield.
Yeah.
I forgo.
I abandon and renounce claim to
the timber rights on your land,
and I apologize for being hasty
and putting forth an invalid claim.
You deserve to be compensated.
You shall be.
I have $22 here.
Keep your money.
I take that kindly, mr. Hatfield.
Young lawyer starting his career,
deceived by a forged document
don't look well.
Don't look well at all.
People might even start to think
that you had a hand in this
forgin' and then bungled it.
What do you want, mr. Hatfield?
Well, you meant to have
all that was mine.
So I must be entitled
to have all what's yours.
At least what you inherited
from your daddy.
That's 5,000 acres.
Don't hardly much want the land.
Just the timber rights.
I don't believe we have to go
in court at all, do we?
Can't find her, pa.
Consarn it.
Keep looking.
It's one little pig.
Mountain lion probably got her.
That pig fattened up feeds
this family for a whole winter.
You understand that, boy?
Misfortune afflicts us both.
Sorry about you losing
your land, cousin.
Still, we cannot let our paths
be diverted
by the treachery of others.
Trust in the lord and do good,
and he shall give thee
the desires of thine heart.
All done, poppy.
You like it?
Fine job, Roseanna.
Here.
I've been meaning to give you this.
A gold button?
It's from the war.
For me?
'Cause you're my favorite.
Perhaps you're right, randall.
But I would not drop my guard.
War changes men.
Peacetime can turn them into
scheming snakes.
I predict Hatfield will keep
coming at you
feigning friendship and generosity.
And when he does,
you'll know I'm right.
I hoped I might find you here,
randall.
Almost like old times, huh?
What brings you to town?
Business.
I just made a deal
with jinx clabberat
to farm out some of his good
bottomland with my boys.
We might just grow us
a big cash crop of tobaccy.
Good.
You come to boast about stealing
from my cousin Perry Cline?
Nobody come here to boast, randall.
I'm just-i'm just trying to be
friendly.
I don't know what you heard,
but nary a thing was stole
from your kin.
Perry Cline gave me his timber rights
when I uncovered how he was
trying to cheat me.
I should've blown his damn head
off is what I shoulda done,
but...
You think I profited unfairly, you-
you take this.
You take that in good conscience.
Does it weigh on you at all,
captain Hatfield,
how you profited while others
stayed the course
and suffered for it?
No man questions what I gave
the cause, randall.
Especially you.
'nother one.
Talk is, they're gonna build
a railroad right through here.
Then we'll send our timber
in all directions
'round the whole country.
Not up north, I hope.
War's long over, jim.
There's no north, no south-
Just people who got money
and people who ain't.
I mean to do business with them
that has.
I always knew we was gonna be rich.
Hey!
It's your boy, william!
Tree fell!
Splinter caught his eye!
I can't see!
Eddie, I can't see!
Why can't I see?
I know it hurts bad, son.
I admire how you-I admire how
you standin' up to it.
Give me some water.
Johnse, why can't I see?
We're gonna get you to
a doctor straightaway.
Anse.
You're not gonna die,
but I won't lie to you.
This is a serious wound.
Howdy, neighbors.
Randall.
Miss sally.
How do you do, floyd?
Blessed day, ain't it?
Sure is.
How's your harvest this season?
Fair to middlin'.
Better than the last one.
Not as good as the next.
Your hogs fattened up nice.
Ah, ornery critters.
Had the kids and dogs try
to round them up,
but these two kept a'squealin' off.
Tell me, floyd, how long have you had
that spotted shoat there?
Well, he bred last year.
I know when it was bred.
That's my markin' on its ears.
Ah, no, randall, you're mistook.
I notch my swines particular
so I do not get mistook.
Well, you know young pigs
is wanderers.
I expect you gots one or two of
mine hangin' in your smokehouse.
I do not.
How many more of my pigs you took?
How much pork you takin' from
my family to stuff your belly?
Now, hang on, randall.
That's a serious accusal.
You's bein' quarrelsome.
I am, am i?
Well, how's this for quarrelsome?
Damn you for a pig thief,
floyd Hatfield.
Come on.
Come on, git.
I guess all you Hatfields
are the same!
Did you get enough to eat, Perry?
Thank you.
An elegant sufficiency, aunt sally.
Elegant sufficiency.
Roseanna, help me clear the table.
Alifair, the little one.
This matter of floyd Hatfield
and the theft of your livestock...
He lied and denied it to my face.
We sue.
It's useful to think of the law
as a muscle.
Like a muscle, it can be
strengthened with proper use.
Used too little, it becomes feeble
and too weak to protect you.
That's fine talk, Perry.
You got the gift.
Floyd Hatfield is on the other
side of the river.
Where a Hatfield sits as judge.
Mm, I can arrange a jury trial.
We'll sit six McCoys
and six Hatfields.
It won't get you justice
for your poor murdered brother.
We win this case, it's a kind of
justice nonetheless.
It strikes me as foolish.
How's that, ma'am?
Goin' to court over a pig.
Makes us look like some
village idiot.
Sally...
I suppose, in the end,
god punishes all transgression.
But, as you well know,
oftentimes the good lord expects us
to be the instrument of his will.
What say you, jim?
I say we sue.
How's the eye doing?
It's gone milky, capped over.
Uh-huh.
- Let me see.
- No, jim.
- Come on, let me see.
- Jim.
Let me see it.
Turn around.
What am I doin' here?
You're supporting your family.
Over a pig?
Anse.
Put it away.
I'm gonna call you captain.
Cap for captain.
Like your daddy.
Shows you're an important feller.
Good name, cap, hmm?
Yeah, I like it.
Hi, uncle Wall!
Hi, uncle wall!
Court is in session.
Thanks to those of you on the jury
for coming here today
and agreeing to serve.
I know most of y'all got crops.
Stock needs tendin'.
So I ain't gonna keep you from
your task
any longer than necessary.
Judge Hatfield, members of the jury,
it is useful to think of the law
as a muscle.
Like a muscle, it can be
strengthened with proper use.
Mr. Cline.
The briefer you make your remarks,
the better your case
is gonna be received.
Serves you, windbag.
Sit down!
Do you mean to call witnesses?
Mr. Randall McCoy
and his wife, sally,
both saw the McCoy markin'
on the ear of the hog in question.
Oh, now, I don't think we need
to call 'em to the stand
just to say so.
So to put it plain,
the McCoys say it is their pig
and their notch,
and floyd says that ain't so.
Is that clear?
Sure.
Is the pig in court today?
No, it ain't.
Why not?
Well, um...
It's done been et.
All right, floyd.
You got any witness saw it
before you butchered the swine
to say it is your notch?
I didn't know I needed one.
If you give me a couple hours,
I might could come up with somebody.
I seen it.
The hog in question, that is.
And I seen floyd actually cut
that shoat's ear.
Oh, do I need to say I seen it
on the bible?
I'd advise you not to.
That pig had black spots on
its hams, as I recollect.
And floyd's hand slipped
when he notched it.
Pretty near cut his thumb off.
Anyways, why would floyd show
him that swine if he stole it?
It don't make no sense.
That's enough, bill.
I trust y'all give
bill staton's testimony
the respect it deserves.
Your honor, I ain't
quite done, you see-
You sit down!
Me Mbers of the jury,
who thinks the hog belonged
to floyd Hatfield?
All right, who believes the hog
was randall McCoy's?
- Here.
- Yes, sir.
Selkirk McCoy, you didn't vote
one way or t'other.
Well, he votes uncle randall.
He has to be the one to say
so, parris.
Well, I'm trying to do
the right thing here.
You see, I am of
the McCoy family, but-
Well, the truth is, deep down
I do believe that pig was one
of floyd Hatfield's razorbacks.
Judgment's goin' down in a second.
Do not disrespect the name McCoy.
Bill staton swears on his oath
that he seen floyd cut that notch.
You are a lying spawn of hell
that voted his Hatfield wife's
apron strings!
Oh, randall, this-
Leave her on out of this.
Gonna give yourself apoplexy.
All this to-do over a pig.
This is about honor,
about lyin' and stealin'
and murderin'.
That is not pertinent to the case.
It's about sin, devil anse!
What's christian right
and damnation wrong!
McCoy!
This case is dismissed!
Everybody get the hell out of here!
By god, I will gut-shoot
the next agitator
who further disrespects my courtroom,
McCoy or Hatfield.
I reckon this is what
I shoulda expected
from a Hatfield court.
One more word out of you, McCoy,
i'll hold you in contempt.
Best watch your high-and-mighty ass,
preacher McCoy.
Here's scripture for you:
"blood toucheth blood."
You don't want to make
that move, Cotton.
See, your daddy won't tell you that
'cause he's trying to beat you.
Thanks, uncle Wall.
Yeah, thanks, uncle wall.
Anyway, what I'm saying is,
you standin' up there in the end
didn't help things, anse.
Yeah, well, I had it under control.
The hell you did.
These picayune squabbles
got a way of turning deadly.
Maybe so, but I cannot have
randall McCoy
continue to embarrass us.
A little embarrassment's
better'n what grows out of injustice,
don't you think?
You see the look on
ol' randall McCoy's face
when I swore that pig had
black spots on his hams?
More you drink, louder you get.
Them McCoys come after me,
i'll cut 'em down
like Perry Cline's trees.
Hell, I'll even nut 'em.
You wanna say that again?
I'd just love to take away that
arkansas toothpick of your,
shove it straight up
your stinkin' asshole.
I said any McCoys come after me
for what I said in court,
i'll take 'em down, and I'll nut 'em.
Well, I suspect you might be
stupid enough to try.
You-you callin' me out, hmm?
This ain't the place.
But you got a mighty big mouth,
bill staton.
Okay, nothin' to do but just
sit here-
Any McCoy come after me
and do me harm,
i'll take you down!
Come on!
Eh!
What, are you scared?
That was fun, skunky, huh?
You had fun with that?
You happy with that?
You know, you're brave.
I ain't gonna drink with you.
Howdy, anse.
I guess I told 'em, huh.
You see a mean dog sleeping,
do you go pester him?
- No, sir.
He awake, you go kick him?
No, you don't.
You leave him alone,
maybe he goes back to sleep.
You get my point?
Yeah, but those shit-butt McCoys-
We understand each other?
Yes, sir.
I don't drink, and I don't smoke
but I give your girl a poke
I give your girl a poke
I said that I don't smoke
I give your girl a poke,
I give your girl a poke
afternoon, bill.
You want to nut us?
I got ya both, huh?
Here we are, bill.
You still want to take us down,
cut off our balls?
Go ahead.
Should we nut him?
Come on, come on.
Shit.
Come on.
It's devil anse.
Alone?
Well, ain't he enough?
Sons a bitches!
Don't you slay us.
Cap...
Yeah, pa.
Pick up them guns.
Let's get these wastrels
back across the river.
It's a nice day for a hangin',
ain't it, ol' randall?
Mean Jim Vance.
Well, you're not all that much.
I mean, up close-like.
Who the hell are you?
Oh, I'm tolbert McCoy,
son of randall.
See, I always wanted to meet
the man that murdered my uncle
and tell him his days are comin'.
Not from the likes of you,
you wet-eared prick-chafing
little shit.
Get out of my sight before
I snap you like a chicken neck!
Tolbert.
We're here on other business.
Move!
What are my two nephews
doing in there
being locked up next to
this godforsaken corpse?
You live with what you done,
you might think twice before
doin' it again
if you should so get the chance.
Judge, I respectfully request
that bail be set
at a reasonable amount.
Denied.
These boys stand accused
of a capital crime.
And I will not have this
business dragged out to fester.
You want to tell me why
I shouldn't hang 'em both for murder?
Bein' a Hatfield,
you're hardly impartial.
I'm the attorney of record here,
and I'll answer the questions.
Bill staton threatened to kill
any McCoys that crossed his path.
Now, we got witnesses to that.
Parris and sam did cross his path,
and staton did try to kill them,
then was killed himself by
parris and sam in self-defense,
which these law-abiding
young men deeply regret.
Amen.
We surely do.
We's real sorry we had to do it,
defending ourselves like that,
but bill staton give us no choice.
In any event, judge,
you got no authority to try
a capital case.
Noted.
Anse, you got anything to say
'fore I pronounce sentence?
Bill staton was a tolerable worker,
always gave money to
and got wood in for his mother
till she died last winter.
He did drink a bit.
Parris and sam both knew that
bill's threats-they both knew-
That they was empty as the
bottles they was comin' from.
They wanted to revenge his
mouthin' off, plain and simple.
Then they lay in wait to get it.
That's premeditated homicide,
for which accordin' to the law
and your almighty god,
they had oughta hang.
You're talkin' like a fool.
This lowlife drunkard lyin' dead here
threatened murder on my family!
God damn it!
Y'all just get over here
and sit down and shut up.
All of us know parris and sam
killed bill staton.
Only the circumstances
remain in question.
It's a damn shame
no one told 'em shootin' a drunk
on the road
was wrong and not worth hangin' for
or even the price
of the goddamn lead.
And it's also a damn shame
that no one stopped his hired hand's
liquored-up threats and curses
from inflaming two fools
to commit murder,
which was damn easy to foresee.
I find you both guilty
of this heinous crime,
for which you are to be taken
to some convenient spot without delay
and thereby hanged by the neck
until you are dead.
A sentence which I hereby suspend
since no one can say whether
it was self-defense or not.
Go on, boys.
Get the hell out of here.
Thank you, sir.
Right there!
Calvin, not guilty!
I knew your daddy
would get us out of there.
As god as my witness,
I will not allow my court
to be the cause of a war
between our two families.
Bill staton ain't worth it and
his ma, who he did do right by,
is dead and gone.
God rest her soul.
Write it in the book:
"miscreants discharged
by judge Wall Hatfield."
Thank you, judge.
You've been a fair and wise man
today.
Indeed.
God is just and shall return to us
the years that the locusts
hath eaten.
Well, you're just a
huckleberry above a persimmon,
ain't ya?
If you two don't mend
what's wrong between you,
hellfire's gonna certainly
rise up and consume
both our families.
Thank you, Mr. Cline, sir.
- That's right.
- That's mighty fine work.
We got him, pa!
It is a good day for it.
- Get up in the wagon here, boys.
- Whoo!
What the hell you laughing at?
Look who it is, huh?
Believe it!
You better believe it!
Boom.
Whoa, easy now, son.
Don't want it going off just yet.
Yeah, mush-head.
Don't blow us all up,
you half-wit bastard moron.
Come here.
Come here!
Find it funny?
Come here.
Apologize.
Yeah, I'm sorry
you's a bastard, cotton.
Tell him!
All right.
I'm sorry.
That ain't good enough.
I apologize for what I called you
and won't never call you
no names again.
Didn't have to do that, pa.
Everybody calls me mush-head.
Well, you ain't like
everybody else, cotton.
God gave you such a big heart,
he couldn't very well give you
a whole abundance of brains,
now, too, could he?
I guess not.
I am a bastard, though.
You listen to me, boy.
Hmm?
A bastard's got no family
that loves him.
Is that you?
No, it's not.
You're my son.
Why do you think your
first name's ellison?
Now, let's see it fly.
Get everybody back now.
Okeydokey!
Everybody stand back now!
Nuh-uh.
I said no.
I gotta make a livin' here,
god dang it.
You want free whiskey,
you go talk to tolbert McCoy
over there.
I might do that.
Don't look now.
Johnse Hatfield is staring at us.
I sure hope crows swoop down
and pluck his eyes out.
What a thing to say, nancy.
His uncle Jim Vance killed my pap.
You don't know that for sure.
Everybody says so.
Don't make it for sure.
He sure is handsome.
Son o' devil anse.
I ain't never seen no devil
look like that.
- Hey, cap.
- Yeah?
Robert e., you all take over.
My favorite nephew.
Now that's just wasteful.
Hello, Roseanna McCoy.
I'm johnse Hatfield.
I know who you are.
Does that mean you won't talk to me?
Me bein' a Hatfield and all.
I don't mean you no harm.
Well, now, that's the way I feel.
You know, I don't see why
there's been so much trouble.
I bet you didn't know I was
named for a McCoy.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey, you want to go see
the second most beautiful sight
in west virginia?
So then am I supposed to ask
what's the first
most beautiful sight?
Well, if you wanna go.
Then you're just gonna say,
"oh, you are."
Just like you told eloise jenkins
and about a dozen other girls.
I've heard all about you.
Well, if all the gossip about
me was true,
hell, I'd have horns
and a spiny tail.
Those are some mighty
interesting boots
you're wearing.
- You like 'em?
- No, I didn't say that.
So...
What is the second
most beautiful sight
in west virginia?
Well, now, i'll take you there.
- Do you solemnly swear?
- Yeah.
Thank you, Mr. Hatfield.
This really is a boon
to busy housewives.
You'll wonder how you got by
without one of these.
You'll never fear
a scalding explosion
with our patent release valve
and the variometric pressure gauge.
Oh, randall, isn't it just fine?
Thanks for the demonstration.
Steam digester.
Time-saving application...
It's a silly trinket.
I've been puttin' food on
the table all these years
without I had me some
pressurized double boiler.
Hatfield can offer his wife
any new contraption she wants.
One day I'm gonna buy you
some miracle,
like that edison feller's
electric fire.
Poppy, I don't need anything
like that.
Yes, ma'am.
Someday, sally, i'm gonna buy you
a double boiler that runs on
electrical-tricity.
How much you want for the fiddle?
It's mine.
I want a greenback and a half for it.
I'll give you four bits.
It were my grandpappy's.
75 cents.
I'll owe you a quarter
and you fill my cup.
Oh, yeah, this here's my drip still.
Ain't she a beauty?
I could produce maybe-
I don't know- A half gallon a day
of fine western virginia corn liquor.
I mean, this is
the horse's head still,
a cash can, you know.
I built this rig myself.
I mean, I borrowed the money
to buy the parts from my pa.
I figure, make a good livin',
support my family proper.
I may even build me a cabin
not far from here
for my wife to have babies in.
You got yourself a wife?
Come on.
You're teasing me, I know.
Well, one thing I know for a fact:
you got girlfriends by the bushel.
I ain't serious about none of 'em.
Look at that mush-head.
You're s'posed to drown
the runt of the litter.
Like this...
Here.
Come on.
Easy to laugh in a bunch, ain't it?
Where's your sister?
Oh, I don't know where she went.
Well, go find her.
We're leavin'.
Let her stay, randall.
The boys will bring her home.
Tolbert!
You're to bring Roseanna home
without fail, ya hear me?
Yes, sir.
Ha!
How many times you been kissed?
Not countin' grandmas and such?
Not countin'.
A couple times, maybe.
I bet you ain't never really
truly been kissed right.
Not to boast, but...
I believe I have a strong
reputation as a good kisser.
There.
Now you can't say you've never
been kissed.
Good lord, it's gettin' dark.
We ought to get goin'.
Roseanna! Roseanna!
Roseanna!
Roseanna, we are leaving!
She ain't here.
Must have rode back with
the mcclintocks or Mr. Cline.
Well, she could have told us.
Pa's gonna take our damn heads off.
Roseanna!
Roseanna, last chance!
Last chance, Roseanna!
Oh, please let them be here.
Please.
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
Upon my honor, they's all
gone, even your kinsfolk.
Oh, god.
My poppy is gonna kill me.
How am I gonna get home?
Well, I'll take you with me.
My name is McCoy.
Your father would hardly welcome
one of us.
You put everything you heard
about devil anse Hatfield
out of your pretty head.
He ain't nothing like that.
One thing I said to do without fail
was bring your sister home!
We figured she got a ride home.
How was we to know?
We tried!
We called out!
She didn't answer!
I said without fail!
Go find her.
And don't come back till you do.
Only a goddamn idiot
would bring randall McCoy's
daughter back here,
and after midnight.
Well, she couldn't very well
walk back home
in the dark by herself.
You don't want her here,
that's fine, but...
Don't strike me as overgenerous.
Shit, I'll hitch a wagon,
ride her back home.
You ain't ridin' her nowheres.
The way you make
this predicament worse
is for randall McCoy to see you
with his daughter afore sunrise.
He'll shoot your damn head off,
and I wouldn't blame him.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to stay away off
o' her, that's what.
Levicy, have the girls make down
a pallet
on the floor for our guest.
Come mornin', you take her
to the edge of the tug
and then leave her off.
Yes, sir.
And then get rid of them
fancy-nancy boots.
You're supposed to be a workin' man.
Good-lookin' girl.
Yeah, well, it don't make it
worth the goddamn trouble.
The look on McCoy's face
when he finds out,
that'll be worth seeing.
You just keep practicin'.
Maybe a different tune.
Shh.
Go back to sleep.
Hi.
Shh.
Oh, and on our honeymoon,
we're gonna take a real train ride
all the way across the country
till we can't go no more.
I read where they got this great
blue ocean up in oregon.
I mean, this thing's so big and wide,
you can't even see the other side.
You cryin'?
What on earth for?
Just wonderin' where I fit in
on this long list of conquests.
My beautiful, sweet darlin'.
You think I'm toyin' with you?
I don't know what to think.
This is my first time.
I was savin' myself for a husband,
just like god told me to.
I ain't foolin' here, Roseanna.
I intend to marry you.
If I hadn't promised my pa,
hell, I'd ride on across
that river right now,
and on bended knee,
i'd ask your daddy myself.
Come here.
I'd go up against the whole
world to make you my wife.
And I can't change my past
or our kin,
but I tell you true,
I ain't never felt like this before
about nobody else but you.
There she is.
That's johnse Hatfield
a'kissin' on her.
That son of a bitch!
Now get over there.
You tell him.
Okay.
- Bye.
I don't wanna cross that bridge.
I'll be here when you get back.
Y'ain't gettin' away, johnse!
Oh, my god!
Johnse!
Johnse, it's my brothers!
Go!
Go on!
I love you, Roseanna!
Ha!
Wait! Wait!
Stop!
Don't hurt him!
He didn't do nothing!
Buddy, buddy, you gotta stop 'em!
We gotta get you to poppy.
I didn't do nothing!
Get him!
You're a dead man!
God damn it, tolbert!
What you so hot about, anyway?
You're the one that left
Roseanna with no way home.
All I did was give her shelter,
feed her dinner,
and keep her safe from harm!
You try to have your way with her?
No, sir!
She spent the night with my sisters.
You saw her-safe and sound.
You think she'd be kissin' on me
if I had violated her in any way?
I did hear Roseanna say...
Shut up, calvin.
Now, I say we kill him now and
t geon back across the river
before anyone knows.
Hell, your sister'll know.
She loves me.
That's a load of bull manure!
No, it ain't.
And I love her too, god damn it.
Since I got to prove it to you.
Well, how bad you shot, johnse?
Ha...
Well...
I'll live.
Think the bullet tore
straight through me.
Tolbert, let's go.
Come on.
You tell your pa
I want to ask Roseanna's hand
in marriage!
Hey, pa!
We found her!
I got Roseanna!
You spent the night
under a Hatfield roof?
With johnse's sisters, sir.
Mr. Hatfield kindly gave permission.
Johnse, he, uh- He wants to marry me.
Beg your damn pardon?
He loves me, poppy.
He wants to ask you proper, you know.
He wants to make sure it's right.
He touch you, Roseanna?
No.
You go on.
Do whatever you want.
You like the Hatfields so much,
why don't you go stay with them
forever?
You're not my daughter anymore.
You'll have to have rutherford
take a look at this.
No, it's fine.
Ow!
Keep your hand out of the way.
He's gonna do the same thing
you're doing.
Daddy, her father don't object.
Well, looks like somebody did.
Yeah, her boneheaded brothers-ow!
Would you hold still?
I want to hear again
that randall McCoy
agreed to you marrying his daughter.
No, not exactly.
He said he don't care.
He don't care.
"Don't care" ain't permission.
Well, he said it
in front of witnesses.
Well, was that before or after
you got shot, hmm?
I will not defy McCoy or any man
when it comes to his daughter.
Daddy, please, if you-
If you give permission,
he'll surely come around.
God damn it, boy!
They tried to kill you!
Now you want to marry into that?
You know what?
This ain't right.
Me and her want to be man and wife-
Now, we're both of age.
Don't be a fool.
You only just met her.
Mama...
Roseanna's been throwed out.
She got no place to go.
You're afflicted, son.
All right.
She can stay here until her
family comes for her
or you two come to your senses.
Thank you.
Thank you, mama.
But she will keep her own name.
Come on.
Oh, watch out for that snake.
I'm just kiddin' ya.
I never knew this existed.
Been comin' here my whole life.
It's so beautiful out here.
Yup.
What are you doin'?
Oh, my-you are crazy, johnse.
Come get in the water with me.
Out here?
In the eyes of god?
God didn't forbid our union.
Our fathers did.
God knows we're married
in our hearts.
Come on.
See you later, all right?
What's the matter?
Hatfield kin.
Plain ain't right.
Over a year now Roseanna's
livin' under the Hatfield roof,
droppin' her skirt
and turnin' out to be
just a steady piece of cake.
Must make old man Hatfield
happier'n a banty rooster
in a henhouse,
having our family so disgraced.
Yup.
Help ya?
Frank phillips.
Work outta the pinkerton office,
louisville, kentucky.
Lookin' for bob levinger.
Ain't seen bob in a spell.
A fella could get himself
into a lot of trouble
lyin' to a pinkerton man
with a US Deputy prosecutor
warrant.
It makes it a federal offense.
So we're talkin' prison, a big fine.
A feller could lose his saloon,
everything he's slaved for.
Time he's outta jail,
he's dead broke.
His wife's run off with some
dandy carpetbagger.
I seen it happen.
Playin' cards, bald one.
Bob levinger.
You got no paper
on where you're livin'.
Squatter, payin' no taxes.
You've been warned twice by
mail, once by federal officer.
I'm here to take you in.
This here's a warrant.
Ain't legal.
That land is Hatfield.
Levingers is cousins to Hatfield.
My great uncle devil anse,
he got papers on file at
the land state office.
Bullshit.
It's federal property.
You people think you're on
the land, you own it.
I'm sayin' that ain't right.
You can tell your story in court.
I don't feel like goin' nowheres.
My little brother ed's
standing behind you,
and he got a regular navy pistol.
You still think i'm goin' somewheres?
Got one.
Can't find the other.
Go much deeper, I might kill you.
'course, if you want,
i'll give it another try.
You going after that pinker?
Got to.
Bastard killed our kin.
I ain't talkin' to you, uncle jim.
You know damn well the levingers
likely had it comin'.
Ed and bob always was jackasses.
Yeah, but they're our jackasses.
Someone thinks they can take
a shot at our kin,
pretty soon someone else thinks
they can lay an ambush
and shoot at one of us.
Hey, do you remember
when we was kids,
pa told me to go shoot that fox
nosing around the henhouse.
Yeah.
You didn't want to kill it.
You poked fun at me for it.
Helped me trap it so's we could
take it across the river
and let it go.
Never come around again.
And pa, he was none the wiser.
Well...
All I'm sayin' is,
smart as you are,
maybe you can figure out another way.
I hear you, ellison,
but you should know the reason
that fox didn't ever
come around again.
After you went home, I killed it.
Anderson is a good man.
This trouble 'tween
our families, well...
Well, it makes it hard for all of us.
And I got to tell ya,
deep down inside,
I ain't got no belief in you
and johnse bein' together.
Well...
We can have a union
in the sight of god.
You know, and children
that weren't born
on the wrong side of the bed.
No.
You need to go back to your own,
where you belong.
Hey.
I can see you ain't a bad person,
and this whole thing, it ain't right.
You askin' me to leave?
And don't you come back.
This bullheaded feud between
your pa and my anderson,
it's a kind of slow poison.
I inherited 500 acres,
which I would pass along to you
on the occasion of your marriage.
But my land will never be
in Hatfield hands,
I can promise you that.
Don't worry yourself now, mama.
Johnse and me ain't never gonna
get married.
Renounce your Hatfield defiler,
and your poppy might let you
come home.
You used to be his favorite.
In time, you'll meet a suitable boy.
Mama-
And you-you-
It's too late.
I ain't had my flow in two months.
I don't know what to do.
You come home with a Hatfield
bastard in your belly?
Hey, mama.
Where's Roseanna?
Gone to her family.
Well, when she comin' back?
I don't know that she will.
Might be best for all concerned
if she don't.
Got 700 acres of corn,
12% of the tug fork sawmill,
and nearly 10,000
in financial instruments.
Only I lack a helpmate,
a loving wife to share
my good fortune.
I'm sure that any number of women
would be happy to entertain
your suit.
Any number I don't care for.
If you're worried about
the physical relations,
I could forego-
I can't marry you, Perry.
I'm having a baby-
Johnse Hatfield's child.
That's unfortunate.
But if we're to marry quickly,
no one would catch on to the
sad truth the child ain't mine.
Otherwise, your condition will
be all the gossip, you know,
the Hatfields laughin' about it.
I'm in love with johnse Hatfield.
Aunt betty?
Oh!
Sakes alive, you scared me.
What are you doin' here, sugar?
Mama said you'd take me in.
Ain't nobody else want me.
Lookin' for a gentleman,
name of frank phillips.
What's your business with him?
That there must be bad
frank phillips with that limp.
I go by the name of phillips,
not the other part.
So if I was you, i'd mind my tongue.
Well, ain't you ornery for a cripple?
I'd give you a lesson in manners,
but the house required
I check my sidearms
'fore I went upstairs with jenny lou.
Well, that's too bad.
Given your attitude,
I might like seeing
how good you could use 'em.
Well, ask your dead
back-shootin' relatives, old man.
Mr. Phillips, I come here
to talk to you,
not have a shootout
in a damn whorehouse.
After I killed you, I'd have
to explain it to my wife,
and I wouldn't much look forward
to havin' to do that, so...
So I'll buy you a drink instead.
You buy me a bourbon whiskey
straight, Mr. Hatfield.
But you have to leave your dog
outside.
He can stay.
So why did you make the special
trip to parley with me?
I come here to give you $100
on condition-
On condition you move on out
of these parts.
I killed your kin.
Why the payoff?
Well, it wasn't my first idea,
I promise you.
Longer you stay around here, people-
People expect me to do something
about you.
Now, I understand you were
doin' your job,
and levingers was always
damn fool idiots at best,
but don't-don't make me raise
my hand against you,
mr. Phillips.
I would kill you.
So take my money and ride on out.
I'll take your money.
Just don't think I'm runnin'.
You took down the levingers.
Didn't expect you to lizard out.
This whole damn thing sticks
in my craw,
especially with my bad leg.
It was your land claim and your
kin cost me my job.
A skunk's profession.
Get yourself into something useful.
You can't go there, johnse.
You're all drunk and crazy.
I'm gonna stare old man McCoy
in the eye.
I'm gonna tell him-
I'm gonna tell him straight out.
You're gonna get yourself killed.
Let go of my arm.
He wants to ride into kentucky
and see old randall McCoy.
Well, I'm Nancy McCoy,
Roseanna's cousin.
And I-I gotta go.
Look, if you go there,
they're gonna think
you mean 'em harm.
Well, I'll shout out,
"i don't mean you no harm!
I just-I just wanna talk things out."
Well, if you go with me,
you'll be safe.
Well, my horse-
We'll come on back and get it.
You are-you're Roseanna's
cousin nancy.
Go on.
That's what I said.
Oh!
Yeah...
I know who you are, 'cause you
look like her, kind of.
Yah!
Roseanna's cousin nancy.
You-you kind of look like
Roseanna in the daylight too.
More at night, though.
I went and visited my aunt
betty blankenship's yesterday.
I suppose you know your
once-intended is stayin' there.
No.
Guess the old man's still riled
at how me and her shamed his family.
Well, especially now that
Roseanna's with child and all.
What?
I'm gonna be a daddy?
Because she carries his child,
Roseanna believes herself
in love with johnse Hatfield.
Does our pap know about this?
Strong as he is, I fear it
may break your father's heart.
Shame we can't remedy the
situation before he finds out.
If it weren't for johnse,
Roseanna might come to her senses
and accept an offer
of honorable marriage.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
Hey...
What are you doing?
Boys.
Boys!
Where are you going?
Well...
Just the boys I wanna see.
You can ride with me
to your aunt betty's house.
I'm going there to rescue my bride,
make an honest woman of her.
Just you shut the hell up!
You ain't lyin' your way out of
it this time.
I ain't lying.
Just found out Roseanna's
carrying my baby.
So I'm going to get her,
seeing as how our daddies
are being such horses' asses.
You're dead, Hatfield.
You're gonna be dead!
Get off of me, tolbert!
Why you want to hurt your future
brother-in-law?
I'm gonna kill you, 'cause
you soiled my sister's honor!
I told you, i'm gonna marry her!
Calvin?
Randall?
What's-what are you doing?
Alifair, get the kids back.
Git.
Git!
What are you doin'?
Are you drunk?
You weren't gonna tell me, were ya?
I had to hear it from Perry Cline.
Well, stop.
That's Roseanna's hope chest.
Stop!
I know what it is!
Suppose you's wonderin' why
I don't kill you straightaway.
'Cause you know it ain't right.
Horseshit!
I'm gonna blow your brains out
exactly at sunrise,
like they do in the army.
See, I want you to know it's comin'.
And I want you to think about it
for all those hours!
Feel the kind of torment
you and all the Hatfields
have brought down on us.
I respect your sister, tolbert.
You know that.
Especially now that
she's carrying my baby.
Let me go find a preacher
and make it legal.
Well, it's too late for that!
I'm gonna shoot you dead come dawn,
and I'm gonna tell you
what time it is
every hour we get closer!
Instead of a last meal,
can I-can I get a last request?
Hell, no!
What do you want?
I want to see Roseanna one last time.
I want to say good-bye to her
in a proper way.
And then I will stand up tall
when you shoot me.
I swear to god I will.
And when I get to heaven,
I won't damn your souls
and ask god to send you
fryin' to hell
for what you done to me.
You're the one going to hell,
and you ain't gonna be askin'
god for squat.
Roseanna does love him.
She'll hate us forever
if we don't allow it.
No, I said!
He gets a bowl of stew.
Nothing else.
That stew didn't set right with me.
Do y'all mind if I go home?
No, sure, bud.
Come on.
You shouldn't be here when we do
the killin' anyways.
Yeah, you're too young.
I ain't too young.
I just don't feel so good, all right?
Bye, bud.
Hell, I'll see you on the other side.
I got to talk to my sister.
Oh, my god, bud.
What are you doing out in this?
Mr. Hatfield!
My brothers have got johnse!
They're plannin' on killin' him
at dawn!
Where is he?
If I tell you, you got to swear
you ain't gonna hurt my brothers!
If my son is safe, no harm
will come to your brothers.
Now, where is he?
They got him at my
uncle harmon's old place.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Please, Mr. Hatfield, hurry!
Go on.
I'll get your boots.
Please!
Now, johnse, we wouldn't
normally kill you,
'cept there's an honorable man
willing to marry our sister
soon as you're dead.
Who's that?
Lawyer Perry Cline has agreed
to make Roseanna his wife.
Having a man killed to marry
their woman and take their baby,
that ain't honorable.
One hour to go, Hatfield.