Get away!
There ain't no gold up here!
Do you hear me?
I hear you, old man.
But I don't believe you.
I know there's gold up there.
What are we
going to do, son?
You got to figure something.
You was wrong, pa!
Like usual.
You said lucifer's pit
was going to be a bonanza.
Please, pa...
Let them have the mine, or
lucifer's pit's gonna be our grave!
You got no right to it!
I found it.
I found it!
We found you, old man.
We got the water
and the supplies.
Ain't but one way down.
Pa...
Maybe we ought
to call it quits.
No, we'll come out
all right, you'll see.
see?
See what they call
this place?
Lucifer's pit.
This is his spread.
He'll bring us the luck.
I'll settle for
the devil's luck.
I'd sell our souls to satan,
Before I give up.
Where you come from?
Came from below, through those
rocks. What are you doing here?
I heard shooting and noise,
thought I could help.
I can help people sometimes.
Who are you?
Paladin.
That's right.
No, I don't want
any part of it!
We can use all the help
we can get.
I haven't offered you any help.
My help isn't for everyone,
And there's a stiff price.
We'll pay your price.
What do they want?
They're trying to jump
this claim.
I found it, it's mine!
They can't get away with it!
Blast 'em. Scatter 'em.
Halt 'em with brimstone!
Brimstone,
that's what I smell.
Yes.
Brimstone and hellfire.
He shall walk among you
under many names.
I told you
the luck would change.
It was the brimstone.
You can smell it!
It was some loose powder,
from a broken shell.
We don't want
any help from you!
How do we even know
who you are?
I know.
You know.
What do you know?
That we starved
all our lives,
Chasing after
your cursed luck!
No fancy black devil is going
to jump out of lucifer's pit
To save our necks!
I'm through,
do you hear me?
You do like I say, son.
Like you always done.
He heard, he came.
You can't quit me now.
We got the luck.
He's here.
Well, you tell him, mister.
Tell him that you
ain't the devil!
Now why should I
tell him that?
I tell you, there's
three men up there now.
Can't be, rudy.
I saw them!
I'm sure of that.
I say rush 'em.
And maybe get shot?
No... Look, we can
wait 'em out.
We got all the water
and the supplies.
They got to be running low.
We got 'em covered.
They can't get away.
Yeah, but how long
we gonna wait?
I want to live
to spend my gold,
Even if it takes all the way
'til tomorrow night.
Your trouble is you want
to get rich quick.
Look at him.
Sleeping.
Safe and sound
in his devil's arms.
Do you know how sick
your father is?
How would I know?
I ain't no doctor.
Pa's had this fever
for close to a week now.
It don't mean nothing.
Pa's been poorly for years.
You must have found
a very rich strike.
Make him that stubborn,
that excited.
That's our mine
and our business.
Look, ain't you
figured it out yet?
He's an old fool.
A superstitious old man,
That's chased every rainbow
from sicily to california.
Looking for
his lucky pot of gold.
And I'm a bigger fool.
I've tagged along.
'cause I haven't had
the nerve to leave him.
I hate him!
I hate him for everything
he is and he ain't.
And you're not
very fond of yourself.
How long have you been
prospecting for gold?
Literally, I mean.
Not that long.
Couple of weeks now.
We ain't done nothing
for very long.
Not even live,
the way things look now.
Where you going?
I'm going to take
a look at your mine.
You two didn't
dig this mine.
We found it.
It was abandoned.
But it's rich. See?
We made a bargain with you.
But only if
we file the claim.
You got any blasting powder?
Yeah.
Get it.
Where are your horses?
Down there.
Tether them as far from
the mine as possible.
What for?
You want to file
this claim or not?
Then you do exactly
what I tell you.
Here.
What are you going to do?
What are you doing?
I'm blowing in your mine.
Pa, don't let him!
All right, you want
your mine looted
While we're in town to file
the claim, I won't blow it in.
We do what he says.
Everything he says.
Sure!
Just how are we supposed
to get out of here, vanish?
maybe.
There's a narrow crevice
behind those rocks.
Leads to the other side.
Your horses can't make it.
We'll have to leave them.
No horses!
Pa's in no condition
to go on foot.
My horse is on
the other side.
Now let's get started.
They may change their mind
about waiting you out.
We ought to dig
some of that gold first.
You got a lot of money
in this sack.
You got at least $2,000.
If you wait to dig some,
They may figure out you
never filed on this claim.
You've got 30 hot miles
to that county seat.
If they figure it out,
They might just
jump on their horses
And beat you to town.
Maybe.
All right.
We're finished waiting.
You may be right.
Now spread out.
What do you get
out of all this?
If you recall, I mentioned
that I have my price.
Come on, old man.
In here.
Down, down!
Come on!
Come on.
I think we better
rest awhile.
No, I'm all right.
We've got to go
faster than this.
Don't worry about me.
They'll catch up with us
for sure at this pace.
Pa's right.
Maybe.
It's always touching
to see a son respect
His father's wishes.
We got to get to
some water somewhere, soon.
The next time you go
prospecting for gold,
Try an island in
the middle of a lake.
We found gold.
We found gold!
That's good, old man.
Now find water.
Come on.
Hold up, hold up!
If we even put up a stake,
they couldn't file a claim.
I should have known it.
They can't beat us into town,
that's for certain.
We got their horses.
Rudy, you're sure
there were three?
So help me, dirks!
Well, there's maybe one horse.
Yeah, but probably
not much water.
Good, good.
Blow a man up, will they?
I'll set 'em out to fry,
if we catch 'em!
We ain't interested
in entertainment.
I'm worried they'll
dump that gold.
It oughta be getting
real heavy about now.
That sun beating
down on 'em.
Not that old man.
He'll hang onto that gold,
Even if he has
to die for it.
And he will.
Oh, don't bother!
It's dry.
That's a very
astute observation.
That's right.
You sleep, old man.
Sleep.
It's getting damp.
Water!
Don't drink it.
it's alkaline.
Told you not to bother.
It's got to seep through
two feet of alkaline.
You're surprised
you can't drink it?
What are you doing?
Your father can't stand
another day without water.
So here's where
we make our stand.
There's no water here.
There will be,
I promise you.
When? How?
Four men will bring it.
Do we have to have a fire?
That smoke'll show
for miles around.
You can't ambush
somebody who isn't here.
They might miss us.
Are you crazy?
Nobody's going to be stupid
enough to come into those trees.
They'll know it's an ambush. Not in here.
We'll leave your father here
out of harm's way.
You and I'll be out there.
Now get me about four
good-sized tumbleweeds.
And incidentally,
Thank you for
finding this mud.
We're going to need it.
There's no cover out there.
Now what are you doing?
"let each soldier
hew down a bough,
"and bear it before him.
"and thereby burnham wood
will come to dunsinane."
What's that?
That, friend,
is shakespeare.
there they are.
I only see two.
You see?
They got another horse.
I told you there
were three of them.
Hey, look.
They're gone.
Yeah, tricky.
Keep an eye on 'em.
This time we'll
do things my way.
What if they try
and run out again?
On foot? Ha!
I'd like that.
You just keep an eye
on that horse, loy.
Without it,
nobody's going nowhere.
Dirks!
Huh?
Thought I saw something
moving out there.
Where?
There ain't
nothing there now.
Maybe I just been
jumping at shadows.
Prairie dogs or something.
Maybe.
They got to try something.
Giving up don't seem
to come natural to 'em.
We'll use the wagon
for cover if we have to.
Keep your eyes open.
Let's go.
Ahh!
Gino! Gino!
Gino!
Come on, boy!
Come on!
Gino!
This wound's not serious,
but he's burning with fever.
The gold is gone.
He got away with the gold.
Help me get your father
into this wagon.
What...What are you...
What are you doing?
What are you doing?!
I'm living up to my part
of the bargain.
No! I won't do it.
I won't do it!
Take mine.
You can't have gino's.
Only mine!
I had no right...
Take it.
What's he babbling about?
He's trying to renege
on the bargain.
He wants to trade his soul
and leave yours out of it.
That's nonsense!
You know it is.
Isn't it?
Can't you take it
a little slower?
You're hurting
the old buzzard!
We'll never catch up that way.
We got to get him
to a doctor fast,
And stop that man from
filing on your claim. Ha!
Ain't there anything
we can do for the old man?
You can pray if
you believe in it.
They're through with him?
Yeah. When I find the other
one, I'll send him to you.
According to
the assay office,
That fellow dirks filed a claim
on your mine an hour ago.
I want to find him while
he's still celebrating.
Will you go to
the doctor's office,
And take care of your father? Yeah.
Is that mirror
baroque or louis couture?
Huh?
How silly of me.
Baroque, of course.
Gentlemen, I might buy.
My round's next.
You hit it lucky too?
I'm not sure yet.
Bartender, bottled please.
Bottle's a dollar
a shot here.
I'll accept that.
We'll have another round
after this.
You owe for four already.
All right, all right!
Yours a rich strike?
I hear you beat three men
to town to file on this.
Two or three.
What's it to you?
I'm the third.
Here.
Take a look at your strike.
Take a good look
at your rich strike.
From my mine!
" tis more blessed
to give than receive. "
Now you just sign this.
I can't write.
Those two gentlemen will be
very happy to witness your mark.
He still owes for eight
drinks. Drinks are on me,
And a bottle apiece
for the witnesses.
Just sign it! You're not
giving anything away.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Dirks, that was
a very kind thing you did,
Shooting that old man.
Bartender, you'll find
the sheriff is looking for him.
Let me see that bottle.
Well, there it is.
Gentlemen.
You ruined our mine.
It's not exactly your mine.
I had the deed
signed over in my name.
Why, you're a crook!
You swindled us.
You were right, gino.
He ain't no devil.
Of all the dirty,
human things to do.
Now I haven't
forgotten our bargain.
I'll sign the deed
over to you gladly.
But for my price.
I'll take that
small bag of gold.
That's all you want?
Sulfur gas.
Any spark will set it off.
Gold ore is often forced to
the surface by sulfur gas.
That smell of brimstone.
That could make you rich.
Now the last man
I showed this to...
He tried to draw on me.
And maybe you'll
want to also.
See, there's no gold
in that mine.
Why, you're a liar!
It's rich.
There is gold
right at the surface.
You found a salted mine.
The gold in these pieces
has been cut or milled.
That mine isn't even
rigged for real digging.
And if you weren't
so gold hungry,
You'd have felt it
the most obvious thing.
Who ever abandons
a mine full of gold?
You cheated us.
You said we'd be rich.
And you will.
The assay office and I
are pleased to inform you
That you are the owners of
a very rich sulfur mine.
Sulfur! There's a lot of money in sulfur.
And a lot of work.
I'd say that mine,
In five years,
will pay off very handsomely.
Five years!
Of course, you could
go back to chasing your luck.
Forget all about the sulfur.
That's your affair.
As for me...
This has been
A very interesting
and profitable few days.
And I thank you
very much indeed.
have gun, will travel
reads the card of a man
a knight without armor
in a savage land
his fast gun for hire
heeds the calling wind
a soldier of fortune
is the man called
paladin
paladin, paladin,
where do you roam?