Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Good morning, sinners.
I can say that because
I'm a sinner, too.
I know the dark path
of drink and debauchery.
I traveled it well.
Yeah, but now I'm on
the path to God's light.
And I invite every last
one of you to come along.
All are welcome.
Black, white, sinner or Saint.
Even you papists.
All are welcome in God's house.
Thank you, Father.
I mean, Reverend.
I'm glad our dear sweet
mother wasn't here to see that.
What?
Just being polite.
Why you always on me arse?
The house was half-full last night.
Be half again tomorrow.
What do you want me to do about it?
Worry about it like I do.
The Swede will
come calling, you know,
sooner rather than later.
That must be the new girl.
The savage one.
What do you mean?
Haven't ya heard?
Mr. Toole told me the whole story.
She was but a girl, white as we,
taken captive years ago.
Sold to the highest
Heathen bidder, she was.
Some say she was a slave.
Others claim she be
an Indian princess.
Would you stop with your tall tales.
She's just a whore, Mick.
Well, then go talk
to her, you bastard.
Make me a liar.
Go on.
Ahem.
Good morning to ya.
He buy the man a drink
first, that's what I hear.
He buy the man a drink,
take him out and goes savage
as a meat axe on him.
You hear me?
He didn't kill Johnson.
They was gonna hang him.
They didn't.
Yet.
Good day, Mr. Bohannon, sir.
A fine day, is it not?
Fine or not...
Guess we got a good
day's work ahead of us.
Mr. Kretschmar...
I need that rail-end leveled
down to the next marker.
Mr. Toole, I need you and your men
down at the end of the iron.
Looks like the train's bringing down
that load of ties, all right?
Yes, sir, Mr. Bohannon, sir.
Elam, I need you and your men...
It's Mr. Ferguson.
Elam...
You and your men get down to the cut.
I need men...
Men not afraid of the Heathens,
men not afraid of making some money.
What is this about?
The fair-haired maiden of the West.
Mrs. Lily Bell,
she has been taken captive
by the Cheyenne dog soldiers.
A Mr. Durant has promised a bounty
to the men who rescue her.
Ain't nobody going nowhere's...
Or there won't be a job waiting
for you when you get back.
Dix will take a party
North, Bolan, South.
You... you...
You.
I told you.
I can't spare these men.
Mr. Durant wants her found.
Mr. Durant wants a railroad built.
You and you.
No, this ain't happening.
Boss man, let 'em go.
We can do their work and our work.
You get your men and you
get the hell out of here.
One more thing...
I'm looking for a man named Harper,
Frank Harper,
he's a friend of Johnson's.
I got something for him.
I believe he's out
with the logging crew.
Where's that?
Oh, must be 15, 20 miles
West of the cut by now.
Is that a bullet?
What?
What you got for sergeant Harper?
Ain't you got some work to do...
Yours and theirs?
Get to it.
The people, they are scared.
The Indian massacre.
They seen the bodies,
heard the stories, your stories.
I need troops.
7 men we lost last night.
Left the employ of the Union Pacific,
some on the train,
others just run off.
More tonight, I'd expect.
Seems the men prefer to keep
their scalps on their heads.
Are you afraid?
No, sir, Mr. Du...
What about you?
Well, as a matter of fact, I...
Enough. Now, why do you
wanna s on my railroad?
Uh, well, under our current pace,
uh, we won't make the 40-mile mark.
So, what I would, uh,
propose is we straighten the route.
The route remains the same.
But Mr. Durant, as I understand it,
the deadline has been pushed up.
And in light of Central Pacific's
recent advances...
Keep to the plan.
I'll make it a reality.
Yes, sir, Mr. Durant.
You're amused?
No, sir.
I'm just looking forward
to watching yet again
as you smite the forces agin you.
The search continues?
For the maps?
For the woman, Lily Bell.
I've got my men
out despite Mr. Bohannon.
Still more concerned about
your killer than my railroad?
No, sir.
But whoever cut
Daniel Johnson's throat
is an ongoing concern.
More importantly,
is my new foreman building my railroad?
He is.
Yet there is something about the man
that does not quite add up.
To... Jordan Crane, Washington, D.C.
Stop.
Honorable Senator.
Work continues at a fever pace. Stop.
However, hostile native
action threatens progress.
Stop. The march of
civilization in jeopardy.
Stop.
To heal the nation we
must displace the savage.
Stop.
Otherwise, the savage
will displace us.
Mrs. Bell?
Whoa, boy.
You speak English?
Yes, sir.
Move.
Who are you?
Joseph Black Moon.
You Cheyenne?
Christian.
Whoa, whoa.
Hold steady.
I'm unarmed, sir.
What did you do to her?
I... I didn't...
Hey. What did you do to her?
I saved her.
From the Indians?
Yes, sir.
She took an arrow to the shoulder.
I'm trying to take her to
the railroad to see the doctor.
When this happen?
2, maybe 3 days ago.
All right.
My horse, there's a field
kit in the saddle bag.
Here.
Hold her down.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Hey, shh. Stop!
Stop it!
Hold on.
Ohh! Ohh!
Now, the man say we gotta
do our work and theirs.
Ha! But I ask ya, why ain't
that negro ass down here with us?
Y'all know who he is,
that's all I'm saying.
Back in the day...
Them days was bad.
Don't get me wrong.
Massah drove me hard.
Nearly drove me to the grave.
You hear me?
Some things was better back then.
At least you knew your place.
Psalms!
Less talk, more work.
Bust me some stone, negro.
How 'bout I bust me your head?
You got something to say to me?
Yes, I do.
What would that be?
How come we got to do
the white man work, huh?
Oh, that's right, 'cause you
think you is the white man,
not the high yellar house n you is.
We got to do their work and our work.
But this ain't for them.
This is for us.
White man ain't gonna
give you nothin'
because they want us to fall.
They all want us to fall.
Hey.
Sir? Are you leaving?
Yeah. Somewheres I gotta be.
Thank you for helping her.
Yep.
Whoa.
Damn it.
You ain't thought this
thing through, have you?
What do you mean?
Indian brings that
woman back to town,
Indian don't get out alive.
But I live there, at the church.
You don't get it, do ya, boy?
They brought them back in
yesterday on a buckboard.
Everybody's seen what
they did to them bodies.
Why cut 'em up?
Huh?
What do you people get out of it?
Your people have done much worse.
Yeah, maybe...
Maybe.
But I ain't gonna keep 'em
from skinning your ass alive,
you bring that white
woman back to town.
I'll have to take her.
Explain to me how
I work harder than them
and they go to bed with 3 more
dollars in their pocket than I do.
That don't make a lick of sense.
Well, it don't.
We work as hard as them, right?
Damn right.
Then why don't we get
the same reward?
You crazy.
We deserve a taste, too.
Huh?
We can't go in there.
You ain't one of them
Nancy boys, is you, psalms?
Now, I know you get horny,
I hear you back behind
that tent every night.
Damn, boy, you gonna go blind.
Heh heh heh.
Look here, you go in there,
you coming out on
the bad end of a rope.
You ain't scared, is ya?
You're damn right I'm scared.
Well, I ain't.
♪ Sun don't rise
if you don't burn ♪
♪ sun don't shine no more ♪
She had a face like a hatchet
and an ass like a Venus, I tell you.
Just what do you want,
ya mule colored bastard?
Spend some hard earned
money, same as you.
Same as me, he says.
Have ya looked in the mirror
lately, Mr. Ferguson?
You think we the same, well then,
you got a big surprise
coming, I tell ya.
Face like a coal scuttle he has.
Why don't you just mind
your damn business?
You the man to make me?
Well, if it ain't Mr. Toole.
Watch out, ladies, he's back.
We call him the Blade,
for he'll gut you like a trout.
♪ Wonderin' what
the day will bring ♪
♪ shut my eyes and hang my head ♪
♪ at least that bird... ♪
And who would you be?
Your next customer.
Look at him, can't even
land a cheap ass whore
been plowed by every Heathen
buck in the territory.
♪ Draggin' this bag of stones ♪
♪ till they bury me down ♪
♪ beneath the ground ♪
♪ with the dust
and rattlin' bones ♪
Is this what you're looking for?
My shoulder's getting much better.
Where's Joseph?
He took off.
Why?
Ma'am, it is way
too late and way too wet
to be trying to figure out
some Indian, all right?
I regret we haven't
been properly introduced.
Cullen Bohannon.
I work for the railroad.
Have I done something?
It ain't what you
done, it's who you are.
What do you mean?
You ain't whore nor squaw.
You shouldn't be out here.
You don't know who I am
or what I'm capable of.
No, I don't, and I sure
as hell don't care.
Request for military support
to be taken under advisement.
Very concerned regarding
lack of progress.
Need to understand
impact of surveyor loss.
Hmm.
The honorable Senator
is very concerned.
If he were in my shoes,
he'd be downright suicidal.
Ahh.
Damn.
Henri?
Your look of disdain reminds me
of my dear wife back in New York.
What Hannah failed to
grasp is that where most
men seek the warm glow that
only whisky can provide,
I imbibe to fuel a conflagration.
There's a fire in my belly
which must be fed.
Otherwise, we'll
never see the Pacific.
And... did your wife accept
this excuse, Monsieur Durant?
As a matter of fact, she didn't.
Ahh.
Sorry, mate, uh, you missed
the last show, I'm afraid.
Oh, very well. I see.
Mr. Durant, sir,
an honor and a pleasure.
This is quite
an establishment you've got here.
I'm only sorry you're
closed for the night.
The next show begins
at dusk tomorrow.
Quiet, you daft bastard.
This is Thomas "Doc" Durant.
A private view he'll be having.
Thank you.
Ah, how much?
Ah, that will be 5...
Dollars.
The going rate...
For a private show.
Mickey, show time!
I have followed your exploits
and investments since
I got off the boat.
How you rose up from nothing,
pulled yourself up
by your bootstraps.
You're a gentlemen
and a true capitalist.
Thank you.
Hmm.
I assume you two are immigrants
from this beautiful country?
Aye.
From county Wicklow, to be exact.
We left our sweet mother
and 4 brothers
and set out for the new
world to seek our fortune.
You left a beautiful life
to come and wallow in this
filth and squalor and muck.
Well, it beats starving to death.
No, but you could have remained
in New York or Boston or Chicago.
There's plenty of work to be had.
Yet you chose to come here.
It makes me wonder why.
I'm not quite sure
what you mean, sir.
Well, you and thousands like you
have followed me out here,
and I'm genuinely curious.
Why?
Well, sir, um...
It seemed a proper investment
of our time and efforts.
That's not it at all.
I remember it well...
Like it was yesterday.
What are you talking about?
What is it you remember?
Ahem. We were just lads, me and Sean,
never been much further afield
than the bitter land our father worked,
God rest him.
And one day, we heard the whistle.
And it was the Dublin
special on its daily run.
Well, we jumped the steaming bastard.
It took us all the way to the city.
Ha ha ha.
Yes, I remember.
I never felt so free.
The railroad, it gave you freedom.
Aye.
And our father...
Gave us the whipping of a lifetime.
I prayed you'd stay away, my son.
This is my home.
It's not a very safe one right now
for one born out of the Grace of God.
But I'm baptized, Father.
Yeah, well, that does not always sway
the cruel prejudice of others.
It's not your fault.
But it is.
They were from my band.
Our dog soldiers,
they're the ones that did this.
Your family had nothing
to do with this.
I recognize the arrows, Father.
It was my brother.
You must tell no one.
Never speak of this again.
But it's the truth.
Never.
Well, there you are, kitty cat.
What do you want?
Oh, we want you.
We've been searching
over hill and Dale
for the fair-haired
maiden of the West.
We come to rescue ya.
Thank you, no.
I'm quite all right.
No, you ain't.
You barely escaped massacre.
You've been held captive.
You've been sullied by the Heathen.
You're out of order, sir.
Listen, you ain't come with us,
we ain't get compensated.
Oh, yeah, there's a bounty on
your head now, 100 gold eagles.
Go ahead.
Easy now, girl.
You just take it easy.
Stay back.
Easy now.
Stay back!
Now, you making this a lot more
unpleasant than it has to be.
Aah!
Uhh!
Mrs. Bell!
Damn it.
Come on!
My ear!
My ear! My ear!
Where is it?
Whoa. Whoa, hold up there.
Death is no stranger
to this God-forsaken place.
Death abides in the hard
labor of a rail gang
or the searing heat
of a prairie fire.
Death abides at the bottom
of a whisky bottle
or at the smoking end of a gun.
There's death by famine, flood,
or pestilence, and
a thousand other ways.
But yes, brothers,
death abides and he will
reap his dark harvest.
But must we be death's accomplice?
Must we do his bidding?
I know that your
hearts seek vengeance
for the deaths of
those men, I know that,
but haven't we had our fill of war,
our fill of killing,
the shedding of blood?
And they will hammer their swords
into plowshares...
And their Spears into pruning hooks.
Nations will not lift up
swords against nations.
And never again will
they learn war. Never again.
Isaiah, chapter 2, verse 4.
Wake up the mighty men,
let all the men of war draw near.
Hammer your plowshares into swords
and your pruning hooks into Spears.
Job, chapter 3, verse 10.
I, too, am sick of war, Reverend.
But we must consistently ask
ourselves what is worth fighting for?
What is worth laying our
lives on the line for?
Robert Bell gave his life
for this undertaking.
For this grand idea,
and I assure you,
he did not give his life in vain,
for he knew what this railroad
would mean to us as a nation.
He knew this railroad is
a new birth of freedom.
Not just the freedom
of long distance travel,
but the freedom to choose your fate,
the freedom to make
your fortunes in this untamed land.
And we cannot let
that freedom be threatened
by rag-tag bands of marauding
stone age primitives.
But that is not to say
that there is not a peaceful solution.
If they will put down their sticks
and stones and come into the fold,
like this young man here...
Then we will talk peace.
Now, look at him...
Wearing our clothes,
speaking our language,
washed in the blood of our savior.
If these violent nomads
roaming the plains
are willing to do as he has done,
then there is very real hope
that our mission might be
accomplished peacefully.
If not...
Then they are the authors
of their own destruction.
It's been months since
I've seen such a...
S hole?
Whoa.
Will you be all right from here?
You're not taking me in?
The church and the Doctor
straight on up ahead.
Wait.
What about the bounty?
I told ya,
I got business to attend
to in Cheyenne territory.
I got about 4 hours of daylight left.
I gotta move.
Mr. Bohannon?
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com