Anybody there?
Drop the rifle.
Turn around.
You Harper?
No, sir.
Where is he?
Who wants to know?
I'm your new foreman.
Why should I believe you?
Well, I guess Mr. Durant
didn't have time
to come out and tell you his self.
Durant?
Yeah, he told me to come
look for Harper.
Why?
That's his business.
Where is he?
Harper hightailed it.
When?
- A few hours ago.
- Which way?
North.
Towards the Ridge.
Is it true about Johnson?
Yeah, it's true.
What's the world comin' to, sir?
The world ain't
comin' to nothin', son.
Same as it ever was.
Harper!
Is that you?
Whoa.
Uh!
Uhh!
Shit!
Shh shh shh.
Shh shh.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Mrs. Bell?
Mrs. Bell, it's me, Thomas Durant.
They said you were up here.
I know who you are...
Mr. Durant.
The whole world's been looking
for you and, uh...
Here you are.
And here I am.
Uh.
You must excuse my appearance.
We need to get you
some medical attention.
Please... allow me to escort you.
Ah, you... you won't
need this anymore.
Your ordeal is over.
My deepest condolences
on your loss, Mrs. Bell.
Thank you.
How in God's name
did you make your way back here?
Uh... can't remember his name, um...
A Southerner, I think.
Bohannon?
Yes, I believe so.
Hmm.
Did I tell ya about me rendez-vous
with the tattooed harlot?
The Scarlet whore of Babylon
had nothing on this lass, I tell ya.
Give us the particulars, man.
I have never seen nothin' like
it in all me life, boys.
She used her organ like a velvet
hand on me tally whacker.
And to hear her tell it,
she's practiced these
dark arts of love
on all manner of beasts and men.
Chinks and monkeys and horses
have all known
the pleasure of her touch.
In fact, there is but one creature
in all the world with whom
she refuses to copulate.
And what would that be?
Well, the common American
nigger of course.
Damn it, I've heard enough...
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
All right.
Never thought I'd see you again.
You kill him?
Where you going?
Sooner or later,
you gotta give us some orders, boss man.
The demise of head
surveyor Robert Bell
and party, a great loss to railroad.
Stop.
Bell's work must continue.
Send funds for new surveyors at once.
Stop.
What news?
Payroll is late... work
disorganized and slow.
This new foreman of yours
just up and leave yesterday.
Nobody seen him since.
He rode out to rendez-vous
with the tree cutting party.
He informed me yesterday
at our morning briefing.
There's something about this man.
He's up to something.
He crossed paths with Mrs. Bell.
Bohannon?
He brought her in.
Did she have the maps?
Shh.
She's right next door.
No, she didn't have them.
How will you reach the
Pacific without them?
You let me worry about that.
Oh, there's a supply train
arriving tomorrow morning
with a shipment of black powder.
My men will meet the train
and guard it all morning.
New telegram to my damn stock broker.
Invest $147,000 in R&R
railroad stock as discussed.
Stop.
Ahem.
Mrs. Bell?
Are you all right in there?
Yes, thank you, Mr. Durant.
I, uh, ahem, I brought out my...
Personal Chef from Delmonico's
in New York City.
I wondered if you would like to
join me for dinner this evening?
Yes, that would be wonderful.
Is there anything else
I can get for you?
Actually, has the reward
been given to anyone?
Uh, I believe it
belongs to Mr. Bohannon.
I don't think he's claimed it.
Would you like me
to see that he gets it?
No.
There's someone else who deserves it.
Stay off my corner, sweetheart,
unless she wants her
own crib, right, ladies?
Leave her alone.
What do you say, blondie?
Them Injuns teach you anything?
Leave her alone!
Hey, I'm sorry, ma'am.
These dirty whores don't know
a lady when they see one.
Where there is hatred,
let me show love.
Where there is injury, pardon.
Where there is doubt, faith.
Amen.
Joseph?
Mrs. Bell?
You look like you're
feeling much better.
It's amazing what
a little soap and water can do.
I didn't mean to leave that night.
But that man...
There's no need to explain.
You've cut your hair.
Yes, ma'am.
Did you come to pray?
No, um... I came to give you this.
It's the reward money.
No, please, take it.
I can't.
There'll be no trouble,
nobody knows it was you.
No, that's not it.
I'm not a bounty hunter.
It's my duty to help.
Joseph, that money will
buy a lot of bibles.
Mrs. Bell, Reverend Cole.
Reverend.
Your donations are always welcome.
Please.
Thank you.
So, this is the fair-haired
maiden of the West?
I beg your pardon?
"Robert Bell fought valiantly to save
the virtue of his beautiful wife,
killing a savage
with his final breath.
Is that not how it happened?
Yes.
My husband... saved my life.
Well... what about
the rest of it? Um...
Outnumbered 10 to one?
Sullied by the savages?
I didn't write it.
But this is true?
Of course not.
Well, Indians will die
as a result of this.
The Indians attacked us.
If they die, they will
be to blame, not me.
Maybe you've heard of
the Sand Creek massacre?
I didn't come here to speak of this.
You know, the Cheyenne were
flying the American flag
over their camp and it
didn't stop the U.S. Calvary
from killing 100 innocent
women and children.
That was a terrible
thing that happened.
I wasn't a part of it.
Please, I'm just saying,
try to see the bigger picture.
My husband was slaughtered
right in front of me.
It's a little difficult
to see the bigger picture.
Good day.
Hey.
Hey, hey.
That son of a bitch
got away because of you.
Because of me?
How you figure that?
You killed Johnson before
he could give me Harper's name.
Oh.
Well, I... I killed Johnson
before he killed you.
Now...
But I would have got
a name out of him.
He would have blowed your brains out.
And then I could have killed Harper
before he had a chance to run.
You're either drunk or crazy or both.
You have any idea
what they took from me?
They ain't took nothin' from you
that ain't been took from me.
Fly away home, just a nickel a show.
Feel the mist against your cheeks.
Give it a rest, Mick.
They're sick and bloody tired
of the mighty Shannon
and the blarney stone...
The bloody Irish bog.
Well, then we need new slides.
New slides cost money.
You've got some copper
squirreled away, brother,
now's the time to tell me.
Maybe we should relocate.
The rent is low down by
the slaughterhouse, right?
The rent was low
in Wicklow, too, Mick.
We're done with that shit.
It was a high rent dream
that brought us out here.
I'm not going to let that big
Swedish bastard kill our dream.
Am I right?
Mick?
Hold on now.
I just had a grand idea.
Oh, no.
It's a business idea.
Ideas ain't your strong suit, Mick.
Ah, ha ha.
This one's golden.
I'll prove it to ya.
I've taken the liberty of
telegraphing your family in England.
I just wanted them
to know you were well.
Thank you, Mr. Durant.
I'm afraid you'll grow
weary of my gratitude.
I don't know what news of
the attack may have reached them.
I didn't want your father
worrying needlessly.
I'm sure my father was happy to hear
he was right...
About me coming to America.
He was against it, no doubt?
My father had every aspect
of my life planned out,
including whom I should marry.
Robert interrupted those plans.
I saw him give a lecture
at the British Museum
of Natural History.
He spoke of the American West.
I fell in love...
With him and with this land.
I, too, came under Robert's spell.
His dream of a transcontinental
railroad became my own.
Then it's a shame you two had
such a terrible falling out.
Well, Robert and I didn't
see eye to eye on everything.
Such as how to squeeze every
last dollar out of the railroad.
Mrs. Bell, your husband
was a starry-eyed dreamer.
I am a realist.
Without me, his dream would
have remained just that.
Thank you for your hospitality,
Mr. Durant.
Mrs. Bell, please, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to impugn Robert.
Yes, he needed me,
but I needed him also.
Our marriage wasn't
perfect, but it worked.
Mrs. Bell, there's nowhere
for you to go out there.
Please... accept my apology.
Do me the honor
of remaining my guest.
Why you following me?
You tryin' to get me killed?
Mister, you do that all by yourself
bustin' in on a white cathouse.
What you want then?
Huh?
You still want to give me a roll?
I thought you were mighty clear
on where you stood on that.
Honey, I'm already a cut rate whore
on account of my beauty marks.
My white customers know I laid
with a colored fella, I starve.
But... if you got a dollar,
then... maybe we can do
one off the books.
Now you tryin' to get us both killed.
Look at him.
Drop your hanky...
Madam?
Ah!
Now, now, boys.
I doubt Mr. Durant
wants his new foreman assassinated.
He shot my dang ear off, Swede.
Too bad it was not your tongue.
Move aside.
Mr. Bolan, you need
to leave here right now.
Damn it.
Come on, Tommy, let's go.
Let's go. Come on.
Magnolias.
They grow just outside
the gates of the Andersonville.
Some nights, their perfume was almost
enough to mask the awful stench.
Oh, you're a difficult man
to cipher, Mr. Bohannon.
Let me buy you a drink.
I won't turn down free liquor.
Need another glass.
Thank you.
No.
I know you killed Johnson.
Hmm.
What I do not know yet is why.
Who are you?
Hmm?
Ah, I'll figure it out.
You let me know when
you do, all right?
Oh, by golly, you will be
the first to know, hmm?
Oh, but in the meantime,
I've got a business
proposition for you.
Now, there is a... there
is some black powder coming in
on the train...
Tomorrow morning.
That is your cut.
And you just look the other
way while my boys unload,
uh, you know, a few barrels.
Is that some of that... immoral
mathematics, Mr. Swede?
Huh? Hmm.
Hmm.
All right...
You got a deal.
Yeah.
For another five.
Well, well, well.
Lookee.
How them Injuns treat you?
Well... they were people.
You know what people are like.
Some of them are good and...
Some of them ain't so good.
What about the ones that
put that mark on you?
Well... this wasn't that bad.
Did it hurt?
Not as much as a lot of things.
Folks be telling all kind of
tales 'bout what that mean.
Well... what do you think it means?
I reckon it mean you
was a slave... just like me.
Tuunuchch... hamokm...
Ahatch... asentk.
It's three blankets and a horse.
That's what I was worth to 'em.
Them eyes of yours alone
worth a hundred horses.
They was fools.
Maybe there's another
way of looking at it.
Maybe this mark was their way
of giving me their name,
telling the world
that I was one of them.
Hmm.
I got my master's name, too,
but I sure as hell ain't one of them.
Best I can tell... you ain't
one of nobody or nothin'.
Just like you.
Hmm?
Nothin' like two peas in a pod, huh?
40 miles.
Who came up with that number?
It's completely arbitrary.
I don't have enough
to worry about with savages
and the cutthroats
I have working for me.
It must be hard to be you.
Those milksops in Washington,
I begged them for more troops,
but get none.
And my investors, do you
think they'll give me
even a penny for new surveyors?
Hmm.
They haven't got your guts, Thomas.
Robert was a lucky man
to have you at his side.
Thomas... are the new surveyors
to finish Robert's work?
Yes, this time.
Forgive me.
I thought the lion's share of
Robert's work was finished.
Yes, it was, but he still
owed me some surveys.
I think he was keeping them from
me because of our falling out.
I see.
What kind of surveys?
There.
The Rocky Mountains?
It's a 14,000-foot barrier
of stone and snow...
But I think Robert
knew the way through.
But when you didn't
have his maps, I...
Oh, you poor man.
You must have been crushed.
I was.
That's not to say I wasn't
elated to see you safe and sound.
Let's have a song, shall we?
Henri?
Chante quelque chose pour la danse,
s'il vous plaît.
À la Claire fontaine,
m'en allant promener,
j'ai trouvé l'eau si belle
que je m'y suis baignée.
Il y a longtemps que je t'aime,
jamais je ne t'oublierai.
Sous les feuilles d'un chêne,
je me suis fait sécher.
Sur la plus haute branche,
un rossignol chantait.
Il y a longtemps que je t'aime
et jamais je ne t'oublierai.
Tu as le coeur a rire,
et moi, je l'ai à pleurer.
Il y a longtemps que je t'aime
et jamais je ne t'oublierai.
J'ai perdu mon ami
sans l'avoir mérité,
pour un bouquet de roses,
que je lui refusais.
Chante, rossignol, chante,
toi qui as le coeur gai,
tu as le coeur a rire,
et moi, je l'ai à pleurer.
Il y a longtemps que je t'aime,
jamais je ne t'oublierai.
Dark night here in hell,
brothers and sisters.
Come on in.
I got eggs, I got coffee,
I got scripture.
Oh, Mr. Bohannon.
Hi, Mr. Bohannon.
Did the good Lord
save you from hanging
so you could drown
yourself in whiskey?
It's a little late for proselytizing,
ain't it, preacher?
You know, you were right.
You know,
you don't deserve forgiveness.
Oh, yeah.
Neither did I.
You know, I stand here,
my wickedness washed away by
the... by the blood of the lamb.
What the hell do you
know about wickedness?
You ever hear of bleeding Kansas?
You know, I rode with
the martyr John Brown.
John Brown was a cold blooded killer.
You in a position to throw stones
on that account, Mr. Bohannon?
That's right.
Because you know one night...
You authored the deaths of 5 men.
Slave owners.
We pulled them from their homes
and butchered them with broadswords.
You know, drunkard I was,
I... I neglected to put
an edge on my blade.
It was hard work, brother, but I...
I kept a hacking and a hacking...
And a hacking till
I couldn't hack no more.
Now, that's bleedin' Kansas.
Why didn't you just shoot 'em?
Oh...
The mercy of a bullet was
something they didn't deserve.
Well, I owned slaves.
Yeah, well, lucky for you, you
weren't in Kansas that night.
Ahh.
No, preacher.
It's lucky for you.
No one deserves forgiveness, brother.
That's the beauty of grace.
Yeah. Ah.
Well, thank you
for the sermon, preacher.
I used to be a lot like you, Cullen.
The only difference
was I had a cause.
What is yours?
Yeah, John Brown's dead.
Ha ha.
That's right.
Yeah, I believe
we hung his sorry ass.
Âª I wish I was
in the land of cotton ♪
♪ old times there
are not forgotten ♪
♪ look away, look away ♪
Ha ha.
Look away.
Dixie Land.
Careful with this stuff, boys.
Hey.
Ohh.
You got a brick in your hat
this morning, boss man?
That hill we comin' up on
don't meet grade.
We either gotta blow it or go around.
Blow it.
My men ain't never
handled that black powder.
Uh, it ain't my problem.
You ain't no better than
Johnson, you know that?
How come every time I turn around
you're knee deep in my business?
Because you the boss.
I want to keep my job.
You better get to work then.
You got men ready to work
and there ain't
no supplies or no foreman.
You got to get up off
your ass and get out there.
The black powder is
on the damn supply train.
I ain't your master.
You wanted freedom, you got it.
Figure it out your damn self.
Ahh.
Mick, where the hell you been?
Makin' us some money, Sean-O.
Right this way, lads.
You won't be disappointed, I promise.
Hey, hey, hey.
No shoving.
One at a time.
Everyone will get his turn now.
Shh.
Right. Come on.
Go easy.
Are ya daft, Mick?
What?
It's brilliant.
It's a nickel a peep,
the show's always changing,
and there's no need for new slides.
You know, there's a lot
of uncontrollable factors.
Hey, hey!
This ain't no peep show.
Get out of here, you hobos
and you coal crunchers.
You pay your $3.00
like everyone else!
- Jeez.
- Get!
How's about a kiss for us instead.
Oh, how's about you
kiss my whore ass,
ya thick Irish bogtrotter!
Get!
Good morning.
I trust you had
a decent night's sleep?
This is the first bed
I've slept in in a long time.
I'm sorry for my behavior last night.
I'm afraid I had too much to drink.
Oh, please don't apologize.
I enjoyed myself immensely.
And today I was hoping to
see more of your railroad,
what you've accomplished,
what lies ahead.
After all, your passion...
For this great enterprise
was an inspiration.
Well, in that case, you shall
have the grand tour, my dear.
That is, if you're
well enough to ride?
I believe...
Let's go!
Run, Bolan, run!
Move, move, move!
Run, bloody, run!
Get out of there!
Oh, shit.
Shut the hell up.
Uh!
They're gonna blow!
Oh, my leg!
Oh, my leg.
Quit your cryin', madam.
Get the hell out of there!
Come on, lads, pull it up.
Pick it up.
Another bucket.
All right!
Careful now.
Hold his head.
May I?
Lift up the arm and put
pressure on the vein.
Right here?
Little higher.
Right... there.
You got it?
I think so.
All right. I gotta go.
Stay with him.
All right! That's enough
lally gaggin' around.
Rail crew better be hammerin' rail
by the time I get to my horse!
Cut crew out to the cut!
Let's go!
We got a hill to blow, boys!
Back to work!
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com