Narrator: Previously on
AMC's Hell on Wheels.
Chang ain't gonna take this layin' down.
Takin' over payroll, bringin' in workers.
I'm not afraid of Chang.
Maybe you outta be.
You are to be our new prophet.
I see what is happening.
How you look at her.
Ain't like that.
We share a common enemy.
(GUN COCKS)
Mr. Chang has you chasing wild geese?
(HIT)
(SCREAMING)
You did this?
The assassin was a white man.
Pity the only witnesses...
were Chinese.
(SOBBING)
(SNIFFLING, WHIMPERING)
(BOTH SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING IN CANTONESE)
(CONTINUES SHOUTING IN CANTONESE)
- No.
- (MUFFLED) (SPEAKING CANTONESE)
- It ain't worth it.
- (SPEAKING CANTONESE)
- No.
- (GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(YELLING) Mei!
- (CRICKETS CHIRPING)
- It's okay.
(EXHALES)
(SOBBING)
(SNIFFLING)
(SIGHS)
(CHATTERING OUTSIDE)
He wanted to go home.
(MEI SIGHS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
(BUSTLING)
Need to talk to him.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
Thirty million dead in south China.
Scores by my own hand.
A dozen or so, maybe, here.
Mr. Bohannon, I am exhausted
by all the killing.
You gonna pay out
that man's wages to his son.
For the duration. This ends now.
I admired Mr. Tao. He was a brave man.
Give me an affirmative so I can
walk out of here with a clean shirt.
It's the least I can do.
(HOLSTER CLATTERING)
Nobody else dies.
MEI: I no take his money.
Pride ain't gonna bring him back.
Won't ease the hurt none,
neither... Nothing does.
I take my father to China.
(HAMMERING)
JAMES: A translator?
For Christ's sake, have Chang
send for one of the little shits.
He can have 'em here in a day.
Need a translator I can trust.
Fine, all right. Fair enough.
You know, Bohannon,
since you're gonna be up there anyway,
you mind picking up
a bolt of gingham for Hanna
and some rock candy for the boys?
And Janie's canary flew away last night,
got spooked by the fireworks.
So, there's an avian depository
there, just north of Downtown...
Ji... Jim. I'm going to get a translator.
Well, keep it in mind.
Most folks don't get to
San Francisco as often as you.
Get back quick.
Be gone a day.
(YELLING) All aboard!
CARRIAGE DRIVER: Hey!
(SCRAPING)
Step aside!
(GRUNTS)
- Brigham.
- Thomas.
DURANT: Ah, gentle... Thank you, gentlemen.
Well, what brings the Defender
of the Saints to Laramie?
Without a telegram or even an invitation.
Oh, no, no. Not that you're not welcome.
You owe me half a million dollars
for the Mormon graders I sent you, Thomas.
Payment is long overdue.
Uh... (STUTTERING) Sit, please.
(CHUCKLES) My good man,
I would not dream of withholding payment,
were I not so viciously
cash poor at present.
The government pays out $16,000 per mile.
You're making five miles per day!
Which requires an enormous
outlay of capital,
as you can imagine.
I'll give you a day on the
matter. I'm at the hotel.
I can't do anything on such short notice.
Then you'll be without a third of
your workforce come sundown tomorrow.
Every last damn nickel, Thomas!
(SIGHS)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
(THUD, SQUEALING)
(CHATTERING)
CULLEN: What's the hold-up?
Repair crew.
Bridge ain't safe.
You can pick up a train
to San Fran from Sacramento.
It's a two day ride by the Dutch Toll Road.
How 'bout this nice looking
work road right here?
- She'll shave a day off.
- Obliged.
Sit tight.
They'll have the bridge repaired
in a few days. Three at the most.
No good, bossman.
Too hot. Waiting no good.
Take us.
Please... Take us?
Ain't got the time, nor the supplies.
Here, give that to the foreman.
Tell him you want a hot meal
and your own tent for the night.
(PANTING)
- (SCRAPING)
- (GRUNTING)
(THUD)
Hell.
(NEIGHING)
CULLEN: Ho.
- Railroad Man.
- Stagecoach Mary.
Headed to Sacramento?
- Truckee?
- That's right.
There's bridge repair ahead, you'll
have to go around at the camp.
But then you're straight and
smooth all the way to the barn.
You got an easy ride on up to the river,
but you wanna take care crossing.
She's running high and the bed is jagged.
Obliged.
Sacramento's awful far. You in need?
I can use a side of bacon,
you got any spare?
I got some to sell.
I could let it go for $3.
One dollar.
- You see any pigs out here?
- (CHUCKLES)
Drive to Truckee three day.
Sun hot. Meat spoil.
Bridge crew will be happy to pay
top dollar for some fresh cut bacon.
Fresh yesterday. Yesterday $3.
Tomorrow, one dollar.
Two dollars then... Today.
(CHUCKLES) Pleasure doing
business with you, Mary.
Careful on that river, Railroad Man.
(CHUCKLES)
STAGECOACH MARY: Heh!
Glad we ran into ol' Mary.
Pay too much.
(CHUCKLING)
You are tough, ain't you?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
So China, huh?
San Francisco steamer to Hong Kong.
I have gold eagle, right?
No. Mmm-mmm. Railroad'll pay.
Figured there wasn't nothing left
for you back in China, is all.
My father,
he no let rebel leader take me.
He give up everything.
Everything except you.
Now, I bring my father home.
Yeah, I tried that once.
Going back home.
Did it for my grandfather... And my father.
(SCOFFS)
Hell, I did it for honor.
Sometimes, I still wake up
with ashes in my mouth.
My father say you good man.
Honorable man.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
Goodnight.
Let me get this straight.
Brigham Young is here to get paid,
for services you contracted?
Yes.
And if he isn't satisfied,
he's going to pull his workers
and send them home?
- To the Great Salt Lake.
- (CLATTERING)
Poor miserable bastards...
- How do you take it?
- Light and sweet.
(SIGHS)
We're flush, New York.
There's better things for you and
I to do with the railroad's money.
You know, in the cattle business,
the only thing more valuable
than beef on the hoof
is information.
And what information have you
in mind for Mr. Young?
Oh, all kinds of information
can be valuable.
Particularly information regarding
the whereabouts of rustlers.
Now, didn't you mention something to me
about a map from the Central Pacific?
(LAUGHS)
Here's to rustlers.
And schemers.
Do you know who I am, young lady?
My mama taught me to love you.
Same as I loved Jesus and Joseph Smith.
You're a Mormon.
Jack Mormon.
We was on our way to Salt Lake City
when the Yavapai attacked.
You've spent time amongst the Lamanites.
EVA: Yeah.
I thought I'd have myself a nice
Mormon husband when I was grown.
A family of sister wives, and, uh...
I thought I'd spend
every Sunday in the Temple,
listening to the Lion of
the Lord preach the Word.
I thought I'd spend my whole life
spittin' distance from you.
You would have been
very welcome in Zion, child.
Yeah, well, instead I got this
marked up face,
little bit of Indian magic,
and a brothel full of whores.
Mmm-mmm. Mmm-mmm.
You're still Mormon.
Jack.
It's never too late...
to return to the fold
and be forgiven, my child.
Heavenly Father's
loving embrace awaits us all.
We have only to accept it.
(SOFTLY) I will pray for you.
(WATER GUSHING)
Ho! Ho, ho!
(GRUNTS) Hold this.
Go around, bossman.
No. Dutch Toll's too far.
We got to cross here. (SIGHS)
Slow and steady.
You do as I say, all right?
- (CLICKING TONGUE)
- (HORSE NEIGHING)
Easy.
(CARRIAGE CREAKING)
(GRUNTING, WHINNYING)
Easy.
Damn it. The bottom's too
rough, got to turn these horses.
(CLICKS TONGUE) Hup! Come on!
Hup!
- (HORSE NEIGHING)
- Hup!
Hup! Hup!
(CREAKING, CARRIAGE BREAKING)
(WHINNYING)
(MEI GRUNTS)
(YELLING) Swim for the shore!
(GRUNTING)
Swim for the bank!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
- Let me go!
- Mei!
No! Mei! Mei!
- Let it go.
- (SOBBING)
EVA: You shouldn't be up
after all you've been through.
I heard Brigham Young was outside.
You've got to let the slippery
elm do its work.
(STUTTERING) I am. I... I will.
From bed. In case of
infection, you need to rest.
(SIGHS) Eva, thank you.
I truly appreciate
everything that you've done,
and I promise you that I will rest.
But I... I need a story, Eva.
I haven't had a decent scoop in months.
Slippery elm don't work on
your schedule, Miss Ellison.
If you don't respect it,
it can turn real bad.
I'm fine. (CHUCKLES)
Now, what is your interest
in the railroad, Mr. Young?
The interest is not mine,
madam, but Heavenly Father's.
I'm His instrument in this,
as in everything.
Uh, so...
Uh, God wants a railroad?
(CHUCKLES)
Just this morning,
I met a young lady
who was attacked by savages
on her family's pilgrimage West.
Let me ask you,
would Heavenly Father,
who sent a million gulls to clear
the locusts for his starving people,
would He want His saints
scalped and defiled on their way to Zion?
So, you're hoping the Union Pacific's route
will allow the faithful safe
passage to the promised land?
Salt Lake City is to be the terminus.
The terminus?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Uh, forgive me, Mr. Young...
(SLURPING)
but, uh...
Is that your faith speaking?
I have assurances from both railroads.
Are you ill, Miss Ellison?
Can I offer you a drink of water?
I'm... I'm fine.
Thank you, that... That's all.
Thank you for your time, Mr. Young.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Thank you.
CULLEN: Please, get on the horse.
MEI: No.
The wagon's gone.
We've lost most of our supplies, and it...
This has gone on long enough.
We gotta go back to Truckee.
Go without.
I bury my father.
He's gone.
Mei, it's over.
We both got to live
with things left undone.
(BIRDS SCREECHING IN THE DISTANCE)
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
Shit.
(MEI SOBBING)
(GRUNTING)
(CULLEN SIGHS)
(MEI SNIFFLING)
We'll bury him here.
No. No, no.
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(WHIMPERING)
(CULLEN GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Set that shovel down. Sit.
It's son's duty to bury father. (GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Just be his daughter, then.
Come on.
(MEI SIGHS)
(DIGGING)
You have dug many graves.
(GRUNTS) Too many to count.
But the worst was the ones I couldn't bury.
When my mother was killed,
we couldn't bury.
No wake.
No funeral.
No grave for ancestor to take care of.
Her ghost wander...
Tired, hungry...
All alone.
Now my father,
his ghost too must wander...
Hungry, lonesome...
Just like my mother.
Maybe they'll find each other.
Collis Huntington sat at my dinner table
and assured me of his commitment
to a Salt Lake City terminus.
DURANT: Clearly, he intends to go north,
bypassing Salt Lake altogether.
I fail to see what this has to do
with the money you owe me, Thomas.
We are both victims
of Huntington's treachery.
I have engaged vast resources
toward Salt Lake, as promised.
Including plans to bridge the Lake itself.
Uh, Mrs. Palmer.
As you can see, it is an
expensive bridge, Mr. Young.
Now, you came he for payment,
and payment you will have,
along with the great
Transcontinental Railroad
and all its goods and
services, capital and trade,
flowing through your backyard...
The lifeblood of Zion.
Just as soon as the railroad is complete.
I shall have payment in full
before I leave this room, madam,
or I shall call every
sober saint home to Utah.
You leave here th your workforce
and you will have no payment whatsoever!
Nor railroad terminus.
You will remain as you are...
An aging charlatan,
the polygamous master of a
doomed and desert-locked sect!
Or...
take this map,
proof of the Central Pacific's
dirty dealings,
as down payment.
Brigham, allow me to keep
every available worker
laying track toward Salt Lake.
Our contract stands for now.
Lay one track north of Salt Lake,
and you'll learn why they
call me the Lion of the Lord.
I've defeated the United States Army.
I'd damn sure make short work of you.
I'm going home.
I'm weary of gentile serpents
and their honey-lipped harlots.
Well, I believe that man just
called me a "honey-lipped harlot."
I believe he just called you
my honey-lipped harlot.
Steady on, New York.
We got a land deal to finish.
EVA: Shh...
I found you by the hotel.
You have an infection.
We have to ke your fever
down while you fight it.
- Mmm.
- No, Miss Ellison, stop that.
- Please, lay back.
- No, you need the bed.
Louise.
You don't have to do this for me.
Hey, I'm your friend.
Now, lay down.
(CRYING)
(SOBBING)
(WHIMPERING)
(FIRE RUSTLING)
My mother's things.
Please.
Come.
(SINGING IN CANTONESE)
For my father.
Light will help ghost find his way home.
For your ghosts.
Those you have buried
and those you could not.
When light goes out,
(SIGHS) they will be home.
(HOLSTER CLATTERING)
The night is cold.
Too cold to sleep outside.
(GUN CLATTERING)
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
I lost my wife and boy.
I'm sorry.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
MEI: Thank you...
For everything, bossman.
Cullen.
It's Cullen.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Oh...
(GRUNTS)
I ain't slept this late
since before the war.
(SNIFFLING)
Long journey today.
Mmm.
Coffee first.
- Brother.
- Ah.
My father has declared a work stoppage.
We're to report home
to Salt Lake immediately.
Are you certain, my son?
Collis Huntington has deceived him.
Oh, this is a great blessing.
Your time is upon us.
Are you prepared for your ascension?
With your help, and by the
grace of Heavenly Father,
I will be.
- I'll go order the men to start packing.
- Uh, brother.
A band of apostates
lurks in the Utah hinterlands.
If these unholy creatures
unearth themselves,
they will destroy us
with their hideous lies.
They have already tried to destroy me.
Who are these apostates?
They are known as Hatchites.
Aaron Hatch and his clan.
We must root them out, Brother Phineas.
I'll speak to my father on it.
- Perhaps he knows their whereabouts.
- Mmm.
(SIGHS)
This'll ease the cramps some.
Still gonna hurt a few days, though.
(WHISPERING) You're an angel.
(SIGHS)
No one's ever cared for me like you.
Not even my own mother.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
(TYPING)
LOUISE: "Brigham Young has assurances
that the terminus of the
great Transcontinental Railroad
will be Utah's capitol.
But I have it on good authority
that the Union Pacific's plan
to bridge a large lake
is a boondoggle.
There is no larger lake than the Great
Salt Lake for which the city is named.
Which leads me to wonder, dear reader,
is the Union Pacific
deliberately falsifying its plans
in order to deceive the Mormon leader?
Thomas 'Doc' Durant has promised
"Christmas in New York,
New Year's in San Francisco.'
A romantic notion from a man
who has served time
for defrauding the American treasury.
But where will the Central Pacific
and Union Pacific meet, if at all?
Will the American people ever
have the railroad they deserve?
Or, like Brigham Young,
have we all been hoodwinked
by the notorious railroad baron
in the greatest swindle of our time?"
Been more than a day.
Long story, Jim.
Well, where's the damn translator?
You're looking at him.
I don't suppose you have
a canary in your pocket?
Well, hell, who cares?
We got bigger fish.
- Shit.
- JAMES: No shit.
President Ulysses S. Grant has
called a meeting in Salt Lake City.
Huntington's already on his way
there. And you, my friend, are late.
Get your ragged-lookin' ass to Utah.
I'll see to it John here
gets to the tunnel.
Fong.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
www.addic7ed.com