Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Brake! Brake!
What's going on?
Keep your yankee hands
where we can see 'em
And no one will get shot!
We want your valuables.
Give me your money, let's go.
Let's go. Empty those pockets.
Let's go.
Come on there.
Don't you hold out on me, now.
Take this.
Damn it, give me that gun!
Damn--
give me that!
What have you got?
Get back there!
Blow the lock!
All right.
Don't shoot me.
Whoo!
What you think about that, huh?
Bring that sack in here!
Let's get moving.
Come on!
You'll be all right!
Let's go!
Can you ride?
Yeah.
You on?
All right, go, go, let's go.
Come on, Mississippi!
Come on!
Come on, boys!
One more man
on the front line. Let's go!
Where's my money?!
Not again.
Hey, you.
Hey!
Why don't you kill the bastard?
All right, get back to work!
Go to hell, Schmidt!
Get back to work, you bastards!
Ain't you gonna do something?
Not my job.
What exactly is your job?
You'll see.
Graders are averaging less
than 2,000 feet per day.
And last week only
1,200 rails were spiked.
1,800 ties laid.
It's simply
not acceptable.
Have you talked to
Mr. Schmidt about all this?
Yes. He tipped his hat
at me and looked coy.
I considered wiping the grin off
his face with the back of my hand.
But I thought better of it.
Good.
Lily, you must remember
we males
have very fragile egos.
Especially when it comes to
dealing with a strong woman.
Hmm.
You poor things.
Mm.
Well, today is payday.
Tomorrow will be better.
Wouldn't hold my
breath, Mr. Durant.
Payroll train's
been robbed again.
Damn it!
Thom, now is the time.
Send word to Fort Kearny.
We need protection.
We can't. If our enemies
in Washington knew
we can't protect
our own payroll...
Mr. Ferguson.
It seems we'll be needing
your services again.
Happy to oblige, sir.
What in the hell is that?
This here?
200s worth
of Yankee bank notes.
That's your cut, Bohannon.
I thought the idea was...
We save our take
for the colony for Mexico.
General Shelby and Magruder's
already down there.
We're going to Mexico,
I assure you.
I told you, these boys,
they don't get it.
We're gonna need
this money for...
Buying land, putting in crops,
cattle, I don't know.
Look, if we're gonna do this,
we're gonna do it right.
I call the shots here, not you.
I'm just asking for...
A little contribution.
Then you can keep calling the shots.
How about that?
You worry too much, Bohannon.
Heh heh heh heh.
More coffee?
We won last night.
We deserve a chance to whoop
it up a little, right, boys?
That's right!
Viva LA Mexico.
Here you go, doc.
Put that in the kitty.
Another contribution, Cullen?
Yeah.
How's Tommy doing?
He's dead.
Yeah.
Let's take a look
at that shoulder.
Come on.
I seem to remember
pulling buckshot out of
your rear end once before.
I must have patched you up
more than any other kid
in meridian.
Seems like a lifetime ago,
doesn't it?
Well, it was.
Hey, you know, Cullen,
I had mixed feelings
about you joining up with us
when we ran into you
down in meridian.
Doc...
You don't need to worry
about me, all right?
I knew what I was getting into.
Hey.
To a new start
down in old Mexico.
Amen to that.
And all them pretty senoritas.
I'd like to talk to you
about the love of Christ.
Brothers and sisters...
Be firm.
Be watchful.
Stand firm in your faith.
Act like men.
Be strong.
As Jesus turned,
and seeing her, he said,
"Take heart, daughter,
our faith
has made you well."
And the woman was made well.
Buy some property in the
fastest-growing town in the territory.
Right, chief.
Start a business.
Build a homestead.
The finest tent...
Right here, sir.
Consider yourself
the proud owner
of a prime piece
of railroad real estate.
Step right up!
Fine property,
waiting to be had.
Lots for sale!
What?
Mick.
Shouldn't you be getting on with
that other business of yours?
What other business?
I don't much care, brother,
as long as you get on with it.
Right.
Miss Ruth.
What can I do for you today?
It's about the rent,
I'm afraid.
Late again?
It's father.
He's not well.
And if he's not well,
he can't preach.
And if he can't preach, there's
no collection money coming in.
I'm sympathetic
to your plight, miss Ruth,
but, uh, there's only
so much I can do.
I'm but a humble employee
of the railroad.
I'm afraid I don't know
what to do.
Maybe we could
discuss this at dinner.
With my father there,
of course.
I was thinking maybe
just the two of us.
Mr. McGinnes, what sort of
girl do you think I am?
I'll do my best
to have you the rent soon.
You have my word.
Yes.
Mr. Gundersen.
Ah. Mit Herredomme...
What happened to him?
Ah, stabbed in the eye
it would appear.
Another victim of the
chaos that presides here.
Bandits rob your trains,
murderers run your streets,
work has slowed to a--
to a crawl.
You needn't remind me
of my own business, Gundersen.
Sir, I have worked for you
since before New York.
I've always been faithful
and diligent, hmm?
Let me help you.
I appreciate it.
But since those Irish boys
tarred and feathered you
and ran you out of town
on a rail...
Embrace this new job,
Gundersen.
Lowly and noisome
though it may be,
you provide an invaluable
service to the community.
Community.
♪ Hurrah, hurrah
♪ for southern rights, hurrah
♪ hurrah for
the Bonnie blue flag ♪
♪ that bears a single star
Think they would have
learned their damn lesson.
Especially after
general Sherman
had that little
barbecue of his.
Just ignore 'em, Cullen.
I can't.
How you boys don'?
Ohh!
Aah!
Come here, boy.
You gonna feel that tomorrow.
Them Yankee farm boys are gonna
feel it a whole lot worse.
Ahh.
Your father had
a penchant for spirits
and a good fight.
Like father like son, huh?
I said a good fight.
Tell me, Cullen,
what did you gain in there?
You teach those Yankee
boys a lesson, did you?
Something like that, yeah.
It's you who needs the lesson.
You are better than
them damn fools in there.
If they's fools, what you
don' ridin' with 'em?
Well, sad as it is, right now,
those boys are the closest
thing to family I got.
They dug up my family, doc.
Carpetbaggers,
they tore up plenty of graves
in our hometowns
looking for loot.
They dug up my boy.
My Mary.
What kind of man does that?
Elam?
In the flesh.
Why are you here?
Just passing through.
You still working
for Mr. Durant?
I'm on the job right now.
I guess you got
what you wanted, then.
Hello, Mr. Ferguson.
It's a surprise to see you
again, sir.
What brings you
to our fair town?
He's on railroad business
for Mr. Durant.
Ah. I, too,
work for Mr. Durant.
He appointed me
station agent here.
Congratulations.
To both of you.
Would you like to join us
for supper?
Well, maybe
some other time, then.
Yeah.
Maybe some other time.
Wake up!
Get up!
Supply train
leavin' in 5 minutes!
Ain't all of you
ain't got a job.
Get up, you bastards!
Penny is dead!
Ginny?
What is it?
Get back to work.
There's men waitin'.
Ohh...
Such a terrible thing.
Truly it is, brother.
Tragic.
But this could be
the opportunity
we've been looking for.
You ain't gonna
believe this, boys.
There's a nigger guard
in the payroll car.
Let me take point, captain.
Shoot that buck dead.
Let me see him.
I've been the first man
through the door all along.
I think I've earned the right
to take him down.
All right, Bohannon,
you got it.
No, don't.
I don't know why they bother
me with these things.
Thomas, what is it?
It seems a woman
has been murdered.
A first for
our little community.
She was just a whore,
but still...
Do they know who killed her?
Certainly one of our employees.
Lily, you don't have to
concern yourself with this.
Thomas, this man
needs to be found.
He will be punished.
I'm afraid nobody's
going to care very much
about the killing
of a prostitute.
Thomas, you hang
horse thieves here.
Are you saying horses are more
valuable than these women?
Sad to say, but yes.
Yes, they are.
You don't mean that.
Lily, she chose
a dangerous profession.
With choices come consequences.
Let's eat our
breakfast, shall we?
Now!
Hyah!
All right,
this here's a stickup!
All right, everybody,
wallet, watch, jewelry,
put it in the bag right now.
Come on, now.
Don't be foolish.
Open up!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Open the damn door!
Bohannon?
Damn right. Open up.
Son, you want to sit down?
What the hell you don' here?
Trying to keep you
from getting yourself killed.
Get that gun out of my face
and give me the payroll.
You hand that money over
I can't.
Or I'll kill you my damn self.
Go on, then.
Pull the trigger.
What the hell's going on in there?
You stupid son of a...
Aim high.
Keep shooting.
Right now!
Put it in the bag.
He's got the drop on me!
Come on! We gotta
get off this train!
Come on.
Uhh!
Let's get outta here!
Come on, boys.
Let's ride!
Hyah! Hyah!
Come in.
Eh...Tor Gundersen, ma'am.
Here to empty your Jerry pot.
Thank you, Mr. Gundersen.
Not necessary, ma'am.
It's my job.
We all must do our jobs, huh?
Yes, but...
I imagine it's hard with...
Considering--
how far I've fallen.
Look h...how far
you rose up.
Hmm? Mm.
Aye.
We all do what we must
to carry on.
Hmm.
Mr. Gundersen.
The woman, um...
The one they killed...
The whore?
What--what will happen
to her?
She'll have a whore's grave.
See that she gets
a proper burial.
Ah...
The reverend and I will--
will bury her 6 feet down, eh?
Like a proper lady.
Thank you.
Mm.
Have a good day.
Good morning, father.
I'm preparing--
For Sunday's sermon.
Matthew 7:13.
You sure you're up to it?
I am, Ruth.
Then I suppose you won't
be wanting this today.
I know what you're doing.
And what is that?
You--heh heh-- you don't
believe in me anymore.
Of course I do.
Then we--we don't need--
we don't need this.
Praise Jesus.
It's wonderful.
I'll pour it out, then.
Y-you can't.
I--I'll have one last drink.
Ahh...
Let's go to Mexico, boys.
Right now.
Whoa.
Slow down there, son.
We'll take a paddle steamer
to Louisiana.
Texas-New Orleans railroad
from there to Galveston.
Hell, it ain't but a 300-mile
ride to Mexico from there.
That's a good idea.
Right after we take down
another train.
We got enough money.
Besides, they're expecting us.
The guard on that last train
was waiting for us.
You scared, Bohannon?
Is that it?
You're treading
on some skinny ice, son.
You want to do this,
Mississippi?
Why didn't you draw down
on that darkie?
Just the way
it played out, I guess.
All right.
One more train.
Then we go to Mexico.
Cullen Bohannon is robbing my
trains and you didn't kill him?
You hired me to protect your
payroll and that's what I done.
Yes, you did at that.
Maybe I could do more
for you, Mr. Durant.
More?
This town's goin'
to hell in a handbasket.
Your point is?
I'm the man
that could fix things.
I have no doubt you are up
to the job, Mr. Ferguson.
But it's not as simple
as all that.
Maybe if I was
a few shades lighter?
I won't lie to you--yes.
I can do it.
All I need is a chance.
Let me think about it.
Appreciate that.
Bohannon.
I should have known.
Another brick on
his road to hell.
The man did this
would be dead already
if the Swede
was still running things.
I miss him.
The Swede put a thumpin'
on you, Nell.
Hell, that was just business.
You think I don't beat on my
girls when they hold out on me?
That man ran this shithole
of a town like a fine watch.
Well, it's
your lucky day, Nell.
'Cause that's why
me and Mickey are here.
How the hell are you two
skinny chaps
gonna protect my knocking shop?
Give us a chance.
What have you got to lose?
We're in, boyo.
Same deal as the Swede--
10% of the take,
after expenses.
That's great.
There's one small catch.
You have to kill that man
that did her dollymop.
What?
I ain't no killer.
Mick, that's what you said
in Boston.
But that was different.
Things...got out of hand.
I ain't a killer.
Cullen, you need to get on
this horse
and ride away from here
as fast as you can.
Them Alabama boys are none too
happy with you right about now.
Doc...
If you'll excuse me,
I got a train to rob.
Cullen, this ain't
gonna end well.
It rarely does.
♪ Will there be enough water
♪ when my ship comes in?
♪ Water
♪ when my ship comes in
♪ will there be water
♪ when my ship comes in?
♪ When I set sail
♪ will there be enough wind?
♪ Cool water
♪ oh, cool wind
♪ just because you caught me
♪ does that make it a sin?
♪ Yeah, just because
you caught me ♪
♪ does that make it a sin?
♪ Cool water
♪ yeah
♪ and that cool wind
♪ be enough water
♪ when my ship comes in?
♪ Be enough water
♪ Oh, when I set sail
♪ will there be enough wind?
♪ Yeah
♪ oh, cool water
♪ yeah, and that cool wind
watches in the bag.
Watches in the bag.
I know you got a watch.
Don't give me that.
You know, man it smell
like Yankee in here, don't it?
Ma'am, I need you to put
that purse in this bag.
Take the ring off your finger!
Hurry up!
I'm gonna put a hole
in your boy's head
if you don't give me that ring.
Hurry up!
Hurry up! Try harder!
You want a dead child
in your lap?
I will kill this Yankee spawn.
Take that ring off your finger!
Get that ring off your finger!
Do you want this boy to die?!
You better stand down, son.
Last chance.
No. It's yours.
Hey.
Shit.
They're watching us.
I can feel it.
After what happened
to you and Robert,
I can understand your unease.
We surveyed this area.
The Sioux believe the land
across that river
is sacred...
Where the earth touches heaven.
Robert wanted to avoid it.
What do you think?
My husband was rarely wrong
on these matters.
I know they're over there
waiting for us.
We can't ignore them.
But they will be
the least of our troubles
if we don't get
this railroad under control.
Unless you got a bee
in your throat,
best cease that hum sound.
A happy man's got a right
to hum, all right?
Son, you're getting set
to be hanged.
Nah, they won't hang me.
Shoot me, most likely.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
♪ Take me home
to the land of cotton ♪
♪ old times there
are not forgotten ♪
♪ look away, look away
♪ look away...
♪ Dixieland
Shut up.
I don't...
I don't know what to say
about this.
Whore. Hmm?
Well, it was a whore who...
Bathed the feet of Jesus
with--with her hair.
Yeah. Amen.
Huh?
Yah.
Uh...
Father, accept this whore
into the ground
so that her corruption
may be completed.
May her soul
be eternally forgotten.
May we be cleansed
of her memory.
Yah.
These things in your name.
Humbly.
Amen.
Dig! Dig.
New graves, sir.
Many new graves.
We shall plant our--
our strange crop,
and the lord...
The lord...
will pour forth
his bounty upon us.
Hey, Johnny Reb!
Time to wake up!
You better start
singin' "Dixie."
'Cause you're next!
Aim...
Fire!
Aah!
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com