Previously on AMC's Hell On Wheels...
Tell me about Moretti...
How do you know about Moretti?
***
A father to his child...
You stay away from my family!
***
Did you kill our man, son?
Tell me the truth!
*** always sides with the winner.
***
[Mule brays]
[Women shouting in the distance]
[Shouting continues]
Squaws!
Jimmy Two Squaws?
[Gunshot]
[Horse whinnies, mule brays]
Holster your hardware
and declare your intentions.
[Gunshot]
[Mule brays]
'Twould behoove you to oblige.
[Pistol safety clicks]
We're with the railroad.
Looking for a guide to take us
through Indian territory.
- Haden send you?
- He's my surveyor.
Says you speak Kiowa.
Now what do you want
with the Kiowa?
Just trade.
Haden says the Kiowa
got a copse of spruce.
Well, the Indians
around these parts
say that you took heads off
of peaceful women and children.
Thems was Bluecoats.
That wasn't me.
And they was acting
on behalf of the railroad.
And they ain't here right now.
I don't want no bloodshed.
Where you from, boy?
- Union Pacific Railroad.
- No.
No, no, no.
I mean where was you borned at?
Shit.
Meridian, Mississippi.
I knew it.
[Women shouting indistinctly]
Yes, sir,
you got Mississippi river water
on your tongue.
Me, I'm from Louisiana.
My daddy was a fur trader.
My mama was a slaver's daughter
in New Orleans.
I used to go to New Orleans
once a year before the war.
Cotton farmer?
No, failed tobacco.
I used to stay
at the St. Charles Hotel
right there on the avenue.
Well.
Huh.
I went through there
once myself.
Had me a sazerac.
Hey, how 'bout you lower
that rifle?
You know, your surveyor Haden,
he ain't half-bad
for a mud chicken.
And the Kiowa got spruce.
But now, Chief Red Bear,
he ain't an easy man
to bargain with.
I need you to translate for me.
Pay is in gold eagles.
Hmm.
The last man that paid me
in coin
gave me pesos back in Santa Fe.
The Kiowa scalped him,
and they rolled his people
back to Chihuahua.
You can keep your gold eagles.
But now, I can't leave
my Squaws here empty-handed.
Well, what would appease?
Well, I reckon
that they would be happy
with your mule here
and the contents of its pack.
Red Bear ain't got no use
for no white man groceries.
[Clicks tongue]
Come on.
[Mule brays]
All right, then.
What?
He--he ain't right
in the head.
- We need him.
- What you need me for?
You got someplace else
you'd rather be?
Mm-hmm, I could think of
a few place.
[Women shouting indistinctly]
Let's ride.
I got business with Red Bear.
[Shouting continues]
Go, go.
He gonna get us killed.
Well, that's why you're here.
So he don't.
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Yeah, I got me a you
and an old Squaw.
And the young Squaw is lazy.
But the problem is
is that the old Squaw
used to be the young Squaw,
and she's lazy too.
And now, all they do is fight
about who's doing what.
And neither one of them
is doing anything but fightin'.
And that's why I sleep
on the roof.
Oh, now, I might go down there
if I want a little
jackrabbit stew or--
or if I feel
my sap a-rising.
How about you back there?
You got you
a woman there, sourpuss?
And a baby girl.
Then what the hell are you
doing out here for?
Putting food in they mouth,
roof over they head.
Mm.
You know what the Kiowa do
to strangers?
They like to set fires.
Fires to your hands,
fires to your face,
fire to your chest.
Hell, I seen a Texan one time
stark naked, tied to a post.
And they had relieved him
of his scalp,
his fingers, and his plums.
But then, they shoved hot coals
under his skin.
They watched him slow roast.
Good thing you ain't
a stranger, then.
No, no, I am not.
I'm family.
Red Bear is
my father-in-law.
[Steam whistle blows]
[Wheels screech]
Put the big bells on the
bottom of that fork, will ya?
[Steam whistle blows]
Big ones over there.
For Christ's sake,
McGinnes, I didn't die.
You were locked up
in the clink last I heard.
I wintered on Hudson.
Surely, no one will
begrudge a man his past
in this citadel
of freethinkers.
Mr. Durant.
What brings you
to Hell on Wheels?
[Wheels screech]
Engine fire?
A spark ignited the hay car
and the blaze spread.
We lost an entire shipment
of ties.
Kinda interesting,
you showing up here,
what with Mr. Bohannon
gone and all.
Relax, Mickey.
I am just a stockholder
checking in on his investment.
[Bell ringing]
"Hotel."
[Rings bell forcefully]
The New York Tribune.
Hmm.
Madam, I once had
the displeasure
of meeting its editor,
Horace Greeley.
Utopian, whig, vegetarian.
I hear he has Karl Marx
writing for him now.
Have you read Das Kapital?
[Scoffs]
The ignorant ravings
of an overeducated gasbag.
I would like a room,
your largest suite.
The suite's taken.
- By whom?
- Her.
Miss Ellison.
Miss Louise Ellison
of the New York Tribune.
Uh...
[Clears throat]
Thomas C. Durant
of Credit Mobilier.
I know who you are,
Mr. Durant.
Oh, perhaps, um, I could
compose a statement for you.
I'd be happy to read it.
You can usually find me here
when I'm not at the end
of the hall...
in the suite.
[Knock at door]
- The man of the house is out.
- The man of the house is dead.
I just wanna see the child.
You have my word.
No harm'll come
to either of you.
All right.
You can see her.
- But then you gotta leave.
- Just say the word.
Hey.
[Baby fussing]
Oh, come here now.
[Laughs]
Isn't she gorgeous?
Spit of her father.
Puts me in mind of my son.
You have a son?
Patrick.
He and his mother were taken
by the influenza.
I know a little about
what you've been through.
Hey.
Elam wouldn't want you
here long.
[Baby fussing]
Elam's a decent fella, Eva,
a testament to his race.
But that child
doesn't belong to him.
She deserves better.
As do you.
You don't know what I deserve.
I know your past.
And I don't judge it.
[Baby crying fitfully]
Everyone deserves
a fresh start.
Come away with me to New York.
We'll get married.
This wee one will be raised
a clean catholic
instead of some black bastard's
bastard child.
I asked you to leave.
[Sighs]
Your heart knows what's right.
I can wait.
[Baby fussing]
[Indistinct shouting]
Don't touch them pistols
or draw a breath
unless you want an arrow
through your throat.
Tell 'em we came to trade.
[Speaking Kiowa]
[All whooping]
Oh!
This is Red Bear.
He wants your horse.
I need my horse.
Well, the trouble is
I owe him a horse.
Well, give him your horse.
He likes yours better.
This buckskin that he wears,
it holds the ashes
of his eldest son
who was killed by the cavalry.
You tell him I lost a son
to the Bluecoats too.
Tell him.
[Speaking Kiowa]
He can have the horse.
What about the trees?
[Both speaking Kiowa]
[Pistol clicks]
[Speaking Kiowa]
Well, he says you can take
the one-leggeds,
but only if you can beat
his son and braves
at a game of stickball.
Stickball?
Red Bear learned it off
of some Choctaw.
He's made it an initiation rite
for his fiercest braves.
Look, Jimmy looking out
for Jimmy.
We don't know
what he telling them,
getting us into.
Railroad needs them trees.
I gotta play.
You do what you want.
It ain't what I want.
But I'll do it.
Tell him we'll play
for the trees.
Uh...
[Speaking Kiowa]
[All ululating]
[Grunts]
Papa says I'm the best
at finding nests.
Ah.
I have a sharp eye, he says,
as good as any eagle's.
Don't fall and crack your head,
for an eagle is a noble bird,
an excellent predator
and one who is not above
eating carrion when he must.
Papa's very wise.
That's why we're moving
to Fort Smith.
- I can't reach it.
- [Groans]
All right,
closer to the edge we go.
[Chuckles]
And what is the wisdom of moving
to Fort Smith?
We were called there
by Brigham Young.
Their bishop was killed
when one of the gentiles
tried to steal
his youngest wife.
And now, they are a flock
without a shepherd.
Huh, will your father be
that shepherd?
Papa's gonna be a bishop.
A bishop?
He'll be the most powerful man
in all of Fort Smith.
Hmm.
[Sighs]
I got the eggs.
Ha!
- Should we go back?
- Nah.
Let us find another nest,
huh, eagle eye?
You can tell me
more about your Papa, hmm?
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
Oh.
Here come your opponents.
[Snorts]
Their mamas know
they're out here?
That scarred-up one
is Red Bear's son.
They have raided and killed
red and white alike.
It'd be a mistake
to underestimate him.
[Speaking Kiowa]
He's gonna give you
another player
to even the odds.
He's a captive
from another tribe.
[Speaking Kiowa]
This is little raven.
He's gonna play with you.
He's a good warrior.
[Speaking Kiowa]
Get out there.
Go on out there.
[Drumming continues]
Let's go.
Come on.
[Whooping]
[Grunts]
[Groans]
[Whooping]
What tribe did you say
he was from?
Arapaho, his was the village
where your Bluecoats
took them heads.
- [Groans]
- [Whoops]
[Whooping]
[Tense orchestration]
♪ ♪
- He's dead.
- I reckon game over.
No, you can't leave.
The game just started.
Yeah, well, it just ended.
If you walk off that field,
they will kill you.
Lose or quit, you die.
Told you before.
Didn't I?
Come on now.
Jimmy fixed this up
to settle his gambling debts.
He probably betting
against us too.
All we got to do is outlast
these braves.
I'll deal with Mr. Two Squaws
when all this is said and done.
[Whooping]
[Groans]
[Sighs]
Whoo, hee!
[Groans]
All they tryin' to do
is kill us.
You think so?
We got to kill them here
with these here sticks.
Be ye live or be ye dead,
I'll grind your bones
to make my bread.
Fee, fum, foe, foy.
I smell the blood
of a Mormon boy!
I'm gonna get you!
I'm gonna get you.
[Laughs]
[Sighs]
That's Papa's hat.
So it is.
- You like it?
- Yeah.
Big boy.
My turn to hide.
I'm sorry, Sara.
I have a new girl
who needs the cot.
Good luck to you both.
Sara, why aren't you in bed?
Mickey's kicking me out.
Fellas, come on.
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
Mattress, sheets, the lot,
burn it.
Mickey.
- Why are you throwing her out?
- I told you.
I can't have her dying here.
I gave her train fare to Omaha.
She can see a doctor.
No, a doctor ain't gonna do
nothin' for her.
- Take everything, boys.
- She's gonna die bad, Mickey.
I know.
Thank God
for Mr. Toole, aye?
- Mr. Toole?
- Mm.
If he hadn't married you,
it might be you
on your way to Omaha
for some sick bed.
You think I don't know that?
You might wanna keep it
in mind.
I know Declan's called on ya.
[Baby fussing]
Sara.
In Omaha,
there's a lady doctor,
Dr. Borthwick.
He took care of me.
He'll take care of you too.
Thank you, Eva.
Good luck.
Eva.
A drop of water in the desert.
You're looking well,
Mr. Durant.
Freedom agrees with me.
No doubt you heard
about my troubles.
Well, you're here now.
Oh, uh, I had the baby.
So I see.
A Madonna and child
for the new world.
I've just been reading
about you.
- Sorry?
- Hmm.
Is that--
is that supposed to be me?
Well, the sketch is
not very good.
But the--the article's
not bad.
Take it home.
Eva, what is it?
Mr. Toole's brother is
in Hell on Wheels
and he wants this child.
And sometimes...
I'm not a very good woman,
Mr. Durant.
That is rubbish.
I will never forget you
holding my hand
as I lay bleeding out
on my desk,
through pain, laudanum,
every accompanying indignity.
You are an exceptional woman
who is in a vexing situation.
What should I do?
I have something for you.
A baby gift.
What?
A piece of paper?
Stock in Credit Mobilier.
Now, it is worth more
on some days than others
so don't cash it until you have
exhausted all options.
- Thank you.
- Hmm.
[Whooping]
[Groans]
[Grunts]
[Whooping]
[Ululates]
[Singing in native language]
That's his death song.
Send him to the spirit world
with honors.
[Groans and sighs]
I won't kill a kid over...
some damn game.
Tell him.
[Speaking Kiowa]
[Tense orchestration]
♪ ♪
[Sighs]
[Speaking Kiowa]
What's he saying?
You have shamed the chief,
his son, and his people.
Oh, yeah?
What's that?
Fire.
[Groans]
[Crows chirping]
What we gonna do now?
[Sighs]
I don't know.
- Where's Jimmy?
- I don't know.
I told you not to trust him.
What you want me to say, Elam?
Damn it, I threw in with you.
I gave you every damn chance
to back out, didn't I?
You should've killed
that Indian.
Didn't seem right somehow.
After all them men you killed?
Well, this is how we gonna die?
'Cause you picked today
to stop killin'?
[Sighs]
How long before Bohannon
gets back?
I'm not sure, sir.
He's ridden out
to Indian territory
to get timber.
Huh.
So...
that's his solution
to the tie shortage?
Take wood from the savages.
Uh, it would seem so.
Yes.
Tell me about
his latest transgressions.
Well, he hasn't really
done anything wrong.
Really?
That is a matter of perspective,
Mr. McGinnes.
But this is Bohannon
we're talking about.
Surely he's killed somebody.
Oh, he did hang a Mormon youth.
Really?
[Chuckles]
Well, tell me more
about his hanging a child.
I'm pleased you're taking
an interest
in the word, Anderson.
[Sighs]
Something happened while I was
resting in the wagon.
I had a dream that I was--
I was awake.
You had a vision.
I was surrounded by love
and people who I felt
was my family,
but I had never met them.
You saw the celestial kingdom.
Perhaps heavenly father
has blessed me
with a-a testimony
for Joseph Smith.
I knew it was his will
that we found you.
We must teach you
the gospel principles.
[Laughs]
Once you commit to keeping
the commandments...
I'll be honored to baptize you.
The honor will be mine, friend.
[Chuckles]
The honor will be mine.
Would--would've like to seen
the Pacific Ocean.
Eva and me never got
to get married.
Elam...
I'm sorry.
[Tense orchestration]
♪ ♪
God...
[Inaudible]
[Groans]
[Horse neighs]
Red Bear says that you can take
all the timber that you need.
Who I gotta kill now?
Oh, now, it ain't like that.
You can have your horse back.
I don't understand.
Well, they say that
three balances out the home.
Maybe them other two'll
quit fightin'.
You sayin' we can ride up
outta here?
- Yep.
- What about Red Bear's shame?
Oh, Red Bear is happy.
He just want to see
his children happy,
e-especially Buffalo Face here.
- Is that his daughter?
- Yeah.
He's been trying to get her
married off
for a long time now.
Married?
Well, I said I'd do it
if he'd let you boys go.
[Sighs]
Well, thank you.
- Congratulations.
- Eh, thank you.
- [Sighs]
- Oh.
I-I suppose
they're gonna have
to call me
"Jimmy Three Squaws" now.
I suppose so.
Jesus.
I don't know what you're doing
with Durant, brother.
And I don't wanna know.
Then why are you lurking
about in the rain then?
I just wanna warn you
that, whatever it is,
you're on your own.
Don't come running to me
when this turns into trouble.
I'm through pulling you out
the fire.
You're a long way from Boston.
[Scoffs]
A long way.
[Upbeat folk music]
♪ ♪
I heard you were out
brokering with hostiles.
If you've come for my funeral,
you come too soon.
You got your lumber?
Yep.
Was it worth the trouble?
Wasn't no trouble at all.
[Chuckles]
Yes, indeed.
Miss Ellison.
Eh, care to join me
for breakfast?
Are you ready to give me
that statement?
Well, first,
I would like to refute
this article you've written
about my successor.
Coffee?
Just because you don't like
what you read,
Mr. Durant,
doesn't mean it isn't true.
[Sighs]
[Laughs]
Cullen Bohannon
is not the man of integrity
you have painted him as.
- No?
- No.
What do you know about him
that I don't?
Well, he's a murderer
for one thing.
[Dry chuckle]
He killed at least five men
in a revenge-fueled fever.
Thank you.
Those are serious allegations.
"Captain Daniel Johnson,
Private Prescott..."
Uh, you might want to write
these down.
[Clears throat]
Prescott?
Johnson?
"Lieutenants Wustner
and Tanner,
"and a Sergeant Frank Harper,
all members of
the 13th Ohio Infantry."
Ah, look into it.
- I will.
- Who knows?
Maybe Greeley will even bring
you in from the wilderness.
Hm?
[Chuckles]
That sounds like a fable.
More like a joke.
There I was, tied up,
burning alive,
all for a bunch
of railroad ties.
[Sighs]
Prayed to God.
He didn't answer me.
This crazy feller, he--
he upped and saved me
by marrying a bearded Squaw.
[Giggles]
Think that's funny?
[Laughs]
Yeah.
And how do you know
it wasn't God who saved you?
'Cause it was Jimmy Two Squaws
and Buffalo Face.
God can have a sense of humor
too, Mr. Bohannon.
Well, it is one hell
of a big one, then.
Crew'll be around in an hour
to take down
that steeple, all right?
[Laughs]
[Door opens]
What you doin', woman?
We need to pack up and go.
Bohannon's moving the camp.
Will you read this to me?
"Amidst the dirt and debauchery
"of the sin-laden railroad camp
known as Hell on Wheels,
"a woman of exceptional strength
and beauty
has built herself
a second chance."
- You sellin' me a dog.
- No.
- It truly say that?
- Truly, it does.
"Eva Toole, formerly Eva Oates,
"endured a rough childhood
on the Texas frontier
"'fore her family fell victim
"to a vicious Indian attack
in 1853.
"Eva's subsistence life
of servitude
"ended seven years later
when she was spotted
"by a soldier at Fort Yuma.
"But her return to civilization
did not mark the end
of her hardships."
Yeah?
Well, go on.
I wanna hear what folks
in New York
are readin' about me.
"Eva found herself
in the Nebraska territory,
a cut-rate
railroad dove."
- Yeah, that means "whore."
- I know what it means.
"But calamity has not dimmed
this remarkable
woman's spirit."
- Oh, she crazy.
- That part true.
The strength
and beauty part too.
"Eva's back in Hell on Wheels,
"where she offers care
and comfort to the prostitutes
"she once suffered alongside,
"and to the--
the freeman lover
with whom she's set up house."
[Lightning crashes]
"Freeman lover"?
That's what I am to you?
No, of course not.
You're my man.
That's not...
Anybody been here
while I was gone?
- I just let him in...
- You let him in?
For a minute,
and then I-I told him to leave.
That's why you care so much
about what folks
- think of you in New York?
- No.
'Cause you wanna run away
with him?
- I don't wanna run away--
- You've been thinkin' of it.
You actin' different
ever since he showed up--
No, I ain't, Elam.
Elam!
Elam, wait!
I wanna show you
something, Elam.
Elam.
I don't wanna run away
with him.
I wanna run away with you.
But I can't stay here.
Now, look.
Durant gave me this.
And he said this is
our ticket outta here.
I can't stay here, Elam.
Eva, look at us.
Where we gonna go?
I can't sleep at night
because my heart's thumping
so hard.
You scared of what?
I'm scared that something bad
is gonna happen
if we stay here.
I told you I'd protect you
and our little girl--
No, that's not it.
I'm--I can't stop thinking
about Toole
and what he done.
And sometimes, I get scared
that I'm gonna hurt the baby.
No, you ain't gonna do that.
- You ain't gonna hurt--
- But what if I do?
You ain't gonna hurt our baby.
You're not gonna hurt our baby.
That's not you, Eva.
That's not you.
What I read in there,
that's you.
That's who you are.
At least it was before this--
Yeah, before the baby came.
Not no more.
Mr. Bohannon,
I need to speak with you.
A source has given me
some information
about your past.
That source be Thomas Durant?
What does the 13th Ohio
Infantry mean to you?
You want a railroad story?
I just made a deal
with the Kiowa
to harvest spruce
off their land.
Now this is gonna be
the first time
we're making our own ties.
That's unprecedented.
Is it true
you killed five men
in cold blood?
That's not a railroad story.
I got a town to move.
It is a railroad story,
Mr. Bohannon.
Is it true?
Did you do it?
[Screams]
Where is she?
Where's my baby?
Where'd she go?
- Have you seen my baby?
- Where is it?
My baby's been taken!
[Indistinct clamor]
- Elam!
- My baby.
She was right there.
We'll find her!
- Ow!
- Where is she?
Elam.
[Tense folk music]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com