It is good to make
this sacrifice
where the sun can
look down and see you.
It is a great privilege
to dance with the sun.
The sacrifice will be hard,
but you are strong... and brave.
You will not give up,
as I did not give up
when my father brought
me to this place.
Ah.
Follow the sun...
All day and pray.
If you are strong and true,
your sacrifice will be rewarded
and you will have a vision.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Ahem.
Ma'am.
It's not your manners, Mr. Bohannon.
It's your manner.
Beg your pardon?
Yesterday...
When everyone was running
from the disaster...
You walked calmly in.
You are their hero, Mr. Bohannon.
Lily!
I just heard from your father.
Everything is arranged.
I'm assuming you're here to see me?
Yes, sir, um...
Payroll didn't come in
on the train this morning.
Mr. Bohannon, one
of the reasons I spared
your neck was because
I thought you were a capable man.
Was I mistaken?
No, sir, but the men
are already grumbling
about not getting their
pay last week, sir.
Well, see the Swede about petty cash.
Mr. Durant, uh, that
won't cover the men's pay.
Of course not, you idiot.
It's for the walking bosses,
but keep quiet about it.
We don't want a riot on our hands.
Just keep the men in line
until you get your money
troubles sorted out.
My problems are no concern of yours,
Mr. Bohannon.
Actually, today Mr. Durant,
your troubles are mine.
But y'all go have yourselves
a nice picnic, all right?
Reverend... I can find someone
else to help with this.
Just a moment to catch my breath.
Whoo-yah! Yah!
Get the hell out of the way.
We need to ride out and speak
to many horses immediately.
My father's people won't
feel threatened by 4 men.
Well, these men are the
eyes of the Union Army,
the tip of the spear.
Let's go.
Business has been slow, Mr. Swede.
We will pay ya though.
Yeah.
We just need a little more time.
Well, thank you, gentlemen.
Thank you for telling me that you
are unable to pay what is owed.
I shall give you
a little more time, hmm?
See, I told you Mr. Swede
was a reasonable man.
Heh.
Yeah.
Don't say that.
He just took one of our slides.
Are you sure we can find them?
Yes.
But they're not going
to be happy to see us.
Why is that?
These rituals... they're not
meant for white man's eyes.
Father?
It's Ruth...
Your daughter.
What are you doing here?
Mother died.
I came to find you.
Well, we'll send you to
the mission in council bluffs.
They'll take care of you.
The mission sent me here.
They said...
Yea, you're not staying here.
I have nowhere else to go.
She can stay in the church tent.
At least till we get back.
I'll decide where
you go when we return.
In the meantime,
there's a bed in the back.
Thank you, father.
How long has it been
since you've seen her?
12, 15 years.
I don't exactly recollect.
And you're just going
to leave her here...
In a place like this?
You're right.
There are some things
I need to tell you.
There's... bacon in the bear box...
And... and... and coffee and flour.
Don't let the, uh,
the drunks stumble in and...
And sleep on the pews.
There's a butcher knife under...
Under that altar if you need it.
And just... you know,
try to make yourself useful.
Don't leave the tent...
You know, unless, uh...
It's on fire.
Understood?
Either the roof or...
Mum's hair was set ablaze...
By the Harrigan brothers?
Those bastards.
Did they say they were
able to put the fire out?
Uh...
What the hell is this strange wind?
The bloody last page is missing.
Oh, Jesus!
It's a whirlwind!
Where did you...
No. No, no, no!
Bloody hell.
What are you...
We thought you said you were
going to give us more time.
You asked for a little more time,
and that's what I gave
you. A little more time.
Put your backs
into it there, boys!
Come on! Work, you mules.
Hey, up!
I want all the walking
bosses right here, right now.
Thomas, Toole...
Y'all are getting paid
to work the men
until the payroll
situation gets figured out.
Again?
If they aren't paid,
they'll strike, Mr. Bohannon.
Then you keep quiet
as long as you can.
Hey, now, walking bosses only.
I am a walking boss.
Tell 'em you made me a walking boss.
Get back to work.
This about all you walking
bosses getting paid again
and we ain't gettin'
paid again, right?
Tell you what... you keep
your mouth shut and you keep your job.
Now, get back to work.
Come on!
Someone needs to put
that boy in his place.
2,000 miles due west
lies the Pacific ocean,
and yet I remain stranded here,
blocked by the great rocky mountains.
The rocky mountains...
They are some 500 miles from here.
Beyond that rise,
the Platte River forks.
Do I follow it to the North or South?
A mistake here and
we could miss our strike
on the Rockies by hundreds of miles.
I'm assuming you strike
the mountains at any route you take.
The problem is not striking
the mountains, Lily.
The problem is crossing
the mountains.
And you think Robert was
the only person who knew the way?
It took him 7 years
and my open purse...
But yes, he told me he'd found it.
Surely there'll be other surveys?
Oh, yes. Ha ha.
Yes, someone will
build this railroad,
but... without the secret,
which Robert took to his grave,
it will not be me.
If I'm remembered, it will
be as the man who failed.
Unfortunately, Robert will
probably not be remembered at all.
At pay up, I'm gonna buy
me a double hot soak.
And liniment.
And a bottle of whiskey
that don't burn going down.
Ha ha.
We ain't gettin' paid.
Well, they ain't paid us last week.
I was figurin' on double pay today.
You might as well put
that tool down and go back to camp.
That's what I'm gonna do.
Hey!
It ain't quittin' time.
It is for me.
I done worked for free my whole life,
I ain't doin' that no more.
You get back in that cut.
Get down off that horse
and put me in the cut.
I don't need some slave
uprising on my hands this day.
That's how you see it?
All I see is some field hand
acting like a house boy.
Take off that gun.
Take it off.
Give it to him now, boy!
Mr. Bohannon!
I hired you to run these
men to build my railroad,
not to wrestle in the dirt
with your former chattel.
What is the meaning of this?
Payroll!
Lack of.
And who told the men
there is no payroll?
I did.
Well, you told them nonsense.
Gentlemen, I see
that unfounded rumors
have caused tempers to flare.
Believe me, the payroll is en route,
merely delayed.
And as for you and
your sparring partner,
Mr. Bohannon,
I suggest you settle your differences
like the gentlemen
I know you all to be.
This evening,
when you have completed your work,
I suggest a pugilistic match
between Mr. Bohannon
and his negro Nemesis!
A real fight.
Yeah!
And to compensate
you for the tardiness
of your well-earned pay,
I will donate 10 cases of
whiskey for your refreshment.
I didn't know you had a daughter.
Well, now you know.
Why don't you ever speak of her?
Are you really going
to send her away?
You know, Jesus says,
"if any man come to me
"and not hate his father
and hate not his mother
"and his wife and his children
and his own life,
then he cannot be my disciple."
I don't think I have enough hate
in my heart to be a good Christian.
Whoa. Whoa.
Black moon.
Father.
Why have you brought this
man to our sacred place?
He's putting a curse on you.
He calls you black spider
because you trapped
my son in your web.
Joseph came to Christ
on his own free will.
Is that so?
Tell me, do you have
no children of your own?
I had... I have a daughter.
Who just returned to him.
Praise God.
Where has she been?
I left her.
You abandoned your
child and steal mine.
What kind of man are you?
A flawed one.
Father, reverend Cole has come...
Because he's concerned
for our people.
Chief, the soldiers
have already come.
Yeah.
4 soldiers on horseback.
But more will come,
enough to wipe out all the
human beings from the world.
But there may be another way.
If you come to town,
we discuss peace.
I will come, but only if
my son black moon asks me to come.
Please come...
For me.
Come inside, gentlemen,
and witness the greatest contest
in the history of hell on wheels!
The finest corn liquor compliments
of Mr. Thomas Durant, president
of the Union Pacific Railroad.
Hey, over here.
Give me one of those.
You must be able to spell
your name to wager, you morons.
Now, who just flung down that silver?
This here's enough peppers
to make a Mexican cry.
It'll probably kill you.
Sean's putting everything
we got in you.
I thought you were broke?
We put the magic lantern
up for collateral.
- Sure that was a good idea?
- Sure.
The whole town's betting on you.
There's time enough if you want
to place a bet on yourself.
Nah.
I ain't doin' this for money, Mick.
Then why are you doing it?
Hmm. That man needs
to be put in his place.
There's only one thing
he understands.
What if, God forbid...
You were to lose?
That ain't gonna happen.
You win this fight,
they're gonna kill you,
and if you lose,
they're gonna kill you
for thinkin' you could win.
You don't understand.
This is somethin' I gotta do.
Why?
Because you're half white...
Or because you're half black?
All my life folk
been tellin' me who I am.
One white man tell me I'm a slave,
another one say I'm free.
Tonight I say who I am.
Hello.
Tonight and one night only,
you will be allowed in.
But one sign of misbehavior...
And I will throw you all in chains.
Understood?
Good.
You are welcome. Come in.
Yeah. That's it.
Your corner here.
Mr. Ferguson's corner.
Bloody hell.
Look at what the bowels of
the place have s out.
Get the bloody hell out.
What do you think you're doing?
Make way for Mr. Bohannon.
You gonna win this fight, ya hear?
You gonna win this fight for us.
You hear me?!
Jesus, he is a big buck,
Mr. Bohannon.
It ain't all about the brawn, Mick.
Now, this fight is going
to be a fair fight.
No grappling below the waist.
No eyeball gouging.
No biting.
No unnecessary kicking.
Now, the fighters will come from
their corners and toe this line.
Mr. Dix is going to be the referee...
For this contest.
Now, I assume both fighters
are ready to fight.
Toes on!
Yeah!
Fight!
Push them back, will ya?
All right, boys,
back to your corners.
Back to your corners.
30 seconds!
Out of the way.
Sit down.
The bank is denying the request
for a credit extension.
Reply.
If credit not extended forthwith,
will call in all shares
of aforesaid bank stock
to be joined by other
4 major investors. Stop.
Anticipate collapse of bank
by close of business tomorrow.
Stop.
And send.
Samson brought
the temple down on his head.
I will happily do the same.
Give him a fat lip, Mr. Bohannon!
He already has two, lad!
Get in there and fight, boy.
Get him!
Knock him down!
Knock his nappy n head off!
Punch his black arse back to Africa!
Get up!
On your feet.
Are you gonna start fighting or what?
Huh?
About to see this now.
All right, break it up.
Break it up.
Give us some room!
Give us some room.
Back it off!
Get him to the corner, now.
Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
What?
He ain't fighting.
What the hell's
wrong with you, boy? Huh?
Is it 'cause you ain't never
hit no white man before?
Is that it?
Look here, son...
That man who sired you,
that won't your father,
that a white man
who raped your mother.
You know?
The same man done
beat you all your life
with his foot on your neck. Huh?
The same man who say he your master...
When you supposed to be free.
Huh?
Look over here.
That's him sitting
on his soft white ass.
Huh?
I want you go over there...
And I want you to kill him.
You hear?
You go kill him.
You ain't gonna do this for us...
Do this for you.
Take a knee, Mr. Bohannon.
Take a knee!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Don't worry.
You still in this.
You sill got him, Mr. Bohannon.
You still got it. Don't worry.
Take a breather, boy.
Take a breather.
Lent to thy neighbor
in time of his need.
He paid thou thy neighbor again...
Excuse me.
You're almost there.
Mrs. Bell?
Where have you been?
I looked all over for you.
I took a walk.
And then I heard all the commotion.
Ah.
It's a little vulgar for a lady's taste,
I'm afraid.
Ah, I'm afraid my Latin was
a little undernourished.
Bread and circuses.
You engineered this fight as a
distraction until you could get payroll.
Just like the Romans
did with unruly crowds,
give them food and spectacle.
Ahh.
I think you overestimate
my abilities, Lily.
I hope not, for all our sakes.
Holy mother of God.
You had us worried there.
I thought for a wee bit
we'd lost our wager, right, Sean?
Sean?
Shall I walk you back to the car?
I have Robert's maps.
And yes... he found the route.
To the Rockies?
And beyond.
And you've had them all this time.
I have.
I knew it!
Oh, I could strangle you
and embrace you at the same time.
Where are they?
They're in a safe place.
Ah.
How much?
What Robert is owed.
All right. Let's go. Let's go.
All right.
That's right.
You gonna do this. That's right.
Time!
Now, boy.
Now!
You got it.
Come on, Bohannon!
One more time.
Get in there.
Come on!
Come on, Bohannon!
Get your hands up.
Hands up.
Come on, boy!
Come on, Bohannon.
Get in there.
It's over.
Why are you so glib?
We just lost everything.
I bet it all on the darkie.
30 to one.
We're rich, brother.
What'd you use?
The liniment, hmm?
Was it a little pepper
powder to the eyes, was it?
Are you trying to get us both killed?
And Mr. Bohannon... being
our only friend and all.
This is my only friend.
Ohh.
Are you all right?
Never better.
Good.
Did you enjoy the fight?
Very much.
Good.
Unh.
Thank you for the water.
Unh!
Ah.
Next.
Gregory Toole, walking
boss for cut crew 3.
And to be completely honest
with you, Mr. Bohannon,
we thought you had more in you.
Mmm.
Life does have its surprises,
don't it, Mr. Toole?
Next.
Elam Ferguson, walking boss...
Freedmen cut crew.
Ahem.
You have done it, my son.
The sacrifice is over.
Father... I was blessed.
I had a vision.
I've seen a great steel beast,
its breath was smoke...
It shook the ground.
I killed it.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com