Previously on AMC’s Hell on Wheels…
They found Heckard's body in Nebraska.
Yes, certain skills, Mr. Snow.
Then you're our new marshal.
[Screams]
He's arrested our key railroad men.
All on trumped up charges.
I can't build a railroad
with them men in jail.
I need a place to stay. I'm a wanted man.
I can't think about goin' back.
We're better off here.
The new marshal?
Upstairs.
[Laughs]
Damn, Bohannon. Don't you know interruptin'
a federal marshal while
he is conducting business
is against the law?
Never figured you for a lawman.
Yeah, well, job does have its advantages.
Come to see my workers released.
Your criminals, you mean.
You have 'em down at the depot by the time
the mornin' train arrives, all right?
What, and leave my lady
all by her lonesome?
I don't think so.
I think I'm comfy right here.
Damn, Bohannon. You're all twisted up.
You might could use a good poke.
Francine, why don't you
go over there and see
if you can help Colonel out?
Come on, now.
I ain't gonna tell the missus.
This here fight's between
Durant and Campbell.
Got nothin' to do with you and me.
Well, this here badge
says I work for Campbell.
Last I heard, you work for Durant,
so reckon that makes this here fight
'tween us, don't you?
You're workin' for a carpetbagger.
[Chuckles]
My loyalty runs the length
of a dollar bill these days.
Let go of my men.
Let's say I don't.
If you'd come to kill me,
I'd be dead already.
My men, at the depot, 10:00 A.M.
You done lost your nerve.
Mm.
That's for putting a
gun on my wife and boy.
Next time I won't knock.
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com
Days to build, two weeks to dig the grade.
We'll be over sherman peak in a month,
laramie by July.
It won't build itself.
Men'll build it.
All the skilled men are locked up
thanks to your friend Sidney Snow.
You let me worry about him.
[Chains jingling]
Whatever you're thinkin', Bohannon, don't.
Leave Snow to his job, us to ours.
Got a message for you
from the new marshal.
Spit it out, Dutch.
He said, "You want the men?
Come and get 'em."
You see this, Bohannon?
"Known killer hired as marshal."
I mean, what is the world comin' to?
I gave you a chance to let
go of them men easy-like.
Then I gave you a chance to let
'em out yourself.
Come on back anytime!
Good mornin'.
No, it ain't.
Dutch, get your ass back in there.
[Chains jingling]
If Mr. Bohannon should get any ideas...
- Step a hair out of line today...
- Arrest him?
Shoot him.
Well, it's about time.
Time, Mr. Durant,
is a fickle mistress.
First it appears an endless supply,
and then suddenly the
last few grains of sand
trickle down the hourglass.
For God's sake, John.
Persecuting me on trumped-up
charges is political suicide.
You have no evidence
that I had anything to do
with marshal Heckard's death.
You've no witness. No proof.
That's for the judge
in Omaha to determine.
Omaha?
All of you will be
returned to the jurisdictions
in which your alleged crimes were committed.
You will acquit yourself
there for better or worse.
I can't go back to Alabama, Mr. Campbell.
You have Mr. Durant to thank for that.
The train leaves today.
You can't be serious!
Oh, I can...
And I am.
[Steer moos]
I need your ranchers, Maggie.
Can't fight Campbell on my own.
My husband built up a small ranch out here
when there was nothin' but rollin' hills
as far as the eye could see.
- We had a house, small herd.
- Come on.
We were wantin' for nothin',
and in early September '58,
one of our hands...
A down on his luck cowpoke,
a Jack somebody...
He led a bunch of rustlers.
Tore through our herd.
Lost my husband that night.
Ranch a month later.
I had to rebuild it all, and I did...
With blood, sweat,
and whatever else it took.
Sidney Snow, he's Campbell's
brand on this town.
Fighting him is only gonna
lead to more bloodshed.
Somebody's got to take a stand.
That's exactly what my husband said
just before Jack killed him.
Campbell won't let go, Cullen.
You know that.
I'm off to the north valley.
Thought that was Mickey McGinnes's land?
Sold it to me yesterday
for 10¢ on the dollar.
Y-you said this is yesterday?
Hold on to your topknot, Mr. Bohannon.
Campbell just requisitioned a train.
He's sending the workers back East.
Bohannon...
You know what this means?
Means I got less time than I thought.
Thought you were the new marshal.
Thought you turned tail and run.
Come back with a plan, I did.
I got men coming.
Any day now.
Campbell's shippin'
Durant and the men back East.
I don't care what happens
to that Judas Durant.
He deserves what he's got coming.
The men don't.
I don't care about your
railroad, Bohannon.
I've got me own travails.
When my men arrive,
I'll take care of these Campbell
bastards meself, all right?
You're likely to find yourself
on the wrong end of a rope.
That's no business of yours.
You should take your wife
and move on from here.
My wife and child are back at Fort Smith.
It's the railroad needs movin' now.
Campbell's not just gonna
hand over these workers.
We're gonna break 'em out.
Today.
You and me?
Two men against all them?
All them amounts to one man: Sidney Snow.
It could be suicide.
Doing nothing ain't a choice, Mick.
Most of them are drunkards and shitpokes.
Half will fold if the bullets start flying
- and I'll take care of Sidney.
- [Door opens]
Wash up for lunch?
We'll need guns, and lots of 'em.
Most of 'em won't be expecting
a fight nor ready for one.
Surprise is better than bullets.
I'll take the surprise,
but I'll be having me bullets as well.
You should be ashamed of yourselves.
All this talk of guns and bullets?
We won't trouble you and Ezra much longer.
Thank you.
Appreciate the sanctuary, Ruth.
He's evil, you know.
Mickey?
That new marshal, Sidney Snow.
Lot of men lost their way after the war.
He's not lost, Mr. Bohannon.
The forces of darkness reside within him.
I looked into his eyes.
I saw a wickedness there
that is yet to be unleashed.
Be careful.
There are still people
here who care for you.
You believe in God, Bohannon?
Jesus and all that shit?
I never understood people prayin' to a guy
who let himself get crucified.
And for what?
I reckon faith ain't
easily explained to some.
See, I stand here and I look,
and I see Cullen Bohannon,
but I sure as hell don't recognize him.
The jail, the load-up,
or the first water stop.
Which it gonna be?
I know you're planning something.
- Railroad work.
- Come on, now.
Lying just outside the house of the Lord?
If you're so sure I'm lying,
why don't you arrest me?
Well, shit, I don't want
to ruin all the fun.
Ain't too late to walk away.
Yeah, it is...
For both of us.
Hmm.
Best pray on it then.
Just to be safe.
Oh, I leave the prayin' to you.
You gonna need it.
I got no feud with Campbell.
He arrested your workers!
And your boss.
Durant dug his own grave,
as I knew he would sooner or later.
Road won't get built without him.
Going to war with the Governor
is insurrection, Mr. Bohannon.
Wouldn't be my first do-si-do.
You'll wind up in prison or worse.
Yeah, danced that number likewise.
What are you lookin' for?
Lookin' for the keys to the damn armory...
And a partner.
Mr. Bohannon, I'm an engineer,
not a gunslinger.
You work for the Union
Pacific, Mr. Delaney.
That's a dream for some.
For others, it's an obsession.
My granddaddy tore hisself a cotton empire
out of swamp bottom and a sun,
and I aim to do similar
with this here railroad.
So you either give me them keys...
Or you get out of my way.
All right then.
You got a plan...
I hope.
That's great. Thank you.
You surprise me, miss Ellison.
A nice dinner and a glass of wine
don't change the truth, Mr. Campbell.
Nor would I expect them to.
I just didn't expect you to lend
any credence in your article
to my position over that of Mr. Bohannon's.
Mr. Bohannon sees the
world in black and white.
But we don't, do we?
I suspect what you and I have
in common, Mr. Campbell...
Among other things...
Is the certainty that the world
is neither black nor white
but decidedly gray.
That's what makes it both daunting and,
at times, alluring.
Not to mention surprising.
Perhaps it wouldn't be intolerable
to discuss a world,
in all its shade of gray,
over lunch at the Palmer?
That wouldn't be intolerable
at all, Mr. Campbell.
Shotgun. Balls and powder.
All of 'em.
The whole rack?
All of it.
I ain't trading on credit.
Neither am I. On the hop.
Ain't no secrets in this town, McGies.
You ought to know that by now.
Damn.
Lookee here, Bohannon.
Caught me another one.
[Grunting]
Now, I know them shotguns
wasn't just for shootin' fish.
I guess you just ain't had enough yet.
[Laughs]
You got that right.
Stop it!
He obviously knows nothing or
he would have told you by now!
Yeah, you keep squawkin',
you'll be next, huckleberry.
Now, I know Bohannon is planning
on busting these men out...
And I know that you are a part of it.
So...
Why won't he talk to me, Parker?
I don't know, Sid.
- Maybe he don't like you.
- Doesn't like me?
[Groans]
[Laughs]
[Coughs]
Go ahead, get him up.
Don't! No more!
No more.
That's enough.
He's gonna bust the men out.
Yeah, I know that.
Where?
The jail? The load-up?
The first water stop?
The load-up.
Get us out in the open. That's smart.
What else?
It's all I know.
I swear.
Lock him up.
Prep the prisoners for load-up.
We ain't leavin' for two hours.
Adapt or die, atwood.
Adapt or die.
We still need to sweep the town.
We ain't got time...
And neither does Bohannon.
[Knock at door]
You sang like a Irish canary.
I challenge any man here
to endure a beating like
that and keep his mouth shut.
Bohannon was our last
chance to get out of here.
I go back to Alabama, I'm a dead man...
But you ain't gonna make it out this...
Whoa, hey! Easy!
Leave him be!
He gonna get what comin' to him!
Not from the likes of you, he won't!
Gentlemen, please!
Fighting amongst oursel...
Quiet, fat man!
It's 'cause of you we in here.
Got to say for yourself, Irish? Huh?
Speaks for itself, don't it?
- [Gasps]
- Where is he?
You been hidin' him, ain't you?
He's not here.
Yeah, but he was here, wasn't he?
Him and that lyin' shit-ass irishman.
I've done nothing.
I have nothing for you.
Don't be playin' with fire, church lady.
All right, bring 'em out.
Bohannon?
Stay awake, gentlemen.
What are you thinking?
Considering your past...
Romantic predilections.
You have been curious about me.
Oh, I've made inquiries.
When I was younger,
I used to think it made me abnormal.
But after my time covering the war,
I realized that there were
men who were equally as...
Confused?
Curious.
What do you want, John Campbell?
From you?
From life.
One day...
When I get what I deserve...
Without a fight...
And without regret.
[Laughs]
Is that even possible?
So far... no.
Mr. Campbell.
Sidney Snow.
Mr. Governor, sir.
Come on.
Be quick.
I need you to wire julesburg for
all the deputies they can spare.
Have 'em meet me at the
water stop at kenmore.
- Bohannon?
- Yeah.
I never want to hear the
name Cullen Bohannon again.
All right, load 'em up.
[Train whistle blows]
[Laughter]
Hey!
Y'all get your minds right.
This ain't over till I say it is.
I don't like the way you're lookin' at me.
Lookin' at what?
You hear what I said?
[Grunts]
You ignorant son of a bitch.
That's gonna cost ya.
[Gasps and coughs]
No!
Free the rest of them men.
- Watch over them guards.
- Thank you, Bohannon.
Aye, lads. Here's the business.
Unlock us.
- What's the matter?
- Shit!
I told you this wasn't over.
Stop the train! Now!
We're goin' back.
All right, Bohannon.
If we return to Cheyenne
with them on our tail,
we'll be right back where we started.
Free, ain't ya?
For the moment.
Them men might fight for Campbell's cause,
but they sure as hell won't die for Sidney.
What makes you so sure?
For one thing, they're outmanned.
- And we're outgunned.
- Not anymore.
He's not going to give up without a fight.
Yeah, I won't kill Sidney...
But I will bring him in.
Now, when we get back to Cheyenne,
you make things right with Campbell.
He wants to keep his job.
He'll negotiate with you.
Your confidence is very
annoying, Bohannon.
I was just ponderin'
what you'd do if things was similar.
I'm wrong, you tell me now.
Just like old times.
I preferred the cover of the hotel...
When they were shooting at you.
[Train brakes squeal]
Sidney!
That weren't real gentleman-like, Bohannon...
Stealin' all my prisoners like that.
Never should have given me them keys, son.
Ah.
I'ma need those prisoners back.
Them prisoners is liberated, and armed.
- Can't win this one.
- Oh, yeah?
I ain't gonna parlay with you, Bohannon.
I reckon we gonna have to shoot it out.
Yeah, you could always give yourself up.
[Laughs]
Ah. Why don't you come on over
here and give yourself up?
That's what I thought.
Just gonna have to come get me, I guess.
Mm-hmm.
Delaney!
[Whistles]
Last chance, Sid. End of the line.
[Gunshots]
Whoo!
Keep 'em pinned, boys!
Delaney! Damn it, Delaney!
Do it now!
Hold your fire!
Hold! Enough!
Enough! Hold it!
Damn it, Delaney! Hold your damn fire!
Sidney!
Sidney Snow!
Where'd he go?
Where is that bastard?
Gone.
No, he ain't.
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com