Previously on AMC's Hell On Wheels...
***
Now you listen to me, you pinhead!
You play a very dangerous game here, son-o.
***
A Northern general and a Southern soldier
working together,
that's what the country needs.
***
[Piano playing melody]
♪
[Wind whistling]
[Melody continues]
♪
[Bird screeches]
[Retches]
[Gagging]
[Groans]
[Piano keys tinkle]
[Discordant piano notes]
Water.
Aagh!
[Discordant piano notes]
No, wait, come back.
Uhh!
[Groans]
Please, please.
[Western folk music]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
[Groans]
[Indistinct chatter]
Today's sick list.
They're starting to spill over
from the infirmary.
Crossed-out names
means back to work?
mean deceased.
They're thirsty,
but when we give them water...
It comes out both ends
till they're dead.
Knock the spigots
off the water tanks.
We're short on water as it is.
Knock 'em off, Dutch.
Bad water's making us sick.
Drought's driving the rats
and snakes into the tanks.
Might be cholera in camp.
[All murmuring]
What's the fix, Bohannon?
Water.
Clean and clear.
Cures cholera.
I'll find us some.
What are you
expecting us to do?
Well, get to work,
if you're well...
infirmary if you're not.
Spread the word.
Shit.
Y'all check your hands
before you head to the cut.
All right?
They're yellow like this,
you go to the infirmary.
Come on, let's go.
So work without water?
In this heat?
Or die in the infirmary?
Them's our choices?
Tanks'll be full by lunch,
Mr. Hersch.
Got my word on that.
I ain't sending
a hundred of my best men
to an infirmary.
Lost too much
for this damn railroad already.
Huh?
Can I see your hands,
Mr. Bohannon?
Plenty of water
in Omaha, Mr. Hersch,
if that be your choice.
[Chuckles]
Now, the good lord...
He was kind enough
to leave me my thumb.
[Moves chair]
And my trigger finger.
[Gun cocks]
[Grunts]
Get him a ticket to Omaha
and a half-day's pay.
Congratulations, Mr. Quinn.
You just made walking boss.
Hell we gonna find
water out here?
Nearest river's
a five-days' ride with wagons.
Workers ain't
gonna last that long.
Durant's got water in Cheyenne.
He ain't just gonna
hand it over.
I'll ask him nice.
Hyah!
You've seen the pictures
of ships lining the wharves
up and down the river Thames,
haven't you, Nathan?
Imagine--train after train,
stacked up on spur lines.
North, south, east, west
of the city.
Filling Cheyenne with trains
like ships fill
the port of London.
So you're planning
to imagine this city
into existence, then?
Well, imagine, plan, build.
That's what
we empire builders do.
We build an empire
out of nothing.
And that's exactly
what you have here--nothing.
In the middle of nowhere.
My controlling interest
in Credit Mobilier
will see this through.
You would squander
the one valuable thing
you have left
on this pathetic whistle stop?
No, it's over, Thomas.
We've lost.
The government sent word.
They're auditing
my state treasury.
I need to be back in Boston
next week,
and the coffers
need to be filled by then,
or else I'm gonna be
looking at the world
from the inside out.
Everything I have
is tied up here.
I-I couldn't possibly--
Except your controlling
interest in Credit Mobilier.
W--Nathan!
Wait, Nathan!
I brought the head
of the union pacific out here.
I brought the next president
of the United States
out here
for your great play, Thomas,
and you failed.
I made you a fortune!
And it cost me everything.
You and your promises
are nothing but hot air,
like this--
this stifling little room,
which I predict will become
your mausoleum.
That's humorous,
coming from such
a fatuous ass as yourself.
Where are the certificates?
- No.
- Hey!
You're signing them over today!
I will not!
Then I will see to it
that you are returned to jail,
and not on the Hudson,
but somewhere in my home state
where, occasionally, an old
newspaper will make its way,
and you can read
about Collis Huntington
and the glory
that could have--
no, should have been yours
when he completes the railroad.
Don't push me, Nathan.
Idle threats, Tom.
Worth about as much
as this fantasy town of yours.
- No.
Look, you're signing the--
[gunshot]
Mr. Durant?
Oh, my God.
What have you done?
What have I done?
[Indistinct chatter]
[Groans]
Durant?
Cullen Bohannon.
I'm on business.
Durant?
Bohannon!
What do you want?
Business.
Come down.
[Chair squeaks]
I come about water.
Much as you're willing
to sell me.
I built this city
in the middle of three streams.
Those streams
have turned to sand.
[Sniffles]
1 1/2 times market, in cash.
[Fly buzzing]
What spooked your horse?
This railroad
will never be built.
Leave me alone.
I'll take that water by force,
if need be.
Try!
And I will open those tanks
and flood the street
before you fire a shot.
Yeah.
Yeah, you'd do that,
wouldn't you?
I certainly would.
[Piano key pinging]
Miserable.
[Indistinct chatter]
Sean.
Uh...
hello, Michael.
Michael, is it?
How deep are you
into it this time?
Deep.
[Sighs]
[Woman coughing]
[Indistinct chatter,
men coughing]
Eva, are you feeling ill?
No.
Stay as far away from
these men as you possibly can.
[Baby coos]
This place
has beaten me down, Eva.
I can't drink the whiskey...
or the water.
Providence is urging me
to take a train home.
[Baby cooing]
I wanna go to New York
with you.
Whatever your reasons,
it's the right decision.
The baby wouldn't make it here.
How did you leave it
with Mr. Ferguson?
I'll meet you
aboard the last train.
Eva...
thank you.
[Indistinct chatter]
- [Clicks tongue]
- Hold up.
Where the hell
are you men off to, Dutch?
You promised water by lunch.
Never came.
Men dying by the dozen,
Mr. Bohannon,
and we ain't gonna join 'em.
You deserting, then?
Moving on to the Mormon fort.
They got plenty of water,
food, and wives to marry.
- Couple days' ride.
- Says who?
Mormon riders
come through yesterday.
Them's U.P. wagons
and them's U.P. horses.
Y'all get down now.
Mr. Bohannon,
we won't make it
to the fort on foot
in this heat.
You either get your ass
back in the cutter,
or you can hoof it in the heat.
It's your choice.
I ain't asking, Dutch.
[Cocks gun]
I'd rather die in the move
than stuck in hell on wheels.
[Men murmuring]
Shit.
What the hell
these Mormon riders?
I ran 'em off twice already.
We ain't gonna be able
to keep the men here
unless we get water.
Durant give you any?
We're on our own.
Look here.
According to surveyors,
this here might be a spring.
That's 10 miles out.
And it look like just
a drop of ink.
It's gotta be a spring.
Hoping it's a spring
don't make it a spring.
And how a spring 10 miles out
gonna give us water here?
We'll pump it up
with a windmill
we'll build in pieces
and then wagon train it out.
Round up all the carpenters
and millers we got,
knock it together.
[Exhales]
Where you going?
Gotta see if it's a pool
of water or a spot of ink.
You don't look so good to ride.
You drink that bad water?
Might've.
But this here is good.
You'll never find water
if that cholera gets you first.
If I'm not back
in a couple of days,
you strike camp,
tell Durant he was right.
He'll know.
[Clicks tongue]
Oh.
Whew.
[Grunts]
All right.
Here.
You smell something?
[Horse snorts]
[Bird chirping]
[Groans]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Hammering continues]
[Grunts]
[Sniffles]
Must have been two, three years
since I felt heat this strong.
Whew! Mm.
Feel like Alabama heat, hear?
Whew.
It's too hot
for all that jawing, negro.
Ah. Won't hear me
complaining, though.
Yeah, I was built for it.
Thrive in it.
Live for it, hear?
Reckon I done felt
every kind of heat there is.
Uh-huh.
Dry heat,
wet heat, windy heat,
calm heat.
Hell, I done even
felt cold heat.
What the hell is cold heat?
[Chuckles]
Know it when you feel it.
Yeah.
Yeah, I been feeling it at home
ever since the baby come.
Hmm.
Don't you know nothing?
That always happens.
Babies change things.
You get married,
it'll all trim up good again.
Get you some hot heat, huh?
[Chuckles]
Look, you settle in,
baptize that baby,
give her a name, and all
will be right with the world.
I hope you're right.
How come you never
give that baby no name?
Seem like every time
I name something,
somebody take it away from me.
Aw, man...
you're feeling down
'cause of all this
sickness, huh?
Ain't nothing
gonna happen to you, me,
Eva, or that baby.
Yeah.
Hmm.
You know what?
Cholera would be a good name
for a little girl
if it don't mean what it means.
[Both laugh]
You crazy.
I always wanted
to call her rose.
Rose, huh?
That's nice.
- Rose.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hey.
Some heat, huh?
Hey, me and Psalms
built a windmill today.
- Yeah?
- Know something?
It's gonna work.
Yeah.
That wind gonna
turn the blades,
shaft gonna pump the water,
and water
gonna spill and spill.
Hmm.
[Baby coos]
Caught this breeze
while we were trying it out.
Huh.
Sound like my little sister
skipping rope
in our pack dirt yard.
You know?
Clickety-click.
How them rope girls sound?
Aw, you know.
Tell me.
- Clickety-click.
- [Laughing]
Clickety-click.
What?
I just love you so much.
I love you too.
You love me,
no matter which way I am?
I love you
every which way you is.
No matter what?
No matter what.
[Fly buzzing]
Get his feet.
[Grunts]
You gonna help me or not?
Did you have a hand in this?
I came into the room,
and it had already happened.
Durant handed me the gun.
And you took it?
My boss handed it to me!
Durant hired me to help him,
and that's what I'm doing.
He's pinning this on you.
And who do you think
the law is going to believe?
Him or you?
Uh...
you really think
the law will come?
He's a United States senator.
From Massachusetts.
Where Boston is!
Did you ever think of that?
Help me. You'll help me.
Help me.
I'm done cleaning up
your messes!
I'm done
cleaning up your messes.
I'm not cleaning up
anyone else's.
Mick, please don't
turn your back on me now.
[Sighs]
I understand you're in need
of a good magician.
Someone who can make
all your problems...
[Blows]
disappear.
[Exhales]
I know how you feel right now.
You just killed a man.
And you don't know what to do.
Your legs barely hold you up.
You can't eat.
You're not able to sleep and...
the whiskey...
[Chuckles]
the whiskey seems to have
no effect at all.
Bugger off, Sean.
Go upstairs.
Start straightening up
Mr. Durant's room.
Now, you're not gonna run.
You're not gonna call
any attention to yourself.
You're gonna do exactly
as I say, do you hear me?
Do I hear you?
[Chuckling]
But you're--
you're a saloon keeper, a--
a pimp, uh...
you run a bordello,
for God's sakes.
[Laughs]
Why would I listen to you?
[Laughing]
Ah, he was my...
he was my friend.
As for right now,
that's my job.
It's gonna be some job indeed.
But it'll all be all right.
Sure, it's America.
You're probably not
the first person
to squeeze a bit of lead
into a U.S. senator.
Oh.
[Chuckles]
No matter.
The magic...
the magic'll save you
this time.
[Vomits]
[Coughing]
[Groaning]
[Retches]
[Insects buzzing]
[Grunting]
[Groans]
[Piano playing]
♪
[Rock clatters]
[Grunting]
[Gagging]
[Groaning]
Mm.
[Grunting]
Oh, whoa.
It's okay.
[Grunts]
See?
[Grunting]
Where'd you get this?
Hup.
Whoa.
[Insects buzzing]
Got one more for the fire.
[Grunting]
Grab his legs.
[Both grunting]
Thank you...Mickey.
I never...
want to see you again...
in my life, Sean.
Ever.
[Fire crackling]
[Sighs]
[Dog barks in distance]
[Baby coos]
[Baby cooing]
[Singing in Mojave]
♪
[Singing continues]
[Slurping]
[Bird screeching]
Joseph Dutson?
Bishop Dutson...Please.
Forgive me, bishop.
We expected you weeks ago.
The elders sent us
to see you and your family
safely back to camp.
Heathens.
They attacked my family.
Took my wife.
My boy.
There was...
so much blood.
I tried to save them, but...
my boy.
He was only just eight.
How horrible.
Let's get you to camp,
shall we?
Mm.
Look.
Found it!
[Groaning]
[Hammering]
[Indistinct chatter]
[Clatter]
[Wheel squeaks]
Come on now.
See if we can get it spinning.
[Hammering, indistinct chatter]
[Wheel squeaks]
Let it go.
Hey, cut that out.
Cut that out.
[Indistinct chatter]
Yeah.
There we go.
[Indistinct chatter]
Yeah.
Pumping now.
It's pumping.
- Come on.
- Sure is.
Come on.
Yeah.
It's pumping.
Come on.
Come on now.
Coming in directly.
Yeah.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
It's still pretty dirty.
There it go.
[Water splashing]
- Not yet.
- Mud.
- Yeah. It's--it's going.
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
- Fresh water.
Come on, fresh water.
Fresh water, fresh water.
Come on.
Fresh water.
[All cheering]
Thank you, lord.
[Chatter and cheering]
Hey, get out of there!
Back up, back up.
- Give that to him.
- Yeah.
Some fresh water here
for you, Mr. Bohannon.
[Gasps]
[Coughs]
Ahh! Ah!
Fill them tanks!
[Grunts]
Ah.
Fill 'em up.
[Indistinct chatter]
Hell are we supposed
to do with a boy
in a place like this?
I was hoping you would know.
[Coughs, grunts]
You all right?
[Groans]
Oh, hey, it's all right.
You're all right.
Is that all your stuff?
Yeah.
Never was much
for words neither.
All right.
You know what
we call this out here?
Railroad Bible.
You like it?
Yeah.
Men say that luck's
the only God left out here.
I reckon
you were my luck today.
What, you wanna play?
I'm pretty good at this, now.
Oh.
You sure you're up for this?
Ohh.
Yeah, you're tough.
All right,
best two out of three.
Ohh.
You're killing me.
[Train whistle blows]
[Indistinct chatter]
You're gonna love the city.
[Baby cooing]
[Baby fusses]
[Train whistle blows]
[Bell clanging]
You take good care of her
now, Mr. Toole.
You hear me?
[Baby crying]
You're not coming?
Hey...
Eva...
Good-bye.
I don't even know her name.
Rose.
Her name is Rose.
All aboard!
[Train conductor shouts
in distance]
Eastbound.
First stop, Omaha.
All points east, all aboard.
[Engine chugging]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com