Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
I asked you here today to acknowledge
the exceptional work you've done.
We could not have
come this far without you.
Now tonight
at the 40 mile Celebration,
we shall have the pleasure
of entertaining senators,
investors and sundry
other dignitaries.
And since we are in such short supply
of, uh, ladies of repute,
you will all be invited to the dance.
Oh!
All right.
But you will have to make
yourselves presentable
and behave like the proper
ladies I know you can...
Pretend to be,
but I warn you, pick pockets,
Blushingtons, bug hunters
will be severely dealt with.
Now, go clean yourselves up.
Boys.
How we doing?
Getting ready for the dance.
Oh.
Listen. Y'all been tailing
Swede like I told you?
We have. But to no avail.
He's a slippery bastard, that one.
He rode out of town last night.
You know where he went?
No.
Uh... well, he bought
two bottles of whisky
at the starlight before he left.
Must be going on a bender.
Swede don't drink.
Then I guess he's
meeting someone who does.
I wasn't there that night.
Check the date on my discharge.
I was wounded at Starkville
two weeks before Meridian.
Then how could you know
what happened that night?
I stayed in touch with Johnson
and the boys after the war.
They told me all about it.
And you can still testify
as to why Bohannan had motive
to kill Johnson and this other man?
You think I'm crazy?
He already tried to kill me once.
I'll finish the job
if I go back there.
This man, he's not going to give up.
You can keep running,
but... one day
he just going to show
up on your doorstep
and kill you dead.
Now.
Let's finish this thing, huh?
Hmm?
Now.
Hey.
That whisky goes to Dan's town.
Yes, sir.
Not in your town.
I'm going to check 'em later,
make sure they ain't light
one or two bottles.
Damn it all!
Right.
You having trouble
with your floorboards, ma'am?
Well, you're very
perceptive, aren't you?
I'm afraid I'm not
much of a carpenter.
No, ma'am, you ain't.
Could you possibly help me?
That is, if you're not
busy killing anyone.
Well, sure as heck
can't do any worse.
Great.
You're quite handy
with a hammer and nail.
Were you really
a farmer before the war?
Is that so hard to believe?
Yes, actually.
I find it hard to imagine
you in a domestic setting.
I couldn't, either.
I always had one eye on the door.
So you were married.
Was.
Had a son, too.
War come along and...
Jumped at the chance.
Mary didn't want me to go, but, ahh.
She didn't stand in my way, either.
Now I'd give anything
to be home and just...
So you lost them both?
Your wife and your son.
I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
That about does it here.
Wait. Please, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to upset you.
Please, don't...
Whatever happened
to your wife and son,
please don't let it
kill the man they loved.
Sorry, Mrs. Bell.
It's too late for that.
Mr. Grant.
I thought you'd be
well on your way by now.
Decided to stay.
Is that wise?
I ain't never been accused
of being wise, sir.
So we'll see you
at the dance tonight?
You will if I'm there.
Special ordered from New York.
Oh, Thomas.
I cannot accept this.
Oh, it's not a gift.
Think of it as payment.
For what?
I've invited many potential investors
to the celebration this evening.
What does that have to do with me?
It's become clear to me
that this railroad
could do with a face
other than my own
associated with it.
You're thinking of
the fair-haired maiden of the west.
Yes.
You think she'll lure the investors.
Like moths to a flame, my dear.
I'll consider it.
On one condition.
Why is nothing ever
elemental with you?
I want to be a part of it.
Part of what?
The building of this road.
I want to see it through to the end.
Do we have a deal?
Your condition is accepted, madame.
Sorry.
Uh... ahem.
I don't... I don't mean to
disturb your prayers, preach.
How can I help you, son?
Well...
I'm on a dark path, sir.
Been on it for a while now.
Where does the dark path lead?
More blood.
More hatred.
I met somebody who reached out to me
and asked me to turn
away from the darkness.
Been wanting to preach to me,
so...
Here's your chance.
Ahh.
Well, there's a God.
That I have no doubt.
Um...
But there's a...
There's a devil, too.
And you know...
You know what that old...
That old devil did?
You want me to tell you about that?
Yeah?
Well, that devil, he, uh,
he cut off God's arms.
And he hacked off God's legs.
And he gouged out his eyes.
Ripped out his tongue
and left him lying there
in a bloody heap on the floor.
But he left God's ears
so he could hear us down here
when we're wailing and thrashing
and praying for his help.
But, Brother...
There ain't a damn thing
God can do to help us.
What are you saying, preacher?
Just choose hate.
It's so much easier.
Brother!
Choose hate.
I thought everybody was
supposed to have the day off.
Everybody but us.
We had no say in it, neither.
Want me to talk to Durant about it?
You sittin' in some mighty high cotton,
ain't you, boy?
Watch yourself, son.
I'm still your boss.
Who do you think you is in
these fancy clothes, huh?
Who cocked your hat, boy?
You did.
Ain't supposed to be our boss, hmm?
You're supposed to be our leader.
Thinking you're looking out for us.
Turns out you're just looking
out for your own damn self.
Ain't nobody else going to do it.
I ain't your master.
You need to look out
for your own self, huh?
Carlton.
Mr. Bohannan.
Been looking everywhere for you.
What's going on, Sean?
I'm just making plans for the Swede.
He's just rolled back in.
And I don't think he's alone.
Oh, yeah?
Who's he with?
Well, I didn't hear any names,
but he had on a union jacket
with Sergeant Stripes.
Sergeant's jacket, huh?
Yeah, I think so.
I know we've had our differences...
- Are you sure you saw Sergeant Stripes?
- Yes!
Where they at?
Swede's caboose.
Will this make us even for the fight?
Bohannan.
A couple of federal marshals
are coming to arrest me tonight.
For what?
Murder.
So why haven't you just up and left?
Sergeant's here.
Swede tracked him down.
I reckon he talked him
into testifying against me.
How you know Harper will be
the man you're looking for?
He has to be.
You don't know that.
The hell is your stake in all this?
I ain't got none.
Why do you even care?
You told me something once.
It was the only thing
that ever set me free.
Yeah. What's that?
You got to let go of the past.
You will be the king of the ball.
Unfortunately with
no queen by my side.
Are you referring to Mrs. Lily Bell?
Hmm.
Sir, shall we take a walk?
Hmm?
Mr. Gunderson, have you ever had
your heart ripped out by a woman?
I was married once, sir,
but she ran off with a gypsy.
My heart was not ripped out,
but she did steal my cuckoo clock.
Well, my gypsy is Bohannan.
Ahh. Loki, yeah.
What?
So he and Mrs. Lily Bell.
I gave him a chance to run,
but he wouldn't take it.
Run? But why?
Mr. Gunderson,
I told him about the federal marshals.
He knows you're up to something.
Ohh.
Why did you tell him?
I wanted to get rid of him.
The fool wouldn't leave.
Why are you telling me this now?
Because I want you to succeed
in your plan, Mr. Gunderson.
You need to get out of here.
Now.
Why?
He's coming.
Find a place to hide.
Where?
I don't want to know.
Why not?
So Bohannan can't get it out of me.
Now listen, no matter what,
you must meet that train
when it arrive.
The marshals will protect you.
Where is he?
Where is who?
In the myths of my homeland
there is a God that go
by the name of Loki.
This Loki's the God of chaos.
He causes nothing
but trouble everywhere he go.
No matter how hard
the other gods try to catch him,
the slippery little devil
always manages to escape.
You have 3 seconds to
tell me where he is.
I honestly do not know.
If I did, I would not tell you.
Go ahead, kill me.
I go to my grave happy knowing
that I'm the one who'll bring you down.
Just as I thought.
Killing me does not equate
in your moral mathematics.
Eva!
Whoo-ee, darling.
If you ain't slicker
than a fine gentleman's snot rag.
You ain't looking too
shabby your ownself, gal.
Thank you.
Where'd you get that pretty thing?
Mrs. Bell gave it to me.
What you doing out here?
They're building the town.
A real town.
I've been on the move
for as long as I can remember.
Since before them Indians took me.
I was thinking it might be nice
for us to, you know, settle down.
What you mean?
Well, we're getting hitched,
so why not settle down
like a proper man and wife
and raise a family.
Getting hitched?
Like we talked about.
I ain't never said nothing
about getting hitched.
But I... I thought the other day
you said you wanted me to be yours.
I do.
Well, I thought that meant...
I just ain't thought
things out that far.
And I sure as hell ain't staying
in no Podunk railroad town.
Look at me. Huh?
When they freed me,
I ain't have a penny to my name, Eva.
Now I work for Mr.
Thomas Durant himself.
Oh, I see.
For the first time in my life,
I got money in my pocket.
My money in my pocket.
Might be looking at some
kind of real future.
Without me.
No.
I want it with you.
What, as your private whore?
Ahh, yes, good to see you.
Imagine it.
A journey that now takes 6 months
would be cut to 7 days.
7 days.
It boggles the mind.
You will be able to spend
Christmas in New York and...
New years in San Francisco.
Gentlemen, I give you Mrs. Lily Bell.
Ma'am.
Mrs. Bell.
There's room on the dance floor.
How you been, Miss Eva?
Mr. Toole.
Are you not waiting for Mr. Ferguson?
No, I am not.
Well, if I'm not
overstepping me bounds,
would you do me
the honor of dancing with me?
I'm sorry, Mr. Toole,
I don't much feel
like dancing right now.
I understand.
Thank you, ma'am.
Mr. Toole.
There was a time out in
the frontier with Robert
when I wondered if
this beautiful landscape
might not be better unspoiled.
Part of me still wonders that.
But after seeing all these people
working so hard to build this road,
after understanding
the sheer audacity
of this American endeavor,
well, I see now there
truly is greatness in it.
To Lily Bell,
the fair-haired maiden of the west.
Cheers.
Hear, hear.
You following me?
Oh, no. No, sir.
Just taking the evening air.
What is this?
It's about a payment.
No, not now.
Hey!
Hey! Get your bloody rope off me!
Someone help me.
Get your bloody hands off me!
Your bloody hands off me!
Get off!
We're here to collect a debt,
Mr. Swede.
You be careful, Irish boy,
what you choose to do now,
you son of a bitch, you.
Bloody... aah!
How do you like that?
Aah!
Aah! Uhh!
Bust his head!
Bastard! Get your hands
off me, bloody Irish.
Aah! Aah!
Gah!
Would you like to dance, sir?
I'm sure some of these other fellows
are much better dancers than me.
But I don't want these other fellows.
You'll see a lot of perks
working for me, Mr. Ferguson.
Is that right?
Mm-hmm.
Excuse me a second.
Ahh.
Elam!
What the hell are you
doing with my woman?
Hey, now, Ferguson.
Stop it!
Elam, let him go.
Come on. Elam!
I ain't your woman.
You made that pretty clear.
I didn't make nothing clear.
You're still mine.
What, like your property?
I'm staying behind, Elam.
It seems like Mr.
Toole has got the same idea.
You and him?
No, there ain't no me and him.
We're just two people who don't
want to be vagabonds no more.
I love you, Elam,
but I'm tired of being a tramp.
Excuse. I'm sorry,
I'm afraid I need to cut in.
Damn it!
We don't have to do this.
I wasn't there, Mr. Bohannan.
You're a liar.
Johnson said the Sergeant
strangled my wife.
And I saw the picture.
You was the platoon sergeant.
Not then I wasn't.
You raped and murdered my wife.
I wasn't there.
Just admit it.
I can prove it.
No.
You have to be him.
I can prove it.
Uhh!
I...
Ahh!
Uhh.
Hey.
I've been looking for you.
I seen the marshals back there.
Oh.
You killed him?
Yeah.
But he wasn't there.
I killed the wrong man.
What's you gonna do now?
♪ This train,
it's bound for glory ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ this train,
it's bound for glory ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ this train,
it's bound for glory ♪
♪ don't give it nothing
but the righteous and the holy ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ it's bound for glory ♪
♪ and this train
don't carry no liars ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ and this train
don't carry no liars ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ and this train
don't carry no liars ♪
♪ the truth is what
the lord desires ♪
♪ this train
don't carry no liars ♪
♪ This train ♪
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
♪ This train,
it's bound for glory ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ and this train,
it's bound for glory ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ and this train,
it's bound for glory ♪
♪ don't give it nothing
but the righteous and the holy ♪
♪ this train ♪
♪ it's bound for glory ♪
♪ and this train
is bound for glory ♪
♪ this train ♪