Previously on AMC's Hell On Wheels.
Payroll train's been robbed again.
Seems we'll be needing your services.
You ain't gonna believe this boy.
What are you doin' here?
Tryin' to keep you
from gettin' yourself killed.
You don't believe in me anymore.
Nobody's gonna care about
the killing of a prostitute.
Would you like to join us for supper?
Look how far I've fallen.
The Sioux believe this land is scared.
I call the shots here,
not you.
Wake up cause you're next.
Here, Jenny.
Got some feed.
Bessie.
Mr. Toole!
Rise and shine!
Morning, Samuel.
Ehh.
Samuel!
Samuel, did you hear that?
I don't want to. Put me down!
Aaigh!
Sync by YYeTS, correction  by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
Now, Mr. Bohannon,
you are guilty of armed
robbery and sedition,
a capital offense.
I may be able to get that commuted to life
if you give me the names of your cohorts.
Yeah. I might just fly my ass out of here
if I sprout me some wings. Heh heh.
Now, let's try this again.
The names of the
confederates you rode with.
You think they wouldn't
give you up in a heartbeat
if they were in your spot?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Wait, wait.
I'll tell you. I'll tell you
their names, all right?
Wise decision.
Their... their names were...
Robert...
E...Lee,
Stonewall Jackson,
Jeb Stuart,
Nathan Bedford forr...
leave him!
Mitt herredømme?
What in God's name is...
sorry to disturb your
slumber, mitt herredømme,
but I was passing the railroad office.
An important, urgent message has arrived.
You may retrieve my chamber pot
at a more reasonable hour, Gundersen.
Of course.
Good day.
Thomas, what is it?
Indians. Attacked Durant.
Apparently burned the place to the ground.
Let's go! We got to get moving!
Everybody!
Mr. Ferguson!
Where do you think you're going?
Thought you might need my help, sir.
No, I need you here to protect my railroad.
Yes, sir, Mr. Durant, sir.
Potatoes, meat, what's left of the cheese.
This blanket is thin, so keep
your coat buttoned tight.
Ruth, I'm only gonna be gone a day.
To keep you safe.
Child.
You have forsaken me.
Father!
Why did you not come to me when you heard?
Because we have no use for you.
But I... I can help stop the bloodshed.
Jesus... Jesus said...
that Bible means nothing to them, reverend.
I know you view our relations
with these savages
as some kind of divine mission.
Trust me, God has forsaken all of us.
Your services are not necessary.
Father, sorry.
I'll be home soon.
Sit down.
What happened, Mr. Toole?
A band of braves rode in from the west,
attacked at daybreak,
scorched the very earth.
Ying
did they damage the track?
Not as I can tell, sir.
Steal anything?
No, sir.
How many killed?
7 men and 2 women.
Bleedin' savages.
What tribe?
You even know how to tell?
Sorry. I was too busy
saving me lily-white arse,
if you know what I mean.
They didn't look like Cheyenne to me,
if that's what you're wondering.
There they are!
They're Santee Sioux.
Sioux?
But this is Cheyenne territory.
Why are they attacking so far from home?
This was a murder raid.
They're sending you a message.
What message?
That you're now at war
with the Sioux nation.
Ying
ying
you got a visitor.
Visitor?
Make it fast.
What in the hell are you doing here?
Don't worry. Paid them guards a nice stack
of yankee bills.
Stupid ass.
They, uh...
They tell you when yet?
It's bound to be soon.
They're running out of people to shoot.
I'm sorry, Cullen.
Don't start, doc.
I got you caught up in this
nonsense to begin with.
I, uh...
I should have never dragged you into it.
You and me's square.
Now get the hell on out of here.
You make your peace yet, son?
What you suppose the lord's gonna think
about a man like me, huh?
He knows what's in your heart.
I murdered a man.
He was innocent.
I wrapped my hands around his throat,
and I looked him in the eyes,
and I choked the life right out of him.
I know you must feel... you
must feel bad about that, son.
That's just the thing.
I don't feel nothing about that.
Not a damn thing.
It's time. Come on, now.
I'll pray for you, son.
If you're gonna pray,
pray for me to die well, doc.
That's all I got left.
A small deposit will secure a lot
fit for tent accommodations.
However, the tents themselves
are for sale, not rent,
but for a slightly larger deposit,
you can pitch your flag closer to town.
Mr. McGinnes. Yeah?
These people lost everything.
They need shelter.
What size lot can they afford?
Really, Mr. McGinnes. We'll not profit
or further people's misery.
Bloody good that,
coming from an englishwoman.
I bet your pardon?
Ah, you people built an empire of misery
on the backs of the Irish
and everyone else,
haven't you?
The point is, Mr. McGinnes,
that these people need a place to live,
and we have land here, for everyone.
Mr. Durant, with whom I have an agreement,
has land.
Do you speak for him?
As a matter of fact, I do.
My agreement with Mr. Durant
states my percentage for
brokering his land,
plus a stake in all tents I provide.
Then we'll negotiate a settlement.
How's that, Mr. McGinnes?
And my brokerage fee.
Of course.
After all,
this is not England or Ireland, is it?
It is, in fact, America, Mrs. Bell.
Yes, and welcome to it.
Good day, Mr. McGinnes.
As I was saying...
Ready...
Fire!
Afternoon, boys.
Going out to play in the water again?
Hold him tight. I got to get the...
hang on.
Take him out.
Thought you liked me, boys.
Give it a go.
Hold him!
Come on. It takes 3 of y'all
to kill one confederate?
You ought to be ashamed of yourselves.
Keep moving.
You sons of bitches gonna answer me?
Just do it. Get it over with.
You still there?
Where the hell did y'all go?
I was ready.
Get back in here.
I'll skin your asses alive
and run you back across the bull run!
Come on and finish this job right now!
What's the rush, Mr. Bohannon?
I just heard about, um...
The girl who died here a few days ago.
Yes. Um, the whore who was murdered.
She was my friend.
I'm sorry.
You should know, Eva, I... I did
secure her a proper burial.
Yeah. All due respect,
a burial don't do nothing
for the girls still there,
and I want the man responsible
to pay for what he did.
Eva, the situation...
It would be difficult to convince
people to do the right thing.
Because she was as whore?
No. I didn't say that.
She didn't deserve what she got.
I understand.
What the hell you doing here, anyway?
This is a warrant for your execution.
Yeah. No shit.
And this...
Is a pardon...
Signed by my friend Edwin Stanton,
secretary of war.
Playing God comes natural to you, don't it?
Well, yes, it does.
But like any benevolent God...
I'm here to help you.
I'm supposed to believe you
don't want nothing out of this?
On the contrary.
My motives are purely selfish.
But that is not to say that
you can't benefit as well.
You have a lot of unfinished business
on this earth, Mr. Bohannon.
What will it be...
life...
Or death?
I hope it's first-class.
All right.
Thank you.
You sure you got to do that?
That's for robbing my railroad.
It takes a tragedy to fill our church.
God is at work.
His ways are mysterious.
Maybe your God works too hard.
He is our God, Joseph.
Father. You should be in bed.
How sharper than a serpent's tooth.
And he maketh...
His angels to the wind
and his minister into the flame of fire.
Father, stop.
These people have lost their homes.
This isn't the time.
Go...
Please?
Don't judge, or you, too, will be judged.
You, too.
Reverend...
Please, father.
No.
This is my church.
It's best you go.
Welcome back.
Well, if it ain't Mr. Ferguson.
Sad state of affairs right here.
You come here to gloat?
No. No, no.
I come to give you this.
Something to see you through
till you get back on your feet.
I don't think so.
Your husband ain't gonna approve?
No. I don't approve.
And why don't you save that money
for one of them fancy suits?
I was just trying to help.
A whole race of people will be wiped off
the face of the earth by this iron beast.
Perhaps.
Then again...
Maybe the sioux have a beast of their own.
Have you heard of the white
spirit, reverend Cole?
It's an old Indian legend.
Aye. Oh, it's more than a legend.
Now is his season...
For the white spirit comes with the cold,
feasting on blood and human flesh,
leaving nothing but famine and
pestilence for his enemies.
And I look...
And behold the pale horse.
Nej.
Whose name...
It's his name that sat on him
was death.
And hell will follow with him.
"Revelation"?
Yeah.
Yes...
It will be apocalyptic.
Yeah.
Where a tide of blood will be unleashed.
Indian blood, no doubt.
Nej, nej, nej.
The white spirit will prevail.
I don't believe such things, Swede.
Ahh. All right.
May I show you something, then?
Heh.
What the...
I dug this up by the river side.
What in...
what in God's name is this?
There are more things in heaven and earth
than are dreamt of in your
philosophy, reverend Cole.
Glory. Woman: *charlotte
the harlot lay dying *
whoo! Whoo!
♪a pisspot supporting her head ♪
♪surrounded by six horny sailors ♪
♪she rolled on her left tit and said ♪
♪ "I've been screwed by the
pohmmies and the Irish" ♪
♪ "I've been screwed by
the yanks and the Jews" ♪
♪ "now I've come over here to Nebraska" ♪
♪ "to be screwed by bastards like you" ♪
♪ "so out with your dirty old organs" ♪
♪ "and give me the juice of your..." ♪
♪ "I said, out with your
dirty old organs" ♪
♪ "and I'll tattoo my name on your guts" ♪
may I sit?
Sure you're in the right place, ma'am?
I have a job for you.
I already got a job.
Have a drink.
I ain't drunk out of it if
that's what you're wondering.
What can I do for you?
I want you to...
Deal with the man who
killed the prostitute.
What you mean, "deal with"?
I want to be sure he never does it again.
Oh. You want me to give
him a good talking to.
You know that's not what I mean.
Then say it.
Mr. Ferguson.
Say it.
I want him punished.
I'm afraid I can't oblige
you on that, ma'am.
Fine.
I'll tell Eva that's what you said.
Eva?
Who do you think asked me to come here?
♪your iron horse is running ♪
♪your iron horse is coming... ♪
I can't help wondering...
I haven't made a grave mistake.
I'm beginning to come around
to the same conclusion.
I think you should thank me.
I tell you what...
I'll say you're welcome.
I could always make you.
Nah, I don't think so.
You don't know a thing about me, Bohannon.
Well, I know...
I know you're the type of man
that likes to do his dirty
work from a distance.
Not up close like this.
Who's the executioner now, huh?
Why don't you ask me for a stay, huh?
No.
Sometimes it seems...
One has to make a deal with the devil.
Who's the devil in this deal, huh?
Oh.
Here you go.
Mornin'.
Something I can do for you?
Don't know.
Is there?
Maybe there is something you can do for me.
And what would that be?
I got me a whore that needs killing.
I can't help you.
I heard you can.
Heard you the last customer
that poor girl had
the night before she got beat to death.
You better watch yourself, boy.
The only thing worth less in
this town than a dead whore,
a nigger don't know his place.
So will you do it for me?
You know who I am?
Yes, sir.
Mr. schmidt, foreman of the railroad...
And whore killer.
I just need you to tell me you did it
before I shoot you in the gut.
You're not gonna shoot me.
Everybody would hear.
Yes, I killed the bitch.
You right.
I ain't gonna shoot you right now.
I like what you done with the place.
Like I said,
you have your work cut
out for you, Bohannon.
What's to keep me from lighting out of here
first chance I get, huh?
For a man like you,
his word is stronger than
any set of shackles.
But if I'm wrong,
I could always get him to shoot you.
♪I'm gonna ask the question ♪
♪please answer if you can
♪if any of you people can tell me ♪
♪what is the soul of a man? ♪
♪won't somebody tell me
♪answer if you can
♪what is the soul of a man? ♪
no gun?
♪I've traveled different countries ♪
♪I've traveled foreign lands ♪
you gonna need one.
♪I found nobody could tell me ♪
♪what is the soul of a man? ♪
♪I saw a crowd stand talking ♪
♪I just came up in time
♪the teachers and the
doctors and the lawyers ♪
♪say a man ain't nothing but his mind ♪
♪a man ain't nothing but his mind ♪
♪won't somebody tell me
♪answer if you can
♪what is the soul of a man? ♪
ha ha ha!
You got him!
♪I read the Bible often
♪I done to read it right
♪as far as I can understand ♪
♪ain't nothing but a burning light ♪
♪well, Christ stood in the temple ♪
♪the people stood amazed
♪he was showing the
doctors and the lawyers ♪
♪how to raise a body from the grave ♪
♪won't somebody tell me
♪answer if you can
♪what is the soul of a man? ♪
♪what is the soul of a man ♪
Sync by YYeTS, correction  by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com