Previously on AMC's Hell on Wheels...
You are evil!
Cheyenne is my city,
run by my mayor in support of my railroad.
He shot a cheater.
- That's no crime here.
- It is now.
We're leaving here together,
you, me, and baby William,
You'll be shot, you try to leave.
By your hand, you took his life!
- Praise God!
- I'll get us to Cheyenne.
- It's a big city.
We thought you was dead.
To build the transcontinental railroad,
Thomas "Doc" Durant once said
"A man must face his demons and destroy them
or become undone by them."
The hell on wheels of 1868
is no place for bashful men,
the deluded, or unassured.
No place for sloppy men,
drunk and disorderly in their
heavenly vestments on their
way to an early grave.
The railroad has contained the
west these last three years,
with its iron horse and
rails pinned to the ground.
And each passing day brings
with it civilization,
if not civility.
And men in suits, who do now with their pens
what earlier,
rougher men did with their guns.
Cullen Bohannon, late of the union pacific,
is more gunman than suit.
His return to Cheyenne;
These days referred to
as the "Magic city of the plains,"
after months lost to the
prairie and presumed dead,
with a mormon wife and child in tow,
might be just the grease we need to turn
the wheels of our national obsession,
buried these long winter months in snow
and now, up to its Wheel-Wells in mud.
Or might it be the match
strike of self-immolation?
For Mr. Bohannon has
always worn his integrity
like a millstone around his neck.
Howdy.
Ho.
Help you?
You can step aside.
Bohannon's back!
- What's your business here?
- None of your business.
Ha. You hear that, deputy?
It's none of our business.
There's nothin' here for
mormons but trouble, friend.
I ain't lookin' for trouble.
Just the kind of people
trouble finds in my town.
There's a mormon settlement
50, 60 Miles to the northwest.
You'll be welcome there.
Let go of my horse.
Don't touch me.
I'd listen to her.
I suggest you turn around and...
Ahh!
Still blockin' my horse.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Cullen Bohannon has come home,
dear reader.
And in our little world
just west of civilization,
we find ourselves once again at his mercy.
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com
Are you telling me it's impossible
to tunnel through that Mountain?
No man can do it?
We've been blastin'
for morefor more than a we.
Damn thing keeps caving in on itself.
God sakes, Delaney.
The Sierra nevadas couldn't stop huntington.
This blip of a molehill
is not going to stop me.
The sierras are made of granite, Mr. Durant.
We're dealing with more
unstable terrain here.
Mudrock and shale.
Excuses will not get my tunnel built.
Now, do whatever you have to do.
Put on an extra shift to clear the rubble
and print up more scrip to pay the men.
They won't work for nothing,
not even the freedmen.
Mr. Durant...
That will be all. Thank you, Delaney.
This is the railroad office,
not the ticket office.
Behind the building.
Across the tracks at the depot.
Cullen Bohannon.
Here to see Durant.
Martin Delaney.
Oh.
Builder of stone and brook Bridges.
Chief engineer at the union pacific.
It's the ghost of Cullen Bohannon.
And... mormon, no less.
If ever there was proof
that you cannot be killed,
this is it.
The last time I saw you,
you were being dragged away
by a gang of masked outlaws,
never to be seen again.
It was her dad who took me.
Mormon militia on account of the...
This is my wife Naomi and,
uh, my son William.
We wintered up at fort Smith.
Took some doin', but I'm back now.
And how many mormons did
you have to put in the ground
to effect your escape?
Wasn't like that.
It's always like that with you, Bohannon.
You start a gunfight in my town,
nearly have us all killed, and for what?
A girl you got pregnant.
Come back for my old job.
Is it mine or not?
No. Not.
Your railroad's stuck, Durant.
I'm the only one who
can get it movin' again.
Even if I could fire Mr. Delaney,
he has done nothing to warrant it.
You, on the other hand,
stand there wallowing
in moral turpitude, having just confessed
to complete lack of regard
for the most basic fundamental
needed to get this road moving:
Dependability.
What you need to get this road movin' again
is a man who can get you over
sherman summit, all right?
He ain't him.
I am not going over, Bohannon.
I am going through.
And without you.
Welcome to Cheyenne, madam.
This ain't how I planned on things goin'.
This ain't how I pictured Cheyenne.
I'll figure it out.
We'll figure it out together.
Come on.
Mr. Bohannon!
You are a sight for sore eyes.
Just when I thought me luck had run out,
here you be.
What happened to you?
Got a mormon girl in the family way,
and I need a job.
Any more questions?
Grant sent a carpetbagger out
to install law and order.
He hung a man from the rafters of my casino.
I could use a man like you.
Mm-mm.
No, thanks.
You just said you needed a job.
Not that one.
It was good to see you, Mick.
By the way, I'm the mayor now!
Congratulations.
Is he a close friend of yours?
Killed his brother,
and I helped to bury him.
Suppose that makes us somethin'.
I paid $28 for this rifle.
You can take it out of his hide.
When?
When I tell you.
A rare Bulgarian, that one.
Steal the milk out your tea
as soon as he look at ya.
A surveyor for the union pacific.
An employee of Mr. Durant
who happens to be a partner
in my casino.
He stinks.
Get him out of here.
I'll leave that to you.
Get him out of here, Mcginnes.
He's your trash now.
And next time ye decide to turn my business
into a gallows...
You clean up before you leave.
Gentlemen.
Ho.
Hey! You coming to lunch?
This yourn.
I knowed you's comin' back, I'd have guarded
what little money was
hid backside and front.
That money fed us good for a month.
Bought us one hell of a hangover, too.
If you give me a job,
we'll forget about the money.
You ain't been in the sun long
enough for that, Mr. Bohannon.
I got a family to feed.
Freedman work, Freedman Wes.
Fair enough.
Never thought I'd see the day
I'd be the boss of the boss.
Don't get used to it, Psalms.
Mm-hmm.
Ruth.
I was just on my way to see you now.
Well.
We all got the shock of our
lives today, didn't we?
W-with Mr. Bohannon's return to Cheyenne.
Yes.
I've been praying these many
months for such a miracle.
How are you, Ruth?
Still praying.
Reckon nobody'll start
a war if you stay here.
It'll do just fine.
Here.
Eat.
Yeah, there we go.
Now.
You have trouble on the way,
you can see church lady.
Her name's Ruth, she'll help.
I won't need any help.
I'll be fine.
We'll be fine.
What you think?
You gonna be fine?
Huh?
Yeah?
I expect miss Ruth happy you're back.
Took it hard the day you gone missin'.
Got her hands full with that boy, too.
I expect she won't be none too happy
she find out you got yourself a new woman.
New baby, too.
Uh-oh. Here come your other woman problem.
Elam went after you
and got his self killed!
Elam went his own way, as always.
Eva, calm down now!
You disappeared and he went after you,
as always!
Eva, I'm sorry.
Sorry ain't gonna bring him back.
All right, load 'em up, children!
That my daylight you burnin' here!
And I ain't cookin' up no more.
I'm curious to know if
Mr. Bohannon will resume
his role as chief engineer
now that he's returned.
No, Mr. Delaney is chief engineer now
and will be for the foreseeable future.
You don't expect any political pressure
from Washington to restore
Bohannon to his post?
No, why?
He saved a young boy's life?
People around the country
view him as a hero.
Washington loves a hero.
There is a difference between a hero
and a man who's lost his way,
miss Ellison...
Something Washington nor
you seem to understand.
If I didn't know better,
I might mistake your obsession with Bohannon
for something more, uh...
Personal.
He's not that interesting.
Excuse me, miss Ellison. I, uh...
That's the flag of the
new Wyoming territory.
Odd place for it.
One day when people arrive on your train,
they'll look up, see that flag flyin'
above my statehouse
and know the value we place
on law and order around here.
Law abiding people who
admire the confiscation
of private property, hmm?
That's railroad land.
Technically,
if it's not in use by the railroad
for railroad purposes,
that land is available
for acquisition by the
state under eminent domain.
That's the law, Mr. Durant.
I will not be intimidated
by your interpretation of law, Mr. Campbell.
Nor by the hanging
shenanigans of your lawmen
in the casino a few days ago.
Now, that land's the future site
of the union pacific food depot.
My engineers are drawing
up plans even as we speak.
If there is no structure
on that hill within 24 hours,
Mr. Durant, my office will file form 0939,
condemning that property for state use...
As set forth by the united
states railroad act.
Fair enough, Mr. Campbell.
Fair enough.
Mr. Campbell.
Miss Ellison.
That's a lovely color.
Excuse me?
On you, that is.
Thank you.
Allow me.
Oh, I can manage on my own.
Thank you.
I need half a dozen of my
chicken coops on the hill
just east of the church by tomorrow morning.
Divert whatever manpower
and supplies you need.
I just put a second shift on the grade.
Per your orders.
Oh, well, thank you, Delaney.
Let me know when it's done.
You're late.
You playin' faro in here now?
I don't see how that's
any business of yours, Eva
how much does the last three cards pay?
Clean the tables.
You ain't thinkin'
of gambling in my casino now?
Uh... yeah.
I'm thinkin' I will, Mickey.
You could lose everything.
I got nothin' left to lose.
Small bit of advice then.
Stay away from the Faro table.
The box is rigged.
Afternoon, fellas.
You, uh, lost little lady?
Why?
My money ain't good enough for ya?
- It's good enough for me.
- Hey.
You want to hear the story
of how I lost my scalp?
Not again, Wallace.
Deal me in.
My pleasure.
- Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
- Name's Bohannon.
Yes, sir.
Any you all ever been
chased by a bloodhound?
- We familiar.
- Yeah, well,
on Sherman's march to the sea,
he told his men,
he said, "You come across any bloodhounds,
you shoot 'em," right?
So, they get to Savannah.
And this real green private,
he's walkin' down the street
and he sees this lady
walking with a poodle.
You know, bows in its hair and everything.
One look at the poodle, pulls out his gun.
Right in the head.
Sherman comes runnin' up to him,
says "Son, why'd you kill that poodle?"
And the private says "Sir, well,
on account of you... You never
what they're gonna grow into."
Come on.
What's a poodle?
That'll be $9.00 and 23¢.
We take cash or scrip.
Can I get credit?
No credit.
If you ain't got cash nor scrip,
I can't sell you nothin'.
But I need these things.
And I got a business to run.
That's all right, Mr. Adler.
I'll take care of Mrs.
Bohannon's sundries today.
I'm sure Mr. Bohannon is good for it.
Yes, sir, Mr. Campbell.
Whatever you say.
I'ma raise ya.
All right, young lady.
Call.
Full house.
Queens over 10s.
Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa, easy now.
Not so fast.
You know, it really is hard to beat a lady.
Unless you're a king.
But how did... how'd you do that?
No, that ain't right.
Don't cry. It's only money.
Howdy, ma'am.
I don't want my money back, I swear.
I just want to know how you cheated me.
You cheated yourself, woman,
by sittin' down at a table
with the likes of me.
Now, you are either desperate,
greedy,
or stupid.
I'm just desperate.
And stupid.
And I need to know how you did it.
That's dangerous knowledge
for someone who don't know how to use it.
I know how to use it.
It's all in the grip.
Now, say if someone were to cheat...
Thumb, fingertips.
Teach me.
What took me years to perfect?
I ain't stupid.
I'll make it worth your while.
Double the powder on those charges.
Yes, sir.
That much powder's likely
to get us all killed.
Boss man decide how much powder we use.
You ain't boss man no more.
Mr. Delaney.
That rock?
It's shale.
Where there's shale, there's methane.
You double that powder,
Shrapnel's likely to kill every man
within about a hundred yards
of that wall right there.
Get back to work, Bohannon.
I want your advice, I'll ask for it.
All right. Turn them tables over,
get behind 'em before that thing blows.
You know I ain't one to come
between two feudin' white men.
You don't want to die, neither.
Do it! Turn 'em over!
Light those fuses.
Mr. Bohannon,
you about to get your job back.
Shit!
What do you want?
I didn't know Elam'd gone lookin' for me.
You shoulda known you'd
disappear like that,
he's gonna come lookin'.
I didn't disappear. I was took.
By armed men against my will.
But by then he wasn't listenin' to me.
I've been havin' dreams...
About Elam.
Not every night, but most nights.
I'm in a big city somewheres.
Chicago.
New York.
I'm lost.
Walkin' the streets.
Lookin' into peoples' homes.
Their nice warm windows.
I'm on the outside.
Always on the outside.
Everyone's afraid of me.
I think it's 'cause of my tattoo.
And then I realize...
That's not what it is.
I see my reflection.
I'm not me anymore.
I'm a bear,
and I'm lookin' for Elam.
Thems is just dreams, Eva.
They don't mean nothin'.
He considered you a friend, Mr. Bohannon.
I expect that might mean somethin' to ya,
since I know you ain't had many.
Well...
One fewer now.
Mr. Thomas Durant of the union pacific
is not the first person we've run into
who didn't see things my way.
No, sir.
Come here!
If people believe any one
of them is above the law,
there will be no law.
Durant?
I'd like to ask judge Webber
his opinion on a remedy.
This hour, you're likely to find him
at the faro tables or the whorehouse.
Yes, sir.
Hey!
Get off! Get off!
How was your day, husband?
It was fine.
- Yours?
- Just fine.
Mr. Bohannon.
You in there?
Governor Campbell.
Why, it's nice to see you again,
Mrs. Bohannon.
You got somethin' to say to my wife, son,
you talk to me.
I bought her a meal is all.
How you enjoyin' it?
I can buy my own meals.
You handled yourself
mightily with my men yesterday.
Like I told 'em,
I ain't lookin' for trouble.
Y'all have a good night.
General Grant holds you in
high regard, Mr. Bohannon.
What do you want?
A man of your stature
livin' amongst the, uh...
Negros?
Freedmen.
Now, you don't have to live
in squalor, Mr. Bohannon.
You work for me. I'll pay you a decent wage.
I already got a job.
I'll pay you three times
what you make layin' rail.
And I'll helyou build a
house for your family.
Until then, allow me to engage
a room for you at the hotel.
Hot bath, warm bed.
You could be there tonight, Mrs. Bohannon.
Work for a carpetbagger?
Not a chance in a hell.
The freedmen's bureau,
sir, is but one legacy
of reconstruction I believe
I shall be remembered for.
And fondly.
Should you change your mind.
By my count, that's two good jobs
that you've turned down since we got here.
What're we meant to do then?
Naomi...
Everything I done...
All the death and
destruction I put my hand to
and was put to me...
All that is for naught if
I don't finish this road.
Mr. Bohannon.
Hmm.
Surprised you're still here.
Likewise.
Ah.
Somethin' about the place.
The cuisine, no doubt.
Thought you would have hightailed it
back to New York by now.
Story keeps me here.
Mm...
Careful it don't kill ya.
Hasn't killed you.
Yet.
I hear you got married.
Yeah.
Nice mormon girl.
I'm interested in your
story, Mr. Bohannon.
My readers will be as well.
Ain't a story, miss Ellison.
Just a life.
It's mine to live, nobody's to read about.
Oh, I...
Sorry to interrupt your supper.
Thought I should come by and say howdy.
Hey.
We thought you were dead.
Huh?
Why'd you think that?
You would have come back otherwise.
Why don't you go wait outside, boy.
Go on.
Ezra has missed you, Mr. Bohannon.
He grieved for you.
As did I.
You done right by him.
He's growin' up tall.
Yes.
We're our own little family now.
The two of us.
Ruth...
I'm sorry.
Now you're back.
With a new wife and child.
I'm sure as the railroad starts moving,
you'll be moving with it.
I have my church to look after.
And the boy.
We'll be staying here.
I come to ask a favor.
I don't think I can help you.
Naomi and my boy, William...
When I'm out in the cut,
they're here all alone.
I know how you feel.
About mormons.
I was hopin' you could find it in your heart
to lend a hand.
If need be.
I have built the walls of
my church to be a stronghold
for the needy, Mr. Bohannon.
Should your wife and
child ever find themselves
at my door,
they, like everyone else in this town,
will find it open.
You know, ain't none of
this your fault, son.
You traded yourself for me.
Come on.
You would have done the same.
Anyways, thank you.
You're welcome.
The defrocked Chief
engineer's return to Cheyenne
means another actor has entered the play,
already half finished.
With the bombastic dreamer,
his legacy depending on
completing this road.
And the carpetbagging bureaucrat,
tasked with bringing civilization to a land
that, just yesterday, boasted wild and free.
Cullen Bohannon, for reasons
this reporter has yet to divine,
seems determined to see this road through.
Whether he does it as laborer or boss,
alive or dead,
only time will tell, dear reader.
Only time will tell.
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com