Prviously on AMC's Hell On Wheels...
- Joseph Dutson?
- Joseph Dutson
You murdered my chief of police.
***
You owe me a life for
the one you took from me.
War must continue.
If all contracts will be assigned to me.
***
I felt his spirit pass.
He's the father of my child.
I pronounce you husband and wife.
I want to register a formal protest.
Noted.
Have you thought of everything?
Course not.
It doesn't occur to me how to
engineer my own destruction.
We crossed the Missouri like this,
greater river than the crow.
Thicker ice, colder weather.
And larger balls than my chief engineer.
You're the boss.
Who holdin' the money?
- Everybody in?
- Uh-huh.
You there, big fella.
They call me Psalms, Mr. Durant.
Psalms, yes, of course, Psalms.
What's the wager?
How far across before the engineer jump.
You don't think the train's gonna make it?
I ain't bettin' against the railroad itself,
Mr. Durant, just the engineer.
Of course.
Engineer, take it across.
Ugh!
Congratulations, Mr. Durant.
Red hot boiler on ice, wheels spinning.
What'd you think was gonna happen?
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com
water is sweet and good.
You get attacked by
Indians now or set fire to,
won't have to go down to the river.
You'll not be here, should that happen?
Gave you my word,
I'd be here till the crops is in,
baby's born.
Naomi's due any day now.
Only thing keeping me here
after that'll be Bishop Dutson.
Well, you have honored your word to me.
No doubt, he'll feel the same.
I try to walk out that gate,
he'll put a bullet in my back.
Bishop Dutson is not the
man you claim him to be.
Father Hatch, I keep telling you,
he ain't the man he claims to be.
An imposter could never lay on hands
and speak in tongues like Bishop Dutson.
Yeah.
One day you'll see.
Close the gate!
- Brother Bohannon.
- How's Cheyenne?
Sodom and gomorrah's got nothing on it.
Railroad started stockpiling rail yet?
Railroad's stuck and busted. I did hear
the cavalry's got the comanche on the run,
though.
Mind you don't get a haircut next time.
Slim pickings.
Wonderful work on the new well.
Careful you don't fall in.
Oh,
try to enjoy God's peace within these walls.
Fort this pretty,
it's hard to remember I'm a prison.
You are a free man, brother Bohannon.
Free to leave, you mean?
Mm.
It's good to see the men
fight with their fists.
Usually,
they reach right for their knives and guns.
It's the final tally for the material
lost in the river.
I don't have this kind of money on hand.
Find it,
or the central pacific will meet us here...
In this God forsaken place.
Your wife is unhappy here, I take it.
Her father was one of your best friends.
He goes missing, you do nothing about it.
Well, at's not true. We looked everywhere.
You know,
we really should have dinner sometime,
so we can reacquaint.
I can explain it to her.
Oh, she'd love that,
since she worries you had something to do
with his disappearance.
Who could possibly have
put such a hairbrained idea
in her head? A Boston detective.
The one who came out here last year.
Her father, senator metcalf,
was one of my oldest and closest friends.
I was her godfather, for Christ's sakes!
Well,
that's what makes it so frightening for her.
I will do everything I can
to answer her questions.
Meanwhile, advise your wife to be cautious.
Cheyenne is a dangerous place.
Eva?
Howdy, Mr. Durant.
Eva, surely, you can find
something more suitable than washing whores'
bedding.
Well, Mickey was good to give me the work.
It's either this or go back to whoring.
Look at me, Eva.
The eyes of the world are upon me,
as I stand on the verge of ruin.
Harassed on all sides, my wife left me
while I was in prison, I have no friends,
but you don't see me crying, do you?
No, so pick yourself up.
Yes, Mr. Durant.
Good.
Mr. Mayor.
I am seeking counsel.
Always happy to oblige
one of my constituents.
Ahh.The railroad.
Mm-hmm.
If you were me, what would you do?
Historically, sir, you'd have gone back east
and sold a bunch of phony
paper for millions of dollars,
but after sinking the train,
I'd say you have credibility concerns.
Correct, so what would you do now?
Sell off anything you have of value,
including that watch.
I'll give you a fiver for it.
I have land,
20 acres either side of the track,
and any land I can claim mineral rights to.
You should sell it... At auction.
And you should buy it, at auction.
I don't want it,
and I don't want that kind of trouble.
I made you mayor. I made you rich.
You arrived with a magic
show and a dopey smile.
You could leave with a lot less.
Post a notice, something official.
Oh, and bring cash.
And for God sakes, get Eva out of the mud.
Some people don't want to
be pulled out of the mud,
Mr. Durant.
True. Don't be one of them.
Here.
Go ahead and read it.
Your railroad's fallen
behind during the winter.
Durant sunk a train into the crow river
and called it a minor setback, so...
He struggles,
probably 'cause you're not there.
"Chief engineer Martin
Delaney announced today."
Damn it! I can't believe this.
- What is it?
- I can't believe
durant hadn't fired that
idiot Martin Delaney by now.
I beat him out for the job once already.
I know how much that railroad means to you.
You came out here to build it,
not live a life among
people who aren't your own,
with a wife that you may not love.
Come to the railroad huntin'...
The men who murdered my wife and child.
Killed the ones I could find.
Now, Naomi...
You're married to a killer.
You're just tryin'
to scare me into not lovin' you
so you can leave.
No, I'm just bein' truthful is all.
You can leave, Cullen.
I'll be all right.
Thank you.
It's quite all right.
Bread, husband?
Why don't you have a seat? Rest a spell.
There you go.
Well, I'm glad.
After four months among us,
you're making friends.
I can count 'em all on one finger.
Hmm.
Brother dultey.
I talk to him, he talks to me.
Especially when he returns
from his trips to Cheyenne.
Let go of Cheyenne, your former life.
- Uh-huh.
- Mm.
I want to talk to you about something,
Bishop.
Yes?
That thing you said about freedom earlier.
Hmm?
I think I finally understand it.
Good. Good!
- And... and something else.
- Mm-hmm?
I had me a vision.
Tell me.
I had me a vision that I
was leaving this place.
But why?
Th-there's still...
So much to be done with you.
I don't know, I just...
Saw myself walkin'
straight through that gate.
No, no. Walkin' right out
through that gate, whistling Dixie.
You...
you would not abandon your wife and child.
Yeah.
I wouldn't worry none.
It's just a vision.
Hmm.
Mr. Campbell,
general grant will see you now.
General grant.
With my election assured,
I'm sending you west, Campbell.
Wyoming. Ever hear of it?
- Vaguely.
- Lawless place.
Union pacific has gotten
itself bogged down out there.
Things are running amok.
I don't think I'm the man
you want to send there.
You will not be returning to Atlanta.
My work there is incomplete.
I'm saving you from yourself, Campbell.
You were a bit overzealous.
Mistakes were made, but order was restored.
And you'll do the same as
the provisional governor
of Wyoming. Good luck, sir.
General, you honor me with this opportunity.
The greatest good
to the greatest number
is the object to attain.
This requires security of
person and property in every...
Gentlemen, the general is very pleased
with our success in Atlanta.
He's not giving us the boot?
On the contrary,
he appointed me governor of a new territory.
- Which one?
- Wyoming.
- Never heard of it.
- The frontier.
It's a wilderness.
This is worse than getting the boot.
Well, not so fast. There's gold out west.
Free land out here,
opportunities for those with a keen eye.
This is not a place of hooded rascals,
a city in ashes.
It's wild, surely,
but so is an unbroken horse.
We'll break it.
You'll be provisional marshal
of the whole territory.
You'll be the judge.
You'll be the treasurer.
Grant says all this?
Pack your gear. No carpet bags.
Wyoming.
Good morning, gentlemen.
This morning, you have a rare opportunity
to buy some very valuable land.
Now, what bid do I hear
for parcel 21 in the north valley?
It breaks my heart to offer it.
Ours too. It's open range.
What if somebody fences it in?
That open range, as you call it,
was granted by the largess of
the union pacific railroad.
$400.
$500.
$500. The bid is $500, gentlemen.
And the advance?
$501.
$501. Going once, going twice...
$600.
Mrs. Palmer.
Just what is this stunt, Thomas?
This is an auction, Maggie.
Hmm, I see that.
I thought we had an agreement
about the use of this UP land
- for free range.
- Yes, and perhaps
you can strike a similar
deal with the new owner,
whomever that may be.
I struck a deal with you,
durant, in perpetuity.
Now,
you're reneging behind your flunky here.
I'm not a flunky. I'm the mayor of Cheyenne.
If you're looking for a range war,
just say, "Barbed wire."
I'm looking at a bid of $600.
$601.
$1,000.
$1,001.
$2,000.
I'm going to ruin this scheme.
$2,001?
$3,000.
Oh.
Shh.
Hey. Hey! Hey!
Hello, down there!
Drop down that ladder, Bishop.
Brother Bohannon, I've been contemplating
your vision to leave us.
When was the last time you had to draw a gun
or raise a hand in violence?
Isn't there a peace in that?
I was hoping digging
this hole into the earth
would give you time to
contemplate your soul,
a daily reminder of...
Of our need to return to the light.
God has put me on earth to save your soul,
brother Bohannon.
I believe you believe that.
Don't say no to this second chance.
Beautiful young wife and precious son,
whose arrival may be heralded as we speak.
The ladder.
God has spoken to me that it is a boy,
you know?
- Cullen!
- Drop down that ladder.
Will you use this time to
meditate on these words?
Cullen! Cullen!
Throw down that ladder!
- Cullen!
- Ugh! Bishop!
Cullen!
Bishop!
Bishop asked me about your leaving.
Yeah? What'd you tell him?
Nothin', I thought you liked it here.
No, we wait.
To hell with that.
Cullen, please!
You too?
I don't want that sumbitch
anywhere near my wife.
There seems to be
a difficulty in the birthing.
She's begging for the gentile.
Cullen!
Let me go.
Please?
Oh, Cullen, please!
I'm here, I'm here, I'm here.
It's okay.
You're gonna have to turn the baby.
We're doing that.
Do it faster.
We're doing the best we can.
She's young, healthy.
My first wife was young
and healthy, and we lost twins.
Do it.
Shh, shh, shh, shh. It's all right.
It's all right.
And you made me an enemy of Maggie Palmer
- and her cattlemen.
- Shitkickers and cow-punchers.
She called me your flunky.
Ah, the grit in your oyster.
Mr. Mcginnes, you are the mayor of Cheyenne,
and now, the second largest property owner
in the entire Wyoming territory.
You wiped me out.
Merely transferring money
from one ledger to another.
Thank you.
Ah. Flunky, no.
Partner, yes.
You are not your brother, Michael.
Pray for me.
Please?
who art in heaven.
Shit, forgot the rest of it.
Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done...
On earth...
And forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
Careless bitch.
Look what you've done.
I'm not gonna be an improvement to you.
As head of the family,
you should be the first to hold him.
Bless you, Bishop Dutson,
for saving us with your prayers.
Lord God, bless this child,
yours, mine, ours.
Forever and ever, amen.
Amen.
And bless you, my children.
God's will be done.
Wire Omaha to ship rail and ties.
That's the new bank ledger.
This came for you.
Confidential, from general grant.
You got company comin',
new provisional governor of Wyoming.
"John Campbell and staff."
You're to show Campbell every
courtesy and assistance.
Don't overstep, Delaney.
General grant sends his
best to me and Mrs. Delaney.
First,
my own company sends you to spy on me,
and now, the government sends an overseer.
Everyone knows what you're capable of.
Steady, you son of a bitch!
I am capable of anything,
as your wife so clearly intuits.
I never said killing her
father was a bad idea.
What was your father's name?
William. William Edgar.
William. Did you like him?
I like him better the older I get.
Yankees shot him.
Let's name him William.
I like it.
We're leaving here together,
you, me, and baby William,
but you can't tell nobody
till right before we go,
you understand?
You want me? Y-you want us?
Yes.
You promised my husband a life for a life
after you hung my son.
There's more to it than that.
Yes, there is.
Every time I see you,
all I can think about is my Jeb
swinging from that horrible
noose at your hand.
I'm sorry, mother Hatch.
It's not your...
Your sorrow, your pity I want.
I want you to leave this place.
The sight of you sickens me,
as it does others.
Naomi will raise the child as her brother.
His name shall be Jebediah Hatch.
In time, you will be forgotten.
Naomi is young and healthy
and will outlive her husbands,
as is our custom...
Beginning with you.
Jesus.
Shh, shh.
What happened to you?
I've done all I can for you, Eva.
Twice I gave you train
fare out of this place,
and you still don't leave.
Shh.
There's no place for me in this world,
Mickey.
You bring it all on yourself.
You involved yourself with a... negro.
I loved Elam.
You loved him so much
that you gave away the baby that he adored.
That ain't right.
You should never have left off the whoring.
You were good at that.
A natural.
All women are whores by nature...
I suppose except for me mum.
It's the one thing that
all women have in common.
Whoring.
Just whores.
At the end of the day...
They're all whores.
Is everything where you thought it would be?
What?
I said, "is everything where
you thought it would be?"
I...
I wouldn't...
Didn't mean to.
Maggie! Join me.
I actually liked you until today.
Oh, you still like me.
You just don't trust me.
That's perfectly normal.
I had to do it, Maggie. I needed the money.
So here you sit with your money, alone.
I'm expecting the new
governor of the territory.
His train is late.
One day,
you will need someone that you can trust.
All you'll find is a room of...
empty chairs.
I have bags just like those.
Oh, those are your bags,
and here is your bill.
Bill?
Figured you'd bring the threat.
A plea.
Well,
things can be two at once in your mouth.
You kill me outright,
you'll be seen for what you are.
Hmm. I kill you outright,
you'd be some kind of Saint, and I'd hang.
Once outside those gates,
I cannot guarantee your safety.
Our safety. Taking my family with me.
Your family?
That's right.
Oh. Hmm.
You not allowing me to leave...
Is that as Bishop Dutson,
or as The Swede,
also known as Thor Gundersen?
The late Thor Gundersen was Norwegian.
Oh.
Well...
Whoever you are...
You better shoot to kill.
I'm coming back to finish
this once and for all.
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com