[Distant gunfire]
[Indistinct shouting]
[Guitar playing]
♪ Cold is the water ♪
♪ it freezes
your already cold mind ♪
♪ already cold, cold mind ♪
♪ and death is at your doorstep ♪
♪ and it will steal
your innocence ♪
♪ but it will not
steal your substance ♪
♪ but you are not alone in this ♪
♪ and you are not alone in this ♪
♪ as brothers we will stand ♪
♪ and we'll hold your hand ♪
♪ hold your hand ♪
♪ and you are the mother ♪
♪ the mother of your baby child ♪
♪ the one to whom you gave life ♪
♪ and you have your choices ♪
♪ and these are
what make man great ♪
♪ his ladder to the stars ♪
♪ but you are not alone in this ♪
♪ and you are not alone in this ♪
♪ as brothers we will stand ♪
♪ and we'll hold your hand ♪
♪ hold your hand ♪
♪ but you are not alone in this ♪
♪ and you are not alone in this ♪
♪ as brothers we will stand ♪
♪ and we'll hold your hand ♪
♪ hold your hand ♪
♪ but I will tell the night ♪
♪ and whisper,
"lose your sight" ♪
♪ but I can't
move the mountains ♪
♪ for you ♪
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
Yes, I know this area quite well.
As I remember, Robert warned you
about laying track here because
this area was prone to washouts.
Robert was right.
I was wrong.
Is that what you needed to hear?
Well, I've said it.
Now, this section needs
to be re-surveyed and re-built.
Can you do it?
Yes.
But it'll have to be
re-routed south...
As Robert intended.
Do you see this Ridge?
This is solid bedrock.
Yes, but that'll take longer.
You'll have to have
your men work faster, Doc.
You get paid to build 40
miles of useable road.
If you build here again,
it will get washed out again.
Well, it may not
rain again for months.
Those are my terms.
Of course, you could always find
another surveyor...
Somewhere.
Excuse me.
Black Moon...
You're gonna answer for this,
you know that.
I should have let
my brother kill you.
You should try right now.
Hey! We've had enough
killin' for one day.
I don't suppose either of
you are keen on joining me?
To do what?
What I came for.
You'll never find them.
We'll see about that.
They know that you're following them.
They'll kill the both of you.
Yeah, we'll see about that, too.
Last chance, Bohannon.
I figured.
What about you?
You don't need his permission.
He's nobody's master anymore.
Go if you going.
[Horse neighing]
Mr. Bohannon...
You have to finish this.
What are you talking about?
This.
What you came to do.
We came to kill the bastards
who derailed the train.
We got 'em.
No one's gonna believe you...
Unless you have proof.
You mean scalps?
They're just gonna have
to take my word for it.
I ain't bringing back proof.
Not even for $20 a head?
Seems a shame leaving all this money
lying around here for the buzzards,
don't you think?
My brother belongs to me.
[Twigs snapping]
Don't look at me.
I'm a sinner, Ruth.
You know that better
than anyone, don't you?
Father?
No.
You... you let me finish.
I've been wrasslin' with God, Ruth.
And I honestly believe
that I was chosen for a great mission.
And that's why I left.
But you failed.
You know, I'd like to
think that my work
with John brown may
have... may have helped,
in some small way,
to free the slaves.
I didn't say John brown failed.
I said you failed
one drop of love...
That's all we needed.
One drop of love
would have sustained us.
Now, Ruth,
I'm... I'm trying to tell you I'm sorry.
Don't you walk away from me!
Uh!
Praise his name, Sister.
Praise his name.
Praise!
The McGinnes Brothers
Magic Lantern Show.
Back in business!
You know what we forgot, Seano?
We forgot to get a new sign.
There's no more drama,
comedy, history, is there?
As usual, brother, I am
3 steps ahead of you.
Painter's due in an hour...
With a new sign by nightfall.
Nell! Nell!
A word!
Now that is a fine
door-ful of a woman.
Nell... you know we have an agreement.
Nobody's working, Swede.
When nobody works, nobody gets paid.
If nobody gets paid, then
nobody comes to see my...
Aah!
Ahh.
Son of a bitch.
Now, we have an agreement.
[Screaming]
There's a better way, brother.
Aah!
Straight and steady, please, sir.
Yes, ma'am.
Mrs. Bell, somebody's coming.
Mrs. Bell.
Mr. Bohannon.
What you doin' out here?
Surveying.
I'm helping Durant
complete his 40 miles.
We killed the dog soldiers
that murdered your husband.
I thought you should know.
So, Robert's death has been avenged.
I'd hoped it would close
the hole I feel in my heart.
Ain't nothin' gonna
close that up, ma'am.
Ahem.
Very impressive, Mr., uh...
Ferguson.
Elam Ferguson.
I suppose Mr.
Bohannon sent you to collect the bounty.
Bohannon ain't take them scalps.
I did.
I guess I owe you some money, then.
Uh...$10 a scalp,
if I remember correctly.
20.
And if you don't mind,
I prefer them gold eagles to paper.
Well...
Would you like a drink?
I ain't too much of a drinkin' man.
Hmm. Well...
A cigar, perhaps?
Thank you.
Well, please... sit.
You strike me as a capable man.
I know which end is up.
Well, that is good to know.
Because I am always on
the lookout for a man
willing to get his hands
dirty from time to time.
A man who's willing to, uh...
Do things off the books, as it were.
I'm looking for a man who wants
to be feared and respected.
A man trying to improve
his station in life.
[Woman moaning]
Oh, you slay me, honey.
You really do.
[Moaning]
How's about you stay home tonight?
Whatcha mean?
I means... why not take a night off?
Maybe take more than a night off.
Are you saying...
I want you to be mine.
None other.
Man:
Ferguson, you in there?
Elam Ferguson, come on out here.
You...
You son of a bitch.
Mercy.
On the immaculate heart
of the sweet virgin herself,
I pray for mercy.
And I beg you to hear me out.
You shot me straight
in me gob, Mr. Ferguson.
A shot that would
any man to his grave,
but praise the mother's son,
at the last second...
An angel reached out...
And she flicked
the bullet out of me neck.
I tell you, it's true.
It's the reason
I kneel before you now.
Let me show you.
Let me show you the hole.
Please, Mr. Ferguson.
Bear witness to a miracle.
As I wandered in the wilderness,
like our lord himself...
I came face to face with me
ignorance and cruelty towards you.
And I swore to God almighty
that if I survived,
I would come to you on bended knee
and beg for your forgiveness.
Not me.
Her.
Come on out here.
You tell her you're sorry.
I'm sorry, Lass.
Sorry as the sorriest sinner.
I should not have harmed you such.
All right, then.
Elam: Go on and git.
Man: Black Moon.
Come down.
It's your father.
Father, you're safe.
I come looking for Pawnee killer.
Instead, I find a burial.
Have you nothing to tell me?
I came to do it myself.
Go.
Climb up.
Let's complete the ceremony.
Step right this way,
lads, and get an eyeful.
See the loveliest creatures
from the bluest streets of Paris,
France. Hey.
See soiled doves bare all.
You been gone.
Took the train to Chicago.
Whew, what a town.
Jeez.
Looks like you brought a bit
of Chicago back with you.
Indeed.
Do you want to take a peek?
[Whistling and hollering]
On the house, of course.
Anything for Mr. Bohannon.
[Men whistling]
Ah. Thanks.
Hold on.
Sean would like a word with you.
Looks like you been
doing some business, hmm?
Aye, we're packin' 'em
in like sardines.
How'd you pay for the extra slides?
Win another fight or somethin'?
[Whistling and hollering
in background]
Yeah.
'Course, the, uh...
The Swede will want his pound of flesh.
He takes a cut?
And then some.
What you want me
to do about it, Sean?
Here's the thing.
We're not the only
ones being preyed upon.
All the merchants of Hell on Wheels
are payin' him off.
So...
So... we took up a collection.
Everybody pitched in.
There's $100 in here... for you.
What the hell for?
For killin' the Swede.
I ain't no gun for hire.
[Sighs]
All right, I tell you what...
I happen to know the Swede's
been stealing from Durant.
Dig you up some dirt on him,
and Durant will ride him
out of town on a rail...
Free.
[Indistinct chatter]
[Chatter stops]
Ask me to sit down.
Go on, ask me.
Have a seat.
[Indistinct chatter resumes]
Now... pour me a drink.
Another glass.
Your health.
[Exhales]
Tastes like shit.
You ain't much of
a drinking man, is you?
Gave it up.
Why is that?
Last time I got drunk...
I got into somethin' bad.
Listen, I need to ask you somethin'.
You know that bidness
we had to attend to?
You good with that?
I'm better than good.
'Bout time I be the one
who gets to do the hurtin'.
Besides...
Seem Mr. Durant
took a likin' to my work.
He say he might just
call on me when need be.
Durant?
Better watch yourself.
That's a slick slope
you're headin' down.
Slick with blood.
Somebody else's, for a change.
For somebody who don't drink,
you're putting that down pretty good.
[Bangs]
Ladies and gentlemen...
Take your glasses in hand for a toast
to the great Indian killers
who have made our home
a safe place to work and drink!
[All cheering]
Shut up!
Listen up.
I want y'all to get
a good night's sleep.
Tomorrow, we hit that 40-mile marker,
and I'm gonna work
y'all like mongrel dogs.
It's gonna get built, gentlemen.
And we're just
the bastards to build it.
[All cheering]
Senator.
I am glad you were able to
witness such a momentous feat.
No, you're not.
You're only interested
in our quid pro quo.
If you insist.
I had the Pinkerton track down
the Illinois man you were looking for.
"Whereabouts
of Sergeant Frank Harper."
Seems he's holed up at a trading
post near council bluffs.
Your brother was
the runt of the litter.
Smaller than all the other boys.
Ah, they picked on him
and teased him.
He was always in a fight,
but he never backed down.
It made him strong.
It made him a great warrior.
But not a great man.
He never learned, as you did,
that... sometimes,
it's better not to fight,
and other times...
You must fight the ones you love.
When I saw what you were wearing...
When I saw what you had
prepared for your brother,
I hoped that you would return to me.
But now, I see in your eyes...
You are becoming your own man.
And so today, I mourn for one son,
Pawnee killer.
And I mourn the loss
of my other son, Black Moon...
Which hurts me so much more.
[Men yelling throughout]
That's it boys, almost there!
This is it right here!
This is your marker!
We're gonna make it.
Now put your backs into it.
Pick it up, boys!
I want them next two rails
laid in the next 5 minutes.
Pick up the pace.
We run out of flanges again,
I'll skin the runner alive!
Hold the spike with
it. Hold the spike.
Well, jeez!
3, 2, 1.
[Men grunt]
Swede: That's it, boys, almost there.
Break time's over.
Back to work.
Don't bloody look at it, sink!
[Indistinct shouting]
Nail crew, just get 'em nailed in!
Clean-up crew, finish it.
1, 2, 3!
That's it.
Back into it.
[Train whistle blows]
Almost there!
You embarrass me now, boys,
and I'll skin the lot of ya.
Let's go!
[Train whistle blowing]
[Indistinct shouting continues]
Hold! Down.
Last one, boys!
Last one.
Durant:
Mr. Bohannon!
May I?
Ahh.
Ah.
[Crowd cheering]
[Laughs]
Congratulations.
[Indistinct]
[Cheering and applause]
Ruth?
I'm sorry.
You were waiting for me?
Every night.
Joseph, are you hurt?
No.
I killed him, Ruth.
[Crying]
I killed my own brother.
[Kisses]
[Harmonica playing]
[Crowd cheering]
Thanks.
[Indistinct chatter]
Excuse me, sir?
Yeah?
Oh. Pardon me, ma'am.
What will you be having?
Well, um...
Champagne, perhaps?
Uh... ahem. What?
Um... how about a glass of Sherry?
I love a good Sherry.
Ah. Brandy.
Fine.
Brandy would be fine.
It's on me.
May I?
By all means.
Thank you.
Not good?
Uh... I've had better.
Ahh. Yeah.
Well, you did it.
40 miles.
You said you would, and you did.
First time in my life.
Failed as a tobacco farmer,
lost a war...
Now I'm a railroad man.
Maybe third time's the charm, huh?
Maybe.
That first night we met, uh...
You told me I had no idea who you was
or what you was capable of, and...
You was right.
Ha ha.
I thought you were some
spoiled limey brat.
Uh.
Yeah, I guess I got you wrong, huh?
Well, what do you think
of me now, Mr. Bohannon?
Mrs. Bell!
Mr. Bohannon!
Ahem.
Doing a little celebrating?
Well, you both deserve it.
What you did today was historic.
Thank you, Thomas.
Will you join us?
I would love to, but, um...
There are a few issues outstanding
that I need to discuss
with my foreman.
Excuse me.
Black Moon.
You in here?
Black Moon?
You made me a pledge.
You told me you would win this
war called the Union Pacific.
Today, you won a major battle.
You're a man of your word.
Thank you, sir.
I wanted to both congratulate
you and offer you a bonus.
Oh. I don't need any more money, sir.
It's not that kind
of bonus, Mr. Bohannon.
It's much more valuable than money.
Information.
Oh, you... you're Lieutenant Griggs
from the Calvary.
I heard about you.
Yeah?
Well, I heard Black Moon
was livin' in here.
You feel that Joseph led you astray?
He needs to be made accountable.
You know, the Swede has been,
shall we say,
focused on you for some time.
Like a hound got the scent.
He just sent a wire
to the federal marshals
in Washington, D.C.
Claims he has evidence
linking you to
several murders back east.
You a family man, Lieutenant?
Do you have a wife and children?
I mean, what if...
If someone, uh...
Killed your son and scalped
your daughter and raped your wife?
Would you stand idly by?
They'll be coming to arrest you.
You telling me all this 'cause
you want me to run, Mr. Durant?
I'm giving you a chance
to save yourself, Bohannon.
I don't know, could you... could you...
Find it in your heart to forgive him?
Is he here?
Not now?
Sure, I'll forgive him.
Right after I kill him.
We're... we're all held accountable...
You know, one way or another.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com