Previously on "Killer Women"...
Parker!
What's up, babe?
Not you. Your sister.
You're for real? Thought
all rangers were dudes.
I keep forgetting they let
lady folk into the ranks.
Just two.
- Didn't expect to see you here.
- My ex-husband.
Not quite yet.
This marriage is over.
I am the judge here, Ranger Parker,
and it isn't over till I say it's over.
I'm never gonna divorce you.
(Lowered voice) Sign the divorce papers,
or I'll tell the world who you really are.
Don't forget you have to take
Lu to swim practice tonight.
- I can't.
- You're busy again?
You need to tell me what
is going on right now.
- And I want the truth.
- I have to go into town.
He's screwing around.
- Lady wanna go up on the plane?
- No.
Why not? Don't you trust me?
(Engine roaring) You're safe.
I believe you.
(Screeching)
(Aloe Blacc's "Can you do this" playing)
♪ Grab your shotgun, cock it back ♪
♪ shoot the sun until
the sky is black ♪
Now you have a great day, sir.
If you open a checking account,
Beeville Union will give you
- a free and very pretty microwave.
- (Woman) Howdy!
Would you like to open
a checking account today?
(Women scream)
(Woman) Everybody down on the ground!
Nobody move! You, get up! (Woman whimpers)
- Empty your register.
- (Cash register dings)
♪ Now I don't know who you
are, but, girl, I wanna know ♪
You, down!
Hey!
You reach for the dye pack again,
the next shot's your head. Understand? Yes.
Hurry it up.
♪ And you
(siren wailing)
♪ Gonna make me fall in love with you ♪
♪ if you keep on shaking your hips ♪
♪ now can you do this? ♪
(Wailing continues)
- (Pops and crackles)
- ♪ can you do this? ♪
(Wailing continues)
♪ I know you think
that you can't move ♪
(Wailing continues)
(Engine revs, gunshots)
♪
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(chicken clucking in distance)
Irrigation in the back pasture's fine.
Okay. Good to know.
You told me and Becca
that something was wrong with the pump.
I checked. The pump's fine.
Feel free to help, molls.
(Chuckles) Really.
(Rustles and thuds)
You're wife thinks you're cheatin' on her.
Well, maybe my wife should
address me with that,
- and not my sister.
- (Feed clatters)
What are you really doing
when you go out at all hours?
You know what? I never once asked
what went on between you
and that jackhole senator
that you married,
so why don't you afford me the same respect
and stay the hell out of
my business? (Bag thuds)
Hey! (Bag scrapes and thuds)
What are you two fighting about?
(Sighs) You know, cattle.
I need you inside now.
Yes, ma'am.
- I like the sound of that.
- (Chuckles) No. No.
Stop. Stop. The dog
puked in the living room.
Again.
(Cows moo)
(Motors rumbling)
(Radio chatter)
Ranger Parker. It's always a pleasure,
even when it's an unpleasurable situation.
Sounds like this one
was exciting, at least.
Yeah, we don't get too many
bank robberies around here,
definitely none with napalm and flares.
Since this is a bank job, FBI came in, too,
after I called you.
This is Special Agent Linda Clark, FBI.
Molly Parker, Texas Rangers.
You've got quite the reputation, Ranger.
Do I?
Well, since I don't know
exactly what that means,
I'm gonna take it as a
compliment. (Chuckles)
Oh, yeah. I would.
Take it from me, honey.
It's always good to
ignore interagency chatter,
especially when it's about yourself.
Okay. I wasn't aware...
Keep doing what you're doing.
I'll do my best.
So what do you have so far?
Well, the suspect came in
wearing a motorcycle helmet.
No visual I.D.,
but the witnesses confirmed female.
She was wearing gloves, so no prints.
- How much money did she get?
- Almost 18 grand.
- Marked?
- Nah.
She knew to avoid G.P.S. trackers,
she didn't touch anything,
and she picked up all her casings.
This wasn't her first rodeo.
What can the Rangers do to help?
(Chuckles)
Usually, this is where I give my spiel
about you should let the FBI handle this,
because we're bank robbery experts,
and we do this every
single day of our lives.
But if you think you can add value,
then you go right ahead.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I've got one-half of a
modern-day Bonnie and Clyde
on the loose.
It's gonna be fun.
Well... I guess I'll
see if I can "add value."
Hmm.
- (Speaking inaudibly)
- Who are they?
Witnesses.
I'm sure y'all are shaken,
but this'll be real quick.
Besides the motorcycle helmet and the gun,
can any of you remember
anything about the suspect?
She was downright rude.
Anything else?
She was wearing black leather lowriders.
Okay.
- And you're certain she was a "she"?
- Yes, ma'am.
She went out like this and out like that.
What's that?
It looks like your tiara collected
a little bit of evidence.
(Woman) Hi! How would you like
to open a checking account?
(Gunshots, women scream)
- Hi! How would you like to open a checking account?
- Suspect hit 3 1-inch targets,
- on the move, at 10 meters.
- (Women scream)
(Screams)
Practice makes perfect.
Oh, and I gave the FBI a
heads-up on the shell casing
from the beauty queen's
crown. It's in the lab.
Where they got a hit.
The shell matched the casing collected
at a bank robbery in edna last month.
The suspect wore a ball cap
and bandana during the robbery.
But...
Traffic cam got a shot
of her leaving the scene.
How much money did she get away with?
$8,000. She only got
the cash from one drawer.
She was less experienced.
And no napalm there.
(Thuds)
She's escalating, getting smarter. (Typing)
(Beeps)
- What?
- The teller gave her sequential bills
and recorded the numbers.
Some of those bills turned
up in a D.E.A. investigation.
The D.E.A. is slow as dial-up
when it comes to interagency cooperation.
Luckily... you got a high-speed connection.
Luckily, that's none of your business.
(Chuckles)
(Mariachi music playing)
You can't force me into counseling, Jake.
Neither can the judge.
Well, cancel the session. I'm not going.
I'll take my chances. (Beep)
- Hi.
- (Sighs)
You and the Senator
have to go to counseling?
(Sighs) Four times in the next month,
before the judge will even
consider my divorce petition.
How exactly do you walk
into court for a divorce
and walk out in marriage counseling?
Welcome to Texas.
The judge has a right to delay,
and the judge is Jake's buddy.
- You okay?
- (Mouth full) Not especially.
Want to talk about it?
Not especially. Ketchup.
Did you find my bank robber?
(Mouth full, chuckles) You wish.
(Clears throat)
(Lowered voice) D.E.A.
has an informer in a gang
who steals and deals prescription meds.
A street dealer named "Q-Ball"
was re-upping his inventory of oxycodone.
He paid our guy with bills
from your bank robbery.
So your q-ball and my perp are intimate.
A drug dealer and his addict...
can't get more intimate than that.
Where's q-ball being held?
Nowhere. We're not gonna arrest him
until we roll up the whole crew.
But you know where he is, right?
Then come on. Let's go.
You know... (Clears throat)
I really just wanna finish
my bacon burger, okay?
God, I walked right into that.
(Crickets chirping)
(Clatter in distance)
Yo, Q-Ball, open the
door! (Q-Ball) Stay back!
I got a shotgun pointed right at your head.
(Lowered voice) It's all right.
Gonna light you up right through the door,
- send you to hell.
- (Lowered voice) That doesn't sound all right.
Trust me, the only thing
that q-ball can effectively
light up in his bong.
We're comin' in!
Hold your breath. The guy smokes
more inventory than he sells.
Ugh! (Grunts)
You again.
- What did I do now?
- Bought major weight of oxy.
That'll get you a long stretch.
You can't prove that.
Oh, as a matter of fact, I can.
We need some information
on one of your customers.
Oh, I'm gonna have to assert my privileges.
And what did they look like?
Well, I've been researching
it on the Internet.
I run an "alternative pharmacy."
And that makes me a health care provider.
- Patient information is confidential.
- You're serious?
- Hell, yes.
- Cool.
Well, let's see if the U.S.
attorney agrees with you.
Can I borrow your handcuffs for a second?
Wait! Wait. What did you want again?
Last time you restocked your pharmacy,
you paid with some new
hundred-dollar bills.
- I did?
- Yeah.
Most of the bills that
pass through your hands
are crumbled-up twenties covered in snot.
- Oh!
- Oh, there it is. Yeah.
(Whispers) Yeah.
Those hundreds. Nice.
Where did you get 'em?
- Oh, from the Terminator.
- The Terminator?
He is a customer.
He's got, like, one of those robot arms.
The Terminator is a "he"?
I'm pretty sure I know the difference.
He's got a girlfriend?
Do I look like a matchmaker?
How do we find him?
- Dude usually scores every Tuesday and Friday.
- Where?
My pharmacy.
(Dan) It's Tuesday.
(Molly) Yep. Supposed to be Terminator day.
(Sighs)
Look at Basil shake it.
- Basil?
- Ah! Ah!
Don't... denigrate Basil.
She's my good luck charm at stakeouts.
(Moos) Can you do that?
(Vehicle approaching)
(Sighs)
15 years doing stakeouts,
and they still suck.
I don't know. I kinda like 'em.
Huh?
You enjoy sitting around,
wishing something would happen?
I'm not an adrenaline junkie like you.
I'm not an adrenaline junkie.
I just... if I don't have
something to react to,
I get bored.
I'm bored.
(Chuckles) (Sighs)
Life can't be big all the time.
- Basil disagrees.
- (Moos)
(Chuckles) (Grunts)
- Someplace I'd like to be?
- Hmm?
You just went somewhere else on me there.
(Sighs)
I was thinking about my mom.
Stakeouts remind me of her.
Is she a wanted felon? (Chuckles)
She died when I was 11.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
You had no idea.
How?
Cancer.
(Sighs) Oh.
(Sniffs)
(Sighs) The whole month before she died,
she would lie on an old
couch on the screened porch,
where the sunlight kept her warm.
Dad said Billy and I weren't
supposed to bother her,
but... (Chuckles)
I'd go in there all the time. (Chuckles)
- Oh, that's surprising.
- (Chuckles)
(Clicks tongue) Uh...
sometimes she'd wake up...
and we'd talk about the small things...
something an animal did that was funny.
(Sniffles)
But mostly I just sat
there and watched her.
I guess waiting reminds
me of my mom. (Chuckles)
(Flicks toy)
(Chuckles) (Chuckles)
You owe my cow an apology.
(Car doors shut)
Who's she?
I don't know. You're girlfriend, maybe?
- I'm married.
- Does your wife like to rob banks?
(Clears throat) Who's she?
Special Agent Clark, FBI.
Sorry to interrupt your fun here,
but I was uninformed
you were being detained
up until an hour ago.
Welcome to the party.
Shouldn't have started without me.
(Chair scrapes floor)
What's this woman's connection to you?
I just told her. I don't know her.
Well, the thing is, Mr. Lauterbach,
those nice new hundred-dollar bills
we found in your pocket
were stolen from a bank...
by her.
She steal the money, give it to you
so you can get high?
So I can "get high"?
I got this arm blown off in Afghanistan,
and it still hurts like hot needles
sticking in it, even
though the arm ain't there.
That's pretty funny, huh?
That's why I "get high."
You could go to a V.A. hospital.
No, I did. They gave
me a bottle of aspirin.
Who's the girl?
I just told you.
I never saw her before in my life.
Then where'd you get the money?
I found it...
under my pillow.
I know it sounds far-fetched, but...
It didn't seem like he was lying.
Really?
I'm trained to read
tells, and I'm good at it.
I'm sure.
Why don't you take a shot?
♪
Okay.
I'll start slow, Mr. Winston.
- It is Mr. Winston?
- It is.
Did you sleep alone last night?
Did I sleep alone last night?
- Yes.
- That's a lie.
Oh, you're a genius, since
you were lying right beside me.
(Chuckles) It was a control question.
Ah. Mr. Winston...
last night, did you like
it when I took my tongue...
(Whispers inaudibly)
♪
Yes.
You're telling the truth.
- Oh, 100%.
- (Chuckles)
Okay, Mr. Winston.
Would you like to go back to your place
and let me do that exact same thing again?
Would I like to go back to my place? Yes.
What?
You're lyin'.
- No, I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
You always repeat the
question back before you lie.
(Chuckles)
But it's not a total lie.
I would love to go back to my place...
just, after we eat. It is finally Tuesday.
And I have been waiting since last Tuesday
- for Elizondo's carnitas.
- (Speaking inaudibly)
Son of a bitch.
(Under breath) I'm gonna kill him.
(Engine revs)
Billy!
(Sighs)
(Door creaks)
(Chickens clucking in distance)
(Rustles)
(Coffee pot clatters)
It is my business.
What is your business?
This is my family, too,
and I'm not gonna let you destroy it.
Wow, Molly, that is real heroic of you.
(Sighs)
(Mug clatters)
I saw you with a woman.
(Newspaper rustles) What woman?
This is how it's gonna work...
you're gonna keep it in your pants,
- or I'm gonna tell Becca.
- (Scoffs)
And you will lose everything.
Molly.
I thought I heard you.
This is Corinne.
She's gonna help us plan
Hailee's quinceañera party.
(Billy) I just picked her up in town.
As long as Hailee
doesn't fall off the rails
- anytime soon.
- (Chuckles)
Hi. (Chuckles) It's so
great to finally meet you.
I'm just... a little star-struck...
a ranger and a lady.
Molly, you remember Garrett McCarthy...
my buddy from high school?
Well, Corinne here is his wife.
That's me. (Chuckles)
She just started her own
party planning business.
(Corinne) I am so excited
to help with Hailee's quinceañera.
It's gonna be an amazing party, I promise.
(Chuckles) Great. Amazing. I...
- I can't wait.
- What were you two talking about?
- Nothin'.
(Crickets chirping,
dog barking in distance)
(Door creaking)
(Floorboard creaks)
(Paper bag rustling)
- (Girl) Hi.
- (Gasps)
Are you the tooth fairy?
(Dog barking in distance)
(Man) Way I see it, God was testing me.
And I'm not gonna lie about it.
I was real tempted to keep the money.
I think anybody would be.
$12,000...
in cash,
right by my bed.
Was there a note or anything
- explaining why the money had been left?
- Nothin'.
(Chuckles)
I tried to convince myself
an angel had left it.
You know, just find some reason to keep it.
You know...
I lost my house last year,
and, uh, I had to move back in with my mom.
I really wanted to make
a go of it on my own.
I mean, I'm on disability.
I get treatment at the V.A.,
but there's no provision for extra money
to keep things like...
(Chuckles) your own house.
So what made you notify the
police about the money then?
(Chuckles) Stupidity.
- (Chuckles)
- (Chuckles) No, I...
I know not to take what isn't mine.
Simple as that.
Did you see the person who left the cash?
(Inhales deeply) I didn't.
(Exhales deeply) But my
little sister Katy did.
Katy. (Grunts)
Come here, mija.
It's okay.
Hi, Katy. I'm Molly.
I like your hat.
(Chuckles) Oh, thank you.
I like your friend.
Sweetie, can you tell me
anything about the person
that was sneaking around
in here the other night?
She wasn't the tooth fairy.
And how do you know that?
I asked her.
You spoke to the lady?
Well, what else did she say?
She said that she liked Rudy.
'Cause she was an armadillo, too.
- She said she was an armadillo?
- Yes, ma'am.
An armadillo who liked to fight.
(Chuckles)
You're awesome.
(Car door closes)
Sheriff?
I'll be damned.
What's a Ranger doin' out this way?
Just running down a lead
on a bank robbery suspect.
Now that might make more sense
if we still had a bank.
I'm thinking the suspect
might be from around here.
♪
Bifocals. (Chuckles)
(Chuckles) Any chance you recognize her?
(Eyeglasses clatter)
- You're joking, right?
- No.
Well, then you're chasing the wrong girl,
because that's Andrea Corbett.
Why would I be wrong about her?
She's a distinguished 'dillo.
- A what?
- Come on over here.
I want to show you something.
Might be surprised who
lives in our little town.
All our distinguished citizens are up here.
And let's see. Where's Andrea?
Bingo! That's Andrea.
She's a bona fide... a war hero.
Hello?
Texas Rangers.
(Doorknob clicks)
(Door creaks)
(Door bangs wall)
- Anybody home?
- (Man) Who's there?
Mr. Corbett?
Yes, ma'am.
I'm Ranger Parker.
Are you Andrea's dad?
Yes, I am.
- I'm here because...
- Please don't tell me my daughter's dead.
That's Andrea,
the day before she left for Afghanistan...
proud, beautiful, and brave.
Are you sure it's Andrea
robbing these banks?
I'm afraid so. Two that we know of.
(Scoffs)
Well, she's been all riled
up ever since she got home.
- Do you think she's using drugs?
- No, no, no.
She's a medic. She's
dealt with drug addicts.
Nope, this is something else.
- You were also in the army, sir?
- Yes, ma'am.
20 years, combat medic.
My little girl wanted
to do what her daddy did,
only she did it a whole lot better.
Andrea was awarded the Silver Star.
That's the third highest
military decoration for valor.
You understand that?
You know what that means?
It means your daughter is a hero.
Yes, ma'am. She is.
(Object clatters) But when she got home,
she was on edge all the time.
Impatient.
She used to be just the opposite.
I mean, hell, she'd
fight with people in line
at the post office over
nothing. (Silverware clinking)
I thought she just needed more discipline,
like she was used to.
So I instituted some house rules...
early morning P.T., bed
checks, cleaning duties.
(Lid clanks)
It only made things worse.
She started to argue with me,
and that never used to happen.
What did you fight about?
(Clatters) How the V.A. wasn't
doing this and that for the soldiers.
She said she needed to do
something about it to fix it.
And then, suddenly...
- she changed.
- How?
Well, she wasn't angry anymore.
She was calm.
"Corporal Corbett traversed
into hostile territory
under heavy fire to drag
a wounded soldier to safety.
After administering life-saving care,
she picked up the soldier's
rifle and single-handedly
assaulted the nearest enemy position,
killing four insurgents
and wounding many others."
This woman is a hero.
"Corporal Corbett then
repelled repeated enemy assaults
until reinforcements arrived."
We already know she's a skilled marksman.
"Her calm and focus under
fire were remarkable."
Ranger, I don't know if you notice,
but this is Texas, not Afghanistan.
Her violence is... is escalating.
And we don't give out
medals for robbing banks.
You're not hearing me.
She's calm when she robs,
and then gives away the money.
This is a woman who feels
the need to be heroic,
but doesn't know how to
be a hero in civilian life.
And that's sad.
Fortunately, yours is the
only heart that's breaking.
(Sighs) Lieutenant, are we
here to praise Andrea Corbett,
or do we want to stop her
before she kills somebody?
We've distributed the suspect's photo
to all area banks. They've
stepped up precautions,
added extra security,
activated silent alarms.
Then you've covered the basics, Lieutenant.
I expect to be kept in the loop.
I'm not walking into another interrogation
15 minutes after it started.
(Object clatters) You know...
I had a chance to apply
to the FBI one time.
And?
I didn't care for the dress code.
(Mouse clicks)
(Indistinct conversations)
(Sighs) What a nice surprise.
Yeah. I wish this was.
(Envelope rustles)
You got a subpoena?
Yep. From your not-quite-yet ex-husband.
He wants me to testify
in your divorce case.
- About what?
- I don't know.
Probably those things
you do with your tongue.
He's raising an adultery claim.
How does that help him?
Turn the judge against you,
maybe push things his way.
Because I won't go to those
damn counseling sessions.
It seems like your life
would be a lot easier
if you just did what the judge said.
- No.
- (Scoffs) Well, I'm not telling you to reconcile.
Just... grind through the sessions.
Then you'll get your divorce.
And I don't have to testify in open court.
Oh, did your fun, carefree lifestyle
just get complicated?
Yes, it did.
And I'm okay with that.
Well, then what's the problem?
I'm an undercover D.E.A. Agent, Molly.
This is a public case. It's a big problem.
Listen to me.
A tactical surrender
isn't always a bad thing.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
You're not thinking of yourself here,
- not at all?
- Thinking about myself? No.
I'm thinking of the best way
to handle a bad situation.
- You just repeated the question.
- What?
It's your tell.
- When you lie, you repeat the question first.
- Oh.
- Come on.
- I'm sorry my divorce is such an inconvenience for you.
Whoa. Whoa, Molly.
Hey. Look. (Sighs)
Look, let's just take a step back.
I've got a better idea.
Let's take a real big step back.
That way you can go back to your old life
just like you want to.
Are you serious right now?
Because if you are, I'm offended.
(Huffs) Come on, Dan.
We both know you're not
a long-distance runner.
(Envelope rustles) I've got work to do.
(Bahamas' "lost in the light" playing)
♪ I'm lost in the light ♪
♪ I pray for the night ♪
♪ to take me ♪
♪ to take me to ♪
♪ I held my own ♪
♪ still I rattled your bones ♪
♪ I've said some awful things ♪
♪ and I take them back ♪
♪ if we would try again ♪
♪ just remember when ♪
♪ before we were lovers ♪
♪ I swear we were friends
♪ so if someone could see me now ♪
♪ let them see you ♪
(Andrea) Stay down!
- Hurry up!
- (Alarm ringing)
Hurry up! Go! Behind her.
Behind where I can see you.
(Bell dings)
Hurry!
(Man) Ma'am, drop the gun!
Please, put your hands up.
Just get outta my way.
Ma'am, I can't let you
leave with the money.
Move outta my way now.
(Alarm continues ringing)
Tom...
look at me.
Your hands are shaking.
That's because stress
is causing epinephrine
to surge through your veins.
If you pull that trigger...
you have almost a zero
chance of hitting me.
Now look at my hands, Tom.
When I pull the trigger,
which I will do if you don't move,
you will die.
Now if you don't want that to happen,
move out of my way.
Please, ma'am. I cannot do that.
(Sirens wailing in distance)
- Aah! Aah!
- (Gun clatters)
- (Siren continues wailing)
- (Groaning)
(Woman speaking indistinctly over P.A.)
Hi there.
I'm looking for Tom Sikorsky.
He was shot in a bank robbery.
- I understand he's out of surgery?
- (Typing)
There is a good chance he's still sedated,
but he is in room... 312.
- Elevator's down the hall to your right.
- Thanks.
Sure.
(Monitor beeping steadily)
(Indistinct conversations)
Excuse me. You can't be in here.
Visiting hours don't start till 10:00.
Uh, I'm sorry.
I just wanted to see how he was doing.
(Elevator bell dings)
I see that the bullet
missed his femoral artery.
And you are...
Oh. His niece.
You really shouldn't be in here.
If you leave your number,
I'll call you when he wakes up.
That would be so nice.
Um... do you have a pen?
There's one at the nurse's station.
Thanks a million.
Wait. Uh... are you with
the girl who was here?
No, ma'am. Ranger Parker.
Any chance he'll wake up soon?
That's hard to say.
I'll tell you what I just told his niece,
- leave your number, and I'll call you.
- His niece was just here?
Yeah. I don't know what happened to her.
- Is that from her?
- Could be.
I didn't notice it there before.
(Rustles)
- That niece... when did she leave?
- Like, two seconds ago.
She was standing right here. I...
(blinds rattle)
(Banging on window) Hey, Clark!
(Sighs) Call security.
(Engine revving)
(Siren wailing, tires screeching)
(Static crackles) Sierra one.
(Siren wailing)
(Tires screech)
(Engine revving)
(Tires peal, siren wailing)
(Tires screech)
(Sirens continue wailing)
(Brakes squeal)
Shooter's on the roof. Take cover.
(Grunts)
I will blow his brains
out! Stay the hell back!
(Molly) Andrea, it's over! Let him go!
Move! Okay, okay.
- Move! Go. Get up!
- (Grunts)
Let him go!
(Glass shattering)
(Gunshot)
How do you like your war hero now?
(Breathing heavily)
- Move, move. Down! Go!
- (Clark) You're surrounded.
Stay low! Drop your weapon and
come out with your hands up!
I'll communicate with your sniper directly.
- You're planning on taking her out?
- Oh, yeah.
She's not firing blanks.
Don't you think it's odd
that she's a skilled marksman
and hasn't hit anyone?
Well, maybe she's having an off day.
Now step out of my way
and let me do my job.
Sierra one, are you set up yet?
Sierra one in position.
Let me know when you have a shot.
(Static crackles)
I'm clear.
Don't do this. Let me talk to her.
- Take the shot.
- Copy that.
Delay that order. This
is Texas Ranger Parker.
The suspect is a decorated army veteran.
Stand down, Parker. Now!
She's deliberately aiming off target.
She won't shoot to kill.
We have a hostage at gunpoint.
We need to help her, not kill her.
(Static crackles) Sierra
one, I repeat, take the shot
if you've got the suspect locked.
(Static crackles)
Target's obscured.
Say again, Sierra one.
I repeat, the target's obscured.
I don't have a shot.
Parker, you're out of your league.
Just back down. What
the hell are you doing?
Bringing her in. Andrea?
Up. Up, up, up.
I'm Ranger Molly Parker.
I'm coming over to talk.
One more step, and this man dies.
I don't believe that.
(Belt clatters) You're a medic.
You take care of people just like he does.
Let him go.
You know how this ends if you don't.
(Breathing heavily)
Fine. I'll kill you instead.
You need to turn yourself in.
No one needs to die here.
Then let me go, and no one will.
You know that's not gonna happen.
And it would be a damn shame
for you to survive Afghanistan
and get killed in a parking lot in Texas.
Really? You think anybody cares?
I know they do.
Who cares about those vets
that I gave the money to?
They lost their houses,
they lost their limbs.
And all they got from the government
- was the runaround.
- People care about them.
- I care about them.
- Yeah?
What have you ever done?
These people get home,
and all they've got
waiting for them is bills.
No parades. No "thank you"s.
They get off the plane,
and they have to search
for enough money to get a bus home.
So you're doing this for them?
Every... single... one.
Only thing is, Andrea, that isn't true.
So you're telling me why
I'm doing what I'm doing?
That's a bit much.
I talked to your daddy.
You got home from the
war, you were all antsy.
You only got calm again when
you started robbing banks.
'Cause I was doing the right thing. No.
Because it got your adrenaline rushing
just like combat did.
Your silver star citation said
how calm you were in battle.
You've got 50 guns
pointed at you right now,
and you're as cool as the
other side of the pillow.
It's the only way you can feel good again.
You're throwing some money to some vets.
But you're doing this to
make yourself feel better.
I've got a gun pointed at your head,
and you don't seem real shaken.
Maybe you got the same problem I do.
I know you won't kill me. What I don't know
is if one of these cops is gonna kill you.
But that's your plan, isn't it?
You know you can't rob
banks 24 hours a day,
so that's not a long-term solution.
You're looking for some
other way to end your pain.
You calling me a coward?
No, not a coward.
You've been wounded. You need help.
- There are people that can help you.
- (Cries)
I'll make sure they do.
Andrea, you're not alone.
- Your daddy loved you with everything in him.
- (Sobs)
Just put the gun down...
and let someone help you for once.
(Crying)
(Whispers) It's time to stop fighting.
(Sobs)
(Gasps, breathing deeply)
(Handcuffs clinking)
You're gonna be okay.
(Exhales deeply)
(Woman) ♪ waking in the
morning, feeling slow ♪
The theme's the most important,
so you can pick the color
and strategize from there,
but if we get the theme,
then we can pick the color.
(Clatter)
♪ Ain't no reason for
the hustle and flow ♪
♪ because I got good
lovin', that's all I know ♪
♪ desert high ♪
♪ desert low ♪
(sobbing)
♪ Ain't no joke, I'm
gonna steal my soul ♪
♪ desert high ♪
♪ desert low ♪
♪ and you can tell anybody
that I told you so ♪
(Jet roaring)
(Turns off engine)
(Seat belt clicks)
(Moos)
(Cell phone chimes)
♪ You take a long walk
down a dusty road ♪
♪ just let that sun warm my soul ♪
♪ hiding in the plains
where the wild winds wail ♪
♪ just taking my turn
with the holy grail ♪
♪ home is a heart and it has a beat ♪
(Buttons clicking)
♪ But it could be a rock,
and it could be a tree ♪
(Line rings)
- (Woman) Family and marriage counseling.
- Yes, this is Molly Parker.
I'm calling to schedule a
counseling session with Jake Colton.
Is this court-appointed counseling?
That's right.
Marriage counseling.
Okay, so we have an opening
tomorrow at 2:00 P.M.
Will that work for you?
2:00 P.M. tomorrow's fine.
Great. We'll see you then.
♪ Ain't no joke, I'm
gonna steal my soul ♪
♪ desert high ♪
♪ desert low ♪
♪ you can tell anybody ♪
Corporal?
♪ That I told you so ♪
I'd just like to thank you
for everything you've done.
♪ That I told you so ♪
♪ mmm, tell anybody
that I told you so ♪
(Indistinct conversations)
(Woman speaking indistinctly over P.A.)
Lieutenant? What is it?
Dan's been shot.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -