What you want to be is the trailblazer.
Bill: And that takes you where, exactly?
To the Yukon.
Bill: It was 4,650 miles,
six weeks nonstop.
Dawson City. Where naiveté comes to die.
First name's Jack, last name's London,
and I recommend you putting
that away in your memory.
Man: Folks around here,
they're hungry for gold.
1,000 years ago, there was a landslide...
pulling gold out of the hillside.
Waiting for a couple half-asses like us.
Byron: You're just guessing.
We're all just guessing.
- [Gunshot, dogs barking]
- Ep?
Who'd do it?
Who wouldn't?
Man: Word is mounties are on their way.
Superintendent: I've heard
the local tribe up here
think the land is theirs.
I spend my time thinking
about more lucrative things,
like my hotel, the Fairview.
Count: Forgive me,
Father, for I have sinned.
When did you commit these acts?
Well, I haven't yet.
You got a day to vacate.
We didn't kill your friend.
That's not good enough.
I am not leaving Dawson
until my friend gets justice.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[Wolf growls]
[Gunshots]
Bill: The Klondike in October.
Two things are going south right now...
the weather
and people smart enough to
get out before winter comes.
Some, like my friend, never got the chance.
Death has come to the Klondike,
seeking like the rest of us.
While we search out gold and
abstractions like justice,
death only seeks more.
His instruments are many...
the land,
the animals,
the people,
and that most violent and
irrepressible of forces
to which man, especially in the Klondike,
- [insects buzzing]
- has no defense...
disease.
- Cash dollars!
- Man: Dollars?
50 bucks!
Any man who wants to give
up on his horrible toil,
get his claim off his back,
I'm offering $50!
Goodman: Wouldn't pay
for the equipment, soap,
you low-grade son of a bitch.
God's own truth,
but it's better than
being dead, now, ain't it?
Take a look yonder. What do you see?
Nothing. Same as any other day.
No, what you don't see
is what's slowly creeping up the creeks...
nervous fever.
Kill you like the 100 men
they already put in the ground in Dawson.
I'll take my chances.
I did mention the tlingit, too, didn't I?
I guess you just got to ask
yourself which is greater...
chance of you hitting a pay streak
in one of these prospect holes,
or the chance the nervous fever gets you.
Or the tlingit gets you.
Man: You son of a bitch!
Soapy: Whew.
- You.
- Yep, me.
Oh, I know that look.
Shameless opportunist, right?
Am I? Look at your conscience.
Oh, I see it a whole different way.
I'm saving lives.
What do you say? 50 bucks.
Wouldn't get me 100 miles,
which out here is just
another part of nowhere.
Au contraire.
Get you out of the radius of the fever
and the tlingit.
I'm offering you nothing
short than a ticket to life.
Meeker: [Coughs]
How about you step back, huh?
Put a few paces between us, friend.
Why don't you step back so
I don't get any of you on me?
No way to talk to a man
trying to liberate you.
Fine by me.
It's gonna be cheaper
for me when y'all die.
You do have a fine day, now.
Don't pay him any mind, Meek.
Meeker: It's not so much
him I'm worried about.
[Coughs]
You got to get that looked at.
It's just my lungs ain't agreeing with me.
If that's typhus you're carrying,
they got to get to it fast...
before it gets into your head.
As soon as your brain
stops agreeing with you,
you're done.
I'll hitch a ride into town
with Gornerstein tomorrow.
[Shuddering] Judge: Saint Blaise,
invoked against diseases
of the throat, protect them.
Saint Agathius, invoked
against headache, protect them.
Saint Christopher, invoked against storms
- and plague...
- Man: Enough.
- What are you doing?
- Moving them out.
- Where?
- The street.
They'll all die out there.
Well, they're gonna die anyway, right?
And until they're dead, I
can't have them on my land.
Your land?
Yeah, cheapest plot in
town, believe it or not.
What in God's name are you
gonna do with a mortuary?
There's no hospital here.
These people have nowhere to go.
Well, God will protect them, right?
Why are you so callous?
Prudent.
I'm being prudent. I'm not being callous.
I can't have infectious
disease on my property.
Well, then, I'll take them to my church.
Oh.
You really think your
lord's gonna protect you?
You think he's gonna save
you from this nasty disease?
[Chuckles] I'm already saved.
You're the dead man.
And not just in this life.
Well, I do wonder about that, Father.
This foundation is going.
The soil's wet, but not that wet.
Shouldn't be giving like this.
Tell that to the hillside.
I'm gonna do some reckoning,
and by my reckoning,
we need more wood in a bad way.
[Insects buzzing]
The world feeds off of
itself up here, doesn't it?
Man dies, birds get his flesh,
poachers gets his boots,
someone gets his claim,
and I get his story.
Bill: Got that thinking look on your face.
I was thinking about whoever it was
that turned tents into a city on a chunk of
what's effectively a typhus-ridden swamp.
Miss Mulrooney, we got to talk.
Inside.
Without more wood, that
bench is gonna give,
and that's eight weeks
of digging gone south.
I'm up against a vein. I know it.
Miners are always up against a vein.
If a tenth of them were
right, we'd be paving a road
back to the states in gold dust.
This claim is different.
That superstructure falls in on itself...
I don't know if I got the ability to wait
out till spring to start building again.
By "ability" you mean "money."
If you stake me two quarts for fuel,
30 poles to shore up the build...
He wants credit.
[Chuckles]
I ain't in the business of charity.
You got a stake in that claim, too.
That bothers you, doesn't it?
It makes you wonder whether
I had something to do with Epstein's death.
In terms of my stake in that claim,
I have no interest in mining,
as I've always maintained.
What I have is an investment in Joe Meeker.
[Chuckles] And why is that?
He's a cousin.
He's a walking, talking,
two-legged labrador.
Don't need much more than
a bone to keep him happy.
If that bone is a half a stake in a claim,
I ain't averse to keeping Joe Meeker happy.
- What if I put up my half?
- [Chuckles]
Two halves of nothing.
That's just what I need.
A lot of speculation about this claim.
And even if you don't believe in it,
it'll sell for something
on the open market...
for more than the price
of the wood I'm asking.
You're either stupid or
you got way too much faith.
Hold it...
- [Paper taps]
-... For a week.
That's all it's gonna take
for me to get to that vein.
[Indistinct conversation]
But after a week, if you
don't pay back the loan,
I will sell it.
Capital does me no good
tied up there in the claims.
It has to be down here in Dawson.
These properties are all too nice.
See, I don't want nice.
What I'm looking for is shit...
shit that you can polish
up and then make nice.
That's real estate. You understand?
Superintendent: A word with you.
I heard you threatened the priest.
There will not be any murder in this town.
Do you understand?
Well, you and I both know
there's gonna be murder.
This is the wilds.
A lot's gonna slip through the cracks
for us as a law-enforcement unit.
We got 10 men to police
200 square miles of claims.
We got to pick our
priorities, what to protect...
that starts with church.
You're Catholic, are you?
It's another institution
that can help civilize this town.
You stay away from it.
Faster than you know what hit you,
I'll put a cage around you.
I might not have to kill him myself,
Superintendent.
God might do it for me.
[Thunder rumbles]
[Water dripping]
You shoot my friend?
Why?
You're not going to get
an answer out of him.
But you can take solace in the fact that,
one way or another, he'll see justice.
A problematic word.
How so?
Justice for us is hanging a killer.
Justice for them is maybe
fighting off people taking their land.
All we get is a couple of
dead men. Who's the wiser?
That's a pretty even-keeled response.
I'd think you'd be seeing red.
Oh, I'm seeing plenty.
Just not sure if it's here.
Man: [Speaking native language]
He wants to know if you want some.
Says he prefers it to
the white man's water.
Must have been a hell of a shot
with a dead trigger finger like that.
Ain't exactly made for marksmanship, is he?
One way or another,
we'll find out the truth.
Man: A little higher. A
little over to the left.
Guy buys a mortuary, and now
he's looking to add to it?
Up there?
Who buys a cemetery?
Belinda: I don't think
he bought a cemetery.
I think he bought dirt.
I don't like people buying
dirt next to my dirt.
He's making offers,
talking about putting up
- saloons, a hotel.
- Let him.
Location's location, and that up there...
that ain't location.
But it is dry.
[Sighs]
Look around.
People are tired of living in the mud.
He's figuring a city. City build to last.
What are you getting at?
Front street isn't exactly
a model of sanitation, now, is it?
That's why he's buying up there.
Do you think he's planning
on making a new downtown?
It's exactly what I'd do.
Find out who he's talking to.
I want to talk to them first.
Tell them I'll pay more than the Count.
The Count pays cash 100%.
You've taken too many notes
from miners, too many IOUs.
Load's ready to go up to
152, Bill Haskell claim.
Should we send them up
or wait on the roads?
We'll send them up.
You want to compete with the Count,
you got to sell that claim.
Which means whatever you do,
I would not bring him that wood.
[Thunder crashing]
- [Indistinct conversations]
- [Fiddle music plays]
[Man singing indistinctly]
Sabine: [Giggles]
Give us a feel.
[Chuckles] But we're in public.
I know. That's kind of
the point, don't you think?
Oh, I prefer to be a bit
more classy than that.
Yeah? So you have an opinion, do you?
Eh?
I just bought it off you.
And the next one.
And the next one in your head.
- Well, then...
- And the next one.
Perhaps I can request
that we take this upstairs?
- You see, now...
- [Music and conversations stop]
to make a request, that
requires you to have an opinion.
And I just bought your opinions, didn't I?
And the next one in your head.
[Coins clinking]
What do you want me to do?
You're a whore. Take your clothes off.
[Wolf-whistling]
More.
This is the Klondike, love.
[Men whooping]
I don't see you digging.
That enough whore for you, Count?
No, not quite.
But I think we're getting there.
[Coins clink]
I'm just kind of curious.
How much is enough whore
for you in a woman?
A little bit ain't enough, is it?
You...
you want more.
[Coins clink] All of you!
You want more
- of the whore?
- [Whooping continues]
Who will do whatever you want?
Let you do,
whatever you want to her.
[Gasps]
Belinda: Enough.
The lady's done for the night.
I think you'd know not to interrupt
a man who spent money on a hooker.
You've been outbid, asshole.
Showed him.
You didn't show him a goddamn thing.
Standing out there buck-naked in the rain
with money in your hand?
He's right. You're a goddamn whore.
Now, you give me that.
Don't you look a gift horse in the mouth.
I just saved you.
- Who said I need any saving?
- [Chuckles]
You shitting me, woman?
We all do what we do.
Now, I need that money.
Please.
[Sighs]
I'll do whatever you want.
Inside my coat, there's a pocket.
You reach in there...
you pull out that compact...
you open it up.
Look.
See what you are?
You go to hell, bitch.
You righteous, rich bitch!
Money. That's what men have over you.
And once they don't,
they ain't got no sway.
And you get to keep your integrity.
And that is worth a whole lot more
than all the gold in this
goddamn frozen shit box.
I'm sorry.
You don't say sorry to me.
You say sorry to yourself.
God may be a fairy tale...
but the fear of God ain't.
You put that in her. You understand?
[Door closes]
[Sniffles]
[Thunder crashes]
[Sighs]
You look vaguely surprised.
It's a long way for the Deputy Minister
of the Interior to come, that's all.
We do tend to hibernate in Ottawa
at the first sign of winter.
The Dawson problem is apparently
too pressing to let wait till spring,
at least according to my superiors.
Dawson problem?
As you know, the government
is encouraging companies
to come up here, develop the Yukon.
But said companies are a little uneasy.
Word's gotten back, justified or not,
that the natives are restless.
You want to scare a white man
in a corporate boardroom?
Tell him he's investing in a land
full of angry brown people.
Ah. Thank you.
So, obviously, they need to be reassured
that there is the rule of law in the Yukon.
If they're killers, they need to die.
Granted, but I am not yet 100% certain
that they're the ones.
Then get 100% certain.
[Thunder rumbles]
Dan: Good news... the tailor said
he'd talk to you about the property.
I know you don't want the Count to get it,
but don't offer the man cash for that land.
You don't have it.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Knock on door]
McDonald, it's Belinda Mulrooney.
Come in.
I appreciate you seeing me, sir.
Mr. McDonald and I were just finishing up.
It's not signed yet.
What if I offered you more?
Count's paying me a nice number...
$200.
$300.
$400?
$500.
You know, you should really walk away.
You've pressed me twice already.
I'm liable to come unhinged.
$600.
$2,000.
[Scoffs]
You spend money like that, I
won't have to worry about you.
You'll be broke.
Mr. McDonald, if you please.
Nobody pays $2,000.
Only an idiot does.
[Thud] [Groans]
And you're right.
[Gasping]
Nothing...
is a far better price.
Now...
I need to know that I'm done with you.
Tell me that I'm done with you.
Oh, yeah, I'm done with you.
Good girl.
[Door opens]
[Door slams]
[Sighs]
[Thunder crashing]
[Rain falling]
[Sighs]
[Panting]
[Clanging]
We're going for a walk.
[Gun cocks]
Hit the bottle, please.
[Whimpers]
Again!
[Breathing heavily]
[Gunshot]
Trying to fool me,
playing lame, aren't you?
Let's put some real stakes into it, hmm?
Now make the shot.
Make the shot like you
did that night or he dies!
Make the shot!
[Gunshot]
[Crying]
It's all right.
[Thunder rumbles]
Ain't enough to share.
I never killed no man,
but you don't get wide of that wood,
I may have to start.
Don't make it about that.
[Both grunting]
[Grunting continues]
You're gonna have to
split me in two to stop me!
[Grunts]
[Breathing heavily]
[Door opens, closes]
Haskell's asking for the wood.
In this weather?
Half-wit's got way too
much faith in fellow man,
thinking I'm just gonna saddle
up and ride out into that.
Deliver him wood that he wants on credit.
I ain't doing it.
I got too much else on my mind.
There's plenty of men
have died in the Yukon
on account of the wrong kind of courage.
It'll be a shame, though.
He's a good one.
[Match strikes]
Don't you put that on me.
I don't put nothing on nobody.
I just talk.
How much firewood does he have?
Not enough.
[Thunder rumbles]
Ed?
That's my husband!
What happened? What happened?!
He's still with us. Don't worry.
You all right?
Get in the house.
[Breathing heavily]
Light, you son of a bitch!
[Horse approaching]
[Horse whinnies]
If I were more of a religious man,
I'd say you were an angel.
Been called a lot of
things, but never that.
[Grunts]
What are you doing?
Giving somebody something they need.
This ought to burn right.
The man tried to take an ax to you
and you still gave him wood?
It wasn't him swinging it.
Something inside him.
Something the weather put there
he'd rather I not have seen.
[Wood creaking]
[Horses neigh]
[Gasps] Oh, no!
[Wood clatters]
[Sighs]
God damn.
[Breathing heavily]
Idiot, idiot, idiot! Stupid woman!
Thinking I'd get back
before it went 100% to shit!
Bill: Wish I could offer you something.
Hot bath would be nice. Dry bed.
Like I said, wish I
could offer you something.
Remind me never do anyone a favor.
Dig someone out of a hole...
[Grunts]
just end up putting dirt in your own grave.
We drink it when we want to knock
the sharp edges off the world.
[Sighs]
It's gonna be one of those kind of nights.
Full of sharp edges.
[Sighs]
[Groans, coughs]
[Chuckles]
[Fire crackles]
Too damn smart to be
digging around in the dirt.
You know...
you keep talking to
someone like a neophyte,
you're liable to alienate them.
All the better.
Then they don't get the
wrong idea about things.
You got, what,
one more season than I do up here?
One season is all it takes
to undo 5,000 years of civilization.
[Chuckles]
God damn us. The species regressed.
Nah.
We come a-ways.
Sabine: What do I do, Father?
I'm stuck up here, and I swear
sometimes it's hell on earth.
Well, between you and me,
hell's bullshit.
No fiery brimstone cave
under our feet, no devil.
I mean, if hell's real, it's right here.
It's when we start believing that
fear is something
different than what it is.
It's just a feeling. That's all it is.
Bones buzzing, blood pumping.
And when you see that,
you're through the looking glass.
Can't steer you no more.
So, if there are only
two things in the world...
love and fear... what are you gonna choose?
Love.
But I ain't seeing it.
But you do see the fear, don't you?
Why people are doing
the things they're doing?
It's because they're scared.
And when you see a person like that,
when they're afraid,
you see the little kid in them.
[Sighs]
You see the scared thing inside of them
and you can't help but love them.
Father...
[Chuckles]
what am I gonna do?
Well, you're gonna learn how to love.
[Thunder crashes]
You're different, Haskell.
What makes you so different?
Try to bathe at least once a week.
[Laughs]
Well, it ain't doing you any favors.
[Chuckles]
You got some white in your mouth.
Teeth... every civilization.
Is the first thing that goes... hygiene.
Civilization ain't gone up here.
Not if you don't want it to go.
Oh, it ain't what you want.
It's what nature wants.
And she'll pull the
animal right out of you,
even if you don't know it's in there.
Nature can't take what
you don't want it to.
God damn if civilization
ain't a beautiful thing.
If you say a word of this to anyone...
[Sighs]... I'll deny it.
Belinda: One hangover.
I'm used to two hangovers.
Whole 'nother thing.
Two?
Lot of intoxication in the air last night,
in more ways than one.
It'll wear off.
Always does.
I'm too far gone, Haskell.
Too many closed-up places in me
that need to be open for
something like this to work.
A woman needs to be like that up here.
Keep that civilization
burning bright, won't you?
- You do the same.
- [Scoffs]
It's been beat out of me.
I think I made that clear with all that
pontificating last night.
And yet that wood's here.
It don't show up last night,
I'm out here in the mud, dead,
and I think you knew that.
So don't talk to me about civilization.
Maybe that's the biggest
curse of the Klondike...
how it saps your ability to trust.
You never know what's in a person's heart,
what they really want from you.
They'd just as soon kill you as love you.
Because you kill someone
and they're never a threat to you again.
But you love them, they can
take everything from you.
Your gold, your land,
your soul.
[Up-tempo music plays]
Whoo!
Half-wit's supposed to be
on the straight and narrow.
Jack: Well, she is, believe it or not.
She's just celebrating.
Celebrating what?
Well, if I'm not mistaken,
she's in love
with the divine holy light.
There you are.
I just need a few signatures.
Liquidation papers for
the Bill Haskell claim.
Who's that by?
[Clicks tongue]
We talked about this.
You want hard cash to
compete with this man,
and this is the way to do it.
[Sighs]
[Indistinct conversations]
Ms. Mulrooney.
I trust you're here to consummate the deal.
Not consummating that way,
but you do get my point.
You shut up, Soap.
Don't you make this any
dirtier than it already is.
[Grunts]
Meeker: The good news is
I've got walking pneumonia.
Not a lot of people
qualify that as good news.
It is if it means I don't got typhus.
Well, now, congratulations.
And you'll be elated to know I figured out
why the site's been filling in on itself.
It's flowing to the surface...
plaster, soft as clouds.
Meaning, if there's science to any of this,
that is optimum gold-bearing soil.
You might want to hold off on that.
I started with the good news.
[Machinery whirring]
Is it true?
You sell up that claim from beneath me?
Told you there ain't no civilization in me.
I sold your note to Soapy.
He's not gonna give you the
week I was to pay back the loan.
He's gonna foreclose tomorrow.
[Insects buzzing]
I thought we had an understanding.
I'm formally requesting a judge be sent
so a proper case can proceed,
'cause if you want justice up here,
then you're gonna need a justice.
You don't want to do this.
Don't you tell me what I want to do.
Tell you what.
What I'm going to do right now
is save you.
That's going to the telegraph office.
I'll have them type another.
Now, you listen to me, friend.
There's a reason you came here.
I know what it is.
I know exactly who you are.
20-year veteran that's
never risen above constable.
A wholly uninspired candidate
incapable of original thought.
Year in and year out, you get passed over,
so you come up here,
take the job that no one else will.
Your one last shot to be someone...
a superintendent.
And suddenly you get that original thought
at exactly the wrong time.
Were this to get through, I
would simply countermand it.
You would be relieved of duty,
and I would have more
public-relations complications
when I want less.
I'm giving you a chance to reconsider.
What's happening here is going to happen,
whether you retype this or not.
You're a son of a bitch.
Yes, I am.
A son of a bitch who's
saving you from yourself.
So...
What do you say, Superintendent?
Let me save you?
[Sighs]
[Grunts]
Meeker: Man puts a shovel in
the ground that many times,
God is bound to reward him.
He's just got to.
We'll find another claim.
No. This was it, Meek.
Our one shot.
[Grunting]
[Pants]
Don't give me that look.
I gave you a chance.
You could have cashed in.
Save it, leech.
I'd rather be a leech
than an idiot, friend.
A leech's never hungry.
Idiot.
Well, g... go find yourself lunch...
someplace else besides my claim.
Bill: Meek! We're still in it, Meek!
It ain't over yet! We're still in it!
- Come on!
- Hey, hey!
What the hell are you doing?!
This is my claim now!
No, it ain't. I got a contract.
Soapy: Yeah, well, in case you can't see,
I'm holding that contract now,
and since you can't pay the
balance due this very day,
I am ordering you to vacate.
You do not have the funds.
That's where you're wrong, Soapy.
We are fully funded.
Go on! Get!
[Laughs]
Man: Death is here.
The sky will darken soon
like a coffin lid closing,
and we will be alone with death.
God isn't fooled
by our shelters
or by the rags covering our bodies.
He knows.
We're no different than the coyotes.
We are predators.
Creatures of fortune and
circumstance, that's all.
God, no.
There's no end to them.
He is the storm.
He is the mudslide. He is
the typhus-ridden mosquito.
He is gold and he is our greed for gold.
[Gallows door opens] [Rope snaps]
He chooses who to kill,
like an infant smashing sticks.
I come here to tell you
that I feel his grace.
I feel him pulling me to him.
I can feel it coming... a storm.
What storm?
[Sighs]
I will kill.
Have you killed before?
Yes.
Whom have you killed?
A wandering Jew.
A young man with the sap
still rising in him.
And you will kill again?
Whatever burns inside you,
man always has a choice...
always a choice.
Not when it's God's
own gravity pulling you.
Like the rain out of the
sky, it just happens...
an inevitability.
That's my confession.
[Coughs]
[Sighs]
[Indistinct conversations]
Man: Attention!
Attention, all you dirty pricks!
This boat leaves in two days,
and there won't be another
one until next spring,
and only the healthy
will be coming with us!
Careful with the piano, please.
If you have a sniffle,
a speck of a sniffle,
cough, rash, scratch in
your throat, forget it!
If you're dying, planning to die,
hoping not to die, this ain't your ship.
You will not be coming aboard! Understand?
That is life-and-death drama.
Most of these people don't have supplies
to last through the winter.
They'll die if they're still here.
Makes this a business-tunity, don't it?
I got 10 tickets
- to the highest bidder!
- [Excited chatter]
Now, we all know how this works,
and we're doing it in an orderly way.
[Dog whining] All right?
Somebody says a number,
then somebody says a higher number.
Who will do $40? I hear $40!
This is your one opportunity
to get out of here
before winter sets in and y'all
start to freeze your asses off!
Now y'all know about the typhus.
Dog?
$40... I hear $40. This
gentleman right here.
- $40...
- Dog?
For a ticket out of here.
Who can give me more?
Think about it!
This is your lives we're talking about!
I hear $45! $45 to the young miss!
[Shouting indistinctly]
[Gasps]
[Sighs]
We're in a tavern up north,
and there is this big Indian there.
Tlingit, I think.
And he's had a few, but he's not drunk.
We decide we're going to
have a little fun with him.
Now, the man is standing with
his back to a mirror, see,
and we tell him, "if you turn your
head really fast toward the mirror,
you can see the back of your head."
[Laughter]
Well, this savage just stares at us,
doesn't say anything.
Indian doesn't understand
English, we think.
[Chuckles] Then we see him.
When he thinks nobody's looking,
he's whipping his head around like this.
He does it every three seconds or so.
- Almost saw it.
- [Laughter]
Could I have a word with you alone, sir?
How may I help you, Father?
Well, the prisoners you're about to hang
are innocent.
And you say that why?
Because I've spoken to the murderer.
He's a white man.
What's his name?
I don't know his name or his face.
It was in the darkness of the confessional.
And the bond of the confessional
prevents you from saying more,
- no doubt.
- Yes, sir.
Even if I did know more I wouldn't say,
- but I don't know more.
- Ah.
Catholic evidence.
[Laughter]
Boys, remind me never
to confess to a priest.
He'll blab it all over town.
[Laughter]
I've known men like you.
Strong with others, weak alone.
I said what I came to say.
Now you do with it what you will.
Hey, priest.
You know if you turn around really fast,
you can see the back of your head?
[Laughter]
Wait.
The man who confessed, you sure it was
the killing of Byron
Epstein he was talking about?
It's amazing to me... how you can all
have a chuckle when innocent
men are likely to die.
You don't understand how it is.
There's a lot more going on.
I can't think of anything that would
trump the death of innocent men.
You'd be the last person I would think
to get on a soapbox.
Why?
Because I'm a whore?
There's only one whore
standing out here, Superintendent,
and it isn't me.
Bill: Think this gold we're pulling
out is just the tail of the beast.
The beast itself lies below.
We just got to dig deeper.
The beast.
Let's go. We're burning daylight.
- [Wood creaking]
- Hey! Hey!
[Crashing]
Meek! Meek!
[Groans]
Meek!
[Panting] [Groaning]
Help!
[water trickling]
[Scraping, thudding]
[Crumbling]
[Grunting] [Coughs]
Where's Meeker? [Coughs]
Meeker?
He's over there.
Arm's broke up, but he's over there.
[Gasps]
Beast got us.
His arm is busted up.
We're taking him to Dawson.
[Coughs]
Did you get a look at the assailant?
Got to be the same one that killed Epstein.
They want the mine.
That's the problem with property
rights in this territory.
If the claim owner dies, his next of kin
has one week to take possession.
No one can get here in a week.
Unless they're already here.
No relation shows up,
the claim's up for grabs.
If both you and Mr. Meeker had died,
that mine would be a free-for-all.
You're incentivizing
killers, Superintendent.
I did not write the law.
You're keeping something back.
The murderer... he's been talking.
He as much as admitted
the killing to someone.
Who?
[Door opens]
[Men coughing]
I have nothing further to say
that this gentleman hasn't already heard.
- That you saw him?
- Heard him.
Must have seen something.
I am bound by God
not to divulge what I've
seen and heard in that space.
Was it a miner?
[Coughing continues]
Well, it wasn't a tlingit.
This is what he wants, you know.
For you to become just like him.
[Door opens]
[Door slams]
I'm sorry for my behavior this morning.
It was weak of me.
I accept your apology.
You were right, what you said.
I guess maybe you saw it in my face.
It's what we whores do.
We read men.
Don't say that.
Why do you feel you have to prove
anything to me, Superintendent?
I don't know.
[Coughing continues]
[Coughs]
You in the wood business now?
You look awful.
It's not catching, is it?
It's time we had a conversation.
You've been bad ever since I've known you,
but things have taken a turn for the worse.
Well, you can put a stop to it.
I intend to.
You want to be the real estate
baron in Dawson, I'll let you.
All I care about is the Fairview Hotel.
I'm willing to let you buy me out.
Give you the pick of any of
my properties on front street.
$6,000.
So I can keep the Fairview
construction afloat.
Front street properties are
a swamp. I don't need them.
Well, come spring,
all the establishments on front street
are the first thing folks
see when they dock in Dawson.
I'm your only competition.
I'd advise you to buy me out.
I'll tell you what I'd do,
all right?
I'll give you your $6,000, but...
I want the lot... everything you got.
That's highway robbery.
$6,000,
for all of them.
I'll bring the paperwork
to the saloon tonight.
You know, when you're
not being such a bitch...
you can be really rather fetching.
[Up-tempo music in distance]
Has anyone seen dog?!
How about you? You seen dog?
Dog have a name?
What's a dog need with a name?
He's got a love affair with a critter.
Gate's closing.
Belinda: [Coughs]
[Sighs]
What's going on, Val?
Count rented the place for the night.
How about I lift that off you?
Ain't no way to conduct business.
Are we gonna have a problem?
That's a good lass.
How about we have a seat over
there at the special table?
Count pay you by the day
or pay you by the gun?
You ain't gonna buy me out.
I got no need for your type.
Count: $2,000 U.S.
The deal was for $6,000.
Yeah, but your properties are rotten.
They're not worth that.
You're not buying properties.
You're buying peace of mind.
$3,000?
$6,000.
You know, I was the first
one that believed in you,
back when even you didn't believe in you.
Now look at you.
Eh?
Was I wrong?
You don't have it, do you?
Your men here know you
don't have the money.
What my men know is that my new lumber yard
has got better equipment than yours.
On any given business
day, I pull in $1,000,
which means that $6,000 is nothing to me.
Then pay it.
Get me a beer while you're at it.
Champagne's... soft.
There's cash in the back. Get it.
Man: That cash is a
big chunk of your money.
I know.
So, get it.
How do I know you're not gonna
shoot me like you did McDonald?
Well, because McDonald and I,
we didn't have the history that we have.
I suggest you sign that.
'Cause otherwise I might change my mind
and wait you out, watch you drop dead.
You got the typhus, right?
Bring me the cash.
Give me a pen.
[Pen scribbling]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Gasps]
[Breathing heavily]
It worked.
- It worked.
- Jesus.
You're burning up.
Give us a hand here!
God damn it! Give us a hand!
[Indistinct chatter]
[Sighs]
You're up here by your lonesome.
Where's dog?
He's run off.
Dog knows something.
Smells a blizzard coming, maybe.
You ascribe a lot of intellect to that dog.
Well, he's got what's
needed in these environs.
More than we got.
You ought to know...
Belinda's taken down with the typhus.
She's on a cot in judge's.
I know you two have feelings.
You're like school kids.
You show your love by fighting each other.
How bad is it?
Go on down there or I'll
shoot you through your head,
make you stupider than you already are.
[Door opens]
[Man coughing]
You should be out mining.
Well, you should be
out overcharging miners.
I am wicked.
You just want people to think that.
Never fooled me.
[Breathing shakily]
I'm sleepy.
You can't sleep now.
Keep talking.
When I first saw you,
I thought to myself, "that woman
is stronger than iron."
You dominate a room just by standing in it.
And the room is better for it.
A little thing like a fever?
You'll just kick it aside.
I'm tired of kicking.
My mama used to do this
to me when I was sick.
It must be nice,
having someone you love do that for you.
[Whines]
[Sighs]
What else did your mama do?
She talked...
[Sniffles]
and told me everything she was doing...
"I'm changing the sheets.
I'm airing out the room."
[Laughing] Like I couldn't see her.
Sometimes she sang to me.
[Sniffles]
[Voice breaking] No,
I'm not singing to you.
[Sighs]
[Crying softly]
- Is there any chance?
- She went days
with the disease skulking
through her body like a wolf.
Most people wouldn't even be able to walk.
She'll be all right.
She's tougher than rubber.
Arm's feeling better.
Won't get better without help.
Doctor help, you mean.
We got to get you to the mainland.
Ferry leaves day after tomorrow.
- You're going to be on it.
- And what about you?
What about the mine?
The season's up, Meek.
It's the last ferry of the year.
You ain't answering my question.
What about you? You don't go, I don't go.
Don't be stupid.
That arm don't heal right,
you're crippled for life.
You don't go, I don't go.
I'll get us both tickets.
How about that?
You'd do that?
If it gets you out of here. [Sniffles]
Yeah.
I lied to him.
I had to.
We'd found gold, but I hadn't
- satisfied the real obsession.
- [Dog barks in distance]
The killer of my best friend.
Hiding out there somewhere like a dog,
in the mud, in the rain
with his great secret.
It was just a matter of time
before someone saw his face...
and the real endgame would begin.
Safe travels.
[Men coughing]
Belinda: [Coughing]
Bill.
Her fever's broke.
She might make it.
Must have nodded off. [Clears throat]
Looks like you had a little help.
[Sighs]
Yeah, well.
Help at night, hell in
the morning. [Sniffs]
She all right Belinda?
Maybe yes, maybe no.
[Dog howls]
- That's him.
- Who?
That's dog. I'd recognize
his voice anywhere.
He's gone back to the wild.
He's howling with his brethren.
Well...
It's good to know you, Bill Haskell.
[Sighs]
Bill: You're not coming back, are you?
You're gonna be on that ferry.
[Dog barking]
I've collected a lot of stories.
Don't have much meaning
unless people hear 'em.
Put me in one of them, will you?
I'll think about it.
But right now...
I'm burning daylight.
Confused...
where exactly all our customers are.
[Indistinct conversations]
Well, I suppose they're up
the street at Belinda's mill.
She's suddenly selling her wood on credit.
That helps her how?
For a woman so desperate for hard cash,
selling on credit helps her exactly how?
Well...
it helps her keep the
customers away from here.
[Chuckles] Smart little rat.
Knew you were strapped,
took all your cash on hand.
Why?
Well, so I can't pay you lot.
Sundown and his boys ain't the
type you want to be in hock to.
Well, there's more than
one way to raise capital.
Trust me.
Goodman: Got some color, do you?
A little.
And yet I get the sense that
your mind is a whole world away, thinking.
I'm working out something
that don't have a solution.
Well, not much point in
thinking about it, then.
Thinking about how to
ferret out a murderer.
How would you do that?
Is that why you sent your friend away?
Keep him away from whatever
nastiness you were planning?
Something like that.
I ain't as innocent as him.
So?
That son of a bitch, he
hit my claim last night.
Got two months' worth of flakes.
Now, that's not what you got,
but still, it's every penny I had.
You know, you can't be certain it was him.
Well, there's one way to find out.
We find him.
We make him talk.
If it's the mine he wants,
we're gonna sit right back here
and let him think he can have it.
[Thunder rumbles]
[Dog barking]
Got movement.
Son of a bitch was in my camp.
And he's headed for mine.
Move and I'll shoot you
right where you stand!
You're the one that tried to kill me?!
You come for my gold now?!
Didn't kill no one.
Just looking to steal something
to feed my family with.
Well, maybe you're here to finish the job?
Kill me like you killed my friend?
I told you, didn't kill no one.
I'm telling you, I didn't do nothing.
Superintendent's gonna iron all that out.
Whole difference between stealing
and killing. I didn't even steal.
Shut it.
Bill Haskell, what are you doing?
Think I found our man.
No, you haven't. This isn't him.
You know something, you talk now.
Who is it?
I'm bound by God to honor the
sanctity of the confessional,
but I can tell you right
now, it's not this man.
- Told you.
- Shut up!
Step away. Now.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Sighs]
Talk.
You know, I come down here,
give myself a little peace,
see if our murderous friend is smart enough
to get on the last boat out of here.
Disappear with his sins,
leave the rest of us alone.
- I didn't get that peace.
- [Boat whistle blows]
Prison's closing in now.
We're all locked in together.
[Boat whistle blowing]
The die had been cast.
God had sealed us in with our fate.
What we were before we came
to this place was no more.
The land had taken over, drawing from us
the animal instincts we'd rather not know.
It had already killed
hundreds, maybe thousands.
But only one of those
deaths mattered to me.
The ache of a friend lost forever
is a pain I'd wish on nobody.
You was just trying to get me out of here,
weren't you?
Only to save that arm.
Who's gonna save you?
[Sighs]
Jesus.
Sometimes friendships, even new ones,
are the only solace we have,
even if the moment is only fleeting
and the worst storms are yet to come.
Bill: A murderer walks amongst us.
That's not God's plan.
It was Goodman.
Wasn't it?
[Breathes deeply]
Count: The good lord saw fit
to put all that gold down there.
And now, men are just yanking it up...
Oh!
Men like Bill Haskell.
I say we go and pay him a little visit.
I want you to work for me.
Tonight, there will be no words,
only blood.
I seen that look. The killer look.
The Yukon got you.
Yukon gets to all of us sooner or later.
[Grunts]
Bill: If they're hanging him
for the death of my friend,
they got the wrong guy.
Where is it?
Was it worth it?
Sabine: Count and his men...
they was going after Bill Haskell.
Well, this is a bit of a predicament.
[Breathing heavily]
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -