Walt: Character is fate.
The philosopher Heraclitus said that.
I think he meant,
Man makes his destiny through
his choices and his values.
Martha: Be careful, Walt!
I'll try, Martha.
I'll try.
So, as the arresting
officer of July 27, 2010,
Is it your opinion Malachi Strand
should be granted early parole?
My opinion is that as
the Tribal Police Chief,
Malachi Strand was in fact
the most dangerous criminal
on the entire Cheyenne reservation.
Where are those federal
agents the B.I.A. Promised?
I got tired of waiting for 'em.
So you're going to arrest
Malachi in his own station
without any back-up?
Not entirely without back-up.
Mr. Strand has expressed
remorse for his record.
As a matter of fact,
he has convinced a number of people here
of his rehabilitation and
fitness for reentering society.
Walt: I don't doubt that.
Malachi can be very convincing.
Well, if it isn't the long face of the law
and his little sidekick... Deputy Hank.
This is a federally issued warrant
to arrest you on extortion charges.
Henry and I are here to serve it.
You two should probably
set your weapons down now.
You really think I'd
walk in here to arrest you
without federal back-up?
You're bluffing.
Am I?
Man: We understand who
Malachi Strand used to be.
What we're trying to
determine is, who is he now?
How's he changed?
A few weeks ago, Malachi tried to extort me
into giving favorable testimony
by threatening the life of my friend.
If Malachi is released,
his abuse and corruption
will only continue.
Malachi's character has not changed.
And jail is the only proper
fate for a man like him.
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
www.addic7ed.com
Ruby, as soon as there's a ruling
on the parole hearing, I want to hear it.
Whose parole hearing?
Malachi Strand.
Ruby, how many vacation days do I have?
All of them.
- Vacation days?
- I'm taking the day off.
As far as I can tell, the
best way to clear Henry
is to find the person that
actually killed Miller Beck.
Since when is finding a
murderer not police business?
It's not our police
business. It's Denver's.
I don't think our taxpayers
should be paying for me
to pursue a personal matter.
So you think one of these guys
is behind your wife's murder?
I think they had motivation, intelligence,
maybe even opportunity.
Malachi was in prison
when the murders happened,
but, uh... not this guy or this guy...
...or this guy.
Now I need to figure out
where these three were,
so you're in charge.
I'm sorry. In charge of who?
You told Branch to take time off
and Ferg's at that certification course.
Well, I got my radio if you need me.
Things have been pretty
quiet around here, so...
Walt, Newt Cunningham called.
Apparently, someone stole one
of his Rhode Island red hens.
Well, I stand corrected.
I told you I don't know
anyone named David Ridges.
My friend Tom and I know
that you're a White Warrior.
Just like Ridges.
My name is Sam Poteet. I
work in a hardware store.
I never even heard of a White Warrior.
Then why did my friend Tom
here see you all painted up
with your buddies, dancing
around Ridges' ashes?
Ashes?
Why are you even looking
for this Ridges guy
if he's not alive?
Let's call one of your
White Warrior friends
so he can explain it to you.
I know of the Bow String Warriors
and the Kit Fox Warriors.
And the Golden State Warriors.
I don't know any White Warriors.
Where's Ridges?!
- I don't know!
- Like hell you don't.
Hey, if he knew anything, he
would have told you by now.
Hand me my thermos!
Now!
[grunting]
[breathing heavily]
Dad. What are you doing here?
Taking that vacation you suggested.
So, did you get through
all the discovery yet?
Let us discuss this in my office...
So we can speak in private.
Cady: Basically, their entire case
hinges on Miller Beck's teeth
being in Henry's possession.
But if we find Hector,
he can testify how Henry
actually got the teeth.
So I think we need to get
Hector's face out there,
put up some "wanted" fliers.
If we want people to talk about Hector,
we need to offer a reward.
With whose money?
Everyone's.
We still have all the money
donated for Henry's bail fund.
And my bail has been paid for,
so that money should be returned.
Henry, these people want to help you.
That doesn't just stop
because you're out on bail.
Plus, Omar and Ruby have
already offered to pitch in.
I still have some money
set aside from the cabin.
I did not ask to be the object of charity.
I didn't ask you to keep
self-incriminating evidence.
But here we are.
So...
What do you propose?
We pull together a reward
for locating Hector.
Now, it doesn't hurt to get people talking.
While you two look for Hector,
I'm gonna track down some men
that may have actually killed Miller Beck.
If we go with my theory
that Martha's death
wasn't a random mugging...
...That would mean
someone actually paid
Miller Beck to kill her.
And then killed Miller
Beck to cover any tracks.
Who are they?
Murderers, drug dealers,
and sociopaths I've arrested,
Each one a little smarter and
more ruthless than the next.
Every one of those three
men was out of prison
at the time of your mom's murder.
And I'm gonna pay each of them a visit,
see if they have connections
to Denver or Miller Beck.
Wait. You mean you're going alone?
Well, if something happens to me,
We know who our chief suspects are.
[door slams]
Travis: What are we doing?
Branch: What's wrong, you scared?
You could have bailed out at any time.
Man, I-I didn't even
know what you were doing.
When you grabbed that guy, for all I knew,
A bunch of Cheyenne drug
dealers were gonna come after us
with uzis a-and tomahawks.
And then I realized you
were taking him hostage.
I just wanted to make sure
that, you know, you didn't
screw up your entire life.
By what?
Killing him?
How crazy you think I am?
Look. I'm not gonna screw up my life.
Yeah, I thought the same thing
when I pulled that gun on you.
Now look at me.
That's the thing.
Guys like you get caught.
Guys like me don't.
[Sam groans]
Let me out! Let me out!
[grunting]
It tastes like... purple in here.
What the hell did you give him?
Peyote tea.
He'll still be hallucinating
by the time they find him.
So no one will believe
a damn thing he says.
Walk him up.
[grunting]
Are we... are we just gonna
leave him out here alone?
I'm sure the spirits will
take good care of him.
Okay.
Calm down. I got you.
[gasping]
They say...
They cracked you open for real this time.
Now you can let all that dark stuff out.
[vomiting]
[gunshot]
You're violating the
castle doctrine, Sheriff.
Castle doctrine doesn't apply
if I'm in your yard, Chance.
You just passed through my front door
and you entered my home's zoned perimeter,
which means we are both
standing within my domicile
and I'm legally entitled
to stand my ground.
Isn't that right, Sheriff?
Unless you got a warrant.
I'm just here to talk.
You have a gun?
- Yep.
- Then I feel threatened.
This isn't necessary.
The last time you came around,
you shot and killed my baby brother,
Tried to put me away for murder, right?
I'm sanctioned by the constitution
to put a bullet in your head.
I'll just step outside.
You knew a man named Miller Beck.
I'm under no legal obligation
to answer any of your questions, Sheriff.
How about this car?
Expired Colorado plates. Is this yours?
Is that a threat to
dispossess me of my property?
So it is yours.
Wrong again.
Then you can't claim defense
of property if I take this.
That's the letter of the law.
Ruby: He's gonna be in
everyone's sights now.
I printed out about 100 of these.
And Newt Cunningham called
again about his missing hen.
Ah, yes. The case of the missing chicken.
[sighs] Where's Walt?
Taking a little R&R. I'm in charge.
Well, I need some help.
Someone on the Rez found a
Cheyenne man named Sam Poteet
tripping on peyote in their backyard.
Okay.
Sam claims he was abducted and drugged
by a couple bleach boys.
White guys.
Do these bleach boys got names?
Yeah. Tom and Jerry.
- [laughs]
- I know.
I called the hardware
store Sam Poteet works.
Turns out this is the
fourth shift he's missed
in the last two months.
So he's making up a
story about a kidnapping
to avoid getting fired?
That or he's just tripping.
Either way, I still got to follow up.
Okay.
Well, we got a binder...
with mugshots in it...
...that you can borrow.
Well, when this guy sobers up a little,
I'll have him take a look.
Ruby, I need you to run a
Colorado license plate number.
Baker, Charlie, Baker, 32, Charlie.
Ruby: Okay.
And, uh, any word back on
Malachi's parole hearing yet?
Not yet.
[trumpet playing "Dixie land"]
What do you want?
Walt: A favor.
I'm busy.
It's dangerous.
You might get shot.
I'm listening.
They keep pouring in.
I asked Ruby to send all
the reward-seekers here.
So that if they actually have seen Hector,
you can help me question them.
And if they haven't, they
might still be thirsty.
I have lucked into a brilliant attorney.
How are the interviews going?
We might actually have
something. Come here.
Can you tell Henry what you told me?
Yeah.
So, I was hiking up near
summer pass by the caves.
I heard this rustling
and I figured it was just some animal.
But it was this Indian guy.
And it looked like he might have had a gun.
Can you give us a physical description?
Sure. Uh, he's pretty skinny,
about medium height, looked
like he had long hair.
Uh, that's not Hector?
No, that is nearly his opposite.
Sorry.
Lucian: More.
More.
Whoa, that's good.
All right.
Hold that.
[knock on door]
Who is it?
Man: Pizza!
I didn't order no pizza.
I did. Let me handle it.
[sighs] No, not again.
Come on, Jamie.
This is Creeley Dorn.
I put him away for
manufacturing crystal meth
seven years ago.
He's been out for a while now.
You know where I can find him?
Uh, I have no idea.
Y-you know, I don't
deal with the hard stuff.
So, um, knowing any meth guys
would be categorically impossible.
Jamie, I'm not trying
to tie you to anything.
Walt, why you trying
to pussyfoot around it?
This is your snitch boy. Get to snitching.
[sighs] Okay.
Uh, but... but I need
you both to recognize,
if I do know where this guy is,
it's only because I
delivered pizzas to him,
w-which is what I do for a living.
Okay. I might know where to find him.
But he doesn't really
look like this anymore.
I am off to investigate a stolen chicken.
If I don't make it back, tell
my husband that I love him.
Looks like my kidnap victim
is doubling down on his story.
He I.D.'d one of his abductors.
Which one?
This guy.
Travis.
Better get some info on
him and go have a talk.
No, I know this jackass.
I'll handle it for you.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
[sighs]
What the hell they
making? Christmas cookies?
Walt: I don't know, but I
don't like the look of it.
I'm looking for Creeley Dorn.
You know him?
You recognize his face?
Rome is burning!
Dónde está?
Rome is burning.
What's that? Some kind of code?
Or an alarm. Check that corner.
Hey, Walt, it's a damn security camera.
Creeley's not in here!
[engine turns over]
- Windshield?
- Tires.
Softie!
Come on, Creeley.
You got a key?
You got a warrant?
Lucian: Fore!
Have a seat.
Possession with intent to distribute, Walt.
We got him dead to rights.
Looks like prison didn't
do you much good, Creeley.
Actually, prison was
just the break I needed.
Big leagues at last.
You know I was the best
damn cook in that joint?
[scoffs] We're all proud of you.
What are you cooking these days?
Not a damn thing.
Cooking's dangerous business.
I moved myself up to management.
So what are they cooking? More gutter meth?
Nah. Meth's old news.
That's cheese heroin.
You never even heard of it, have you?
Heroin, sleeping pills, a
little strawberry flavoring.
The after-school set loves it.
Yeah, my little cheese bags
are blowing up everywhere.
You still have delusions of grandeur.
Yeah?
Drive out to Salt Lake or Denver.
Tell me what you find.
Let's start with Denver.
You know this man?
Miller Beck?
Nah.
I don't fraternize with customers.
How'd you know he was a customer?
Homeboy looks like the type.
What'd he do?
Walt: He died.
I'm trying to find out who killed him.
[chuckles] What, you think I did it?
I think you're capable.
The two witnesses who testified against you
both showed up dead two
weeks after you were released.
Come on, Sheriff.
Lex O.D.'d and P-Magnet,
he... he died in a car crash.
At least, that's what I hear.
Besides, you're the one who arrested me.
Wouldn't that put you at
the top of my bucket list?
Maybe I was.
Maybe you sent Miller Beck
to kill my wife instead of me.
Come on.
Stand up.
[handcuffs click]
Woman: What happened? Is there trouble?
I just need to speak with Travis.
Oh, no, no, no, no. Travis is sleeping.
Ma'am, this is official police business.
And this is mothering business.
And you're doing an awesome job.
He needs his rest!
Okay.
Morning, sunshine.
So, which one are you? Tom or Jerry?
Travis: Huh?
Don't you lay a hand on my son.
Would you please close the door?
God. Now, what's going on?
Did you really abduct a Cheyenne man
and force him to take peyote?
'Cause there's a man named Sam Poteet
who identified you from your mugshot.
O-okay. Wait, wait.
You're saying that... that some Indian guy
got high on peyote and picked
my mugshot out at random?
That... that's why you're busting in here?
Can you tell me where you were?
- Travis.
- Mom!
Did she hurt you?
What are you doing?!
When a uniformed officer
breaks into my house
to harass my undressed
child, I document it.
Ma'am, this is totally unnecessary.
- Identify your badge number.
- Can you just...
[gasps] I captured that. I got it.
Okay. Stop. Look.
Maybe, uh, maybe the two of
us can go down to the station
- and just talk about this.
- Mm-hmm.
Would you two just give
me a second, please,
To get dressed, or do you
want to film that, too?
I will not apologize
for protecting my child.
So, you're saying that you saw Hector
steal how many pineapples?
Approximately four.
Chapman: Arnie, you should
be ashamed of yourself.
Selling out Hector to these
people for a little big of cash!
Miss Chapman, I just... leave! Leave!
Can I help you?
Yes, you can. Stop the search.
Hector is a good man.
Who are you to put his
face on a "wanted" poster?
What do you even know about him?
I know that he beats people up for money.
Because sometimes
that's the only way justice can be served.
Vigilantism isn't justice.
Sometimes on the Rez, that's all you get.
Do you remember, Standing Bear,
when that young Cheyenne woman
was raped by those two men?
Yes. I remember.
But I'll bet you don't.
This young woman went to the
police chief, Malachi Strand,
to report the rape.
But everyone knows that Malachi
only investigates crimes if you pay him.
So the young woman dug up
every penny she could find.
Malachi took the money
and found the two men.
Do you remember what happened next?
Yes.
Nothing.
That's right. Nothing.
Because the two rapists
paid Malachi even more money
to drop the charges.
That was it.
Until Hector found out about it.
And he tracked those two rapists down
and he beat them unconscious.
Then he dragged them to
that young woman's house
so she could know that
justice could be done
even on the Rez.
I had no idea.
The Rez needs Hector.
Don't take him from us.
[clears throat]
Adele, we do not want
to put Hector in jail.
I know back then
he was the only one willing to help you.
Right now, he might be the
only one who can help me.
[sighs]
I thought Martha died of cancer, Walt.
You never told me she was murdered.
So you think this here Miller Beck
you've been talking about from Denver,
this here junkie scum killed her?
Yep.
Now Denver's saying
that Henry killed Miller Beck in revenge?
[sighs] Yep.
So, what really happened?
Well, I think someone
with a grudge against me...
...paid Miller Beck to murder Martha
and killed Miller Beck
after I started getting too close.
And you think one of these
here jokers is behind it all?
Well, that's the theory.
Creeley Dorn, his drug distribution
stretches all the way to Denver.
Chance Gilbert, he still has
his younger brother's car,
which is registered in Colorado.
What do you think?
I think that...
I am sorry for your loss, Walt.
[sighs]
I never said that to you and I should have.
Martha was... irreplaceable.
Thanks.
I made a pass at her once.
She told me it was twice.
Really?
I believe I was a bit inebriated.
I do miss our Christmas potlucks.
Yeah.
[sighs]
So, who's next?
Stanley Keene.
Wasn't expecting to see you here.
Thought I'd finish up some paperwork
so I can hit the ground running tomorrow.
I'm been doing fine, by the way.
Thanks for visiting me in the hospital.
I don't do hospitals, nephew,
just like you don't do old folks' homes.
Creeley: Where you taking me?
Back to the big leagues.
Is that your chicken thief?
No. A Cheyenne guy claims
two white dudes kidnapped him
and forced him to take peyote.
Our friend Travis here was I.D.'d by him.
Travis... what's going on?
I mean, defaulting on your home,
That's one thing, but kidnapping?
When did this happen?
- Last night.
- Really?
Well, then it can't be Travis
'cause he was hanging out with me.
He pulled a gun on you last year.
Yeah.
And we got drinks at
the Red Pony last night.
To bury the hatchet.
I had a few too many, Travis drove me home.
Bigger fish, Walt.
Vic: Why didn't you just tell
me this in the first place?
I just wanted to get us out of that house.
Can you blame me?
So did he resist arrest?
- No.
[chuckles] Not this time.
Then I guess that's it.
I'm on my way out, and I owe Travis a ride.
[sighs]
Want me to call Mathias,
tell him that his suspect has an alibi?
No, I can do it.
Easy enough.
Let's go.
It's so good to see you again, Walt.
Stanley, I wanted to ask
if you knew this man... Miller Beck.
Doesn't ring a bell.
So, this is business, then?
I thought maybe you might
want to talk about Martha.
What about her?
I heard she was killed.
Why didn't you tell me?
How did you know about my wife's murder?
I'm in jail, Walt.
Not on some other planet.
I'm profoundly sorry. I...
I know the pain you must be in.
I was so heartbroken when Rebecca passed.
It's an unbearable thing
to lose a soul mate.
Rebecca Pound was not your soul mate.
She was a woman you stalked and assaulted.
And I did my time for that.
And finally, the moment I'm released,
Who's there to meet me at the gate?
Not her. You.
With a restraining order?
Telling me I can never go near her again?
Never see her again?
But you were wrong about that one, Walt.
There's no denying true love.
You tracked Rebecca down
to Laramie, murdered her,
And spread her body parts
across four different counties.
Because you gave me no choice.
You made Rebecca believe
that our love was this filthy thing.
Rebecca would have been so happy with me!
We'd be together now if it weren't for you!
If it weren't for you!
Hey. Any luck finding Hector?
According to today's eyewitness accounts,
we should be able to locate Hector
in three different campgrounds,
one stolen dune buggy...
and a produce dumpster
at the Piggly Wiggly.
Well, I will take that to Walt
and see if there's something he can use.
Henry, can I ask you something?
Branch come here with this guy last night?
He did.
They close the place down?
No, I believe they had one drink apiece
and left by 7:00-ish.
Thanks.
[sighs]
Did you ever feel you created
more evil than you stopped?
Well, I always figured it
was a neck-and-neck race.
You let your highest self rule
and your truest self grieve,
and the world will still strip away
all you ever hoped to achieve.
If you do the job right, Walt,
by the time you put down
your Sheriff's badge,
you're a wanted man.
I always figured that I'd
die by violence and die alone.
That's the price we pay for our ideals.
And I made my peace with that.
What I didn't make my peace with
everyone around me paying for those ideals.
[crowd cheering on TV]
You Wyoming people and your unlocked doors.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Why didn't you just tell me
right off the bat that
you were with Branch?
I-I don't know.
'Cause I was hungover and
naked and then my mom...
I just, I needed a little room to breathe.
That's all.
Besides, going down to the station meant
you and I could spend a
little more time together.
It must have been some hangover.
Just how drunk were you
when you drove Branch home?
[chuckles]
You can't arrest me for DUI after the fact.
Can you?
No.
I was just curious how many cocktails
a couple of real cowboys
can throw back in one night.
- [scoffs]
- Double digits?
Let's just say it was a long fade to black.
That's interesting, Travis.
Because your bar tab at the Red Pony says
you each had one drink and
you left at a quarter to 7:00.
Which means that your alibi is shit.
What are you doing?
I'm taking you in on kidnapping charges.
[scoffs]
Damn it. He was right.
Guys like me get caught
and guys like him don't.
Who was right? Branch?
Look.
I didn't even know what was going on
at first. And then I just went along
to make sure that Branch
didn't kill that guy.
I've known Branch since we were kids
and he's a Connally so
he's always had a temper,
but I had no idea.
No idea what?
That he was psycho.
And now he's got a gun and a badge.
I mean, you got to do
something to stop him, right?
Branch: Missed me, didn't you?
Yeah. Everything ached.
Any luck narrowing down the suspect pool?
Not really. All three guys we talked to
seemed more suspicious than before.
I'm running some
background checks right now.
Meantime, I'm catching up
on these, uh, reportings
of Hector sightings.
Something else?
What should I have done in Philly?
About what?
Bobby Donolato, the dirty
cop that I turned in.
Should I have just kept quiet?
Has there been another
incident with Ed Gorski?
No. No.
Um... [sighs]
Just look at all that's happened
since I turned Bobby in.
The I.A. investigation,
Bobby's own suicide,
Sean and I having to
move, Gorski stalking me...
None of it would have happened
if I'd just kept my mouth shut.
Maybe not.
Or maybe you just stopped a
bad situation getting worse.
Doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter... why not?
I don't think you had a choice.
Looking the other way and keeping quiet,
that's not who you are.
Did you check on that chicken?
Uh, no. The chicken, mmh-mmh.
It was stolen from Newt
Cunningham's farm, right?
Stolen is the wrong word.
Um, whoever took the
chicken left behind 20 bucks,
which is pretty much blue book value.
Sounds like Hector.
So you think Hector took the
chicken and left behind money?
It'd be in his character.
He's always followed a code.
Cady told me that, uh, a woman came in
begging her to stop the search.
Adele Chapman.
She lives here.
Why mark her house?
Who comes in and asks you to
stop looking for a wanted man?
Someone who knows where he is.
And both these locations are
close to the caves at summer pass,
where that hiker claimed he saw an Indian.
Well, yeah, but the hiker's description
didn't sound anything like Hector.
Long hair, thin build, medium height.
You know who this is, right?
It's David Ridges.
You admitted it yourself, Walt.
There's a chance he could still be alive.
I don't think it's Hector hiding up there.
I think it's Ridges.
There's only one way to find out.
Malachi: Such a fine feeling being free.
Ain't that right, Hank?
Sort of a blessing.
You just come and go as you please.
[chuckles]
Well, some of us, anyway.
What do you imagine you are doing?
Ahh. To sweet freedom.
Ahh.
[sniffs]
Hey. Thanks for holding my seat.
[sighs]
The Brotherhood, Hank.
It wears many faces.
You have not even served
half of your sentence.
How can you be out on parole?
I guess the word of Walter Longmire
doesn't hold the same sway that it used to.
Funny how things work out.
I'm free, you're going back inside.
Times be a-changing.
Why, Hank.
Why in the world
would you put this noble
specimen up for sale?
It's not because of money troubles, I hope.
[chuckles] Now that I think of it,
you're gonna have to sell this place
before you go back inside.
You know, maybe it'd be better
if you keep it with your
people, your brothers.
We are not brothers.
Oh, lighten up, Hank.
We'll talk about it when the time comes.
In the meantime, I'll go ahead
and take these stuffed
critters off your hands.
This ought to add some color to my study.
I'll have the boys come by
and pick up the rest later.
I'm not getting shot again.
I need Hector alive.
What if it's not Hector?
Then I need David Ridges alive.
Walt, blood.
Hector!
Hector: You're too late, law man.
What the hell happened to his head?
He's been scalped.
I was outside the cave when he shot me.
One in the chest, two in the legs.
I dragged myself back in here.
But the snake followed me in.
Who's the snake?
Was it him?
Yes.
That is the snake who killed me.
Why would David Ridges come after you?
I don't know.
Doesn't matter.
If it wasn't him, it'd be someone else.
It was always going to end like this.
I always wanted to die
as a warrior, law man,
under the big sky, on my people's land.
Not in some cave like an animal.
Come on.
This is between me and my ancestors now.
A good man is dead because of me.
I need to take matters into my own hands.
Where are you?
There was something urgent
I needed to take care of.
Think I'm losing it.
This is about me trying
to find the man who shot me
and maybe coming back for me.
Found Hector, shot and scalped.
- Sorry to hear that.
- You're lying.
Maybe you're not thinking
so clearly either.
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
www.addic7ed.com