- [creaking]
- [owl hooting]
[Henry grunts]
Sorry about smacking you.
But you totally buried the lead.
If you'd have started with what happened
to Gab, I wouldn't have hit you...
so hard.
[grunts]
Where is Gab?
[Gab] Right behind you.
Do you want a Diet Coke?
- I'm addicted to the stuff.
- [can opens]
[grunts]
- What's wrong with your ass?
- I got shot.
I have something for that.
Ibuprofen.
Reduces swelling.
So... Gab shot a man and needs to lay low.
That requires some serious medicine.
Heather Crazy Dog.
Close enough.
There you go.
After those men attacked you,
your friends tried the sweat?
To call you back?
Did it work?
I wanted it to.
Sometimes it takes more.
My great-grandmother watched white
soldiers massacre her entire family.
She was raped.
She passed this skull down as her
medicine because it's the truth.
Do you have medicine?
I'm not sure what that is.
Your medicine... is a power.
I can change your name.
I can even change your
Social Security number.
But only your medicine
can change what's inside.
Now you're here.
We'll find your medicine.
Okay, you, say goodbye.
I am not leaving her.
You've got a car parked across the
river where the cops can find it
and a truck with your blood in it at home.
You want to help her out?
Go... clean up your mess.
[Gab] She's right.
You need to take back Mandy's
car, or she'll turn us in.
[grunting]
Gab, I am so sorry.
Why?
You got me here.
No.
[grunting]
I think I gave you the
idea to shoot that man.
When I told you to write to Hector.
I think I already had that idea in my head.
You just reminded me
that I had the strength.
Thanks for bringing her.
Never come back.
Subtitle sync and corrections
by awaqeded for www.addic7ed.com.
Henry, it's me, again.
Please give me a call
when you get a chance.
It's kind of important.
[door opens, cell phone beeps]
Morning.
Good morning. [chuckles]
- Coffee?
- Uh, no, thanks.
I just need to go grab my, um...
- Pants?
- Yeah. Yeah.
They're over there, so...
[chuckles]
I'm... I'm gonna go get the paper.
Hi.
Hi. Just met your roommate.
Um...
You have to get dressed and go.
Whoa, whoa. Not till
I have a cup of coffee.
- No.
- Just one cup of coffee.
Otherwise, this feels dirty.
Okay. Okay.
But, um...
Put your clothes on first.
- All right.
- Okay. Okay.
[door closes]
[chuckles]
Met your friend.
Yeah.
Um, Eamonn. Mm-hmm.
Eamonn the deputy?
Uh...
Uh, you can't tell your dad, okay?
[whistles]
Oh, uh, sorry, Ferguson. Morning.
You all right?
- You seem distracted.
- No, I'm good.
I just need to talk to the
sheriff before he gets in.
Sheriff!
Monte? What are you doing here?
I'm sorry to say, but I'm filing
charges against one of your deputies.
Charges? Against who?
Sheriff, I've been
waiting for you to get in.
- You're too late, Zach.
- Whatever this guy has told you...
- Don't you threaten me again.
- Again? I never threatened you.
I don't know what this guy's
problem is, but he's out of control.
I was minding my own business. I
wasn't doing anything to anyone!
He comes busting into my
room without probable cause!
Hey!
My office.
[bird cawing]
Shit.
[tires squeal]
That's messed up, all
right? He's been watching me.
He storms into my room without
permission and with violent intent.
I have witnesses that will tell you
- that he assaulted me.
- All right!
Monte, do you want to
file a formal complaint?
- You're damn right I do.
- [Walt] Ferg's in the bullpen.
He'll take your statement.
Look, before you say anything, can
I show you what I took from his room?
No! You can't.
Anything you have, you got without
a warrant and without probable cause.
He was following me.
Paranoia is not probable cause.
Paranoia is when there's no factual
basis for fear. Now, in this case...
You mean Monte's case?
Because he has a case.
Everything you took from his
room was obtained illegally.
Now, this is the last thing I need when
I'm already dealing with two murders.
[knock on door]
- It's Henry.
- Not now.
He says it's important.
You wait here.
I don't need you and
Monte in the same room.
Sheriff, what am I supposed to do?
Take his statement.
[Trot] Hey! I'm hungry!
Yeah, we all have problems.
Henry, what's so important, it can't wait?
My truck has been stolen.
[Walt] When?
Hard to say. I have not used
it since the night before last.
So sometime in the last 36 hours.
I hate to say it, but I think
the person that took your truck
did it because it's yours and
they didn't think you'd call me.
Who do you think...
Gab. She's fleeing a murder charge.
- Murder?
- [Walt] Yeah.
Tyler Malone died last night.
I do not think Gab
would've stolen my truck.
Ferg found evidence of a
getaway vehicle in the woods.
Gab doesn't own a car.
Your truck is missing, so...
That is still quite a leap.
[sighs] I hope so.
Meantime, we'll call the state police.
I'll let you know if it turns up.
[tires screech]
- Ruby.
- Yeah, state police.
Green '58 GMC truck.
- Looking up the license plates now.
- Thanks.
Where are you going?
I'm going to talk to the
last person that saw Gab.
[grunts]
[Walker] Who the hell are you?
I'm talking to you, asshole.
What are you doing with this car?
Nothing. I was just walking by.
I saw you get out.
Where's Gab, girl who killed my guys?
I really have no idea
what you are talking about.
Gab borrowed the car. You're returning it.
You got to know something.
Hang on a second.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
I do not think so.
No, no. Hey. No, no.
You were at the casino
the other night, right?
You were following me and my guys.
I think you are confused.
[grunting]
Confused, huh?
I feel really good about
this, Mr. Blackwolf.
From what you've told me, there's
absolutely grounds for a case here.
[knock on door]
Uh, I'll come meet you
in an hour at the casino.
- Okay. Bye.
- [cellphone beeps]
Hey, Punk.
Dad.
I was just gonna go outside
and get some... get some air.
Was that...
Yeah. Uh, Cady's his daughter. I
didn't... I didn't tell you that?
No, you didn't.
Huh.
- I need to know everything.
- About what?
About when you saw Gab
yesterday. You said she was alone.
Are you sure?
Why wouldn't I be sure?
Was she hurt?
Not that I could tell, no.
Why couldn't you tell?
Was she in a vehicle?
No. No, I told you. I-I
saw her walking, and then...
Was there one nearby?
There may have been one parked.
Could it have been Henry's truck?
What? No.
Good morning, Walt. We got to go.
There's been some sort of a
kerfuffle at Mandy Plitt's house.
Ruby's word, not mine.
If you remember anything,
you call me, okay?
I don't know what you two have been
doing, but I caught an accomplice.
An accomplice to what?
- This Indian...
- [groans]
- Hey!
- ...either helped Gab murder my guys
or knows where to find her.
Back up, Walker.
We don't even know that Gab had
anything to do with Tyler's murder.
Well, you may not, but I do.
Owen here said he saw Gab the
morning after Tyler was shot.
You saw Gab?
Right here. She was in a
hurry to borrow Mandy's car.
After Mandy said no, she threatened Owen.
That ought to tell you
a little bit about her.
What'd Gab say?
She told Mandy to hand over the
keys or she'd accuse me of rape
and that I'd end up dead...
just like Will and Tyler.
Okay, in my book, that's an admission
of murder for both Tyler and Will.
What's he got to do with this?
Gab borrowed the car. He returned it.
So he's either in on it or
he knows where to find her.
Is that true?
- No.
- Bullshit!
This Indian was following me and my guys.
He was there at the casino
the night Tyler that was shot.
For all I know, the girl was
laying in the back of the truck
while he was talking to me.
So, you gonna arrest him, Sheriff?
Unfortunately, I can't.
See, this is the Res.
I got no jurisdiction here.
[scoffs] I don't get this. I...
What do you got against us? What
did me and my men ever do wrong?
Aside from rape and murder,
you all seem like great guys.
So, this is... It's just
a goddamn joke to you, huh?
This Indian, he's an accessory to murder.
Even if that's true,
there's nothing I can do.
Then I will.
[Walt] You don't have
that authority, either.
He's got to go to the tribal police.
Sir, who would you rather
take you to the tribal police?
Me or him?
Out!
[groans]
Henry, are you okay?
It got a bit physical before you
arrived. I landed on something sharp.
What the hell's going on?
I am as confused as you are.
Well, you're sure not as mad as I am.
What are you doing in Mandy's car?
The one that Gab borrowed the
morning after the shooting?
She asked me to return it for
her this morning as a favor.
You saw Gab this morning?
No. She called. I do not know from where.
Why couldn't she return the car herself?
She did not say. I did not ask.
She said she had parked it at the Red Pony.
When I went down this morning to get it,
that is when I noticed my truck was
missing, and that is when I called you.
Do you think it's possible that
when she dropped off Mandy's car,
she took your truck?
It is possible.
You knew Tyler had been
shot. I told you that.
It didn't cross your mind that maybe Gab
had done it and she was trying to escape?
I was with Gab yesterday morning.
She was not trying to escape then.
You were with her?
Yes.
We took a walk.
Ask your daughter. She saw us both.
Cady saw you?
Yes.
Get back in.
Why? So you can yell at me some more?
There's clearly no point.
You've said all you're gonna say.
So what, then, are you
going to take me to Mathias?
I'm not taking you to Mathias.
Then I would rather walk.
[Vic] Henry, you're hurt.
Best thing for an injury is to walk it off.
So, did you really hit Monte?
Not on purpose.
Well, I'm sure he was asking for it.
How screwed do you think I am?
Ruby, call Cady. Tell her to
come here as soon as possible.
Okay.
Ferg, do you have Monte's statement?
Uh, yeah. I got it right here.
- But I just want to s...
- Let me see it.
I'm not sure which is
more surprising to me...
the fact that Cady Longmire has
voluntarily come to pay me a visit
or that she's friends
with Calvin Blackwolf.
- I represent Mr. Blackwolf.
- In what?
[Cady] In the matter of
his wrongful dismissal.
Wrongful dismissal? You were fired?
What happened?
I'm here to ask you the same question.
You're his employer.
That's true.
But I don't handle day-to-day
personnel decisions on the floor.
- And that would be?
- [door opens]
Malachi Strand.
Why did Malachi fire you, Calvin?
He, uh... He said I was missing
shifts. But that's not true.
Every time big tippers came to the table,
Malachi would tell me to go take a break.
I needed those tips. It's not fair.
And you complained to him?
He did.
And he was fired.
My client believes that this was
about Malachi playing favorites.
But I think Malachi's behavior could
suggest even more egregious improprieties.
"Egregious improprieties."
All the self-righteous hostility
one expects from a Longmire,
but with notably more elegant vocabulary.
You are free to treat this
like a joke, Mr. Nighthorse,
but you have 24 hours to
respond to my client's complaint.
After which time, we will be filing suit.
Indeed.
Well, I will take all of
this under consideration.
I'm sure you will.
So, do I get to defend myself?
You read this?
Is it all true?
Well, yes. But...
Then the "but" doesn't
really matter, Zachary.
I'm sorry, but you can't storm
into somebody's room without cause,
steal their property, and hit them.
- That was an accident.
- [Walt] Well, I'm sure it was.
But it should never have happened.
Well, I promise...
I won't make another mistake like that.
[Walt] But you already have.
You got into a fight at the oil
field your first week on the job.
Now this.
That's two physical altercations
in such a short time.
You once told me...
that the best way to stop a problem...
was to get there before
it becomes a problem.
I'm sorry, but that's
what I got to do here.
You don't have to say any more.
Well, unfortunately, I do.
I need your badge and gun.
Sorry I screwed up, Sheriff.
I know.
So am I.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Hey.
What's up?
I understand the rest of
the world disappointing me.
But you?
What are you talking about?
You lied to my face.
Twice.
You saw Henry walking
with Gab yesterday morning.
And yet you told me again
and again that she was alone.
How did you find out?
Henry told me.
He did?
Well, if he was willing to tell you,
then obviously, he has nothing to hide.
He only told me because he was cornered.
And you only confirmed it...
because I caught you in a lie.
Why did you feel you had to lie?
I thought that maybe Henry
was involved with... something.
But I was obviously
just being overdramatic.
What did you think he did?
Okay.
We've gotten to a place where I'm
uncomfortable answering these questions.
Cady, this is serious.
I have reason to believe he's
involved in a serious crime.
Which is why I can't talk to you about it.
He is, after all, my client.
Ex-client.
Well, we never dissolved the relationship.
You're going to use legal technicalities
so you can... you can lie to me?
I'm not lying to you. And I'm sorry.
But if I tell you things without
Henry's permission, I could be disbarred.
- He's not here.
- What do you mean he's not here?
Henry Standing Bear is
an accessory to a murder.
That's why he's not here. That's a felony.
I'm not authorized to
deal with cases like that.
Strictly misdemeanors around here.
- So you let a criminal go.
- [sighs]
- Well, that's the flip side.
- Flip side of what?
Well, you and your men can do
whatever you want on the Res
without anybody being able to hurt you.
The flip side is when something goes wrong,
there's nobody that can help you, either.
So the sheriff's not gonna lift
a finger to find this murderer.
You aren't, either.
That doesn't leave me a lot
of goddamn options, does it?
Sure doesn't.
[laughs]
[Mathias] You were right.
He was here, and he's pissed.
Okay, Mathias. Thanks for the update.
You fire Zachary?
I did.
So what was it that he found over there?
I don't know.
You didn't let him explain himself?
What difference would it make?
I don't know.
But neither do you.
Look, I'll admit it.
Took me a little while
to warm up to Zachary.
But I think he's a good cop.
So do I.
So what happens if he was right?
What happens when he's not?
What's that tell you and Vic
about how you should do your jobs?
Obviously, this is your decision to make.
But I think you're making Zach
pay for someone else's crimes.
Yes. This is about Branch.
That was the last time my
personal feelings about a deputy
led me to make the wrong decision.
But Zach's not Branch.
Branch was always trying
to prove something.
It was always about Branch.
But Zach...
I just think he really
wants to help people.
You might be right.
I believe his intentions are good.
But I have to think about the consequences.
I've made my decision.
[door closes]
[Henry inhales sharply]
[knock on door]
Come in!
Jacob?
Wow.
You must really love the Red Pony...
to willingly live in a place like this.
And to stay on, even after
you got bought out by Malachi.
"Bought out" is not how I
would put it. He tricked me.
Well, he tricked me, too.
I thought that Malachi's past mistakes
were attributable to his circumstances
and that if someone like me believed
in him, his best self would come out.
But there may be no best
self left in the man.
Jacob, why are you here?
I have mounting evidence
that Malachi has been using the casino
as a base for illegal activities.
He's threatening everything
that I have set up.
And I need your help.
Illegal activities are more
of a Sheriff Longmire thing.
Why not go to him?
Well...
Because... he hates me...
and doesn't trust me.
And you think I do?
Maybe not.
But in the end, Henry, I think
that you and I want the same thing.
Betterment of our people,
achieved by our people.
Walt would see my trouble with Malachi
as an opportunity to destroy my casino.
You might see it as an
opportunity to save your bar.
Just when I was beginning
to see you as an idealist,
the pragmatic negotiator comes out.
[Nighthorse] Ah, yeah, well...
we both like being our own boss.
If you help me keep my business,
I'll help you get yours back.
What are you proposing I do?
Malachi's been stealing money.
He's got to hide it somewhere.
I'm guessing it's here.
- Money laundering.
- Yeah.
If you could help me prove that...
they wouldn't let him run
this place from prison.
Think about it...
Henry.
[knock on door]
Monte, can I come in?
Sure.
I'm gonna leave the door open
in case things get out of hand.
[Walt] I want you to know that
we take these charges seriously.
Zachary's been let go for his behavior.
I'm here to apologize personally.
Wow.
Okay. Apology accepted.
Knowing what a harsh
outcome this is for Zachary,
I wanted to suggest that
maybe you find your way
to dropping the charges against him.
What's in it for me if I do?
Nothing.
[chuckles] Ah, it was worth a try.
Bribery would have made a really
juicy addition to the complaint.
What complaint?
This one.
You're suing me for your
little tiff with Zachary?
Or is this just your way of getting
back at me for not hiring you?
I'm not the one suing you.
I'm just the investigator.
Who's suing me?
Barlow Connally.
[Ruby] Frankly, I don't care...
[Walker] No, I don't!
[Ruby] Yelling is not
gonna change my answer, sir!
It's just gonna make you look foolish!
- Just call him on his cell phone!
- He doesn't have one.
- Bullshit! Who doesn't have a cell phone?
- Watch your language, sir!
There he is.
Time's up, Sheriff.
Make an appointment.
How 'bout instead of
that, I set a court date?
You've been holding Trot for two days.
- It's actually only been 36 hours.
- Close enough.
As far as I know, you haven't
charged him with anything yet.
- We've got 48 hours to do that.
- Right.
But if you haven't charged him, I can only
assume it's because of lack of evidence.
And we both know that you're suddenly
not gonna find some in the next 12 hours.
Not when the actual
killer's still out there.
- What do you want, Walker?
- What do you think I want?
You charge him or you release him.
If you do neither, I've got lawyers at
Newett drawing up paperwork right now
to drop a wrongful-arrest
suit against you.
Wrongful arrest? Based on what?
Abuse of power, corruption, colluding with
tribal police to conceal the real suspects
while intimidating and
harassing me and my men.
Shall I go on?
I hope you all realize next time you try
to hang false charges on me and my guys,
not gonna be so patient.
Okay, Walt.
I'm sure you got a good
reason, but why would you...
Because now is not the time for
me to be fielding any questions
about corruption, abuse
of power, or intimidation.
Why not?
Because I'm already being sued for
the wrongful death of Barlow Connally.
[Ruby] Walt, Walt.
Not so fast.
So, Ruby said, uh, Steve
Rosato saw the abandoned truck
in a lane behind his store.
Sounded like it could be Henry's.
You think Gab is somewhere around here?
[Walt] Don't know.
You worried about that lawsuit at all?
I mean, I know that Monte took
a lot of stuff out of context,
but there's some pretty
damning stuff in there.
Why should I be worried?
The feds cleared me. It's
just gonna be a hassle.
These lawsuits eat up a lot of time.
Yeah.
It's a bad time to be shorthanded.
[grunts]
About that, uh, I was thinking,
instead of going through
a whole search again,
you think Eamonn might be
interested in taking that job?
Uh...
I don't, uh... I don't really
think that that's the best idea.
Why?
Um...
Because Eamonn and I are in a relationship.
Um... a sexual one.
We're sleeping together.
Oh.
Oh?
Seriously? That's your response?
What do you want me to say?
I don't know.
"Wow, I had no idea," or, "How
long has that been going on?"
It's none of my business.
Yeah, Walt, you know... [sighs]
We used to be close, you
know, so close, in fact,
that my ex-husband thought we
were too close, and so did Lizzie.
And everybody else always thought that
there was something going on between us.
You know, it's not like you actually
encouraged me to stay married.
And then, you think that Eamonn is
flirting with me, so you push him away,
and then all of a sudden you
start dating the psychiatrist,
and you want to hire Eamonn?
Why?
Feel guilty?
Please don't walk away from me.
I'm not walking away from you.
I'm walking away from
that truck. It's a Chevy.
It's not Henry's.
So, what exactly is the nature of
your relationship with Dr. Monaghan?
The exact nature of my relationship
is none of your business.
It is my business, Walt.
Whether you like it or not,
your life, it impacts mine.
[sighs]
[Ruby] Walt, Dr. Monaghan called.
She needs you to get over
to the church right away.
[police radio chatter]
[Donna] Thank you so much. Yeah.
[sighs] Oh, thank God you're here.
Is that your van?
Yeah. I, uh, came out after my
group, and... and it was on fire.
And the fire department said
that someone broke the window
and threw a Molotov cocktail inside, so...
Jesus.
You think it was your patient?
Well, i-i-it's hard for me to imagine
any other explanation right now.
What's your patient's name?
I'm sorry. I'm just not really
comfortable giving you that information.
I don't think you're bound
by doctor-patient privilege
in the face of a violent act like this.
No. It's...
This patient hasn't made
their last four sessions,
so I'm completely in the dark as
to their state of mind right now.
So, someone lit your van on fire, and
you don't want to tell us who it is?
Yes. That's right.
[Walt] Well, I don't
think you should go home
till we know that this
patient is no longer a threat.
You got somewhere to stay?
Uh, yeah, I can...
You should just stay with Walt.
It'll be a lot safer for
you with a man around.
[police radio chatter]
How did you get in?
Boyfriend gave me a key.
What do you want?
To talk.
Where is your, uh, friend Gab?
I don't know.
[groans]
[coughs]
Aah!
[coughs, groaning]
You tell me where she is, and this'll stop.
[grunts] No, it won't.
Aah!
[rock music playing]
Hey.
You know, you were right.
About Monte.
He's trying to dig up dirt
on Walt for a civil suit.
Monte's bad news.
I saw the stuff you found in his room.
You know, the transcript
of my conversation with him?
It was totally taken out of
context to make Walt look bad.
Monte's really trying to take Walt down.
What are you gonna do?
Actually, I thought I might
take another run at Walt.
- Get him to take you back.
- Nah.
That ship has sailed.
Are you drinking?
There's no reason not to anymore. Hmm?
I can think of a bunch.
All right, look. I'm gonna take you home.
No, I'm good.
Hey.
Come on, man.
Come on.
I'm tired of people not listening to me!
Give me your goddamn keys!
You know, it's, uh...
It's been a long time since there's
been something positive in my life.
I thought this job was going to be that.
I just got sick of cops always
getting there after the crime,
after someone had been raped or murdered.
And I thought that I could be the guy
who could stop those things from
happening in the first place.
Look, man, I'm...
I'm really sorry... I gave you such
a hard time when you first showed up.
You didn't deserve it.
It's good, man.
It's all good.
What are you doing?
Well, since you're driving,
I can have another drink.
Bartender!
I've been checking with
the state police hourly,
and they have absolutely
nothing on Henry's truck.
They put out an alert to all
the counties, other states?
It's not their first
stolen vehicle, Walter.
What about Gab? Anyone respond
to the missing-persons alert?
- No.
- [door opens]
- [Mandy] Please.
- [Ruby] Oh, Lord.
You have to help her.
Mandy, what happened?
I didn't tell him anything, I swear.
I don't know anything. But you...
You have to find Gab before he does.
Who?
Who did this?
[Malachi] Mr. Browning.
It's a pleasure to see you again.
[Walker] I need to find a girl.
Oh? For you this time or one
of your [chuckles] colleagues?
Not that kind of girl.
Her name's Gab Langton.
She killed one of my guys.
Well, I am not a bounty hunter.
If I don't find her, they're gonna
pin the murder on one of my boys.
I can't have that.
If Trot goes down, he
might take me with him.
And our lucrative arrangement where
I overpay you to take care of my guys,
that's over.
[Malachi] Do we have
anything other than a name?
[Walker] Make, model, and license
number of her getaway vehicle,
and her accomplice is an Indian
by the name of Henry Standing Bear.
[laughs] Hank Standing Bear's involved?
Well, now I am interested.
- Well, the sheriff sure isn't.
- [chuckles]
Walter Longmire's not going to help you.
He's Hank's best friend.
But tell you what, I'll put
the word out to the brotherhood.
And if any of them has seen
Gab or Hank, I'll let you know.
I know you know where Gab is.
I know you helped her escape.
Now you need to tell me where she is.
Walt...
you tried to get justice for her...
and could not.
And now, just maybe, she found
the only justice available to her.
Why are you working so
hard to punish her for that?
Because if I don't get to her first,
Walker Browning will hunt
her down and kill her.
Now, I'm gonna ask you one more time.
Where's Gab?
[rock music playing]
Hey.
Hi.
I promised you a home-cooked
meal and I never delivered, so...
Oh, you delivered.
[both chuckle]
Also, this is a restaurant,
so not really home-cooked.
Ah.
Well, the guy who cooks here... Henry...
also lives here, so it is his home.
Well, that's thin, but I'll allow it.
[laughs]
[clears throat]
Mm.
Also, I wanted to let you know that
Walt brought up the idea of hiring you.
And I know that I should have
spoken to you about it first,
but I told him that it
just couldn't happen.
Yeah, you definitely should've
spoken to me about that first.
Well, yeah, but I mean that it
wouldn't have mattered anyway
'cause we can't work together
if we're in a relationship.
All I did was pick you up at the hospital,
and now we're in a relationship and
you're making career decisions for me?
Vic, I told you I liked it here.
And my current boss turns out
to be ethically challenged,
something I helped expose.
So I don't know how long
I'm going to be in that job.
- I'm sorry, Eamonn. I...
- Are you?
Because...
'Cause it... It feels like
I'm just some kind of pawn
in whatever weird dynamic
you and Walt have going on.
That... That is not true.
Really?
He fired me because he was jealous,
and now you tell him not to hire me
because you want to make him jealous?
[scoffs]
Okay, so I'll admit that I didn't
handle this situation particularly well.
But none of that means that
I don't really like you.
You know, Vic? Ah.
I like you, too.
But before there's gonna
be any kind of "us,"
you got to figure out
what's going on with you.
Gab?
Hey.
So, here it is, the great demon
your mother fought so hard against.
Christina.
It's not that bad, is it?
Well, my client sure seems to like it,
so I'm hoping you have
some good news for him.
Well, that's not why I asked you to come.
Please, sit.
If we're not talking about
Calvin Blackwolf's job,
then we're not talking.
I think you're gonna want to hear this.
Please.
The profit generated by all this was
never intended to enrich any one person.
It is intended to change
the life of the whole tribe.
And yet you're the only
one in a Prada suit.
I want to fund the construction of
schools, hospitals, treatment centers.
I-I really don't have time for a speech.
Um, I have a complaint I
have to write for my client.
And I would also like to fund you.
[chuckles]
Excuse me?
Most of our people
don't understand the law.
They can't afford lawyers.
But with a properly funded
and managed legal-aid center,
we could start to change that.
Are you trying to buy me off so that
I'll make Calvin's lawsuit just go away?
Calvin shouldn't have been fired.
His job's still here if he wants it,
along with back pay and
an extra week's vacation.
What I would like, Cady,
is for everyone in Cheyenne Nation
to have access to representation.
And I'd like you to provide it.
I was raised by a white woman.
And I know there are a
few special ones out there.
So call my office if you're interested.
[Walt] Gab?
You can't come in here.
You're supposed to fast
for at least 24 hours first.
Gab, you need to come with me.
We have to leave now.
Are you here to arrest me?
I'm here to protect you.
There's another man
who's trying to kill you.
Why?
He thinks you killed his
friend, the oil worker.
And if you're not around
to tell your story,
he can pin a second murder on you, too.
I don't care.
I wish I did kill them both.
I know.
But if you let them blame
you for both murders,
that means they get away with everything.
And they can do it again.
[Gab] Marilyn says this medicine wheel
is like a microphone to our ancestors.
I've been asking for their guidance.
It's hard to believe they would
send a white sheriff to help me.
Spirit helpers can take on strange forms.
Maybe this time your ancestors
just worked through Henry.
He drew me this map.
Do you think he would've sent
me if I wasn't on your side?
Well, isn't this a coincidence?
[Walt] Out of my way, Walker.
[Walker] All right.
As long as you leave Gab with me.
- I can't do that.
- [Walker] Of course you can.
Look, I know we've had our differences,
but we're both just doing the same thing.
- No, we're not.
- [Walker] Sure, we are.
We're looking out for our friends.
I'm doing right by Tyler,
who this girl shot and killed.
And you're trying to protect your pal Henry
from getting busted being her accomplice.
I'll keep your secret.
Leave the girl with me.
Or what?
Gonna shoot us?
[scoffs] I'm not gonna shoot you.
He is.
- [gun cocks]
- Put the gun down, Sheriff.
And the handgun.
You don't think killing a
sheriff will catch up with you?
We're on the Res.
All kinds of crazy shit happens on
the Res that nobody has to pay for.
[gunshot]
[groans]
Aah!
Gab?
Hey.
Where is she?
Who? Gab?
She's gone.
I know that. Where did she go?
She hasn't gone anywhere.
She's gone.
As, uh... in, Gab is no longer Gab.
Who is she?
It's more like, "What is she?"
She's been transformed
into a red-tailed hawk.
Just now?
She's always been a hawk in spirit.
Now she's a hawk in reality.
Did you fire that shot?
What shot?
[Walt] Somebody just
killed a man down there.
Saved my life.
Gab's, too.
Good deal.
Yeah. I suppose it is.
Are you gonna go after her?
There's no point.
If she's a hawk, that's
outside my jurisdiction.
[hawk screeches]
Hey. Look what I found.
Thanks. I have been
looking all over for it.
I bet.
How can I repay you?
With blood.
Hector.
So, do you want to talk about any of it?
Maybe.
Eventually.
Not now.
Okay.
It's really quiet out here.
Yep.
It's great.
It's a little too quiet, don't you think?
Do you play this thing?
Not in a long time.
Come on, play me something.
I'm a little rusty.
Like, rusty-rusty or chicken-rusty?
[clears throat]
[notes play]
[piano plays]
There.
No! No. Come on.
Play some more. Move over.
[piano playing]
[music stops]
[indie rock song playing]
♪ I am nothing without pretend ♪
♪ I know my thoughts ♪
♪ Can't live with them ♪
♪ I am nothing without a man ♪
♪ I know my faults ♪
♪ But I can't hide them ♪
♪ I still keep my baby teeth ♪
♪ In the bedside
table with my jewelry ♪
♪ You still sleep in the bed with me ♪
♪ My jewelry, and my baby teeth ♪
Zach, it's Ferg.
Where are you?
Give me a call, okay?
[Walt] Do you ever feel you've
created more evil than you've stopped?
♪ I don't need another friend ♪
♪ When most of them ♪
♪ I can barely keep up with ♪
♪ I'm perfectly able
to hold my own hand ♪
♪ But I still can't kiss my own neck ♪
Subtitle sync and corrections
by awaqeded for www.addic7ed.com.