Previously on Longmire...
I have to pretend to be weaker than I am.
We're both done pretending.
Where's Ridges?!
If he knew anything, he
would have told you by now.
I'm taking you in... on kidnapping charges.
- He was right.
- Who was right? Branch?
This is about Branch?
There's no way he should be carrying
a badge and a gun, right now.
David Ridges, he was here!
He's a time bomb just waiting to go off.
He was standing right behind me!
[Sighs]
We've been trying Branch's
cellphone since yesterday.
He's not answering.
So... where is he?
[Scoffs] What makes you think I would know?
Well, you two were pretty close.
I mean, you do kidnap people together.
I had no idea what Branch
was doing that night
w-when I met him for a drink.
You went along with it, though.
I wasn't gonna leave that
Indian guy alone with Branch.
Look, I-I seriously thought
that Branch was gonna...
look, I told Vic what
happened the very next day.
I'll swear before a judge right now
that what I said was true,
but if I do, you two...
you need to give me some kind
of protection or something.
Are you afraid of Branch?
[Sighs]
You know, he... He came
by a few nights back.
He offered me a check for
more money than I've ever seen,
and all I had to do was change my story...
tell Vic that what I said about
the kidnapping wasn't true...
but I said no.
How did he respond?
He said, "you better pray
that Vic doesn't tell
anyone for both your sakes'."
And after that, he took off.
I have no idea where he is right now.
You really think Branch
will come after you?
[Scoffs] You... you don't get it.
When a guy like Branch falls,
there ain't no helping him.
And when things don't go his way...
There's no telling what he might do.
[Cellphone ringing]
Hello.
Ridges: The crazy dogs led me to you.
Ridges.
You've been chasing ghosts.
The only way you can catch
a ghost is to stop running.
Stop and look all around you.
Ridges, get your hands up!
You can't shoot me.
I've counted coup on you three times.
I've already taken all of your power.
Stay where you are.
First time, I touched you with a feather.
And I took your courage.
The second time, I went inside your dreams
and I took your peace.
[Screams]
The third time, I took a picture of you.
[Camera shutter clicks]
Your soul is now mine.
One more step, and I shoot.
You can't even pull the trigger.
The next time I see you,
I will take your life.
[Gunshot]
[Shouting]
[Shouts]
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
- www.addic7ed.com -
[Door opens]
Ruby: May I help you?
Yes, I'm here to see the Sheriff.
Oh.
- Walt!
- Excuse me, for yelling.
Mr. Poteet, come in.
Straight through.
You get ahold of Branch?
Not yet. Who is that guy?
Sam Poteet.
Why is he here?
'Cause I asked him to
be. Keep trying Branch.
Poteet: I hope we can make this quick.
I'm starting a new job at Lanton Plumbing,
and I don't want to be late.
We just need to ask you some questions
about your recent abduction.
You've already identified one of the men.
Is this the other one?
He works for you.
Can you think of a reason
that he might want to kidnap you?
No.
Well, Branch was recently attacked
by a white warrior named David Ridges.
He may have thought that
you were also involved.
- Why would he think that?
- You tell me.
After all, you're the one
who sits behind the moon.
This is starting to seem
like you're more concerned
with protecting your
Deputy than helping me.
Nope. No, my Deputy broke the law.
No, this department is behind you
if you want to press charges.
No, I trust that the universe
will see to my justice.
I'm sorry, but there's no smoking in here.
Burning sage... purifies the spirit,
gives us strength for the battles ahead.
You're gonna need that
to face this man who works for you.
He's been all hollowed out
and filled with... bad medicine.
Best of luck, Sheriff.
Is there any way we can
make him press charges?
- No.
- What kind of charges?
Maybe we should try calling Branch
from an outside phone line.
We could have Cady call,
but considering what she's been through
- and what happened...
- Whoa, is Cady okay?
What? Yeah, yeah, she's fine.
Ferg, uh, call the Highway Patrol.
Put out an APB on Branch.
He's in Cady's vehicle.
No!
Not until one of you
tells me what's going on.
Ferg, now's not really the time.
When is the time?
I know you haven't noticed,
but ever since Branch started going crazy,
I really stepped it up around here.
And that's not easy with you
two shutting doors in my face,
treating me like I'm not even
a part of this department.
I do everything you
ask, and I do a good job,
but if you want me to keep doing it,
you can't just throw me in the
corner at this little kid's desk
and ignore me.
There.
Now sit at your big, new desk
and call the Highway Patrol.
[Clattering]
Cady: I really thought I'd
find one person in Denver
who'd at least seen Darius and
Miller Beck in the same room.
[Sighs]
Then I would have had something
to build our defense on.
Henry: I suppose Malachi and Darius
are more careful than we realized.
So now what?
Now we go back to the murder book.
Let me see that.
[Thuds]
Seems a little light.
The prosecution assured
me this is everything
they're planning on bringing
against us in the trial.
Yeah, but what are they not bringing?
The prosecution tends to
leave out any information
that can disprove their case.
We need to search through
every page of this,
see if there are any
holes in their argument.
- I will bring coffee.
- [Cellphone rings]
[Beeps]
Cady Longmire.
What? When?
Keep the judge there.
I'm coming right down.
We have to go to the courthouse.
- They're trying to advance our trial date.
- To when?
To two weeks from today, and
we are nowhere near ready.
I've never heard of a trial
date being advanced that much.
Hey. Hey.
It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna get a continuance.
I know you will.
Walter.
Just... please don't say it.
I understand I, uh... I overreacted.
I'm angry with myself.
All the signs were there
that, uh... Branch wasn't okay.
He wasn't ready to come back.
I should've forced him
to take some time off,
but, uh... instead,
I gave him just enough
rope to hang himself.
All you did was treat Branch
the way you would want to be treated.
Problem is, he's not you.
What's that?
Well, it's something to
take your mind off Branch.
It's from Vic's husband.
From Sean?
Yep.
[Sighs]
Why would he send these to me?
Why do you think? [Chuckles]
He wants you to deliver
divorce papers to his wife.
Branch: Walt! Walt!
Where's Walt?!
Walt! Walt!
I found Ridges. He's alive.
He's alive. He called my phone.
Just... just slow down. Where you been?
He... he was on Pike's Bridge.
I-I tried to bring him in,
but he jumped in the river.
I followed him on the
road as long as I could,
but then the river, you know,
it turns away from the road into the woods.
Walt: Just stop, Branch.
Came back here for ammunition and backup.
I figure Ferg and me could lock down...
one side of the river bank.
Vic could cover the other.
First, we need to talk about
what you did to Sam Poteet.
You just couldn't keep
your mouth shut, could you?
Don't you dare put this on me.
I'm not the one who decided
to go bat-shit crazy.
[Shouts]
- Hey, get off her!
- Get off her!
Get off her!
[Both grunting]
Get the key, Ferg!
- Quick!
- [Shouts]
What are you doing?
Ridges. He's alive.
I'm gonna head over to see Nighthorse.
When he hears that, uh,
Ridges has been spotted,
he, uh... he might be ready to talk.
You really believe what Branch was saying?
Take a look at him, Walt.
The guy is messed up.
Maybe so.
But just because Branch
isn't right in the head
doesn't mean he's not right.
- So, what are we supposed to do with him?
- I don't know.
Walt just went to go see Nighthorse.
You don't have to whisper.
Some of us are trying to work.
I understand why you had to tell Walt.
I want you to know there
are no hard feelings.
[Laughs] Speak for yourself.
Look, Vic, Ridges is still out there.
His car's on the bridge.
If you would just go out there, please.
Look, I don't know what your deal is,
but I know that I am not driving
all the way out to Pike's Bridge
just to find out that
the car has disappeared
like every other piece
of evidence about Ridges!
[Keys jingling]
The car's still there.
I took his keys out of the ignition.
Now, you can stand there
and just say that I'm crazy,
but later, you'll have to explain to Walt
how you could have caught
the guy who shot me,
but you just... let him go.
I can go check it out.
No, I'll go.
Anything to get me out of here.
Let me out and I'll come with you.
We can track him down together.
Not a chance.
[Door slams]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Echoing] Nighthorse!
We need to talk.
You'll have to come up here, then.
Nighthorse: Very busy day today.
We're about to finish phase
three of our construction.
Walt: I'll make this quick, then.
It's time you admitted you
lied to me about David Ridges.
Seriously, again with this?
It's getting boring, Walt.
I got hard evidence that Ridges is alive.
One of my deputies saw
him, even talked to him.
Really?
This wouldn't be the same Deputy
who recently kidnapped a good Cheyenne man
and force-fed him peyote?
Where did you hear that?
Word gets around.
So it looks like
all you really have to
prove that David is alive
is the word of an obviously
unstable criminal, really.
I wouldn't call that hard evidence, Walt.
Now, this game you're playing
with discrediting Branch...
having him drugged with peyote,
sending Ridges in to mess with his head...
this ain't gonna work much longer.
I know you lied to me about Ridges.
He is alive.
And it's only a matter
of time before I prove it.
Barlow: Longmire!
[Door opens]
Longmire!
Uh, he's not here right now.
He'll be back soon.
Dad, I thought you were bringing a lawyer.
I don't have time to waste.
Open that cell. Release my son.
I can't do that... not
until Walt gives the okay.
Ferguson.
Does your dad still own
that roofing business?
Because I swear to you, if
you don't open that cell,
your father will never get
another construction job
in this state again.
- You can't do that.
- Try me.
Your honor, the state's request
to advance our trial date
is completely out of line. This is nothing
but the Prosecution's
attempt to derail our case.
You don't need to get
emotional, Miss Longmire.
The state has a valid reason
for requesting that the date be moved.
- Which is?
- Witness availability.
Our key witness, Detective Fales,
leaves the state in a month's time.
We need to hold the trial before
then in order to get his testimony.
Your honor, the D.A.'s office
could easily record Fales' testimony.
Well, you might find it hard
to cross-examine a video, Counselor.
Well, the state's request for
an earlier trial date is granted.
Well, in that case, we'd like to
formally file for a continuance.
There's no reason this case
even needs to go to trial.
We'd be more than happy to make a deal.
Under what terms?
Your client pleads guilty,
we take the death penalty off the table.
We can offer a life sentence
with a possibility of
parole after 25 years.
[Laughs]
Miss Longmire will have
to consult with her client.
There is nothing to discuss.
That deal is not an option.
It is an option. Your only one, actually.
This trial's happening in two weeks.
What, exactly, were you
planning on presenting in court?
What we talked about...
that Malachi hired Darius
Burns to kill Miller Beck.
No, you have no proof
that Darius even has
a connection with Beck.
I hate to say it, Cady,
but you've got nothing.
Other than the fact that I am innocent.
[Sighs]
[Door closes]
Where's Branch?
I got him a burrito.
His dad came and picked him up.
How did Barlow even know he was here?
Well, everyone we arrest is
allowed to make a phone call,
and technically, we never arrested Branch.
And Vic didn't file a complaint,
and you said that Sam Poteet guy
wasn't pressing charges,
so we had nothing to hold him on.
He assaulted an officer.
So did you.
I'm sorry.
I know you were just defending Vic.
[Sighs]
- But, um...
- What?
Barlow threatened my dad, Walt.
Where was Vic during all this?
She left before it all happened.
She went to check out that car
that Ridges' abandoned on Pike's Bridge.
We have an unstable, violent cop
and the person who told on him,
both out there right now.
Does Vic know Branch is out?
No.
Walt, what's wrong?
Barlow managed to get Branch
released while I was out.
I thought, uh...
I thought Branch may come after you, so...
You get rid of one stalker,
here comes another one.
I wouldn't let that happen.
But, uh, still, with Branch out,
be better if someone
stayed home with you, so...
Vic: You mean, like, my husband?
Well, I didn't know if
he was traveling, so...
- No, he's around.
- Okay.
Okay, good.
Vic: Yeah.
So, how did it go with Nighthorse?
Well, he's sticking with his story.
Well, a ghost didn't drive this car, so...
Walt: Huh.
Even though I know he's lying,
we still can't prove that Ridges is alive
and working with Nighthorse.
- [Cellphone beeps]
- Walt.
The history on this phone
says that Ridges did call Branch.
But he also called someone else.
Call the Judge on your phone.
Tell him we need an arrest warrant.
[Cellphone beeps]
[Ringing]
Barlow: You know, I got a dry-aged t-bone
for dinner tonight,
but looks like we might
ought to put in on that eye of yours.
I'm fine.
[Chuckles]
- Hey, dad?
- Yeah.
I need to borrow the car.
Why?
I got a job to finish.
No, you don't.
You don't believe me, either.
Son, don't take this the wrong way,
but frankly, I don't care.
The way I see it, there
are two possibilities.
Either you're imagining all this,
in which case your
judgment can't be trusted,
or this David Ridges is still alive
and trying to kill you.
In either case, I can't allow my only son
to put himself back in harm's way again.
Now, come on in.
After you've had a shower and some sleep,
we'll work this out together.
Come on.
What's my pronghorn doing here?
I seem to recall paying
you good money for it.
Yes. And then you threw it away.
Oh, so you've been dumpster diving.
Is that, uh, really
what it's come to, Hank?
I think you know exactly
what position I am in.
After all, you put me in it.
Your man Darius forced
Deena to steal my money.
- You threatened...
- Wah, wah, wah, wah.
That's the trouble with most
indians. They're always whining,
trying to blame someone else
for their own misfortune.
"This man stole my money.
This man took my land.
This man moved up my trial date."
Hmm.
You know, if I pitied
myself the way you are now,
I'd still be in a 6x3 cell,
whining about who put me there.
Instead, I've decided to make my own luck.
I suggest you do the same.
Oh, by the way, my offer
to buy the bar still stands.
[Chuckles] All cash.
[Whistles]
[Indistinct conversations]
[whispers] Jacob.
Uh, Jenine, call Malachi Strand.
Tell him we have an un-invented guest
that needs to be removed.
Sheriff.
So sorry, but this is a private party.
Feel free to grab a couple
of beers for the road.
Jacob Nighthorse,
you're under arrest for conspiracy,
aiding and abetting,
and accessory to the attempted
murder of Branch Connally.
Jenine, call my lawyer.
You are both gonna regret this.
I doubt that.
You have no evidence David is alive.
Nothing, except the fact
that you two spoke 17
times in the past 2 weeks.
Ridges is awful talkative for a dead man.
[Sighs]
I imagine it gives you great
pleasure to see me in here.
Walt: Your lawyer's on her way.
Till then, you have the
right to remain silent,
and I suggest you use it.
You might be interested in
a few things I could say.
[Scoffs]
I would have been a few weeks ago,
but I'm a little tired of your denials.
I might be willing to revise my statements,
if you were to give me something.
What?
I realize there are laws against fraud
and making false statements.
You agree not to prosecute me for those,
I'll tell you what you want to know.
Fact is, I was just trying to help a friend
get out of trouble.
I had no intention of
helping him commit any crimes.
Well, if that's true, I'd
consider making a deal.
What do you want to know?
Well, you can start
by telling me about David's fake suicide.
[Sighs]
David called me one
night, said he needed help.
I didn't know he was involved
in your daughter's accident at that point.
He just said that he
had made some decisions
that he couldn't outrun, that
he had a plan to disappear,
but required assistance.
I know what that's like,
to be moving through the
world alone, no tribe,
so I agreed to help.
I'm going to take with
me everything that is bad,
and return with the true strength and honor
of the crazy dogs.
After that, we just waited.
All that was left was to explain
what happened to the body.
[Bird screeches]
David stole some blood that
he'd donated at the Res Clinic
and poured it over the deer.
After it was done, he promised
me that he would leave Wyoming.
But David didn't go.
Those legends he talked about,
the... the... the crazy
dogs and the time travel...
I thought all of that was him
just trying to sell his story.
But after he killed Hector,
I realized that David actually
believes in it... all of it.
He's convinced that he's
a time-traveling spirit,
sent to count coup against his enemies.
"Count coup"?
Indian warriors believe that
the greatest glory in battle
doesn't come from killing your enemy,
but from getting close
enough to touch a living enemy
and getting away to tell the tale.
Last time I talked to David,
he told me he was gonna
touch Branch three times
before he killed him.
I mounted an argument against
it, but David no longer listens.
You didn't think Ridges
was capable of all this?
I admit that my desire to help the man
may have blinded me to his growing madness,
but then I'm sure you
know what that's like.
So...
...do we have a deal?
No.
Walt!
I may not like you,
but you've always been a man of honor.
Surely you're not going
to go back on your word.
David called you 17
times in the last 2 weeks.
Next time he does, you
find out where he is.
If you give me his location,
I'll make your deal.
You hungry?
I can fix you a sandwich.
[Bottle opens]
No, thanks.
[Chuckles]
What?
Seems weird, you trying to take care of me.
I mean, you never even
held my hand as a kid
when we crossed the street.
No. No, I didn't.
I always walked ahead of you.
Laid out a path for you to follow.
I wasn't gonna coddle you.
And I trusted that you were smart enough
to see the dangers around
you and make your own choices.
Yeah, well...
You were always there to tell me
when I made the wrong ones.
Whether you realize it or not,
I have always looked out for you.
I just hope, one day, you can tell me
what it is that's tearing you up inside.
'Night, son.
[Lock clicks, keys jingle]
Ferg, take Nighthorse's
cooperation agreement
to the D.A.'s office.
- Have them file it immediately.
- On it.
So, Nighthorse gets off
the hook for everything?
Yep.
He gets out of a couple hours of community
service for making false statements,
- but we get a murderer.
- What now?
- We wait.
- All right.
Call me at home the
second you hear anything.
Uh, uh, uh...
Before you go, um,
I need to talk to you about something.
All right.
Uh... One of the
less-desirable parts of this job
is that we have to serve legal papers
when the county is
short of process servers.
Do you want me to serve someone a subpoena
on the way home?
No.
Um...
[Sighs]
I'm required to give you
this on behalf of the court.
[Breathes deeply]
So, uh... the other
day, when you said you...
you might be leaving the department.
Well, I didn't say what I,
uh... what I wanted to say,
uh, 'cause I didn't think
it was my... my place
to, uh... to get in the middle of things.
Um, and you have the right
to make any decision you want, um...
But the point is, Vic...
I want you to stay.
You got a pen?
[Grunting]
[Vehicle approaches]
What's so important that you
need to get me out of bed?
Whoa.
I've been thinking over
your offer to buy this place,
and I will sell it to
you under one condition.
Tell me where Darius was
when Walt's wife was murdered.
[Gasps]
Or I can just burn this
place to the ground.
Now, now, hold on, Henry. This is crazy.
You don't want to lose your bar.
- You need this place.
- No.
You are the one who needs this place
to launder your dirty money.
[Chuckles]
Tell me where Darius was
and I will sign the deed
over to you right now.
No deal?
Oh, well.
[Alarm beeping]
Branch?
[Beeps]
[Sighs]
Oh, shit.
[Police radio chatter]
Henry, you all right?
He did not do it.
What?
Darius burns... he did
not kill Miller Beck.
How do you know that?
Malachi Strand told me.
You can't be sure anything
Malachi says is true.
This time, I can.
If he had not told the truth,
the bar would be in ashes right now.
Did you start this fire?
I thought if I could get Malachi
to tell me where Darius was
when Miller Beck was killed,
then Cady could link them together
and we might have had a shot in court.
But my gamble did not pay off.
Turns out, Darius was in Connecticut,
doing a job for Malachi when
Miller Beck was murdered.
Well, Malachi might have told you that,
but we still need to confirm it.
Cady already did.
When I go to prison,
Malachi will own this place.
I should have just let it burn.
Henry.
The fireman are hungry.
I promised I would make sandwiches.
Sheriff, it's for you.
[Cellphone beeps]
Hello?
Hey. I just spoke with David Ridges.
[Bell rings]
Hey... hey, bud. What are you doing here?
Branch: Just tying up some loose ends.
I got some time on my hands.
[Voice breaking] Okay.
I warned you what would happen
if Walt found out about Sam Poteet.
Look, I... I'm sorry. I had to tell Walt.
I-I-I can't take that back.
Think about this, Branch.
If I turn up murdered,
you're the first person
that Walt's gonna suspect.
I don't care what Walt thinks anymore.
Please don't kill me, Branch.
It's not much fun when the
barrel's pointed at you, is it?
Don't worry, Travis.
I'm not gonna waste a shell on you.
But you're gonna have to do something
- to make this all up to me.
- What?
Give me the keys to your car.
Okay.
Here.
[Police radio chatter]
[Bell dings]
Ferg: Sheriff, you there?
What is it, Ferg?
Looks like Branch took
off from his dad's house.
Travis Murphy just called
and said Branch held him up with a shotgun
at the gas station and took his car.
Travis says he has no
idea where Branch went.
Where's Vic?
She locked herself inside of your office.
Well, keep her there.
Where are you right now?
I'm heading out to Horse Creek.
There's a medicine woman
who's got a trailer there.
According to Nighthorse,
Ridges' got pretty banged up
when he jumped in the river.
He went there to get patched up.
You want some backup?
Yeah, but under the circumstances,
you should stay there, watch out for Vic.
Lock all the doors in case Branch shows up.
Copy.
[insects chirping]
[Engine shuts off]
[Engine sputters]
No.
[Woman humming]
[Grunts]
No! No!
[Shouts]
[Humming continues]
Stand up, Ridges.
Turn towards me slowly.
What do you want?
I'm looking for David Ridges.
I was told he was hiding out here.
[Chuckles]
If he is, he's doing a heck of a job.
I haven't seen him.
Who told you he was here?
[Engine revs]
[Panting]
[Exhales sharply]
[Gun cocks]
[Gunshot]
[Horse whinnies]
[Shouting]
[Shouts]
[Grunts]
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
- www.addic7ed.com -