Previously on Longmire...
Don't you compare yourself to Walt!
I forgot you two have
a special relationship.
I'd understand if you felt
you had to tell Walt.
Billy didn't do what he said he did.
It was me.
This is Darius.
He works for Malachi Strand.
If we can prove Malachi had Darius kill
Miller Beck, you'd be off the hook.
I wanted to know if you killed my wife.
Surprised you didn't try
and sew this yourself
with fishing line.
I ran out.
[Chuckles]
Well, you're a lucky man.
The bullet just grazed you.
[Gunshots]
[Breathing heavily]
No serious damage.
Now you just need to go
and buy some lottery tickets
and take some time off work.
And, Deputy Moretti,
if you, uh, still have
a headache in 24 hours,
come back and see me.
A grade two concussion is
a really serious injury.
[Sniffles]
[Sighs]
Walt: It'll be all right.
A little needle and thread,
it'll be back to normal.
Yeah.
[Sniffles]
[Crying]
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
- www.addic7ed.com -
Ruby: Walter, where are you?
Taking that trip to Denver
that got interrupted.
Walter Longmire,
you just got shot.
Yeah.
Just once, though.
Yeah, hilarious.
Anyway, Ferg called.
Denver will have to wait.
Sean: How you feeling?
Vic: Fine.
Did you get any sleep last night?
Mnh-mnh.
I was afraid you were gonna stop breathing.
[Sighs] We need to talk
about what happened.
What's there to talk about? It's over.
- Where are you going?
- To work.
What?!
Is that your brain injury talking?
I still have a job, Sean.
Yeah, and that's the problem.
I'll let you go into work
if it's to put in your two weeks' notice.
[Sighs]
Ferg: One of the guys from
the prison road crew found it.
The inmates I questioned
say some serial killer
is roaming the countryside,
biting off body parts and eating them.
[Chuckles]
That's pretty farfetched, obviously.
But, uh, still, I had Ruby
run the details through Vicap,
you know, just in case
there is a serial killer
with cannibalistic tendencies.
That's not necessary.
It's not?
These teeth marks are from a small animal.
Something must've gnawed this foot off
and dragged it out here,
which means the rest of the
body can't be too far away.
Good thing we got some extra help.
Yeah.
[Door slams]
[Sighs]
Oh, you have got to be shittin' me!
[Phone ringing]
Hey, did you quit yet?
No. I'm too busy wondering why my husband
was snooping around on my laptop.
What are you talking about?
You opened up a document
that I started writing a week ago...
a private one called "Dear Walt."
That's a clever title.
It's for work, Sean!
So you think I snuck into your computer
and looked at it?
- It was at home...
- [Door opens, closes]
It was at home, so you're
the only one who could have.
You okay?
I have been better.
Bob: I was wondering...
I mean, maybe it's not my
place to ask about her...
Cady's doing fine, Bob.
How about you?
I haven't had a drink in months.
That's good.
[Sighs]
You know, I built that thing.
Well, me and a couple other guys.
You worked construction?
Yeah, I used to be a pretty good carpenter.
I used to be a lot of things.
Ferg: Hey, Walt!
[Door hinges creak]
Raccoons.
Give me a hand, Ferg.
Easy.
Bob: Oh, no.
- [Sighs]
- Oh, you know him, Bob?
Yeah, that's George
Linder. This is his farm.
He hired me to build the barn.
Hell of a nice guy.
- Does he have a family?
- Back when I knew him, he did.
His wife's name is Dawn. Had
a little girl named Cassie.
If they're not around, maybe they split up.
Tough marriage?
Tough life.
[Sighs]
Guys, Walt has a dead
farmer out near Shawnee Road.
He could use some help.
Why don't you go ahead and go?
You sure that's a good idea?
Could be gruesome.
Might trigger feelings of...
acute distress that'll
hinder my performance.
What did you say?
That's what you think, isn't it?
Maybe, but I never said it.
Get over here.
I wrote it
in those exact words in
a document on my computer.
- Have you been on my laptop?
- You tell me.
Apparently, you know me better than I do.
That laptop was at my house, Branch!
Did you break into my home?!
[Grunting]
You were missing. I was trying to find you.
And opening up a document on my computer
is gonna help you do that?!
Are you gonna rat me out
like your friends Bobby
Donolato and Ed Gorski?
How is that working out for you?
This macho intimidation bullshit
may work on drunk girls at frat parties,
but it doesn't work on me, so
get the hell out of my face!
[car door closes]
Vic: What have we got?
A farmer named George Linder.
Branch couldn't make it?
He's not feeling 100%.
Right.
[Camera shutter clicking]
Okay.
So, Walt,
if the raccoons had enough
time to take off the foot,
he must've been out here for a while.
Three to four days, I'd guess.
Vic: I'm gonna go out on a limb here
and assume that he wasn't nibbled to death.
Uh, he was shot in the back.
He was probably trying
to run away from someone,
or somebody surprised him.
I haven't found any casings yet.
Does this, uh, George
Linder guy live here alone?
No. Apparently, he has
a wife and a daughter.
And where are they?
I don't know yet.
It's not clear if the
family's still together.
Ferg.
Why don't you go ahead
and call the hospital?
Make arrangements for an autopsy.
[Sighs]
Do you need the number?
No. I got it.
Still.
Cady: Can we talk?
Why am I guessing this
isn't a personal visit?
Yeah. [Chuckles]
So, um... Here's the deal.
My dad was gonna go to Denver with me
to help with Henry's case,
but, um, he got called away on this murder,
so I have a backup plan.
Most professional private investigators
cost about $75 an hour.
I'm looking to hire one
to do 24 hours of investigation in Denver.
Covering expenses and travel,
that will come to about $2,500.
So you want me to loan you
more money to help Henry's case?
And hopefully, um, give
a P.I. recommendation.
The trial's in six weeks, and I really need
to track down this Darius guy.
He's my only alternate suspect.
[Sighs]
What do you think?
I think I'm a little offended.
I'm sorry. I...
Why are you asking me for money?
Why not just ask me to help?
You feeling okay?
Yeah.
It's just a little frustrating
looking for a bullet
casing in an alfalfa stack.
Sheriff!
That's close enough! Why were there
convicts crawling all over my land today?
'Cause I asked them to give me a hand.
Isn't this George Linder's farm?
George farms here. The land's mine.
And you are?
Nick Holman. Is there something wrong?
I wouldn't be here if there wasn't.
Is that George?
Yeah.
Someone shot him.
Well, I suppose that could've been anybody.
George was always sparring
with suppliers and creditors
just about every other day.
Money problems?
George was pretty handy.
But he didn't have the business sense
that God gave a 2x4.
He ever spar with you?
No.
George paid his rent... barely.
But he paid it.
What about his wife and his daughter?
They live around here?
Oh, yeah.
Dawn and Cassie, they
live here with George.
Well, give them my condolences.
Well, either George's wife and daughter
are out of town and don't know he's dead
or they do know he's dead
and they've already left.
Or maybe a psychopath
is holding them hostage
and blown their heads off.
You think you should take a break?
After what you just went through?
No. But I do think
people should stop acting like
they can tell me what to do.
I'm not telling you what to do.
I'm offering you a break, if you want it.
The last thing I need is another Deputy
whose mind is only halfway on the job.
[Vehicle approaching]
Vic: Who's that?
What do they want?
Are you George Linder's wife?
Yes, I'm Dawn.
Are you here to evict us?
No, ma'am.
No, I'm here because someone's been shot.
Who?
Well, I'm afraid it was your husband.
[Engine revs]
Hey! Hey!
[Tires screech]
Lock the doors and windows, Cassie,
and get the rifle!
Do you want me to get the Colt, too?
- Here.
- Ma'am, what are you doing?
- Getting ready!
- For what?
Nick Holman!
We just talked to him. He
said to send his condolences.
Well, you give him a message from us!
He may have gotten George,
but there are still two more of us left,
and he is not getting us off
this land without a fight.
George and I met while working
for Nelson Holman, Nick's dad.
Mr. Holman leased us this
house and all of this land
so that we could start our own farm.
Mr. Holman sounds like a good man.
He was.
And we thought Nick was,
too, until Mr. Holman died.
Cassie?!
Where are you?!
You know what? I'll go find her.
[Sighs]
So, what happened when
Nick took over from his dad?
He decided that his
dad's farm wasn't enough.
He wanted ours, too,
but the will said that he had
to honor the terms of our lease.
Of course, Nick found a loophole.
Our contract didn't say anything
about guaranteed water rights,
so he started charging us as
much as he could for water.
We're paying double our
rent just to water our crops.
That has to be tough.
Me and Cassie drive out twice a month
to clean rich folks' homes
from Teton Village down to Aspen.
We make ends meet.
Well...
I'm sorry for your loss.
We're farmers.
Losing just becomes a
way of life after a while.
- Hey, Ruby.
- Ruby: Hey.
Hey, Ruby?
- Hmm?
- Where's Branch?
Oh, he went off to
Denver with your daughter.
Said he was gonna help
her out with Henry's case.
Oh. That's surprising.
Oh, you got visitors.
Glad you finally showed up, Sheriff.
Hello again, Nick.
Hey, Ty. What are you doing here?
I'm George Linder's insurance agent,
and Nick was insistent
that I come by and make sure
that George's life-insurance
policy was being expedited.
George also just died, so
maybe show some respect.
How about this... you show some respect,
and I'll conduct business
over here in the real world.
What sort of business?
The deadline for George's
rent is midnight tonight.
Now, I'd like to direct
the life-insurance payout
to the rent rather than evict the family.
So, if you could inform me now
what recommendation you'll be making
on George's death certificate,
I can start the paperwork on the payout.
I haven't got any autopsy results yet.
Until then, I won't be
recommending anything.
Vic, could you show Ty out?
Nick and I need to talk.
[Sighs]
[Clears throat] So...
You think you might find the decency
to give Dawn Linder a
grace period on the rent
until all this is figured out?
"Decency."
My father used that word a lot.
[Sighs]
He died a broken, decent
man at the age of 59
with $200 in his bank account
and tens of thousands of dollars in debt.
I sure as hell don't
plan on doing the same.
Farming's changed.
20 years from now,
there will be 20 farmers in all of Wyoming.
I aim to be one of 'em.
Are you willing to kill a man
and take his farm to
make sure that happens?
Dawn Linder certainly thinks so.
Well, I'm sure she does.
Did it ever occur to you that maybe Dawn
got tired of being on
the losing end of things
and finally took matters
into her own hands?
[Door closes]
Excuse us. Sorry.
[Music]
So, this is where Henry found
the guy who killed your mom?
Yeah, Miller Beck.
So, here's the plan...
we have to try and prove
a connection between him and Darius,
prove that maybe Darius hired Miller Beck
and then killed him to cover his tracks.
Where do you want to start?
[Music continues]
Management.
Cady: Hey, you know this guy?
Yeah, Miller Beck, right?
- But, uh, isn't he dead?
- He is.
- Did he come in here a lot?
- Yeah.
Miller and his pals would come through,
mostly try to score junk in the men's room.
I'll show you.
We've got a lot of our
old regulars up here.
Uh, here he is.
Who's that guy with him?
That's Tug Renton! He's dead, too!
Not the greatest life
expectancy with these guys.
You ever see this guy with Miller Beck?
Uh, I don't know.
Uh, it's been a while now,
and I sort of, uh, donated
most of my memory [Chuckles]
when I was in my 20s.
Can I get your info and anybody
else who may have known Miller Beck?
No, actually, that's... that's fine, yeah.
- Just follow me.
- Okay.
[Music continues]
Hey.
Are you, uh, looking for that guy?
Yeah, you know him?
Well, I'll only tell
you under one condition.
What's that?
You let me take your photo.
I've never seen a real cowboy before.
[Camera shutter clicks]
So, you know him?
Nope.
George Linder was insured for...
$220,000.
That's a lot of rakes and shovels.
[Chuckles]
[Knock on door]
[Grunts]
Hey.
So, Dr. Weston
estimates that the victim died
three days ago... as I thought.
And he found [Clears throat]
a single .38-caliber slug
lodged about a half inch
from George Linder's spine.
Half inch away?
Yeah.
So the spinal cord wasn't severed.
Vic: You thought it was?
If the spine was severed,
that would explain
why the victim didn't
move after he was shot,
and he didn't move because
there was no blood trail.
I really need those alibis
for Dawn and Cassie Linder.
And Nick Holman.
Okay.
$220,000.
People have shot their spouse for less.
Yeah, well, sometimes the way
your husband chews his oatmeal
is motive enough.
[Sighs]
Vic...
You and your husband
have been through a lot.
Yeah, we have.
He's also demanding
that I give you my two weeks' notice
and, uh, quit my job.
So...
[Sighs]
Okay.
"Okay."
I just tell you that Sean
is demanding that I quit.
And that's all you have to say?
Well, I recall you're not someone
who likes to be told what to do.
I also don't like being
treated like a replaceable part.
I understand this is a...
this is a big decision for you.
And what is it for you?
Uh...
Well, this department has
lost and hired deputies before.
I'm so glad that we could have
this little heart-to-heart.
[Sighs]
[Door opens]
George Linder's daughter,
Cassie, just called.
Something's going on over at their farm.
[Door closes]
Hey, you ever seen this guy?
I smell [Sniffs]
Bacon.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Cellphone chimes]
Ridges.
No.
No!
What the hell?!
Have you seen a native guy with long hair?!
Get off of me!
[Breathing heavily]
Has anyone seen an Indian with long hair?!
Hey, hey! What's happening?!
Did you see Darius?
No.
David Ridges... he was here!
This girl, she... she took my
picture, sent it to my phone!
He was standing right behind me!
Okay. Can I see the picture?
It disappeared.
It's my mom. I think she might kill him.
- Kill who?
- Nick Holman.
She grabbed our rifle and went after him!
- [Gunshot]
- Get in the car!
Hey! Stop right there!
Hey!
[Muttering]
Dawn!
[Both grunt]
You almost killed her!
She almost killed me!
He's trying to steal our equipment!
No, it's mine! I'm not stealing anything.
Like hell! It's ours!
No, it is not!
God, I've been trying to tell her!
George sold it to me so he
could pay his rent last month.
I agreed to lease it back
to him on a monthly basis.
Okay, it's now past
midnight, so rent is overdue!
I'll write you a damn check!
It'll bounce.
I got tired of the late payments,
so I told George to set up
an automatic payment plan.
If you had any money,
it would've been deposited yesterday.
That's impossible.
According to the bank,
you're completely dry.
Which reminds me...
your water bill is due in 10 days.
This is not the time.
Oh, yeah, that's right, Sheriff.
Yeah, we must be decent. Right?
Okay, how about this?
I won't press charges
for the threat on my life!
Hell, I won't bill Dawn for
the hole in my windshield!
Maybe I'm a decent guy after all! Huh?
How about that?
[Engine turns over]
[Door opens]
Did you find David Ridges?
No.
I couldn't find the girl either.
The girl who sent you
the disappearing picture?
Yeah, it must've been one of
those apps that lets you send
texts and photos that erase themselves.
Like Snapchat or something.
[Chuckles]
You don't believe me.
I hope that you can see why it might be
a little difficult for me to believe
that a dead man photo-bombed
you in a self-erasing picture.
So, then, I'm hallucinating?
Wouldn't be the first time.
Branch, you see David Ridges everywhere.
This is the bar where the
guy who murdered my mother
used to hang out..
We're supposed to be figuring out
who else could've been involved.
Your mother's dead, Cady.
I'm still alive.
Okay.
I hope you find what you're looking for.
Walt: What are you gonna do now?
You heard Nick.
The water bill's due in 10 days,
and our checking account's empty.
That means I have to
harvest as much as I can.
It's gonna be pretty hard
to keep this farm running
if Nick keeps taking your best equipment.
[Sighs]
[Engine sputtering]
The starter's not kicking in.
Maybe you could, uh, jump
the posts on the solenoid.
[Sighs]
All we have to do
is sell enough of the crop
to pay this month's bills.
And then once dad's life
insurance kicks in,
we should be okay.
So you know about the
life-insurance policy.
Yeah. Everybody's got life insurance, right?
Right.
When you and your mother
first heard about your father getting shot,
you went for a rifle and a Colt.
Now, this is the rifle.
I was hoping I could also
take a look at that Colt.
Cassie: [Clears throat]
What caliber was it again... .45?
Um, no.
Uh, a .38.
Your father was shot with a .38.
Did you ever find that Colt?
[Engine turns over]
I've been a little busy.
If you know about the
insurance, your mom does, too.
You think she knows where that Colt is?
Thank you for all your help, Sheriff,
but I've got work to do.
[breathes deeply]
I got in late last night,
and I didn't want to wake you.
Okay.
I'm sorry that I accused you
of going through my computer.
It was a mistake, and I overreacted.
But...
But what?
Today is a new day.
How come you always get to be on top?
[Laughs]
How come you always let me?
[Laughing] Let you?
[Laughs]
[Chuckles]
You have to fight your way to be on top.
[Laughing]
[Grunts]
[Chuckles]
[Laughing] So, is this how
our marriage is gonna work?
I have to pretend to be weaker than I am?
No.
I think we're both done pretending.
[Cellphone ringing]
[Sighs]
Hello?
Hey, Vic.
I was trying to get a hold of my dad.
- Um, is he with you?
- No.
Is something wrong?
When we found George,
you weren't sure if he and
Dawn were still married.
Old George, he was a gentle soul.
Dawn's a bit on the harsh side.
Sort of a natural-born judge.
How about executioner?
What do you mean?
Could Dawn kill someone?
Yeah. Sure.
If they were coming
after George and Cassie,
she might get angry enough to do it.
You ever see this anger?
When George, um... George...
When George what?
Old George tried to kill
himself a few years back.
Dawn was pissed off.
At him, at the doctors... everything.
George was suicidal.
That damn Nick Holman was
squeezing him for more money.
George came to me and
the other boys and said,
"I can't afford to keep you on any longer."
Then he swallowed a
bunch of sleeping pills.
Dawn found him, called the ambulance.
She just couldn't imagine
what George was thinking,
trying to off himself like that there.
She should've just asked me, I guess.
[Sighs]
Bob...
You've got just a few
weeks before you get out.
Don't you even think about giving up.
I appreciate the sentiment, Walt.
But what do I have to look forward to?
It's not the worst idea, you know?
Cutting your losses and...
Sailing out into the great unknown.
Now you listen to me, Bob.
You're not the first man
that's thought that way.
Plenty others have stared over the edge
of that particular cliff.
But if you do something stupid...
I promise you, I will dig you up myself
and kick your ass up
and down Durant square.
[Sighs]
Okay.
Cady: Thanks for picking
me up at the train station.
So, you left your car in Denver?
Yeah, I was kind of in a rush.
Did you find out anything
about this Darius guy?
Nope. But Branch thinks
he found someone else.
Let me guess... David Ridges?
Ding, ding, ding.
We were at a bar,
and... and he starts suddenly going on
about how some person texted
him a picture of himself
with David Ridges in the
background at the bar.
Was there a picture?
No. [Scoffs]
Has he hallucinated before?
When I went to visit him in the hospital
after he was shot,
he thought that I was David Ridges.
Okay, and what'd he do?
He attacked me.
Did you tell Walt?
No.
I was hoping that it
was just the medication,
but then this happened.
I don't know. I...
when I look him in the eyes,
all I see is this dark, mean, unstable man.
Okay.
Please just have him
call the Sheriff's office.
- [Door closes]
- Thanks.
Where's Vic?
Not here.
How'd those alibis check out?
Well [Clears throat] Dawn
Linder refused to give us
the numbers to any of her clients.
She was afraid that she'd get fired
if a Sheriff's Deputy called,
asking about a murder alibi.
And Nick Holman?
He said he was too busy to talk nonsense.
So we've got three murder
suspects without alibis.
Actually, there's a fourth suspect
- we haven't been talking about.
- Who?
George Linder.
The dead guy?
Turns out, he tried to kill
himself a few years ago.
Maybe he tried again and succeeded.
Someone found him.
Shot him in the back to
make it look like murder.
I get why someone would
try and make a murder
look like a suicide,
but the other way around?
Well, suicide would cancel
George's life-insurance payout.
An unsolved murder wouldn't.
So, which one of them do
you think found and shot him?
I don't know.
But both the victim's
family and Nick Holman
had their eyes on that insurance money.
We need to get a warrant
and search both of their
properties for a Colt .38.
Yep.
Thanks for coming out on such short notice.
I'll take any excuse to
get out of the office.
Have you determined the
nature of George's death yet?
Not yet.
But there's bound to be
good news for you either way.
Appears George was shot with his own gun.
Suicide would invalidate his policy,
so your company wouldn't
have to pay out the $220,000.
It can't be suicide.
How could George shoot himself in the back?
So you read the
confidential autopsy report.
It's a small town. People talk.
Uh-huh. Well, um...
That must mean that
George was actually killed
by a family member.
Now, Dawn is the main
beneficiary of the policy.
When she's arrested,
that should save you a lot of money.
Dawn didn't kill George.
How do you know that?
Dawn and Cassie were out of town.
That means it must've been your friend...
Nick Holman.
He's always had his eye
on taking over this farm.
He seems pretty comfortable
taking George's property.
Maybe he took George's Colt, as well...
And shot him with it.
Maybe George had an accident?
Maybe he dropped the gun.
See, if it was an accident,
the Colt would be here.
It wasn't.
It's not at his house either.
I'll tell you what I did find at his house.
George's cellphone.
You were the last person he called.
Phone records say the
call lasted for 12 minutes.
Were you trying to talk him
out of another suicide attempt?
He swallowed sleeping pills the first time.
We haven't run a tox screen yet
to see what it was this time,
but I could call the hospital
right away and ask for one,
- and...
- No.
Don't.
It was the sleeping pills again.
George, wake up!
I'm calling the ambulance!
Too late.
I took all of them.
You're a good friend, Ty.
You were right.
I did it all wrong the last time.
Walt: What did he mean?
When he first tried to kill himself,
I tried to talk some sense into him.
What'd you tell him?
That if he killed himself,
Dawn and Cassie would never
collect on the insurance policy.
What I meant was that suicide
wouldn't solve anything.
But he heard something different.
- I want you to shoot me.
- What?!
After I'm dead, so it looks like a murder
and my girls can get that money...
just like you said.
Get rid of the pills and
the gun when you're done.
I'm asking you as my friend.
This is the only way I...
This is the only way I can save the farm.
Please.
George.
George!
Do you know how often my
company has denied claims
because of some loophole?
Do you know how many times
I've taken from people
so much more than I've given back?
George Linder was one of the most decent,
honorable men I knew.
And now...
His family was gonna lose
everything he stood for.
[Gun cocks]
[Gunshot]
I decided I was gonna be
the friend I always claimed to be
and help him save his farm.
[Sighs]
That's some kind of story.
But a little farfetched for my taste.
You can tell Dawn and Cassie
all about it if you want.
But I think I'm just gonna declare this
an unsolved homicide.
[Sighs]
I don't want to read this.
I didn't want to write it, but...
I did.
So now you have to open it.
This is about Branch?
You need to read it all the way through.
There's no way he should be carrying
a badge and a gun right now.
He's a time bomb just waiting to go off.
[Music]
[Engine idling]
[Music continues]
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
- www.addic7ed.com -