Previously on Longmire...
How did you find me, anyway?
Come on, I used to be a cop.
That was in my mailbox this morning.
Who do you think took the photo?
Ed Gorski.
What do you think I'm going to do?
I don't know, Branch.
Kidnap a guy and force him to take peyote?
His name is Darius, he works for Malachi.
Is this the guy that had Mom killed?
Maybe one of these guys is
behind your wife’s murder?
I'm going to pay each of them a visit.
I'm sanctioned by the constitution
to put a bullet in your head.
That's your wake-up call.
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
www.addic7ed.com
- [Sighs]
- Be careful.
- Uh-huh.
- And step on the grass.
- And stop.
And ta-da!
- [Chuckles]
- A convertible? What for?
It's a five-hour trip.
There's no reason the ride can't be...
- romantic, huh?
- [Laughs]
Uh, it's a little loud.
I know, but it's the only one I could find.
And convertibles are
surprisingly hard to find
in Wyoming.
So, where are we staying, anyway?
Jackson Hole is all you need to know.
- You're all packed, right?
- Yeah, I think I have everything.
Well, not everything,
remember? No gun, no badge.
No cellphone. I know.
Well, cellphone, that
was... that was your idea.
Yeah, but when we made
the plan for the trip,
there wasn't a lot going on at work, so...
Vic, if you'd rather go to work
than spend a weekend
with me, I'm not gonna...
that is not what I mean,
and you know it, Sean.
It's gonna be great.
It's just...
Work stress doesn't
disappear in a few seconds.
It takes a few minutes,
cruising in a convertible,
listening to some '80s hair metal...
- Slayer?
- [Chuckles] Whitesnake.
- Oh. Classy.
- Right?
- [Dog barks]
- Vic here?
Walt: Nope. [Clears throat]
- Have you spoken to her?
- Yup.
She and Sean are taking
a three-day weekend.
Why don't you get a fresh shirt?
- Ferg.
- [Sighs]
What's going on here?
Uh, I'm trying to find out
what Darius' last name is.
Darius?
While you've been away, there's been
a pretty significant
development in Henry's case.
Uh, this is Darius.
He works for Malachi Strand.
He operates out of Denver,
so he might be connected to Miller Beck.
If we can prove Malachi
had Darius kill Miller Beck,
Henry's off the hook.
I created a list of all the Darius's
in Colorado and Wyoming,
but I could really use some
help following up on all this.
Darius have any connection to David Ridges?
[Foreigner's "Feels Like
the First Time" plays]
♪ won't you open up the door? ♪
[Sean mimics drumming]
♪ it feels like the first time ♪
[mimics drumming]
♪ it feels like the very first time ♪
♪ it feels like the first time ♪
- [mimics drumming, volume decreases]
- Can we, uh...
Pull over so we can put the top up?
What? What's the point
of having a convertible
if you can't feel the wind in your hair?
Come on. It'll only take a few seconds.
I'm f-freezing and these curves are making
me sick. I think I'm going to throw up.
[Both scream]
[Tires screech]
[Door slams]
You gonna hand me another book?
Pull me off my investigation
to do something you could have Ruby do?
Ruby's not an investigator, Branch.
- You are!
- Damn right I am!
And I'm trying to find
a guy who shot two men!
But I guess since it
didn't directly affect you,
it's a low priority.
It affected me plenty!
Now, we only got so many people here.
We need to put our resources
where they can do the most good.
Which you decide.
That's right, Branch... which I decide.
Ridges killed Hector.
That has a direct impact on Henry's trial.
I would've thought that
would've mattered to you.
It does.
But I'm not gonna hunt down
David Ridges and kill him,
which seems to be the only
plan you have right now.
I'm going to Denver for a couple of days...
try and make some sense of
this new Darius information.
I expect you to be here
helping us out, investigating.
Now, you think you can do that?
Honestly, Walt...
I don't know.
[Sighs]
How's your knee?
It's not good, but I'm gonna live.
I'm gonna go for help.
We're gonna starve before
another car comes by.
[Stones clattering]
You think the bear's coming back?
- I thought we said no guns.
- That was your idea.
Now, I don't see anything,
but we can't risk that thing coming back.
We need to call someone.
W-we can't. We left our cellphones at home.
Are you serious?
With all that's going on at
work, it would have been harder
for me to relax if I
didn't have all this stuff.
It's fine.
Damn it. The cellphone's almost dead.
Well, give it to me. I'm
call AAA before it dies.
Eh! There's no signal.
[Grunts]
Maybe if I go up that hill...
With your knee and a bear out there?
I saw a mailbox a couple miles back.
I'm sure whoever lives
there has a landline.
No, no, no, no. Don't go. We'll
stay and charge the phone at the car.
I can get there and back
before we can find a signal.
Take the gun, at least.
You keep it. I'll be right back.
[Sighs]
Henry.
I hate to bring up a sore subject, but...
I need to talk to you about Deena.
Deena... Deena...
I'm drawing a blank.
Look, I'm... I'm heading down to Denver.
We got some interesting leads...
Darius, Malachi, Miller Beck...
But we still need to connect them.
So I need to know everything Deena told you
about how Darius approached her in Denver.
Emotions were a tad high.
I did not get much,
other than the name of the
bar where she met Darius.
I hate to ask you,
but can you get in touch with her?
I believe that bridge is fully incinerated.
Okay.
Let's talk about Miller Beck.
You said you followed him
before he was murdered.
Yes, and I told him to
get his affairs in order.
Where'd you follow him to?
To a bar not far from I-25.
Ronaldo's Rec Room, I believe was the name.
You think I need a reservation?
Perhaps a tetanus shot.
[Vehicle approaching]
Oh.
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hi! Hi! Ah!
[Sighs]
- [Tires squeal]
- No! No! No! No!
"VTNL-276X."
[Telephone rings]
- [Telephone beeps]
- Hello?
Sean: Hey, hey! Can you hear me? It's Sean.
I had to... I had to
climb up to get a signal.
I can hear you. There's been an accident.
Nobody's hurt, but Vic is gone.
Sean. Take a breath, tell me what happened.
Vic went down the road to get some help,
and soon after, a car came
from that same direction.
And as it passed, I could see the driver,
and it was Ed Gorski.
I'm afraid he might have kidnapped her.
[tires screech]
Vic!
Sean!
Walt: Hey, it's me. Who's there?
[Sighs]
Hey, Sheriff. It's Ferg. What's up?
I need you to run a license plate...
Victor Tango November 1-2-7-6 X-ray.
Not sure of the state...
probably Pennsylvania.
Is it Darius?
No. The driver is Ed Gorski.
Wait.
Ed Gorski, as in...
Ferg, just run the plate.
I got reason to believe
Gorski abducted someone.
Who?
Vic.
Radio me back when you know something.
[Sighs]
Man: Sheriff!
Gorski?!
Where's Vic?
If you hurt her, you're a dead man.
You cowboys.
You think every problem can
be solved with a gunfight.
I'm not gonna tell you anything about Vic
until you put down your
weapon and turn around.
What'd you do to her?
I didn't do anything with her,
and I got nothing to do with any of this.
But I do think she's in some trouble.
Thanks for this.
If you had nothing to do with this,
why are you out here?
- I've been keeping an eye on her.
- You mean stalking her.
The language of most
stalking laws is pretty vague.
I like to think of myself
more as a guardian angel.
Doesn't look like you
are doing a very good job.
So, what happened to Vic?
I don't know.
But I do know what happened to Sean.
Hey. Thanks for stopping.
So, it's kind of an emergency.
We got in a car accident,
and then my... my wife...
[all grunting]
[tires squeal]
Walt: You get a license plate number?
The plate had been removed.
Where's the last place you saw Vic?
Heading up a driveway back that way.
How far that way?
About 2 miles.
That's Chance Gilbert's place.
So, where you headed?
I don't know, actually.
My husband wanted it to be a surprise.
Oh, one of those.
Yeah. [Laughs]
I... so, the phone.
Can I use it?
Only after we feed ya.
It's the least we can do.
Besides, these two failed
to tell you something.
What's that?
We don't have a phone. Sorry.
They were dishonest.
What did I tell you about that?
Technically, I never said we had a phone.
Hey Derrick...
Don't you lawyer me.
Okay?
Sorry, sir.
I don't trust phone companies.
They're all crooks in cahoots with the NSA.
So I just simply cut the line.
Snip snip snip. [Chuckles]
Yeah, a lot of people are doing that.
Do you have a cellphone
that I could borrow, then?
Reception sucks. Dead spots all over.
What did you say your name was, again?
- Vic.
- Hmm.
Mustard or Mayo, Vic?
Were out of mayo.
Ah, shit.
Mustard, it is.
Classic yellow.
I'm... I'm good. Thank you.
You don't like a bologna sandwich?
What kind of American doesn't
like a fried-bologna sandwich?
- Come on.
- [Chuckles] It's not that.
It's just, if you don't have a-a phone,
I should get back to my husband.
Well, take him a sandwich.
Make one for the road, please.
You know, we ate on the way, so...
Thank you, but I-I should just go.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- You are?
- Yeah. I should go.
Thank you so much for your hospitality.
It's a free country, Vic.
[Door opens]
We've been expecting you, Deputy Moretti.
I'd feel a lot better if you'd
give me one of my guns back.
I wish I could, but I can
tell you don't trust me.
And I feel like you wouldn't be able
to resist the temptation to arrest me
on your trumped-up stalking charges.
And right now, we can't
afford that distraction.
- Vic is in real trouble.
- Is she?
Or is this just another one of your games?
Like sending her husband
a photo of Vic and me.
What makes you think I sent a picture?
You wrote "32" on the back.
Vic told me that was a little
secret between the two of you.
Did she describe room 32 to you?
I wasn't interested in anything
but the fact that it proved
you never left Wyoming,
like you were told to.
So, Ed, apart from stalking my Deputy,
what else you been up to?
You made any friends?
I-I found a dentist I liked, thanks to you.
I wouldn't say we're friends.
How do you know Chance Gilbert?
The names out here, you
just don't get 'em back east.
So it's just a coincidence
that Vic disappears
in his part of the county at
the same time as you appear?
Sheriff, I'm just looking out for Vic.
I have no idea who this Chance is,
but clearly you do.
He's a survivalist...
anti-government, end-of-days type.
Like a crazy cult leader?
Worse.
The guy's smart.
He served as his own
attorney in a murder trial
and got himself acquitted.
I killed his brother a few
years ago in a standoff.
He's angry about it.
Oh, great.
You think he abducted Vic?
I think you did.
Maybe with Chance's help.
And this guy, Chance... is he violent?
Quite.
And what about the other
guys, the ones who took Sean...
who are they?
Some are family.
Some are like-minded disciples.
Okay, stop.
I didn't have anything to do with this.
You believe me now?
Nope.
[Sighs] I didn't think so.
I think I'll be keeping your sidearm.
Branch: So, who's Ed Gorski?
- Huh?
- Come on, Ferg.
When Walt mentioned his
name, you knew who he was,
and now he's supposedly kidnapped Vic?
Who is this guy, and
why is it such a secret?
There was an incident
at a motel a while ago.
I think Gorski is someone
Vic knew in Philly...
And...
And was maybe having an affair with.
What kind of incident?
He was beaten up pretty badly.
I didn't know if it was Vic's
husband who did it, or...
[Keyboard clacks]
I didn't know what happened.
But Gorski never filed any charges.
Ed Gorski was a cop in
Philadelphia, but he got fired.
When?
Right after Vic showed up here.
Chance: Now, how do we find out information
when the subject won't cooperate?
Check her pockets?
Or maybe it makes more sense
for your mom to do that.
[Chuckles]
Oh.
Look at that.
A cop losing her gun.
Shame on you.
What are you doing here, Victoria Moretti?
Walt Longmire send you, huh?
I told you that my husband and I had...
yeah, you and your husband, you had what?
We had car trouble.
You had car trouble.
We almost ran into a bear.
Right down the road from my house?!
A grizzly or a black bear? I want to know.
Look, I don't know who
you are or what you want.
- You're such a liar.
- You don't believe me?
Now, why should I believe you?
My husband is out there
right now with our car.
Well, I'm not saying you haven't
thought everything through
and you don't have a good cover story,
but I'm not buying it.
Gorski looks to have been pulled
into an I.A. investigation.
A cop named Bobby
Donalato committed suicide
during the hearing process.
Then Gorski and two others
were kicked off the force.
And the whistleblower
that started the whole
investigation process was...
Officer Victoria Moretti.
Did you know about any of this?
No.
Seems like Gorski's got
a pretty legitimate ax to grind with Vic.
If he's got her, we better find him quick.
This guy hates catalogs.
This guy hates the government
and everyone he thinks represents it.
So, where does the Sheriff's
Department fall in his mind?
Pretty firmly on his list of enemies.
[Grunts]
Maybe you can answer this for me, Walt.
How does a woman like Vic
end up with someone like Sean?
Dunno.
I mean, he didn't even put up a fight
when those guys abducted him on the road.
Probably the smartest
thing in the circumstances.
They were armed... he wasn't.
I know, but how do you not
get in one punch... or try?
Not everyone can be a cop.
My point exactly.
There's no way Vic belongs
with someone who isn't a cop.
I just don't get it.
You mean you don't get
why she's not with you.
No. That's not what I'm saying.
I'm... an acquired taste, no question.
I get why she needed a
break from me, but Sean?
Mr. milquetoast?
It's just baffling to me.
I don't know.
He probably looked pretty good
after a couple of months of you.
Vic and I were good together.
Really?
I heard you were married
and didn't tell her.
Bad timing.
I married the wrong woman,
then I met the right one.
- I made the wrong decision.
- No.
You didn't make a decision at all.
You tried to have it both ways.
Well, that's not gonna
be a problem anymore.
I got a divorce.
But Vic got married.
Right.
Sure hope Sean makes it
out of this in one piece.
What the hell?
[Grunts]
Walt: Is that the car you saw pick Sean up?
Uh-huh.
Seems like we're probably gonna
have to call in some backup.
It'll mean more coming from you.
No.
Sheriff, you said this guy was violent.
Yup.
And the last thing we
need is another Ruby Ridge.
The only way we get Vic and Sean out
is if Chance doesn't know we're here.
You a baseball player?
Little league?
[Door bursts open]
Sean?! Oh, my God! Sean?!
- What the hell did they do to you?
- Are you okay?
Oh, bravo!
A couple of committed thespians.
Sean! Sean!
Sean!!
[All grunting]
All right.
So, she's Deputy Victoria Moretti,
and you're Sean Keegan.
Wow. Different last name.
Hey, Vic, I can't tell
you I know you that well,
but he doesn't seem like your type.
I think I know your type.
I didn't take his last
name, but we are married.
Just shut your mouth!
I'm not talking to you any longer.
Hey, Sean, who did you call
before we picked you up, eh?
The feds? State troopers?
Did you call the Sheriff,
Walt Longmire? You can tell me.
I didn't call anybody.
I thought you said
you and your wife had some car trouble.
We did.
And you sent her all
the way over here, then,
to borrow a phone?
And you already had one.
That makes no sense. Come on, Sean.
The phone was dead. We had to charge it.
I told you to shut your mouth!
I'm trying to converse with
your undercover colleague here,
Officer Keegan.
- I'm not a cop.
- But you called one.
- I didn't call anybody.
- All right.
You see, I'm gonna check your history.
And if it turns out
you've been lying to me,
this is not gonna go well.
[Chuckling]
I-I don't understand why people bother
to... to lock their phones.
The NSA are listening in
on every damn call anyway.
Now, I need you to give
me your pass code, Sean.
I forgot.
Come on.
Don't try to be a hero.
The pass code, Sean.
Seriously, when I'm
stressed, I forget things.
I'm stressed, too.
Maybe we should bring the helmets, huh?
All right?
[Grunting]
Thank you.
- Last chance.
- Sean!
What the hell are you doing?!
- Shut her up!
- Sean!
All right. Mnh-mnh.
- [Grunting]
- No! No!
- Sean!
- I can't concentrate!
- [Gasping]
Sean! Sean!
[Muffled] Sean!
You think you're smarter
than me. You're not.
You're not even close.
[Whimpers]
[Music]
[door opens]
Branch: "Dear Walt,
"it is with great regret
that I write this report
"about the conduct of my colleague
Deputy Branch Connally..."
[Cellphone rings]
Hey, Ferg.
The highway patrol found
Gorski's car... abandoned.
And Walt's bronco was nearby,
parked by a wrecked convertible,
but no sign of Walt.
The trooper's gonna canvass the area,
but he says it's pretty sparsely populated.
Tell me where they found the cars.
[Car door opens]
[Car door closes]
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Quiet! Quiet!
Hey!
[Gunshot]
- [Both grunting]
- Oh, God!
For God's sakes, stay put!
She must be in there.
They'd never risk shooting a patrolman
unless they had something to hide.
You better hope Vic's alive.
Or that won't be the last
man that goes down today.
[Vic coughing, vomiting]
Oh. This isn't good.
You clearly have a concussion.
A concussion is the least
of our problems right now.
[Breathing heavily]
Did you not hear those gunshots?
Yeah.
I heard one... gunshot.
But, you know, that
could just be one of those
psychotic hillbillies taking
target practice, you know?
[Gagging, vomiting]
Oh, baby. Oh, you need a doctor.
Sean! Sean!
I'm fine.
No, you're not fine!
But it's okay.
This guy just wants this pass code, right?
Right?
So, uh, why don't I go...
Negotiate with him...
tell him I'll give him the pass code
in exchange for setting you free.
Yeah.
Sean...
Honey, they didn't
blindfold either one of us.
They have no intention of... letting us go.
That stupid pass code is the only thing
that's keeping us alive right now.
We have something they think they need.
If you gave them my cellphone,
would they find anything?
[Sighs heavily]
Yeah, I, um... I called Walt.
What do these guys want?
Why does he keep asking about Walt?
Because I think this is the
guy that killed his wife.
[Sniffles]
Walt had his picture on his wall,
and he came out to question
Chance a couple weeks ago,
so he knows that Walt is honing in on him.
[Sniffles]
I just... I walked up the wrong driveway.
I had no idea he lived here.
But it's okay.
If you called Walt, he
will... he will be here.
[Door opens]
Chance: Incoming!
[Screams]
[Door closes]
Walt.
Walt. Walt. Walt.
[Crying]
[Screaming indistinctly]
[Breathing shakily]
[vehicle approaches]
[Indistinct conversation]
[Generator whirring]
[Grunts]
[Lid closes]
[Sighs] I counted 20 of 'em... all armed.
But I didn't see Vic or Sean.
I thought I knew why
Chance was overreacting
to Vic's appearance,
but I just got a second reason.
They got a dead federal agent
in an underground freezer
on the West Side of the compound.
They killed an FBI agent?
No, he's a census officer...
went missing two years ago.
It was a federal case...
not my jurisdiction.
Chance probably thinks we're onto him.
Probably thinks that's why
I came to talk to him two weeks ago.
Okay.
So, we can't call for federal backup,
or a lot of people will die, as you said.
And we can't walk away if Vic is in there.
So we wait.
After dark, we go in and find her.
Branch: Walt!
Walt: Psst.
[Grunts]
I'm looking for a friend
of mine... blond lady.
- She in there?
- She's government.
And I know who you are. You're the Sheriff.
- You killed my dad.
- Is she in there?
Tell us where she is.
All we want is to get
her out of there safely.
Walt: And her husband.
They're on trial.
Chance doesn't like to deliver a sentence
without due process being served.
That's the law.
Whose law?
Chance's.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Conversations stop]
Chance: You two have something
to say before the trial begins,
like an opening statement of some sort?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Um, I'll tell you what you want to know.
Um... The pass code is 1325.
You'll see that I called the Sheriff,
but he's not looking for you.
Well, thank you, Sean.
I appreciate it.
Now, why can't you be
more like your fake husband, here, eh?
What? No! No! No! No! No!
Listen up, everybody!
The court, in appreciation of
the defendant's cooperation,
hereby pardons Sean Keegan.
- No, but you have to let my wife go, too!
- Get him out of here!
No, Sean!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
Don't! Get that away from me!
Get that away from me!
Get him out! Get him out!
- [Indistinct shouting]
- Let my wife go!
He's got a pardon.
Silence!
[Shouting stops]
The court is in session.
Deputy Victoria Moretti,
you are being accused of the following.
First, as a representative
of the U.S. government,
you are being held accountable
for the murder of my brother,
committed by your superior,
one Walter Longmire.
Secondly, you're accused of
trespassing sovereign territory.
Third, by misrepresenting
yourself and your intentions,
you're in violation
of all international diplomatic statutes.
And finally, espionage.
[Breathing shakily]
This is bullshit.
Where is Sean?!
When I defended myself,
I didn't get to put the
U.S. government on trial,
but I fared okay.
Now that you're on trial,
you don't get to question our legitimacy.
Did Walter Longmire send you here?
No.
Oh. [Chuckles]
Let me rephrase this.
What does Walter Longmire know? Hmm?
[Breathing shakily]
H-he knows that you had his wife killed.
That's why he was out
here a couple of weeks ago?
Yes.
And he believes I-I killed
this Miller... Miller Beck guy?
Yes.
Multiple murders across state line.
Oooooh!
Are the "feds" coming?
[Laughter]
God, I hope so.
What did you say?
[Breathing shakily]
I said, "God, I hope
so," you crazed nut job!
Listen, you pious bitch.
Every person in here
has made a courageous, informed choice
to separate themselves
from a corrupt society
and to live here with their
own wits, skills, and laws.
Yeah, so one can argue that crazy people
are those just like yourself,
who blindly follow others.
You see, in here, we're all united.
But out there, you're all divided.
[Breathing heavily]
So, uh...
Do you have any more names
you want to call me? Huh?
Before the jury announces the verdict?
Chance! Chance!
Walt Longmire's here.
Go. Move.
[Breathing shakily]
Did you put a bullet in him?
No, sir. He got my gun.
[Laughs]
Well, what the hell does he want?
He wants to settle out of court.
Longmire!
Hey, show yourself!
Walt: There are a couple of
ways this thing ends, Chance.
Now, you can kill us,
but the feds will send an army after you.
You may take down a few of them,
but they'll kill all of you.
There's another way.
[People murmuring]
How about I let all your people go...
You let all mine go?
Everybody goes free...
Except you... And me.
I'll stand in for all my people's crimes.
You stand in for all of yours.
What are you proposing, huh?
A duel?!
Remember what Thomas Jefferson said?
"The tree of liberty must be refreshed
"from time to time...
With the blood of tyrants."
"Patriots and tyrants."
What do you say, Chance?
I'm thinking.
Give one of your cars to Vic and Sean.
I'll send them out with
one of my guys here.
My people are safe...
I'll let yours go.
And you and me can settle this.
Give me your word
that my people can leave
as free men and women.
You got a deal.
Somebody get me the keys to the granada.
And get Sean.
[Breathing shakily]
Walt, you can't do this!
It's okay, Vic.
You'll be all right.
Here's the granada keys, Chance.
You... hold it right there.
I'll take those.
Toss him the keys.
Go with him, Vic.
[Grunts]
[Breathing heavily]
Everybody head out to our backup position.
You heard me! Get out!
Now! Come on! Move!
[Engines turn over]
[Engine turns over]
[Chuckles]
I saw your guys gun down
that highway patrolman
in cold blood.
Yeah?
They saw you do the
same thing to my brother.
Did you kill that Federal Census Agent?
[Gasps]
When did you find out?
This afternoon.
That's not why you came poking around,
like, a couple of weeks ago?
No.
I wanted to know if you killed my wife.
Did you?
No.
[Chuckles]
I don't suppose you'd
let me arrest you quietly?
I've been fighting my whole
life for my right to freedom.
I fled a fascist country
to find my freedom here in America.
I'm not giving up now, Sheriff.
You see, I've been fighting too long.
So, how do we do this, now, eh?
Well...
I guess we count it off.
[Chuckles]
1...
2...
3..
[Gunshots]
[Music]
Stop here.
Goodbye, Vic.
[Music continues]
[Car door opens, closes]
[Engine turns over]
Have you been in my laptop?
You tell me.
Did you break into my home?
_
David Ridges! He was here!
You see David Ridges everywhere.
He disappeared.
All I see is this dark...
unstable man.
Did you tell Walt?
What are you going to rat me out?
Get the hell out of my face.
Sync and corrections by awaqeded
www.addic7ed.com