[Drum beats continue]
[Car door closes]
[Buzzer]
[Sighs]
Who's responsible for that?
Hard to say.
The Native American
Brotherhood hunt in packs.
But I am confident the novelty
of beating up the new guy will wear off.
Malachi Strand tried to make
a deal with me last week.
He said he could make the beatings stop
if I agreed to vouch for
him at his parole hearing.
Under no circumstances are
you to make that deal, Walt.
Hopefully, I won't have to.
Cady's scheduled your bail
hearing for Friday at 5:00.
Now, if all goes well,
you'll be out by the weekend.
Meantime, if you need anything...
Actually, there is something.
It might seem small, but
it is important to me.
I need you to take my place as a Judge
for a competition on the reservation.
The event is very sacred.
It is the Miss Cheyenne Nation Pageant.
A beauty pageant.
It is not your typical beauty pageant.
[Cheers, applause, and tribal chanting]
Announcer: Contestant number
one... Micheala Grey Wolf!
[Cheers and applause]
Contestant number two... Lilly Stillwater!
That's right. Show Lilly your love.
Contestant number
three... Jeanine Redcloud!
Walt!
[Cheers and applause]
Contestant number four... Kendall Marsh!
Walt!
Contestant number five... Candace Akape!
All right, that is contestant number 6.
Walt.
Vic, I'm a little busy.
Yeah, well, sorry to interrupt
the swimsuit competition,
but we got a body.
[Tribal chanting, drum beating]
[Cheering]
[Car door closes]
Walt: Sorry. Took me a while to smooth
things over with the other Judges.
So, what's the story?
High-school kid and his
girlfriend called the body in.
I tried to ask them some questions,
but, like typical teenagers,
they wouldn't tell me
what the hell they were doing out here.
I got a pretty good idea
what they were doing out here.
This property's been abandoned for decades.
Become a popular destination
for teenage couples.
- [Gloves snap]
- How romantic.
Victim's name is Ben Mallory.
He's 32 years old.
He took two stab wounds to the left torso.
The blood on his shirt and
the mattress are both dry,
so I'm assuming that he, uh,
got killed sometime last night.
Sorry, did you know him or something?
No.
No, stabbing's just a bad way to go.
Any signs of robbery?
No. His wallet and cash are still on him.
But I did find this.
[Pills rattle]
Prescription pills,
medical supplies,
and a Durant Regional I.D. Badge.
It looks like Ben Mallory was a doctor.
Well, then, let's get Dr. Mallory
to the hospital for an autopsy.
You can talk to Ben's co-workers,
find out what a doctor
was doing way out here.
I hope the suit fits. I
had to buy it off the rack.
Nothing in your closet
was really formal enough.
Whatever you think will
help our chances, counselor.
Okay [Sighs]
Decent.
It's a little loose,
but it looks good.
How do you feel?
Like an Indian Al Capone.
[Exhales sharply]
I even have the scars.
Well, don't worry about that,
because I came prepared.
Now, remember, this is not a trial.
It's a bail hearing.
There is a Judge but no jury.
And we don't have to
prove that you're innocent.
We just have to show that
you're not a flight risk.
And how do we do that?
By showing that you're a model citizen.
Which you are... you've
never even been arrested.
Actually...
Ben Mallory's associates said
that he'd only lived in Durant
for three months.
Before that, he spent two years
with doctors without
borders in West Africa.
Did Ben have a wife or kids?
No. But his parents live in South Dakota.
I just spoke to his mom on the phone.
She said they'd get down
here as soon as they could.
Ben's secretary said that he got a call
around 6:00 last night.
A few minutes after that,
he left the office with his medical bag...
didn't say where he was going.
She just assumed that he
was making a house call
on his way home.
That barn's a pretty odd
place to make a house call.
Yeah, but he's new in town.
He had no idea where he was going.
It sounds like this caller
was trying to lure him out there.
Did Ben have any recent problems
with colleagues or patients?
All the nurses said that there'd
never been an incident at the hospital.
But one of them did say that he also
worked out at the reservation clinic, so...
Uh, I can head out there if you want.
You sure you're up for that?
[Chuckles]
Driving and talking?
I think I can handle it.
[Door closes]
Hey, there.
[Laughs] Hey.
[Chuckling]
Oh. [Grunts]
It's good to see you!
I guess you remember me.
Yeah, it's good to see
you up on your feet again.
You know, don't rush it, though, boss.
You got to rest up as much as you can.
[Chuckles] Rest will have to wait.
Does a Dr. Ben Mallory work here?
Yeah.
What can you tell me about him?
[Sighs] Not much.
Ben's a volunteer with
Indian Health Services.
Lot of those guys come through here.
Cocky white dudes sent to
rescue us with their medicine.
[Chuckles] But Ben's not too bad.
And the ladies, they
certainly don't mind him.
[Laughs]
Looks like someone murdered him last night.
Seriously?
Did he have problems with anyone?
Uh, one guy got into it with Ben last week.
They were both yelling
at each other pretty loud.
Can you tell me who it is?
Uh, no, not offhand,
but I can check the logbook.
[Indistinct yelling echoing]
Do you know what the
patient was yelling about?
No, I wasn't in the room.
But you were in the room
when I was brought in.
Yep.
First time I ever saved
anybody's life before.
It was kind of wild.
[Shudders]
Did I say anything weird?
Naw, by the time I jumped in,
you were already out of it.
Anyone else come in around that time?
Someone with a gunshot wound?
Like who?
You mean David?
You know him?
Oh, yeah.
He comes in all the time to donate blood.
When was the last time you saw him?
Mm, 'bout a month ago, I guess.
[Sighs]
You see him again...
Call me right away.
Yeah, sure thing.
Uh, hey, don't you want
the name of the patient
that was yelling at Dr. Mallory?
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
So, don't mention the fact that
you arrested Henry last year
- during that fracking protest.
- You sure?
I thought I'd lead with it.
Cady: [Chuckles]
Please don't try and be funny on the stand.
Are you wearing make-up?
A little.
Bailiff: Court will come to order!
The Honorable Joseph Mayhew presiding.
All rise.
Judge: All right, everyone, settle in.
All right.
In the matter of the state
vs. Henry Standing Bear,
the defense is seeking bail?
Yes, we are, your honor.
I see that this is a murder charge,
and if convicted, your client
could be facing the death penalty.
My tentative judgment
is to deny bail outright.
Knowing this, do you still wish a hearing?
Yes! Yes, your honor.
My client has been a business
owner for over 20 years,
and... and this shows that...
I'll give you the weekend to decide
if you want to waste the court's time.
[Glass thuds]
That's enough, miss.
[Scoffs]
I'm sorry, were we not in
the same courtroom today?
You heard what the Judge
said. He's made up his mind.
Henry's not getting bail.
I heard the Judge say you had
two days to figure something out.
So order some food and get to work.
You're not staying to eat?
I can't. Branch found
a suspect in our murder.
So I gotta go talk to him.
[Chuckles lightly]
[Sighs]
Dale: Every time an
Indian raises his voice,
it's just a matter of time
before the cavalry shows up.
Mr. Grey Wolf, why were
you yelling at Dr. Mallory?
Because he's a pervert.
Did Dr. Mallory touch you or something?
No. My daughter.
She went to see him a couple of weeks ago.
She was sick. It looked like the flu.
But instead of taking her temperature,
this doctor took off her pants
and gave her a pelvic exam.
Did Dr. Mallory tell you why he did that?
Oh, he said he was just being thorough,
but he abused his medical authority
to look up my daughter's skirt.
So, yeah, I raised my voice.
Are you here to press charges against me?
Not yet. We would like
to talk to your daughter.
If she was molested, a
report should be filed.
She's at a friend's house tonight.
And frankly, there's no need
for you to drag out this ordeal.
The situation has been dealt with.
Vic: "The situation has been dealt with"?
Is that a nice way of
saying he murdered the guy?
Check Dr. Mallory's background
for reports of sexual abuse by patients.
In the meantime, we need
to talk to Dale's daughter.
Get her side of the story.
I'll make some calls, see
if I can track her down.
No need. I know where
she's gonna be tomorrow.
How so?
I recognized her from the pictures inside.
She's a contestant in the
Miss Cheyenne Nation Pageant.
I was sort of surprised to
see you in the courtroom.
Back in school, I never
pegged you as a litigator.
So, how'd I do? What'd you think?
I think that was your first bail hearing.
- [Chuckles]
I'm not really a trial lawyer,
but there's a lot riding
on this case for me.
You've done a lot of these
bail hearings, though, right?
So, aside from the client's record,
what else could I use as proof
to show that he won't run?
Is this why you called
me? To pick my brain?
You never minded tutoring me in law school.
Right...
But I had other intentions.
So, how about [Chuckling]
I buy you dinner tonight
and you give me your expertise?
Save your flirting for the Judge.
What questions you got?
Okay, are there any laws
that I should reference
in the bail hearing?
Or is there any way that I could, like...?
Cady...
Bail hearings are about people.
If you want the Judge to grant bail,
you need to prove to him
that your client is an honorable person.
Right.
Bring out his family...
preferably daughters.
The Judge has three girls.
Henry doesn't have any family.
That's bad.
So you gotta spin some bullshit
about how Henry's got
ties to the community.
He does.
There's a whole group of people
on the reservation that depend on him.
I could bring them all in to testify.
[Chuckling] Whoa.
Judge Mayhew hates a long hearing.
Find one good witness
and put them on the stand.
But I can't guarantee even that'll help.
Is there anything that you
can guarantee will help?
Yeah. Prove Henry didn't do it.
That was the hospital.
The call that lured Ben Mallory to the barn
came through the switchboard.
So the call is untraceable?
Right.
There's no way to tell
if it's Dale Grey Wolf
or someone else entirely.
You know, I've been thinking,
maybe Dr. Mallory wasn't
at the barn on business.
Back in high school,
the only reason anybody went up there
was to hook up without being caught.
So instead of making a house call,
he was making a booty call?
The guy at the Res Clinic said
he was popular with the ladies.
Maybe Ben was meeting one of them
up there to... "Play doctor."
Walt: I'm sorry to bother you.
Are you, by any chance,
Ben Mallory's mother?
Stepmother. I'm Dr. Sylvia Mallory.
And this is Ben's father, Dr. Oren Mallory.
I'm Sheriff Longmire. I
think you're here to see me.
Well, we were just about to head inside...
I can't.
I know how hard this must be.
Facing the loss of a child
is about the worst thing
a parent can go through.
I just can't go through this again.
My oldest son, Andrew,
was murdered in Detroit.
They ever figure out who did it?
The police have pretty
much given up at this point.
As far as they're concerned,
Andrew's just another one
of Detroit's unsolved murders.
That was a year ago.
And now Ben.
Did Ben have any enemies?
Ah, no. He made friends everywhere.
He always volunteered for the places
that needed the most help.
He wanted to be just like you.
Oh, he was a better man than I.
Now, I spent my fair share of time
working for Reservations and free Clinics.
But I did it to pay off
my medical-school bills.
Not Ben.
Ben was different.
He was selfless.
Ben could afford to be selfless.
He had you to support him.
Yeah, well...
[Groans]
You know, I keep thinking...
...what did I do to deserve this?
I know this is difficult,
but any information you have may help.
Yeah, well, please, no offense,
but...
I'm finding it hard to
see the point to all this.
When Andrew was killed, I
spent hours with the police,
and nothing came of it.
I know what that's like,
more than you think.
I'm sorry I can't do
anything about Andrew's case,
but I can do something about Ben's.
Now, I promise...
I promise...
things are gonna be
different this time around.
Walt: Vic, put in a call
to the Detroit Police Department.
Ask them for a copy
of Andrew Mallory's murder file.
Detroit?
Since when did we start
investigating murders in other cities?
I'm just taking a look
for Oren Mallory's sake.
Okay.
In the meantime,
I got some information on Ben Mallory.
There are no allegations of sexual abuse,
no malpractice suits.
The guy was a Saint.
Dale Grey Wolf, on the other hand,
has two priors for assault,
and he's obviously got a temper.
So, depending on what
happened in that exam room,
he totally could have snapped.
We'll know more after
we talk to his daughter.
"Contestant Grey Wolf,
what are your thoughts on world peace?"
"Oh, and, by the way,
do you think your father
could be a murderer?"
[Tribal chanting]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Scraping]
Neena Wapasha.
Is this your first time judging, Sheriff?
Yeah. I'm guessing you've
done quite a few of these.
About 15 between here
and my home in Oklahoma.
Don't be nervous.
It's just like talking
to your own daughter.
You mean they're gonna talk back?
[Both chuckle]
Contestant number two...
Lilly Stillwater.
- Hi, Sheriff.
- Hello, May.
Hello, Sheriff.
[Clears throat]
Contestant number one,
Micheala Grey Wolf.
Any relation?
My daughter.
Oh, she's cute.
Isn't this supposed to
be the talent competition?
Where are the batons?
Your idea of beauty pageants is a joke.
Bouquets and bikinis.
The Miss Cheyenne Nation Pageant
is a proud cultural honor.
These girls must prove
their knowledge and skill
at carving the animal.
The Judges ask them difficult questions
while they work
to see if they stay calm under pressure.
I imagine that's hard for some people.
Miss Grey Wolf.
What are the best spots to shoot a deer?
A hunter should always aim
for the lung and the kidney.
A direct shot to either will kill the
animal quickly so they won't suffer.
Where did you learn your butchering skills?
From my father.
These knives have been handed down
through my family for generations.
Are you sick?
I know you recently
went to see Dr. Mallory.
What did he have to say about it?
He said it wasn't contagious.
Thank you. Think we have all we need.
- Good job, Micheala.
- Thank you.
So, what'd you think?
I think she's pregnant.
Walt: Whoever stabbed Dr.
Mallory knew what they were doing.
Direct hits to the lung and kidney
would have killed him almost instantly.
And from what I learned today,
Micheala and her father are
both experts with a knife.
All this because Ben
gave Micheala a pap smear?
Seems extreme.
Well, there's a little more to it.
It looks like Micheala may be pregnant.
Wow. Okay.
Well, from what Branch found out,
Ben was pretty popular
with his female patients.
Maybe he and Micheala
were having an affair.
That could explain what he was
doing at the barn that night.
Dr. Mallory meets Micheala
there for a little privacy.
Dale Grey Wolf finds out
about it and ambushes him.
That, or maybe Ben tried to end the affair.
Micheala got pissed, decides to kill him.
Walt: Before we go too far with theories,
we need to confirm she's pregnant.
We need to get a look at
Micheala's medical files.
- Cady: Thank you.
- Thank you.
Just gonna take this.
Okay, so, um, this isn't quite right,
but it's a great start, so I'm
gonna go get you a-a clean sheet,
and you can take another crack at it, okay?
Okay.
- We are so screwed.
- Cady?
It's gonna be okay.
Have you even read these affidavits?
Most of the people are afraid
to sign their own names,
and of the ones who did, the best one
says Henry was pretty good at darts.
You are not wrong. These are terrible.
But it is early.
We'll give them some pointers.
Okay?
Good. Now, just relax.
It's gonna be okay.
[Clears throat]
Excuse me.
[Chuckling] Hi.
I'm so sorry.
I completely forgot we were having drinks.
I didn't think I was working tonight,
but Cameron said we've
got to log in some...
some hours if we're gonna
give Henry a fighting chance.
Who's Cameron?
Uh, Cam... Cameron Maddox?
He's, um, he's an old
friend from law school.
He's got a lot of trial experience.
So I've brought him on
as my shadow counsel,
which is kind of like
an unofficial adviser.
He said I... I need one
good witness for Henry,
so I threw this little affidavit party
to see who the best spokesperson might be.
Mm.
May: You're gonna need more food than that.
[Laughs]
Hello, May.
Where did everybody come from?
They made an announcement
after the pageant finished
for the day.
Lilly sang the Cheyenne departing song.
You should have heard her.
You trying to sway my vote?
[Laughs] I don't care which way you vote.
I just wish you could see how far
Lilly's come these past two years.
It wouldn't have been
possible without you and Henry.
Oh [Chuckles] I don't know
how much I had to do with it.
She's a good kid.
Yeah. She is.
Okay.
- Nice to see you.
- [Screams]
You were looking for anything you could use
to get my daughter disqualified!
And I guess now I know why!
What the hell are you talking about?!
[Grunting]
You told the Judges Micheala was pregnant!
Is she?! Well, is she?!
You can answer me here...
Or at the station!
[Groaning]
[People murmuring]
[Groans]
Walt: When I mentioned to the Judges
that Micheala might be pregnant,
I had no idea it was grounds for dismissal.
Thanks to you, the other Judges
forced Micheala to take a test.
When it came back positive,
they threw her out of the
competition on the spot.
I tried to keep it a secret
until after the pageant.
That title meant everything to Micheala.
And to you.
So, who's the father?
What business is that of yours?
Vic: Because we think Dr.
Mallory might be the father.
And when you found out that a white
doctor knocked up your daughter,
you decided to kill him.
What?
You never told me he was dead.
I didn't kill him.
It was Micheala's boyfriend
who got her pregnant.
That doctor had nothing to do with it.
So why were you really
yelling at him at the clinic?
Because he offered Micheala an abortion.
Dr. Mallory said it was "an option."
That's what he called it.
But it really was just the latest ploy
white doctors are using to wipe us out.
They've done it before.
In the 1880s they'd wrap newborns
in disease-covered blankets.
Up until the 1980s,
they were sterilizing Indian
women without their permission.
A woman would go to the
clinic for an appendectomy
and leave with a hysterectomy.
Now, every time an Indian
girl turns up pregnant,
they tell her to abort.
They say it saves their future...
But all it really does is
destroy our tribe's legacy.
[Footsteps approach]
Branch: Walt.
The Detroit P.D. just sent
over Andrew Mallory's case file.
Turns out he was stabbed in the
exact same places as his brother, Ben.
No money was missing off his body.
You think the same
person killed both of 'em?
Dale clearly had reasons to kill Ben,
but there's no cause for
him to go after Andrew.
Dale isn't the only expert when
it comes to knives and anatomy.
So, what, you're thinking Micheala?
She didn't have a motive
to kill Andrew either.
I was actually thinking
about a different woman.
Sylvia Mallory. She's a doctor...
Knows where a knife can do the most damage.
Plus, Oren Mallory sounds
like he's got money.
With his sons out of the
way, she'd get everything.
Wouldn't be the first wicked stepmother
to try and kill her stepchildren.
[Sighs] All right.
Check into the Mallorys' finances.
See if there was money worth killing for.
Also, check on Sylvia's whereabouts
around the time of Ben's death.
What about Dale Grey Wolf?
He hit an officer. Leave him in the cell.
I see you had him ditch the suit and tie.
He's a Native American.
Dressing him up like a banker
just hides who he really is.
Shall we?
I'm afraid you're on your own.
Believe it or not,
I do have cases of my
own that need attention.
Of course. Yeah.
Look, I am sure you'll be fine on your own.
[Sighs]
Besides, the Judge gave
his tentative ruling.
So, don't forget...
you're already doomed.
Thank you for that vote of confidence.
Anytime.
What's in the box?
Ferg had it sent over from Rawlins.
Files on men I put away over the years.
One of them might have committed the crime
that Henry's on trial for...
To get back at me.
You think your wife's
murder and Henry's arrest
are all retaliation?
Whoever did this wanted to
make sure I suffered every day.
You got anyone in particular in mind?
Plenty.
You find out anything about the Mallorys?
Sylvia's office said she was
at a conference in Billings
when Ben was killed.
But I haven't been able to
find anyone from the event
that can verify that.
Checked into Oren Mallory's finances.
He's loaded.
Oren built up and sold medical
practices all over the country...
Virginia, Oklahoma, South Dakota.
His net worth is about 22 mil.
And with both his sons gone,
Sylvia gets everything.
Okay.
Okay, uh...
Maybe, instead of looking
at who benefits from the boys' death,
we should think about who suffers.
Ben Mallory's body ready to be released?
So, in addition to being
the arresting officer on this case,
you've known the defendant a long time.
Based on your experience,
do you think he'd be a
good candidate for bail?
You mean will he stay put?
He's a Cheyenne. We're originally nomads.
Look, Henry Standing Bear
has no wife and no kids.
Now, he can give you his word he won't run,
but frankly, I don't think
his word can be trusted.
Why do you say that?
I watched him sign an intent
to waive his extradition.
Then later, it was ripped up.
Which shows total disrespect
for the laws of this court.
Objection!
This is not a trial, counselor.
Sorry. Point of clarification, your honor.
This extradition waiver...
you said it was ripped up.
Did you actually see my
client destroy the waiver?
No.
Was it in fact another
party who ripped it up?
Yes...
then it appears my client has
no disrespect for the court.
It is the other party that does.
I guess.
It was his best friend that tore it up,
which is all the more reason
to deny Henry Standing Bear bail.
He obviously has
some questionable associates.
And if you can't trust
the company a man keeps,
you can't trust the man himself.
Judge: Court recognizes the defense.
Cady: Your honor...
I have 125 affidavits here,
each one of them a testament
to my client's strong character
and the community's reliance on him.
I was up for seven hours
last night reading them.
To spare your honor this task,
I have chosen one person
who can speak for them all.
Miss Stillwater, would
you share with the court
a little of your history with my client?
[Sighs] About two years ago,
my daughter Lilly ran away from home.
She was 15.
I started hearing rumors
that she had fallen into...
Prostitution.
I tried looking for her everywhere,
but it was like she'd disappeared.
The tribal police wouldn't help me.
No one would help me...
Until I called Henry.
Henry, along with his best friend,
they brought my Lilly home.
After that, he came every
single week to check in.
He got her started in school again,
and he paid for a good therapist.
Because of him, Lilly is now thriving.
She's even competing to represent our tribe
in the Miss Cheyenne Nation Pageant.
[Chuckles lightly]
And Henry did all of this
even though he wasn't family?
We Cheyenne have a different
definition of family.
Family is not a matter of
biology, but of loyalty.
And if that's the way you look at it,
Henry is the closest family we have.
In your opinion, do you think Henry
will flee if given the opportunity?
No. His name is Standing Bear.
Would you mind clarifying?
Many people think when they see
a bear standing in the forest,
it means to run.
But the bear is just standing guard,
looking to protect those he
loves from whatever may come.
[Voice breaking] Henry is a standing bear.
And a standing bear will never run,
no matter what.
Thank you, Miss Stillwater.
Oren: Did you find out who did it?
Walt: Not yet.
First I...
I thought Ben's murder might
involve one of his patients.
Then I looked at your first
son Andrew's case file,
and it turns out Andrew's murder
is almost identical to Ben's.
Are you saying they were
killed by the same person?
Well, I admit it's hard to believe.
After all, there's nothing really
linking the two boys together.
They live in different places,
have different jobs.
In fact, the only things
they have in common
are the same father...
And the same stepmother.
If you're implying that Sylvia had
something to do with this, you're wrong.
We were together on vacation
when Andrew was killed.
And as for me, I...
I could never hurt my sons.
I know that.
And I think the killer knew
that taking them away
would make you suffer.
Well, I can't think of anyone
who would want to hurt me like this.
I have dedicated my life to helping people.
Yes.
You said you worked on the Reservations.
I know that in the '70s,
about the same time you were practicing,
doctors on the Res were
sterilizing Native women
without their consent,
sometimes without even their knowledge.
Did you ever take part in that?
This again.
Listen.
No charges were ever filed against me.
What I did was within
my rights as a doctor.
Most of the women I cared for
couldn't care for themselves.
I remember once a 32-year-old
mother came into the clinic
with her 15-year-old daughter.
Both pregnant, both alcoholic.
It was a constant cycle of poverty
and substance abuse.
Sterilization was the only
way of breaking that cycle.
Now, some saw it as radical.
I saw it help women escape
the horrors of the Reservation.
Despite what you may
think, I know I was right.
[Sighs]
You never know if you're right.
I told you before I could solve this case.
But in order for me to do that,
I need you to waive
doctor/patient confidentiality
and open up your medical records.
Your son's murder did involve a patient,
and I think it was one of yours.
Before this hearing began,
I told you what my tentative ruling was.
In murder cases,
I find it hard to justify
the granting of bail.
But, in light of the testimony given,
I've decided to make an exception.
Bail is set at $1 million.
[Spectators murmur]
Cady: I spoke to the bail bondsmen.
He said they'd cover 90% of the bail.
But we still need to come up with $100,000
that we don't have.
Well, there's some money in my
retirement fund. It's not a lot,
- but it'll at least get us started.
- [Knock on door]
The important thing is
that bail was granted.
You did good, punk.
Thanks, dad.
Just get back here. We'll figure it out.
Okay.
- Okay, bye.
- Bye.
So, I've been going
through the list of patients
that Oren Mallory gave us.
So far, it doesn't look
like any of the women
have a connection to Dale Grey Wolf.
It's possible it's a distant relative
with a different last name.
Could be an Aunt or an Uncle or...
Never mind.
Release him.
What?
- Walt.
- [Door closes]
It's a good thing we
waited to have a drink.
Now we can celebrate your big victory.
[Sighs]
Not much to celebrate.
Henry's still in jail.
And even with dad's retirement
and the collection jar we passed around,
we're still short about 50 grand.
[Clears throat]
What are you doing?
I am writing you a check for $100,000.
What?
No. No.
Branch, no, I'm not letting
you spend your money on this.
I will find some way to raise the cash.
You can't bake sale your
way out of this, Cady.
I don't know what to say.
Henry will really appreciate it.
I'm not doing this for Henry.
[Chuckles]
Besides, we both know it's not my money.
I'm sure your dad will be
thrilled when he finds out.
He'll get it back.
Unless...
Henry's not planning to run, is he?
[Chuckles]
Announcer: First runner-up...
With a total score of 112...
Jeanine Redcloud!
[Cheers and applause]
Walt!
What's wrong?
Where are the Judges?
Uh... I think over there.
And now for the moment
you've all been waiting for...
With a total score of 151,
your Miss Cheyenne Nation 2014,
Lilly Stillwater!
[Cheers and applause]
Whoo, Lilly! All right, Lilly!
[Drum beating, tribal chanting]
Neena?
Sheriff, where you been?
They just announced the winner.
I'm sorry.
I've been a little preoccupied
looking into the murder of Ben Mallory.
I think you knew him.
Or at least you knew his father,
back in Oklahoma.
Oklahoma.
[Chuckles]
That's where I won my crown.
That was the best night of my life.
I was a young woman with
so much to be proud of.
Something worth passing
on to my daughters one day.
But you never had children, did you?
I thought it was just bad luck.
But a year ago, I had a hernia operation.
During the procedure, they...
Found I'd been sterilized.
Oren Mallory was the only doctor
who had ever operated on me.
An appendectomy.
I was 16.
He took away your ability to have children.
So I took his sons.
I just...
I wanted Oren Mallory to...
feel the pain he caused.
I wanted him to know what it was like
to have all your dreams for the future
[voice breaking] taken away by a stranger.
Neena...
I thought I would feel
peace when I got my revenge.
I was wrong.
I...
I feel emptier than before.
[Laughs]
And the irony is,
Oren Mallory probably
doesn't even remember me.
He'll never understand...
he'll never understand why his sons died.
Let me help you, Neena.
Ahh...
Let me help you.
[Whimpers]
You need to tell people
what happened to you.
You tell them.
It will mean more coming from you, Neena.
[Buzzer]
You're never going back in there.
You should not make
promises you cannot keep.
My freedom is temporary.
And it has limits.
No matter what happens,
you're never going back.