[SPEAKING IN CROW LANGUAGE]
I'm sorry!
[GRUNTING AND MOANING]
BOYS: Three one-thousand,
four one-thousand...
...five one-thousand, six one-thousand,
seven one-thousand...
...eight one-thousand,
nine one-thousand, ten one-thousand.
Ready or not, here we come!
Yah!
- Say your prayers, Indian.
- Uh!
Neel! I got her!
ADDYSON:
Neel!
CHARLIE:
I looked everywhere.
- I called all the neighbors.
WALT: Mr. Fielding.
Please. Sit down.
You need to put out an AMBER Alert or
something. All we have is his shoe.
That's my son!
Neel is our foster son.
We've had him five months.
CHARLIE: He was playing
with our daughter, Addyson...
...and our neighbor's boy, Dylan,
in the empty lot, at the dead end.
Now, do you remember seeing
or hearing anything else in the woods?
Just that his horse was there
but he wasn't.
- Neel ever try to run away before?
TRACY: Never.
We were two weeks away
from adopting him.
From what we've heard,
Neel's birth parents are a real mess.
They're addicts, I think.
Now, maybe they found us.
Maybe they took him.
I'm going to the reservation to look.
Better if you stay
and don't jump to conclusions.
- There's no time.
- Yes, there is.
This is all hard to believe, I know.
We get a few cases like this every year.
Usually, the child comes back in an hour
or two with a line of trout...
...wondering
why everybody's so upset.
I need you to put
out a statewide broadcast. Montana too.
Neel Cody. Eight.
I just texted you a photo.
Hang on.
Yeah, Branch.
Check the registered sex offenders
in the county.
I want an alibi check
on every one of them.
Uh-huh. Good.
- You ever run away from home?
- Yeah, once, when I was 13.
Lost my temper,
walked out of the house.
Middle of winter.
- You have your shoes on?
- Boots, I think.
A kid doesn't run away
with just one shoe.
Unless he wants to run in circles.
What are you thinking?
We can't discount what Mr. Fielding said
about Neel's biological parents.
About half of all abductions
are family members.
Custody disputes.
If you're gonna take a kid in broad
daylight, this is as good a place as any.
Trees for cover, road to get away.
- No screams.
- What?
Daughter never said anything
about screams.
So Neel either didn't see his attacker
and the person covered his mouth...
...or Neel saw a face
that didn't scare him.
Is that what you think
or what you hope?
VIC:
Hi.
- What's that, a dinosaur?
- It's a Parasaurolophus.
[RIFLE COCKS]
What do you want?
MOTHER: First you take him away
and then you lose him.
Mrs. Cody, we didn't lose Neel.
We're just trying to locate him.
What did you mean by "take him away"?
They took our son right out of school
and put him in a foster home.
Didn't even have the decency
to tell us.
- They?
FATHER: Family Services.
Told us it was for Neel's own good.
They say we're addicts.
Said a neighbor talked about abuse
and neglect in our house.
All lies.
- Did you try to fight it in the court?
- A Cheyenne in a white court.
- Ever read history?
- That's not what I meant.
Did you ever try to visit Neel
in the foster home?
I walk three and a half miles
to my day job.
Minimum wage, part-time.
I come home,
shut my eyes for a few minutes...
...then head out to my night job.
In a month, if no one gets sick...
...maybe I have the money
to finish rebuilding that engine.
Then, maybe, I find something full-time,
with better pay.
And then, we can talk about hiring
a lawyer to get Neel back.
- Ruby.
- This week's fan mail and love letters.
I put together
an impromptu press conference...
...with a mobile unit from Casper. They'll
share the video with the other networks.
Should be on every set in the state
by end of day.
Also dug up the arrest records
for Neel Cody's Cheyenne family.
VIC: Reckless driving citation
for his mother from 10 years ago...
...and a dropped drunk-and-disorderly
for the father. That's it?
My grandma's got a longer rap sheet.
Seems like their biggest crime's
just being poor.
I gotta tell you, if someone walked into
my kid's school and took my child...
...I'd be pissed enough to take matters
into my own hands.
You really think the car
was broke-down?
It was. I looked. No alternator.
That doesn't mean
they couldn't have borrowed one.
Where there's a will, there's a way.
I'll get the Tribal Police
to keep an eye on the family.
But, Branch, did you follow up
on the sex offenders?
Yup. Eight registered in the county,
every one of them accounted for.
Good. Now head over to the group
home where Neel used to live.
See if he's hiding
with any of his friends.
Sometimes kids have a way
of keeping secrets from...
[VIC CLEARS THROAT]
...adults.
- You said you wanted to see me, Dad?
We need a favor.
A Cheyenne boy, Neel Cody,
has gone missing.
- We need your help.
- Oh, that's horrible.
And interesting, because my boss
is handling the Neel Cody adoption...
...for the Fieldings.
Dad, I can't believe
you're asking me this.
He's not. I am.
I understand,
it's attorney-client privilege.
But all I want is a legal way for you
to get us access to Neel's file.
Translated in Wyoming:
You want me to break the law.
No one's breaking the law.
But, Cady, you know how volatile
these custody battles are.
We're trying to find the truth.
There've been a lot of accusations
on both sides.
Which is why this is being handled
in court.
God, are you always
such a goody-goody?
No.
There's a difference
between being a goody-goody...
...and not wanting to get disbarred.
WALT: Vic, hey, Cady's right.
She can't help us find this poor
missing boy, even if she wants to.
Thanks for coming by, Punk.
Okay, look.
I can't tell you anything about
the Fielding adoption. That's private.
But I might have some insight into
the byzantine bureaucracy of the state.
I'm sorry, can you translate
that into Philadelphia for me?
I might be able to point you
in the direction of some public records...
...that are not covered
by attorney-client privilege.
SHANK:
It isn't like Neel to run away.
I'm just worried sick.
Do you have any opinion
on the Fieldings?
I try to be impartial. But I must say,
I wish more foster parents were like them.
What about Neel's biological parents?
You hear any stories about them?
- They ever come around?
- No.
I mean, these kids
are throwaway kids.
Once they leave the res,
they're kind of forgotten.
I don't mean to sound racist,
it's just the way it is.
You wouldn't happen
to have Neel's paperwork, would you?
Chaos is sort of our
organizing principle around here.
Neel's papers are probably down
with county already.
Well, if you hear anything, give a call.
Smallest thing may help.
I heard you the first time, Mathias.
But all I'm asking is,
you keep an eye on the Cody house.
Yeah.
Always a pleasure.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
RUBY:
Sheriff.
We've got a crying woman
in our lobby.
My son is missing.
- How old is he?
- Thirty-five.
Your 35-year-old son
is missing?
And then I saw that television report
and I knew I had to come in...
...but I just couldn't make myself
come through the door.
Slow down, ma'am.
- Now, what's your son's name?
- Jeremy. Jeremy Thompson.
He hasn't returned any of my calls.
I'm afraid for him, sheriff.
For what he might have done.
Why are you worried about Jeremy?
He was a teacher's aide in Tulsa.
They said...
...he touched one or two of the boys.
He admitted to his sin.
He did his time.
And then, he moved back to live with me
about a year ago...
...so that I could help him.
Your son was a sex offender.
But he never registered.
[SOBS]
I didn't want him persecuted.
He promised me.
I wanted him to have a fresh start.
But now I fear evil
has got hold of him again.
Ruby, put out an AMBER Alert
for Neel Cody. Now.
We gotta find this boy and soon.
RUBY [OVER RADIO]: The sheriff's
department of Absaroka County...
...Wyoming is issuing an AMBER Alert
for a missing 8-year-old boy...
...Neel Cody.
In connection with this abduction...
...we are seeking a man
named Jeremy Thompson...
...driving a silver and white
1995 Ford F-350 pickup...
...with Wyoming license...
- Lights out, guys.
...24-30-C-six-H.
We have reason to believe the child
is in imminent danger.
[THUD]
You said there were two missing
Cheyenne boys.
I pull in at 6 a.m. And my supervisor's
not even here. No note, no nothing.
- Your supervisor. Is that Ryan Shank?
- Yeah. I've tried calling. No answer.
Neel Cody, another Cheyenne
foster child, was abducted yesterday.
Now two more are missing.
- That's three in less than 24 hours.
COOK: Oh, God.
- You think they were taken?
- It's starting to look that way.
Did any of you see this man
last night?
No. We were sleeping.
What kind of car
does Ryan Shank drive?
A Ford Explorer. Gray.
I'll make sure Ruby updates
the AMBER Alert.
Would you show us Shank's office?
- These the boys that were taken?
COOK: Yeah, Cierre and Michael.
And Ryan.
He would do anything to protect them.
- Are the boys' case files in here?
- They should be.
Thanks for your time.
VIC: Didn't Branch say
that Ryan Shank said...
...he'd send Neel Cody's file as soon as
he got it back from the county?
That's right.
It was right here.
Right with the others.
What the hell you doing?
Sometimes you can learn a lot about a
person by looking at their bookshelves.
- Really? And what have you learned?
- A lot of science fiction. Asimov.
High school yearbooks,
which is odd for a man Shank's age.
He's either sentimental,
or living in the past.
For years, the county has been taking
Cheyenne children off the reservation...
...and placing them in homes run
by white men and white women.
But we expect that, don't we?
What we don't expect is for the county
to misplace one of these children.
And we don't expect
Sheriff Walt Longmire...
...to allow a pedophile
to roam our streets at will.
You think the sheriff would be doing so
little if the pedophile was a Cheyenne...
...or Lakota?
ALL: No!
You bet he would not.
Still think you want my job,
Branch?
That guy really doesn't seem to like you,
sheriff.
- You're not Facebook friends, I take it.
- I don't expect everyone to like me.
I expect them to leave politics out of it
when we're dealing with missing kids.
Kids?
Plural?
Ryan Shank ever call you
about Neel's file?
Not yet. Sounded like
there was a lot of red tape.
He lied. The file was in his office
the entire time.
- Was Shank up to something?
- He's missing.
Along with two boys
from the group home.
- You think he took them?
- You talked to him.
You get any kind of a hit off him?
He was upset, but under
the circumstances, that seemed normal.
Dig deeper. Vic, give him a hand.
Contact the missing boys' biological
parents, see where they were last night.
I'm gonna go deal
with the bureaucracy.
Seems both kids
had the same social worker.
Maybe she knows
something worth knowing.
According to Mr. Shank's files...
...you handled all three boys' cases.
- Mm-hm.
- Is there anything else that links them?
- Abuse, neglect, malnourishment.
That's what links them.
Unfortunately,
it's also what makes them typical.
There are so many Native children
to help, but with our limited resources...
...there's only so much we can do.
Do you have much contact
with Ryan Shank...
...the group home supervisor?
- I do. Why?
You think Shank might have acted
inappropriately with these kids?
Oh, wow. I, um...
[SCOFFS]
Look. You have to be very careful
with those kinds of accusations...
...and rumors
when you're working with kids.
Right now
we're just trying to find him.
When was the last time
you spoke with him?
Last night.
It was a pretty mundane conversation.
But it was weird that he called so late.
A little after 10:30.
Have you dealt
with any emotional parents lately?
No.
But I did have
a Cheyenne gentleman...
...visit me recently
about a friend's situation.
I tried to explain to him
the proper guidelines for appeal...
...but he was not interested
in having that conversation.
He became enraged.
The child that man came
to discuss, Cierre.
He was one of the boys taken
from the group home last night.
HENRY:
I was not enraged.
I was insistent.
- She said you were pounding her desk.
- A rhetorical flourish.
- Henry, why were you even there?
- They took Cissy Ponson's son.
They claimed
she was a falling-down drunk...
...that her car was here at
the Red Pony morning, noon and night.
Was that the case?
Cissy Ponson is my employee.
A single mother. She does not drink.
What'd the social worker say
when you told her this?
She said there was nothing
she could do.
Well, I assume you know
that Cissy's son has gone missing.
Jacob Nighthorse told me.
He seems to be taking
a particular interest in this matter.
Good. Everyone should.
A pedophile's on the loose.
I wanna find these boys
as much as he does.
But the more Nighthorse
makes this a political issue...
...the harder it is for us to do our job.
Or maybe he's making sure
you all do your job.
I apologize.
But, Walt, you have to understand how
upsetting this situation is on the res.
There used to be a saying among
the white people who settled the West:
"Kill the Indian, save the man."
Sometimes it seems like
nothing has changed.
[SIGHS]
No cream. Two sugars.
Thanks.
Gotta say, I'm surprised to see you
compromising your ethics.
There's no compromise.
These are all public records.
There's nothing unethical...
...about helping all of you
navigate the state bureaucracy.
Besides, though Neel's a client,
the other two boys aren't.
Shit. Hey, Walt!
Walt!
Shank and Jeremy Thompson
wrestled together in high school.
- They know each other.
- Okay, that is creepy.
Think they had an arrangement
or something?
Like a child sex-ring?
Why would Ryan Shank
abduct these boys...
...when he could just walk right
down the hall?
For money?
The AMBER Alert worked!
They got him.
Which him?
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[MEN GRUNTING]
VIC: Hey, guys, knock it off!
MAN: We got him, we got him!
VIC:
Hey, come on. Unh!
The kids are in there!
[GUNSHOT]
Jeremy, you mind if we talk?
- You can't do that. I got rights!
- So do we.
- What are these?
- They're vats for heating candle wax.
My boss had me drive over
to Salt Lake to pick them up...
...and now I'm gonna be late
for my delivery.
Why didn't you just
unlock the door?
Because these jerks aren't cops.
And you need a warrant.
That's the law.
So is registering as a sex offender.
Don't move.
- Well, lookie here. Is this the pervert?
WALT: Jacob.
- How can I help you?
- Has he told you where the kids are?
- He's not talking. But that's his right.
- Oh, yeah? Well, that's good to know.
What about the rights of the children?
- What's your angle here?
- What?
I don't think you'd take a glass of water
if there weren't some profit involved.
NIGHTHORSE: There is an angle here,
sheriff, but it's not mine.
A whole lot of money is being made off
of our children.
Each of these foster homes
receives federal money...
...for the children in its care.
But they get double for Indian kids.
Double.
You know, to motivate foster families
to take them in.
That's a good thing.
Not when they've been kidnapped
from good Cheyenne families.
Are you saying people
are kidnapping these children for profit?
Not people. Your government.
Branch. Come in here.
Nighthorse wants to talk politics.
I got work to do. Let's go.
- Ruby, tell Henry we're on our way.
- Where are we going?
Luke, you didn't speak up
when I was here before.
But I really need to know.
Have you seen this man?
I don't wanna make any more trouble.
These are good people, Luke.
They are my friends.
You are not in trouble.
All we wanna do is help.
Did you see this man?
[WHISPERS] I saw Hotametaneo'o.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Grandma always
told me if I didn't behave...
...then Hotametaneo'o would come
through the window and take me away.
I'm sorry, Hota... Hota-meta...
Help, help me.
There was a band of Cheyenne warriors
in the 19th century.
They were called Hotametaneo'o,
or dog soldiers.
It was believed
they could change shape...
...from man to dog and back again.
I broke Mr. Shank's radio this week.
That's why Hotametaneo'o came.
When did the dog soldier appear?
Right at midnight,
as Grandma always said.
How'd you know it was him?
I saw his face.
- Luke, what'd he look like?
- He looked like a soldier.
He had a scar right through here.
HENRY:
Each dog soldier wore a leather strap.
They would stake that strap
to the ground and fight to the death.
These men were figures of defiance,
figures of hope.
The U.S. Army hunted them down,
one by one.
But there were rumors
of one remaining survivor.
And this is who Luke saw last night?
- Yes.
WALT: No.
- Well, which is it?
- That was no spirit.
That kid saw Hector.
HENRY: You do not know that.
- Henry, Luke described the scar.
But kidnapping has never been
part of Hector's repertoire.
Okay, I'm sorry. Who is Hector?
Hector is a former boxer
who lives on the reservation.
Since most Cheyenne
do not trust the courts...
...they often hire Hector to right their
wrongs. - Means he makes a living...
...knocking out the teeth of thieves,
rapists, thugs and wife-beaters.
Hector is an unfortunate necessity
of reservation life.
But a necessity, nevertheless.
So we show the kid a picture of Hector
and we're done with it.
- I would, if one were known to exist.
RUBY [OVER RADIO]: Walt!
Walt!
What is it?
The Highway Patrol
found Ryan Shank's car.
It's near Spotted Horse
in Campbell County.
What's it doing way out there?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER
OVER POLICE RADIO]
I found it right here.
Keys are in the ignition.
[VIC SIGHS]
VIC:
Here, boy.
Come on. Good boy.
[DOG WHINES]
That better not be a child's ear.
WALT:
It's not a kid.
VIC: It's a Shank.
WALT: He was run over.
What do you think, Henry?
Has the dog soldier struck again?
- Where's Jeremy Thompson?
- His alibi checked out.
Had to release him.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
It's Ryan Shank.
- This is Deputy Connally.
WALT: Shank's dead.
- What happened?
- Murdered.
He had his cell phone on him and this.
I gave him that yesterday.
Said to call if anything happened.
- We got a suspect?
- We do.
I'm sending you
to the reservation to look for him.
People are dying,
we need to find these kids.
- Who am I looking for?
- Hector.
- The Hector?
- Take Vic.
She'll fill you in on the way.
Dad. Who's Hector?
Ah. I think he's the kidnapper.
And possibly, now, a murderer.
Do you think Shank was killed trying
to protect the boys?
I don't know.
Because I might have found
another reason Shank was targeted.
Jacob Nighthorse was right.
For every Native American kid...
...the foster homes get nearly twice
as much money.
And Shank's facility
has 13 Cheyenne children right now.
It gets $700 extra
a month for each of those kids.
And what's odd is that Shank
wasn't reporting the additional funds.
So Ryan Shank was skimming
the extra federal money.
Thirteen kids, $700 a month,
12 months a year.
We're talking
an extra hundred grand a year.
You were talking about anger
on the res concerning Family Services.
- Maybe the killing was payback.
- Hector's a high-school dropout.
He gets paid 200 bucks per tooth.
How does he figure this out?
RUBY:
Walt.
What was the name
of that social worker you talked to?
Crystal Shoemaker.
CRYSTAL:
I didn't even see the other car.
It ran me off the road.
I saw this man approaching
and I thought that he...
He wanted to help.
But he grabbed me and he told me
to leave Cheyenne children alone.
The next one I took, he said,
he'd kill me.
Crystal, we just
found Ryan Shank's body.
What? My God.
We're just trying to help
these poor kids.
This man who tried to run you
off the road.
What'd he look like?
He was big.
Dark-skinned. Cheyenne, I think.
And he had a big scar under his eye.
Nobody on the res will tell
my deputies anything about Hector.
So I need you to tell me, Henry.
- Where is he?
- I do not know.
You trying to protect him? Or are you
gonna help me find these boys?
Hopefully, both.
Three children are missing.
A man is dead.
And now that social worker
you yelled at a couple weeks ago?
She been run off the road
by a big Cheyenne man with...
...and I quote, "A big scar under his eye."
What's it gonna take to
convince you this is no spirit?
I do not know, Walt, proof?
I'm telling you, none of this
sounds like Hector. He is not a killer.
I still got five years of Hector's
arrest warrants back at the station.
Those warrants get forwarded
to the U.S. Marshals...
...unless Hector turns himself in.
If Hector goes into the federal system,
he is never coming out.
Then let him come in
and clear his name if he's innocent.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[GASPING]
HECTOR:
You dead, lawman?
I don't think so.
Neither was the fat man
at the foster home.
When he woke up, I warned him
to stop stealing our children.
I did not kill anyone.
- Where are the boys, Hector?
- I had a vision.
Of Cheyenne children returned
to their rightful home.
- What about the social worker?
- Stop looking for the innocent, lawman.
And find the bad.
[GRUNTS]
You know, Hector,
I can't just let you walk out that door.
[SCOFFS]
This is you stopping me?
That's what this is.
[GRUNTS]
[SNORING]
Dad. Look, I...
- What the hell happened to you?
- I won. I think.
- Did that man do this to you?
- Hector. Yup.
That's Hector?
Is he this dog-soldier guy?
Hector's taller.
- Did he have the boys?
- No.
Well, I worked all night looking
at the missing kids' files.
And each case was initiated by a call.
Someone reporting neglect or abuse.
But, Dad, the weird thing is that...
...when I tried to contact
all of these concerned callers...
...they all turned out
to be the same man.
And he lives on the res.
- Really?
- Yeah.
What'd he have to say?
Well, nothing, now,
because he's in the hospital.
Unconscious.
He was admitted two days ago.
And his wife says
that he took a bad fall.
But the doctors are pretty sure
that he was beaten.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Uh, Henry. On line one.
- I found Hector.
HENRY: Good.
But I have something better.
Come alone. I just closed for the day.
They were here when I
arrived this morning. In my office.
Back door was wide open.
- Who brought them in?
- Ask them.
Hello, boys. You doing okay?
A lot of people gonna be very happy
to see you.
Um...
Can you tell me who took you?
The dog soldier.
Let me guess.
He took you at midnight,
as the myth goes.
No, it was after bed-check,
which is at 10 p.m.
Are you calling Family Services,
or can they go back to their real families?
By law, I should call Family Services.
But?
Just because it's lawful
don't make it right.
This, we know.
I look at my friend's face
and I want to know what happened.
Hector used his one phone call.
You'll never guess to who.
NIGHTHORSE: Morning, sheriff.
- Hello, Jacob.
This man's being held
without being charged with a crime.
Objection. Look at his face.
NIGHTHORSE: Hector has been
in custody for eight hours.
You have to charge him or let him go.
Actually, Jacob, I have 24 hours
before I have to charge him.
- Ask your lawyer.
- If you're holding Hector for kidnapping...
...you have no evidence
to charge him with.
Really, how do you know that?
Because if you had any evidence,
you would have charged him already.
And if those children turn up healthy
and unharmed...
...not only will you be forced
to release Hector...
...but you could be subject to a civil
suit. You could be charged. You could...
- You're not even listening to me.
- What? No.
Not really.
But you've convinced me.
Release the prisoner.
- Excuse me?
- Walt. What are you doing?
I had a vision.
A vision of empty pockets.
Hector's a hired gun.
He only works for pay.
These boys' families, they could never
afford to pay Hector, could they?
That is a good point.
Someone else must have paid him.
Someone with a lot of money.
Interesting. Just a shame that visions
never hold up in your courts.
Hector.
This is me letting you go.
VIC:
I'm sorry, but I'm concerned.
- Did you get a concussion last night?
- Nope. I'm fine.
Then why else
would you let our prime suspect go?
The boys were returned to the Red Pony
while Hector was in custody.
By who?
They all claim the dog soldier took them
and brought them back.
- Okay, what about murder?
- And attempted murder?
Not to mention the beating
that Hector gave you.
WALT: Sometimes the best way
to catch the killer...
...is to make them think they're free.
I know who's responsible
for the murder of Ryan Shank...
...and the threat on your life.
But I can't prosecute
without your help.
So...
- This the man who threatened you?
- Yes.
His name is Hector.
He's a Cheyenne mercenary.
Pretty scary guy.
He did this to me.
Don't worry. I brought him
into custody late last night.
- Oh. That's good to hear.
- Released him a few hours ago.
What?
He tried to kill me.
And you said he killed Ryan.
I thought so.
I know on the night of the kidnapping...
...he assaulted Ryan, took the boys
around 10 p.m...
...right after their last bed-check.
Here's what's confusing.
Ryan made a phone call at 10:34,
alive and well.
He called you.
- I told you we talked that night.
- Ryan had just been assaulted.
The boys had been kidnapped.
Why call you? Why not my deputy?
I don't know.
He called to tell you
someone had discovered your scam.
You take Cheyenne kids
from their families...
...place them in Shank's group home,
collect the federal money.
I don't get any extra pay
for reservation children.
Not up front.
Shank took the extra federal money
and split it with you.
All those children
are in better hands now.
I was following up on reports
of abuse or neglect.
All those reports of neglect or abuse
were made by one man.
He was your plant.
He'd call in some fake complaints
for you in exchange for a little money.
You stole all these children
from their homes.
I do whatever I have to do
to protect children from neglect.
I'm betting you'd do whatever
you have to do to protect yourself.
I think you saw Ryan Shank
after he called you.
I bet he was scared
after seeing Hector.
I bet he wanted to come clean.
But you weren't ready
to turn yourself in.
So you ran him over, repeatedly.
The next night, you drove yourself
into a tree...
...to cover up the damage to your car.
Shank had described the big,
scary Indian with the scar to you.
So you knew exactly what to tell me
to frame Hector.
I've devoted my entire life
to helping children.
That's certainly what
a Wyoming jury will see.
They'll see an articulate,
compassionate...
...white social worker accused
with circumstantial evidence.
You're right.
They won't see the cynical, burned-out
sociopath who's just out for herself.
You'll walk free.
Legally it's the perfect crime.
But there's something
you're forgetting.
Hector.
He knows about your scam, Crystal.
Also knows you tried
to frame him for murder.
Right. He'll make a great witness.
The scar-faced Indian
who kidnapped those boys.
The boys said it wasn't him.
They say a dog soldier abducted them.
The Cheyenne believe
an avenging warrior spirit...
...can take on any form.
Animal, human.
- And you believe that?
- I believe in transformation.
I believe we become vessels...
...for forces
we cannot control or understand.
When you drove over Ryan Shank...
...maybe it was the spirit
of the dog soldier that guided you.
Perhaps that spirit guided me,
once upon a time, as well.
So congratulations.
Without your confession,
we have no case against you.
But the dog soldier knows
what you've done, Crystal.
And when he comes for you,
I'm just a phone call...
...and a 20-minute drive away.
I'll come as fast as I can.
[English - US - SDH]