A man-child.
- Look, look!
- Gather round.
He is a man-child.
He shall be called Osceola.
Get to your homes.
- No, l must be with you.
- No, go.
What is this place?
We are Seminole.
This is our home.
We run bunches just like this one
out of Florida.
Before the war.
Half-breed trash, colonel.
Filthy mix of outlaw lndians
and runaway slaves.
You know what to do, captain.
Yes, sir. Company dismount!
- Dismount!
- Take food and supplies.
l respect no man's law but my own.
You can beg your Yankee
carpetbagger government...
... for compensation.
And you tell them...
... the ghosts of the Confederacy
will not die.
You wanna mess with me?
Your orders were to take food
and supplies. Nothing more.
Well...
... l'll be damned.
Hey, what do you got?
Give me that.
Oh, it ain't nothing
but a bunch of dirt!
Colonel!
Look what l found!
ls that what l think it is, sir?
This is the face of our new land.
Gold.
The ancient alchemist thought
he could turn lead into gold...
... but l know l can turn gold
into bullets.
Fire!
- Reload.
- Reload!
l would appreciate knowing
where your gold is coming from.
- There is no more.
- No.
Of course there isn't. l guess
we need another demonstration.
Swing it around.
l'm afraid l must insist on an answer.
We have no more gold.
- Carry on.
- No, wait.
Colonel, what if this man
is telling the truth?
lf we had money for arms...
... there are thousands living
under the heels of the Yankees...
... who would be willing to join us.
Stand aside, captain.
We will find the gold.
There's a mine!
There's a mine in the hills!
Get the men ready.
All right, men. Mount up!
Mount up!
We will return in seven days.
And that hole will be filled with gold...
... or we will fill it with your blood.
Company!
- Move out!
What we going do? There's no gold.
The mines, they collapse years ago.
Would he have believed that?
We got few warriors, no guns.
Now we gonna have to leave
before they come back.
Where will we go?
This is now our home.
We must get help.
We cannot go on running.
No. We must stay and fight.
Let me go!
What are you doing?
Town always this lively?
Trail herd from Texas.
All liquored up.
Got in the mood for a lynch.
Where's the law?
Marshal and his deputy.
That isnt even his horse.
Stop right there.
Step aside, lady.
We don't hang men around here
for no reason.
He killed a good man. Said he was
a doctor, but he let him die.
l never said l was no doctor!
Nathan didn't kill your boss.
Gangrene did.
You ought to be thankful
we're getting rid of this quack.
Ain't no darkie doctors.
And there never will be.
You're not hanging that man.
l said, get out of my way!
We're late for a funeral, boys!
Get this wagon moving!
Are you people
just gonna let this happen?
You walk off with that rifle
and you're fired.
Hell, l'm probably gonna
get myself killed.
Now l gotta worry about
a new job too.
Hey, mister! Where are we?
You get your damn head back in there
if you know whats good for you!
- Hey, this ain't your stop.
- lt is now.
This is why l came west.
Figure you'd like to watch
your killer swing, Mr. Fallon.
What the hell do you want?
Cut him loose.
Reckon y'all would be happier
if you just rode away.
Not a chance, boys.
Shot a lot of holes
in the clouds back there.
Anybody stop to reload?
l got him.
l got him! l got him!
You don't shoot nobody in the back.
- Name's Chris.
- Vin Tanner.
- New in town?
- Yesterday. You?
Last week.
Buffalo hunter?
Among other things.
Not many left to hunt.
One of y'all wanna pull the knife
out that fellow? Cut me loose here?
Gentlemen, l run the Clarion News.
Where did you come from?
Saloon.
Hey, l wanna talk to you.
Where are you going?
- Saloon.
- The sight's a little off.
- You can keep it.
You know them, Virgil?
Don't you recognize that stranger?
The one in black?
Chris Larabee.
Whiskey.
One for the doc here.
Like the man said,
ain't no darkie doctors.
l was a stretcher bearer
in the Union Army.
Picked up what l could
in the field hospital.
We wanna hire you.
Thirty-five dollars, give or take.
This may not seem like much to you,
but it's all that we have.
How many of these ghosts
are there?
Would 20 men scare you?
Hell, l was making $5 a week
at the hardware store...
... without anybody shooting at me.
Assuming you pay $5 a head,
that gets us all of seven men.
The Seminoles risked their lives
for many an escaped slave.
They took us in
when nobody else would.
For $5, they can have
a week of my life.
Or all of it.
Hell, l wasn't planning on dying
with a broom in my hand anyway.
All right. Tomorrow afternoon, then.
- We cannot put our trust in them.
- l don't.
lf they're asking for help from
the white man, they're desperate.
But how are we gonna find
hired guns for $5?
l think l know a man who can help.
l know one too.
lf we can get him out of bed.
Hey, you in there with my wife?
Lord, it's gotta be my Billy.
l thought he was in Yuma prison.
Oh, he is. He was.
Just a minute, hon.
l hear you in there! Open this door!
l gotta go.
Someone's gonna get you,
you rabbit.
Sorry, ma'am. Wrong room.
Afternoon, Buck.
lnterrupt something?
Chris. Hey, you old war dog!
Good to see you, buddy.
Easy, big fella. Folks will talk.
l got a job. You interested?
Yeah. What's it pay?
- Five dollars.
- A day?
l know it ain't much.
- How are the odds?
- Three, 4-1.
Just our kind of fight.
How did you know l was here?
l make a point of knowing
who's in town. Live longer that way.
You with us?
ls he with you?
There gonna be ladies there?
l imagine so.
Then imagine l'm in.
He says he's not coming.
He says that's his penance.
- For what?
- He won't say.
Word is, he done killed a lot of men.
He's a hard man to persuade.
Could be useful in a fight.
The Seminoles are the dispossessed
of the Earth, Josiah.
Ain't saving lives
a part of saving souls?
Seems to me, a man ought to
put his own house in order first.
We can promise you a hell of a fight.
Hell?
Already been there.
- Think he'll change his mind?
- Maybe. We could ride by tomorrow.
Dead center.
Let's see you beat that.
Stand aside, sir.
You are obstructing my view.
This should be a piece of cake.
- Pay up.
- Nonsense.
l was encumbered by the debris
on the floor.
- Then let's just try it again.
- Pleasure.
Double or nothing.
lt's your money.
Get ready to duck, boys.
He put all six in the same hole.
My, my. How astonishing.
l've never done that before.
You sure sobered up quickly, mister.
Must be the desert air.
We don't take kindly
to being hustled.
Let's see how good you can shoot
with one eye.
Sorry for the mess.
You only got one shot left
in that pop gun.
Well, then, you'd best discuss
amongst yourselves...
... which one of you is going to die.
- Nice shot, pard.
- Dreadful.
l was aiming to kill him,
but the mirror was cracked.
The first shot was louder
than the other five.
What are you attempting
to suggest?
The first bullet was real.
The rest were blanks.
Well, sir...
... l abhor gambling, and as such,
leave nothing to chance.
We're looking for guns to protect
an lndian village. You interested?
Who's financing?
The village. Five dollars a man.
Five dollars?
Wouldn't even pay for my bullets.
Would he be riding with you?
Not interested.
Reckon you should
be leaving town anyway.
l'll sleep on it.
Meet us at the livery at dawn.
lf you live that long.
Why would we wanna use
a cheater?
Might need one.
Fewer ways to split that huge pot.
Looks like you gotta shoot straight
for once, old pard.
l hear you fellas
are headed for a fight.
My name is J. D. Dunne
and l can ride.
And l can shoot.
And he can fly.
And he can swim too.
You! Why didn't you grab
my damn horse?
Real funny. Nice jacket.
- You made it.
- Hell, l couldn't stay away.
Not once l saw l'd be riding
with a genuine celebrity.
''The streets ran red
with the blood of 20 men yesterday...
... as new resident and notorious
gunslinger, Chris Larabee...
... turned our quiet town
into a shooting gallery. ''
l see you've read it.
As l recall, your quiet town
was full of drunken scum...
... looking to lynch a man.
lf l have to bend the facts a little
to keep our town safe...
... and if the next bunch of
drunken scum decides to steer clear...
... then it was worth
another black mark...
... on your already less-than-stellar
reputation, Mr. Larabee.
You see, l took the liberty
of researching your past...
... in my late husband's files.
You read secondhand trash
and you think you know a man.
You don't know me.
l'm just trying to scare
the bad element away from this town.
Lady, l am the bad element.
Why'd you change your mind?
- The crows.
- What crows?
A sign.
What does that mean?
Death.
- Whose?
- Probably mine.
Well, well, a sense of humor.
l look forward
to many lively conversations.
What about all this?
These stones will still be here
if l get back.
- We can use another good man.
- l'm not so good. But l can fight.
One...
... two, three...
... four, five... .
Six. lf you're trying to stay hid,
it's best to remove your hat.
Welcome.
We greet you with hostility.
l think he means hospitality.
Nope. l think he means hostility.
Some of our people find it impossible
to trust white men.
- And you?
- Not impossible.
Just difficult.
You never told us
they had a cannon.
You didn't ask.
Hey, boys!
Look what l found.
Come on.
l was covering you.
Making sure you weren't
walking into an ambush.
- How did you get here ahead of us?
- l told you, l can ride.
l cut around the canyon rim.
Well, l suggest you ride back
the same way.
l can help.
- Give me a chance, l'm ready.
- You think you're ready?
Let me guess.
You learned to ride in prep school.
Then you read some dime-store novel
about Kit Carson...
... that got you all fired up.
Figured you'd come out west,
try your hand as a gunfighter.
That about right?
Go home.
You're not the type.
A man comes to you
because he respects you.
Because he'd be proud to work
with you. This is how you treat him?
Go home, kid.
He is young and proud.
Carve that on his tombstone.
l'm an expert at prayers
for the dying.
l like this guy.
Lord help me, l like him.
l'm in this for the laughs,
if nothing else.
Let's get started. We got four days.
Less.
He is an old warrior.
He will come early to surprise us.
His main force
rode straight into the village.
Then he left some men back here.
He's a trained soldier.
He'll probably repeat himself.
Then we should take
the high ground.
Yeah.
lf we can force him through
this chokehold, we'll have him.
Set that hay over there.
We may not have guns...
... but we have our ways of fighting.
Anderson will provide the guns.
You ever fired one of these before,
Eban?
They don't give guns to slaves.
Well, you're not a slave anymore.
Okay.
Now take aim at that target.
Now, bring it back a bit. Right there.
Rest your elbow. Right there.
Okay. Now take aim at the target...
... and squeeze that trigger gently.
She kicks like a mule, doesn't she?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- All right, who wants to go next?
- No!
l can do this.
- Ezra, look.
- Well done, my little craftsmen.
But there is plenty more to do.
- But you said--
- Of course, a deal's a deal.
Gather round.
l did say, if you work,
l'll show you tricks.
Pull it tightly against your shoulder.
You got it?
Squeeze the trigger.
Still doing your penance, Josiah?
Well, how high you going up?
High enough to make a sensible horse
think twice about jumping.
Collecting firewood, my friend?
We got a battle coming.
l'm boiling us some water.
Gonna be plenty men wounded here.
And dead.
All right, children.
Let's see what we have wrought.
Spectacular.
You've all earned another trick.
Gather round. Gather round.
lf my lovely assistant
would pass me my blindfold, please.
Thank you very much.
This one is called, ''Aces High. ''
Prepare to be amazed.
Problem is, you didn't have the gun
pulled tightly against your shoulder.
To find the mystical ace of spades...
... one must become sensitized
to its vibration.
Now, of course, l will expect you to
applaud as l have taught you.
For, when one is sensitized...
... one can better ascertain
its location.
Thank you.
Nothing at all, l assure you.
Come on out of there, now.
You don't want me
coming in after you.
Cut me down.
My father told us they hired
white men to protect our village.
Cut me down now.
They sent us here because
these men could not be trusted.
That was probably
real smart of him.
You a slave?
Long time ago.
Then you are one of us.
Many runaways
sought refuge with our tribe.
Now we are one people.
Now we gonna cut me down?
You are strong.
You have a woman?
No, ma'am.
Opa-Locka is looking for a husband.
That's real sweet, ma'am...
... but can y'all please
cut me down here, please?
The wind blew, the clouds parted
and out came the sun.
l knew you wouldn't let me down,
you old dog.
Well, what do we have here?
Found them up at that canyon.
Actually, they sort of found me.
What y'all doing down here?
Didn't l tell y'all to stay hid?
ls this not our village too?
Why should we hide
while our grandfathers defend us?
l say we let them stay.
You touch my daughter,
l promise l'll kill you.
Which one is your daughter?
No harm will come to your women.
Let them stay, Tennessee.
Well, the hat is a marvelous touch.
Howdy, how you doing today?
You new in the village?
You look beautiful,
l gotta tell you right now.
Have you met my friend here?
My name's Buck, by the way.
Hard to get out.
There we go.
Excuse me.
Ladies.
For the bandages.
Who are you?
Nobody you need to use
that pigsticker on.
- Why are you in my village?
- Hey, l'm one of the good guys.
You're wearing the wrong skin.
l got him!
You stupid son of a... .
You damn near shot me.
lmala, he has come back.
lmala.
Buck, let him go.
lmala. lmala. lmala, my son.
l thought you were dead.
l escaped from
the white man's prison.
Do you know why l was in prison?
For the crime of not being white.
And what do l find when l return?
These white men.
That's it!
What in the blue blazes
we doing here, then?
Risking our lives for a chunk of gold
that wouldn't even fill a tooth.
And why would l die for you?
lmala.
Your son.
He is called Osceola,
for the spirit of his father.
He'd be dead right now,
if it weren't for me.
- You damn near shot my ear off.
- But l didn't, did l?
l saved your life. Twice.
- Twice.
- You think l couldn't handle him?
Don't use the butt of your gun
as a weapon.
You keep smacking it around like that,
before long it's gonna misfire.
And another thing,
get rid of this damn stupid hat.
What Buck means is, ''thanks, '' kid.
- l just wanna prove to you that l can--
- Save it.
lf you wanna die young, stay.
Yes!
This guy's crazy.
There's a little backwater town
up in the Texas panhandle. Tascosa.
Flatter than
a felt-covered poker table.
You know it?
- Heard of it.
- lf l wind up getting killed...
... take my body back there.
You'll get 500 for it.
How come you're so valuable?
Well...
... when the buffalo done run out,
l became a bounty hunter.
l was going after Eli Joe...
... a bandit who had
shot up a few banks.
Two-hundred-dollar reward,
alive or dead.
l found him dead.
Took the body in.
Except it wasn't him.
Old Eli had framed me up
for murder.
Since l didn't do it, l decided not
to stick around for the hanging.
Wound up with a hefty bounty
on my own head.
So l figure, if a friend collects,
l get the last laugh.
Why'd you sign on, Josiah?
What is it you expect to gain?
Saw the birds of darkness
in a dream.
When l woke up, a crow
was sitting on my windowsill.
Staring at me like the devil himself.
Why come here?
lf death's coming...
... l'd just as soon meet it head-on.
Gonna get your reward
in the hereafter?
No.
No, l was a... .
l was a priest once.
But l had a little trouble
turning the other cheek.
l did a turn
preaching the word myself.
- ls that right?
- Best swindle l ever knew.
Just stand up there under that tent...
... terrify the congregation
with a vision of hellfire...
... and pass the collection plate.
Yeah.
Did fine too. Until l attempted to save
the soul of the mayor's daughter.
Yep.
Saving souls has its hazards.
Time's up.
Everybody, take your positions!
l thought you said there were 20.
No, l asked if 20 would scare you.
Twenty, no. Forty, yes.
Sand.
My instructions could not
have been more explicit.
You were very explicit, colonel.
And yet for some reason,
they were not carried out.
l have shot my own men for less!
Colonel Emmett Riley Anderson
of the Confederate States of America.
And you are... ?
There's no gold here, colonel.
No, of course there isn't.
You're here for your health.
Or the company perhaps?
We came to ask you to leave.
And purely out of the goodness
of your hearts.
Yep. Something like that.
Well...
... how many of you
humanitarians are there?
Enough.
What do you say, captain?
You think there's gonna be trouble?
No trouble, colonel.
Just turn around and ride out.
l like that.
Audacity.
Move on, colonel.
These people have nothing you want.
Shoot them down, captain.
Company.
Fire!
Now.
Come on, pull!
Watch it, over there.
Thattaboy, thattaboy, fire!
- Stand and fight, damn you!
- For God's sake, colonel!
We're almost gone, colonel, let's go.
Damn it all to hell. Sound retreat!
Come on!
Retreat!
Now!
Come on!
Oh, God.
Ride on, colonel. Ride on.
We have won.
You people fought well.
- We fight well together.
- We whipped them good, old pard.
Buck, get up on that ridge,
keep a lookout.
Hell, they won't stop running
till they hit the Rio Grande.
- l'll take first watch.
- All right.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Oh, it's not my blood.
Damn lucky it isn't your blood, son.
Now, you don't fan your guns.
That spoils your aim.
One good shot is better
than six bad ones.
Anything else?
No, that's about it for now.
l prefer to use it for healing.
Keep pressure on that.
Let me see that arm.
lt's fine. l just bruised it when l fell.
No, no, no. That ain't no bruise, now.
Let me see.
l said, it's fine.
Suit yourself.
Just like l thought, you dislocated it.
lt'll be sore for a while...
... but you still have
two hands to cheat with.
Rest easy, friend.
- Not good.
- Whoever your god is...
... you can go to him in peace.
Leave him.
We don't believe in your
white man's religion.
Nor do l, my friend.
He been hit.
Look like the bullet
went clean through.
But he lost a lot of blood.
Why didn't you tell us
you were hurt?
You didn't ask.
Your birds lied, Josiah.
We shall see.
ls he all right?
Wasn't like them dime-store novels,
was it?
l didn't count on seeing their eyes.
Well, if you can see their eyes,
then you're too close.
And you never break cover.
You stand in front of bullets,
you're likely to die.
You done, Buck?
- Slow down a little, son.
- What gives you the right...
... to tell me what to do?
He had a son once.
Never had a chance
to see him grow up, though.
He lost that boy...
... and his wife...
... in a fire.
And that burned half the soul
out of that man.
Josiah, you still with us?
Scoot on over there, Buck.
l'm a spiritual man.
Sometimes l turn to
the wrong kinds of spirits.
Your fate is in the cards,
gentlemen. Remember that.
What's my fate?
You shall grow to be a great warrior.
- Big, strong and fearless.
- Like you.
There are two kinds of people
in this life, my friend.
Those who seek battle
and seem not to fear death...
... like them.
And those who avoid battle,
but will stand and fight to the death...
... if their loved ones are threatened.
Like them.
That is true courage.
Now, you have lost to me at poker
and l have read the cards for you.
The time has come to pay.
You see...
... l've heard tell of a gold mine
in these parts.
We're not to speak of it.
Well, good.
Then it is a valuable secret.
One such secret
could wipe out all your debts.
So...
... let's talk about this mine...
... shall we?
- He's beautiful.
- Yeah.
l've had many children.
l've outlived most of them.
Now, all of these are my children.
Home, family...
... things worth fighting for.
El Dorado.
- What's cooking?
- Chili and beans.
Well, we'll be back in two hours.
- lt'll be ready.
- Who's on watch?
- Ezra replaced me a couple hours ago.
- All right.
This must have caved in years ago.
Right, we'll take a wider arc across
the plain. Make sure they're gone.
What the hell is that?
lt's the cannon.
Fire!
Bring it around. Reload.
Move it!
Ready. Fire!
Few more rounds,
they'll have the range.
Lower the damn elevation.
Come on.
Fire!
Colonel, that village
has no fortifications.
We're wasting powder and shot.
Waste?
Men who survived the battles
at Shiloh and Bull Run...
... the finest sons of the South.
And they die here?
l'll wipe this place
from the face of the earth.
l'll fire rocks if l have to.
- Fire!
- Ready, fire!
Reload!
Everybody, into the bluffs.
That cannon will tear
these adobes apart.
Ready!
Come with me. Come on.
Go! There! Leave it! Leave it!
Fire!
Father?
Oh, God, not my dad.
Oh, my God.
We got to go!
- We got to go, Rain!
- Why?!
Come on.
Down! Down! Everyone, down!
- What the hell happened to Ezra?
- l don't know.
Reload!
Fire!
We got to get them out of here!
Come on. Come on.
Then there's a third kind.
Fire!
Go.
We got two options.
We can ride up after that gun--
- That's no option. That's suicide.
- Or? What's the other option?
We raise a white flag.
Reload!
Or three, we can mount up
and we can ride the hell out of here.
Go, then. But with my last breath,
l will fight these men.
Them Rebs up there.
That makes it my fight.
l'm not going.
l haven't shot anyone yet.
They'll see us coming up that trail
before we get five paces.
And that gun is gonna
cut us to pieces.
There's gotta be a way up there.
There is. We can climb.
You remember why we're doing this?
- Does it make any difference?
- Guess not.
My hands are shaking so bad, Buck.
l can barely hang on.
- Good.
- Good?
Yeah, good.
Means your juices are flowing.
Fear keeps you sharp, kid.
- Buck?
- Yeah.
You are full of crap.
Just figuring that out now?
Come.
l didn't go to West Point.
l'm really just a sergeant.
Well, you're a captain now,
so speak up.
l think we should save ammunition
and give them a chance to surrender.
Fire!
Well, thank you
for your advice, captain.
You keep firing.
And hired killers, captain.
Not soldiers.
You may
be underestimating them, sir.
Keep firing.
Fire!
Surrender or die where you stand.
l'll take that $5 now.
One battle don't win the war, boys.
Chain them up, Sergeant Darcy.
Make them nice and tight, boys.
l was there, in Shiloh, captain.
l know you were at Shiloh, colonel.
Union lines had broken.
They were in full retreat.
There was no way
they could counterattack.
But they did.
Our surviving officers
were herded up like cattle.
Forced to watch
as they raised their Union flag.
Then they fired off that cannon.
And we were all left for dead.
l lay there amongst that carnage...
... surrounded by the bodies
of my dead brothers.
Well...
... we gonna raise the Stars and Bars
over that little village.
l want it to be the last thing
these boys ever see.
All right, now,
let's get some muscle behind it!
Move it up over that flat now.
How do you like
the Wild West now, kid?
You all think you got me pegged,
don't you, Buck?
A rich kid, had it all.
Yeah, l lived in a mansion.
My mother was a maid.
Never knew my father.
They made me a stable boy
and l taught myself how to ride.
Mama died last year.
She'd saved a little money,
wanted me to go to college.
lt wasn't enough.
Life's tough, huh?
And then you die.
Mind not leaning against my bad leg?
Are you ordering all these prisoners
to be executed, sir?
That is correct.
But, colonel,
these men surrendered.
Then we shall reward them
with a quick and merciful death.
They shall not be made to suffer,
as l was.
That's murder, sir.
Are you refusing my order,
Corcoran?
Colonel.
Colonel, we've been riding together
for a long, long time, you and l.
Your orders have saved my life
more times than l can remember.
- But this time... .
- Yes?
l can't do it, sir.
- But that's treason.
- Treason?
Treason against what?
The war is over, sir.
Darcy!
You disappoint me, Francis.
Sir?
This man is stripped
of rank and privilege.
You're hereby promoted to captain.
Place the mutineer
among the other prisoners...
... and execute them all.
All, sir?
l think l made myself clear,
Captain Darcy.
When our flag reaches the top
of the staff, execute the prisoners.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. Private.
How about it, Johnny Reb?
l bet you never thought your boss
would go loco on you.
l'll have you know, Colonel Anderson
was one of the finest soldiers...
... in any man's army.
l owe my life to him.
And soon your death.
Captain, l gotta go get rid
of some of this coffee.
Set up the flagpole over there.
Well...
... l hear the clank of gold bars
and the roar of the guns...
... as we hit back at the Yankees.
Here's what we gonna do now.
We gonna have us a little
flag-raising ceremony.
Then we gonna execute us
some prisoners with our little cannon.
Then you gonna show me
where that mine is.
There is no gold in that mine.
Oh, no, of course not.
You gonna show me, old man.
About time.
l wouldn't wanna miss this.
Nobody move or he's dead.
l leave you boys alone for five minutes
and look what happens.
You'll only get one shot off
before we take you.
Then you'd best
discuss amongst yourselves...
... which one of you is going to die.
Pick him yourself.
Well...
... then l guess l'll just have to take
all of us.
Why, that powder keg's empty,
mister.
Drop it.
Raise the colors.
Big mistake, sonny boy.
You shouldn't have tried that.
l know. l can't imagine
what came over me.
You're outnumbered 3-1.
Anderson's a mad dog.
You'll all die.
We know what to do with a mad dog.
Don't ever run out on me again.
Take me with you.
l know him. l know him.
l know his methods.
l'll kill him.
Give me that glass, soldier.
What the hell?
- Troop B.
- Yes, sir?
Check out that cannon.
- Come on, now.
- Come on.
Come on.
Let's finish this.
All right, you men
take the high ground.
Man the approaches.
Drop your guns...
... or join your friends.
Much obliged.
Show yourselves, damn it.
Show yourselves.
Show yourself.
Come on, let's go.
Troop C, run them down.
Watch it over there.
He's up there! He's up there!
Get down, get down, get down!
Get Anderson.
No matter what, get Anderson!
Come on!
l can't hit him.
- Show them what you're made of.
- Come on!
Bastard won't go down.
You can't kill me.
l'm a ghost of the Confederacy
and l will not die.
He's so full of laudanum,
you could chop his head off...
- ... and he wouldn't feel it.
- Well, he'll feel this!
Finish it!
Sir.
This has to stop, sir.
Francis...
... you were like a son to me.
Don't make me do this, sir.
My God.
You're a coward.
The war's over.
Go back to your families.
He's dead.
lt's finished now.
Hey, pard.
We got him.
We did.
- Buck.
- Hey, kid...
... do me a favor.
Get yourself a real hat.
Never did get to spend any time
with those fine ladies.
You will. But first let's get you
stitched up, Buck.
lt's lmala's.
You fought with him.
Not against him.
Where you headed?
- Tascosa.
- Tascosa? Why?
Never know how much time there'll be
to set things right.
They got a saloon there?
l reckon.
Leaving?
Yes.
Never could figure out
how to split it seven ways.
Use it again.
Next time you're threatened.
Oh, the next time we will welcome
our enemies with great hospitality.
- l think you mean hostility.
- No, hospitality.
l will even open the doors
of my home to them.
That'll do it.
You will always be welcome
in our village.
My friend.
Hey, kid. lf you're not
gonna wear that hat...
- ... then l'll take it back.
- Buck.
You look awful.
Well, son,
that's damn near impossible.
You riding with us?
Try and keep me away.
Don't make me laugh, kid.
Ezra, can l come?
A brave warrior like you?
You gotta stay
and protect the village.
You remember what l taught you?
Never draw to an inside straight.
What about you, Mr. Jackson?
You willing to ride
with an old Southern boy?
l figured l'd stick around for a while.
Help these folks get things right.
You shoot a cannon
pretty well, pard.
Dreadful.
l was trying to hit Anderson.
Where you going?
Get down off that horse.
You lost too much blood, now.
You gonna die out there.
lf that's what's meant to be.
Your birds will get you soon enough.
You don't have to go chasing them.
You're a good man, Nathan.
Go.