Equipe Oldies
proudly presents:
THE WILD WEST - S01E01
"THE NIGHT OF THE INFERNO"
Gid' up, now, you!
Come on!
You got somebody important
coming in, Lieutenant?
I wouldn't know.
It must be an important fellow
to get all this.
I wouldn't know!
You wouldn't know,
now, would you.
Hey, do you know...
Hey, watch that jug.
People around here
don't know nothing.
Evenin'.
Well, what's your big secret?
You got a dead body coming?
You might call it that.
Yeah? Who is it?
Prisoner coming in on the train
is Captain James T. West.
That name mean anything to you?
Nope.
He's a renegade,
deserted the army.
And, the army catched him
and killed him?
No, he ain't dead yet.
But he's sure going to be...
right after they hang him.
Move!
You know what they're going
to do to you, mister?
Hey, how about them boots?
You ain't going
to be needing them no more.
Open.
Follow me.
Sir,
this is the man
we call Jim West.
Good morning, President Grant.
It's good to see you, West.
I'm sorry we had
to rough you up a little.
It's all right, sir.
It was an effective cover.
Good...
because we need you again.
You're the finest underground
intelligence officer we have,
and I'm going to lay it right
on the line with you, boy.
This nation's
in a pot of trouble.
Inflation eating
the South alive.
Washington...
Washington crawling
with carpetbaggers,
jackals just gathering
for the kill.
And now...
...now new trouble.
Colonel Shear will brief you.
Southwest Territory,
Santa Fe.
Sangre de Cristos.
The Adelanto Valley.
It's a good 2,500 miles.
We're going to get you there
right away.
How?
Well, we brought you
back to Washington
disguised as a deserter headed
for the gallows.
So I leave in a pine box?
Nothing like that, Jim.
We're taking you out of the
capital in the grand manner
to which you have
become accustomed.
- The train.
- Right.
You're posing as the dandiest dude
that ever crossed the Mississippi
in his private railroad car.
You're going to give me
the train?
Now, let's say
it's a long-term government loan,
but as far as the outside world
is concerned,
it's the sole property
of Jim West,
big spender from the East.
You know, Colonel,
I like the sound of that.
About six months ago,
a series of guerrilla raids
broke out in this area here.
Now, this is new territory
we can hardly hold by a thread.
The guerrillas are organized,
methodical, ruthless.
But you can't send
the army in.
That's true, Jim...
Now, that would
precipitate a war,
but an undercover man
might be able to get in there.
A fancy dude with, um...
a private car?
That's right, Jim.
Now, there's a certain pattern
to these raids,
starting here, then
here, then here,
like the spokes
on a wheel.
And the hub of that wheel
is a town called Quemada.
Quemada?
Who's leading the guerrillas?
A vicious, sadistic, very
clever predatory beast
named Juan Manolo.
Don't leave anyone alive!
Let nobody live in this town!
Yeah, that's right,
burn their houses!
They will remember Manolo!
Yes, they will, yes, they will!
Hey, how about them boots?
You still got them boots?
Funny, Artie,
real funny.
Well, I got
a little bit carried away.
I got word to put myself,
the wagon and your horse
on a freight get out here,
and you'd brief me.
Now, what is
it this time?
Not it he...
Juan Manolo.
Ever hear of him?
Yeah, the name
gets bandied about
at funerals and such.
How about a town
called Quemada?
That's where they
usually hold the funerals.
Manolo sent word to the settlers
to leave in a week.
They didn't, so he sent his men in,
burned them out, hit and run.
They got the message.
They're leaving.
What's his hurry?
He's moving guns and supplies
out to his men
the day after tomorrow.
He's planning a revolution.
Now there are enough arms in
Quemada to start a war, a big war,
and we could lose most
of our western territories.
What's the job?
You find the supplies,
I find him
and bring him back to Washington
before the day after tomorrow.
And if you can't?
Then I'll have to kill him.
In Quemada?
I think I'll turn
this one down.
Artie, you can't
turn this one down.
You're under orders,
just like me.
Thank you, James.
Artie...
I wouldn't hit that one.
That's beautiful.
And this?
Not bad,
not bad at all,
but a gun barrel
would have been better.
The gun barrel's
in that one.
I'll never learn.
- We'll go in town separately.
- Fine.
Thanks.
Well, James...
Quemada's a bad place, James.
Watch yourself.
You, too, Artemus.
Bye, Henry, Henrietta.
There is a band of color
which begins at your shoulders
and progressively repeats itself
layer after layer.
It is infinitely varied
and infinitely beautiful.
Take what you will
from the shelves,
the prices of the merchandise
are marked.
Perhaps there is something
I want to buy.
Information.
Let us go in.
My office is
more comfortable.
Something?
You're the biggest Chinese
I've ever seen.
We are a remarkably
versatile race.
A terrible weakness.
Would you care for a pipe?
No, no,
no thank you.
It is filled with joy.
A comfort in the face of disaster.
What happened here?
Someone seems to
have paid us a visit.
A Juan Manolo, perhaps?
Perhaps.
And now, Mister...
West.
James West.
I have a proposition for Mr. Manolo
which I think might interest him.
Should it interest him,
there would be
a generous percentage for you.
That is, if you take me to him.
It is said that the owner
of the Casa Estrella,
our local palais de chance,
is a friend of Mr. Manolo's.
She might be able to arrange
a meeting if you were very...
persuasive.
She?
Miss Lydia Monteran.
You know her.
I've had the pleasure.
Fortunately, the Casa Estrella
was also undamaged
in the recent raid.
- Fortunately.
- Should the meeting be arranged,
please give this to Mr. Manolo
with my compliments.
Why don't you take me to him?
Unfortunately, Mr. West, I am a
coward as well as a philosopher.
I will be satisfied
with a generous percentage.
Miss Monteran is considered
extremely beautiful...
although, I must confess
that, to the Oriental eye,
all Occidental women
tend to look alike.
I shall be at
the Casa Estrella, Mei Mei.
- My... housekeeper.
- Of course.
¿Con permiso, señor.
Mr. West, do you by any chance
have a coin for this poor man?
Gracias, señor.
Mr. Wing.
Come in, come in, sir.
We're not expecting
any patrons today, Mr. Wing,
but the salon
is always open to you.
Thank you, Paul, thank you.
I would first appreciate a word
with the lady of the house.
Be seated, gentlemen.
I will see what I can do.
Gambling is a passion
with me,
any kind... of gambling.
Quite an establishment.
Watch the feather.
I am told that every stone
in this building
was brought here
by freight wagon from Mexico.
It used to stand
in the plaza in Mexico City.
This way, gentlemen.
- About that little game, Paul?
- I will arrange it, Mr. Wing.
This way, please.
Mr. Wing, how pleasant
to see you again.
Miss Monteran.
I understand you know my friend,
Mr. James West.
He has a favor to ask of you.
Your servant, Miss Monteran.
Poor Mr. Wing.
I'm afraid we're not open for
business today, but perhaps...
Paul is arranging a little game,
gracious lady.
If you will excuse me.
You're looking
well, Jim.
And you as magnificent
as ever.
You may go, Bedford.
- I've missed you.
- And I missed you...
at the station in New Orleans.
I waited on that hard bench
for hours all alone.
That is, until the police came.
And I'd hoped you'd
forgotten about that.
No, I haven't forgotten
about that.
$22,512
that's what that little affair
in New Orleans cost me.
But it wasn't
your money.
But it was... till you
made me give it back.
This a business call?
That's what I thought.
What do you want this time?
I want to meet Juan Manolo.
- I never heard of him.
- You sure?
You can have this money
if I meet him.
You know what I think?
I think you'd better
leave my house.
Your house?
Some people think
it's Juan Manolo's house.
I'm going to count to three.
Is that thing loaded?
- One...
- Give me that.
Two...
You wouldn't shoot me.
Just you try me.
Three.
Colonel Shear, what
are you doing here?
President Grant
is worried about you.
Things are worse ten times bigger
than we thought they were.
The President is offering you
a chance to quit now
if you want to.
Sorry, Colonel. I'm staying.
I'm getting closer to the jackal.
Besides, there's a girl involved.
She used to be a friend.
The odds are
against you, West.
That's your choice,
you're on your own.
One thing more,
we never met here.
Any luck?
They're too frightened
to talk.
I can't say that I blame them.
You find out anything?
No, I've been through
the remains of every...
burned-out barn
and warehouse in the area, nothing.
Freight wagons keep coming in
and... going out.
Come in where
and go out where?
Come in the main road
and go out the... cemetery.
In the main road
and go out the cemetery?
Right.
- I'll meet you in an hour.
- Where?
At the cemetery,
it's out behind Lydia's place.
Bring an extra horse
in case we have
- to make a run for it.
- Yeah, right.
Jim?
What are you doing?
Trying to find out
why freight wagons
are lighter after they pass
through the cemetery.
A lot of wagons are lighter
after they pass through a cemetery.
Yeah, I know, Artie,
but freight wagons shouldn't be.
Well, how do you
know these are?
Wheel tracks. They're deeper coming
in than going out.
You like this kind of work?
What are you looking for?
What are you
looking for now?
This.
There's oil
on these hinges.
See anyone you know?
Yeah, the one with
the blue eyes looks familiar.
Cozy little place,
isn't it?
Bring the lamp.
Whiskey, whiskey
everywhere?
Gunpowder.
Gunpowder, grenades.
Every barrel is loaded with them.
Artie, later.
Watch the feather.
This one's all mine.
Fine. I'll see you
at the wagon.
What are you doing here?
Where is he?
You know, all I have to do
is pull that cord...
And Juan Manolo appears
or maybe he doesn't appear.
Maybe he's
here already.
If he were, you wouldn't
live very long.
- Now, will you get out of here?
- No.
I warned you.
Lydia, you surprise me.
I knew you'd do a lot for money,
but I'd thought you'd
draw the line at murder.
What do you mean,
murder?
These innocent people,
the town you helped destroy.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You're a liar.
- Is there a Juan Manolo?
- Yes.
- Are you his partner?
- No.
Tell me why his supplies
are in your cellar
with your name on them.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
There's nothing in
my cellar but wine.
Tell me that when you see
his hidden munitions.
Are you going to walk
or do I drag you?
See? I told you,
nothing but wine.
Jim! Jim!
What...
Must be convenient to live
right above your own arsenal.
Now, tell me
you didn't know about this.
No, señor.
She didn't.
¿No entiende, amigo?
You don't understand?
This is a private wine cellar.
Private stock.
Perhaps you would like
a sample of this wine?
It's nice, rich
red wine.
You know, you have
a friend in this pueblo.
A most uncooperative man...
and very dead one.
Perhaps you will
be more cooperative
and tell us just what
it is you want here.
What are you going
to do with the girl?
When you talk,
I will decide!
When you decide, I'll talk.
You like some
more wine?!
Search him!
Something.
You have something else?
That's a good exchange, gringo...
weapons for wine.
Something else?
What do you have?
Something else? What is it...
What is this?
Look at what the gringo have.
All right,
loosen his tongue!
I regret this incident.
It was a pleasant diversion
from this serious business
of war, you know?
Move the queen three blocks
that way.
Good...
For that is what it is
going to be, American, war.
Not a revolution.
This territory was taken
by the Americans by force,
and I propose to take it back
the same way.
And when I am finished,
- I have plans.
- What plans?
What plans?
Big ones!
When I get through,
the whole world will know my name.
I will have the world
in the palm of my hand!
I will be number one!
You stand at attention
when I get up!
Good.
You come with me,
and you two remain
with our guest.
It will take me some time to decide
what is to be done with him.
Let the girl stay where she is.
She can wait...
until I decide
what is to be done with him.
It might be, poetic justice
to have a double execution.
You might as well
give up the game, señor.
I have you checkmated
in 14 moves.
- Jim?
- Lydia, I'm sorry for this.
Forget it.
How do we get out of here?
Where are the guards?
One's on the other
side of the room,
the other one's
on the steps.
Keep watching them.
Tell me if they move.
Are the guards
in the same place?
Come here.
- What's that?
- It's a smoke bomb.
Just stay right there.
Excuse me.
Downstairs, move!
Artie, the handcuffs
are in the cell.
I underestimated you,
Mr. West.
So you did.
I have men up there!
If you hurt me,
it will take you a week to die.
Yeah, sure,
sure, sure.
- Can you handle him?
- Yeah, I'm fine now.
Maybe I ought to throw
him in the pit
with some of his little friends.
He'd probably
poison them.
Hey, do you have to do that?
By some unhappy
coincidence,
every time I run into you
I lose something.
Last time it was money, now it's
the only house I ever owned.
Get him out of here.
Put him on a horse.
Move!
- Artie, take care of her.
- Right.
I got to get him out of here
before his friends come looking.
They will,
and when they do...
See you on the train.
Let's move.
In your country, this is
how you treat an officer?
You wanted the world?
Here.
Good evening, Mr. West.
Take these off.
In good time.
I want to...!
I've been expecting you,
Mr. Manolo.
Fascinating.
- How?
- The cards.
The one you gave me,
the one you sent him.
There was only one man
important enough to send for him
when he was... busy.
Perhaps an introduction
is in order.
Mr. James West, General Andreas
de la Torres Cassinello,
an ex-employee
of mine.
What do you mean?
I fear you have been
very stupid, General
very stupid, indeed
and you are
no longer useful
now that our little
masquerade has ended.
And see that the engine crew
is well taken care of.
It is true, I am Juan Manolo.
Or Huan Man-Lo, to use
the Mandarin pronunciation.
I fear the general
has fallen from the train.
- All right, sit down!
- You better do it, Kelly.
Mr. West, I must confess, I am
impressed with your ability.
For this reason I am reluctant
to remove you
before we conclude
the conversation
which you intended
to have with me originally.
I came to Quemada
to make a deal with you.
I still want to make that deal.
What did you intend
to get from me?
Partnership.
Not an equal partnership.
I just want 25%.
And what did you intend to give
for this share?
May I?
Make no sudden movement
of any kind.
This is just a sample.
I know where
there's $250,000 more,
and I'm prepared
to turn it over to you
on one condition.
You're hardly in a position
to make conditions.
I can make a condition about this.
If you want the money,
you do business on my terms
or not at all,
and I won't talk
in front of them.
We talk, we talk privately
or you can go ahead and kill me.
I find you very amusing,
Mr. West.
Wait on the platform.
When Mr. West's friend,
Mr. Gordon, arrives,
kill him.
And the girl.
It's all right, Joseph,
I am armed.
This is quite a useful
base of operations.
I will enjoy it
after you are gone.
A week after we sign
our partnership,
I'll deliver $250,000 to you.
If you kill me, you won't get it.
Now, you've lost your general.
You need a front man,
a second in command.
That's the job I want.
I'm a trained cavalry officer
with ten years of top experience.
Mr. West,
I admire you very much.
You are a true gambler.
Perhaps I should
wait a little
and see if you can deliver
what you say you can.
What about Gordon and the girl?
Sorry, they have already caused
me a great deal of difficulty,
and they must pay for that.
As must you, if you...
fail in your commitment.
Quite an ingenious
arrangement.
- And do you play?
- I enjoy it.
Do you bet when you play?
Always.
A terrible, terrible weakness.
You are very good indeed,
unless that was an accident.
- I'll make a bet with you.
- Have you anything left to risk?
I own the title to this car.
I'll sign it over to you if I lose.
If I win, you don't kill Gordon
and the girl.
Why do I need the title
to this car?
I could simply take it.
You might be able to take it,
but you couldn't use it.
Not on any railroad line
in the United States.
Without the title,
they won't let you on the track.
I will say this
for you, Mr. West
you have considerable style.
Shall we say a short game?
13 points.
My car against Gordon
and the girl.
Trouble.
How do you know?
The light at the end of the car
it isn't lit,
and it should be.
It's a signal.
Something wrong, Mr. West?
No.
Don't bother, Mr. West.
I concede.
I may miss.
You may.
But I won't.
Ahora... sabe usted
la verdad de mi, señor.
Why, Manolo? Why?
Our revolution
must spring unexpectedly.
Who would suspect
a Chinese merchant
of being a leader of armies
Like I said before, one would
suspect such a big Chinese.
So you did... so you did.
What about the girl?
What does she know about this?
Nothing.
She was permitted to operate
the gambling palace, no more.
And... so I die,
and an invasion dies with me.
For you, West, you get nothing.
You're a fool!
Well, let's say I'm buying a stake
in the future for a lot of people.
You're a hero, señor.
But who will know that?
What's it matter?
Artie, is this
the best you can do?
That's the best $1.98 gown
made in Chicago.
Lydia.
Come here.
You know what?
You're perfect.
Takes talent. Some people have it,
some people don't.
- Champagne?
- Yes, indeed.
Why didn't you tell me
you'd owned one of these?
We don't.
It belongs to a friend.
- What's your friend's name?
- Sam.
- Sam?
I'd like to meet Sam.
He must be very rich.
He is, but he's got
a lot of expenses.
Poor Sam.
Equipe Oldies
equipeoldies@gmail.com