(SONG PLAYING ON CAR RADIO)
Listen up
Got don'ts and dos
You got hot
I got typecast
Gonna have to
break all the rules
'Cause I'm cool and wacky
I feel like a wrong man
throwing out the rules
Out of control and spacey
Don't tell me
what I ought not to do
I reserve the right
to get crazy
(SINGING)
I reserve that right
I reserve the right
to be all intelligent
I reserve the right I
meant exactly what I meant
I reserve the right
Guess who's doin' yours?
I reserve that right
(CAMERA CLICKING)
MAN: Help me! Please!
Please! Somebody help me!
Help me! Please, help me! He's coming!
He's coming after me!
Help! Help me!
(GRUNTING) Help me!
I gotcha, man.
I gotcha.
Give me your other hand.
Help! I don't wanna die.
I don't wanna die!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
No!
(PANTING)
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(SNARLING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPING)
(SNAPPING)
Stow that cell phone.
You can't get a signal out here,
and that's the way I like it.
(PANTING) That was him. The Graboid.
Affirmative. You've just
been greeted by El Blanco.
Did you kill him?
He's protected. An endangered
species. Concussion grenades.
Non-lethal, but the loud
noise drives him away.
Good.
For a few minutes.
Hey, there was
another guy.
What?
A hiker or someone.
It got him.
Damn. Damn!
Not again.
(STUTTERING)
It was bad, man.
I mean, it just swallowed
him. It was horrible.
Trust me. I know what it's like.
And nothin' we can do
for the poor guy now.
Yours?
No, mine's
under there.
Dodge Charger,
V-8, 326 horse...
Tourist? Stopped to take
a picture of the sign.
Yeah, but I'm not
actually a tourist.
Left the radio on,
engine running.
I keep telling 'em that sign
does more harm than good.
(WRIST-SEISMO BUZZING)
El Blanco's comin' back
for more. Let's move out.
Burt Gummer.
Man, am I lucky you
came along when you did.
Luck had nothin'
to do with it.
I monitor my geo-phone network 24l7.
Knew you were comin'.
Saw where you stopped.
I track all seismic
vibrations in the Valley.
You said that
on 60 Minutes.
Made me look like I was some kind of
antisocial, para-military paranoid.
And right in the middle,
Chang's Discount Market.
Discount?
Well, discount's just what we call it.
Located right in the
heart of downtown Melville.
(SCOFFS) Melville.
Melvin, you would actually rename the
town you grew up in after yourself?
Why not?
It's all my vision.
I mean, without me, you guys are
pretty much futureless around here.
Futureless.
(CLICKING TONGUE) My store's
doing just fine, thank you.
And we are steadily growing ourselves
into a viable tourist destination.
(SCOFFS) Sure you are.
Come on, Jodi.
Now, I'm offering you a chance to
become part of the Melco family.
Turn your business into the kind of
place your uncle always wanted it to be.
Jodi's uncle loved this valley,
Melvin, just like the rest of us.
Oh, everyone
except you, that is.
Hey, forgive me,
Miss Woodstock of 1969,
but how many ceramic pots
does the world need?
And how many mini-malls and tacky
tract houses does the world need?
(CAR APPROACHING)
Melvin, look. Here
comes your best friend.
(SIGHING)
Lincoln Navigator,
luxury package.
There could be one in your
future, Jodi. Think about it.
That little turd.
He's a developer,
owns half the Valley.
He'd love to turn us
into the next Reno.
NANCY: Hi, Burt.
Who's your
friend?
Tourist. Stopped to take
a picture of that damn sign.
Actually, I'm not a...
Bad news is El Blanco
scored another kill.
Oh, no.
Who?
A hiker or backpacker.
Probably unregistered. This
guy just got his car sucked.
Oh, sorry about that.
Brings us to seven.
That many?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, yeah,
the ATVs.
Nope.
Separate list.
Gotta report it
to Twitchell.
We got forms
to fill out.
These tourists think everything's
"Pirates of the Damn Caribbean."
Like I keep tryin' to say,
I'm not a tourist.
(CLANGING)
You with the government?
No. Bought myself
a business out here.
That.
Desert Jack's
Graboid Adventures.
You're gonna restart
the tour business?
Yeah. Met Desert Jack
himself in Vegas.
Said it's a real
money-maker.
That's great. I was wondering
who was gonna pay his debts.
Excuse me?
JODl: You see, you buy his
business you assume his debts.
It's a law. State
Statute 4715-B, section 7.
You know, we should really
talk business synergy here.
Okay.
Well, let me see what
I got myself into here.
(GRUNTS) Hey!
Who are you?
Guess I'm the new owner
of that battery.
Jodi, I thought you said this
was all abandoned and stuff.
Not anymore. Rosalita,
Tyler. He bought the business.
Bought the business?
This business?
Well, yeah.
Oh, I get it. Tax write-off
kind of thing, huh?
Nah. Just one of those things that
seemed like a good idea at the time.
Coming all the way out here
seemed like a good idea?
Well, what are you
doin' out here, then?
I'm taking care of myself, getting away
from people who ask too many questions.
And I guess I'm buyin'
myself a new battery.
Jodi, you really get
that for a battery?
I'll take 10% down.
Okay, let's start with the
injury report. What's your name?
Uh, Tyler Reed,
double "E."
Double "E."
You be sure to give Big
Brother all your personal data.
NANCY: Burt.
Burt.
Now, if you're gonna live here,
there's a lot you're gonna need to know
and it's all in this video. You
may have heard of it. It's called...
(WRIST-SEISMOS BUZZING)
(MONITOR BEEPING)
(SHUSHING)
What's...
(RATTLING)
(CLANGING)
(SIGHS)
... Burt Gummer.
Monster Hunter.
Tips for stayin' alive when targeted
by Graboids, Shriekers and Ass-Blasters.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
wait, was that...
El Blanco,
of course.
He comes into town?
You gonna stop him?
If he's gonna
hang around,
he could use a wrist-seismo
and a right boot.
But how often
does this happen?
Not often, about once or
twice a day. Here, put this on.
Thanks. No biggie. It goes on your tab.
What tab?
Date of birth?
Mother's maiden name?
Blood type?
El Blanco, what have you
been up to all day?
(INTERFERENCE ON COMPUTER)
What the hell?
(DONKEYS BRAYING)
(RUMBLING)
(GROANING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Relax. If El Blanco's anywhere nearby,
you'll feel your seismo vibrate.
Hmm.
Thought you might
want some breakfast?
Oh, thanks.
Aren't you guys kinda
pushing the envelope out here?
I mean, he goes
right under your store.
Well, we're kinda like
the Hindus with the cow.
Excuse me?
El Blanco's endangered.
Nobody can touch him.
So that developer,
Melvin Plug?
He can't make a move because
all this is El Blanco's habitat.
So, the thing that protects your
lifestyle also wants to eat you?
Hmm. The word that comes
to mind is "paradox."
You'll get
used to it.
NANCY: Burt?
Wait a sec!
(GRUNTING) Yeah!
I want you to be the first to see
my latest creation. Gung Ho Gummer.
This one's
for you.
Yeah.
It'll do great in Japan.
You're welcome!
(BLOWING)
(VULTURE CAWING)
I call it
Grabboccino.
(GROANS IN DISGUST)
Oh, come on!
Sorry, hon,
it needs work.
(O VER RADIO) Jodi,
Burt here. Come back.
Yeah, Burt.
Got a dirt biker runnin' around out here
somewhere. You know anything about it?
Haven't seen him and no
one's rented a wrist-seismo.
Idiot. He's just askin' to
be Graboid chow. Burt out.
Maybe more nutmeg.
(ENGINE STOPS)
(FLIES BUZZING)
Jodi, Burt here.
Come back.
Yeah, Burt.
El Blanco just had himself
a wild burro burger.
Guess that backpacker
didn't hit the spot.
Ah, Burt, that's cold.
That's Perfection. My point
is the dirt biker's safe.
That much food should hold El
Blanco for a few days. Burt out.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(COWS MOOING)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHING)
You gonna be okay today? I could stay.
I've been wondering about something
ever since I left Las Vegas.
How come I don't
get a day off?
Well, let's
put it this way.
Your Uncle Miguel left
the ranch to you, not me.
You're buildin' equity, and
I'm workin' for minimum wage.
Oh, and, uh, Rosalita,
don't overdo it.
You know, ranchin's
all about slow and steady.
(CHUCKLING)
What the hell?
All points. Come in. Repeat.
All points. Come in. Over.
Burt, I'm tryin' to
run a business here.
BURT: Repeat. All points come in, over.
Yeah, Burt, you got Nancy, what's up?
Hold on. Rosalita, do you
copy? Rosalita? Do you copy?
(GRUNTS)
Rosalita, do you
copy? Rosalita.
BURT: Do you copy?
Repeat, do you copy? Over.
(SIGHING)
Repeat. Do you copy? Over.
Jodi, Rosalita's got her walkie-talkie
off again. Try to get a hold of her.
I've got six more
dead burros here.
It's like he's on a feeding
frenzy. Watch your backs.
He's never acted
this crazy before.
Jodi, let the new guy know.
Burt out.
What are you looking at?
To me, you're just hamburger.
(GRUNTS)
(MOOING)
(WRIST-SEISMO BUZZING)
(SCREAMING)
(EL BLANCO GROWLING)
Burt, come in, Burt.
Burt he's here. He's here.
Blanco's here
and he is after me.
Copy. Rosalita,
what's your 20? Over.
Burt, do not give
me those numbers.
Your location, Rosalita,
where are you? Over.
ROSALITA ON RADIO: My location is on top
of my bunkhouse, and he'd better go away.
(CRASHING)
(SCREAMING)
Burt he's hitting
my bunkhouse!
ROSALITA: Burt he's
hitting my bunkhouse!
Hang on, headin' your way.
ETA is 20 minutes!
Twenty minutes, I'm gonna be
dessert for this guy.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CRASHING)
(ROSALITA EXCLAIMING)
(CAR HONKING)
JODl: Tyler! El Blanco's after
Rosalita, and we're closer than Burt.
We gotta get up there now!
I thought you
guys coexist.
He's acting crazy, okay?
Come on, we gotta move fast.
You wanna move
fast, move over.
(ROSALITA SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
Hey, Dale Jr., where'd you
learn to drive like this?
You know about racin'?
A little.
I learned from Dale Sr.
(SCREAMING)
TYLER: We're blocked in.
Come on, guys!
Come on, help me!
(TYLER GRUNTING)
Oh, that sticks.
Really?
Really.
ROSALITA: Guys! Help me!
(EL BLANCO SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
ROSALITA: Jump, Jodi!
(SNARLING)
This barn ain't
gonna last long.
Yeah, that's why I called
you, you know, help me.
All right, you got the
keys to your car? Yes, I do.
You sure?
Yes!
When we get there
let Tyler drive.
Why? Trust me, you'll see.
JODl: We gotta hurry. Cars
aren't safe from El Blanco.
Come on. No big deal. Let's go.
I just don't get what's
going on with El Blanco.
I thought we had
him figured out.
You're gonna
figure out a worm?
So, how soon are you planning on selling
the business and getting out of here?
Uh, I don't know. The place
does have its good points.
You're being sarcastic.
No, I'm not. This
place sure isn't boring.
You like almost
getting killed?
What, you used to be a fireman,
mountain climber, or somethin' like that?
Come on, you saved my life. I
think you owe me an explanation.
I do?
Yeah, you do.
I raced cars.
Drove the NASCAR circuit
for a while. Southwest tour.
Was workin' my way up
to the big money.
But what you really wanted to be was a
desert tour guide and sleep in your garage?
I'm in kind of a pit stop at the moment.
Let's just leave it at that, okay?
Jodi, Burt here. What's the
sit rep on Rosalita? Over.
Hey, Burt, I'm here. I'm fine.
Jodi and Tyler came
and got me off the roof.
Hey, what's a sit rep?
Situation report.
Hey, can I come up to your place?
'Cause I sure don't wanna go home now.
Affirmative. Over.
(CAR DOOR OPENING)
Jodi. Rosalita. And I'm,
uh, talkin' to...
Hey, Tyler Reed. Just took
over the Graboid Tour business.
That a fact? I don't remember
approvin' any new residency permits.
A what?
Residency permit.
W.D. Twitchell,
Department of the Interior.
Nobody settles in this
valley without my say-so.
Excuse me, this is America.
Land of the free, you know.
Home of "you can live wherever
the hell you wanna live."
Hey, Twitch, um,
they're headed to Burt's.
Can you drop me
at the store?
Uh, yeah, sure. You
got forms to fill out.
He will, he will. Did you get
the report about the backpacker?
Of course!
That's why I'm here.
I mean, you people
don't fill out permits.
How am I supposed to
keep track, huh?
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Tyler? Yeah, he is in
charge of El Blanco.
If he, like, decides that it's
too dangerous to live here,
he can kick all of
our asses out of here.
So, be nice, and keep El Blanco
trashing my place on the D.L. Got it?
Got it?
Got it.
This place is totally
nuts, you know that?
Not to be one of those people who
ask questions, but I was wonderin',
what are you
doin' out here?
I mean, you look like a model
or, you know, Vegas showgirl.
(SCOFFS) Well, actually,
I was a Vegas showgirl.
You're kidding.
No. I headlined at Tops
and Bottoms at the Flamingo.
Sorry I missed it.
You ought to be.
It was so artistic.
What you really wanna do is raise cattle
and live five miles outside of nowhere?
Rosalita. You sure
you're all right?
You told me that I was
gonna be safe up there.
That El Blanco didn't
like to go up to my ranch
'cause he didn't like the
shallow dirt or whatever.
I know. I know, he's never done
this before. I can't explain it.
But at least you'll be
safe in my place.
(SIGHING)
His place?
You're standing
right on top of it.
He lives underground?
Yeah. But it's
Graboid-proof.
You see, he built the cement wall
under the dirt surrounding his property.
Hmm. Guess it's good to know an antisocial,
para-military paranoid at times like this.
Yo! Over here!
I assume you've
noticed these.
Dirt bike tracks.
No, not really.
Survival tip.
Know your terrain. Be
aware of every change.
(INTERFERENCE
ON COMPUTER)
What is it, Burt?
BURT: Interference on
my geo-phones, again.
Had it yesterday,
too. Radio waves.
But very low-frequency.
May be a covert op.
Some secret government
experiment over at NTS.
Maybe it's not good to know an
antisocial, para-military paranoid.
(WRIST-SEISMOS BUZZING)
(GASPING)
Worm alert.
No need to worry. Perfect
time to employ my USGDS.
Ultrasonic Graboid
Defense System.
My own design,
surplus parts.
Each unit generates
a 10-thousand-cycle tone.
It will overwhelm
his sound sensors.
Make my concussion grenade
seem like a cap gun.
ROSALITA: (STUTTERING)
Well, go, do it, stop him!
Uh, have patience. It's about to
come into range right about now.
Oh, Burt, he's still comin'.
Isn't he supposed to stop?
Affirmative. Run!
Tyler! Come on!
Tyler!
Let's go this way!
This way!
TYLER: Where
in the hell we goin'?
Follow me!
Bastard just knocked
down my fence,
tryin' to get over
my underground wall.
But you can't,
can you, Shamu?
Just four-inch ABS, couple
of mirrors duct taped inside.
Survival tip, just do what
you can with what you got.
Why don't you do that bomb
thing, Burt, and get rid of him?
Why waste a grenade?
My concrete Graboid barrier
is more than a match for him.
TYLER: Like your Graboid
defense system.
That was experimental. The
wall is a proven concept.
But damn it, that system should have worked.
Somethin' has changed in the equation.
Somethin's different
around here.
Why are you
lookin' at me?
Did you have anything
unusual in your car?
Something that might affect a Graboid?
Fuzz buster? Contraband receivers?
What are you
talking about?
You wear a pacemaker or any
other internal electronic device?
Uh, Burt, how long are we
gonna be stuck down here?
Once he locates his prey,
he just lays in wait.
Could be stuck
a couple days.
Days?
Might as well make ourselves
comfortable. Anybody hungry?
I haven't eaten
since Vegas.
Tyler...
When a flock of ravenous Ass-Blasters
kamikazed my house, I had no choice
but to detonate the domicile. I sustained
serious collateral damage to my lifestyle.
No insurance?
They claim we're
too high-risk.
My insurance was all in silver bars
converted to shrapnel by the blast
and disseminated
over several acres.
Since then, I've been forced to stretch the
food budget with, uh, edible wild plants.
Prickly pear cactus.
Fully de-spined. Not bad
with a shot of Tabasco.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Tastes like cactus.
You know, Burt, there's
lots of people out there
who'd actually love to learn how to
eat this stuff. I mean, for a fee.
You ever consider doin' somethin'
like, Burt Gummer's Survival School?
Uh, Tyler. Burt here is not what you
would call "people" kind of people.
Well, I'm just thinking,
anyone livin' in a hole in
the ground eating cactus,
well, maybe could
use some income.
People would pay me?
(MONITOR BEEPING)
(GASPS) He's moving.
I think he's leaving, Burt.
He never leaves.
What is going on here?
Probably that surplus Russian
satellite I had in my car.
(BEEPING CONTINUES)
Why don't we
all go into Bixby.
Just until we figure out
why El Blanco's doin' this.
(WHISPERS) Nothing happened
at Burt's yesterday.
I know
the drill.
(SIGHING)
Residency forms.
Read 'em. Sign 'em.
Everybody out here
has to do this?
Everybody, including
a couple snowbirds,
a few prospectors and one
very annoying survivalist.
And snap it up. I got
a schedule to keep.
Do you ever think
of bein' polite?
Oh, he used to
work at the DMV.
Wait a second. You're restrictin'
my business to just daylight hours?
Well, it's hard enough
keepin' you people alive,
I can't have a bunch of tourists
runnin' around here after dark.
I think these folks
do a pretty good job
of keepin' themselves
alive out here.
What about free enterprise?
The plans for my business.
Like my
Moonlight Monster Tour?
How do I do that
without a moon?
(CHUCKLES)
Guess you won't.
(GRUNTS) Wonderful.
You brought your cannon.
El Blanco's been
misbehavin'.
You shoot that Graboid and I
will slap you with a $50,000 fine.
I act only
in self-defense.
Tell me, Twitchell, are
you holdin' out on us?
Excuse me?
They've done years
of research out here
amassing a huge repository of
data of all things subterranean,
and who controls
that data?
Certain cells in
our own government.
And who represents
that government?
You been out in the sun
too long, Gummer.
You know more than we'll
ever know about El Blanco.
Why has he changed his habits? Why
has he suddenly got such an appetite?
Well, I really
have no idea.
We got a dirt biker
runnin' around the Valley.
Never buys gas, water,
never comes into town.
You don't know anything
about that either?
What the hell are you
gettin' at, Gummer?
We all know your life would be
easier if we were outta here.
But you've never quite been able to
make a solid case for eminent domain.
Wouldn't hurt if maybe just
one or two of us got eaten.
Burt, Grabboccino?
That's slander, Gummer.
That's slander. Slander!
I'll invoke the Freedom
of Information Act!
We'll see what's slander
and what ain't!
(WRIST-SEISMOS BUZZING)
I hate that friggin' worm. Hate him.
He'll leave us alone
if you just keep quiet.
(RATTLING)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
Gummer, shoot him! Shoot him,
Gummer! Shoot the damn worm!
Gummer, shoot it!
Shoot him!
Shoot the damn worm! Shoot
it, Gummer! Shoot him!
(EL BLANCO SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
Kill him! Kill him!
El Blanco,
don't make me do it.
Gummer, he's over here!
He's gonna eat me!
Burt!
(SCREAMING)
Gummer, what are you
doin'? Over here!
(EL BLANCO GROWLING)
Cover your ears!
Why?
Do it, you'll see!
(SCREAMING)
(EL BLANCO GROWLING)
(SIGHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Burt! Wait up!
Damn, Burt, that shot
was like a half a mile!
Yes, it was.
Techno-Ranch Corporation.
Elko, Nevada?
Whatever it is, it's been
makin' El Blanco nuts.
Who would do that?
I thought it was Twitchell.
Can't be. He wouldn't set it
up so he gets himself munched.
(MOTORCYCLE RUMBLING)
It's the dirt biker.
That SOB's been movin'
this thing all over.
You know, there's no way we're
gonna catch some dude on a dirt bike.
This dude, we will. He
went up this box canyon.
It's a dead end! A man has
got to know his terrain.
No, sir! No.
Up. Put 'em up!
Up! Go!
What are you doin' out
here? Who's behind this?
Damn it! Damn it! It wasn't
supposed to go like this.
I didn't want to
have to kill anybody.
(STAMMERING) Hold on. Hold on, you don't
have to... Let's just talk a minute.
No. No! Get on your knees now! Do it!
(GRUNTING)
Good work, son!
You got him!
And it's about time.
Back off.
Back off!
(EXCLAIMING) Absolutely,
son. Absolutely.
Man... Hey!
Hey, I like that helmet, by the
way, the whole camo-face thing.
About damn time someone
got ol' Gung Ho Gummer.
(MOCK LAUGHING)
Listen up, friend.
Just between you and me, since havin'
to deal with this old pompous blow bag,
it's probably the last thing
you wanna have to deal with.
(LAUGHING) Why don't
you just shoot him!
Shoot him, come on,
shoot him. Huh?
Hey, just leave it up to the
old yours truly here, huh?
Give him the old work over,
huh? Drive, drive, huh?
Huh, Gum? Huh? What? What?
I can't... What'd you say?
(CHUCKLING)
I can't hear you.
Yeah, old Gummer, what you gonna
do? Come on. Get him, baby, get him.
(GUN FIRING)
(GRUNTING)
Pompous blow bag?
I was just ad-libbin',
Burt, jeez.
He's gonna have to
follow that streambed.
We can go over that
ridge and cut him off.
And what?
If we move fast.
If you wanna move fast,
let me drive.
Take it.
Deal's done, man. They shot up
the machine. Now, give me my money.
What do you mean,
the deal's done?
And you get your money
when you finish the job.
Shut that bike off!
Not until
I get paid, pal.
I said
shut it off!
(ENGINE REVVING)
(WRIST-SEISMO BUZZING)
(BIKER SCREAMING)
BURT: Hold on! Hold on!
Make for those rocks.
Hey, who's that?
The little turd.
Oh, him.
(WRIST-SEISMOS BUZZING)
Watch it, Burt. El
Blanco is really close.
We know. What are you
doin' way out here, Melvin?
Just, uh, checkin' out some of my
land. In fact, you're trespassing.
You just didn't happen to see a
guy on a dirt bike just now, did ya?
A dirt bike?
No. Sorry, man.
What are those
tracks, then?
'Cause I thought the idea
was El Blanco kills one of us
so Twitchell can move
us out. But, no!
Somebody wanted us
to kill El Blanco.
Say again?
You'll learn to
ignore this stuff.
I don't think so.
If El Blanco became so aggressive
we had to kill him in self-defense,
poof, no endangered species.
No protected habitat!
And we're livin' in
downtown Melville, Nevada.
You're, uh, raving,
Burt. As usual.
(EL BLANCO GROWLING)
(SCOFFS)
So some idiot biker
gets swallowed!
It's got nothin'
to do with me.
With the little turd, always
count on plausible deniability.
(EXHALES)
Yeah, yeah. Thanks.
Good-bye.
Just as I thought. This thing
was stolen from a company
called Techno-Ranch
two weeks ago.
It was developed for
the livestock industry.
Here's their website. The
Model 1200 transmits a signal
to stimulate an animal's hypothalamus.
Increases the hunger response. A
healthy alternative to growth hormones.
Wow. I may start
eating meat again.
So, El Blanco couldn't stop
eating even if he wanted to.
Mmm, this is good!
(TYLER SPEAKING MANDARIN)
They got lost on their way to Vegas,
and I talked 'em into taking the tour.
Wrote out their commentary in phonetic
Mandarin. We're going international.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(TOURISTS GASPING)
You just called them all
a bunch of monkey butts.