Wild Boys - Episode 2
~ Wild Fangirl ~
u-sub.net sous-titres.eu
Szaki
Mary.
Forgive my countrymen.
They did not want you here.
They are scared.
Scared?
Of what I saw on the farm.
The family, the Ryans.
All dead.
Take your time,
we only got all night.
Night's gone.
Sun's up.
I'll see you ten guineas.
And... I'll raise ya.
All in.
I really respect a man
that underestimates his opponent.
One bullet.
Two bullet.
Three bullets.
Four bullets.
Right between the cheeks.
Stay easy on that trigger.
Lucky boy.
It's not luck.
It's skill and good breeding.
- You mind if I join your game?
- You can take my seat, friend.
As much as I have enjoyed
this sparkling wit and hospitality,
I'm in need of a hot bath.
And the patronage
of a beautiful woman.
Lucky for me...
I can afford both.
But it would be very rude of me
not to allow you the chance
to recoup some of your coin.
Drink.
- It will help with the pain.
- What pain?
I really must be going now,
because that bath's screaming at me.
You gave Mulligan a chance
to win back some coin.
What about me?
Had something to wager.
It looks to me like you've got...
nothing left of value.
My boots.
I've got boots.
We'll make this easy.
What do you say highest card wins?
Very hard to beat.
Would you look at that?
- They're a perfect fit.
- Will you be wanting your old boots?
Have em.
You know what?
In the spirit
of Christian generosity.
You kidding me!
Pleasure.
Here's for skill.
Here is for your good breeding.
Come on, let's get him up there.
A month's wages.
- String him up.
- See we usually
drown card cheats in this town.
- You're too good for drowning.
- You realise that the Queen's law
prohibits hanging without a trial?
I'm the only law here in Stanley.
Ballarat diggings.
Leaving in five minutes.
Single passage, please.
Four pound six.
Good day, gents.
Hey, hey, hey! Stop it!
Alright fellas.
More than happy to divvy up
my winnings to the four of us.
The only thing
we'll be divvying up, mate...
are the gold fillings in your teeth.
- Excuse me.
- Farrier.
So good to see you.
- What do you want?
- What's he done?
It's a misunderstanding.
You tell him, Conrad.
I don't cheat at cards.
- You're a mate of his?
- Kind of.
Tell him he's got me pegged all wrong.
I'm really a great guy when you get to know me.
- How much to let him go?
- How much you got?
Bank of England, eh?
There's the right of exchange.
Any gold?
Now is not the time
to be cheap.
OK, ok, ok!
If I see you in Stanley again,
it's gonna take more than a bag of gold
to save your miserable ass.
You alright?
I just caught my breath.
Oh no! No, no, no!
Wait!
Wait.
Stop, hold up!
He's got my gear.
You can always buy another ticket.
With what?
I just gave that bloke him all my coin
to save you from the rope.
And I will pay you back every bob,
tenner, penny, and sprat.
I swear on my dear mother's life.
To be alive, Conrad.
Jack.
- Am I dreaming?
- No, Jack.
It is me, Mary.
Am I dreaming?
Giving all the opium
these Chinese diggers stuffed you in.
Maybe.
Li Ping fetched me.
Relax.
No one knows you're here.
Besides, Fuller and his traps
are out at the Ryans farm.
I got to get out of here.
- You need to rest up.
- Gotta find Dan.
Knowing Dan,
he is drunk in some brothel...
Or out brawling,
or brawling drunk in a brothel.
I can't just leave.
What else are you going to do?
I gotta find who murdered the Ryans
and who shot me.
You just get well.
Let Superintendent Fuller worry
about justice for the Ryans, okay?
Looks like the family was shot
before the house was torched.
Bushrangers.
Bushrangers rob banks.
Stick up travellers on the road.
Don't murder families in cold blood.
Expert are you Scanlon, in the depraved
workings of the bushranger's brain.
- No, sir.
- Don't undersell yourself.
- You used to be a thieving scum.
- I was never a bushranger.
I just don't think bushrangers did this,
that's all I'm saying.
Recognise this?
Afternoon, Fredrick.
Catherine
I brought you something
for the school.
I cut em from the stone meself.
That's very charitable of you.
God knows we're stretched for funds  here.
Possum.
To teach the kids about the bush.
I was going to bring you
a wild pig...
I didn't managed to catch
the stupid little bugger yet.
Pigs are much smarter than possums.
Thank you.
Was there something else?
No.
Uh, yes...
I was wondering if...
one evening,
we might...
Wonder what's got them in a hurry.
Haven't you heard?
What's going on?
You can't just come in here
and tear my place apart.
Yes, I can.
If I suspect you of harbouring
a bushranger.
Sir.
Tommy, come on, let's go.
Hello, Superintendent.
A bit early in the day for it...
- Idiot.
- Money upfront.
- Everything's okay.
- You people think you know Jack Keenan.
You think he's a good man.
It'd change your tune if you saw
what he did at the Ryans' farm.
A whole family, butchered.
Jack wouldn't have done that.
I'm told you're a smart woman,
Mary Barrett.
No small achievement to have bought
that life for you and your boy.
So why risk everything for him?
Because if I can prove
you're a sympathiser of the bushrangers,
I would drag you out of here
by your hair in front of your son.
And throw you in prison
with the rest of the criminals.
I've got work to do.
Watch the bar.
- I didn't kill that family.
- Just keep applying your ointment.
Might stink to high heaven but Li Ping
knows what he's talking about.
Leg of mutton.
Go!
Hey.
- What happened to you?
- I got shot.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You had it easy.
Wait till you hear about my day.
- What's he doing here?
- It's a long story, but it ends
with us both loosing all our cash
and having to steal a couple of nags.
Now I am a horse thief.
You can always
look on the bright side, farrier.
- Things can't get much worse.
- Actually they can.
We're wanted for murder.
Murder?
Who have you killed?
The Ryans.
Shawn Ryan?
- Wife.
- Son.
Very pretty daughter.
- What are we going to do about it?
- Nothing tonight. I'm starved.
- Can't believe you got shot.
- Can't believe you lost all your money.
I can't believe
I'm wanted for murder.
What's going on?
Where do you come from?
Get to the horses.
Get them!
Keep up, farrier.
Faster, we're losing them.
Tracker.
Charlie.
That way. One of them's
lopsided in the saddle, boss.
I'd say he's wounded.
- How far down the stream we need to go?
- They got a tracker.
Those fellas, They'll read the ground
like a storybook.
- Tell you what you had for suppe last night.
- Name of the women you last slept with.
- Even how many children you'll father.
- All by the shape of the hoof.
Water's the only thing
that can throw a tracker them off the scent.
- We're leaving then.
- About here, I reckon.
Anything?
Boss?
I'll get the money, ain't I?
You'll get your money
when you finish the job.
- I've heard that before.
- Not from me, you haven't.
They came out here.
Heading for the drop.
Stay on that ridge.
Down there?
That's a dead man's drop.
Too stiff to climb.
- How steep?
- What don't you understand?
I think They found us.
You got any prayers,
you'd better start saying them.
Okay, Ma.
Looks like your oldest son's coming on.
Your mother's She's dead?
You swore on her life you'd pay me back.
- You won't need money in Heaven.
- Alright, boys.
Damn it!
You can't let the traps shoot him.
- Who?
- Conrad, the farrier.
- The horse thief.
- He is not a horse thief.
Fuller invented the charges
so that he could arrest him.
- And what do you care?
- I love him.
- He's the man I'm going to marry.
- You'll marry who I tell you to.
And I tell you now it won't be some
horse thieving farrier called Conrad.
Emilia!
I'll stop him myself.
Stay still, little piggy.
It's alright, miss.
I'm not gonna hurt ya.
Where's my horse?
Got scared, he bolted.
I gotta go.
They're gonna shoot Conrad.
The farrier?
You got a nasty habit
of greeting your mates like that.
What are you doing here?
Conrad!
- I thought you were going to the diggings in Ballarat. - Someone liked to join ahead?
There's a time and a place for that,
and this is neither.
Jack!
The traps were following us.
But we covered our tracks,
we laid down some false markings.
It'd be next to impossible
for anyone to track us here.
Keenan!
Is that right, Jack?
Surrender.
We have you surrounded.
- If we come out, you'll shoot us.
- Possible.
But it'll be no more than you deserve
after what you did to that family.
It'll be a waste of breath
telling you we'd nothing to do with it.
You can waste your breath,
if you come out
with your hands on your head.
I promise you a fair trial.
Damn fair for us hanging.
You boys have two minutes.
Then we're coming in.
Hurry up.
- Who owns this hut, Sergeant?
- I don't know, sir.
Any ideas?
Yeah.
We keep her hostage.
And we use her to bargain our way out.
Try and you'll have to deal with me.
- You got to get out of here.
- I'm not leaving you.
- You gotta go while it's safe.
- This is safe.
I'd rather die here with you.
Oh, please.
Even if somehow we get out of here,
that tracker will find us.
And Fuller won't stop
until he shoots us all in the back.
Great. We'll just kill ourselves now
and get it over with.
That's the best idea yet.
- I was kinda joking.
- I don't know.
I got heaps of gunpowder
and a new thing called glycerine.
I say we blow ourselves
to kingdom come.
Time's up, Keenan.
Sergeant.
On my mark.
Let's torn the hut.
Wait!
Please.
You can't fire.
Emilie?
They're innocent.
You can't shoot them.
All of them.
They've got barrels of gunpowder.
If you shoot,
the whole hut will explode.
- Fire!
- No!
Hey, boss.
Guess I'll be getting my money now?
Have some respect for the dead, Charlie.
Successful outcome.
Reckon you got them good, boss.
That's a job well done, men.
Tom!
Take this upstairs to the girls
to wash their head.
OK.
Mary.
Drink?
- No.
- It's a pub, Mick.
The only reason coming here
is for the grog.
I'm on duty.
He's dead.
They're all dead.
I make a decent living.
Honest one.
Solid and stable.
I'd make a good father for Tommy...
A husband for you.
I'll make sure
Fuller gets you no grief.
You hear.
I just want to put that on the table.
If you would think about.
He didn't kill that family.
Jack was shot
by whoever killed the Ryans.
The Chinese pulled the bullet
from his ribs.
You know Jack.
There's no way
he could have done such a thing.
The Jack I knew
always put himself first.
He's capable of doing a lot of things
as long as it suited Jack.
You deserve better.
- Won't you freak.
- Alright.
Watch it.
You call that a tunnel?
Heritage wombat.
Kept digging underneath
to keep food safe.
It should be wild spuds?
Hid a pretty bugged stuff, too.
- How does it feel to be dead?
- No money.
No horses, no prospects.
We might as well be dead.
Come out of the ground
like newborn babies.
New life means new opportunity.
- We get to start afresh.
- Alright, fellas.
Looks like we walk.
Dan, pick a direction.
Nearest hot bath.
That way.
- Mary!
- Emilia!
I've got a message for you.
From Jack.
He's not dead.
Jack asked me to tell you
that he plans to claim some land
and start a farm, and once he's up
and running, he'll get word to you.
To do what?
You'll get word to me to do what?
To be with him.
- To be together, the two of you.
- Is he serious?
I've three businesses to run.
What is he expecting me to do?
Sell up and walk away?
The arrogance of the man.
Typical ruddy Jack.
Can't even go back to Hopetoun.
I'll have to leave the district.
- Keep a low profile.
- Change our names.
You know how long it took me
to come up with the name Captain Gunpowder?
How about Captain Cook?
- What?
- Fellas.
This guy has horses.
Hi there!
- See you found our horses?
- My horses.
Wait a minute.
The thing is we had a little incident
which caused our horses to do a bunk,
so we'd be grateful...
They're mine.
What do we say we have a fresh start?
Hang us.
How much for one?
Ten guineas.
Just the one?
That sounds like you got more than}enough in there
to cover all of us here.
I just blew up my home.
Everything in it to save your bacon.
You think I'm gonna buy you horses?
He just bought my horse.
Maybe we can come to some other arrangement,
we take the horses now,
and pay you later
at an inflated price, of course.
What you got to trade?
Trade?
Just the clothes on our backs.
I need boots.
- The boots are all yours, my friend.
- Not your dirty old boots.
His boots.
Dan, give me your boots.
I love these boots.
These are the comfiest boots
I've ever had.
They've got sentimental value,
I won't give them.
Give the man your boots.
Here you go, take the boots.
Where did you get these?
I won them in a card game.
Fair and square.
"Fair and square."
What card game?
When was it?
A couple of days ago.
A pub in Stanley.
- Who do they belong to?
- I don't know, some bloke.
You should have seen him.
He comes in, sticks his stack of gold.
Stack of gold.
My gold.
Give me that.
- Where do you go?
- To Stanley.
Come on.
Jack!
Who owns these?
Take a good look.
Someone must know
who owns these boots.
Reckon I know.
What will it be worth to you?
Why don't we start
with half an ounce of lead.
Bloke's name's...
- John Grady.
- Where do I find him?
Tent city.
He's holed up there with his...
Chinese woman.
John Grady.
Looking for John Grady.
Can anyone tell me where he is?
Anyone tell me where John Grady is?
- John Grady?
- Who's asking?
Can't you see I'm busy?
What are you doing?
Why did you do it?
You didn't have to shoot them.
Why?
Jack!
What are you doing?
That's the dog who shot the Ryans.
That is not the dog
that owns those boots.
It's not him.
Why did you tell me those boots
were Grady's?
I didn't not say that.
Jack!
Jack. Jack.
Allow me. Allow me.
- Where is my money?
- This isn't about your money.
I'll ask you one last time.
Why did you lie about those boots?
- I was doing you a favour.
- How?
By getting me to kill some bloke a guy you
don't like or whose woman you want?
Alright.
The boots belong to Joey Butler.
- But you don't wanna mess with Joey.
- Where is he?
Where is he?
Joey likes to punt.
You'll find him down the road.
I want my boots back.
What are you doing?
- You gonna kill him?
- Yeah, probably.
No other way to deal with this guy?
Not unless
you breathe life back into the Ryans.
Every troop of this side of Sydney
will be looking for us if we just stop and}kill him.
- Stop and think about it.
- There's nothing to think about.
What's this about?
Is this about you getting justice for the Ryans
or is this just about you getting even?
Get out of my way.
Which one is he?
Can you see him?
What odds will you give me
on the bold guy?
Looking pretty pink for a dead white.
- How did you find us?
- You kidding? You boys stink.
Didn't fool me
with that dead pig either.
That white fella fell for that much.
- What are you saying?
- I'm open to a deal.
- What do you want?
- What do you got?
How about that?
It's a start.
What else you got?
I won.
Pleasure doing business.
Well?
Joey Butler disappeared
and no one's saying a word.
No say nothing.
I told Gunpowder and Conrad
we'll meet them at Peaches Creek.
We'll ride west together.
Come on.
Let this one go.
Fresh start, remember?
Come on.
New beginning.
"In the beginning was the word.
"And the word
"was with God."
Copy the phrase on your new slates.
- You weren't seen, were you, kid?
- No, but we shouldn't be here.
Jack said...
Keep our heads down, and he goes
riding off to Stanley like a bull in a gate.
- I had something I ought to do.
- Is it done?
- How're you doing?
- Never been better.
I don't know what is the plan for you lad.
I reckon I had enough coin
for a bath...
What's keeping Gunpowder?
Farrier's probably
up his horse again.
When I kill a man
I like him to stay dead.
Why?
Why did you do it?
Why did you murder the Ryans?
Why?
You should have heard them squeal
when I shot them.
Beg for mercy.
They would have done
anything I wanted.
Put the gun down.
- I said drop it.
- Stay out of this.
- This bastard murdered the Ryans.
- I know.
I heard him admit it.
I know he shot you too.
I got the lead
from the Chinese digger.
It's got nothing to do with me.
It's not about me.
The law will deal with him.
He'll hang for what he's done.
You shoot him,
you'll hang in his place.
I don't think he will.
How did you find us?
I followed these two clowns.
You make sure he hangs.
He'll hang alright.
I'll walk you back into town.
You play hop?
I'll be forced to shoot you.
And my hat?
- What did I miss?
- Not much.
As for the rest of you,
I'll be back to arrest you later.
We'll stay right here.
Tell us again how you called
that murderer Mongrel Butler.
Nah, Bill.
Seems you're
something of a town hero, Sergeant.
- Just doing my job.
- If so, you would have caught Keenan.
Not let him get away
when he was right under your nose.
I figured he was a ghost,
as we all believed he was dead.
You deserve a freebee.
Or maybe half price.
I don't think so, Ruby.
Not tonight.
Mary.
Taking your chance, aren't you?
Mick told me everything.
That you were so full of revenge.
Nothing else mattered.
- I can explain.
- Don't need to.
You'll never change.
Mary.
I've got to go.
Got a business to run.
Mary!
Mick Scanlon asked me to marry him.
Szaki