Any officers in the Kowloon Bay area?
Yes
We've got a reported suicide
in Hoi Bun Road
Go check it out
Roger that. Out
Sir, did you call the police?
Yes, up there...
You take down the information
I'll go check it out
May I see your I.D. please?
Okay
Be careful! It's everywhere!
His pulse is weak. We need to do
a blood transfusion
Doctor
Find out what's wrong with her
Yes
The blood bank is out of AB negative
Find some more donors! Okay
Tell them to come here at once
Excuse me
Wait a moment
Did you manage to
save that couple?
Which ones? What are their names?
I don't know their names
Look, I just brought them in
I'm sorry. I'll call you back
Thanks, bye
The one who jumped off
the building died
The couple who cut themselves
are still in the ER
Have you found any
AB Negative donors?
They're critical!
I know. There are two donors
on the way
I'm AB Negative too.
I can donate
Can you? Great!
Walk along the red line to Block D
the blood bank
Our nurse will meet you there
Okay. Let's go!
Yes, Block D, transfusion room
A police officer is coming
to give blood
Miss
You won't feel a thing
Okay
His pupils are responding
He's still unconscious
What about the girl?
She's in a coma
She has cancer anyway
I don't think she can make it
Certified dead at 2:45 a. M
Check again!
Prepare her
Have a drink
No thanks, I've got some water
Thanks, nurse
Thanks
Hi. Hi
Office, who did we save?
A couple
They attempted suicide
I hope they make it
You're working on a Sunday?
I'm an architect.
I have to survey sites
Here's my name card
As we've the same rare blood types
if anything happens...
We can help each other
Miss, I'm Eric
I'm a Catholic
Sorry. I don't have a name-card.
I'm Joy
J-O-Y
A happy name!
Really?
Sir, what's your name?
Sam Ka Lok. You can call me Lok
What's happening?
Are they going to be okay?
The man is in a coma
And the girl is dead
Nurse, how's my daughter?
Are you her immediate family?
Yes, I'm her father
I'm her mom
We tried our best
I'm sorry, but she didn't make it
The nurse will help you make
the necessary arrangements
I'm sorry
Lets open it up to check
Calm down
Undo the bandages
You shouldn't go over there.
Stay here
Calm down
My daughter...
Calm down...
Madam, calm down
My daughter is still alive...
Calm down
Calm down and I'll go and check
Doctor
Tell her family that she's dead
Tell them
It was only a reflex action
Your daughter is dead.
Please calm down
Lucky the man survived
I hope he's all right
I think he'll be okay
I'm waiting for a police car
to pick me up. And you?
There's a taxi
You go first
Do I know you?
I don't think so. What is it?
Did you see it?
What?
The girl looked at us
What are you doing?
Master Sam, you'd better
move out of here soon!
I'm scared coming
all the way up here
You're the only ones
left in the building
Not the only ones!
What about the Taoist temple
over there!
Isn't that kind of spooky?
No, not at all
I... Come in!
I'm scared. I'll go now
Don't move
Dad
Oh, you're back
Mrs. Chan
Don't move
Lok, how are you?
You're looking better every time
I see you
When will you bring
your girlfriend home?
Soon...
A good-looking guy like you
can't be shy!
The girls will think you're boring!
Dad, don't talk about me to everyone!
It's all right. You know Mrs. Chan!
I mentioned it on purpose
So she can help find you a girlfriend
Good, finished. Take a look!
Perfect!
Right!
I'll show you something!
Is that your son?
I won't show you my girlfriend
What's she like? Cute?
Don't you get scared
looking at dead people, Lok?
It’s just a job
Look at him. He's so handsome
in his uniform!
Another blackout! What a dump!
Be careful
I think we have to fix the fuse
Why bother? Just move
Master Sam, I'm leaving
So soon?
Another one from another angle
Have you got enough? Yes
I'll see you soon
Still here? Everyone's gone
I'll be leaving soon.
What about you?
Work, work and more work!
Are you okay?
Yes
How can you give blood
when you're so weak yourself?
I just want to help people
Help?
You helped the wrong person
Look!
The man is in a coma and
the woman is dead
You split them up!
Let them die if they want to,
for God's sake!
What is it?
Nothing
I'll finish up here
Mr. So, can you tell us anything else?
What happened just now?
What did you see?
Mr. So?
Mr. So, that'll be $40
What about the camera?
We've checked it.
The flash is all right
Did you drop it?
We've checked it
It's okay now
Thanks
Father
I've never seen this person before
But ever since I gave blood
she's been following me
It's all right. Don't worry
You just wanted to help
She won't hurt you
You haven't slept for the whole night
You must be tired
Take a rest here
The donors who gave blood
last night saved his life
Does he have a girlfriend?
You show him the way
The girl you're looking for
is in the second bed
Thanks. I'll be fine
You don't belong here
Our Father who art in heaven
Hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come
Thy will be done
Our Earth as it is in heaven
Give us this day our daily bread
And forgive us our trespasses
Why did you split us apart?
I would have stayed with Jack
but they separated us
They must bring Jack to me!
They must!
Hello?
Yes
He is our principal
Father... What's happened?
He's dead!
A mourner has arrived!
Please stop
One bow
Two bows
Last bow
Family bow
Please burn your incense
Did you have a dream?
The east wind blows
The altar is raised
The east wind blows from the hell
Miss Yau Yin Ping
Leave hell and fly to heaven!
Stand up
Stand there
Take your sister's spirit tablet
Go in there and
See what your sister wants
Are you okay?
Ask your sister to tell you
What she wants
Ask her to tell you
Otherwise, we can't help her
Get away!
Leave me alone! Eric!
Eric
Are you okay?
I'm fine
Do you want to see a doctor?
There's no need
I don't understand
The master only wants to
save this woman from hell
I don't know why she doesn't
want to leave
Dying isn't so bad
Everyone has their own worries
What kind of disease do you have?
Mental illness
I had a nervous breakdown
On my 7th birthday
My mom bought me a cake
I was very happy
They sang me a birthday song
Happy birthday to you...
Then mom killed dad
She cut me a slice of the cake
The cake was covered with blood
And yet it was so sweet and delicious" '
Why did you mom kill your dad?
Mom told me...
I killed your dad...
Because I love him
My mom had nervous breakdown
She had nervous breakdown...
Do you hate your mom?
I don't hate her
She loves me
I hate her!
She shouldn't have killed my dad!
She shouldn't have killed him!
The doctor says my mom had
a nervous breakdown
She is still in the hospital
I've been there too
My doctor says it's in my genes
No-one knows when it will recur
And so I have to keep
taking medicine
At least you're okay now
Tell me, do I know you?
Please tell me!
I can't tell what's real from
what's imaginary
Tell me whether I know you!
Tell me please
Of course you do
Why else would I be here
listening to you all this time?
Right?
Miss Yip, Doctor Liu is here
Who is he? Don't let just anyone
in here!
Sir, I'm sorry.
Please wait outside
The patient needs a check up
I'll be waiting for you
OK, wait outside, please
Are you all right?
Did you take your medication?
Yes
You should be all right
if you keep taking your medicine
What is it?
I still have other patients to see
Who's having the tea?
Hello?
Before he lost consciousness
He called out your names
But we didn't know how to reach you
Then the nurse checked
the donor records
And we realized that
you gave blood together
Can I see my friend?
Joy
Pills... Have you got any pills?
Pills...
I don't know what your relationship is
I think you'd better
not see her any more
Why?
Don't you know she's insane?
I know
Don't you know
she could seriously injure someone?
So what?
Hey! What are you doing?
Have a glass of water
Please save me, I didn't do it!
Calm down
Believe me, I didn't do it!
I believe you, I believe you!
Please give us a moment
Excuse me
Calm down
It's alright. Don't worry
Joy is possessed by demons
Bullshit!
Are you all right?
Be a good girl.
Finish your statement
Don't worry.
The patient will be all right
Finish the statement
What's your name?
Yip Tze Man
Where do you live?
Kowloon City
What do you do?
Stop it!
Go inside
Don't you know she's insane?
She had a nervous breakdown
She's lost touch with reality
She doesn't know what she's doing
Is this what you called
demonic possession?
You haven't done anything
to help her!
Cut it out. I'm her doctor
I know what's best for my patient
I don't want her to hurt
herself or anyone else
Sending her to the hospital
is the best way
Can you help her?
You're still on duty.
Are you crazy?
Don't come in!
The master left a message for you
The man has become zombie and
the woman is a vengeful spirit
So now you have to pay for it
The ghost wants you
to kill her boyfriend
That's the only way
you can save your friend
Don't worry. It's all right
Mom is here. It's all right
Don't be afraid...
Lok, you have to help me.
Kill him!
Stand up...
Be good
Paul! Fancy seeing you here!
Yes, I'm checking on Joy
See you around
Be careful what you say
I don't want anyone
to know about us
I am the only person
who can keep you out of jail
Understand?
You're crazy!
Yes, I'm crazy
I could kill someone and
still not go to jail...
This woman has
a severe psychotic condition
She claims she always sees ghosts
What should I do?
Joy, how do you feel?
Let us help you
Joy, we can't help you
if you're like this
Joy, you say you can see ghosts
Can you tell us what they look like?
It's an open and shut case.
We don't need to any more tests
Are you looking for me?
I'm Yau Yin Ping
You won't understand
how a woman feels
Someone enduring an incurable disease
who wanted to die
Together with her lover
I didn't want to leave alone
I wanted Jack to die with me
That's why I cut myself so deep
I can't be without him
The three of you saved his life
Listen to me.
No one can help them
Whoever helps them has to die!
Lok!
The patient is gone!
Get him! Hurry...
Sit down! Sit...
Give him the beads
Lok
Lok!
Master
you know what will happen
Why help them?
Just because we know
what destiny holds for us
Doesn't mean we can escape it
Whether or not they can be saved
depends on their destiny
That ghost really loves
her boyfriend too much
We can only save the woman
I hope she will leave your son alone
Master, someone's moving the corpse!
Joy, help me!
Kill Jack for me!
We love each other
He wants to die
because he wants to be with me!
Lok!
Master!
Joy, you understand
Do you remember
when you were young
Your mom killed your dad
the same way
Because she loved your dad?
She didn't want your dad
to leave you
Love him...
Lok... what are you doing?
Lok, what is it?
Joy, this is love. You know it
No, my mom shouldn't have
killed my dad!
Why is this happening?
Master... save him! Master...
Help me... kill him
Joy, you shouldn't try and
protect him
You'll regret it
What are you doing?
Why did you break the string of beads?
Lok...
Don't be afraid. Dad is here
My son didn't hurt anybody!
He always tries to help people
Why are you doing this to him?
He's my only son!
Let him go!
If you want to take a life, take mine!
Just let him go, please!
Take my life...
Let him go
Lok...
No...
Lok, are you still here?
Open the door, Lok!
Uncle, I'm Joy, open up!
No... Run...
Let me see Lok!
Don't touch my son...
I'm not a ghost. I'm Joy!
Go! Get out!
Don't you dare touch my son!
Go... what should we do?
Go in. Don't be afraid.
Dad is here
Lok
Lok, open up!
Lok...
Help... is anybody here? Help...
Help! Anyone here?
Anyone here? Help... anyone?
Anyone?
Help!
Anyone? Help...
Lok...
Lok
Miss!
Joy...
We love each other
Joy, help me!
Your mom killed your dad
the same way
I'm Yau Yin Ping
Kill Jack for me!
Joy, no!
Help me!
I know my illness can't be cured
So this is the only way
we can come together
We love each other
We just want together!
The girl looked at us
Joy
Joy, help me, please!
Help me, please!
Help...
Open up...
Open up!
I'm here to kill him for you
Let go of Joy!
I've been certified insane
If I kill someone,
I don't have to go to jail
Do I know you?
Of course
Think...
We donated blood together that night
Do I know you?
I don't think I've seen you before
Tell me if I know you
Please tell me
Of course you do
Why else would I be here
listening to you all this time?
Right?
Lok...
Lok!
Which school did you go to?
Where do you live?
My name's Joy. What's yours?
What did you see?
I going upstairs to work
I saw a woman come in
A woman? Was she alone?
She told me that
she was following a man
Did you see him?
No, she was alone
Are you sure?
She was all by herself
Miss!