Pipe down, Thunder.
Did you ever see a catfish
riding on a yellow jackass before?
Not that I can remember.
No touch.
Him Golden Ass of Apuleius.
Him very mean.
No touch.
Excuse, please.
Hello.
Who's that, anyway?
I don't know.
Looked like a Jap to me.
He's Chinese.
-How do you know?
-Because I ain't stupid.
Well, whoever he is,
he sure come to the wrong town.
Hello.
You miserable piece of junk!
I ought to--
Excuse, please. Excuse.
Excuse.
Who're you?
Name Lao.
Doctor Lao.
Ain't nobody sick here, unless you
know how to remedy this machine.
Do printing here?
No. We sell ladies' underwear.
What's the matter with you,
big wise guy?
All the time make jokes.
Make fun of old Chinese fellow.
Take it easy. It's too late
in the afternoon for tantrums.
Who you? Who you?
You boss?
No. Boss, he over there.
Busy?
Well, you might say.
Okay. I wait.
Hi, Tim.
Ed.
-What can I for you, Mr. Stark?
-Nothing.
Not a thing. Just passing by.
Thought I'd drop in to say hello.
Of course, if you have
some business to do.
That's okay. I wait. I wait.
I read your editorial this morning.
That was a fine piece of writing.
Real fine. You certainly know
how to put words together.
I'll just bet you liked it.
Of course I liked it.
I always like it when a man
speaks his mind.
That part where you told
all the people not to sell out.
Boy, that was brave.
And where you talked about fear.
Now, what was that again?
Here, you read it.
''The prices paid
by Mr. Clint Stark
for real estates and labor
are so patently unfair
as to be ludi-cross.''
Ludicrous!
Down about three paragraphs.
Three what?
''All dictators past and present
have thrived in a climate of fear.
Without fear, they perish.
People are afraid of Clint Stark
and so long as this
situation exists
he will continue to rule Abalone.''
That's great stuff.
Then I take it you agree with me.
Of course I agree with you.
But the thing is,
the people are afraid of me
because I own them
lock, stock and barrel.
-They sold out a long time ago.
-Then what are you so worried about?
You.
I'm worried about you.
See, you're a smart boy
and I just hate to see you wasting
your time. Now, don't get me wrong.
I appreciate a fighter.
I especially appreciate a fighter
who has the odds against him.
But there aren't any odds here.
And there isn't any fight.
Maybe I can stir one up.
Not a chance.
You'll just make the people feel bad.
Believe me, this town isn't
worth the trouble.
Then why are you so interested
in buying every square inch of it?
Because I'm a philanthropist, boy.
I like to help people.
Now let me ask you one.
What's your stake in this?
How come you're so concerned
about Abalone?
-Abalone is my home.
-That won't wash.
A year ago you hadn't heard
of the place.
You're a city boy, Ed.
You have some other reason.
Well, now, Mr. Stark, I guess I just
can't keep any secrets from you.
The real reason is,
''I'm a philanthropist, boy.''
You wanna know something?
I think you are.
I really think you are.
Good luck, Ed.
You're on the wrong side,
but I like your style.
I wish I could return the compliment.
Let's go.
What can we do for you, mister?
Very small matter.
I like to run advertisement.
Excuse.
In newspaper.
Something wrong?
You sick maybe?
It's just it's kind of a shock.
We don't get much new business here.
How much?
Well, that depends.
You want a full column or a--
Big, big, big!
Full page. Run two days.
Start right away, chop-chop.
A full page for two days?
How about
$50?
Good, good, good.
American money?
Yes, we'd prefer it
if you don't mind.
No, no. Don't mind.
Fifty dollars.
You fix?
I fix.
Mr?
Lao.
Doctor Lao.
What part of China are you from?
Last residence Panohai.
Pee-a-en-oh-ha-a-ai.
Panohai.
Hello. Goodbye.
Thank you. Thank you.
What in Tom thunder?
You gonna print that stuff?
Why not? He paid for it, didn't he?
Besides, I smell a story.
Howdy! Have you
got anything to read--?
I'm sorry, Mrs. Benedict.
I said, ''Have you got anything--?''
-I heard you.
-Where?
The section on manners
is right over there.
I've read those.
I'm looking for something on China.
When do you leave?
As soon as you marry me. I thought
it'd be a nice place to honeymoon.
Edward Cunningham!
lf you--
Seriously, I want to check
on a city called Panohai.
Section on Asia, third shelf
from the top.
-You wouldn't want to help me?
-You can find it.
It’s called The History of China
by D. Boulger.
Would you like to have
dinner with me tonight?
lt should be clear by now
that I do not
wish to go out with you,
Mr. Cunningham. Ever.
Why not?
All those stories about me,
they're lies!
I’m not a bank robber
or a cattle rustler.
And I’ve never kicked a woman
in the stomach even once. Really!
It’s quite impossible.
I’ve a little boy and a mother-in-law
to take care of.
And you've only been in town a short
while. I don't even know you.
-So please, stop asking.
-Never.
lt isn't Mike or your mother-in-law.
It’s because you're afraid.
-Of you?
-Of falling in love.
Of being a woman.
That's what you are, Angela,
underneath all those widow's weeds.
Isn't that right, Luther?
You got any more of that pie, Gram?
-Certainly.
-He can get it himself.
All right.
Thank you.
Ed likes apple pie too.
When are we gonna invite him over?
Don't be disrespectful.
His name is Mr. Cunningham.
Come on, Mom.
He said I could call him Ed.
And I say you can't.
Now you get the pie
and go finish your homework.
All right.
Don't bother with the dishes.
I’ll do them when I get back.
All right.
-Good night, Mom.
-Good night, Michael.
Good night, Grandma.
Good night, Mike.
You're being a little hard on him.
It’s not easy for a boy to grow up
without his father.
I know.
You could change that, Angela.
Did you hear me?
Yes.
He is such a fine man.
Who is?
Ed Cunningham.
Oh, Sarah, I do wish you'd stop
going on about that drifter.
He is not a drifter!
He's been here almost a year.
Whatever else you may
think of him
you have to admit he is the only
man in town with spirit enough
to stand up to that devil, Stark!
Well, it takes more than spirit
to make a fine man.
I loved your son, and no other man
will ever take his place.
No, Sarah.
We'll manage, just you and l.
After all, Mike has two mothers
and that makes up for quite a lot.
I won't be late.
Good night, dear.
I don't think Cunningham's
going to show up.
Why not?
He doesn't want to lose.
Who does?
I do.
Mayor, every time I bet on weakness,
corruption and fallibility
I want to lose.
But I always win.
Hey, boss.
Meeting will come to order.
Now, folks, may I have your attention?
Now a few words from someone
who don't need any introduction.
The man who's done more
for Abalone than any other man
Mr. Clinton Stark.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen
fellow citizens of Abalone.
I know you're all tired of waiting,
so I’ll cut the fancy talk
and come right to the point.
Abalone is dying of thirst.
Now, you all know we get our water
from a point 16 miles from here
through an underground pipe.
That pipe is worn out.
It’s crumbling.
According to the top engineers
of this state, it has
maybe another six months left.
Then it's finished.
So looking at it realistically
it seems you all have two choices:
Either you repair the pipe,
or you let it rot.
Now, if you repair the pipe
it'll cost you $237,000!
And what do you get for your money?
I’ll tell you that too.
Nothing. Because that's
what Abalone is. Nothing.
Zero.
Is that what you want?
To spend the rest
of your lives here
as bored as you've always been?
Of course not.
But you don't want
to die of thirst either.
Now, you can't afford to leave
your homes, lose your possessions.
Folks, I have an alternate
choice for you.
Sell.
Sell what you've got and move away.
Leave Abalone
to the buzzards.
Folks, I’ll buy this town from you.
Every house.
Every building.
Every single nail.
And pay you a fair price to boot.
So you don't have to go
head over heels into debt
to raise $237,000.
You don't have to lose
everything you've got.
That makes sense!
Well, I think we all agree
that Mr. Stark has been
more than generous with us.
I suggest, therefore,
that we take a vote--
Just a minute!
I’d like to say a few words
if Mr. Stark doesn't mind.
Not in the least, Mr. Cunningham.
After all, this is a free country.
It’s good someone remembers that.
You know, folks,
I haven't been here long.
But it's home to me.
And I believe in fighting for
your home when it's threatened.
Now, Mr. Stark wants us
to sell our home.
Because it's gonna be
an effort to keep it.
Even if we make the effort, he says
that Abalone is nothing. It’s zero.
I say he's wrong.
I say any place where people live
and work together
is something.
Something very important.
Now, one more thing.
Just outside of our town,
there's another
with even less of Mr. Stark's
kind of future.
There's one of its citizens.
Stand up, please, George.
This is George G. George.
He's a Navajo Indian.
Most of you know him.
His forefathers were here before
the white man even heard of America.
What will happen to his family,
his friends
without our town to help him?
I’d like to say something.
All right, Mrs. Benedict.
lf Abalone is as worthless
as Mr. Stark says
why is he so anxious to buy it?
That's a fair question.
I’m glad you asked it.
Mrs. Benedict, you're a teacher,
a librarian.
And as such, you can take a dull boy
and make him into a smart boy.
ln a manner of speaking,
you can turn a profit.
It’s the same with me.
I’m a businessman, and as such
I feel I can do this,
well, without taking a loss.
-It’s as simple as that.
-But just exactly--?
You should be ashamed of yourself
for doubting Mr. Stark's integrity.
Mr. Stark, when do we
have to give our answer?
Well
frankly
I’d hoped to settle this
this evening.
But if you want some time
to think it over
well, let's say
within a couple of days.
Thank you.
Thank you very much, Mr. Stark.
We owe you a vote of gratitude
for being so fair with us.
Don't you agree, folks?
Meeting adjourned
until 9:30 Friday night.
Oh, George.
We didn't accomplish very much
but thanks for coming down.
Not a chance, Ed.
They're sentimental, but that
doesn't make them stronger.
That's what you want to think.
You'll find this
hard to believe
but I was like you once,
a long time ago.
I believed in the dignity of man.
Decency. Humanity.
But I was lucky.
I found out the truth early, boy.
And what is the truth, Stark?
It’s all very simple.
There is no such thing
as the dignity of man.
Man is a base, pathetic,
vulgar animal.
Good night, Ed.
Halt, you miserable redskin!
You're keeping the wrong kind
of company, boy.
Ain't good to be seen
with a man like Cunningham.
Bad medicine. Savvy?
Cat got your tongue?
I believe that's what's happened.
Cat got his tongue.
Who told you you could go?
He's a sassy one, ain't he?
You know what my old man used to say?
He said the only good
Injun's a dead Injun.
What do you think of that, boy?
Talk, you miserable redskin!
Talk!
Excuse, please.
This town ain't big enough
for you and me, partner.
Smile when you say that,
you miserable horny-toad hombre.
What happened?
Read all about it!
Circus coming to town!
-Good morning, Mr. Ramsey.
-Why don't you aim, boy?
I do, Mr. Ramsey! I do!
Hey, Bunny, look it here!
I can't come out like this.
Says here a circus
is coming to town.
To Abalone?
That's what it says.
I can't believe it.
Hasn't ever been a circus here.
Read all about it! Read all about it!
Circus coming to town!
That darn kid.
He threw the paper under the car.
Mr. Frisco, good morning.
Good morning, Mrs. Cassin.
And how is our esteemed mayor
this morning?
Oh, fine, thank you.
Just fine!
Read all about it!
Circus coming to town!
That young hoodlum!
It’s just the Daily Star, dear.
Don't mess me up, stupid.
Go get the paper.
Yes, dear.
Somebody ought to arrest
that rapscallion!
He's just like that no-good
Cunningham. A troublemaker!
Give it here.
And sit down.
You give me the jitters.
I’m sorry, dear. I don't mean
to give you the yitters.
Say ''jitters.''
What in the world is a Medusa?
A Medusa, dear heart, is a.
Well, it's a mythological creature
with snakes on her head
instead of hair.
And
if you look at her face
you turn to stone.
Shut up, Luther!
And don't be ridiculous!
Yes, dear.
Wait! I wanna talk to you!
Edward Cunningham, Esquire.
Editor in chief of the
Abalone Daily Star. How do you do?
Who's talking? Where are you?
Here.
There.
Everywhere.
Are you going to write about me
in your newspaper?
lf you give me something
worth writing about.
As a rule, Dr. Lao does not approve
of our speaking for publication.
But I see no harm in telling you
that I was born in the year 1 204.
Or is it 41 2?
I can't seem to remember.
But at any rate
I am the greatest magician
the world has ever known.
It’s funny.
I’ve never heard of you.
But you have heard of me. Indeed.
The name is Merlin.
-Merlin?
-Merlin.
The magician from His Majesty
-King Arthur's court.
-Of course!
And that big ape I saw hammering the
stakes, he was from the Himalayas?
Precisely. Abominable, isn't he?
About this Dr. Lao
where's he from?
China. But you needn't
bother about him.
No talent there.
Strictly an executive type.
Pray, do not quote me.
I wouldn't dream of it.
But tell me, what does he do?
Oh, dear.
I’m frightfully sorry.
I’ve said much too much already.
Oh, but do, do let me show you
some small sample of my craft.
May I have the notebook
which is in your pocket?
Now tell me, Mr. Edward Cunningham
what you most desire.
Oh, no. That's terribly
stupid of me.
Mortals have but one basic desire.
Now hold this in your hand.
Now close your eyes
and say the magic word.
-What is the magic word?
-''Money,'' of course. Say it.
Money.
Open your eyes.
It worked!
A small sum, of course.
But then, I tire easily.
-Magic is extremely exhausting.
-No, thank you.
-Beg your pardon?
-No, thanks.
I came here for a story,
not a bribe.
Merlin! Merlin!
Oh, dear. Oh, dear!
Now I really am in trouble.
Welcome to the Circus of Dr. Lao.
How may we serve you?
By giving this money
back to the old boy--
What money, Mr. Cunningham?
Come on, doc. What kind of Oriental
hocus-pocus is going on around here?
A circus with no wagons,
no animals, no cages
a crazy old magician?
What's it all about?
Our circus is different.
That's what I promised.
I’m not interested in promises.
I’m interested in the real story.
And don't tell me about Panohai.
I looked it up.
Panohai went out of existence
thousands of years ago.
Forgive me, but you worry too much.
You worry about how I brought
my circus to Abalone without wagons.
You worry about the future
of your town
or if the sun will rise
a year from today.
The answers to such matters
remain posed behind a curtain.
Then time says, ''Presto!''
And out they come.
Tomorrow night
I promise you ''presto.''
The strangest story you've ever known.
Now, Mr. Cunningham
do you suppose this garrulous
intruder may be
a swindler perhaps?
An assassin?
A charlatan plotting some curious
disaster for your town?
Such characters exist, but they are
secretive rather than mysterious.
l, sir, am a major mystery.
You're a convincing talker
about very unconvincing things.
Whatever men do not understand,
they find unconvincing.
But please don't suppose I’m
dangerous, because I’m unfamiliar.
I ask
that you believe in me.
As what?
As a friend of yours,
of your town
of all human beings.
That's quite a spiel.
Thank you.
Well, I’m leaving in a cloud
of befuddlement.
And with nothing to go on
except a hunch
that you're a nice guy.
Good afternoon, Mr. Cunningham.
Hey! How come you speak
perfect English all of a sudden?
Oh, it comes and goes.
Whatever dialect the mood requires.
Comes and goes?
What's the matter?
Always asking questions.
Wise guy!
Get on your motorcycle!
Hey, mister, how'd you do that?
So sorry.
Don't speak English.
You do too. Ed said so.
And I know who you are.
You're Dr. Lao.
Astute observation.
Goom-bye.
I’ll carry your posters.
Even help you put them up!
-lf you'll show me how.
-What name?
-Mike Benedict, sir.
-Okay, Mike. You come.
-Are you an acrobat?
-Only philosophically.
-What?
-Only philosophically!
Really? Can you walk a tightrope?
lf required.
My specialty, however, is wisdom.
Do you know what wisdom is?
No, sir.
Wise answer.
I can walk on my hands.
Wanna see?
Not now, please.
How do you do that?
You come circus.
Bring Mama and Papa also.
All my guests.
You mean free?
Gosh! Thanks!
But I can't bring my father,
because he's dead.
Oh, that's very sad, Mike.
But I never knew him.
He got killed when I was little.
I’m the man of the house.
You're a very fine young man.
I’m not so young.
I’m 8 going on 9.
Eight going on 9 is young,
believe me.
Eight going on 9
is remarkably young.
How old are you?
I believe I shall tell you.
I am seven thousand
three hundred and twenty-two
years old
this October.
That is old!
It is, rather.
lf you ask me,
that's quite a stunt!
I guess he's got a gramophone
hid somewheres.
That's it. lt must be.
This is the Circus of Dr. Lao
We show you things
That you don't know
We've spared no pains
And we've spared no dough
For we wanted to give you
One hell of a show!
And youth may come
And age may go
But no more circuses
Like this show
Fifteen cents.
You free.
Step up! Step up!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
Thank you, sir.
Isn't it exciting?
I haven't been to a circus
in, well.
In a long time! I hope
they have a fortuneteller.
Not that I believe in them, of course.
But they are fascinating.
Go in and wait about 45 minutes.
Thank you, boss.
See Apollonius!
See the Snowman!
Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
See the Medusa turns
men of granite to stone!
And see the Great Serpent. See him
rise, see him coil, hear him hiss!
See wonders never before beheld
by the eyes of mortal man.
See the Great Pan,
the incarnation of the carnal!
See Apollonius of Tyana.
He sees all, tells all!
Nothing but the truth.
It's the chance of a lifetime.
The dark mysteries unfolded.
Step right up!
Only 1 5 cents!
Now please keep in line.
Step right up! Fifteen cents.
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
You frightened me.
You wish your future told?
You look like Howard
my poor, dear departed husband.
You know he did not die.
He simply walked out of your life
years ago.
Yes. Well, you know everything,
don't you?
lf you know my past so well, let's see
if you can really tell my future.
Be seated.
Five cents, please.
Shall I ask questions?
If you wish.
This is so exciting.
Let me see now.
I know.
How soon will I strike oil
on that 20 acres of mine?
-Never.
-But I paid a fortune for that land.
You wasted your money.
Next question.
I can't hear you.
You must listen.
You needn't be so brusque.
It's just a game, after all.
All right, you naughty man.
You see, what I really
want to know is
when shall I be married again?
Never.
Well, what sort of man
will come into my life?
Let's put it that way.
There will be no more men
in your life.
Really! Really!
What's the use of my living
if I’m not going to be rich
no more men, for heaven's sake?
I only read futures.
-I don't evaluate them.
-That's utter nonsense!
The future is always nonsense
until it becomes the past.
Well, go on. Do your job.
I paid you.
Read my future!
Tomorrow will be like today
and the day after tomorrow will be
like the day before yesterday.
I see your remaining days
as a tedious collection of hours
full of useless vanities.
You will think no new thoughts
and you will forget what little
you have known.
Older you will become, but not wiser.
Stiffer, but not more dignified.
Childless you are
and childless you will remain.
Of that suppleness you once commanded
in your youth
of that strange simplicity
which once attracted men to you
neither endures
nor shall you recapture them.
You're a mean, ugly man!
Mirrors are often ugly
and mean.
When you die
you will be buried and forgotten.
And that is all.
And for all the good or evil
creation or destruction your
living might have accomplished
you might just as well
never have lived at all.
I am sorry, but you see, it is
my curse to tell the absolute truth.
Oh, Mrs. Cassin.
Angela, whatever you do,
stay out of there.
Why? Isn't he any good?
Oh, no. He's wonderful!
Absolutely the most magnetic man
I’ve ever met in my whole life
next to Howard, God bless his soul.
Do you know what he told me?
That I’m going to be rich, strike oil.
And promise you won't tell.
I’m going to be married again.
And Clinton Stark is the lucky one.
That's very nice,
but why shouldn't I go in?
Well, he's not very polite.
He pinched me three times.
But I suppose you haven't anything
to worry about, come to think of it.
Toodle-loo.
Estimable educator.
Mother of fatherless Mike,
good friend.
Lose something?
Yes. My mother-in-law.
She over there, I think.
Have plenty fun. You too?
Well, it's very nice, thank you.
Good, good, good.
Exhibit around corner.
Step in. Step in.
Step this way, if you please.
The most charming figure
in the old Greek
polytheistic mythology
is Pan, the God of Joy
combining the forms of man
and goat.
It's a fake.
It's gotta be.
Hi, there.
Why, don't be frightened, kiddo.
I’m harmless.
Dr. Lao saw to that.
Come here.
Do I look familiar to you?
Now that you mention it, you do.
This circus is like a mirror.
You see yourself in it sometimes.
Sometimes someone else.
Didn't Dr. Lao tell you about it?
He will, Mr. Stark.
How do you know my name?
I know a lot of unimportant
stuff like that.
Well, whoever you are
and however you work
you interest me.
You know why?
Because we look alike
and have much in common.
For one thing
our suspicion.
-Why do you buzz your tail like that?
-Why not?
It's the most treasured gift
of my ancestors.
-I wouldn't care to trade with you.
-Maybe not.
But the point is, my scaly friend
that you are in a cage
while I’m free to walk about.
Oh, you have your cage too.
You test your bars just as
often as I test mine, kiddo.
Why do you wear those things
over your eyes?
So I can see.
I have an astigmatism.
They're glasses.
The creator who made you cunning
made my eyes efficient enough
to perceive objects
without aid.
In fact, the Lord of All Living
dealt with me quite generously.
Strength He gave me
and symmetry and endurance
and patience.
But look at you.
You even have to hang rags on yourself
to protect your weak skin.
You have to hang things in front
of your eyes in order to see.
Look at yourself!
I’ll admit I’m not perfect, but--
You can say that again, kiddo!
You're just about the most imperfect
creature I’ve ever seen!
And I’ve seen some lulus!
To tell you the truth
even the thought that
I resemble you makes me ill.
Well, it doesn't make me
too happy either.
Hey, boss
we've been looking
all over for you.
You don't have to worry
about no newspaper no more.
Who was you talking to?
-No one.
-Well, I thought I heard--
-That's an ugly devil!
-Let's scat. Let's scat!
You wouldn't say that if I were
on the other side of these bars.
Let's get out!
Mr. Stark!
“Monsieurs et Mesdames”, it give me
great pleasure to present to you
direct from a long and successful
run at the court of King Arthur
that inimitable dramaturge
that master of magic, sorcery,
wizardry and prestidigitation
the crown prince
of the black arts
Merlin the Magician!
Go on!
On with the show!
Oh, dear, I’m terribly sorry.
What sort of magic
would you like to see?
What kind have you got?
Oh, all sorts, really.
Though I am a bit out of practice.
Well, let's see now.
What have we here?
Oh, we have a ball, haven't we?
Just an ordinary ball, isn't it?
I suppose so.
Oh, dear, now we have two!
Make a rabbit come out
of the bag.
Oh, very well. I’ll try it.
Hocus
Pocus.
I wanted a rabbit!
Oh, I’m sorry.
I did my very best.
Disappear.
Can you do magic with cards,
Mr. Merlin?
For you, sir, I will.
One
two
three.
I don't like that.
Faker!
Phony!
Why don't you change
the water into booze?
Very well.
Hocus-pocus.
Come and take it.
Would you care for some, young lady?
I never drink.
Neither does he.
Let me try some of that stuff.
Tastes just like ginger ale.
I beg your pardon, sir.
This is the finest vintage champagne
ever served in America.
Come on, do something!
Don't just stand there!
Show us some real magic!
Mother, have him do
something I like.
Do you like flowers, little lady?
A little.
The last one is for you, my dear.
Now come on.
Do something really big!
Yeah! Make a woman float
in the air
like I seen once in Tucson!
She was beautiful.
Mother, I’m tired of this.
Be still. This gentleman
is trying to do tricks.
Tricks!
Gadzooks, madame.
These are not tricks.
I do magic. I create.
Il transpose. I transubstantiate.
I break up. I recombine.
But I never trick.
You stink!
It’s just done with mirrors!
-Fake!
-Phony!
You're wrong!
I’m a great magician!
I have just created something
from nothing. Isn't it enough?
Anybody can make a bunch of flowers.
Very well. Flowers aren't enough?
Perhaps you'd like
a few man-eating tigers!
Fat chance.
How about a pink elephant?
Wag.
Willow.
Wick!
Bugs! Let's go!
You can't throw the lady
in the air?
Come on!
Wick. Wag. Wiggle!
Wee. Wire!
Oh, how does that go?
I’ve forgotten.
I’ve forgotten
so many things.
So long, girls.
It's all right, Mr. Merlin.
They don't understand,
but I do.
I think you're the
greatest magician ever.
-I believe in you. Really.
-You do?
Thank you, my boy.
Hey, doc.
What's this supposed to be?
Him my pet!
Him pet!
A catfish for a pet?
My man, you are gazing upon the
legendary terror of the seven seas.
A genuine, bona fide sea serpent.
What's the matter with you crazy
people? All the time ''ha-ha''!
Please! Please!
You make sea serpent very mad!
If I was to catch a itty-bitty
thing like that, I’d throw it back!
I fear you do not understand, laddie.
There are certain lakes
in Switzerland
certain lochs in Scotland
which are called
the eyes of the sea.
They are so called because these
lakes and lochs are bottomless.
Aye. They extend far beneath
the surface of the land
and lead to the great
and mysterious oceans
of which they are a part.
Not unlike salmon, sea monsters,
as they're referred to
come to the lochs to breed.
I caught this one
as a wee baby myself.
It was a wee, sleeked,
cowering, timorous beastie!
That's a lot of hogwash.
Just what do you take us for?
Those lads who are fishermen
are doubtless familiar with
the species maculatus spheroides
otherwise known as the blowfish.
The blowfish is a small creature
inhabiting the depths of the sea.
Take him from those depths,
where the pressure is extreme
or into the air, where there's
little pressure
and what happens?
His eyes bulge, then
he puffs himself up
many times his natural size.
Hence the name blowfish.
So it is with the sea serpent.
In the water
he is small,
insignificant, petite.
But out of the water
and exposed to the air
and he doubles his size
every 10 seconds
until he reaches his full growth,
and no man knows how big that is.
You see what happened? He pulled
his head out of the water
it has grown huge,
and men on passing ships
have sworn they have
seen a gigantic monster.
Which explains the legends
of lurking sea serpents.
There ain't no pressure in that bowl.
Just a little water.
Show us a demonstration.
Oh, so sorry. No can do.
Look, this monster's fondest ambition
eat up Dr. Lao!
Cannot understand why.
Very bad thing.
Honorable servant probably taste
like leftover turkey!
Don't touch it.
-We just wanna take a look!
-Watch who you're pushing!
Carey!
Come on.
Step up. Step up. Step up.
Good citizens of Abalone,
you are about to see
the Medusa.
The Medusa is a third cousin
of the original Gorgon sisters
who disturbed the land of Greece
in the time before Ulysses
Agamemnon, Achilles
et cetera, et cetera
and, of course, et cetera.
And like her Gorgon sisters
she has the power to turn those who
dare to look straight into her eyes
into stone.
To spare you good people
from being converted
into monuments, obelisks
and so forth
I have rather ingeniously,
I think
made it possible for you
to see the Medusa
only in a mirror.
Thus seen, she is
harmless.
I entreat you, please be content
with the reflected image.
Do not go peeking around
the edges of the canvas.
It is a move which might produce
most unpleasant results.
She is a genuine Medusa
over 3000 years old.
She don't look a day
over 500 to me, doc.
It's a disgrace!
Now, Kate, please.
I just wanna say one thing.
Where is he?
-Where is that old faker?
-Yes, madam?
I wanna say one thing
that I never listened to such
lies in all my born days.
Snakes turning people
to stone! The idea!
Please. Don't make trouble
in front of all these people.
Shut up! I’ll say what
I darn well please.
My dear lady
the role of skeptic
becomes you not.
There are things in the world
not even the experience
of a lifetime spent
in Abalone could conceive of.
Is that so? I’m gonna make a liar
out of you in front of everybody.
Get out of my way!
I’ll show her!
All right, cheap little hussy,
you don't--
It's all right.
Pete, help me.
Arthritis attack.
She's had them before.
Hey, Luther. Did you
buy yourself a statue?
This ain't no statue. It's my Kate.
Stoned again?
She looks better that way.
-Call a doctor.
-This is the worst attack she's had.
Hocus
pocus dominocus.
Chay, Chay
Chay.
Luther.
Let's go home.
Giddap. Come on, giddap.
You see
I told you.
I told you I was a good magician.
Did you see?
Everybody go home. Circus over.
Oh, dear. Oh--
Come back tomorrow. Big finale!
Goom-bye. Come back tomorrow.
Big show.
Scram. Goom-bye. Goom-bye. Phew!
Now eat your food,
Mr. Cricket. Eat it.
You're making me angry at you.
You're a bad cricket.
Don't speak back to me.
I’m very disappointed in you.
What's the matter you?
You crazy boy.
You want mother and
grandmother to worry?
They're asleep. I snuck back out.
Dr. Lao, I wanna have
a talk with you seriously.
No. No time. Very upset.
On account of Mrs. Lindquist
turning to stone?
No. On account of cricket.
Okay. You have problem?
I need a full-time job,
and I was just wondering
if maybe you could use me
with the circus?
But I like your circus.
And I’ve always wanted to
be in the circus. I’d work hard,
and I wouldn't be any trouble.
And I can do a lot of tricks. Look.
How you do that?
Oh, that's very good. Very good.
But, Mike, we have a magician.
Confidentially, you much better.
But that make the Great Merlin
very sad. You understand?
I understand. You can't use me.
Mike, let me tell you something.
The whole world is a circus
if you know how to look at it.
The way the sun sets when you're tired
and comes up when you're on the move
that's real magic.
The way a leaf grows.
The song of the birds.
The way the desert looks at night
with the moon embracing it.
Oh, my boy, that's circus
enough for anyone.
Every time you watch a rainbow
and feel wonder in your heart.
Every time you pick up
a handful of dust
and see not the dust
but a mystery, a marvel,
there in your hand.
Every time you stop and think:
''I’m alive, and being alive
is fantastic.''
Every time such a thing happens
you're part of
the Circus of Doctor Lao.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
Well, I always say:
''If you're gonna do something,
do it right.''
You look surprised.
I am. I didn't think
Stark was this worried about us.
Well, he ain't worried no more.
What are you aiming to do?
Get drunk!
Angela!
Is that you?
Yes, Mother.
What is the matter?
Nothing, nothing.
Just that infernal music.
It makes me nervous.
What music?
Never mind, Mother.
You're perspiring.
Am I?
Are you sure there's nothing wrong?
Yes, Mother, very sure.
Go back to bed. I think
I’ll get a glass of cold water.
All right.
Do you suppose that crazy little
Chinaman had something to do with this?
Who else?
How?
We'll figure that out later.
Right now let's get to work!
What's your problem, cousin?
Where's Stark?
How are you, Ed?
Couldn't be better.
Glad to hear it.
What can I do for you, boy?
Not a thing. I thought you might
wonder about your paper.
Well, I did miss it.
No problems, I hope.
Just one.
The presses broke down.
Oh, I’m sorry to hear that.
It's all right.
They're fixed now.
A short tissue this time, but you'll
understand. Won't you, Mr. Stark?
Let's see. You're not
a subscriber, are you?
You ought to think about it.
How're you gonna know what's
happening in town without the Star?
Here's a complimentary issue.
For you too.
-So long.
-Ed.
You really think you have a chance?
Well, I was beginning to wonder.
Then something happened
that cheered me up.
You read about it on page one.
Boss, it couldn't be.
It really couldn't be!
We ruined it.
Shut up!
It ain't possible, is it?
I hate to tell you this.
There aren't any fish in that river.
In fact, there isn't any river.
That's okay. Me no use bait.
Oh, I see.
I want to thank you
for what you did.
I don't suppose you'd
tell me why or how?
What's the matter? All the time, talk!
Scare away fishie!
-Wise guy.
-Hey, Ed.
Ed, come here!
Ramsey and some of them
other fellows had a get-together
in the café.
-Well?
-They're gonna sell out to Stark.
-You sure?
-Vote's tonight. It don't look good.
They're scared.
Stark was right.
I was crazy fighting for--
Mr. Cunningham. Please.
You come to circus tonight.
May be big surprise.
I got you.
Oh, fishie!
Oh, look what Dr. Lao has! Trout!
Did you see that?
Yeah. Come on. Come on.
Ed.
It's a trout.
Big, big trout.
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen!
Welcome to the final showing
of the Circus of Dr. Lao.
Tonight we present to you what they
call in the language of France
the piece de resistance.
In the words of Philosopher Mencius,
''You ain't seen nothing yet!''
You can say that again, doc!
I’m sorry.
Hello.
You remind me of someone.
A woman I know.
Her name's Angela Benedict.
Same height. Same weight.
Same general features.
Ever meet her?
No, but I’ve heard of her.
She's supposed to be
a most unpleasant person.
Oh, no.
Now.
Whoever told you that? It's a lie.
Angela is.
Well, you see,
Angela has got a problem.
What kind of a problem?
The worst kind, same as mine.
Loneliness.
It's the worst thing
to happen to a person.
You see, people think
that Angela's hard.
People think she's cold.
But she isn't hard and she isn't cold.
She's soft and warm.
She's afraid to let anyone know.
Well, that sounds very odd to me.
No, it isn't odd at all.
I’m trying to tell you,
loneliness can do that.
Then, of course, it isn't
any of my business, but
why don't you and this person
become friends?
I mean if-- lf you're both lonely.
She doesn't like me.
And it doesn't make
any difference now.
Town we live in will be deserted
in a few weeks.
They haven't decided yet?
Just pretend they haven't.
I’m pleased to meet you, Miss--
Call me Angela.
Angela.
Beautiful name.
You were born with a great love
for humanity, Clinton Stark
but this love soon turned
to bitterness and contempt.
Why?
It's because in all your years
you've never been able to
understand that perfection exists
only as an ideal.
Who's interested in ideals?
Get the money. That's what counts.
Hold it out to the people.
They'll grab at it.
That's the truth.
There's nothing in between.
Oh, but there is.
Life is sharing.
You began with an extreme notion
of man's good
his strength and his nobility.
You ended with another extreme,
equally false.
The notion of man's evil,
his weakness and his ignobility.
Now you are involved
in proving that point.
I’m proving it pretty well, I’d say.
If you believed that
you wouldn't need
to reassure yourself every day.
Look at you now
gloating over a victory
which is a defeat.
A defeat for all the ideals
you once held sacred.
They'll vote to sell.
What have you shown
but your own greed, your own
sick hunger for self-destruction?
If they sell their town to you,
you'll realize an extensive profit
because you alone know a railroad's
planned for this area within the year.
How'd you find out?
I am Apollonius of Tyana.
Did you tell anyone?
That would have the effect
of altering the future.
Five cents, please.
Am I going to win?
Yes.
I can't figure out how he managed
to get so much into this tent.
It seems to be bigger on the inside
than it is on the outside.
-Dr. Lao is a remarkable man.
-Peanuts.
Hey! How soon's the show gonna start?
Almost instanter.
How much is peanuts?
-One penny.
-I’ll take a bag.
Out of a nickel.
Pass that up, please.
-How much is the popcorn?
-What's that?
-Popcorn's free.
Right here!
And now
on with the show!
Ride him, sonny, ride him!
Ride him, sonny.
For me?
Oh, thank you.
Nice man. A real gentleman.
He's blind.
He can't see. He can't see.
Ladies and gentlemen
the spectacle you've
been waiting for:
The Fall of the City.
I almost forgot.
Excuse very much. Excuse.
My pet.
The Loch Ness monster.
Excuse.
Excuse very much. Excuse, please.
The Fall of the City.
The city's name was Woldercan.
It existed beyond the edge
of the world
some years before the beginning
of history.
There are no records of Woldercan.
No artifacts.
No descendants of its people.
In fact, there is no proof that
there was such a place.
Yet it was as real as pain.
Citizens of Abalone, I give you
Woldercan.
It was a small city. A humble city.
Its people had little
in the way of worldly goods.
And this little made
for themselves by themselves
or euchred from the stubborn soil
or plucked from the cold
and capricious heart of the sea.
Yet the Woldercanese were content
for in the goods of the spirit
they were rich.
For them, it was enough
to partake of creation
and to give thanks unto their God.
Enough, and more.
Then one day, a stranger
appeared in Woldercan.
And he said to the people:
Not enough!
You are poor when you could be rich.
You eat of humble fare
when you could feast.
You scratch at the ground,
and the ground mocks you.
You pray to your God
and He laughs at you.
Fools. Be gone
from this blighted place.
Fools.
And suddenly people were not content.
They listened to the stranger
and sold their souls
for pieces of silver.
Then a fearful thing happened.
The God of All Life looked down
upon the people of Woldercan
and was displeased.
And he said:
Treasures I had given
thee beyond compare
yet thou didst spurn them
and for a handful of silver
sold thy souls.
And because He had been angered
God pointed His finger
and visited upon
the city of Woldercan
the greatest plague of all:
Oblivion.
The time has come
when we must decide
whether to accept
Mr. Stark's terms.
But before the final vote is taken.
I’d like to say.
Well, I’d simply like to say:
''Let your conscience be your guide.''
Would a show of hands
be satisfactory, Mr. Stark?
All right then.
All those in favor of accepting
Mr. Stark's proposal
raise your hands.
I said, ''Those in favor of accepting
Mr. Stark's proposal.''
Those against?
Citizens of Abalone, I’ve lost.
I want you to know
it's the kind of loss
I’ve wished for, a long time.
So I guess I’ve really won.
I think you ought to know
the railroad's coming
through Abalone
which means money for you.
But you've gained something
more than money, my friends.
So have I.
How it happened
I don't exactly know
but somehow
I think
we all owe a debt of gratitude
to an old Chinese faker named Lao.
Dust storm!
Well, good night.
-Good night, Tim.
-Good night.
Isn't it a beautiful night?
Oh, yes, it's beautiful.
It's getting worse!
You'd better stay a while.
How do you feel?
Wonderful. I woke up
and found out something.
Care to tell me?
Just that there's music in the air,
and that I’m a liar and worse.
I’m in love.
And I say he's a hypnotist.
Who?
That old Chinese faker.
The way I figure it, he's
got everybody hypnotized.
Dirty foreigner.
Harry, some more redeye, and fast!
What do you suppose happened
to the boss?
He turned yellow, that's what.
And I’m through with him.
You hear me? Through!
Carey, you know.
You know, I think we ought to pay
that little baldy a visit.
Yeah. Shake him up a little.
You'll see how fast them people
come to their senses.
-We'll show them who's boss.
-What about the storm?
Well, who's afraid
of an itty-bitty storm?
Carey, how come the tent
don't blow down?
He's got it hypnotized too.
He's got everything hypnotized
except us.
Let's go.
Hey, Baldy. Where are you?
Come on out, you old Chinese faker!
Hey, Carey!
Have a look.
Ruin it. Ruin it.
Hey, Carey!
Look here. The fish.
Come here.
Carey, finish him off!
Dr. Lao
open up, Dr. Lao! Hurry!
Dr. Lao! Please open up!
Dr. Lao! Please hurry!
It's Mr. Stark's men!
They're wrecking your circus!
They let your pet out.
Loch Ness monster out of tank?
Hey, look. Wait.
Okay, Mike. Oh, my pipe. My pipe.
Over there!
Lucas, don't stand there!
Help me!
Oh, please.
Be careful!
Dr. Lao!
Please! Please!
Out. Get out. Get out.
Go. Get out. Out.
Dr. Lao!
Dr. Lao, look out!
He's gonna eat you!
My pipe. My pipe!
Dr. Lao! Dr. Lao, are you all right?
I guess so.
My glasses.
My glasses!
Here my glasses.
My pet!
My pet.
Oh, I got him. Oh, I got him.
I got him. I got him. Okay.
That's show biz. Come on, Mike.
Look, the circus is gone.
Mike, I want you to tell the truth.
Honest, Mom.
I saw it with my own eyes.
It was bigger than a building.
It chased them out of town.
It was gonna eat up Dr. Lao.
But I lit the machine and it exploded,
and then it began to rain and--
This belongs to Lucas.
I recognize it.
You see. Now you
believe me, don't you?
I believe something fishy's
been going on the past couple days.
There they are.
Michael! Mike, come back here!
Mike, come back here!
Dr. Lao, Dr. Lao! Wait for me!
Mike! Michael!
Come back!
Wait for me, Dr. Lao. Wait for me.
Come back, Mike.
Wait for me, Dr. Lao!
I wonder where he came from.
Or where he's going.
Or if he was ever here at all.
I can do it. You see, Dr. Lao,
I can do it.
Look, Dr. Lao. Watch me.
I can do it!
Mike, the whole world is a circus
if you look at it the right way.
Every time you pick up
a handful of dust
and see not the dust
but a mystery, a marvel,
there in your hand.
Every time you stop and think:
''I'm alive, and being alive
is fantastic. ''
Every time such a thing happens,
Mike, you are
a part of the Circus of Doctor Lao.