Otto.
Mr. Habershaw.
-Stop him!
-Mr. Habershaw.
Stop him.
Mr. Habershaw.
You're leaving me now.
Mr. Habershaw?
Henry Drummond.
Henry Drummond. you're not leaving.
Henry!
They're here.
Come on. get back.
Come on. make room. Come on.
Mr. Buford. Howdy. Mr. Buford.
Hello. we're here. and we got
our 200 head just outside of town.
-We made it all right.
-No. you didn't.
-What are you talking about?
-We made a deal.
You said you were gonna have
them cattle in here 1 2:00 noon.
But it's only 1 2:30.
A deal is a deal.
-Mr. Buford. Please. Mr. Buford. please.
-Mr. Buford. Mr. Buford.
-Mr. Buford.
-Please. Mr. Buford.
Get back. Stand back there.
Come on. get back. Stand back.
Come on. Hey.
Back. l said. back.
Let's play cards.
We need glasses.
Whoa. pull up there.
All right. everybody out.
Everybody out.
What's happening. Sam?
Come on down. Sam.
Tell us what's happening in there.
-They're still playing.
-We know that.
What we wanna know
is who's ahead.
-Sam.
-Oh. Sam.
Toby.
Toby. did you find out anything?
-He ain't talking.
-You know Sam.
-Sam. listen.
-Sam.
Somebody's losing a lot. huh. Sam?
What's happening. Sam?
What's happening?
-They're playing.
-But who's ahead?
ls you gonna tell us old Buford's
cashing in? l don't believe it.
l didn't say nothing about Buford
or Tropp or Wilcox or nobody.
Well. say something.
How much money you figure
is on the table right now?
None of my business.
Oh. come on. Sam.
lt ain't no secret who's winning. is it?
l don't know.
l ain't in the secret business.
l'm in the hotel business.
Now. l hear you say something
about buying a drink?
No. not me.
-Sam.
-Yeah?
Oh. hi. Doc.
Who's winning?
Drummond's winning.
The stage is leaving in 1 0 minutes.
Hey. Sparrow.
Hey. Toby.
Stagecoach leaving in 1 0 minutes. folks.
for Mirando. Hebbronville...
...San lgnaba. Bustamante.
and points south.
Yes. sir. you got 1 0 minutes. one and all.
Mirando. Hebbronville. San lgnaba.
Bustamante. and all points south.
Hi. Doc.
Get out of Doc's chair.
Seriously?
l thought you'd like that.
-Hello. Chester.
-Hi.
Large whiskey.
Coming up. Doc.
Drummond was heavy winner last year.
And the year before.
Where you been. Doc?
lt ain't like you to miss the fun.
l been over the mountains
to the Hill place.
Louisa have her baby?
lt's a false alarm.
l gotta get back there tonight again.
That's a lot of riding
just for one baby.
Well. their mare's in foal too.
so l come in double handy.
l just hope they both arrive
at the same time.
Well. you'll be here for the finish
because they just got started.
-Charlie.
-Yes. Doc?
l need some portable food. Sandwich.
Anything you say.
-Drummond winning?
-Drummond's winning.
What's the news from Mclntosh?
Two new babies. one flood.
That's my news.
-What's yours? How much is he ahead?
-l don't know. it's hard to figure.
l wouldn't play poker with Henry Drummond
if his back was to a mirror.
Even if l had the money.
What do you think. Sam?
l'm not in the thinking business.
Stagecoach leaving now for Mirando.
Hebbronville. San lgnaba and Bustamante.
Give it to them. Sparrow.
Yeah. also Escobas. Randado.
Guerra and Agua Nueva...
...then turn around and back again.
See you. Sparrow.
Everybody up. Everybody on.
Last call.
Hey. Sparrow. hang on to them reins.
Yeah.
-Stay away from them cliffs. boy.
-Everybody aboard.
-Give them a comfortable ride.
-Giddyup.
So long. Sparrow.
So long. boy.
-Evening. Doc.
-Tate.
This is one fancy rig
old Ben Tropp rides around in.
Yes. it is.
Don't he give a damn what people think.
him riding around the country in a hearse?
lf you're the richest undertaker in Texas.
you're entitled to a fancy rig.
But if you spend your days and nights
trying to keep people alive...
...you ride around in the likes of this.
Giddyup.
-Hey. Sam.
-Who's winning?
Come on. Sam. Who's ahead. Sam?
Hey. they're on
their second keg of bourbon.
-lf we was you. Sam. we'd tell us.
-Yeah.
ls it Drummond?
ls Drummond still ahead?
Just tell us that much.
for the love of Pete. Say something.
How's it going. Sam?
Come on. tell us something.
Well. don't you know
something about--?
-Meredith?
-lt's all right. Mary.
Meredith. you know
you're not supposed to carry--
Sign outside says hotel.
l assume that means you have
accommodations for transients.
-You asking if we got rooms?
-One room for the three of us.
This is a cattleman's hotel. mister.
Not a family type.
The rooms we got
ain't fitting for women and children.
Please. any kind of inside accommodation
would look good to us right now.
-We've been on the road for days.
-We're very tired.
Well. top of the stairs. number 7.
That's the only room with two beds in it.
Boy can sleep in the wood box.
Unless you care for two rooms
for an extra dollar.
Another dollar?
l like to sleep in the wood box.
don't l. Mama?
One room will be fine. thank you.
-How long you fixing to stay?
-Just overnight.
We broke two spokes.
We intend to get it fixed here.
-Where could we find the blacksmith?
-End of the street.
-Thank you.
-Thank you very much.
Hey. wait a minute.
Here. sonny.
Stuff that in the wood box.
make it more comfortable.
-Say thank you. son.
-Thank you.
Sam? Sam.
Yes. sir. Mr. Wilcox.
-Three thousand.
-Three thousand. yes. sir.
Three thousand. yes. sir.
Three thousand. Mr. Wilcox.
-What's going on back there?
-Poker.
-Meredith.
-Must be a big game.
The biggest. mister. The biggest.
-ln this town?
-Yes. sir. in this town.
You just try to find a bigger game
between here and the Mississippi.
-How big is that?
-Mister...
...the five richest men in the territory
are in that backroom playing for blood.
-How often does this go on?
-Once a year.
Twelve months they've been
saving up their blood.
Meredith. let's go upstairs.
We're all very tired.
-ln a minute. Mary.
-Come now. Meredith.
-l was only gonna ask--
-l know what you were going to ask.
-What's wrong with asking?
-You know what's wrong.
So let's not talk about it.
We have things to do.
-What's the big rush?
-We've got to take that wagon to the smith.
We've got time for that.
We've got to get washed up.
then we've got to see about food.
-We've got time. we're here overnight.
-Meredith. l refuse....
-Now. Mary.
-Now. Meredith.
Who's winning. Mr. Habershaw?
Mr. Habershaw?
-What's your pleasure. Mr. Habershaw?
-Who's winning. Mr. Habershaw?
Little more of that dog hair. Sam.
You quitting the game.
Mr. Habershaw?
-Just stretching my legs.
-We hear Drummond's way ahead in there.
He's ahead. He ain't way ahead.
Game's got a way to go yet. huh?
That's right.
Excuse me. you said the blacksmith
was down the street.
You didn't say which way.
Due west to the end of the street
and turn right.
Thank you. thank you very much. Sir.
Your health. sir.
And to the queen.
and to the jack.
Thank you. sir.
Am l correct. sir. in assuming
you're one of the players in the game?
-The assumption is correct. sir.
-ls it a private game. sir?
l mean to say. sir. would you permit...
...a passing stranger
to watch for a little while?
-Meredith.
-l said watch.
Nobody who ain't in the game
gets in that room. huh. Mr. Habershaw?
Meredith--
Jackie? Jackie. come here.
Oh. Jackie. what have you got--?
Meredith. we've got to get
that wagon to the blacksmith.
We've got to leave town tomorrow.
There's a lot of work
to be done on that wheel.
All l asked the gentleman
was to be allowed to-- Mary. please.
-Mary. lookit. all l want to do is watch.
-Meredith. you promised.
Good Lord. you don't want
to deprive me of that too.
-l can't get into trouble watching.
-l never said you were going to--
Please listen. You and Jackie
drive the wagon down to the smith's.
Let me watch the game
till you get back from the blacksmith's.
-Meredith. you know very well you won't--
-This is fate. Mary. Don't you see that?
Chance to get into a game of cards
in the middle of nowhere.
The good Lord give me this one last chance
just to watch a game of cards.
There won't be any cards
on the farm. you know that.
l've given my word.
Give me this one last little concession.
l won't be breaking my word
if l just watch.
You just heard the gentleman say
they don't allow any spectators.
ls that a hard and fast rule. sir?
lf l say you can watch. you can watch.
-But if the lady objects. l wouldn't think--
-There.
lt's up to you. Mary....
Meredith. the blacksmith
may be a long time. l don't--
Give me just 1 5 minutes.
then l'll join you at the blacksmith's.
l cross my heart. Mary....
Oh. Meredith.
Jackie. you stay right here.
You stay with him every second
while l'm gone.
-Don't you let him out of your sight.
-Oh. no. Mary.
Giddyup.
ls it all right if...?
Can't we come in too?
l'm in.
Hey. who's this?
Friends of mine.
Friends of yours?
What in the hell are they doing here?
-l said they could watch.
-Otto. you know the rules.
-Yeah.
-Ain't nobody--
l said they could watch.
Cut.
Five card draw. ante 25.
You on the poker wagon. mister?
-Mister?
-What?
Oh. yes. you might
put it that way. yes.
Little woman make you give it up?
Well. we talked it over.
but it was my decision.
You open. Otto.
Twenty-five dollars.
Like to see my wife ask me to quit.
Oh. l didn't say my wife--
Can't you just see Genevieve...
...asking me to restrain myself
from a nice. friendly little game of cards?
Twenty-five. and 50 more.
How long since you've seen
that wife of yours. Denny?
Oh. l don't know.
Two. maybe three months.
You don't pay too much attention
to little old Genevieve. do you?
-You're darn tooting.
-Why should he?
Any man gets himself married
is automatically stupid.
Denny's just refusing to stay stupid.
He just don't ever see his wife.
Words of wisdom
from the confirmed bachelor.
Confirmed and reconfirmed.
l hate women.
l believe you.
You've buried enough of them.
Sure l did. l put them back
where they belong.
-Cards. Otto.
-Come on.
What's your hurry. Tropp?
You nervous l might bury you?
Get it. boys?
l'll bury him. and he's....
We get it.
-Two cards.
-Three.
Three.
Where you folks bound for?
San Antonio. San Antone.
One.
Texas.
One. and dealer takes three.
San Antone. huh?
San Antone. Texas.
Oh. that's a long way.
Fifty dollars.
ln.
We bought a place there.
Plan to do a little farming.
And 50. Ain't no such thing
as a little farming.
Yeah.
Well. what l mean.
we don't have a big place...
...a big spread. just a nice piece of land
just outside San Antone.
-How much land?
-Forty acres.
Forty acres?
What you planning to do.
raise stinkweed?
Y'all listen. listen.
One whole year
l've been honing my backside...
...to sit in on this game
and what am l doing?
Playing poker? Hell no.
l'm talking about the stinkweed crop
in San Antone. Texas.
Let's play cards.
l bet a hundred dollars.
You know what l give up
to play in this game?
-A million dollars.
-No. more than that.
More than that to me.
Mr. Big-Mouth Lawyer.
My daughter Ceely
was getting married.
-Ceely?
-That's right.
When Tropp come for me.
she was getting married.
And they're holding up the love.
honor and obey part till l get back.
You walked out in the middle
of the wedding?
l did. l ain't been late
for this game in 1 6 years...
...and l ain't about to start now.
wedding or no wedding.
l told them. l said. ''You start late.
and l may not be around for the finish.''
The groom got held up
by the flood in Baker Flats...
...so the wedding
was late getting started.
''When Tropp and Habershaw
get here.'' l said...
...''l'm walking out of this house
whether Ceely's hitched by then or not.''
Now. that's how much
this game means to me.
Do you mind if we indulge in what l left
my little girl waiting at the altar for?
Do you mind if we play a little cards?
l just raised a hundred dollars.
l don't think that's a very nice thing
to do to your daughter.
Well. look who's mealy-mouthing me
about being nice.
Old Mr. Tight-Fist-30-Percent-on-My-Money-
Or-l-Foreclose...
...Mr. Jesse Buford himself in the flesh.
Now. don't you give me
no Sunday-school lesson about being nice.
Sit up and pay attention to this game.
Now. are you gonna call
or ain't you gonna call?
Now. l got 300 United States dollars
in that pot says that l got a hand.
That's a lot of money. l fold.
l got lots more.
l come loaded for bear. not chickens.
Let's play for money.
You're the one that said it.
And 5.
Beat three deuces.
Full house beats it. l guess.
You're an expert on the rules.
Mr. Wilcox.
According to Mr. Hoyle. the rules say
that a full house beats three of a kind.
-That's what they say.
-That's what l thought.
Horse shoes.
Oh. no. Henry. l am not lucky.
l'm just skillful.
Yeah.
-Pardon me.
-Yeah. what do you want?
-You bet a hundred dollars on three twos?
-l bet the way l feel like it.
-ls this a private game?
-What does that mean?
Well. l mean.
can anybody pull up a chair?
-Papa.
-Quiet.
-Pull up a chair. huh?
-Well. now....
-We got a rule about that.
-What's that?
You can pull up a chair. all right.
if you got the price of admission.
-How much is that?
-One thousand dollars.
Cash. On the line.
Come on. deal. Otto.
Twenty-five dollars.
five-card stud. Cut.
-l've got the price of admission.
-Papa. no.
-What did you just say?
-l said l've got a thousand dollars.
You got it. go get it.
-Right away.
-Papa.
-You mustn't take that money.
-Now. don't you worry. son.
Your mama knows all about it. l told her.
She knows all about it.
l'm not taking the money. l'm just
borrowing it. that's all. Just borrowing it.
Papa.
Papa. no.
Sam.
You got a big man's drink?
Sarsaparilla or something?
-Sure.
-Pour one for the gentleman here.
ln a beer glass. if you please.
How's that. Jackie. old man.
old boy. old friend? ln a beer glass.
Step up to the bar
and have a glass of beer.
Keep your eye on him. will you?
l'll be right back.
Step up to the bar. mister.
-Sam. how about some chips?
-Count the money. Sam.
-One thousand even.
-Give him his chips.
And l thank you. Sam.
Come on. son.
l bet his wife
wouldn't give him the money.
You paid for it.
-lt's table stakes.
-l assumed as much.
-And Western rules on betting.
-Meaning?
Meaning you can't tap out
if you ain't got enough to bet.
Just bow out.
leave your money on the table.
-That's a rough game.
-lt's the game we play.
Good enough for me.
Then it's your deal. mister.
Been a long time.
Sure feels good.
Hi. son.
Wanna watch?
Wanna watch your papa buy us
another 40 acres in San Antone. Texas?
Will it take much longer?
-Sorry. ma'am. what'd you say?
-l said. will it take much longer?
This is a bigger job
than you think. ma'am.
You wanna ride that wagon for a while yet.
you better let me fix it right.
l'm obliged to you.
My pleasure. ma'am.
-Fold.
-l'm out.
Me too.
Two hundred dollars.
Beat three tens.
l got one good hand.
Why don't you wait for it?
Why keep betting on the bad ones?
-May l?
-My pleasure.
-Papa.
-Why don't you go get another drink. son?
Papa. when are you gonna stop?
Don't you ever get tired
just hanging around?
-Why don't you go upstairs?
-Hey. sonny?
Why don't you come over here
next to me?
You ain't gonna learn nothing
watching Papa.
l can see now why your old lady
made you quit this game.
Now deal.
-lsn't it time we had a new deck?
-Dealer can call for a new deck any time.
-Papa.
-Will you please be quiet?
lt's a question of averages.
-The cards are due to break for me.
-Famous last words.
Pretty good mitt he's got there. huh?
Handles them cards real good.
Yeah. just like
my old grandma used to.
Oh. he's a real expert mechanic.
Hey. ain't it great to see
an artist handle them pasteboards?
Must have had a lot of practice.
Oh. takes a lot of practice
to keep on losing the way he is.
Twenty-five dollars ante.
five-card draw.
-Otto?
-l'm in.
Oh. God.
So you were good to yourself?
He's got himself a hot one this time.
l bet he's got himself
two dandy little deuces. eh?
-Come on. Ben. Come on. Ben.
-Seventy-five dollars.
-Call.
Dealer calls. Cards?
Two.
Three.
One.
Two.
Well. now. l'll tell you something.
l'm just gonna have one little old card.
Any one of four particular ones
you got left in that deck will do.
And you. sir?
Oh. l guess l'll just sit tight.
Well. now. what do you know?
He's got himself a big one.
Why. sure he has. He said he would.
Watch out. boys.
He just might have himself five deuces.
Two hundred dollars.
What's the matter. mister?
lt ain't hot in here.
Why. sure it is.
That is. if you got four aces.
He can't have four aces. l got them.
No. you can't have four.
l got three myself.
Well. l'll call that 200.
And l raise 200.
That's $400 to you.
And you know something. mister?
You ain't got enough left
to stay in this pot.
And you know the rules.
We said Western style.
You just keep them there till l get back.
Don't let anybody see those cards.
-Hey. mister. Wait a minute. mister.
-Now. wait.
-Hey.
-Now. wait a minute.
There's nothing in the rules
about leaving in the middle of a hand.
So long as he leaves the cards here. Denny.
So long as he leaves the cards here.
Well. boy. it's a good thing
your mommy ain't here. huh?
She'd give him a what for.
What's Mama do
when Papa loses all the bacon?
She push him around some. sonny.
like a good little wife?
Who's bigger. sonny. Mama or Papa?
And who wears the pants?
Hey. wait a minute. boy.
where are you going?
Hey. boy. come back here.
What are you doing out here?
-Did anybody see those cards?
-No. Papa.
Sam.
Count it.
One thousand.
Two thousand.
-Three thousand dollars.
-No. Papa.
Quiet. Well?
Give him chips.
One...
...two...
...three thousand.
Ain't you gonna count them?
You're sure you didn't let anybody
see those cards?
Good boy. Now let's get rich.
l'm in. gentlemen. l'm in.
He just bought himself
3000 dollars' worth.
Sam.
So the big gambling man from San Antone
thinks he's got himself a hand. huh?
Well. l got some inside information for him.
l got one too.
And so have l.
-Me too.
-And me.
-Count me in.
-Sam!
Get that big box of chips
and bring them in here.
-The big box?
-You heard me.
l'll tell you now. son. you're gonna need
that $3000 to stay in this game.
Every cent of it. lt's $400 to you.
Four hundred and two.
And two.
Call.
Call. and raise two more.
Call. and 300. Henry. if you please.
And l raise 300.
That is $ 1 000 to you. sir.
-There. is that right?
-That's it. Thank you.
Thank you.
-Sorry it took so long.
-Just as long as you did a good job.
l ain't a man to boast.
but you couldn't get a better job.
-Not for $2.
-l'm sure of that.
-Good luck. ma'am.
-Thank you.
Well. all l know is
he bought himself 4000--
-Yes. ma'am?
-Thank you.
Excuse me. but have you seen
my husband and my son?
l....
No. ma'am.
-Do you think they might be upstairs?
-Well. they might be. ma'am.
l don't rightly know.
Thank you.
Excuse me for troubling you again.
but could you let me in. please?
-My husband seems to have the key.
-Why. sure thing. ma'am.
He's still in that backroom. ma'am.
They're playing cards.
Mister.
Hear what l said. mister?
Mister?
l don't think
you're paying strict attention.
What l said was.
if you wanna stay in this game...
...you better go upstairs
and get 420 more dollars out of the sock.
-lt isn't fair.
-What isn't fair?
This rule about not being able
to tap out of the game.
That's the rule. mister.
That is the rule.
Now. we told you all about it.
Well. you going upstairs?
-There's no more money upstairs.
-Now. ain't that a shame.
-Up to you. Tropp.
-Now. wait a minute.
You can't wash me out of the game.
You just can't do it.
Now. look. mister.
First rule of the game of poker...
...whether you're playing
Eastern or Western rules...
...or the kind they play at the North Pole.
is put up or shut up.
You can give me credit.
-Meredith.
-Mama.
-Stay out of this.
-Look here.
-We don't allow no woman in here.
-Listen. l've got-- l've got this.
All right. l'll give you a hundred dollars
on the watch. now you need 320 more.
ln the name of heaven.
what are you doing?
l say we ain't never allowed
no woman in here.
-Shut up.
-But she's a woman.
-That's a solid gold watch.
-lt's worth more than a hundred.
-No.
Just give me a minute.
Mary. Mary. listen.
lt's not what you think it is.
We got a chance here to earn more money
than you ever dreamed of.
ls all of our money on that table?
Have you taken every cent of it?
But l know what l'm doing.
With this hand. l can't lose.
Trust me. Mary.
you gotta trust me just this once.
-The whole 4000?
-But l haven't lost it. Mary.
lt isn't as if l'd lost it.
l'm investing it. l'm still in the game.
Mary. dear. listen to me.
l got a hand of cards here
comes to a man once in a lifetime.
You hear me? Once in a lifetime.
Trust me. you just gotta trust me.
Trust you?
Trust you? God in heaven.
how many times have l trusted you?
How many times and how many days
and how many years...
...have l trusted and trusted
and sat and waited and wept...
...while you played with cards
that couldn't lose?
But you lost. and you lost
until you got sick with losing...
...and you swore by all that was holy
that you would never play cards again.
And l trusted you. Meredith.
but look at us.
You've thrown away every cent
we've saved in this world.
All we've got is the team
and the wagon.
l'm gonna win this time.
l'm gonna win. lf l can ju--
l got a $ 700 team and wagon
l'll sell for $500.
-Meredith!
-Did you hear me?
Meredith. whatever you do.
please don't--
l got the team and wagon.
l got 1 1 wagons. Maybe two. 300 horses.
You need a team and wagon. Ben?
Jesse? Denny?
-Otto?
-Did you hear what l said?
l'll take a $200 loss
on a brand-new team and wagon.
That's a bargain. all right...
...but it ain't a bargain
unless it's something you need.
But it's a brand-new team and wagon.
We bought it--
Meredith!
Meredith.
Sam. Sam. Toby. Pete. somebody.
lt might not be such a good idea.
ma'am. to move him.
Go get Doc Scully. Get him fast.
-Get him.
-Toby.
What's the matter. Papa?
What's the matter?
Jackie. run upstairs
and get that bottle of pills.
You know the one l'm talking about?
Hurry.
Please. can someone get him
a glass of water?
-Yeah. right away. ma'am.
-Yeah. all right. everybody out.
Everybody out.
Come on now. give the man some air.
Hey. Doc. We need you. Doc.
lt's an emergency. Doc.
l'm coming.
Doc.
-Hey. Doc. answer the door.
-Come out.
Doc. we were sent for you.
We need you. Doc.
lt's an emergency.
Doc. we was sent for you.
lt's an emergency. Doc.
Come on down.
Now. you open this door.
-Come on down. Doc.
-The door's open.
Doc. get your bag.
Doc. it's an emergency.
a real emergency. There's a fella--
A man's dying. Doc.
You gotta come with us.
-Wait up now. wait up. Who's dying?
-Well. this new fella came into town.
And he got into the game.
He's playing in the game.
ln the middle of the game.
he's on the floor.
And then they call us in.
tell us to come get you.
All right. Now. calm down. now.
Calm down. let's start all over again.
Well. Doc. there's this fella. see?
And he come into town
with his wife and kid.
Here. Mama.
Oh. please.
-How many. ma'am?
-One. only one.
-Did someone bring the water?
-Water be damned.
Pardon me. ma'am.
Drink it. mister.
-Go on now. drink it.
-He's not accustomed to liquor.
-Be better for him if he was.
-Mary.
You....
Oh. darling. what is it?
What do you want me to do?
-You....
-The doc's here.
Come on. he's here. Let him in.
ln here. Doc.
All right. ma'am. Ma'am. l need room.
Will you please...?
What's this?
The heart?
How many times
has this happened before?
Madam. l haven't got time
for bedside manners.
Now answer my questions
and answer them quick.
How many times has this happened
to your husband?
Once. Only once.
He ain't breathing so good.
is he. ma'am?
Lend a hand.
Sam. where's the nearest bed?
And l don't mean upstairs.
We got no beds downstairs.
lnto the kitchen. Clear the room.
-Yeah.
-Gently. gently. you clumsy....
All right now. boys. back to the bar.
Plenty of good liquor back in the bar.
Come on now. that's it.
-Come on.
-Meredith.
-Just a minute. please.
l'd rather you didn't
come in here right now.
l'm his wife.
His wife is the last person
l want in here right now.
Be sensible and do what l say.
l'll let you in as soon as l can.
Now. you two stay here.
l may want your help.
What are you gonna do?
Whatever l can. madam.
l promise you. whatever l can.
-Doc.
-What is it?
-l just wanna ask a simple question.
-Well. what is it?
ls he gonna be able
to finish this hand?
Henry Drummond. for the love of....
Well. l was just asking.
How can you be so vile?
Now. look. lady.
you got problems. all right.
l'm sorry you got problems.
but l got problems too.
-l come a long way to play in this game.
-l'm with you. Henry.
For God's sake.
Look. a man's sick.
All right. a man's sick.
Anything l can do about that? No.
But l got a little girl sitting.
waiting for her daddy to come home...
...so she can get married.
And there's something
l can do about that. l aim to finish.
l am getting a little sick and tired of hearing
how much you give up to get here.
My daughter's wedding.
that's how much l give up.
l give up a man's life.
You gave up what?
l was defending Owney Price on a charge
of horse stealing when Tropp come for me.
l was fixing to make
my plea to the jury...
...when Ben busted in that courtroom
hollering for me.
l give you all my word l'd be ready
the minute he showed.
Did l let my duty as counsel
for the defense stand in my way?
l did not.
l left that courtroom
the minute Tropp showed.
l left Owney's head halfway in the noose
when l walked out of that courtroom.
That's what l did to play
in this game of poker.
But l ain't entirely forsook
my membership in the human race.
l ain't worrying
about a game of poker...
...while that little lady's husband
lays dying.
Well. that's the difference between
you and me. let's put it that way.
The man's gonna die.
There ain't nothing we can do about it.
So l aim to finish this pot
here and now.
And if he can't be around to finish....
What happens?
Tell her. Denny.
-We have to go by the rules. ma'am.
-What rules?
He loses the money. by default.
Oh. but that's every penny
we have in this world.
Ma'am. your husband didn't take that
into consideration.
Why should l?
You better come in. ma'am.
-How is he?
-Better come in.
Meredith.
-Mary.
-Oh. darling.
Mary. you--
-Mary. you--
-Darling. quiet.
-Mary. you....
-Please.
You....
What's he trying to tell me?
lt's my guess. ma'am...
...he's asking you
to play the hand for him.
He wants me to play the hand?
All right. ma'am.
you better get out of here now.
How do you play this game?
What'd you say. lady?
l asked you.
how do you play this game?
You mean to tell us. ma'am.
that you don't know the rules?
l've never played a game of cards
in my life.
-Sam.
-Yeah? How is he?
Doc wants the shutter
used to carry drunks.
Right.
-ls he all right?
-No change. ma'am.
Oh. what are you doing?
We're a long way
from a hospital. ma'am.
Next best thing in these parts
is my house where my equipment is.
-Now easy. boys.
-Darling. Darling.
Now. let's have
no more talking. ma'am.
-Move along. move along.
-Wait a minute. wait a minute.
l wish we could stay.
but l've got to get him to my house.
-Papa.
-Move along.
Papa.
Never mind the boy. Hurry up.
Jackie. Jackie.
-You go with your father.
-No.
Well. all right then.
you sit over in that chair.
Gentlemen. l have no choice but to continue
to play this game in my husband's place.
You're gonna what?
That money represents 1 0 years
of scrimping and saving.
lt represents our new home
in San Antonio...
...and it represents all our dreams
of a decent future for our son.
l have no choice but to protect it.
And you have no choice. gentlemen.
And what do we have to do?
You have to teach me
how to play this game.
l told you when she come in here.
But. ma'am. it takes years--
Let's not even talk about it.
lt's crazy to even talk about it.
-Pour me one. will you. Otto?
-Women.
l say let's get her out of here.
-Hold it. Ben.
-Hold what?
Hold it.
l can explain enough to the lady to clean up
the situation to everybody's satisfaction.
How in a big fat pig's eye are you
gonna clean it up to my satisfaction?
Listen carefully.
Yes?
This is the way it is.
We're all of us holding cards. see?
And we. all of us. each of us.
we think we got better cards...
...than anybody else in the game.
-You follow me. ma'am?
-Yes.
Now. we're each of us so sure
that we got the best hand...
...that we're willing to bet on it.
That is the principle
of the game. ma'am.
You make a bet
you got the best hand.
l understand.
You bet money.
Mr. Drummond is correct.
l've got $3500 on that table
that says that l've got the best hand.
Mr. Drummond here. he's got $3500
in there saying the same thing for him.
And the same goes for Mr. Tropp.
Mr. Buford and Mr. Wilcox.
Everybody at this table
is betting $3500...
...that he's got the winning hand.
Well. go on.
Everybody but your husband. that is.
That's the nub of it.
All your husband could throw in there
was $3000.
Now. he's gotta get up
another $500 to stay in...
...or he's gotta bow out of the game.
ls that clear. ma'am?
Oh. extremely clear. Mr...?
Habershaw. ma'am.
Mr. Otto Habershaw.
You left out something.
Mr. Habershaw.
Tell her what happens
even if he does raise the 500.
Tell her it ain't gonna be enough.
Because this pot's
gonna get higher and higher.
l guarantee it.
He's right. ma'am.
And my name is Drummond. ma'am.
Mr. Henry P.G. Drummond.
Well. my husband offered to sell
his gold watch and chain.
l heard him.
Maybe you heard me say.
out of the goodness of my heart...
...that l'd give him
a hundred dollars on it.
He was also offering our team
and our wagon.
Oh. any you boys wanna buy
a team and wagon?
Gentlemen all.
All such gallant gentlemen.
Yeah. we're gallant on Sunday.
This is Friday. and we're playing poker.
Now. you wanna play with us.
you ante up $500.
Now. listen. Henry.
there's no need to insult the lady.
Oh. now. look. since damn when did you
climb up on that big white horse?
Just because you're teasing yourself
with some hot ideas...
...for you and the lady after the game--
-Henry--
-Now. don't tell me.
l know you.
so don't tell me how to behave.
Once a year. l come here to play poker.
l don't come here
for a lot of sweet talk and la-di-da.
l didn't come to listen to you
shoot your big fat mouth.
Now. hold it.
Now. just a doggone minute.
None of us come here
to listen to a dogfight either.
Now. let's stick to the point.
You tell them. Denny.
And the point's very simple.
Now. you got $500
to play a man's game...
...or ain't you got $500?
lf you ain't. time's a-wasting. We wanna
get home before the rainy season.
Yeah.
Will you accept an lOU?
Ma'am. if you want credit
from a businessman...
...you have to come up
with some real security.
ls there a bank in this town?
-What was that again. ma'am?
-l asked you. is there a bank in this town?
The Cattle and Merchants Bank.
right across the street.
-Come on. Jackie.
-Ma'am.
You bowing out of this game?
l'm going to the bank.
-For what?
-For money.
From the bank?
Directly across the street.
did you say?
Lady. maybe you don't understand.
lf we don't extend you no money. credit.
how do you expect to get it from a bank?
On your team and wagon?
lt ain't that kind of a bank. lady.
lt just ain't that kind of a bank.
Come along. Jackie.
Just a minute. ma'am.
Ma'am. Ma'am...
...l don't like to be. like they say.
the lawyer for the devil...
...but you just can't walk out of this room
with them cards in your hand.
-Why not?
lt just ain't poker. that's why.
lt don't go by the rules.
You see. ma'am.
while you're out of the room...
...anything could happen. you could....
-l could cheat?
-Well. no. ma'am. What l--
Now. ma'am. l didn't say....
What l mean is. since you don't know
the rules of the game--
Now. let me tell you something.
all of you.
You may play poker for fun...
...or whatever selfish thrill
you get out of this horrid game...
...but l am playing for my life.
My life. gentlemen.
And l have no intention
of letting these cards...
...out of my possession.
My husband gave them to me.
and l am playing for him...
...and l will not relinquish these cards
for any reason whatsoever.
-Yes. ma'am. but--
-And you will not force me to.
Now. it is time for the five of you
to show one spark of human decency...
...and allow one compromise
in your silly rules.
Silly rules?
l think we can accommodate the lady
and still keep everybody happy.
Oh. he's got another suggestion.
-l have.
-What?
One of us goes to the bank with her.
You. huh?
l'd be honored.
l raise one little point of order. ma'am.
Yes?
Are you willing to turn your back
on them?
What do you mean?
Well. once you leave this room. you don't
know what they'll do with their cards.
l trust them.
Seven. eight. nine. 1 0.
A lot of money. Mrs. Craig.
My money.
Oh. Mr. Habershaw. Mr. Drummond.
Mr. Wilcox. how do you do?
And Mr. Tropp.
Game over. gentlemen?
-No.
-Not yet?
Well. then something l can do
for you. gentlemen?
The little lady you can take care of.
We come with her.
Yes. Can l help you. ma'am?
Well. l'd like very much....
Oh. you're only the teller.
l am the teller. ma'am.
l'd like very much to speak
to the manager. please.
Manager. ma'am?
We got no manager.
but what we got is Mr. Ballinger.
Mr. Ballinger is the manager.
and the assistant manager...
...and the president and the cashier
and the landlord.
Mr. Ballinger owns the bank. ma'am.
Then it's Mr. Ballinger l'd like to see.
Well. this time of day.
Mr. Ballinger's always very busy. ma'am.
Can l help you?
l'm the teller.
She wants to see Ballinger.
Well. l don't guarantee anything.
Come in.
Ballinger.
Will you come this way. please?
-You want to see me personally?
-Yes. Mr. Ballinger.
Well....
Well. well. well.
the game must be over.
lt's still going on.
We're just taking a little rest.
No rest for the wicked. Henry.
you know that.
And this is not siesta time.
This is an office.
designed for the transaction of business.
The little lady is here on business.
We come with her.
Well. all right.
Back to your cage. Fleeson.
Sit down. madam. sit down.
ls this yours?
Oh. yes. this is my son. Jackie.
Shake hands with Mr. Ballinger. son.
How do you do. how do you do?
Now then. madam. why do you...
...under the protection
of this brigade of citizens...
...insist on seeing me personally?
Well. Mr. Ballinger. you seem to be aware
of the poker game going on at the hotel.
l am.
For reasons...
...too unreasonable to go into here.
l happen to be playing in that game.
-No.
-Yes.
-ls this true. Otto?
-lt's true.
-l don't believe it.
-Oh. it's true.
All right.
l believe it. l don't approve of it.
but l believe it.
Proceed.
There's a grand total of $20.500
sitting in the middle of that table right now.
-You mean in one pot?
-Yes.
-That must be a new record. Henry.
-lt is.
Twenty thousand. five hundred dollars.
-Good heavens.
-And it's my turn to bet...
...but. you see. l don't have....
l mean. my husband and l....
Oh. how can l explain it?
We've put $4000 into that game
and l have to stay with it.
l will not be forced out of that game.
You have grit. madam.
l always admire tenacity and grit.
But just how does your desire to stick
with the game concern me and my bank?
l don't have the money
to stick with it.
l see. What collateral
do you have to offer?
On what do you propose
to borrow this money?
On this.
Well. it must be a good hand.
lsn't it a good hand?
lsn't it a very good hand of poker?
Don't you know?
No. l'm only taking
my husband's word for it.
Your husband's word?
-Well. he took sick.
-Sick?
Well. he was playing the hand.
and then he had a....
Now. please don't make me
try to explain it. because l can't.
But. now. isn't that a good hand?
Put those cards away.
young woman.
-What?
-Put them away.
-Otto. this is one of your jokes.
-No.
One of yours. Henry.
Young woman.
woman l've never seen before...
...tells me she's involved in the biggest
poker game that ever came down the pike.
That one was hard enough to swallow.
And then she tells me she wants
to borrow money from my bank...
...to stay in the game.
That's when l should have called
Mr. Fleeson...
...to have you ejected
from the premises.
What was your next unholy revelation?
You offer your poker hand
as collateral for the money.
Pelion on Ossa. madam.
Pelion on Ossa.
A quotation from the Greek poets.
lt means when you pile one mountain
on top of another...
...one horrendous glob of flummery
on top of another.
Now. young woman...
...you have the bile and the gall
to tell me you don't know about poker.
All right. the joke is over.
As for me. l'm a busy man.
-You've got it all wrong. Ballinger.
-You got me all wrong. Otto Habershaw.
At compound interest.
They didn't take the trouble to tell you.
when they put you up to this...
...that C.P. Ballinger
is the kind of man...
...who can't tolerate liquor. cards
or women. reading from left to right.
And l would appreciate it
if you and your fun-loving friends...
...would remove yourselves
from the premises.
Fleeson!
What happened? What happened?
What happened?
Ma'am?
Did you get the money. ma'am?
Huh. ma'am?
lf you'd asked us. ma'am.
we'd have told you.
lf you wanna borrow money
from C.P. Ballinger...
...you gotta at least come up
with a second mortgage.
All right. Ben. let's play cards.
Come on. Ben. she's out of the game.
lf l ain't being too nosy. ma'am...
...just what kind of collateral
did you offer Ballinger?
She asked Ballinger to lend money
on the hand she's holding.
She-- She what?
Yeah.
Hey. C.P.. how much interest would you
charge me on an inside straight?
Hey. me too. C.P. How about 6 percent
on a dandy little flush?
So it was a joke. wasn't it?
l came over to see for myself.
lt was no joke.
Then what's so funny?
lt ain't funny. C.P.
Don't tell me.
l told you before. l'll tell you again.
Ballinger. lt was no joke.
The lady meant it.
That's what these damn fools
are laughing at. if you really wanna know.
lt isn't me they're laughing at?
Hell no. C.P.
lt'd be dangerous for any man
in this room to be laughing at you.
Now. wouldn't it. C.P.?
That it would. Dennis. that it would.
With quarterly mortgage
payment time coming up.
-You. Sam Rhine.
-Yes. sir?
What'd l make you do before l gave you
the mortgage on your house?
-You made me fix the cellar.
-Correct.
Give me collateral with a solid foundation
or don't ask me for money.
Forty-six years ago...
...l started lending money
in Larry Bingham's backroom.
My first customer
was a drover named Penney.
Wanted $2 on a brindled cow
at 6 percent interest.
Said she gave 6 quarts of milk a day.
You know what l made him do?
l made him move that cow
into my backyard for a whole week.
And l watched him milk her every day.
Sure enough. she gave an average
of 6 and a half quarts a day.
So l gave him the money.
at 6 and a half percent interest.
Not only that. l kept the 60 pounds
of manure she left behind.
Show me collateral. madam.
You better make sure it's good collateral.
Forty-six years l've been lending money
on good old-fashioned principles.
And l stand here now
to tell you one and all...
...that l've never been offered
a better piece of collateral...
...than l hold in my hand
right now. Chair.
What did you say?
You heard me. Henry Drummond.
Keep them close to the vest. madam.
Close to your vest.
Nobody sees those cards
but you and C.P. Ballinger. Sam?
-Yes. sir?
-Bring some chips in here. Lots of chips.
Yes. sir.
Hold this. son.
l don't like to sweat in a new hat.
Just blues. please.
Blues are a hundred dollars apiece.
l presume.
Make it 55 to start with.
Don't go away.
Now. how much did you say
you needed to stick. madam?
She needs $500.
Five hundred.
Four. five. Now. let's play some poker.
The good old-fashioned way.
Let's you and me
and the Cattle and Merchants Bank...
...just raise the bet once again.
You gentlemen
want to stay in the game...
...you'll have to put in
another 5000 apiece.
Of course. you understand there's
the usual interest charge. 7 percent.
Make it 6.
Lend a hand. sonny.
-l've won?
-That you have. madam. That you have.
lf you don't mind. ma'am.
could l take a look at your cards?
Mr. Buford.
the game is called poker.
The lady doesn't
have to show her hand.
-You ought to read the rules sometime.
-How true.
-Sam. cash me in. l'm going home.
-Yes. sir. Mr. Wilcox.
-Home?
-Yeah. home.
To my wife.
Coming. Ben?
The Cattle and Merchants
lent you a sum total of $5500.
At 6 percent.
that makes another $330.
-Now. how did you care to pay that off?
-Oh. right now. all at once.
That's the way to do business.
Now. if l may escort you
to the lobby. madam...
...we can exchange
these chips for cash.
Oh. will it take very long?
But one minute. madam.
Only one minute.
-Well. because l want to see my husband.
-Toby...
-...get a buggy ready.
-Right away. Mr. Ballinger.
Ma'am.
lt's been a pleasure. ma'am.
A very great pleasure.
Shut up.
-To Doc Scully's you say. madam?
-Yes. and can we hurry. please?
Be there in a jiffy.
-Let's go. sonny.
-Giddyup.
-Henry.
-Yeah?
How many good women
have you met in your life?
l mean good women.
Otto?
One.
Papa. Mama!
Henry!
How was it. Pa?
Welcome home. Henry.
Welcome home.
-Mama.
-Oh. l told you he'd be back.
Hello there. Drummond.
Welcome. Mr. Drummond. Dad.
Oh. Papa. Papa. Pa.
-Who won?
-You shut up.
What'd you do. sleep in that dress?
She ain't had it off since you left. Henry.
That'd be bad luck.
All right. everybody.
let's get ready now.
Mr. Monckton. first thing.
let everybody know...
-...that Henry's home--
-Now. just a minute.
-Henry. we've got a lot to do.
-You got nothing to do till l tell you.
You. come with me.
l said. come with me.
Yes. Mr. Drummond. Dad.
Where are you going?
Well. what are you going to do?
-Mama!
-Henry.
Here.
-Sit down. Arthur.
-But l--
-l said. sit down.
-Yes. sir.
ls this chair all right?
Sir?
Thank you. Mr. Drummond.
How old are you. Arthur?
-Twenty-six. Mr. Drummond.
-Ceely's 32.
-Oh. but l can take good care of her.
-Shut up.
l'm talking.
Never interrupt when l'm talking.
-What are you marrying her for?
-What?
Stop asking questions.
l'm asking the questions.
What are you marrying her for?
Well. Mr. Drummond. Ceely and me.
we love each other--
No. you don't.
You're marrying Ceely
because your old man...
...figures it's one way
to get his hooks into my property.
l know it. he knows it.
and you know it.
Now then.
why is Ceely marrying you?
Because she love--
Because she's homely as a lemon
and just as sneaky as her old lady.
And every man sets foot
in this house needs just one look...
...to figure it ain't worth 40.000 acres
and a soft spot for the rest of his life.
ls that what you were gonna say?
-Yes. sir.
-Now you're talking sense.
Arthur. l want you to light out
of that window right there...
...and shinny down the rain pipe.
and get on my horse...
...and get the hell and gone away from us
and your old man as far as you can get.
And don't waste any time. Arthur.
There's a whole world
waiting for you out there.
Good places and bad places.
Nice people and some not so nice.
Look them all over. Arthur.
Bide your time.
And maybe somewhere. someplace.
you'll find a real woman.
A good woman.
Now get.
Why are you doing this.
Mr. Drummond?
Find one that will love. honor
and obey you. Arthur.
Find one that will comfort you
in sickness and in health.
-Get.
-Yes. sir.
Find a good one. Arthur.
Where have you been?
We've been waiting for you.
Bar was so crowded downstairs.
took me a long time to get a drink.
-Has the game started?
-Not yet.
-Ninety-four twenty.
-That's 9420 to you. C.P.
That's the stake and your raise.
And one-fifth
of the net receipts. 3300.
One-fifth of the net receipts. 3300.
That's 3300 to you. Ruby.
Thirty-three hundred to you. Doc.
And for me. and 3300 for Jackie.
How about this citizen?
Can l pick a crew
or can l pick a crew?
You can pick them. Benny.
Time for bed. big fella.
-Do l have to go to bed?
-Yeah. we gotta get up bright and early.
l promised your old man l'd get you back
to the carnival in time for church.
Now. say good night to everybody.
-Good night. Doc.
-Good night.
-Good night. Ruby.
-Good night. honey.
-Give your mama my love.
-l will.
Howdy-do?
Howdy--
How do you do. how do you do?
l want to thank you. C.P.
for cutting me in on this deal.
You were Ruby's choice.
And a very happy one. my boy.
A very happy choice indeed.
Yeah. well.
-l have just one small suggestion.
-Yeah?
l wouldn't show my face
around Laredo again if l were you.
lf any of them suspicioned
how we cheated them....
Cheat?
We didn't cheat them. we bluffed them.
That's the nature of the game.
l am shocked at you. C.P.
We may have bluffed them
with a few extra trimmings...
...but it was within
the spirit of the game.
l am horrified
that you think that we would cheat.
-No offense.
-That's not the point.
Bedtime. Jackie.
Be seeing you.
What are you gonna do
with your money?
Benny. you know Roscoe Busby?
Do l know Roscoe Busby?
Well. Roscoe come up
with a proposition....
When are you going back
to Laredo. C.P.?
Oh. tomorrow. the day after.
When do you go back. Joseph?
Who knows?
Doc?
What do you hear out there?
New Orleans? Chicago?
After 40 years of fixing their chilblains
and frostbite. bellyache and pip...
...l figure they owe me this.
They owe me a little vacation.
-Joseph.
-Yes?
You gave a great performance.
Sweet revenge. huh. C.P.?
You bet it is.
How many years ago they cheated you
in their real-estate deal?
Sixteen years it's taken me
to get my money back.
But l've got it. l've got it.
What do you intend to do
with all that money?
-Oh. you know. C.P.
-l do?
Well. we play big poker
here in Black Creek.
Ruby.
-You promised me.
-Promised what. C.P.?
You said if l got you a big stake
you'd give up poker.
l didn't say for good.
Now. you know l couldn't do that.
You gave me your solemn word.
l did not. l never did.
Ruby. you're lying again.
Ruby. Ruby. Ruby. come back here.
You know we talked this all over.
We talked. C.P.. sure.
but l never promised.
You did. You promised me
on your word of honor.
Crossed your heart and hoped you'd die
that you would never play another game.
You weren't listening.
You weren't listening. what l said--
What you said was that you would never
sit in on another poker game...
...if you came out
with a big enough stake from Laredo.
Ruby--
Ruby. listen to me.
Why do you want to bring on
those palpitations?
l'll bring on palpitations
if l feel like it.
-Ruby.
-Honey. a girl's gotta have some fun.
-Ruby. please.
-Now. C.P.
What am l supposed to do when you're
sitting in your big fat bank in Laredo...
...and l'm waiting for you
here in Black Creek?
l'm in. boys.
l only see you once every six weeks.
-Hello. Steamboat.
-Hello there. Ruby.
-Ruby.
-Quiet. C.P.
Let's play cards.
-Hello. Benny.
-Ruby.
-No limit poker?
-l assumed as much.
Western rules on betting?
Ante a hundred?
That's what l like to hear. Gentlemen?
Doc. Doc. they're playing.
So am l. my boy. So am l.
-Five-card draw.
-Ruby!
[ENGLlSH]