Oh, Wakantanka,
Great Spirit of the Sun...
source of all life, created
in violence, pleasure and pain
which then takes life
to sustain life,
continuing the eternal cycle
of life and death...
l stand humble and obedient
before you.
Make me worthy!
How many is that?
Six, Your Lordship.
Maddock.
l'm sorry.
"John."
You may address me as "John."
Yes, sir.
lt won't happen again.
You slip at least
once a day.
How many weeks have l been
dinning it into you.
Yes, Sir John.
Six, did you say?
ln a row.
That's good shootin', John.
Thank you, Maddock.
You may address me as "Joe."
Joe.
What did you say that was?
Prairie chicken.
Grouse.
Huh?
At home in England,
l'd be shooting grouse.
lt just occurred to me,
l've traveled halfway
around the world
at great expense
simply to kill
a different kind of bird.
Well, what's wrong with that
if you ain't got
nothing better to do?
Oh, l ain't, Joe.
For five years, l ain't got
nothin' better to do.
You musta picked up a lot
of beans
somewhere.
Not only beans, Joe
but family titles, family
property, family position...
all picked up,
all inherited.
Everything l ever wanted
in life l've bought,
including you three.
ln England, l looked up
to God and royalty
and down upon everybody else.
Well, what you been doin'
for five years?
Looking, Joe.
Just looking.
ln 1820, l committed
the unpardonable sin
of resigning my commission
in the Guards.
lt wasn't an earned commission
anyway.
ln my family,
it came with birth.
So, here l am...
shooting birds.
Your Northwest Territory...
it is beautiful.
Hey, Ed...
l dumped the water outta that
damned tub into his tent.
All over his tent...
And look what l found.
Oh.
Rum.
That spell "rum", don't it?
R-U-M.
Yeah.
Hey, Ed... draw.
Still drunk as coots.
l'm going to have
to talk to those two.
ln a pinch, l've known
'em to drink coal oil.
Oh... beat the drums
and sound the brass,
here come one big horse's ass.
What were you two firing at?
Nothin' in particular.
That was an accident.
Even at this range,
l'm inclined to believe you.
How long would it take us
to go back to St. Louis?
Maybe a month if,
if we don't do no more huntin'
and that wagon holds up.
We'll start in the morning.
lf the wagon breaks down,
abandon it and the team.
We'll travel by riding horses
if necessary.
ls them orders, John?
Those are orders, Maddock.
Well, you've boozed us
out of another job.
We ain't shuttin' down camp.
He guaranteed us
four months wages.
You'll get your money.
That's one thing
the dude ain't is... cheap.
Yeah, and if he runs
a little short,
his family can always
sell the "cawstle'.
Oh, l never seen such a fella.
He won't even chew tobacco.
That water's powerful cold,
Your Lordship.
Thank you, Maddock.
l can assure you l've been bred
to get used to it.
This ain't gonna be no bath.
He's goin' ice-skating.
Listen, you rum-heads,
that's enough.
We was just warnin' him.
Somethin' must have spooked him.
Coyote maybe.
Naw. He seen Tin-pan Morgan
goin' by.
Oh, my God.
Christ!
l've had enough!
You bunch of bloody bastards.
l'm not a horse!
l'm not an animal.
No! No!
Whatever the bloody hell
the name is.
Man! Man!
l am a man!
Homme, oui.
Pauvre bête. ImbêciIe.
Une fois, tu I'as eu
Ia chance. Une fois.
Pas content.
AIors maintenant peau faire
Ia grande promenade, promenade?
Qui es tu?
Amêricain? Huh?
American.
Don't be absurd.
AngIais.
AngIais?
Oui.
Merde!
Arrête. Reviens.
Eh, eh, eh, eh.
Me speak AngIais.
Good AngIais.
Well, when you address me,
would you kindly speak it?
Yes. l will speak it.
You lucky chief like angry.
You yell, make strong.
Lucky not kill.
Yes, very lucky.
l can hardly believe
my good fortune.
Who the blazes are you?
Moi. Batise.
Prisoner, five years.
Five.
Well, you speak French
in a most peculiar way.
You're not French.
Non. Sacre BIeu, non.
Papa Francais.
Blue eyes, see.
Mais maman...
Flathead lndian.
Pure. See.
Family all killed.
These lndians. These Sioux.
l can well believe it.
Did you never try to escape?
Yes.
Cut leg.
Oh, yes.
Zip.
Me try to run again...
zip, zip, other leg.
After crawl. Crawl.
Ah.
But now me very clever fellow.
Play crazy, see?
lndian don't
kill crazy man...
Crazy man no hunt, no work.
Got spirit. Wakantanka...
Good luck for village.
So you gave up.
Me give up nothing.
Nothing!
Me very clever fellow.
But you, oh...
Great important Englishman.
Yes, you go, yes.
Like fox.
Dodge hounds.
And you know what happen?
Mean, bad lnjuns out there.
Shoshone, Blackfoot,
Rikaree.
Cut off everything...
zip, zip, zip, zip, zip.
But you no man
anymore anyhow.
You workhorse for old woman.
Buffalo Cow Head.
Maybe she...
maybe she...
maybe she zip anyway...
Stallion no good for workhorse.
Everybody be happy,
except you maybe.
No, no.
No! No! No! No!
lt's rancid fat.
Don't you have any dried...
dried meat?
Batise...
What in the hell's
going on?
Black Eagle come
for Yellow Hand sister.
Sister?
l thought she was one
of his wives.
No, no. That one
Running Deer.
She is sister.
Other one is wife,
Thorn Rose.
Now, Black Eagle buy sister.
Buy her?
Yes. Marriage.
Marriage lndian way...
Must buy wife.
Very big important
for Black Eagle.
He only chief number two.
lf she have him,
he be Yellow Hand brother.
Très important.
Big trouble...
Yellow Hand say no.
Work hard, eh? Water?
Yes...
now that her son is dead,
she has no other man.
Nobody protect her.
Nobody care.
Cut off finger. Scavenge.
Come winter, she die.
Like you, one time
big grand English...
Now horse, toujours...
& Pour toujours
et tous les jours. &
Shut up!
Stop that idiotic giggling,
you bloody fool
and listen to me.
l've had enough
of your nonsense.
Now, you play your fool
to them, but not to me.
l'm going
to get out of here
and you're going
to help me.
And why l do this?
Because you want
to get out, that's why.
Now, these other lndians
around here you spoke of
we'll need a war party
to get through them.
l don't suppose
these Sioux have any guns?
What they know about guns?
Never see guns.
Must fight close.
More brave to touch enemy.
They count coup.
You look, hmm?
You like, hmm?
l have a big idea...
You marry Running Deer.
Then maybe Yellow Hand
give you war party...
All that for you,
grand white gentleman.
She say no
to Black Eagle
and give herself
away to horse.
Hey, but, ah, you got mane.
Not even old squaw
kiss hair on face.
l have a lot to learn, Batise,
and you are going to teach me.
Give them to your mother.
For her with my compliments.
l didn't think that giving
flowers was so humorous.
Um...
l'm sorry.
Me make love to her?
Good God! No.
Batise! Batise...
What is this about her shoe?
What is she
trying to tell me?
She say she have no hole
in her moccasin.
What the hell is
that supposed to mean?