Whoa, boy.
Go on, yah!
Giddup!
There you are -
three lovely ladies.
You sure fell into it tonightl
Beats me. Deal me out.
Quitting early, Henry? On a night
like this, you're better off here.
I can't afford it.
Business is bad lately.
Never thought about an undertaker
having business worries.
He's bound to get a soul
sooner or later!
You look as if
you might be next!
Play again?
- I'll sure try.
There you are, gentlemen.
Stage team -
they just come in.
Just the team, huh? No stage?
Si, senor. No stage.
Somebody there. I can’t make him out.
Leave it to me. I'll check into it.
Huh!
Well, I am acting sheriff now,
ain't I?
Sure, Jim.
We just don’t want you to get hurt.
But if it's only horses
you're investigating...
I can take care
of a darn sight more than horses!
Maybanks, Dorfman, Kincaid, go round
the post office. You, come with me.
I can't believe it.
How could you do it?
The woman snatched the scarf from
my face and they all recognised me.
We had to finish it. Oh!
Nobody meant it to go that far,
but it's done.
Where are your men? I sent them
back to the ranch, like you told me.
They won't talk - they know better.
I can't stand to think about it -
a little child and her mother!
The whole territory'll be down here.
Don't worry, Luke.
They'll figure Apaches did it.
Apaches take scalps.
You could go back and scalp 'em.
You got $63,000 there.
You can give me my share now.
I'm getting out.
Give Clantin my share, too.
He'll need to go
a long way to forget.
I wouldn't do that, Luke.
We're in this together.
I'm not so sure.
I want no part of this... What's
the sheriff going to do?
We’ll take care of that
when the time comes.
Who's there?
He's in the bank.
- Who's there?
Mr Stanley?
- Yes.
Did you get him?
- No, he got away.
He shot Anderson
and might have held up the stage.
He came in riding one of
the stage horses. It’s likely, then.
He's killed Luke Joiner. No! Not
Luke! He won't get far in this storm.
Get after him.
I'll join you as soon as I can.
We'd better not be seen together
for a few days. Just as you say.
You know, he couldn't have come at
a better time. I wonder who he was.
Come on!
There's nothing there. Come on!
It's no use. You can't see ten feet
in this storm.
Anybody get a look at him?
Anderson.
He hasn’t come to yet.
He wasn't much of a deputy anyway.
Don't worry,
we'll find him in the morning.
It shouldn't be difficult
to find one man.
And when we do find him,
I want to deal with him myself.
Luke Joiner
was the best friend I had.
What could have happened to the
stage? We’re all anxious about that.
This man we're looking for
probably knows the answer.
How are you today, Betsey,
with seven little kittens?
Huh? What shall I name them?
Doh, Re, Mi, after the seven notes?
Or after the seven days of the week?
You're not the Seven Wonders
of the World!
"As I was going to St Ives,
I met a man with seven wives.
"Each wife had seven cats.
Each cat had seven kits.
"Kits, cats, man and wives.
"How many were going to St Ives?"
What are you doing here?
I’m on my way out, ma'am.
Who are you?
I didn't say.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
I’m relieved to hear it.
Why did you come in this house?
Didn't you see the flag?
I came in by the cellar door.
You couldn't. There must be
two feet of sand on the cellar door.
- Not last night.
You've been here all night?
I slept in the wood pile. I'm
obliged to you for a jar of peaches.
Did you like them?
I never tasted better.
I think you'd better go now.
With your kind permission, ma'am.
Oh...
it was 400,
wherever they were going. Who?
The man with seven wives
and the cats and kits. 400.
To St Ives? Oh, no - only one.
You said the man had seven wives,
each wife had seven cats...
But I met them.
They were COMING from St Ives.
That makes only one - me -
going TO St Ives.
Correct, ma'am.
Goodbye.
Whoa.
There's a man outside. Who is it?
Dr Mason, probably.
We have yellow fever here.
I'll wait in here.
You’re on the run, aren’t you?
How do you know I'll protect you?
I'll leave that
to your good judgment, ma'am.
Morning, Nadine. Morning. I thought
the town would blow away last night.
How's the sheriff this morning?
His temperature seems much higher.
Well, let’s have a look.
It's a mild type of yellow fever,
but that's bad enough.
I'll send over some medicine, but
he'll still need constant attention.
Thank you. Have you slept in the
last four days? I'll be all right.
Everyone's afraid
to come over and help you.
I don't need any help. Nadine,
do you have any coffee made?
Yes, there's some on the stove.
Thank you, dear.
It's been a bad night, Nadine.
I wish your father wasn't laid up.
Has anything happened?
A man tried to rob the bank.
Killed Luke Joiner.
Shot him in the back. Same man shot
Anderson, but he’ll pull through.
The whole town's out looking for
him. They haven’t found him yet?
No.
Was it... somebody around here,
or a stranger? Anderson's the only
one who saw him and he can't talk.
Then he's still in town?
Must be.
He couldn't get very far on foot.
There aren't any horses.
Someone ran out the front door!
Lock the door. Don't open up for
anyone but me. And keep a gun handy.
Keep quiet.
I thought you were in a hurry to go.
Who’s in this house besides you?
Go - there's nobody stopping you.
Who else is here? Just my father.
And he's... I know. I heard what
the doctor said. Then will you go?
No. I'm better off
in the sheriff's house for now.
With yellow fever?
- I'll take my chances.
Water... Want some water...
Oh, Dad!
Water.
Want some water.
Need...
...water. Want some water.
Get me a pan of fresh water
and some towels... Well, go onl
He's asleep? For a little while.
Did he say anything
while I was gone? What?
Sometimes when he's delirious
he starts talking.
Oh, they all do.
It didn't make any sense. Oh.
You're better than I am. Maybe I’ve
seen more sickness than you have.
Do you think it's out of my line?
If what the doctor said was true.
It was, as far as it went. It's a
right unfriendly town you live in.
So you WERE in the bank. Why do you
want to wear your father's badge?
The clothes in the trunk downstairs
would be a lot more becoming.
I didn't know you saw me.
I'm afraid I couldn't help it.
It looked pretty good.
Don't think I'll keep quiet
when they come looking for you.
I need water.
Get some water.
Take it easy - you're choking him.
Go ahead - give him some.
Lift his head.
Just leading you out of temptation.
I wish you'd go now.
- It's not politeness that's keeping me.
Are you sure you can describe him?
Well, I looked him over real good!
Try and get a sketch
for the newspaper. Go ahead.
Well, he was tall.
Oh... 6ft 4in, maybe.
He had a mean face
and little, beady eyes.
What colour?
- Black.
Mm-hm. Hair?
Black, too.
Long and stringy.
That look anything like him?
Sure does.
Sure - it fits him to a T.
Not often you get such a detailed
description to work on.
I always try
to keep my eyes open.
Let's find him.
Should be easy
now we know what he looks like.
Mm-hm.
I helped myself to some coffee.
There's bacon and eggs
if you're hungry.
I helped myself to those, too.
20 dollars. For bacon and eggs?
And a night’s lodging.
This isn't a boarding house. Well,
drop it in the church collection.
You do it.
Or do you ever go to church?
Believe it or not, I once sang in a
choir. Must’ve been a long time ago.
It was.
Might have been better
if you'd kept it up. Yeah, it might.
What made you stop?
Oh, you grow up. Things happen.
What kind of things?
Are you still wondering
if I shot that man in the bank?
Did you?
No.
Your father uses good shaving soap.
I gave it to him for Christmas.
Why are you hiding? Half the town’s
out taking shots at me.
If you're not guilty,
why not give yourself up?
Because my name
happens to be Wes Steele.
WESLEY Steele?
Yeah.
I never met a notorious outlaw
before. Now, wait a minute.
I'm not an outlaw. But I didn't know
my reputation had travelled so far.
You underestimate your reputation.
How does a man like you become
a gunman? It’s easy once it starts.
You learn to handle a gun better
than anybody else. Quite an art.
It's one that some people never
master. They’re just as well off.
My father wasn't.
He was what you'd call
an educated man.
He thought
you should reason with people.
Your father was right.
A gun killed him.
I made up my mind
that wouldn't happen to me.
So YOU do the killing.
There isn’t always a choice.
Fellas try and prove you're not as
good as they are. Soon it's out of
hand and you have to shoot to live.
And it was always you that lived.
So far.
Nadine.
Nadine!
Go ahead. Answer it.
Did he come back? No-one’s come
since you left. I was worried
about you. How’s Mr Anderson?
He'll be all right, but...
What is it, Doctor?
They sent out a search party
for the stage.
The stage?
All dead.
Five people. Elizabeth Nelson
and her little girl. Oh, no!
That man must be gun crazy!
I wish your father could take over.
Are you sure it's the same man?
Who else? It could be Apaches.
No, it's robbery
and cold-blooded murder.
I ought to leave a man here, but...
No, I'll be all right.
Then keep your gun handy.
If he shows up, don't ask questions.
Shoot to kill.
Something wrong, Nadine?
No, it's Elizabeth Nelson
and her little girl.
Yes, I know.
All right.
I had nothing to do with that stage.
Then who did? Who could have done it?
I don't know.
They were so sure.
- They want to be sure.
Like that deputy. No questions -
just shoot. Can't blame him.
I'll give you until dark.
Just until dark.
Nadine!
There's eggs and milk
and medicine the doctor sent.
That sandstorm was awful!
Thank you, Mrs Maule.
There's a paper there, too. They're
getting together a BIG posse.
That's good.
There are guards posted at the pass.
He's going to pay for this with his
mortal life. Well, I gotta get back.
They're searching Mexican Town
and likely he's there.
Too bad you won't see him
when he's caught.
Nadine!
Water!
Water.
Nadine...
I wish you wouldn't walk so easy!
This coffee's pretty muddy.
This eggshell will clear it.
I want to thank you for last night.
- That's all right.
I fell fast asleep. I didn't mean to.
I couldn't help it.
I don't wonder.
You shouldn't have stayed here.
You don't look anything like that
picture in the paper.
I hope not!
What about the picture of the man
killed in the bank - Luke Joiner?
- What do you mean?
Was that a good likeness?
Yes.
Then he was the man I saw
in the bank. He took a shot at me.
And you didn't shoot back?
No.
- Then who could have killed him?
The only other man with him was...
But it couldn't have been him.
Who?
Mr Stanley.
Who's he?
- Mr Joiner's partner.
Oh.
That's the doctor.
Go ahead. I'll wait in the cellar.
- All right.
Morning, Nadine.
- Morning.
The doctor's gone. My father's awake.
He should be up in a day or so.
Then I guess I'll be going, too.
The roads are blocked.
Everyone has a gun.
They're looking for the man in that
picture in the newspaper - not me.
Well, at least wait
until it gets dark.
When you leave, where will you go?
One place is as good as another.
I'm getting kinda tired
of running away. But...
But where will you go?
I don't know. Anywhere where Wesley
Steele is a name, not a reputation.
Is that all you're running
away from? A reputation?
It can get too big
for a man to live with.
Where did you get that money?
I didn't get it from the stagecoach
nor from the bank.
Then how did you get it?
Suppose I told you I had a little
spread and I sold it - that I came
by it honestly. What would you do?
What would you do? Nothing.
Suppose I told you I stole it.
What would you do?
I said, "What would you do?"
Nothing.
What are YOU running away from?
I'm not running away from anything.
You don’t have to get on a horse
and ride 1,000 miles to run away.
You could run away right down
a flight of cellar steps.
Silk. Linens.
That little jar
you put rose petals in.
It's my hope chest.
Yeah, I've heard of 'em.
But why do you hide it,
here in the cellar?
You’re being too personal.
Oh.
Well, forget it.
I suppose it's only fair.
It's my father -
it made him unhappy when I got it.
So you hide it down here because
he didn’t want you to grow up.
He's done everything for me. Mm-hm.
Except let you grow into a woman.
I am grown-up.
Are you?
All right, boys. Place these two
at the centre of the altar.
Let's go out and find him!
Just a moment, friends.
The Bible tells us,
"Vengeance is Mine. I will repay."
But I declare each of us may justly
be an instrument of punishment
for such cold-blooded work as this.
It is a crime, not only
against these silent victims
but every member of this community.
Tomorrow morning,
when the minister comes,
we will commit these lost ones
to the earth.
But our duty to them will not be
done until this killer is destroyed.
A watch will be kept
in the church all night.
It is only fitting, for the sake of
my friend and partner, Luke Joiner,
for me to take the first hour.
Every trail, every pass is guarded.
This man must not get away alive.
If he is found,
report to me at once,
and justice will be swift...
and final.
Who's there?
I understood this watch hour
was to be private.
Something you want?
You.
Who are you?
My name is Wesley Steele.
A long way from home,
aren't you, Steele?
Oh - then you know about me.
No, not exactly.
Quite a picture of me
in the newspaper.
I'm the man you're looking for.
You're mistaken.
We're not looking for you.
I shot your deputy. I'm the man
your partner shot at in the bank.
Remember your partner, don't you?
You were behind him when
he was killed. RIGHT behind him.
We have nothing against you, Steele.
You can ride out of town tonight.
Ride out with me and my men and go.
I wouldn't ride with a man
who shot his partner in the back.
And that's not all
you've got to answer for.
You must be out of your head.
You've got no quarrel with me.
If you think I was involved with
the stage holdup... I know you were.
I heard you talking it over.
The gun that killed the little girl
was working for you.
Any man's got a quarrel with you.
I... I won't draw.
I'm no gunman.
I won't draw.
I'd hate to turn my back.
I won't draw. I...
I'm dropping my gun.
Go on.
Get out!
Go on, get out!
You can't shoot an unarmed man.
No, but I can beat you to death.
Get up!
Where have you been?
Church meeting.
First time in years.
Oh... you're hurt.
Had a fight.
Is your father still asleep?
Let me help you - please.
Come into the kitchen.
Did anyone see you come in here?
Not as far as I know.
Who were you fighting with? Stanley.
Stanley?
He was in back of it all - Joiner,
the stagecoach, all of it.
The coach?
That's why I got him.
Because of that child.
Oh... That little ch...
Oh, Wes!
What is it, Doctor?
A slight concussion. He'll be
all right with plenty of rest.
Does your father know he's here?
No. Everybody else does.
Clantin saw him leave the church
and head up your front steps.
Must've been after he tangled with
Stanley. You know about that, too?
I just treated him. Mr Stanley?
Then he isn't...
He's all right.
Steele didn’t kill him.
He didn’t kill those others, either.
How do you know? I just know.
Don't open the door.
They’ll only break it down.
You stay with him. I'll go.
Don't tell them.
We know he's here, Doc.
Who do you want?
Who do you think?
You know who.
The killer.
The man here
doesn't fit Anderson's description.
Mason, the man we want is in
this house and we're gonna take him.
You can't have him now.
Why not?
Who says we can’t?
I say it. He has yellow fever.
He's lyin'.
If you think so,
step in and stand near his bed.
We'll take him anyhow.
He won't be sick long.
Out of the way.
I can shoot him from the door.
Get off this porch.
She won’t shoot.
Let’s drag him out!
Nadine!
What's that?
I'll kill the next one.
Now get out, all of you!
Nadine!
You're being a fool, Nadine.
In more ways than one.
- Get out!
And stay out!
What's going on here?
Nadine's hiding a murderer.
Wesley Steele.
Steele? Here?
He's killed six people.
I saw him go in this house.
Wait a minute. Just hold on.
I'll handle this.
Go on inside the house.
You men wait right here.
He took care of you when he might
have got away. That's why he's here.
You through now?
Do you think you can make me
believe that Wes Steele risked his
neck just to nurse me, the sheriff?
You were raised different than that.
Don't try to lie to me.
How long's he been in my house?
Where have you been hiding him?
Carrying on behind my back
while I was sick!
Your mind's dirty!
Like that mob out there!
You do that again and I'll kill you.
So help me God, l'll kill you!
She means it, Gil.
She loves him.
Gil, doctors take an oath
as well as sheriffs.
There's a reason for both.
I save lives,
no matter what I think about a man.
That's why I said
he had yellow fever.
And you're bound to uphold the law
by due process,
to protect an accused man from mob
violence, no matter what you think.
That principle's more important
than that man, Nadine, or me or you.
You can't give him to that mob.
I think Gil
will do the right thing.
He never has before.
You men all know
I've been down with the fever.
Otherwise
this wouldn't have happened.
No-one blames you, Gil. Turn that
killer over to us and go back to bed.
I'll make up my own mind about that.
-  Do it now for your own good.
I'll decide what's good for me
without help from you.
But he's a very
dangerous man.
I'll still handle him myself.
You won't let us have him?
No.
Henry, go to my office and get
me a set of leg irons and shackles.
This gunman won't be leaving here.
You can bank on that.
Do you want some water?
You let them put chains on me?
I couldn't stop it.
They've got my name on a rope,
haven't they?
Wes, can you talk a little?
Yes, to you, honey.
Stanley’s alive.
I'm so glad he didn't die.
Well, if he'd died,
we never could clear you.
You think my word
against his'll do it?
He's got this town in his hands -
you know that.
Can you give me some of this water?
What is it? Drink it down.
Try and sleep. You'll feel better.
Find what you're looking for?
What WERE you looking for?
I know Stanley has
this town in his hand.
I didn't think he had Gil Corrigan
there. What makes you think he has?
You said things in your delirium
you never would have said otherwise.
What a man says when he's sick
means nothing.
That's what I thought at first and
what I tried to make myself believe.
But now I know better.
The sheriff in this town gets
his house free and $110 a month.
How much have you been able to save?
Some. As much as I could.
Not this much.
Stanley came to Macer six years ago.
We were poor then - remember?
Real poor.
Well, we're not poor any more.
Who put these kind of notions
in your head?
That saddle-tramp killer?
A man who would shoot
another man in the back - and did?
Who shot a deputy the minute he hit
town? You'd take advice from him?
Why not mention the people on the
stage he's supposed to have killed?
Well? Why don't you?
Why don't you?
How do you know he didn't?
He’s not that kind of man.
I don't believe you are, either. You
know where I was when that happened.
But not when the Trinidad Bank was
held up. And the Bonded Stage Line.
And the assay office in New Eldorado.
You didn't solve those, did you?
Nobody was killed in any of them.
I don't hold with killing, Nadine.
Then don't let them kill Wes Steele.
He'll have his day in court.
He’ll have five minutes if he gets
that far, and you know it.
Wes Steele’s a gunman. He’s killed
in Texas and he’s killed here.
I don't set myself up
as judge and jury, like you.
All I can do is turn him over to the
court as soon as he's able to walk.
I've tried to raise you
the best way I could,
to make you happy, to teach you the
difference between right and wrong.
Then, when I can't help myself, you
get taken in by this saddle tramp.
He's poisoned your mind and your
heart, too, against your own father.
If I catch you in another low trick
like this, I'll kill him myself.
He won't sneak into another man's
home and ruin it - do you hear me?
I hear. You taught me the difference
between right and wrong.
You knew it once. Well, I haven't
forgotten. You don’t understand.
I understand more than you think.
I'm not a child any more.
You heard what I said!
Ah, Dr Mason. Join me for a drink?
Thank you. Don’t care if I do.
How's your star patient getting on?
Better than I expected.
He'll be out tomorrow.
He’ll be as good as ever?
It seems my diagnosis
of yellow fever was a little hasty.
Thank you, gentlemen.
You hear that, Judge?
How's that?
Wes Steele
can stand trial tomorrow.
That's why I'm here, sir!
Bring your men. Meet me at the bank.
Seems like a waste of soap.
Don't say that. It's not very funny.
No, I guess it isn’t.
I'm not used to chains. It's the
first time in my life and I hate it.
Wes, I've searched everywhere for
the keys. I don't know what to do.
Don't cry, Nadine.
I've had a good life
and I've lived it - all of it.
But being Wes Steele,
I knew it might end any minute.
Of course, I'd like to live
100 years if I could live with you.
But, if it's going to be tomorrow,
well, don't let it worry you
too much.
A better man will come for you yet.
In Wes Steele’s hand,
that gun could kill five men.
I'd have to be the first.
Nobody gave Elizabeth Nelson
a chance. That’s not my fault.
You're going to let them hang Wes
for those killings.
How can I stop them? Tell them
what you and Stanley have been up to.
Tell them the truth.
You'd sell me out for a stranger?
You sold yourself out, Dad.
I won't try to justify what I've
done, but maybe I can tell you why.
This is hard country.
It killed your mother, and I had
to sit there and watch her die.
She was as young
and as pretty as you, once.
As young and as fine.
We had high hopes and big dreams,
but none of 'em came true.
Not a one.
The first year we were married,
all the wells on the ranch went dry.
Not a windmill turned for 240 days.
Cattle broke into the yard
and just stood there,
bawling for water.
But we didn't have any.
We sat, praying for rain
and watching them die one by one -
one thousand head.
I still hear those cattle
in my sleep!
We lost the ranch, moved into town
and you were born.
I went to Phoenix and worked on the
new railroad for six cents an hour.
And when I came home, I found
your mother taking in washing,
so thin, gaunt and sick
I hardly knew her.
It was too late to make things right
for her, but not too late for you.
You know how it is here, Nadine -
hot and dry and dirty and dusty.
Can't grow crops. Half the time
you can hardly raise cattle.
It's dog eat dog. It's the only way
a man can get along.
Back East, they talk about
how wonderful the West is,
how you can get rich overnight.
Just throw out a handful of seed
or pick up some gold
from a stream bed.
Folks'll tell you that
who've never seen the West,
at least, never seen what I have.
Back East they have different ideas.
They'd say it's wrong for a sheriff
to make a deal
with a man like Stanley.
It IS wrong.
I had to live!
You had to live!
You were only two years old
when your mother died.
I promised myself then you'd never
know a hungry day or a cold night.
So far, I’ve kept that promise,
Nadine.
I mean to go on keeping it. I don't
know how, exactly. But giving Steele
that gun won't make things right.
Go on, honey.
You'd better get some sleep.
I'll figure something out.
I'll figure something.
Steele? I’m not asleep.
Hold out your hands.
So I run and get shot
trying to escape, huh?
Strap this on and get your hat.
It’s almost daylight.
You're taking a chance,
giving me a gun. I guess not.
I'm gonna kill Stanley. You won’t
see him. You sure of that? Be quiet.
Nadine's asleep. Stanley’s in back
of these killings. You know that.
What I know is my business.
Come on - through the cellar door.
Over that ridge you'll pick up
the old army road to the Colorado.
It's Apache country.
They’ll know you’ve turned me loose.
Let me worry about that.
I'm thinking about Nadine.
...So am I.
I'll be coming back for her.
No, you won’t.
Not if you care about her.
Nadine has good stuff in her.
Maybe not from me, but it's there.
I want her to marry a man with more
prospect of life than you've got.
Where have you been?
Where is he?
He's gone.
You turned him loose?!
I don't believe
he did those killings.
That's for the court to decide, Gil.
I’ve decided already.
That man's got to be brought back.
They'll try and make you tell
where he went.
They might.
Let's get out of here - now.
There's nothing to run away from,
Nadine.
Hey!
Is that the tree? Yeah.
Boy!
If this man is able to stand trial,
we shall proceed with it.
Here comes Dr Mason.
Corrigan let him go. You’re joking!
He's gone. Why should he do that?
I can’t say. You must know! There’s
something between Nadine and Steele.
You don't know.
We’ll find out from Corrigan.
You'd better go out there and quiet
those people down. What can I do?
They'll listen to you. They won’t
listen to anyone. Gil's your friend.
So was Luke Joiner.
You've been drinking too much.
If you won’t... Judge?
There'll be no lynching.
Ortega -
go out and help. Sheriff?
What are you doing?
I'm gonna throw up.
GENERAL HUBBUB DROWNS SPEECH
You should've kept riding with Wes.
I live here, Nadine.
Didn't take them long.
Where is he, Gil?
They say you
turned him loose.
He didn't kill... You let him go
because he’s carrying on
with that daughter of yours!
Dad!
Hang him!
Put a rope round his neck!
You can't do this!
Serves you right!
They're lynching Gil Corrigan.
You must stop them! Do something!
There's nothing I can do. We must
get the sheriff away from that mob!
Besides, he knows where Steele is.
He’d only lie to us.
Looks like he's in with Steele.
I don’t, I WON'T believe it!
Stanley thinks
we should string him up!
Tell Stanley to come out and
give his orders to me. Who are you?
Wes Steele.
Turn that man loose.
I'll kill the first man
that goes for his gun.
That's far enough! I can hit
a lot of you before I go down.
You with the rope - take it off.
Take it off!
Untie his hands.
Let him go.
This is a rotten town. But for once,
you're gonna listen to the truth.
The man who did the killings
works for one of your most
distinguished citizens.
Get out there and gun him down!
Stanley, come out and tell us how
you shot Luke Joiner in the back!
Come out, Stanley!
Come on, Stanley, and deny it!
Go on - get out there!
I'll go.
Steele’s telling the truth.
I know - I work for Stanley.
Clantin - look at me.
GIL: I'll blow you to pieces,
Stanley.
Drop it.
You're forgetting, Corrigan.
You're in this as much as I am.
Am I? It's gonna be your word
against mine. I'll take my chances.
Come on.
Hey, you - out.
Lucas, Turner -
take these two and lock them up.
You'd better go with Steele, honey.
What about you?
I'll stay here.
Don't worry, I'll be all right.
I'm not leaving you.
There's no life for you here.
This is a rotten town.
Wherever you go has to be better.
- She's not going anywhere with me.
I'm not leaving. Who knows
if this place is any worse
than the next one I hit?
From the look of it, it has a good
chance of being better. I'm staying.
Let's go home.