Get down, you!
No, no!
Well, where is he?
For her we had to waste the whole day?
I heard Willer was supposed
to be coming this way.
He must have been taking the
trail west. Let's go.
That may be, but
we ain't taking you along.
My father don't wanna hear any more
stories, okay? Now find that bastard!
Hey, here they are! Here they are!
I can see them!
They're coming! They're coming!
Hey, girls!
Alright, goon.
You, move it! Brlng the beer!
And you, fill up those glasses!
Let's make these boys
feel welcome! Ladies...
They're coming!
Put a smile on your face!
Hurry, hurry, hurry,
come and see the mermaid!
The only living mermaid!
She's the eighth wonder of the world!
Half woman, half fish!
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
She is like no other mermaid
you've ever seen before!
Let go of me!
I saw her first, let go!
No, me!
I mean it!
Three jacks.
Three aces.
Are you playing, pal?
Yeah.
You shouldn't play that hand.
Oh, it's you! Find a chair, and sit down.
It's more than likely that
this man is stealing your money.
What do you mean?
Well, I'm only stating an opinion.
Well, you know what? Nobody asked you.
No sir, not really.
Okay, mister, I'm busy.
I'd better be moving on,
because you know how it is,
you just might have
an ace up your sleeve--
I got no gun, mister.
Well, what's this?
The very ace I was talking about.
Harry, what did you do that for?
Come on, Harry!
Watch your head!
You stay right where you are!
And you, why don't you buy
yourself a gun?
I can 't shoot.
So learn!
It's easier said than done. Watch?
See what happens to my hands?
It's always been like that.
Got delicate nerves,
that's your trouble.
Here, try this.
That's murder!
Where did you get it?
I have my little means...
Maybe you should stick to fire,
rather than fool around with poker.
What if I hadn't been there?
Well, now you don't ask me
things that I...
l'm not as innocent as all that. But,
mister, you didn't tell me your name yet.
Tim. Just how much did you lose?
A drop in the ocean, Tim.
Here, I still got this...
A little bag of gold.
You'd better look around and
find a good place to store it.
The bag is safe.
They'll find it. Do you think your drawer
is any kind of protection?
Well, do you know of a place?
A good old bank. Walk in, deposit it,
they give you a receipt.
That's the best way.
Anybody you know
have a bank, Harry?
No, unless you have?
In Pueblo City there's one.
I'll set you up.
No! l've never been in a bank,
and I feel just a little fear to go.
Are we too late?
Sorry, gents, the show is all over!
For a dollar?
It starts again!
But, tell me, how were
they able to catch her?
I don't know. With a line and a pole...
If she gets married, does she have to
get into his bed or...
is he getting into that tank?
Well, he'll have to get in there.
I mean... she can't stay
outside of the water.
Am I right!
A fish! Pure and simple!
Convinced? They have a special place...
Everything has its place.
Oh yes, that's true!
Even a sack of gold...
Gold...
In a bank...
Ah...
Ah yes, I'd better be going back. Listen:
I wouldn't try to influence you.
You go to bed and sleep on lt.
If in the morning you decilde to do it,
come on to Pueblo City. I'll be there.
Hey, mister! ls this here Pueblo City?
Are you sure?
Guess I ought to know. I am the sheriff,
and I youldn't be here
if I didn't know where I was!
You're right.
Looking for someone?
They're all working in the fields.
Trying to find something?
You're doing the right thing.
I've seen some poor, towns,
but this is the worst I've seen yet.
First impression. It's got potential,
and it will be the prettiest
little town in the whole state.
Business naturally is slow now,
but if you just wait in that chair,
you'd get to see it with your own eyes.
- No!
- Yeah.
Where is that bank
you were talking about?
Eh, over there.
That?
That's the only one there is.
After you.
I give three percent interest,
that's all.
Is that okay, three percent?
Is what okay?
You deposit the gold...
...and when you take it out,
you get some more.
More gold?
Alright there, you wanna make this
deposit or not? I ain't got all day!
I'm sorry, Harry,
but you should be more careful.
Now banks, they got vaults, don't they?
Of course, a bank always has a vault.
But I won't show you, young man.
I don't believe it:
He wants to see that vault.
Nobody gets to see our vault!
He's a banker, ain't he?
Thirteen ounces,
or value 673.00 US dollars.
You'll bee needing that receipt.
Well, thanks, and good day.
At your service, gentlemen.
And you? Where are you headed?
Ohl, I'll just ramble.
I think I'll get a pole and some line.
A pole!
Yeah, I get it! The fish lady.
Hey Tim, I hope she takes the line!
Hey, honey, how about it?
We're paving guests!
We want to eat!
If she laughs again, l'll plaster her.
This won't cut.
We got nothing better.
Hey, she's right. It does cut...
Take it away.
Hey, bring me another knife...
You boys just see that you get him...
just a minute.
I'm gonna find that sugar-tongued rat,
no matter how long it takes.
When I get my hands on him, I'll...
Tell me where they went! The fish!
Where was she headed for last?
What direction?
That way, for Sandstone.
Yes, they did. Your friend was here,
with another fellow he started
to fight, and he had no gun.
Are you forgetting anything?
No, he didn't stay.
Probably left for good.
You know where he went?
I can't tell, mister.
That miner was with him, he'll know.
So he's Billy's pal.
Billy? I've never heard of
anybody of that name.
Now look, my friend, don't play cute.
I know you two had a fight
here the other night.
Oh, it was Tim!
Billy.
No, no, Tim, Tim, Tim.
Tim or Billy, it doesn't matter.
Do you know where he was heading last?
All I know is
I'm gonna break open his noggin'!
You can't have Billy.
No, friend, l'm the one who's
gonna see to it. Remember me...
my name is Roger Pratt.
Doesn't that sound nice?
Alright, l'll see you again.
Hurry, hurry, hurry,
ladies and gentlemen!
Step right up, and gee
the marvellous mermald!
The only one of its kind in captivity.
She's on the inside folks.
Half woman, half fish!
She's in there, folks,
right inside the tent!
It will cost you 20 cents to have a look!
But what's 20 cents to see a
real mermaid! A freak and a miracle!
Step right up, folks, she's...
the eighth wonder of the world!
A really spectacular woman!
And you, sir, why don't you
have a look for yourself?
Hey, you!
I knew I'd find you here!
Hi, Harry!
Hey, you, the price is 20 cents!
Tim, you tell him!
You, that bank story,
the bank disappeared!
The bank that...
but no... did you ask?
Yeah, I'm asking!
Hey, you!
Now wait a minute!
Are you sure it disappeared?
Maybe it just moved!
Hey, that there ain't even a real fish!
You're a madnan!
You stole all my gold, you bastard!
I made a mistake. Just let me explain
it to you. I'll pay it up, really!
Then start paying!
If you knew how much I counted
on that gold, you wouldn't have took it!
But supposing that most of it's been
invested right here in the water show!
Invested?
All my gold?
If you figure how much you can get,
you can double that money!
This show is a real gold mine!
And so... there is no more?
lt's all here, really!
The fish tank, it ain't so awful!
This is gonna make you a bundle!
Are you sure that, this here mess is
mine right here? The fish tank, the tent?
This is a fine joke!
What am I gonna do with this stuff?
What will l do with the fish girl?
No, for crying out loud!
Not with the hammer!
Everything was just starting...
No! No!
That tent was new! What will I do now?
Oh, sorrv!
Breaking my wagon!
You ruined everything!
Now get out of this wagon, go on!
Well, why did you go
and wreck the wagon, too?
Now won't you understand
that you threw away your own money?
So that's it? You owe me slaps
I took because of vou.
How's that?
On account of a certain Roger Pratt.
What a mess you got me into!
Very old grudge.
Something that happened long ago.
Eight months of mine life,
to be on my ranch.
Ranch? What ranch?
The one I inherited from my uncle.
My pa wanted, after he died,
that I go back to it.
It's big ranch... heaven there...
far as you can see.
And turkeys.
No turkeys, no!
Prices are better now than they ever
were. Can't you just plcture that?
Hm, it's up to you, it's your ranch.
Hey, wait!
You want your gold or don't you?
Yeah, I want it, sure!
Let's go then, come on!
Or don't you trust me?
You're gonna get it,
and that's fact! Hm...
I'm watching you. Get a move on.
Just don't go trying
to cheat me twice.
Why you, get inside!
Adios! I'll buy you a new tank,
if you'll wait! So long, darling!
Hey, what the hell is this?
Would you please stop it?
You see I'm not toting a gun.
You don't live long
in these parts wthout a weapon.
I might have shot you, and then what?
Then you would have murdered
an unarmed man.
No.
I knew it.
Have you ever heard of Jessey James
and Rick Hitchgold and Hank Gaspery?
I heard they were the most vicious
in all the west.
And they all used guns. Murderers.
And they all died before they reached
thirty. No, guns only bring problems.
I prefer to do things clever.
There's much less danger.
Okay, so start doing something
clever about the gold.
Yeah, that's just what I was thinking.
Suppose we could sent
something to Boston?
We got a daughter who lives there.
You bet you can. Boston, New York,
Philadelphia, and Washington...
No, Washington no,
that's going too far.
And so Washington...
Come on! Are you gonna get
in touch with the big world?
I said don't touch that,
you'll get hurt.
Can't you keep still?
Seventy cents, better hurry up!
Who'd like to get in touch?
And they'll answer us, I suppose, eh?
Mister, this little machine will work
the same as any other.
Its workings are miraculous.
Excuse me, lady, this is urgent.
Write this down:
Come back this very day,
Violet Brodigan
Violet huh?
Brodigan. I'm Brodigan.
“Come home immediately,
and all is forgiven''.
If not, I'll shoot you both.
You stay and you'll see.
I'll put it in code, mister.
You pay the cash here.
Come-back-this-very-day-...
Violet-Brodigan: ..
Friends, do you or don't you?
Do you want to send a thank you
message from the whole town?
Okay, mister, we'll send
the president a message.
President of
the entire United States
Rutherford D.
Just that, mister.
He knows his own name, don't he?
Affront your own presidgnt, would you?
Why can't you show a llttle respect?
Western Junction would
like to give its thanks official
Mister, you better make that official!
Don't you think he can spell?
ls that his rank?
Of course now then:
And we are anxious to bring
you our thanks
Official, right?
Hey, Mo! I think we've been took!
Hey! What have you just been doing?
Er, there's two men over in Westin,
passing strangers.
This morning me and Jonn were out poking
around, but there ain't no cable line.
Hn, I would like to hear
a bit more about this story.
It might be interesting to hear.
One, two...
You're feeling reassured?
Better watch what you see!
First note to mister Brodigan: You dear
Violet says she is coming tomorrow.
- Dance?
- Yes!
Drop that, Harry!
We've got to make tracks!
But we can't just leave this way!
Roger's here!
Hey, what about Washington?
Ah, you see, Washington's calling
on the other line.
The lines got crunched!
What line?
Hurry, Harry, hurry!
- They're over there!
- Let's go,
come on!
You go over there and stay down!
Let's separate, men! Youtake
that side, the rest come with me!
And now, Jack MacDonald, here we leave
you ln peace to flnd your eternal rest.
You're going to a far better place than
whence you came. You re leaving this Valley
of tears to take your place with the angels.
We know how much you suffered in this life.
We'd better be ggtting on
about our busmess.
All your pain and goodness and
graciousness harken those habitual evil...
Roger's boys are here, too.
...but I say to you, I want you to
have mercy: love your enemies...
l think we'll have to split up.
I have another way.
What another way?
Haven't you ever heard of
the late Jack MacDonald?
MacDonald who?
Harry, how long were you
in those mountains?
I don't know.
Little trigger Mac!
So what?
But you mean...you can't be telling me
you've heard nothing about
the Abbelane bank!
No.
Just 200 bags of gold, that's all...
He and his gang.
The federals put the others
out of the way.
Little trigger Mac made away with
200 bags of gold dust,
and no one's been able to find him.
Do you mean to say,
MacDonald there, it was him?
Oh, I'm tired of this.
If you're thinking of leaving,
that ll be alright. You can take all of
the profits we made with the telegraph,
and we can say that the book is shut.
No, no, you owe me more than just
those measly dollars in the cash box!
But don't you see I've just now
found I can pay you!
Just you imagine going along with
more money than you could possibly
spend in a lifetime!
But it's too good to be. Mean that?!
And we can even buy those turkeys!
No, no turkeys!
Our saviour, who watches,
will protect his chlldren...
But you think that really...
little trigger Mac is there?
Yeah, yeah! It's Jack!
But I bet you the booty is
still hidden around these parts.
If the widow will tell,
well... she ll tell me.
But how are you gonna
make the woman tell?
Just look.
I thought so. But if you even think of
cheating me out of my share,
I'll make you pay twice over!
Well, you'd better get out of here.
...dust thou art, and to dust thou
shall return... Thus says the Lord,
and we cry Halleluja and Amen. And I pray
to the Lord to look down on Jack's wife,
this inconsolable woman,
who devoted her whole llfe to your care.
And so, to the rest Jack.
Your speech was a beauty.
Mister, are you a friend of Jack's?
I'll never be able to forget Jack.
What a loss!
A marvel lous man, your Jack,
and mighty warm.
But he never even mentioned you.
Madam, you knew Jack,
you knew he spoke little.
Right?
Your kind words hqve given me
such comfort. I didn t here your...
It's Tim, Tim Hawkins.
You must call me Dorothy.
Tim! What is it?
It's alright...
Just a spell.
I galloped all night loqg to make
it here for you and Ben s sake...
Jack!
Yes, of course, Jack!
Do forgive me,
I know how very good you've been.
I'll get you a little coffee,
if you d like.
A nice house. You live alone?
Yes, now I do.
You shouldn't you mustn't go to pieces.
Jack would never want me
to leave you like this.
He expressed it so simply:
Now look, Tim, if you can smile,
it will get better.
I'll make the coffee.
Yes, Jack would like to
see you like this.
Help yourself to some if you'd like.
Jack always preferred turkey.
lt smells so nice...
It's a good smell,
warfting upwards, full of purity.
But you never give it to Jack with
mournful eves, a smile is better.
You thought of every little thing.
I try to.
What do you want?!
Are you moving in there?
I might just do that.
But... I can't always...
Better now, Dorothy?
Better, but I'm still...
Yeah...
maybe we should finish this here turkey.
Are you okay?
The money is buried over there, over there
under that bush near the fence, you see?
I'd better keep the widow
busy while you dig for it.
I'll dig for it, but are you sure?
Sure I'm sure! Right over there!
I'll do it.
Oh...no...no,
please... I better not... Oh...
Poor Jack, rest his soul.
What a sad life he had!
Never able to leave his wheelchair!
I'm sure God will show him
how to walk again in heaven.
Yes, right now he is walking
among the stars.
What a nice thought!
What did you say?! Jack couldn't
get out of his wheelchair?!
For how long? Tell me about Jack!
Since when had been like that?!
He was seven years old
and fell off a donkey, and...
Tim! I'll kill you!
What the... What's going on?
You dirty sidewinder!
I'm your pal!
You'll pay this time!
Help! They won't stop!
They're wrecking the house!
Somebody call the sheriff!
Someone call the sheriff!
It's his fault! What do you want
to keep me here for now?
Haven't you two destroyed a house,
haven't you disturbed the poor lady,
you and your friend, too?
And you dug a big hole
and you caused a brawl.
Come on, stop saying such stupid things.
It's about time you let us out of here!
You'll have to wait in there
till the judge gets here,
or pay 70 dollars,
and that's for the both of you.
You can't wreck this town!
76, okay,
that's 76 dollars.
Now that I'm going, Tim,
let's just say this brings
an end to our partnership.
But... you mean you won't pay mine?
No!
So now it's finished.
You're leaving me this way?
Is that what you want?
What a fool you are.
There's a bunch of jackasses outside,
waiting to bray at you...
How wi ll you manage alone?
They don't scare me; It's you they're
after, not me! It's your business!
That you were with me is enough.
Roger never asks any questions.
He'll shoot you.
You figure it will get better
if I stay?
Sheriff, I've got the money!
Enough for both of us!
You can't have your guns
until after the trial. Come on out.
Aren't you coming? I paid.
No, not yet, Harry.
It's not so simple, but don't worry,
wake me in six hours.
How much did we make today?
Two dollars and 70 cents.
Hi, friend!
Oh, no, it's him! What do you want?
Hey, don't start yelling!
Is this any way to greet a person?
Can you beat that?
You don t want me around!
Please, I haven't recovered yet from
the last time! Out, I say!
Shhh, that's not helping.
I propose that we make
an association, huh?
You know what I always say:
First see my lawyer.
But aren't you even thinking
about your future vet?
If all you want is a penny
and a freak show, why don't you complain
about it, tell me!
Do you know how much money it would take
to get this thing into condition again?
Oh, let's get out of here.
We'll move out tonight.
You are a lunatic.
What's your hurry anyway?
Why leave tonlght?
But I think we shopld.
Maybe we shouldn t.
This is your miss, let her say.
He's right. This once, let'go.
We're out of money.
Broke is what you call lt. Heh!
You've got almost no business.
I 've got here your man
who can get it for you!
You've only got to get
at it this second!
Let's take a look at this miracle!
Er, yeah...
I'd like to see the miracle.
And so now, we offer the demon
from below, the human salamander!
He is known as Fogo, and he gets beans
like you folks eat your dinners!
Only don't forget:
he first sprinkles it with fuel oil!
And for his first act
he'll present his halo!
If they spotted us
what are we gonna do?
A spectacle never
before seen on this earth.
We're gonna out this on.
The very, the only,
the human salamander!
Go, go on!
Now settle down...
It won't take but another moment before
we go on with the show, folks!
Why, he is just preparing.
Go on! Go!
And here he is!
More!
Tim, they're out there,
I saw them! Where ls Tlm?
You're crazy!
Why?
But, my husband!
Oh, don't worry!
You must be crazy!
Just be quiet...
Are you gonna do it?
Uh-huh.
You're really something, Tim.
You'll be staying, won't you?
Yeah, just for the present.
I'm leaving as soon as
we get out of this place.
There's a ranch
Just past Jubilee Creek.
It's pretty...
Fire Harry owns it, but l began to think
of that little old place as if were mine.
Bravo!
Fire! Fire!
Roger !
Okay, run for it!
My clothes!
Hey, where are you both going?!
Help! Fire! Don't, don't!
It's burning up! Oh!
Oh no, I'm ruined!
Better not do it...,
My pa will want to know him
when he sees hlm.
Billy boy, you're shooting is ended.
Well now Billy, are you haonv
to see us agaln?
Pa has been expecting vou.
And won't he be awful glad to know
you're safe with us once again.
This other one, wnat are we gonna do
with him? He s dead weight.
Pa would say, do you pray son?
Confess pure, you die absolved.
Mount up!
But hold it! I hardly even know him!
He's your amigo, yeah? See what you
brought upon your friend, Billy?
Sure glad I ain't your friend.
Get moving.
Tell me, will you? Are you scared?
No, I feel cold!
Such a pilty. If we'd made it out to that
ranch, I d have given in to you anyway.
I don't get it.
The turkeys...
You're just tel I ilng me that
because you know you re going to...
Uh uh, no, vou could have had them.
Guess I 'm unlucky...
Why not that bastard?
Only six bullets. One up there,
and the rest down here.
How come Tim? You've began lying.
You told me you couldn t shoot.
I can shoot, just don't like to.
I'm not able to use my hands. I prefer
to use my wits. Take it easy there!
Big liar!
Listen to me, Harry,
l m really able to shoot,
but if I do,
they ll know who I am. Look.
Who are you then?
My name is Billy Boyd.
In Virginia
I worked for Samuel Pratt.
One day I decided to make a change,
make a new start.
Ha, he's really mad, believe me!
Just imagine what he tried to do?
To hunt you down.
Yeah. He even sent two of his sons.
They both missed.
Then you left?
Yeah, after putting two shots
in the middle of their foreheads.
It's about ready, Harry.
If the lord provides abundance,
why should man have to toll?
My pa always said man was born to toil.
Then I think he was nght.
My father almost never spoke.
He rarely spoke to me.
My father would say...
What's that?
Mourning.
Pretty soon let's make our way
out to our ranch.
Hold on! It's my own!
What do you mean, the whole place?
We'll see, but let's get there first.
Ah, we'll get there, don't worry,
and I'll start right away
building the turkey coops.
I told you, no turkeys!
Hey wait, you already promised.
Eh, a promise qin't worth a gold urn
when you re ready to go.
Why, you stinking bastard!
I thought I told you never
to call me by that word!
But when was the time
before this that I cursed you?
Eh? Oh, excuse me!
Where is that coach headed?
It takes the gold from the mine
in San Juan to Laredo.
Something to drink!
A wagon full of gold.
It sure makes you feel itchy.
What?
I mean that wagon.
Better just forget it.
Let me tell you:
Brent Beauregard wanted
that gold too,
and when he couldn't get it,
poor Brent was fit to be done.
Who is Brent Beauregard?
There he is.
Mlight take him with us.
We d have a better chance.
Who can tell?
We could ask him to go along.
No, no pal, I've made up my mind.
And please, don't mix
with men who are already fuzzy-headed.
You really think it would be so easy?
What's that?
Getting our hands on that gold.
Alright: Now, what distinguishes
the coaches of Wells Fargo?
Why...
A sign,
and if you put this sign
on the side of your own carrlage...
and beat theirs to the mine by leaving
just as it's morning, then you get?
About two hours sleep!
You get the gold!
And you needn't bother to shoot anyone.
Always use your wits.
Ain't you even tempted?
N0, siree.
Remarkable. I've never hea[d of
anything as clever as thls.
Man, you really have quite a head.
Hm, I guess so. Perhaps, I don't know.
You really do. More than I figured.
Keep this in mind
then: You're better off using this.
Know what I mean?
Didn't I tell you?
Just like I sald.
Nice and easy.
You were right.
Who are they?
The military escort.
Are they coming with us?
We'll find out.
We got the gold,
don't be worried about it.
We'll just have to move fast.
Put a smile on your face.
Whoa! Whoa!
You're new on the job, aren't you?
It's our maiden voyage, lieutenant.
Let's go!
I'm gonna, get off and maybe... walk a
while. I'm can make it back alnght.
No! No, you won't.
We're in this together now, get on!
Nobody told me it would
turn out this way!
Take it easy, amigo.
You Just let me handle this.
Don't shoot them, no!
Come on, a little closer...
Now what wi ll you do?
Stop, I say!
You're crazy, you know that?!
I told you: no shooting,
and you did it anyway!
You shot a military escort!
You know what's gonna happen? They're
gonna catch us and sting us up!
Then how are we gonna spend the gold?
Thanks for everything,
you real Iv had some great ldeas.
Adios, amigo.
Just what the hell have you been doing,
Harry? Let's go!
But the gold! It's all there! Wait!
Yeah? Then look over that way...
We'd better get out of here!
Brent Beauregard, he's been after this
for years. He can stop tryrng now.
It's all here. Looks like
the other one got away.
So you inherited a big ranch, did you?
It's gonna take
a lot of work, I would imagine.
Discouraged? Let's take a peek inside.
I think it's got possibilines.
Come on in! Just think, this all
belongs to us. Dirt, bugs and all.
The only thing your uncle forgot is
where there is a big stick of dynamite.
Well,
might as well get at it.
This time next yea[ we'll have the most
beautlful ranch ln thls whole area!
Fields of wheat
Just waving in the wind.
Wheat? Where is it?
We'll have to raise it!
I want you all to meet my daddy,
Samuel Pratt!
There they are!
Better have a word with them.
Get them!
Ah, let me go! take your hands of me!
Hey, Roger, they're gone!
Where are they?
Let me go!
Where have they gone?
Hold it!
Women are more talkative!
Bring her to me here.
Let me go!
Come on, sister.
Hand the little wildcat over to me!
I wanna know where those other two are.
Tell me now.
I don't know what you're talking about!
Now don't you get smart with me, miss.
What do you want?
What are you gonna do to me?
You get away from me!
There s nothing to tell!
Like your back scratched, mermaid?
You've got to believe me!
I can t tell you anythlng!
Listen to this, mermaid:
I mean busmess...
Ah! Oh!
Your pa seems to be having a sweet time.
No! No! Ah!
Yeah, he always was a lady-killer.
I heard... Jubilee Creek, a ranch, ah!
Yeah. That's what
I call cooperation.
Hey, that fox has sprung the trap again.
Must be something wrong with the bait.
Don't worrry. Sooner or later,
we'll catch him.
Now the roof is fixed!
It will hold a bull now!
That a bull! Just keen at it.
I'll take one of those.
Will that do it?
Well, l'll take one of those oil cans.
All together it's 20 dollars and 50 cents.
Yes. We're a little
short now. You recall
those twenty dollars worth of goods
we took the other day out to the ranch?
You'll put it on the book, yes?
Everybody does...
Thanks. Could you come out
and see me at the ranch?
I hope you got everything, Tim.
What do you think of this,
Mrs. Miller, you want it?
I'll try it.
Thank you. Morning!
With this one we've got six.
Perhaps wg're gonna have ourselves
a llttle house-party!
Hey! You better
watch it! You busted the teacup!
Your party is arriving.
Hey! Ha!
Let's go! Take your position! Come on!
Let's get the dynamite.
Thls is gonna take all day. Jack!
Hey, you! In the chimney! Go on!
Don't let up, Harry, keen at it.
Hurry, light this!
Then get in the woodshed!
No, not the house!
Get in there!
Light it!
- Where are you going?
- The turkeys!
Leave them where they are!
Up with your hands, Billy.
It's your turn now, Billy...
I'm not gonna kill you vet.
Your're gonna suffer first
I wanna see you beg to die!
Have a little fun with him.
Yeah... Dron your holster, Billy!
Eh,
Watch him, Roger.
If he drops his hands,
you're a dead man.
Uh-huh, you ought to listen
to your pa there, Roger.
If you wanna take it, come on.
Didn't I tell you we'd catch
that fox one of these days?
Yeah, that's it...
lt's alright, you'll just
bulld another beside it.
What do you mean, boy? Alone?
Yeah. Alone. It's better I go.
You'll make it.
It's better we go our own ways.
Tim!
Billy!
Where are you going? Very far?
I'll send you a letter!
Wait for me!
Keep that letter, I'm coming with you!