Come on, come on!
Dead One, let's go.
Come on!
- Dead One, let's go.
- Wait! I'm winning.
- Which one is yours?
- That one. Can't you see he's winning?
You lost. Let's go.
Are you staying here forever,
or are you coming with me?
OK, OK.
Come on, I want an answer!
I'm coming with you.
The enemy comes
at a gallop...
and moving in the wind...
their red flag.
And moving in the wind...
The enemy comes
at a gallop...
Get down! Hands up!
- Easy...
Leave your gun there.
- Calm down...
- I'm OK.
Do I look nervous?
Do you know what I do
when I get nervous?
Am I nervous?
I'm not, you bastard!
Where's the gold?
It's in the saddles, on the
horses.
There's nothing in the
stagecoach
Vargas! Pig! Go search the dead.
Let's see what you got here...
What are you looking for,
you ignorant gaucho?
I told you, there's nothing
there!
I'll show you how we,
ignorant people, sign.
Don't fucking move!
Aballay!
Hey Aballay,
let's go, others are coming!
Go get the gold, Dead One!
TEN YEARS LATER
Say it, come to me.
These cards I hold right now...
are almost shouting out...
for me to show off...
and "flor" and "truco" cry!
"Flor", you say?
Then I must call and raise...
"Contra-flor"! I win!
Fuck! I want to see them!
Here!
What's this fuckin' saint
doing here?
If the Dead One gets you,
he'll cut your throat.
It's bad luck for me!
Shit!
Stupid gaucho!
They've burnt you, Saint...
Old, stupid gaucho...
Shit...
Shit! I can't find my "pingo"!
Pissed gaucho...
Torres! You pay what you owe!
Where are they?
Who?
Aballay, Pig, Dead One!
I don't know them.
At La Malaria.
But please don't kill me!
I'll work for you,
I'll do whatever you want!
I have seven kids.
Please, don't kill me, I'll!
So you're an orphan...
Good morning.
I heard you're looking for
workers.
The salary is meager.
Meager salary, a roof and food?
That will do.
Julian Erralde
Benavides, at your service.
- Where are you from?
- The city of Buenos Aires.
"Negro"! Come help the man.
Please, don't... It's OK.
Thanks.
Pig!
Good morning
Morales!
Nice animals, Morales...
I'll take the four of them.
But after paying your taxes
and giving you some animals for free,
I need some cash.
I see, this is your job.
And how much for these animals?
They're strong, healthy, well-fed.
At least ten each.
- What the hell do you feed them?
- Boss!
What is it?
Torres's been killed.
And who killed him?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- Have you seen them?
- What, are you blind?
- I was drunk
So you were drunk!
You fucking asshole!
You were drunk?
Give the animals to him.
What about what we discussed?
Heads, you're dead.
Tails, you live.
Hope your lucky streak goes on.
Take him to Lopez's, you asshole!
Mind the steps.
You'll be comfortable here.
This is La Malaria?
No, it's near here.
Across the river.
Why do they call you
by a man's name?
Careful.
- What's your name?
My name is Juana. And yours?
Julian, and yours?
Juana...
And yours?
Oh, Saint who performs miracles
I know I shouldn't bother you.
You look after the Dead and the Living.
But Pauper, please,
I have no one else to turn to.
I'm calling out for you, asking you
to work a miracle
and help him stay alive
and safe from harm.
A true miracle,
like the captives faith.
Hi.
Come in, boy. Come in.
What are you looking for?
Bale wire.
I have something special.
This... It's just arrived...
Look at this. Look.
This fabric. Look.
This fabric is great.
The curtains you could make with it!
This is Jacquard. Look.
- I'll give you a discount.
- No. Wire. Bale wire.
Wire? Bale wire?
I have the best one here,
but it's sold.
But I'll get more. Tell me where
you live and I'll have it delivered.
At Don Benavides'.
Don Benavides? Sure.
You like scarves?
Take a look at this one.
It's cotton from India.
Take it, it'll make
a good present for a young lady.
- It's on the house.
- Thank you.
OK. But you know what, dear?
You can't wear those pants
any longer.
No, look at them...
Thank you.
You like it?
Yes
He's The Pauper, a local Saint.
Nobody knows where he lives,
but he keeps appearing.
Those who have seen him say
he's always on horse. He lives up there.
From there he's cured kids, they say.
He helps people.
He's very good.
He performs miracles.
Who carved it?
My godfather, from Cordoba.
He's a good person.
He lives near the river.
He used to live with Clarisa,
a friend of mine.
But she kicked him out because...
he drinks a lot.
And she got tired.
He's a devotee of the Saint,
so he makes lots of these...
Bigger ones, with a long beard,
short beard, another hat...
He has an altar and prays.
I'm also a devotee.
Kiss him, he'll bring you good luck.
- You're wrong, Boss.
- Why?
Why are you so happy?
It's an albino pig.
It's still a baby.
It's 20 days old, but...
It'll be white forever.
Does it have a name?
- Ramon. Do you like it?
- Yes.
- Sounds nice. Ramon.
When I call it, it'll come.
- Juana...
- Yes?
Let me make a portrait of you.
- A portrait?
- Yes
What's a portrait?
A drawing.
Oh, a drawing.
Why?
To remember you.
Are you leaving?
No. Because I like drawing.
Just because you like it...
- With Ramon?
- Of course.
OK.
Excuse me.
He'll make a portrait of us,
Ramon.
Smile.
Pig, go get Benavides.
Good morning.
Here's a present for you
to wear tonight.
- Nice day, isn't it?
- Yes.
- Nice...
Hello.
Commander Frutos,
La Malaria's Judge of the Peace.
And who are you?
I asked what your name was!
Julian Erralde.
Mr. Erralde is working for us
And how long are you staying?
Not long.
That's OK. People from big cities
are not good at field chores.
Come here, Pig!
Here's a son of yours!
Ramon... Easy...
You can prepare it
for the feast tonight.
And you, Juana, get ready.
I'll send for you tonight.
Sure. Here's the money.
What business do you have
with these people?
Come, Pig! We have to prepare
the party for tonight!
I see you in the light of dusk
walking with your girl, and I'm behind.
I don't know where you're from
or what your name is,
I bark at you for a while,
but you don't even look at me.
I dream that you come and get me,
we get stuck together, then we go to sleep.
In the light of dusk I watch you go by
I return home alone, then I start to bark.
Music man, stop the music!
You all know our sacred values:
God, our Nation and our families.
So I've gathered you here today
to leave my path of sins
and tell you that
I'm getting married.
Cheers!
Cheers, Commander!
Long live Commander Frutos.
Stop it!
Here's my future bride,
so happy she's almost crying.
Let's hear it for her,
poor thing!
Bring her to me, Vargas!
Come here, girl!
We'll continue with the ceremony.
The religious one
will take place some other day.
You don't like the ceremony, baby?
What a pity, darling!
Grab her!
Now we'll have this one.
This is the real ceremony.
Dead One!
Let her go!
Oh, we have a guest.
What's wrong with you?
You fallen in love with her?
I'll show you
who's mounting this mare!
A fucking gaucho roulette!
Musicians...
We need some music!
Where is he?
Where are you? I'll find you...
Where is he? Maybe here,
maybe there...
I don't know, but I'll find you.
I'll find you.
Where are you?
Where's the big city guy!
Where are you?!
Let's see...
Go, go!
The Dead One's responsible,
Godfather.
Do you think he'll be OK?
He's hurt. If you don't
take care of him, he'll be blind.
Fuck! Shit!
I'm sorry I got you involved
in this, Godfather.
Dear, you know I curse just because.
But if in a case like this
you don't ask me for help,
I won't talk to you again.
You understand, "Negro"?
We must run away from here.
I'll go get Pastrana.
Take this. Just in case.
Tell The Pauper to be careful.
That's a package
stolen from the Dead One.
I'm blind.
I can't see.
Of course, you really hurt your eyes.
Don't touch the bandage.
Be patient.
You'll be able to see again.
Who are you?
Antonio like your uncle,
the one that's wicked? No.
Mariano.
No, the female version is better.
I like "Mariana".
How about Silvan? Or José?
José, like Virgin Mary's husband.
Aballay!
What's wrong with you, Aballay?
Are those bags too heavy for you?
Why don't you give them to me?
Come here, girl. You're pretty.
Get down here!
You want to pray?
Pray, you asshole!
Aballay, what shall
we do with them?
Do you believe in God?
Tell him the Dead One sends his regards.
Come here!
Kill him, Dead One!
You son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch!
Take this!
After me, somebody
more powerful will come.
I'm not worthy
to untie His sandals.
When He comes, deserts will
open up and lilies will bloom.
Meanwhile, let's celebrate the Virgin
with the words of the prophet.
Praise the Lord! It is possible
to wash away your sins...
...and the pain caused by them.
But nothing is possible
without a sacrifice.
Simeon the Elder,
the first stylite,
redeemed his sins
and withdrew from the Earth
where he had sinned
by staying on pillars in the desert
and never coming down,
so that he could be closer to God.
He would endure freezing weather
and the boiling sun, night and day.
After spending decades on a pillar,
the Lord, who knew
about his sacrifices, said:
"This is a fearless man,
deaf to the debauchery of the winds,
whose body feeds from Heaven's bread
and Heaven's wine."
Rejoice, since he who
approaches God and is remorseful
will receive God's mercy
and be forgiven,
like those brave stylites.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Amen.
I was born in your valleys,
I'm made of stone and sand.
I was born in the woods,
I was raised in stony ground.
And calandra larks and thrushes
used to sing to me.
I was born in your valleys,
I'm made of stone and sand.
And calandra larks and
thrushes used to sing to me.
I'll see those birds again.
Father, I'd like to know
about the saints you talked about.
I said that they lived in sanctity.
They were anchorites, or hermits.
Didn't you say something else?
Something else?
Stylites, maybe?
It's the same.
Stylites were a special
type of anchorites.
Anchorites were solitary people.
They would willingly withdraw
from other people.
They would inhabit caves
or live on a mountain top.
What for?
To serve God in their own way.
You said they were on top of...
On top of pillars or columns.
Those were stylites.
And there they stayed...
through cold or hot weather,
whether they were sick or hungry...
How long?
For eternity! Simeon the Elder
spent almost 37 years like that.
Simeon the Younger, 70 years.
So, what do you think now
of their sacrifice?
Could you imagine such a thing?
And how did they eat?
Uncomfortably. Bugs, mice...
Sometimes sad people or believers
would go on a pilgrimage
to ask them
to ask God to help them.
You said they used to...
Show repentance and meditate.
Why did they show repentance?
To relieve the pain
caused by their sins.
Stylites would stay on pillars
to get closer to Heaven
and to withdraw from the Earth,
since that was where they had sinned.
Will you bear with me, brother?
Will you bear with me?
It's forever.
Are you always on a horse?
Always.
Do you sleep on it as well?
I do.
So you're The Pauper.
People pray to you.
That's just a belief.
I'm just riding my horse.
And why don't you get off it?
What's the matter, my friend?
There are still people
I have to kill.
And that's terrible.
What comes afterwards...
...is even worse.
My wife has returned.
Thank you so much, friend!
Where's the city guy?
The Earth has eaten him...
Didn't even spit his heart!
Did you miss your daddy?
Won't you give him a kiss?
Come on, kiss your daddy!
Kiss your daddy, kiss your daddy!
Come on, kiss him!
Where's that handsome boy?
You've stolen him from me,
so you'll give him back to me.
Understand?
There he is!
Get him! Don't let him escape!
Get him!
Oh, Saint who performs miracles.
I know I shouldn't bother you.
You look after the Dead and the Living.
But Pauper, please,
I have no one else to turn to.
I'm calling out for you, asking you
to work a miracle and help him stay alive.
A final miracle that finds him safe from harm.
Pretty boy!
Don't you want some meat?
City guy!
Don't worry if you have loose teeth,
the meat's already been chewed!
Dead One!
I brought you a present.
Is that Aballay?
Let Juana go,
and the Saint is yours.
Aballay is the Saint?
What a surprise!
Vargas!
Drop your gun! And the man!
I'm getting nervous.
You stinking city boy!
What is it, Julián?
I'm leaving.
You're leaving?
- I thought...
- I have to go.
I know.
It's because of the Dead One.
It's because I've been with him,
that son of a bitch...
I'm dirty...
- It's that.
- No, you're not.
It's me.
I'm poisoned.
I've spent my whole life thinking of
avenging my father's death.
But you've killed all of them.
Not all of them.
The worst one is alive.
Who?
The Pauper.
The Pauper?
What are you saying, Julian?
The Pauper saved your life.
He is a saint, Julian.
You can't kill a saint.
You can't, Julian!
Don't do it.
Stay with me.
Get down!
No. You know I can't get down.
I had to do it.