ELEGY
Mr. Ramazan.
Did this man bring us
to a wrong place?
Sari Veli knows
smuggler's place better than us.
Rocks are falling.
Mr. Ramazan.
I give up, Ramazan.
Let's go.
Don't push me. We don't harm you.
Use your mind.
Selamun Aleykum, Coban Agha.
Hello, Coban Agha.
Your men don't know us.
We're here for business.
- What business?
- There are 4 cans of stuff.
They must be in Incesu on Friday.
We need to deliver them on time.
Mr. Nizamettin is a respectable
trade man.
- Sari Veli told us your place.
- Bread money.
You won't sell us for money?
We worked long time together.
Have I ever betrayed you?
How much will you pay?
I don't know.
- We'll think something.
- If you think, we won't do it.
- Why is that? - We haven't
forgotten the last time.
It wasn't my fault.
I'm only the commision trader.
Comission traders
sell their father for money.
100 lira for each of you.
You don't risk your life for 100 lira.
How much do you want?
200 lira each.
And trousers, a shirt, 2 kilo soap,
50 bullets, 10 packs tobacco.
The shirt will be striped.
Agreed. You get what you want
at the delivery of goods.
We get 500 lira in advance.
Mothers, sisters. The basis of
our health is being clean.
In the water you drink and use,
live harmful micro-organisms.
Typhoid, cholera, polio are
contaminated by water.
By boiling the water we kill
the germs.
To dig wells near toilets is very
dangerous. We have to...
be careful about child-care.
In our country, 162 children...
out of 1000 die as sauglings.
Children must be vaccinated.
They say you don't waccinate for
measles. This is wrong.
Thousands of children die
because of this mistake.
Doctor, hurry up.
Ismail fall from a tree.
Make way for the doctor.
- What happened?
- Villagers are having fun.
Nobody has fallen.
It's better if they don't do it.
I'm here for them,
they're not aware of it.
They've caught another one.
There won't be anybody left soon.
Use your head.
If there's no man on mountains...
...what will become of our business?
Talk to smuggler Osman.
Three cans for them,
we share the other one.
Use your head. There
are 4 cans, that's a fortune.
- What about you?
- One can is enough for me.
- Where do they pass?
- This is a river bed.
Here's Kepez mountain.
Most probably they'll go through here.
You've to kill Cobanoglu with
the first bullet.
- What if we don't benefit?
- Are you scared?
A coward is always hungry.
Ismail, over the hill.
Tefik, over here
Look, you get a chance
like that once.
If we succeed you save your life
with your share.
If you're still scared,
you may go.
You can't stand
Gendarme bullet by this heat.
- Osman, if I die.
- Don't think bad things.
If we get shot, what will happen
to our shares?
Spread around!
Mehmet Emin, Sivasli.
Don't kill them.
Let's catch them alive.
You got it.
Cobanoglu, Jackal of fields.
Leave the donkeys.
Don't make me shed blood.
I'm the lion of these mountains.
You jackal.
- Sivasli, back me up.
- Alright, brother.
- I'm really worried.
- Why? You're fond of us?
- Aren't we brothers?
- Brother like you is fit for the grave.
- We were surrounded.
- By Gendarme?
You know it better than us.
Bring him here.
We were stopped.
Who was the cause of it?
Sari Veli could do it.
Sari Veli!
Why do you cry?
What do you want?
Cows are in your fields.
What cow, whose field?
Welcome, Coban Agha.
Help, they're killing people.
Sari Veli is your friend.
You did business together.
We were friends,
but we didn't work together.
Don't lie.
We know everything.
Aren't you commision trader
for smugglers?
That was in the past.
I'm a honorable trader now.
Honorable, huh?
You'll tell us smugglers' places
that you know.
If you're helpful,
it'll be to you interest.
Really? My interest?
Nothing left on the tree.
The owner could kill us.
Potatoes, make fire.
You know what I think,
we should be in my village.
By the Cam Stream.
We should drink cold water.
Then we'd let you on the pasture.
That would be great fun.
I wouln't mind, if I were there.
I feel uneasy.
I have bad dreams.
I worry about my family.
It's dangerous now.
There's a right time for everything.
- What the family will eat?
- Nobody dies of hunger.
If they're lucky,
when we get a sum of money...
I hope it won't be too late.
- Gendarme!
- Run for your life!
Wait! Surrender!
Keep the Gendarme away.
That must be the Gendarme
and the smugglers.
White Pants for sure.
Cobanoglu is fighting.
- Shootings are over.
- Shooting is none of my business.
Let them kill each other.
This man is going to die.
That will be our end.
- Where's Mehmet Emin?
- He'll fetch the doctor.
Could the doctor be remedy
for Gendarme bullets.
- Who is it?
- Open up. Someone is sick.
- Who are you?
- A villager.
There's a wounded man.
We need a doctor.
- What is it, Ahmet?
- A man is wounded.
- Is she the doctor?
- What kind of wound?
Wounded by a bullet.
Don't go at night. It's risky.
Look at the man.
He'll die, if you don't come.
This man has to live!
- Who is wounded?
- Cobanoglu.
- Cobanoglu?
- Yes, Cobanoglu.
They're coming.
- How is Cobanoglu?
- He's about to die.
Boil some water.
Don't blame us
We utter your name
Don't think it's a legend
We reach to God
We're too many to count
We don't be finished by killing
Nobody knows how
we are inquiring in the province
People think we're insane
Our insane is wiser than sane
It's over.
I'm worried about them.
Shall we call the Gendarme?
We'll wait till evening
then we call the Gendarme.
God bless you, sister.
You're free to go.
Thank you.
- Won't you take the donkey?
- It's a gift.
I've never seen anything
like that.
The man we dreamed of for years
was lying on a straw bed...
with a bullet in his lung,
unconscious and bleeding.
I didn't know what to do.
But the look in the men's eyes....
They believed that I'd save him.
That gave me strength.
It was my first surgery,
on difficult conditions.
He didn't look like the remarkable man
whom story you're writing.
The Gendarme bullet takes
remarkableness away.
He was a brave man.
No more business for us.
The mountains are cleared of men.
Our last hope
is that Cobanoglu gets caught.
Shut up. I am talking.
I wish I could get Cobanoglu entrapped.
It'll be to my benefit.
Because Cobanoglu is the last man
on mountains.
You were unconscious for three
whole days. We were hopeless.
The Lady Doctor saved you.
Take a breath.
Take a deep breath.
- Selamun aleykum.
- Aleykümüs selam.
- Who's next?
- Me.
- You look well today.
- I feel fine.
Doctor said, you should rest.
You were alone at home
all day long.
I'm worried about him.
They would let us know
if anything was wrong.
- If they couldn't?
- We'll visit him tomorow.
- I finished the story.
- What did you name it?
I'm not sure yet.
Maybe 'Cobanoglu' or 'Hor Earth'.
- I'd call it 'Elegy'.
- Elegy?
How do I look? In jail
I had pants and high boots.
When I walked, the earth shook.
If I hadn't escaped, I'd be
free by now, and with my family.
Do you think
Cobanoglu would let us go home?
The doctor is coming.
- She saved your life.
- Who is she with?
They live in the same house.
Welcome doctor, welcome brother.
- I'm glad to see you well.
- I'm fine thanks to you.
Don't fear. This old snake
is the guard of our village.
He couldn't go away
as we couldn't.
This was our home.
What's happening?
The rocks will fall down again.
- You like Cobanoglu?
- More than my own life.
Is Cobanoglu well off?
- What do you mean?
- I mean money.
We're starving, brother.
We had a job the other day.
Our share was 200 lira each.
Any news about amnesty?
- What amnesty?
- The amnesty.
Once there was a large village here.
The rocks and feud destroyed us.
The graves weren't enough
for dead.
Sometimes three deaths on one day.
The rocks were our enemies.
- You know rock fear?
- No, I don't.
One has to live it. Rocks
came down like rain falls.
Rocks killed my mother.
Feud killed father.
- Feud didn't make you fugitive.
- How do you know it?
Everybody around here knows you.
I was 14 then.
As a teenager, we were experiencing
exciting days.
Young people told your story
and Hatice's beauty.
- Are you from Balözü?
- Yes. I'm hunter Halil's daughter.
He was good to us.
That's why you're so kind.
- I'm not that kind.
- You are. You're very kind.
You saved my life.
You could go to Gendarme.
I waited till you get well.
I have to tell them.
My duty is to help people.
I must respect the law too.
You're right, we respect the law
but to die is hard.
We're all waiting for the amnesty.
Ten years on the mountains
we lead a miserable life.
Being poor, being a sheppard
made me fugitive.
We became the jackal
on the mountains.
If we were considered a human being,
things wouldn't be like this.
Cobanoglu is the most feared
smuggler on the mountains.
He can always get away.
He's the chief of White Pants.
You find him either in
desolatad village or in cemetery.
The cemetery?
He had a beloved once,
she has died.
I took out Cobanoglu's bullet
I'm a doctor.
I'm concerned about people's health,
not about what they are.
I also do my best to help law.
I saw him in the desolated village.
His wound was serious.
Now he must be well.
But I don't know where he is.
Sivasli missed his family
very much.
I suppose the earth is calling him.
- Haven't you slept, Sivasli?
- I can't forget my family.
God help you.
Sivasli has gone!
Get up, brother.
Sivasli has gone.
The earth called Sivasli.
Who was on guard?
Forgive me, I've fallen asleep.
And Sivasli has gone.
We've entrusted you our lives.
Get lost.
You're on your own now.
Wait!
Four packs of tobacco,
two white one green soap, linen...
...a rosary, a gun,
bracelets and a doll.
They must be around here.
This is their place.
- We searched every place.
- Let's wait. They'll come back.
Don't follow us! How can a man who
sleeps on guard be trusted?
Forgive me. It won't happen again.
I have never done it before.
I've suddenly fallen asleep.
I dreamed Sivasli going.
If you follow us, I'll kill you.
Coban Agha, forgive me!
What can I do by myself?
I swear I won't do it again!
Coban Agha!
Don't leave me here!
Don't come. Don't.
- Don't come!
- I will!
Don't come or
I will blow your head!
- Don't come!
- I will!
I will come! I will come!
You're my family!
We have been sharing the same salt
and bread for years.
- You can't leave me alone!
- Don't come, I said!
I will.
I will even if you kill me.
- I swear I'll shoot you.
- You can't, Mehmet Emin.
- I said, don't come!
- I will.
I will. I will!
- Don't come!
- I will!
We're waiting in vain.
They won't come back.
Don't talk like that.
I hope they do come back.
Let's wait a little longer.
Cobanoglu comes here for sure.
I beg you, they'll come here.
Let's wait till dark.
Please don't go.
Come on, hurry up.
Come here.
What a bad luck.
You watch the Gendarme.
Mehmet Emin,
give me a mirror.
- Gendarme is coming this way.
- Keep them away.
Wait! Don't run away!
Don't run! Surrender!
I'm sorry, I came to say goodbye.
Don't take me wrong.
I'm not after your beauty.
You're the only person
who cared for me.
- Are you leaving?
- All my friends are dead.
I can't stay here anymore.
- Where?
- I don't know.
I owe you a humble life but
I don't have time to pay it back.
I'm sorry.
God bless you.
God is on our side, woman.
I'm right, it's Cobanoglu.
You wait here,
I'll call the Gendarme.
God. Our lives are saved.
THE END