Out West where men were brave and bold
The most exciting story told
Is all about a stranger
Who lived a life of danger
And he loved that shining gold
Jesse James was his name
Let me tell you now Before
a guy could wink his eye
He'd rob the stage as it went by
And just as sure as Hades
He'd kiss the lovely ladies
And you ought to hear him sigh
Jesse James was his name
Oh, yeah, well, a
trigger-happy guy was he
As fast as any guy could be
I'll lay you two to one, man
Not another gunman
Was half as fast as he
Jesse James was his name
He made a lot of friends
But there the story ends
'Cause all good gunmen die
Jesse James was his name Was his name
The wealth and might
that is America today
is reflected in its farms, its
factories, its banking institutions
and certainly in its various
mammoth insurance companies.
These gigantic corporations owned by
millions of stockholders and policy holders
have, since the beginning of our country,
been an integral part of our life.
Untold thousands of Americans
have received their educations
through the benefits
of insurance policies.
Millions of American families have
been raised partially, or entirely,
on a monthly check from
their insurance company,
and the history of the expansion of
these institutions could almost be
the history of the
expansion of America itself.
But, vast as the resources and holdings
of these mighty companies are today,
each is the result of
great pioneering courage
and perseverance of
these great founders.
And who deserves much of the credit
for the evolution of these companies
from their simple beginnings
into their present size?
It is no one but
that almost forgotten,
hardworking door-to-door
insurance salesman,
to whom we respectfully
dedicate this picture.
The time is the early 1880s.
The place is New York City.
The occasion is a sales
meeting of the employees
of the Plymouth Rock
Insurance Company.
Yes. Now, may I have the
other charts, Miss Raskin?
Let's see how you other
gentlemen have done.
Crimshaw. Oh, yes, yes.
You've done an
admirable job, Crimshaw.
You dipped a little there in May,
but I see you bounced back up,
and you'll soon have a
leg on the gold watch.
Yes.
Now...
Well. Hastings! You're
right up there, aren't you?
You keep this up and you're well on your
way to that free weekend at Coney Island.
Why, this is amazing.
Oh.
Farnsworth.
Farnsworth, when are you
ever gonna sell a policy?
May I remind you, sir,
that just two weeks ago,
I turned in a signed policy
for a Miss Elfrida Bennett?
Which was rejected.
On a medical technicality.
Yes, a slight technicality.
When the doctor arrived to
examine her, she was dead.
Well, we've got to
get a faster doctor.
A 30-year endowment policy
on a woman 98 years old.
Well, she lied about her age.
And much as I dislike
tooting my own horn, sir,
I was solely responsible for the sale
of Plymouth Rock's first marine policy,
issued on the new schooner Nantucket.
Please, please, don't
remind me of that launching.
I can still see the bubbles.
How did I know the anchor
was heavier than the boat?
Milford, I've given
this a lot of thought,
and I think this company can
get along very well without you.
Turn in your key to the washroom.
Well, can't I even have
visiting privileges?
Farnsworth, I'm curious.
What do you expect to achieve
with such crass ineptitude,
such utter incompetence,
such colossal stupidity?
Well, I was hoping to
become your assistant.
Sorry you couldn't get in yesterday,
Milford. We all missed your nickel.
Charlie, have you thought
any more about that insurance?
Some other time.
Sullivan beat Gentleman
Jim? He hasn't a chance.
Yeah? That's what they said when they
matched him up against Paddy Ryan.
Well, you can see their legs
clear up to the knees, I tell you.
Yeah? What'd you say
they called themselves?
The Gibson Girls.
Clear up to the knees. I tell
you, it's enough to drive you mad.
If you're talking about the Kansas
City bank, he got away with $25,000.
Jesse James wouldn't pull a gun out of
his holster for 25,000. The bank said...
Pardon me, gentlemen,
the exact amount was $33,228.33.
That's Jesse James!
Whiskey.
Forget it. It's on the house.
Charlie, if you're going
to buy any insurance,
today is the day. I've
got to make a sale.
Later, Milford. Later.
Charlie, there is no
later with insurance.
You can't put off till tomorrow
what may strike you today.
Please, Milford, not now.
No, you're taking a lot of chances. You
got a lot of money laying around here.
Milford...
I mean, cash for your payroll, cash
for your customers, money in the till.
- This place is a gold mine.
- Have another sandwich. No charge.
Now what's to prevent
somebody from walking in here
and pressing the cold barrel
of a. 45 against your temple?
Very little.
Yeah, one shot and your wife is an orphan.
But not with Plymouth Rock Insurance.
You can leave her 5,000,
10,000, anything you want.
And when your time comes, you'll
find yourself slipping away
with a smile on your lips
and a song in your heart.
You got to think about that.
That's the way to go, you know.
You got to think.
Please. Watch out, kid.
- Charlie...
- I wanna talk to you.
You'll have to excuse us, sir.
This is a private conversation between
the two of us, if you don't mind.
You two may not finish.
I'm interested in slipping
away with a smile on my lips
and a song in my heart. I'll have
my drink over at the table here.
This may be a hot one.
You caught me just at the right
time. I think I have one policy left.
Pleased to be of service
to you, sir. My card.
What is a Milford Farnsworth?
Oh, that's me. That's my
name. I'm Milford Farnsworth.
All right.
Oh, no. Whiskey is
the weak man's crutch.
Now, we at Plymouth Rock are honored
to have been chosen by you, Mister...
- James. TJ James.
- Oh, yes.
I'd like to hear a little
more about this insurance.
As I understand it, your company is
willing to bet me on how long I'll live?
And they'll take the short end
by betting I'll live a long time?
Yeah. I guess you
could put it that way.
Well, if I'm dead, how do
I know I'll get paid off?
My good man, the Plymouth
Rock Insurance Company
wouldn't be in business two minutes if
they didn't make good on their policies.
Just so long as we understand each
other. Now, who gets the money?
Well, your wife, your mother,
whatever loved one you designate.
Well, then you take out your
pencil and paper and start writing.
- The money goes to Miss Cora Lee Collins.
- Cora Lee Collins.
- Angel's Rest, Missouri.
- And what is her relationship to you?
- Loved one.
I don't think the company
has that classification.
Well, make it wife. She will be.
Now, how much money is your
company prepared to put up?
Well, we're prepared to go
as high as you want to go.
That's 1,000, 5,000, 10,000...
- Well, let's say 100,000.
- Yeah, let's say that. Oh.
Well, how would you like
to make the payments?
Would that be quarterly,
or semi-annually?
- I'll pay it all now.
- You'll pay it all...
No, no, you don't understand.
See, that's about $33,000.
100,000. That's the premium and I...
Yeah, well, just keep the change.
Yeah.
You just wait here and I'll run
across the street to the doctor's
and arrange for your physical.
Don't you take any drinks or anything.
You look fine just as you are.
Good morning, Mr.
Quesely. You remember me?
With deep horror.
I hope you haven't had the
lock in the washroom changed,
because I'm gonna be around
here for quite a while.
You have 30 seconds to leave
before your beneficiaries cash in.
Mr. Quesely. I sold a policy.
Ten seconds. And get
that trash off my desk.
Mr. Quesely, do you
know what's in that bag?
It better be something you can
defend yourself with, Farnsworth.
There's $33,000 in that bag.
Farnsworth, do you feel all right?
It represents the premium paid in full
on an insurance policy of $100,000.
I suggest that this be counted and
turned over to the auditor at once.
Here's the policy, if you'd
like to look it over, sir.
Why certainly, sir. I mean, Milford.
Yeah, let's see now.
"Mr. TJ James, beneficiary
Miss Cora Lee Collins,
"in the amount of
"$100,000."
Well, who is this
Mr. TJ James, my boy?
Oh, he's quite an operator.
But what are his sources of income?
Well, naturally I didn't
pry into any details.
- Naturally.
- But I gathered from him
that he's well known in
railroad and banking circles.
Well, this is too big to fool with. Better
set up an appointment for his physical.
Oh, I'm afraid it's too late for that.
Mr. James left last night on the train.
But I had Doc Bishop rush him through
right away. Here's the medical.
I promised you'd send
him a box of cigars.
Send them? I'll take them over myself.
Here's the morning paper, Mr. Quesely.
Miss Raskin, how many times have I told
you not to interrupt me in conference?
And never, never when I'm with
our star salesman, Mr. Farnsworth.
Just a minute, Miss Raskin.
How much have you been
drawing a week, Milford?
Oh, $7.50.
Raise that to $10. And
do you have the $25 bonus
that I told you to draw for
Milford this morning? Good.
See that he gets it right away.
Now, Farnsy, my boy,
I am going to carry the ball from here
on in. You take the rest of the day off.
- Oh, but it's a working day.
- It's a day to celebrate.
Go on to the beach. Take
a ride on the new elevated.
You've earned it. Go on.
Get out of here. Scat.
Farnsworth! Farnsworth!
Another bonus?
Farnsworth.
Funny, I have a feeling
I've seen that face before.
Farnsworth, is that or is that not
the man to whom you sold a
$100,000 life insurance policy?
I told you, I thought
his face was familiar.
Anything happens to that
man, this company is ruined.
Funny thing, not once
during the whole evening
did he mention that he
was a notorious killer.
Will you shut up?
Farnsworth, you're gonna
take the next train west.
What?
You're going to return this money to
James and make him give up that policy.
Me, make him?
And if James refuses
to return that policy,
you are to remain by his side
forever, to protect our interest.
You are to ride with him,
eat with him, sleep with him.
At the slightest sign of danger, you
are to lay down your life to protect his.
- Go.  - But, Mr. Quesely,
I'm liable to get killed.
Stop trying to cheer me up.
And I knew the minute I saw you
that you were responsible gentlemen,
men who are keenly aware
of your financial obligations
to your family and estate.
Now, no other policy can give you
the protection that this one can.
And you don't have to
worry about the cost.
Your wampum can be
divided into 12 easy wamps.
Well, that's my story. Are you sold?
No? But I've explained everything.
Believe me, you can't go
wrong with Plymouth Rock.
Why won't you buy? Give me one reason.
Foreigners.
They're foreigners.
All right, everybody. Reach!
All right, let's get 'em up.
Come on, now. Get out the money
and the valuables. Come on.
All right, get 'em out.
You heard what he said.
You got anything?
You sure?
You wouldn't fool me?
What is that, a gold tongue?
Now, let's have the rest of it.
That's it. There's a good boy.
- Now, let's have the rest of it.
- That's all there is.
Oh.
- What's that?
- Oh, that's just my girdle.
- Oh, it's your girdle.
- I'm wearing it a little loose this...
Oh...
Say, that'll just fit me.
But I'm supposed to give
that money to somebody.
You just did.
Did you ever hear of a
man called Jesse James?
Who's he?
Well, he happens to be a very close
friend of mine that I'm gonna visit.
How do you think he's gonna feel
when he finds out how you treated me?
Heartbroken.
All right, boys,
let's get out of here.
Didn't I hand you $1
when we left New York?
Yes, sir. Right here.
Well, thanks for keeping
an eye on it for me.
Say, where can I find Jesse James?
I wanna talk to him about a robbery.
There's a guy here, wants
to see Jesse about a robbery.
Hey, open up. I want
to send a telegram.
I don't know what I've got, but
I hope there's a cure for it.
Jesse, a stranger in town wants
to see you about a robbery.
Thanks a lot.
Take care of that, Frank. Not too
rough. Just get him out of town.
That's New York. Send it collect.
Man could get a cheap nose job here.
Hey, where can I find Jesse James?
Never heard of him.
I'll find him.
I just got to figure out what a man like
Jesse'd be doing at this time of day.
It's for my new number.
You like it?
Yeah. Sure do like
it, Cora Lee, honey.
My, you're as pretty as a new bank.
Please, Jesse.
Don't ruin it before I've
had a chance to wear it.
Well, buy another one, if
that's all that's bothering you.
I'm sorry.
I guess all women feel
that way about a new dress.
Maybe so.
Oh, I forgot...
I got you something.
Looks mighty expensive.
Yeah, I'd have got it for you sooner,
but the train didn't come
through till this morning.
Thank you.
You got to keep it. We're
gonna get married, aren't we?
I'd like to think about it.
You thought about it long enough.
I'm getting tired of waiting.
Ma's coming in today. She's
gonna make the arrangements.
You always get what you
want, don't you, Jesse?
Always.
Cora Lee Collins.
Cora Lee Collins. I thought
that name sounded familiar.
Jesse's beneficiary.
Howdy.
Hi.
Hi, sir.
Nice day for drinking.
Wasn't it?
- What'll you have?
- Oh, I'd like some information.
We sell liquor here, boy.
Oh.
I'll take what he's having.
Do you know where I could
find a Miss Cora Lee Collins?
She works here at night.
If you're still here
by then, you'll see her.
You should have a wick in this.
What's the matter, don't you
like the liquor I'm drinking?
Yeah. It's okay.
Why don't you drink it?
That'll be 50 cents.
Here's your change.
Lucky I didn't have a bigger bill.
I hit it. Struck it rich.
The drinks are on me.
Hooray!
What'll it be?
Some of that.
- You drink that all the time?
- Ever since the goat went dry.
A man like you needs protection.
Now my company is willing to bet you
on how long you're gonna live, and
we'll take the short end by betting you
you'll live a long time.
- Really?
- That's the Plymouth Rock.
Fill them up again.
Where do I make the bet?
You just sign right there. And the bet's
on as soon as you pass the physical.
How are you fixed?
Hey, Grigsby!
You double-crossing
varmint! You jumped my claim!
He'll never pass the physical.
All right, drink up, everybody.
Anybody doesn't drink
with me is a dead man.
Well, what're you gonna do?
Oh, I can't play. I
don't have any money.
That's better than money.
Oh. Well, as long as
it's a friendly game.
- I'm out.
- Me, too.
- I pass.
- How many?
- I'll stand pat.
- I'll suffer through.
- Give me three.
Three.
- Give me three cards.
- I just gave you three.
I didn't like those.
Oh.
That's better. Now give me two.
Hope you find something you like
soon. I'm running out of deck.
That's fine. I got all I
need now. What do you do?
- Oh, I think I'll take one.
- You was pat.
Fair is fair.
Anything I can't stand,
it's cheating at cards.
Me, neither. Another thing
I can't stand is killing.
Well, now, killing in this town'll get
you 90 days. Cheating'll get you shot.
That's what I like. Law and order.
I bet two stacks.
Oh, I can't go any further.
I haven't got any more money.
Why, sure you have.
What're you fellas with, a laundry?
The pants.
I didn't think the
stakes were that low.
All right, there you are.
- I call you.
- Four queens.
Wait a minute. I didn't see 'em.
Mister, if you don't find four queens in
that deck, I'll give you your money back.
Hold it. I got you beat
anyway. I got four kings.
All right, let's see 'em.
I said, let's see 'em.
There.
If you don't find four kings in that
goat, I'll give you your money back.
Why, you cheating tinhorn.
Hold it. Don't anybody make a
move or I'll blow my brains out.
You've all had your little
joke. Now I'm giving the orders.
Okay. Give me my shirt. Here,
hold my coat. Give me my pants.
Here, hold my gun. You
don't know who you're...
Where have I failed?
One thing I know, a Westerner
never shot a man in the back.
Oh. Wait till I tell the
Chamber of Commerce about this.
I'll be right there, Ma.
What are you doing in here?
Oh, I'm with the fire
department, ma'am.
Just checking safety regulations.
Yep. Yeah, it'll burn.
Yeah. Oh, that'll burn.
I'm sorry.
It's very warm.
Get 'em up.
- That's what I'm trying to do.
- If I was you, I'd get out of this town.
Do you know whose room that
was you just come out of?
- No.
- Jesse James' gal.
Oh. Do you know who I am?
- No.
- Thanks. When's the next train leave?
That city fellow sent
this telegram a while ago.
Well, so he wired his
boss for more money.
Maybe we better be nice
to him till he gets here.
Where is this Farnsworth?
I just put him on the train, Jesse.
Don't worry, I'm used to
getting things off that train.
Why, it's Jesse James.
Put 'em down. Put 'em
down. This one's on me.
Hiya, Milford.
- Hiya, Jesse.
- I've been looking all over for you.
- I've been looking for you.
- Come on, we're going back.
- We're miles from town.
- Oh, I got a horse waiting.
Yeah?
He's my client.
Ma, I want you to
meet a friend of mine.
From New York. His name
is Milford Farnsworth.
- I'll go get your room ready.
- Howdy, son, and welcome.
Pleased to know you. Mighty
fine place you have here.
Well, I guess I'll be running along.
Oh, it's you.
I didn't recognize
you with your pants on.
Not so loud, please.
It's all right. The boys
told me all about it.
They was just joking with
you. They're kind of playful.
Yes.
You come on in with me. I'll
fix you a cup of raspberry tea.
Oh, don't let me
interrupt your housework.
Oh, don't fret. I already
done the big pieces.
I'm always cleaning up after the boys.
They're so careless.
It's important to keep
a gun clean, you know.
Oh, I know. A guy can
get blood poisoning
from getting killed
with a dirty bullet.
This here's our game room.
Who's playing here
tonight, Smith and Wesson?
Jesse got that for me
when he was just a boy.
I used to send him to the museum.
Imagine. A little kid like that, soaking
up culture, no matter what it weighed.
Sport model?
- What's this?
- That's one of Jesse's hobbies.
He collects gold watches. He's
got enough there to open a store.
Probably how he got most of them.
Milford, your room's ready for you.
Say, I sure appreciate your letting me
stay here where I can keep an eye on you.
I gotta make sure
nothing happens to you.
Hey! Here's a little present for you.
Really? For me? Gee, thanks, Jesse.
Hey, and you had it engraved, too.
I did?
Yeah. "To Milford Farnsworth
from his grandfather. "
- And Cora Lee. How nice.
- Hello, Ma.
What a pretty dress.
- You look mighty pretty yourself.
- Thank you, dear.
Come on in to the house.
- Evening, Miss Cora Lee.
- Evening, Cole.
- Hello, Hannah.
- Frank, here's Cora Lee.
- Good evening, Cora Lee.
- Good evening, Frank.
- Nice to see you.
- Thank you.
- Pardon me, will
you? - Mmm-hmm.
Oh, Mr. Farnsworth.
- How do you do?
- I believe you two have met.
- Oh, yes.
- How are things at the firehouse?
- Well, not too good.
- They found a sliver in the pole.
- I'll go get you two something to drink.
Say, I want to apologize for
breaking in on you like that.
Oh, that's all right. I
guess you lost your head.
That's not all I lost.
They do play a rough game
of poker in this town.
It's lucky I quit. My next
bet would've been skin.
Come in. Welcome to the party.
Come right on in and make
yourselves comfortable.
Oh, hiya, Milford. Some party, eh?
Oh, Cora Lee, honey.
Would you do the honors?
I'll fetch the cigars.
Milford Farnsworth, this is Luke
Hutchins, our mayor of Angel's Rest.
- Hi, Mayor.
- Welcome to our town.
It's yours for the asking.
And this is Jeremiah Cole,
our village blacksmith.
Oh, well, who's watching
the chestnut tree?
- Mighty glad to know you.
- Thank you very much.
You can quit pumping. I think
we got a pretty good blaze going.
And over here we
have Mortimer Hobclaw.
Mr. Hobclaw's our undertaker.
- How do you do?
- How are you?
Oh, I'm sorry. I meet so
few people standing up.
You can take inventory later.
Say, you have some mighty
interesting people here in Missouri.
That's very good.
What is your name, son?
Harry Truman.
Keep playing. You'll help the party.
- Shall we try the porch? It
might be cooler. - Mmm-hmm.
Is this your first trip
west, Mr. Farnsworth?
Yes, I've always wanted to open up
this territory for my insurance firm.
- Oh, you're in insurance.
- Deeper than you think.
- Is Mrs. Farnsworth here with you?
- No. She's too old to travel this far.
Besides, she wouldn't
want to leave Dad alone.
Oh, I know what you mean.
No. I guess I'm what you'd
call an eligible bachelor.
Oh.
Well, I guess there's no
harm in a man taking his time
before embarking on
a sea of matrimony.
As long as he doesn't wait till
he's too old to make the trip.
Oh, Ahwahnee.
This is Princess Ahwahnee.
Mr. Farnsworth, dear.
An Indian Princess. Do I
curtsy or just tip my scalp?
How do you do?
If you don't see what
you want, just ask for it.
Your eyes, they should be on a woman.
Yeah. They usually are.
Well, I see you've made a conquest.
Well, this is pretty
strange for me out here.
Different than New York?
Well, you could walk for days through
Central Park without seeing an Indian.
Really?
I'll get you a drink.
- No, thanks.
- How about something to eat?
- No, thank you.
- Would you care to dance?
Mmm-mmm.
Well, that doesn't leave very much.
- Hey, Cora Lee, how about it?
- All right.
It's a mighty pretty
evening for a barbecue
Got the banjos out
to plunk a bar or two
Moon is shining bright
And there's a star or two
And I can smell the donuts and the pie
But I just ain't a-hankering
for banjo plunking
Ain't a-hankering for pumpkin pie
Ain't a-hankering for donut dunking
There's something else
entirely on my mind
Oh, there's something
else entirely on my mind
And it ain't cotton picking
And it ain't berry pie
And it ain't eating chicken
There's something else
entirely on my mind
Oh, there's something
else entirely on my mind
I'll bet that Broadway's all lit
up And Central Park's in bloom
Swell hotels with belles
a-smelling from perfume
Folks a-grabbing hansom
cabs to see Grant's Tomb
And the carousel is swell
at Coney Isle But I just
Ain't a-hankering
to see trees blooming
Ain't a-hankering to see swell styles
Ain't a-hankering
to go Grant's-Tombing
There's something else
entirely on my mind
Yeah, there's something
else entirely on my mind
And it ain't hansom cabbing
And it ain't Coney Isle
And it ain't brass ring-grabbing
Oh, there's something
else entirely on my mind
Oh, there's something else entirely
on my mind
Everything all right, Frank?
Just like a church social. I told
the boys to lay off the rough stuff.
Him. Butter wouldn't
melt in his mouth.
- Maybe butter's not what he's after,
Jesse.  - Forget it, Frank.
- Okay. She's not my gal.
- Relax. Milford's our friend.
Till the dough comes.
Till the dough comes, then we
won't need Mr. Farnsworth anymore.
- Okay, Jesse. Just let me know.
- Let you know?
Yeah, you have all the fun.
Let me have this one, huh?
Well, I'd better say
goodnight to Jesse.
- Jesse.
- You have to leave so soon?
- I must. I'm a working girl, you know.
- Yeah, but not for long.
Oh, Milford, I gotta take
care of my other guests.
Would you mind showing
Cora Lee back to town?
I'd be happy to, Jesse.
- Good night, honey.
- Good night, Jesse.
You don't need to, Milford. Out here, you
know, women aren't quite that helpless.
Don't move.
There. Boy, the mice grow
pretty big out here, don't they?
- That was a Gila monster. They're deadly.
- Really?
You're a very brave man.
Why? For just killing a
little old Gila monster?
- I know. But with a rattlesnake?
- Yeah...
Come on, I'll take you home.
Later we'll toss to
see who takes me home.
I won't have it, Son. I
tell you, I won't have it.
I already told you, Ma. There's
nothing I can do about it.
I've got a position in this community,
and I'm gonna do the
best I can to uphold it.
I declare, Jesse, you're the most
stubborn son a mother ever had.
I'll leave it to anybody.
Oh, Mr. Farnsworth.
Oh, evening, ma'am. I was
just on my way up to my room.
I wish you'd help me talk some
sense into this fool son of mine.
He's bent on having a
gunfight tomorrow at dawn.
- Oh, you shouldn't do that.
- 'Course not.
I won't have him leaving
without breakfast.
I wish you'd quit babying me,
Ma. Snake Brice is in town,
boasting he's gonna shoot me
down. What do you expect me to do?
Eat a good breakfast.
Your pa never went out shooting
folks on an empty stomach.
You remind me of my own mother.
Besides, it's damp at dawn,
and Jesse's liable to get
pneumonia before he gets killed.
"Killed"? Hey, we got
to talk about this.
- What about the policy?
- We'll talk about it after the shooting.
No, that may be too late.
Promise me you'll wear your
rubbers if it's damp, Son?
Sure, Ma.
And remember to take
a clean handkerchief.
Stop fretting, Ma. I won't
go without my breakfast.
Well, I better get to sleep. Man
says he's gonna gun you at dawn,
you want to be there.
Jesse's a good boy.
- You mean you're gonna let him go?
- It's his work.
It's like being a doctor. If
somebody wants you, you gotta go,
any time of the day or
night. Know what I mean?
Anything happens to that
man, this company is ruined.
All right, I'm getting
tired of your ugly face.
Go for your guns.
Don't move. I got the drop on you.
Come on, get going.
- Jesse, somebody turned the horses loose.
- What?
- Somebody turned the horses loose.
- Well, round 'em up.
I've been robbed.
Here's the chance you been waiting
for, Snake. Jesse's in town.
I'll be ready soon as
I finish my breakfast.
I'm ready.
You wait in the stable.
I'll take it from here.
Anything I hate, it's a brave horse.
You go rest. I may be
heavier on the trip home.
Okay, Jesse, I'm
gonna give you a break.
You draw first.
I knew you was yellow, Jesse.
But it ain't gonna do you no good.
Draw.
Why, that's the fastest
draw Jesse ever made.
I never even seen his
hands touch his guns.
- Neither did I.
- No.
Nice shooting, Jesse. Hey,
wait a minute, that's not Jesse.
- That's Milford. Milford?
I hope that teaches him a lesson.
If he's not out of town by
noon, I'll wing him again.
- What's all the shooting about?
- Snake Brice was looking for Jesse.
- Jesse get him?
- No, but Milford did.
- Milford?
- He's got the fastest hat alive.
- Tell him I want to see him.
- All right.
- Have you been hit?
- Calm yourself, missy. I feel fine.
- You're sure you're all right?
- Yup.
You put on Jesse's clothes?
And you faced Snake Brice?
- Yup. Yup.
- You outdrew him. You shot him down.
- You're a gun-slinger.
- Yup. Yup. Nope.
- Then why did you do it?
- Well, I had to.
- It was either him or me or Jesse.
- But what does Jesse mean to you?
Jesse means everything to me.
I got him insured for $100,000.
But I don't have to tell you that.
After all, you're his beneficiary.
- His what?
- You mean to say you didn't know
that if Jesse gets
killed, you get $100,000?
Why would Jesse arrange
a thing like that?
You can answer that better than me.
After all, you're his girl, aren't you?
Well, aren't you?
Jesse doesn't ask questions. If he
wants something, he just takes it.
And who's gonna argue
with him? Are you?
Well, it hadn't occurred to me before,
but now that you mentioned it, nope.
Milford. Milford, will you do something
for me? Something I want very much?
Well, I reckon that depends.
- Now, what was it you wanted?
- Get out of town.
You sure got a funny
way of saying goodbye.
I wouldn't want anything
to happen to you.
If you stay around here, you
haven't got a chance. Will you go?
I don't know, but I'd sure
like to say goodbye again.
You're a little late, Jesse.
Milford already took care of Snake.
Where's Milford now?
You see, I told you.
Somebody shot at you.
Let's have a little more
respect for heroes out there.
I reckon I better go down
and teach him a lesson.
- No, wait.
- Huh?
Please, don't start anything, Milford.
Oh, as long as I don't come
unstrung, I'm still in business.
Sorry, Milford. Thought
I saw a man in here.
Oh, maybe it's because
I'm wearing your clothes.
Yeah, would you mind telling
me what this is all about?
Well, I want to talk to you about that
insurance policy, but you won't let me.
He was only trying
to protect you, Jesse.
Yeah, if anything
happens to you, I'm dead.
Well, let's not have any more of this.
And I don't like anybody
doing my shooting for me.
Or anything.
What's that?
Well, I shaved this morning,
and I'm a slow bleeder.
Better get out of here
before I become a faster one.
Got something for you, Jesse.
This just come for Farnsworth
from that insurance
company in New York.
"Milford Farnsworth,
Angel's Rest, Missouri.
"You are fired. Repeat, fired.
"You are the Benedict Arnold
of the insurance business.
"Am coming west with another $33,000
"to buy back policy.
Arriving 10:00 tonight.
"Kindly do not meet
me. Titus Quesely. "
Oh, we ain't gonna meet him.
We're just gonna shake hands
with his money. Thanks, Elmo.
Wait a minute, what's all this
about my being your beneficiary?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
Well, one day soon, you and
me are gonna collect $100,000.
Then we can settle down.
To collect $100,000,
you've gotta be dead.
Oh, I won't be dead.
It'll be some fellow
who just looks like me.
- Milford.
- Yeah, Jess?
You wear that outfit.
Looks great on you.
- Can I keep it?
- As long as you live.
And don't tire yourself out down there.
We got a little business deal tonight.
Say, Jesse, I wonder what's
holding up that train?
In case you forgot, we are.
- Hey, nobody's gonna get hurt, are they?
- Not necessarily.
Whatever you do, don't get shot.
My company would never forgive me.
I don't plan to.
- Hey, here she comes now.
- Hey, Jesse, I've been thinking this over
and I'm gonna sit this one
out. I just don't like it.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
All right, let's go. Come on.
Aw, it might be fun after all.
You know what to do?
I ought to. I've been robbed myself.
Well, now's your chance to get even.
I'm pretty fast on the trigger, too.
And there's the trigger, right there.
Just remember. These people try
to hide their jewels and money.
We have to search everybody.
Check. You take the men
and I'll take the women.
Come on.
Reach.
We'll cover you. Get busy.
All right, get your valuables out.
Don't any of you varmints reach for a
weapon or I'll let daylight through you.
Put it in the poke. There
you are. Okay, all of it.
All right, shorty, get it up. Come
on, let's have it. Where did you go?
Toss it down, redwood.
You got snow up there?
All right, get 'em up. Up.
What a bank. Drop that
turnip in here. Watch it.
Okay, let's have it. Okay, come on.
Young man, I hope you realize what
you're doing's against the law.
Hide it. Hide it,
we're over our quota.
- What are you trying to do?
- Sorry, we don't take confederate money.
Here, let me see that. All right...
Nothing wrong with that stuff.
What are you trying to do,
go in business for yourself?
What's wrong with that?
Nothing. I just wanted to
see if you're on your toes.
Boys, let's get out of here. Yeah.
- You, guard the rear.
- Guard the rear?
Oh, but, Jesse, Jesse, wait for me.
Jesse, wait for me. Jesse,
Jesse, where are you?
Come on. What are we waiting
for? Let's get out of here.
One little chore we
ain't attended to yet.
- Oh! Oh, there you are.
- Let's get outta here.
Jesse!
- Okay, Jesse, I covered the rear.
- You ride on ahead. We'll take over.
Well, that's that.
Get in touch with the insurance people
and tell them that Jesse James is dead.
I needed that.
You look like you had a
hard day at the office.
We're going to the ranch tonight.
Start packing your things.
- What for? What is all this?
- We had an accident at the train tonight.
I got killed.
He's dead.
The tombstone on Boot Hill
will have my name on it.
As soon as the insurance
company pays off that $100,000,
we'll have enough for
the rest of our lives.
We're getting married tomorrow.
Now, let's take this
a little slower, Jesse.
Now start packing.
- You the telegraph operator?
- That's right.
Never figured she'd make it on
time after getting held up tonight.
- How did you know the train was held up?
- That train always gets held up.
Here.
I want this message delivered promptly to
the telegraph operator at the first stop.
We'll get ourselves a
fine spread somewhere.
A long ways from here, 1,000
miles. Maybe California.
You and Frank can have this place.
Gonna be all right, Ma,
working out real great.
What if they come around
here, looking for him?
- Looking for who?
- Milford.
Just tell 'em he went back east.
Sounds reasonable.
Milford was a nice boy.
Yeah.
Too bad he didn't have
some of his own insurance.
So they'll be looking for him.
Leastways they won't be
looking for me no more.
There won't be any more
sheriffs riding up to my door.
It's Milford.
Whoa. Oh, boy. Whoa girl. Whoa.
Happy yogurt.
Oh, good. You made it. I
was worried about you, Jesse.
I would've gone back and looked for
you, but my horse got away from me.
Boy, I thought sure they got you.
Good boy.
Oh, boy.
It's sure good to be home.
What a night.
What's the matter with you two? You
look as though you've seen a ghost.
Why, we heard you got killed
in the train holdup, Milford.
What happened? I can't
understand how we could've...
I mean, I thought you stopped
a lot of lead out there.
Oh, I did. I gained twelve pounds
in seven seconds. But I was okay.
Boy, it's a good thing
Jesse went to that museum.
I was wearing my heavies.
- Pretty good, eh, Ma?
- Oh, yes. Yes, indeed.
- You were very lucky, Milford.
- Lucky? I could've been Swiss cheese.
Those bullets were playing Goodbye
Forever up and down my spine.
Oh, but I've had it. I'm gonna find
Mr. Quesely first thing in the morning
and give myself up. It won't be
bad. You know, about 10 years.
- Give yourself up? What for?
- I robbed a train tonight.
- Well, so what? I was there, too.
- Yeah, but that's different with you.
That's your business. Yeah.
Well, I'll see you in the
morning before I leave, Ma.
Good night, Ma.
- Good night, Jesse.
- Good night, Milford.
Boy, I'm glad you're okay.
That's the main thing. Good night.
- How about that?
- Now, now, Son.
Things went a little wrong
tonight. Don't let that bother you.
Remember what I
always taught you, Son.
What you can't do today
you can do tomorrow.
Good morning.
- Going someplace?
- Yes, it's back to the big town for me.
Well, I'm kind of glad,
and I'm sorry, too, Milford.
We'll miss you around here.
Yeah, well, I gotta get back
and report to the company.
I got a lot of big deals cooking.
I think you're one of the
nicest persons I've ever known.
I'm glad I'm here to hear it.
I'm sorry things didn't
work out better for you.
Oh, things worked out fine, just fine.
I got myself mixed up in a robbery.
Practically put my
company out of business.
Double-crossed my friends.
It's not easy to louse up a whole
town in three days, but I made it.
Compared to me, General
Custer was a big success.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Milford.
I'd kind of like to say
goodbye like we did before.
Yeah.
- Goodbye, Milford.
- Cora Lee.
- Hi, Jess.
- Milford.
Milford, I was thinking about
what you talked about last night.
You didn't do anything wrong.
Your boss was bringing that money
out to give to me and I got it.
Yeah, but you don't understand, Jesse.
The money was for the
return of the policy.
Return the policy.
- Well, I might just do that.
- You would?
I always knew you were my friend.
You ride into town and tell Quesely
that I'll be in for a talk, huh?
Oh, great.
- Oh, Milford.
- Yeah.
Be sure you take the shortcut, the
one over there through Stone Canyon.
- Stone Canyon?
- Yeah.
- Thanks, Jesse.
- Real pretty that way.
- Bye, Cora Lee.
- Bye, Milford.
I'll be back in a minute.
He don't scare me, but if you're
chicken, we better get going. Come on.
Come on, baby.
All right, this is
it. Whip it into high.
If I was in shape, you wouldn't...
You...
Oh. I wasn't trying.
I know how you feel about me, Princess,
but try and control your emotions.
- Keep head down. Maybe come more rock.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it's a good thing
you bumped into me.
- That could have been a nasty accident.
- No accident.
You might not be so lucky next
time. Now, this policy protects you
against falling objects, buffalo
stampedes and termites in your wigwam.
Just sign right here.
What do you mean it was no accident?
- If you die, Jesse collect insurance.
- Jesse? But I've got him insured.
How could he collect if...
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, he could dress my
body up in his clothes,
and there's plenty
of crooked witnesses.
Yeah.
Come on. Let's get outta here. They
may be loading that slingshot again.
I'm deeply honored by your
obvious affection for me, Princess,
- but I'm not your type, honest Injun.
- Ahwahnee know that you love another.
- Cora Lee?
- She send me to warn you of ambush.
- Really?
- She love you.
Love me? Oh, I couldn't be that lucky.
- It is sad that you let her marry another.
- A doll like her, loving...
What was that again?
She does not wish it,
but Jesse marry her today.
Well, he can't do that to my girl.
- We got to figure out a way to stop that.
- How?
This is no time for Indian
talk. Let's get moving.
Whoa. Whoa there.
- Someone's coming.
- Yeah?
- Maybe Jesse's men.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa, there. Whoa, there.
Hey, Indians. Indians.
Halt! Halt in the name of the law.
- Me, Justice of Peace.
- Me no savvy. Gotta scoot.
- Me big hurry.
- I'm in a hurry, too.
This is one bridegroom I'd
better not keep waiting.
Are you make marriage?
Come all the way from
Elderberry City for this one.
Which way is the James Ranch?
Me show paleface. Me show how go fast.
Go fast like wind
through cheap teepee.
I'm in a hurry. I'm late now.
Ah, come. Come.
- Just tell me. Point.
- No. Come up hill. See James' wigwam.
Very good, from hill. Come.
Well, a man don't get
married every day, you know.
What a beautiful day for a wedding.
Like they say, "Happy is the
bride the sun shines on. "
Then I don't see why it doesn't rain.
Oh... It would cool things off.
Oh, you're just fretting,
dear. And you don't need to.
Jesse's going to treat you real
nice. Jesse respects womanhood.
He ain't never shot a one.
How do you like the foliage?
Oh, you fool me.
Thanks to you, old man. When we get
to town I'll buy you a flyswatter.
We can't ride horse. Horse
get sick. Been eating these.
- What are you talking about?
- You see.
He looks all right to me.
Whoops.
Looks like somebody
stole his merry-go-round.
- Is he going to happy hunting ground?
- They no kill.
Just make loco for short time.
Hey, they sound like
wonderful party favors.
Hey, get a rock, we can grate
some of these in the buckboard.
These may help our case. I hate to
go to a party empty-handed. Come on.
Hey, Jesse, come here.
- The justice of the peace is here.
- Well, it's about time you got here.
I'm sorry about that. I got a
late start from Elderberry City.
My wife forgot to wind the rooster.
Yeah. Well, let's get started.
Hey, you guys, pipe down.
All right, we'll start the wedding.
Oh, guns have no place in
the sanctity of marriage.
I will not share the room with
weapons of the devil. No, sir.
Well, all right, boys. Take off your
guns. We'll put 'em in the kitchen.
Put 'em on the table, boys.
Well, a mighty fine
spread you got here.
Oh, I'm sorry, Judge. I'm
not used to being a host.
- Have a drink.
- Well, just a little one.
Oh, go on, have a real drink.
Well, it wouldn't be proper for me to
drink unless it was a toast to the groom.
That's it. A toast to the groom.
To Jesse James, a good son,
- a good brother and a good...
- Down the hatch!
Let's have another one.
Everybody ready?
Here comes the bride.
My friends, we are...
How you feeling?
Fine. Will you get on with it?
My friends, we are all gathered here
today to mourn for the dearly departed.
Oh, I'm sorry, that's
where I left off yesterday.
What about today?
Oh, you nervous bridegrooms
are all the same.
- What are you doing?
- Just checking.
A healthy marriage
is a happy marriage.
Do you, Jesse James, take this
woman to be your lawful wedded wife?
Yeah.
And do you, Cora Lee Collins, take this
man to be your lawful wedded husband?
She does.
- The ring, please.
- The ring?
Ring?
Well, if there's no ring, you can
hardly expect to have a wedding.
I knew this marriage wouldn't last.
Pardon me.
Jesse, come and get some coffee, dear.
I told you you were making
that punch too strong.
Hey, you guys. Get in the
kitchen, coffee up. Fast!
There, they'll never
come through this door.
They sure won't. That's the
closet. The door's over there.
Hey, wait. I got an idea. I
want to look for something.
Hurry.
Let's go, men.
Here we go.
They're coming. Come on.
Here they are. Up
here in this room here.
It's locked.
All right, men. Let's
break this door down.
Put your shoulder
into it. Come on, move!
I'll bet you this is the first time
the preacher ever eloped with the bride.
There they go! Come on, men!
Missed. They're getting away.
Move, you nincompoops.
Head for the depot. We
gotta catch the train.
- What's the matter, Milford? Are you hurt?
- No, I'm fine now.
Thanks for the rest.
Darling.
Boy, I'm sure glad that's over.
Hey, Cora Lee, come back!
Bring a ladder.
I wonder what's par for this hole?
Find a river, quick.
I've had enough of that.
We've missed the train. Now what?
- Head for town. The Sheriff will help us.
- Yeah.
Whoa.
Come on.
- Sheriff, you gotta help us.
- He's gone.
Yeah. Wait. I'll get one of these.
Milford, be careful. I
know Jesse. He's dangerous.
Look for some ammunition.
- You fool. You might hit Jesse.
- Down, Mr. Quesely.
What are you trying to do, ruin me?
I got no time to talk to you.
I'm gonna get killed in a minute.
You'll get killed when I tell you to.
I've sent for the proper
authorities. They'll handle this.
Hey, you ruffians.
Put down those guns.
I'm making a citizen's
arrest. I say that...
Mr. Quesely! Mr. Quesely!
Mr. Quesely!
There you are, Mr.
Quesely. Have one on me.
Milford, look. Look what I found.
Darling, are you all right?
Yeah, you're all right.
- Is he dead?
- No.
He's one of those sneak-drinkers.
Here, stop making a pig of yourself.
- Look, Milford.
- Huh?
Oh, he's mine.
- You got him.
- Of course. I had him surrounded.
Here, notch that. Oh, I'll get him.
That got 'em.
That's one more. Notch it again.
Well, back to the wagon.
- Wonderful, Milford.
- You want more, huh?
Well, another one for Boot Hill.
I'll bet they're sorry
they ever tangled with me.
Happy trails to you.
You hot little heater.
You want a teddy bear, baby? Stand by.
Frank, give me a light.
Shoot at my friend, will you?
Make smaller notches.
I may run out of handle.
I never saw such shooting.
A little high.
I'm slicing again.
Yep.
Man, do I handle this thing.
Milford, I think there's
a man behind that barrel.
Give me that rifle.
Poor fool, he never had a chance.
Paleface bite dust.
Somebody's been smuggling
guns to the Indians.
- Anybody left out there?
- This is the shot I've been waiting for.
All right, stick your
head up, I dare you.
This fellow needs all
the help he can get.
Man, I didn't know he
could shoot like that.
Yeah.
All right, drop those
guns or I'll show no mercy.
Anything you say, Milford.
Throw down your guns, boys.
There they are. I didn't think they'd
give up that easily. How about that?
Wonderful job!
Watch my trigger finger.
It was one of my shorter battles, but
I don't want to take all the credit.
Here's the gal, right here.
She helped load my guns.
It was nothing. Nothing at all.
If I've done anything to restore
law and order to this community,
I just want to tell you that I've
been amply rewarded. And I mean amply.
- Milford.
- Oh, yes, Mayor.
In gratitude for what you've done,
the citizens of Angel's Rest are
going to erect a statue of you
right on this very spot.
Oh, Milford. Just think, a
statue of you, right here.
Not yet, you fools. Not
yet. Wait till they build.
I tell you, insurance is a must for
everyone. I wouldn't be without it.
I carry protection against
every possible contingency.
I have life insurance, health insurance,
fire, accident, horseless carriage,
lightning, collision,
flood, personal liability...
- Mrs. Farnsworth is here.
- Oh, good. Send her in.
Will you excuse me? Think it over.
- Hello, my darling.
- Cora Lee.
Milford.
- Hi, Daddy.
Daddy. Daddy. Daddy.
Well, you can't get
insurance against everything.
Daddy. Daddy. Daddy.