Quick, Merrick.
They are lynching
a rustler.
Do not eat?
The beans are delicious.
Dan ...
Drop that whip!
Who are you?
My name is Merrick.
I'm sheriff
U.S..
He's new here, right?
The law no.
We are the law.
This man is a murderer.
He killed my son.
It hangs from a rope
government.
Colguémosle now
What's the difference?
We will take you to Santa Loma,
the court will decide.
Come on!
Shoot, Billy.
Before you die.
Shoot.
This is absurd, Len.
You're going to die by a murderer?
Take him to Santa Loma.
Come on!
Shoot!
You and Lou take you
the prisoner.
I'll catch up.
Sorry, Roden.
I had to do.
Hang the murderer
and the sheriff.
Reflect,
It is a federal sheriff.
Let's follow him!
Let your father fix it.
Do not risk everything
for revenge.
I lost a son.
Do not want to lose my ranch.
Who is coming?
You know what will happen
in Washington when they learn?
Who cares
one horse thief!
It will just be one more incident.
One more incident.
And maybe the last.
A rustlers were hung.
Well, I'm waiting.
Forget it.
We know how you feel.
Let us help you ...
Bury Ed ...
Out of here!
All of you!
Where are you going?
A bury Ed
We'll bury him at home.
The ranch.
I'll help you bring it.
I'll take one.
Why I can not go?
He's my brother.
It was my son.
So do I.
See you at the ranch.
Gather all men.
No one follows us.
We can rest.
It's new, is not it, sheriff?
Why?
You do not know
the Roden family.
They never rest, ...
To me ... hanging on a rope.
They may not be the law.
I did not kill him, though I suppose
I lose time.
You're wasting my time too.
The jury will decide whether
innocent or guilty. Not.
Anyway, ...
Thanks for everything ... Dick.
No tricks.
Billy,
rides in front with him.
The horses are thirsty
and soon darkened.
We should find a place
sleeping.
Guys, if you want to spend
night indoors, ...
My house is ... road,
two hours from here.
I would not mind sleeping
indoors.
Accept the offer.
When I left my home
in this single and alone ...
for fame ...
and fortune ...
I can not believe I'm
singing on the way to my own judgment.
hear my call
small cottage on the plain ...
You are going to judge
the wrong crime.
Stop!
That's where they say killed
young Roden.
Where is your home?
West.
Back
of those peaks.
Go ahead, Billy.
I catch at home.
Come on, Daddy, let's go.
It has saved a murderer,
What do you want now?
Sorry about your son.
At the ranch, my son was worth
by five men.
She was everything to me.
He was the best son in the world.
The revolver was made
for you.
There was no horse
I could not ride.
Neither man who
not win.
But now he's dead.
Your broken heart
by the bullet of a robber.
- I'll help.
- Take your hands off me!
If you want to help,
hang the murderer.
You do not know if he killed him.
All he knows is that
this man stole their cattle.
Do you believe me capable of killing
a man for stealing cattle?
He killed my son.
And die for it.
We shoot, we are not
livestock!
For your kicks any
'd say you're a mule.
I'm glad you're not.
Let go!
- Leave it!
- Quiet, Daddy.
- Friend of yours?
- It's my daughter.
The old set us
a trap.
What happened?
We came riding
quietly, ...
Old singing ...
his lungs, ...
When he started ... hooting
as an owl.
We thought he was crazy.
Suddenly she appeared
and told us that we marcháramos.
We discuss and began
shooting.
So treat your guests?
Never invite farmers.
Leave it, Anne.
I've tried to convince them.
But they are the law.
The law?
What do they want?
- His father is arrested.
- Why?
For stealing.
- Stealing says?
- That's what I said.
Well, now that we
friends ...
Thank you.
Want ... maybe dinner.
Anne cooks very well.
Let's try their food,
What can we lose?
As our lives.
The Old Testament.
Incredible document!
Shot dear. I can not
cleaned more.
OLD RIFLE
THIS IN THE BARN
This is what I call
a good home cooked meal.
You yourself dinner!
I'm hungry!
Set the table,
I'm not your maid!
Notes:
Whereas,
hereby ...
Bequeath my heritage ...
my daughter.
The recital does not make you
lack.
Well, as you say, ...
But many ...
recitals ...
To look like ... seriously.
And this knife I leave ...
I leave it to me.
Of time.
All right.
He writes:
I leave the sheriff Merrick,
to my regret.
Furthermore, ...
Inquire ... ...
All parties ...
interested, ...
Me ... I want my daughter Anne, ...
Relive ... Lancaster.
Whereas living
Aida with her aunt Bessie.
That goes to put it.
It is my will.
Write it.
Do I have to leave my daughter, no?
I have to leave it to someone.
I tell you what has
to put ...
What will ...
on his tombstone.
Here lies my beloved father ...
Killed by the sheriff ...
Merrick.
Tell me, what is your name?
So we can put it completely.
Where are you going?
A put liniment,
Cares?
His spurs were
goose.
And you, where you are going?
It would be wrong to leave her
go alone.
Do not trust me?
It is a very ugly wound,
need help.
Do not worry, sheriff,
knows the way.
Sit down, I'll play
guitar.
Play the guitar
for them.
And redo the owl.
A cautious type,
not trust anyone.
When works.
Ie, from sunrise to sunset.
I'm going to water the horses.
I already gave them.
I have to put more things
to complete the document.
Here I have some boots.
I bought by mail
twelve years ago.
I have not used, it's a shame,
They are almost new.
- What number do you wear?
- The same. Thank you.
Well, moving on.
Look what's here.
I forgot, the reserved
for the wedding of Anne.
He writes:
Hereby
leave this ...
Better forget it.
It is very dark.
Are you afraid?
Yet.
I'll get it.
Sit.
Sting. Special
for horses and mules.
This will serve.
Hop pants.
I've marked it well, right?
It's nothing.
I would not have tried so
knew it was a girl.
I do not blame.
Sorry, but it would be easier
if you wore a dress.
The dresses, clog.
Depends on what you do.
It will be enough.
Sheriff, I'm sorry
I said before in the house.
It was to kill you
my father.
I did not take it seriously.
Let it go.
Do not you understand?
If you are caught you will be lynched.
They did not lynch,
I promise.
You do not know
these farmers.
We have burned the harvest
for three consecutive years.
Farmers do not want
these lands.
The fourth year we burned
the house.
Do you think you are not able
yo lynch?
He's been caught stealing cattle.
Give it a chance, sir,
please.
Why you?
If you want.
No hurt so needed.
Hurt me??
I use simple spur.
You are struck with
a Mexican spur.
No, let me do.
He is very stubborn you.
Did he use
as a crutch?
I thought tie it around his neck!
Sheriff, nobody knows
we came.
Talk.
Roden try to prevent
Loma Santa arrives ...
Man ... with his ranch,
stop them.
Before he was thus
What happened?
I did not know who had
a sheriff.
I do not want trouble for lynch
a rustler.
They also want to lynch
to you
Escóltenos his men
to Santa Loma.
I live here.
No one will face
Roden for a murderer.
Still not been
convicted.
What more proof do you need?
Ed is dead.
And the old man had won.
If you are a murderer,
court deal with it.
If no handles Roden
to do before.
Did you know what he wrote
boy in her grave?
Here lies the heart
of a parent.
A man without heart
It is a dangerous enemy.
Thank you.
Any law prohibits scrub?
Sit, Len.
Today we do not eat.
In March, guys.
Do not spend the night here?
Roden seeks him.
Or we go fast
or we are lost.
I do not get it.
We'll go through the desert
Santa Loma.
The desert?
We are in August.
Not make it,
very hot.
It is impossible
Loma Santa around.
We have no choice. Roden
We find if we follow another path.
We kill them all.
Give him the old,
only give us problems.
Give up and save your skin,
coward.
We're now
through the desert.
I know it will be very hard, but
never think of looking for us there.
And if they do, take
overnight lead.
In March, Billy.
Come on, we finished dinner.
Put your hat.
Two more.
Make sure that the saddlebags are well attached.
Do not carry too much food.
You can not miss us water
on this tour.
Sheriff, I feel cause
many problems. I want to thank ...
It is not for you,
it's the law.
I would even if I had
killed 10 men.
Do you think I killed him?
I do not think anything
neither one nor the other.
You are not going anywhere.
I'm going with him.
Stay, we will
Santa Loma.
I will not leave you alone.
This new generation.
Do you think you resist?
Since, Mt.
It is hard, Billy type.
It is a righteous man.
It can be.
I think there are over
songs.
He's right.
Although it may be best
keep singing.
Down in the valley ...
... the valley so low, ...
About your head ...
... hear the wind blow.
Hear the wind blow, ...
On your head
hear the wind blow.
Do not sing that!
Hear the wind blow, ...
Enough!
What's the matter, son?
Do not call me son again.
I do not because it is
my blood.
Forget it.
What's the matter, Billy?
Not bad singing.
No one has ever said anything.
If I were you,
sing no more, Daddy.
Why not?
His father used to sing.
Merrick, listen.
My father could only escape ...
But with so many horses ...
they follow the trail.
Give it a chance,
let go.
My obligation is to take
before the judge.
They hang.
Then it will hang.
Hopefully his father also dies
hanging from a tree.
Sure, you've hit the mark!
What's up, Dad?
I got him.
Me loose before
soportándome follow.
Down in the valley, ...
... the valley so low, ...
over your head ... and ...
... hear the wind blow.
Hear the wind blow, ...
... hear the wind blow, ...
over your head ... and ...
... hear the wind blow.
Hate this song.
His father used to sing.
Sorry, Len.
I remember your father, do not you, son?
Will it also led him to the gallows?
Why do not you call me daddy?
So do you keep the joke.
We have a tough road
ahead. The burning wind.
Billy, checks the water.
Lou, full canteens.
Before I prepare the food.
Eat without dismounting.
What?
We have ridden all night.
Must rest
during the day.
Within hours
the desert is so hot, ...
- ... You can fry eggs.
- Fill it.
I almost drowned.
His father also
chewing snuff, son?
Down in the valley, ...
... the valley so low, ...
over your head ... and ...
... hear the wind blow.
Let dad.
Do not get cause.
Assign, I have given
a good stab.
If I could catch
his revolver.
This song is better
a gun.
Down in the valley, ...
... the valley so low, ...
over your head ... and ...
... hear the wind blow.
Hear the wind blow, ...
... hear the wind blow, ...
over your head ... and ...
Hold me tight, ...
... give them my warmest ...
... if you do not love me ...
... love who you please.
You are full, Len.
Very well.
Underway.
We will.
I love it.
Monte on his horse.
It is the stream of dead man
You know, Billy?
And that?
A sheriff fell from his horse
and drowned right here.
valley low, ...
over your head ... and ...
... hear the wind blow, ...
... hear the wind blow.
If you love me ...
Are not you going to shut up that old?
He seems to have stepped
a monkey tail.
No one can stand
in this heat.
It's my fault.
I should not talk about ...
About what?
I'll also
on this tour, you know?
Nothing.
If you love me ...
... love who you please.
Hold me ...
... give them my warmest.
Give my warmest  ...
... give them my warmest ...
Hold me ..
Follow this starts
to like ... son!
Rest here.
Prepare food, Lou.
Are you hungry now?
Basta, Lou, he also
what's going wrong.
Put a medal.
Merrick, make a deal.
What would not hear me
more singing that song?
Soon will be darkened, and no
blame him.
I will try to cross the desert
to the border, ...
And ... will not hear
that song.
No deal.
Return with others.
Very good, very good.
Answer me one thing, son, ...
... About his father.
I'm curious, child.
What he also hung up?
Drop it!
Father!
What happened?
Not to make a deal.
Do not even talk about it.
What is it?
Have you gone mad?
Lou helps with food.
Len does not make sense
behave well.
Do you also want to sing?
I do not know.
You know, maybe we should not
take him to Santa Loma.
What are you saying?
It's just an old
scoundrel,
You know what I mean ...
Looks like a murderer ... no.
It's none of your business.
Not mine.
Our duty is to deliver it.
Mount up!
Give us the thief ...
Or you will die ...!
I warn
Last, Roden, ...
More ... stay away!
Come on, take cover!
Keep shooting.
I hit the water.
I want the thief.
Fast!
Come on!
Squat!
Look, Roden!
The catch the thief.
A trigger finger more
will be fine.
I also know how to shoot.
Go back to your site.
Come on!
Drop it.
Hurry!
Still, and raising hands.
Get over there.
Tell them to stop!
Stop them!
Alto, father!
Stop!
Cease fire!
Release my son!
- Go away from here, Roden!
- Okay.
You can stay
the rustler ...
Release ... but my son.
YOUR child will come to us
Santa Loma.
Thus, it will cause us
more problems.
Drop it, I command you!
Go away or I'll kill him!
I lost a son.
I can not lose another.
I Átalo.
What happened?
I turned my back.
I'm a clumsy assistant.
You remove the plate as
get to Santa Loma.
You have to go back now.
You can not cross the desert with him.
Shut!
Do not listen, Len, I'm fine.
We only water is
of the canteens.
- There is a well half desert.
- Is it true?
Sure, I'm thirsty.
You can be lying.
Return.
No, ...
Roden attack us ...
in the gorge.
And I will not lose.
In the desert
you can not hide.
Move!
What are you waiting for?
Sorry, Billy.
Can you do it?
We will.
Lou, who rides
horse Billy.
You'll be fine, boy.
Sure, ...
I have been hurt ...
other times.
Want to relax?
Lean, Billy.
Stop looking for your father.
Appreciates your life.
We did not follow.
I'm burning, ...
Ardo ... inside.
I thirst.
Do not waste water.
Missing a day's journey
to reach the well.
I feel that escaped me
sorry about your father, Len.
Forget it, Billy.
You saved my life
many times.
Can you forgive me?
Forget it, Billy.
Everything will be fine.
Sing that song, ...
I like ... that song.
Sing.
In the valley below ...
... the valley so low, ...
over your head ... and ...
... hear the wind blow.
Hear the wind blow, ...
I follow you, Len.
I will follow you forever.
He's dead.
If I had heard, ...
If he had left ... go to my father,
would not have died!
You and their law!
How many more will kill?
Continue in an hour.
Pray for him.
And when we get to Santa Loma
pray for you.
- I did not shoot him.
- You, your father, all are guilty.
And you you will pay for it.
Look what you've done!
If he had not killed
my brother!
What are you talking about?
Murderer!
We should hang when
catch him.
Father, but we
have been arrested?
It's what they say, small.
Do not think saying a prayer?
He knew the risk he was taking.
Do not you feel anything?
Do not you care that your best friend
he's dead?
It was not me who killed him.
The fulfilled the law.
The law!
Does the law will lead to my father
to the gallows?
Billy followed the law
and he's dead.
If you forget the law, Billy would still be alive
and my father would not die.
I did that once.
Once I forgot the law,
and my father died for it.
I let hang
my own father.
I killed him.
I was his assistant,
Billy as mine.
Had to deliver
two prisoners.
They wanted to lynch them and I thought
they deserved.
We discussed ...
My father and I ... ...
... And he took the prisoners alone.
We waited on the road.
We also lynched him.
Is that why it behaves like this?
If I had gone with him, ...
Billy came ... like me ...
... Had followed the law, ...
Rather than take ...
justice for my hand, ...
My father ... still be alive.
Or you would also be
dead.
They could lynched him, too.
It would have been better.
Stop agonizing over
a past mistake.
Long ago
I stopped doing it.
But when his father
sang that song ...
Well ... my father did ...
I remembered everything ... again.
Why did not you tell me
who accuse my father of murder?
Who told you?
That does not matter ...
But ... now I know why
did not tell me.
Because he knows I love him ...
As much as you want ...
yours.
We are very similar,
You and me.
You are blamed for failing
saved his father, ...
And ... I just try to save
mine.
I can not fool you.
He risked his life Billy
on behalf of the law, ...
Has ... but also risky
yours.
I wish my father did not
between us.
I've been thinking.
What?
You could win
lot of money.
No one is bitter sweet.
Want to be the foreman
our ranch?
If you let me escape ...
Reward you ... my father.
I'll tell you what you've done,
and make you foreman.
I do not think enough.
Okay calls.
What is enough?
I own ranch.
Continued.
A big, ya understand me.
Ten acres, perhaps ...
- ... And won.
- You got it.
My father will give the best
ranch all.
You are afraid.
You are scared!
Why would I be scared?
By Merrick.
Do you think enough?
So I do not accept
your proposal.
I do not want to pursue
the rest of my life.
He will not do anything.
No, because I will not
to give him a chance.
Do the same.
Billy has been murdered, ...
Do not like you ... and nothing.
Nothing at all.
You and I are in the same boat.
We have to be together.
You and me?
I killed your brother,
Remember?
- You said you did not.
- Do you believe me?
Yes, of course.
Is that why you tried to kill me?
Hey, I made a mistake.
All were wrong.
Your mistake could cost me
life.
Better
did you calm down ...
He has given you ... a lot of sun.
We must do something.
We can not wait
that crazy to kill us.
You got that right, ...
But ... what can we do?
They have guns.
- What about us?
- We have the girl.
What?
She knows to handle him.
That is, kill!
Let them!
Let them finish!
What has happened now?
They have fought.
Nothing more.
Your duty was to prevent it.
Add the horse.
Collect, Lou.
I'll take care of you.
You do not occupy anyone.
Where is your gun?
Here!
Come on, stupid, ...
... Take off your belt.
Toss it here.
My father with me.
You have to understand.
You made me believe ...
I think all I said ..
But I will not ... I die.
Take my belt also.
We're even.
Now we're even.
Do not repeat ...
If put back ...
hand over ...
I will ... kill you.
I wish I was dead
Maybe it is
sooner than you think.
Stop!
My horse was hurt.
Eh, sir!
That well, ...
Is there ...?
Yes, but there is way.
The horses will not hold
much more.
Soon be dark.
Where did you get that?
Why?
For nothing.
My brother had one like it.
I found it next to him.
Now it's mine.
Now everything here belongs to me.
Give it to me.
Which you will not do you
no foul.
Lou, mounted on horse
the girl.
And you ride with your father.
I warned you.
And if horses
do not stand up well?
Walk.
Move!
He is asleep ...
But ... no.
Go back to your site.
Better sleep also.
Now I sleep in Santa Loma ...
... Hanging from the gallows.
We do not know
the jury's verdict.
Think will not go well
standing, right, Sheriff?
I do not like to hang
anyone.
Is it because you remember
his father?
No, it's not that.
Why her?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I know you do not want to see me
Hanging, and neither.
So ...
... If I have a chance to get out
from here and Santa Loma ...
I think ... do.
I do not back
unless you want to die.
I have nothing personal
against you, friend, ...
... On the contrary,
thank you ...
Not to say ...
of which I am accused.
But that does not change the situation.
Now I know
get out.
He knows perfectly.
Do not believe that feelings
going to cloud my judgment.
Fair enough, sir.
Also do not expect anything from me.
And I see that prefer
talk to sleep ...
Up ... again.
Collect.
Father, ...
Brings us to ... well
or to the border?
As well, small.
There soon ...
If ... we have not lost.
Have you heard, Len?
You've killed a horse, ...
Or find the well ...
or kill them all.
Not only the horses.
Ride out.
We will, at a gallop.
Roden and his men!
Cover!
Where are they?
There!
Have you gone mad?
Are some rocks.
Look, the brave sheriff, ...
Shooting ... rocks.
Congratulations heroic sheriff,
has captured a mirage.
And with one hand!
Hang in breathing, ...
That's ... not a mirage.
Adelante!
Take cover and keep your
head down!
Lou, remove the handcuffs.
These bugs await their dinner.
There is the well.
It's a trick.
He killed my brother
and kill us all.
When you fall rendered
will flee to the border.
Before you all you will fall.
Look! I told you!
Water!
Do not drink!
The water is poisoned.
My father did.
Wants to kill me ...
So ... has.
And you also
wants to kill me.
The sun has upset him.
That water would kill us all.
No water will not get
Santa Loma.
What will you do now, Len?
Guadalupe River is
part time.
It is true, to the south.
What are we waiting?
Come on!
Hold it!
The Guadalupe is on the border.
Continue towards
Santa Loma.
That's what you say.
Enough is enough.
We've followed here ...
But now we go ...
south.
You swore to obey
orders.
Billy also
And what do you get?
Come on!
I give the orders!
We'll go east!
Ride your horse.
All of you!
Mount up on horses.
You, put handcuffs.
Sheriff, ...
Yesterday ... we were three against you
Today we are four.
How long has sleepless
Merrick?
Yesterday did not sleep, ...
Or ... the night before.
Forty hours without sleep, ...
More ... maybe.
Your gun will not be
awake while you sleep.
You also you need
sleep.
We slept last night
and sleep today.
Sleep in Santa Loma.
We will not stop until then.
We will sleep before
in the chair.
Yes, in turns, while
You wait for fall.
Sweet dreams, sheriff.
When you wake up,
if you do, ...
Do not wait ... find here.
So take leave
Now, it is more polite.
Wait.
You ride with me.
So we say goodbye better.
Move!
Not last much longer.
I thought I would fall before.
Do not you drive them back?
Wait till you close your eyes
and you'll see.
You will not regret,
I promise.
Of course not.
But as you fulfill
the deal, yes you will.
I know you're tired.
I'd stop ...
But ... we have to follow.
Anne, ...
Sorry ... this.
But do not blame you.
I know only try
save your father.
Have you become human?
You forget that you're the law?
Not the best time
to quarrel.
Not now.
We have the few minutes.
We'll make it.
Are you okay, Len?
Wake up!
- I have.
Just what
we were expecting!
We are free!
You can not leave him,
die.
Finish him.
Dad, do not!
Speak thou.
It's your daughter.
It is the occasion
we were expecting.
Len, wake up!
Len ...
Len is now.
Do not you understand that only
I'm trying to save your father?
I can help you
across the border.
No one can stop us.
I will be the master of the ranch,
and throughout the country.
Now, my brother is gone.
Your brother?
You do not sound very sorry.
Dad!
Come on, shoot!
Shoot and go!
No! No!
So what are you waiting for?
Have the gun.
Use it while you have time.
Take it you, I'm no good
to maintain law.
You killed him.
Why do not you finished the job?
How stupid you are!
Lou had a rifle.
Dad killed
to save your life.
Wasting your time, Anne.
It's just a petty and limited man.
You had your chance ...
Left ... and escape.
Sometimes
we all feel confused.
I put my head
hanging.
Well, sheriff,
Now it's up to you
Has the gun
and it is the law.
What will you do now?
Bury Lou.
Start digging.
We have blades.
Use your hands.
It seems that now ...
... Have to use your feet.
Congratulations, sheriff,
got what he wanted.
There is Santa Loma.
Three days on
waiting, sheriff.
We delayed.
Well, sheriff, ...
... Are all yours.
- Sheriff Merrick?
- Yes
I am the judge Marlowe.
And his assistants?
Dead.
His son replies
by one.
- And the other?
- The old killed him to protect me.
Roden, can share
your child's cell.
Mr. Roden want to pay
the security of your child.
Of that coyote?
Tomorrow would be in Mexico.
Do you plan to stop me?
You will not flee.
Not while the old alive.
The deposit is $ 5,000.
The court will meet in 3 hours.
Honor, ...
Think ... not celebrate
trial tonight?
I have no choice.
I will judge Keith tonight
Roden and the morning.
I have a trial in Pueblo.
Justice! Is this what
we promised?
I warned, is justice
of farmers.
A night view
to hang him soon.
Already you satisfied?
Young, I understand that
worry about your father ...
Justice ... but does not depend
the time of day.
The trial of his father will
equally fair lady.
The people of this territory
against Timothy Keith.
Do you swear to tell the truth
and nothing but the truth?
I swear.
That morning, Ed got up
before dawn.
He was always the first
to rise, ...
... And go to work.
He had ...
Born ... for the ranch.
That morning, went to the
northern part to find the cattle.
That was the last time
I saw my son alive.
I saw my brother out.
It was 6:00.
I returned to the ranch, ...
By ... a food for my father.
Dan had discussed
with his father.
Did not understand why
Dan was not like his brother.
He got angry with us all ...
And said ... think we were in a hurry.
We did not have time for breakfast.
We ordered Sam and me,
that we were to help Ed
We found the body at 10
in a cotton field.
He was on the floor with a bullet
back the size of a dollar.
The ground was trampled
by cattle.
Wilson and Bill Jerome Jake
arrived then, ...
And ... we trace
livestock.
At noon, we reached the murderer
and at 12 head of cattle.
No resistance.
He could not.
Even tried
draw his revolver.
He was too scared ...
But I ... found guilty.
Stole cattle, it is true.
I will not say I did not.
But I tell you the truth,
I did not kill Ed
He could follow the track,
but he passed me.
The only problem is:
He is not here to prove it.
The defense rests.
The accusation is over.
Wait a minute!
Your Honor?
I am an officer of the law.
When a man is accused
of a crime, I arrest.
When finished my work ...
Is ... the jury decides
if he's innocent or guilty.
It has never mattered to me
verdict.
But this time is different.
I can not prove it,
but I know he's innocent.
He took my revolver
and could kill me ...
Used it ... but to defend
Man who tried to kill me.
I do not speak because
I saved his life.
What is important is that
had the opportunity to escape, ...
And ... did not.
A murderer would not have wasted
that opportunity.
You have escaped, regardless
where.
I think that's it.
Believe me, he's innocent.
Honor, ...
I can give ...
a question to the sheriff?
Go ahead.
Are you in love
daughter of the accused?
Yes.
That's all, Your Honor.
I hope the verdict.
Gentlemen of the jury,
Do you already have your verdict?
You see, judge, ...
... Want a fair verdict.
Nobody saw kill the young Roden,
but he's dead.
No other
suspect, ...
Defendant wore ... and won
stolen.
So we have no choice
to find him guilty.
Prisoner, stand up.
You heard the verdict.
The penalty is mandatory
as dictated by law.
This court convicted ...
To be hung ...
until he dies.
The sentence will be executed
at dawn.
You can not stay here.
If it's against the law,
arrest me.
You respect the law.
Yes, respect.
I told you it would
a fair trial.
He had a fair trial.
Then you'll be satisfied.
You testified in his favor,
Your conscience is clear.
But it was not a fair trial.
You've not allowed.
"It is not my
decide whether innocent or guilty. "
That's what you said.
No matter you discover
the truth ...
Dad deliver only ...
the judge.
What do you think I've been
thinking all night?
Yes, now you think ...
Now ... it is too
late to prove his innocence.
They dug his grave and you
he pushed her.
Father!
Go home, dear.
No, I'll stay with you, Father.
I'm not leaving.
Out of my sight!
You killed your father
and now you've killed me!
What does this mean?
It was crazy.
I want to see the execution, too.
You paid bail
to view.
I want to see die murderer
his brother.
What are you talking about?
Son wanted
and did not want.
Dan always knew.
That's what you told your father
poisoned the well ...
To get rid of you ... because
You were not like your brother.
Do not listen.
What are you trying to insinuate?
I think Dan deserves
what is going to get, ...
Included ... this.
Do not be afraid,
it's just a watch.
The dedication reads:
"For my son Dan, ...
21 ... on your birthday. "
Give it and be done with it.
Roden, I have kept for you
I found him
the body of her son.
Do not listen.
I was not there.
I found him
the body of his brother.
I lent it to Ed
He had lost his.
Lie, ...
Wearing his watch ... in the
pocket when he was buried.
- Back!
- Drop the gun!
I learned a quick trick, Merrick.
Remember!
Drop the gun, Dan.
Would you hang me?
I want to die with a bullet
on the back, as you killed your brother.
It's your fault.
Everything for him and nothing for me.
I had to do to get
my part.
I worked and killed her.
You can not take it.
On the back, you coward!
You shot ...!
Do not follow me!
Have you seen what
happened to me?
A lawman
in the family, ...
something ... that's scary.