In every war...
In every age...
The forgotten weapon is...
...Food. For to kill,
soldiers must live...
...to live, they must eat.
And a herd of cattle is...
...as vital as a herd of cannon.
The United States in 1 864.
Hey, we made it, amigos!
When you're ready to talk business,
Kelly, I'll be at my hotel.
- You're Steadman.
- Major Steadman.
Major Steadman.
Sorry.
Major, I've got the most
marvellous beef in the world for you.
The best beef in all of Mexico.
No, Sanchez?
They're a little thin by now,
but it's been a long walk.
- A few days in the pasture...
- You are late, Mr. Kelly.
Ten days late. Ten miserable days
in this stinking, hot town.
Is it Vermont or Massachusetts?
I'm from Boston...
...which, may I tell you, is one
long way from this prairie rat hole.
Well, there are certain compensations,
major, in a railroad town.
I was hoping that you brought
a couple of them along.
I see.
I don't happen to be a procurer,
Mr. Kelly.
Forgive me.
Whiskey or sherry?
I'm here on business, Mr. Kelly.
United States Army business.
I'm waiting for an explanation.
What were you in civilian life?
A lawyer. I want an explanation.
Lawyer, huh?
- You've never driven cattle?
- Hardly.
Hardly.
Three months, major. Not ten days.
Three months, staring into
the rear ends of those beeves.
Smelling their stink,
choking on their dust...
...listening to their
damn bellowing night and day.
I'm a reasonable man.
If I weren't...
...I might go over to the other side
and see how their manners are.
You'd do business
with the Confederates?
No.
Their money's no good.
Kelly.
What's he doing?
If I'm not mistaken,
someone's stealing my wine.
I thought you were a soldier,
not a sheriff.
You like my wine, Paco?
I like it if you do, huh?
Costs five dollars a bottle.
That's ten dollars out of your pay.
Since you're a generous man,
share the rest with your friends here.
I don't understand you.
I don't understand you at all.
A thief should be punished.
We'll have dinner now.
And take a few more bottles of wine
out to our friends.
He's a Ionely thief, Steadman...
...trying to celebrate
after a rough journey.
He'll be happy to go home.
They all will.
And so will I.
I'm afraid you won't be going home
quite yet, Mr. Kelly.
There's been a change.
Take the cattle by rail to Virginia.
Deliver them to a plantation
near Richmond. The pasture is there.
You'll be paid on arrival.
That's not in the agreement.
I was ordered to bring
the cattle here.
The war's going into a new phase.
We're concentrating on Richmond.
And when we take it, we've won.
I don't care who wins.
You want that herd in Virginia?
It'll cost you
five dollars per head extra.
I'm authorized to pay you one dollar
a head extra. Not a penny more.
That's not Army beef yet, major.
Not until I get paid off
on my contract.
The contract specifies, in rather
small print, I'll admit:
" Payment shall be made when the beef
is delivered to the area...
...deemed most urgent
by the commanding general."
Which is 30 miles south of Richmond.
It's in order. I prepared it myself.
Even specifying the size of the print.
Now those steers
are going east, Mr. Kelly.
Oh, by Godfrey, that judge.
He thought he had me licked.
Licked, Kelly.
But he underestimated the man
he was dealing with.
I hit that judge...
I hit him with a writ of certiorari.
It's like a brilliant bolt
out of the black, a tiger springing.
A writ of certiorari!
Play cards, Steadman.
Thousands of them.
The boys in blue
are gonna eat beef tonight.
And tomorrow and next month.
Till it's coming out of their craws.
Maybe it's our stomachs
making us see what ain't there.
Colonel, how about me going
and bringing back proof.
Just to make it official.
My orders are to scout that herd.
Go ahead.
Just make sure
the Yanks don't scout me.
Oh, Lord.
This is always embarrassing.
I'm sure you'll handle it
with your customary tact.
- Take over, captain.
- Yes, sir.
Major Steadman, ma'am.
I'm Charity Warwick.
This is Alvarez Kelly,
who brought the cattle here.
I was ordered to arrange quarters
for the two of you.
Your men can camp in the field
below the house.
Mr. Kelly, the grazing is best
in the north pasture.
You may eat
in my dining room tonight, major.
But from tomorrow on,
you'll make other arrangements.
Mrs. Warwick...
...will you join us for dinner?
Nice try, but I don't think...
She's a lady, Kelly.
A great lady.
One rarely has the privilege
to meet such a...
What does that mean?
Woman.
- Pick up those strays.
- I'll get them.
Go get that meat!
Sir?
Cleet Warwick must be
rolling around in his grave.
I'll bet this is the first time
his place...
...has been lit up like that
since Manassas.
- Eat while it's hot.
- The man who brought the cattle.
- Colonel, I promise you...
- That man really knew his business.
Moved that herd like it was
a column of infantry.
That's prime beef, Johnny.
And there's enough down there
to feed a lot of people...
...who haven't chewed on meat
in a long, long time.
Thirty-eight, thirty-nine, forty.
Now with the $1 0,000 advance
paid to you in Mexico...
...it makes it a total of $50,000
and completes our original contract.
Plus the...
...additional $2500.
Just sign here.
- Buying beef at three dollars a head.
- Two.
- And selling them for 20.
- Not bad.
It's outrageous.
You go to some nice place
to count your profits?
I spend it, Steadman.
I spend it and enjoy it.
And when it's all gone,
raise it again.
You make it sound simple.
It is, if you don't want it too bad.
Money, whiskey and women.
Your three deities.
Tell me something, Mr. Kelly:
Have they made you a happy man?
No.
But not as miserable a one as you.
Mrs. Warwick.
Dinner is served, gentlemen.
How nice. You changed your mind.
A lady's privilege.
Your privilege is our pleasure, ma'am.
I got hungry.
Driving thousands of half-wild
animals across thousands of miles.
For someone brought up in these parts,
it seems impossible.
I have such respect
for special knowledge.
It's nothing.
You certainly know how
to charge for it.
Do you object to making money,
Miss Charity?
In wartime? I think so.
Making money out of war.
It's almost an act of nature.
Do you have any idea
what a major's salary is?
I wasn't talking about that.
What about a colone"s salary?
And the prestige afterward?
You'll carry that rank
into every courtroom for life.
- I didn't go to war for that.
- No, but you'll use it.
Every man, in his own special way,
takes care of number one.
I don't admire men like that,
Mr. Kelly.
Mrs. Warwick...
...if there were a kind of profit
driven right into your own back yard...
...would there be any reason not
to take advantage of it?
What do you mean by that?
I would say it's a matter
of the north pasture.
The north...
You're talking in riddles.
To you, ma'am?
I don't understand.
I was curious.
When Mrs. Warwick specified the
north pasture, I wanted to know why.
The soil, major, is overworked.
Dying for the lack of fertilizer.
- Well, yes, but I still don't...
- Manure, major.
I didn't know you were a farmer.
I was raised on a farm.
My father's estancia in Texas.
Estancia. What a lovely word.
So is caridad.
Charity.
Yes, it was lovely.
It was lovely and big.
Open.
Fifty families lived on it.
My father was like a lord.
Like an Irish lord.
Yet this virtuous Irish lord...
...was not quite able to stop his son
from turning pirate, was he?
Make jokes, Steadman, about the war,
about God, and about me.
But don't make jokes about my father.
He was killed defending our home.
Mexican War, I think you called it.
We had other names for the theft
of a piece of our country.
The officers wore the same uniform
you have on.
Only some of them now
have changed it to grey.
So I say, "Alvarez Kelly...
...take what you can from both sides.
Small return for your birthright."
- Beg pardon, ma'am.
- What is it?
A guard found one of our drovers...
...beaten and unconscious.
- We're 30 miles behind the lines!
They butchered a steer
inside the gates.
Where the hell were the sentries?
Excuse me.
All right, let's go.
The poor major.
He finds duty more fascinating than...
...pleasure.
Do you undress every woman you meet?
There has to be some beauty.
Then it's no special compliment.
Being a beautiful woman
is compliment enough.
From what you've said
about your father's estancia...
...it must have been something
like it was here before the war.
Very much like it.
Might be interesting
to buy some land around here.
Not to help rebuild, though.
Not to live.
- Just to buy cheap and sell dear.
- It's a nuisance the other way around.
You disappoint me, Mr. Kelly.
After what happened to you, I should
think you'd sympathize with us.
I have no sympathies, only instincts.
And they shy away from losers.
I'm overstaying my welcome.
You must be tired.
You underestimate yourself, Mr. Kelly.
Rarely.
Thank you for the evening.
How long since you've been
with a woman?
Three months.
A lifetime.
My husband's been dead three years.
There was someone
under the bed all the time.
Hatcher.
The money.
I got just as many men outside.
I warn you, I'm a Mexican national.
Doing business with the Yanks.
- My privilege.
- Grazer!
The money.
Obliged, Mr. Kelly.
Just how far would you have gone?
You bastards couldn't have
waited a while longer.
Hatcher.
Good night, Charity.
God bless.
Take care, Tom. God bless.
God bless, Charity.
Bless.
Oh, Mrs. Warwick.
Good night and God bless.
Yes?
Major Steadman.
- Yes, major?
- You had visitors.
Old friends of mine.
Old, dear friends.
And why did they take Kelly?
For the money, wouldn't you say?
They didn't have to kidnap him
to get his money.
Perhaps they didn't want to shoot him
in front of me.
Shoot him? For what?
The way they see it, he committed
an act of war against the Confederacy.
Of course, they're prejudiced.
Mrs. Warwick...
...did you know about this?
Of course! I saw it happen.
No, I mean beforehand.
I mean aiding and abetting.
Oh, that difficult lawyer talk, major.
Mr. Kelly was certainly right.
Alvarez Kelly hijacked by rebels.
You appreciate that, major?
Mrs. Warwick.
- Beaurider.
- Yes, sir.
Get back to camp fast as you can.
Straight back. We've had
our enjoyment for the evening.
Yes, sir.
Turn them around, boys!
Now that that's over, would you mind
telling me what this is all about?
Not yet. Get in.
- Tell him to keep his hands off me.
- Get in.
I may choose not to.
You may choose to die too.
You'd give up those stripes for that
privilege, wouldn't you, sergeant?
As long as you knew
my hands were tied.
Rossiter, we both know you didn't
bring me this far to shoot me.
For some reason, you want me alive
and in one piece. Why?
You know, Mr. Kelly,
you talk too much. Get in.
I'd like to tell you
a little something.
This river winds
all the way to Richmond.
Now, if I was to put you to sleep...
...you'd miss some of the prettiest
scenery in all of Virginia.
Colonel, in my inside pocket,
where my money used to be...
...there's a cigar.
You could get it for me.
Or better yet...
...I could get it for myself.
Bust him, colonel, sir!
Make him shut his big mouth.
Confederate man-of-war?
Kelly, we've got to have that beef.
The army and the whole South
is starving.
- That's your problem, not mine.
- Damn it!
If hungry people don't mean
anything to you, this should!
That already belongs to me.
We'll double it.
In gold, colonel?
Are you suggesting
our currency is no good, sir?
Can I tell you what for?
Colonel, I have to hand it to you.
You're not just half-mad.
How do you figure you're going to
get 2500 head of cattle...
...over Grant's lines? By balloon?
Nope. We don't have
that many balloons.
All right, we can't get over them.
But we can go around.
We can make this big circle.
Come up behind the plantation.
Then we just shoo those cattle
back the way we came.
- Just "shoo" them back?
- That's right.
You know there's a small army
guarding those steers.
Don't you expect a fight?
I'll handle the military.
You handle the herd.
- Fair division.
- Then you'll do it?
Mr. Harrison, I intend to die in bed,
in the arms of a beautiful woman.
We all share that wish, sir.
I do not intend to die
from a Yankee bullet.
So I say the hell with it, colonel.
You're not walking out of here.
This city is swarming with spies,
and you know our plan.
Worth nothing.
You couldn't even try it without me.
Oh, look at the soldier boy!
Morning.
Enjoying yourself?
Oh, yes.
I like cockroaches with my soup.
Specialty of the house.
You about ready to leave?
Not under your terms.
- But I've got some advice for you.
- Yeah? What's that?
Nobody's even gonna start to move
that herd out without drovers.
- My Comanches can handle it.
- Cavalry?
Top riders. Fought under Jeb Stuart.
Any Texans among them? Cowhands?
They're Virginians.
And there's no damn thing anybody
can do on a horse they can't match.
No, except maybe drive a cow
out of a closet.
Takes a long time to train a drover.
Jailer!
Open up.
Mr. Kelly, your education
has been sadly neglected.
Not bad.
But you're not charging the enemy.
You're pushing cattle.
For that, you need trained cowboys.
- Now look...
- These is warhorses, mister.
I reckon they can handle
them little old cows.
All right, lieutenant.
Take your warhorses and push those
little old cows into that back corral.
With your permission, colonel?
Move, cow.
Come on, cows! Get in there!
You darn fool cows, get in there!
Come on, get in there!
Colonel, where the hell you get these
cows? From an old ladies' home?
Move them out!
Get on! Get out of here!
Get out of here!
All right, you darn fool cow!
Come on!
Get out of my way!
Go on! Move along there!
Watch out!
- Sound retreat.
- What's that, sir?
- I said sound retreat!
- Yes, sir.
Close the gate.
Get those cattle! Go on, get them.
Now, listen:
There are 2500 head of Mexican
range-bred steers on that plantation...
...stupid, temperamental and a lot more
vicious than anything you've got here.
All right, so we got plenty to learn.
But you can train us.
Damn you, Kelly,
you're gonna train us!
Back to jail.
Are you coming in or am I going out?
General Lee has approved the raid.
That makes you the only missing link.
Missing's the word.
That's a lot of cash to carry around,
colonel. It'd be safer in a bank.
Matter of fact, I'll give you
permission to open an account in...
They'll be butchering and eating
that herd before long.
I figure you've got no more
than ten days to get us ready.
Burn it all.
Ten days before we start.
God deliver me from dedicated men.
Ten days.
You used to have ten fingers.
Now you got nine.
Tomorrow, you'll have eight.
You stay stubborn, the day after that,
you'll have seven.
The day after that...
...it's up to you.
You decide whether you want to end up
with a pair of stumps...
...or lend us your talent.
You decide.
Get a doctor.
Don't split them up like that.
Get them.
All right, get those back.
Get them together.
He drives hard, I'm glad to say.
Don't split them up! Slow down there!
Take it easy with them.
I deplore what happened, colonel.
- However, under the circumstances...
- It was necessary.
Still, there's a time for sandpaper
and a time for silk.
From now on, I think we'd be wise
to cater to his taste.
I want to borrow a hat.
- Tool of the trade.
- Will mine do?
Mr. Kelly, I'd be honoured if you'd
accept the hospitality of my home...
...for the remainder of your visit.
I believe you'd find
the accommodations more cheerful...
...than your present quarters.
- And the bourbon?
- More plentiful.
You gentlemen have a way
of making it hard for me to refuse.
Who am I?
You're a rich land speculator
looking for bargains.
Seems to me I heard you mention
something like that...
...recently.
Satisfactory?
Yes, yes, that would go down well
with anyone who was curious.
Mrs. Townsend is having a soiree
next week. Nothing pretentious.
No, certainly not.
Not in starving Richmond.
I can't offer you a clean shirt...
...but we'll take care
of the one you got.
That's thoughtful.
Now watch this.
Slow down.
When he moves to your house...
...one of my men goes with him.
Naturally.
Oh, Mr. Kelly, I couldn't.
I'd love to, but I just couldn't.
- I'm spoken for.
- Loudly?
By a seafaring monster
who can shrivel a girl right up.
Where's he?
Very impressive.
Since you and I are only
going to be friends...
...it's only fair that
you turn me over to her.
Liz Pickering?
You're really running in luck tonight.
- Married?
- Engaged.
It's not the same, is it?
I bet you could tell me,
if you really wanted to.
Military secret.
- Damn the military and their secrets.
- Come on.
I suppose it's very dangerous.
Not as dangerous as you.
The way you look tonight, you could
start pandemonium in the streets.
And that perfume...
But you do prefer horse sweat.
Oh, Tommy, I'm sorry,
but I see you so seldom.
You know, that's what
I hate most about the Yanks.
They keep us apart.
I understand married officers
have more leave than single ones.
But what if one
of those nasty old Yanks...
...threw a speck of dust
in my other eye?
How would you look leading
a blind man down the street?
As foolish as you sound
talking about it.
Thank you.
Who's he?
Rich businessman from Mexico.
Friend of the Harrisons.
But not a friend of yours?
No.
Tom, what's the matter?
I don't know.
I guess the war's the matter.
War's the matter with all of us.
Mr. Kelly, this is
Captain Angus Ferguson of Glasgow.
- Captain.
- Isn't he magnificent?
Aye, it's good when they adore you,
especially when they're half your age.
Or could it be the wee gifts
I bring her in my ship?
The French perfumes
and silk nighties?
- Let's dance.
- I'm not used to a ballroom.
There are many stout lads
to stretch your muscles.
If you don't put your arm around me
now, I'll take you up on that.
I will dance the whole night through
with you in my rooms.
Angus, you're a devil.
No use telling her
it's my farewell night, is there?
Not till morning, that is.
Which one of you will help me
make an old sea dog jealous?
Tom.
Rank does have its responsibilities.
Go ahead, darling.
So I weigh anchor tomorrow evening,
courtesy of Secretary Harrison.
After four months wait
and a good deal more effort...
...than a Scotsman cares to spend.
For mercy sakes, no, Mr. Kelly.
That stuff there will
distemper a whale.
Here, you take a taste of this.
Blessed nectar from Scotland.
Will you believe it, there are
1 000 bottles of that aboard my ship?
Sounds like paradise.
I was commissioned to run it
in here, but then I found...
Confederate money isn't worth
the match to burn it with.
Aye, so I'll take it to New York.
Heavens, Mr. Kelly, don't tell me
the currency there is still wampum.
Mr. Kelly, you have my flask!
If I may suggest, Miss Pickering,
the punch is pale.
This will improve the colour.
You're gallant enough
to be a Virginian.
And your beauty goes beyond
the bounds of geography.
I'm Alvarez Kelly.
And you've learned my name
and a few particulars.
Only one.
You've shortchanged yourself.
You could remedy that.
Are you any kind of gambler, Kelly?
I've lost my last few bets.
Will you come to my house?
I need some advice that
can't very well be given here.
What time?
Midnight, number 1 9, Royall Street.
Make sure there's no carriage outside.
Why, Mr. Kelly, whatever
happened to your hand?
One of the bets I lost.
Darling, I think he's rather charming.
Yeah.
- You understand?
- Playing with fire, aren't you, lad?
It's not my house.
Now, follow me.
With all of the beautiful women
that were here tonight...
...the result is
I don't feel much like sleeping.
You know what I mean?
I don't know how to put it to your
delicate ears, but in Richmond there...
There must be a house of joy.
There's a few.
Now, let me guess
what your orders were.
Let him do what he wants...
...but don't let him
out of your sight. Right?
Well, let's be off.
Two men of the world.
You ever seen him before?
No, but I wish I had.
Kelly, you might not like these women.
I understand that the Mexicans
like their women fat and dumpy.
Relax, Hatcher, you can't
make me angry tonight.
What part of Mexico, amigo?
Durango, amigo.
You Ionely?
Not really.
Friendly?
Not very.
Thirsty?
Not especially.
You're the one I want.
A bottle of your best wine.
- This is where I draw the line.
- I'll wait.
May take all night.
Should I take it off?
The wedding ring.
Some like it on, some like it off.
You men are peculiar.
What do you do in case of fire?
I don't know, we never had one.
Well, suppose you had one right now.
There's a window with
a big, old wisteria vine right by it.
Show me.
Now, look, I want you
to stay here all night...
...and improve your mind.
Your body's already perfect.
Come in, sir.
Miss Pickering will be down
in a minute, sir.
My Japanese room. Uncluttered.
Does she have to stay here?
You can go to bed now, Ellie.
Why, Kelly, whatever
are you thinking of?
I was thinking there might be...
...some chimney sweeps
up there in grey uniforms.
I've grown to expect anything
from Southern belles.
I'm not a Southern belle.
I'm Liz Pickering.
This house was something
quite special in its day.
Sorry you couldn't have seen it.
Used to be a lovely miniature
over the mantle.
Till last week. It paid for
the gown I wore this evening.
I don't know why you asked me here,
but it was not to pity you.
Hardly. Pity is the real
empty room I despise.
I amuse you, Kelly?
It's too early to tell.
Well, we're getting older
by the minute.
Would you like to drink that
where it's more comfortable?
Whatever your friend's got,
he ought to market it, huh?
Well, good night.
Wherever did you get wine
at this time of night?
Ask me no questions.
Haven't tasted anything so good
since the war began.
You should've seen that too, Kelly.
It was grand.
That was the year Tom Rossiter
and I became engaged.
The year the boys went off singing.
I begged Tommy to marry me.
It wasn't very ladylike,
but I begged him.
I loved him so much.
But he was noble, he had principal.
Said he couldn't risk
leaving me a widow.
The second and the third years...
...the singing somehow stopped.
I still wanted Tommy to marry me.
He'd lost an eye by then,
but that didn't matter.
But he was nobler than ever.
Said it might be an arm next
or a leg.
Those were the years of frustration.
Then tonight...
Tonight I realized
what he feared the most.
Losing his sight.
Tom Rossiter is right.
I couldn't stand
to live with half a man.
God, Kelly. It must be
some hideous failing in me.
I'm so sick and tired to death
of all the fighting and killing...
...and trying to be brave
and patient over a lost cause.
So then we come to the fourth year.
The year of temptation.
Thank God you're not another one
of those honourable men.
I've spent my life
surrounded by honourable men.
Enjoying myself is one
of my weaknesses.
I guess people like us
have our own kind of honour.
It's not your advice I want, Kelly.
It's your money.
- House mortgaged?
- I've been asked to vacate.
Any other assets?
Myself.
To buy another dress?
I want you to help me
get out of Richmond.
At the moment, impossible.
Nothing's impossible for you...
The minute our good colonel
found out I was missing...
...he'd send a regiment after me.
I wouldn't make it to the city limits.
Tom and you?
- You're not what you're supposed to be.
- Who is?
Then why did you come here tonight?
Many reasons.
Mainly because you were his girl.
Only now, I find out you're not.
If I could manage something for you,
would you be willing to go anywhere?
Anywhere.
There's a chance.
Just a chance.
Then you will try?
Yes, I'll try.
Kelly, I think we ought
to drink to that.
I think we should.
I promised a friend that...
...this might take all night.
I wouldn't make a liar out of you
for anything in the world.
Now, the main thing
to remember is that...
...cattle are like women.
Sometimes you have to be firm.
Sometimes you have to be gentle.
And sometimes you have to give them
a slap on the rump.
Your pistol, captain.
Now that's just a reminder that
the sound of gunfire spooks cattle.
A sound that's practically
guaranteed on our venture.
All right, now start singing, captain.
That's right. Sing.
Music's the best medicine
for scared animals.
Now, look here.
The man said sing!
Yes, sir!
Loud and clear!
I wish I was in the land of cotton
You, Hatcher, out there and sing.
For the want of one voice,
the battle could be lost.
Sing.
- Damn it, sing!
- Colonel.
You know, I keep wondering
why you came back to us...
...after slipping away from Hatcher.
I have a commitment.
Don't suppose you'd care
to say where you went.
Not yet.
- Morning, sir.
- Morning.
Developing a new weapon, Tom?
Trying to scare the Yanks to death?
His idea.
I hope those wailing banshees
are ready.
They're ready.
We move tonight, on schedule.
I know your opinion, I want his.
What about it?
Can the men manage the herd?
If he would keep after them
so that the men sing on key...
You're beginning
to annoy me, Mr. Kelly.
To the point of refusing my services?
Mr. Kelly, I'd give you
the Richmond symphony...
...if they weren't already
in the army.
Polish up your contralto, Tom...
...and I'll notify General Lee
you're set to go.
Carry on. I'm going back to town.
Nothing like a bath, a bite to eat
and a bottle of whiskey before battle.
- Reception.
- Yes, sir?
My name is Kelly.
Captain Ferguson is expecting me.
Tell him I'm in the dining room.
I shall tend to that, Mr. Kelly.
I'd like a double whiskey.
- Make that two. One for the captain.
- Mr. Kelly.
- Hope I didn't disturb you.
- Not at all.
I was just packing my gear.
- Getting ready to shove off.
- Aye, that I am. At nightfall.
Now, what can I do for you?
Book a passenger. A lady.
Anyone I might know?
Beside the point.
And yourself.
No.
Now, the Athena is a broad ship,
but she's tiny.
I don't think...
Two thousand.
On the other hand, I am a man
with no contempt for money at all.