Gary!
Look. This is the liberation.
This is not the liberation
which I'm waiting for.
- I can imagine otherwise.
- Beware!
Gary Hamilton?
That's me.
Are you Gary Hamilton?
Lieutenant Gary Hamilton?
In view of the decree,
that the President issued regarding
the amnesty of political prisoners,
your extraordinary military
services during the war
and your exemplary conduct
in captivity,
was decided
to pardon you.
In view of the Decree
you are a free man.
Johnny! Come on, Johnny.
- What do I owe you?
- Nothing. This is on the house.
I ask the guards
an additional charge.
No. I have learned
that everything has its price.
How long were you there?
Ten years.
Let us go! It is a long way.
- Gee!
- Goodbye and good luck.
The heat is quite exhausting
after my stay in West Point.
Will you go back to the north?
Another year, and then I'm done.
Are you then an officer?
Yes. Then I will decide,
whether I continue or return.
- What would you prefer?
- I don't know.
If it were me, I would
look for a girl and get married.
- Who's stopping you?
- My father, I suppose.
He has big plans for me.
Are you from here?
My father owns all the gold mines
in the area. My name is Dick Acombar.
Did you just say Acombar?
- Do you know my father?
- Yes. I see him very often.
I meet him often in the market
in Tortonian City.
I did not know that he is married
and has such a great son.
My mother died when I was little.
Sorry.
Didn't you want to get off here?
Please tell your father,
that Gary Hamilton is back
and that I will visit him tonight.
- What was your name?
- Gary Hamilton.
Are you a friend of my father?
The man has forgotten his water bottle.
You can give it back tonight,
when he comes to visit.
What do you want?
I need a horse and a gun.
Isn't that enough?
This is the reward for ten years of
stone breaking.
For this dead presidents,
I can sell you Uragano, my mule.
But he is dear to my heart.
You can have Morello. He is good.
The other crocks are almost older than me.
It is said, that animals over the time
will be more similar to their owners.
My horses will falling out of teeth soon.
Here I have something fine for you.
A new model.
It shoots fast.
Pretty, isn't it?
What do you say?
Why were you so sure
that you can find me here?
In all the years the devil could get me.
For some things you wait in vain.
You say it.
Good shot! Super!
Now we will probably never know
the wind direction again.
That'll be sorry you
when he comes tonight.
A severe tornado is approaching.
When do you think it will arrive?
Before sunset.
I am not mistaken.
The years have passed,
but this crappy place remained.
Man toils hard
and builds up something
and then a tornado comes
and tears down everything.
In the last ten years, he swept
at least four times the entire city away.
You'll hardly recognize it.
Only the old gold mine and the
Indian Cemetery still look the same.
But no one goes out there anymore.
Only your house weathered out all  tornadoes.
- Does Acombar live there?
- Sure. Like a king in his palace.
You left it to him, including
furnishing and the harem.
I've seen a lot of whores,
but it is by far the worst.
What are you up to?
Going to town?
- I wait until the wind comes.
- This will be a hurricane.
Acombar expected a tornado
but not your return.
There will be a hot night.
Die!
You'll only make you enemies.
Kill!
And then you will have the power.
I want the power for my son, Dick.
The stagecoach is coming!
Look at the old boy, Rosy!
Now your admirers even
bring their beds.
- Come on. We need two more.
- Do you do a brisk mattress feast today?
- Hurry up!
- I'm still going.
It was my idea.
We hide all the bottles
and cheat the tornado.
For me the house can fly off.
The bottles and I, we're safe.
- Take good care on them!
- Count on it.
How are you and your brothers, Jim?
Good. They are with your father.
Everybody is waiting for you.
My luggage!
- How are you, Dick?
- Well, and yourself?
Then, are we going?
See you soon, I hope.
If you go to the market with your father,
come visit us!
Goodbye, Mr. Acombar.
A conquest, or?
If it is something serious,
you only have to say,
and I and my brothers
will kidnap her for you.
And we will pave his way.
He faces a steep political career.
They will vote for him as senator.
Without opponents.
And through our relationships it is
just the beginning of his career.
Governor of the State and then ...
President of the United States.
Welcome home, my son!
I hope I will not disappoint you.
Even though I may not be that successful.
The army of Santa Maria is
entirely at your disposal.
Like the three musketeers!
At some point I'll be your D'Artagnan.
- Where's Mary?
- She's upstairs. Let us go.
Juanito!
- Welcome home!
- Juanito!
- Maria keeps free the most beautiful room for you.
- I'm looking forward.
- Welcome back, Dick.
- Thank you, Trick.
Come on, let's drink to it!
Dick! Welcome home.
You look great in that uniform.
He can hardly expect to take it off
and take a bath. Isn't it?
Yes. It is very hot.
I can hardly breathe.
It will cool down soon.
- A tornado is approaching.
- Do you remember two years ago?
The old say,
the tornado will be stronger today.
Well, where is our welcome drink?
Coming up.
- Have a drink with me?
- No, thanks.
- After the Bath.
- Good.
I accompany you upstairs.
Listen, this water bottle was left
by a man in the stagecoach.
He got off at the fork.
He said he would come tonight.
I think he is a friend of yours.
A friend of mine?
- Yes. His name is ...
- Señor.
Oh yes, his name is Gary Hamilton.
What's that?
Flocks of birds.
They are fleeing the tornado.
The animals feel it and avoid it.
Give him the bottle back,
when he comes.
Accompany me?
Of course.
Let's go.
I recognize it, it is his.
We put it into the coach back then,
attach it to him.
Shut up!
I will not hear of it.
If he really should come,
we will receive him properly.
But he mustn't get a foot in here alive.
This is also in your interest.
My son may not know about it,
understand?
You can count on us.
Gather the men at the entrance to the city!
- Do you think that he has fled?
- That doesn't matter now.
- You must stop him.
- What do you mean with 'stop'?
You've already understood.
He must be stopped. For ever.
This man must die.
Get out!
A mind that returns,
can only have one wish.
He can only aspire one thing.
Revenge.
- Are you afraid?
- No.
But your son has a suspicion,  indeed.
He asked me if I know him.
What did you answer him?
I said that I do not know him,
I have never heard his name.
Maybe I told the truth.
In reality I had no time
to get to know him properly.
I only had the time
to deceive him.
You do not know him, understand?
Dick must know nothing of it
and he also will not.
Gary Hamilton will never set a foot
in this house in alive.
Whoever they expect to come,
I wouldn't like to be in his shoes.
What do you think, Judge?
- Where are you going, children?
- Hi, Uncle Jonathan.
Is it true that the great
wind comes tonight?
Yes, a fairly strong wind.
Don't peer out the window.
The tonights wind could even
bring dangerous lead.
- No, stop it
- No, my little one.
The uncle can't see without his glasses.
- Go home! The storm begins.
- Come on, kids.
- Send them to bed at once, Jane.
- You should also go home.
Acombar apparently tries
to chase the tornado away.
Where is this guy?
Are you crazy, you idiot?
Come on, people! Come all with me!
Back in the city before we even
shoot each other. Go!
Catch that horse!
- Let's search for the horse.
- Go!
He couldn't have dissolved.
We search the houses.
You catch the horse.
Come on!
Is it true that Acombar
will pay a bounty?
Yes, a very high bounty.
But first he must be found.
For whom do you seek?
That's none of yours, old boy.
Go home!
Got it?
Damned wind!
He is certainly not here.
Let's go!
If we continue to look so aimlessly,
we'll never find him.
So much for $ 10,000 bounty.
- That would be something!
- This way, Amigos!
What's up?
- Why did the father rings the bell
- It is not the father.
He has locked the door earlier
and tied the bell.
Someone must have loosened them.
This doesn't please me.
Enough!
It's enough to drive you mad!
Now I feel better.
You're a new man!
What is going on tonight?
The wind must have
broken loose the bell-rope.
And the shot?
Probably a drunk, trying
to drive out the tornado.
Let's drink to your return.
- Mary, don't you drink with us?
- No.
My brother!
He's dead.
Who has rung the bell?
We need to find him.
Do you now believe that he's no ghost?
I'm going to Acombar.
I stay around here.
I killed him, father.
Father. How stupid, to name a man father,
who is younger than oneself.
Just as it is stupid to speak to someone,
who asks God for forgiveness.
But Gary Hamilton's lifelong conviction
sticks in his blood.
Innocent.
You have sentenced me to such a life.
The life and the world
have no meaning for me, anymore.
For me, I only count on my revenge.
He is dead.
His brothers will be next.
And finally Acombar.
I have waited ten years
for my revenge.
If one may punish an innocent man,
then I may kill, too.
Even if God will tell me the same thing
he said to Cain.
This pig has managed
to come into the city.
- He killed Jim.
- You let yourselves fooled by him.
You have more than thirty men.
You need to find him.
Who has rung the bell?
- He, I suppose.
- Aren't hungry?
- The table is set.
- I'll be right there.
You'll go over there.
Apparently many drunks are
on the road, tonight.
Do you still want a bit of these?
Over there! Quick!
Gary, I knew it is you!
I've been expecting you.
I'm still your friend.
When I saw the horse, I knew you
have hidden in the old Indian Cemetery.
None of Acombar's men
dares to go there,
not even for gold.
An Indian has previously attempted.
Luckily I still have a good ear
and good reflexes.
And a good gun.
It wasn't neccessary in the past,
but now, things have changed.
People are afraid of Acombar.
Only Rosy from the Saloon let not bully herself.
But she also had to pay.
They killed her husband
and make it look like an accident.
- And the judge?
- The judge?
He is one of the first
of which were corrupted.
- For him, everything looks like an accident.
- What happened to your leg?
- A gift of Francisco Santa Maria.
- Also an accident?
Sure. If I wanted to live,
I had to tell it was an accident.
And you?
A long vacation
with lots of sun and snakes.
But that's over now.
Stay here and do not stir from the spot.
Pedro! Quick!
We put him in the saloon.
Help me, Carlos!
Put him on the floor.
If it's true
that you were formerly a doctor,
then you have to help him.
This man mustn't die.
It wasn't Gary Hamilton.
It was a monster.
From hell.
Pedro, you mustn't die.
You mustn't die! No!
I choose my victims.
I need whiskey for my men!
Now  it's time to overcome
this senseless fear.
He's not a monster, but a coward,
I would like to get my hands on.
I will find him.
Spread these!
Take also these!
Do you want money?
Do you think Acombar hasn't the money
for these few bottles?
Give them back!
It is only raspberry juice.
Right.
It's raspberry juice.
If it's Gary, you are looking for,
he now has one less enemy.
Let them shoot me by all means.
Catch it!
Here!
What does Gary Hamilton want from you?
Is he in there?
Get the bell down!
I can not hear them, anymore.
Who rang the bell this time?
So, Father ...
Who has rung the bell?
Answer me!
I will avenge you, Miguel.
Let us go!
Get the bell down, at last!
- Are you up there, Chico?
- Yes.
Untie it and let it fall!
Do you understand?
Let it fall!
Out of my way!
Let's go.
To the villa.
Come on!
I have searched for you.
Why this carnage?
Why do you hate my father?
You want to kill him, right?
Yes.
You don't need to fear,
I'm unarmed.
I only want to talk to you.
I would like to know the truth.
I know I haven't listened to you.
I want to help you.
Even if it is only with this old rifle.
Caution!
This is the son of Acombar.
We traveled together.
He sat with me in the stagecoach.
He wants to know the truth.
The truth about his father.
You can tell a thing or two about it.
But you must be prepared to hear everything.
Until the end.
Yes, I must know it.
Have you seen Dick?
Where's Dick?
Wasn't he with you?
- He followed you when you left.
- And you gave permission?
You should have had to hold him back!
I have to protect Dick.
He has nothing to do
with the whole story.
If something happens to him,
you will pay for it.
Let the paperwork
and get you a gun!
Dick is on his way to the city.
- Get the men!
- Come on! The horse cart must be out of the way!
Take the horses into the other shed!
This one could collapse.
There he is.
Are you crazy, just to slip away?
Come on!
We go home.
Frank, we go home.
The men should come into the villa.
Only three or four remain here.
They're gone.
The boy did not betray you.
I don't trust him anyway.
Quickly, it could collapse.
- Why did you leave the house?
- I wanted to talk to Hamilton.
Go! Move!
- Bring the horses to safety!
- Go on!
The street is empty.
They are certainly all in the villa.
If Dick should talk ...
After all, what they did to you,
are you still so naive.
Why?
I wouldn't have told the boy that much.
His father would have skinned
your son alive.
No.
A son should not pay for
his father's mistakes.
Mary is also in the villa.
I know.
Here!
No, I rather keep mine.
It has always brought me luck.
Hey, look!
Someone runs to the villa.
- Where is he?
- Here.
Come on!
Look around!
View all exactly!
Here.
This here is what Gary Hamilton is keen on.
Look at that.
This gold belongs to you alone.
Only to you.
Do you understand?
With gold one can coin money.
The only thing that counts these days,
believe me,
is money.
Do you have a different opinion?
Isn't it?
Do you prefer to live in the dirt,
like me during my youth?
I do not agree with you.
Does that mean you renounce all that?
I spoked to him.
I know the truth.
The truth ...
Here is a fortune
and you talk about truth?
What truth?
That's the truth.
We rather should divide us.
Then one of us will make it at least.
Hopefully you.
Good luck.
- What did he told you?
- Everything.
And that would be?
He said,
that the war wasn't over yet,
when you have attacked the
gold transporter of the Confederates.
You have massacred them
and blamed it to him.
He had an alibi.
He was in this house,
that belonged to him at that time.
He was here with his wife,
but you ...
You have persuaded Mary.
She stabbed him in the back.
She has lied shamelessly.
Now I know,
why he wants to kill you.
I also know that we must stop him
before he destroys you.
I am your son
and must be on your side,
even if ...
I'm becoming a murderer like you,
when killing an innocent man.
Stop!
Frank, why?
Because Gary is innocent.
You know that exactly.
Idiot!
I have had hit him for sure.
No one will stop him.
No, Gary.
No.
Oh Gary.
Gary, forgive me!
For what I did to you!
I was forced to, believe me!
They would have killed me, you know?
I was afraid.
I was foolish and stupid,
but I was afraid.
That were years of hell for me, too.
He has captived me.
I have never loved him.
Bring me to him.
He's here! Gary Hamilton is here.
He will kill us.
- Be quiet!
- He will kill us!
Caution!
My son!
Why?
It is solely your fault.
You know what will happen now.
You killed him!
- No!
- Yes, you did!
I warned you,
if something happens to him,
- you have to pay for it.
- No.
No.
Now you also gonna die.
This way!
He's over there! Stop him!
Where are you?
I'm here.
Where?
Show yourself!
Where are you?
Where?
Hamilton, show yourself!
Show yourself!
Stop hiding!
I am here, Acombar.
Here.
I'm standing right in front of you.
No! No!
Dig,
under the rubble you will find enough gold
to rebuild everything.