Oh no!
Looks like they are at war,
with their Turks.
I didn't know that the
Indians were on the warpath.
- Shepherd! Shepherd, look!
- What is it?
It's nothing.
They have their problems,
we have ours.
Let's go.
THE ACTRESS, THE DOLLARS AND
THE TRANSYLVANIANS
Hello!
Leave the horses here.
Dear Sir...
two rooms, two.
He says that he has no vacancies.
I understood, I'm not stupid.
A couple of slaps might change his mind.
What is he saying?
He says that Bob is not allowed,
but it's nothing, Bob will find a place.
But why?
Because Bob is black.
So.........
You lot go to the market.....
And see how things are
goin on.
- Buy some clothes for the lady.
- Traian, be careful.
Call me shepherd Traian,
I'm older than you.
Go!
What does he say?
It's beautiful.
Let's go now.
So...
How is it, "Shepherd Traian"?
- How do you think? It's ok.
- Alright.
He managed to understand, finally.
Otherwise, he's a good boy.
It's perfect, "Shepherd Traian".
Ion!
You should be ashamed.
Bob, close the door.
I don't say no,
to giving the man a slap or two...
But not like this,
shooting everywhere.
Instead try to say something nice,
because we are good men from
Poplaca,
who don't shoot for no reason.
Have you seen this?
You were prepared to
shoot him.
Brother Traian....
I don't wanna hear!
I'm the oldest one here,
I'm the leader.
Must I lock it?
Well, dear brother...
You must know that it won't be
easy for me.
- Shepherd I think that...
- You, Romi...
Mind your own business.
And take care of this girl.
She will sleep here,
in the room.
Alone!
This is the rule.
We will sleep together.
Well...
I'm going to check out
the town,
but I think that here...
it's good to be very careful.
Bob, come with me,
I want a beer.
And I don't want to
drink it alone.
Dear Bob, I suggest that we go to take a
look at that fair.
The last time I saw something
like that was in Vienna and Peszta.
And it was so funny!
Bob likes too.
Bob...
Look at her,
she's like an angel.
Hey...
I think...
that they'll kill each other.
Dear Miss, don't be upset,
because in the end...
everything will be fixed if
a person doesn't loose hope.
And please don't cry,
your eyes are like two shining stars.
Have you seen what happened?
The business with the
Indians is messed up.
It's their business.
We're going to get something
to eat and drink at the saloon.
It's your business.
Shepherd Traian, you're fucked up.
What is it?
Why are you entering like this?
It's the end of the world,
come and see the impossible.
Look.
It really is the end of the world.
Hear?
IS there any money left?
Bob, stay here with me.
God damn this whiskey.
It's worse than death.
Well, dear Ms. Anabella...
I came to tell you that I'm
very concerned about your troubles.
I hope you don't think that I'm stupid.
I saw that the play was just fantasy.
It was not the first time for me
that I was at a theater.
For I was enrolled at ........
Regiment.
So, I know what it's all about.
But those tears were real,
and they really upset me.
Because nobody cries on command.
Only if he has in his soul...
a hidden pain.
Bob....
translate what I've said.
Your Mom and Dad,
are they alive?
Or, are you left alone on
the face of the Earth.
Her father, is dead.
Then, rest in peace.
Something wrong?
Dear Anabella...
are you coming for a ride?
Bob, listen carefully to me.
2 beers!
She's a good girl.
But she's unlucky. 'Til now.
Well, well.
Lots of noise outside.
You're pretty enough.
You still have some snowdrops.
Mind your own business.
Don't you worry about me.
I've been here for 8 years.
It's subtle, you're
still stupid.
Oh my god!
Ion, what's that
man doing here?
They called them to the city...
They promised that nothing would happen,
then they killed his father.
What are we going to do?
He's wanted now.
What do you mean by:
"What are we going to do?"
Come, come, come inside.
Ion, give him that key.
Because he hasn't came here
just to visit us.
He's here to ask us for help.
We need to ask questions.
So, he'll stay here as long as it's
necessary.
'Till we sort everything out.
Stop, we have time.
What do you want here?
Wait a second!
Where the hell are we?
In the woods?
In the desert?
Ion, don't lock it.
I have something to do.
And you, take care of everything.
- Don't forget the Indian.
- Ok, ok, go,
There are some beautiful
places around here.
But not like in Poplaca.
Unfortunately the lands in Poplaca
belong to the nobles, not to ordinary people.
But it's not a bad thing.
There will come a time when the land
will belong to the people.
It's not the end of the world yet.
And you must know, Anabella...
that I'll take care of you,
like I take care of a fragile Easter Egg.
And you'll have
no worries...
As long as I have these hands.
And you're talent won't be lost.
I already see all the people...
that are watching your shows.
And you'll say...
DESTEAPTA-TE ROMANE ( AWAKE, ROMANIANS )!
( the national anthem of Romania )
What's with these people?
What does he want?
No!
I'll take care of this.
Good night Anabella,
good night.
How long are we staying
here?
Dear brother, we'll not stay
for much longer.
I took care of you until now.
Now, it's my time.
You see,
I'm still young.
And it will be bad if I don't
live my life.
Do not embarrass yourself.
- You know what those actresses are?
- Johnny!
Or whatever the hell they
call you around here.
If you say one more word...
I'll leave you with
no teeth.
Romi, my son.
It's hard, isn't it?
Money isn't
easy to earn.
Blacksmith!
Give him some slaps,
if he doesn't do his work!
Yeah, yeah.
Because...
Hey, leave her alone!
I see that the Americans are
eating with their hats on their head.
Not like this, my dears.
How's it possible to eat like this?
We stay at the table, and he stays there, like a dog.
Maybe, that's the tradition around
these parts.
Now, I like it.
Good appetite.
Ion... where's Romi?
What is he doing,
every evening he's late.
He's missing my slaps.
He's a man now.
A man.
Don't talk, I was outside.
[shitty song]
Brother, for God's sake,
don't embarrass yourself.
You spend all our money on
this woman.
Since when was it our money?
Say something,
you idiot!
She's leaving.
Who's leaving?
The actress, the theater.
The circus.
You see?
And what's with that?
Translate.
Farewell.
Shepherd, if we're
talking about translation...
How did you manage to
understand her?
Shitface Mucho.
Don't talk to me
like that.
Hey!
You forget about respect?
Romi.
You must think that
I'm very stupid.
And I wanted to take
you to a show.
To learn something new.
But, here's some money...
go get a beer.
This is for you.
Bob, you'll go with them.
It's enough.
Bob knows.
Bob sad.
This, for good luck.
Be careful.
My dears...
I'm very happy,
because I can invite you
to the wedding,
and bring all of your families.
I can't believe my eyes.
It's the same tradition for
the Americans too.
When they marry, first they visit
the parents.
Well, I've seeen a lot of men like you
in my life.
Traian!
I think you're finished.
Come here.
Not now.
Alright.
C'mon.
God will punish you, BITCH.
You broke my heart.
C'mon.
Look, our man is coming.
If we keep going like this,
it will take us a long time to reach Poplaca.