Did you find what you
were looking for?
Not exactly.
Neither has anyone else.
A lot of people know the
story of Gila Valley.
They all come looking for the gold.
I'm not looking for gold.
What's that?
It's a grave. An old one.
The soldiers dug it when they got
here, but they were a little late.
So they buried what was left.
- And you ...
- Yeah, I dug 'em up.
They didn't mind. I think
they were glad I came.
Could you use some coffee?
- If it's hot.
- It's hot.
What's your name?
- Karyl.
- First or last?
Karyl Orton.
Mine's Slater. Jim.
- You got a cigarette?
- Nh-nh. I don't smoke.
Mine are in my saddlebag.
Do you mind?
No, I don't mind.
You wanted some cigarettes, they're
in your saddlebag. Get 'em.
Get 'em!
You don't lie very good, do you?
Who is he?
I don't know.
You set me up for him. Who is he?
All right. Now, who is he?
I told you. I don't know.
You don't, eh?
I'll tell you something
of which you do know.
What's that?
You're kinda good-looking.
- What are you going to do?
- Take him back to Silver City.
Why?
Cause that's where he comes from.
It says here.
Get the packhorse, will ya?
Sheriff!
- What happened?
- I killed him.
He's one of my deputies.
That mean anything to you?
Yeah. You ought to be
a little more choosy.
We don't like to have
our deputies murdered.
- Killed, not murdered.
- I'll pick my own words.
Take care of Tom. Come inside.
Sit down.
Take off your gun and
tell me how it happened.
We were at the Gila Valley.
Your man took a shot at us.
I said, take off your gun.
Don't push it.
You move like a man I used to know.
- Do I?
- Wear your gun the same, too.
Seems like a handy way to wear it.
- What were you doing at Gila Valley?
- Just passing by.
People don't just happen to be passing by
Gila Valley. What were you doing there?
Having some coffee and looking for
a package of cigarettes. Mine.
They were in the other saddlebag.
You were looking for the
$60,000 in gold ...
that's supposed to be buried
out there, weren't you?
- No.
- Then why were you there?
I was looking for a grave.
My father's.
Wasn't a nice way to go.
Pinned down for weeks while the Apaches
waited for him to run out of food.
Which they did.
They didn't have to go that way.
One man was in the clear.
What do you mean?
One man got away. Left the
rest to be massacred.
Not according to the records. There
were five men at Gila Valley.
- All of 'em are buried there.
- There was a sixth man.
He could've written to the
cavalry post at Tucson for help.
But the, uh, gold was more important.
So he let 'em die.
- And you're looking for that sixth man?
- That's right.
The, uh, deputy you killed is Tom Welker.
Does the name mean anything to you?
Yeah. Yeah, there was a Welker buried
with my father at Gila Valley.
Tom's brother. And
he's got two more.
- It's a big family?
- Yes. Only it isn't funny.
They're good with their guns.
When they hear about this, they're
gonna come looking for you.
Seems logical.
If it's your idea to shoot it out
with them, you're gonna lose.
Could be.
And even if you beat
'em, you're gonna lose.
Cause I'm gonna hang
the man that wins.
We don't like gunfights in Silver City.
I don't want you here when they arrive.
Our mail's aboard.
Anything else for Tucson?
- Yes, two passengers.
- He's still wearing his gun.
You wanna take it away from him?
It's a hard ride into Tucson, but
you'll both like it better there.
Well, I like it here in Silver City.
- Your luggage in your hotel?
- Yes.
Get on the stage, we'll
send it to you later.
Uh, oh, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
I'll, uh, give you $50 for your
horse, if you're leaving without him.
- My horse?
- Welker killed yours. You own his.
- You keep him. A gift.
- Get her aboard, Harry.
- Yes, sir.
- Thanks.
I don't want anybody telling
the Welkers about this.
You're a little late. Joe
Harris just rode out.
I still don't want any gunfights in
Silver City. Why don't you go away?
I can't.
- What do you got in mind?
- Well, I came here for information.
- And if you got it?
- I'd leave.
Ride into Tucson and have
a talk with George Lake.
He's the sergeant in charge of the detail
that found the bodies and buried 'em.
Could be he'll have
something to tell you.
All right.
If you hadn't been so stubborn, you'd be
riding into Tucson easy on that stage.
Yeah, but then I wouldn't have
known about Sergeant Lake.
- Oh, my name's Jim  ...
- I don't wanna know your name.
I just want you to go away. That's
why I told you about Sergeant Lake.
While I was riding, I'd
look back once in a while.
Jeff and Tony Welker
aren't nice people.
Thanks.
- The orderly room in here, corporal?
- Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Hello, Colonel. My name is Slater.
I'd like permission to speak with Sergeant
George Lake about a personal matter.
Strange. That's the second request
this morning I've had about Lake.
The first wasn't phrased
quite so formally.
Well, I'm sure it wasn't
turned down for that reason.
No, I told Miss Orton she could find
Sergeant Lake at Benton's trading post.
He's in charge of the detail I sent
at the request of the Indian agent.
- Hm. Trouble with the Apaches?
- Yes.
You, uh, tell her about this?
I advised her to stay well clear
of Benton's trading post.
I advise you to do the same.
60,000 in gold won't do you any good if your
scalp is hanging from an Apache's belt.
- I'm not after the gold, Colonel.
- You are.
Mr. Slater, you're a civilian.
I can't prevent you from going.
If Sergeant Lake wishes
to see you, he may.
Thank you, sir.
- If this is a hold-up, you're dead.
- If I did it this way, I'd deserve to be.
- What'd you stop us for?
- The Apaches are talking.
Thought you might wanna listen.
The man's right. That's
an Apache signal.
That man's half right. Can't
no-one listen to smoke, though.
Can't they?
- That could be the trading post.
- It is.
- How do you know?
- Cause I rode up and I had a look.
Then I rode right back again.
- We ain't even looking.
- I would if I were you.
- They got us in the middle.
- Yeah, and this ain't no place to fight.
Well, there's a cavalry detachment at the
trading post. Why not make a run for it?
- Why didn't you make a run for it?
- I was kinda lonesome.
Giddy up!
Don't waste 'em on me,
save 'em for the Apaches!
Well, then get out of the way!
Hey, grab this!
Catch the leaders! Catch the
leaders as they come in!
Get inside!
Swing her around to the back!
Tie up the rigging and get inside!
Keep these horses under cover!
Don't we have enough trouble
without you bringing us more?
Oh, I wouldn't call her trouble.
But then again, maybe I should.
- Trouble or not, she's your guest.
- My guest? What do you want with me?
- I can wait, Sergeant.
- You sure can.
- They're coming.
- Gimme a gun!
Well, you lost us our horses, but I got
to admit you do real good with that rifle.
- Well, you're not exactly bad.
- It's my trade.
And there's days when I wished I
didn't work at it. This is one of 'em.
I don't blame you.
- You're Sergeant Lake, aren't you?
- That's me.
Well, uh, there's another bad
day I'd like to find out about.
It happened at Gila Valley.
- What do you know about Gila Valley?
- My father's buried there.
- What's your name?
- Jim Slater.
- Wait a minute, Sergeant. I came ...
- I wasn't there during the shooting.
I was just sent in to
bury what was left.
And I hope somebody'll be around
to bury us in the morning.
Why do you say that? We've got guns, food,
cartridges. We can hold 'em off for a week.
By then, even that stupid crowd at the
fort will know something's wrong.
Mr. Benton, it's a shame those guns you sell
the Apaches don't shoot a little straighter.
Can I have a little coffee, miss?
They'll send riders back
in the hills tonight.
Tomorrow morning we can expect a
few hundred of 'em out there.
An hour later they'll be
coming through the door.
You got any ideas?
I say, let's get outta here. We've
got the stage, let's use it.
All of us on one stage? They'd
run us down in no time.
- Some of us could get through.
- Yeah, some. And you'd be one of 'em.
On the other hand, we
could try to make a deal.
They ain't really mad at but one of us. And
if we give 'em that one man, they might ...
- You wouldn't do that.
- Then keep your mouth shut.
I'll think of something when it gets dark.
Where can I find some
more coffee, Sergeant?
- Oh, help yourself, there's plenty of it.
- I'll get some.
That ain't government issue, Sergeant. Anything
that's drunk or ate has to be paid for.
Mister, you got a deal. You
collect from the Apaches.
I'll get you some fresh water, miss.
Sergeant? I've read your report on
Gila Valley. That's why I'm here.
I'd, uh, like to find out more.
There isn't any more. There were
five men out there, and I buried 'em.
Three of 'em I can identify
from letters and papers.
There was Turnbloom, Gibson and Welker.
I knew Welker. He was no good.
Are you sure you can't
identify the other two?
No. There was no way of telling.
What about the sixth man?
Why don't you leave it alone, son?
I'd like to, but first I've
got a few questions to ask.
They had a few at Gila Valley.
The Apaches answered 'em.
They might do the same here.
Need some help?
To make the coffee or look
for the gold in Gila Valley?
Look, I've told you once. I'm
not interested in that gold.
I am. Part of it belongs to me.
How do you figure?
One of the men who died
there was my husband.
I thought so.
You got any ideas?
Yeah. But I'll listen
to yours first.
It's my guess they got most of the
horses bunched out there in the rocks.
Two men could step out, find the horses,
stampede 'em, put the Apaches afoot.
Uh-huh. Then they could load up the
stage and make a break for it, eh?
- Yeah. Sound good to you?
- Well, I can't think of anything better.
Well, I need to find a good
man to go out there with me.
Vogel's too clumsy, Marcus
is new to this country.
Why don't you settle for me?
- You looking for a medal?
- Nope. I got one.
I bet you would've traded it for
a meal after the surrender.
How'd you guess?
Oh, I fought against you rebels.
All guts and no sense.
Hey, Sarge. Can we
light a lantern?
Why not? They know you're here.
We're taking a little walk.
To see if we can stampede the Indians'
horses and give you a chance to break out.
Miliken, have the stage loaded and
ready to go as soon as we get back.
- Well, what if you don't get back?
- Now, that's a pleasant thought.
You're going with Lake.
Mh-hm. Too bad you can't
tell the Apaches.
They might have better luck
than your friend, Welker.
You know, uh, ever since I first saw you,
there's been something I've wanted to do.
What's that?
Say goodbye.
Well, good-bye.
Well?
Of course, I got no idea how to
get to the horses. Have you?
Only one.
- Just keep moving.
- Let's go.
Well, there they are.
There must be a guard
or whatever he is.
- That's a good trick.
- I learned it from a rebel.
Keep him happy.
- That was another good trick.
- I learned it from a yank.
On top for you, Benton.
Get up there.
- Time to go, son.
- Come on, let's get outta here!
Keep going. I'll hold up here for while.
You can make Tucson easy.
Go on, get outta here. I only got
a few minutes, and you know it.
- Are you fixing to die noble?
- Not exactly.
- Then get out while you got time.
- I got time. Here.
I figured you for a good soldier.
I should've known better.
- Good soldiers never volunteer.
- Maybe I wanted to keep you alive.
Huh. You've done a rotten job.
Look, uh, Sergeant, I don't
like to push this, but ...
Yeah, I know. What
do you wanna know?
- You buried five men at Gila Valley, right?
- What was left of 'em.
And you could identify three:
Turnbloom, Gibson and Welker, yeah?
Yeah.
All right. Now, what about
the other two you buried?
Well, there wasn't much
left to go on by, just ...
One of 'em had a hand missing. Left hand.
Even before the Apaches got to him.
I don't know who he was. And the
other one, there's no way of telling.
- What about the man who ran out?
- Leave it alone, son.
- Who was he?
- I don't know.
- Sergeant, I got to know. Who was he?
- Don't go into it, son.
Who was he? Where
can I find him?
We found a horse,
wearing a Texas brand.
Diamond C. Carson's outfit.
Just beyond Sierra Blanca.
Leave it alone, son.
Well, that's your fault, not mine.
I told you the Apaches had
guns, and they wanted more.
But this time they decided
not to pay for them.
All right, make out your claim and sign it.
I'll put it through regular channels.
- Sergeant, give him the forms.
- Yes, sir.
Colonel? Two men to see you.
Jeff and Tony Welker.
- Yes?
- We're looking for a man named Jim Slater.
We heard in Silver City we
might find him here in Tucson.
- I'm afraid you're a little late.
- What for are we late?
- He's dead.
- Who killed him?
The Apaches. Benton was there,
he can give you the details.
- Did you see Slater die?
- Don't bother me.
Did you see Slater die?
I ... Yes, I saw him die.
Did he die slow?
Yes.
- My key, please.
- That's fine.
May I say that you're looking
mighty elegant, ma'am?
- You may. And thank you.
- Hello, Miss Orton. Uh ...
Any news come through
on Slater and Lake?
No, nothing. I've asked Colonel Welnick
to let me know if he hears anything.
Might as well forget 'em.
They're dead.
- Miss Orton?
- Yes?
I'm gonna buy you a drink.
- Thank you. I don't drink.
- Well, I'm still gonna buy you a drink.
Sir, you don't know this lady.
You got no right to ...
What for are you looking at me?
Put him back in his chair.
Drink up. Over there.
Drink for me. Two drinks for them.
How long do you know Jim Slater?
We met yesterday at the trading post.
I was on the stagecoach.
- Going where?
- El Paso.
- From where?
- Here. Tucson.
- She's a pretty woman.
- Yeah, Tom liked pretty women.
- Were you in Silver City?
- Were you?
She was in Silver City. She's
the one Tom wrote about.
- Ain't you the one Tom wrote about?
- No.
Maybe he told her more than he told us.
Maybe he told her where's the gold.
- Bottle. Scared?
- No.
Tom learned things in Gila Valley. Claimed
he was this close to something real good.
Of course, he could've meant you.
Or he could've meant the gold.
Oh, that's fine, doll. You're
gonna talk and I'm gonna listen.
- Clerk?
- Something you want, ma'am?
Yeah, jug of water.
Well, well, well.
You do get around.
- Does it bother you?
- No, no. No, not at all.
Have a nice time, Miss Orton.
- Thank you, Mr. Slater.
- Slater?
Who was this?
Jeff Welker.
And you set me up for him.
- I guess I didn't hit you hard enough.
- Yes, you did.
- What do you want?
- To see you.
I didn't think you could tear
yourself away from your friends.
It was easy.
You know, if I was smart,
I'd run you outta here.
- Why don't you?
- I'm not smart.
And you're good-looking.
Oh, don't tell me that makes
any difference to you.
At times it does.
With a shoulder like this,
tonight's not one of those times.
Why not?
- Help yourself.
- It's a beautiful thought.
At least you could do a
better job than the Welkers.
Yours wasn't such a good job.
Tony Welker's still alive.
Soon as he's able, he'll
come looking for you.
And you'll be here to
set me up for him, huh?
Does that amuse you?
I don't mind playing games as
long as it's winner take all.
Bite on this.
Thank you.
- You'll need it.
- Have a nice time.
Thank you.
Next time you get any
ideas about me and men ...
or you ...
I won't set you up for anyone.
I'll kill you myself.
You know, you're ... you're
right about tonight.
Try this. Might help.
- Arsenic?
- Could be.
What'd you come here for?
To make a deal. I want that gold, but
you've learned things that I don't know.
- And you'd like to know?
- Naturally.
Well, uh, what have you
got to offer in return?
What do you want?
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
- Are you all right?
- Yup.
- Are you tired?
- Nope.
- Sleepy?
It's a lazy woman who won't
spread her own blankets.
Thanks.
Hey, what was that thing you gave me?
Just an old Southern painkiller.
One we used back in Atlanta.
- Atlanta, huh?
- Mh-hm.
I was born there.
Married there, too.
- Tell me about your husband.
- What?
- Was he in the war?
- Yes.
- Did he lose a hand? The left one?
- I don't know.
- Paul didn't come home after the surrender.
- Why not?
Unless you lived in the South,
I don't think you'd understand.
I lived in Texas. I still don't understand.
Why didn't he come home?
Well, Paul was proud.
Some friends told him
about me and, uh ...
- ... the things I was doing to keep alive.
- Consorting with the enemy.
- I'm trying to be nice. Why don't you?
- It's impossible.
So he went to Arizona and
he found himself some gold.
Being a gentleman, he wrote to you and
offered you to share his wealth with him.
- That was a very nice gesture.
- You can try harder than that.
I don't like gentlemen.
Not that kind.
The kind who won't forgive a
woman when she's made a mistake?
Was it a mistake?
You know, it's a funny thing.
That shoulder isn't
nearly as bad as it was.
Not nearly as bad.
Old Southern painkiller ...
- Lady, you do pick your spots.
- And my men.
Why did you ask me if
Paul had lost a hand?
One of the men buried at Gila
Valley was short a left hand.
- Did Lake tell you this?
- Uh-huh. Just before he died.
- What else did he tell you?
- Nothing much. Just what he told you.
He could ... he could
identify three men.
That leaves an unidentified
body and a man with one hand.
- And a sixth man.
- Did he tell you his name?
Nh-nh.
No, but there was a
Texas-brand horse there.
It was one of Carson's.
His place is just beyond Sierra Blanca.
And that's where we're going?
- We?
- We.
- Just like that?
- Just like that.
- There.
- Thanks.
- How's the shoulder?
- Uh, pretty good.
What's that for?
It's new. And a gun's no good
unless it fits well in your hand.
- Where did you learn so much about guns?
- Just picked it up.
- From your father?
- Nope.
I never knew my father. He went
away when I was a little kid.
- Don't you remember him at all?
- Nh-nh.
You know, it's a funny
thing about your father.
You begin to wonder about him.
What he was like. What he was doing.
- I can understand that. Drink?
- Oh, thanks.
You know, this is nice
country, isn't it?
Mighty, mighty nice.
I sure like it here.
I'm glad I came out.
- You are?
- Mh-hm.
There's a a strip of
land near Gila Valley.
It's got good grass,
and there's water.
A man could put in some
cattle and raise beef.
If he could use a hammer and
saw, he could build a house.
Trouble is, I'm not much
good with a hammer and saw.
You could learn.
Yeah. I will someday.
- But you won't.
- Why not?
You've learned to hunt.
That's much more exciting.
- Think so?
- Yes. When you're hunting a man.
Why don't you stop
looking for trouble?
Go on, build your house.
While you're at it, you
might find some happiness.
I didn't look for this, Karyl, but
my father was killed at Gila Valley.
And I'm gonna find the
man who murdered him.
We must be getting close
to Carson's ground.
- We're on it now.
- How can you tell?
I asked the steer.
Stay where you are!
Oh no, not again.
You know, a man can get awful tired
of being shot at. Now, who are they?
This one's on you.
This is as far as you go, mister.
You're on Major Carson's ground.
- I know that.
- Who told ya?
He asked the steer.
Oh. You're a funny girl.
I like funny girls.
I don't like you.
Why don't you teach
this brat some manners?
Keep your hand off
that gun, Johnny.
Well, I don't like nobody to stop my draw.
I don't like nobody to tell me what to do.
As long as you work for the Diamond
C, you'll do what I tell you to do.
You can go now. You too, ma'am.
That way.
If you don't mind, I'd
like to see Major Carson.
- You would, huh?
- Yeah.
Well, all right. You can see the Major.
Ride on ahead.
And have, uh, Jumpy here
put a bullet in my back?
Ride up beside him, Johnny.
You're riding with me, ma'am.
He said, beside me.
All right, miss.
I noticed you use a tie-down.
Does that mean you're fast?
Everybody west of the Pecos
they think they're fast.
What I said back there still goes.
I don't like ya.
That makes me very unhappy.
I like your woman. Does
that make you unhappy?
- How far is the ranch?
- Why?
You keep that up, one of
us might not get there.
Reach for your gun.
You might be right.
Maybe you better take off your gun-belt,
mister. Just hang it on the saddle.
- Thanks. I'll wear it.
- You heard what the man said.
- You take off your belt, or I'll knock ...
- That'll be enough, Johnny.
This is neither the time nor
the place for fighting.
You'll have more than enough
on your hands in the morning.
How's that? In the morning?
I can wait.
- I'm Major Carson.
- Oh, how are you, sir? I'm Jim Slater.
And this is Miss Orton.
- Miss Orton.
- How do you do?
- May I?
- Thank you.
Tom, will you take Miss
Orton into the house?
- Certainly.
- Pedro, you take care of the horses.
I hope you're looking for work,
Mr. Slater. I can use a good man.
Well, I don't know. Looks like you
got one or two on hand right now.
- I'll take all I can find.
- Any particular reason?
A very good reason.
A thing called survival.
- Nice place.
- Thank you.
- Is this a picture of your son, Major?
- My nephew.
That was taken when he was released
from the hospital in Richmond.
- Oh, uh, drink?
- Yes, please.
I had hoped he would join me in Texas.
But he was young and there
was gold in Arizona.
- I needed him very badly.
- Thanks.
I, uh, I could still use
a good man, Mr. Slater.
- Would high wages be an inducement?
- No, I'm afraid not.
That's too bad. You might face up
very well against Jim Bonniwell.
- Why do you say that?
- Well, you're a gunfighter, aren't you?
Oh, that's not an uncomplimentary
term in this country.
I'm not interested in
Mr. Bonniwell, Major.
You will be if you stay in Texas.
You see, for years, these hills
have been a haven for outlaws.
We haven't liked it, but we haven't
been particularly concerned.
Oh, you lose a steer now and then, but all
in all, they've left the big ranches alone.
Then Jim Bonniwell arrived.
- And became their leader?
- Their employer.
Mr. Bonniwell is a very
respectable rancher.
He arrived in Texas
with about $60,000.
All of which he invested
in land and equipment.
But Mr. Bonniwell neglected
to buy any cattle.
Today, there are 5,000
head that carry his brand.
- When did he first come here?
- Not long after the surrender.
In fact, it was Mr. Bonniwell who
brought me the news of my nephew.
He happened to be in Silver City at the
time the Apaches went on the warpath.
He met Norman, and the boy told him about
a strike they'd made in some place called ...
- Gila Valley?
- Yes. Yes, that's it.
Otherwise, I might not have known.
Major Carson? The
sheriff just came in.
Has he agreed to ride with us?
Maybe you better talk to him alone.
- If you'll excuse me ...
- Of course.
Turnbloom, Welker, Gibson.
And now Carson.
Five men in one grave,
and we've identified four.
- Now we know.
- What?
- The sixth man.
- Bonniwell.
- That's the name he wears now.
- The name he used to wear?
You should know.
Jim, let's go away. Let's forget Bonniwell.
Please take me with you.
- I'll be good to you. I'll never do ...
- This is kind of a quick change, isn't it?
- What about your gold?
- I don't want it.
All of this to keep me from
killing a man who ran out on you.
A woman loved me that much,
I'd never leave her.
When I find your husband, among other
things, I'll tell him he's a fool.
- My husband?
- The man who calls himself Jim Bonniwell.
Jim!
Have you ever stopped to think
Bonniwell might be your father?
- Don't ... Do-, do-, don't say that.
- Why not?
You've been thinking it
ever since you read this.
It's a nice letter.
From another man who
ran out on his wife.
struck it rich.
You still say you're not
interested in the gold.
I'm not!
Then all of this is just to find a
murderer and get him under your gun?
- Look, look, Karyl, I, I, I've got to go.
- Jim, this could be your father.
If it is, will you kill him?
- Jim, please!
- Karyl, it won't work.
There are things a man has to know and has
to do, and it's best if he does 'em alone.
All the boys would feel better if they were
riding as deputies under you and Dobbs.
Oh, Mr. Slater!
Who is he?
A gentleman who decided
no to sell me his gun.
- Am I right, Miss Orton?
- I'm afraid you are.
Well, one man more or less
won't make much difference.
Unless it happens to be you, Sheriff,
we'd still like to have you with us.
Officially, I can't take
part in a range war.
If Bonniwell's a thief, and I'm sure he is,
the rangers will have to take care of him.
We're not gonna wait that long.
Suppose you sleep on it, Sheriff.
In the morning, we'll ride through
town on the way to Bonniwell's ranch.
- That's the present plan, isn't it?
- That's what I told all the men.
We'll stop by your office.
You've changed your mind, well ...
In the meanwhile, how about buying
you and Dobbs a drink for the road?
Thanks, I'll take my drink at
the other end of the road.
I'll need it when I get there.
C'mon, Dobbs.
Carson's gonna make his
move in the morning, Jim.
They'll ride into town, pick up the sheriff
and hit you with everything they got.
- What's my name?
- He's gonna make his move, Mr. Bonniwell.
- Picking up the sheriff here, huh?
- That's right.
- I rode all the way in just to tell ya.
- Very well, you've told me.
Carson and the sheriff
won't be coming alone.
They'll have fifty, sixty, maybe
a hundred men riding with them.
More than that, Pothook. If he brings
in the Triangle Bar, the Two Sixes ...
... the Y-4 riders and the
sheriff, he'll have 107 men ...
... when he rides through Sierra Blanca.
But we ain't got that many.
What are you gonna do?
- Bet. Ten dollars.
- That sends me home.
You haven't got a home, Sleepy.
None of you got homes.
So don't get any ideas
about leaving in a hurry.
- I'll stay.
- That's a profound statement.
All blue, the king on top.
And we haven't time for
another hand, gentlemen.
Fresno, you and Pothook get the line camps.
Bring in every man you find.
Sleepy, you and Johnny
ride to the river.
Ortega and his men are
putting a herd across there.
- Tell 'em to leave it and ride in.
- Right.
Whiskey.
You can buy me a drink, mister.
Well, Jumpy.
Give the, uh, boy a glass of milk.
I did that on purpose.
- Having none of that tonight!
- Get out of my way.
You see what he did! He hit me!
I did, too. And my gun's out.
Now do as you're told. Ride out
with Sleepy and bring in the men.
A word of advice. He's faster
than a baby rattlesnake.
And twice as dangerous.
Thanks.
Say, uh, where would I find
a man named Jim Bonniwell?
Uhm, friend of yours?
Could be.
How long since you've seen him?
Why? Is that important?
No. Not to me.
You figuring to work for him?
Put out a bottle, Rebel. We both need
a drink, and we need it right now.
Wait a minute. I'm still
trying to find Jim Bonniwell.
Ride north along the stage road
and turn west at the hills.
Thanks.
Didn't I see you ride out
from Major Carson's place?
Yeah, he's the man. Carson wanted to
buy his gun, but he turned him down.
So now you'd like to sell it to Jim
Bonniwell, along with some information?
But you're not gonna do it.
And who's gonna stop me?
Lock him up.
- What about my drink?
- I'll bring it along.
Might even give you a drink
if you behave yourself.
Howdy, Major.
Understand you have a little
job of work that needs doing.
We're glad to have you, Dick.
We're still waiting for the Crocker
and the boys from the Two Sixes.
- They'll be along in about an hour.
- Glad to hear it.
Bonniwell won't be. When're
you gonna hit him?
Soon as there's light
enough for good shooting.
Where do I find Jim Bonniwell?
- So early in the morning?
- Where do I find him?
Lady, this ain't a post office,
it's a saloon.
Well, in that case, let
her have some whiskey.
- We don't serve ladies.
- You serve this lady.
Whiskey.
You and me, we're gonna have those
drinks you didn't have with my brother.
Remember him?
Name was Jeff. You got him killed.
Jim Slater did that job.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Oh no, you're a smart girl. You know
everything. You know where he is.
I told you the truth. I
don't know where he is.
Maybe you just forgot.
Have a drink. Have a lotta drinks.
Maybe you'll remember when
you have a lotta drinks.
- Where's Slater?
- Mr. Bonniwell ain't gonna like this.
You were supposed to get the men.
I got the men. Now I want Jim Slater.
What for do you want him?
Oh.
I remember you.
- You're the funny girl.
- Am I?
I like funny girls.
I like you.
Careful, Johnny. She was
asking to see Mr. Bonniwell.
- Fine. We'll go and see him.
- What for do you want Slater?
I'm gonna kill him.
You ain't gonna kill nobody.
Who says that?
I do.
Tony Welker.
Draw.
Olson heard that shot. Now
get outta here, quick!
Who cares about Olson? Come
on, we'll go see Bonniwell.
Johnny! Hold up there, Johnny!
Something you want, Sheriff?
- What was that shooting?
- Aw, nothing much. I just killed a man.
Could do the same to
you if I wanted to.
I was only fooling with the sheriff.
When I see your man, I won't be fooling.
I'll kill him!
You're real lucky.
We ain't gonna have to go to Jim.
He's coming to us.
Hey, Sheriff! You got company!
That's Jim Bonniwell coming!
Which one is Bonniwell?
Now, don't you go getting interested
in Jim. I'm gonna be your man.
What's Bonniwell doing here? I thought
Carson was gonna gun him down at the ranch.
Carson thought so, too.
Johnny Cool must've carried the word.
- Am I right?
- How would I know?
Why not? You're one
of Bonniwell's men.
- If there's gonna be any killing ...
- Leave it alone, Dobbs.
Put the shotgun back in the rack.
I'll handle this.
Ortega? Johnny? Get with Ortega!
Right, Mr. Bonniwell.
Why have you brought your men
into town, Mr. Bonniwell?
I understand you've been talking
with some of my neighbors, Sheriff.
Talked to Major Carson and
the men at Diamond C.
Did you now?
And did you decide to ride with him in
the morning when he raids my ranch?
No. I told him, officially, I
can't take any part in it.
- But you talked to him.
- That's right.
- You didn't talk to me.
- No.
- Then you'd ride against him.
- Oh, I see.
I'm paid to keep the peace. If there's
gonna be a range war, I gotta stop it.
Well, I am riding against him.
You're gonna stop me, huh?
- I'm gonna try, Mr. Bonniwell.
- Don't be foolish, Sheriff.
I gotta try.
Take care of him.
All right, hide your
horses and spot your men.
Relax, Dobbs. I'm gonna
save you for a while.
Lock him up.
- What's he doing here?
- Olson figured he was one of your men.
What's your name?
Jim Slater.
Let him out.
Step out here.
- Jim Slater, huh?
- Yeah.
- Where you from?
- Texas.
Texas is a big state.
Where about in Texas?
Nacogdoches.
- Born there?
- Yeah.
What are you doing in Sierra Blanca?
Looking for you.
I knew I kept you alive
for some reason.
Usually, when Johnny Cool goes
for his gun, I don't interfere.
But last night something said,
don't let that man die.
And I was talking about my own son.
What's on your mind?
I've spent six months looking for a killer.
What do you do when he turns
out to be you father?
Killer? Aren't you a little
careless with your words, son?
Yes, I kill when I have to. But I never
killed a man who wasn't trying to kill me.
And that goes for the sheriff,
in spite of his badge.
You doubt me, huh? Come here.
In a little while, you're going to see
97 men riding through this town ...
looking to kill me.
Olson was waiting to ride with 'em.
It's the old, old
story of dog eat dog.
I've got what they want, they
wanna take it away from me.
I'm not gonna let 'em. Does
that make me a killer?
I give you my word, son. I never killed
a man who wasn't trying to kill me.
What about the men at Gila Valley?
- What's your name?
- Karyl Orton.
- I knew a Paul Orton.
- My husband.
Oh.
He wasn't much of a man.
He was man enough to dig $60,000
worth of gold out of the hills.
You don't take this kinda gold out of the
the hills. You take it out of a bank.
What are you talking about?
Well, after the surrender, things were a
little rough on the boys who wore gray.
But your husband got just
a little too greedy.
So you talked things
over with the Apaches.
Who the devil talks with an Apache?
Your husband and his friends took
my guns away, ran me outta camp.
I passed a war party
heading for the stockade.
Lotsa rocks in Gila
Valley, so I hid out.
And watched your partners die.
I could think of no
reason to die with 'em.
And there were 60,000
reasons why you shouldn't.
Hello, Slater!
Get back to your place, Johnny!
Move over, funny girl.
I'm gonna kill you, Slater.
That shouldn't be hard.
He hasn't got a gun.
Give him yours.
Be careful, Mr. Bonniwell.
This time my gun's out.
Put it in the holster.
Call it, Mr. Bonniwell.
Go!
Not an easy thing to do, is it, son?
I didn't think there was a man in
the world could beat Johnny Cool.
Except me.
- You're a Slater, Jim.
- Shut up.
- Every inch a Slater.
- Shut up!
Why don't you leave him alone
and let him get out of here?
Get out? Why would he wanna do that?
Because he has a chance to lead
a decent life. He's a good man.
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
You could be wrong about him. True, I
haven't seen him since he was born.
But it's my blood that flows in his veins,
and it's a little thicker than water.
Suppose he wants to
go away with me.
I wouldn't stop him for the world.
We're all spotted, Mr. Bonniwell!
- Fresno, you up on the hotel?
- Yes, sir!
- Jenkins, where are you?
- Up here, Mr. Bonniwell!
- Jim, we're leaving. We're going away.
- No, Karyl.
I had a ... I had a gun in my
hand, and I couldn't kill him.
- Of course you couldn't. He's your father.
- Yeah, that's right.
I'm a ... I'm a Slater.
And that explains a lot of things.
Jim, you're not going to stay here?
Jim, you mustn't.
Don't let him turn you into a killer.
Maybe he did give you your hands.
Maybe he gave you a lot of things.
- But he didn't give you what's inside you.
- I don't know what he gave me.
Jim, we've got to get out of here.
He says it's all right.
- He says he'll let you go.
- He says? What about Carson and his men?
- I don't care about Carson.
- You don't care, huh?
He'll be riding in here with
more than a hundred men ...
and they'll be shot
down without a chance.
Jim, you've got to get out of here.
No, I can't now, Karyl. I've gotten into
this and some way, I've got to finish it.
- What are you going to do?
- I don't know.
I don't know what I'm gonna do, but
I can't let a hundred men die.
I can't just ride away and let it happen.
I knew you wouldn't, son.
I've tried to tell her you wouldn't ride
away and let me face my enemies alone.
Well, practically alone.
I've waited a long while for this day.
For twenty-odd years, I waited for
one man to stand at my shoulder.
One man I could trust.
And now I've got him.
My own flesh and blood.
- Mr. Bonniwell, they're coming in.
- All right, stay in your places.
Every man likes to have his own gun
when things get a little warm.
I found yours in the sheriff's office.
- How do you know it's mine?
- Because it fits well in my hand.
Just as it does in yours.
We got plenty of time, son. Rebel!
Let you and me have a drink.
Celebrate the occasion.
Bring us a fresh bottle.
Sit down, Karyl.
All right. Now go out and tell
the men I want absolute quiet.
Yes, sir.
You know, I've never seen it fail.
When you take a trigger-happy bunch
sitting it out like this ...
somebody's bound to start
fooling with his gun.
Ordinarily, I don't care. This is supposed
to be a sleepy little border town.
All Carson needs is one gunshot ...
and he'll stop his men and send in
McCloud to find out what it's all about.
- And that would spoil everything.
- It certainly would.
They're getting awfully close,
Mr. Bonniwell.
Step out in the street and see how
close they are, will you, boy?
I'm glad you're not trying
to turn him against me.
- And if I did?
- You'd be sending him to his death!
Sometimes living's not that important.
I oughta take you with me.
You're no good.
But Carson'll do what I can't.
Jim, don't!
Don't shoot!
That's exactly what
he wants us to do!
Anybody pull the trigger
now, we're all dead!
Jim!
Use your gun!
This could be an ambush.
We'll surround the town!
Mr. Bonniwell! They're pulling a circle!
What do we do?
I'm gonna bust that circle.
Let's hit it and head for the border!
That's it! Ride out on
me, you yella fellas!
They're breaking out.
This could go on a long while, son!
Let's you and me make a deal!
What kind of a deal?
Let's both put our guns
back in the leather!
Then, when I give the word,
we'll both step out!
We'll see whether you're as
fast as you old man!
Made up your mind, son?
Yeah.
Yeah, I've made up my mind.
My gun's in the leather. Where's yours?
Mine's in the leather, too.
Whenever you're ready.
Step out!