BLOOD ON THE MOON
Who's that?
Put a light on yourself.
With what?
Man, man. I didn't
know anyone was here.
- Well, I had a fire.
- I couldn't have stopped 'em if I'd seen it.
I don't think I've seen you
around here before, have I?
Nope.
- You c ome over the peaks?
- Yeah. With an outfit.
What are you doing here?
I'm waiting for you to clear out of my camp.
Then I'll gonna turn in, if I can find my blankets.
My camp just below.
Maybe you better come along.
We can make it double that far.
I guess I can do with a cup of coffee.
Hey it's me, Bart.
Who is he?
I don't know.
I was bringin' my gather down the creek when they cleaned out his camp.
So I brought him along.
You come over the peaks?
That's right.
Why didn't you come to the pass?
There's no law says a man has to stick
to a wagon road, is there?
My men caught your horse.
It's branded "Lazy J".
I don't know it.
Don't you?
Wait a minute, Cap.
Make a fellow feel right at home don't you?
All right my name is Lufton,
John Lufton.
This is Cap Willis, my foreman.
A month ago, nobody would've asked you any questions.
It's different now.
Who are you?
Jim Garry. "Lazy J" is Texas brand.
Headed for Sun Dust?
That's right.
You know anybody there?
Nope.
Alright. I apologize for my steers.
We'll replace your outfit.
Make yourself comfortable.
Give him something to eat, Joe.
- Rotten night.
- Yeah.
Sorry we have to be so rough on you Garry,
but you're a loose rider.
We gotta watch them these days.
- Little argument over grazing land.
- Oh.
Yeah. For five years now, I've been supplying the
beef to feed the Indians here on the Reservation.
This year they've got new agent.
Fellow named Pindalest.
He's rejected my beef
and he's kicking me off the Reservation grass.
That doesn't explain about the loose riders.
No, but I haven't got any graze to move to
except what I used to claim in the Basin across the river.
And there seems to be a little difference of opinion now
as to who owns that.
Me or the homesteaders that have been drifting in.
I'm moving back.
They'll fight.
Yeah, I reckon they will.
A newcomer moved in this summer.
He's got 'em organized.
Name's Riling.
Still doesn't explain about the loose riders.
He's bringing in gun men.
Nobody can blame you for being careful.
I'm afraid you don't get it.
- Get what?
- This.
It's work for me or -
keep on riding.
And if I don't?
I'll give you a day in Sun Dust
and then you'd better drift.
Sleep on it, Garry.
Much obliged for the outfit.
Working for me Garry?
No, I guess I'll be drifting.
Well, it's your choice.
D'you mind dropping a note
at Block house with my women folk?
That's my place over in the Basin.
It's on your way.
Glad to.
Thanks.
Good luck.
Hold it! I'm riding through.
Come on out and talk.
Don't care who you kill, do you?
Maybe that'll cool you off.
- Got a note from John Lufton.
- I'm Carol Lufton.
- You're working for us now?
- No.
Bringing herd across river
at Rock Ford tonight. - Dad
Did Dad say when he was coming
down from the Reservation?
- No, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Stop right there.
You're the man that shot at me by the river.
Yeah, I guess I am.
Well I'm gonna show you how it feels.
Put that gun down, Amy.
Amy stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it! You hear?
Have you gone crazy?
- What's going on here?
- Ask him.
I was only giving him back a little
of what he gave me.
- What about it?
- She's right.
Why has Dad had to guard at the river
for a week if it isn't to keep the riders from crossing?
- What are you doing here?
- He brought a note from Dad.
Well, I tried to tell her
but she wouldn't give me a chance.
Alright you delivered the note.
Now, get out.
Well, for once you bit off
more than you can chew.
- That him?
- Yeah, what do you think?
- Hmm, maybe.
- Maybe my foot, Manker! You gotta get hit on the head with it?
- Lufton threatened to get one, didn't he?
- Well you ain't sure it's him.
I cut his sign going into Lufton's ranch this morning
and I cut it going out.
John Lufton's got a right to hire a range detective
if he wants to, Milo.
Not to watch us, he ain't.
Well, let Riling handle it.
And no shooting.
Take the third stall.
The boy'll bring you some hay.
Any idea who that fellow is?
"Lazy J" is the brand but I don't know it.
He say anything?
- He asked where he could find Tate Riling.
- Riling?
- I'll take it at the table Barney.
- Sure.
Lufton's watcher just drifted in.
- Cattle detective?
- What else?
- He asked for Riling.
- Riling?
If he's Lufton's watcher,
what d'you figure he wants with Riling?
Let's find out.
Yeah. Why not?
But how? Riling ain't here.
Sure he is.
Where?
Right here. Eh, Nels?
Well, let's wait 'til Riling gets here.
We wouldn't want to make no mistake.
Alright, Nels.
Maybe you want the law to come in here and find out what we're planning to do.
So he can go back and tell Lufton.
Alright, Milo, alright.
I'll tell Barney.
Know where I can find Tate Riling?
Back table.
Ace, Queen, Mitch.
Tate Riling?
That's me.
I'd like to talk to you.
Go ahead.
These are my friends.
I'm looking for a riding job.
Who said I was hiring riders?
I heard it.
You hear what I'm hirin' them for?
I heard that too.
Why yes.
Dumb play boys.
Stay set Army.
He's headin' for the street.
Mr. Riling, Lufton's watcher's in town.
Asking for you.
And he wanted a ridin' job with us, Tate.
- Then go get him.
- There he is.
Jim Garry!
Hello, Tate.
This is Jim Garry. The man I sent for.
He's no range detective.
What went wrong, Jim? What Happened?
Who started this?
Ask these jokers here, Tate.
If that's Garry, what's he doing at Lufton's?
Were you at the Lufton's place?
Yeah he was. I seen him.
That's right. I delivered a not from him to his women folk.
What about it?
Well it's Lufton's outfit that's tryin' to
run us out of the country, Jim.
Am I supposed to know that?
Why no. I forgot.
I never wrote Jim about our fight with Lufton.
I told him I needed him and asked him to come on up.
Now stop chewin' leather and
go and get yourself a drink.
Sam old Jim, when lightning strikes
you're there.
It wasn't a fair test.
Come on, let's get you a room.
It's good to see you again Jim.
I wasn't sure you'd come.
I'm here.
Yeah. I heard things haven't been
breaking too good lately.
Well, that's a bootless job - trail driving.
I told you that we split up two years ago.
Understand you fin'lly got your own herd.
And two weeks later I saw 'em strung out along the
bottomlands. Dead of the Fever.
We'll forget it. There's money in this deal.
Big money.
- Barney, how about a room for my friend here?
- Sure.
I wouldn't wish one on him if was a friend of mine though.
Oh. This has got your name on it.
Somebody fired it through the back window during the ruckus.
We're goin' out tonight fellows.
I know where Lufton's crossing.
- How do you know?
- Never mind, I know.
Be ready to leave in half an hour.
Drink up, Jim.
Wait here, I'll be right back.
I suppose you'd like to know what
this is all about?
I have been kinda wondering, yeah.
Well I'm not gonna tell you, Jim.
I'm gonna show you.
Come in.
Jim, this is Mr. Pindalest. United States agent for
the Ute Indians over at the Reservation
This is Jim Garry, my partner.
How do you do?
You didn't tell me before about a partner.
Well I'm telling you now.
Before we go on any further,
I want to understood how he'll figure in this.
You mean money?
Don't worry Pindalest.
I'll share with Jim.
Hmm.
Well, here's the, uh, item we were talking
about the other day.
Think you'll find it satisfactory.
United States dollars are usually satisfactory,
aren't they?
Now look. I told you Garry is my partner, Pindalest.
What I know, he knows..
So relax and sit down.
No, I won't stay.
Scared?
Just cautious, Riling.
Well that's our partner, Jim.
Cautious...
And this is our working capital,
courtesy of the United States Government.
There's enough there to buy me 2,500 head
of Lufton's beef, four dollars a head.
That's cheap enough, isn't it?
It's too cheap. Where is the catch?
There isn't any.
You, um, met Lufton, you say?
Yeah, I camped with him last night.
Did he tell you that Pindalest has ordered
his cattle off the Reservation?
Yeah. He said he'd refused his beef.
And did he tell you that the army from Fort Liggett,
has orders to seize the cattle if they're not off
the Reservation by the first of November?
No he didn't tell me that.
Well that's the layout Jim.
I've organized these two bit ranchers
to fight any move Lufton makes to push his
herd across the river and into the Basin here.
The ranchers'll fight because they figure
they're fighting for their own range.
But the truth is, they'd be fighting for me.
Now withut any graze to move to,
Lufton'll be caught on the Reservation
and his herd seized.
So what does he do?
Sell?
To me. Cheap.
Because he'd rather get a little money than lose everything.
Sounds like you've got him over a barrel.
I have!
I buy 'em cheap and sell 'em back to the Government
through Pindalest for full contract price.
Your cut will be ten thousand dollars.
What do I have to do to earn it?
Lufton's tough. My ranchers aren't.
You'll make up the difference.
I see.
I've mixed up a lot of things, Tate.
But up to now, I've never been hired for my gun.
Can you afford to be particular?
No I guess I can't.
Now you're talking, Jim.
I'll meet you down in the lobby in 10 minutes.
Come on, slow poke.
Don't you want to know if Dad got across?
Of course.
What's the matter?
Did I get you out the bed too early?
I'm worried about dad.
I hope he didn't have trouble crossing last night.
Could only be trouble if Riling found out about it.
Nobody's crossed here.
Looking for someone, Miss Lufton?
So you're one of 'em?
- I guess dad wasn't so wrong about you after all.
- Wrong?
He must've spotted you for one of Riling's
gun men the minute he saw you.
Funny isn't it Riling?
But not to you. By now Dad's probably got his herd
across the river some place else
while you wait here at Rocky Ford to throw him back.
- Is that why we're here?
- Isn't it?
Simply because Dad was smart enough to give this saddle
tramp a not that he was sure to read.
He knew he'd tell you and decoy you over here.
How do you like it now, Kris?
You and your son?
Why you aren't even being led by a smart crook.
We're only fighting for what belongs to us, Miss Amy.
You didn't fight for it before Riling gave you the idea.
Why didn't you talk to dad, Kris?
Talk to him.
You use to work for him.
You know he's not unreasonable.
Call it unreasonable to kick us off our land?
I don't believe I've seen you around here before.
- You fighting for your own graze too?
- No ma'am.
And you?
I thought you were all old timers, fighting for land
you settled on, Kris?
At least that's in the open now.
Paid gunmen against working riders.
You did read that note, didn't you?
No.
You're a poor liar.
Yes.
Well. Lufton's across the Massacre.
John Lufton's no fool, mister.
Garry did not read that note.
- Then where did you get the tip?
- None of your business, Milo.
I got a wrong tip and I won't get another.
Well if you don't like it, Milo.
Just ride it on out.
Lufton's across the river with that herd.
Yeah, sure. But steers have got legs.
They can be driven back.
The thing to do is find 'em
before Lufton can get 'em scattered.
After that we can move.
Didn't you notice how them four always stick together?
Why not?. Reardan and Shotten work for Riling.
Garry's a friend just came in to help.
I can buy me that kind of a friend
for $75 a month and no questions asked.
You know, Lufton's smart.
Yeah he's smart enough to spot me.
He had spotted Shotten and Reardan
before I even knew they were there.
They are a couple of beauties.
Who are they?
Doesn't matter who they are, Jim.
The thing that matters is, they don't scare easy.
Well, it's pretty crude.
Not so crude.
I've made everybody swallow it but Lufton,
and I'll make him swallow it too.
Shotten, Reardan and me.
Hired gunmen.
Shotten and Reardan will get paid in gold eagles.
You get paid in thousands.
Yeah. Only difference between us is the price.
All right boys, cut for town.
I'll be in touch with you.
Tate, I didn't know it was a trick of Dad.
I swear I didn't. Until I heard Amy say it.
Of course you didn't, darling.
Forget it.
It's done and now we've got to fix it.
But I'm glad in a way.
I couldn't bear it this morning when I though
you and Dad were fighting.
It isn't for you, Carol.
But I have to do what I'm doing.
You see that, don't you?
- Yes, Tate.
- You see, I'm a poor man, darling.
Money has to come hard to me.
Nothing for me to do but join up with men
just like myself and fight for what little I've got.
I tried to make Dad see both sides.
But he's just as sure he's right as you homesteaders are.
We've got to fight.
But he's across now.
What are you gonna do?
I'm not gonna ask you to risk your dad's life, darling.
But I am going to ask you to help.
Find out where he's holding the herd that he crossed.
and get word back to me as soon as you can.
You won't let any harm come to Dad, won't you?
You know you can trust me, darling.
Still a lot easier when we go through the gap.
- We ought to make it by noon.
- Yes.
I scatter 'em in the scrub pinion
west of Avery's patch.
Amy!
What the devil are you doing here?
You didn't think I'd stay home
when you're this close.
This is no place for you.
I told Bart to tell you girls I'd be home by noon.
I told 'em and it didn't do no good.
She was bent on coming along.
I couldn't wait.
All right, Cap, get 'em started.
Bart says you crossed without any trouble?
Yeah. We're primed for it but didn't come.
I think I know why.
Did a rider name of Garry drift into the ranch
yesterday with a note?
You mean that hired gunman of Riling's?
So I had him pegged right.
Too bad, he was a nice seeming fellow.
Too nice to read that note.
But he did.
Do you think this Garry's a killer?
Joined up with Riling, didn't he?
Get out of here, Amy!
I'll make Riling remember this.
They'll run 'till they're worn out.
Four days to the deadline.
It'll take us a week to round 'em up
and get 'em off the Reservation again.
It's young Barden.
I hope it wouldn't come to this.
Just a month ago me and him
went to a shindig together.
Yeah, he was a nice boy.
Well, what do you want?
It's about your Barden.
He was killed on the raid.
I figured maybe that's what happened
when he didn't come home.
I was with him when he got hit.
Nothing I can do.
It's a big price to pay for
a little bit of graze.
Too bad you had to get mixed up in this fight, Barden.
I joined up with the other small ranchers
'cause I figured their fight was my fight.
We ain't being paid to fight, mister.
I'm sorry about your son, Mr. Barden.
You can believe that if you want to.
Sure. Sure.
I've lived here more than of half my life
with my wife and my son.
She died about four years ago.
And now...
Now he's gone.
Go on in the Hotel, Amy.
I told you to ride on through.
- So you did?
- You're time's up, get started.
- Get out of here, Amy.
- No.
- Go on into the hotel.
Don't move, Lufton.
Your drift, Shotten.
Get that girl out of there.
I said, drift.
What are we waitin' for?
But this is what Riling wants.
He said so.
That's your horse, Reardan.
Get moving.
I ain't taking orders from you.
All right, Reardan. Any time you want.
Make up your mind.
I won't wait.
You won't be this lucky next time, Lufton.
I don't get it, Garry.
I just don't get it.
You're riding on, aren't you?
I'm glad. Not for us, but for you.
I want to thank you for this.
I want to apologize too, for what I said to you.
Don't let a man's whim fool you.
I haven't.
COMMISSARY
12 MILES
What do you want, amigo?
Whiskey.
Would you be looking for me?
I ain't looking for anybody, mister.
Is that you, Kris?
I heard about Fred.
I'm sorry, Kris.
I'll make Lufton pay for that.
What good'll that do? Fred's...
Fred's dead.
It'll make me feel better.
Did you come all the way over here to
tell me that?
No. I missed you this morning.
I didn't know you'd be here.
Why are you?
I'm leavin' the country.
But Kris, the fight's almost won.
Lufton's herd is stampeded half way up
the Three Braves.
Who cares?
Hey Jim, where have you been?.
I've searched the country for you.
How'd you find me?
Settlemeir said you took the Commissary road.
I took a chance.
What's up?
Let's have a drink. I've got news.
Give me a glass and a handful of cigars
and then get out.
On the level, Jim.
What are you doing here?
Running out.
Any reason?
Two. Shotten and Reardan.
I never heard of you running away
from a pair like that.
- Well, I. I never did.
- Then why?
They were gonna kill Lufton in cold blood
when I stepped in.
I'm glad you did.
Are you?
Jim, what's eatin' you?
Why we've got more at stake here
than a bag of marbles.
You mean, you have.
Jim, Lufton isn't dead.
He isn't even hurt.
And after that stamped he hasn't got a chance.
- Then why bother about me?
- Because, I need you.
You don't think Lufton'll do
business with me, do you?
No.
No he'd rather lose his herd.
Exactly.
But today you stepped in
and saved his life.
He won't forget that.
So when you ride up with an offer,
he'll take it.
Because he has to.
Why not?
It's, something you wouldn't understand.
Try me.
It starts with your double cross
of a bunch of poor jugheaded homesteaders
and the hiring of gun hands.
It goes on to you making love to man's daughter
to get her to turn against her own father.
And your try for Lufton yesterday...
It goes past that
to the death of Kris Barden's son.
And it winds up right here.
with Reardan waitin' outside to see
if I go with you
or he shoots me in the back.
I've seen dogs that wouldn't claim
you for a son, Tate.
All right, get off.
I said, get off.
Hold it.
Give him time.
Can you make it to your horse?
Get out.
Why'd you do it?
I always wanted to shoot one of you
and he was the handiest.
Get out.
What are you doing here?
I want to see Lufton.
Why you dirty saddle stiff!
Get out of here, quick.
Lufton'll have to run me off.
I don't need orders from him
to cut down on you, Now get out!
What is it?
I'm looking for your father.
- Oh he's...
- Careful Miss Amy.
It don't matter to him where your father is.
It's all right, Ted.
That's a bad cut.
Come inside. I'll fix it.
Sit down.
Tate Riling?
Is he - dead?
No.
I keep remembering what you said yesterday in Sun Dust.
Was this a whim, too?
This business with Riling?
It was a pleasure.
What brings you back?
Gall, for one thing, John.
I got in a little jangle with Riling down at Commissary last night.
I'm through with him.
- Well?
- You may not believe me, Lufton
I want to tell you what you're up against.
Then it's up to you.
I already know what I'm up against.
You don't know that Pindalest aims to
buy your herd, do you?
He rejected it.
He won't reject it when Riling offers it to him.
Sure. Riling and Pindalest planned it together.
Pindalest's part of the deal was to order
you off the Reservation.
Riling was to prime the homesteaders to keep you
out of the Basin.
Do you figure you can round up your stuff
and cross it before the deadline?
- No
- And rather than let the Army take 'em you'd sell and take the loss wouldn't you?
Not to Riling.
But to a stranger like me with cash in his pockets.
That's the deal. I was supposed to make the offer
with Riling's money.
I don't believe it.
No, he's right, Cap.
I'd be a fool not to sell.
Well, I'll drift.
I just thought I'd let you to know.
Jim, wait a minute.
You don't tell a dead man he's dead.
You came here for something else, didn't you?
Well, I did had kind of an idea.
- Might not be what you'll like.
- Let's hear it.
Suppose the deadline was put off for a week.
That would give you time to round up your herd.
- Deadline hasn't been put off.
- It can be.
How?
Pindalest would laugh at me if I asked him to.
He wouldn't laugh at me.
No I'm not hiring a gunman to save my herd
or anything else.
Jim!
Jim, please wait a minute. He didn't understand what you were saying.
Please don't leave until he does.
He understood all right. Now step back.
I'm gonna follow you 'till you turn back.
You'll have a long ride.
I'm header for Texas.
All right.
We better quit this.
- You'll come back with me and give Dad a chance to apologize?
- No.
But you better go. They'll be looking for you.
I won't go unless you got with me.
Well, I'm gonna turn in.
I'm not leaving.
Well you're not staying here.
- Will you go back with me?
- No.
Then I won't go.
- I'll give you one more chance.
- No
You'll go now, unless you want more of that.
I don't want more of it, Jim.
But I won't go.
You really meant it, didn't you?
That much?
Jim, I know you better than you think.
You've been in hard luck
and you've made mistakes.
You hated those mistakes.
But you never admitted them
except to yourself.
Like this mess with Riling.
You never liked it.
That's why you walked out on him.
Today you, tried to do something
to make up for it.
And Dad threw it back in your face.
He thought you meant to kill Pindalest.
I didn't think so.
I know why you did it.
You thought it would help wipe out the past.
You're a proud man, Jim.
But this is the wrong kind of pride.
If you ride on to Texas
you're lost.
Cap's gone on ahead to get the drive started.
Only hope Riling doesn't get wind of what Garry's up to
or there'll be the devil to pay.
He knows what kind of man he's dealing with, Dad.
Yeah, I reckon he does.
At any rate, it's our only chance.
So you're going to let Dad risk everything
just because Garry sold you
a wild lying scheme.
Lie?
You don't believe what Jim told me?
No, Why should I?
He's nothing but a cheap gun man. A killer!
- That's not so. Jim wouldn't...
- Jim?
Yes. Jim!
What's the matter with calling him Jim?
He's no more a gun man than I am.
Amy, what is this?
He's trying to help us
and I'll stick up for him to you or anyone else.
Sounds a little stronger than sticking up for him.
Maybe it is.
But a gun man, Amy.
A man that'll go up against hired killers.
How did get get so expert?
You've thought of that?
More than you know.
Nothing made him come back and help us.
Except wanting to get even with Riling.
Not it's not that. He's really decent.
He...
Does he love you?
I don't know.
You're a fool, Amy.
He'll break your heart.
Come in. Come in.
Who is it?
Jim Garry.
Oh oh fine, Sit down.
I'll be out in a minute.
Been riding all day and was just taking a little nap.
- Drink?
- Don't mind if I do.
Well...
How are things?
Fine, Mr. Pindalest.
Just fine.
I brought that news you've been waiting to hear.
Everything went off without a hitch, huh?
Well, maybe one little hitch.
You might say.
What's that?
Lufton wants more money.
How much more?
Three thousand dollars.
Riling said his selling price to you still held.
This was just a loan.
Well, if that's all that holding us up
there's nothing to worry about, huh?
Success.
You know. This might cause a little trouble after all.
I don't keep that much cash here
at the agency.
Lufton wants cash.
Means I'll have to ride over to Sun Dust with you
and draw it out to the bank.
Riling figured you'd likely would.
How's the pass? Clear?
A little snow.
It will probably hold off.
Well, I'll throw some stuff together.
I'll get out of here
Oh I came close to forgettin'.
Riling says call off the Army.
Lufton'll likely run over the deadline
roundin' up some beef we stampeded for him.
Riling says he doesn't want to
explain to the Army about that.
Good idea.
I'll get a man out to Fort Liggett with a message right away.
Tate, what happened to you?
A fight. Where have you been?
I couldn't get out.
I know who you fought with,
It was Jim Garry.
How do you know?
He's been at the ranch.
Tate, I want to talk to you 'bout something.
That's why I came here tonight.
Well?
What is it?
Garry told us something very interesting.
He said that you and Pindalest had cooked up
this fight with Dad
to crowd him off the range so he'd sell his
cattle to you cheap.
Is that true?
So, Garry told you that, did he?
What else did he tell you?
This sounds good.
That you wanted him to make the offer to Dad.
Did he tell your father that?
Yes.
Tate, you haven't answeredr me. Is this true?
Of course.
You mean you've been making those poor homesteaders
that it's their rights you're fighting for?
I wanted money for us.
This is a way to get it, a lot of it.
Money your Dad could spare.
Tate, look at me.
Do you love me? Have you ever loved me?
What do you want me to say? Sure.
Don't lie to me.
You used me to beat Dad.
I betrayed him for you.
Now that's all you ever wanted,
It's all you ever counted on, isn't it?
I wouldn't say that.
Would you go in town with me this minute.
And marry me like you promised?
Not until I get money to support you.
What's funny?
I was thinking of something
I told Amy this morning.
Wasn't that the Lufton's girl?
- What's she doing here?
- None of your business.
What are you doing here?
I thought you said Garry quit
Well?
What's he doing at the Reservation?
- The Reservation?
- Yeah, yeah.
Nels saw him there this morning.
Heading for the agency.
Feel kind of stiff, don't you?
When we get to Sun Dust,
I'll sleep for a week.
We won't be getting to Sun Dust for
quite a while.
We'll just stay right here.
What do you mean?
You've been taken in, Pindalest.
Riling never sent me to see you.
I came to take you and
hide you out until the deadline.
- And Lufton did not agree to sell?
- No.
Also he's rounding up his cattle right now
with no Army to bother him.
But you're a Riling man.
What? I'm with Lufton now.
You can't get away with it, Garry.
Riling's no fool.
He'll be on our trail in twenty four hours.
Let him.
When he does find out what's happened,
he'll pull his men off to hunt you
That'll make it all easier for Lufton.
I'd take it easy with that If I were you Pindalest.
it will not last out the week.
Don't move.
Maybe I won't nurse this quite as long as you figured.
If you're plannin' on movin out,
you're going alone.
I'm giving you a chance to change your mind.
I'm staying here.
Now look, I can lick you and you know it.
Keep this up, you'll end up with a sore head, and that's all.
Suit yourself.
All right.
You win. Untie me.
Come on.
Come on cheer up, Pindalest.
Now we can start looking for a place to make camp.
- Toma! Where are you?
- Over here, Riling.
- Toma, Sing out!
- Riling, Over here!
Send the Indian to Fort Liggett.
with the message to bring the Army on.
- Hey, Milo.
- Yeah?
- Get back to the Basin.
See the boys hold Lufton on the Reservation
'till the troops get there.
What about Garry?
We'll take care of him.
Carol.
You've got to stop this.
I know.
I'll make some coffee.
I could have seen Dad and told him.
You must stop thinking about it.
Only, if we knew what was happening to him.
You just got to believe in what
Jim's doing would work.
He has a good chance.
Do you really think so?
Of course I do.
Why don't you lie down for a while.
I'll bring you some coffee.
Why Kris, I thought you'd left the Basin.
I did Miss Amy but...
I guess I've lived around here a little too long.
It got lonesome.
I knew you couldn't leave us for good.
Well I'm back to stay
and I come over to ask for your help.
I maybe ain't got no right asking
considering who it's for but..
Do you remember that young fella
you combed out over at Rocky Ford the other day?
He's been hurt.
Jim Garry?
Came home this morning found him lying on the floor in my shack.
He got a knife stuck in him.
I'll go get dressed.
It's me, Jim.
Lie still.
You gotta get out of here.
No, Jim.
Kris.
Kris, tell here to get out of here.
I'm going to fix this up.
He's asleep.
Good.
So him and your dad are in this together?
Yes.
Young lady, you're going on a ride.
Riling's on his trail. He'll probably
end up here sometime today.
That's why Garry wanted, to get you out of here.
We gotta get help.
Do you know where your dad is?
No I don't.
Oh Kris, I don't. We haven't heard from Dad for days.
Well you better find him.
What about Jim?
If they show up I can stand 'em off
till your Dad gets here. Don't let that worry you.
Where you gonna look for him?
I don't know. Somewhere south.
- I'll try and pick up the trail of the herd and follow it.
- Good.
What are you doing here?
I might ask you that?
Barden home?
Yes.
Who else is in there?
Nobody.
You're a lovely little liar.
All right fellas, let's take a look.
Hold that the door.
Here take this.
- Riling?
- Yes. And Pindalest and Shotten.
Look here, Kris.
Before this goes any further
tell Riling, I'll go with him.
These walls are good and thick. They can't burn us out.
And we got plenty of cartridges.
He won't quit till he's got me
and he'll kill you both to do it.
So wel let him shoot you,
just to save our necks.
Then tell here she's coming out.
They'll let her through
No. I won't go.
Make her go.
Why do you think she risked her neck to get back in here
if it wasn't on account of you?
Why do you think I want to get her out?
Same reason, I reckon.
He's right, Amy.
But it wouldn't work. Not even if you'd have me.
Now will you go?
No.
Look, I've been fiddlefooted and no good all my life.
I'm not askin' any woman to take that.
I knew that when I came here.
That's what I am, Amy. That's me.
Don't you see how useless talk is?
I'm here and I'm staying.
- Jim?
- Yes?
Jim, what are you doing up?
I'm going out there and try and get a crack at them.
No let me talk...
We can probably hold out a few more hours, but...
You ain't going out there just to save our necks.
I'll try and save my own too.
We might as well face it.
They're not gonna give up.
It's not likely anybody'll be along to help us.
Then I'll go.
I got a score to settle with Riling myself.
No, Kris.
It's me Riling's after.
I'd like to finish this my own way.
- You will let him go Miss Amy?
- Yes she is.
Where are they exactly?
They're all scattered out.
Riling's over on the left of 'em trees.
The other two are closer to the corral.
If I just make it to the corner of the corral
I can circle around and get behind them
But they'll see you.
Soon as I get out
you open up on 'em.
That'll draw a return fire. Their powder flash will
blind 'em for a couple of seconds, thats all I need.
- Ready?
Hold it, Miss Amy. Hold it!
I think he made it.
That last shot came from another direction.
- Do you want to get hit?
- But I got to know.
Hey, Shotten?
Pindalest?
All right Riling, It's just you and me now.
It's a pleasure, Jim.
For me, Tate.
Same old Jim.
When lightning strikes, you're there.
You and me together, Jim.
We coulda licked 'em
But you,
you always had a conscience
breathing down your neck.
Jim!
Riling's dead.
Shotten too.
And Pindalest?
No I do not think so. He's over there.
- Dad. - Carol told me you were here.
She was afraid there might be trouble.
- Where's riling?
- He's dead.
Well Lufton, don't look like you're gonna
get Riling to do much talking now.
I'm going to have you arrested for murder.
Put up a fair fight, John. And
I'll tell that to the sheriff.
Or anybody else that wants to know.
Lufton was telling us about a little deal
that you and Riling cooked
up to swindle him out of his cattle.
- What about it?
- I had no deal with Riling.
Don't forget I was in on it too.
Well boys, that's the man
you've been fighting for.
Get your horse. Me and you are going to
have a little talk with the marshal.
I guess we been a pack of fools, Lufton.
Say fellas. I've got a jug I been saving
for a special occasion. This looks like it.
What do you say if we...?
Garry I guess I was wrong about
quite a few things.
Yeah I was wrong about a few things myself.
We've been plenty stubborn.
That's going to make two stubborn
men in the family.
Well I guess Kris was right.
This is a special occasion.
Come on.