"Here we are, born to be kings"
"We're the princes of the universe"
"I am immortal"
"I have inside me blood of kings"
"I have no rival, no man can be my equal"
"Take me to the future of your world"
HIGHLANDER 1x04 "INNOCENT MAN"
Subtitles subXpacio
HOMELESS VETERAN
WILL WORK FOR FOOD.
Hey General, want a ride?
Suck jerk naïve!
That's a breach of contract,
A breach of visual contract, moron!
They've no respect
for their Country or their flag,
or medals or anybody!
I'm gonna put you on report,
that's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna put you on report
with the Department of Transportation.
Hello! Hello!
Department of Transportation? Hello!
Sunspots!
Is there anything more beautiful?
I'm sitting next to her.
I love you.
- A little music?
- Fine.
- That's terrible.
- You've no taste.
This wing... I'll look like a mess.
- You look fine.
- No!
- Will you leave that alone?
- No, leave it!
- Oh, come on.
- Ah!
Wow.
It's nice to be in the Country.
City streets got bums on every corner,
pushin', shovin', hustlin'...
There's no competition out there.
We should do this more often.
- Get lost?
- We're not lost.
Why is it a man
will never admit he's lost?
We passed half a dozen stations and you
wouldn't pull to one of them for directions.
But what does the map say?
The map isn't saying anything.
Wait a minute.
The cabin's a mile south
of Steepston?
Yeah, that's what Lucas said.
You won't believe this.
We're almost there!
- The cabin should be over...
- Just around the corner, yeah, I know.
Go on.
Let's walk.
It's beautiful.
How long has your friend lived here?
Lucas? About... no long.
Well, which for you
could mean half a century.
It’s more like 12 years.
After all that time, why does he
suddenly want to see you?
I don't know... he...
He said something was worrying him.
Mac!
He's dead.
Your friend?
How can you be so sure?
I just know.
What would we have here?
What you do, boy?
Oh no...
I didn't have nothing to do with this.
Body on floor...
You standing over him
with a sword in hand...
Looks like your guilty
as hell to me, boy.
You all right, son?
- What's your name?
- Leo.
Leo Atkins.
I have never seen you before.
You from around here?
No. I'm from...
I'm from nowhere in particular.
I'm real pleased to meet you, Leo.
Let me tell you
where you're going.
You're gonna ride the lightning.
You killed a man.
And you're gonna fry.
- Sorry Mac.
- Are we bored?
No, we're not bored.
Actually, I was looking at
this book of drawings, Da Vinci.
This dude was making flying machines
when you were in diapers.
The thing is, if he can
design gliders and stuff,
why didn't he get our butts
airborne back then?
'Cause he was hired
to make gunpowder, instead.
- You finished those invoices yet?
- Ah... no.
No? Why not?
- I've been busy.
- Yeah, you being busy?
Yeah! I've been busy!
You know, I thing you got
a little bit too much time on your hands.
- You need to spend a little time in jail.
- Jail! Why? For...
assault with a paper airplane?
For littering your office? What!
- I'll tell you on the way to Steepston.
- Steepston?
That's a place that doesn't
even have crosswalks.
- Why would we want to go to Steepston?
- What's this about Steepston?
- Because you're driving.
- The T-Bird?
- Bring it around the front, would you?
- Good, I'll get my jacket.
I need to talk to the guy
they're holding for murdering Lucas.
Ok, I'll close up the shop
and I'll come with you.
No, I need to do this on my own.
But you are taking Richie...
Well, I need him for something.
I know why
you don't want me there.
You're afraid that what happened
to Lucas could happen to you.
That never crossed my mind.
- Then, stay here!
- Tessa...
they may have the wrong man.
I can't let him just...
stew in jail.
I'll be back.
Smile!
- Promise?
- Scout's honor. Here.
The police blotter mentioned
a report of a...
just tell me
if I got this all wrong...
a sword fight
on these premises?
This is Chinese.
You got it wrong.
So, what did happen?
We caught a young burglar.
The boy, who has
a vivid imagination...
was trying to steal a sword.
- No sword fight.
- No.
You've heard about
the headless body they found up North?
Of course, who hasn't?
I just thought there might be a connection.
Why?
Because the victim had a big sword
next to his body when they found him.
Sounds like a great story.
Good luck with it.
Yeah, well, thanks.
I guess you know
a lot about swords.
You're so good at fencing.
I might have to come back
for your expert opinion.
My expert's opinion
is that you're wasting your time.
Yeah? Well, thanks.
I'm sure with your help,
this will be a dynamite story.
I'm Sergeant Powell.
I talked to you this morning.
Sergeant Powell,
I'm Howard Crowley.
Come on in.
So, our little horror story
brought you here.
Coffee?
Yeah, we got one of those ourselves:
We got a headless body
on a city bridge a while back.
I know that, Sergeant.
We do get TV reception,
even way up here.
Sorry.
I was going to call you anyway
to compare notes.
We got no suspects, no witnesses.
Ours was done with a
very sharp instrument.
So it probably wasn't an ax,
or a chainsaw or...
What it was, probably,
was a sword, right?
You're guessing or you've got something?
We've got a sword.
I'd run it into our lab
to check the theory...
if we had a lab.
Planned to send it
to the county seat this afternoon.
I'd be happy to help with
the interrogation if you're interested.
I think that can be arranged.
I suppose you like to see
the crime scene first.
If I could.
Who was the victim?
A man named Desiree,
Lucas Desiree.
- He kept pretty much to himself.
- French?
Old southern stock.
Funny, him coming all
the way up here to live.
His kinfolk probably owned
a lot of your kinfolk...
once upon a time.
So we like go to cabin sift through
the place for clues the police missed?
No, they probably didn't miss anything.
I still don't get what would posses Lucas
to move out in the middle of nowhere.
He just wanted get away,
be on his own.
Like you did?
Out in the country, you can't take
your mistress into the woods...
for a quickie without
twenty people knowing about it.
Lucas was very careful.
He didn't advertise
his whereabouts.
And you don't think it's this bum that
the papers are talking about, who did it?
Maybe. Maybe not.
I need to get close enough
to be sure.
Wait a minute, Sherlock...
are you trying to tell me there is
a loose Immortal cruising around here...
chopping off people's heads...
in this vicinity, where
you and I are going?
Possibly. We'll find out.
Oh, man!
You're trying my patience, Leo.
You talk but you don't say anything.
- I'm trying.
- Tell me again.
I don't know nothing I didn't
know five minutes ago.
You do that pretty well, Leo.
"Crazy old Leo, wouldn't harm a flea"
That's what that man in the cabin thought.
Then you took off his head!
I never took no heads!
Oh, I knew a guy who took heads.
He put it on the end of his bayonet.
Yeah, you knew our guy.
And I bet you knew him real well.
Old habits die hard, don't they Leo?
You think you're back in Nam,
collecting trophies off the VC!?
Is that what we got going here?
It's okay, Leo.
You can tell me.
See, I was there too.
I understand.
- You were there?
- Bet your ass.
- Two tours. Airborne. What about you?
- Dog soldier.
I hate the jungle. Snakes.
I hate snakes.
And tunnels, I hate tunnels.
What about cabins, Leo. You like cabins?
Cabins?
You were there, Leo.
In the cabin, with the sword.
Oh, yeah, I was.
- I remember that.
- Yeah, but not everything!
You see, that's why we're here, Leo.
We're trying to help you remember!
Oh yeah, 'cause you
were there: in Nam.
Yes, and that's what
you thought too, didn't you?
You were out there on patrol,
weren't you, Leo?
- That's right.
- And you came to the cabin.
- Cabin?
- And you went inside with the sword.
- I don't remember no swords in Nam.
- But you just said you did!
Hey look, you got to keep it straight, Leo!
I'm trying to help you here!
You're out there on patrol.
You had your sword.
And all of the sudden he was there.
Charlie, the VC.
Yeah, I could smell him.
He was that close.
And you were scared.
Peeing in my pants.
He was so close, I could reach
out and touch him in the darkness!
And you were so scared, you took
your sword and you swung away.
You killed him.
It was "him or you".
I know how it is, Leo.
That's right. Him or me!
Him or me.
Him or me!
That's right. Him or me.
Yeah, him or me!
Yeah!
I don't see a stop light.
I don't even see a stop sign.
Maybe that's why Lucas came here.
To do what?
Play bingo and pitch horse shoes?
To live.
To not turn every corner
expecting to meet out destiny.
Sounds like a simple thing to do.
To love, hate, drink and dream...
about going someplace else.
Someplace better.
We are a little philosophical
today, Mac?
Lucas just wanted to get away,
try to retire for the Game.
Like you, before the Gathering.
That's what this is all about, isn't it?
One of your guys is out
head-hunting. He finds Lucas...
So you come out here hoping this same
guy comes looking for you, am I right?
Maybe.
- Why do you owe good old Lucas, anyway?
- It's a long story.
Now you know what to do,
go and do it.
I could smell him.
I could hear him breathing.
And the sergeant said:
"Leo, take the point!"
And I took it.
Down on my belly like a damn snake...
until I ran right into Charlie!
I couldn't see him in the dark!
But I tried to tell him...
"Don't do this. Slip away, man!"
"We're both gonna die today!"
But he shot me!
He shot me here on my face!
Leo, come back, man.
Come back!
¡And then everybody was there!
¡Sergeant, Jerry and Al!
They were firing tracers,
like the fourth of July,
like a fountain of fire,
like a helo!
And then... then...
and then the chopter came,
and it lifted me out.
I saw it all.
I though I was asleep.
Later... later...
they told me that a bullet went
in my brain and made me crazy.
But that ain't so.
I saw it all.
I know what happened.
I so do you. Cause you were there.
- Take it easy...
- You told me you were there!
Take it easy now, soldier.
Take it slow.
Yes, sir.
Like a...
Like a fiery fountain
on the Fourth of July, you know?
Ok, Leo. Sit here.
It's not him.
Come on, I could've been in New Mexico
in fact by now.
Are you doin'
what I think you're doing?
Hi Officer... doing what?
Give me that.
Down here.
This man needs water!
- Hush up, spy!
- He's dying of thirst!
He'll die of more than that
if you don't hush up.
Soldier! At ease!
What seems to be
the problem here, corporal?
This'n there Captain, nobody but
a troublemaker and low down abolitionist.
Came in and stole folks niggers
right off the plantations.
They caught him without
a uniform behind our lines.
They's gonna hang him today.
He's wearing a uniform now.
And he will be treated with respect.
Give these men
water, and rations.
- But the colonel, he said...
- Now, soldier!
Yes, sir!
By whose orders, sir?
Captain Lucas Desiree.
- I've been here for an hour.
- Reflecting on your sins?
Right, give me out here!
Come on Ryan, I'll process you out.
Leo.
You are my lawyer?
You don't look
like no damn lawyer.
I'm a friend of the man
they say you murdered.
I have murdered nobody.
When I came upon him on the cabin
he was already hacked to pieces!
Like a broken toy soldier.
- Did you see anyone else?
- No.
Only the lightning.
The lightning of his terrible...!
Shut up!
Anything else?
The sword.
Looked like something
from "Gone with the Wind".
- I'm gonna get you out of here, Leo.
- You and what Army?
Just trust me.
You're a hoot, friend.
Last person said that to me
stole my shoes while I was asleep.
- Time before that...
- Hey, you!
- I'll be seeing you, Leo.
- I won't bet on that.
You are a reporter, right?
That "stolen car bull" was just
so you could talk to our prisoner.
No, I'm a friend of Lucas Desiree's.
Was anyone else in town
asking about him before his death?
I think we would have noticed.
Would have been hard not to.
Or maybe a stranger passing through.
Only stranger passing through
was the one we caught.
You caught him?
Nope. Sheriff Crowley.
Aha.
How?
What do you mean, how?
- He didn't just passed by Lucas' place?
- Never said he did.
Fact is, half a dozen folks
who live up in the Valley...
saw some kind of lightning or electrical
explosion or something about the same time.
- And that brought the Sheriff?
- Yeah.
Around these parts we don't get
too much lightning in a clear blue sky.
What do they think caused it?
Electrical Company
can't say for sure.
Some kind of surge
in a transformer, maybe.
Anyway, like you said that's
probably what brought the sheriff.
You weren't with him.
You are a reporter.
Why don't you just say so,
like everyone else?
- Somebody else was asking questions?
- Yes.
But she was a lot prettier than you.
SAVE THE LOGGERS.
SHOOT AN ENVIRONMENTALIST.
So you found out for sure
that old Leo isn't an Immortal.
What do you guys got, anyway?
A secret handshake?
- A tattoo.
- Really? Where?
We know how to handle
some psycho killer up here.
- How's that, Bob?
- Well, I'll tell you what we wouldn't do.
We wouldn't like some environmentalist
sensitive public defender...
get him off on an insanity plea
because he had too much sugar in his diet.
Could I get an orange juice
and a Coke, please?
- Yeah.
- Isn’t that right, friend?
You look like you would know.
You look like you've got
too much time on your hands.
You know what I bet
we got here...
I bet we got another bird watcher.
Another Spotted Owl lover
come up here to save the environment.
Put a lot of good men outta work.
Give it a rest.
I'll tell you something: You know, one of us
will be happy to hire out as a guide.
We'll take you right back into the forest
right to them damned spotted owls,
Won't be boys?
Yeah.
Somebody starts playing a banjo,
I'm outta here.
What's that?
It's a... nice hat.
My favorite team.
What do you want, tourist?
Just something to eat.
I'm sorry if the mill closed,
or the wells dried up,
or the grasshoppers ate your crop
or your life isn't what you hoped it to be.
But I'm a friend of Lucas Desiree's and
we're just here to find out how he died.
Now, don't you feel even
more stupid than usual, Bob?
What the hell are you lookin' at?
See you, Bob.
We're all real sorry about
what happened, honey.
Doesn't make a bit of sense.
Everybody liked him.
He kept to himself
and was polite to a fault.
You knew him?
Oh no, nobody really knew him.
He came in here for food and supplies.
He was a real gentleman.
Yes, he was.
Don't you ever get hungry?
Thanks. What's the special?
Nothing's ever special here.
Try the meat loaf.
No, I'll try number four.
And I would like the...
cheeseburger, but with processed cheese
and sweet pickles on the side.
Tomato, lettuce, onion,
ketchup, mustard...
Look, how many ways can I say "No Comment"
before I bore you, Ms. McFarland?
Look, no microphone, no hidden camera.
Just on background, sergeant.
Look, this is the early stage
of our investigation and we...
Aha! So you're investigating the
beheading in the city a while back.
I mean, why else would you come
clear up to the boonies?
Steepston isn't the boonies,
Ms. McFarland.
It's the sticks...
right before the boonies.
- Any leads on the suspect?
- No...
...comment, I know. And I understand and
I appreciate your need for discretion.
So, if everything I've just suggested is true
just say "no comment". I'll understand.
Look, I may be taking a suspect back
with me for a psychiatric evaluation.
Check back then,
I'll give you whatever I can.
You're on my Christmas list, Powell.
Isn't that nice?
...extra mayo and not that light stuff.
Only the real stuff. I you got only
the light stuff, forget about it.
And I would like that well-done with...
onions rings and French
fries on the side.
You know something? I'm gonna spurt,
actually. Make that a double.
Salad and cheeseburger.
- He'd just know that's what I want, right?
- Oh, yeah.
Did he have any friends
here in Steepston?
He got along with
the old sheriff real good.
Used to play chess every...
Friday night right over that table.
Really?
With Sheriff Crowley?
Oh no, old Nate Perkins.
He retired and moved
to Florida a few years back.
Since then, Lucas kept pretty much
to himself. Hardly ever saw him.
I guess Sheriff Crowley
wasn't much for chess.
Who knows. There's another one
who keeps to himself.
Get's along well enough with the
likes of LeMoyne, but he's a loner.
Well respected though.
Nobody messes with the sheriff.
Not even Lucas?
Lucas? I don't think I ever saw
the two of them together in the same room.
I got the feeling they wanted it that way.
I still don't understand why you changed
your mind. I though you wanted help.
I naturally assumed that
a big city force...
would do a better job
conducting an interrogation.
You fell for his "crazy Leo" act
like a catfish to a stinkbait.
Let's let a psychiatrist
decide that.
In my professional opinion,
Leo didn't behead anybody.
And our lab found no trace
of the victim's blood,
not even microscopic particles on
the sword you recovered from the cabin.
Maybe there was another weapon.
You said you showed up on
the scene moments later.
What'd Leo do
with the other sword, swallow it?
Now look, he is what
he says he is:
A guy who staggered into
the wrong place at the wrong time.
I'm afraid that won't wash with
the good people of Steepston County.
I've got a valid
psychiatric warrant for him.
You tell the good people of Steepston
it's out of your jurisdiction.
Not until you're over the County line.
You know what route to take, ah?
Look, I don't need his help.
He's gonna show you a back way
out of the county.
I don't need any trouble
on my watch.
- Okay, let's go.
- You're not taking your car?
Not, I think I'll ride with Leo.
See, I'm such a city fella, I might
just get lost on these back roads.
I'll send somebody back for my car.
You do that.
No bother at all.
Diner? Speak up.
Who?
Tommy Riley, it's for you.
- Who is it?
- I don't know.
He mumbled so bad
I couldn't understand him.
Hello?
- So, you ok?
- Yup, thanks.
Tommy, you intend
to pay for these?
Put it on my tab.
Yeah, yeah.
Put it on the tab.
By the way, they're taking the guy
they say killed your friend...
down south
for a psychiatric evaluation.
Sounds fair, Gwenn.
Yeah, if somebody
doesn't hang him first.
I'm Duncan MacLeod,
of the clan MacLeod.
Thanks.
Good thing they buried
you way out here.
Not too crowded.
If I hadn't happened by today, you could
have stayed under there for quite a spell.
Some would think this was
a good time to take my head, Lucas.
Some would, I expect.
It was hard hanging you,
even knowing what I knew.
- The others seemed to enjoy it.
- You stole their slaves.
You're destroying their way of life.
Revenge is all they have left.
You follow that road North
to your lines.
I just might follow it myself, one day.
You're on the wrong side,
you know that, Lucas.
Oh, we just get attached
to the people, don't we?
Lot of good folks down here.
Friends.
Loyalty is a real funny thing.
Probably causes
as much harm as does good.
Yes sir...
I think I'll up and follow
that road North one day.
I'll look forward to that.
Be dark soon.
You'd best be going now.
So, he says: shut up,
they're coming closer!
Easy boys.
- I don't believe we've met.
- I know who you are.
If you're here for the hunting,
the season's just opened.
He claims to be a friend
of Lucas Desiree, Sheriff.
- Is that a fact?
- That's a fact.
We heard that big city detective
is taking the bum back with him.
Wish I could tell you different, Bob.
City folks just don't see things
as clear as you and I.
Makes a man lose hope.
To an outsider it might seem like you want
these men to do something about it.
Do? Have I asked you
boys to do anything?
I'm just informing
the most concern citizens.
We do appreciate that, Sheriff.
We just might voice our concern.
That's very civic minded of you.
Let's go, boys.
Well, got to run.
I suppose I'll be
seeing you again.
Your friend Lucas died
on his knees begging for his life.
We'll see how you do.
- Looks like we missed them.
- What do we do now?
I though we were jamming.
Nobody's told them Leo is gone.
So they got a bad tip.
Is she your type?
- Definitely.
- Good.
- Can I help you with something?
- No, no, no.
Just thought you might be here
to interview that bum, Leo Atkins.
- Yes, so...
- I don't know...
He might not make it out
of Steepston County.
You got a police scanner, right?
- Let's go find 'em.
- Let's go.
What's this?
Looks like somebody broke down.
Hey, don't go out there.
Hey, around these parts
we like try and help out.
Struthers, get back in here!
That's enough!
We don't want to hurt you, officer. Just
give us the psycho and we'll be on our way.
That's not going to happen.
Get back in your trucks and go.
Now!
You're not in the big city
now, detective.
What're you gonna do,
call for backup?
Now, this is the last time
I'm gonna ask nice.
You did your job. Now give him up.
Come on, all we want is the guy.
We'll let you go.
Just give him to us, right?
Is this a breaking story,
or what?
- Roll tape, Frank.
- You looking to die, friend.
Put that camera down!
I said put it down!
Macleod.
Go ahead, shoot him.
Shoot her, shoot the boy,
the officer or me. That's
your idea of justice, isn't it?
Isn't it?
Go home!
All of you!
Crawl back under the rocks
you came from.
It's over!
Let's go, boys.
And take this disgrace
to the badge with you!
What in the hell
are you doing here?
I think some people want to talk to you.
...here with Sergeant Powell,
who has just stood off a mob...
of masked men intent on taking
the law into their own hands.
You've a statement,
Sergeant Powell?
Later.
Hey, hey. Hey. You owe me, Powell.
Or didn't you notice?
I suspect collusion
by the local authorities...
in the attempted abduction
of Leo Atkins.
They clearly made an attempt
to violate due process...
and the suspects civil rights.
I'll be asking the FBI to look into this.
Thank you, Sergeant Powell.
You really were there.
You were there.
Going home, Leo.
The other hero
of this amazing encounter...
is a mysterious man...
- Where the hell is he?
- I don't know.
You couldn't let him live in peace.
That's all he wanted.
Wasn't very ambitious, was he?
Why Leo?
People in a small town like to talk.
If they don't get a fix
on who did what,
they keep picking at it like a scab.
Eventually, they would
have figured it out.
People aren't as dumb
as we wish they were.
I was starting to like it here.
Now I'll have to move on.
But you're staying here.
I guess one of us is.
In the future...
I'll remember to leave
your friends in peace.
What future?
I guess I've got
all I need for now.
- You might get called as a witness.
- I'm sure.
Did they ever find that sheriff?
Disappeared
off the face of the Earth.
- The FBI will find him.
- What about Leo?
He's out in the car.
I'm taking him to the Bus station.
Excuse me,
I don't mean to bother you folks,
but I seen the sign out front,
I was wondering if you bought
old medals and such.
I'm a little short.
- That's yours?
- That's right.
I figure I can sell it if I want to.
Well, I don't think
I can buy it from you, Leo.
But I might be able to...
lend you something against it
until you come back this way.
Deal.
This antique business
is a going concern.
I should've got rid
of that long time ago.
Don't do not good
to hang on to the past.
More that one day
in a man's lifetime.
Well, I got a bus to catch.
I'll give you a ride to the Station.
- Take care, Leo
- Bye.
Bye, Leo.
Thank you.
You think they're going
to find the sheriff?
Eventually.
What about Lucas?
I took care of him.
SubXpacio, TusSeries & Proy_Babylon.