[ Man ] All right, men,
time to go wolfhuntin'
How's it look?
[ Both Chattering ]
- [ Fiddle ]
- [ Man Singing, Indistinct ]
This is the song
they sing
Hey, get along
Get along Josey
Jim along Joe
Hey, get along
Get along Josey
Jim along Joe
Watch your turns.
[ Continues ]
Ladies, bow.
Gents,you know how.
Do-si-do
and around you go.
Sure was nice of you
and your father to come
over tonight, Miss Webb.
Oh, it was nice of you
asking us.
We been intendin'to-- Ma has,
I mean-- to come visiting,
you bein'new folks here.
Well, we've been
wishing you would.
[ Skillet Scraping ]
[ Continues ]
Looks like the Kents
are merrymaking.
Let's see if we can't
help 'em celebrate.
[ Continues ]
[ Caller ]
Oh,yeah.!
- Stop the music.
- [ Music Stops ]
[ Wolf Howling ]
[ Growls ]
That's what
we've been told not to do.
Now put that back...
and get your mother
and the other women and children
down into the storm cellar.
- [ People Chattering ]
- Dad, what is it?
- Mr. Webb, would you go to
the barn and let the horses out?
- Certainly.
[ All Shouting,
indistinct ]
- Ma!
- [ All Talking At Once ]
[ Chattering ]
Be careful now.
Don't--
- [ Ma ] Be careful of those steps.
- What is it?
- it's a raid.
- But why?
- They hate us. We're Mormons.
Go on. Hurry now.
- Mormons?
Hey.! Here's one.!
- Come on out, Mormon.
- Get out here and find out...
what the state of illinois
thinks of you.
Come on, come on.
- [ Door Slams ]
- [ Footsteps ]
Cut me some firewood.
Has-Has anything
like this ever happened before?
Five years ago in Missouri.
Just because you people
are Mormons?
Just because
we're Mormons.
- [ Crying ]
- No.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Gunshots ]
i got one of their Mormon bibles.
Let's make 'em spit on it.
- Make him spit on it.
- Spit on it.
- Stuff it down his throat.
- Go on! Spit on it!
''Blessed be ye when men revile
you and say all manner of evil
things about you for my sake.''
Don't ''blessed'' us!
Come on
out of there!
- Ma, they set the house on fire.
- Oh!
Now hide in the fields
until they're gone. Hurry! Quick!
This is what you can expect
if you don't clear outta here.
Why are you doing this?
We only want to live
in peace with everyone.
[ Grunts ]
[ Ma ]
Oh!
Caleb!
Oh, Caleb.
Dad!
[ Crying ]
[ Screams ]
My father, Caleb Kent.
- How?
- Beaten to death.
[ Man ]
Jasper Palmer.
- How?
- Beaten.
Well, what are you gonna
do about it, stand back and pray...
while they drive us
out of another state?
The Lord works
in strange ways.
Sure, but that didn't
prevent him turning Samson loose...
on those Philistines
with the jawbone of an ass, did it?
What those fellas need
is a little lead in their bellies.
- if you say the word, i'll--
- Tear them limb from limb. i know.
- That's what they're itching for.
- Our people have had
enough trouble without that.
They can't stand much more,
Joseph. They can't stand to
pull up stakes and move again.
Let's settle this
the wise way then.
Give them the political
power they want. Vote
the way they say to vote.
[ Man ] Yeah.
Let them use that power to destroy us.
The authorities will protect us
if we do as they say.
i wouldn't trust them
any further than i can chuck a mule.
We can't take
any more chances, start all over.
We've got the biggest
city in illinois to protect.
Promise them anything they want,
only let's have peace.
What do you say, Hyrum?
A man has a right
to fight for his own life.
And you, Heber?
Seems like
we'll have to.
Otherwise they'll drive us clear
out of the United States.
All my life, i've asked only
one thing of my neighbors--
to be left alone in peace.
We've stuck to that in every
state we've been in.
- But i guess it won't work.
- What?
You may be right, Angus,
but perhaps it's time...
for us to show
a different kind of courage...
and do something besides
be killed for what we believe.
Tell the people
i said to arm themselves.
- That's treason.
- That if there's any more raiding...
we're going to fight back.
Tell them i'm going
to lead them myself.
if they haven't got guns,
get guns for them.
Tell them we're through
turning the other cheek.
Hallelujah!
What's the difference
between a white man
and a Mormon?
- Blamed if i know.
- About 50 wives.
[ All Laughing ]
[ Man ]
There he is...
the man that says
he talks to God.
A man so eaten
with pride and ambition...
that even the word ''treason''
holds no horror for him.
A prophet and saint
who walks up to God...
anytime he feels like it,
whispers in his ear...
and gets talked back to--
Joseph Smith.
Now, gentlemen,
you've heard the evidence.
Of all that,
I need say no more.
However...
i would hold myself
no better than a skunk...
if i did not
bring up a matter...
which is the very heart
and core of this case--
to wit,
the teachings ofJoseph Smith.
[ All Shouting, indistinct ]
Quiet down!
Quiet! Quiet!
Order!
Go ahead, Pete.
Joseph Smith,
a half-educated boy
just like you or me...
brought up
in a two-by-four town called Palmyra...
in New York state...
has the unmitigated nerve
to stand up and say...
God told him
to rewrite the Holy Bible...
because
it's full of errors--
errors, mind you--
and to go out and preach...
that all churches
are an abomination
in the sight of the Lord...
except this one...
that God told him
personally...
to go out and get
an army to run.
Give him a trumpet, and i bet
he'd say he's Gabriel hisself.
- [ Shouting, indistinct ]
- Oh, wait a minute!
Go on and sit down.
And remember,
this is a court of law and justice.
The self-respectin'
people of three states--
New York, Ohio and Missouri--
God bless 'em...
have already told Joseph Smith
to pack up and git.
But has that stopped him?
Oh, no!
He's come all the way
here to illinois to save us.
And what does he do?
He buys himself a swamp hole
for almost nothing...
and builds himself
a town called Nauvoo...
and sends his missionaries
all over the world to tell people...
God set our land aside
as their inheritance.
Before long, they'll own
every stick and stone in illinois...
fill every public office,
run every church and school...
unless we get rid of them!
Your Honor,
the prosecution rests.
[ All Cheering ]
Order in the court!
- [ Crowd Chattering ]
- Has the defense anything
further to offer?
Your Honor, if there's no objection,
i'd like to say something.
- [ Shouting, indistinct ]
- [ Bell Clanging ]
i say we all let him say
what he's got to say!
Let yourself go, Brigham.
Your Honor,
my name is Brigham Young.
- i'm not a lawyer, but--
- Never mind that. Go ahead, talk.
All right.
Go ahead.
Gentlemen, it looks to me like there's
been a little mistake made here.
The lawyer for the other side
has been so busy...
trying to pin every crime
on the calendar on Joseph Smith...
he clean forgot to mention
that us folks was the victims
of all those outrages...
he was talking about,
not the ones that were doing them.
Sure, we finally got around
trying to protect ourselves.
You push even a coyote up in a corner,
and he'll snap back at you.
That's the first time
I ever heard it called treason though.
in other words,
the whole point is...
whetherJoseph Smith or
any other American citizen...
has a right to worship God
as he chooses.
So that's why i figured
i'd like to tell you
a little bit aboutJoseph Smith.
Now, me,
I'm just an ordinary everyday fellow.
i used to farm a little,
do a little carpentry work...
painting-- anything
to make a living.
But all that time, i was trying
to find the right church...
for me and for my family, and i was
willing to give them all a try.
But somehow none of them
hit me just right.
i'm not saying, gentlemen,
there was anything wrong
with them for other people.
i'm just saying
they didn't suit me.
One day i picked up
The Book of Mormon...
and I said to my friend
Heber Kimball...
''Heber, let's go out to Ohio
and see this prophet.
Let's see what he's got
to say for himself.''
i remember it was about noon
we came up toJoseph Smith's house...
and his wife Emma
came to the door.
Excuse me, ma'am, is this
whereJoseph Smith lives?
- Yes.
- We'd like to talk to him, please.
You'll find him out yonder,
the other side of the lake,
chopping wood.
Thank you, ma'am.
That sounds kind of funny
for a prophet to be out swinging an ax.
- Don't seem just right.
- Prophet ought to act like a prophet.
Can't expect to build a church
if he acts like a farmhand.
Good morning.
How do you do, sir?
i'm Brigham Young.
- This is my friend Heber Kimball.
- i'm glad to meet you.
We've come
a long ways to see you.
We want to ask you some questions
about your church.
Gladly. i'd like to tell you about it.
Won't you sit down?
What's this about you folks
calling yourselves saints?
Well, we believe
that any man, dead or alive...
who keeps
the Ten Commandments is a saint.
You don't pretend to be
the Lord himself, do you?
No. i'm just a mortal man,
same as you or your friend here.
Well, this plan of yours
you call the United Order,
what's that?
it's not my plan.
it's the Lord's.
Well, whose ever it is,
what is it?
Well, i-- i suppose
you'd call it the law of nature.
You see, it's his idea
that the land of Zion will
be sort of like a beehive...
or like that anthill
over there...
with everybody doing
his share of the work...
and getting his part
of the profits.
Aplace where everybody
will have everything
he can eat and use.
There'll be great storehouses
to keep food and things in...
for the sick and the poor,
the old folks.
You see, under
a brotherhood plan like that...
it'll be impossible for any one man
to pile up a lot of goods...
or have power
over his neighbors.
That'll mean there'll be
no social distinctions...
no caste,
no special privileges.
any more than, i take it,
there is in that anthill over there.
We had it once, but somehow
we've all but lost it.
We've got to get back
to it again.
Well, that--
That sounds all right.
But then there'll
always be lazy people,
ambitious people.
There'll be some honest ones
and some dishonest ones.
What i'm telling you,
Brother Brigham, is
a revelation from the Lord.
it's up to us
to work it out.
This isn't an easy religion.
Well, i'm not looking
for an easy religion.
i'm looking for one
i can bring my family up decent in.
Joseph.
Dinner is ready.
Won't you stay
and have dinner with us?
[ Young ]
Well, thank you. We'd be glad to.
All right.
Come on.
Now, gentlemen,
i'm not asking you to believe...
a single thing
Joseph Smith said...
but i do ask you--
let him believe it.
Let me believe it
if we want to.
Your forefathers and mine
came to this country
in the first place...
for one great reason--
to escape persecution
for their beliefs...
and to build a free country
where everybody might
worship God as he pleased.
That's what brought
the Puritans to Massachusetts...
the Quakers
to Pennsylvania...
the Huguenots to South Carolina,
the Catholics to Maryland.
And when they found
what they were after...
they fought a great war
to hold on to it...
and they drew up one
of the noblest documents ever written--
the Constitution
of the United States--
to govern free men.
And the very first words
they put on that piece of paper...
guarantees to every man...
the right to worship God
as he pleases...
and prohibits Congress
or anybody else...
from ever doing anything
to take away that right.
You can't convict
Joseph Smith just because...
he happens to believe
something you don't believe.
You can't go against
everything your ancestors
fought and died for.
And if you do, your names--
notJoseph Smith's--
will go down in history
as traitors.
They'll stink
in the records...
and be a shameful thing
on the tongues of your children.
Thank you, sir.
The jury can go out now
and decide.
[ Whispering ]
[ Man, Shouting ]
Hey,Joe!
Give it to 'im!
- What are ya waitin' for?
- [ People Chattering ]
We don't have to go out,
Your Honor. He's guilty.
- [ All Cheering, Clamoring ]
- [ No Audible Dialogue ]
- [ Clamoring Continues ]
- [ Gavel Banging ]
[Judge ]
Order.! Order.!
- [ Banging Continues ]
- [ Clamoring Continues ]
Order!
Sheriff, take charge
of the prisoner.
- Have him here tomorrow morning
at 1 1 :00 for sentence.
- Yes, sir.
-Joseph, if you'll say the word--
- You'll do nothing of the sort.
- i'm going with you,Joseph.
- So am i.
Come on.
Joseph, i'm going too.
This is the end.
i want you to stay and
take care of my people.
Don't look so solemn,
Brigham.
Only the Lord God
of israel can whip us...
and i don't think
he's in cahoots with the sheriff.
[ Man ]
There he is.! Here comes HolyJoe.!
[ Crowd Laughing,Jeering ]
[ Man ]
How about a couple
of miracles,Joe?
[ Shouting,Jeering ]
[ Shouting,
indistinct ]
- [ Man ] There goes HolyJoe.!
- [ Man #2 ] String him up.!
[ Shouts,Jeers Continue ]
- [ Singing Hymn, indistinct ]
- [ Mob Shouting ]
- Shh.
- [ Stops Singing ]
[ Shouting, indistinct ]
They're coming.
Ask the Lord
to save you,Joseph.
[ Shouts Continue ]
The Lord God of israel
has spoken.
Verily i say unto you
that one will be raised up
to take my place...
endowed with courage,
farsightedness, common sense--
[ Glass Shatters ]
He will lead my people...
even as Moses led
the children of israel
across the wilderness.
[ Pounding ]
- [ Pounding Continues ]
- [ Shouting Continues ]
[ Pounding ]
[ Groans ]
O Lord, my God!
[ All Shouting, indistinct ]
[ Knocking On Door ]
We thought we'd
just come over and see
how you were getting along.
Won't you come in?
- i'm going away.
- Where to?
You see, i have an aunt
back in New York-- not really
my aunt, but just by marriage--
- and i wrote her and asked her--
- We came hopin' you'd
come over and stay with us.
Oh, thanks just the same,
but i-- i'm afraid i couldn't do that.
We'd sure like
to have you if you could.
We thought, seeing
you lost your father had
something to do with us--
- Oh, but i'm not a Mormon.
- That wouldn't make any difference.
But i--
i just don't understand.
it's been so terrible,
all this hating and killing.
- it won't always be like that, Zina.
- i couldn't stand it.
i've just got to get away.
[ Sobbing ]
Oh, well. Now, now.
You come over
and stay with us.
[ Crying ]
i don't know hardly what to do.
Well, now, you can stay
for a little while.
And then a little later, after
you're getting to feeling better...
then you can decide.
[ Crying ]
[ Rooster Crows ]
[ Hammering ]
i'm afraid you folks
are making a sad mistake...
fixin' to run off
and leave a fine farm like this...
when there's
no sense to it.
Brigham Young thinks there's
sense to it. Gettin' ready
to leave by spring.
What Brigham Young thinks
and what the Lord says
are two different things.
Brother Duncan has been picked
to takeJoseph's place as prophet.
- Duncan?
- He's had a revelation.
What does Brigham Young
say about your being
head of the church?
As i told you before,
what Brigham Young says
and what the Lord says...
are two different things.
Everyone knows thatJoseph
wanted me to take his place.
i was his chief counsel
long before Brigham Young
ever came along.
- i stood up for him.
- Like Brigham stood up
for him in court you mean?
He'd never have been in court
in the first place if he hadn't
listened to fool advice.
i warned him what would happen
raising an army
instead of compromising.
''Compromising''?
Listen.
i stood right here in this yard
and saw my father--
who'd never hurt anybody
in all his life-- beaten to death...
Zina's father shot down
in cold blood.
And you sit there
and talk about compromising.
I'd rather be shot down
than go crawling on my belly...
asking a lot of murderers
to let me alone.
And i don't believe that the Lord said
anything to you at all.
if he picked anyone to be head
of this church, it was Brigham Young.
And if Brigham tells me to stay here
and fight, that's what i'm gonna do.
And if he tells me to pack up
and go on somewhere else,
that's what i'm gonna do.
And there's nothing you or anybody
else can say that'll stop me.
Can't anything stop me any more
than it could stop my father...
from saying he believed
in Joseph Smith even if he
knew he'd be killed for it.
if you're in such a hurry
to talk about compromising...
you'd better get on your way
right now.
Come on, Ma.
Eliza, i've always thought
a lot of you and your husband...
so i won't hold this
against you.
Good day.
[ Hammering Metal ]
Young fella's got
quite a temper, ain't he?
Brigham Young put him up to it.
You mark my words.
Who's that girl there
with 'em?
i never saw her before.
Must be an outsider.
Jonathan!
Jonathan! Look!
They're headed
for Nauvoo.
You'd better get out
the back way.
Looks like
our runnin' days are over.
- Hallelujah.
- [ Knocking On Door ]
- Brigham Young?
- Yes, sir.
- Come right in.
- Thank you.
Young?
- How do you do, sir?
- How do you do?
i've come over here
to warn you.
You'd better
get your people out of here
just as fast as you can.
- Why?
- Because i've held off
those mobs as long as i'm able.
From now on,
i can't be responsible.
You mean you want us to leave
everything we fought all our lives for?
i mean, if you don't go
and go quick...
blood's going to run
like water in the streets...
and nothing i can do
will stop it.
We're not budging
one inch.
i am sorry
that's your answer...
but i'm afraid the law
can't help you much.
The law?
What law?
The law that lets
a pack of scoundrels come in here...
and hunt us down
like wild animals?
Burn our homes,
ruin our crops?
Arrest our leader
on trumped-up charges...
and then looks the other way
when a mob breaks in and murders him?
They call that law,
let 'em keep it.
We don't want
any more of it.
i appreciate this warning, Major,
but, no, this time...
we're going to stand up
for our rights if it kills us.
You tell that bunch of hoodlums
that i said...
if they come over here again,
we're going to fight...
clear down to our boots
and up to our necks in blood.
You mean that, don't you?
- Do you doubt it?
- No.
Then i guess that's all
we've got to say to each other.
- Good day, sir.
- Good day.
Funny thing that major
taking it for granted that
i was the head of the church.
Why didn't he go
to Angus Duncan?
He's been going around
from house to house...
telling everybody
he's been picked to run things.
Still, if i'm the head,
why doesn't the Lord tell me so?
One thing's certain-- somebody's
got to be head pretty soon...
or there won't be
any church left to be head of.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
You'd better put this
around you.
Brigham, they're over
at the council hall meeting--
Duncan and Crum
and the others.
They found out that
the raids are gonna start
all over again tonight.
Duncan says they're
not gonna listen to you anymore.
They're gonna make peace
with those people over in
Carthage any way they can.
Well, maybe he is head of the church.
Maybe it's up to him.
Brigham.
i stood here in Joseph's footprints.
i knelt where he did...
trying as hard as i know how
to get an answer...
but the Lord
won't talk to me.
He won't tell me what to do
one way or the other.
He didn't say you were
not to head the church, did he?
He didn't say anything.
Brigham,
when you asked me if i loved you...
i didn't
say anything either...
but that didn't mean
i didn't love you.
Sometimes silence is the best answer
you can give a person.
Mary Ann,Joseph told me
to run this church...
and i'm going to run it
the way it ought to be run
until the Lord says no.
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
[ Duncan ] We're headed for
the worst trouble we've
ever had this very night...
unless we act
and act quick.
[ Man ] Minute they heard what
Brigham said about fighting,
they started organizing.
[ Duncan ]
i wish i'd have been
there to hear him.
i'd have shut him up
quick enough.
He's acting as if
the Lord chose him to run this--
How else should i act?
i hear you've been making
some sort of a deal with
those rats over in Carthage.
Whatever it is, you're not
going through with it...
because i'm taking
the bull by the horns and
spitting in both his eyes.
- We're leaving here tonight.
- Tonight?
- We're crossing into iowa.
- You can't bluster
your way into power.
it might do you some good
to know that the Lord said--
- We cross the river
into iowa tonight.
- Was it a revelation?
Yes.
That's a lie.
Angus, i'd like awfully well
to see you live to a ripe old age.
Maybe you will
if you hold your tongue.
- But the river is frozen over.
- How else could we all
cross it in one night?
- But it's fixin' to storm.
- They'll never expect us to start.
- We couldn't get our things.
- The lighter we travel,
the better time we make.
Don't listen to him.
We can't run off now
and leave everything.
- i've got my granary to think about.
- And my store.
Every cent i've got
in the world is right here.
Maybe we're getting
too interested in granaries
and stores and things.
Remember how when Joseph
started out, he had an idea
about nobody getting rich...
but everybody
sharing alike?
Somehow his idea
seems to have got sidetracked.
- i figure it's time we got back to it.
- But i've worked hard.
- i've saved and scrimped.
- if a little money means more
to you than this church...
you'd better stay here.
Heber, put some fellas on horses.
Tell them to spread the word.
Tell everybody to come
just as they are.
We've got to put the river
between us and Nauvoo by morning...
or there won't be enough
of us left to worry about.
[ Duncan ]
No, no. Wait a minute.
Don't pay any attention to him.
You're making a mistake.
Think of your homes.
You'll just be run out of
this state like we've been
run out of every other state.
Listen to me.
You're making a mistake.
[ Door Slams ]
Here he is.
They won't compromise.
They won't do anything.
They're leaving.
- Leavin'?
- Where are they going?
- They're crossing the river
into iowa tonight.
- You're lyin'.
it's the truth. Brigham Young's
making them leave.
- And good riddance.
- Now you won't have to raid.
You better get over there
and see that they don't
change their minds.
- We'll fix it so that
they'll never come back.
- You won't hurt my property.
- i did my best. i played fair.
- You're no better
than any other Mormon.
Look, there's plenty else.
What about that promise?
You're not gonna
destroy my granary.
it's full of Mormon wheat,
ain't it?
- [ Pulley Squeaking ]
- [ Man ] Take it easy.
Let 'er go.
Come on.!
[ Man ]
Get on.! Hyah.!
All right, Mary Ann.
i'll meet you
down at the river.
Lord, Brigham's
a great and good man.
i'm his wife, and i know.
i've known him
longer than anybody
but you and Heber Kimball.
Only sometimes
he's so sure of himself.
Sometimes he's bullheaded
and thinks nobody else
knows a thing but him.
But he's only trying
to do what's right.
So won't you
look after him...
maybe speak to him?
Because this is an awful thing
he's asking us to do.
And right now,
in his heart...
he's not half as sure of himself
as he makes out to be.
Everybody meet
on the other side of the river.
Get together on the other
side of the river. Everybody.
[ Men Whistling,
Shouting ]
Jonathan. Meet at Sugar Creek
on the other side of the river.
Right.
[ Man ]
Giddap there.!
Giddap.! Hah.!
Ho.!
All right, go ahead.
Keep moving.
Supposin' the ice
breaks through?
i'll get my horse.
Let me try.
[ Bleating ]
Ho! Hie!
[ Gunshots ]
Hyah!
[ Gunshots Continue ]
Come on!
Get those wagons across the ice!
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Man ] Get your children
in the wagons.!
- Eliza!
- Henry! Henry!
[ Gunshots Continue ]
Come on! Hurry up!
Watch where you're going.
Keep driving.
Get those wagons
across the ice!
Well, if you ask me,
it looks like the end
of the Mormon Church.
Come on.
Mary Ann, look.
Looks like we've burned
our bridges behind us.
Couldn't turn back now
even if we wanted to.
- Get your tuba.
- Tuba?
And get hold of the rest of the band.
Tell them i said to start playing.
Yes, sir.
- Where are we going?
- Well, wherever it is,
we'll get there.
[ Band Plays Hymn ]
[ Continues ]
[ Muttering,
indistinct ]
Don't take it so hard,
Porter.
We'll build another city
someday.
Who gives a hoot about a city?
My gun jammed.
i didn't get to kill
even one of them.
[ Rifle Clatters
On Ground ]
[ Cattle Lowing ]
Brigham, there ain't no sense
tryin' to hide the truth.
Folks are as mad as wet hens,
cussin' you all over the camp...
claimin' you're to blame
for gettin' them in all this misery.
Everywhere you turn,
they're gettin' ready to pull out.
- Where to?
- Well, anywhere but here.
They don't seem to know,
but they say they're awful fools...
pullin' up stakes and leavin'
everything they got...
to come out here and squat
in the mud and slop till they freeze.
- That's enough, Mary Ann.
- it's high time somebody did
some thinkin' around here.
Why, there ain't 50 families
in camp ain't got somebody
sick or hurt or already dead.
it's true, Brigham.
i've been out all mornin'...
and it pret' near breaks your heart
just to look at 'em.
And they've got to know
what you're gonna do about it.
Mary Ann, you and Clara
get Emmaline and Lucy
and some of the others...
and help you take this stuff
around to those that need it
just as soon as you can.
Well, what are you
gonna do about it?
Well, i've got an idea,
but they're gonna need...
some of this hot composition
in their bellies before they
hear about it.
[ Exhales Loudly ]
What in tarnation's that?
it's one of Brigham's
remedies to put down colds and ague...
and fever and rheumatism
and such.
What's in it
besides fire?
Hot water and cinnamon bark
and ginger root...
and cayenne pepper
and anything else that's hot.
Throw the stuff out. Ain't folks
sufferin' enough without
burnin' their insides out?
- Feel better?
- i'm all right, thanks.
- [ Baby Crying ]
- You better give her to me.
- it's past her feeding time.
- Oh, but you're not strong enough to.
She's hungry.
[ Fire Crackling ]
- How's Ma?
- She's feeding the baby now.
Hmm. Doc Richards
said he'd be over in a minute.
Plenty more hurt.
i wish he'd hurry up
and come.
Zina, there's a family fixin'
to pull out today...
and i've arranged
that you can go with them.
No, i'm not going. i couldn't
leave your mother and the children...
what with her hurt
and everything.
- But we got no call on you.
- No, i-- i'll stay.
That's nice of you,
Zina.
Ma will appreciate that.
- How's your mother?
- You know Ma.
She doesn't complain.
She's a fine woman.
- New convert?
- No, sir. i'm not a Mormon.
- What are you doing here?
- Her father was killed
the night they raided our place...
and she's been
staying with us ever since.
Well, i guess we can
feed one more mouth.
Thank you, but that doesn't mean
i'm going to be a Mormon.
- You don't seem to like Mormons.
- No, it isn't that.
But, well, it's just
that i'm a Christian.
- So am i.
- Well, i mean, i've got
my own religion.
i wouldn't change that
for anything or anybody.
And besides--
- ''Besides'' what?
- Well, there must be something
wrong when there's so much hate...
people being tortured,
killed...
everything they've got in the world
taken away from them.
A lot of folks seem to think it
worth going through all that for.
[ All Chattering ]
You folks have been doing
a lot of worrying...
and wanting to know
what we're going to do next.
Well, in the first place,
we're gonna start acting like
we've got some common sense.
We're gonna build
some strong new wagons,
gather in all the food we can...
get enough guns and ammunition,
warm clothes and whatever else
we need...
and then we're gonna
get out of here.
And we're gonna keep going
until we're clear out of
the United States...
across the Rocky Mountains
into Mexico.
- Hallelujah.
- Mexico? Across the Rocky Mountains?
When it's got to the place
a man can't stay in the United States...
and believe what he wants to,
then he's got to get out.
- [ Man ] That's 1,500 miles.
Take us four years to get there.
- [ Young ]Just about.
it took Moses 40 years
to get where he was going.
- [ Man ]
But 1,500 miles.! We'd starve.!
- [ All Chattering ]
Doggone you, Brigham Young.
We've stood for all your
foolishness we're aimin' to.
i'm through, through with
the whole dang setup.
i'm quittin'. You understand?
Quittin' you and the church.
i'm goin' someplace
where me and my family can live.
[ All Chattering ]
i know. i know it's not
an easy thing i'm asking you to do.
But we can do it
if we've got faith enough.
There's good stock
here, Lord.
They're about as fine
a bunch of men and women as ever lived.
All they need
is a little bucking up...
and a kick in the right direction so's--
so's they'll know their own strength.
And then you'll see how soon
they'll stop all this infernal whining...
and all this talk about running off,
quitting the church.
First thing you know,
they'll be letting their beards grow.
They'll be getting dirt
under their fingernails...
and calluses on their hands
as big as hoecakes.
And they'll be ready to whip
the tar out of the first fellow...
that says
we'll never make it.
if there's anybody here
doubts that, they'd better
haul tail right now...
because we don't want 'em.
We'll build our wagons,
and we'll scratch for our food.
We'll shiver, and we'll
go hungry if we have to.
And maybe some of us
will keel over and die in our tracks...
but that won't
stop us neither.
Because the rest of us
will keep going,
and we'll never stop.
Never, not until
we've found the place.
[ Young's Voice ]
Well, Lord, we're on our way.
Just as far as the eye can see,
they keep comin'
I doubt if there's been
anything to equal this...
since the children of Israel
set out across the Red Sea...
and you--
you had to open up the waters
to let 'em through.
And talk about miracles.
Just take a look at the way
some of these wagons
have hung together.
Of course, it took
plenty of scurrying around
to get together what we did.
But I knew that as soon
as we stopped arguin'..
and grumblin'about
what had to be done...
and started findin'ways
to do it, that we'd manage all right.
Some of our folks aren't really
in shape to travel.
Some, like Eliza,
with bullet holes in 'em.
Everybody,young or old,
has his or her work cut out.
The women are busy
sewing, mending, weaving...
or taking care of the babies,
doing the cooking.
And the men
who don't have to drive
or look after the livestock...
are turning out new shoes
and seeing that
our harnesses hold out.
And we don't aim to let
our children get far behind
in their lessons either.
Classes are being held
every foot of the way
so's it'll never be said...
that a Mormon
can't read and write
with the best of them.
[ Woman ]
Seventy-two--
Yes, sir, we're on our way.
Load your wagons
and get ready to start.
There's only about
five feet of water.
[ Man ]
Ho there.!
it's all right,Jonathan.
We can make it.
it's only about five feet deep.
Take care of him.
Come on!
[ Cattle Lowing ]
- Can you swim?
- No.
- You will.
- [ Screaming ]
[ Woman Screams ]
[ Screams ]
Whoa, boy!
[Jonathan ] All right.
Now straighten it out.
- There. All right.
- We should've built
arks instead of wagons.
if we had, we could've floated
clear to the Rocky Mountains.
Has this wagon
grown roots?
Angus, i didn't know
you were here.
- Yep. in the mud with the rest of us.
- it's my church too, Brigham.
Sure it is.
if we all push together,
we'll get someplace.
- All right. All together.
- All together.
Heave! Heave!
[ Young ]
Lord, the way these sisters
swing an ax is a caution.
They go at it as if they had
the devil himself on the ground...
fixin'to lop offhis tail.
In the meanwhile,
we keepjogging along...
putting plenty
of good Iowa mud between us...
and those scoundrels
back in Carthage.
It's rough country
we're going through...
and it's just as hard
on the wagons as it is
on them inside.
Zina, come here.
What do you want?
i want her to drive, Ma.
i want to find Brigham.
Tell him we're gonna
drop out for a little while.
We can catch up later.
- All this jolting--
- You keep going.
if you let one stop, then somebody else
will want to stop too.
Then a third and a fourth,
and, before you know it...
the whole shootin' match
will be fallin' out.
i don't want it said
that we were the first to give up.
Not for anything.
Understand?
Zina, you go and sit
with Jonathan.
it ain't right
you cooped up in here...
and all that springtime
outside.
Go on now, dear.
[ Young ]
We've been seeing Indians, Lord,
for several days now.
Sometimes there's just one.
Sometimes
there's two or three.
Sometimes a whole tribe
just lookin'
Porter Rockwell says that...
their main village
is up ahead at Council Bluffs...
and there must be a couple
of thousand around here
and with more comin'
Kind of gives you
a creepy feelin'..
knowing they've got
their eyes on you.
Some of our folks are getting
downright uneasy...
but I tell them,
''Indians can't be any worse...
than some Christians
I know. ''
Till we find out
a little bit more about them...
we mean to trust
in you, Lord...
and to keep
our powder dry.
Zigzagging. That means
he wants to talk in peace.
You zigzag out
to meet him.
My name's
Brigham Young.
We folks have been run
out of our homes...
and some of us
are pretty tired and sick.
We'd like to stop
in Council Bluffs for a while.
My people knows
of your coming.
We know why you are here.
As Superintendent of indians,
my advice is to say no.
Not many years ago,
we were driven out of our homes.
You are welcome here.
Chief, those are the first words
of real welcome...
we've heard
in 1 6 years.
And don't think
we're going to forget them.
You can count on us
for anything you want.
[ Young ]
We're welcome here!
We can stay here
as long as we want to.
Unhook your oxen,
turn them out to graze.
Clara. Mary.
We're welcome here.
We can stay as long as we want to.
Oh, i'm so glad,
Brigham.
Tell everybody to unhook
their oxen and horses.
They can hunt too.
This country is running
over with wild game.
Look, Brigham,
good, rich earth.
Sure.
Anything would grow here.
i think i'll let the main body
stay here and raise a crop.
The rest of us will push on
and find someplace to settle in.
They can follow us later
and bring whatever they've raised.
Tell the people the band's
going to play tonight.
Tell them we're going
to sing and dance like we used to.
First you tell us
we can rest.
Now you say
we have to dance.
i bet i've lost a foot of belly
since we started out.
- it's good for the figure.
- it looks good.
i'm going to take a bath,
even if i muddy up
the whole dang river.
You'd better go now,
because this afternoon
you're going to be awful busy.
- Buryin'.
- Buryin'?
There's quite a few...
counting the old folks,
babies.
- Eliza Kent went this morning.
- Eliza?
Jonathan.
Why didn't you tell me
about Eliza?
She didn't want me to.
None of them did.
She told me
to tell you, Brigham...
that even though
we might be the last wagon...
we'd never be
the first to fall out.
i just couldn't go away
without leaving her
some kind of marker.
You know,
Ma used to say...
that a good wheel
always sings.
Ma would've loved
those flowers.
i never saw a body
so crazy about 'em.
Dandelion, ragweed,
any of'em.
Sonny,
will you hold him?
- Hi.
- Howdy.
- Mind if i get a drink?
- Nope.
You one of them
Mormon fellas?
- Yes, we're Mormons.
- i heard you was coming.
Leaving off the ''mister,''
my name is Jim Bridger.
- What might yours be?
- Leaving off the ''mister,''
Brigham Young.
- Say, how many--
- Twelve.!
Hmm. How about a chaw
to oil your tongue with?
No, thanks.
i never use it.
How come?
What's the matter with you?
- You see this?
- Mm-hmm.
i've been carrying that
now for 1 5 years.
Whenever i feel myself tempted,
i hold it up and say...
''Am i stronger than this tobacco or is
this tobacco stronger than me?''
And I put it back
in my pocket.
i'll be doggoned.
[ Children Shouting ]
- Little more?
- No, thanks.
You?
Yes, sir.
it's all over California, i tell you.
And some of them nuggets
are as big as the hub on a cart wheel.
Sounds like
tomfoolery to me.
My brother ain't the tomfoolin' kind.
He wrote me all about it.
All you got to do
is yank up a pea vine...
scrape the ground
with your finger and there it is.
Gold-- any way you turn,
pretty and yellow...
- ready to buy anything you want.
- Don't go blabbing it around.
We don't want people
talking about how rich she is...
leastwise until
we get California
into the United States...
now that we've been dragged
into this war with Mexico.
[ Chuckles ]
Don't worry about us
talkin'.
See that you don't talk
to our people about it
and get them upset.
We're not searchin'
for gold.
We're searchin'
for a place to live.
You don't have to worry
about us either.
Well, thanks.
Good-bye.
- Bye.
What's the matter
with you?
Have you gone
out of your mind?
i don't think so.
i had to hush
those fellas up.
i've just had
a revelation.
There's gold
in California.
Well, this is a revelation,
and i think the church...
is about to find
a new leader.
As captains, each of you
are in charge of 1 00 people.
it's up to me and you to see
that the Lord's will be done.
if there's all that gold
out in California...
it seems strange and peculiar
nobody's heard about it before.
The Lord chose
when he wanted it known...
and who he wanted
to know it.
Now you brothers get busy.
Each of you know who you
can trust in your own companies.
What's Brigham Young gonna say
when he finds out about this?
The Lord will handle
that too.
Zina.
- Zina, are you asleep?
- Uh-uh. Aren't you?
No.
if you were asleep...
i bet i could tell you what
you'd be dreaming about.
- What?
- All that gold in California.
[ Sighs ]
Just imagine, Zina.
Chunks of it
as big as oranges.
Wish i had an orange
right now.
i'd cut a hole in the stem
for the baby to suck.
About the best thing
there is for colic.
Gold.
You know, next to the Lord
and maybe the land...
i reckon it's about
the most powerful thing there is.
Hmm.
What would you do
with all that gold?
Oh, about
a million things.
i'd get a new saddle.
And i figure that the wagon
needs a new doubletree.
Baby ought to have
a cradle to rock in.
And you--
i'd get you
a new dress and a hat.
Lots of boats come into California
from China and everyplace...
full of silk and things.
i'd get you a parasol
and shoes to match...
pretty finger ring--
lots of things, Zina.
All you got for yourself
was a saddle.
Well, maybe i'll get me
a horse to go under it.
Jonathan, suppose
Brigham Young doesn't want
to go to California.
He couldn't help it.
it's--
it's just like
the promised land.
Zina?
You know what i've been
thinking about?
Sounds funny, but...
i've been lying here
thinking about the time...
before i got
into long pants.
All the talking
i used to do about...
what i was gonna do
as soon as i got
into grown-up britches.
Now, I don't know, I--
I don't even care anymore.
Reckon the only thing
i care about is...
having somebody like me...
likin' them and...
just always
bein' with 'em.
Zina.
Zina, seein' as you're so crazy
about the children...
and they're
so crazy about you--
Well,
i was just wondering if--
Course, i mean,
after we get settled...
and i get a crop goin'
and some of that gold
i was talkin' about.
Well, i was sort of hopin' that
maybe you and me could, uh...
[ inhales, Exhales
Slowly ]
get married.
Hmm?
i told you to let me
cook that stew.
- Sure was good stew though.
- Henry, shut up and go back to sleep.
- [ Crowd Clamoring ]
- [ Shouting ]
Ladies and gentlemen!
For the championship of Fort Bridger,
a frog-jumping contest...
between
the defending champion...
- Jim Bridger...
- [ Cheers, Applause ]
and the challenger...
- Porter Rockwell.!
- [ Cheers, Applause ]
- i'll bet you Porter wins.
- Bet what?
Oh, that new silk dress
i'm gonna get against
the horse you're gonna get.
Sounds like a fair bet.
[ Man Stuttering ]
G-G-Get set.!
T-T-T-Tickle 'em.!
[ Onlookers Shouting ]
Come on, Bridger!
Looks like you're not gonna get
that dress you haven't got yet.
[ Shouting, Cheering
Continue ]
Dang saints, listen to 'em.
Gambling.
- They're only tryin'
to have a little fun.
- Fun?
There's whiskey
bein' drunk.
Porter Rockwell
is chewing tobacco again.
- Since when did he ever stop?
- i'm not going to put up with it.
- i'll not have the devil
flipping his tail in my face.
- Brigham.
Why do you lie to yourself?
You're worried about
all this talk of gold...
and going to California.
Day and night,
that fella Duncan has been at 'em...
with his talk
about gold.
That all you do is stick a seed
in the ground, and it pops up
before you can turn around.
You're dead set against
California, aren't you?
You know human nature.
Take a crowd of people
to a place of milk and honey...
and in six months' time,
they won't be worth shooting.
Our only chance
is to find someplace...
that nobody else
has even put foot on.
Sometimes i think
i'm being punished...
for saying
the Lord told me to take charge.
i don't think so.
Not after what you've done
to hold us together.
[ People Chattering ]
if i only knew for sure
where we're heading.
You set out to find a place
across the Rocky Mountains...
where we could live in peace
according toJoseph's plan.
That's what the people
trusted you to do.
i wouldn't
disappoint 'em.
Mary Ann, you're as fine a wife
as a man ever had.
Sometimes, i don't know
what i'd do without you.
Always the same,
never complaining.
You're never jealous
of the others.
No, Brigham.
Sometimes, i think the Lord
has been almost too good to me...
just letting me take care
of a fine man like you.
That's funny.
When folks have been together
as long as we have, it's--
it's kind of hard to say
what's in your heart...
about lovin' a person.
i know.
Remember
when i was courtin' you...
how we used to sit out just
like this on moon-bright nights?
[ Chuckles ]
Mm-hmm. i remember.
Suppose you had to do it
all over again?
Would you still have me...
knowing all
you do about me...
and all that you've
had to go through?
Yes, Brigham.
i'd do it exactly the same.
[ Young ]
Well, Lord, here we are again.
All I keep hearing
is talk of gold in California.
So far I haven't said anything,
that is, the way I feel about it...
figuring that as long
as we're heading west,
they'll be satisfied.
I can't
keep that up forever.
I'm not feeling
very well myself.
I don't seem to be able
to eat or sleep.
And then I'm all cold inside,
kind of shaky.
I must have got hold
of some bad water back yonder.
Maybe it's a touch
of mountain fever...
from eating that
rabbit stew the other night.
You've got to help me
find the right place, Lord...
and find it quick.
Because I can't go on
like this much longer.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
i tell you, Mary Ann,
if we lose him, we're done for.
Well, they're leavin'.
They're goin' to California.
- Leavin'?
- it's that white-livered skunk Duncan.
- Didn't you talk to him?
- Talk to him? Sure.
That doesn't do any good.
- They can't leave him like this.
- That Duncan's so shrewd...
he's got people thinking everything
he's doin'is to help Brigham.
Go hitch up the horses
and help me get him into the wagon.
- You're not takin' him?
- i am.
He's not able to move.
He'd never forgive me
or you either if we let
the people go on without him.
- Woman, he'll die.
- He can't stand it.
i know the risk
i'm takin'.
But if Brigham has to die,
it'll be with his people.
You'd want it that way,
wouldn't you, Clara?
it'll kill him.
i'll hitch up the horses.
You get him ready.
Come on.
- Where are we?
- High up in the mountains, Brigham.
What's that strange noise
i keep hearing?
it's an echo. The wagons
sound like a lot of hammers goin'.
Porter set to whistlin' a while
back. You'd have thought it was
a dozen flutes playin'.
Look out and tell me
what you see.
There's nothing
but mountains.
Over yonder's one
a mile high.
No, not there.
Look south.
The mountains
suddenly fall away?
- Over here they do.
- You can see, maybe...
a hundred miles
straight off.
Yes, i can.
Pull up.
This is the place.
We'll build our homes
down there.
it was a revelation.
He knew it
before we even got here.
it was a revelation.
- [ Whispering ]
- it was a revelation.
i thought we were going
to California.
So did i.
You said that Brigham Young
himself would want to go.
Well,
i thought he would.
This isn't the place.
This isn't the place!
Look at it.
it's nothing but a lot of desert!
Just a lot of sand and rock!
We'll shrivel up
and die like rats.
We're going to California,
do you understand?
- We're going to set up our own church.
- Are you?
Yes, we are.
We let you drag us away from Nauvoo.
We left every cent,
everything we owned in the world.
We've watched you mark every
foot of the way up here...
with the bodies
of our women and babies,
and we haven't said a word.
But when it comes to stopping
and settling in a place like that--
the most desolate country
we've seen yet--
with California just up ahead waiting
for us, it's time to call a halt.
He says God told him
this is the place.
But i say it was
the devil talking.
And as far as i'm concerned,
the devil can keep it!
- We're going on!
- All right, Angus.
That's the way
to California.
i'm not
going to stop you.
i wouldn't lift
my little finger to hold you...
or anybody else
that feels the same way.
Moses went up in the hills
like this once...
and right away the devil
started putting in his licks.
Remember how he got the people
to build a golden calf
and to start worshipping it?
You remember how mad
God and Moses got...
and how close God came
to washing his hands
of the whole business?
i don't claim
to be a Moses...
but i say to you just what
he said to the sons of Levi:
''Who is on the Lord's side,
let him come unto me.''
Well, you can have
your desert. i'm going
to California.
[ Angus ] Come on.
You said you were comin', didn't you?
You're goin',
aren't you?
Well, are you comin'
or not?
Think of your family
and your children.
What's the matter with you?
You're not gonna build your home
down in that desert, are you?
You'll all starve to death.
Come on. Get up and get goin'.
You said you were comin' with me.
Think of your family!
Our hearts...
are mighty humble
and mighty thankful.
Lord, we'll make
this desert blossom.
There'll be hamlets
and cities...
vineyards and orchards...
with every kind
of tree there is.
There'll be no filth
in our cities.
There'll be no ugliness
of any sort but...
broad, clean streets
with flowing water.
And the law of the valley
shall be that...
no man may buy or sell land...
for all land
will be held in common.
It'll be measured off
to him, both in the city
and for farming.
And any man may have
as much as he can till...
but he's got to take care
of all he gets.
All wood and timber will
belong to the community, too...
as well as ditches
and canals.
Any person caught
trying to take greedy advantage
of these materials...
will be run
out of the valley.
Now, as to the city itself...
it shall be built in
blocks of ten acres each...
with streets
eight rods wide...
and with gardens and lawns
on both sides.
Right in the middle,
I'm setting aside ten acres
for the temple...
which we'll start building
the day we get our first crop
in the ground.
We're going to establish
Joseph's idea of the United Order...
and build
a mighty empire here...
based on labor and love
and fellowship.
And this time,
doggone it...
I mean to see
that we stick to it.
[ Brass Band ]
- [ Continues ]
- Zina. Come on. We have to hurry!
[ Continues ]
- [ Ends ]
- it's a nice sight
to see you people...
come up here to put your food
in a common storehouse...
to be rationed out
to everybody alike
during the coming winter.
Joseph Smith
would be proud of you.
it's not just a tithe
we're giving this time...
although that's the law
of the church...
but everything we've got.
if one eats,
we'll all eat.
And if one starves,
we'll all starve.
Now, we're gonna have
our hands full to make this food
last until spring.
So don't waste anything.
Eat regular...
but don't let me
catch any of you people
putting on weight.
Now it's up to us men
to fish and hunt and lay in stores.
And you boys get out
and see how many rabbits
you can lay your hands on.
But don't eat 'em.
Pen 'em up and give 'em
time to multiply...
- like good saints.
- [ Chuckles ]
All right, you fellas in the band,
let's hear... ''Come, Come Ye Saints,''
while everybody takes their food
over to the storehouse.
And play it good and loud,
especially loud.
Leah.
Well, all right, dear. Martha.
John. Harriet.
[ Continues ]
Oh,Jonathan. i'd like for you to go
with Porter back to Council Bluffs.
Tell the people there
to harvest their crops...
but that they must stay there
through the winter.
Then they can join us in the spring
and bring whatever food's left.
Well, i--
i'll look after them.
- Will you do it?
- Why, yes, sir.
- When can you start?
- i'll be ready to leave
by tomorrow morning.
Thank you,Jonathan.
- That all right with you, Porter?
- Fine. See you in the morning.
Good.
How long
are you gonna be gone?
Four or five months,
i guess.
He has no right
to ask you to go.
You've got a family
to look after.
Besides, there are plenty of others
who can go in your place.
You know how it is here.
Everybody has his job to do.
- This is mine, and i've got to do it.
- Brigham-- Brigham Young.
Don't you care what
anybody else thinks or feels?
- He's head of the church.
- Even if he is, he isn't God.
- He can't run everything.
- He'll look after you
and the children.
i can look after the children,
and i'm not worrying about me.
it's just that--
Oh.
i'm sorry that you
had to go and get mad.
- i'm not mad.
- 'Cause if you hadn't been mad...
i had it in my mind
to tell you about something.
i'm not mad!
Well, if you'd been
in smilin' good humor,
i meant to talk about it.
- Talk about what?
- What i was gonna talk about...
if you hadn't got mad.
Maybe you had
a revelation.
Well, you might
call it that.
We ought
to get married right away.
- Right away?
- Well, in the spring...
soon as i get back.
Well, i don't see any sense
in puttin' it off any longer than that.
Oh, but your Brigham Young'll
want you to marry a Mormon girl,
won't he?
- Several of them.
- Several?
if you're gonna be rich,
you'll have to have
a lot of wives, won't you?
i've been wonderin' how you're
gonna go about askin' 'em--
one at a time or all together.
Maybe it would be easier if you said,
''Sisters, will you kindly marry me?''
- Zina!
- Then after you've married
20 or 30 of them...
suppose you get to lovin'
one more than
all the rest put together?
Then there's poorJonathan,
loving one and divided by 30.
Now, Zina, you're
just talking nonsense.
There they'll be, all darning
the same socks and cooking
for the same man...
and all talking about
their husband.
Just imagine, 30 wives
combing your beard!
You haven't answered
my question yet
about our being married.
Oh, well, it--
it isn't spring yet.
Well, figure it out
for yourself.
Say every man's
got 20 wives.
- There aren't that many women.
- Oh, we can get 'em.
Women convert easy. And say
every wife's got ten children.
That's 200 children apiece.
And say every one
of those 200's got 20 wives.
That's 4,000. And say
they got ten children apiece.
So that'll give you
40,000 grandchildren.
Figurin' 5,000 men to start with.
Well, that's 200 million.
Quite a settlement.
if arithmetic'll do you any good,
i'm willin' to call you grandpa now.
Oh, i'm aimin'
to do my share.
[ Young ] I don't remember,
Lord, ever seein'a winter
to equal this one.
Started out mild enough,
but now it's hit for sure.
It's just one blizzard
after another.
Snow is so deep that game
has run clean out of the hills.
[ Lowing ]
And even what little cattle
we had left are lost...
or they're frozen to death
where we can't get at 'em.
I've had to cut rations
three times already...
till there's hardly enough
to keep body and soul together.
The babies look mighty hungry
and peaked to me.
The women and the old folks
arejust hangin'on...
livin'on roots or whatever
they could lay their hands to.
Well,just the same,
we're gonna hold out till spring...
when the winter wheat
and the new corn come through.
I don't know how
we're gonna do it...
but we're going to,
Lord, somehow.
[ Crying ]
Mary.
Mary, dear.
- Would you like to play
a game with me?
- What kind of a game?
Well, it hasn't any name,
but here's the way you play it.
Now first,
open up your apron.
Why, that's it.
Now, see the sun in it?
- Yes.
- All right. Now fold your apron back.
Quickly.
Catch the sun.
That's right.
Got it?
All right.
Now bring it over here
to me and the baby.
Careful.
Don't drop it.
All right.
Now open your apron and let's see it.
Oh, it's gone. You've lost it.
You had it just a minute ago.
i saw you catch it.
Look. There it is.
it's still over there on the floor.
Hurry up.
Get it.
Zina, i--
i don't feel like playing.
i-- i'm hungry.
[ Weeping ]
Oh, don't, darling.
Don't.
- [ Sniffling, Sobbing ]
- Now, don't cry, sweetie.
[ Mary Crying ]
Jonathan!
Jonathan,
i'm hungry.
Hungry?
- Zina, what happened?
- [ Sobbing ]
[ Crying ]
Tablespoon
every hour.
Now there's no use playing possum
any longer, Miss Zina.
Anybody as pretty as you are
can't be very sick.
That girl in there, there's no telling
how long it's been...
since she's had
anything to eat.
- She probably gave everything
to the children.
- Yes.
And she isn't the only one
who's done that.
- She'll be all right, though,
won't she, Doctor?
- i hope so, son.
Now--
Come on now. i'd hate
to have to hold your nose and pour.
Zina, Doc Richards said
you have to eat something.
Careful.
it's hot.
You'll never
be hungry again.
i promise you that, Zina.
Never again
as long as you live.
Open.
There.
You know, all the time
i was gone, i kept thinking about...
well, how soon
it was going to be spring.
One day...
it was
just about noontime...
but i made old Porter
stop and camp...
right on the spot
where our wagon stood that night.
Remember?
You almost promised to marry me...
but you fell asleep.
Remember? i asked you again
before i went away.
You told me it wasn't spring yet.
Well, it's here now.
Oh, if thinking could've helped
to make the time go quicker...
spring would've come
an awful lot earlier this year.
it's no use.
We'll never be able
to get married now.
Zina,
you couldn't mean that.
[ Sobs ]
i tried to believe.
i almost did once.
Not anymore.
i can't.
There's nothing left
to believe in.
- What are you doing?
- Well, the boys are eatin' 'em...
and-and the indians
eat 'em and--
You kids get in the house.
Go on. Hurry up.
Get!
Jonathan!
Hello,Jonathan.
i'm glad to see you.
- What's the matter?
- You promised to take care of Zina.
She's so sick over there,
she hasn't even got
the strength to eat.
She doesn't care
whether she lives or dies.
i don't believe God
would let that happen.
- God? What's he got to do with it?
-Jonathan!
if there is a God,
where has he been?
Where is he now?
-Jonathan!
- You said you'd take care of her.
You said a heap of other
things, too, but you sayin' 'em
didn't make 'em so.
But me, i believed 'em
just because it was you sayin' 'em.
if you'd told me you was
God Almighty himself...
i reckon i'd
have believed that too.
But not now,
not anymore.
Pa dead. Ma dead.
Everything that i ever loved dead.
Just because you said God
wanted it that way.
And now Zina.
We were plannin' to go
to California like the others.
i told her we would.
We had it all fixed up
between us, but no.
You wouldn't let us go.
You said God wanted us
to come down here.
He wouldn't let us starve.
And i thought you meant it.
i thought God was talkin'
to you every step of the way.
God talkin'to you--
Maybe you and him
don't speak the same language.
i know you and i don't,
not anymore.
Why did you do it?
Why didn't you leave us alone?
Why did you have to take
everything that we love--
even God?
Brigham!
Brigham, come on. There's bugs--
crickets-- millions of'em!
- Where?
- Comin' down the mountain.
They're in the wheat already.
- They're eating the wheat.
- Half the fields are covered already.
Crickets in the fields!
Hurry!
[ Pounding ]
Hurry! The crickets
are ruining the wheat!
[ Man Shouting ]
Come on! The fields
are full of crickets!
What are you gonna do?
i don't know.
Go on out
to the grain fields.
Listen, people!
Don't waste your time here!
Let's save the grain!
Come on!
Here, you children, get away
from there. Let's hope we can
find your ma. Come on.
[ Banging ]
- Food?
- Run and get some wood
and start a fire.
Mary, you get
some clean water in a pot.
Honey, a plague
has struck the place.
Crickets are overrunning
the fields.
As soon as you get
your strength back,
we're gonna get out of here.
We're going to California
like i promised.
Brigham!
Brigham! Look!
Millions and millions--
the hills are black with 'em.!
They're too much for us, Brigham.
it's no use.
Might as well try to push back
the ocean with a broom.
i told you what would happen
if we stopped in this valley...
but you wouldn't
listen to me!
You ran off with a false prophet!
That's why this happened!
it's true.
We're all gonna die!
You brought us out
into this place to starve,
you--you devil you!
But we've one chance!
Repent and throw him out of here!
- it's true. You ought
to be run out of here!
- Yes, you!
[ Angry Shouting ]
i wouldn't do that
if i was you!
And i'll plug
the first one of you that moves!
[ inhales Deeply ]
it's true.
i lied to 'em, Lord.
i told them that you said
i was to run things.
But you and i know
you didn't.
Do anything
you want to me, but--
but save them, especially now
when they need you most.
Only your strength
is left.
i'm licked.
i'm all done in.
From now on,
it's up to you.
What am i going to do,
Mary Ann?
i meant to do
so much for them.
i've got to tell 'em
the truth...
even if
they kill me for it.
i've got to tell 'em.
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
[ People Murmuring ]
- [ Murmuring Continues ]
- [ Young ] Listen to me, people.
You've a right
to know the truth.
i told you that the Lord
wanted me to run this church.
i said he wanted you to build
your homes in this valley.
And I promised you in his name
that you wouldn't starve...
that no harm
would come to you.
- i used the Lord's name.
- [ Gulls Squawking ]
[ Man ]
Seagulls!
- [ Squawking Continues ]
- [ Excited Chatter ]
The sky is black with seagulls.
They're headed toward the fields.
Look!
They're eating the crickets!
[ Excited Chatter]
- Oh, our crops are saved!
- Look at them eat!
There are more coming!
Hallelujah.
- What is it?
- Zina, you'll have
to see it for yourself.
You see, Brigham?
He was talkin' to you
all the time.
Maybe that's
the way it is.
Maybe he's ready to say
something any way you turn...
if you only know
how to listen.
Maybe talk--
speech like we use--
maybe that's
not his language at all.
i know
what you're thinking.
Maybe we were both wrong.
There is something
to live for.
[ Young ] And someday, good Lord,
we'll build a great city here...
on the shores of Salt Lake.
And when we do,
we'll erect a monument...
to the glory of God...
and to the symbol
ofhis benevolence--
the seagull.