Little heavier in the shoulders?
That's from slinging that
ten pounds sledge.
They all get it.
It's all there.
Do you mind if I look?
It's just that.
I don't know.
I keep my eye on all
that stuff myself.
Deveraux!
Let's go.
Where?
The Governor wants to see you.
I don't want to see him.
I'm thorough here.
- Let's go, partner.
Here's your grub.
Sidewinder.
Thanks.
Good gun.
Nice balance.
Come on over.
Joe Deveraux.
Yes, it'll be just a minute.
The Governor'll see you now.
Good luck, Joe.
Thanks a lot.
Glad you came, Joseph.
I couldn't do anything else.
I wanted to talk to you.
The simplest way was
to bring you here.
Sit down.
You look different, Joseph.
More mature, I guess, and...
...changed.
Three years brings changes.
- You're not interested...
...in what prison did to me.
Yes I am.
I'm very interested.
Barbara still hasn't married.
Anything else?
- Yes, there is.
There's considerably more.
Sit down.
I brought you here to keep
you from being killed.
You can think I'm hypocritical.
But for the respect
I had for your father...
...and your mother...
My mother?
Never mind.
There's been enough violence in
the ranch. I won't have any more.
I won't have any more.
Your brothers are in the next room.
They've a proposition to make you.
A business proposition.
They assure me it's a good one.
I'd like...
I'd advise you to take it.
Come in.
Hello, Joe.
Joe.
- Joe.
I told him and I tell you, Ben.
I'll stand for no trouble.
There won't be any trouble.
We don't want any and...
...l'm sure Joe doesn't.
I'll give you ten minutes.
- Fine.
You look good, Joe.
I'm glad to see it wasn't
too tough on you.
I know it wasn't easy but...
The Governor said you'd a
proposition for me.
He told me to take it.
What? Before you'd even heard it?
Why he should know better than that.
Besides, this is a family
matter, Joe.
We're still your brothers.
- Just tell me the proposition.
All right.
You see, Joe...
...there have been
a lot of changes...
...since you went in.
I can see some of them right here.
What kind of...
- I'll do the talking, Denny.
Sure, Ben.
That's one of the changes.
The other is that we run
the ranch from town now.
It's gotten too big to
operate from home.
What did you do with my mother?
You know, Joe, she doesn't like town.
She went back to her own people,
Joe. That's all she wanted.
Anything else we'd have done it,
just as we will for you, but...
...I think you ought to realize...
...that we've got different
responsibilities now.
Deveraux Ranch isn't just cattle
any more. We've got...
...oil leases, mineral rights...
...and stockholders
we have to protect.
Just tell me the deal.
All right, I'll tell you the deal.
It's Oregon. Brand new territory.
We'll buy you a spread, stock it and
cover your losses for three years.
Or else?
There is no 'or else'.
That's it.
I think that'll get you started.
What if I don't like Oregon?
You'll like it.
- I hear it's real nice country.
We worked it out for you
the best we could, but...
...if there's something else...
There is something else.
Three years.
Three years out of my life.
Three years I spent in
that stinking jail.
Can you give me back those?
No. Not even if I had
them to give you.
I lost mine sweating out chores
for Pa before you ever born.
I'm not crying about them.
I'm just telling you.
You've got our offer and
you've got our money.
The train goes through here at six.
Be on it and the deal stands.
That's not very smart, Joe.
But the rest of the deal stands
if you make that train.
He's real hot, ain't he?
He'll cool down.
When he does, he'll take
the deal. He's too smart.
Ain't that right, Ben?
- I don't know.
Anybody that throws 10,000 dollars
in a spittoon makes me nervous.
Pick it up.
For the price, he'll get
you three and back.
You sure you want that saddle?
Another couple of dollars and
I give you a better one.
What's your hurry?
Ben said find out where he was going.
I know where he's going.
Get on your horse, fellow!
Joseph! It is you.
Hello, Two Moons.
The gods, they smile on us this day.
I guess they do.
You missed me about three inches.
Maybe you're getting old.
If I want to hit you, I hit you.
You come home to stay, Joseph?
I don't know.
Your mother is at the meeting
place of our people.
Is she all right?
- She is the same.
She waits for you.
Yeah.
There's something else
I got to settle first.
You are alone. I have 20 men...
- And have your tribe destroyed?
No.
Where you go?
To the home place.
- Good.
Talk to Running Wolf.
- I'm not talk to anybody.
The Old Man's dead.
Do you listen to that
medicine man too?
At night, I hear wolf calls.
- You always hear wolves.
Pa never let anybody kill
them, you know that.
You want to ride in with me?
Well?
It is fitting you go alone, Joseph.
Superstitious old fool.
Hello, Pa.
I came back.
The old men said you wouldn't
rest easy till I did.
I've heard the medicine men...
...think you're running
the hills with the wolves.
Maybe you are at that.
What should I do, Pa?
Have you a sign for me?
Or are you to let me figure...?
Hold him still.
Just brand him, don't barbecue him.
'¿Cómo está, señor?
- Muy bien, Francisco'.
'Señor' Matt...
...all goes well?
- Yes.
We'll have the other camps
cleaned up by sundown.
Here too.
We'll drive the beef herd
toward home tomorrow.
Take them slow.
They're running off stock
on the east range.
Johnny was riding herd last night.
They shot his horse under him.
He walked and told Two Moons.
- Ben!
Get a horse!
You want I get some boys?
- No, we'll handle it.
Not a sign of them.
They rode in the stream.
You can't tell where they went.
Horse slipped, no?
- Which way, do you think?
Let's go.
Two, three...
...four, five, I count, Pa.
Six!
It's Pa!
Get out of here!
Let's go!
Get out of there!
Get up, you're not hurt.
Let this steer loose.
Could you change the brand
without botching it?
I've seen these two before.
We fired them last year.
They're no good.
Well?
We didn't mean nothing, Pa.
Just a couple little old steers.
- Why?
I don't know.
We needed the money, that's why.
Money? But you got money.
If you mean that lousy
40 a month...
Don't ever use that tone to me.
- Pa, we didn't mean nothing.
No, you didn't. You figured you've
steal some cattle and sell them.
Anybody would know that brand,
even though it had been raised.
But you figured nobody...
- Pa, we didn't even think of that.
I don't think you did.
You two together couldn't
have figure that out.
But somebody did?
Who put you up to it?
Nobody.
It doesn't make any difference.
You did it.
Be sure it wouldn't be a secret...
...you had to drag these
two lunkheads in with you.
They no talk.
Let them be. They're not to blame.
Just these two.
What should I do with'em?
They were caught rustling cattle
and changing the brands.
If you notify the Sheriff
the whole state'll know it.
We could hang them or shoot them...
- Cut it, Pa.
He thinks I'm fooling.
Lots of fellows felt that way
until we taught them...
...that you don't steal cattle
from Deveraux Ranch.
But the cattle are as much
yours as they are mine.
And they would have
been yours too, but...
What do you think, Ben?
You don't pay them enough.
Or you either, Ben?
They get the same as you.
If you ask me, I'll tell you, you
get twice what you're worth.
There ain't a man living who can
say that he stole cattle from me...
...but you two mushheads thought...
You wanted them so bad,
take them and get out.
The money you get for them'll keep
you until you can steal more.
But remember this: . .
...don't steal them from here.
We can't let him do this.
Why not?
I warned them they were
only asking for trouble.
Pa, you don't mean this.
They're your own sons.
They're a couple of cheap
tinhorn cattle thieves.
Two men are dead because of them.
- You just can't do it.
I did. Let go, son.
You should have had
all this yesterday.
If I'd been half smart I never
would've let you see it.
I don't know why it is but
every wife thinks...
What are you trying to do, kill me?
- Finish the telling.
Nothing to tell. I just
sent them packing.
Money they said they wanted.
I pay'em, don't I?
They have all they needs on
the ranch, haven't they?
Haven't they?
Perhaps.
But I don't think it
is money they need.
They were stealing cattle to get it.
What is it they do need?
They are not my sons.
It is difficult to say.
I think it is you, my husband.
You have never given them
anything of yourself.
That's a lot of! That kind of talk!
I got a big ranch to run.
The biggest of the country.
Besides, I've built it all
up for'em, haven't I?
Al right, I built it for myself.
But it's theirs when I die.
Suppose I haven't given'em time.
Does that mean they've to grow
up to be cattle thieves?
You are the father.
They want to be part of you.
If you do not give yourself,
they take.
Even if it means stealing
something that is yours.
That's Indian talk, squaw talk.
I don't understand you.
You understand.
That's what makes you angry.
That and because you've sent'em away.
They are your sons.
They're not yours. If Joe had
done a thing like that...
Because they're not, I have tried
to love them as much as my own.
And you have too.
That must take a power. I know
nothing about. But as I say, Joe...
Joe wouldn't do that.
He's my son, yet I don't
know what he would do.
He is yours, and you do not.
Bring them back.
- No!
I sent'em away and that's that.
Let me.
Sore at me?
No.
It's only because
I don't understand.
You didn't get a very good bargain,
my little Princess.
I have never regretted it.
No all these years you haven't?
How have you stayed so beautiful?
Am I?
Still?
You know, the first day I saw you...
...riding that little paint pony...
...with the antelope skin
shirt and the beads...
...and the feather in your hair...
...I though there was nothing
in the world so beautiful.
I didn't know the half.
We have guests for dinner.
- Send them home.
But they're already here.
You go downstairs and pacify them.
- Without you?
What's the matter? Are you afraid?
- No.
They'll bow and smile
and be very polite.
They'd better.
They know that too.
Are you afraid of them?
I'm afraid of no one,
but you my husband.
Princess.
That sounds like it has
a little of the old Irish.
Are you sure you haven't any
Irishman before I came along?
There is no other Irishman
like you, my husband.
Princess.
Did you?
- No!
I...
Please don't.
Matt!
'Señora' Deveraux.
We've been waiting for you.
- Horace, my apologies. Sorry.
Clem, nice to see you.
Where's Grace? Couldn't she come?
It's her back again.
Hasn't been out in a week.
Must be two weeks
since I've seen her.
I haven't met this young lady.
I should never forget it if I had.
Of course you have, uncle Matt.
It's not Barbara!
Why it can't Barbara, when you
went east you were this high.
I was a little taller than that.
Good evening, 'Señora'.
Not very much.
My, if the years had just done
for me what they've done...
You've met my sons.
- Yes, all four of them.
I expected you two would still
be out with the cattle.
I thought they ought to be
here, so I brought them in.
I see.
Are they entertaining you properly?
They've been most gallant.
- A fine set of boys, Matt.
Yes, Madame Deveraux taught
them their manners.
If they smack of the range
still, that's my fault.
I think they resemble you
amazingly, Uncle Matt.
So handsome and charming.
- Your manners weren't neglected.
Shall we go in to dinner?
- May I?
Joe.
What about them?
It was tough, but I got'em drunk...
- I'm not talking about that.
You heard what I said'em...
- You were mad, Pa.
I figured once you...
- You figured!
You've more courage that brains.
One of these days...
- Not tonight, Pa.
You got your good shirt on.
Besides, I think I could
lick you anyway.
That'll be the day, son.
Get in there.
Dear, that old heifer
never did come back.
That was in the days before
I had a seat in my pants.
But they were pretty good
days at that, eh Horace?
What are you eating, Uncle Matt?
- These?
They're pickled cactus grapes.
Cactus grapes?
- Yeah.
I don't think I've seen'em.
- They don't have'em in the east.
They're wonderful appetizers, eh Ben?
Yes, If you like them.
They're real good, Barbara.
Try it.
Don't!
It's a Mexican pepper.
It'll burn the roof of your mouth.
One of Pa's funny jokes.
The Mexicans grind them for cayenne.
Is that right, Uncle Matt?
Yes.
They're not that hot though.
Joe has a tendency to
be tender hearted.
But you eat them.
I eat anything that doesn't eat me.
Not bad at all.
Holly smoke!
Not hot?
A little!
She would deny it if it tore her
mouth off. Quite girl, Horace.
Why I didn't see before her, if
she's been here for a month?
If you came in town often
you might have.
I had to bring her out here.
- He doesn't come to town.
You've to run a ranch from the back
of the horse, not from a chair.
You find out about
mineral rights, though...
...and beef prices.
I get as good a price as
the next man, isn't right, Ben?
No.
I can show you the figures.
The boys are given me a bad time
tonight. Where did you get tem?
I asked them.
Most of them are averaging a 100%
and a half a pound better'n we are.
What should we do?
Open an office in town,
like the rest of them.
Watch Chicago prices and...
- And who would run the office?
What about Ben? He could do it.
I don't know, he hadn't
mentioned it to me.
Now...
- Wait a minute!
Let Ben talk for himself.
Go ahead, Ben.
Mr. Deveraux...
...our friends need more wine.
My apologies, Madam.
And you, Barbara.
'Vino'.
Sometimes the task of
managing four sons, is...
They look like they're able
to take care themselves.
They've been raised to.
Why wouldn't you to let one of
them take over for you in town?
Barbara, I think we should.
Let her alone, she's perfectly right.
Matter of fact, I think that
Ben could take over in town.
That means giving up part of
the control of the ranch to him.
And you don't like that a bit.
And what's more, I won't do it.
I tell myself he's not ready for it.
That's one problem when you
raise a flock of sons.
You must remember when some
man gains your hand in marriage.
Remember to have daughters.
Simpler...
...and much prettier.
I would be better advise in the
choice of who's to be their father.
The pepper was hotter than I thought.
What's that?
- Cold milk.
It's the only thing tha'll
cool that pepper.
They burn like a fire.
I thought my teeth would melt!
Heavens!
Now if the rest of me'd cool off.
- Shall we walk in the patio?
The wind's died down.
You don't have to be afraid.
Now...
...why should I be afraid?
I don't know.
They think that we'd turned
out to be quite a family.
That's way you came
out here, isn't it?
I suppose so.
Well, do we come up
to our reputation.
Your father certainly does.
Does he always act like that?
- Pretty much.
He's a bearcat, ain't he?
He's and old tyrant.
But you're crazy about
him, aren't you?
Why...
...yeah.
Yeah, I guess I am.
You're not afraid of him.
The rest of them are.
I don't know.
- I do.
Ben is, and so are the others. And
so is my father. It's ridiculous.
It was the peppers that
made you jump him.
He's stubborn and spoiled and mean.
You all let him get away with it.
- You like him too, don't you?
They said in town you'd turned
out to be smartest of the lot.
What else did they say?
That you'd inherited all his charm.
But I don't see it.
Look closer.
Was that to maintain
the Deveraux tradition?
No.
Maybe we'd better go back in.
Joe, I want you.
There's something
wrong with the herd.
Mrs. Deveraux'll show you the rooms.
- All right.
Take off that Sunday's clothes.
We're going to work.
Loco weed, maybe?
They'd be all swelled up.
The tongues looks funny though.
They got funny looking tongues
even when they ain't dead.
How may do you think?
Must be thirty eight or forty.
Pa!
This water smells funny.
What?
Tastes funny too.
Like when you was a kid and
one put a penny in your mouth.
Like copper.
They're dumping stuff in this stream.
That may be it. What do
they call that...
Whatever it is. They're dumping it
in my stream. Get your horses.
Where we going?
To the copper works.
Where do you think we're going?
Keep the cattle away
from this stream.
The copper mine!
- What of it?
We haven't slept.
- You didn't think of that...
...when you were in the east
range changing the brand.
All right, rest them.
Good coffee...
...with a stick in it.
What you aiming to do, Pa?
Stop them.
Big outfit.
- So we are. Are you nervous?
Nope. I just thought we might
get smart for once.
How?
Get some law in.
Law!
- Get an injunction and stop them.
They're on our land.
- Sure, that's right.
In the mean time we lose four
maybe five hundred head of...
What's the matter with you?
That was a wolf.
- He wasn't doing any harm.
He'll kill a steer.
- Only if he's a hungry.
I've told you...
- How long as he's around...
...a coyote won't come
within 10 miles.
They'll pull down an animal
just to be doing something.
The river's full of it.
It's from the mine all right.
Hold it.
Sorry boys, not today.
I'm Matt Deveraux.
I want to see McAndrews.
Not today. They're paying off
up there. I got my orders.
I don't care what you got.
I'm going up there. Stand aside.
You ain't going through
this gate, don't try...
Better get McAndrews.
Round up the other boys.
- Sure, boss.
Deveraux...
...good to see you.
You don't come here very often.
- I'm here now. I'll tell you why.
I lost forty head of cattle.
That stuff you're pouring
poisoned'em.
Poison!
That doesn't sound right.
A stream's supposed to purify
itself every few yards...
I don't know what a stream
is supposed to do...
...but it's killing my cattle
and want it stopped.
Where you going, boys?
I can see how you might be annoyed.
Tell you what you'd better do.
You keep your herds away from
the stream for a while...
...and I'll write to
the office in Chicago...
...and if they'll stand still for...
- Listen to me.
Don't worry about
writing any letters...
...or about my moving my cattle.
The river is on my land.
You're on my land.
You close this operation down...
...till you clean that stream
or I'll close it for you.
And just how do you
propose to do that?
The first thing I'll do...
...is get an injunction against
you in the Federal Court.
Then I'll get a Deputy
Marshal to enforce it.
That's a fair idea.
If you did that, you'd throw
all these men out of work.
They wouldn't like that.
- You're breaking our hearts.
Another thing.
Remember that the Government's
got contracts for our ore.
You think the court would
give you an injunction?
That's the second time I've wound
up with a busted head.
The first time when I forgot to
check the mineral rights...
...and the second, of course, when...
...I didn't realize that they
wouldn't send a fool in charge.
Coming from you, that's a
very pleasant compliment.
We'll just see who's right.
Now listen to me, you...
...pasty-faced Eastern tinhorn.
You close this operation down or
I'll pull it down around your ears.
I'll be waiting here for you.
You're right about one thing.
The company didn't send
me here to be buffaloed...
...by a loudmouth farmer with a
sqaw for a wife and a half...
Go ahead...
...pull it.
Draw and I'll blow your head off.
Cut it out, Joe. Put it away, Ben.
There's not going to be any
shooting. You've been warned.
Close it down or we'll be back. If I
come back I'll be looking for you.
Let's go.
Stay close to me. Walk slow.
Get them!
We ain't got a chance, Pa.
- Shut up!
Rush them, you fools! Rush them!
Shoot at their feet!
Make for the horses!
Wreck it! Tear it down!
Go!
All here?
- Some hurt, not bad.
Where'd you come from?
I think maybe trouble.
We follow you.
We wait, hear shooting, we come.
All right, go ahead.
They're not going to like that, Pa.
- I'll bet they're not.
They'll think twice before
they dump in my stream.
They won't think twice about
starting legal action.
That's not my worry.
Let Lawton about that.
Ride back to the ranch and tell him.
- Right.
If he's not there, go into
town and find him.
I'll ride in with you.
Me too.
- You're going to ride herd.
We got keep the stock
away from the stream.
Holy crow, don't he ever give up?
What're you doing here?
Looking at your horses.
Isn't it allowed?
You mean you were there with King?
He's a stallion.
He could kick your head.
You sound as if you wished he had.
He happens to know a lady
when he sees one.
Which is more than you can
say for the rest of us.
You're saying it, not me.
Where's Lawton, up at the main house?
No, he went into town with
Dad early this morning.
What about you?
I just didn't feel like
getting up that early.
You didn't figure we might
be riding today, did you?
Well of all the gall.
For your information I've already
asked for someone to drive me in.
Yes.
Might I ask how you
happen to be here?
Me.
Pa wanted me to see Lawton and I...
...just had a feeling that
you might still be here.
And you're, aren't you?
Yes, I'm here.
And you did figure that I might
ride in, didn't you?
Why?
Why did you ride in?
Ma, tell Pa I'll try and make
it back by suppertime.
I've got a feeling your mother
doesn't approve of this.
Or me either.
- Lf she didn't, she'd say so.
She never says anything.
She always seems to know just
what you're thinking.
I thought that too when I was a kid.
It's only because she's Indian.
I'd almost forgotten that.
But everyone call her 'Señora'. Why?
People like to pretend she's
Spanish, thinking it looks better.
Pa likes it.
Pa don't give a rip what they think.
- What do you mean?
You know.
If I did, I wouldn't have asked you.
Well.
Though you've been away...
...you should know that a white man
doesn't marry and Indian...
...even the daughter of a chief.
They call him a sqawman
and his kids breeds.
I'm a half-breed.
All right.
But does anyone call you that?
No since my first day in school.
But it still bothers you.
- No, why should it?
Yeah...
...I guess it does sometimes.
Was your mother really
the daughter of a chief?
He ran this whole territory.
I was named after his father...
...Tuekakas, Chief Joseph.
- I've heard of him.
They didn't want Pa
to marry the Princess.
A wild Irishman with a
few head of cattle...
...and three motherless kids.
The old chiefs were opposed to him.
So?
Pa'd tell it to you with
the trimmings...
...how he, rassled a bear,
and whipped six braves...
...so they allowed him
to marry the Princess.
Wonderful.
I'll bet he did it all too.
What about his family?
I never did hear much about them.
Ellen, his first wife, died right
after they came out here.
Came out from where?
- I don't know.
East, I guess.
His father, a farmer, left Ireland
during the famine.
Dirt farmer or something.
Were kicked by a mule when
Pa was just a pup and...
What're you laughing at?
I thought you were worried
about being an Indian.
You just don't like being Irish.
If I were you I wouldn't
try to rush things.
Let me talk to Deveraux
myself and see if...
There's one of them now.
Yes, so it is.
Isn't that your daughter?
Yes, it is.
You're making too much
out of this, Horace.
They're a little hot under the
collar, but they'll calm down.
Talk to'em nicely and they'll
settle. They want no trouble.
I tell you they're going to
sue you. They're mad, Matt.
You wrecked a building...
...banged up half their crew.
- They killed 40 of my cattle.
What should I do, kiss'em?
I'll pay for the damages,
if they're fair.
And if they put in a sump and
stop polluting my stream.
Going to court is a waste
of their time and mine.
They don't care about that.
They're out to get you.
This is a big company.
They dislike the shooting
in their property.
They'll make an example of you.
Do you think they can?
Well.
That depends on what
happens in court.
What lawyers they bring in and...
...who the judge is. You know.
Well...
...you could do something about that.
This is a federal case...
...with eastern lawyers,
the papers will pick it up.
If this was just a...
...local thing, we could handle it.
- Horace...
...I don't know but...
...something sounds sour to me.
You made the wrong move
with the wrong people.
I've mad a lot of wrong
moves, Horace.
You know, it isn't that,
it's you, Horace.
Sometimes you helped,
sometimes you couldn't.
That's all right, but...
...you're not even pretending
now that you want to help me.
You could appoint the judge,
couldn't you, Horace?
I suppose I could.
It couldn't be quite ethical but...
- Never mind about that.
Let's talk about you and me.
You want something.
What is it? What do you want?
I want your son Joe to stay
away from my daughter.
I ought to kill you,
Horace, right now.
No! No!
Not you. After all these years.
Matt!
I don't care what the newspaper
and the town say...
...or the fact that Lawton's wife is
sick every time we ask them.
You!
You never could understand
why I married her.
And you never liked this country
out here, did you, Horace?
That's why you sent
the girl back east.
To get her away from
the dust, the cattle...
...the Indians and the half-breed.
- Matt, don't.
I like the boy, but...
...this is something that's born
and bred in me, I'm 56.
I tried to change but...
- You're 56...
...and you're Governor of the state!
And who made you Governor?
I took you off of a...
...accountant's stool and pulled a
pencil out from behind your ear...
...and made you a politician.
I made you mayor.
I sent you to Congress and
I put you in that chair.
Fifty-six years...
Fifty six, you owe me thirty of them.
You're right, I do.
You've done everything but change me.
I wish you had.
And maybe I will.
Maybe I will. I can still pull that
chair right out from under you.
Maybe I will.
But I'll do something else first.
I'll tell my boy that if he wants
your girl, to take her...
...if he has to pull her out of the
house by the hair of her head.
Dead beat?
I guess so.
I'll show you something.
Go on.
That's wonderful. And cold!
- Comes from away up.
It's beautiful here.
How did you ever find it?
I've known it since I was a kid.
This is where Pa'd his first
powwow with the tribes...
...and saw my mother.
There used to be a stone
that marked the place...
...where the old Indians made
a deal for the land.
I don't come frequently.
- Don't you come here often?
No, it's sort of out of the way.
- Then why did you bring me here?
I don't know. We were
out this way and...
No other reason?
Maybe it wasn't such a good idea.
I just don't understand you.
Four days ago you behaved as if I
were a girl in a dance hall...
...and now...
Four days ago I wasn't
in love with you.
Was it that hard to say?
You don't know about what
you're finding out...
...of what they'll say...
- Yes I do.
Just as your mother did.
Should I go in and talk to him?
- Nope.
Don't you start getting honourable.
I need time to work on him.
Unless you really want to?
I'd rather rassle a bear.
Joe!
Come in here, this concerns you too.
The Mining Company has filed a
claim against us in the Court.
Clem thinks we're in real trouble.
You'll be if they get a
judgment against you.
I don't know if they...
- Then why bother with it?
Because no lawyer guarantees
what a jury'll do.
As I said, if Horace were
appointing the Judge...
He isn't, and I'm not
gonna ask him to.
I still think we've got a good case.
If I didn't I've told you so...
...but I want you to be protected
against any eventuality.
You insure yourself against
accident and death.
No.
What is it, Mr. Lawton?
If he splits the property
between you...
...he won't be the sole owner.
- You're wasting your time...
...because he doesn't trust any of
us with more that 40 a month!
Sit down!
What about Ma, couldn't she...?
No, Joseph.
Well...
You see, Joe, it's...
The government doesn't allow
an Indian to hold land.
What about me?
That's different, you can.
He won't turn a thing over to us.
- I'll make decisions around here!
Get out of here! I'll think it over.
Joe!
Come here, will you?
There's something I want to ask you.
Yes, Pa?
Never mind. It's not important.
I take it the death of these 40
cattle was important to you?
The death of one cow is important
to a cattleman, sonny.
Important enough to send
you to the mine...
...where 12 men were injured?
Yep.
You consider 40 cattle more
important than the lives...
...of 12 men occupied in making...
- Objection.
Prosecution is trying...
- Let him go.
I'm willing to answer any questions.
That sound like pure
nonsense, sonny...
...but I know the difference
between cattle and people...
...as any man can tell you.
Thank you.
How many head of cattle have you
at this time, Mr. Deveraux?
45,000 or 50,000.
You don't know exactly?
There're the books of my Ranch.
Why don't you look it up?
I don't want to look it up.
I want you to tell me.
Then you'd better change
the tone of your voice, sonny.
Will you ask for a directly answer?
- I already have.
Mr. Van Cleve, unless you have a
a specific reason for pursuing...
...the book...
- I've a specific reason.
The defense has stressed
the importance of 40 animals.
Yet the witness can't tell me...
- Objection.
Prosecution wants to discredit the
witness by indirect examination.
Sustained.
Your Honor, I don't understand
this legal hocus-pocus...
...but I'm willing to tell this
fellow about my cattle.
I don't keep any books
in my head but...
...every cow on my Ranch
is important to me.
Important to other people too.
I ship 10,000 head to Kansas
City every year.
My cows goes into every
city in the East.
It feeds over 200,000 people.
That's may line of work, sonny.
We're all very grateful for
this additional information.
But could we confine ourselves
to specific answers? Thank you.
You've stated you built up you
ranch over a period of 25 years?
Approximately.
During this time you've had
other disputes over...
...prior claims and water rights?
- Plenty.
Were they settled in court?
- No.
This is the first time
I've ever been to court.
Usually the men I had to deal with...
...were men enough to stand
up and argue it out.
I see.
Do you happen to remember the
name of Lucius Hennaberry?
Yes, I remember him.
Do you remember shooting
him in White's saloon?
In a fair fight.
Objection.
Your Honor, I can see no reason
for this line of question.
I demand.
- It's an integral part of the case.
If the Court allow me to proceed
I'll so demostrate.
Proceed.
Thank you, Sir.
The dispute between you and
Hennaberry was over a water right.
No. Not over water rights
just over water.
Luke said he was going to
water his herd on my ranch.
He didn't.
Judging from the results,
that seems obvious.
Water seems to play a important
part in your life.
I don't quite understand this.
Seeing as how you came here
on a train, all nice...
...and comfortable like, why,
I can understand that.
But you see, I didn't.
I packed in here with a
wife and three kids.
The first year I lost my herd and
the second I lost my wife...
...because there was no water.
Water's important to me like it is
to everybody else in the state.
Without water there'd be no state!
Your Honor, please...
- You asked me, I'll answer.
You can bet your hat water's
important to me...
...as it is to everybody
else in the state.
Every drop on my ranch I either
dug for or channeled in.
When you're back on that train
riding out of here...
...over the right of way
that I gave'em...
...think it over.
I concede Mr. Deveraux's
contribution to his state...
...but that does not give him
the right to flout the laws...
...of this state.
- Object.
Sustained.
Just keep to direct questioning.
I'm sorry.
Do you remember the names
of Charlie Munger...
...Red Dog Johnson,
or Carlos Ramirez?
No.
The incident may be
too trivial to recall.
But isn't it true that you summarily
hanged all these men...
...on June...
- They were stealing cattle.
Did you just remind'em?
- I didn't ask'em their names.
You just hung them.
- They were thieves.
I see.
Wasn't Charles Malone
sheriff at that time?
I guess he was.
- Did you try to contact him?
No.
- Why not?
He was 40 miles away and drunk.
Do you know this for a fact?
- I knew Charlie Malone.
Have you ever, during your
years on Deveraux Ranch...
...called in legal authorities?
- Lf I've needed them...
...l've asked for them.
- Why didn't you ask for 'em...
...two weeks ago?
- It wasn't necessary!
Order! ¡Order!
If there's any more of this,
I'll see you in my chambers.
If you can't restrain yourself,
I hold you in contempt.
Proceed.
You say you've asked
for the authorities.
That's right.
- Did you attempt...
...to notify the present
sheriff this time?
No.
- Why not?
I didn't think it was necessary.
You stated that it was
your intention...
...to discuss with McAndrews and
arrive at a sensible solution.
Do you still say that
this was your intent?
Yes.
- Then how it happened...
...that 20 minutes after
you arrive at the mine...
...your formal appear
with 30 armed men?
Maybe he thought there
was any trouble.
Did he know there was any and
you warned to be there?
No, I did not.
I see.
Is it customary on Deveraux Ranch
to proceed without orders?
It isn't customary but...
- Yes, Mr. Deveraux?
I didn't have to say anything to him.
I see.
Suppose I didn't believe that.
Suppose I say that you
deliberately caused the trouble...
...to bully and force McAndrews
in a opened fight.
Suppose I say to the jury you're
lying, aren't you?
Then I would tell you to get
a gun or leave town...
...because when I leave here I'll
chase you until your heels smoke!
Got get'em
- Thatta boy, Matt.
Order! Order!
Mr. Deveraux, I hold you in contempt.
This court will be in
recess for an hour.
One more disturbance...
...and the rest of the proceeding
will be made to closed door.
Matt, come on.
That did it. He hasn't got a chance.
What're we going to do?
What can we do?
Lawton said they'd to prove
him solely responsible.
He was, wasn't he?
- We were all with him.
I never asked to go.
- Me neither.
They'll put him in jail.
Look, Joe...
...l'd do anything to help him...
- So would l, Joe...
...but we can't just say...
- They'd arrest us for perjury.
That's right.
Yeah.
I'm going to get a smoke.
Me, too.
We got to do something, Ben.
Why?
They'll put him in jail.
- No.
Not him.
We got to do something,
we owe it to him.
Maybe you do, Joe, but not me.
You heard him up there...
You heard him telling
about his cattle...
...and his wife, and going
it alone with three kids.
What do you think we did while
he was building up the state?
I worked 16 hours a day for him
when I was ten years old.
And all he ever did was
treat me like a hired hand.
Ben, listen...
- You don't know about that.
You came along later
when things were good.
So you figure you owe him something.
All right, go ahead,
do anything you like.
You're his little pet...
...you always were.
It looks bad, doesn't it?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry about the judge.
- Yeah, he's tough.
I mean about Dad.
What about him?
Why, about him having
the fight with your father...
...and refused to appoint the judge.
- He fought with Pa? What about?
Us.
Well, was it?
I thought he must have told you.
Where are you going?
- I've got to see Lawton!
Well?
It's all right. I made
a deal with them.
You'll have to give up
the land the mine is on.
Give up the land!
- Then you'll got to jail.
Look.
- Will you listen to me!
All right.
You give'em the title
to the mine...
...and pay the injured men and the
costs on the wrecked building.
We can work that out later.
That wrecked building is worth...
- There's one more thing.
I'm going to put Joe on the stand.
Why?
- Somebody...
...must be responsible...
Not Joe!
- Wait a minute!
I just talked to him.
He wants to do it.
He says McAndrews
called him a half-breed.
He says...
- Joe is not going on the stand!
Look, Matt...
This is a deal.
Somebody has to do this.
You just destroyed any
chance you had.
If they convict Joe,
we can appeal it.
If you give up the land,
they won't contest the appeal.
The worst that can happen is that
Joe will be held for a few weeks.
I don't like this.
- I don't ask you that!
I'm just asking you to
take some advice!
The court is now in session.
Please come to order.
I'm going to call
the boy to the stand.
If you say one word
until after the appeal...
...it'll mean at least ten
years behind bars.
Call Joseph Deveraux.
Defense calls Joseph Deveraux.
Take the stand, please.
Do you swear...
...to tell truth...
...the whole truth...
...and nothing but the truth?
We can't do anything more, Pa.
- Get away from me!
I don't want to talk to any of you!
Get away from me!
You are making yourself
ill, my husband.
Please! This will pass!
Two Moons said Lawton
brought some papers.
They're here, I will get'em.
And food.
- No food, just the papers.
But you must eat.
- I sent Two Moons to look for 'em.
They're still your sons.
Please send them to me
when the come, 'Señora'.
You wanted us?
No, I don't want you.
I told you to come here. Sit down.
All right.
What is it, Pa?
Papers.
Lawton wrote'em.
It's an agreement to keep
Joe out of jail.
You own the property, so you sign
them. Here you, make your mark.
I can write.
How much, Pa?
80,000 cash and the mine property.
Sign it!
No.
Is too much, Pa, get
them to cut it down.
Why you...?
This is to keep Joe
out of jail. Sign it!
No!
We are not gonna sign it, Pa.
You'll sign these papers
or I'll kill skin the lot of you!
We decided we're not gonna
sign, it's too much money.
Joe'll only get 7 or 6 month.
- Sign it!
Take it easy, Pa.
It won't do you any good to
get yourself wound up...
Get him to bed.
I'll send for the doctor.
You, Deveraux!
Come on down.
You got a visitor...
...a pretty one.
No.
- Joe, don't give me no trouble.
Joe!
Yeah, it's me.
Get out!
Orders are to stay with prisoner.
- Get out, now!
Joe, ¿what's the matter?
What are they doing to you?
- Nothing!
Nobody's doing anything to me.
I was working and it's hot.
I don't understand, Joe.
- I'm a convict.
I work and eat here and sleeps
in these stinking clothes.
My darling...
...as if that could...
You shouldn't have come here.
Don't do it again.
Shouldn't have come?
Why not?
Three years isn't forever, Joe.
No matter how hard it is, I can...
- It isn't hard.
It's just being here, and
not being able to get out.
Is it your father?
He's been sick but he's been...
- I know about it.
Two Moons has been here. I know
what they're doing to the old man.
They killing him, just little by
little, day by day...
...they're tearing him apart.
While I'm in this...
- Joe, stop it!
Stop thinking about your father and
your brothers and the crazy ranch.
Forget it, you've got your own life.
- Forget it?
That's what keeps me going.
- But...
...it's insane to brood for 3 years.
Joe...
...please...
...when you get out, we'll go away.
Just the two of us, any place...
- Stop it!
You're going to be on the outside,
with people, free to move around.
I can wait.
Maybe you can.
I'm not so sure about me.
When I see you...
Now do you understand?
Don't come here again.
Stay here.
He's coming.
I know he's coming, but
when? I want him now.
He's here.
Please, my husband...
...no more quarrels.
Try to understand him a little.
Hello, Ma.
Pa.
Leave us alone, will you 'Señora'?
Sit down, Ben.
This is all right.
What's on your mind, Pa?
The land.
They tell me you're selling
some to an oil company.
That's right.
Why?
We need the money to operate with.
To operate that office in town?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell me?
You wouldn't like it...
...and the Doc says it's
bad for you get riled up.
Yeah.
You're real concerned about
my health, aren't you?
I don't like it. I don't
like selling the land.
It's good business for the ranch.
I'm selling it, Pa.
It's yours to sell.
I spent my life building it for
you and the others, but...
I've been rough on you, Ben,
because you were...
...the oldest.
I guess I felt I could
expect more from you.
I never did this before,
but I'm doing it now.
I'm asking you, Ben.
Give up this sale, will you?
No.
It figured.
I always knew there was something
between us, some way.
What is it, Ben? What is it?
Joe, maybe, Ben? Joe?
Because he's smarter
than the rest of you?
Because he stood up to me when
the rest of you were afraid to?
You hate Joe, don't you, Ben?
No, I never hated Joe.
Me, then.
I'm no trouble to you now.
- No, not now...
...because you're old
and crippled and sick.
So now you call me in and ask me
something. You're a little late.
Did you ask me how I'd like and
Indian stepmother after Ma died?
Or how I liked doing all the chores
and caring for Mike and Denny?
Or how I liked quitting
school to work for you?
Did you ever in your life...
...ask me how I felt or what
I thought? What I wanted?
No, you didn't.
So, it's...
...it's a little late
for asking now, Pa.
But the gate is always open, Ben...
...you could have left. I would
have understood that...
...I did it myself.
I always used to think there was...
...too much of me in you
for us to hit it off.
But I know now that was wrong.
There wasn't enough of me in you.
Now I'm telling you again.
I'm not asking you, I'm telling you.
You're not going to sell any
of the Deveraux Ranch.
Because I'll stop you, Ben.
I'll stop you!
- Sit down, Pa.
You're not telling anybody
anything anymore.
I run Deveraux Ranch
and I run it the way I like.
And right now I'm riding
into town to sign a deal.
'Señora'!
Two Moons!
Two Moons, get my horse.
'Señor' Matt, to ride
the horse is death.
He's right. It will kill
you, my husband.
What difference does it make?
If you die...
...I die.
'Señora'...
...this must be done.
You understand?
Ben!
Ain't that Pa?
Yeah.
He's trying to head
us off. Come on!
He's got us, Ben!
- Hold it still!
Mike!
Is he dead, Ben?
I wonder how long?
Go on back to the ranch
and get a buckboard.
Do you wan't that we stay here?
- No, go on back.
Both of you.
I'm sorry it had to be this way, Joe.
No!
No more of this!
You are brothers.
Joseph.
Ma!
- My son! My son!
You've changed.
Not much.
What about you? These clothes...
When your father died...
...I went back to my people.
To die, too, I think.
But I knew I must see you.
What do you do with the gun?
It's his.
It's all he had when he started.
I'm starting too.
That's not a start.
It is the end.
To take that is blood.
- They killed him.
Ben did.
Slow death!
You saw it happen.
You know what they did.
You're speaking like
a boy, my son...
...and you should already be a man.
- You don't understand.
Listen to me.
He was my husband for 25 years.
I loved him more than
anything in the world.
Perhaps even more than you, Joseph.
I know, Ma.
You think to take up
his gun and his life.
You cannot, Joseph.
It is finished with him.
You must make your own life.
Go away.
Take the girl with you.
Barbara?
She has come to me may times.
For her, too...
...there can only be one.
Take her away, Joseph.
And when you're together...
...you'll now there's not
need for blood...
...nor for him...
...nor for that.
Give it to me.
What about you, Ma?
There is no longer need
for me, my son.
Keep riding, Joe.
Get going.
There's no need for this, I made
up my mind. I'm pulling out.
You missed your train.
- I' don't need any.
I said I'm leaving.
- I believe you.
But for how long?
What do you mean?
- Just that.
I could never be sure when
you might get an idea.
There's always that lance
you threw at my feet that day...
That was an old Comanche sign.
- Sure, I know that.
You see, I'm mighty superstitious.
I got to thinking about it.
I figured I might not sleep good
nights, worrying about you.
I slept awful good these past years.
- You're crazy, Ben, you...
Take it easy, Joe.
Just swing off there...
...we'll get up into the hills.
Move!
You won't get away with it.
You could cut your own throat.
May be.
No sense you worrying
about it though.
What about Denny and Mike?
You can't keep'em quiet.
I sent them into town.
I know better than to let them
in on anything like this.
I could have saved you
the trouble, Joe.
It's lovely and peaceful here.
Doesn't seem to go with Pa,
somehow, but you can't tell.
Do you think he'd like these?
I know he would.