I have many girls.
Come. Come. I show you.
Look.
Nice?
I'll take this one.
Look.
What's wrong with her?
Bound feet.
Very special.
Yes?
I'll take her.
Sale.
I must be out of my mind
to be out here in the middle of nowhere
with these little bitches.
That's right. Eat up.
I need you girls nice and healthy.
Stop staring at me like that.
Maybe what you need is a lesson, huh?
That's what these girls need,
a lesson.
Just hold her there.
I got it.
Bring it in, Billy. Come on, let's go.
Keep it steady.
There you go.
I'm looking for a Tom Harte.
I'm his uncle.
Harte's got a family?
Who would have figured?
Tom, boy.
Young Tom.
Jack, this is my uncle, Print.
Print Ritter.
What brings you out this far?
I thought maybe you'd gone under.
No, sir.
I ain't gone under yet. No, sir.
But your mother did.
She passed away two weeks ago.
Her hired man found her
in the vegetable garden.
Is he taking care of the place now?
Yes, sir.
I need to say something straight out.
She wrote a will.
She left it all to me.
Now, I don't know why she done it,
or what was crossed between you two,
but she done it.
The land, the livestock, everything.
It ain't a fortune, but it's legit.
Is that it?
That's it.
Well, she did write this letter to you
a while back.
Your name, Tom, is on there.
I don't feel good about this at all.
That's why I come out here.
I want to talk.
You see,
your mother made me
the executor to her will.
She left everything to me,
except there was a codicil.
You could buy the old Fairburn place,
you know the two sections that run down
from the Steens to the Malheur,
from her estate,
if you've a mind to.
I can buy it?
Yeah. Market price.
The will's on file over the Burns.
Son of a bitch.
That's mother's milk.
Yeah.
More like hind tit.
You know, son, I don't like this
any more than you do
but I got this idea,
might be good for both of us.
I got this idea to take horses
back to Wyoming.
Listen to this, you're gonna like this.
Listen to this.
"Wanted,
"hot or cold-blooded horses.
"Sound and disease-free.
"Three to eight years of age.
"Purchase price commiserate
with the quality of stock.
"Contact William Moncrieffe,
Sheridan, Wyoming.
"Agent for Her Majesty's War Office,
British Empire."
What do you say?
Like that idea?
Why don't we take some of your ma's money
and buy a big string of horses?
Might be a handy way
to increase our capital.
And I'm thinking tough,
high-desert mustangs.
They can go unshod
and ought to be fairly broke
by the time we get to Sheridan.
On shares?
I figure
a 25-75 split on profits
after expenses and loan repayment.
- Loan repayment?
- To the bank.
I'd have to put the ranch up as collateral.
Well, what the shit kind of deal is that?
You take the family ranch
to borrow money to buy horses?
Well, that's...
That's one way of looking at it.
What's the other?
Well, you can stay here,
cutting the nuts off another man's cows
for chuck and wages till you're all
stove up and walking around like a crab,
like all the other bachelor cowhands
from here to the Dalles.
No disrespect meant.
Truth is,
you're as loose as ashes in the wind.
How many horses you say we can handle?
Three to five hundred head, give or take.
Well...
Good to see you're still riding old Bob Tate.
You bet.
So, you ready, buckaroo? Let's do it.
Keep going.
The other way.
Go the other way!
Just hold on.
Hold up. Just hold them up to the right.
You heard him.
Move them to the left.
Come on.
Let's do it!
Let's move them out.
Move it! Move it!
Let's move them out. Hold them!
Move them out east.
Let's go.
Get them to a run.
Nothing like a 10-mile romp
to knock the edge off them.
Figured out who's gonna be the caporal
of this mob, Mr Ritter?
I'd say that stout grey,
that flea-bitten mare right there.
You're gonna have your hands full,
Mr Ritter.
You sure you don't want
a couple of us to go along?
No, boys, we can handle it.
That ought to about do it, Vick.
Appreciate the help.
Thank you. See you next spring.
Plan on it.
Come on, boys.
Come on now, boys.
Gonna walk them all the way
to Wyoming, Nephew.
Walk them in the morning.
Graze them at night, all night,
and let them rest.
We don't want to come in
with a bunch of skin and bones. No, sir.
When the Indians first laid eyes on them,
they called them "god dogs."
"God dogs"?
Yeah, it was the Spanish in them.
Been on the loose for a long time.
Yeah, we ought to think about
coming up here and spending next summer.
Yeah.
Let's get your herd delivered first.
It's a damn sight more yours than it is mine.
Well, I don't feel that way.
Don't think your ma would either.
"Tom.
"As you seem to have had
little interest in the homestead,
"I see no reason to burden you
with its ownership.
"You are free to pursue
your own opportunities.
"Your mother."
Not very generous.
She never got over
my running off to buckaroo.
Yeah.
Losing your pa made her a hard woman.
Still,
I sent money home after every season.
You know,
sometimes I look up there,
I see those lights,
I think maybe the Old Man
is not too happy with the way
things are down here.
Yeah.
It's funny,
I always got the feeling
it meant he was pleased.
Yeah.
It's a great life
when it ain't raining or snowing.
Come on, boys.
Come on, boys. Let's go. Come on.
Nephew, let's go.
Get going.
Wyoming's waiting on us.
Let's do it.
They say Wyoming's hell
on women and horses.
We're going to find out soon enough,
at least one aspect of it.
Where is he taking us?
Our families sold us into service.
He must be very rich to need five servants.
This is not a rich man's cart.
Maybe he plans to kill us.
Why would he buy us just to kill us?
He does not plan to kill us.
But I think we may wish he did.
You girls shut up.
I'm sick of listening to that cackling.
- You feel like going in for supplies?
- Sure.
Go easy on the whisky.
It don't always suit your temperament.
And don't dawdle.
I don't want to be having to worry
about coming to fetch you.
Thank you.
Ma'am.
Howdy.
Hi, can I help you?
I need supplies.
Flour,
bacon,
four sacks of Arbuckles,
some cut tobacco,
and four boxes of therapeutic papers.
Anything else?
You sell whisky?
No, sir. Up the hill at the saloon.
They'll take care of you.
Hi.
Howdy.
Get a shot of whisky
and three bottles to take away?
I thought I told you yesterday,
no panhandling in here.
It's a free country.
I got a right to earn a living.
Not in here. Let's go.
I'd like to hear him play the fiddle.
And who the hell are you?
Just a fellow that enjoys fiddle playing.
I'll kick the both of youse out then. Let's go.
Want a drink?
Don't mind if I do.
It's on him.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
Much obliged.
I hired a new man.
What for?
I thought you might like some music.
And that's his purpose?
That and to help out with the nighthawking
and pull that pack horse around.
- Does he have a name?
- Yes, sir.
Henry Gilpin.
But you can call me Heck.
All right, Hank.
We'll see what you can do.
Thank you, sir. I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Nature's call.
Man guaranteed me
those therapeutic papers
wouldn't have any splinters in them.
Let you judge that.
Hey, I was thinking we ought to stay off
the main trail as long as possible.
Probably be better forage anyway.
Okay with me
long as the river crossings ain't bad.
How's it going?
Find any wood chips or splinters?
I tell you, it beats corncobs
and sage grass any day.
Yes, sir.
Morning.
Y'all off to church?
No, indeed.
Captain Billy Fender.
Gentlemen,
as you can see, I have purchased,
at a great expense mind you,
five exotic virgins from the Celestial Empire.
I'm headed out to the mining camps,
where those men out there
will pay good money to deflower
one of these little lotus blossoms.
You seem to be travelling
in the same direction.
You gents mind if I tag along?
God only knows I can use the company.
Conversation's been a bit thin.
Pick that up!
Put some more wood on that fire.
Got a couple of extra rabbits,
if you'd care to join us.
Don't mind if I do.
Drink up, gents.
Gentlemen,
I don't mind confiding in you, but I have
a little problem on my hands here.
I was supposed to deliver virgins,
but since I left San Francisco
I deflowered one,
which cuts back on her
enhanced value considerably.
You know, it must be an acquired taste. I...
I don't understand it.
I like to have a gal that
knows what the hell she's doing.
But some men will pay a big price
to get that first slice of the cake.
I'll tell you what, gents.
If you're interested,
I'll let you have a stab at the almost virgin
for a buck apiece.
How does that sound?
I'll pass.
Hey.
Get me another bottle out of my bag.
Not you, her.
Her.
I tell you they are as dumb as dirt.
Give me that. Get out of here.
Jesus, what's wrong with her feet?
Her feet?
I'll tell you.
In China, when they're little girls,
they take their feet
and they break their toes.
And they bind them up
underneath real tight.
You know why they do that?
'Cause it gives them a stronger sex desire.
Yeah, those guys at the mines
will pay premium for that one.
How about another one, gents?
This is the last one for me.
Okay.
Here have another one. There.
I'll take just a touch.
Oh, that's plenty. That's plenty.
Last one.
Oh, God, he will be drunk again.
This man has abused us.
Now there are three more men.
We are ruined.
Maybe they are not like him.
- Can you play that fiddle?
- I do.
- Why don't you play me a little tune?
- Well, not tonight, Captain.
Come on, you know what,
play me a nice Irish jig that I can dance to.
You know, I love to dance.
I tell you, I used to be a good...
I used to be a good dancer in my day.
Not tonight. I think I'll pass.
He who sins when drunk
shall be punished when sober.
Amen.
Are they dead?
Hey.
Gilpin.
Print.
My money belt's gone.
Oh, shit! My money belt's gone.
Shit!
Where's our money and horses?
Easy, boy.
They sure as shit didn't take them.
That little weasel doctored the bug juice
and swapped stock on us.
What idiots. All of us.
What idiots, all of us. Idiots.
At least we're still heeled.
You wait here.
What're you doing?
I'll tell you what I'm doing,
I'm going after that jackass.
I'll get our money back.
Yeah, well, make sure you get back.
Ladies,
it's about time we was introduced.
Hey, now.
Okay. All right.
Here's the deal.
Now,
you're gonna be Number One.
All right?
Could you say "One"?
One. You're One.
One.
Very good.
You're Two.
- Say "Two."
- Two.
No, no, she's Two, you're One.
One. Two.
Say "Two."
Two. Say "Two." Say "Two."
- Two.
Good. Very good.
Now you, you're Three.
- Three.
- Very good.
And she's going to be Number Four.
Number four, number four.
She doesn't want four.
It's bad luck, means death.
Four. You're Four.
I don't want to die.
She doesn't want to be Four?
She can be Number Five.
It's okay, don't be scared.
When Tom brings your sister back,
she'll be Four. All right?
So, that's what?
Get it right or I'm gonna paint numbers
on your back.
One.
- Two.
Three. Four.
- And little Number Five.
- Five.
Give me a smile. Little Number Five?
Five. Five.
Good.
Dance now, son of a bitch.
Number Five. Yum, yum.
- Ye Fung.
- Ye Fung!
He did it.
Bring her here.
Put her by the fire.
Was he sober?
What's that?
Captain Fender, was he sober?
He said, "If you sin when you're drunk,
you'll have to pay when you're sober."
He was sober enough.
You ain't been introduced.
Ladies.
Ladies, this here's Tom.
Everybody say "Tom."
Tom.
Very, very good.
Tom, this is
Number One,
Two,
Three,
Four.
That's little Number Five.
Now, there you go.
Everybody knows everybody.
Thank you.
So what do they call you?
Ladies,
who am I?
Honkle Pren.
"Honkle Pren."
Uncle Pren, huh?
Yeah.
So I went and got horses and our money,
and I had to stretch a fellow,
while you started a finishing school
for Chinese girls.
You all right, son?
Yeah, I'm all right.
I left my rope back there, though.
Listen,
man like that ain't worth the food he eats
much less the price of a decent rope.
I think these masters will be kind.
The young one killed our last master.
To save Ye Fung.
I was not saved.
But you are alive.
No, I am a ghost.
Take that back. It's bad luck.
My luck cannot get worse.
You will curse us all.
I entered the 18th hell a long time ago.
We are already cursed.
Stop it.
She only has us. We only have each other.
Hey, darling.
A little magic here now, a little magic.
See?
This is the way you eat it, see?
You open it up. Like that.
See?
You eat it.
See, like this.
It's called a peanut.
Okay, you eat it.
They're sure gonna be
a hell of a drag on our trail time.
Nephew, if they was five ladies
from Canyon City, telling us what to do,
with all the gaggling and prattling going on,
we'd be ready to slit our throats.
Even so, I'll feel better
when we find a safe place to leave them.
Get back to the task at hand.
Yeah.
If you don't eat, you will get sick.
If you get sick,
they will leave us behind.
Please eat, Ye Fung.
Don't make them leave us behind.
I don't want to.
Eat.
Let's go.
Now, miss, you grab this horn, see,
and one, two, three.
There you go. Put your leg over. That's it.
Good.
It's easy.
Easy, all right.
Okay.
Hold on. Hold on.
There you go. You'll be fine.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Come on. Another short man in the West.
Come on.
Come on, now. Come on. You're doing fine.
Easy.
There you go. There you go.
That's okay. You're doing great. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Look at Number Five. She's got it licked.
Come on. Attagirl.
Come on.
Yeah.
Attagirl. You're doing great.
How'd you like it? Really?
You liked that, didn't you? Come on down.
Told you you could do it. Now grab hold.
Found your balance all right.
Good.
Yeah.
Told you you could do it.
What? Huh?
Yeah?
You betcha.
I agree with everything you say. That's right.
Go!
Go! Go!
Whoa!
Don't watch, turn your heads.
Turn your heads.
Mai Ling, turn your head.
What happened?
Come on. Come on.
Giddyup. Giddyup.
Busted foreleg on that big sorrel.
Afternoon.
To you as well.
Whoa.
Are you boys local or just passing through?
Heading north.
Up from old Mexico?
No, from Navarra.
Navarra, Spain. We're Basque.
A friend or enemy?
A friend, I think.
Yes, a friend.
What's your name?
Valentin Ugalde.
Print Ritter.
Now, how's it out east of here?
You been there?
We're heading north.
Some Paiutes jumped the reservation.
Thanks for the heads up.
Now, let me ask you something.
Can I buy one of them sheep off you?
We're about played out on rabbit these days.
You buy the lamb,
I'll cook it for you tonight.
A new menu tonight.
- Yeah?
- Lamb.
Sounds good to me.
Man says there's Paiute trouble to the east.
Recommend we change course.
We go south there's nothing but
blowed out country all the way to Ogden.
Let's head north.
You're the boss.
Sure does smell good.
There.
They overcook and ruin the lamb.
Am I doing this right?
Yes.
Girls.
Try that. No?
No, we don't eat that, but thanks.
No? All right.
That stuff stinks.
We've been using the wrong bait.
- Try this here.
- Oh, yeah.
- You know what, give me one.
- Here we go.
I got it. Give me that one.
- Give it here.
- Oh, so good.
It's okay. Try that.
Go on.
Yeah.
First peanuts, and now this.
- Here you go, ladies.
- Try some of Mr Ritter's biscuits.
All right, come on. Thank you.
I tell you, Nephew,
we were fishing with the wrong bait.
Go in there, Hank.
And now, One, Two, Three, Four.
Where's Number Two?
Gilpin, cut one of them biscuits in half,
put some more jam on it for Number Two.
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah.
Where is Number Two? Where's she at?
She don't look good.
Hell, man, she's on fire.
Is she dying?
Hank, what do you make of this?
What's that?
Let's see.
That's a tick.
Probably tick fever.
That ain't good.
No, it's as bad as milk fever is
in young ones.
Let me go get these girls
and we'll check them for ticks, too.
- What else can I do?
- You're doing it.
You got any pull with the Almighty,
you might wanna speak up for her.
We're not properly equipped or suited
to take care of these girls, I tell you.
Let's pay our respects.
Mai Ling.
We wish you a good journey.
Come on.
Goodbye, Mai Ling, little sister.
You have anything you want to say?
Said it last night.
Okay.
The second time I've done this.
It don't get any easier.
We're all travellers in this world.
From the sweet grass to the packing house.
Birth till death.
We travel between the eternities.
Nephew.
Whoa.
Howdy.
Horse took a wrong step in a creek
a ways back and snapped his cannon bone.
Whoa!
Got a cheque here. Think you could cash it?
How long's a man got to stay in prison
to come out with $17.45?
Awful nosy, ain't you?
Hitch that team up, and let's go!
- Hey.
- You heard him.
Hey there.
Come here, darling. Have a seat on my lap.
Glad to see your business has been
good to you since I've been away.
Your timing couldn't be any better.
- Really?
- Really.
Remember Billy Fender?
Captain Billy Fender?
That's the one.
That's the kind of a shit-house rat
you always want to stay upwind of.
I don't pay people for taking baths.
I sent him to pick up and deliver back to me
a load of Chinese girls I bought
from an associate in San Francisco.
Well, he's way overdue.
Knowing him, he's probably
drunk on his ass and hobbling all your girls.
I got a proposition for you.
Yep?
I'll pay you to go find him
and bring those girls back to me.
No.
Maybe later.
Right now all I want is a bottle
and some trim.
I got some new gals
I can turn you loose with.
What about Nola?
Is she still around, Nola?
Why don't you try some of the new talent?
I kind of had my mind set on Nola
for some time now.
Coming through.
Hello, Nola.
It's been a while.
Where have you been, Ed?
Oh, I think you know where I've been.
I figured you must have moved on
to other business.
Yeah, right.
Working for the government.
Three cents a day
making little rocks out of big rocks.
Been thinking a lot about you.
Not much else to do.
Does Kate know you're here?
Oh, yeah.
She sent me up especially for you.
You got orders to wear me out.
Come on, boy.
Come on.
Problem?
Not sure.
Whoa.
Move off to their right. Keep your distance.
Watch me.
- Hank, let's hold up here.
- Yes, sir.
No, don't do that.
Just watch me.
All right.
Hold up there, mister.
Hold up, mister.
Don't I know you?
What's your name?
My name is my own business.
I suggest you tend to yours.
Will you give me the road, sir?
Hold on!
I know who you are.
I go by several names.
I doubt any of them are your concern.
If you refuse to let me pass,
you'll soon learn a few of them.
Well, would one be Jack Ketch?
If that's who you think I am,
then you know better than to block my path.
Hold on there, mister!
Don't let him get away! Kill him.
And you kill his horse.
Big Bob.
I got him. I got him dead centre.
Right through the heart. I got him.
Stay back, Heck. Don't go there, stay back.
I got him.
Yes, sir.
What the hell was that? We killed two men!
About as close as you'll ever get
to seeing the Grim Reaper.
Bullshit. Make sense to me, Uncle.
- Boys, I'm talking death.
- Horseshit.
We just killed two men
and all their livestock!
I told you to stay back!
That there is most likely
the infamous Smallpox Bob. I'm sure of it.
Probably killed more red men than any
one man in the Northwest.
- Hell, I ain't never heard of him.
- I have.
He trades blankets and hides with the tribes,
mostly infected with smallpox.
Smallpox, typhoid, tuberculosis.
He was death travelling the country,
but no more.
Well, if there was ever an evil bastard
worth killing, I reckon he's the one.
No more evil than the ones that hire him.
Boys, I tell you, we gotta tend to this mess.
That's the second rope I've lost
to some worthless son of a bitch.
I'd say both were for a good cause.
You really think that fellow killed
that many Indians, Mr Ritter?
Of course I do, Hank.
That's why I killed him.
What do you think they will do with us?
It's not just up to our protectors.
If we are to live, we must have courage.
I didn't see you help Ye Fung
when that man attacked her.
Look, she is coming.
There. Right up there.
It's only the moon.
You think she will save us?
Ghee Moon, enough. That's enough.
She comes over the fields of our village.
We must be close to home.
You are right.
She will follow us.
And lead us home.
She is barely visible.
But the moon is like us.
Sometimes she has to hide.
But she stands strong.
So we must be good to one another.
We must be brave.
Gilpin.
Hey.
Wake up, it's your shift.
Oh, Lord, I thought I just dozed off.
Yeah. About four hours ago.
Wouldn't mind getting
a full night's sleep sometime soon.
Well, you can when we get to Cariboo.
Are we really going in there?
Yeah. That's what my uncle said.
- Wake me up in four hours.
- Okay.
Damn it.
Herd is pretty settled.
I'll stay out here and watch things.
I want you to take the girls into this town
and see if you can find some
civil authority to take them.
Take Heck with you.
- I thought you'd be the one to do that.
- Well, you thought wrong.
Well, why here? Why now?
Well, you're the one that's so hot
to get rid of them.
- According to who?
- You.
Now just go and get it done.
Why did they argue?
Wait.
Heck, get everybody in the wagon.
We're going into town.
I got to be honest, Tom. I'm not so sure
about this. I think they might...
Well, you know what? I don't have a vote.
You don't have a vote.
That's becoming evident.
Just get them in the wagon.
- All right, ladies. Let's go.
- Tom.
We're going into town.
Let's go, girls, come on.
I still ain't seen Billy Fender
and that load of Chinese girls I bought.
- I'm still offering to pay you to find them.
- No.
I got business of my own in mind.
All you know how to do
is what got you sent up for.
It's small fry that gets sent up.
I'm looking to get big.
- You could be my banker.
- Lf I'm your bank, you're working for me.
You're a good businesswoman.
You know how to get a return
on your investment.
$500 will get me started just fine.
Howdy.
- Whoa.
- Good day to you, sir.
- You be needing a room?
- Yes, sir.
Two rooms for one night.
It's $4, up front.
Is there a mayor in this town?
Not hardly.
- What about a town council?
- Nope.
- Do you have a sheriff?
- No, sir, not anymore.
Mister,
this town is as rough as cob.
It's hard on lawmen.
Hard enough to put two of them
in the ground over the last three years.
Well, who's in charge?
Well, the town sort of works on
a live-and-let-live basis with
a touch of every man for himself thrown in.
Ain't the kind of place where you check
your firearms when you get to town.
One minute.
Biggest operator is Miss Kate Becker.
Big Rump Kate.
She runs the Southern Cross Saloon.
Who are them girls, anyway?
They're with me.
Well, these rooms are for sleeping,
not for cooching.
Good. Because these girls are tired
and they need their sleep.
Well, that room down at the end
has got cots for six men,
so I guess you ought to have enough space.
You know where a fellow can get a bath?
- You speak English?
- Yes.
- My name's Tom Harte. What's your name?
- Lung Hay. My name is Lung Hay.
Long Hay.
Dragon. Lung.
Dragon.
Well, Mr Lung Hay,
through a series of circumstances,
fate has placed four Chinese girls
in the hands of me and my uncle.
They got room for our horses
over at the livery.
- Good.
- Who's this?
- He's our new interpreter, Mr Lung Hay.
- Lung Hay.
Lord knows we need it.
All right.
Tell them that I'm sorry about
everything that's happened to them.
But we'll try and find a safe place for them.
No harm will come to them.
They say they want to stay with you.
Please to be good as to not leave them.
No, no.
No, they can't live on the trail with us.
Ask him why.
This is an old story.
There's no place safe for them.
Nowhere.
They will be like meat before hungry dogs.
They'll be devoured.
Not to make you angry,
but it would be more of a kindness
to cut their throats than to leave them here.
But they can't stay with us.
We've got to get our horses
through the passes before winter.
This whole land is not safe.
You tell him that.
Could you watch them
while we go get some supper
and maybe feed them some of your food?
- Yes, I can do.
- Thank you, sir.
Goodbye, Old Paint, I'm leaving Cheyenne
Leaving Cheyenne
On to Montana
Goodbye, Old Paint
leaving Cheyenne
My little girls.
Adis,
One, Three, Four and Five.
It seems like we're drifting from our purpose
of delivering those horses to Sheridan.
But I'm not as hard-hearted
about those girls as you might think.
I'm not gonna just chuck them
at the first opportunity.
Nobility, no boundaries.
- Evening, gents.
- Evening, ma'am.
I'm Kate Becker. Big Rump Kate.
How's your supper? You doing all right?
We are, thank you.
Nothing like a bath, some clean britches,
a little whisky and a steak
to make a man feel almost human again.
Well, that ain't all a man need to feel human.
How about finishing off the evening
with some high-dollar sporting gals?
Well, I reckon a fellow can only handle
so much humanity at one time, ma'am.
Hey, Rose.
I call her my English Rose. Newest gal
to work the line. Come here, sweetie.
Rose, we got a stout lad here that
needs the knots worked out of him.
I think I speak for both of us
when I say I think we'll pass.
Well, maybe you prefer getting some trim
from those Celestials you brung into town.
You boys thinking about
getting into the skin trade?
Well, let me set you straight.
The gold I mine from this burg,
I don't get from digging.
There ain't a shot of whisky,
a hand of poker,
or any fellow that wants to dip his wick
that I don't get a cut of.
We're just passing through.
You know about a Billy Fender?
Captain Billy Fender?
Those girls were bought and paid for,
and you know it.
I don't give a damn about Billy Fender.
But they're mine!
Well, it's a stupid sack of shit
who believes he can waltz into this country
with a wagon full of women
and thinks he ain't in for trouble.
You kiss your mama with that mouth?
What do you take for your troubles?
We came here to eat and
have a little bit of whisky. That's it.
Come on, mister. Everything has a price.
Not everything.
Come on, Rose.
What's going on?
Come on, damn it!
Hold her still!
Come on, darling.
You know you want it. Come on!
Stay down!
Get over here. Get over here.
Stay back.
You girls get together. Stay back.
You like to spoil women? Do you?
Come on.
- Will you take me with you?
- Go on.
Come on.
Boys.
You ready to donate your nuts?
Get your hands away from those pistols.
Do it now!
What about my property?
That's the price of being a capitalist, lady.
Now back off!
Heck.
Let's go, Heck.
Just remember,
it's money that greases the wheels, mister.