WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
Now, I'm gonna say something to you
that I hear nearly every day.
"I need a change."
You ever notice how the people
that say it always stay the same?
That's because change finds you.
- MAN: Oh, oh...
- WOMAN: No.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
No! Fuck!
No fucking way!
Damn it!
Fuck!
(WIND BLOWS)
WOMAN: Erm... Yeah,
it's Earlene. I hate to ask this.
I know it's really awkward, but...
can you lend me some cash?
Nina, hey. I need to
borrow some money.
Nothing. I'll pay you back.
Tom, yeah!
I know, I know.
It's been a long time.
(SIGHS)
No problem. Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
("EVERY TURN" BY MATT VAN SCHIE)
♪ Now you don't feel the same
♪ Walking round in the rain
♪ Now it's your turn to
♪ What you got left to lose?
♪ The road is long
♪ But can we stay strong?
♪ Every turn
♪ The risk is us
♪ So do we give up?
♪ Every turn
(TURNS RADIO ON)
(TURNS TV ON)
(WHISTLING)
"Experience is the name
we give our mistakes."
So what does that make you?
- What's your name?
- Earlene.
- What's yours?
- I'm Bruno.
EARLENE:
Bruno? That's kinda butch for a boy.
It's what my folks wanted.
- Where are you from?
- Australia.
- Wow. Are you on vacation?
- No. Are you?
Hmm.
Yeah, not exactly. You know,
it's kind of more like a break.
So, Bruno...
Do you ever think that...
- Ah, fuck it. Never mind.
- Go on.
Do you ever think...
that tomorrow can be so
fucking different from today?
I think I only live the tomorrows.
Helps you get past the yesterdays.
(LAUGHS)
I like you.
I think.
(LAUGHS)
("DARKNESS" BY DU TONC)
- EARLENE: They didn't ID you?
- BRUNO: Nope.
EARLENE: This fucking country.
BRUNO:
I think I look older than I am.
EARLENE: You're a baby.
- BRUNO: Where are you going?
- EARLENE: Back to my hotel.
- BRUNO: Let me walk you back.
- EARLENE: Let go of me.
BRUNO: I'm not letting you
walk home alone like this.
EARLENE:
Right. My knight in shining armour.
Why don't you go conquer the other
women like the rest of the guys?
- BRUNO: I'm not like other guys.
- EARLENE: Get your hands off me.
Fuck.
I'm lost.
Come on, drunkie!
Is this your art?
Er, yeah. Although I've kinda
moved away from that style.
Yeah. It gives you headaches.
To new friends.
Nice try.
("AIRPLANES" BY UTAH CAROL)
Are all these yours, cowboy? (LAUGHS)
I mean, don't sweat it.
It's OK if you live with your mom.
I'm sorry. I get a little
mouthy when I'm drunk.
You're a good kid.
What's this?
BRUNO: What's it look like?
- They're different parts.
- Parts of what?
Parts of a whole.
- What's this?
- Oh, that's just a dream I had.
I've always wanted to go to Paris.
It's on the other side of
the world, though, so...
There's an Eiffel Tower about
a six-hour drive from here.
- Really?
- Yeah.
It's a replica.
It's what Americans do best.
Wow. I would love that.
Stay here tonight.
WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
That was Utah Carol with "Airplanes".
(RETCHING)
(CAR APPROACHES)
Shit!
We have to go!
We have to go right now!
Come on! Come on!
- Jesus.
- Come on!
(BRUNO LAUGHS)
I'm calling the police!
They're gonna catch you!
EARLENE: You gonna tell me what
the hell just happened back there?
I was couch surfing. On the sly.
Jesus. You've got a lot
of explaining to do.
- I don't have to tell you anything.
- Er, yeah, you do.
I just unknowingly committed
a crime back there!
- I'm an accomplice to a criminal.
- I'll pay them back.
You're gonna pay them back... Great.
- (LAUGHS)
- It's not funny.
You are gonna be a bad influence.
So, how do you do it?
Well, you go on
vacation rentals sites.
You say you want someone's place for a
few days, you know, a week, a month.
Tag them along and delay
the deposit. Then you pull out.
They won't cancel their trip,
so you stay there while they're gone.
- And you break in?
- Yeah.
- That's pretty smart.
- It is. I don't act alone, though.
How many of you are there?
There's too many at the moment.
People are catching on.
Well, you don't know that.
Maybe she just had a shitty vacation.
What's going on? Where are you going?
BRUNO: To do a deal.
- Are you on drugs?
- What are you, my mum or something?
Listen. I think you're really cool.
I'll see you around.
MAN: (ON RADIO) It's LA Talk Radio.
We say what we want.
WOMAN: ON RADIO) It's payday
Friday, dudes and dudettes.
Who's up for tearing a trail
down Hollywood Boulevard
and etching their names
on one of those stars?
Watch out for mine, though.
You'll have to wipe off the
dog poo to get a look at it.
In the meantime, this is
Matt Van Schie, "Airboy".
WOMAN: You're not usually like this.
What I'm saying is if you
don't want to do it...
BRUNO: I'm fine.
- BRUNO: I want to do it, Kris.
- WOMAN: Ta.
Kris-ta.
How many times do I
have to tell you that?
Whatever. Just follow my lead, OK?
Don't.
What is it?
We need to open up. They're waiting.
WOMAN: Hey.
Hey, D. So, what's up?
What's going on?
Same as last time.
It's more if... you know.
Yeah, I know. But this time,
we're calling the shots.
He's not... Is he?
Good luck.
Hello, Krista.
- This is Bruno.
- Hello, Bruno.
Follow me.
Why don't you just...? You here.
There!
Now I can get a good look at you.
Kris...
What are you?
PAIS. Partial androgen
insensitivity syndrome.
"Syndrome."
I hate that word. "Syndrome."
- Were you aware of this?
- Yeah.
MAN: But you're not quite sure
what we do here, are you?
Chromosomes. The building
blocks of us. And you.
I study people like yourselves
and gather information
for scientists, paediatricians,
psychologists, psychiatrists.
But mostly for parents.
The people who created you.
They want to make the right
decisions for their kids.
We help them make those decisions.
Take off your clothes.
Yes? How may I help you?
I'm looking for a guy with dark hair.
Tall, dark skin, erm...
I'm sorry. We're not authorised to give
any information about our clients.
Yeah, I know. I'm a concerned relative.
Can you tell me where he is?
No. All our patients sign
confidentiality agreements.
They're all over 18. We're not...
You can't go back there!
I am calling the authorities!
(CAMERA CLICKS)
What the...?
Jesus! Come on!
Who the fuck do you think you are?
Someone who gives more
than half a shit about you.
Now are you coming or not?
You just cost me a shit ton of money!
For what? Do you have any idea
what that man was doing up there?
Did you ask any questions?
- Did you sign on a dotted line?
- No!
So what made you think there was
anything legit about that place?
When people take photographs,
it's forever. There are ramifications.
If you needed money,
you could have just asked me.
- Can I have some money?
- That's not the point.
- Why not?
- Because I don't have any! God, Jesus!
Just get in the car.
(SIGHS) Do you know what?
It's none of my fucking business.
Hey.
You got any more tricks lined up?
WOMAN: I was sucked in.
I'll need you to forward me all
contact you had with the person.
Did you guys ever speak on the phone?
Here's the note they left.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Oh, sorry.
OFFICER 2:
I don't think they'll come back.
Look. It's like a child wrote it.
Someone who knew they were doing
something bad, but had no hard feelings.
This is LA, Cookie.
Get with the programme.
It's signed with a kiss.
Then they're crazy, like all
the other dopes in this town.
Trust me. I know.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Rise and shine, freeloaders!
We weren't stealing anything.
We were occupying.
Well, now you get to occupy a nice
room at the LAPD Continental.
My dad's a lawyer. Ow!
COOKIE: Shut up.
(BUZZING)
OFFICER 1:
What am I not getting here?
Jeez, what's his problem?
Is it that time of the month?
There aren't enough
tissues for those issues.
- Word, girl.
- I know.
- BRUNO: What did you do to my hair?
- I smartened it up.
BRUNO: Yeah, thanks.
How did we get in?
(BOTH LAUGH)
What have I created?
- Is this for me?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Wow.
What do you say about taking a
trip together? Just you and me.
Why?
Because I figure you could
use a vacation. I could too.
I could take you to
see the Eiffel Tower.
I mean, it's not Paris, but it's as
close as you'll get to the real thing.
What's wrong with you?
Forget it.
There's nothing wrong with me.
I'm just a bit mixed up, that's all.
It's a great place.
There's tons of room.
Yeah. Bring the gang. Bye.
EARLENE: Sharing the love?
We've never really belonged,
so we're more inclined to share.
EARLENE: Hop in.
WOMAN: (ON RADIO) It's nothing but
clear skies and blazing heat today, folks.
Just like any other day.
But is it just me or is there
something in the air?
Oops. Guess it's just me.
EARLENE: Half a mile for a pee?
I'm not a cougar yet, you know.
MAN: (ON RADIO) LA Talk Radio.
We say what we want.
WOMAN: (ON RADIO) You ever
noticed how when you drink milk,
you can get one of those moustaches?
Yeah... Yeah. (LAUGHS)
BRUNO: This woman's nuts.
She also happens to have
great taste in music.
And besides, I can relate.
- Hand me a beer, will you?
- You're driving.
OK, make it a light.
- Alcohol gives you memory loss.
- That it does.
You should try it sometime.
EARLENE: Are you gonna
start being nice to me now?
Like the Bruno I first met, huh?
I'm sorry.
So what was that doctor
gonna do back there?
He's not really a doctor.
He's more like a researcher.
He takes pictures of people who are
different and sells them on to fixers.
What do they fix?
Problems. Or rather,
society's problems.
I don't think you have to worry
about that. I mean, you look good.
You do. You look nice and healthy
and robust.
(LAUGHS)
You know, you remind
me of when I was a kid.
Yeah, you do.
Man, I was just trying to
figure out who the fuck I was
and what the hell I was all about.
Nobody ever says that they
want to raise a teenager.
I mean, it's always about the baby.
You know, the baby, the baby,
this little bundle of joy.
Nobody ever talks about
raising a teenager.
I mean, no wonder all these fucking
kids are so lost, you know?
They were never meant to be.
Yeah, well, people change.
Stop eating that.
Jesus! Did anybody ever teach
you about nutrition? God!
140 calories. Zero fat, trans fat...
Yeah, and vitamins?
Minus numbers don't count.
All manmade shit is bad.
And I think I'm gonna
go find a bathroom.
I'll be right back.
(SIGHS)
Earlene?
(CHURCH ORGAN PLAYS)
EARLENE: Ah!
- You found me.
- I had a feeling.
You know, there were toilets
back at the gas station.
Yeah. Yeah.
But they're not as clean
as the holy ones.
(LAUGHS)
They don't come with
the freebies, either.
Whoa! Jesus is such a giver.
Yeah. Good girls go to heaven.
Bad girls rule the world.
Here.
- No!
- Yeah.
(LAUGHS)
- Did you get these from back there?
- Yeah.
My God! It's totally a sign.
The Eiffel Tower!
What makes it so special, anyway?
It's one of a kind.
The artists of Paris
petitioned against it.
They thought it was ugly
and that it shouldn't be built.
They were afraid of
something different.
But then over time,
they grew to like it.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hang on.
I'm gonna hang on to these. OK?
I'm gonna wear them for the
perfect moment. Trust me.
- OK?
- OK.
- Yeah?
OK.
So, are we getting
out of here or what?
- EARLENE: OK. But twin beds.
- BRUNO: Sure.
Howdy.
- (BOTH LAUGH)
- EARLENE: God!
Billy, you're interfering
with the signal.
Fashion TV's gone blurry.
EARLENE:
He was totally looking at you!
Please. He doesn't want
my tired old snatch.
He's totally a queen. Bottoms up.
- You think?
- Hmm. Yes, honey. Please.
- What, is he your type?
- What's a type?
I'm gonna get some smokes.
- I'll be right back.
- Cool.
Billy! Bring the Kardashians back.
My knight in shining armour. Oh!
You guys don't have any
T-booster, do you?
- It's for testosterone.
- MAN: No. Sorry, ma'am.
- You don't have anything like that?
- No.
Fuck.
Shit!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WHISPERS) Jesus Christ!
Bruno, why did you lock the door?
What, you don't trust me, huh? Huh?
Why did you lock the door?
I'm just gonna come
right out and say it.
And it doesn't matter, OK?
I didn't make a point of it earlier
because I wanted you to know that...
I'm fine with it.
I'm fine with you being...
whatever it is you wanna be.
I let go of a lot of
bad things in my life.
Turns out they were the only
things keeping me company.
I was alone for a really long time.
Then you came along and it's
like I really know who I am.
I just never knew what it
was people wanted me to be.
EARLENE: Open the door.
You don't have to
prove anything to me.
WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
Pop quiz, frog lovers!
Win a romantic trip to France if you
can answer tnis simple question.
How tall is the Eiffel Tower?
1063 feet.
Call in now for a chance to win.
Remember, no snail mail.
("TWO LOVE" BY MATT VAN SCHIE)
BILLY: Oh, oops!
Sorry, bud. I was in
my own little world.
I'd give you something to
dry yourself with, but...
As you can see...
You wouldn't mind if I...? Thanks.
It's good. It's good for your teeth.
There's no calcium.
Good for your jaw, then. Mastication.
Billy! We are not staying here.
They don't have wi-ﬁ and
the coffee's not organic.
BRUNO: Hey.
EARLENE:
We gotta go. I packed your stuff.
What is it?
My boyfriend's car.
Come on.
EARLENE: We need your help.
Can we get a ride?
- Now?
- Like right now.
Follow me.
- You ladies holding tight?
- Yeah. Why?
Cos this jeep ain't mine.
Billy!
You stay on board,
- you're officially accomplices.
- Billy! This is my dad's car!
(SCREAMS)
BRUNO: Go!
You bitch! Billy! Come back here!
BILLY: Yee-ha!
Send your dad my love!
Shouldn't we be
sticking to the highway?
Not when you got heat up
your ass. Carjack virgins, huh?
Alright, you know what?
We're usually a little bit more careful
when it comes to hitching with dudes.
We're a dangerous breed.
You should be.
Don't worry yourselves.
I'm a new species.
What's that?
The type that doesn't reproduce.
The world doesn't need
more people like me.
- Why?
- Because I steal.
Girls and guys. Hearts and cars.
The former I break, the latter I take.
Great! We got Dean Moriarty here.
What's your problem?
You all dried up?
You know what?
Watch your fucking mouth.
You know, you remind me of
that actress from that movie.
- Susan Sarandon?
- That's the one.
- I've thought that too.
- Susan Sarandon? She's fucking old!
When she was younger.
- That buddy movie.
- The Banger Sisters?
- That's the one!
- That's it.
Well, if that makes you Goldie Hawn,
then I got the better end of the stick.
- EARLENE: No.
- BILLY: I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- EARLENE: No. Fuck!
- BILLY: No, listen.
EARLENE: No. No, no! Fuck!
No fucking way! No fucking way!
We are in the middle of no... Shit!
Damn it.
Fuck!
- Prognosis?
- Not good.
Isn't this great?
And here I was, thinking we
were all on the same page.
- Going off road really worked out, huh?
- Hey, you two are the ones on the run.
You fucking dick.
- What's her deal?
- Period?
BILLY: So now, I'm just
going on and on and on.
- No family, no ties, no regrets.
- So you steal cars to keep moving?
I thought I found what
I was looking for.
Turns out we'd fallen in love
with an idea, not each other.
The problem was, I was a long way from
home and I'd already said goodbye.
Here. Temperature's
gonna drop pretty soon.
BILLY: Well, it's not Vegas.
- But it'll do.
- It's beautiful.
Let's go!
WOMAN: (ON RADIO) It's getting
late and the sun's gone down.
You've just clocked off
from a hard day's work.
Hubby's home with a six-pack of
beer watching "Wheel of Fortune",
but it's karaoke night
down at the saloon.
What are you gonna do?
(SCOTTISH ACCENT) Down the brown!
(SCOTTISH ACCENT) You'd know
all about that, wouldn't you? But I...
prefer to sink the pink.
Any hole's a goal.
MAN 1:
Ever fucked a girl on her period?
MAN 2: Just cos I'm straight,
doesn't mean I've poked the jam.
- Of course I fucking have.
- Parted the red waves?
Aye. Damn right. Just put
a towel down. It's all good.
- Guys.
- Fuck's sake.
You guys, you guys,
shut the fuck up, alright?
- There's a lady right here.
- MAN 2: Are you on your period?
- BARMAID: Fairy talk.
- MAN 1: We're speaking Scottish.
BARMAID: If a woman's bitchy,
she's on her period.
MAN 1: There's a big difference.
In Scotland, they deep-fry everything.
Put the peanut down or else
your brains will be in that bowl.
- How did you get here?
- Our truck broke down.
- Did you use a map?
- No.
Give me that!
I am so sorry. She's been
itching to use that toy.
Hey! You're lucky to be alive.
We're the only people out
here within 100 miles.
- Where are we?
- Nowhere.
- What kind of place is that?
- Any place but somewhere, honey.
A place where nobody can find us.
- Unless it's by accident, of course.
- Or by fate.
Fate, my ass.
- COOKIE: No signal?
- No sleep?
Lucky me.
So, why are we here?
This property went up online
as one of the vacation rentals.
Lo and behold, the tenant
got screwed last minute,
so now we just gotta sit and wait.
- Who were you trying to call?
- Just a friend.
Yeah. Right.
- What's it to you?
- Nothing.
Just thought maybe you were
trying to call your boyfriend.
If you're into guys, that's fine
by me. Just a hunch is all.
You know, if you weren't right...
It wouldn't make any difference.
I didn't mean it as a slur.
Well, Miss Know-it-All,
you're right and you're wrong.
I was trying to call my ex.
Good for you.
So, are you into girls?
Is that how you can tell?
Now, why would you think that?
Is it cos I carry a gun?
- Cos I bust dudes' asses for a day job?
- Women commit crimes too.
Is it cos I look in a rear-view
mirror or a side-view mirror
more than a compact mirror?
Perish the thought. Don't make
it out like it's such a bad thing.
- What?
- Being attracted to the same sex.
Well, you're making it sound
like it's a bad thing not to be!
OFFICER 1:
I bet you're a church girl, huh?
Gospel.
I bet the only bang you
get is from a tambourine.
Sorry. That was out of line.
I had a thing with a girl once.
She was Latina.
Her name was Carmen.
Didn't feel anything, though.
No chemistry. That's how I knew.
And here I am, thinking the tough cookie
had a chocolate chip on her shoulder.
- Isn't that supposed to be you?
- Uh-uh. White chocolate.
COOKIE: That explains a lot.
Yeah, well. Sweet tooth.
So, after the stakeout, we still need to
get four more tickets to fill our quota.
We can catch some jaywalkers
while we're at it.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Love that shit.
(GUITAR MUSIC)
(BRUNO SINGS)
♪ Everything is bursting at the seams
♪ Feels like you're treading water
♪ All the while
♪ The riptide's getting stronger
♪ Carrying you to
Give me that.
I'm the alcoholic around here.
So, what's your deal, buddy?
It's like there's just something
about you you're not telling us.
- Trust me, it takes one to know one.
- You don't have to tell him anything.
It's fine.
I should get used to it.
To explaining, I guess.
A few years ago I decided to get lost,
so that when I found myself,
I'd know where and who I was.
I thought it was this rebellious act,
but I kind of learned that it
didn't really change anything.
I can't escape the person
who's inside of me,
and I'm kind of learning
to love that person.
- We all want a drink, right?
- EARLENE: Yeah.
BILLY: Sure.
My mother produced two eggs.
XY for a boy and XX for a girl.
Now, normally this
would create twins.
But the eggs merged and
a chimera was formed.
A boy was born with a uterus,
an ovary and a fallopian tube.
A boy whose parents
were fucking terrified.
A boy who never saw his sister,
but can always feel her spirit.
Can't you just have them removed?
She's a part of who I am.
Well...
You're drinking for two, aren't you?
(LAUGHTER)
BILLY: We're learning new
things about each other, OK?
EARLENE:
Alright, fair enough. Fair enough.
(THUNDER)
("GO ON YERSELF" BY AARON WRIGHT)
♪ Who no one knew had died
♪ With a poet whose
friend was a painter
♪ Yet a hero was left unsung
♪ They took me in
♪ Don't know where I've been
♪ Half of the time you
know you're asking why
- Whoops.
- What?
It's fine, though.
It's not that bad. It's fine.
- Disgusting.
- It's the five-second rule, big boy.
Get off, you arse bandit!
Ah, Sleeping Beauty's risen!
Sit down.
Let me get you a juice, eh?
He's still pished.
- Leave him alone.
- What happened?
MAN 1: Well, you were asleep in
my vegetable patch. In the buff
MAN 2: Melted.
MAN 1: We won't tell the Sheriff
Happens to me all the time.
- Too bloody right it does.
- Fuck off.
What are you guys doing here?
We used to be strippers out in Vegas.
- The Hot Toddies!
- Something like that.
We were the toast of Vegas.
Then decided, fuck it, it's time
to do something a bit different,
you know what I mean?
- So what are you doing now?
- You asked for it.
♪ I'll forever walk
these streets again
♪ And forever be
knocking on your door
- You get the idea.
- Yeah.
We were going to start
touring as a band,
but being out in the desert,
you get a wee bit lazy.
It kinda does funny things to you.
- That's debatable.
- Yeah.
What about you? Where are you headed?
I don't know.
Maybe I've arrived.
♪ Go on
♪ Yerself
WOMAN: (ON RADIO) That was Aaron Wright,
"Go On Yerself". A song from Scotland,
who are apparently trying to
separate from the United Kingdom.
A fresh start apart
or better together?
(CHUCKLES) We've all been there.
♪ I never wanna drink again
♪ Don't crowd me and my friends
(SINGS UNDER HER BREATH)
Lift! Lift! There.
(SINGS)
Oh! I'm sorry. So sorry.
Alright? Here we go. Alright.
There you go. And there we go.
What is this?
What? Turn that frown upside down?
It's a face, dummy.
Now it's herpes.
I don't know why you have to be
so fussy, Cher. Bon appétit!
(RETCHING)
Earlene?
You alright?
Bad dream?
I wish.
- You look thirsty.
- EARLENE: Oh, my God.
Thanks. It's good to be on this
side of the bar for a change.
So, how'd you end up here?
Dude, you should not ask that kind
of question in this kind of dump.
(LAUGHS) Why? What,
did you do something bad?
Did I do something bad?
Yeah, I suppose I did.
I used to be a showgirl.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Sounds tough.
It sure wasn't easy, let me tell ya.
Especially with a little rugrat
running around, you know?
The worst part was when he
found out what I was doing.
Oh, God.
It was OK at first, but...
I never saw the sun.
Fuck it. What's your story?
(LAUGHS)
Oh... I'm fine.
- Is that your son?
- Is that my son?
- Oh, my...
Don't tell me I look that
fucking old. Come on!
Hey, man, it can happen.
It can happen, alright?
I had mine at 16.
- True, that.
- OK?
You haven't seen the dark-haired
one around here, have you?
- (LAUGHS) Yeah, that girly looking one?
- Yeah.
Yeah, he's out back with
the Scottish dudes.
So, what happened to your kids?
I'm still trying to figure
out what happened to me.
I left a shitty situation,
changed my name, never looked back.
Well...
Do you miss them?
BARMAID: They're in a better place.
- Jean Goodsprings.
- Goodsprings. Isn't...
It's about seven miles
west of Jean, Nevada.
(LAUGHS) You picked a good one!
I like it! It fits, you know?
You know, everybody's
been someone else before.
The question always is,
who are you gonna be next?
- Cheers.
(HORN HONKS)
Planning on staying long?
I don't know. I like it here, though.
You like being alone, don't you?
Me too. Not him, though.
He thinks Mr Right's
gonna blow on through,
sweep him off his feet and take
him back to bonny Scotland.
- Is that not you?
- Are you kidding me? Pair of numpties.
What are you two
grannies moaning about?
Fuck off. He thinks
I'm a poof. With you.
(BELL RINGS)
Hurry up, you Scottish faggots.
Some of us have mouths to feed!
JEAN: It's worse than that.
Oh, it's fucking garbage,
but it gets you drunk.
When you're fucking 14. Fuck!
So anyways, we get to the park
and buy all this fucking shit.
"Get your picture taken."
We get the beanie hats with the names,
you know what I'm talking about?
- You remind me of my son.
- Where's he?
When he was 19,
he went to live with the Lord.
He was a force of nature.
A catalyst. Like you.
- What do you mean?
- Look around.
You come into my town
and you bring us change.
Life.
You bring me life.
Thank you.
You're a good kid.
Eat up.
JEAN: We were in Colorado, right?
(LAUGHS)
- We needed to score some pot, right?
- MAN: As you do.
JEAN: So I pretended I
was a high school kid...
- (TAPPING)
- Listen up, friends. Family.
I have an announcement to make.
You know, you could have
told me to my face...
instead of me hearing it from
somebody I don't even know.
- I thought we were in this together.
- BRUNO: Yeah. Well, I like it here.
What about Vegas, huh?
And the Eiffel Tower?
What's gotten into you?
Where did you get that?
From the last asshole
who let me down.
We're runaways, Earlene.
It's not about the destination.
Yeah, well, it still would have
been nice to get there.
BRUNO: I think I've found
what I'm looking for.
And what's that?
A family.
They're not your family, Bruno.
- Look, I know what you're thinking.
- No, you don't!
I'm so sick of people fucking telling me
what I'm thinking! What I'm feeling!
It's like I've got it wrong
for so fucking long.
It's like I'm finally
getting it right.
ENGLISH WOMAN:
Oh, look, there's someone.
I say, cooee! Cooee!
Do you happen to know where
we are? We're awfully lost.
Our sat nav sent us to
this godforsaken place.
WOMAN 2: We're parched.
Could you tell us where a pub is?
WOMAN 1:
A gin and tonic should do the trick.
- Then we'll be on our way.
- We don't take no euros.
- Neither do we.
- Oh! Welcome!
My name is Jessie. Y'all go on inside.
We'll be right with you, OK?
Y'all go on right up in there.
(LAUGHS)
See? I told you it
pays to be welcoming.
- Come on, lovey.
- I'm liking the concept.
OK!
WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
Now I don't know about you folks,
but I'm getting pretty
damn tired of this heat.
The weatherman tells me there's a big
depression heading up from Phoenix
that's carrying a lot of water,
so be prepared to get wet,
and enjoy some home alone time with me,
hostess with the mostess, Artie Duke,
providing some light for
when it all gets dark.
("I CRY AT FILMS" BY
BRIGHT LIGHT BRIGHT LIGHT)
There's somebody...
I think somebody wants a drink.
The bar's covered. Trust me.
(JEAN LAUGHS)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Come in.
I couldn't help but notice
the lovers' tiff back there.
We're not lovers.
You know, it's funny how you
always leave with more.
You're always welcome to stay.
Hey. Some alone time
will do you good.
And I can get you off the hooch.
I need the hooch.
No, you don't.
- I can't stay.
- Where you gonna go? Home?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
I... I'll go somewhere.
Anywhere but nowhere.
Well... Send me a card.
- When's your birthday?
- Middle of November.
Like my dad.
Hey.
You're not the chatty type, are you?
Not when it's expected of me.
A bit of a man of mystery, then. We get
plenty of them coming through here.
Do you work 'em out?
Not usually, no.
Funny, how people try
to figure each other out.
They don't always
like what they find.
Do you... do you have a lighter?
Thanks.
JESSIE:
Sheriff! The township needs...
And you were doing so well.
Earlene is leaving.
She reminds me of when we
first got here. Should we stay?
Should we go?
I'm almost done in here. Is there
anything else I can get you?
Make me look pretty tonight.
OK. Only if you wear
my Christmas present.
Ooh.
Polyester makes me itch.
Oh, you ungrateful cow!
You know how much this thing cost me?
A penny? A thousand?
- 700?
- (JESSIE GRUNTS)
- I'm sorry. I'm just cranky today.
- JESSIE: You're cranky every day.
- I remember when I wore this.
- At the Bellagio in '97.
The Bellagio was a bowl of
dust in '97. Check your facts.
Or was it at the Flamingo?
Or was it the Golden Nugget?
It was the Debbie Reynolds.
Oh! The Debbie Reynolds! Look at us!
She still has that same hairdo.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
We were so young then.
You know what they say.
Time heals all wounds.
Not all wounds.
♪ All your wishes
♪ Your wishes come true
♪ Your wishes come
(ALL CHEER)
JEAN: Yeah, Freebird!
OK. So, next time he goes
off at me like that...
Oh! Look at you!
Just gonna do a little
something for you guys, OK?
(TAPPING)
- Uh-huh!
- (ALL CHEER)
This town! I just need... I need...
♪ You come here looking for
♪ Your hopes and dreams
♪ The funny thing is you leave here
♪ On your knees
♪ I've seen better people than you
♪ Go and tear their lives away
♪ Cos they can't tell
the difference between
♪ If it's night or day
♪ Be yourself
♪ Nobody else
Are you coming?
- Hey.
- ♪ Be yourself
- I need to ask you a favour.
- Name it.
I need a ride.
- Give me five.
- I'll be in my cabin.
♪ Nobody else
♪ Be yourself
Happy memories.
MAN 1:
Yeah, well, I guess I've been lucky.
BILLY: I've never been to Scotland.
I've never even left the USA.
You're a traveller. You should...
You should visit.
Is that an invitation?
It could be one of the destinations.
Go to a lot of interesting
places along the way.
- Where are you from, anyway?
- Oklahoma.
That would be a good place to start.
You wouldn't like it.
- Tell me about this.
- I got that done years ago.
It's... It's just a lighthouse.
It's on fire.
I just like the fact
that it's on fire.
Sometimes things that seem
really safe and strong
need saving as well
sometimes, you know?
Yeah.
(MAN 1 SIGHS)
It's not just going to be
another son of one-night...
It's been really a long time.
Me too.
What's up?
I never was good at goodbyes.
- Please don't leave.
- I have to go back.
Why?
OK. You really wanna know?
I'm pregnant.
- With who?
- An asshole.
It's funny how you make the same
mistakes your parents did, huh?
BRUNO: What are you going to do?
Keep it.
You've got your family.
Now I've got mine.
I'll see you around.
("NEVER MESS WITH SUNDAY" BY YPPAH)
- LAPD!
- Hands behind your back.
- Hands where I can see 'em.
- Stay where you are.
OFFICER 1: Hey. Now are
you gonna be like all the rest
or are you gonna cut us some slack?
(PHONE RINGS)
(VOICES OVER POLICE RADIO)
Listen, how would you like it
if someone moved into your
home without you knowing?
I've never had a home.
And that's why we do it.
Cos we've got nothing to lose.
He taught us that.
Who?
Please don't hurt him.
He's been hurt enough.
Bruno!
Where is he? Where's Bruno?
- We don't know.
- I thought he was still here.
- Who saw him last?
- Me. I saw him.
- He split. He said he was going home.
- He doesn't have a home!
Honey, I know it's difficult,
but sometimes people leave,
not because they want to hurt anyone,
but because they have to.
- He didn't have to do anything.
- JEAN: Dude, wait a second.
He just said he had some family
crap he had to take care of.
Can I get a ride?
- Listen...
- I'll come back.
ARTIE: (ON RADIO)
OK, I've got a letter here from...
Well, let's just call her Amanda.
Now, when I read this,
it made me think real hard.
It reads, "Dear Artie. I'm in such a
low piece, I don't know what to do."
"And if I stick this
through to the end,
well, it would all
have been for him."
"The kids, the house, everything."
"I think I'm beginning
to change my mind."
(KNOCKS LOUDLY)
MAN: Who is it?
Was it your kids that did this?
Erm, no. No, I'm just
a concerned neighbour
from down the street. What happened?
Some crazy kids broke in
and trashed the place.
No respect for other
people's property.
Those of us that live in the real
world have to pick up the pieces.
They've done it all over the city.
There's a ringleader.
They've got him now.
They'll set him straight.
I blame the parents.
Hey!
Sydney!
COOKIE: Is this the place?
Yeah. It's the place.
You got ties? Boyfriend, girlfriend,
best friend, people that care about you?
We need to see you in the flesh.
How about Tuesday? OK.
MAN: That's it. Just relax.
It's OK.
That's it.
I'm sorry.
- It's not what it looks like.
- MAN: It's exactly what it looks like.
Get your clothes on.
- Come on, come on.
- MAN: There's no easy fixes.
No easy fix!
- (DOORBELL)
- Come on.
Why is no one answering
this fucking door?
- (RUNNING FOOTSTEPS)
- Don't move!
(GUN CLICKS)
You thought you could screw me?
What's it gonna be?
One good turn deserves another.
("WE ARE FOREVER" BY EVIL SPIRIT)
♪ If I had one more day with you
♪ I'd screw it up
♪ I'd put my heart
♪ In a little cage
♪ All bloodied up
♪ I thought it'd be best
♪ If I don't have to love
♪ Then I don't have to hurt
♪ Hear the rumbling
♪ Of the horses
♪ And the wind
♪ Coming to set me free
♪ I don't need blood
♪ I don't need skin
♪ I don't need a mind
♪ Forgetting is the art
♪ I don't need my heart
♪ I want to move on
♪ Did I learn my lesson yet?
♪ Will you let me go?
♪ You must let me go
ARTIE: Something a little
different for you there, folks.
I'm not even sure I
understand it myself,
but it sure as hell made
for good company.
This is Artie Duke, your guiding
light, KNDRD, signing off.
♪ Maybe it's just another birth
♪ It's not the end
♪ I will meet you there
♪ On the other side
♪ It is just another birth
♪ It's not the end
♪ I will meet you there
♪ We'll go on and on and on and on
("TIMBER MERCHANTS" BY DISCOPOLIS)
♪ You stood up for me
♪ In the middle of November
♪ The middle of November
♪ November
♪ He cuts wood
♪ To feed his family
♪ There's a flashing light
where your heart should be
♪ There's a thousand words
where our mouths should meet
♪ Our mouths should meet
♪ He cuts wood
♪ To feed
♪ There's a flashing light
where your heart should be
♪ There's a thousand words
where our mouths should meet
♪ There's a flashing light
where your heart should be
♪ There's a thousand words
where our mouths should meet
♪ Our mouths should meet
♪ He cuts wood
♪ To feed his family
♪ And he cuts wood
♪ His family
♪ Family