Three...
...on the hour...
...every hour.
Until somebody talks.
Where is Victorio?
Number three, then. That boy.
Hold your fire!
Order your men to lay
down their weapons.
I'm Captain Orrin Draper
of the Texas Rangers.
And my commission is
legal and it runs in...
In Texas. This is federal land
under military protection, captain.
And as such, I am arresting you and
your men for trespassing and murder.
Murder?
Now lay down your weapons.
You let me tell you something
about murder, blue boy.
In less than a week, Victorio
and his renegade Mescaleros...
...burned down nine
rancheros all along Big Bend.
They didn't leave nothing
alive, chick nor child.
Now, my men and me, we been
tracking that band for over a month.
And the trail led straight here.
Your so-called federal land and
your so-called military protection.
Which one of these do you take
for the great Apache war chief?
Texas?
Victorio's here.
And 400 mile of his stinking
trail has led me here.
And they know he's here, holed
up in some canyon or cave.
They ain't saying nothing.
Reservation Indians!
Sergeant Ruth.
Front and center.
Ask the boy what he knows.
Boy says he don't know nothing.
You ain't gonna take that
Injun brat's word, are you?
Even a nigger can't be that stupid.
Corporal Lloyd, Corporal Boyer.
First sergeant?
Let's get these prisoners
ready for transport.
All right, I want you all to mount up
and extend your wrists over your pommels.
- Get on the horse!
- Corporal Christy.
- First sergeant.
- Corporal...
...the first sergeant intends
to send a detachment out...
...to complete a thorough
search of the reservation.
For that...
...the first sergeant
requires a sergeant.
You think you can hold on to these for
more than a few months this time, sergeant?
Well, I always think so, Wyatt.
- That's the hell of it.
- Take half of the muster.
See if you can flush Victorio out.
- And shag that calf home to his mama.
- I got him, Wyatt.
If Victorio's come this deep
into New Mexico territory...
...there has to be a reason.
Richer pickings in Texas.
Easier to jump to Mexico.
You be careful out there.
Don't make me come
looking for them stripes.
You take your own advice, Wyatt.
I ain't the one going
picnicking with rattlesnakes.
First squad on me.
What kind of soldiers are you?
Buffalo soldiers, sergeant!
What kind of a soldier is that?
The best damn kind there is!
Prove it.
- Corporal Boyer.
- First squad on me at a trot. Move out.
These are no longer
the colored barracks.
Have the Negro troops
move their belongings...
...across the parade grounds
and set up their tents.
Yes, sir.
When I say clean, I mean
plenty of hot water and lye!
I want those barrack bunks
kerosened and tallowed for bugs!
Yes, sir.
The second's used to a
certain level of hygiene.
My men expect it.
That'd be John Horse.
Pike's scout. Half black,
half Seminole Indian.
Swamp nigger.
Sorry for putting you out
on the streets, Benjamin.
I imagine you've been ranked out of
a few post commands in your time, sir.
More than a few, if memory serves.
I was in Philadelphia recently.
Just before this posting, actually.
I had memory of your father.
My father.
Theo Grierson didn't have much
give to him, and that's a fact.
It hurt him to think of you
throwing your life away like this.
One word, Benjamin, and I'll have
you out of this self-imposed exile...
...and commanding a real cavalry regiment
within a month of our capturing Victorio.
I volunteered for command
of the 10th, General Pike...
...because I believe
in our Negro troops.
H troop coming in.
Well...
...if that is your belief, sir...
...then this belief will finish you.
This experiment with the
coloreds is doomed to failure.
It's been 17 years, sir.
And a waste of time.
Troop...
...dismount!
See to the horses, Sergeant Ruth.
That would be Wyatt, yes?
First Sergeant Washington
Wyatt. Yes, sir.
You've written him up for
meritorious commendation often enough.
With good reason.
He's the best damn
soldier I ever served with.
Posting our company near the
latrines. Kicked out of our own beds.
Digging holes and shoveling dirt. What
the hell's going on with our barracks?
Watch it, Eddie.
Suck those eyes back in your skull,
Tockes, or I'll knock them out full.
- What about the Rangers, sir?
- I'm going to file charges on them.
Secure them here.
I've got a report to make.
And while leaving Sergeant Christy to
continue searching the reservation...
...I brought Draper and his
men back to stand trial, sir.
Stand at ease, sergeant.
That was a fine report. Fine.
Sir, the first sergeant
thanks the general, sir.
Sergeant, besides rescuing
Apaches from Texas Rangers...
...I assume you had some other reason
for being on the Mescalero Reservation.
Yes, sir.
On routine patrol, H Troop...
...cut trail heading up from the
southeast onto reservation land.
Victorio has kin on the reservation.
Now, isn't that exactly what
the Texas Rangers did, sergeant?
No, sir.
H Troop committed no murders, sir.
For those of you
who don't know yet...
...John Horse is my personal scout.
I requested his services
for several reasons.
Stand at ease, sergeant.
Not the least being his familiarity with
the Arizona and New Mexico territories.
This last week or so,
Horse has been scouting...
...reports of activity along
the Arizona-New Mexico border.
Mr. Horse.
The Mimbreno Apaches have
left the Arizona reservation...
...because of Nana's vision.
Another vision yet.
Witch doctors, general.
Old fools smearing themselves
with horse dung and corn meal.
Praying to the great sky father
to make the white eyes go away.
In Nana's vision...
...the Mimbreno joined with
Victorio's Mescaleros...
...to form an army.
The Mimbreno and the
Mescaleros hate each other.
It goes back so far
they don't even know why.
Despite that, they're
willing to band together...
...to drive the whites out
of the Apachería forever.
You see the problem, gentlemen.
If H Troop did track Victorio
onto the Mescalero reservation...
...he and Nana are within
spitting distance of each other.
Except I'm not going
to let that happen.
I pray you didn't let Victorio
slip through your fingers, sergeant.
Just for the sake
of two Apache brats.
Sergeant, you're dismissed.
Joju.
You're late, sergeant.
I was with my mount.
He wants to pick a fight
with some of the new mounts.
You did good, Sergeant Ruth.
I did what needed doing.
I don't like it much,
I don't mind saying.
Put out of our own barracks without
so much as a thank you, kiss my ass.
Wait till Christy finds out. When he
gets back, no telling what he'll do.
Sergeant Christy will do as
ordered. Same as you. Same as me.
Yeah, well...
- Colonel Grierson won't stand for it.
- Same as Colonel Grierson.
Sergeant of the guard!
Sergeant Ruth, assemble the men.
Get up! Get up!
Riders! Riders coming hard!
William, you all right?
Hell, I'm dead.
I'm just too damn tired to
lay on down and admit it.
We had us a running gunfight
up to that last 10 miles.
- That son of a bitch Draper, he was right.
- Victorio?
He out there. We drew him out of
his hiding hole but we lost him...
...at the foot of the
Guadalupes. He just disappeared.
Got out ahead of us. Ain't no way
no living man could have done that.
Get out ahead of us
like that and flank us.
Then picked at us
all the way in here.
I mean, he picked at us all the way.
Victorio.
Son of a bitch.
From Mesa Caliente it seemed
Victorio managed to outflank...
And outmaneuver you, sergeant.
Taking the high ground...
...firing at will upon your men.
- Isn't that how it happened?
- Sir, we couldn't even...
General, Sergeant Christy isn't
an hour out of the infirmary.
It might be a good idea if he sat.
No, sir. Thank you, sir.
The sergeant is fine, sir.
Then the sergeant is a liar.
Gentlemen, Victorio has
been allowed to escape...
...and is once more free to
find and ally himself with Nana.
Tomorrow, C Troop will leave
Fort Craig and not return...
...until Victorio is
either dead or in chains.
I don't care which.
No doubt the 10th is a fine regiment.
But even you would have to admit that
H Troop comes in shy on leadership.
General, I'm sorry, I have to...
No reflection on Sergeants
Wyatt and Christy.
They're not trained to command.
Their kind relays orders.
They don't give them.
As the general says, sir.
Robert, I want you to
take command of H troop.
And back up C troop in the field.
Command niggers?
General, you're asking me
to throw away my career.
Good God, general,
we can't have that.
What would Bobby do without his fancy
uniform and his little toy sword?
You're out of line, Calhoun.
Out of line, but volunteering.
I'll take H troop, general.
I wonder what your late
father would think...
...about your serving
with field niggers.
Are you interested in my father's
opinion as a slave owner...
...colonel in the Army of Northern
Virginia or major in the Union Army, major?
The only interest I have in a traitor
is the date and place of his death.
July 2nd, 1863.
Gettysburg, Pennsylvania.
Perhaps you've heard of it.
Sir.
As the 10th's regimental CO, I'd hope
this would meet with your approval, sir.
Sir?
I have to wonder.
Does anyone in this room
remember who the real enemy is?
Schubert, Sergeant Wyatt.
You are rest, gentle peace
You are longing And what calms it
I never wanted the Army.
Did I ever tell you that?
No?
Well, it's true.
Horses, blue wool.
I don't know which I hate more.
And you, sergeant?
Do you want the Army?
Is this what you and your fellows...
...bargained for with
your newfound freedom?
Sir, it's not my place to say.
Speak up, man. You hold the rank of
first sergeant in the United States Army.
You have the right to an opinion.
I chose the Army, sir.
With all due respect...
...my men are scheduled
for target practice.
With your permission.
Ruth! Lloyd! Sea! Firing range, now!
Right forward!
Choose right!
March!
Company, move!
Company, left!
Company, ho!
Why'd the general turn them loose?
They murdered them boys, and Pike's
thanking them with fresh horses.
Because they aren't Apaches.
Because they kill Apaches.
Because they're white.
And we are at attention, sergeant.
My, my. C Troop.
- Don't they look fine?
- Yep.
- Good enough to eat.
- Hey, now, that's a fact.
Just look at old Tockes there.
I think he could polish
off a dozen all by himself.
And don't big Christy
look pretty today?
All patched up with his
spit and baling wire.
And ready to ride and still
looking for some lost soul...
...to tag behind that
mule wagon with a shovel.
You and your brother got plans for
the next 100 miles or so, Boyer?
Keep your troops
back, Captain Calhoun.
Parade regulations. Colored
companies 15 yards behind white.
Prepare to dismount.
- Dismount.
First sergeant.
What the hell are you
doing, first sergeant?
Colored soldiers not supposed to
ride through town with fanfare.
Regulations, captain.
That is not military, first sergeant.
It's not for the first
sergeant to say, sir.
Mesa Caliente.
This is where Victorio turned
the tables on Christy and H troop.
It's as good a place as any to
split up, cut the Mescaleros trail.
I'll take C company south,
captain. You and Wyatt ride north.
We'll have to find
something, someone that way.
Trot...
...forward.
Trot forward!
- Troop, halt.
- Why are we stopping, sergeant?
Up ahead, in the rocks. Riflemen.
They're watching us.
Could be a feint. Pull us
off Victorio's real trail.
There ain't but one way to find
out. Leader, Thomas, Hobley, Wages!
- Yes, sir.
- On me.
- Giddap.
They just disappeared.
Fall back! Fall back! Take cover!
Fall back. We're
surrounded. Take cover.
Go! Come on! Go! Go!
I'm cut!
Come on! Come on!
What are you doing, Eddie?
What the hell you gaping at, boy?
Get back to your own business!
Come on, come on, come on.
William?
Christy?
- Joju?
- Wyatt?
Right here, Joju.
Right here. Right
here, I'm here. Come on.
- Wyatt?
- Damn.
Son of a bitches.
They took my eye. They
took my eye. The good one.
Captain?
Damn!
And I was such a pretty thing.
You hit, captain?
You take a bullet?
My back.
My family never owned a slave.
Don't tell Major
Carr. Break his heart.
Hold... Hold still.
Come on, come on. Hold still.
Oh, I got it. That's it. Hold
still, hold still, hold still.
That's it. That's it.
You know what you're doing, son?
Oh, yes, sir. My
granddaddy taught me this.
Fixed all them scars on his back.
First sergeant. I need your help.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
What's wrong with your brother, Carl?
What is it, Andrew?
Don't know.
Got ants crawling underneath my skin.
Eating at my vitals.
He doesn't have a fever, sergeant.
They're eating me from
the inside out, Carl.
What is it, sergeant?
It's poison.
Poisoned you with them arrows, son.
First sergeant?
He done it to us again.
Victorio. He left behind just enough
shooters to keep us holed up...
...while the rest of them
backtracked out of there.
- Backtracked?
- Look, we can't let go like this, Wyatt.
I mean to turn Victorio
over to Pike myself...
...and invite him to kiss my
big, black, untrained behind.
Give me Tockes, Corporal
Sea and one other.
In the morning, we'll make our way
back, climb up over that crest line...
...and sneak up behind them waiting
on us in them rocks as we go.
- Hell of a climb, William. You sure?
- I'm sure.
I'd rather die doing it
than get picked off...
...like cans on a fence.
- Me too.
Get it done then, in the morning.
Hold up. Hold up.
Put down them rifles.
Now.
Tockes, cover me.
Corporal Sea, watch them now.
- Get over!
- Get down now. You understand me?
Told you to put down
that rifle, didn't I?
Lord help us. Sergeant, it's a woman.
She's a damn murdering Apache...
...and she'd cut your throat
as soon as look at you.
Where is he?
Which one of you sons
of bitches took my eye?
Andrew, come on, now. Come on.
Come on, now. Andrew, come on, now.
Rider approaching, sergeant.
That's the general's scout.
You gonna hold on, you hear me?
You gonna hold on, Andrew. Come on.
Carr picked up Victorio's
trail to the south...
...but lost it once
they forded the Gila.
He wants you to come about and...
I been spit on before.
- What she say?
- She promised to cut my heart out...
...first chance she got.
Damn.
Congratulations, sergeant...
...you've captured Nana.
They killed my brother.
Andy, come on, now.
Nana, the great Apache
prophet and wizard.
Major Carr will be
sorely disappointed.
He wanted Merlin or a charlatan.
Something flamboyant, even if a fake.
What do you think of him, sergeant?
I think he's the most
alone man on this earth.
Alone? Nana?
With the U.S. Army at his throat
and the Apache nation at his feet?
Half himself buried...
...and the other half left to wander.
Looking for what's dead and gone...
...and it's him.
Being a ex-slave in
Mississippi's bad as it gets.
You're colored, new freed.
I did what all the
Mississippis couldn't.
To prove something
Carr and the general...
...would never believe anyway.
I will dwell in the
house of the Lord forever.
I killed Andy Boyer.
Amen.
And I might as well killed Carl too.
Soldiers die, sergeant.
- For something.
- You captured the one man...
...who had the power to turn a murdering
renegade like Victorio into a holy crusader.
You. Not Carr. Not the general.
And it brings you...
What?
Seven dead men.
It's brought me seven
dead men, colonel.
Y'all heard how we lost
Victorio at the Gila.
Yeah, we lost him.
But we didn't stop.
No, we crossed the Gila.
We followed it south for
miles, then north, backtracking.
Looking for signs of Victorio.
Any signs.
We found them. We found lots of them.
We just couldn't find Victorio.
Maybe if there had
been a few more of us.
How's that make you
feel, first sergeant?
Knowing you might've been the difference
between life and death for these men?
You got nothing to say?
Sir, first sergeant has made a
full report to the post commander.
Said report was accepted complete
and without prejudice, sir.
One of these days, Mr. Wyatt...
...you're not gonna be able to
hide behind Army regulations.
Have you anything to add...
...to Major Carr's
report, Army scout Horse?
I may remember things different.
- How different?
- Not so urgent.
Carr knew when he sent
me to find H Troop...
...it'd take three days for Calhoun
to join up with him at the Gila.
If I found him right off.
Whatever Major Carr found
at those homesteads...
...was long done before
I could even get back.
Anything to add to your
earlier report, sergeant...
...in light of what
Major Carr has said here?
No, sir.
Lacking proper leadership skills...
...I relied on my
limited field experience.
I believed then and I believe now
that the mission was best served...
...by seeing Nana back to Fort
Craig and properly secured.
Now, Major Carr...
...had every right to
expect reinforcement...
...from another troop commander,
another officer. But then...
...the first sergeant
isn't an officer.
- Are you, sergeant?
- No, sir.
Of course, Captain Calhoun's death...
...placed the sergeant in a position
he readily admits was just too...
It was just too complicated
for him to handle.
Upon further
consideration, I accept...
...that Sgt. Wyatt acted
to the best of his ability.
You are out of line, Major Carr!
Step carefully, Colonel Grierson.
You step carefully!
You are dangerously
close to insubordination!
Draw upon your charges! I will
no longer sit in silence...
...while you and your fice terrier...
- I resent this, general!
...chew at this man! My men!
For God's sakes! Have you
forgotten who brought you Nana?
You are absolutely right, colonel.
What matters is that I have Nana...
...the soul of the Apache uprising.
But Victorio is still the heart...
...and Victorio is still free...
...and I want him. I want him dead!
Before I have to look at
another mutilated white man!
Am I making myself clear?
God, will he never shut up?
What sort of trick was that, anyway?
Dragging dead folk out like that?
Just for folks to gawk and stare.
It's a shame and a pity.
That's what my mama would say.
Shoot. Your mama never had
words for what Carr did today...
...and you be glad of it.
I'd kill anybody who'd try to
do my brother Andy that way.
Toss his body out
like he's an animal.
He's just trying to stir things up.
I mean, look how he
baited the sergeant.
Yeah. Yeah, and Grierson
never said a word.
Colonel Grierson wasn't there.
He wasn't gonna say nothing
nohow. Pike's in charge now.
Grierson's about as
useless as tits on a boar.
One more word out of you, Tockes, and
I'm gonna put the chains on you myself.
Something I can do for you, scout?
Thought maybe you
might like to thank me.
- Thank you?
- For going on record against Carr.
Damn, are you such a stupid nigger?
Maybe.
Why don't you tell me what
kind of nigger you think I am...
...'breed.
If Grierson and I
hadn't backed you...
...Carr would've managed to
get you drawn up on charges.
I asked you to tell me what
kind of nigger you think I am.
I don't understand you.
I don't understand who you are.
I'm a first sergeant in
the United States Army.
Army?
Army bares you no love.
None of you. They endure you.
They'll endure you...
...until they've wiped all
the tribes from the slate...
...with our blood.
You have no pride, first sergeant.
You have no pride.
One thing's for sure, scout...
...I didn't leave it in a bowl
on the floor next to Pike's boots.
Lights out.
Now maybe you'll shut up!
- Come on, now.
- Dang, Roseman...
...you look like you
died and gone to heaven.
It weren't no accident
Jesus was a carpenter.
What kind of notch you
done chopped in here?
It's a dovetailed finger joint.
Well, it ain't dovetailing.
It's cut right. Ain't my
fault it ain't fitting.
Well, if it don't fit, this log ain't
no good for nothing but firewood.
Wyatt, this thing ain't
gonna stay up here by itself.
Wyatt!
Next time you ride your
horse out from under you...
...I’m gonna leave
your butt in the desert.
What you looking at, old fool?
Young fool, I guess.
I was just going to
send for you, sergeant.
Well, step up. Don't
tell me you've gone shy.
There's been news. Good
or bad, it's your call.
Horse has been out
scouting the last two days.
He thinks he may have
cut two separate trails.
Victorio's Mescaleros
and Nana's Mimbrenos.
While we've been here acting like the
Apache Wars were all but finished...
...the Mimbrenos have actually made
it into the heart of the territory.
From what I saw and
pieced together...
...both armies intend to link up at one
of the watering holes along this route.
They have to.
There's no other way to cross some
of that desert and get out alive.
All we have to do is figure out
which one and get there first.
I was going to send for you,
sergeant, because I intend...
...to give this mission to H Troop.
I know Major Carr's report cast
a pall over the capture of Nana...
...through no fault of your own.
I'd imagine you and your colored
troops would appreciate a chance...
...to set the record
straight. For good and all.
I'll be in command, Wyatt.
It's been a while since you
and I took the field together.
H Troop will be ready to take
the field, dawn tomorrow, sir.
Andy's dead.
You think Pike or
Grierson even cares?
Even noticed that a face was missing?
What, you think they lose sleep over
every white face missing from roll call?
Boy, now, I want to live
in the world you come from.
Yeah, they didn't
even know he was dead.
Didn't even know he was here.
See, that's what kills a body.
We're not soldiers, we're sponges...
...going around soaking up
the blood and the guts...
...and for what?
Until I joined this here Army,
I didn't even know me no Indians.
Never even cared to meet one.
Now I've killed a dozen...
...and I have to wonder why.
Because some white boy with
gold braid on his arm...
...tells us to, that's
why, and we let them.
Everyone of us gave them the right
to tell us what to do, when to do it.
We might as well be back on the
block, the mess we made of this thing.
Well, everybody got something to say.
How about you, Wesley?
You feeling misunderstood these days?
I like the Army.
It ain't a bad place to be
when you slow and to the point.
Somebody tell you what
to do and you do it.
And the food pretty good.
Lord have mercy, boy. What's
the matter with you, son?
Nana's Mimbrenos are still looking
to join with Victorio's Mescaleros.
Tomorrow this troop
goes after Victorio.
We don't come back until he's
captured or dead. Or we are.
Bringing Nana and
his children along...
I don't know, are you
sure that's a good idea?
Best protection we got, colonel.
Most Apache riflemen
would think twice...
...before taking a chance
at hitting the old man.
I'd carry him in my
pocket if I could.
Victorio's here.
Power meant to warn us off.
Here's where Horse first cut track.
Now we know Victorio
is partial to this area.
It's easy for him to skedaddle down
into Mexico first sign of a blue coat.
These watering holes run
20 miles all through here.
So we'll cut trailside along here...
...flank him, come around...
...and beat him to the water hole.
Whichever water hole. That'd be the plan.
We cannot outmarch the Apaches.
We don't travel like that.
We could try, sir. We could try.
Troops forward! Troops
forward! They shot the colonel!
Half muster to the left!
Rally on the colonel!
They've shot the colonel!
Free the sergeant!
All dismount!
Take that hill! Come
on, get up that hill!
Advance the ridge!
- There's nobody here!
- Damn!
How is he?
Wyatt, come here.
Sergeant...
...I’m relinquishing
command of the troop to you.
Washington...
...I don't know if I'm
gonna live an hour or a week.
It doesn't matter.
- It matters.
- No. The mission matters.
This regiment, H Troop, they matter.
If we fail in this, men like Pike...
...will use it to force men
like you out of the Army.
We...
You can't let that happen.
We've come so... So far.
Always knew what you tried
to do for us, colonel.
Take him home.
Maybe that's the direction
we all should be heading.
You can leave whenever
you choose, scout.
What about us, sergeant?
Are we any less than Grierson,
left to be picked off, one by one?
Fighting men. We have more in
common with them than we dare admit.
Found a conscience, have you?
No telling where you'll
find one these days.
Don't cross me, scout.
I'm a free man, Wyatt.
I come and go at my pleasure...
...for my reasons.
Can you say the same?
Any man without the balls to follow
me after Victorio, fall out now.
You and the scout can catch up
with the detail, head back to post.
But any man stays...
...stays from here on out
and keeps his mouth shut.
Any man deserts on my watch,
I'll put a bullet in his head.
And any man talks mutiny...
...I'll rip him apart
with my bare hands.
Is that understood?
All right, Wyatt.
You're the man.
What now?
Take the girl, Corporal Tockes.
Come on, girl! Shut up! Shut up!
Do what I do, corporal.
You wanna help the
girl? This old man?
You translate exactly what I
say, word for word, you hear me?
- Weapon ready, corporal?
- Weapon ready, sergeant.
I'm running out of time. I'm gonna
ask you once. Corporal Tockes...
...if this man
refuses to answer me...
...you will shoot the girl
in the back of her head.
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Old man, where is Victorio?
- I said, shut up!
- Corporal Tockes, shoot the girl!
- You can't!
- Sarge, you sure?
- Sure, I'm sure!
- Come on!
Shut up! Shut up!
Give me that!
The watering holes!
I know that, old man! Which one?
Rattlesnake Springs!
Victorio is making for Rattlesnake
Springs to meet with the Mimbrenos.
Our job's simple: Be there first.
That's 50 miles more
than we got water for.
We have our orders, William!
I thought you was
in charge, sergeant.
I am!
There is something you're
gonna need to see, Wyatt.
The Rangers.
Kill me.
For the love of God, man.
Shoot him, Tockes.
- Troop, ho!
- Bivouac here for the night, sergeant.
- Troop...
...dismount!
Joju's been shot!
Everybody down! Dismount!
Wyatt!
That's the last bullet
I'll take for you, Wyatt.
All right, all right, Joju.
Get those horses out of here.
- Get these horses out of here!
- Move those horses!
Get him off the horse! Dismount!
Single sniper over
here, to the right.
Over to your right.
Get the horses out of here!
Scout, you're following me up.
Horse, you're coming with me.
I don't mean to come back and
find you gone, and my men too.
Cover us, Tockes.
Scout!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! We did it.
We outsmarted the
damn freaking Apache.
They're still about
a couple hours away.
From what?
See that ridge behind us?
That sits right above
Rattlesnake Springs.
And that's where we gotta
be in less than an hour.
Corporal Sea...
...I want all four platoons up to the edge
of that ridge above Rattlesnake Springs.
Nobody stays back with the horses.
Wyatt, if we have to retreat, we
won't have any mounts, any supplies.
We ain't got no way back, damn it.
Victorio has a hundred warriors.
You can pretty much
rule out retreat, Tockes.
Corporal, pick ten
men from your platoon.
I want the mouth of that canyon
sealed as soon as Victorio's inside.
All right, sergeant.
Yeah! Water, here we come!
Tockes, get their attention.
Troopers, attention!
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Help the wounded and
get those canteens full.
I want this place
swept clear of tracks...
...and everybody on
that ridge in 15 minutes.
Never think they might do that.
Play splash and such.
This is it. Let's move.
Drop your weapons.
Do not fire, do not fire.
Drop your weapons now!
I said, drop it!
Put your weapons down. Drop them now.
Scout, tell them we want to talk.
I want to speak to Victorio.
The war chief, Victorio.
This is Victorio, sergeant.
Victorio, the man...
...not the myth.
We named you Buffalo
Soldiers, for your hair.
It was a good naming. You
are much like the buffalo.
On the move, you stop for
nothing. A good naming, I think.
I think so too. We
made it for our own.
When an enemy praises an
enemy, the smart man listens.
I've come for you,
Victorio. You know that.
Are you a slave?
No, I am not a slave.
You were a slave.
Yes, I was.
Why do you fight for those
who were your masters...
...Washington Wyatt?
Sir, you are surrounded.
We hold the high ground.
You cannot escape.
I am offering you a
means of surrender.
We will fight you.
And fight for our dead.
We will not be slaves like you.
I wish to save as many
of you here as possible.
I cannot promise much
for yourself or...
Why? Why do you murder my people...
...for those who made
you less than cattle?
Please.
You have children here.
Old people. Lay down your weapons.
Believe this, then.
Come tomorrow's sun...
...I will kill every man,
woman and child in this canyon.
And it will be on your head.
Tell him that.
Though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death...
... I will fear no evil,
for thou art with me.
Thou preparest a table before
me in the presence of my enemies.
Thou anointeth my head with
oil. My cup runneth over.
We can't do this.
Wyatt.
They're nothing.
Hungry, starving...
...dying where they stand.
Then I'm doing them a favor.
Putting them out of their misery.
How can you do this, Wyatt?
How can you live with this?
It'll be on your soul, Wyatt.
Pick your target.
I will fire the first shot.
On my shot, commence firing.
Lord, have mercy.
Army scout Horse.
How far is it to the Mexican border?
Victorio. Mexico.
I will deliver the following report:
We could not hold Victorio.
He fought through our
barricades, taking Nana with him.
We regret their escape, but with
food and water running low...
...believed it best
to return to post.
We will pursue at a later date.
Is that not correct, gentlemen?
Yes, sir!
You do not use the word
"sir" for the first sergeant.
You only...
...salute.
It's the Fourth of July, sergeant.
Left into line!
March!
Troop, halt!
Prepare to dismount!
As you were!
Forward, march!
Ripped by: SkyFury