For a handful of onion
Translation and adaptation: RRZXXX
Look, that turned three.
It is rumored that they had brought
wood to dig my husband.
Look it, bastards.
Is what they're up to
this time?
Now the whole earth
belongs to Mr. Lamb.
There remained only Foster's farm.
- Let us help you?
- Get out. Forget it.
Poisoning the wells this area
fucking oil.
Foster tried to
humanly understand us with you
But it seems that you do not want to understand,
the worse for you.
Why do not we have heard, Foster?
What, you afraid?
I had to teach you mind first.
An ideal place
an accident, right?
- Yes, not bad.
- Courage, give him a nudge.
Goes the last farmer.
Gentlemen, our company will become
largest in the country,
because oil is about
to become the most used
Future raw material and
then animal traction
will be replaced completely
internal combustion engine.
Humanity can no longer
do anything without oil.
So strong is the oil gentlemen.
Power that will rule the world.
In this country under the feet
our
is the largest reservoir
crude oil in the world.
Who will be with us well.
Who will be against us, eh ...
So gentlemen we have control
this region.
One moment Mr. Lamb.
Forgot to mention the
land of Paradise City.
My knowledge, there
still be problems.
Yes, yes ...
Paradise City, yes.
But that's not a problem at all.
Just a little misunderstanding
a farmer.
A man named Foster.
I had small problems in trying
buying
piece of land.
As you can see land
which already belong to the company
are marked in gray
and this piece is still green
land we are talking about.
- Mr. Lamb!
- Yes?
- A telegram from Paradise City
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
Gentlemen, I am informed that the d
Foster landowner
the victim
an unfortunate accident.
I can say that from this moment
problem in Paradise City
can be considered solved.
And this ...
Somebody help me ..
But you said
this was blocked?
Yes, but the situation is that now
My finger was stuck.
I need help ..
Help!
Finish with the wail
and get to work.
Are you sure the problem is as
Mr. Lamb addressed? Because ...
- Hey Jack, where to stop?
- We stop at least the bar.
I have a dry throat.
Onion .. ! Onion .. !
We're here!
Bar .. !
Just what I needed, a glass,
a bath and a hearty meal.
And a sexy mare for me.
Horatio, you always
want the same thing.
You wait here and make sure you
not steal anyone onions.
Listen, I'm horse
no cart horse guard.
Hello!
Apparently does not like
conversation. Too bad.
- Tears, why are you crying?
- But why are you crying?
I do not know, but suddenly I
began to feel very sad.
What the hell did
whiskey this from the onion?
- Mr bartender!
- Hey, buddy, what do you serve?
- A glass, please.
- A glass of what?
Gol, please.
Sorry, I can say as
Foster firm's reach?
What job do you have
Foster's farm?
I mean the former land
Foster's.
Now the farm is mine.
I bought it.
He bought it.
Foster's farm.
Why laugh? There is good ground
for onions grown?
He wants to grow onions!
What you have with onions?
Good for health.
Look, if S
to your health,
i have scârboºeniile and disappear.
I am quite clear?
Why?
Because otherwise you risk to have
a tragic end.
Special edition!
Read and learn the latest gazeta
news from Paradise City!
The whole truth about past
strange happenings!
- Hey, Pulitzer!
- Thank you.
An attempt of capitalists
to destroy
What was once a city
peaceful and happy!
And turn it into an inferno
unbreathable and smoky!
Two cents for the truth, town!
Take courage!
ACCIDENT OR MURDER
Give it here.
That was not for you.
Want to know how it
really works?
How can you live here and
not know what happens!
Hey! To read less together
Pulitzer.
Truth or murder. Crime?
No, better out
this ugly word.
And the rest of stuff ..
out, out ..
Why do not you see your affairs.
- A Pulitzer was an accident.
- Who says it was an accident?
- Come on, everybody knows.
- Everyone knows?
Of course.
Look! It was an accident.
Try to stick well to head
Pulitzer.
Fai semper a con gran casino
the character di piombo
Be careful or you'll Pulitzer
wake up with fillings in the stomach.
Come here!
Newspaper comes!
This is the last warning
Next time do not lose
as easily.
Hey.
- Are you looking for someone.
- Who?
- Well, I.
- Who? You?
Hold on boys at a time.
You go.
- Why me?
- Go along.
You go.
- Go you.
- Yes.
Go t. ..
Apparently it's my turn.
- Are you okay?
- Yes. I think so.
- On your feet!
- Hey, be careful.
You think we fear you with that?
Now what?
- Come, lead you back home.
- Thank you.
I let go right?
Hey, ceparule, how are you?
Leave us?
With all your tricks
not yet made me laugh.
Pay attention son, you better leave him
alone. It's a great villain.
Let's go.
No, just play, joking.
Wait for me outside, right?
Whatever.
- So, onions or gun?
- Gun.
No onions.
Not one but 2, 3, 4 onions ...
The eye is quick but hand
is even faster ..
Now, attention onions disappear
each remaining onions ...
count, count ...
one two three four ...
Pistol!
Now be careful ..
Two onions, a gun ..
Remove onions and bag guns ..
There are three guns now
Beware of guns ...
Four guns ..
Now be careful ..
The gun is made onion ..
onion is gun ..
Look at the guns,
Beware of onion, 1 2 3 4 ...
And 4 3 2 1 .. Gun spinning,
watch the onion ...
I told you to watch onions.
We arrived.
I live here and work here.
No big deal that job
but that housing is worse.
Please come.
Well, to be ...
But .. this is a printing,
so they say no?
- Here is printed newspapers ..
- Yes .. is printed here.
Only that in this town newspaper
no one reads it.
You see, O people
afraid to know the truth.
My newspaper is censored, burned.
The only things that are left
them are printed obituaries
publicity and advertising
the funeral.
The names of all those
read newspaper obituaries occur.
Sorry, but we still do not
we became acquainted.
I called my Pulitzer
Henry J. Pulitzer.
Jack for friends.
I am editor, director,
printer and reporter.
But unfortunately the only reader
of the newspapers in town.
Glad to meet you,
I'm Onion (Onion).
- Onion? Onion and how?
- Onion and nothing more.
I never never knew his father.
- I'm sorry ..
- Why, you know?
Finally you get home father.
But what's that smell
strong onions.
To be honest I do not know.
The smell comes from me ..
.. comes only from me ..
If I could see was
this place before, Onion ..
Once this place
was a small paradise
and would have remained a small town
peaceful farmers.
Everything changed when they discovered
that the area is full of oil.
A handful of people took
control of the city.
Many fled the city,
and those who remained
died in mysterious circumstances.
Onion, what do you think of
oil industry?
- It's wonderful.
- What is beautiful?
What? Mind
if you repeat the question?
Forget it, eat, let's courage!
Eat as it cools.
It's under your plate.
True.
Miss Mary Ann,
smell bother you?
No .. no .. no .. I love that smell.
- Really?
- Yes ..
No .. get both.
It's good, is not it?
He gave it ready.
Look Horatio, the .. !
Thank God!
That you gave me to see land
which I dreamed all my life.
Here my onions
can love and multiply.
A tit ...
Hey!
- Onion ...
- ...
I go, telling me later
to me who won.
Do not move, stay away!
Raise your hands!
Drop your weapons.
Now lift your feet!
I said standing.
Look, I am standing.
Return slowly!
****************************
Which of you fired?
- I.
- With that?
- Yes.
- Who threw the bombs?
Where do you steal?
I have not stolen. We make it.
So you will encounter neighbors?
Father trust
neighbors, and finally to the cemetery.
Your father?
Foster told me that not having children.
I am Cal. Caligola Foster
Nerone and he is my brother.
I am the Onion.
It's nice to meet you.
Nerone come to make peace.
Caligola and Nerone ...
Father knew how
you play?
Now you are convinced that the father
I sold your land?
Yes it's true. It's written and
father's signature.
- Your brother has doubts?
- He does not know how to read.
Listen guys, my father
sold this land two months ago.
And I made him promise
not to give it the petroleum industry.
I promise I will keep this.
Now that they killed
do not know where to go.
- Why are you sure you killed?
- Are safe and ready.
You do not have anyone to
take care of you? Any relative?
I have it on Nerone and Nerone
I have myself,
and on our land
we do not go.
Look What's up guys, I
I gave all my savings
your father in exchange for
land, you understand?
- $ 236.50, is not it?
- That's right
- These are?
- Yes, I even mine.
- I recognize by smell.
- Okay.
Take your money and your piece of the cart
and disappear.
No, that's not correct.
If planting fast
lost harvest onions.
And I have no money
fertilizer.
You should make a loan.
- And who gives a loan?
- Okay, so we associate.
You two put money
and I land.
Profit share,
agree boys?
One hand washes the other ...
But we work together.
All right.
Of course he was assassinated.
Poor, was found dead
off a cliff, a few days ago.
A sheriff said the accident.
But I have seen body
He had signs of violence on the body
and the gap was far
the earth's.
What to look for him there?
And you suspect that you threw?
You can be sure that one
not been discarded.
And of course they are not evidence.
The fact is that since they started
to pump that shit black
happened a lot of accidents.
And all were people who refused
Petrus Lamb to sell his land.
For example, Armstrong
which remained ...
- But it happens, right?
- So, in the middle of the desert?
It's too much coincidence.
Austin. John J. Austin,
Nello fugatto the Stagno.
There's even
to wash feet.
Taney, Taney old Bill,
lost his arm in the war
They said he committed suicide with
a blow to the head.
- Tempio E donkeys was sinister.
- I see you begin to understand.
Earth is just right
for my onions.
I go to register
the act of selling
Onion, if you stay you die
before the first harvest to gather.
Listen to the advice of a friend
go, go until you can.
- Look, it e.
- Yes, sure. It's right at the bar.
While it is true that he
skirmished in all five?
Sure, well I saw with my own eyes.
- Look, what sin is so young.
- Yes, we had a hard life.
I would say very short.
Get ten men and
Paradise City no longer exist!
- What will be?
- Ride people
know that the sheriff does not want
assemblies on the corners.
- This is a quiet town
- Yes, quiet as a cemetery.
Onion, Drang Drang ...
Wake up!
Thank you, Horatio.
Hello. Is there a judge
these parts?
Of course, it
is a respectable town
Ceparule hear that job
of you to judge?
Just register
an act of ownership.
Judge lives
the street.
It's a banner there, but I
doubt that you read.
Oh, it's a signboard.
You heard Horatio?
- Thanks
-
You feel like answering Mr. Horatio?
Take that ...
- Thank you.
- I gave it to me.
Goodbye.
Judge Logan?
Honor?
Mr. Ju ...
But what?
What strange city.
Le bisteche sutta royalties
judges under the table.
Judge Mr. ..
Judge Mr. Logan!
That'll wake him up.
- Objection rejected!
- I have not objected to anything.
Finally a quality whiskey
Excuse me, Your are
Judge Logan?
Let's see what he wants.
Open, I am.
Can you record it?
You brought the certificate?
- Birth?
- Not my son, to death.
The register ...
No more said
Foster's farm, what about you
You suicidal?
I only need to register.
On behalf of my firm's yours.
Give me the stamp ... stamp ..
Look.
Sit still, stop moving.
I come to you ..
Thanks!
See you at your funeral,
try to be punctual!
I have not time to waste.
He said he goes to legalize
document.
Yes. Who knows why the document
was.
You are immediately
that here we do not move.
Once everything has to come out, right?
Yes, we HAP .. catch it.
Hey .. where are you?
You end the bitter ceparule.
Gentlemen I give you good news.
Minor legal problems, which hinders
affairs with Foster's land,
has been resolved.
In fact the new owner,
we gave the contract rights.
Yes, but not the land still belongs
Oil company & Company.
No, but I just
to deal with two orphans.
We'll take care even
new child poverty.
- I will deal personally.
- Attention to toe.
That should do.
Sure but before the governor
to learn of our activities.
Yes Comuncue taxable hour .. la luce
Massimo del Sole nel .. from the law.
Sheriff announced that tomorrow
I transfer in Paradise City.
After you finish with screaming
Go and bring me your hand.
But what the hell you want to do,
die young?
No, no, no ..
Do not be stupid, think carefully.
Pack your bags and go.
And hurry up before
it is too late.
I want to talk to the sheriff.
No go, I got mad,
take advantage of me know why?
- Because they are too good.
- No, you are naive.
Non become fare ..
- Where are you going?
- To see the sheriff!
- I ask the help of the law.
- Go slowly I pull a cart.
- Just the act of selling and ready
-
Poor has already begun
to speak alone.
Yes, as may
so as possible.
If I do not do justice ..
- What a shame.
- Yes That's right
I deserve to end up so bad.
- You wait here.
- It depends.
- Where's the sheriff?
- Inside.
- Mr Judge Logan, hello!
- Sssstt!
- Just trying to ..
- Ssssssssstt!
So ...
I was stolen document
ownership of land.
- Can you prove?
- Sure Sheriff.
Judge Logan saw him,
Come tell your honor.
Your recorded this
act Mr. Judge?
No, I do not I seen
this guy does not know anything.
- But .. but ..
- Ceparule not move!
You never got better, and I see that
behave like a boor.
- Searched it!
- Welcome.
How much onion ...
Look ..
Now you burned ..
Ceparule Remember, if you see my
it will be the last time.
I was told that this
is a nice town.
Not notice anything strange?
Who stole my wagon wheels?
Can you prove that you had
when you arrived?
- Good day asshole.
- Attention to speed.
Now it was angry.
Are you hurt?
I told you to watch your step.
- Does it hurt?
- Want to Mom?
Get him!
Now give me back wheels
and contract.
So I'm not angry, number 3.
If you were smart
guarding your back, buddy.
Seriously?
Really, what's wrong?
- To know is right.
- What?
Return
and look to see.
Bella Trech, Stechinetti and
M.
What do you do, laugh?
Give me the gun with repetition.
- And what you did with the pipe?
- Yes, there is no pipe ..
You see sir, one day ...
a calf annoyed me, and I ...
I think he left ..
I'm going to see!
Wait! Hold it!
END PART
PART TWO
At the station, quick!
Horatio! Horatio, you?
- Who else is?
- Hello, Horatio!
- How did you find?
-
- Where did you get the wheels?
Me when I fall in head an idea
Need to plant to sow.
I did a lot of things.
Courage, let's go home.
-
- Look sexy e.
- What?
How what?
First work then pleased.
Let's go!
With you all the time only working
with pleasure what about?
Do not get older the difference
between a cow and a mare.
Are you sure that
Onion can rub?
Hello Mr. Lamb!
Mr. Lamb has come!
Welcome to Mr. Lamb!
What do you think our wonderful
Paradise City?
Abominable, nor can
breathe so much dust!
Benjamin, my phalanx ..
Benjamin, hurry up.
I will provide
best room in the hotel!
Petrus Lamb has everything
available.
But all other rooms
are occupied Mr. Lamb!
Yes, yes, I understand, if all
rooms are occupied when ..
Benjamin I get sick ..
All rooms in the hotel boys
are busy! Dezocupati them!
You build a casino.
Ocupaatt!
- Shower me!
- There she is!
Benjamin, my finger.
I put them all in a bag
and I connected.
Then I saw some 500
that surrounded me.
Then I beat all 500 ..
Then another 500 have tried to
attack from behind the back,
three-meter tall giants,
and then ...
I stole the title deeds.
And now of course
employers you are.
I do not have any reason to remain.
You said something?
Then ... I can go.
I saw the contract,
I shook hands ..
and a man of honor
Keep the promise.
I knew they could not find two
associates better than you!
Thanks!
Caligola Thanks!
Thank Nerone, sleeping!
Come, you go to bed.
Bondarel dear sleep,
Nani do baby.
To dream of angels.
- Ssssstt!
- Shhh ...
Ms. Pulitzer.
Ms. Pulitzer. I am ..
I .. so ..
So powerful.
I .. Once I fought a bull
empty-handed,
and I hit
fist full force ..
And .. and ..
But you're looking for
here so late?
Dad had talked to someone
now it's dark
I can walk around town without
I see people Mr. Lamb.
- I'm going to wake him Horatio.
- No. .. no ..
Do not bother anyway
everyone sleeps in the city.
It's so good here, and out
full moon is so beautiful.
And then it's the first time
I got the opportunity to remain single,
And I missed
little conversation.
Actually I'm not too talkative,
Miss Miriam.
Say the first thing that
will think of.
Onions .. Then ..
My onion seed is one of
the best in California.
- Seriously?
- Yes.
It's young, sweet and fragrant ..
Say ..
- And then there's the Russian Nebraska.
- How is the Russian Nebraska?
Exciting ... and spicy ..
And passionate ..
I was me, I would not allow
I swear .. I ..
I do not do stuff like that.
No, it is counterfeit ..
Seeing yourself
As you have skirmished
we realized
they are not invincible.
Onion, if you want to give you
one hand,
the whole town will be on your side.
- So you agree?
- It's true, you know.
Well .. I am pretty busy
sowing and is a lot of work.
Wait, what are you going to do?
I'm going to see what's up
and come back.
No, there is only one way
the sheriff's tops,
by Lamb and his murderers.
We need to find a single proof
about their illegality.
A story we published in Gazeta and will
reach the ears of the governor.
- But you do not have any proof?
- No, all they found something
ended at the cemetery
Remember that learning.
- Then let's see how do.
- Almost dawn.
- Hey Bob you started to cry.
- I console him immediately.
- Whose turn?
- Stink's turn, let's day!
Do not mumble, speak normally.
- Give drinking.
- Trying to get rid of remorse.
But Those bastards ...
So now ..
- Sheriff!
- What?
Type the onion returned
out and instigate people.
On my Indian law if you do not
finish guy.
- Ceparule, attention!
- Quiet!
You and your stupid rhymes.
Imbeciles, forgot orders?
Gentlemen, you must leave
before.
The best thing would be that
you three to disappear.
You will cross the border tomorrow.
Go up there and
stay there long.
- Let's go.
- Continue as planned.
I do not do poetry,
I have talent as a poet.
I'll try and judge
to solve personal
work with the guy
onions and two orphans.
- It's not that Mr. Judge?
- Ready to go,
I will not interfere in the affairs
voasre, handle your own.
Then I guess you have not heard
I said.
I said
ready
with
violence.
Do you understand?
To be legal guardian of children
I just need your signature.
Move .. !
Benjamin!
We do not want to go
the orphanage, Trofio.
We should thank Mr.
Lamb that is worried for you.
Everything is arranged at the expense
Oil company & Company.
You will like there children
is a great place.
A large and beautiful city.
And the journey will
an accident, is not it?
Hold on buddy, everything is legal.
Look, it's an order issued by court
with the stamp and signature.
Oo .. see, see. But you know
and I have a document.
Where do I put was here ..
Here it ..
You guys should write that
remain here.
- Where does it say?
- Come closer.
Guys, just one night to grab us.
Let me give you a helping hand.
- And now fuck off!
- Sheriff, Sheriff!
Where's the sheriff? Sheriff!
- Thanks partner.
- Always keep my promises.
I say?
- We have proof.
- What evidence?
Tata gathered it in hand when
I found the bottom of the abyss.
Stink is the Indian's saddle.
Hey guys,
That's proof we needed.
Here's why all three have left
city this morning.
- In which direction?
- To San Juan.
- San Juan, huh?
- Uh, I know what you think.
And if you think about what I think
you should not go alone.
This test will help us
the governor.
I propose to go that attach special
from gazeta Paradise City.
- Horatio, went to Mexico.
- By train, I hope.
Here's where it is.
From this saddle.
- Let's spin least here.
- Who are you looking gentlemen?
- The owners of horses, is not it?
- Yes.
- Waiting for you.
- Where?
The flour mill.
You pick up there.
Onion!
On we looking for?
Come ..
Now you've got.
Hey, Onion.
With-in!
A, there you are?
Hey, wait!
Thanks,
little and I suffocate.
- Hello.
- Yes where is Bella stretch?
- Trech I'm looking for Bella?
- Yes.
Look a little later.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
What a coincidence,
you even looking for you.
- This will make you sings.
- No, never.
How? How?
And come to horse asshole
since lightning speed.
That crazy guy with onions and
The journalist had captured
Stink and the idiot of course
trying to make
confess the truth about
work with Foster and others.
But here I am Mr. Lamb law.
I use ostrich tactics.
- Total Insabiamento.
- Tactics ostrich, the ostrich!
There are so stupid to
believe what they say.
More than likely will notify
Federal police dim El Passo
and this will mean the end
our company.
We take refuge, one
work remains to be done,
To intercept them and to
shut forever.
- I make myself clear?
- But you have said
to finish with violence.
Sheriff will now see how
remove a man in legal ways.
They will cross El Passo and
ESTA will cross and obviously Gola
- Do not you?
- That's right!
And we may expect
the word of Petrus.
If those two tâmpiþii
May I laugh buffer.
Shut up!
You need me sir?
Maybe I am wrong but the world will
hear of this man.
What else do you want from me
I already told you everything I know.
We just want to sign a statement
sheriff before federal
when we arrive in El Passo.
Just so.
If we arrive in El Passo.
Ceparule terminus,
let's go ahead Stink!
Sure, sure, even this
I wanted to do
I used it only as
compass that knows the area.
Ready.
I am a lucky man finally
I found
And we have killed you.
Oh .. Manitou
Indians have great luck.
Always attack on its soil.
Kill a man in cold blood,
motherfuckers, you are like assassins.
Yes, exactly, you are like assassins.
- Who, us?
- Of course.
We all witnessed the
Stinky you killed.
- Do not you guys?
- And arms belongs to Onion.
Yes, I admit this gun
it's even.
- No, no!
- Come do your job Sheriff.
Onion and Jack. You Pulitzer
arrested for first degree murder.
Happened to know
any good lawyer?
I do not.
If anyone has anything
To say ... I eat
Quiet!
Make peace in the bar.
Gentlemen ..
You speak.
Objection.
- Defense is the word.
- Your Honor, I have no words ..
You're stupid when I speak
I should not stop anyone.
We have gathered here to learn
truth
lawsuit against him
Onion and Jack Pulitzer.
The Court heard
those here present ...
sheriff and 11 other witnesses.
Your Honor, as
The defense lawyer ..
I said not to speak one
until I give the word.
After I saw the defendants
Onion and Jack Pulitzer
how they killed an unarmed man
and defenseless.
Before the jury asked
to deliberate
and to render their verdict, if
witnesses for the defense
to come and testify
Your Honor, defense ...
One more word and ask to be arrested.
So someone else .. let courage
even no one,
for defense?
When the jury may withdraw
to decide the verdict.
You do not need Mr. Judge, the verdict
was already decided: GUILTY!
Father!
Before .. Court to rule
sentence
defendants have something to say?
Yes ... I would like to hear what he wanted to
Our lawyer told defensive.
He did not want to talk ..
After listening to all
testimony and jury verdict,
is left to do is
sentenced to death.
The sentence will be executed
tomorrow at dawn.
Yes, at dawn.
I can not rest at all
after this failure.
Stop a little pang
and we shall rest from all
Damn!
Take care.
What do you want dwarfs?
I just wanted to see him friend
our last.
- And in what you?
- I brought some food.
Onions, Sheriff what to do?
Well, eat that shit
it will smell and hell.
Hey guys!
- Hello Onion
- How nice to see you.
Are for me? Oo Thanks!
Bomb!
Finally the truth, the life I
expected to draw an issue like this.
Brave boys, but be careful
...
Come on, give it up.
Thank you, thank you .. Onion.
How cool you are.
Let's face, and not
try to do tricks.
I was hard to find after
smell your stinking onion.
I said to the wall.
And you shorty.
And watch how you move it
this is gun barrel.
Stop it or else ..
- And now what about these two?
- I have an idea.
- Sheriff! Sheriff!
- Ssssstt!
- What?
- Come say!
- I've looked everywhere, I did not find.
- Disappeared.
Others have not yet come
may have found her.
Accident.
- What does this mean?
- I am the last edition.
They printed pajamas.
Hey Jack come and read
Look, Stink murder
the killers oilmen.
Here are the names of all those
I've removed.
Come to light.
Here are listed all the money
that we received from Oil & Company.
If any of the newspapers reach
I put a governor's hands!
Do not go, stay quiet.
FINALLY THE TRUTH
- Go, get lost.
- Where to go?
You need a newspaper
to end the newspapers.
- That?
How to fix newspapers
Mr. Lamb?
Make them disappear,
destroy all copies.
And I want 'ready' to type
with onions until noon.
Cheese and nemarinat.
I want dessert.
- Were unmasked at last, is not it?
- Type of onion saved us!
Finally the truth came out.
Learn the truth, the whole truth
in Gazeta in Paradise City!
The whole truth! The truth about
illegal oilmen.
Destroy newspapers. Burn them,
burn them all!
Eliminates hârþoagele this!
You make me to stop smoking.
- Ready! Reading banned.
- Get out of here.
I want all copies of the newspaper
to be burned right now.
Needless, Sheriff!
You want to destroy the papers, but
truth can not be hidden.
And what about the law, Sheriff?
One law matters, and
that's my gun!
Teach yourself ceparule.
You still have time.
You alone against all!
So I like.
- Onions or gun.
- Gun.
What was dressed sexy sheriff ..
- Stand still, stop.
- Freeze ceparule.
It's ours is ours.
Asshole. Cretins, idiots!
It's your fault!
It is useless to try to flee,
dude, stop or pull ..
Prepare for the worst.
- I give permission .. ?
- Who is it?
You are dear?
Even open.
Door .. !
- Hey, where are you going?
- At ..
How do you feel
- Does it hurt?
- Yes.
I think that would be
better to go.
Let's go boys, take it easy not to
get out from the crowd.
Ajutooor!
Mr. Lamb!
Are you finished Mr. Lamb!
You only left hand gold
but it's good just to catch flies.
- You left all.
- Yes I was alone.
But in your place
I would not sing victory.
Now I was just us two.
To kill you would be a good idea
I would turn into a hero
and do not want to do that.
I want to make you dust.
Courage, let's see
you know to do.
This time I will destroy.
You have my word.
Fuck you, come here ..
- Young man sitting on my stomach.
- Actually Your stay on mine.
My hand ..
Freeze!
Sit or I'll shoot!
Peace, to make peace, Mr. Lamb!
Please forgive me.
- Friends? No?
- No.
No, no ..
Benjamin!
Courage, and close the holes
we are sowing ago.
Are you sure that you are interested in a
million dollars in a Swiss bank?
- What do you think Horatio?
- No, not God.
- In Switzerland there are many cows.
- Sorry, Horatio is old,
and Switzerland is far ..
Benjamin run and bring cans,
Hurry!
- Yes sir!
- Oh, no.
There is no place on this planet
where to you can make a hole
in this land,
without that mess out?
Yes, in Italy.
Earth this is not good
the cultivated onion, Horatio.
- Finally you understand.
- What are you doing?
I take my cart and go, live?
Hey ceparule I finished with you.
Come back!
S F A R S I T