Throw down that strongbox.
[Gunshot]
[Screaming]
[Rattling]
You're sure gettin' mighty
handy with them guns, Johnny boy.
Yeah. It's too bad
Ma wasn't here to see you.
She'd be mighty
proud of you.
I kinda wish, though,
that...
you hadn't had
to kill that girl.
Yeah.
[Hoofbeats]
I know what you're
thinkin', Lattimore...
but you let the law
take care of this.
This is the only law
those two understand.
[Gunshots]
Come on!
Hyah!
[Gunshot]
[Gunshots]
- Looks like you got 'im.
- Yes.
I think the kids can take care
of themselves from now on.
- [Wood Cracking]
- [Dog Barks In Distance]
[Man]
Don't touch it.
You're lucky it's me found ya
instead of Ben Lattimore.
[Tapping]
If I were you, Jethro,
I'd go fishin'.
Well, you ain't me,
and the creek's dried up.
Now you're not
as fast with a gun as you used to be.
It's a 24-hour ride from Prescott
to Apache Wells-
even if you take
the shortcuts.
Now you know nobody's
gonna back you up...
not against
Ben Lattimore.
You don't hear too good,
Benton.
I said it was a 24-hour ride
from Prescott to here.
Me and the Sims boys won't be here
when Lattimore shows up.
We gonna catch the morning
stage for the territorial prison.
Well, you're
the marshal.
- Oh, no time for that now.
- Did they get 'em?
- Locked up in Apache Wells.
- Don't worry about it, old girl.
We'll ride in and bust 'em
out like we did before.
Well, this is a different
town and a different jail.
And the kids killed a girl,
so nobody has any sympathy for them-
- not even for littleJohnny.
- That fool kid's trigger happy.
- He's been asking for this.
- Hold your tongue, Adam Scott!
- He's my baby.
- That's one tough baby.
Well, he had good teachers-
you and me and the rest of this outfit.
Look, Jeb had the same teachers,
but he doesn't go around shooting women.
Johnny had to shoot
that girl.
His mistake was not to make
sure that she was dead...
like mine was not to make
sure that Lattimore was dead.
- Well, isn't he?
- No.
So we have him
to worry about too.
He won't let my kids come to trial.
He has sworn to kill them.
We'll get 'em outta
that jail fast.
We don't have to.
The marshal's going to do it for us.
Ben, how could you?
Over her grave.
- She'd understand.
- I don't.
- Well, Sis grew up with guns around her.
- And died by one.
- So the men who killed her will have to pay for it.
- They've been caught, Ben.
- They're in jail.
- They've been in jail before and got away!
[Sighs]
Let the law punish them, Ben.
Punishing's gonna be
my job.
Well, if you go, I won't be here
when you come back.
Sally, I love you, but I can't let them
get away with it.
[Clears Throat] You goin' straight
through to Moccasin, miss...
or stopping off
at Apache Wells?
- Straight through.
- [Laughs] So am I.
Uh, someone meeting you
in Moccasin?
- Nobody's meeting me anywhere.
- Oh. [Laughs]
Come on, baby.
Here you are.
All right, you two. I wanna get you
to the territorial prison...
before Beth Lattimore's
brother catches up with us.
There's no one
in there, ma'am.
I would like
to buy a ticket.
Here comes
the agent now.
- How much is the ticket to Moccasin, please?
- Huh?
How much is the ticket
to Moccasin?
Fifteen dollar, ma'am...
but if you take my advice,
you'll wait till tomorrow.
- Well, I'm in a hurry. Why should I wait?
- [Footsteps]
That's why.
[Horse Blusters]
In the back.
- That's Jeb and Johnny Sims.
- Who are they?
- You never heard of them two hoodlums?
- No!
[Grunts]
Well, alongside of them...
John Wesley Hardin
was a Sunday school boy.
My, my, my! And one
of them is just a child.
Yeah, well, so was Billy the Kid.
Now you still want a ticket?
Well, you see, my daughter's
going to have a baby.
Don't you remember? I telegraphed last
night to her husband that I was coming.
Well, you'll have to
sit on top with the driver.
- It's good enough.
- So will you, miss.
How about me?
- You sit inside.
- With those murderers?
There's always
tomorrow.
- Who are these people?
- Passengers.
I'm still runnin'
a stage line.
Two of'em have got through tickets,
so I can't kick 'em off.
And this here lady's
gonna have a baby.
[Laughs] At my age? He means
my daughter is going to have one.
Well, I'd appreciate it
if you folks would take the next stage.
I've got some
desperate men here.
Well, Marshal, I just
have to be with my daughter.
- You see, this is her first child.
- And I just can't wait.
I reckon ain't nothin'
I can do about it.
But you ladies'll
have to ride up top.
- It's safe up there.
- [Grunts]
What's your name,
mister?
- Sam Gill.
- Occupation?
Drummer.
I'll take that,
Mr. Gill.
I may need it
to protect myself.
Any protectin' needs
to be done, I'll do it.
That's a lot of gun
for a drummer.
I ride the stages
a lot, Marshal.
They get stuck up
a lot.
Hop aboard.
When Ben Lattimore gets here,
I want you to keep your mouth shut.
Tell everybody else too.
I don't want him catchin' up to us.
What's the matter,
you scared of him, Jethro?
Bible says a man's life span
is three score and ten years.
I got ten more to go.
Expect to be around
at the finish.
- This'll be a pretty dusty trip, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Wire my old man at Cottonwood we'll
be stoppin' long enough to change horses.
Oh, yeah. Tell 'im
to try to stay sober.
Giddyap there!
[Stagecoach Rattling]
[Hoofbeats]
[Telegraph Tapping]
[Horse Whinnies]
[Gunshot]
- [Shouts]
- [Whinnying]
Now get outta here!
Hyah! Hyah! Get!
- Just a couple of Indians.
- Good. We'll blame it on them.
- How?
- Take 'em out and bury 'em.
Everybody knows you can't
trust an Indian.
We lost a few men.
How do you explain their bodies away?
- Bury 'em too. The old man
we'll leave for the buzzards.
- All right.
Now then. You just give the keys
to the drummer there...
then lock your hands
behind your head.
Could be that gun
ain't loaded.
Well, maybe I'll just
pull the trigger and see. The keys!
I ain't got 'em, sonny. Gave 'em
to Piute just before we pulled out.
[Laughs]
He's lyin', Jeb.
- No, he isn't. L-I saw him do it.
- Pull the trigger.
Go ahead.
Dixon'll hear the shot.
Next thing you know,
him and that Indian will have their guns...
stickin' through
both them windows.
Chances are, they'll
take you both back to Apache Wells...
turn you over
to Ben Lattimore.
Or, then again,
theyjust might shoot you-
Be done with it.
Don't let 'em
bluff ya, Jeb.
I never bluff, sonny.
I like life
just as much as you do.
Now why don't you just
give me that gun and let me load it?
We had a chance, and you-
you passed it up!
Now, now, now. There'll be-
There'll be others.
Why, you
old buzzard, you!
I don't like ridin' on rough roads
with loaded shotguns.
Sometimes they just
go off by themselves.
So I'll just keep ol' Betsy
pointed at you two...
in case that happens.
Now they were here yesterday,
but they're not here today.
Why?
Could it be that somebody might have
warned the marshal that I was coming?
Yup. Telegraph key.
Now he didn't take 'em
outta town on horseback...
so he must've used
the stage.
What stage, mister?
Well, now, I ain't at liberty to tell you
anything, Mr. Lattimore.
Now come on, now.
Put that thing away.
Unless I'm misinformed, you never shot
an unarmed man before.
Well, I never had any
cause to until now.
[Sighs]
Well, the marshal's my friend.
He told me not
to tell you anything.
Now if that's cause
for killin', go ahead.
Well, say I had shown up
unexpectedly.
Would you have helped
him stand me off?
Not me or anybody else.
We don't care how Jeb
and Johnny Sims die, just so they die.
Well, they got a lot
of friends in the territory...
friends that might help
them if they had a chance.
Now if I don't kill them,
they just may not die.
Well, now, I'll tell ya, their friends ain't
gonna get 'em outta territorial prison.
- [Laughs]
- Well, thanks.
- Did I say anything for you to thank me for?
- Yeah. Uh-huh.
Now, do you know of anybody around
here that's got a good horse for sale?
Mine's just about had it, and it's a long,
long ride to the territorial prison-
even if you know
the shortcut.
Let's get outta here, Dix.
That's my old man
over there, Marshal.
Horses gone. Old man dead.
Indian boys gone.
- You think they killed him?
- No. Good boys.
Take a look around
while I get a shovel.
- Too bad.
- He was a no-good old drunk.
- So? Leave him to buzzards.
- You don't do that to your old man, Piute.
Somebody please
help me down.
You stay where you are, ma'am.
We may have to get outta here in a hurry.
Any signs to tell ya
who might've done it?
No. Looks like they
wanted the horses.
Or maybe they didn't
want us to have 'em.
Dix, I know how you feel
about your old man...
but we gotta get outta here
fast, son.
I'm buryin' him,
and that's that.
Lady, I told you
to stay put.
Them that done this
might still be around.
Oh, dear. I didn't
think of that.
Since I'm down, I might as well
stay down, hmm?
- I'll take a look at your bag.
- What on earth for?
Women have been known
to carry Derringers.
Hey, old man. You'd better search her,
she might have one in her bustle.
I have a good mind
to slap your impertinent face.
You stay away from them.
They kill women.
I wish now I'd stayed in Apache Wells
and turned them over to Ben Lattimore.
Much shooting. Much blood.
Many tracks.
White men's tracks.
I think Indian boys dead.
If you want,
I find bodies.
No. I just wanna plant the old man
and get outta here.
[Horse Blustering]
[Blows]
[Piute]
That good, Dix.
A bottle'd be more
appropriate.
How 'bout givin' me
my gun back, Marshal?
I can be some help
if we're attacked.
You wanna help?
Help her up top.
And you'd better
tie her down.
Hey, Dix! Hurry it up!
- Say a prayer, Dix?
- Not for him.
For us.
Keep movin'.
Giddyap!
- Whoa!
- Now what?
Sorry, folks. You're gonna have to
walk for a while.
Otherwise, we'll never
make it up this grade.
Dix say hill too much
for horses. Everybody walk.
Well, that's all right
with us, ain't it, Johnny?
When Dix said everybody walk,
he didn't mean you two.
Piute, take
the other side.
Giddyap there!
Hyah!
- Shouldn't you be running behind us?
- Marshal say watch them.
They cannot run away
chained up like that...
but somebody might
sneak up behind us in the dust.
You want to see behind?
Go back there.
- [Rumbling]
- Let's get outta here.
[Indistinct]
Come on! Hyah!
[Horse Blusters]
Why don't we stop in Calico
and get some fresh horses?
I wish I could, ma'am,
but nobody lives there anymore.
When the gold ran out,
everybody pulled up stakes...
and the only thing alive yonder is rats,
bats, and rattlesnakes.
At this rate, we'll never get
to Moccasin.
Well, if we go any faster, ma'am, we'll never
make the next relay station 15 miles away.
Giddyap there!
Dix! Come take look!
Piute! Everybody
stay where you are!
Watch the prisoners.
That took a bit
of doin'.
A few sticks of dynamite.
You beginnin' to rile me, ma'am.
You get right back up there.
- I just wanted to look.
- You can see all there is to see from up there!
- Inside.
- And get myself shot?
Hello, Jethro.
- Did you wreck the bridge?
- No, it was down when I got here...
a halfhour ago.
You see, somebody else
besides myself...
is interested in that scum
that you been protecting.
Now I can pick both
of those boys off real quick...
but I'd rather
give 'em a chance.
That's more than
they gave my sister.
Now you get 'em outta there
and turn that stagecoach around...
and go back
the way you came.
But leave the keys with me
so I can take off those handcuffs.
- Then what?
- Well...
I brought along
a spare one, Jethro.
I thought they might
take turns usin' it.
Well, that isn't exactly
what I'd call "a chance," Ben.
- I've seen you in action.
- Have you seen them?
They've killed a lot of people, Jethro-
and not always in the back.
Lawman's job is to protect his prisoners,
see they get a fair trial.
I don't trust juries.
Now hop to it and get 'em outta there.
Do what he says, Marshal.
I wanna get this stage outta here.
Well, then turn it around.
I've lived a long time without
takin' orders from a gunfighter.
I'm too old to start now.
Hold it, Ben.
Sims boys deserve killing.
Take chains off.
Whoever wrecked that bridge
didn't do it for fun.
Let 'im have 'em.
I wanna stay in one piece.
Boys take pistol,
we in worse soup.
Ben, I won't let you
murder them!
If I wanted to murder them,
they'd be dead by now.
Are their deaths
more important than our lives?
I'm saving your lives
by taking them off the wagon.
Will you let us
get rollin'?
I've got a tired team here
and I got no place to go but back.
Come on along with us.
We can use your guns.
No, there's no use
talking to him.
He's so full of hate,
nothing else matters to him.
Let him go, Marshal.
He wants his blood, let him have it.
He's beyond decency,
beyond reason.
All right. The killing can wait.
Turn the wagon around. I'll ride with ya.
Come on, miss.
We got no more time to waste.
Too bad. Gunfighter's way
much better.
Maybe shotgun
go off by mistake, huh, Chief?
Both barrels.
Get aboard, you
bloodthirsty savage.
Stop up ahead up there.
Hold up there.
You know, nobody's been over
that road to Calico in a dog's age.
Why should they be?
Town's been dead for 40 years.
There's still plenty water,
feed and shelter up there.
I say it's a good place
to hole up.
I don't think that road back to Apache Wells
is going to be particularly safe tonight...
not with a team
that can barely walk.
What you suddenly
interested in us for, Ben?
I thought all you wanted to do
was to kill my prisoners.
That's still
the only interest I have...
but I still say
let's hole up in Calico.
What do you think, Dix?
Well, if I'm gonna get shot at,
I'd just as soon be inside.
There's nothing
to hide behind up here.
And he's right about the horses.
They're beat.
Well, I wish you'd thought of it
instead of Lattimore.
I've never seen a gunfighter
you could trust.
Nobody's asking you
to trust me.
I'm here
for only one reason.
Taken me a long time
to catch up with those two...
and I don't intend
to let them get away.
Well, maybe
what you're suggesting...
is just what those men who blew up
the bridge want us to do.
Maybe we're walkin'
right into a trap.
Traps are easy to see
in the daylight.
Besides, maybe, uh- maybe you've got
something here they don't expect- me.
You make the difference?
[Chuckles]
Why don't you ask your prisoners?
Turn me loose
and give me a gun...
and you'll be looking at the man
who killed Ben Lattimore.
I might just do that,
sonny.
One way or the other.
Won't make any difference
to the world.
All right, Dix.
Let's take this man's advice.
- [Door Closes]
- Giddyap here!
[Organ, Faint]
[Continues]
What do you think,
Piute?
Wind blow signs away,
maybe.
Yeah, maybe.
This best place?
Well, I'll take
a look inside. Here.
[Continues]
- [Snake Hissing]
- [Gunshot]
Snake.
All right, stay outside.
There may be some more in here.
Your man?
No.
Look, I thought I told you
to wait outside.
Why should I listen to you, Ben?
You never listen to me.
- Well, we'll talk about that later.
- Later?
The shooting will be over,
and either they'll be dead or you will.
- There won't be any shooting for a while.
- But eventually there will be.
Where you are,
there always is.
My being here
has nothing to do with it.
- Ben-
- Look, who ran out on who?
You know why I ran out.
I don't like to be touched
by hands with blood on them.
Sally, I've told you before.
You picked the wrong man.
You should have looked
at my hands the day we met.
[Chain Clatters]
All right, you two.
Out.
[Chain Rattling]
- Now inside.
- You know, if you were smart, you'd let us go.
We'll be free
by tomorrow anyway.
We got friends. Who, uh-
Who do you think wrecked that bridge?
- Shut up, Johnny.
- If you do have friends...
and if they do show...
you ain't gonna be
in no condition to meet 'em.
Now get inside.
Right in there, Marshal.
- ## [Humming]
- Over there.
Marshal, we couldn't find
any beds or chairs...
so your prisoners
have to sleep on the floor.
Sit down.
- We won't be staying long.
- I sure hope not.
Sooner the marshal puts you back
to jail where you belong, the better.
Yak, yak, yak. Will you get her
out of here, Marshal?
I mean, being chained up's
bad enough...
without listening
to a gabby old woman.
I have got a good mind
to put you over my knee!
You know, Johnny, our ma should've
done that to us a long time ago.
Then maybe we'd have turned out to be
fine, upright citizens-
- like the marshal here.
- [Chuckles]
It's a little late to start
blaming your ma, ain't it?
She's got
a lot to be blamed for.
Oh, I don't know. Our ma always wanted us
to have the good things in life.
- We've had 'em.
- And we'll keep havin' 'em.
No, I wouldn't count on that if I were you,
not as long as I'm alive.
One day you're
gonna run into someone...
who really knows
how to handle a gun.
- Like you?
- Like me.
Well, you might find things
a little different.
You see, I'm not a woman,
and my back won't be turned.
Well, I'll nail the shutters on the windows,
and that ought to do it.
Oh, Marshal, you know, when I came
in here before, this, uh, desk was open.
Now unless Mrs. Gregory
is a very, very tidy woman-
[Johnny Laughing]
The help we're gonna get's
comin' from the outside, Mr. Lattimore.
Now don't
get yourself killed...
because, uh,
I want that pleasure.
Johnny, will you shut up?
This man is gunnin' for you and me.
Well, he's got scruples.
That's another thing
I wouldn't count on.
They've got them in the old saloon.
It's not gonna be a picnic.
You're forgettin'
one thing- Ma.
Marshal, would you call the driver and
that nice Indian to come to have supper?
As soon as I get through eatin',
me and Lattimore will relieve 'em.
Well, then. That leaves only those
two miserable boys.
Probably do them both good
to go hungry.
[Sighs] That wouldn't be
Christian, would it?
Is it all right if I take them some food?
Or would you rather do it?
You take it, ma'am.
I gotta watch this window.
But, ma'am, before you do-
and I don't like
asking you to do this-
but would you let
the young lady search you?
I ought to be indignant,
but I suppose...
you have to be
suspicious of everybody.
However, I refuse
to undress in public.
Back of those curtains,
miss.
You better start
trustin' somebody, Marshal.
You may need help.
I'm gonna need help
pretty bad...
before I start trusting a man
that calls himself a drummer...
and carries a.38
double-action Colt.
Carried, Marshal.
Past tense.
You took it.
I could have told him
it was ridiculous.
Oh, don't blame him, Sally.
He's a worried man.
Well, if I were you,
I'd be very angry.
And we are dealing with murderers now.
Don't forget that.
She had a Gatling gun
in her bustle.
Oh, Sally, don't. Don't.
You're upsetting
the poor man.
I do what I think
needs to be done.
Uh, keep the door open.
Why?
If she gets too close to them,
they might grab her.
Say something loud and mean.
About time you gave us
something to eat!
Can't you at least give us somethin'
to wash this muck down with?
[Shouting] Having children myself,
I hate to say this...
but hanging
is too good for you!
[Softly] Uncle and his men
will be here before morning.
Hey, I knew Ma
wouldn't let us down.
She let us down
from the day we were born.
Brought us up
to rob and kill.
And when our old man protested,
she kicked him out.
Johnny, Ma loves us.
Look what she's done. We got guns,
and Uncle Adam is on his way.
Uncle, hell.
He's no kin of ours.
He's one of the reasons
she kicked Pa out.
Well, knowin' Pa better than you did,
I can't say as I blame her much.
He let the whole world
walk over him.
[Dog Barks In Distance]
Drink it up. We want to get
these dishes washed.
Johnny, you didn't eat anything.
Johnny, baby.
Don't call me "baby."
I'm a grown man.
I shot a girl
in the back, remember?
What's wrong with him?
He's tired of living,
scared of dying.
Oh, Johnny. Johnny, baby, everything
will be all right.
She's sure been in there
a long time.
Here.
Ungrateful little beasts!
I should have
let them starve.
They're not gonna live
long enough for that.
[Dog Barks In Distance]
Come on down, Dix.
I'll take over while you eat.
- Be sure and watch that back window.
- Right.
- Don't see nothin'.
- Go get yourself somethin' to eat.
- Here you are.
- Thank you, ma'am.
[Door Opens]
What are you doing out here?
We left some things unsaid.
- I didn't want to walk out on you.
- And I didn't want you to.
- But you wouldn't do what I asked you to.
- I couldn't.
Nobody kills somebody I love
and gets away with it.
So bent on vengeance
you'd destroy us both.
- Not vengeance. Justice.
- An eye for an eye isn't justice.
Well, in my book it is
and always has been.
It's not right to kill, Ben. No matter
what the provocation, it's just not right.
Sally, this is Arizona territory,
not a Quaker meeting house.
Out here you don't turn
the other cheek and stay alive.
You could take off that gun belt
like I asked you to.
Oh, Sally.
Ben, someday you're gonna meet
someone younger and faster...
and then Boot Hill,
and a gravestone will say...
"Here lies a man who
didn't know when to quit."
Honey, I don't
want you to die.
Yeah, but you want me
to turn the other cheek.
- Well, that's different.
- What's different about it?
Tonight there's going to be a shooting,
and somebody will get killed.
If I asked you to make the marshal free
the Sims boys, would you?
- I asked him to free 'em.
- So you could kill them.
I still have that in mind.
[Dog Barks In Distance]
From the top of that building,
you can see the saloon.
- Get up there.
- What do you expect me to do, draw their fire?
Just get up there and keep your head
down and your eyes open.
They got guards posted, and I want
to know where they are.
[Horse Blusters]
Wait here.
[Hoofbeats Approaching]
Go inside and send Dixon out.
Piute! Move out of the water trough.
[Marshal]
What was that all about?
I guess they're just
feeling us out.
Marshal, this shotgun's
no good at long range.
Why don't you go inside and cover,
and I'll take over here.
Oh, you better give this
to the drummer.
I ain't too sure
about him yet.
That character we were just
shooting at didn't come alone.
And we're gonna need
all the help we can get.
All right, Ben.
[Dog Barks In Distance]
I suppose if I trust Ben Lattimore,
I have to trust you.
Yeah, it's a beauty.
If you have to use it, be sure
it's pointed at the right people.
- Can you use a gun, miss?
- No.
All you have to do is to point it,
cock it and pull the trigger.
The Bible says,
"Thou shall not kill."
I'm afraid the Sims boys and their friends
don't live by the good book.
Well, I do.
When someone's about to shoot at you,
there's no time for quoting scriptures.
Anyway, the Bible
is full of killing.
Marshal,
let me have a pistol.
I may not be CalamityJane, but I sure
know one end from the other.
All right, ma'am.
You watch that rear door.
You get behind the bar.
Gill, you watch the front.
I'll take the back window.
- You spot him?
- Yes.
Get back up there and pick him off.
We'll circle the place.
[Dog Barks In Distance]
[Whispering]
Hey! Pistolero...
you see 'em?
No, but they're out there.
[Gunshot]
- [Gunshot]
- [Glass Shatters]
Drop it, Marshal.
[Gunshot]
[Groaning]
Handcuff keys.
- [Screams]
- The keys!
Give it to me.
[Groaning]
Come over here.
Get the keys
out of his vest pocket.
Give it to me.
Give me those shells.
[Gasping] In my- In my left-hand
coat pocket- gun. Give it to me.
[Exhales]
Put it in my hand.
- Can you shoot?
- I don't know. I don't know.
Lift me. Lift me.
[Grunting]
It had to be done, girl.
Lift me up.
[Groaning]
Put- Put my finger
on the trigger.
[Gasps]
Cock it. Cock it.
[Hammer Cocks]
[Exhales]
Good girl.
You shot once.
Can you do it again?
I think so.
Take that pistol.
Both hands.
Rest it on the bar.
Now point it at-
at that rear door...
and if you miss,
keep pulling the trigger.
Oh, Johnny, baby.
Johnny, baby-
Oh, let me go. Come on, Jeb,
we're gettin' out of here.
[Grunts]
- [Gunshots Continues]
- Trouble inside. You go.
[Gunshot]
[Clicking]
Adam!
Poor Uncle Adam.
Ma's sure gonna miss him.
[Groaning Softly]
Which one of you killed him?
I did.
- Ma-
- She's dead, so you can't help her.
- There's somebody with a gun
at the end of the bar.
- [Hammer Clicks]
- You've run outta help.
- Who needs it?
I do,
for one, Johnny.
Maybe we better quit
while we're still alive, huh?
He won't let us
stay alive.
Well, if we threw out
our guns, maybe he will.
And then
it's up the rope we go.
I'm comin' out.
You'll have to go in
and get him, Lattimore.
He's a stubborn boy.
[Johnny]
Nobody's hangin'me, gunfighter.
When I die, it'll be
with a gun in my hand.
[Ben]
That suits me.
This afternoon you were gonna
turn me loose and shoot it out.
- Still willing to?
- If that's what you want.
I'll, uh-
I'll need a gun belt.
Ben, please.
Don't do it, Ben.
You'll have to
come and get it.
First, those guns you're packin'-
Pitch 'em out on the bar. Come on!
Where is it?
Over there on the chair.
This'll do just fine.
There's your gun.
Ben, he's only a kid.
You can't. It's murder.
Oh, he's a few weeks
older than he was...
when he killed my sister.
You're a plain
damned fool, Johnny.
Yeah? Watch.
[Whimpering]
[Whimpering, Crying]
[Sniffling, Crying]
I walked out once.
I wouldn't have walked out again.
How was I to know it?
There's a lot more blood
on my hands tonight.
There's blood on mine too.
[Crying]
[Sniffles]
Cheer up, Johnny.
They ain't hanged us. Not yet.
You think
more friends come?
You can't never tell.
Better not. Blow guts
out left hand same as right.
Ben, I don't make
mistakes very often...
but when I do,
they are beauties.
I was wrong about you.
If I'd have handed over the keys
to the jail to you in Apache Wells...
none of this would've
ever happened.
I don't think you would have
handed me the keys.
[Chuckles]
[Groaning]
[Sighs]
Piute, you keep
that shotgun cocked...
and pointed
in the right direction.
You take care of this.
[Grunts]
And this.
Hyah!
Subripped by Tantico (Croatia)