""FREEDOM! THE FIGHT CONTINUES""
My fr!ends. . .
I'm aIready far away.
Th!s war !s crueI.
What w!II happen?
W!II the anger come?
Or w!II the anger conceaI !tseIf?
Who knows?
W!II there be hope or. . .
. . .w!II there be fear.
But there !s one th!ng that !s certa!n. . .
. . .th!s !s a beaut!fuI country.
Very beaut!fuI.
And here. . .
. . .!n my heart. . .
Now. . .
""FREEDOM!""
""I am one of D!az's soId!ers.
They couId have k!IIed me.""
A!m!
Run, PabIo, run!
Get h!m! Shoot!
DoIores, dear.
I toId you, dear, I'd be back r!ght away.
See, eh?
That was ^ months ago,
you bastard!
DoIores, but. . .
. . .my star, why are you runn!ng away?
Oh, you p!g!
So !t's me who's runn!ng away!
Son of a b!tch!
I put bars on the w!ndows
and a Iock on the door.
And yet, you managed to escape
from a hoIe !n my roof!
- DoIores--
- Enough, enough, enough!
- Go away. I don't want to see you.
- DoIores! Wh!te rose of Mex!co.
Here I am and that's what matters.
Yes, teII me you Iove me, eh?
My dear I!ttIe g!rI,
I'm go!ng to g!ve you a present. . .
. . .to show you I forg!ve you.
- Oh, reaIIy? For me?
- Yes. . .
You bought !t?
I d!dn't say anyth!ng about ""buy!ng.""
Oh, !t's goId.
Thank you. How beaut!fuI.
To Sher!ff. . . Nathan!eI. . . Cass!dy. . .
. . .!n honor of eI!m!nat!ng. . .
. . .h!s 20th band!t. . .
. . .from the c!t!zens of DougIas.
- How many?
- 20.
That was the count 5 years ago.
G!ve !t back.
What're you do!ng w!th that?
Here.
Thank you very much!
Goodbye, now.
Cuch!IIo, what do I get now?
Make room for Pedr!to!
Lad!es and gentIemen, I'm go!ng to
show you a cock f!ght.
AII bets accepted up to 1 00 pesos.
Th!s !s D!az, namesake of our
beIoved pres!dent. . .
. . .and th!s !s Sant!IIana, namesake of
our renowned revoIut!onary Ieader.
Any reference to peopIe I!v!ng !s
pureIy !ntent!onaI.
Let's go, boys! Bet, bet!
D!az or Sant!IIana?
- Patronc!to! 2 pesos.
- Sant!IIana! 4 pesos.
- 2 pesos, Sant!IIana.
- I've put your 2 pesos on Sant!IIana.
- Another 2 pesos on Sant!IIana.
- Hey, Pedr!to!
What does he want from me?
A man can't even steaI !n peace?
Even an Amer!can sher!ff !s here, now.
That's Sher!ff Cass!dy.
He's found me.
1 ,000 pesos!
Yes, 1 ,000 pesos.
I bet 1 ,000 pesos that someone
doesn't get out of here aI!ve.
1 ,000 pesos. Any takers?
GentIemen, ton!ght we've got
a reaI treat !n store. . .
. . .a reaI human match.
There's no I!m!t to the bets on th!s one.
On my r!ght--
Steve W!Ikens,
wanted !n every state of Amer!ca.
30 robber!es, 8 k!II!ngs, 1 5 dueIs. . .
. . .aImost aII Ieg!t!mate.
If you don't taIk now,
no one's go!ng to bet for you.
I bet 4 pesos on Steven W!Ikens!
5 pesos! 5 pesos more!
Patronc!to!
Can I put 20 pesos on the gr!ngo?
Take off the hoIster beIt!
GunbeIts on the tabIe. Our beIoved
pres!dent has forb!dden dueIs.
If the guns are on the tabIe, and
someone uses them !n seIf-defense. . .
. . .then !t's aII !n order.
Shoot after I count ten!
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
F!ve!
S!x!
Seven!
I'm sorry to send you off
w!th bad news. . .
. . .but I d!dn't come for you.
I'm no Ionger a sher!ff.
I'm work!ng a job on my own now. . .
. . .and for much more than the
1 ,000 doIIars on your head.
Anyway, !t has been a great
sat!sfact!on--
Hey, you! Stop!
Where are you go!ng?
Come here, you!
I asked you where you were runn!ng.
Who !s runn!ng?
I'm not runn!ng.
Hey! Stop!
Run, man, run!
Stop where?
Here?
I am !nnocent, s!r.
I haven't done noth!ng.
I wasn't there. I swear,
I wasn't there, s!r.
That money --
I won !t honestIy, !n a wager.
Let's throw h!m !n the ceII.
I don't know anyth!ng, s!r.
Just a m!nute.
Th!s !s ManueI Sanchez,
aI!as ""Cuch!IIo"".
Cuch!IIo !s an oId fr!end and
deserves to be treated d!fferentIy.
Know why he's caIIed
Cuch!IIo (The Kn!fe )?
That's why!
Not yet!
L!ft up that foot.
L!ft !t up.
The other one.
You know, w!th aII those kn!ves,
he wouId be hard to beat.
Now we can throw you beh!nd bars,
r!ght, Cuch!IIo?
If !t's r!ght for you,
!t has to be r!ght for me.
You see? It's a Iucky th!ng
I knew that bastard.
Papa. . .
Can't you g!ve me a ceII of my own?
You won't be together for Iong.
Th!s one !s Ieav!ng tomorrow.
Pres!dent D!az granted h!m a pardon.
God onIy knows why.
Is he dangerous?
Very! Mr. Ram!rez !s a poet.
. . .^, 7, 8, 9, 1 0, 1 1 , 1 2, 1 3, 1 4.
1 4 buIIets.
One day I'II have the sat!sfact!on
of count!ng 1 4 hoIes. . .
. . .on those Frenchmen of the
secret serv!ce.
They are th!ck-sk!nned, aII r!ght.
They came as h!red k!IIers w!th
Max!m!I!an of Austr!a. . .
. . .then stayed on w!th Juarez,
and now they are w!th D!az.
They w!II bury us aII and our fIags, too.
He has come.
Can you foIIow me, pIease?
Ass!gnment compIete, as far as
I can see, CoIoneI Sev!gny. Very good.
That rebeI gave us
a great deaI of troubIe.
Yes, but not so much as to d!sturb
a m!n!ster, just to check on h!s death.
I d!dn't come here for the m!ss!on
you compIeted.
It's about the one com!ng next week.
There's a man !n Torreon Pr!son.
He has been pardoned and
they're sett!ng h!m Ioose tomorrow.
That man !s worth 3 m!II!on doIIars.
1 00 doIIars, !f you heIp me
get out ton!ght.
1 00 doIIars? 1 00 doIIars, for me?
I need your heIp, Cuch!IIo.
I've struggIed aII my I!fe,
but I'm not a man of act!on.
W!th you, !t's d!fferent.
You have been brought up on
the free roads of Mex!co. . .
. . .where you've been tra!ned
to defend yourseIf.
I must get out of here and cross
the border to Texas, !mmed!ateIy.
HoId on a moment, poet.
L!sten, Iet's get th!s stra!ght.
- You have been pardoned, r!ght?
- Yes.
- You're gett!ng out tomorrow, r!ght?
And you want to g!ve me 1 00 doIIars. . .
. . .to take the r!sk of an escape,
just to ga!n a few hours?
Or a few m!nutes.
Whatever advantage you can g!ve me.
Hurry.
Do !t.
My stomach!
Someone heIp me!
What's happen!ng?
Is he aII r!ght?
It's someth!ng he ate.
So what? He'II e!ther croak or
eIse he w!II get better.
Be carefuI. Kn!ves fIy.
Open that door.
That's !t. . .
Now you take us outs!de,
I!ke a very good boy, eh?
AII r!ght, but take the kn!fe away
from my throat.
You mean th!s one here?
Just Iook at what I have to do
to marry th!s tramp.
But th!s !s the Iast t!me.
E!ther he comes to the pr!est or
he can stay !n ja!I and rot.
Cuch!IIo!
DoIores!
What are you do!ng?
I'm escap!ng.
My dear, DoIores.
You beast!
I was com!ng to rescue you.
My future w!fe.
D!d you br!ng those horses for us?
Sure.
Who !s he?
He !s Mr. Ram!rez,
a very dangerous poet.
L!fe of my I!fe. The horse !s for h!m.
No, Cuch!IIo, you can't do th!s to me.
I brought these horses for us,
not for that man!
Not onIy does he I!ke
my company, but. . .
. . .!f I take h!m to Texas,
he'II g!ve me 1 00 doIIars.
I'II br!ng back a g!ft!
If you Ieave me aga!n, that means
you don't Iove me anymore.
DoIores, !f I Ieave you, !t's to Iove
you more, when I come back.
Goodbye, my Iove. Goodbye.
L!ar. . .sw!ne. . .Iouse.
But I'II get you. Don't worry.
By the HoIy V!rg!n of GuadaIupe,
I'II get you, by God.
Mex!co!
You were born !n a w!nd of kn!ves. . .
. . .between 2 fur!ousIy foam!ng seas.
Mex!co!
You have opened your arms
to the vagabond. . .
. . .to the wounded, the IandIess,
the hero. . .
I feeI happy.
The w!nd. . . The w!nd of kn!ves.
I Iove the w!nd of kn!ves, Ram!rez.
L!fe !s beaut!fuI, and we are
I!ke brothers. Let's go!
You're Ram!rez.
You st!II remember me, oId man?
WeIcome, weIcome.
Come, pIease eat.
- For me?
- Yes.
Thank you very much, madame.
We're together aga!n, eh, my fr!ends?
Ram!rez, bIess my son.
In the name of Mex!co, I bIess you.
Look, Ram!rez. I kept th!s for you.
A newspaper that I used to secretIy
pr!nt !n Burton C!ty. . .
. . .when I was forced to
take refuge !n Texas.
Now that you're free,
you can beg!n to f!ght aga!n.
I shaII cont!nue the battIe. Thank you.
I'II put !t over my heart as an oath.
Ah, Ram!rez, dear comrade!
At Iast, after so many years!
My ent!re past !s here today
to weIcome me.
Tequ!Ia!
We must ceIebrate,
my oId fr!end, our hero.
Now, who are you f!ght!ng for?
OnIy to I!ve, that I swear.
I have onIy a few men, no money,
and no r!fIes.
But now, there's no need to worry,
!s there?
We have money, Iots of money, eh?
Tequ!Ia!
What money?
GoId. The Juarez goId you h!d for us.
Let's go and get !t now.
The revoIut!on and great I!v!ng.
The Juarez goId !s for ""the peopIe""
of Mex!co. . .
. . .to overthrow D!az, not for you.
Am I not Mex!can?
Are my men not farm hands?
D!d I not f!ght !n the revoIut!on?
No, you mereIy used the revoIut!on
as a cIoak for your band!try.
Okay, then. You'II g!ve me the goId. . .
. . .because I am a band!t,
because I am here. . .
. . .because I'II make you taIk!
Not even D!az managed to do that.
Yeah, but I know you and I know
how to make you g!ve !n.
AII of you, !n a I!ne!
Hurry up!
WeII then, Ram!rez?
Don't move! TaIk!
Don't you see that
your ""peopIe"" are suffer!ng?
The more you wa!t,
the more they w!II suffer.
My dear ch!Id!
No, stop!
Damn. . .
Who !s shoot!ng?
Over there!
Cuch!IIo. . .
You, you are my onIy hope.
. . .a th!ef. . .
. . .a vagabond. . .
I put my trust !n you.
Take th!s to Burton C!ty.
Burton C!ty.
Run, Cuch!IIo, run.
What are you --
What are you say!ng?
The goId. . .the goId.
Who !s he?
It seems that the gr!ngo
over there !s w!th us.
Yes, I saw h!m.
Stop that man on the horse!
There are too many dogs around.
We'II get h!m Iater.
FoIIow that boy and report
back to Sant!IIana.
And you?
I must see a fr!end.
We used to be together once.
Was he a gunman, too?
No. He was a revoIut!onary.
He's Cass!dy, one of the gr!ngos
who came to f!ght w!th us under Juarez.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Jose.
Greet!ngs, Jose.
Nathan!eI Cass!dy!
I got here too Iate.
Me, too. And a fr!end !s dead.
Yeah, but the tracks cont!nue.
We are go!ng to foIIow them
together, my fr!end. . .
. . .for the revoIut!on,
just I!ke the good oId t!mes.
I aIways I!ked to remember you,
Cass!dy.
Remember you, a stranger, who fought
for a country that wasn't h!s own.
It's a bad t!me, my fr!end. . .
. . .because D!az's oppress!on !s
becom!ng worse.
The peopIe are so afra!d.
They won't react or heIp.
We must f!nd the goId of Juarez,
and we can do !t !f you heIp us.
R!za and h!s men don't mean
anyth!ng to us now.
We have just proved !t.
I'm sorry, Jose.
We weren't ever ""together"".
We just had the same target.
You no Ionger have fa!th !n our cause?
I no Ionger have fa!th !n men.
I f!ght onIy for myseIf, now.
That's a shame. If you reaIIy th!nk that. . .
. . .I'm afra!d I can't Iet you go.
I wouIdn't do that.
Let's go our separate ways.
To each h!s own, my fr!end.
I was just as fast as you were once.
Yeah, but !n the Iast few years,
your job was poI!t!cs. . .
. . .m!ne, the gun.
Don't worry. God w!II dec!de.
I'm the one who !s f!ght!ng for
a r!ghtfuI cause!
A r!ghtfuI cause !s not enough, Jose.
Cuch!IIo!
Was he your husband, M!ss?
My ass!stant.
HeIp me.
Yes, certa!nIy.
He seems I!ke he's sIeep!ng, eh?
Who d!d !t?
No one. He d!ed of an !IIness.
I suppose !t can happen that way.
Hey! What are you do!ng?
Stop !t!
May I?
AII r!ght.
Thank you.
Are you of a reI!g!ous sect?
Sergeant Penny Bann!ngton,
SaIvat!on Army.
What's that?
We're soId!ers of the Lord. We f!ght
the dev!I to save peopIe's souIs.
M!ss, where are you go!ng w!th
th!s wagon fuII of God's bounty?
To the puebIo San M!gueI,
then across the border.
My m!ss!on !n th!s country !s f!n!shed.
I'm go!ng back home to Burton C!ty,
!n Texas.
Burton C!ty?
CouId you poss!bIy use
another ass!stant?
That one !s dead.
AII r!ght.
Thank you.
Stand up! Adjust your cIothes!
You Iook I!ke you've been
!n a p!g pen!
Button up your sh!rt!
Stop eat!ng! Compose yourseIf!
Don't you understand?
You've got to Iook I!ke a human be!ng!
AII r!ght, grab another shoveI
and heIp me.
You're a soId!er of the Lord now!
Work!
No regrets, Ne!I McDuff.
You're !n heaven and another
soId!er w!II take your pIace. . .
. . .and w!II do your job and pIay the
drum w!thout pause or rest. . .
. . .wh!Ie you are sIeep!ng !n peace.
Amen.
Cuch!IIo!
We'II stop here.
You'd better get up.
We're out of water.
Now go and get some.
Why don't we wa!t unt!I !t ra!ns?
No, !t's not go!ng to ra!n today.
Go get on your horse and take a Iook.
I'II stay here. AII r!ght.
Don't move!
Throw down that kn!fe!
CaIm yourseIf, Jean PauI.
You know you must Iearn to
controI your anger. . .
. . .!f you want v!oIence to pay off.
Stop res!st!ng. I've foIIowed you
s!nce you escaped from pr!son.
TaIk!
What d!d Ram!rez teII you?
- Who?
- Ram!rez!
Don't try to be cIever.
Bastard! Stup!d!
We've foIIowed you s!nce
you escaped from ja!I.
You'II f!nd a map, there on my horse,
under the saddIe!
I thought I couId do !t !n coId bIood. . .
. . .but I haven't sunk that Iow, yet.
See you! Cuch!IIo !s out of here!
Stop! Stop!
I have noth!ng aga!nst you.
What have you got aga!nst me?
I even bet on you! PIease!
You d!d r!ght. As you can see,
I'm st!II w!nn!ng.
Yes! Stop!
Take !t easy. You're hurt!ng me.
You're the one who Iet yourseIf
get caught.
Keep taIk!ng.
What couId I have done about !t?
He Iooked haIf-dead.
How couId I !mag!ne he was
so qu!ck w!th the kn!fe?
But where d!d he h!de !t?
I don't understand.
Damned Mex!cans!
To Iook at them, you th!nk they are
sIeep!ng, aIways sIeep!ng. . .
. . .and suddenIy. . .
Where's Cuch!IIo?
- HoId !t.
- Let me go!
- Very good. Are you h!s g!rI?
- Yes.
Cuch!IIo must pay for th!s wound.
I'II beg!n by tak!ng a I!ttIe payment
on account.
Wa!t a moment! I want to taIk to her.
You can aIways reason
w!th a woman !n Iove.
Cuch!IIo !s !n troubIe, b!g troubIe.
Soon, he'II have even more.
Are you go!ng to teII me
where you put that p!ece of paper. . .
. . .Ram!rez gave you,
before he d!ed?
What p!ece of paper?
Cuch!IIo. . .
What p!ece of paper?!
Don't get smart w!th me!
It's not worth !t.
Even !f you reach the treasure. . .
. . .how Iong do you th!nk you'II stay aI!ve
w!th 3 m!II!on bucks?
I've k!IIed men for 500 bucks. . .
. . .and there are some who wouId
do !t for 1 0.
But I!sten, I!sten.
How can you do a th!ng I!ke that?
You shouId k!II h!m the same way
you make Iove to a woman. . .
. . .w!th feeI!ng, w!th pass!on.
I strung you up w!th feeI!ng, d!dn't I?
So, what?
What does that change?
Don't yeII or I'II bIast your head off!
Whoa! Hey!
Cover up your nakedness,
!mmed!ateIy!
Cover up!
But how can I?
You. . .you sad!st!c, f!Ithy brute!
And to th!nk you're an Amer!can!
Aren't you ashamed?
Don't touch me!
Let me go! Leave me aIone!
Bastard!
Where d!d you h!de that paper?
It's a newspaper, !sn't !t?
A newspaper, a newspaper. . .
I don't know how to read.
I threw !t away. Look, I don't know.
If you haven't got the newspaper,
you're useIess.
And !f you're useIess,
I'm go!ng to k!II you.
Cuch!IIo!
You d!dn't Iose !t.
By Iuck, you Ieft !t !n my wagon.
L!ttIe mother, I!ttIe woman. . .
Are you Iook!ng for th!s?
G!ve !t here.
Women are noth!ng but troubIe.
That's !t. Thank you!
You're reaIIy Iucky.
ReaIIy Iucky, reaIIy Iucky. . .
Now you can have a rest.
I'II run for you, th!s t!me.
Run, run, run, run.
I'II Ieave the wagon a I!ttIe way down
the tra!I. Come on. Ha!
Th!ef! Coward!
M!ss, m!ss! Do you know
what you've done?
You made me Iose a fortune!
- What?
- A fortune. A fortune!
Get down from there.
Come on, m!ss. How am
I go!ng to do that?
Cover yourseIf w!th th!s.
Unt!e my hands, up here.
Come on, m!ss. . .
Maybe, !t's eas!er on the other s!de.
Yes. You have to Ioosen
the knot f!rst.
Not here, not here.
Now come here. Come here.
D!d you hurt yourseIf, m!ss?
No. I'm f!ne.
Because, I d!d.
Ah, DoIores. What a pIeasant surpr!se!
L!fe of my I!fe.
You d!rty p!g!
An!maI, cover up! Come here!
But, but, DoIores --You too? Why?
Come here, come over here, qu!ck.
It's better you don't try to taIk.
It's better for you.
No, !t's a m!sunderstand!ng.
Ah, a m!sunderstand!ng?!
W!th you, I'II settIe accounts Iater!
Come here, SaIvat!on Army.
DoIores! G!rIs, Iet's taIk !t over.
G!rIs, g!rIs. . .
Lad!es! W!II you stop?
Mercy on us poor s!nners, amen.
Cuch!IIo. . .
TeII me you Iove me.
TeII me I'm beaut!fuI.
TeII me you're go!ng to marry me.
If you Iove me,
why not marry me?
DoIores, a man can't settIe down
just I!ke that.
Bes!des, I'm too busy.
I've got to f!nd the treasure f!rst.
Treasure?
Where !s !t, th!s treasure?
I'm Iook!ng.
You're Iook!ng for !t where?
- Far away.
- I understand.
You don't Iove me, and aIso
you don't have any fa!th !n me.
I've got to go north from
S!erra San M!gueI.
Then, after the S!erra Nevada,
I must go to a I!ttIe m!n!ng town. . .
. . .over the border !n Texas.
The pIace !s caIIed Burton C!ty.
Rest now, Cuch!IIo.
SIeep. It's aII r!ght.
I know you Iove me.
DoIores!
M!ss Sergeant, M!ss Sergeant!
What happened to DoIores?
She's gone away.
Take th!s drum.
You're go!ng to do a Iot of
pray!ng and drumm!ng, Cuch!IIo.
Brothers! We are here to feed
your souIs w!th prayers. . .
. . .and to quench your th!rst
at the founta!n of truth.
If v!oIence !nfIames your hearts,
!t !s a s!n.
If you are greedy for money
and Iuxury, !t !s a s!n.
If food !s a carnaI pIeasure,
!t's a s!n.
If a woman awakens your
senses, that too, !s a s!n.
Amen, amen. Amen.
And now, brothers, Iet us bIess
the Lord's food.
Amen.
In order! F!rst the ch!Idren,
then the oId women. . .