Señor Reece is coming.
- Beg your pardon?
- He's here, in Chicago.
Mr. Reece, did you say?
- He'll be here soon.
- He wants his usual accommodations?
- Just like always.
- Tell him everything will be ready.
Right.
Tucker, Hamblin.
Mr. Reece is in town.
He'll want the south wing
of the 2nd floor.
- We already have people in that wing.
- They'll have to be moved.
Tucker, the kitchen and liquor pantry
will need extra waiters.
We'll put Mr. Reece in 200A as usual.
Mr. Fowler,
the Vidals are in that suite.
You're well acquainted with
Miss Vidal. Move them elsewhere.
You just don't move
people like the Vidals.
Bring Mr. Reece's trunks up.
Everything is to be pressed,
evening clothes first.
You know I cannot see you here.
My aunt is inside,
and my father is due.
I know, I have to speak
to your father.
- My father?
- Yes.
It's a hotel situation.
Something about the rooms.
May I wait inside? Please?
Yes, of course.
Last night, I thought it was
the moonlight. I was wrong.
- About what?
- You're just as pretty in here.
- Frank, please!
- You said she doesn't speak English.
She can see the expression in your
eyes. Anybody can understand that.
Did you understand the poem I sent?
Poem? What poem?
- Father, this is...
- Yes, I know Mr. Harris.
There's been a mistake.
It seems these rooms were reserved.
However, I have another suite of rooms
that is much larger.
- There's a breeze...
- We're comfortable here.
Yes, sir. But I'm only acting
on orders from the manager.
- Isn't there anything I can do...?
- Yes, there is.
You can tell me if you wrote...
...this poetry to my daughter.
I'm in love with your daughter.
I'd like to marry her.
I could never approve.
Our way of life is too different.
I don't intend to remain
a hotel clerk.
I came to get in the cattle business,
to make a fortune on the trail.
In Maria's world,
money is no recommendation.
Maria, we are going home.
Let's start packing.
And now, be good enough
to have my bill sent up.
Goodbye, young man.
And don't think
that love can find a way.
I know all the ways.
Here he comes!
- Pleased to have you again.
- Pleasure to be here.
- I want my men taken care of.
- We'll take you to your rooms.
- Bring a large herd?
- Worst trail ever.
Storms, droughts and Indians
fed on my beef.
Send up whiskey and cold chickens.
I'm sick of beef.
Right away.
- You have enough food for the party?
- All taken care of.
And hot baths. We've been
on the trail for two months!
First one to the bath, boys!
- Señor Vidal, what are you doing here?
- A visit. I'm returning to Mexico.
We'll be there in spring.
Any cattle worth buying?
I can sell you all you want.
Hold on to them.
We'll do business when I get there.
Thank you.
Maria.
Maria!
We lost 87 head on the stock train
between here and Wichita.
They got shaken off their feet,
kicked to death.
You should have seen that roadbed.
It had rail gaps in it
8 inches wide.
Might've been safer to trail through.
Lose a few pounds, save a few cow.
- How's the opera season this year?
- Beg your pardon?
Opera, man. Opera!
- I don't know, I guess it's all right.
- You guess?
You call yourself civilized,
but know nothing about the opera?
- I keep my mind on business.
- Let's get to business.
- I have 2476 head. Quotations?
- Two and a half cents per pound.
- Could go down by morning.
- Could go up.
I got 80 percent grassers...
...10 percent half-fats,
10 percent canners.
- Little low on canners.
- Little high. You get the best of it.
I figure two and three-quarters
for the lot.
We figured two and a half.
Two and three-quarters,
or I feed them till they go to three.
Decide. I want a bath.
New York market's closed.
We should wait.
- He's right. We should think it over.
- You do that, Mac.
Paco, go keep an eye on those cows.
We're holding on to them for a while.
Chicago has all the coal in the world!
You can't get enough hot water!
Where's that boy?
Boy, when I take a bath,
I want hot water!
When I mean hot water,
I mean hot water!
Hot water...
Can't take a bath...
Tom...
...you ready to talk business now?
Boot's grown to my foot.
I think I'm beefsteaked.
- You were kind of quiet out there.
- Let the boys do the bickering.
Makes it easier to close the deal.
Two and a half cents for everything
if you deal right now.
You know how I feel about cows.
I'd just as soon own them and be poor
as sell them and be rich.
You can't wait for them to fatten,
you have to start on a new drive.
You need beef so bad
your mouth's watering.
You can have the whole lot for 48,000.
You got a deal.
Now we can quit lying
and get to business.
Pull up a chair and open the whiskey.
Have a drink.
- Boy, we need more whiskey!
- Yes, sir!
Tom, when will you get smart...
...stop beating yourself
out on that trail?
Hook up with me here.
We'll build the biggest
meatpacking business in town.
I could never learn to play partners.
I just think about it,
I get itchy all over.
Get some nice clothes on,
we're going to the opera.
- Opera?
- Yeah.
- What about the party?
- That's after.
Pour it in, son.
Sounds like the party's
already started.
Close that door out there!
I'm freezing my whiffletree!
Come in.
I took the liberty
of bringing these to you myself.
- Set them down and open one for me.
- Yes, sir.
I understand you're going
back down to Mexico?
If the good Lord spares me.
And if I ever get another drink.
Mr. Reece...
- To the brim, that's what a cup's for.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Reece...
...l'm a farmer.
You had me fooled.
No, what I mean is,
I was raised on a farm.
I know a lot about animals, and I'm
interested in the cattle business.
That's why I came here.
I'd like to go to work for you, sir.
Cockroach.
What makes you think
you'd like to go trail-herding?
All my life I've dreamt
of going into the cattle business.
Getting on the trail.
I hate Chicago,
I'd like to live in the open.
- You know what I mean.
- I know.
Lying under the stars,
the boys singing around the campfire.
And your faithful old horse
grazing at the grass by your side.
- You do much riding?
- Me?
I bet I could ride all day and night.
Is that a fact?
- I bet you like horses.
- I sure do.
I thought so.
You're an idiot. A dreamy idiot,
and that's the worst kind.
Know what it's really like?
Dust storms and cloudbursts.
Only a fool wants that.
And that hogwash about horses.
The loyalty and intelligence
of the horse.
A horse's brain
is the size of a walnut.
They're mean, treacherous and stupid.
Not enough sense to move away
from a hot fire.
No sensible man loves a horse.
He tolerates the filthy animal
because riding's better than walking.
Pour me a little more whiskey.
In spite of having a brain
the size of a bean, no horse ever...
- And did you ever taste horse?
- No.
Hasn't got a gamy or beef flavour.
Just tastes like horse.
As for cattle, those miserable,
slab-sided fleabags...
- Pour yourself a drink.
- No.
No matter what you say,
I want that job.
- Try another outfit.
- I have.
A tenderfoot's
too much responsibility.
- It wouldn't be your responsibility.
- Everything is on the trail!
Can you put the studs
in that dress shirt?
I don't wanna be late for the opera.
I thought I saw a spider up there.
Isn't that beautiful? It is.
Mike, isn't that the most
beautiful thing you ever heard?
One thing about opera: It sounds
just as bad no matter who sings it.
Hey, boss!
This is the best party you ever threw!
- It was good last year.
- She wasn't here last year.
And we weren't expecting
that extra money.
Thank my friend here.
He overpaid for the herd!
Yes, you did!
Well, well, well.
Leaving a little early,
aren't you, Peggy?
- Tom, the poker game's all set up.
- Let's go to work!
You ladies amuse yourselves
for a while. Don't go away, though.
Come on, Mike!
I hate to keep bleeding you, Tom,
but I have to raise it 100.
It's up to you, Reece.
- I'll call you.
- Pass.
Pass.
Three kings.
Beats me.
- $50 on the filly.
- You got a bet.
Joe, you take your hands off me!
Just not my night, I guess.
Why don't you wait over there for me?
It's your deal.
Here's the hand, right here.
Want to buy some chips, Tom?
No, not right now.
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
- Sure.
I'd like to pay my bill.
I'm leaving in the morning.
I better pay
while I still have some money.
Divide what's left amongst the help.
We thought you'd stay for a week.
So did I, but I don't
usually lose quite so fast.
- See you next time.
- Without cash, how can you buy cattle?
My credit's still good.
Mr. Reece...
...could you use some money?
What if I could?
You might take me along
as a partner...
...if I was willing
to invest some money.
- How much you got?
- $3800.
- I beg your pardon?
My father gave it to me
when he sold the farm.
- Where is it?
- Here in the safe.
- Well, get it out, boy.
- Yes, sir.
There they are, gents. All spades.
Where did you get money this late?
An honest man has friends everywhere,
but you wouldn't know that.
I ante.
Mr. Harris would like to talk to you.
- Harris?
- He's the desk clerk.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Deal me out of this one.
You want to see me?
I wrote out an agreement about
our partnership, a contract.
Contract? What for?
So we'd both know what the deal was.
See, it's...
I've never signed a contract
or welshed on a deal in my life.
You think I'd sell my reputation
for $3800?
I didn't think that. I just, it's...
I tell you what you do.
Go home and get some sleep.
We're pulling out in the morning.
Fine. I hope you didn't think
I didn't trust you.
Forget it.
Oh, by the way...
...my name's Tom.
Thanks. Mine's Frank.
Thanks.
Stampede! Come on, let's go!
Pick up your gear.
The train leaves in 10 minutes.
- All right, Mendoza. Wake up.
- What?
- We're heading south.
- So soon? What happened?
You lose all the money so quick?
I won it back. Most of it, at least.
- I'm getting out while I'm ahead.
- I hear you've got a partner.
- Who told you that?
- Hi, Tom!
He did.
He woke me up this morning.
He's excited about going on the trail.
He's got a girl.
She lives down in Guadalupe.
- How are you feeling today, Tom?
- I've got a headache.
- Look, boy...
- My name's Frank.
I borrowed some money last night,
and I'm paying you back.
With interest.
I don't want the money back.
We're partners.
I was drinking. I made a mistake.
I never had a partner, and never will.
Suppose you take this
and go back to the hotel.
- I quit my job at the hotel.
- Why'd you do a fool thing like that?
Because you've got a girl in Mexico?
You made a deal with me.
I paid for a share of your outfit,
and that's all I want.
Don't talk like that.
I've ridden for 20 years.
Sweat over every trail. You think
you bought a percentage of that?
- I bought what you were selling.
- I got four arrow holes, you buy that?
I believed you when you said you
never welshed on a deal.
- I'm giving your money back.
- That's not our deal.
- He's right.
- How do you know?
If he wasn't right,
you would have killed him by now.
You called me Tom.
I'd prefer you called me Reece.
Anytime you want your money back,
you ask for it. Anytime.
- How about this guy, Reece?
- He's all right if you are.
Does he pay off at the end of a run?
You ask him for what's coming
in the middle of a river crossing...
...he'll pay off in dry bills.
There!
- Dirty old dog!
- Curtis, you should've been with us!
You look scarier than last I saw you.
We been in Chicago.
We got barrel fever.
Reece only gave us one night,
but what a night!
- Get my telegram?
- The men and grub are ready.
The horses are outside of town.
- Hire the extra hand?
- Sure.
Here's Doc Bender.
Used to be marshal at Wichita.
Hi.
You got quite a reputation.
I wanted a cowhand, not a gunslinger.
I'm a cowhand now.
I like cows better than I like people.
All right. Let's get going.
Paco, get him something to wear.
He can't go on the trail like this.
Thought I'd buy clothes
if you'll wait.
Nobody's waiting. You stay with us,
you have to keep moving.
See if there's a spare rig
for him in the chuck wagon.
Come on, Harris.
Beats me how women
can go for you cowboys.
Women like the smell of a horse
on a man. It makes them giggle.
The smell of a horse on me
never did me no good.
Just makes them move away.
Maybe you're associating with
the wrong horses. Good-looking boots.
Move them out.
- How's the water supply been?
- Not bad, boss.
Pick your horses!
Pick the horses that haven't
been ridden since we left!
Start breaking the ones
that haven't been broke.
- Do these go on any special way?
- Yeah, like an apron.
Shake your tail, or there won't
be anything left fit to ride.
Bring that horse back!
If you can't ride that horse,
you'll have to carry him.
Set another place, here comes Harris!
Next time catch him.
Here he comes again!
- What is that?
- Salt water and whiskey.
Best way to toughen it up.
Feel any better?
Yeah, it burns instead of just aching.
That's what it's supposed to do.
It fries your hide.
You look like you're half-dead.
I can't get enough sleep.
Don't you get a day off?
No Sunday on the trail. You have
to learn to sleep in your saddle.
Yep. That's it.
Harris?
- I told you to ride night herd.
- I made a deal. Capper's doing it.
Do your own job
and forget about making deals.
If you can't pull your weight, say so.
You can have your money back.
I told you I didn't want it back.
Then get out there and go to work.
This little filly
up in Chicago says to me:
"Honey, stay here with me. I'll take
care of you the rest of your life."
- Why didn't you do it?
- Who wants to live in Chicago?
Turn him loose around a woman
for 24 hours...
...he's got enough flies
to last the season.
Joe, tell the boys about the time
you ate them Indians.
I ain't ate but one
Indian my whole life.
Even then it was just a haunch.
Being a town marshal...
...I figured that was
a pretty good job.
What made you give it up?
Same old story.
You know.
Man gets a reputation with a gun...
...he's just got to do
too much killing.
Last time in Wichita...
...two of them jumped me in the dark
and I had to shoot them.
Later, I found they were just
young, drunken saddle bums...
...looking for excitement.
That's when I quit my job as marshal.
That's no way to live.
I can't understand,
something smells good.
To hear you trail hands talk,
you'd think you were being poisoned.
You've got a visitor!
Snakes. I found one
curled up in my boot yesterday.
No, wait!
I ask you. Did you ever see a more
comfortable picture in your life?
Come to think of it,
I don't believe I ever did.
Harris, want to see a prairie eel?
Shoot him, Slim.
- Shoot him, Slim!
- Ain't my snake!
Cut it out.
- Here, Charlie, it's a girl.
- I like them with bigger hips.
I said to cut it out.
It got me.
Go get him.
I got his legs. I got him here!
- Let go of me!
- Wait a minute!
You trying to pump that poison
to your heart?
Leave me alone.
Must have got him in the vein.
He's bleeding enough.
Oh, my God.
Someday there'll be fences
up and down this trail.
I'd rather fight Indians than
cut my way through fences.
Joe would rather be fighting Indians.
- Makes him hungry thinking about it.
- Cut it out.
I was near starving to death.
Besides,
I didn't even know that Indian.
Anyway, I threw away
everything but one haunch.
- Which one did you keep?
- The left one, of course.
The right one is the working haunch.
They're always tough.
How long do you figure to Guadalupe?
Eight or nine days,
something like that.
I've been dreaming every night
about them Mexican gals.
I wouldn't take $400
for what I dreamed last night.
You've been talking in your sleep too.
I wish you'd dream something else.
You think of something better
to dream about...
...l'll dream about it.
Looks to me like he's dead, boss.
Slim, you, Capper, Harris.
Get some shovels.
Make it deep,
so the coyotes can't get at him.
Keep away from there.
You killed him, aren't you satisfied?
You have to steal his boots?
- I killed him?
- Put it down or I'll bust you open!
You're not busting anybody.
Someone did something stupid.
No reason to make more trouble.
You don't like what goes on here,
that's too bad.
Nobody said you were gonna like it.
Now get out there and start digging.
Anybody know the right words?
All right.
When something like this happens...
...people ask how come it happened.
I mean...
Was it his fault?
Was it somebody else's fault?
It isn't for us to say.
We don't know all the answers.
All we know is a man's dead,
and that's that.
It wouldn't have made a difference.
If it hadn't been a snake,
it would've been a steer.
Or a Comanche.
His horse might even have stumbled...
...in a prairie dog hole
some dark night.
He was a good man with cattle.
Always did the best he knew how.
I hope somebody
can say the same over me.
All right, fill her up.
After seven weeks, it will be good
to have chicken again.
- What are the decorations for?
- Some kind of fiesta.
Ask him where the Vidal ranch is.
He says when we leave this town,
there ain't nothing else but.
We're going to Vidal's
to pick up a herd.
I'm going too.
- What for?
- I'm your partner.
You mean you've got personal business?
I forgot about Miss Vidal.
You men drink now,
we'll be branding tomorrow.
Any man that starts a fight
will have to finish it with me.
- Welcome.
- We're glad to be here.
This is Paco Mendoza.
Frank Harris.
Yes, I know Señor Harris.
He writes poetry.
- He does?
- I used to.
Come in, please.
- May I present Señor Reece...
- How do you do?
...Señor Harris...
...Señor Mendoza.
My sister Doña Luisa,
my daughter Maria...
...and her husband, Manuel Arriega.
Would you gentlemen care for a drink?
If you don't mind...
...I thought we might
look over the beef.
As you wish.
Manuel, please bring our horses.
This way, sir.
How long will this take?
We'll stay till the job is finished.
I hope you're satisfied.
- Looks good.
- Best there is.
By the way, we're having a fiesta.
There will be much amusement.
I hope you all will come.
After the branding. The boys
could stand a little amusement.
- You did not get my letter?
- I left Chicago the day after you.
I wrote to explain the whole thing.
I never expected to see you again.
- Why didn't you wait?
- Please, you must leave now.
- I'm not permitted to see you alone.
- Why didn't you wait?
I should explain, Manuel...
...that Señor Harris is a friend
from Chicago.
And I should explain to you, Maria,
that you are my wife.
You will of course not wish
to see her again, alone.
I believe Señor Reece
is waiting for you.
That's all I could
grab hold of, honey.
You can't win all of them.
The final event,
ladies and gentlemen...
...is the game of the cattle.
- Mendoza, what's this about?
- It's a crazy game. Stay out of it.
That bull in there is a real killer.
See? The horns are painted red.
Man has to put a ring over his horn.
Some do it, some get killed.
That's not for me.
Manuel Arriega challenges anyone
who wishes to compete against him.
Perhaps one of the Americanos
would like to take a chance?
I wouldn't go in there for a whiskey
and a woman to pour it.
Now for the American caballero!
I'll bet 10 on the American.
- Who wants to make a real bet?
- $100!
You got it!
Anybody wants an advance,
go ahead and make your bets.
Harris, come here.
I'm playing this one myself.
- Why didn't you say so before?
- I didn't have money up before.
- Trying to show off?
- Protecting my bet, that's all.
Getting killed for money
is one thing...
...doing it to impress a girl
is stupid.
Paco. Take him away,
I don't want him.
- You crazy?
- I don't want to get him cut up.
The next contestant is
Don Thomas Reece.
Open it up, son.
I could not let you go without
seeing you once more.
Without talking with you, alone.
You know my father was
troubled about us in Chicago.
As soon as we returned here,
Manuel and I were betrothed.
Here, children have nothing to say
about these things.
Do you love him?
I am not a child anymore.
I cannot have everything...
Tell me. Do you love him?
- What's the matter?
- I need a drink.
Better stay out of there.
Charlie's inside asking for trouble.
He'll get himself carved up.
- Doesn't he need help?
- You want to help him? You help him.
Get knifed in the belly, you won't
be able to hold your guts in.
- I'm not gonna run out on him.
- You're a good boy.
Joe, wake up! Charlie's in trouble!
- He's gonna get his throat cut!
- That's his problem.
- You gotta help.
- I told you to stay out of it.
- He's grabbing someone's gal.
- No reason for us to get hurt.
If a man picks a fight,
he's gotta fight it.
The fun's in the picking,
not the fighting.
Doc, you gotta help.
Charlie's in bad trouble.
Four guys in the saloon
are gonna jump him.
- Four of them?
- Yeah. What do you say, Doc?
I don't like the odds.
- What do we do? Let him get killed?
- All right.
We heard about Charlie.
Now shut up and go to bed.
- What'll you do about him?
- Go to bed, same as you.
What happens to him?
Man's old enough to get in trouble,
he can get himself out of it.
I got cows to worry about.
A man's life means nothing to you?
All you care about
is your herd of cattle!
You're the most miserable bunch
of men I ever saw in my whole life.
Not one shred of decency
in the lot of you.
I thought I'd be living with some men
on the trail.
Not just a pack of animals.
I'm sorry we don't measure up
to your way of thinking.
But get one thing straight:
Nobody cares what you thought
it would be.
You wanted to play cowboy.
Didn't realize it's rough.
I'm gonna help Charlie.
Is anyone going with me or am I alone?
Nobody's leaving.
You start trouble, we'll lose men.
The whole town will be on our hands.
Why don't you forget
about what's really bothering you?
Starting a fight won't help you
get that girl back.
That doesn't work, either.
I'm going back and there's nothing
you can do about it.
- The fire!
- I see it.
- You had enough?
- No!
Enough!
- You don't even fight like a man.
- Fighting's no game with me.
I'll remember that.
Next time I'll use a crowbar.
You just do that.
Peggy...
...I want some hot coffee.
All right. Move them out!
How's the arm, Charlie?
It's my drinking arm,
not my loving arm.
He got cut up a little, is all.
Not enough to teach him a lesson.
Harris will make a good cowboy.
You think I've been rough on him.
That's what my father
said to my mother.
He always treated me too hard,
my father.
But he liked me very much.
Capper!
Just leave it for the coyotes.
- He can't keep up with the herd.
- See if you can get a cow to feed him.
I don't want it on my saddle!
- It's worth $20 in Chicago. And you?
- Take him back to the herd.
Get on, cow, cow!
You're learning.
That a cow means more than a man?
I play your rules,
but that doesn't mean I like them.
I've been meaning
to talk to you about something.
What?
That girl back there.
Those things can be pretty rough.
But a deal like that
never works out in the long run.
You got too much going against it.
So you just mark it off,
and figure it's a part of growing up.
Nobody asked me,
but I think you're better off.
You do, huh?
Maybe it's not my business...
That's right.
It's none of your business.
Curtis. Look, Indians.
Been following us for three hours,
hoping to pick up some strays.
We'll bed the herd
here for the night...
...and make camp up there.
Paco!
- How many men are with the herd?
- Two, just like always.
Better put a couple more on tonight.
- Where's Harris?
- He went after strays. 40 of them.
There's Indians. Why send him?
I didn't. He went by himself.
I want two more men
down there tonight.
- Harris back yet?
- Not yet.
Hey, Reece.
Indians.
Comanches.
Hold your fire till they get in range.
- Must make you feel hungry, Joe.
- Shut up, will you?
They're not even heading this way.
They're after something else.
Harris must be down there.
They'll hit him and take the strays.
How come they passed us by?
They got a better deal down there.
Kill one man
and get 40 head of cattle.
We wouldn't stand a chance.
He picked a fine time to play cowboy.
While they're busy with him,
we can get away. He's a goner.
Paco.
We'll stampede the herd into that
arroyo and drive the Indians off.
We'll never get the cattle back
in this country.
I, too, like this boy.
But we have to think about the herd.
It's my herd, isn't it?
It's all right.
You won't be able to ride.
You scattered our herd all over!
Why are you bellyaching?
I could've fought them off one by one!
I wish I'd let you try.
Reece's knee is shot up.
I'm taking over the herd.
Mendoza's taking over.
I'm the partner, not him.
Doc and Capper,
take Reece to the wagon.
We work straight through
till we get that herd rounded up.
- I ought to tear him apart.
- You'll tear yourself apart.
He's young. What can go wrong?
I'll keep an eye on things.
- We'll cut him some splints.
- Come on.
Let's keep moving, men.
We can't rest now.
Come on, it's nearly dawn. Mount up.
Get off my bedroll, Curtis.
I've worked day and night.
I ain't moving.
Move or I'll teach you manners.
You do and you'll
learn more than you teach.
Cut it out!
Now we'll see
what you had for breakfast!
Get back up the hill.
You better slack off.
The boys are getting pretty mean.
We rounded up all the herd
we could find.
- How many head did we lose?
- Just over 200.
- That's a lot.
- Yeah, it's too bad.
- It's too bad for you.
- Why?
We found all my cows.
Seems it was yours that ran off.
That's interesting.
How did you separate yours from mine?
It was easy.
I used a crowbar.
Okay! Move them out!
- How far is it into town?
- Just over the hill.
I'd like to draw my time when we
get in town. Stay a while.
I thought you weren't going back.
I figure if I wasn't marshal,
I could live here peaceful.
There's a fellow in town, Sam Hacker.
A no-good cuss.
But we were good friends.
- I miss the old son of a gun.
- You're getting old.
It ain't that.
A man has to have something
besides a gun and saddle.
You just can't make it by yourself.
I wish you luck.
I hope it all turns out peaceful.
Maybe I'll see you next time.
- Railcar's loaded.
- Twelve cars!
Keep them moving. We've gotta go!
Did you hear about Doc Bender?
He's dead.
- He killed himself.
- You're crazy.
He was in the saloon drinking
with a friend of his, Sam Hacker.
Hacker got real mean and pulled
a gun on Doc. Doc had to kill him.
- What happened to Doc?
- He hung himself.
In the livery stable.
Nobody knows why.
- Thirteen cars loaded.
- Right, 13.
Doc won the fight.
Why'd he want to kill himself?
Nothing we can do about it.
Mendoza!
Get to work. We got cattle to load.
We need that next string of cars
right now!
- You just don't give a damn, do you?
- You're a fine one to talk.
You buried a man once. "In the long
run, it doesn't make a difference."
Maybe watching you
made me change my mind.
If you had anything inside
worth saving...
...l'd beat you down,
but you'll never learn.
You haven't gotten tough,
you've just gotten miserable.
Boss, we're gonna lose some cattle.
We got three down steers
in one car and two in the next.
Harris, give Capper a hand.
- There's four down now, see them?
- I see them.
Are you crazy? Those cows
will rip your belly open.
- I wouldn't go in there.
- They're not your cows.
I have to laugh. You made him tough.
Now you don't like what you made.
Know what I think?
He'd have been all right
if not for that girl.
Come on, play.
Well, he learned how to handle cows...
...maybe he'll learn
how to handle women.
Ain't my business...
...but that crazy Harris
is prying cattle off the floor.
- What did you leave him there for?
- I ain't the ramrod here, he is.
- Where are you going?
- I'm tired of burying people.
I suppose this is one of mine, huh?
It all depends on if we can save it.
Come on, let's go!
Miserable slab-sided fleabags!
Listen...
...about those cattle we lost.
Maybe I made a mistake.
- Yeah?
- I don't think they were all yours.
I'd say about fifty-fifty.
That sounds like a fair split.
Come on, let's go.
- Good to see you again.
- Good to be here.
- Meet my partner, Frank Harris.
- Hello, Fowler, how are you?
Take care of him. He used to be
in the hotel business.
- I have your rooms all ready.
- Fine.
How long will you stay?
One week, maybe.
Two weeks, if it's all right...
- Make it three.
- Ring for anything you want.
- Plenty of hot water and whiskey.
- Make that double.
Pour it in, son.
- Tom.
- Frank.