JOHN!
HERE I AM!
LOOK... LOOK UP HERE!
OH.
I'D LIKE TO SEE MRS. DEVLIN.
WOULD THAT BE
MISS SANDRA?
SHE'S MRS. DEVLIN NOW.
YOUR NAME, SIR?
I'M...
(Mr. Poli)
MR. DEVLIN?
YES... MR. POLI?
YES.
SO YOU ARE THE MAN WHO
MARRIED MY DAUGHTER.
WELL, WE, UH...
SORTA GOT THE
IDEA IN A HURRY.
THROW HIM OUT!!
????
??
ORNERY CUSS,
THAT POLI.
HE DON'T FIDDLE
WITH NOBODY.
HE USED TO RUN A
STAGECOACH LINE,
FOR HE WENT IN FOR
RAILROADIN'.
HUH?
????
??
WAIT!
PAPA IS JUST AS
CRAZY AS YOU ARE.
HE'LL GETHISGUN,
AND WHAT ABOUT ME?
PAPA'S KIND OF HIGH
STRUNG, ISN'T HE?
PAPA SAYS YOU ARE
A GUN-TOTIN',
HIGHBINDIN',
TINHORN GAMBLER.
WELL, PAPA SHOULDN'T
TALK LIKE THAT IN FRONT
OF THE CHILDREN.
BUT YOU ARE.
SANDRA!
HOW'D YOU GET OUT WHEN
I LOCKED THE DOOR!?
GET HIM, MEN!
HEYA!
YOU'D BETTER COME BACK,
OR FROM BETWEEN THE EARS
I'LL SHOOT YOU!
WAIT... MY BAGS!
WE HADN'T BETTER MAKE
ANY STOPS NOW, SANDY.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
IF I CAN'T LOOK PRETTY,
YOU CAN'T EITHER.
WE'RE CLEANED OUT
FOR SURE NOW.
WHO SAID SO?
LUNCH?
NO...
TWENTY THOUSAND
DOLLARS.
THAT CINCHES IT...
SANDY, I LOVE YA.
WHO WOULDN'T?
YOU COULDN'T WIN THAT
MUCH IN A POKER GAME.
YOU MEAN, UNLESS
I WAS DEALING.
(bang bang)
THAT'S PAPA...
HE'S SHOOTING AT US!
(bang)
HURRY UP!
AH, THAT'S NOTHING.
(bang)
ALL I WANT TO KNOW
IS DO YOU TAKE AFTER
PAPA OR MAMA?
PAPA ALWAYS WANTS TO
SHOOT THINGS OUT.
HE HAS NO MORE SENSE
THAN YOU HAVE.
(bang bang)
I DO HOPE HE DOESN'T
KILL US.
HE'D NEVER GET OVER IT.
WELL, I'D FEEL KIND
OF REGRETFUL ABOUT
IT MYSELF.
(bang)
HE'S GOT HIMSELF
ANOTHER GUN!
(bang)
CAN'T YOU GO
QUICKER?!
(bang)
DO YOU SUPPOSE IT
COULD BE, SANDY,
THAT WE WEREN'T
MEANT FOR EACH
OTHER AFTER ALL?
I DON'T LIKE
TO BUTT IN,
BUT I THOUGHT MAYBE
I OUGHTA ASK IF YOU
WOULDN'T PREFER
ANOTHER CARRIAGE?
(bang)
HEYA!
SIT TIGHT, SANDY!
WE'RE HEADIN'
FOR CALIFORNIA!
WELL, DO WE HAVE TO
GO TO CALIFORNIA?
KNOW A BETTER PLACE?!
HOW ABOUT DAKOTA?
DID YOU SAY DAKOTA?
YES, DAKOTA.
OH, I THOUGHT YOU
SAID DAKOTA.
WE'LL MAKE IT
CALIFORNIA.
HEYA!
TURN LEFT AT THE
NEXT CROSSING.
OH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU ALL RIGHT, SIR?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
YOU'RE FIRED!
GET YOUR HORSES!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
HE'S ONLY ANGRY NOW.
WAIT TILL HE FINDS OUT
I SOLD THE GAINSBOROUGH
FROM HIS LIBRARY.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH DAKOTA?
IT HAS LOTS OF PEOPLE
IN IT, HUNDREDS,
AND IT'S A GREAT
WHEAT COUNTRY.
WHAT DOES A MAN DO
IN A WHEAT COUNTRY,
OPEN A BAKERY?
THERE ARE LOTS OF
THINGS WE COULD DO.
ONCE WE'VE ESTABLISHED
OURSELVES...
LET'S TALK IT OVER
IN CALIFORNIA.
BUT SOME DAY,
WHEN DAKOTA IS ADMITTED
INTO THE UNION,
YOU COULD GO
INTO POLITICS.
OH, OUR MONEY!
SPEAKING OF
POLITICS,
WHERE WE'RE GOING THERE
ARE ONLY TWO PARTIES--
THE QUICK AND THE DEAD.
(train conductor)
ALL ABOOOAARD!
THAT'S OUR TRAIN.
HOW MUCH DO
WE OWE YA?
OH, FORGET ABOUT
IT, MY FRIEND.
IT'S ON THE HOUSE.
MAYBE YOU HADN'T
BETTER DRAW UP ANY
PLANS UNTIL...
UNTIL WHAT?
I WAS GONNA SAY UNTIL
YOUR MONEY RUNS OUT.
(train conductor)
ALL ABOOOAAARD!
DID YOU SAY THIS
IS OUR TRAIN?
YES.
THAT LADY IS SANDRA
POLI, BIGTREE.
HER FATHER OWNS
THIS RAILROAD.
THAT SO?
WELL, GUESS MAYBE
SHE'S SOMEBODY WE
OUGHTA KNOW, HUH?
MM-HMM.
HURRY UP... DON'T LET
THEM GET AWAY!!
QUICK, SEND A TELEGRAPH
TO BELLS CROSSING!
YES, MR. POLI.
TO JAKE BONZO
ON TRAIN 67...
SAY, "HOLD MY DAUGHTER!
"TAKE FROM HER THE
BIG TINHORN
AND KNOCK OUT
HIS TEETH!"
NO, WAIT...
IT'S TOO MUCH.
JUST HIS FRONT TEETH,
THAT'S ENOUGH.
AND UH, WAIT...
NO... NO... NO.
MAYBE IT WOULD
BREAK HER HEART.
MAYBE SHE WOULD BE
MAD... IT'S NO GOOD.
NO... NO.
UH... SAY, "DON'T KNOCK
OUT HIS FRONT TEETH."
SAY... OH, WHAT'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
ARE YOU CRAZY...
HOW CAN YOU SEND
SUCH A TELEGRAPH?!
HUH?
SHE'S MY OWN
LITTLE GIRL.
MAYBE SHE LOVES HIM,
THAT BIG NO-GOOD.
AND YOU WILL BREAK
HER HEART, HUH?!
ME?
SEND ANOTHER ONE.
"TO MY DAUGHTER,
MRS... UH...
NOW WHAT'S HIS NAME?
DEVLIN... NO...
YES, DEVLIN!
"HAVE A GOOD TIME,
"AND REMEMBER YOUR PAPA
IF YOU NEED MONEY
OR SOMETHING."
OH, SHE'S A SWEET GIRL...
OH, SOMETHING ELSE!
"IF MAYBE YOU GET TIRED
OF YOUR WONDERFUL, BIG,
LOVELY MAN,
"DON'T WORRY, WE'LL
PUT HIM IN JAIL,
"THAT NO-GOOD RAT!
I MYSELF WILL
TAKE HIM AND..."
HE'S BIGGER THAN I,
THAT'S THE TROUBLE.
BUT THERE'S NOTHING IN
CALIFORNIA BUT FLOWERS,
AND EVERYONE KNOWS
FLOWERS GIVE YOU
HAY FEVER.
I GOT IT MYSELF,
RIGHT NOW.
LOOK, SANDY,
WITH $20,000,
WE CAN OPEN A LITTLE PLACE
IN THE GOLD FIELDS...
A SALOON AND GAMBLING
PALACE WITH DANCE HALL
GIRLS...
WOULDN'T YOU
JUST LOVE THAT?
(conductor) TICKETS, PLEASE.
I BROUGHT THE TICKETS,
LIKE YOU TOLD ME.
(train whistle blowing)
WHEN DO WE GET TO ST.
LOUIS, CONDUCTOR?
ST. LOUIS!?
CAN'T DO IT AND STAY
ON THE TRACKS.
WE'RE HEADED
FOR ST. PAUL.
WHY... WHY, YOU
SEE, JOHN,
I HAD TO DO IT.
I COULDN'T DO
ANYTHING ELSE.
YOU COULDN'T, EH?
I JUST COULDN'T...
I COULDN'T.
I LOVE YOU AND IT WAS
FOR YOU, SO I DID IT.
BUT WHY ST. PAUL?
BECAUSE FROM ST. PAUL,
WE'LL GO TO DAKOTA.
WAIT.
LAST NIGHT PAPA HAD SOME
OF HIS BUSINESS FRIENDS
TO DINNER,
AND I HEARD THEM SAY
THEY'RE GOING TO EXTEND
THE RAILROAD
INTO DAKOTA.
IN A FEW WEEKS, PAPA
WILL SEND AGENTS
TO FARGO TO BUY UP
ALL THE LAND
AND THE RIGHT
OF WAY,
SO WHAT WE'LL DO...
IS BEAT HIM TO IT,
OPTION EVERYTHING
IN SIGHT,
MAKE HIM PAY THROUGH
THE NOSE.
BUT THE CATCH IS
TO MAKE THE PROFIT,
WE HAVE TO GO TO FARGO.
BUT IT'S A
WONDERFUL PLACE!
SURE.
THERE'S PROBABLY
NOTHING THERE BUT
A TRADING POST.
WE'LL BE STUCK UP THERE
WITH NOTHING TO DO BUT...
MAKE LOVE.
HMM, WHAT'S
WRONG WITH THAT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
????
??
STOP IT!
????
??
BELLS CROSSING!
????
??
GET RID OF THEM.
THANKS FOR
PITCHIN' IN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LOOKED LIKE YOU COULD
USE SOME HELP.
HE'S A GOOD MAN.
BIGTREE?
(conductor)
TELEGRAM FOR MR. BONZO!
HE'LL DO... MY NAME IS
BENDER, JIM BENDER.
I'M DEVLIN...
THIS IS MRS. DEVLIN.
HOW DO YOU DO,
MRS. DEVLIN?
YES...
THANK YOU.
MAY I?
SURELY.
IT'S FROM PAPA...
EVERYTHING IS ALL
RIGHT.
HE SAYS IF WE NEED MORE
MONEY OR ANYTHING,
WE JUST LET HIM KNOW.
ISN'T HE WONDERFUL?
NICE GUY TO DO BUSINESS
WITH, BY LETTER.
GOING TO ST. PAUL,
MR. BENDER?
I'M GOING TO FARGO.
SO ARE WE.
REALLY... THAT'S FINE.
WE'LL PROBABLY BE SEEING
A LOT OF EACH OTHER.
????
??
HEYA!
????
??
WE'VE PASSED THE FORT.
SHOULD BE IN ABERCROMBIE
IN A FEW MINUTES.
AND YOU LOOK JUST AS
FRESH AS WHEN WE
STARTED, MRS. DEVLIN.
THANK YOU...
WE BOUGHT SOME
THINGS IN ST. PAUL.
OH, AREN'T THEY
SOLDIERS?
HUH?
PROBABLY AN ESCORT
FROM THE FORT.
MUST BE SOME HOSTILE
INDIANS AROUND.
INDIANS... OH!
JOHN, NOW THAT WE KNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT IT,
DO YOU REALLY THINK WE
SHOULD GO TO FARGO?
WELL, WE'VE COME
THIS FAR.
MAYBE WE OUGHTA STOP
OFF AND, UH,
TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO DO
IN FARGO, MR. DEVLIN?
WE ARE GOING TO INVEST
SOME MONEY IN LAND.
FARMLAND...
WE THOUGHT WE'D
PICK UP A FEW ACRES
AND GROW SOME WHEAT.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT US TO
BELIEVE YOU WAS A FARMER,
WOULD YA, MR. DEVLIN?
MAYBE I OUGHTA
SPROUT A BEARD, EH?
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHY
YOU'D WANT TO BUCK
A PROPOSITION
AS UNCERTAIN AS YOU
MAY FIND IN THE
WHEAT COUNTRY.
WHA... WHAT'S
UNCERTAIN ABOUT IT?
YOU DON'T THINK
NOBODY'S GONNA LET
YOU WALK INTO FARGO
AND JUMP ANY CLAIMS,
DO YA, MA'AM?
BIGTREE MEANS, YOU MIGHT
HAVE A LITTLE TROUBLE
GETTING HOLD OF A DECENT
PIECE OF LAND--
GOOD ACREAGE IS SCARCE.
TRYIN' TO TELL US THAT
THEY DON'T TAKE KINDLY
TO STRANGERS IN FARGO,
MR. BENDER?
I DON'T IMAGINE THEY'D
WELCOME STRANGERS
WHO COME TO FARM, UH,
WITHOUT IMPLEMENTS,
MR. DEVLIN.
WHOA!
EVERYBODY OUT...
WE DONE IT AGAIN!
FORT ABERCROMBIE,
FOLK.
MR. BENDER?
I'M BENDER.
COMPLIMENTS OF
COLONEL WORDEN, SIR.
HE'D LIKE YOU TO RIDE
OVER TO THE FORT WHEN
YOU'RE RESTED.
WELL, I WAS GONNA SAIL
ON THESIOUX PRINCESS.
HAVE YOU GOT ANY
IDEA WHAT HE WANTS
TO SEE ME ABOUT?
THERE'S BEEN SOME
KILLINGS AT FARGO.
THEY'VE BURNED THE
HOMES OF MOST OF THE
BONANZA FARMERS.
- INDIANS?
- WELL, ACCORDING
TO MR. STOWE,
IT WAS MADE TO LOOK LIKE THE
SIOUX WERE MIXED UP IN IT,
BUT HE DOESN'T BELIEVE IT.
STOWE WASN'T BURNED
OUT, WAS HE?
YES, SIR.
IT SEEMS ONLY THE LITTLE
FELLAS ARE LEFT NOW, THE
HOMESTEADERS.
MR. STOWE'S AT
THE FORT NOW.
HE AND COLONEL WORDEN
HAVE BEEN WAITING FOR
YOU TO GET BACK.
FOR ME?
I THINK MR. STOWE HAS
SOME IDEA OF ORGANIZING
A LAW ENFORCEMENT
AGENCY AT FARGO.
OH... WELL, YOU TELL
'EM I'LL WASH UP
AND BE OVER AFTER SUPPER.
WELL, THESIOUX PRINCESS
SAILS AT SIX, SIR.
WELL, I'LL ARRANGE
TO MISS THAT
AND GO WITH CAPTAIN
BOUNCE ON THE
RIVER BIRD.
MY COMPLIMENTS TO
COLONEL WORDEN.
THERE YA ARE, DEVLIN,
THAT'S FARGO FOR YA.
WHAT'S FARGO?
DIDN'T YOU HEAR WHAT
THE LIEUTENANT SAID?
MENTIONED A COLONEL
SOMEBODY OR OTHER,
FORT... SOMETHIN'
GOIN' ON?
NO, NOTHIN' MUCH,
NOTHING VERY
INTERESTING.
BIGTREE, GET OUR
BAGS OUT OF THESIOUX
PRINCESS,WILL YA?
I'LL SEE YOU AND
THE MRS. DOWN AT
THE BOAT, HUH?
YEAH, SURE.
THAT, UH, FARGO BOAT,
SIOUX PRINCESS?
(stagecoach driver)
THAT'S ONE OF 'EM.
T'OTHER'S THE
RIVER BIRD,
THAT'S OL' CAP'N
BOUNCE'S TUB.
SHE'S A HUFFER
AND A PUFFER.
BUT IF I WAS A
MAKIN' THE TRIP,
SHE'S THE ONE
I'D TAKE.
BETTER BOAT?
NOPE, BUT IF YA SAIL
ON THERIVER BIRD,
YOU'D HAVE IT PRACTICALLY
TO YOURSELF,
AND IF THE MOON HAPPENS TO
BE RIDIN' ALONG WITH YA,
AND YOU'RE TRAVELIN' WITH
LIVE BAGGAGE, WOW!
????
??
(toooot, toooot)
COME ON NOW, YOU SLAB-SIDED
PUDDLE SNIPE.
KICK HER OFF FROM BACK THERE!
COME ON, NOW.
NOW JUST EASE YOURSELF TA PORT,
YA SWEET LITTLE LOVIN' LAMB.
SWING IT TA PORT, YA OL'
WING-TAILED MUDHEN!
THERE NOW.
NOW JUST SNEAK UP ON
THAT THERE LANDIN'.
(ding ding)
NOW IF THAT FLAT-FOOTED
SWIPE AIN'T FELL OVERBOARD
OR SOMETHIN'...
BLAST YA, NICODEMUS,
WHERE YA AT!!
NICODEMUS, IF
YOU'RE SLEEPIN',
I'LL KNOCK YA OUT FROM THE
BACK O' YOUR TEETH, BY JUPPY!!
OH, BACK LINE, YA PRETTY
LITTLE RIVER SWAN.
SHAKE YOUR HIPS.
SHAKE YOUR HIPS YA
POTBELLIED... !!!
I'LL TIPTOE UP TO THAT
ABERCROMBIE LEVEE.
NICODEMUS!!!
NICODEMUS, IF'N YOU'RE
STILL ABOARD,
YOU BETTER START
RUNNIN' UP RIVER!!
YES, SIR... COMING, CAP'N.
HURRY, HURRY, HURRY
ALL THE TIME.
WOW!!
COMIN' CAP'N...
NICODEMUS'LL GET IT GOIN'!
WE'LL SHOW THEM ABERCROMBIE
FOLKS HOW IT'S DONE,
YA PUSSYFOOTIN' LITTLE MOONBEAM.
HEY, ON SHORE THERE, SOMEBODY!
HOP ABOARD AND THROW OFF'N ROPE!
I DONE LOST MY BO'S'N!
WHAT THE...
SHUT OFF THEM ENGINES!
(ding ding ding
ding ding ding)
(Nicodemus)CAP'N!
CAP'N BOUNCE, THE
BELL IS BUSTED!
IT WON'T STOP RINGIN'!
JUST KEEP RINGIN'
AND RINGIN!
IT'S RINGIN' BECAUSE
I WAS RINGING IT!!
LIKE I'M GONNA RING
THAT NECK OF YOURS
IF YOU DON'T
OBEY ORDERS!!
DID YOU WANT
SOME'IN, CAP'N?
WHAT DO YA THINK THEM
LIGHTS IS BACK THERE?!
OH, UH.
YOU MEAN THEM LIGHTS WAY
BACK THERE IN THE DARK?
THAT, YOU RIVER HAPPY
JAYBIRD, IS ABERCROMBIE!
IF YOU EVER GET ME TO EAT
SADDLE OF VENISON AGAIN,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO UNSADDLE IT FIRST.
CONTRARY ANIMAL, THE DEER,
GENTLE ON THE HOOF,
TOUGH ON THE PLATE.
(Captain Bounce)
SAILIN' NORTH TO FARGO,
GRAND FORKS AND PEMBINA!
ALL PASSENGERS FOR
THERIVER BIRD,
CASTIN' OFF IN 20
MINUTES... ALL ABOARD!
RIVER BIRD,MISTER? NICODEMUS!
MY BOSUN'LL TAKE
CARE OF YOUR BAGGAGE.
PEMBINA?
FARGO.
HOW 'BOUT YOU, LADY?
OH, WE'RE MARRIED.
WELL, NOW!
SURE GOOD TO MEET
NICE, CLEAN FOLKS.
I'M GONNA PUTS
IT IN MY LOG...
I'M CAPTAIN BOUNCE.
NICODEMUS, TAKE THE
FOLKS' BAGGAGE, AND
GET IT DOWN THERE
AFORE WE SHOVE OFF,
OR BY JUPPY,
OFF COMES YOUR BOSUN'S
RATIN' AND BACK TA
WIPIN' YA GO!
WELL, CAP'N, I AIN'T
NEVER STOP WIPIN'.
I JUST WIPES, 'N...
DOES YOU WANNA
WIPE AS A BOSUN
OR A LOW-DOWN SEAMAN?
MAN NEVER KNOWS WHEN
HE'S WELL OFF, HE DON'T.
WHAT DO WE OWE YA?
WELL, UH...
UH, TWO FARES TA FARGO,
THAT'S SEVEN DOLLARS...
EACH, AND, UH,
THE STATEROOMS
'LL BE, UH,
TWO DOLLARS,
FOR ONE, AND THEN
THERE'S, UH...
THE MEALS ARE EXTRA, A
DOLLAR EACH FOR MEALS.
WHAT DO WE OWE
YA ALL TOGETHER?
WELL, LET'S SEE, THAT'S, UH...
SEVEN AND SEVEN
AND TWO AND TWO,
AND TWO TIMES THREE
THAT'S, UH,
THIRTY-FOUR DOLLARS...
I MEAN, THIRTY SEVEN!
WOULDN'T TAKE
24, WOULD YA?
IS WE GONNA ARGUE
OVER A COUPLA PENNIES?
ROAD FOLKS, AIN'T WE?
GLAD TO HAVE SEEN YOU
AGAIN, MR. STOWE.
THANK YOU, COLONEL.
I WISH YOU COULD'VE TALKED
TO BENDER IN MY PRESENCE.
WELL, WE'LL TRY TO
ARRANGE A LITTLE
PARLEY LATER.
I'M TERRIBLY SHORTHANDED AND
HAVE PLENTY TO HANDLE DOWN HERE,
BUT IF YOU NEED US BADLY, I'LL
TRY TO GET A COMPANY UP TO YA.
- GOOD-BYE, MR. STOWE,
AND PLEASANT TRIP.
- THANK YOU, COLONEL.
GOOD NIGHT.
YOU BETTER GET ABOARD
AND CLAIM YOUR STATEROOM.
IT'S NUMBER ONE...
THE ONE WITH THE
DOOR ON IT!
MR. STOWE,
I'M GLAD TA SEE YA.
HERE WE GO.
CALM YOURSELF, SANDY.
NOTHING'S GONNA
HAPPEN TO US.
WE WON'T TURN UP THE
WELL-KNOWN TOES
UNTIL OL' MAN TIME
CATCHES UP WITH US.
(bang)
IT DIDN'T TAKE OLD
MAN TIME LONG TO
CATCH UP WITH US.
OOH, YOU'RE HURT!
A LITTLE.
PLEASE...
TELL MRS. STOWE...
NOT TO SELL TO BENDER.
JOHN, DO YOU THINK
THERE'LL BE ANY MORE
TROUBLE?
NO.
WHY WOULDN'T
MR. STOWE
WANT HIS WIFE TO
SELL TO BENDER?
THAT'S THE QUESTION.
THIS IS THE BOILER ROOM.
MR. BENDER SAILED ON
THESIOUX PRINCESS,
SO HE COULDN'T HAVE
DONE ANY SHOOTING.
THIS MUST BE IT...
IT'S THE ONLY ONE
WITH A DOOR ON IT.
(Bigtree)
LOOKIN' FOR
ME, FOLKS?
I THINK THIS IS OUR
STATEROOM, COLLINS.
ONLY, UH, WHAT
COUNTS AROUND
THESE PARTS IS...
WHO GETS THERE FIRST.
LET'S TAKE THE
OTHER ROOM, JOHN.
I THINK COLLINS WANTS
US TO HAVE THIS ROOM.
WELL, I GUESS A MAN
TRAVELING WITH HIS WIFE
SHOULD HAVE A ROOM
WITH A DOOR ON IT.
DIDN'T HURT YOUR GUN
HAND, DID YA, DEVLIN?
I CAN STILL...
WRITE WITH IT.
A MAN'S GOT TA
WATCH HISSELF.
AN ACCIDENT LIKE THAT
COULD PUT HIM OUT OF
BUSINESS, HUH?
SEE YA.
????
??
LOOK OUT NOW, YOU SWEET
LITTLE HUNK A MISERY.
LOOK OUT... SHE'S RIGHT
UP AHEAD THERE.
PORT TA HELM, NICODEMUS!
COMIN', CAP'N.
NOW HERE SHE COMES...
LOOK OUT NOW.
LOOK... DROP.
DROP, YOU SNEAKIN' COUSIN
OF A SNEAKIN' CATFISH!
POP YOUR INNARDS!
BUST IS COMING!!
GET OVER THERE!!
THERE, SEE HOW EASY IT IS
WHEN YOU WANNA DO IT?
GOT HER OVER THAT ONE,
DIDN'T YA, CAP'N?
OH, SHE'S SCARED.
SHE'S BEEN HANGIN'
HERSELF UP ON THEM RIVER
WARTS FOR FIVE YEARS,
AND SHE KNOWS IF SHE
JUST SETS HERSELF DOWN
JUST ONE MORE,
I'LL BLOW HER HIGHER
THAN THE COST OF LIVIN'
IN FARGO!
- JOHN?
- YES?
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
IN ABERCROMBIE
WAS NOT A FAULT OF YOURS.
IT WAS MR. STOWE
THEY WERE AFTER.
AND YOU MIGHT HAVE
BEEN KILLED
SIMPLY BECAUSE
YOU DREW A GUN,
WHICH YOU COULDN'T HAVE
DRAWN IF YOU HADN'T BEEN
CARRYING IT.
WHEN I SEE A GUN POINTED
IN MY DIRECTION,
SO FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
I'M PART AND PARCEL TO
THAT DEAL,
AND I'M GONNA ACT
ACCORDINGLY.
(boat whistle)
WHAT'S THAT FOR?
MUST BE TAKIN'
ON PASSENGERS.
JOHN?
IF I DID SOMETHING THAT
WOULD MAKE YOU ANGRY,
WHAT WOULD YOU
DO TO ME?
WHAT A FELLA SHOULD
DO TO A LITTLE GIRL
THAT'S DONE SOMETHING
SHE SHOULDN'T A DONE.
YOU WOULDN'T?
I'D BE EMBARRASSED
TO DEATH.
WELL, WHAT BROUGHT
THIS ON?
WELL, AS I WAS SAYING,
IF YOU HADN'T REACHED
FOR YOUR GUN,
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE
SHOT AT YOU.
DON'T SCARE ME
LIKE THAT.
(Captain Bounce)
WHAT YOU FELLAS WANT?!
WE'D LIKE TO COME
ABOARD, CAP'N.
INJUNS SNUCK UP ON
US LAST NIGHT AND
STOLE OUR HORSES.
WE STARTED TO LEG IT BUT
GOT OFF THE TRAIL.
GIVE ME A HAND, WILL
YA, BIG FELLA?
YOU KNOW WHAT
THIS MEANS?
I AIN'T GONNA TAKE MUCH
OF YOUR TIME, MISTER.
HEY, WHAT'S GOIN' ON DOWN THERE!
GET YOUR HEAD BACK
IN THERE, POP.
(bang)
(ding ding)
WHICH POCKET'S
THAT MONEY IN?
WHO TOLD YOU I
HAD ANY MONEY?
AN INJUN CAME TO ME IN
A DREAM LAST NIGHT
AND SAYS AS HOW
YOU WAS LOADED.
GET BACK THERE,
FLATFOOT!
- AND YOU, MISTER, STAY
RIGHT WHERE YOU ARE.
- YEAH, SURE.
OH, AIN'T I THE
LUCKY ONE?
LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
THAT'S ALL WE HAVE!
GET BACK, LADY.
YELLOWTAIL!
GET BACK!
(bang)
(click click)
WOULDN'T LEND ME YOUR
GUN FOR A COUPLA MINUTES,
WOULD YA, COLLINS?
WOULD YA LEND ME YOURS,
DEVLIN, IF IT WAS LOADED?
NO.
BUT THOSE MEN, THEY'RE GETTING
AWAY WITH OUR MONEY!
TOO BAD, MA'AM.
BUT MY MOMMA TOLD ME,
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE SHAVER,
IF I NEVER BUTTED INTO
TO NOBODY'S BUSINESS,
I'D NEVER GET HURT.
GOOD ADVICE FOR ANYBODY, MA'AM.
WELL, I CAN'T DO MUCH
FIGHTIN' WITH
AN EMPTY GUN.
THEN IT ONLY COST US 20,000
GREENIES TO FIND THAT OUT.
WELL...
HOW WAS I TO KNOW ANYTHING LIKE
THIS WAS GOING TO HAPPEN?
I'LL NEVER TOUCH YOUR
OL' GUN AGAIN!
AND IF YOU'RE GOING TO GET
YOUR SILLY HEAD SHOT OFF,
I'M NOT GOING TO CARE...
MUCH.
FUNNY PART OF IT IS
IF YOU HADN'T
EMPTIED MY GUN,
I MIGHTA TAKEN A FEW
SLUGS IN THE BACK.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY,
SANDY, IF I WERE TO
TELL YA
THAT YOU LOOK AS GOOD
TO ME WITHOUT MONEY
AS YOU DID WITH IT?
OH, JOHN.
(Bang!)
TAKE THAT, DAG BLAST YA!
COME BACK HERE AND I'LL BLOW IT
THROUGH YOUR THIEVIN' BONES!!
BOARDIN' A MAN'S SHIP
FOR ILLEGAL PURPOSES!
HOLD ON.
LOOK OUT FOR THEM
SAND BARS, YOU... !!
NICODEMUS!
GET THEM ENGINES
STARTED!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOIN' THERE?!
WELL, CAP'N,
IF'N IT'S THEM
OIL-SWEATIN' SUCKERS
Y'ALL REFERRIN' TO,
RIGHT HERE IS WHERE
I'M TURNIN' 'EM OVER
TA Y'ALL.
GET BACK IN THAT
ENGINE ROOM,
FOR I START TAKIN'
YOU APART!!
LOOK OUT,
NICODEMUS!!
SO YA WENT AND DONE IT!
GOT YOURSELF HUNG UP!!
HUNG UP FOR KEEPS,
JUST LIKE Y'ALLS
BEEN TRYIN' TA DO!
WELL, FOLKS,
AS CAP'N OF THIS HERE
NOW DOOMED SHIP,
I'M GIVIN' MY LAST
AND FINAL ORDER!
MAN THE LIFEBOATS
AND ABANDON SHIP!!!
BEAT YOUR LIFEBOATS
AND SHIP YOUR OARS!
POOR CAPTAIN BOUNCE,
WASN'T HE CUTE?
BUT WHERE IS HE?
WELL, HE WENT DOWN WITH
HIS SHIP, DIDN'T HE,
LIKE A GOOD CAPTAIN SHOULD.
(Nicodemus)
WELL, HOW'S A MAN GOIN'
DOWN WITH HIS SHIP
WHAT AIN'T NEVER UP?
BUT HE WON'T BE ABLE
TO STAY ABOARD.
WHY DOESN'T HE
COME WITH US?
YA GOT ME.
YA OUGHTA BE ASHAMED
OF YOURSELF,
SITTIN' ON A SAND BAR LIKE
A HEN SITTIN' ON A NEST.
YOU'RE NOTHIN' BUT A NO-GOOD
WOMAN, THAT'S ALL!
AND WHEN A WOMAN TWO-TIMES
A MAN, THERE'S ONLY ONE
THING TO DO!
AND THAT'S PUT ON THE PRESSURE!
YOU'RE GOIN' NOW, YOU
CONTRARY FEMALE.
I'M GONNA GIT YOU
OFF'N THIS SAND BAR
IF I HAS TA BLOW YA OFF!
(Boom!)
I SHOULDN'TA SAID IT, HONEY.
I SHOULDN'TA SAID IT.
PO' CAP'N BOUNCE.
HE DID A POWERFUL
LOTTA SHOUTIN',
BUT IT'S BEEN A WHOLE
LOT WORSE'N HE WAS.
I HOPES WHEN THEY GET
HIM WHERE HE'S GOIN',
THEY DON'T PUT
HIM TO NO WIPIN'.
LOOK.
WE GOTTA GET HIM
OUTTA THERE.
GIVE ME A HAND,
COLLINS.
WHERE IS HE?
HE'S GONE.
COME ON, NICODEMUS.
YES, SIR, THIS ALL
BELONG TO MRS. STOWE,
MORE'N 10,000
ACRES OF IT.
IT'S WHAT THEY CALL A...
A BONANZA FARM.
NOW OVER HERE'S
THE STOWE HOME.
THEY... OH.
DON'T LOOK LIKE THERE
IS ANY STOWE HOME.
ACCORDIN' TO THE WAY
THEM ASHES PILED AROUND,
THIS MUSTA BEEN
THE JUMPINEST FIRE
WHAT EVER WAS.
DOES MRS. STOWE LIVE
IN THAT TEEPEE?
WELL, IF'N IT'S THE
SAME MRS. STOWE
THAT COME UP WITH ME
ON THERIVER BIRD
THREE YEARS AGO,
SHE'S PROBABLY
THERE WAITIN'...
WAITIN' FOR MR. STOWE
TA COME HOME.
THAT POOR DEAR.
THEY CAME HERE TA SETTLE
DOWN AND GROW WHEAT,
HER AND MR. STOWE,
AND THAT'S WHAT THEY DONE.
LOOKS LIKE THAT'S ABOUT ALL
THERE IS LEFT FOR MRS. STOWE...
WHEAT.
MR. DEVLIN?
BEIN' AS HOW I'M JUST
AN OL' MUD TURTLE
AND AIN'T USED TO
BREAKIN' BAD NEWS
TO FINE LADIES,
I THOUGHT MAYBE YOU
COULD SPIT IT OUT
FOR ME, HUH?
I MEAN ABOUT MR. STOWE
GETTIN' PLUGGED AND ALL.
WELL, UH...
I'LL TELL HER.
THANK YOU, MA'AM.
THEY'RE PROBABLY
LOST, TONKA.
WHY, IT'S CAPTAIN
BOUNCE!
OH, CAPTAIN BOUNCE,
YOU'RE JUST ABOUT
THE LAST PERSON
I'D EXPECT TO
VISIT ME HERE.
TELL ME, YOU'VE BEEN
AT ABERCROMBIE?
YOU SAW MR. STOWE?
YES'M, HE WAS THERE.
MRS. STOWE, THIS
IS MR. DEVLIN AND
MRS. DEVLIN...
HOW DO YOU DO?
HOW DO YOU DO,
MR. AND MRS. DEVLIN.
- AND MY BOSUN, NICODEMUS.
- NICODEMUS.
I HOPE YOU'LL EXCUSE ME
FOR NOT GETTING UP,
BUT WE'VE HAD A FIRE,
AS YOU CAN SEE, AND MY...
WELL, I GOT BURNED
A LITTLE TRYING TO
SAVE A FEW THINGS.
TONKA, HAVEN'T WE
SOMETHING FOR OUR
VISITORS TO SIT ON?
NO GOT.
WELL, I'M SORRY,
IT DOESN'T SEEM WE'VE
GOT VERY MUCH LEFT.
POOR ANSON--
THAT'S MR. STOWE--
HE WORKS SO HARD.
THEY CAME AND RAIDED
AND BURNED THE PLACE
THE NIGHT HE LEFT.
OH, BUT YOU MUST BE VERY
TIRED AND HUNGRY.
OH, NO... WE'VE JUST
COME A COUPLE OF MILES.
WE WONDERED IF WE COULD
BORROW SOME HORSES?
WELL, THERE ARE FOUR OF YOU...
YOU MAY HAVE FOUR, OF COURSE.
WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
WE'LL RETURN THEM AS
SOON AS WE CAN.
BUT I THINK IF YOU'RE
ABLE TO TRAVEL,
YOU SHOULD GO WITH
US TO FARGO.
NO... I'LL BE ALL RIGHT HERE
UNTIL ANSON GETS BACK.
WELL, THAT'S
JUST IT, UH...
GO ON, GET THE HORSES.
????
??
THIS HERE'S WHAT
THEY CALL FARGO
IN THE TIMBER.
OVER THERE'S FARGO
ON THE PRAIRIE.
WHY ARE THEY
WEARING THOSE
FOREIGN COSTUMES?
OH, I DUNNO,
SOME KINDA DOIN'S.
SHE IS WHAT YOU CALL
A GET-TOGETHER.
EACH YEAR, ONCE
WE HAVE HER.
WE USE THE NATIONAL
COSTUMES.
(Captain Bounce)
HOW ARE YA, MIKE...
I'M GLAD TA SEE YA.
HELLO, CAP.
I WANT YOU TA MEET
MR. AND MRS. DEVLIN.
MY NAME IS MIKHAIL
PONTELIVONICH CORINO.
HERR KOFFKA,
SENIOR BARONI,
M'SIEUR LaFOND.
LISTEN... THEY'RE
PLAYING A WALTZ.
LADY, YOU
LIKE TO DANCE?
OH, I... I'D
LOVE TO BUT...
OH, A NICE PLACE
YOU HAVE HERE.
OH, YES... IT BELONGS
TO M'SIEUR BENDER.
WE MAKE ARRANGEMENT
WITH HIM
FOR THE HOMESTEADERS TO
HAVE IT FOR ONE NIGHT.
SI... MR. BENDER'S
A FINE MAN, SI?
I HOPE THEY HAVE
ROOM FOR US.
????
??
DID YOU EVER SEE
ANYTHING SO COLORFUL?
IT MAKES DAKOTA A
MELTING POT, DOESN'T IT?
EVER TRY KANSAS
CITY IN JULY?
????
??
(Collins)
GOT HERE ALL RIGHT,
EH, DEVLIN?
HOW DID YOU GET HERE,
COLLINS, AS THE CROW
FLIES?
MET UP WITH A COUPLA
FRIENDS WITH HORSES.
MR. SLAGIN...
MR. DEVLIN.
NICE TA SEE YA
AGAIN, SLAGIN.
YOU NEVER MET
ME BEFORE...
MUSTA BEEN MY BROTHER.
OH, A BIG FELLA?
YEAH, AS HANDSOME
AS THEY COME.
ABOUT AS HANDSOME
AS A PRAIRIE DOG.
HE'S A BAD MAN TO MESS
AROUND WITH, DEVLIN.
WELL, HE SURE GOT THE JOB DONE.
AND HE'S AWFULLY
FAST WITH A GUN.
ABOUT AS FAST AS YOU
ARE, I SUPPOSE?
YEAH.
JUST HOW FAST IS THAT?
(Sandy)
OH, JOHN, IF
YOU'RE NOT IN...
OH.
THIS IS MR. SLAGIN.
YOU MET HIS BROTHER
ON THE BOAT.
WAS THAT YOUR BROTHER?
I THOUGHT IT WAS YOU.
I MEAN...
HOW DO YOU DO?
YOU KNOW COLLINS,
OF COURSE.
YES.
I GUESS YOU'LL BE
WANTIN' A COUPLA
ROOMS, EH, DEVLIN?
YEAH... ONE FOR US AND
ONE FOR THE CAP'N.
WHAT WERE YOU
ABOUT TO SAY?
I WAS GOING TO
SAY LET'S DANCE,
BUT IT SEEMS KIND
OF SILLY NOW.
I MEAN, I DON'T FEEL
LIKE IT ANYMORE.
OH, SURE YOU DO.
DO US A LITTLE FAVOR,
WILL YA, SLAGIN?
YEAH.
WILL YA STEP OUTSIDE AND
ARRANGE FOR SOMEONE
TO STABLE OUR HORSES?
WHEN A LADY WANTS TO
DANCE, WE GOTTA FIX
IT SO SHE CAN, RIGHT?
YEAH, SURE.
I WANT YA TA HAVE YOUR FUN
WHILE YA CAN, MRS. DEVLIN.
YOU NEVER CAN TELL
HOW YA FEEL ABOUT THINGS
COME TOMORRA.
HERE YA ARE, DEVLIN.
ANY TIME WE'RE NOT
HERE, AND YOU WANT
TO SEE ME OR BENDER,
LOOK BACK IN
THE OFFICE.
TAKE WHICHEVER
ROOM YA WANT,
BUT LEAVE US ONE
WITH A BED IN IT.
????
??
DARLING, WHY DO YOU
TAKE SUCH CHANCES?
AFTER ALL, NO ONE
HERE'S ON OUR SIDE.
I LEARNED ONE THING FROM
GENERAL MORGAN, SANDY...
THAT'S WHEN YOU'RE
SURROUNDED AND
HAVEN'T A CHANCE...
ATTACK.
HELLO.
MET YOUR BROTHER
THIS MORNING.
YEAH... HOW'S HE DOING?
NOT BAD, BUT IT LOOKS
LIKE THERE'S SOME SAD
DAYS AHEAD.
JOHN?
YES?
DO YOU THINK I LOOK
GOOD IN BLACK?
THERE AIN'T NO GOL'
DARNED HORSE THIEVES
HOLDIN' UP NO
SHIP O' MINE.
SO I GRABS MY CARBINE,
I GETS THE PAIR OF 'EM
IN MY SIGHTS AND WHAM!
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE
THIS, BUT, EH...
MISSED 'EM, CLEAN
AS A WHISTLE.
THIS OUR KEY, CAP'N?
IT DON'T MAKE NO
DIFFERENCE,
IT FITS ALL
THE DOORS.
I JUST STOPPED BY TO
TALK TO THE LADIES A
MINUTE.
THEY REMIND ME OF MY
DEAR OLD AUNT MINNIE.
OH, THIS IS MR. AND
MRS. DEVLIN, LADIES.
THEY WORK HERE...
THEY'RE DOIN' A SONG
AND DANCE ACT.
OF COURSE, THEY'RE
OFF FOR TONIGHT
ON ACCOUNT OF THE BIG DOIN'S.
- I'M JERSEY THOMAS.
- I ALWAYS THOUGHT
JERSEY WAS A STATE.
COULD BE, ON
OCCASION.
THAT'S NEW JERSEY YOU'RE
THINKING OF, DEAR.
THEY CERTAINLY MANAGE
TO ATTRACT ALL THE
UGLIEST TYPES HERE,
HAVEN'T THEY?
JUST ONE BIG HAPPY
MELTING POT, EH?
BUT DON'T MELT TOO
EASILY, WILL YOU, DEAR?
AND YOU THINKING ALL
THE TIME THAT JERSEY
WAS A STATE.
WHY YOU!
YOU OPEN THIS DOOR,
YOU BIG LADY KILLER!
????
??
WELL, GLAD I MET'CHA,
GOOD-BYE.
HE MUST BE ONE OF
THOSE ONE-WOMAN MEN
I'VE HEARD SO MUCH ABOUT.
OH, I GUESS HE JUST
GONE DOWN TO GIT
HISSELF A DRINK.
SUPPOSE WE LEAVE IT
UNLOCKED, DEVLIN?
SOME OF THE BOYS MIGHT
WANT TO DROP IN.
HOW ARE YA?
FOR THE MOMENT,
SHORT ABOUT $20,000.
IS THAT SO...
HOW'D YA LOSE IT?
TURNING BACKFLIPS.
THAT COULDN'T BE
IT, COULD IT?
YOU PROVE IT'S YOURS,
AND YOU CAN HAVE IT.
WHEN I WALK OUT OF HERE,
IF IT'S IN MY POCKET,
WILL THAT PROVE
ANYTHING?
YOU WOULDN'T TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF A MAN WITH A BAD LEG,
WOULD YOU, DEVLIN?
WELL, YOU WOULDN'T
HIDE BEHIND IT
WITH MY $20,000,
WOULD YOU, BENDER?
YOU TALK LIKE YOU MIGHT
TRY TO TAKE THAT MONEY
AWAY FROM ME,
AND I DON'T THINK
I LIKE THAT.
YOU'RE NOT IN FARGO TO
STAY, ARE YOU, MR. DEVLIN?
OH...
BAD CHARACTER, EH?
OUGHTA MOVE ON.
WELL, I DON'T LIKE
TO SEEM BLUNT,
BUT WE'VE GOT A PRETTY NICE
LITTLE COMMUNITY HERE,
AND WE DON'T EXACTLY
COTTON TO SHARP WITS
WHO COME HERE
WITH THE IDEA OF TRIMMING
THE FOLKS HEREABOUTS.
(crash)
FRIEND OF YOURS
OR MINE?
BETTER HAND OVER
THE MONEY, BENDER.
I GOT THE PLACE SURROUNDED.
THAT'S FUNNY, SO HAVE I.
THINGS OUGHT TO START
TO BREAK SHORTLY, HUH?
RIGHT NOW...
LET'S HAVE IT.
GO AHEAD AND TAKE IT,
IF YOU LIKE THAT
KIND OF A GAMBLE.
THERE'S AN EASIER WAY TO
GET IT, THOUGH, DEVLIN.
LEAVE ON THE
FIRST BOAT?
THERE'S NOTHING PERSONAL
ABOUT IT AT ALL.
THIS COUNTRY'S MY COUNTRY, AND
THE PEOPLE IN IT ARE MY PEOPLE,
AND I'M GONNA LOOK AFTER
THEIR INTERESTS.
BUT IT'S NOT TO THEIR INTEREST
TO LET YOU RUN AROUND
WITH YOUR HANDS FULL OF MONEY,
BUYING UP OPTIONS ON THEIR LAND,
VERY CHEAPLY, FOR THE RAILROAD.
YOU GOT ALL THE FACTS RIGHT
ON FILE, HAVEN'T YOU?
YOU'RE MARRIED TO POLI'S
DAUGHTER... FAR AS
I'M CONCERNED,
THAT CONNECTS YOU
WITH THE RAILROAD.
AND THAT PROVIDES ME WITH
A NEAT LITTLE LIFE INSURANCE
POLICY TOO.
- DOES IT?
- IF YOU GOT ME, SHE'D
SCREAM FOR HELP,
AND PAPA POLI'D BE UP
HERE WITH THE UNITED
STATES ARMY
BEFORE YOU COULD
SADDLE A HORSE,
WHICH LEAVES YOU HOLDIN'
THE SMALL CARDS, BENDER.
SO I'LL TAKE
THE MONEY.
LOOK OUT!
(bang)
SWEET LITTLE BABY.
NOW DON'T YOU GET TO FLIRTIN'
WITH THEM SAND BARS,
AND PAPA'LL BUY YA A
NICE NEW TON A COAL
WHEN WE GIT TO GRAND FORKS.
(bam)
I NEVER SEE'D THIS RIVER
KICK UP LIKE THIS BEFORE...
MUST BE A STORM A BREWIN'.
HEY!
THEM WINDSTORMS COME UP WITHOUT
GIVIN' NO ADVANCED NOTICE,
DON'T THEY?
I SEE'D YOUR WIFE...
HURT HER HARD.
PICKED ME UP AND
SLAMMED ME DOWN
LIKE I WAS A OLD
SPITTOON OR SOMETHIN'...
ALLOWED THEM TO KEEP
THEIR DOORS CLOSED
IN HURRICANE SEASON.
WHICH WAY'D SHE BLOW,
FROM THE NORTH OR THE
SOUTH?
SANDY?
HERE, USE MY KEY.
THEY'RE ALL ALIKE...
IT'S ON THE HOUSE.
LOOKIN' FOR YOUR WIFE?
DON'T GUESS SHE'D BE IN
THAT SUITCASE, DO YA?
YOU AIN'T FIGURIN' ON
SHOOTIN' HER, ARE YA?
NOW WAIT A MINUTE!
MAYBE IT WEREN'T HER FAULT.
FOR A WOMAN, SHE
DIDN'T LOOK TOO BAD.
THE MAN DON'T SHOW MUCH SENSE,
SHOOTIN' A WOMAN...
ESPECIALLY IN THIS COUNTRY,
WHERE THEY'RE SO SCARCE.
(dog barking)
????
??
(Dr. Judson)
HOLD THAT LIGHT CLOSER.
(Sandy)
JOHN.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT, JOHN.
THEY DIDN'T MEAN TO HIT ME.
IT WAS YOU THEY SHOT AT.
THIS MAN KNOW HIS
BUSINESS, BENDER?
IF HE DOESN'T,
YOUR WIFE MAY DIE...
IN WHICH EVENT I
ALSO CASH IN, RIGHT?
NOW IF SOMEONE WILL
HOLD HER OTHER ARM.
TAKE A DEEP BREATH,
MRS. DEVLIN.
JOHN, I'M FRIGHTENED.
NOT SO MUCH OF A WOUND,
THE DOC SAYS.
TROUBLE IS THAT BULLET'S
PRESSING ON AN ARTERY.
IF HE HAPPENS TO MAKE A SLIP
AND PUNCTURE THAT ARTERY,
THEN SHE'S GONNA BE IN TROUBLE.
IS THAT IT, DOC?
THAT'S IT.
ANYTHING ELSE YOU
WANTED TO SEE ME
ABOUT, DEVLIN?
SHE BE ALL RIGHT, DOC?
HER SHOULDER MAY BE
STIFF FOR A COUPLA DAYS.
MY GUESS IS THAT
SHE'LL OUTLIVE YOU.
HOW LONG WILL IT
TAKE YA TO FINISH UP?
A FEW MINUTES.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
DEVLIN, YOU IN A
HURRY?
YEAH.
GET OVER THERE WITH BENDER!
(Bender)
LET ME REMIND YOU,
IF I HADN'T GOTTEN MRS. DEVLIN
OVER HERE TO
DR. JUDSON, SHE
MIGHT'VE DIED.
I'M REMEMBERIN' IT,
AND ALSO HOW SHE
CAME TO GET HIT.
MAYBE I OUGHTA FIX IT
SO ACCIDENTS LIKE THAT
CAN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
THAT CALLS FOR
KILLING TWO MEN
IN COLD BLOOD,
DOESN'T IT?
YES.
IT REQUIRES A
CERTAIN TYPE
OF MAN
TO KILL WITHOUT
EXCUSE, DEVLIN,
SOMEBODY MORE
LIKE MYSELF.
YOU COULDA KILLED HER, BENDER.
THAT'S ALL THE
EXCUSE I NEED.
(Sandy)
JOHN?
IS IT...
IS IT ALL OVER?
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
A SOBERING EFFECT
UPON YOUR HUSBAND,
MRS. DEVLIN.
YOU BETTER TAKE YOUR
WIFE BACK TO THE
HOTEL, DEVLIN.
PERHAPS IT'D BE TO THE
BENEFIT OF ALL OF US
IF YOU POINTED OUT
THE ADVANTAGES TO HIM
OF BOTH OF YOU
RETURNING TO CHICAGO.
SUPPOSE YOU
POINT 'EM OUT.
AN AGENT COMMISSIONED
TO OPTION LAND FOR
THE RAILROAD
CAN'T FUNCTION VERY WELL
WITHOUT MONEY, CAN HE?
I'LL BE OVER
TOMORROW FOR
THE MONEY.
TOMORROW MAY BE TOO LATE
FOR IT TO DO YOU ANY GOOD.
HAVE IT READY.
NICODEMUS!
COMIN', CAP'N.
GET UP OUTTA THERE!
THE TOWN'S DONE CLEANED OUT!
WHERE'S EVERYBODY AT?
CAP'N, WHY... WHY DOES
YOU HAVE TA WAKE ME UP
TA ASK ME THAT?
THEY'RE ALL GOIN' TA
FARGO ON THE SOM'DOTHER,
ON DA OTHER SIDE OF THEM TREES.
FARGO ON THE
PRAIRIE?
WHAT'S GOIN' ON
OVER THERE?
WHY... WHY YA HAS TA
ASK ME THAT, CAP'N?
MAN GOES SOMEPLACE,
IT'S A VISIT.
A BUNCH OF MEN GO SOMEPLACE,
IT'S A PARTY.
EVERYBODY GOES SOMEPLACE,
IT'S A MEETIN'.
WHATEVER'S GOIN' ON OVER THERE
HAS GOT TO BE A MEETIN', CAP'N,
'CAUSE THAT'S WHERE
THEY'S ALL AT.
WELL, COME ON...
LET'S GO OVER.
IS YOU COMIN', OR
IS I GOTTA SHOVE
YA OVERBOARD!!
COMIN', CAP'N.
SO AS SOON AS I SAW THE CROP
WAS GONNA BE TOO BIG
FOR US TO HANDLE,
BEING PRESIDENT OF THE WHEAT
GROWERS ASSOCIATION,
I GUESS IT WAS UP TO ME
TO FIGURE OUT A WAY
TO GET THE CROPS HARVESTED
AND OFF TO THE MARKET.
SO LIKE I TOLD YA,
I WENT TO MR. BENDER
AND MADE A DEAL FOR HIM
TO LEND US THE MONEY
TO BRING IN A GANG
OF HARVEST HANDS,
AND TO TAKE CARE OF
SHIPPIN' COSTS.
(farmer)
BUT WHY YOU GO
TO MR. BENDER?!
THE BANK IN GRAND FORK,
SHE'S GOT PLENTY OF
MONEY TO LEND!
(Slagin)
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH BENDER'S MONEY,
AIN'T IT ANY GOOD?
(Collins)
MR. BENDER'S DONE PLENTY
FOR US AROUND HERE.
HE'S GIVE US CREDIT
AT THE STORE
AND STAKED A FEW OF US.
AND I SAY HERE AND NOW!
IF THERE'S ANY SIDE MONEY
TO BE MADE AROUND HERE,
HE'S THE MAN WHO
OUGHT TO GET IT.
BUT THIS CONTRACT
WE ARE TO SIGN,
IF SOMETHING IS
WRONG WITH CROPS,
ALL OUR LAND WILL BELONG
TO MR. BENDER?
WELL, A MAN HAS TO HAVE
SOME KIND OF SECURITY
FOR THE MONEY HE
PUTS UP, AIN'T HE?
IT'S DUMB BUTTS LIKE YOU
THAT KEEP US SMART FOLKS
FROM PROGRESSIN'.
WHAT YOU GOT TO
SAY ABOUT THIS?
YOU DON'T FARM NO LANDS!
NOBODY CAN TALK THAT WAY TO ME!
WHAT HE... WHAT HE DON'T
KNOW IS THAT I...
I GOT SECRET HOLDIN'S.
I GOT A PIECE OF 10,000 ACRES,
AND I AIM TO SEE THAT WHEAT
CUT WITH FARGO MONEY.
AND IF THERE'S ANY
PROFIT TO BE MADE,
I WANT MY GOOD FRIEND, MR.
BENDER, TO COLLECT IT, SEE?!
AND ANOTHER THING...
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS TO THE CROP,
MR. BENDER'S GONNA PAY US
FOR WHAT THE LAND IS WORTH,
ACCORDIN' TO GOVERNMENT
VALUATION--
A DOLLAR AN ACRE!
AND WHY WOULD ANYBODY WANT TO
BUY WORTHLESS PRAIRIE ACREAGE
WITH NOTHIN' GROWIN' ON IT?
WHAT MR. COLLINS SAID
SOUNDS LOGICAL ENOUGH.
ALL I KNOW IS THIS
DEAL IS FIXIN' THINGS
SO THERE'S A POSSIBILITY
OF BENDER BUYING OUR LAND.
AND ANOTHER THING...
THE WHOLE BLAMED LAYOUT
IS SO SLICK AND PRETTY
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE'S GOTTA BE
A CATCH IN IT.
EXACTLY WHAT I
WAS THINKING,
MR. PLUMMER.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS
TO THE WHEAT CROP,
LOOKS TO ME LIKE I'M
STUCK WITH ABOUT
50 SQUARE MILES OF
WORTHLESS PRAIRIE.
SO AS A FAVOR TO ME,
WILL YOU LET OUT
A MAN-SIZED PROTEST
ABOUT THE WHOLE DEAL,
AND GIVE ME A CHANCE
TO SQUEEZE OUT OF IT?
DON'T GUESS IT'D DO
ME ANY GOOD FOR ME TO
SAY ANYTHING, BENDER,
A COUPLE OTHER
MEN TRIED THAT
AND GOT NOWHERE.
SEEMS LIKE I HAVE TOO MANY
FRIENDS, DOESN'T IT?
IT SEEMS TO ME THAT
WORTHLESS PRAIRIE OR NOT,
YOU'RE GOING TO OWN ALL THE
LAND AROUND HERE, MR. BENDER.
DO YOU EXPECT ANYTHING TO HAPPEN
TO YOUR WHEAT, MRS. STOWE?
WELL, ALONG WITH SOME
OTHER BONANZA FARMERS,
LIKE MRS. STOWE AND MR. WATERS,
I DIDN'T EXPECT TO
GET BURNED OUT.
SOMEBODY COME ALONG
WITH A TORCH, EH?
WHAT HAPPENED TO OUR FARM
BUILDINGS COULD HAPPEN TO
OUR WHEAT.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS TO YOUR
WHEAT, I'M THE LOSER.
SO I THINK WE BETTER TAKE
STEPS TO SEE THAT NOTHING
DOES HAPPEN TO IT.
WHAT KIND OF STEPS,
MR. BENDER?
WHEN THE PEACE OF A
COMMUNITY IS DISTURBED
BY VIOLENCE AND ACTS OF
VANDALISM, MRS. STOWE,
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING
TO DO ABOUT IT
AND THAT'S BRING IN THE LAW,
SO THAT'S WHAT WE'LL DO.
SOUNDS HONEST
ENOUGH, DIDN'T HE?
I'D NEVER HAD
SUSPECTED HIM,
IF ANSON HADN'T SAID HE
WAS JUST NO GOOD AT ALL.
I PROBABLY WOULDN'T
HAVE MYSELF,
IF IT WASN'T FOR THE
FACT THAT EVERYONE
THAT WAS BURNED OUT
GOT AN OFFER FROM HIM
FOR THEIR LAND FIRST.
COME ON, NICODEMUS,
THIS IS NO PLACE FOR US.
COMIN', CAP'N.
????
??
SO THE ONE WITH ALL
THE EYEBROWS SAYS TO
ME, HE SAYS...
"WHAT MAKES YOU
SO DIFFERENT?"
OF COURSE, I COULD
ALWAYS TRIM HIS
EYEBROWS A LITTLE,
BUT EVEN IF I DID,
WHAT WOULD I HAVE?
A WHEAT FARM.
I'LL TAKE A NICE,
DIRTY MINER
WITH GOLD DUST CAKED
UNDER HIS FINGERNAILS.
IF YOU CAN SPARE ONE.
ME, TOO.
THERE I WAS IN CALIFORNIA, UP
TO MY ELBOWS IN HARD-ROCK MEN,
AND I HAD TO COME HERE.
I COULD'VE MARRIED,
SETTLED DOWN AND HAD
MYSELF A NICE HOME.
AND A NATIVE SON.
PUT IT IN A GILT
FRAME, AND I'LL
BUY IT.
LOOK, GIRLS, THEBELL OF THE
NORTHWESTGETS IN TONIGHT,
AND COLLINS WANTS YOU ALL THERE
AT THE LANDING WHEN SHE TIES UP,
LOOKING YOUR BEST, SO BE THERE.
OH, EXCUSE ME...
I THOUGHT THIS
WAS THE KITCHEN.
WELL, IT IS THE KITCHEN.
LOOKING FOR ANYONE
IN PARTICULAR?
I WANTED TO GET
A COUPLE OF EGGS.
WELL, IN THAT
CASE, COME ON
IN.
WE'LL THANK YOU TO SPEAK
OF US WITH MORE RESPECT,
MR. DEVLIN.
WE USUALLY TAKE THE
EGG TO THE CUSTOMER,
UNLESS THE CUSTOMER
INSISTS ON COMING
TO THE EGG.
WE WANT YOU TO BE
HAPPY, OF COURSE.
AND YOU'RE JUST THE
LITTLE GIRL THAT
CAN DO IT, EH?
WELL, THESE EGGS
ARE FOR MRS. DEVLIN,
AND I THOUGHT I'D
TAKE THEM UP TO HER.
YOU SEE, SHE, UH...
SHE HAS A HEADACHE.
PEOPLE GET THEM
IN FARGO.
IF YOU WANT TO
GET BACK TO YOUR
CROCHETING, GIRLS,
I'LL LOOK AFTER
MR. DEVLIN.
HOW ABOUT A COUPLE
OF EGGS FOR MR.
DEVLIN, NORA?
AIN'T GOT NO EGGS...
THE GIRLS ATE 'EM ALL UP.
BUT WE GROW THEM RIGHT
OUTSIDE THE DOOR,
IF YOU'VE GOT
TO HAVE THEM.
WELL, I'M AN OLD
EGG RUSTLER.
NO FUN RUSTLING
ALONE.
DID I SAY RUSTLING?
I MEANT RUSTLING.
(knock knock knock
knock knock knock)
IT'S NOT LOCKED!
WHERE ON EARTH DID
YOU GO FOR THE EGGS?!
MORNIN', MA'AM.
OH.
WHERE IS MR. DEVLIN?
HE'S GETTING ME
SOME BREAKFAST
FROM ST. PAUL,
I THINK.
IS IT SOMETHING
IMPORTANT?
NO, MA'AM, I DON'T
GUESS IT IS.
BUT BENDER IS OVER IN
FARGO ON THE PRAIRIE
GETTIN' THEM FARMERS
TO SIGN CONTRACTS.
I THOUGHT MAYBE MR.
DEVLIN WOULD LIKE TO
KNOW ABOUT IT.
OH, I'M SURE HE WOULD.
RUN DOWN TO THE KITCHEN.
NEVER MIND,
I'LL GO MYSELF.
LOOK...
I DON'T KNOW WHY, BUT
THERE'S A MAN DOWN THERE
WHO'S BEEN WATCHING
THIS WINDOW.
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
HE'S SPYIN' ON
SOMEONE, HUH?
WELL, WE'LL SOON FIND
OUT ABOUT THAT.
HEY, GO AWAY!
(Bang!)
DAGNABIT, I GOTTA LEARN TO KEEP
MY HEAD OUT'N THEM WINDOWS
FOR I GET ALL CUT UP.
FOR THE RECORD,
YOU WERE WITH
MORGAN'S RAIDERS...
FIRST COMPANY...
FAST WITH A GUN...
NONE FASTER...
A KILLER...
WITH BOTH HANDS...
AND YOU'RE AN AGENT
FOR THE RAILROAD?
UH, THEY KNOW THAT.
MM-HMM.
WELL, THAT'S
FOR COLLINS.
NOW WHAT'S FOR ME?
WELL, NOT MUCH, HONEY.
JUST MARRIED?
A COUPLA WEEKS.
GOOD, EH?
SWELL.
NICE GAL?
THE BEST.
SHE'D HAVE TO
BE, OF COURSE,
OR YOU'D HAVE SENT HER
DOWN FOR THE EGGS.
THESE HENS SEEM TO BE A
LITTLE SLOW ON DELIVERY.
THINK THEY'RE
IN THE MOOD?
THEY'VE NO EXCUSE.
I JUST SHOWED THEM
HOW IT'S DONE.
WELL, I'D LIKE TO TELL YA THAT
I THINK YOU'RE
AN ALL-RIGHT GAL,
BUT YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO
HEAR THAT, WOULD YOU?
MM-MM, NOTHING
SECONDHAND.
AND THIS MAY
NOT BE FINAL...
WHO CAN TELL?
ANYWAY, I'LL CHECK WITH
YA FROM TIME TO TIME.
WELL, IN THE MEANTIME,
DON'T PASS UP ANYTHING
THAT'LL DO JUST AS
WELL, EH, JERSEY?
SEE YA LATER.
COME TO THINK OF IT,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL WAIT.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU'LL
BE GOING ANYPLACE FOR...
A COUPLE OF HOURS.
WHY NOT?
WHY... I THINK...
BENDER'S MEN...
THEY'VE ORDERS NOT TO LET
YOU OUT OF THE HOTEL.
WHY?
WHAT'S UP?
WHY, I THINK...
BENDER AND COLLINS,
THEY'RE AT FARGO ON
THE PRAIRIE
SIGNING A CONTRACT
WITH THE WHEAT GROWERS.
DON'T BE A FOOL.
IT'S NOT ONLY THEM,
THEY'VE GOT 20 MEN.
YOU HAVEN'T GOT
A CHANCE.
YEAH.
I KNOW.
????
??
HAVE YOU SEEN
MR. DEVLIN?
PLEASE, HAVE YOU
SEEN MR. DEVLIN?
(bang)
(bang bang)
HE'S RIDING TO FARGO
ON THE PRAIRIE...
ON BUSINESS, I
THINK HE SAID.
I JUST WANTED TO
SAY, FRIENDS,
I'D LIKE TO THANK MR.
BENDER FOR PUTTIN' MY
NAME UP FOR OFFICE
AND ALL YOU BOYS FOR
GETTIN' IN BACK OF ME.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
I WANT TO WARN YA,
FRIEND AND FOE ALIKE,
AS LONG AS I'M MARSHALL,
THERE'S GONNA BE LAW
AND ORDER IN FARGO.
LOOKS LIKE IMPORTANT
THINGS HAPPENING IN
FARGO, MRS. STOWE.
YES, AND ALL IN
ONE DAY TOO.
OH, MR. DEVLIN,
MEET MR. PLUMMER.
HOW DO YOU DO?
HOW ARE YA?
HOW IS YOUR VERY
CHARMING WIFE?
SHE'S ALL RIGHT,
THANKS.
IS THIS A FREE
EXPRESSION OF THE
WILL OF THE PEOPLE?
EH, A LITTLE FARMER
WHO DIDN'T KNOW VERY
MUCH,
OPENED HIS MOUTH
TO SAY SOMETHING
AND FOUND HE WAS
CHEWING ON COBB'S
KNUCKLES,
AND THE WILL OF THE
PEOPLE CURLED UP LIKE
A SICK MACKEREL.
THEN THE DEAL'S
BEEN MADE.
YES, AND IF OUR
CROPS ARE HARVESTED,
MR. BENDER TAKES
A PROFIT.
IF THEY'RE NOT
HARVESTED, HE TAKES US.
IN OTHER WORDS, WITH
COLLINS AS MARSHALL,
WE'LL BE DRAWN
AND QUARTERED.
WELL, IF YOU
DON'T LIKE IT,
ONE OTHER THING
YOU CAN DO...
PACK UP AND GET OUT.
OR ORGANIZE AN
OPPOSING TEAM.
DEVLIN, I BELIEVE
I HAVE SOME MONEY
OF YOURS.
WOULD YOU
LIKE IT NOW?
NO PLACE TO INVEST IT
AROUND FARGO, IS THERE?
MIGHT OPEN UP A
POPCORN STAND,
THE COMMUNITY'S BOUND
TO GROW WHEN THE
RAILROAD COMES THROUGH.
WHAT RAILROAD?
I SEE YOU MADE
COLLINS MARSHALL.
YEAH, GOOD MAN.
YOU RIDIN' MY WAY?
YEAH.
COME ON.
NOW ABOUT THAT
RAILROAD, I...
ON SECOND THOUGHT, BENDER,
MAYBE YOU BETTER LET ME
HAVE THAT MONEY NOW.
IT'S SAFE AT THE HOTEL.
YOU FOUND A USE FOR IT?
YEAH, I'M PULLIN'
OUT TONIGHT.
CHICAGO?
NOPE, GRAND FORKS.
DAKOTA?
YEAH.
YOU'RE TRYIN' TO RUN A
BLAZER ON ME, DEVLIN,
BUT YOU'RE BETTIN'
AGAINST A BAD HAND.
THINK SO?
YEP.
YOU SEE, I FOLLOWED
THE SURVEYORS UP HERE.
I HAPPEN TO KNOW THE
GOVERNMENT'S GRANTED
THE RIGHT OF WAY
AND PLANS HAVE
ALREADY BEEN DRAWN
FOR THE RAILROAD TO
RUN THROUGH FARGO.
BUT THEY COULD CHANGE
THOSE PLANS, RUN THROUGH
GRAND FORKS.
NOT AFTER THEY'VE
SPENT ALL THAT MONEY
RUNNIN' A SURVEY
THROUGH HERE.
HOW MUCH DO YOU
THINK THAT'D COST?
FIFTY THOUSAND DOLLARS.
AND HOW MUCH
WOULD IT COST
TO BUY THAT CONTRACT YOU
MADE WITH THE FARMERS?
ONE-HALF MILLION DOLLARS,
GOOD AMERICAN GO...
OH.
SEE, IT'D STILL BE
CHEAPER TO RUN
ANOTHER SURVEY
AND BYPASS FARGO.
YEAH, I SUPPOSE
ANYTHING IS POSSIBLE.
LIKE CONSIGNING THAT
CONTRACT YOU HAVE
WITH THE FARMERS
OVER TO ME...
FOR A CONSIDERATION,
OF COURSE?
LET'S GO IN MY OFFICE.
WHY NOT?
THERE YA ARE...
TWENTY THOUSAND ON
ACCOUNT, AND EIGHTY
THOUSAND
WHEN THE RAILROAD
COMES THROUGH.
YOU'RE TAKIN' ME
OVER, DEVLIN.
MAYBE, BUT A SURE
HUNDRED THOUSAND
IS BETTER THAN HALF A
MILLION IN THE BUSH.
WELL, THERE IT IS,
CONSIGNED TO YOU
PERSONALLY, RIGHT?
NATURALLY.
(boat whistle)
HERE SHE COMES...
THE BOAT'S COMIN'!
HERE SHE COMES!
????
??
THERE'S NICODEMUS...
THE HORSES MUST BE READY.
BUT I STILL CAN'T
UNDERSTAND WHY
WE'RE LEAVING.
YOU'VE GOT THE
CONTRACTS.
WE'RE LEAVING
BECAUSE WE GOTTA STAY
AWAY FROM BENDER UNTIL
THE WHEAT'S HARVESTED.
IF HE CAN'T GET HIS
HANDS ON THAT CONTRACT,
HE WON'T BURN THE WHEAT--
IT WON'T DO HIM ANY GOOD.
WHAT IF SOMEONE SEES US
TAKING OUR BAGS OUT?
THEY WON'T.
AFTER BOUNCE ARRANGES
TO HAVE US PICKED UP,
HE'S COMIN' BACK FOR 'EM.
THEN THEY'LL SEE HIM.
LET'S NOT MAKE THE
WORST OF IT UNTIL
WE GET IT, SANDY.
WE'LL GO DOWN AND SEE
THE RIVERBOAT COME IN.
DO YOU THINK WE SHOULD?
WHY NOT?
THEY'RE WATCHING US...
LET'S LET 'EM SEE US.
THEN THEY WON'T THINK
WE'RE UP TO ANY TRICKS.
IF YOU WEREN'T TRYING TO
BE SO FINE AND NOBLE,
WE WOULDN'T BE IN
THIS AWFUL MESS.
SURE... YOU CAN REMEMBER
ME AS A MAN WHO...
GAVE HIS ALL FOR HIS FELLOW MAN.
I REMEMBER YOU AS
A BIG SO-AND-SO,
WHO I'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO LIVE WITHOUT.
WAIT A MINUTE...
TEARS AND EVERYTHING.
WHAT IS THIS, GOOD-BYE?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT...
I JUST DON'T WANT ANYTHING
TO HAPPEN TO US.
LIKE THINGS THE
WAY THEY ARE, EH?
WHERE WOULD I EVER
FIND ANOTHER
HANDSOME, EASY-GOING...
NO-GOOD MAN LIKE ME?
YES.
IN ANY FIRST-CLASS JAIL
WEST OF THE MISSISSIPPI.
HOW'D YOU DO WITH
THEM PESKY SAND BARS?
GET YOURSELF HUNG UP
ON OL' CAMELBACK?!
SURE, I DID, AND I GOT
MYSELF OFF OF'N 'EM,
TOO, BY JUCIFER!
GET ABOARD, 'N
COME UP HERE!
WE HAD AN ESCORT
FROM THE HOTEL.
YEAH, SLAGIN
AND COBB.
LOOKS LIKE BENDER'S
TRAVELING.
HE'S PROBABLY LEAVING
ON THE BOAT, TOO.
THAT'S RIGHT,
CHECK UP ON US.
LET'S FIND OUT.
GOOD EVENING.
DEVLIN... MRS. DEVLIN,
HOW'S THE SHOULDER
THIS EVENING?
BETTER, THANKS.
THAT'S FINE.
NOT GOING AWAY,
ARE YOU?
YES, I AM,
FOR A FEW DAYS.
GRAND FORKS?
NO, CHICAGO.
I MADE A LITTLE DEAL.
I'M GOING TO
CHECK UP ON IT.
JOHN, LOOK!
IT'S MR. GEARY.
GEARY?
FATHER MUST HAVE SENT
HIM HERE TO BUY THE LAND
FOR THE RAILROAD.
SANDRA.
I DID IT AGAIN.
BECAUSE YOU LOVE ME?
YOUR FATHER TOLD ME
THAT YOU SKIPPED OFF
WITH A RASCAL NAMED DEVLIN.
I DIDN'T BELIEVE
IT, OF COURSE...
I MEAN, ABOUT HIS
BEING A RASCAL.
SOMEHOW I COULDN'T
IMAGINE YOU MARRYING
ANYONE
WHO WASN'T MADE OF
BONE AND MUSCLE...
THAT MAKES YOU
DEVLIN, RIGHT?
I CAN'T GET OUT FROM
UNDER IT EITHER.
I'M GEARY, CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU MARRIED A GREAT
LITTLE GIRL.
I'VE KNOWN HER ALL HER LIFE.
BEEN WITH HER FATHER
FOR 25 YEARS.
I SHOULDN'T TALK SO LOUD.
I'M HERE, MORE
OR LESS, INCOGNITO.
SPEAK RIGHT OUT,
MR. GEARY, WE'RE
FRIENDS HERE.
NOTHING YOU SAY'LL EVER
BE USED AGAINST YOU.
I'M JIM BENDER...
THIS IS MR. COLLINS,
OUR MARSHALL.
UH, MR. GEARY, I, UH...
WE WERE JUST GOING
TO THE HOTEL.
YEAH... SEE YA
LATER, BENDER.
I'LL WALK ALONG WITH YOU.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD TO
TALK TO SOMEBODY FROM
THE OUTSIDE.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE A
BIG SECRET, I KNOW,
BUT, UH, WE ALL KNOW
THAT YOU'RE HERE
TO BUY A FEW PIECES OF
LAND FOR THE RAILROAD.
BUT DON'T YOU SAY A WORD
ABOUT IT, UNLESS YOU FEEL
YOU'RE AMONG FRIENDS.
WELL, THE BIGGEST PART
OF MY JOB IS TO
KEEP MY MOUTH CLOSED,
BUT OF COURSE, YOU'RE
PRIVILEGED TO THINK
WHAT YOU PLEASE.
I'M PLEASED TO THINK
THAT YOU JUST SAVED ME
A GOOD PIECE OF MONEY.
BY THE WAY,
MR. DEVLIN...
SLAGIN, YOU AND
COBB GO AFTER HIM.
BRING BACK THAT
CONTRACT.
COLLINS, ROUND UP
WHAT MEN YOU'VE GOT,
AND MEET ME AT THE STORE.
SOMETHING TELLS ME
I TURNED UP AT THE
WRONG MOMENT.
OH, YOU CERTAINLY DID.
GOT EVERYTHING FIXED
UP JUST LIKE YOU
WANTED, MA'AM.
CAP'N SPARKS IS GONNA
SLOW DOWN AND PICK YA UP
RIGHT OFF'N WHERE THE
RIVER BIRDWENT DOWN.
BUT YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST
LIKE HE WAS SAYIN'
WHEN I WAS TELLIN' HIM WHAT'S
GOIN' ON AROUND HERE.
YOU DON'T SUPPOSE
WE'RE CHASIN' AROUND,
DUCKIN' OUR OWN SHADOWS, DO YA?
BUT CAPTAIN, RIGHT NOW BENDER'S
MEN ARE LOOKING FOR MR. DEVLIN,
AND WE'VE GOT TO HELP HIM.
OH, I DON'T THINK THAT
MUCH IS GONNA HAPPEN.
BUT IT WILL... IT IS!
LOOK, CAPTAIN, YOU KNOW
MOST OF THE MEN IN FARGO.
PLEASE LET THEM KNOW WHAT
MR. DEVLIN'S DONE FOR THEM,
AND ASK THEM TO STAND BY.
WELL, I'LL TALK TO SOME OF THE
BOYS AND SEE WHAT THEY SAY,
BUT I DON'T THINK THEY'RE
GONNA BE INTERESTED.
WHAT IF HE DOES MANAGE
TO FIND HELP, WHAT THEN?
OH, MR. GEARY, IF
ANYTHING HAPPENS TO
THAT BIG SO-AND-SO,
I'LL JUST DIE,
THAT'S ALL.
A RIDER GO BY THIS
WAY, PARTNER?
(speaking Italian)
ITALIAN?
CIANO.
(speaking Italian)
HE SEEN ONE LOOKED
JUST LIKE DEVLIN.
MR. PLUMMER?
OH, HELLO, MR. DEVLIN...
HOW ARE YA?
HELLO!
WHAT'D YOU DO
TO YOUR FOOT?
OH, SPRAINED IT, I
GUESS... MAKES IT
KINDA AWKWARD, TOO.
I WANTED TO GO
OVER TO STOWES'.
I'D LIKE TO TALK
TO YA A MINUTE.
WELL, COME INSIDE.
WE'RE HOLDING A MEETING
TO TALK THINGS OVER.
AT THE STOWES'?
YES.
HILDA, THIS IS
MR. DEVLIN.
HOWDY, MR. DEVLIN.
MRS. PLUMMER.
THERE'S A FEW OF
US MIGHT NOT LIKE
THE WAY THE
BENDER/COLLINS FACTION
WILL HANDLE THINGS,
SO WE THOUGHT WE'D GET TOGETHER
AND SORT OF, UH...
COUNT OUR GUNS.
WE HAVEN'T MUCH
TO OFFER IN THE
WAY OF COMFORTS.
WE WERE BURNED OUT.
YEAH, WE HAD TO THROW UP
A SOD HOUSE--
HAD TO HAVE SOME
KIND OF SHELTER.
WELL, BENDER'S A LITTLE
CARELESS WITH MATCHES.
WELL, I'VE GOT SOMETHING
HERE THAT MAY MAKE YOU
FEEL A LITTLE BETTER.
I GOT BENDER TO SIGN
OVER THAT CONTRACT
HE MADE WITH THE FARMERS TO ME.
THE RAILROAD'S
COMING THROUGH HERE,
AND THIS LAND'S
GONNA BE WORTH A
NICE CHUNK OF MONEY.
(Mrs. Plummer)
THIS IS WONDERFUL.
AND IF YOU WANT TO
STAY HERE AND KINDA
LOOK THIS THING OVER,
I'LL GO OVER TO THE
STOWES' AND BRING THE
BOYS BACK HERE.
WELL, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT DO YOU GET
OUT OF THIS?
WELL, WHEN THE
RAILROAD PAYS OFF,
YOU CAN TAKE 20,000 OUT
OF THE KITTY FOR ME.
CALL IT A HOUSE CUT.
????
??
LET'S SEE NOW...
I'LL SAY, "COME ON, BOYS, AND
GIT YOUR GUNS AND COME ALONG.
"THINGS IS GONNA
BUST WIDE OPEN."
THEN THEY'LL SAY TO
ME, "WHAT THINGS?"
WHEN I'M TRYIN' TO THINK
OF THE ANSWER TO THAT ONE,
SOMEONE'LL FETCH ME OVER THE
HEAD WITH A SACK A MEAL,
AND THAT'S WHAT I'LL
GET FOR THROWIN' IN
WITH THIS FOOL KINDA BUSINESS.
I SAID IT BEFORE,
AND I'LL SAY IT NOW...
NOTHIN'S GONNA HAPPEN
TO NOBODIES... NO TIME.
(bang bang)
(whistling)
"TO JOHN DEVLIN,
I, JAMES K. BENDER,
RELINQUISH ALL RIGHTS
AND INTERESTS."
THAT'S IT...
ALL RIGHT, MEN.
YOU AND I'LL GET
THINGS STARTED AND
HEAD BACK TO TOWN.
HUH, DON'T LOOK LIKE THE
PLUMMERS IS TA HOME NEITHER.
WHOA.
MR. PLUMMER!
MR. PLUMMER!!
GUESS I'LL TAKE A LOOK.
MR. PLUMMER!
YOU THERE, MR. PLUMMER?!
NOPE, NOBODY HOME.
LOOKIN' FOR PEOPLE THAT AIN'T
AROUND IS A FOOL BUSINESS.
IF THEY AIN'T AT THE STOWE
PLACE, THEY AIN'T NO PLACE,
AND THAT'S AS FAR AS I'M GOIN'.
GIDDYAP, HORSE.
????
??
(applause)
????
??
???? A NIGHT IN JUNE ??
?? A LOVELY MOON ??
?? BENEATH THE TREES
A BOY A LOVELY MISS ??
?? HE SOFTLY SIGHS ??
?? SHE ROLLS HER EYES ??
?? THEN HE SAYS MY DEAR I'D
LIKE TO STEAL A KISS ??
?? BUT SHE SAYS ??
?? COAX ME GO ON AND COAX ME ??
?? IF YOU LOVE ME MADLY
WANT ME BADLY ??
?? COAX ME GO ON AND COAX ME ??
?? I'LL BE YOUR TOOTSIE-WOOTSIE
IF YOU'LL COAX ME ??
?? COAX ME GO ON AND COAX ME ??
?? IF YOU LOVE ME MADLY
WANT ME BADLY ??
?? COAX ME GO ON AND COAX ME ??
?? I'LL BE YOUR TOOTSIE-WOOTSIE
IF YOU COAX ME ??
?? WHEN YOU WINK YOUR EYE AT ME
IT'S OH SO VERY PLAIN TO SEE ??
?? IT'S SORT OF LIKE
TO BILL AND COO ??
?? AND I CONFESS
I'D LIKE IT TOO ??
?? BUT IT'S HARDLY PROPER
DON'T YOU SEE ??
?? FOR ME TO ACT SO BRAZENLY ??
?? ROME WASN'T BUILT IN A DAY ??
?? SO TAKE A HINT BOY
WHEN I SAY ??
?? COAX ME DON'T EVER HOAX ME ??
?? IF YOU LOVE ME ONLY ??
?? YOU'LL NEVER BE LONELY ??
?? COAX ME GO ON AND COAX ME ??
?? I'LL BE YOUR TOOTSIE-WOOTSIE
IF YOU'LL JUST COAX ME ????
(applause)
OUR FRIEND?
YES, HE'LL SUPPOSE
HE'S HERE TOO.
OH, DO YOU MIND?
THE LADY AND I HAVE SOME
THINGS TO TALK ABOUT.
COULD WE HAVE
THIS TABLE?
AND WHERE AM I GOING
TO SIT, PARTNER?
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
LADY, I WON'T LISTEN.
UH, MY NAME'S SUEDE.
NO... WE CAN TALK
SOME OTHER TIME.
????
??
(Bounce)
IF'N YOU FELLAS HADN'T
CUT THROUGH THE WHEAT,
I'DA MET YA COMIN' BACK
FROM THE STOWE PLACE.
HEY, YOU AIN'T HEADIN'
INTO TROUBLE
MESSIN' AROUND LIKE
THIS, ARE YA?
HOW WOULD YOU
HANDLE IT, CAP'N?
WELL, COLLINS IS THE
MARSHALL HERE, AIN'T HE?
IF SOMEONE DID SHOOT
THE PLUMMERS,
WHY, HE'S THE ONE TO DO
SOMETHIN' ABOUT IT...
I'M SAYIN'IFSOMEBODY
DID SHOOT THE PLUMMERS.
I DON'T GUESS
NOBODY DID.
UNDERSTAND I AIN'T
AGREEIN' THEY WAS
SHOT, MIND YOU?
'CAUSE THE WAY YOU
TOLD IT TA ME,
IT COULDA BEEN ONE OF
THEM SUICIDE DEALS
WHERE ONE PARTY SAYS
TO THE OTHER,
"CLOSE YOUR EYES
FOR A SECOND
AND I'LL SHOOT
YOUR HEAD OFF"...
SOMETHIN' I'M FIGURIN'
ON DOIN' TO MYSELF
AFTER WHILE.
(horses running)
LET'S GET OUTTA HERE.
THAT'S IT. GET THE BOYS,
AND DON'T FORGET THE
WHITE HANDKERCHIEFS.
WELL, I'LL DO IT, BUT
DON'T FORGET WHAT I SAID.
AIN'T NOTHIN' GONNA HAPPEN!
THERE'S JOHN!
GIVE ME THAT
CONTRACT!
(Suede)
I'M LOOKIN' FOR YA, DEVLIN!
(Bang!)
YOU'RE A MIGHT TOO FREE
AND EASY WITH THAT GUN
OF YOURS, DEVLIN.
I'M HOLDIN' YA
FOR MURDER.
I GOT A HUNCH THAT
BADGE IS GONNA GET
YOU IN TROUBLE.
HOW YA GONNA HOLD HIM, COLLINS?
THERE AIN'T NO JAIL IN FARGO.
WHAT'S IT TO YA, FRIEND?
I'M THE LAW AROUND HERE, AND
I'LL BE RESPONSIBLE FOR 'IM.
THERE'S BEEN A KILLIN' DONE,
FOLKS, AND THERE'S NO
COURT OF LAW HERE!
WHO'S GONNA TRY HIM...
HOW'S HE GONNA GET
WHAT'S COMIN' TO HIM?
THERE'S A WAY OF TAKIN'
CARE OF KILLERS HERE,
AIN'T THERE, FOLKS?
- COME ON!
- JUST A MINUTE, FELLAS!
THE MAN'S ENTITLED TO A
FAIR TRIAL AROUND HERE!
GET BACK.
(farmer)
THE WHEAT FIELDS ARE BURNIN'!
THE WHOLE COUNTRY'S ABLAZE!
THE WHEAT FIELDS ARE ON FIRE!
COME ON, LET'S GET OUT THERE!
WE'LL NEED ALL
THE HELP WE CAN GET!
(sound of running horses)
(bang bang bang)
BENDER, YOU KILLED
MR. GEARY.
I SAW YOU DO IT.
DON'T LET IT WORRY
YOU, MRS. DEVLIN.
THE GENTLEMEN ON
HORSEBACK ARE NOT
MYFRIENDS.
YOUR HUSBAND'S A...
VERY LUCKY FELLOW.
HEY!
WHAT'S GOIN' ON HERE?!
(bang bang)
HEY!
HANG ON TO 'IM.
FINISH HIM OFF.
(bang bang)
(bang)
-HEY!
- OH, THERE YA ARE.
BETTER BE GETTIN'
BACK TA THE BOAT,
HEY, MR. DEVLIN?
HEYAH!
WHEAT BURNIN', FELLAS
SHOOTIN' AT EACH OTHER--
FARGO AIN'T WHAT
SHE USED TO BE!
NOT GOIN' LOOKIN' FOR
ME, ARE YA, BENDER?
I... I WAS JUST
COMIN' AFTER YA.
I'M GLAD YA STOPPED IN.
I MIGHT A HAD
TROUBLE FINDIN' YA.
YEAH, I FIGURED YOU
WOULD, SO I COME OVER.
I KNOW'D YOU WOULDN'T
WANT TO LEAVE ME BEHIND,
AND SKIN OFF WITH THAT 20,000.
WELL, WE CAN, UH, SPLIT
IT UP NOW, IF YOU LIKE.
YOUR POCKET'S ON THE OTHER
SIDE, AIN'T IT, BENDER?
(bang)
(click)
THERE'S HIS HORSE!
YEHA!
(Sandy)
JOHN!
WELL, THERE IT IS.
COUNT IT.
AND IF IT ISN'T
ALL THERE,
YOU'LL HAVE TO
COLLECT THE REST
OF IT YOURSELF.
STAND BY AFORE AND AFT!
SHE'S READY TO CAST OFF!
GET ON THAT SPRING
LINE OVER THERE!
I HOPE THEY GET THE
SUITCASES ABOARD,
BUT BAGS OR NO BAGS, WE'RE
HEADIN' FOR CALIFORNIA.
YOU KNOW, JOHN, THAT
RAILROAD MONEY
ISN'T GOING TO HELP
EVERYONE THAT WAS
BURNT OUT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEY OUGHTA FORM
SOME KIND OF A POOL
AND FIX IT SO
EVERYBODY'D HAVE ENOUGH
TILL THE NEXT HARVEST.
THAT'S WONDERFUL...
WHY DON'T YOU DO IT?
WE'RE GOIN' TO
CALIFORNIA.
BUT YOU'RE A HERO NOW.
WE COULD GO INTO ANY
BUSINESS WE LIKE.
MAYBE, UM, RIVERBOAT.
YEAH?
WITH A RAILROAD
COMIN' THROUGH?
BUT IT WILL BE ALMOST
A YEAR BEFORE IT'S
FINISHED,
AND IN THE MEANTIME,
WE COULD HANDLE ALL
THE SHIPPING.
CUT IT OUT, SANDY, BEFORE
YOU HAVE ME IN TEARS.
I DID IT BECAUSE
I LOVE YOU, THAT'S
WHY I DID IT.
WHAT?
(Bounce)
ORDER IN THE GANGPLANK!
BOUNCE!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOIN' THERE?!
SURE GOOD TO FEEL A SHIP
UNDER MY FEET AGAIN!
MUCH OBLIGED TO YA, MR. DEVLIN!
MUCH OBLIGED?
WHAT FOR?
I BOUGHT THEBELL
OF THE NORTHWEST...
YOU WHAT!?
AND PUT CAPTAIN
BOUNCE IN CHARGE.
(boat whistle)
Captioning provided by
Paramount Domestic Television.
Captions by Closed
Captioning Services, Inc.