After the epidemic,
the world has fallen,
While the dead rose.
There was no power,
nor food, nor water.
Humankind turned to
a simple way of life.
At that moment,
Kept the dead obeying.
But after the Apocalypse,
A new threat arose.
Apocalypta.
She gave people a choice,
Whether they want it or not.
Becoming cattle
For the horde of the dead,
Or become a warriors,
and fight against
The growing darkness.
It will cost the little spirit
Of struggle that we have
If it's like this
What do you want to call it.
The time is now!
These people
They died
and revived.
Heaps of junks.
Desert Springs ...
They will be mine!
Johnny and Stamper
Are preparing the army.
They got them
in a hunger frenzy.
Don't be afraid.
Do you want to go home?
I'll send you home.
Look at me!
Now you are
My loyal undead.
Your flesh
now belongs to me.
CHAPTER I
THE ATTACK A HARPER'S JUNCTION
They say that there is rest
In death.
But in our world,
This is no longer true.
Keep walking, Stamper.
Move your slaves!
You have places to go,
People to eat.
HARPER'S JUNCTION
16KM EAST
How are you?
How are you, Gregory?
Good morning, Sheriff!
Excuse me, girls.
Copper Heads
They're destroying the gate!
Run! Apocalypta dropped
The copper heads!
- Copper heads coming!
- My God!
They are coming!
Jared!
Dad!
Come on, son!
Come on! Come and get it,
Copper heads!
Apocalypta thanks
For joining the team.
Go, go!
Get out of here!
Go, go, go!
That's right, this way.
I think not.
Not today.
Fuck, where's my gun?
Shoot, shit!
Gun motherfucker!
Need some help, my love?
Hey, baby
What the fuck?
I'm right behind you.
A..a-a, Blondie!
Take it easy.
What do you want, freak?
Apocalypta will conquer
Any city you want.
You and your boyfriend can
Join us, or stay away.
I'll take you
to the Sheriff.
I think we eat him.
Gag it.
It's going to be a long ride.
DESERT SPRINGS
35KM TO NORTH
POLICE STATION
OF DESERT SPRINGS
Good evening, Mayor Shelby,
Apocalypta sends his regards.
Will never conquer
my city.
She took my eye,
but she's got your balls.
And think, you needed a face.
From Harper's Junction
To finally bring in
Apocalypta the best man.
Johnny Vermillion,
It's been a long time.
Harper's Junction
Was just the beginning,
Desert Springs is next.
In fact, what you were looking for
In Harper's Junction?
We wanted their food,
Its water,
Your livelihood,
And your bodies.
It has never been so easy.
To gather an army.
You disgusting bastard.
In fact,
I prefer...
Sociopath with complications.
"We have plans for your city."
- What plans?
The fences will fall,
The electricity will fail.
They can not overtake the dead,
Nor escape from destiny.
Good luck in trying to keep
Your people alive, Mr. Mayor.
They will not last long.
Cowardly, people
Will not tolerate this.
I can stay,
Or is it asking too much?
Make sure he
hanged at sunrise.
Sunrise?
I do prefer the mornings.
Stamper said
That they got him.
They got Johnny.
At where?
Desert Springs,
With the good old
Mayor Shelby and Sheriff Cooper.
Stamper,
Bring Johnny back!
They take from me,
I take from them!
Go!
You definitely got some
Heads-copper, Stamper.
But we have one more job
Before leaving the city.
There he is.
Wait a second.
Hello boy.
What is your name?
Georgie.
Your mother or father.
Are they around?
Sheriff Cooper
Take care of you, right?
I was an orphan myself.
Before my father was
A copper head,
Do you know what he was?
He was a doctor.
Trying to find the cure.
Even if they are
scary,
they are equal
To you and me.
I can help you
To see their parents again.
Apocalypta will attack soon,
And I'm afraid we're not ready.
Look at them, we can not
Accept more refugees,
We barely survive like this!
How did that clown escape?
Damn it!
How did you let that happen?
You find him
And you eviscerate him!
It should already be halfway
From the mountain now.
Then go there,
Do what you need
Find our best
And crazier men,
Take them there and kill him.
Kill the Vermillion
And kill Apocalypta.
Kill until everyone there
Are dead.
And I mean the type of death
Of which there is no turning back.
CHAPTER II
THE MAGNIFICENT DEAD 7
What do you got?
Shit!
You know what I was thinking.
Right now?
I thought the drunker you get,
the better you get.
- I think he cheated.
- Really?
Cheating? Me?
Cheating?
I'll break your heart,
Walsh.
Look at this.
Look at these beautiful
White teeth.
They are not teeth
Of copper head.
I will not be able to sell them.
Never.
There's a game I want to see.
If you're good too.
It's to know
If you're going to leave here alive.
Come on, hickey!
I have to go.
I'm drunk.
I saw what you did in there.
Impressive.
You're Whiskey Joe, right?
Yup.
The one and only.
Are you interested in a job,
Whiskey Joe?
I am putting together
A group of men.
Let's go up the mountain
And defeat Apocalypta
once and for all.
It seems like a suicide mission.
for me.
Of course.
It can be true,
But the attacks will not stop.
They will continue,
Like it or not.
The humanity.
We are an endangered race.
But we can choose
How it will end.
Or it's our way.
Or her way.
What will be your choice,
Whiskey Joe?
"How many men do you need?"
"How many, I suppose."
I have a friend.
If it were legal
Sign marriage certificate
With an rifle,
He would have signed.
Let's get him.
Good...
You are so good
As I remembered.
We got a mission.
Got a job?
On the top of the mountain.
No one comes back from there.
Nobody shoots like the Vacaro .
Cowboy.
Apocalypta.
She is here.
It is everywhere.
It's time to end it.
I know of someone else
That we need to recruit.
We call this guy
Of "The Komodo".
- Because?
- You will see.
Just relax, Doctor.
Do not do anything and everything is fine.
He's like a vigilante ninja.
Swords, flying stars ...
Help who can not
If it helps.
Shoot him!
- Komodo.
- Cowboy.
Whiskey.
Oops.
I have a question.
Why waste time
With those boring idiots?
I pay for my anguish
With medication.
We need your help.
Suarez!
It is!
This is my boy!
How much to send someone?
There are 3 teeth to send a letter
To one of the city-ships.
Anywhere else ...
There is no other place.
No, I want to find someone.
Out there.
How much
To send a hunter?
There are 50 teeth.
Advanced.
I do not have 50 teeth.
How rich!
I have a wife who would like
Of this brilliant little thing.
Who are you looking for?
An old friend.
Thank you very much.
What's the problem?
Why do you want to find
my brother?
He knows that Jack
Only thinks of itself.
He is the best.
Well, second best.
My love, go back to bed.
Where's your ring?
I have a letter to Jack.
Who are you?
I'm just the postman, sir!
What you want?
I have a message,
If you want to receive.
She said she'd be here.
Put it on the floor!
Now, send it.
Have a good day, sir!
I'm going.
Jack, I'm writing
Because I know Billy will not.
Apocalypta destroyed
Harbor's Junction fully
and soon will come
To Desert Springs.
If we are going to stop it,
We need you.
Please, let's leave
The past aside.
Daisy Jane.
CHAPTER III
ATTACK PLAN
POST OF QUARANTINE
Big door of the club.
- We're the whole team?
- I do not know!
Pardon me, Mam.
Sorry, how yo doing?
These are lovely ...
All right, it was bad.
I deserved it.
Go shower.
She likes me.
If you are here to meet
Cooper, come on then.
I brought you
Because they are the best.
Only this can defeat Apocalypta
And Vermillion,
the bizarre
Her right arm.
As you know, he ran away.
From prison a few days ago
And now he has returned to the mountains.
Now,
let's get down to business.
We're tracking Vermillion
for a while.
There is a complex in the mountains
Where it is likely to be.
The problem is getting there.
However, there is a blind spot.
few know
Get out of the valley alive.
So, any of you
Have you ever been there?
I know somebody.
It's ok.
I had him picked up.
He can help.
Very well,
You fucking cowards.
Too much looseness
To join us.
Get out of my way.
This bar is now
Government property.
Let's go then.
No love.
Sit down.
Okay, okay.
You are part of the team.
This is a public place,
Coop.
I do not have to do
what's up.
It should protect us,
Sheriff.
I'll protect you, Jay.
And if you're staying ...
Will have to fight
Like the rest of us.
I will not become
A copper head.
Chupões.
All right, everybody.
Looks like your friend is not coming.
So you are
the last hope
To protect Desert Springs.
We'll leave at dawn.
I have to check
My foster son, Georgie.
Have fun.
Hello!
He left the door open.
You have to be more careful.
I have to clear my mind.
What's your best?
Other than water!
This bottle of Whiskey here
Is over 50 years old.
I've saved it.
I imagine it has the taste
Of the best times.
Like, before the epidemic.
It can do.
How much?
More than you can afford.
That's nice.
Because I will not pay.
Ms.
We still need a way
To walk the mountain.
We need a guide.
The only one worthwhile
that I know
It's the Siren.
- Who?
"A warrior priestess."
She knows the terrain.
Better than anyone.
Known for killing
More copper heads than I do.
You look like my kind of woman.
Either way, it does not matter.
For you can not find it.
She finds you.
I said Jack would not come.
Do not shot.
Do not be like this, my love.
Should know
That he would disappoint you.
Should not even have
If bothered.
Do you really carry
All this hate?
I hate that he never
was present.
I hate
That he is suffering.
And I hate giving up on him.
Cooper?
Back!
Come on, Billy, we gotta get in.
Now!
- Folks...
- He is dead!
- Who?
- Cooper.
He's a copperhead.
There's a lot of them out there.
Here we go!
Who is it?
What happens?
Come on.
I'm coming.
Look after the rear!
Right, right.
I'm ready!
Just a little more.
I think he really wanted to
Back to the bar, right?
They are still coming in!
Billy! I can not
Get him off me!
Jack!
I got the message.
I did not think it would come.
I'm happy to help.
Sorry to do that.
With you, my love.
Jack?
It took a lot.
Hey guys!
Look at this!
Well, that was fun.
Then Cooper died,
So what's the rest of the deal?
If you finish this mission,
I'll give you any crap
That you want.
Cooper had a plan.
I think we should
Continue with it.
Wait a minute.
What about him?
He should know
How to survive outside.
Hey, Jack.
What do you think?
Everybody needs to die
someday.
I may not come back alive.
I do not believe that.
Great. Because I was
Wanting a kiss of sorrow.
I think I have to go.
I have to save the day.
Nothing important.
All right, hero.
When you're done saving us,
find me.
Just tell me where.
I have a friend
On the outskirts of the city,
Told me to look for her
If he needed work.
What kind of job?
I do not know.
And work.
They must have food
And groceries there,
So if you are
On those sides,
show up.
- Let's get his teeth.
- Disgusting!
I prefer the good old gold.
The more teeth they have,
The more valuable you are.
Those willing to face them
And not running, are rare.
I should make a necklace.
Of copper-headed teeth.
You should.
"You're fucking good."
- Do not forget it.
- See you soon.
- Certainly.
CHAPTER IV
A FULL MINE OF ZUMBIS
Where are we going?
For the mines,
Has supplies there.
- How did you get into this?
- We volunteered.
Someone needs
An end to it.
"What's going on between you and Billy?"
- It's a long story.
And Jack?
Longer still.
Sorry, buddy.
Let's go.
Vacaro, show the route.
There will be much more,
Just continue
Do not.
Let's go around.
We spend a lot of ammunition
last night.
There's a small area here.
Are you sure?
By the way, it looks like here
He's been dead for a long time.
A friend said that he had
A stock here.
Is that right, Jack?
Who is your friend?
We entered, we separated
To cover the terrain
And we were within reach
Of the walkie-talkie.
Not so well.
So hidden.
Not the copperheads.
Split up?
You are all
Crescidinhos.
Listen.
If it gets ugly inside,
It's yours on the straight.
Give me your ...
- My bad.
- Face!
What the fuck, man.
Hey, how are things there?
This is dead!
I do not know,
I plan to follow the leader.
There's nothing here, Jack.
Keep looking.
Right,
So there are no guns here.
But there's a lot
Of dead copper heads.
Staff, there are several
Copper heads cut here.
Very dead!
Keep your eyes open.
Watch out!
Did you hear that noise?
Fuck,
Son of your mother!
- Out?
- Yes.
That was a great idea, Jack!
Jack!
Not here.
Go!
Damn it!
You like this, huh?
Want more?
No head-covers here!
How beautiful!
It works very well!
Thanks, honey.
Have you been bitten?
What the hell?
Would be welcome
A little help here, guys!
No, you can,
Vacaro.
Damn it!
- Thanks!
- He is good.
"What happened to you?"
- I made a new friend, come on.
Where are the others?
- Let's get together.
"Shall we abandon them?"
we will send
Our location.
Stamper called,
Said they broke up.
It's going to be easy
Get them now.
Anyway, we are on our way
Of Desert Springs.
Stamper finished
To map the mines.
We can use it
To come back from the attack
And the heroes will be trapped
On the mountain or die.
Who is he?
This is a volunteer.
He thinks he has
What it takes.
I heard you are looking for
good guys.
Do not let them come
In living Desert Springs.
Weak!
"I'll put it with the others."
- Do it.
Now go.
CHAPTER V
TRAVEL TO APOCALYPTA
I will try again.
Billy, Daisy,
Are you listening?
Joe, Komodo,
Nothing yet.
They are not listening,
I can not get anything.
We have to continue.
What the fuck is that?
An old trap.
Keep going.
Let's go.
It does not look like we're going
Meet them so soon.
We need to evaluate
the situation.
All right, hold on.
I will try again.
Guys, are you there?
Billy? Daisy?
Folks,
I think we should go back.
We should go look for them,
do not you think?
No, let's move on.
It's easier.
You will find us,
Do not worry.
- Stupid.
- Hey, guys?
What did you say?
Listen, we're Americans,
We speak English, right?
- Stupid.
"Why do you need to talk like that?"
- I do not know, I do not know why.
- "Put what?"
- Why you?
- I know why, I know.
-  You're crazy .
- I'm not crazy.
Do you speak Spanish now?
Beauty!
I loved this.
What a beauty!
Strange drink.
Did you like it?
The lady of the mountain.
The signs tell us
To go that way.
Come on, Koporo.
Or whatever!
Hey, where are you going?
BAIT
Hey, boy.
What the fuck?
Thank you.
You should be more careful.
They will smell it.
We must continue.
So what we do here,
after all?
Is called
Of Heavenly Burial.
I'll leave it here for the crows.
And vultures feed themselves.
Then he will come back
To the circle.
The copper heads
They are just hungry creatures.
Wolves, lions, humans,
Everyone wants food.
They can be
Understood.
That thing up there on the mountain,
She understands.
If you have any chance
To defeat her,
Will need help.
What is it?
See this? The meat was food
Usually, but look at the bone.
It was cut
To pieces first.
Pets
Are different from the wild.
This one was fed.
What does that mean?
It means that we are
getting closer.
Look at me!
Calm ...
Eat, copperhead.
You tried to kill me!
No...
I arrested him!
And I killed him!
Eat, copperhead!
Great, now what?
Is here.
It's a difficult climb from here.
I suggest you rest.
We leave at dawn.
You should drink this.
It will make you strong.
These celestial burials,
Did someone teach you this?
My grandmother.
She survived the war.
She teached me
Such as tracking,
how to survive.
She taught you
To do it alone?
She met my grandfather.
Before the epidemic.
He was a miner.
So, it all started here?
In these mines?
She said that men
They went home,
With copper dust
In helmets.
Copper heads.
They called themselves that way.
Well before.
He turned first.
Then his team.
She had to kill him herself.
Yes, she taught me.
To do it alone.
Chord.
Time to go.
Obey to me,
Copperhead!
Obey me,
Copper head.
copper head.
Calm down!
They must be fed
To fight!
Do not fear.
Do not be afraid.
They prefer raw meat.
Fix the fence!
Unless you want to
Be next.
Trixie.
Guys, Trixie said
Who would come this way.
I promised that if I came here,
Would pass by there.
There is food, water,
Supplies. Even ammunition.
Come on.
Look at those socks.
Do we die?
We must have died.
I smell it.
It's a brothel!
"It must be where she is.
- What does that mean?
"It's no secret."
"Come on, shall we?"
This should be
The army of Apocalypta.
It seems so.
Let's eliminate them.
What are we waiting for?
We have no ammunition.
Sufficient for all.
Do not kill a dragon
Cutting their claws.
You cut off the head.
The way to the top
It is just after these rocks.
Let's go up the mountain
And get rid of the psychopath witch.
Step where I step.
There are many pitfalls here.
Copper heads.
There will be copper heads.
- What's your business?
- We ...
Sales, ma'am. Panties!
We sell panties!
They want to enter,
Right, boys?
How much will it cost?
We have a lot here.
- That's mine!
- Do not worry.
So?
Can we come in now?
"I still do not trust her.
"But Jack does.
As far as I know, she may want
Deliver us to Apocalypta.
This is a great plan.
It will transform some gunmen
In copper heads?
They'll never get us.
Let's go.
Go to sleep.
CHAPTER VI
THE TRAP
We will see
If Trixie is here,
pick up supplies
And get out of here fast.
I think we should
Go after the others.
Dude, relax.
Let's meet
with them.
But let's do
A short pause.
Which is!
Listen, you know what?
Let's vote, right?
When you count to three.
1, 2 ...
3!
- Gentlemen.
-  Let's go.
Whiskey Joe, why do not you come up?
I want you to meet somebody.
I'll see if Trixie is here.
Hello sir
Hello Miss!
Mamma has
What you need, my love.
Ammunition, Water, Food ...
And, of course, girls.
Do you like her.
I can make it happen.
But first, if the gentlemen
Want supplies, then ...
Go down the stairs with me,
love.
Why would you have two?
Two?
Ah, two!
I'm ambidextrous.
In fact,
This is my whiskey
And this one here has blood.
That's naughty.
- I like shit.
- I can catch?
Wait there, lass!
Do not pull this here.
Simple to turn around
A copper head,
I'll smell blood,
I'll open and drink.
And when to pull this here ...
CABUM!
Whiskey Joe Pieces
Everywhere, you know?
I know where I want
A piece of Whiskey Joe.
You know, do not you?
So, let's go inside.
Just a few more minutes.
A few more minutes ...
She's fast!
Door number two,
It's our lucky day!
Hey!
You are welcome.
- Are you coming in?
- Thank you.
But I paid the bill.
for two.
Get your money, my love.
Love?
Trixie?
This one!
What supplies
we are talking?
Almost there.
Keep going down, love.
Get in there!
Billy!
God, Billy.
Answer!
You need to stay calm.
And talk low.
Billy, are you listening?
Joe, Vaquero,
any!
We are almost at the top.
Already arrived?
Are you listening?
Exchange!
Holy shit!
It's a trap!
Guys, can you talk downstairs?
- We have to get out of here!
- Whiskey Joe is enjoying it!
They work for Apocalypta!
- What?
- Shit!
Bitch
Honey I got to go!
I swear I did not know
What was she doing.
Young girls,
Do not let them escape!
They're worth the price!
Face!
Here we go!
Let's go!
Vacaro!
Come on, Vacaro!
You can face it!
Let's go!
Faster, partner!
Whiskey!
Oh no!
Oh man, Vacaro .
Come on, man! really?
Cowboy!
Of all people,
Did not have another?
EVAN MEYER, 13 YEARS.
TAKEN VERY YOUNG.
I've never seen her so closely.
Few have seen.
This place
Seems to be abandoned.
Where's Apocalypta?
And the rest of her men?
They live in the mines.
We have to find
an entry.
Let's find my brother.
Jack!
Down here.
It seems we found
Our entrance.
- Daisy.
- Billy.
Love.
Daisy!
Release it!
No!
Let her go, Johnny!
I have a surprise
for you guys.
I think the last time
Did not work right.
Hold on, my love.
If you hurt her ...
Tell Apocalypta
I'm cleaning here.
Go ahead,
We can start now.
Johnny is with them.
It's time.
Yes.
Now you're done!
Join your brothers
And his sisters,
And destroy Desert Springs,
by me!
You made a deal
With the Devil, boy.
She will be a great specimen
Of my army!
- No!
- Daisy!
No!
No! Daisy!
Billy!
No!
It's all right.
Let's take
That son of a bitch.
I'm sorry.
Quickly.
Through these doors.
I am behind you ...
Jack!
-720
Thank you.
The son of a bitch has guided us
Even his trap.
Will not laugh when I get you,
You son of a bitch.
Keep running.
That should hold them
for a while.
It should give us an advantage.
Any idea?
At least
We went down the mountain.
From here,
Is to guess where it went.
It looks like it's coming ...
from here.
This way.
Quickly!
Great shortcut.
It's not exactly
Desert Springs.
Follow me.
Sorry
For not having anticipated it.
Apocalypta
Rebuilt the mines
And it's midway
Of Desert Springs.
And does it matter?
Billy, we still have
A job to do.
I do not care.
She would want
That it should continue.
There is nothing
So it's worth continuing.
Will decide for everyone
down there?
That's what you did.
Do not make the same mistake.
Which I have committed.
I messed up.
I messed up a lot.
But I will not commit
The same error twice.
Because you will come with me.
We will go through this together.
Are you understanding me?
You know...
Come here.
- That was good!
- How beautiful.
Yeah, I know.
Let's get everyone.
Almost finished.
Here it is!
- That!
This is great.
Chapel of Desert Springs.
We arrived.
The copper heads are
Returning to Desert Springs.
It may be there that Jack
And the others are.
Well, let's go there and kill
Copper heads.
CHAPTER VII
ATTACK ON DESERT SPRINGS
Not my city.
Who has the balls?
From whom now?
Die.
Come on, girls!
Move it! Come on!
People, are you listening?
Guys, can you hear me?
What is your situation?
We're still alive!
-  Your help would be welcome!
- Understand.
Joe, we have to go!
Pull the zipper off.
And where the hell is Jack?
Billy. Billy!
She knew she liked it hard.
- I can play hard.
- My kind of bitch.
I do not have time for this.
Siren, be careful!
Billy!
Billy is down.
Attract them to the center.
Leave it to me, buddy!
Come on,
Damn copper heads,
It's dinner time! That's right!
Come and get it!
Overjoyed!
It is the same as barbecue,
But even better!
Come and get it!
Billy! Billy!
Not this one!
No, no, no.
- We have to stop.
- It will work.
- We have to finish ...
"No, no, relax.
Should not
Have given up on you.
Billy, you have to promise.
You have to take care of yourself now.
Billy.
Billy, wake up.
Billy!
Wake up, Billy!
Vermillion is mine.
I love you, Billy.
Quick, they're still coming.
Come on, copperheads!
It's time to dance!
Come here.
Come and get it.
That.
That's right.
Komodo, answer, man!
Use your swords,
Where are the blades?
Come here now,
Because there are a lot of them coming!
I caught you, you bastard!
- It's not a good idea.
- Stay behind me.
- Where is it?
-  Moving them away from the city.
I will try to get there
As fast as you can.
Crazy whore!
They are everywhere!
And I'm running out of whiskey.
You screwed up, did not you?
Damn it.
Komodo!
Whiskey, where are you?
Love!
Trixie Trixie.
Trixie.
I Love You Love.
I love you.
Everything I've Known
It was death.
Everything I've seen.
As the Sirene tells,
Was how it ended.
There can be no beginning.
With Apocalypta dead,
humanity has
The chance to start over.
And a chance to rest.
To finally rest ...
in death.
SurgerySquad Subs