Watch out. That gang's around here.
With what we've got
in the cart, 200,000 dollars,
we'd better keep our eyes open.
- Here, this will warm you up.
- Great. We can use it.
- I'm going back. You stay on guard.
- Don't worry.
- He goes to his warm house while we...
- Shut up.
- I wish it was tomorrow already.
- Let's have a drink.
- Did you hear anything?
- Yeah, you gurgling down that bottle.
I heard it. Let's go take a look.
Jack? Pat?
No!
John? John!
That's all. Let's go.
Well, let's get going.
Yah! Yah!
15 years, ain't nobody seen you laugh.
I understand.
Ain't no laughing matter to be in jail.
But you can laugh today
because today is a big day for you.
But you go out of here with that face,
you're gonna be right back again.
Come in.
Come in, Ryan.
It doesn't seem
so many years have gone by.
At least, not for you.
It seems only yesterday
that we met for the first time.
Here's the 83 dollars
you had in your pocket 15 years ago.
Yeah. I hope it helps you get started again.
My gun.
Thank you.
- Now the bullets.
- The bullets?
27.
15 years ago, you put 'em
in one of those bottom drawers.
27.
You have a good memory.
Well, sometimes it's not difficult.
I still had 6 in my gun and 21 in my belt.
If they hadn't double-crossed me,
the count would be a little bit different.
Here. Beautiful horse, isn't he?
Take it from me, he's worth the 60 dollars.
Hey! Come back here! Hey!
What can I do for you?
I haven't been around here in quite a while.
Everything's changed.
Your parents?
That was my entire family.
I'm sorry.
I heard about it some time ago.
Ah. Hi, Bill.
I'm glad you're in town.
I wanted to speak with you.
I've just been talking to the judge.
How would you like to be deputy sheriff?
The job doesn't pay much,
but I'm gonna retire before long
and you'll move up a step.
It's time you settled down. I've noticed
something between you and Betsy.
I've got other things on my mind, Sheriff,
for the time being.
Bill, no one knows you better than me.
I was a good friend
of your mother and father.
I know what's on your mind,
but don't you think it's time to forget it?
Thanks anyway, Sheriff.
Over here.
What's going on?
Who's doing that shooting? Open up!
Come on in.
- What's going on? Night target practice?
- Oh!
Somebody tries to shoot me in the back,
I defend myself.
You defend yourself almost too well, mister.
They're both dead as doornails.
They came in the window.
It wasn't to wish me pleasant dreams.
OK, OK, self-defence, I guess.
But in this town we don't like violence.
I'm asking you to get out of town
as quickly as possible.
Good morning, Bill.
How many glasses have you got?
- A couple.
- Can we dirty them?
I want to have a little talk with you.
What brings you all the way out here?
What's on your mind?
This.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- That my memory is pretty good.
I've thought all night about whether
what I'm about to do is the right thing.
But I've known you
for too many years to keep quiet.
Where'd you find them?
On a dead man's feet.
Who?
Last night, two men were killed.
Those were on one of them.
- Who killed them?
- A stranger.
A certain Ryan. He went west.
All right, stand up. Don't turn around.
Keep your hand away from your gun.
If you're gonna follow somebody,
do a better job of it.
This world is full of nervous characters.
They shoot you in the back first
and then introduce themselves.
Tell me what you're after.
15 years, there's been no new track.
Only a spur.
Then you come along
and there's three spurs.
If you know the story, then you can
figure out what I'm looking for.
We've both got an account
to settle with the same people.
- Only I want to take first crack at them.
- We can go on together.
No, son, you got too much hate in you.
That's gonna get you in trouble.
Hate's hate. There's no two ways.
Somebody once wrote that revenge
is a dish that has to be eaten cold.
Hot as you are,
you're liable to end up with indigestion.
No, I'm going on alone.
- You better shoot me.
- Do I have to?
If you don't, I'm gonna end up
on your heels again.
Yeah, I suppose so.
Important thing is to get there first.
That's why I'm gonna leave your horse
at Red Rock, ten miles from here.
An advantage you're gonna
have to give me. Good luck, son.
You might need that.
Whiskey and water.
Where do I find Cavanaugh?
Another drink?
I'm looking for Burt Cavanaugh.
Look, friend...
...I'm selling whiskey.
Thanks for the information.
Hold it. What do you want up here?
Ryan.
Well, this certainly is a surprise.
Was it a good surprise or a bad surprise?
Why? Did you think
I wasn't happy to see you?
How much did you give those two
to get rid of me?
I don't understand.
It doesn't make much difference. Whatever
you paid, it was a bad investment.
I should kill you.
Or maybe I have learned something
after all these years.
As an example, even a rat like you
can be worth more alive than dead.
I know it was not a nice trick
walking out on you at the trial, but...
No, no, no.
You didn't walk out on me, you sold me.
You turned me in. There's a big difference.
It was a long time ago.
Why don't we drop it?
Here. Here's 100 dollars.
I know it's not much,
but business hasn't been good lately.
- 100 dollars?
- Yes.
100 dollars for 15 years in jail?
Maybe I was right in the beginning.
- Maybe a rat like you is better dead.
- All right, don't get excited, Ryan.
- What do you want?
- 15,000.
- What?
- 1,000 for every year in jail. Cash.
Where am I going to get my hands
on that kind of money?
Oh, you'll find it.
I'm sure you'll find it.
I'm not in a hurry.
Tomorrow morning will be all right.
It warms my heart
to see all my old friends doing so well.
You're all pretty well established,
aren't you?
I'm gonna visit our friend in Lyndon City.
See what the first citizen
has to say for himself.
Till tomorrow. Oh...
Watch out for these things.
Wouldn't want you to get hurt.
Not yet.
- Bad luck at the table, friend?
- Not bad luck, mister.
It was robbery.
They took everything I had.
You look like you need a drink.
You don't understand.
That was just a warning.
They got all my money,
but I wanna keep my skin.
Sure you do. Who said anything different?
- I can't go back in there.
- Come on.
No. I don't want to. No, no, no.
I don't wanna get killed.
Listen, they'll kill me. Do you hear?
Two whiskeys.
- How much did you lose?
- 30 dollars.
What are you doing? Are you joking?
Drink.
Thanks.
Well, take the dough. And beat it.
I never leave without finishing my drink.
That should take care of it.
Stranger, I'm putting you under arrest,
charged with attempted homicide.
Means you can be put in prison
for ten years.
- When can we try this man, Judge?
- Tomorrow.
Take him to jail.
I'm sorry it turned out this way.
Hold it!
If I'm worth anything as a witness,
I'd say this is a case of self-defence.
More than anything I've seen in my life.
Based on the personality of the witness,
the charge is withdrawn. Cards.
You were lucky. Get out of here now.
I want to talk with our friend here.
Young man, you're a faster draw
than all those stupid idiots.
If you're looking for a job, I may
be able to help. Come up to my office.
Hands behind your head, son.
Now let that hammer down. Slow.
At ease.
You still got a lot to learn, son.
This time you got something to learn, too.
Oh?
What?
Cavanaugh's paying me 500 dollars
to kill you.
- Another bad investment.
- You think so?
- Maybe I didn't take him seriously.
- If you didn't, you'd have been right.
But tell me, why does he want you killed?
And who is Cavanaugh?
You ask too many questions.
I can pay for the information with his 500.
He's worth more than that to me. 15,000.
So I suggest you keep your distance.
'Cause if you don't,
I might get mad.
That's a warning.
I'll find out who he is.
And if he's who I think he is...
...get ready to get mad.
Hey! Hey, wait a second.
Wait. I wanna thank you. Yes, sir.
I ain't worth much and it's been a real spell
since anybody's done anything for me.
But if you asked me to walk on fire,
I'd just started walking.
I might ask you a lot less.
Like what you know about Burt Cavanaugh.
- How long's he lived here?
- When I got here, he was already boss.
But if you want to know more about him,
I know the right man.
Get a good, strong bottle of rum,
'cause the more this man drinks,
the more he talks.
All the sheep are gone,
and the pastor lies sleeping alone.
The bottle. The bottle!
Better drunk than dead. Here's to you.
Bottoms up.
Now tell me about Burt Cavanaugh.
That's my drunken wife. Shh!
If there's any alcohol a mile away,
she smells it.
The bottle. Where's the bottle?
- There isn't any bottle.
- Where is the bottle?
I know you've got some.
- There it is.
- But it isn't ours. It's his.
My good man, forgive the impression you're
getting of us. It's just that she's my wife.
She's a bit... The poor woman's a drunk.
Uh... Before you finish that off,
tell me about Cavanaugh.
Cavanaugh. I'll tell you.
He's a scorpion, he's a snake, a beast!
All right, let me tell it.
When I arrived here,
the church was in good order.
I was an upright preacher then.
- But what about him?
- What about who?
- Cavanaugh.
- Oh, Cavanaugh.
All he had was
a pistol and a pack of cards.
You know, now he's called... Four Aces.
- Full house. Queens.
- Not enough. Full house, aces.
Poor man. The ladies love you
but not Lady Luck.
- Give me another chance.
- What security have you got?
You know I've lost it all.
You've taken everything.
My farm, my cattle, everything.
You know that.
Then get out of here. You're using space.
Only 500 dollars.
Just give me a chance, that's all I ask.
Just 500 dollars.
- Who wants to come in the game?
- I do.
My employees don't play.
Deal the cards.
How many?
I stand.
I'm happy to take your 500.
Four aces.
Me, too. Four aces.
Look, young man,
I'm afraid I don't feel like joking.
Neither do I.
Remember, Cavanaugh,
15 years ago at the Mesita ranch?
You and your friends killed everybody.
But you forgot one thing:
To kill me.
Give him a gun.
Get up!
Piano player, hit three notes.
Two lessons, my son.
First, watch behind you.
Second, count your shots.
Four bullets for one man, that's a waste.
I'll go and drive away his horse.
Hey!
Damn.
- Are you in charge here?
- Yes, sir. What is it?
- What time's the train for Lyndon City?
- It left 15 minutes ago.
- What time's the next one?
- The day after tomorrow.
Keep calm.
Your pal left your horse with me.
- He took the train, huh?
- Sure. But that's not all.
He said a pal of his would be coming along.
He said I should give you the horse
and a kiss. The horse is there.
Now, where do you want that kiss?
No, thanks. I'll settle for the horse.
I am proud indeed to be here today,
and I consider it a great honour
to introduce to you
our leading banker, Mr Walcott.
There is more.
Senator Carlyle has kindly agreed
to have the Atchison-Santa Fe line
pass through our growing little town!
Which augurs a fine,
prosperous, up-and-coming future...
While I'd be delighted
to continue to address you,
I must go because duty calls me.
Hooray for Senator Carlyle!
Hooray for Lyndon City!
One is here and
the other will be here very soon.
That's the one who killed Cavanaugh.
Go and get Pedro and Paco and the others.
Just say that I decided
the party is for nine. Hello.
Nothing else. The boys'll get it.
Walcott, a stranger's asking for you.
Show him in, then.
Easy, friend.
You're all alike.
Years go by and you all do the same things.
Gun in the drawer, knife in the back. Lies.
You were afraid that I wouldn't receive you?
Quite the contrary.
I expected you to receive me too well.
So I figured it's safer
to come in from behind.
Walcott, that stranger's gone.
I'm already here, friend.
So you can go on out.
Close the door behind you.
This is a private talk.
The door!
Well... looks like we've become important.
And rich.
You've changed your old clothes,
haven't you?
But you still haven't been able
to change your face.
You still got the meanest-looking face
I ever did see.
- Now listen, Ryan...
- Shut up.
And I can tell you where I've been
all these years, because of you.
I've seen some mean faces. Plenty of them.
Things aren't the same as they used to be.
Because I can pay now.
Just sit down. We'll talk about it.
There isn't that much talking to do.
Just five words.
Fifteen thousand plus fifteen thousand.
15,000 bucks doubled?
A lot of money, Ryan.
It's a pretty high figure.
But not for 15 years in jail.
And you'll have to pay Cavanaugh's share.
He was killed right under my nose and
I didn't get a chance to collect the money.
I'll give you an advance now.
How about... 10,000 bucks?
All right.
The rest tomorrow.
Now it's my turn.
All right?
Hold it.
Don't kill him yet.
He's useful to us for the time being.
We could finish you off now.
But that would be too simple.
Let me tell you this, boys.
Ryan was sent to us by heaven.
Good old Ryan is going to be helpful to us
like in the good old days.
Wait.
I've been working at this for years,
building their confidence in me,
the citizens as well as
the governor of this state.
But the most important thing is I have
in my bank more than a million dollars now.
The funds the state deposited with me
in view of our future public works.
What do you think?
Should I build
their stupid old public works
with this mountain of dollars?
They don't think I should.
I guess I'll have to go along with their idea.
Whoa.
You make sure you don't lose him.
- Mr Walcott.
- Yes. Good evening, Frank.
- Some extra work?
- Open that door while I close this one.
- Who's there?
- Me. Mr Walcott.
Good evening, Mr Walcott.
- My God, look at that.
- A million dollars.