And so, my friends, as your senator
and fellow citizen
it gives me great pleasure to congratulate
you on the outcome of this election.
An outcome that goes well for the future of
freedom, democracy and the pursuit of happiness.
I feel bound to say that I consider it a great honor
that you have chosen my candidate,
the man that I was first to be proposed
as your representative in the State Senate.
And now, Ladies and gentlemen,
how about a big had to David Barry?
Thank you. Thanks, folks.
You don't agree with Senator Logan, right, Dean?
No, I sure don't.
You probably know what I feel anyway.
You're ambitious. You're cruel and unscrupulous.
You're only in politics to make money.
I hate people like you, David.
I bet we'd be better without you.
Maybe we better set this straight once and for all.
Without them.
Just the two of us.
Forget it, David. The senator is waiting for you.
Don't make him angry. He gets impatient.
Wouldn't it be better to postpone this
until after the party?
What do you think, Dean?
Better keep out of this, boy.
Because you will find that it is hopeless.
Excuse me, I was a little nervous.
I can't take them any longer.
If you don't learn to relax
your new job is gonna get you down
...six feet under.
I suppose I'm tired.
I think I need to rest.
Give up this kind of life.
Think how nice it would be to have a wife,
children... a fine ranch?
Wait peacefully for the last judgement.
No, Django.
Oh no. All of that is not for me.
I'm too ambitious. It's true.
It is like having something burning
always inside your mind.
To succeed I'm ready for anything.
Anything.
Come along, Django. I need somebody like you.
I swear that in a few years we
will have so much money and influence
we won't need anything else
for the rest of our life.
Aren't you coming to the party?
No. I have to leave early tomorrow.
Oh, really?
The usual job?
It's bigger than usual.
All the gold from the Bank of Hampton.
I will lead the caravan with the gold.
- Where?
- Atlanta. My wife is coming.
I'd like to come along too, Django.
To meet new people and amuse myself.
I once met some a french dancer from Atlanta.
Quite something.
- Hi there.
- Good morning, darling.
- You're wake already?
- Is is late?
No. Don't be silly. The stars are still shining
and the sun will be out in a few hours.
We are coming to a lake. It is the only water in 20 miles.
You're going to make yourself pretty,
I am gonna water the horses. alright?
Okay, darling.
Pull it out.
Here. Put one under here and one there.
All right now... One!
Come on! Let's ride!
Operator. Operator...
- Santa Fe?
- Yeah.
Is that you, Effie? Alright, yeah.
No, no, no... The hangman is up your way?
I will leave him the message.
The sheriff said he got to get over here right away.
There is work for him to do.
I sure will. Remember me to all.
You should not make noises when someone is calling.
It's rude.
Hey, young fellow...
You must have been there when I was making
that call. Why don't say you something?
What is it all about?
The sheriff wants you to do
some neck-stressing for him.
Neck-stressing... Neck-stressing.
And you're next if you don't shut up.
It is a Mexican farmer.
And what did he do?
It must be something that got him
to your clicking machine.
For five years now the gold
from the local mine has been stolen
on its way to the office of Santa Fe.
For five years they've been investigating
where the gold disappeared to
and who is behind the robbery.
For five years the same story.
Someone stole the gold and not able to stop it.
So they grabbed the chicken thief
they find and throw him in jail
convicting him of stealing the gold and
ask that you put a new "scarf" around his throat.
You ought to be used to hang the innocent.
You have a lot of practice at it.
I want a drink! I want a drink!
You got plenty of water.
No?
Tell the sheriff to hold off this execution.
I got two others to do in the next county.
If you say so...
When is the next shipment leaving?
It is better to leave off that corn liquor.
It's cider. Nothing but cider.
Isn't that right?
Awful! Watch out, you might poison yourself!
Take my advice, young fellow. Stick to alcohol.
You're right, Horace. You're always, always...
No, no! You better not drink anymore.
You got a work tomorrow, Django.
I'll let you know when they
send out the next shipment of gold.
Jonathan Habit, you got something to say before hanging?
I am innocent.
It has that effect on everybody.
It makes them real hungry.
This takes care of "you."
Now you go 15 miles north to Mendez Fort.
There is a deserted village.
You will find some friends.
But my wife, my children...
They'll wait for you.
Then what's going to happen?
Now you are asking too much.
Yankee!
That's what I got for hanging you.
You may need money. Take it.
They hang you again if you'll go back.
This time I'm afraid I won't have the pleasure.
And if you run away,
you will be a phantom forever.
But if I were you,
I'd go to that village in Mendez.
Howdy, sheriff.
Well, it's about time you got here.
I was on another job.
Go on.
If I were you I'd hurry up.
He is more dead than alive.
If you don't hang him fast you lose your fee.
What do you want? What are you doing here? I am innocent!
- Innocent, I tell you.
- If you value your life, keep still.
Take off your coat.
- Get up.
- What are you going to do?
Get into this. It has got a hook.
Come on. Tie it.
What if they see the hook?
They can't see. You have a hood on.
Pretend to be dead. Tonight I cut you down.
Sheriff, we are ready.
It wouldn't be a bad idea
if you go out screaming.
I am innocent! I am innocent!
You can not do this thing.
I don't want to die. I didn't do anything!
Cheer up, son.
No, no. You can't! You murderers!
You can't hang him! He did nothing!
Leave him alone! Leave him alone!
You murderers! Murderers!
He is innocent! Garcia, tell them
that you are innocent!
Garcia! Garcia!
- Help me!
- Why don't you do something?
Are you all cowards?
Why don't you speak up?
Why don't you tell the truth?
You know he didn't do anything!
He is innocent!
You can't hang him! Let him go!
You are nothing but murderers. Let go!
Leave him alone!
He is innocent!
I tell you! He is innocent!
The hangman has to do his work in peace, sheriff.
He has to be left alone so he can do his job.
This kind of ugly scene is
bad for the towns reputation.
Take her away.
Django, I don't know how to use one of these.
Garcia will show you.
That is Garcia.
I'll help you.
Django, why didn't you bring us whiskey?
It would be nice to have a little drink.
I need one.
Do you?
Well, I guess I can wait.
I'm fed up, gringo.
I've been here a month at least.
You still haven't told us why you
are keeping everybody here in this place.
Or why you have saved us anyway.
I need you. I have to settle an account.
Lukas?
That's right.
Hombres, come over here. The gringo
has something very interesting to say.
Lukas is powerful.
His men are all outlaws.
Killers he has got out of jail.
They terrorize the whole country.
They stop at nothing to get their way.
- You better watch out.
- Are you afraid?
No. But...
What do we get in exchange?
Your life, for now.
Afterwards, if you manage to keep it...
You can go home free, and clear the blame.
You've thought of a plan?
All the witnesses against are to blame.
They wanted you hanged.
You've got to find them. One by one.
And make them understand that
the time for repentance has come.
I was sick at home...
And that coward Bill Kirby
said he saw me going outside.
That's how they convicted me. He betrayed me.
Just to get hold of my land.
He'll pay. He'll pay for that trick.
You can bet on it.
Sure he will, Jonathan.
Now calm down.
Than what should we do?
You are dead men. Just phantoms.
Go to their houses.
Let yourselves be seen.
I think you will have a good time.
Enjoy yourselves. But no killing.
Why not?
They're all innocent who illegally
condemned. Not murderers.
I don't like it.
What's the matter if we kill someone?
Pedro, José, vamos.
Where are you going?
Don't worry, Django.
We won't spoil your little game.
We know how to keep... silent.
It's too late now. You should have
thought about going sooner.
I advise you to stay right here.
- Yeah? Until when?
- I don't know.
I already told you.
We're getting out of here right now!
Wait a minute!
Thanks for saving my life.
You go around back and open the corral.
Walker! It's me, Walker!
Walker, remember me?
Why have you done this? Who are you?
Abbott, remember? Lukas paid you
to send me to the gallows.
Now I'm going to pay you!
Liar!
Go see Lukas and tell him...
Jonathan Abbott is back from the dead.
Vamos, muchachos.
- What is this? Who is there?
- It's me, Wallace. Remember me?
I went back to pay you.
Hanging me. How did you like it?!
It's me, Kat! The man you hanged!
You dirty double-crosser!
- Hi, Dan.
- Wallace?
You?
So you thought you could get away with it?
Sell out your friends for a few dollar!
Remember me? I'm Jonathan.
The ghost of Jonathan.
Conway! Bill Conway, come out!
It's your friend Wallace!
Come on out!
All right, who you did this to you?
We got beat up last night. Like the others.
They were attacked and whipped.
After that their houses were burned down.
Who did it?
Well? What's the matter?
It was John Abbott.
You're crazy. It couldn't have been Abbott.
But it was Abbott. I swear to you!
And he wasn't the only one. I saw Pat Mahoney.
And Andy saw Jake O'Connor. Right, Andy?
Idiots!
You pack of fools.
A corpse is a corpse.
Everyone of them is buried, five feet under.
No, Lukas! I saw Johnatan Abbott with my own eyes!
And he was no corpse!
Listen boss, I have got something to tell.
Come around later and bring your family.
I have some special whiskey for you.
With a couple of shots of it
you'll stop imagining you're seeing dead men.
What is it?
Tomorrow morning a lot of gold leave
the mines at Las Cruzes...
On the way to the bank of Santa Fe.
And I found out more. It is certain
they're gonna take the Sierra Road.
If they don't have trouble with the river,
the day after tomorrow they will be
as far as the pass and they'll be safe.
It's the first time they picked the Sierra, right?
Yes, and I'm afraid it will be the last.
Don't put me to the trouble of having to call you.
If all goes the way they planned it,
they want you in five days exactly.
This time the trial will be short.
They already was is guilty. Sam Copper.
He tried to shoot his wife twice.
They got him locked away outside the town.
He will be judged as soon as the gold is stolen.
Poor Sam. All he tried to do was defend his good name
and now they're gonna hang him for
an out-of-law. Two times double-crossed.
So long, fellows.
- Bye, Horace.
- See you soon.
Garcia, I got something important to tell you.
Well?
I forgot what it was.
Garcia, I remember what it was now.
Tomorrow they're gonna hang your wife.
Well, that's life.
Why didn't you warn me?
I figured you needed a day off.
I think you don't get enough rest.
You've been working too hard, Django.
Why let not old Bill do the job?
He may not have your light touch
but his price is cheaper than yours.
And he is well with the sheriff.
- Why convict Mercedes?
- Barry told everybody she was your accomplice.
And then?
She was tried, convicted and sentenced.
Now, I gotta be moving along.
Horace, don't call old Bill.
I've decided to "hang" Mercedes.
A hanging is a hanging,
no matter who does it, Django.
It makes no difference
to the fellow who is strung up.
See you tomorrow.
Let's go.
Tomorrow a lot of gold is leaving
Las Cruzes for Santa Fe.
It will be passing the Sierra the day after tomorrow.
I think it'll be ambushed at Hondo Pass.
Whom by?
The Lukas gang.
I thought we could play cat and mouse with them.
But now the time has come to settle our accounts.
With this?
Not yet.
We'll be waiting for them in the Sierra.
And we will attack them when
they try to grab the gold.
Try not to kill them.
We have to take them to the governor and make them confess everything.
Aren't you coming with us?
I meet you in the Sierra.
What is the idea? You're running out on us?
It was for me that he did it.
They're going to hang my wife tomorrow.
He is going to help her.
I'm sorry about you and your wife.
But there is something more important to do.
You mean that gold?
That's right.
You want your names cleared?
Go on.
We're get them to confess... Lukas and his men.
We go back to our homes and say:
"Look!" Your men are back . "
What will they do?
Then we speak to the judge and tell him
we don't belong to gang of Lukas.
Perhaps he'll believe us... he might not.
You see that?
He'll just has to believe! It's the truth!
Suppose he does. Then what?
Afterwards we all go home...
to misery...
To go on and on and breaking our backs
to provide food
until finally another "Lukas" tries
to take our land away again.
So what are you getting at?
I've been thinking it over. There's
a lot of gold that might belong to us.
Are you gone loco?
We ambush them before they reach the Sierra.
We'll go to meet them, before Lukas.
It will be a surprise.
You are all cowards. You should have been hanged.
It would have been better for all of you.
I'm making tracks.
Wallace, you can't leave now.
You shouldn't have done this, dirty Indian!
Anyone else?
Vamos!
Howdy, Sheriff.
There you are.
- It's you.
- Yeah.
Well, this time you got a woman, young fellow.
Don' spend a long time looking at her
or she will try to get around you.
Yeah. That's Women.
- Put this on.
- No!
Quick. Under your blouse. It will
keep you from being strangled.
If you don't stop that words I'm gonna
wash your mouth with soap and water.
Ain't you Pat O'Connor, the fellow that got hanged?
Yes...
You look sick. Son, you've been wounded.
- Where is Django?
- Django?
What do you want with Django?
I'd say you need a doctor.
I don't want to worry you, boy,
but you are in a pretty bad way.
Calls him...
I mean it... It's serious...
I see it's serious. That is no mosquito bite.
A little whiskey might do you good.
If it don't... pray. They say it helps sometimes.
It's Pat O'Connor! The ghost of Pat O'Connor!
Shut up, you fool,
help me to get him out of here.
Come on!
I was they would come by here.
How soon we're gonna attack them?
Before they reach the Pass. Come on!
- Here come the fellows now.
- I didn't expect to see them so early.
They are shooting for real!
- Crazy fool! Why don't they stop shooting?
- What if they really are bandits?
- Let's go. We go to move.
- Let's split this up.
No! We have to get over the frontier.
Okay.
This marks your grave.
Now you can go.
Find some hiding place. I hope in a few days
you and your husband can be together again.
Alive and free.
Adios and thank you, Django.
Ride!
Shoot!
Howdy, hangman.
That's enough.
Where is the girl?
Smart idea you had, mister.
Pretending to string everybody up like that.
I have to give you credit for that.
You know I like people who can think.
Because they usually...
have enough sense to not to get killed.
Why not be reasonable and play your cards right?
You know, I might give you a job.
Django...
It was Garcia.
He convinced the others to do what he said.
To get the gold first.
Wallace and me refuse to go along...
He killed Wallace, but I got away...
Sorry, I...
- You don't know anything?
- No... no.
I bet you're on with Garcia, buzzard.
That's plenty!
You two stay here and guard him.
Send someone to call me as soon as he comes to.
- It's Lukas.
- Come on.
Evening, David.
You are getting old, Lukas.
It was an accident, unavoidable.
I pay you to avoid them. All of them.
You shouldn't talk to me like that, David.
I worked for you since the beginning.
Sometimes there are accidents.
For five years you had your nerves
under control. Now you don't.
Maybe you're tired.
Maybe.
I warned you that gold was important to me.
I can not give excuses or empty promises
And you know it.
You haven't picked a good time to be tired.
Let me worry about that.
I find where they have hid it.
I don't think they can bring it out the country.
There are federal troops guarding the border.
They may try to get rid of it, by selling the gold.
In that case the receiver is sure to contact me.
What if they are going to another state?
We have an "Trump card".
The man who caused the trouble.
The one who organized everything.
We let him out and he'll lead us to
the place where the gold is hidden.
Who is he?
The local hangman.
Goes by the name of Django.
What is it?
Django... You idiot!
You really are tired. You've lost your memory!
- Do you have data?
- Yeah.
Yes, Django. It's me.
Are you surprised?
Five years ago I advised you to join up, remember?
I promised you honor and wealth, remember?
You wouldn't listen. You were wrong.
Filthy murderer.
The same old arrogant.
The same stupid and naive Django.
Five years... five years and you haven't changed.
I bet you're still dream about that
cozy farmhouse with a pretty girl
to look after you... How did you put it?
To wait happily for the Judgement day.
Wasn't that it?
I have only one thing left...
Hate!
Yeah. But even hate has its price.
If you help me to recover the gold...
one part will be yours.
My wife's life was worth a lot more.
That was an accident! She was a woman.
Why worry. There are plenty of others like it...
Leave him alone, Lukas.
You have been beaten enough.
He is stubborn.
I know.
But it is worth trying to break him.
If he hasn't cooperated in a couple of hours,
I'd finish him off. But uh...
with a pistol.
After all he was a friend.
Come on.
Stop it.
Behave yourself.
Johnny, please you are hurting me.
Don't do that. I can't breathe.
Johnny, you're so gross.
Why are you laughing?
Who are you talking to?
Darling, you're so big and strong.
He won't be needing these, we can use them.
Come on, hurry.
I'm right behind you. Let's go.
Wake up, Django. We're here.
Go find some water.
Django! Django, wake up!
Django! They sure turned you in mashed potatoes.
Come on now, on your feet, boy.
That's right. Come on...
You'll feel better after this.
Where are Lukas and the others?
It will be a miracle if you escape, Django.
So don't go looking for more trouble.
- Tell me where they are.
- In the saloon.
I need some dynamite.
I know my husband. He betrayed you.
- Why did he do it?
- I don't know.
Where is Garcia?
...I don't know where he is.
If it is true what they say, I force him
to come to you and make it up somehow.
Someone's coming.
Alvarez! Alvarez!
Clear everybody out. We got work to do.
Alright, everybody outside.
- I wonder what Lukas is up to now?
- You know Lukas. Always got Something cooking.
I'm tired of your excuses, Lukas!
I can't use you and your gang here,
if you don't set things right.
I want a person who can make
an account of the men's action.
Nobody will take any initiative without informing me.
I don't want any more of your stupid failures.
I need a torch and a dozen rifles.
The dynamite was bad enough.
But where do I find a dozen rifles?
Beside, have you changed your mind?
I thought you were gonna blow them up.
There is someone inside
who is more interested in life.
Let's see if Django feels like talking now.
Go on, before they discover that I've gone.
I wait for you at the other side of the saloon.
Tell me something, Lukas.
If we found out that this all was a trick to
keep the gold away where it was supposed to go,
what would you do about it?
Okay, that's enough, David!
Watch what you are saying.
I got you started, David.
Without me you would be a none identity.
So I don't want any more of this talk
after I have done so much for you.
Wait here.
The hangman won't talk.
We have to work out some way to get that gold back.
I had to rob the general store.
- I'll end up in jail.
- Did you see that ladder?
Over at the other side of the saloon.
You climb up there.
When you hear firing from the other side,
you start firing too.
You won't hit anybody, but it doesn't matter.
Just make a lot of noise.
Won't hit anyone? Are you crazy?
Ask anyone here who it was who won the second price
in the last year shot contest.
It was third, not second.
But see you stay under cover.
I got you.
Takes the others into town.
Django has escaped!
He shot both men who where on guard.
Bill is checking the other side of town.
You fool!
That must be him!
Quick, get the men together!
Fire!
- Water...
- Get water!
All outside. Sam, George, come with me.
Back inside!
Cowards!
You all are going to get him with me.
I shoot anybody who don't get moving on!
Lukas!
Remember five years ago?
A shipment of gold from the mines.
A wagon, a man... a woman.
She was my wife! You killed her!
All right, come on out, Lukas.
Come on out while there is still time.
Outside.
Help me out of here. Help me!
Come out... Come out!
Help me...
The border is that way,
two miles the other side of the river.
Maybe we're better off waiting until sunset,
don't you think?
It's all right. Can cross in safely here.
This part is never patrolled.
Wait. I will not go with you.
- No? And why not?
- I want to get my family.
I want also to cross this river... but not alone.
We all have wives and children too.
We just have to think of them later.
I've made up my mind.
What about the gold? What do we do?
I'll take my part.
- You will? What is your part?
- Whatever I can get.
- How's that?
- Adios.
All right. Let's go.
Stay in line.
Come in.
Excuse me, sir. But there is a person
who wants to speak to you.
I don't wish to be disturbed.
Howdy, chief.
Where are your men?
In Farmers City.
Send them up to the Sierra
to Alvez County, right away.
But Lukas is there.
Was there.
He made a mistake.
Who was it?
The local hangman. He calls himself Django.
It's him you want?
Yeah... but alive.
He is the only one who knows where
a certain load of gold ended up.
He's here.
He has the gold with him.
He is staying out of sight.
Where?
Are you going... to kill him?
No.
afterwards, what will become of us?
I only want to get back what he has stolen.
Save my husband...
You saved our lives before. I don't know why.
I beg of you, let Garcia go home
to live again as before.
It doesn't depend on me.
It's in my house. A cabin,
about a mile from here on the road to Altos.
- Will you come with me?
- No...
You follow me. Wait a little.
You're Django, ain't you?
Barry said to bring you back alive.
Don't try anything!
Pick it up by the barrel, give it to me.
Make it fast!
Pack your things and go.
You're leaving, Garcia?
Stop!
Don't kill him, Django. You promised.
Is it all there?
Forgive him.
He killed Wallace.
Wallace and many men.
You know what made me do it, Django.
All my life I've been poor and hungry.
It's the same for my wife here.
We couldn't keep on living like this.
I'm not the judge or the sheriff.
I only know  you betrayed my trust.
I owe my life to you, Django.
And once I saved yours.
The debt is paid.
Take all the gold and leave us in peace.
Come on. This time
you have to do exactly what I say.
Be a good girl and be quiet in church.
Up we go.
What's wrong?
I'm join you right away, alright?
Alright.
Good morning, sir.
Excuse me for having dared to come at your house.
I am here about something that
I know will interest you, sir.
Which is?
What is it about?
I know who stole the gold from these crosses.
I alone, right. Where is your husband?
Garcia... Garcia!
Well?
Where is the gold?
Can I be sure of what you promised me, sir?
Here is $ 5000, as promised.
Lukas offered me much more money.
I made the deal with your wife, not with Lukas.
You can count it later.
Now think about handing the gold to me.
It's hidden.
In the cemetery of Altez.
Where is it hidden?
There.
Whose grave are you digging there?
Yours.
I'm here for the gold.
Is that so?
Shall we discuss it?
I'll let you have half of it.
That's a good offer. You better accept.
My wife's life was worth a lot more.
In the past I gave advice.
But you wouldn't listen.
Now I've offered you one more proposition.
But this is the last one.
Why don't you just forget that old story
forever and get on with things?
You know I'd like to save your life.
For five years you robbed and killed...
Your debt to justice is pretty big.
Now I have a advice for you...
Pay out.
I pay...
But that is stupid.
No.
He did not betray you.
It was you and your obstinate idea
that I am stupid, like you.
I offer you fifty percent of that gold.
What do you say?
It is a shame.
I'm afraid this is the last advice I'll give you.
The dead are in their graves, understand?
And you... are dead.
You have been dead for five years.
This is your grave. mister.
Dig.
Ready, boys?
Here, Mercedez.
It's yours.
- Take it.
- I can not.
No. It is for you.
Adios, Django.