Mister? Sorry.
You're next.
Pardon me, miss.
My mind was
somewhere else.
No problem.
It happens to me too.
I'd like to wire this
to St. Joseph's
Boarding School in Boston.
It's urgent.
Someone's put an "E"
on every one of these bills.
- I didn't notice.
- People try to put fake money by me
on account
of these cheaters,
- but I've got instinct.
- That money is good.
Yes, it is.
Been waiting long, Destinado?
How are you this morning?
As you can see,
his hoof isn't 100% yet.
But if you don't gallop him
for a few days,
he'll take you
to the end of the world.
Thanks.
Not too often you get to work
on a horse like this.
If you want to sell,
I'd be interested in buying.
Next time he gives me lip about
getting up in the morning,
I'll think about it.
Got that, pal?
Yah!
Stop them!
We're robbed!
They took everything.
- Where's the sheriff?
- He's in the saloon.
Where do you think he is?
My money...
where's my money?
Gone.
Hey, no galloping.
Hey, remember, no galloping.
No!
Bad!
Where are you going?!
No.
- Are you all right, kid?
- I've been better, that's for sure.
Dang snake. You should've
got him in the head.
Then how could he tell his friends
to leave kids like you alone?
Are you saying you didn't
kill him on purpose?
Better to change
the mind of many
than getting rid of just one.
- Ow, my shoulder!
- Hold on.
It hurts here?
Can you move
that arm like this?
Oh, it hurts!
It's broken.
We'll see.
Now tell me
what food
do you like best?
- My what?
- What is your favorite?
- Mrs. Melody's apple pie.
- Oh!
I like apple pie too.
Mrs. Melody's are the best, but what
does that have to do with my shoulder?
Now I want you
to close your eyes
- and picture that pie.
- Why?
Trust me.
Close your eyes.
Tell me why is that pie
so special?
It smells of hot butter.
When you take a bite,
it'll just melt in your mouth.
Oh, what, are you crazy?!
Your shoulder was out, kid.
Now it's not.
Try to move your arm.
Heh, it doesn't hurt
too much.
Are you a doctor?
No, I'm not.
Come on, kid.
I'm gonna get beat if I show up
at the ranch without my horse.
Your Pa will let it go
once he finds out what happened.
I don't have a dad or a mom.
They were killed by outlaws
when I was a month old.
- Sorry, kid.
- What brings you here?
Bandits... I've been
tracking them.
I saw two men this morning galloping
like the devil was chasing 'em.
Which way did they go?
Toward Holysand, I think.
I'm not sure... they were far off.
There it is... Holysand.
I wonder
what that fire's about.
Nothing good, I'm sure.
God will punish you
for this, Mitchell!
Leave God out of this, Victor,
and get it into your thick head:
That land will belong
to me and my cattle.
That's Nathan Mitchell,
the man I work for.
What's going on here?
Sheriff, the seed salesman
sold Nathan
the seeds at three times
the market cost!
- Business is business.
- Free country.
Man can buy whatever he wants.
And he can burn whatever he buys!
Not if it's just to burn it
under our noses,
keep us from getting
what we need.
Gentlemen,
is this really the example
we want to set for our children?
Move this out of the road
right now.
Do it now.
Garvey,
do as the sheriff says.
See you at the ranch.
Consider it done.
Silver, did you hear that?
Douse the fire
and clear the street...
- on the double!
- Don't say anything, you'll make it worse.
I fell from my horse, Garvey.
My shoulder hurts so bad.
Unless you want your face
to hurt too, do as I say.
Hello, handsome man,
what can I get you?
- Iced tea, miss.
- Say that again.
You heard right, Gloria.
Your handsome man
wants tea.
You find that funny?
Out here, mister,
tea's not a real man's drink.
Know what I mean?
Yeah, I know what you mean.
But I can't help it.
- I like tea.
- He likes tea.
Is it true that a man who drinks tea
can't hold a deck of cards?
Probably.
But if you want,
I can play a couple of hands
while I sip my tea.
Let's give this man a seat.
Thanks.
Gloria!
Pitcher of tea
for the table.
I really thought
I won that one.
Doesn't two aces
beat three jacks?
Sure you didn't have whiskey
in that glass, friend?
- Sure you want to keep playing?
- Yeah,
but I lost a lot.
How can I make it up?
- You have to raise the stakes.
- Are you in?
Fine by me.
Gotta be able to pay though.
Even someone who drinks tea
knows that in poker
you always... you always
pay your debts.
Always.
Sorry.
We have to feed our family!
All right.
Tough break, friend.
Hold on, friend.
Isn't this what you call
a royal flush?
Isn't this a winning hand?
You dirty snake.
How come you're so lucky?
Luck has nothing to do with it.
Then how is it you just started
winning every hand like that?
I wasn't the one who thought
he had a sucker on his hands.
One last hand...
all or nothing.
But if I win,
you're gonna walk outside,
apologize to the kid
and finish sweeping
the street yourself.
What are you talking about?
- Are you out of your mind?
- No, not at all.
Think you can put one
over on me, huh?
You good-for-nothing cheater.
I didn't have to cheat.
You're so damn bad.
There's only one way
to settle this now.
Show me that your shooting
is as good as your cheating.
- You're tempting me.
- So what are you waiting for?
Now hold it right there.
You've had your fun.
You had your fun.
He cheated, Sheriff.
Everyone saw.
It's true, Sheriff.
- Right, Sam?
- Yeah.
Don't listen to 'em, Sheriff.
I didn't pick up
on any card sharpin'
and you know I know the difference.
Whatcha got to say for yourself?
- I played clean.
- These three here says you didn't.
- He cheated.
- That's four.
Give me your gun,
I'm gonna lock you up.
Whoa!
- My hat.
- Slow.
Good.
And this belongs to me.
For now, till I get
things cleared up.
- How much in there, Garvey?
- I don't know, Sheriff.
$77
and 5¢.
Substantial.
- What's going on?
- It's all right, kid.
Hey hey, slow down.
Slow down.
You ain't finished yet, kid.
Hey, Sheriff, I told you
I didn't cheat.
I don't know how long you
were in the saloon, but...
You want some tea?
I like tea myself.
Only I don't ever
drink it in public.
I brew it
from a secret recipe.
Make it with
peppermint leaves.
I was learned it
by an old mountain man.
Since we both like tea,
what am I doing here?
For starters, I only got
but three cells.
I don't have enough room
for Garvey and his men.
Besides, I know all
there is to know about them.
You, on the other hand,
are kind of interesting.
Looked to me like
you're hunting trouble,
like you're trying
to get yourself killed.
- What do you want to know?
- Let's start with your name.
- They call me West.
- What're you doing in Holysand, Mr. West?
Two gunslingers... they robbed
a post office in Santa Fe.
Some of that money was mine.
I've been tracking them.
So you caught their sign
and that brought you here.
- I'm sure they're long gone, Sheriff.
- That makes sense,
seeing as you're
the only stranger here.
What line of work
are you in, Mr. West?
I am a professional
card player.
If you check my saddlebag,
- you'll see that...
- I'm gonna find a couple decks of cards
- and a book.
- You read my book?
Not particularly.
I'm gonna leave this
with you.
You're gonna have
a lot of time to kill.
- Thank you, darling.
- You sure you weren't dreaming?
I'm telling the truth!
He hit the snake's tail from...
at least 300 feet.
And then he fixed my shoulder
with one snap,
like a doctor.
You sure you're not
exaggerating?
That seems like
a lot for one man.
I think you hit your head
when you fell off the horse.
No damn cheater hits
a snake's tail from 300 feet.
One thing's for sure...
whoever this Mr. West is,
he's definitely out of order.
You know, everybody's
talkin' about the way
you fixed that little
Silver's shoulder.
Matter fact there's a rumor going
around that you are really a doctor.
They all say I'm a gunslinger
just because I shot the tail
off a rattlesnake.
You know, it's a damn shame
that you're not a doctor.
My back is killing me.
The pain is so bad
- I can't sleep at night.
- Isn't there a doctor in Holysand?
Well, the onliest one knows
anything about medicine
is Mrs. Stark.
She's the teacher.
But I can't let a woman
lay hands on me for something like...
you know, not...
not for that reason anyway.
Well, you know what I mean.
I gotta make my last round.
Why don't you get yourself
some sleep?
Yeah.
Yep yep.
- Sheriff?
- Yeah?
- The pain in the back.
- It's the boots.
- My boots?
What are you
telling me, boy?
These boots cost me
a ton of money.
Special dee-livery
Kansas City.
They ruined my wallet,
but not my back.
The heels are all worn
on the outside.
Get yourself a new pair.
A fella I knew
- fixed his back that way.
- A fella you knew?
- It's a long story.
- Oh. You ain't got time
for long stories.
I'm throwing you out tomorrow morning.
You get some sleep.
- Good night.
- Night, Sheriff.
Am I dreaming?
Or am I seeing what I'm seeing?
Whoa!
Hold up there.
Only one way to find out.
Hold on a second, Burt.
I've only got two for you.
Morning, ma'am.
Don't mean to intrude,
- but anything we can...
- Need a hand?
We're at your
complete disposal.
That's very kind of you, but l...
Jack!
Burt?
You don't remember me?
It's me, Millie.
- Millie Mitchell.
- Here you go.
You two have changed
quite a bit too.
But then again not.
M-M-Millie?
- Is that really you?
- Uh-huh.
Shucks, Millie,
last time we saw you,
you was just a little girl.
I got it.
There you go.
And now you're...
like a woman.
Hold it there, Jack.
Hyah!
Hyah hyah!
- Notice anything?
- What?
Watch this.
- Did you swallow a broom?
- No, I didn't swallow no broom.
I got me some new boots!
No more backache.
I feel like a new sheriff.
Looky here.
Denise.
- Good morning.
- Good morning your own self.
I'd like to talk to the doctor
who fixed your back.
Well, he... he never said
he was no doctor.
Well, a doctor is a doctor
even if he doesn't say it.
If he cured even one of God's creatures,
then he can help me.
Mister, I don't know if
you're a lowlife poker player
or a real doctor,
but I have a problem.
There's a woman in town,
she's been vomiting for three days.
She doesn't have a fever,
but her heartbeat is low
and she can't move.
What should I do?
Don't look at him, look at me.
Can you or can you
not help me?
Did you try some agave juice?
One spoonful every two hours.
One spoonful is not enough.
Get half a gallon and mix it
with half a gallon
of boiled water and honey.
Give her a glass every hour,
and every three hours
give her a cup of tea
made with wild nettle leaves.
That should stabilize
her heartbeat.
Some hombre he knew
got better thattaway.
- It's a long story.
- Well, I'll do as you say,
but I warn you... if you're not
telling me the truth,
you'll be sorry.
She's got some character.
- That's not all she's got, boy.
- Oh.
It's incredible...
nothing's changed.
Still so peaceful, so quiet.
Well, actually things could be
a lot better here in Holysand.
- What do you mean?
- Millie!
Father!
Ohhh.
Grandma Melody!
I missed you so much.
We missed you too, my dear.
Silver, you grew into
a fine young man.
Thank you, Miss Millie.
- What are you two doing here?
- Just trying to help.
Get your filthy hands off
my daughter's luggage.
Get the hell out of here.
Take your fat brother with you.
Easy, Jack, easy.
No point in arguing.
Go!
Let's go back to work.
- Why did you treat them like that?
- We'll talk later.
Right now I've got some
business to take care of.
Get in the buggy.
Sheriff!
What about this West fellow?
Far as I can gather he's a cardsharp,
but he's not a cheater.
- That ain't what my men say.
- Ha ha.
Your men'd say that my horse
drinks out of his behind.
You need to show my men
a little more respect.
You know, Garvey
is like my son. He's loyal.
He's trustworthy.
And that's all that counts to me.
All that counts to me
is keeping the peace in this town.
Even at the cost of sidin' up
with some damn cardsharp?
Yeah, till he gets
his money back he won
honest on the table
every day and twice on Sunday.
West will get
his money back.
He'll get every dime of it.
But if I have any more
trouble out of him,
I'm holding you responsible.
I'm holding
you accountable.
Here, Sheriff Basehart.
- Yeah yeah, Silver.
- Can you give this to Mr. West?
Just tell him Mrs. Melody made it.
He'll understand.
- Is it really that good?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
It was still hot
when he give it to me.
It's still warm.
It's still delicious.
What's in that... apples?
I love apple pie!
I purely do!
I like apple pie too.
Why do you
keep staring at me?
- Do you want some?
- Me? No, not me.
No, not me.
What, are you kidding?
- You ate it all.
- You said you didn't want any.
Well, I know what I said,
but that doesn't...
That's... that's right
neighborly of you.
- What's the stakes?
- Stakes is the truth.
If I win, you got to tell me
who you really are.
If you win, you leave town
with all my secrets.
You see, I have to know
what kind of a desperado
I'm pushing out on
an unsuspecting public.
All right, it's a deal.
And I'd like to know
what kind of man
put me in here
in the first place.
Two cards.
We both know how it is...
you travel 100 miles
and everything changes:
Gunslingers become mayors;
saloon dancers become
respected ladies;
and sheriffs...
one jack,
two jacks,
three jacks,
four jacks.
Who were you
100 miles from here?
Well, I was a cardsharp.
And I was a cheat.
And then somehow or t'other
I became sheriff of Holysand.
Whoa.
I'll get the luggage.
Millie dear!
It's a pleasure to see you.
Dana, what are
you doing here?
Uh, Millie, there's something
I want to tell you.
Dana is my wife now.
We got married a month ago.
Uh, that's not possible.
Why didn't you say anything?
Everything happened so quickly.
We barely even
realized it ourselves.
You were taking
your finals in school
and I didn't want to bother you.
I thought it'd be better
to tell you in person.
You thought wrong, Dad.
I have the right to know when you bring
another woman into Mom's house.
Three 10s,
and two queens.
Nice!
- Too bad four aces beats 'em.
- It sure does.
If you are as good at your job
as you are at poker,
you're gonna need
a bigger jail.
All right, quit stallin', West.
Tell me something I want to know.
I have to give you
an IOU on that.
Hold on now, pardner.
A deal's a deal.
Now!
All right.
I was born overseas,
became a doctor,
then came to this country
to practice in Boston.
I was a good doctor...
but one day
I killed a woman.
I mean,
I could have saved her,
but I didn't.
I just had to extract a bullet.
Easy enough for a doctor
like me but...
But you had drunk that day.
Yeah.
She was a widow... Mexican.
A beautiful woman.
She had a daughter...
three years old.
I've been taking care of her
for nine years now.
She's in one of the best
boarding schools in Boston.
Her name...
is Estrella.
And you play cards
to take care of this young'un?
Uh-huh.
I'm pretty good with my hands,
but I never had the guts
to pick up a scalpel again.
Cards is the only thing
I know now.
- And guns.
- It goes with the territory.
I gotta watch my back.
What the hell is going on?
Woo-woo-woo-woo!
All right, boys,
what's going on here?
Um, Sheriff, it looks like
someone took
the seed man's clothes
and set them on fire.
Now he's running around naked as
a jaybird... that's a public obscenity.
I reckon that neither one of you clowns
knows anything about this.
Sheriff, arrest these two.
They did this to me.
All right, you two,
my office now.
But wait a minute, Sheriff.
It's his word against ours.
I was trying to put
the fire out, Sheriff.
You're trying my patience
but mightily. Haul your freight.
Watch your back.
What are you doing?
You...
Where are you going?
Can I get some water out here maybe?
Can I get a little help here?!
Damn.
It's a $300 suit.
Oh man. Come on,
come on, come on.
Hurry hurry,
get it, get it, get it.
Come on!
Why, you son of a bitch!
Sure is nice
to meet you, Mr. West.
I hope next time you can teach
Garvey the lesson he deserves.
Ain't gonna be a next time.
Mr. West is
leaving us forthwith.
Right, as soon as
I get my money back,
I gonna put many miles
between me and this place.
It's always the best
who are first to go.
Yeah, that's why you're going to be
not leaving here for a long time, boy!
How long are we
staying here?
Watch out for the bedbugs.
But the beans are great.
- What time do we eat?
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- Sheriff!
- I'm hungry now!
Sheriff!
I'm hungry too!
So where are
you headed, Doc?
First I'm gonna get
my money back from Garvey.
Then Santa Fe to wire
the money to Estrella.
And after that, any town
with a poker table.
Well, good luck to you, pard.
Thanks, Sheriff.
- Sheriff?
- Yeah?
You cheated... I caught that.
I expected you would.
It's a wonder, isn't it?
I'm sorry you
took it so badly.
What did you expect?
That I'd hug her and tell her
I'm happy she's my new mom?
No one can replace
your mother.
Dana's my wife
and you must respect her.
You still haven't told me
what happened with the Bakers.
They want to farm that land
east of the Colin River.
I need that land
to enlarge my herd.
- But that land has always been free.
- It can't keep being that way.
Anyway, it's nothing for you
to be concerned about.
Dana is behind this. Isn't she?
You leave her
out of it, Millie.
The Bakers are our enemies.
You remember that.
Try to save as much as we can!
Hurry hurry!
- Try to push it back!
- Come on now.
- Victor, what happened?
- It just went up in flames.
- Get back!
- We're doing everything we can.
If only my good-for-nothing
boys had been here.
They're in jail.
I came to tell you.
- What?
- They stripped Sam the salesman's
clothing and burnt it.
The whole town's laughing.
- So that's why this happened?
- Don't jump to conclusions.
- This might have been an accident.
- Nathan will pay for this!
Let's just get the money together
to bail Burt and Jack out.
I knew your horse would
come back on his own.
Saved me
a chewing out for sure.
- You can always count on a horse.
- Yep.
More than you can
count on us humans.
Out of jail already, West?
Guess Basehart doesn't
like cheaters either.
Quit it, Garvey!
Come inside, we're gonna put
an end to this problem once and for all!
You too, West!
Come on, Garvey.
Give it to him.
You're making
a mistake, Nathan.
We've already discussed this.
Give him his money.
It's all there.
Count it if you like.
Mr. Mitchell's word is
good enough for me.
Millie, are you going to town?
Yes, I have some
shopping to do.
My daughter Millie.
- Nice to meet you.
- We already met.
- We did?
- You were in front of me at the post office
in Santa Fe right
before it was robbed.
But maybe you don't remember because
your mind was somewhere else.
Miss Millie.
You're spoiling him, Silver.
Soon he'll like you
more than me.
I can't help it.
I grew up around horses.
I've never seen one
like this before.
How'd it go with Mr. Mitchell
and Garvey?
I got my money.
- You'll go then?
- Yes.
It was nice
to know you, Mr. West.
I'm sure we'll
meet again soon.
Sooner or later we will.
In the meantime,
don't change.
When we do,
I want to make sure
that I run into a great man.
Everything
all right, Miss Millie?
I was waiting for you.
It doesn't seem proper
for a girl like me
to ride out here all alone.
Would you be so kind as to keep me
company until Holysand?
Actually I was going that way,
and town is thattaway.
Oh, please, Mr. West?
I've always thought of Holysand
as some sort of paradise,
but it's changed so much.
Yeah, you could cut
the tension with a knife.
I want to stop this madness.
I'm going to speak
with Mrs. Stark.
She's the person
I respect most... my teacher.
Did you meet her?
Once, briefly.
Oh, she's a great woman, but once
she gets something in her head,
it's impossible
to change her mind.
I noticed.
She can be tough at times,
but I assure you,
she is sensible and sweet.
One thing I know for sure,
only women can right
the wrongs of men.
You have no proof at all
that it was Nathan.
I don't need any proof.
It was him.
Get this in your head, Sheriff:
This town is a powder keg.
And all of us, including you,
are gonna have to choose
what side we're on.
I'm on the side of the law.
And it is best that you
and everybody else
in this town understood that!
Good day, gentlemen.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Sorry, Pa.
I guess if we hadn't
been teaching the seed salesman a lesson
none of this would've happened.
Maybe Nathan might not
have burned down...
You don't respond to a prank
by burning down someone's barn!
What Nathan did is an act of war
- and he'll pay for that.
- You stooping to his level, Pa?
This is war, Burt.
And anything goes in war.
From now on we're gonna
go around packing guns too.
You think that's
a good idea, Pa?
Thanks for your company, Mr. West.
- Good luck with your peace venture.
- I'll need it.
I'm sorry to see
you go, Mr. West!
Only women can right
the wrongs of men.
Good one.
George Washington?
Mr. West.
We met at the ranch and he rode
back to town with me.
Be careful around him, Millie.
He's a poker player.
Though...
quite intriguing, it seems.
But a fine woman like you
should stay away.
From your tone of voice,
maybe you're the one
who needs to be careful.
Millie, is that what they
taught you in St. Louis?
- Impertinence?
- I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean to offend.
- I'm not offended.
I know how to protect myself
from the likes of him.
Doesn't matter anymore.
He left town.
Anyway, Mr. West was right
about one thing:
That we women need
to do all we can
to talk some sense back
to the men in this town.
Hello again, pardner.
This time we
have insurance.
Even in cases of robbery
your money is guaranteed.
This is marked with "E"
just like last time.
But it's good money.
I know.
I think Victor's easier
to get to than your father,
even though Victor's barn
burned down.
I do too. My father isn't himself
anymore since he married Dana.
Actually, I always thought your father
was the gruffest man in town.
Downright pigheaded.
Okay, so since Victor
is our target,
how are we going to get him to make
an agreement with your father?
Maybe I should ask
his sons to help.
Burt, Jack and I were
friends when we were kids.
- That was a long time ago.
- I think I still have a card to play.
Oh, who's that?
Big, my husband's dog.
Ever since Eugene died,
he likes to go and sit
on that old blanket of his.
Oh, he's a sweetie.
Can I pet him?
He doesn't let
anyone touch him,
not even me sometimes.
It's okay.
Dogs absolutely love me.
I never met one who didn't.
I hope you have better luck
with the Bakers.
West!
What are you doing here?
I thought you left.
I left, but now I'm back.
What?
This is the money
that Garvey gave me.
Have a look at one.
See anything?
Yeah, girl on a bird.
Look closer.
On the righthand side.
Yeah, there's an "E" here.
So what?
After every poker game,
I separate the good bills
from the phony ones
so I don't make mistakes
when I send the money
to the boarding school
in Boston,
as I did that day in Santa Fe.
So this here "E" is for Estrella?
- Right.
- Uh-huh.
What you're telling me is
the money that Garvey gave you...
was stole from the Santa Fe
post office
with some of your money
along with it.
- Right.
- Uh-huh.
And what you're asking
me to believe
is that Garvey was
one of the men
who stole that money
in the post office?
Right.
I want you to arrest Garvey.
Well, I will grant you
that these bills is marked
but you can't rule
out coincidence.
And you also can't rule out
that there ain't a judge
in anywhere in holy hell,
or Holysand, who would ever
convict a man on such
flimsy evidence.
Right.
So are you still leaving?
I'm not gonna leave
until we put Garvey in jail.
I mean until you
put Garvey in jail.
Why, mighty kind
of you, Sheriff.
- Thank you.
- No, thank you.
- West.
- Gloria.
Oh my God,
I thought you left.
I left, but now I'm back.
- Got a room for me?
- For you,
always.
Come, follow me.
Come out of there
right now, Jack Baker!
- Howdy, Miss Millie.
- You too, Burt.
I know you're there.
Hey, my beans!
Come back here!
Gee, Millie, we didn't
come riding down here
to spy on you or nothing.
We always come
for a swim at sunset.
I mean, you did too,
don't you remember?
No, absolutely not.
I remember that I could never bathe here
without you two spying on me!
Come on, Millie. We come down here
to pick the wild berries and such.
I'm kidding, Jack.
Actually, I came here
hoping to find you.
Why?
To talk to you about what's
going on between our families.
I'm sorry, Millie, but there's nothing
we can do about that now.
- Not after the barn burned down.
- I know.
And if your suspicions are right,
well, my father made
a very stupid mistake.
That's exactly
why we have to talk...
to avoid making more.
You know, Millie, that's going
to have to be Nathan Mitchell's job,
not ours.
Come on, Burt, let's go.
Burt! Jack!
I just want peace again.
If you do too
and still trust me, meet me tomorrow
at the Heart's Creek.
Come on, Burt.
All right, you scoundrel.
What are we gonna do
about this?
You're not trying
to butter me up, are you?
All right, you can have it all.
- Mrs. Stark.
- Mr. West!
- What are you doing here?
- I live here.
- Oh.
- What are you doing here?
I was following
my pan of beans.
What are you talking about?
Here.
Big! Are you
stealing food again?
- As if I don't feed you enough.
- You can't blame him.
Those were real good beans.
You like them spicy, huh?
I don't know what to say.
I'm completely mortified.
Mrs. Stark?
You look like
you've seen a ghost.
That's the first time
since Eugene passed that
Big's shown any affection
for anybody.
Maybe it's because we
share a passion for beans.
I don't think it's just that.
I'm sorry for your loss, Mrs. Stark.
Thank you.
It's been 10 years
this December.
Some things take
a long time to heal.
- Big!
- It's okay. He doesn't bother me.
Maybe, unlike his mistress,
- he likes poker players.
- Poker players
or doctors?
Big, get down!
Your agave remedy worked,
by the way.
- She's doing much better.
- Really?
- I thought you'd left town.
- I did.
But now I'm back.
It'll be a long time
until I see a stew like that,
Mrs. Stark.
- Better than the beans Big stole?
- Sure was.
Thank you.
I have to go now.
It's getting late.
He's angry with me.
He thinks I'm sending you away.
He says maybe you're not
as bad as you seem.
I heard that too.
But he didn't say
maybe.
Good night, Mrs. Stark.
Good morning, Millie.
Did you sleep well, dear?
Didn't you hear us?
Is there something wrong?
Is it true you burned down
one of the Baker's barns?
I don't think certain subjects should
be of interest to a girl your age, dear.
- Did you burn it down?
- Millie!
He knows what he's doing.
Not always.
Otherwise
you wouldn't be here.
Millie, how dare you!
You apologize to Dana
immediately!
I wouldn't think of it.
Millie, you come back here!
I order you come back here!
- Nathan.
- What the devil you want, Garvey?
- Something happened last night.
- What?
Someone sabotaged the water pump
for the cattle.
Do you really think this is
such a good idea, Burt?
What are you afraid of, Jack?
- Pa won't like it?
- I ain't afraid of nothing.
But she is Nathan Mitchell's
daughter after all.
Yeah, but she's sincere when she
wanted peace between our families.
You know she's educated,
trustworthy and she doesn't
choose sides.
And she's the most beautiful girl
these parts have ever seen.
Hold on, Burt.
I am the older brother.
Oh yeah?
Well, it means that I get
first crack at it.
No no no no way. What does that
have to do with anything?
- Well, it's a law of nature!
- Jack.
- What... Pa?
- Where do you think you're going?
You have to help me deliver
potatoes to Mrs. Kroger.
- Pa!
- You heard me.
That's the law of nature,
big brother. We'll see you later.
- Pa!
- Come on.
All right!
- Good morning, Silver.
- Mr. West.
- You didn't leave.
- I left.
- But now I'm back.
- That's fantastic.
So we can go for a ride today. I have
to run some errands for Mrs. Melody,
- but I'll be free later.
- That's a good idea.
Silver...
I have to ask you something.
- Something important.
- Go ahead, shoot.
Ask me whatever you want.
It's about Garvey.
He wasn't here.
He wasn't in Holysand!
- What are you talking about?
- Garvey.
He wasn't here
when the robbery
in Santa Fe took place.
- Are you sure?
- Silver just told me.
Garvey takes three days
off every month.
Well, that don't mean
that he used them
to rob the post office in
Santa Fe.
See, he could have a little lady
stashed away someplace.
- There's lots of ladies with no taste.
- Yeah.
But if we were to find out
that there were other robberies
that took place
during his days off?
- Then?
- If "we" were to find out?
You're the sheriff.
I am the sheriff.
And you know what
I'm going to do?
As soon as I finish
cleaning this weapon
I'm gonna walk over
to the telegraph office
and I'm gonna send a telegram
to one of my associates in Hudson City
and ask him if he knows
of any other robberies
that has happened anywhere
on Garvey's days off.
I'm just waiting for you
to finish cleaning your shotgun.
You are something, Doc West.
All right, all right, let's go.
I have to admit, my dad's
a little guilty too.
He could've done more
to avoid butting heads with Nathan.
Will you help me find
a peaceful solution?
Let me help you across
the river first.
I've never heard my dad say the things
he said yesterday.
It's kinda like he forgot everything
he ever taught us.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
I remember you as being
a spiteful boy,
so sure of being smarter
than everyone else.
I never thought you'd be wise.
I wouldn't have thought that.
Me neither.
Maybe it's the effect
you have on me.
- Hello, Gloria.
- Hi, West.
I have that tea
ready for you.
Thanks.
Victor Baker! Damn you
and that fat kid of yours.
What the hell are you
talking about, Nathan?
You don't know anything?
You don't know who
sabotaged the dam
on the pond
where I water my herd?
Maybe it was the same guy
that burned down my barn.
You're getting too big
for your britches, Victor.
Sooner or later I'm going to have to
show you who the boss of this town is.
Oh really?
Why don't you do it now,
if you're able.
Hold it, Garvey.
I'll take care
of this myself.
Very good, Nathan.
Let's see what you can do,
what you're worth
without your henchmen.
You crazy, Pa? You want
to get yourself killed?
Shut up, Jack.
There's no turning back now.
Right, Nathan?
That's right, Victor.
No turning back.
Ow!
Aw, damn.
What the hell?
I wouldn't grab iron if I were you.
See, my aim ain't as good as his
and I might just
shoot you down by accident.
Hyah.
This isn't over with yet.
You're damn right it don't.
I should have took them all in.
- It wouldn't have solved anything.
- Yeah, maybe.
Well, until that land goes
to one or t'other of them
there's going to be an awful lot
of bloodshed.
- Maybe there's a way out.
- Well, yeah,
you could stand right here and keep
shooting the guns out of their hands.
Yeah, I've got a better idea.
Ever heard the story
of the Horatii
- and the Curiatii?
- No, I ain't been to Mexico in a dog's age.
Mexico has nothing to do with it.
Now, gentleman, this here
picture in this book
shows what happened
a time ago...
um, a long time ago, see?
It could be even like
100 years ago...
um, even 200 years ago.
2... 2,000.
Uh, even might even have
been 2,000 years ago.
It was a very old time.
And they had these two cities then
and one of them was
the name of Rome
and the other had the name
of "Abalongium."
Now they come
to the understanding
that the onliest way they's gonna
stop the war betwixt them
was is gonna have a duel.
And so they come to get
these two sets of brothers,
three brothers each...
the "Horatiaios"
and the "Capritiaios."
Let me get this straight, Sheriff.
Are you saying there should be a duel?
No, I'm not a-saying
there's gonna be a duel.
I say it is more like a challenge.
What we could have right here
in the center of Holysand...
no guns,
no weapons of any kind,
no eye gouging. I'll be the referee...
Are you crazy?!
Should the fate of my land
depend on a stupid brawl?!
- That's our land!
- Damn it, Nathan!
If you say that land belongs to you
one more time, I'll shoot you!
- You're a fool!
- Both of you, I'm gonna lock you up.
Sit down now!
Now looky here, you may not
like what I'm proposing
but if you don't accept it
there's going to be
a lot of blood spilt
and it's going attached
to your kinfolk,
the ones you love, like Millie
and Dana. Would you like that?
Or you two boys...
your two boys right here.
Cut down in the prime
of their lives!
Is that what
you're looking for?
Over a piece of dirt?!
See you soon, Victor.
Can't wait to see
the three lambs you bring
to feed my three lions.
I'm afraid he's right.
His men are as used to fighting
as my boys are to working the land.
Reckon I can't keep
a count of how many fights
I had to bust up because
of them half-baked desperados.
Figure they get
that feller Anvil...
killed a bull
with a head-butt I hear.
We'll fight anyway, Jack,
even if it is hopeless.
Maybe not.
I used to do some boxing.
I could train you.
It's a long story.
Trust me, boys.
You're in good hands.
Are those the candidates
for your third fighter?
- Yep.
- Desmond, Kurt, Sean and Larry.
How are you gonna pick one?
I'll think of something.
First thing, try to relax.
Yeah.
- What's his name again?
- Larry.
Larry,
I'm sorry but I have to be sure.
Sure of what?
- Huh. How do you feel?
- I've been better.
Larry is our third man.
Now listen, each one of us
has a hidden talent.
And once we find out what it is,
- we become unbeatable.
- How do we do that?
It ain't easy...
hard work and intuition.
So wh... where do we start?
Hard work.
Why are we doing this?
You have to be fast and lethal
like the swing of an axe.
Well, heck, we've been
doing this for five hours. I'm bushed!
- Can we stop?
- Got enough?
Well, I reckon this'll
get me through December.
Come on.
You can do it.
Come on!
Why can't you understand this?
My family is depending on me.
I can't just back out.
Why don't you just say what you mean?
You don't want to.
Fine, I don't!
And if I did,
I wouldn't be able to look
at myself in the face again.
After you fight with them,
you won't be able to look
at yourself in the mirror
for a long time.
- We'll see about that.
- You don't know what they're like.
They're animals!
Today they massacred
some farm workers
just for the fun of it.
Well, they'll have
a rougher time with us.
Stop being a hero, Burt.
It doesn't impress me.
Why won't you just tell me the real
reason why you don't want me to fight?
I told you.
Because it's ridiculous.
I want the real reason, Millie.
I don't want you to get hurt.
Mm-hmm.
For your punch to be
really powerful,
you have to think of going
through your opponent
like a locomotive
through a tunnel.
Okay?
Watch again.
- Through!
- What do you think, Jack?
What's with you, big brother?
- You haven't said a word to me all day.
- Shut up.
So who's first?
- Ahhh!
- Let me see.
Your wrists are too small.
Sorry, but you'll never
be able to punch hard.
I'd like to give that
a shot, Mr. West.
Mm-hmm.
- Good.
- Take that.
Why don't you have
one of these?
Easy.
Jack, take it easy.
Save it. Jack!
Watch it!
Mr. West?!
- Get him up, get him up.
- Is he all right?
Mr. West.
Mr. West?
He's breathing.
Go get Mrs. Stark!
Go! Go... Mrs. Stark!
Estrella.
Good morning, West.
How are you feeling?
I have a headache.
Did someone get me drunk?
No, you took a major hit
on the head.
I can't remember a thing.
It gave you nightmares.
You seemed quite agitated.
Did I say anything?
Estrella.
You said it over
and over again.
Is she the woman you love?
Hey, West, wahoo!
Lower your shoulder
when you go in for the hit.
- Lord, it's good to see you, West.
- It's good to see you, West.
- Sorry about your head.
- That's okay.
Let's start where we left off.
Remember what I told you
before that beam hit me?
We need to find our talent.
Yeah, that ain't easy.
- We need intuition.
- That ain't easy either.
That's right, Jack,
but I got lucky.
Intuition struck me when
that beam came down on me.
Now I know what your talents are.
I just need to be sure.
Wait.
Kick this as high as you can.
Look out, Larry.
See!?
Your legs and your feet.
This is your talent.
Let's work on it.
Jack?
Burt and Millie.
See?
You're fixated.
Fixation is your talent.
Let's use it.
But not now.
- All right, let's go to work.
- What about me?
Oh yeah.
- Think of yourself as a totem pole.
- What am I supposed to do?
Nothing.
Just stand there.
Sorry.
That was for me...
I just wanted to make sure
that I'm back.
You're back all right.
Well, I was just to Hudson City,
and you were right.
Every time Garvey
took time off,
there was a hold-up.
And the good part of it is
now we got some witnesses.
So now you can arrest him.
Well, not so fast.
I asked the federals for the wanteds
and they should be here any day.
Well, this day is here...
I've never seen so many
people before.
They're coming!
The Mitchells are coming!
Whoa.
There they are, the Bakers!
West and the Bakers.
I want to welcome everybody
to Holysand.
Now this here fight is
gonna decide
onced and for all
who's going to get that land.
- That's right!
- Allow me to remind you
there will be no weapons
allowed among the combatants
and neither among
the spectators.
Now if you still got your sidearms
with you or you got your Spencer rifles
I want you to give them to Gloria
who'll take them and put them away
till after this here contest.
Now the rules is
really simple:
This is a bare-knuckle fight,
the bare-knuckle contest.
Onliest thing we will
not look kindly on
is eye gouging.
Everything else is all right.
So if I got no more questions,
remember the last man standin'
is the winner.
Any questions?
Get it on.
Come on!
Oh!
Think of Burt and Millie.
And stay down!
Legs! Legs!
Okay, yeah.
Burt, yes!
Get up!
Yeah, that's my boys!
Well, due to the sudden
indisposition
of their adversaries,
the last men standing
are the Baker boys
which means that that land
goes in perpetuity
to the Bakers!
Whoo!
- Sheriff Basehart?
- That's me.
Sam Winchet...
Agent Sam Winchet.
I'm supposed
to deliver you these.
Thank you kindly.
Hey, Joe.
Come here, come here.
Hey, alhoot,
you're under arrest.
You're not arresting
anybody, Sheriff. Not today.
Your gun belt.
West!
The sheriff's gun!
I've had enough, West!
Gloria, give West his gun belt.
Do it!
Good.
This is between
me and you now.
Let's settle this like real men.
You and me.
Like we should've done
from the beginning.
Don't move.
No-ooo!
West!
Silver!
Oh God.
Okay.
Stay here,
stay here, Silver.
Stay here with us.
In the back.
His breathing is getting worse
and his temperature is rising.
I sent one of my men
to Hudson City to get Dr. Scottfield.
He'll never get here in time.
We have to remove the bullet now,
- otherwise...
- Oh, please, Silver can't die like this!
Nathan, Nathan,
there must be
something we can do.
Mother, there's no one
in Holysand
that can perform this kind
of an operation.
Well, yes there is.
Where is Mr. West?
West, West!
West!
Silver has to be operated on.
Can you do it?
I'm sorry, I can't.
But the bullet has to be
removed or he'll die.
You have to do it.
You're a doctor.
I was a doctor.
Remember
when you asked me if Estrella
is the woman I love?
- Yes.
- Estrella is not a woman.
She's a little girl
whose mother died
because of me.
I don't understand.
I was drunk!
I was drunk and I
operated anyway
and I killed her.
I haven't had
a drop of whiskey.
It's been 10 years
since I've picked up
a scalpel.
West, listen to me.
Destiny is giving you
a chance to make it right.
You can't back away from that.
Besides, Silver saved your life.
If you don't help him,
you'll never forgive yourself.
You can do this.
Mommy?
Estrella.
West, everything all right?
Yes.
You don't have much time.
Right.
Damnation!
It's been almost two hours.
Mrs. Stark said it
wouldn't be easy.
Let's just hope that West
knows what he's doing.
I'm sure he does.
If Silver pulls through,
I am going to bake him a pie
every day until he
can't take it anymore.
- He'll be fine!
- Oh, thank heaven!
Remember, Grandma...
a pie a day!
I'm going to get
started right away.
I don't know how
to thank you, West.
Doc West.
Dr. West.
I wouldn't be able
to forgive myself
- if he hadn't pulled through.
- Me neither.
Can we see him?
Of course. But he'll be
sleeping for a long time.
As long as he wakes up.
Denise?
I couldn't have
done this without you.
I just reminded you
that things can change...
Dr. West.
I owe you, Silver.
I owe you my life.
Thanks to you
I can believe
in myself again.
I have hope now.
Melody will
fill you with apple pie.
You deserve it.
And she's lucky...
she knows how to make you happy.
My daddy did the same thing
with me.
He'd wait till I was asleep
and then he'd tell me
he loved me.
He figured it wasn't
manly to say it,
but he just couldn't
resist it.
And you pretended
to be asleep?
Oh, that's right.
Doc,
why don't you stay?
There's so many folks here
would just love
to have you as their doctor.
You know I can't
do that, Sheriff.
As soon as Silver gets better,
I'll leave.
Mrs. Melody's really going
to make all that pie for me?
You can count on it.
Dr. West?
You're next, Doc!
Oh right.
To St. Joseph's School in Boston.
Thanks.
Hold it!
Hands up.
If I do that,
we'll drop the mail.
All right,
turn around!
It's only post.
- Dusty out there, huh?
- That's why we's wearing these.
Thanks for the tip.
Delivery.
It sure has been good
to know you, Doc.
Yep.
See that you don't have to use
those fighting lessons I taught you.
We'll try not to, Doc.
Millie, you better keep
an eye on them.
You can count
on it, Doc West.
Damnation, you're going to be
one hard man to forget, Doc.
Yeah, I bet
it'll take you at least a week.
That's a bet
you're gonna lose.
Goodbye, Doc.
Denise.
Don't say anything.
There's no need to.
You can't come with me.
Okay?
You be a good boy.
All right?
Take it easy now.
Take it easy, okay?
I'll miss you, Doc!
I tried to get him to stay.
It was no use.
That's not true.
It let him know how much
your friendship means to you.
You know, Silver,
every man has a destiny
and old Doc chose his destiny
- a long time ago.
- Sheriff Basehart!
Por favor.
- Un... doctor!
- A doctor?
Doc!
Doc West!
The End