THE LAST TRAIN
Here and here we can
take on water.
How will we tell people?
I told you. MacFerry
and De León will look after
the media side of things.
In the communique I think
we should include an urgent
request for a special tax
to increase pensions
by at least fifty percent.
I must remind you that
is not on today's agenda.
Why a special tax?
Can you make ends
meet On your pension?
My daughter maintains me.
What is all this shit?
Wouldn't you help
your daughter?
Please... we have
an agenda To keep to.
Let's vote on the plan.
I vote against.
I don't want to be considered
a supporter of this illegal act.
As the doctor is always wrong,
I vote in favour.
I don't want any
trouble with the police.
MacFerry?
In favour.
Rentería?
Against.
In favour.
It's a draw so far.
My vote is conditional.
In the statutes
there's no such thing.
Then fuck the statutes.
Language! I'll expel you...
I'll vote in favour if we
can persuade Avilés
to take charge of
the operation.
Leave that to me.
It won't come out.
It's jammed.
It won't come out?
OVIEDO TRANSPORT
You see?
What the hell
are you two doing?
Did you do your room?
Go on, hurry up, get
a move on.
Why don't you get your
things and just piss off?
No, the thing
is Guito asked me...
Hugo, not Guito.
Hugo, right...
And I need your room.
Why did your dad give
him the room free?
They were friends.
Pity about your brother.
Those chosen by the
gods die young...
I bet you didn't say that
when you were fifteen.
Worthier to die by a fascist's
bullet than in one's bed.
You're just an old fool.
It's you who's old. I'm the
same age as my hopes and dreams.
Don't tell me, I don't
feel like fighting today.
Number 33 is waiting
for somebody with balls
to restore its dignity.
Those at the association
are all the same.
I didn't come to talk
about that.
I've come to call you
to action.
You've known me for ages.
More's the pity.
You know I've always been
against acts of violence.
Well, have I or haven't I?
And, generally speaking,
violence paves
the way for repression.
But there are times in history...
That's history with a capital H...
when a violent
act is the only way out.
The only way for
decent men to show
that they refuse to go on
living on their knees.
Here.
Anyway, in short... what
the fuck do you want?
I want you to be the
knight in this heroic deed.
Number 33 is counting on you.
Then it's one salami
and two sausages.
What do you think?
No. These two.
I'll get MacFerry.
RESULTS OF TEST
Now, breathing in deeply...
And we let our whole body be
taken along by the breeze...
A gentle breeze swaying
the trees and plants...
Do you want to see
the boys or not?
Do tai chi like everyone else.
I'm not Chinese.
It was your turn yesterday.
Today it's mine.
Time for the news.
...with Jaime Ferreira Fink,
the owner of the engine,
which is to have a special
destination, right?
That's right. In ten
days' time it'll set out
for Hollywood to be
used in a film.
That's the reason for
the whole thing.
Our people have been working
on it for the last few days,
putting the finishing touches
so that it can set out.
Was the engine like this before
or was it, shall we say,
not quite so ready?
No, it was just scrap. It
was nothing but scrap,
so a lot of work with Uruguayan
labour had to be done on it,
and is still being done.
It's taken a month and a half
to make it as good as new,
as the Americans wanted.
How much did you invest?
Hello.
It's " D-Day."
Good.
Call everybody.
Hurry up. Always the same.
Come on!
Where are we going?
Did you tell your folks?
Mum...
What did the doctor say?
Nothing, nothing...
Just a nervous complaint.
Blackie! Blackie!
-What is it?
-Can we come in?
-At this time? What for?
-To steal the engine.
He's always joking...
To take some pictures
before it goes.
That'd put me
in a difficult position.
There are valuable items.
Here, take this.
Have a drink on us.
I've recorded that you're
five minutes late.
Record the kick I'm
going to give you.
Oh, I'm so scared!
This is no time for fighting.
He's provoking me.
-Shall I get the things?
-Right.
-Yes, yes.
-What's that?
-You've done it now!
-Record it.
He's the fireman.
You can't bring him along!
Why not?
Look, 33 isn't a carousel, Pepe.
Stoking's not an easy job.
Who's going to do it? You?
Your hands are used to books.
He's only a child.
We can't take him.
All right.
You're not being democratic.
You have to go along
with the majority.
If that absent-minded
old fool will stoke coal
then Guito stays here.
I've got high blood pressure.
My Sophia Loren!
Who?
Madonna, then.
My black beauty.
I'll take good care of you.
Come on, let's get moving.
So you're the
Professor's nephew.
My mother was his sister.
-Can I stop a minute? I need...
-I'm afraid not, young man.
-Just to...
-We're late as it is.
Have you passed wind?
I'm a man in control
of his sphincter.
Review your troops.
Perhaps one of your men...
My orifices respond
to natural controls.
Come on boy, wake up!
-Good, my black beauty!
-The door! The door!
As if it were made
of paper!
Gave you a fright, eh?
Grandma's last jewel
is not for sale!
Did you see them gaping?
Like a dragon was passing.
That reminds me of
a story by Bradbury.
About two mediaeval knights
on the way to the Crusades.
They see a bright light
and hear a terrible noise.
"A dragon!" says one,
raising his lance.
"Aim for the eye!"
says the other,
and bravely they both charge
at the thing approaching them.
And the train knocks
the shit out of them.
-I don't get it.
-Because you're stupid.
It's very simple.
Did you get it?
More or less...
You explain, if
you're so clever.
You wouldn't understand anyway.
Stop it!
It was a story by Bradbury.
-Ray Bradbury!
-Ray!
About a time tunnel.
The knights go from the road
onto the railway lines.
For me, the main point
is that the knights
don't hesitate,
not for a moment,
and they die fighting.
We wish to notify the public
that the " Friends of the Rails"
have decided that
locomotive number 33,
a jewel in the national crown,
be returned to the
people of Uruguay.
With this our aim,
we have decided to take
expropriational action
which will cease
only when the following
conditions are met.
One... locomotive number 33
shall be declared a
national historic monument
in order to prevent the
purchase by foreign capital
of this, the last symbol
of the once booming
railway network of our
small, dear nation.
We also demand the government
create a special...
No, no, no, not that!
-Fuck off! Keep filming.
-It's not relevant!
It's not relevant!
Right...
that's it.
Okay, Guito, pressure's up.
My black beauty with
the heart of fire!
It's not a machine,
it's a person.
With every sound, she
tells you how she feels.
And what's that?
It's a manner of speaking.
Can you hear? She's happy.
She's better than ever!
-That's phase one complete.
-Shit!
We forgot the banner.
You did. Why bother
to write things down?
-You write it down then!
-I'll stuff that down your throat!
-Come on, boys.
-Him and his notebook!
Unite, brothers.
The minutes...
Include in the minutes
our first victory!
-What's the date?
-The 22nd.
The twenty second of what?
-November.
-November. Of course.
Twenty second of November.
Come on, Pepe.
-Show me how to drive.
-Show everybody.
If the old relic dropped
dead, we'd be in the shit.
Look then. It's
really easy, a joy.
Once pressure's up,
you pull this lever
to speed up or slow down.
This lever operates the brake.
You turn this handle to the left
to reverse, and to the
right to go forward.
It's all very easy
but very important.
But really...
know what you need
most of all?
Well... Feeling.
This is the police station.
Would Mr. Jaime Ferreira Fink
please get in touch
with us urgently?
This is Inspector Ponce.
-Six-thirty a.m.
-Exactly, six-thirty a.m.
I should be in bed, not here.
Look, I know you're the
victim, but I'm in charge.
-You're in charge?
-Yes, sir.
Carlos?
This is Jimmy.
Sorry it's so early.
Really bad, my
engine's been stolen.
My engine! Yes,
you heard right.
I couldn't believe it either.
I haven't the faintest idea.
At the police station
with one of your men.
Ponce, and he isn't
showing much respect.
I'll put him on.
Here.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, yes.
If you'll allow me...
I understand, sir.
Whatever you say.
I'll put him back on.
Thanks, Carlos.
I'll let you know. I hope
everything works out.
Say hello to Estela for me.
The cameraman works for
T.V. so we let him go.
But he was an accomplice.
-We've got his details.
-The recording?
Here it is.
Thank you.
"Arrested for public
disturbance..."
In the sixties.
"Member of the
Communist Party..."
That's not a crime.
Of course not but it
gives you a clearer idea.
I want to speak
to this one alone.
I'm sorry a man your age
has got himself into
such a nasty business.
Yet we're both in this
for the same reason...
Our love of trains, right?
But the difference is that I
think you can't halt progress.
Do you really think some
politician will stand up for you?
I'm afraid not.
Manuel...
Can I call you Manuel?
Thank you.
Manuel, we both know
that when the police
go out after that engine,
anything could happen, right?
It could get violent,
and nobody wants that,
least of all me.
So I'm asking you to
cooperate with me.
Let's work out a solution
together. What do you say?
You see, I was right.
-How are you, my old chum?
-I knew you'd do it.
Over here.
Whenever you like.
OUR NATIONAL HERITAGE
IS NOT FOR SALE
What about the provisions?
The provisions?
Professor, where did
you put the food?
That was your job!
-Look in your book.
-No, not the book.
Hell and damnation!
I forgot the provisions!
Then we won't get very far.
At our age, we can
go without food.
What's the matter with
you? Are you blind?
What about the boy?
-He needs to eat!
-So why didn't you bring...?
What's your notebook for?
All right...
-For fuck's...
-What's it for?
Will you calm down,
please? Calm down!
We'll have to stop.
Stop? Where?
If he's hungry he can go.
You voted for me to
stay, so fuck off!
You've got it in for me.
I'm sorry.
It's just that I... I... I...
I... I... I...
Hello? Who's there?
Hello. Yes.
Eight years.
Who is this?
Article 178, five years for robbery,
and Article 306, three years
for conspiracy to
commit a crime.
You've got to catch
us first, Mr...?
Jimmy. You can call
me Jimmy.
Are you the police?
I'm surprised you've
forgotten, Professor.
I'm the owner of
the locomotive.
Tell me what you
want. I'm very busy.
And what do you want?
I want the progressive
forces in our country
to stop this ignominious sale.
Give me a progressive's name
and you can ring him and ask
him what he's going to do.
Listen, Professor.
You know this is madness.
That's what they said when
the Bastille was stormed.
This isn't a history lesson,
Professor. It's a crime.
And you can't win.
Then why bother to call me?
I don't want any bloodshed.
Now you listen to me.
If any blood's shed,
the press will be very interested.
Talking of the press, your
nephew's video's pretty bad.
You're an educated man.
Admit it's all over.
I don't know if you
realise, young man,
that I'm talking to you
from an engine
that's going at full speed. Listen!
And I'm talking to you
from a police car
that's on the way to arrest you.
Cooperate like De
León and MacFerry did.
-That's a lie!
-Me?
Professor, tell that gentleman
who was born in Oviedo
to mind his language.
I didn't raise my voice.
Professor, give me the
engine back
and I'll try and
sort things out for you.
Or I'll leave things to agent
Ponce who's with me here.
He's the chief of the riot
squad and a very efficient man.
Know what I mean?
You can tell that Ponce
that if his men lay
a finger on this engine,
I'll turn it into scrap!
Do you hear? Pepe!
-What are you doing?
-They got those silly old fools...
You should look at yourself.
Then it's Plan B.
It's Plan Z for me.
Are all Asturians like him?
-As excessive as him, you mean?
-Yes, excessive, extensive...
-Mad! For goodness sake!
-Guito, come here.
You've got good eyesight.
Help me look for the battery.
-What's up, Pepe?
-We have to slow down.
The line's fucked.
Antonio?
Our love is so vast
that it never ends,
and life so short
it is not
enough for our idyll.
Ponce.
What's he doing?
His duty.
What's the gun for?
He always carries one
in cases like this.
Remember this is a
bunch of old men.
I don't think so.
You hear of the occasional
senile old man with a gun.
Last month a pensioner
fired a shotgun at us.
There's no way I'll
risk my men's lives.
Did you know that
dishonourable discharge
means loss
of all entitlements,
including a pension?
Boys, put your guns away.
Might scare the old fogeys.
Now what are you doing?
Look, is this a gang of
crazy old men or what?
If they are, they'll
stop when they see this.
And if they don't know how?
I don't want
my engine damaged.
Either we let them through
or we try to stop them.
My dad was a miner.
So for my brother
and me, explosives
were something we
knew all about.
How did you use them?
That's where
the engine came in.
We'd go out at night
looking for Franco's men.
It was my job to drive
the engine at full speed.
We'd appear, like the
dragon in the story
the Professor told, remember?
I can still hear their
bullets on the engine...
What did you do?
My brother and the militia
hid with the fuses lit,
and as we went past...
Of course, after a
time word of our tactics got out,
and one night they were waiting
for us with an anti-tank gun.
The police! The police!
What's that on the line, Pepe?
Here they come.
Brake, brake!
Brake, Pepe, brake!
Brake, for fuck's sake! Brake!
Fuck them!
Did you see the boy?
-What boy?
-The boy!
Guito!
Come and stoke.
-Almost derailed us!
-But we're serious.
You forgot the boy!
That was irresponsible
of you, Pepe.
But really...
full of poetry.
As Gandhi would say,
"Caught them with
their trousers down."
You break my balls because I
don't bring the kid any food,
and you congratulate
this madman
for almost getting us killed!
I feel like getting off now!
Pepe, we're going
to have to stop.
We really are.
If the media don't hear about
this, there's no point to it.
Stop? Have you gone mad?
What if the T.V. cameras had
been back there with the police?
Everybody would be talking
about what we're doing.
And that's what
we want, isn't it?
Let me see...
Perhaps there.
At this station.
-It's isolated.
-That's what I mean.
-How far is it?
-20 minutes away.
Look, the thing with
the police car worked out
but it might not have.
Mind you, they
know we're serious now
so it'll be harder next time.
It's a risk we have to take.
Pepe, Guito can't
stay here with us.
Okay, you're right.
Guito can get off
whenever you like.
And I'll get off with him.
Kramer, we could divert
them after that bend.
-Where is the bend?
-There.
-And after it?
-A siding.
Ponce, imagine
you get home one day
and find thieves inside.
Do you set
fire to the house?
Not a bad idea.
We did that once.
-Your house?
-No, the man who called us.
I said your house.
A few flames
wouldn't do any harm.
They'd shit
themselves and stop.
You've no idea how
much an engine costs.
-Well, actually...
-Yes?
I don't.
A lot and I don't want
it stuck in a siding.
Understand?
We need to use something
you obviously don't have.
We're very well
equipped, Ferreira.
Really?
This genetic equipment...
even with a brain
transplant you'd fail.
Put police along the line to
stop them taking on water.
Find the old men's relatives
and the boy's parents.
Why so much fuss?
And look up " genetic"
in the dictionary.
Haven't you got
anything thicker?
No, I've sold out of those,
but these are very popular.
Don't know if they're
any good to me.
Trouble with the bladder?
I had a prostate operation
and I leak a bit now.
So two litre bottles of water
and did you slice
the salami thick?
-Yes, sir.
-Good.
You're okay, you're a
journalist.
Yes, uncle, but it's a
wonder they didn't keep me in.
Look, Daniel. Do you
want to be a second-rate
cameraman the
rest of your life?
Then this is your chance to
make people look at you.
Breaks like this one only come
along or times in a lifetime.
-Yes, but...
-I love you,
that's why I'm telling you.
Stop shitting your pants, you
were born with a pair of balls.
What do you want me to do?
They took the video off you,
so go and tell your
people what you saw.
What you witnessed.
-They stole the engine?
-Yes.
-Where's the video?
-Police headquarters, I think.
-What do you mean you think?
-At police headquarters.
Who are you calling?
Our contact there,
who do you think?
I beg you, fellow countrymen...
Spread the news.
Tell the world that a
sepoy from the east,
in connivance with
the American empire,
would deprive us of
this thing of beauty.
He wants to sell it!
Taking it forever
beyond our frontiers!
I beg you! I beg you!
Good news and
not so good news.
The not so good first.
The professor's
wife can't be found.
So an old lady's too
much for your men?
Those men have picked
the boy's parents up.
Yes.
I was lucky enough to film
the engine being driven away.
Montecarlo is the only channel to
have had access to the footage.
Let's see a preview.
This means your job, Ponce.
-I'll have you fired.
-It wasn't me.
-Wasn't you?
-I was with you all the time.
I'll open an inquiry to
see who's responsible.
So it wasn't you? I
prefer a bent copper
to an idiot who can't
control his people.
Hello? This is Jimmy.
Give me Channel Four's number,
please. The direct line.
Yes... It doesn't
matter, Ramírez.
You open the inquiry.
How much did you get?
You're an idiot, Ramírez.
A scoop like that
is worth much more.
No...
Call and say you got it wrong.
First of all...
Guito.
Then this pain in the neck.
And this is mine. Professor.
Did you only buy salami? Why?
Because I like it.
You could have got
some fat-free cheese.
At our age so much fat is bad.
At our age, all's good...
The arteries in
your head are clogged
from all the crap you eat!
I prefer that to just
eating boiled vegetables.
Professor, you know I've got
nothing in common with this idiot.
But this time,
it breaks my heart to
say that he's right.
This salami is marvellous.
It's wonderful.
Ah, do what you like!
Who am I to lecture you on the
connection between a bad diet
and heart disease...
You'll find out for yourselves.
Here.
You're from this generation.
See if you can work this out.
Is that it?
Things like that make me feel
like a useless old fool.
Thanks, kid.
Dani, please. Thanks.
Dani?
Really?
Great, Dani.
My sister, wherever she is,
would be proud of you.
Gentlemen.
Phase two completed with
total and absolute success.
Thousands of people just
saw this mighty machine
break down the
doors of its prison.
What do they want now?
I don't know, but
they'll try and board us.
They can't. They'd
need a bridge for that.
We must let Guito off.
You know that very well.
They're trying to put pressure on.
It's leaking.
Mr. Secretary,
did you buy that sealant?
Here.
What the hell's this?
Glue.
But it says it's for false teeth!
One of the hardest
things to stick.
The bastard!
He gives me this crap!
Give it here.
What needs sealing,
apart from this argumentative
fanatic's mouth?
Well?
What have you got to say?
It was a fluke.
But then, that's typical
of silly old fools.
We're absolutely devastated.
We'd always treated
Pepe like family.
We gave him a room,
and look what he did, taking
our son, making him steal...
I don't really think these people's
pain was in the plans of those
who took the engine.
They're not hardened criminals,
just a group of senile old men.
They're all on medication.
They're mainly
a danger to themselves.
I ask all Uruguayans of goodwill
to cooperate with the authorities,
who are doing everything they can.
Inspector, what's being done to
recover the engine?
As long as the boy
is on board,
our main aim is to try
to recover the locomotive
without anyone getting hurt.
Right, well thank you all.
Who's that?
My wife.
Your wife? Aren't you
too old to be married?
What do you mean?
All the men of
your age that I know...
are widowers.
What about Pepe?
He's single.
He's much younger than you.
And why were
you looking at her?
Because I like to.
I wanted to see
a thing of beauty.
She's got a nice face.
Look, if you don't like her,
just tell me so. It's okay.
Careful, Guito.
Leave Micaela alone or
you'll be in trouble.
She's not ugly...
That's something.
Come on then, name a woman
you think is beautiful.
My mother...
Not now,
but in pictures before
she was married.
She looked like a film star.
It's true, Prof,
what he's saying.
When she was 20 years old,
she took your breath away.
She's less pretty now.
It's my dad's fault.
Why do you say that?
He's always shouting at her,
calling her names,
nagging at her...
There are ups and
downs in all marriages.
Did you call your wife names?
No, it's not my style,
although I expect I've
hurt her inadvertently.
I don't want my mum to
go on living like that.
She's always crying.
Guito, come here.
There's nothing to be
ashamed of, you know...
Know how many people
I saw cry in the war?
Big men with balls
like elephants...
When night fell,
they remembered their
families and cried.
And then the next day,
they were risking
their lives again...
Who said men don't cry?
Come here.
Come and see this.
Look.
The bastards are emptying
the water towers.
Now that's just immoral,
wasting water with so
much drought in the world.
When were
the police ever moral?
Don't overdo it, Pepe.
I was just stating a fact.
Have we got enough water?
We've got enough
for two hours flight.
-Planes don't take on water.
-It was a metaphor,
for God's sake. Have you
forgotten what " metaphor" means?
Metaphor is when
I mean " stupid"
and I say " Pepe" instead.
You must give me the name
of the tablets you're taking.
Wait, wait. Here.
I can't remember the name.
Sometimes I forget
the simplest things
and other times I remember in a
flash, like the metaphor thing.
I don't know what it means
but Finadita used to say
it when she taught at home.
I don't know.
I told you... another fluke.
I really got his back up.
Look, Pepe,
whether by luck or the tablets,
the thing is he demolished you.
Look, there's
a mobile T.V. unit.
The banners!
Where are they?
Shall I brake or go on?
Slow down, but don't stop.
There might be
some police there.
Right! Four... three...
Damn it!
Fucking hell...!
You kidnapped the boy.
What? Is he a hostage?
I'm a member of the group!
Your mother's really upset.
Saying we kidnapped him is vile.
He's a minor.
His parents said
you just took him.
What do you call that?
-You want to know?
-Yes.
This is a set-up
arranged by that sepoy
to get rich on the
country's heritage.
That's what I call it.
Do I look like a kidnapper?
Look at me!
I don't know about that,
but... they want the boy back.
He's right.
We're just common kidnappers.
Guito.
You have to get off.
No, Pepe,
don't listen to those fools.
This is like in the war, Guito.
It's the enemy's final offensive.
You see?
Like Franco's men
they're better equipped
and have the advantage.
But the train has
to go to Brazil.
Yes, that's a great idea
and I'll bear that in mind,
but we shan't be
able to do it that way, Guito.
You see, it's so
easy to stop a train.
They stopped my train
near Gijón, you remember
I told you that?
He who fights and runs away,
lives to fight another day,
you remember?
The Professor said something
very important before.
We have to win the
battle in the press.
He's right.
That's why you have to get off.
The radio and T.V. stations
will be after you like
you were a big star.
You realize how
powerful that makes you?
First I'll say that
I wasn't kidnapped.
Fine, fine.
And it's really important
you learn our slogan,
so that when
they interview you
you can mention it, slip
it into the conversation.
It doesn't matter what
happens to us now.
Even if they
stop us the main thing
is for you to say
everything we couldn't.
Now's the time, Pepe.
It's been a pleasure.
Private Guito, our
fate is in your hands.
We know you'll win us victory.
My friend,
off you go,
and take care, eh?
You too.
Look after the old men...
I will.
First on the scene,
Montecarlo has good news
for the boy's parents.
Nobody kidnapped me.
Then why
were you on the train?
To stoke the boiler.
-You could have got burned.
-No.
I did what all
Uruguayans should do.
Make the
engine stay in Uruguay.
How come your men can't
find the Professor's wife?
In a few minutes...
More like 2,000 or 3,000 minutes.
With all the fuss over the kid,
we can't wait for
the water to run out.
There's a tunnel there,
and it's on a bend.
You get the idea?
Promise me the locomotive
won't be damaged.
I'm not an insurance company,
but I think we have a
99% chance of success.
And I don't want any martyrs.
If anything happens to them
I stand to lose a
lot more than you.
What are you looking for?
I've forgotten the
name. I can't find it...
Whose name?
His.
I can't remember
what he's called.
José Avilés.
What do we call him?
Pepe.
Can you remember my name?
Come on, say it.
Antonio López,
alias " the Professor."
You'll have to come
along with us, madam.
Moraes, you go with Núñez.
They're coming.
They mustn't see us.
-Can we go any faster?
-We're at full speed.
And there's a bend.
Get into position!
Fox One and Two ready.
Hands up!
-This is dynamite.
-Drop it!
Come on, or we all go up.
He's got a 27, he's got a 27!
Abort mission!
Get rid of that, Pepe.
Fucking hell! Get
rid of it, you damned fool!
-Since you ask so nicely.
-Yes...
It's a miracle!
A miracle!
Professor, how could you
think I'd bring along
real dynamite with
Guito on board?
If we were at war,
I suppose I might.
Did you see
those cops jump?
Look, I'm not Guito
so stop talking rubbish.
We all know you
weren't in any war.
I was!
You were a babe in arms.
If you were
a teenager in 1936,
you'd be at least
85 years old now.
So what? The boy loves
listening to my stories.
One day, Pepe, you'll
have to tell Guito
the real hero was your
older brother and not you.
Out of all fairness
to your brother.
And Guito doesn't love
you just for that.
What a bastard you are!
A 99% chance of success!
You and your men
are a dead loss.
And if you weren't
so tight-fisted...
-What do you mean?
-Our intelligence service
tells me the insurance covers
the engine once aboard ship.
Otherwise we could
stop it right now.
Well they're wrong.
The engine's covered here
by a foreign company.
It's not a question of money,
but prospects for
the future. Get it?
It doesn't look like it.
I wouldn't go.
With 100% efficiency my men are
bringing the Professor's wife.
Kramer!
Are you tired?
Where are we?
Coming to Chamberlain.
The water just held out!
My hand's falling off.
Mincho's cantina.
Look, that's me.
The strike of '49
A grand strike.
They sent battering rams.
Poor wretches,
we kicked their backsides.
Where can we get water here?
You know who I am?
I'm the Professor.
And he's Pepe.
I don't know...
I'm the Professor,
and he's Pepe.
What's my name?
Dante.
Dante Minetti.
Don't worry, you're
among friends.
The Professor,
Pepe,
and Dante...
You're Dante, remember?
-Say it, " I'm Dante."
-What am I doing here?
We were riding
with the Professor
and the boy, Guito, on
the engine, remember?
No. I want to go...
You want to go?
I'm hungry.
What would you like?
Noodles and pesto.
We can manage that.
Come on,
let's go and have some
noodles and pesto.
What are we going to do?
He should see a doctor.
I don't think
much can be done.
Nothing at all.
The same thing
happened to my mother.
So now what?
It's okay, we're here to help.
We saw you pass.
Thanks.
Thanks very much.
Can we take on
water around here?
Of course, come with us.
Come with us, please.
Right.
This is the geriatrics
department.
Tell them to call his son.
-Give me a hand, Prof.
-Hey.
Still feel like
noodles and pesto?
Look, you see this gentleman?
His wife makes the best
pesto for miles around.
Yes, she's a great pesto expert.
Go with them, eat all
the noodles you want,
and Pepe and I will
come back for you.
Come on then.
Promise me something.
What?
If I ever get like that,
please push me under a bus.
But he's happier
than he ever was.
Yes, but it's not him any
more, Professor.
We're the sum of
our experiences.
Yes, but if all you experience
is suffering, what's the point?
What's up with you?
What are you saying?
I see it.
Did they take on water?
Affirmative.
Damn it!
We're on our way,
notify all units.
Professor!
Listen to me, you bastard!
Antonio, it's me.
Micaela?
What are you doing with him?
I wanted to hear your voice.
You didn't tell
me about the doctor.
I left you a letter, Micaela.
About very important
things for me...
It's you who's important.
I don't want to lose you.
And I don't want to end
up like a vegetable.
Professor López.
I expect you've heard
of the famous
-Mayo clinic in America?
-So?
It specializes in the
treatment you need.
You could be flying there
with your wife tomorrow...
Now you listen here.
If I wanted an operation
I'd go to Montevideo.
I don't want any surgeon
talking foreign to me.
Understand?
Science knows no
languages, just results.
And your wife's already told me
she wants you to go where
results are guaranteed.
Antonio,
I'll always be there.
I love you, my darling!
I love you.
When this is all over,
I'll kick you into the
operating room if necessary.
All under control, sir. They
won't leave the country.
Fine.
Divert them.
Fucking bastards!
What is it?
We're going into a siding.
You'll have to get off.
I'm staying on.
You're useless with the brakes.
When we've stolen 2 or 3 more,
you'll see how useless I am.
You're under arrest,
in accordance with Articles 178
and 192, and 306, Section One.
Come along with us.
Techera, take the
lady to the van.
Well, did we stop them or not?
Your work's not over.
Clear the line. The engine
goes back to Montevideo.
That's your problem.
It's Montevideo for the prisoners.
Listen, Ponce...
Ponce!
-Where are you taking them?
-Not now!
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's all over.
Please clear the line.
The engine's going
back to Montevideo,
so please clear the line.
Will you do that?
NUMBER 33 NEVER
WENT TO HOLLYWOOD
AS THE DELIVERY DATES EXPIRED.
JIMMY IS STILL ON THE LOOKOUT
FOR FOREIGN BUSINESS DEALS.
THE PROFESSOR NEVER
WENT TO JAIL
DUE TO HIS DELICATE
STATE OF HEALTH.
AFTER A HEART OPERATION
HE NOW LIVES HAPPILY WITH
HIS WIFE AND HIS BOOKS.
FOR HEALTH REASONS,
CHARGES AGAINST THE
SECRETARY WERE ALSO DROPPED.
HE WENT BACK TO
THE OLD PEOPLE'S HOME,
WHERE HE DOES TAI CHI.
GUITO'S PARENTS
DROPPED ALL CHARGES
FOR KIDNAPPING
AGAINST JOSÉ AVILÉS.
AFTER SERVING SIX MONTHS,
HE WAS RELEASED
FOR GOOD BEHAVIOR.
HE STILL USES HIS VAN
FOR TRANSPORTATION.
GUITO'S ONLY DREAM
IS TO DRIVE TRAINS.