I've an announcement to make and
I find it very painful.
I'm unable to continue
this history course.
But as you perhaps know
it's not a matter of my own volition.
However, the study of history can be
suspended and resumed at any point.
Because
though all men must die in time,
other men will make history live.
And each man can choose
his own part in history.
We've been forced to choose.
When the war between the States
declared that we were either
Union loyalists or Confederate rebels.
You are twenty years old.
You will have to choose, many times,
between just and unjust,
truth and untruth.
And always the answer is
only to be found
within you.
And if this small bit of knowledge
can help you in the future,
then I'm truly privileged
for my part in history
will not have been useless.
The class is dismissed. Thank you.
My dear Professor Fletcher. Miss Wilkins
I and I look forward to your return.
I hope you're not disappointed.
Come, come, Fletcher.
You're not as sick as all that.
Tomorrow you'll be far away from this
horrible climate. You'll feel differently.
I feel sure your lungs will improve
as soon as you put your foot in,
Texas. And you'll come back here
to Boston completely recovered.
Yes sir, no doubt.
You talk as though you don't care.
And I must say, given your intelligence,
you should have gone far,
a lot farther than you have.
But I'm not complaining.
That's just the trouble.
You have no ambition.
That's why you've never been promoted.
In this country there are no limits
for the man who is willing to fight.
You've never struggled against
the position fate has put you in.
But that is what you must do now,
more than ever.
Well, I'm late for class.
Have a good trip.
Goodbye, Dean.
Well, Miss Wilkins...
He's probably right about me, you know.
Well, I don't believe him. Professor.
That's good of you, Elizabeth.
Are you asleep. Professor?
No, but very nearly.
I couldn't sleep last night
because of you and your Paco
raising Cain in the next bedroom.
Why, Professor, I do not understand,
My dear, I don't believe you.
El amor, it is not wrong.
You do not think it is wrong to love,
do you, Professor?
Because Paco has gone away,
and I feel so lonely.
Lonely?
Who'd be coming up here?
Get out, go on!
Get down there where you belong!
Give us a little drink,
something nice and cool.
Sheriff! This half breed,
he looks like Beauregard Bennet!
It ain't no affair of yours.
Hurry up, we're thirsty!
But, Sheriff, maybe this could turn out
to be an affair of mine
if we have a visit from Bennet's amigos.
All his amigos are underground.
That is, except for one
who escaped our ambush! Zachary Shawn.
But we'll get him too
and then the Bennet gang is through.
Water!
Don't talk so much and
you won't get thirsty.
Just a minute.
Hey you, what do you
think you're doing?
I'm going to give him a drink.
Hold it! You're doing nothing
for that man.
All members of a civilized society
have fundamental human rights.
What's the guy talking about?
Quien sabe, sheriff. He's a professor
from the East. He reads a lot of books.
Well, Professor,listen to me.
That man's a cheap killer.
Keep your philosophy for someone else.
A killer, eh?
You see, in this country nobody can
be presumed guilty of a crime
before a correctly constituted court
of law declares that guilt proven.
All right, all right, spare me the
lecture, give him a drink.
Thank you.
Drop your guns or I'll kill him!
You, get on the coach and
start going as soon as we're inside.
Go on,
Mas suerte!
I, uh, I'm afraid you could hardly
have made a worse choice of hostage.
I'm terribly ill,
it's the lungs you know.
Yeah? But the sheriff's men didn't know.
Go faster, go!
What for?
You might as well be dead
if you're so sick.
I?
But I'm, I might recover, after all,
I mean it's possible!
And even if I don't, this doesn't
make sense. I've never done you any harm.
You have no reason to kill me.
Yeah, you're right. Why kill a dead man.
Anyway, I may need
an extra bullet some time.
How are you feeling?
I'm feeling like I have a bullet
in my guts, that's how I'm feeling.
I did the best I could.
I put you on one of the horses,
but then after nightfall I got lost.
In the morning I found this stream and
I thought maybe I could clean that wound.
No, don't. In your condition,
you shouldn't move.
Then lemme die, leave me alone.
I wouldn't leave my
worst enemy here like this.
Besides, where do you want me to go?
I don't even know where I am right now.
I know a hideout.
If you could get me to it.
Where?
Well, haven't much choice I guess.
Take my gun. Professor.
Why?
Take it, I said!
Aim for the side,
where the chain joins the manacle,
Yes, but how do you fire this?
Pull back the hammer!
Haven't you ever fired a gun?
This thing? That could
be dangerous, couldn't it?
Yes, Professor, it could.
And remember, it's loaded. And
it shoots when you pull the trigger.
Try again,
that's it.
Get closer,
here.
Look under the floorboards
beside the far window.
What's the matter?
I'm coughing, I mustn't exert myself.
Don't let me down,
you bastard, when I need you!
Do what I say!
Under the floor,
near the window;
use that axe:
break the boards!
Go on,
get moving!
Break that board!
Break it. Professor.
That's right!
Now lift it out!
What's the matter with you?!
Hurry!
I can't, I can't,
I'm not well, I can't do it!
You gotta do it, I tell you! You gotta!
Lift it out!
I can't, I'm too weak.
Sure you can.
That's right, lift it out.
There's something hidden under here.
It's full of supplies,
guns, medicines,
Yes, I know, Professor.
I know.
Put that bottle down.
Now do what I tell you.
Put the blade of the knife in the wound.
Make it bigger if you have to until you
feel the point begin to scrape the bullet.
That's it! You felt it.
Go on! That's it, hurry!
Shove the blade in! Go on! I said!
Are you afraid? Further in!
No... please, I can't do it,
I can't do it!
Look at that!
Look at it!
It wanted to kill me, look.
Now that it's out I'm going
to live! I'll live! Understand?!
Excellent shot.
Only I'm still too slow.
Too slow? I'd say
you were a pretty fast draw.
There's plenty of space on Boot Hill
for pretty fast draws.
Ever since I was ten I spent two hours
every day practising to be fastest.
Since you were ten, huh?
Your life would have been very different
if you'd devoted all that time to books.
If you'd used it
training your brain to think
instead of practising
how to draw a pistol.
There's no doubt that holding it
gives one a curious sense of power.
It seems so natural,
as though it had become part of me.
Look, Beau, I hit it!
I aimed at it and I hit it.
Good!
It was easy.
There goes our dinner! Get it!
Look!
What's the matter? Didn't you ever
eat rabbit back East.
Yes, of course, although
we have someone else do the killing
for us and we don't think about it.
Besides, out here in the West
it's difficult to distinguish
the instinct for survival
from the lust to acquire power.
Why do you want to worry
about things like that?
It's impossible for me to stop thinking.
For example, we have plenty of provisions.
Therefore You could easily
have spared that rabbit.
Over here.
What are you going to do?
Do you know him?
No, and I don't want him to know me.
Are you crazy? Put that away!
It's not like shooting a rabbit.
I'll get rid of him.
Hi, there, stranger!
I didn't hear you coming,
but you're welcome.
It's a real pleasure to see another human
being after all these weeks alone here.
What can I do for you, friend?
You can take me to Beauregard.
What?
Who's Beauregard?
Solomon Bennet,
known as Beauregard.
Tell him I wanna talk.
But I don't know who you are.
Shut up.
And you, take off your gunbelt.
I'm Siringo, Charley Siringo.
So I finally found you, didn't I, Beau?
How did you find me?
I looked around.
I heard that Bennet's Raiders
used to have one of their hide-outs
around here somewhere.
What do you want?
I wanna work for you, wanna help
you reorganize Bennet's Raiders.
That's what you have in mind, isn't it?
We'll begin with Zachary Shawn.
Once he's out of jail,
collect the other boys, and as for the
dead... huh, replace them. How about it?
D' you wanna do it?
You really think I'm going to accept
just anybody who offers to join?
No,
but then I'm
not just anybody.
These posters are my references.
This is my good luck charm
from my first sheriff.
Did you ever hear talk of the
Pinkertons?
Sure, it's a private detective agency.
Well, of all the lawmen on my trail
these days, they're the most troublesome.
They could make up a story like yours.
I understand.
But this'll prove that I don't have
anything to do with them.
A Pinkertons' man would've shot the
both of you by now. Who'd stop him?
I would.
I admit you're plenty smart and that's
the main reason why I want to work for you.
I'm afraid not.
I haven't begun my recruiting
and maybe I never will.
All right.
I'm a very patient type. If you want me,
all you have to do is whistle.
I'll probably be
near enough to hear you.
What are you doing?
Clearing out.
I don't want any more visitors.
Must we?
This is a good place.
D' you think so?
Then why don't you stay here.
Yes,
I might.
Because you're going to begin doing
what that fellow said: getting Bennet's
Raiders together again, aren't you?
That's natural.
Natural?
You picked the right word. Naturally
a wild beast returns to violence,
creeps out of the hole where he's
been licking his wounds and
joins the pack again.
You're an animal, incapable of thought.
You kill people from sheer stupidity.
Tell me: what would you do
if you were stronger than I am, Brad?
Oh, don't cry,
it's nothing.
You have a different kind of strength
and you have it here, not here.
Listen, you know what
we're going to do now?
I have to meet one of the boys
in Purgatory City.
Tomorrow there's a train.
You be on it and clear out.
Get me? You should go back East!
Good morning.
I'd like a room so I can rest.
I'm waiting for the train.
I see,
well, if you don't have anything,
where else could I try?
You are the owner, I presume?
Number Eight.
Uh, thank you.
That man who was smiling, who is he?
Oh, just someone who smiles.
We're pretty friendly people
here in Purgatory City.
We prefer someone who smiles at us,
especially if he's carrying a gun.
But when a fellah
who looks like the spit
and image of Beauregard Bennet
rides into town,
carrying a gun and not smiling,
then we begin to worry.
Where can I find a fellah
called Aaron Chase?
Nobody knows?
I'm talking to you.
I know he lives around here.
He do and he don't, Mr. Bennet.
You see that! Now Briggs is
taking him to see Williams.
And who's Williams?
Why, I'm just an ordinary citizen who's
preoccupied about one of our problems here,
You see, Bennet, for months now in
Purgatoy City we've had a terrible time.
A certain Sam Taylor
has hired a bunch of gunmen and
murderers and with this gang's support
he's managed to gain control of
the entire community.
Listen, I only came here
because your man said you'd tell me
where I could find my friend Aaron.
Outside, Briggs,
The two things are connected.
You see, Taylor controls the sheriff
and the sheriff controls your friend.
In jail?
That's right. But you won't find him in
the local jail. He's really well-hidden.
and I know their hiding-place.
So what?
So, one good turn deserves another.
You restore freedom in Purgatory City.
In return, I promise the freedom
of your friend Aaron,
plus a little sum from my fellow-citizens
as an expression of gratitude:
say, five thousand dollars.
They put a small price on gratitude.
Very well, will you accept
if I double it?
Muy bien.
Taylor is out of town.
He's not due till tomorrow.
You should take advantage of that.
Take advantage of it?
Get rid his gang before he comes back,
Now be careful. Don't get me wrong.
This is a peaceful city.
You must avoid a massacre.
Whoa, In a case like this,
the only person you kill
is the boss and that breaks up the gang.
Do you know who leads them?
Oh yes. Reagon. That hombre's a
mad killer, extremely dangerous.
But, Bennet, what are you
planning to do?
You know best, I'm sure. You're the
expert but remember, Mr. Bennet,
one only one.
Sorry, Senora Reagon,
nothing personal. Just business.
Howdy, sheriff.
I need your help, amigo.
I got a list here of people
who have to leave town within an hour.
Why, there's my name!
"I want you all out of town
within the hour,"
"And if you're not, I'll come and get you
one by one." Those were his very words.
What a man!
Yes, and I never expected this.
It shows nobility of character.
But where are the others?
There aren't any.
What's that? He's alone?
Yes.
Hello.
Thought you'd left by now.
Mm, not yet. My train doesn't pull out
for at least a couple more hours.
I'm just killing time.
Anyway, if they see there're
two of us, they'll think twice.
No thanks.
If any shooting starts,
you'd be right in my way.
Professor, you know what you should do.
You should keep out of this. Understand.
Go and get your train.
You better go back home right now, Brad.
Mr. Williams!
What do you want, Briggs?
I wish you wouldn't bother me right now.
But Mr. Taylor's here.
Taylor!
Well, bring him in at once.
Excuse my clothes.
Naturally I was greeted with the news
the minute that I arrived.
There was no time for me to change.
No need to apologize.
You're the boss around here, eh?
But I hear that the fellow you
got working for you now is actually
Beauregard Bennet.
Bennet, yes.
However,
your boys are all real smart.
Of course.
This should be most interesting.
You have a beautiful view from here.
Excellent.
Briggs, another chair.
Ah, I believe the performance
is about to begin,
Here we are.
On time like I promised you.
And now me and the boys'll be
on our way nice and quiet.
But I gotta say one thing:
the folks in this town sure
are ungrateful.
We tried to help them
and look how they treat us.
Stay where you are.
Hey, you scared? What's the matter?
See, my gun's over there.
I, I only want to return this star.
Thanks.
Buenas dias, Aaron.
What do you say
we look up some of the boys?
Sure, Beau.
Will you sign my notebook.
Professor Fletcher?
Reckon you put paid to quite a few,
eh, Professor?
Do you always shoot'em in the front?
You got a price on your head, too?
Why don't you stay here. You'd make a
better sheriff than the one we got now.
Have a good trip, Professor!
And forget the West!
Vamos!
All aboard!
Hey you! That's my horse!
Wait, wait! I'm coming with you!
You better not do anything rash, friend,
that fellah's a gunman.
He works for Beauregard Bennet.
Hey, Vance, you see him. That's Brad.
He's smarter than the
two of you put together.
You might even I earn something.
Pleased to meet you.
Thanks, Vance. My pleasure.
Anybody know where Zachary's got to?
No, but I know where Jason is.
He had to find work.
Yippy!
Hey, the Professor can sure pick'em.
Gimme that.
That must be at
I east a thousand dollars.
More, more, a lot more.
"Dear Son. We managed to sell the house,
and here's the money for you.
Don't mind about us.
Your Ma and me are pretty old.
Old people don't need very much.
All we care about is you."
Shut up, Brad!
I can read another.
There're more.
Shut up, I said!
Of course it might make you begin to
think and that would be terrible for you.
If you want to leave, I don't mind.
I wish I could.
But I've burnt my bridges too soon,
I have no choice now.
Beauregard,
Beau, but I've been so worried about you.
Howdy, Belle.
This is Brad Fletcher.
Madam.
The others?
They'll get here.
Where's your brother?
He's out after a runaway slave.
Ah dear Mr. Fletcher is from the North.
You looked worried hearing me say "slave".
I suppose yo'd prefer the word "servant".
But a word doesn't change anything.
Nobody'll ever make us change, not even this
Lincoln,
our emancipator. Your pardon, Mr. Fletcher,
even if you're a Yankee,
because you came here with our
Beauregard and you're a gentleman too.
But don't blush.
We're happy to have you as a guest here, in
the ancestral mansion of the De Winton's.
I propose Beauregard,
long may he remain with us;
and I propose Zachary,
may his days in jail be short.
And I propose Bennet's Raiders,
about to ride again!
And I propose the South!
With your permission, Fletcher.
At the De Winton's?
Sure of that, boy?
Of course I'm sure; real sure,
Sheriff. You know why?
Miss Belle keep call in' him Beau
an Mister Max call him Bennet.
Forget it.
Forget what?
I said Forget about Bennet.
Get out. Boy! You're joking, Siringo.
I can prove anything that Max De Winton
is working with Bennet's Raiders,
and capture Beau himself.
And collect a big fat
reward for yourself,
but all the same, you should forget it.
You Pinkerton's men all think
you're something special, don't you?
Yes sir. You got money, a good job,
connections in the government.
You think you can get away with
anything, but
you can't give orders to a sheriff.
Try to understand. Sheriff.
Look, I've had several chances
to catch Beauregard.
I've been following him for months.
But I haven't done it
because he's been trying to round up
some of his former friends.
When they're all together
that'll be the time to arrest Beauregard
and his whole gang with him.
And put an end to
Bennet's Raiders for good.
Smart plan you cooked up, Siringo.
Only Beauregard Bennet is going
to be my prisoner, Mister.
I'm going to De Winton's to arrest him.
And you'd better keep out of my way!
Yep, I better keep out of your way.
I know this isn't very inciting for you,
talking with me here all evening but
there's something I really have
to show you, something very dear to me.
That's part of
a Confederate Cavalry scarf.
That's right. I gave it to my fiance
before he left for Gettysburg.
Gettysburg. You have my sympathy.
It was the only time
I've been in love, that once.
To have been in love once is
something to be thankful for.
Not everyone is that fortunate.
This is the only memento I have now.
Belle.
Listen, old girl, don't begin
that old story again.
You know it only makes you sad. Then I
have to work so hard to cheer you up.
Mister Bennet, would you please
leave this room. Yours is next door.
As usual, no? With the
connecting door. What's wrong?
Oh, I get it.
You don't want him to know.
It'd make a bad... impression, eh?
But you don't have to worry Belle.
Brad's a gentleman.
Aren't you, Brad?
I suppose I must be. So far.
But, ah,
I think I'm learning.
I already told you, Beauregard, I'd
never be too far away to hear you.
But for all I know it might have been
you who told the sheriff that I was here.
Forget it. If it was me though,
would I warn you now.
Maybe.
I wanna think about it.
Hold it, Bennet! Don't move!
You too. Max!
Everyone stay where you are! We've got
you all covered! Don't move, I said.
Unfasten your gunbelts real slow and
don't make any mistakes!
Siringo, my instinct warns me
not to have faith in a man like you,
but the Professor here says
don't trust your instincts, he says.
The brain is really all that matters
and it will consider
true whatever the eyes see.
All right, boys,
this here's Charlie Siringo.
He's with us.
Puerta de Fuego.
Beau!
Welcome home, Beau. We been doing a
heap of worrying about you.
I know who you're looking for, but
Zachary ain't arrived. Sure as shootin'
the vigilantes
bushwacked him on the trail and
God knows where the took him.
Bourbon.
Thanks.
Your memory's sure deserted you.
Don't you recall Annie?
She's all skin and bones, that little girl,
that's what you used to say last year.
Sure, sure, Annie,
and you're still the same little girl,
just as skinny, just as bony.
How about a kiss for me? Growing, eh,
last year you were all knees.
And I still got knees, see?!
Not dancing?
You mind going away so I can finally
have a little peace and quiet.
You kids should all be
in bed taking a siesta.
Baby's willing if you're ready
to rockabye your little baby.
You ought to be spanked;
you're a child not a grown-up!
And you know what you are?
You're a prissy son of a...
Shut your dirty little mouth,
hear?! You!
Wanta?
No, don't know how.
Talking about me in town?
How much reward they offering for me now?
Come on, Rusty. What do you mean reward?
Who do you think's looking for
you after thirty years?
Mean they forgot me? Why the whole
west knew who... Rusty Rogers was.
You said Rusty Rogers?
Is that you?
You, you mean
you heard of me, stranger?
But... surely you're joking.
Why you're a legend.
Your name is so famous
I didn't really believe you existed.
I thought you'd been invented
as a symbol of the wild west,
a figment of the public imagination.
Why, composers have written
whole ballads around you.
Well, as for you reward,
it's gone on up until it's now
your worth five thousand dollars.
No, i'm wrong;
it's gone up to ten thousand dollars.
It's true?
Thank you, I sure do thank you,
Mister. Yippee!
Old Rusty.
A ghost out of the past.
If I've been able to breathe a little new
life into him, it means I'm still alive.
In that case you'll have
plenty of work here.
All of us in Puerto de
Fuego are ghosts of the past.