João!
Come João.
Mother.
If it was up to the world...
there would be no place
for me in it.
That's what I spend my life
looking for.
But there are things we
choose ourselves...
and there things that choose us.
And I was born with lots of
unfinished business to settle.
Tonho, get me a shot of cachaça.
Another one.
Hold it right there.
I had nothing to lose.
Drive.
That's why I was not afraid.
Don't do it, kid.
You're young.
Don't do such a stupid thing.
Get out of the car.
I told you to get out.
On your knees.
Don't you do such a terrible thing.
You'll kill me...
Sometimes...
we must kill a few
things in order to plant...
to water,
and be born, again.
Wait, wait.
A real man always pay his debts.
-There he is!
-Stand up!
Stand the fuck up!
JUVIE - BAHIA
And I have paid...
up to the last penny.
Then I turned to my path.
But now, times were different.
Good evening, Brasilia!
One, two, three, four!
We live in the city
And so does the president
Everybody pretends
To live a life that's decent
But I don't mean
To be so decadent, no
Boredom whit a big B
Just for you!
Walk under the rain
Sometimes I dig it
I have no fuel
Do you have some good stuff on you?
-What?
-Do you have some good stuff?
-I do. Show me the money.
-I'll pay you tomorrow.
-You'll pay me tomorrow?
-Tomorrow...
I just got this glass.
I live in Brasilia!
ARAGUARINA STATION
FREIGHT
Hey, man, what is it?
What are you doing?
-I want no bum in here.
-I ain't no bum.
I was wondering if you know
a relative of mine.
Who's it?
Pablo.
Go on.
-Do you know him?
-He's well known here.
I'm the son of Mazé and Vicente.
From Santo Cristo.
My father told me
I could look for you.
You look like your mother.
Do you want a smoke?
Relatives tend to show up
when they're fucked up.
And you're fucked up,
aren't you?
You're thirsty, you're hungry,
you're cold...
and you have nowhere to crash,
isn't that so?
I'll get you some food.
Come on.
-Do you like scotch?
-I'm not used to it.
Money changes people's tastes.
Do you know what I do
for a living?
I begun selling very nice
stuff here.
Some coming from Bolivia,
some coming from Paraguay.
-For real? Paraguay?
-Yeah.
I'll introduce you to my girl, but
this one, you can only look at.
Teresa, come over here!
She is the true reason
I stayed in Brazil.
Teresita!
You're so rude!
This is my cousin, João.
Are you sure?
I told you, my father was Brazilian.
You're the first relative Pablo's
introduced me to.
First and last,
the rest is dead.
Better scrannel than without a nose!
Pablo told you to come here, right?
He told you what I really need
in a watchman, didn't he?
If you want, I can do both.
That's fine. You're hired.
Stop playin' this shit, man.
Play something good.
That's it! Now that use your anger
to play Clash, Ramones.
Play Pistols.
If you go to Berlin to play this
shit, you're screwed.
You're going to have a short career.
You'll be deported right away.
Hey.
What's up?
Maria Lúcia.
I'm going home, I'm tired, Chris.
-Wanna a ride?
-No, that's cool, I'll ride with Beto.
Snap out of it, Mary...
I'll call you.
What is this mess?
Answer me, boy!
Look amount of wood you chopped!
Do you want to wreck my business?
Drive me bankrupt?
I used the night to make a chair.
And it's got no nails.
The good indeed. Who's gone ask us to
fix something that never breaks?
Massul told me you're
a big help.
You're alert all night long.
Too far?
Winchester 22.
Does it work?
I'll show you.
Your turn.
This way.
You have to look
where the prey is.
Where you have to shoot.
Let's go?
Let's go. I'll bring you
some candy later.
Come on, shoot it.
We don't have all day!
Luck shot!
God damn! Fuck you!
Pick it up!
Fuck you, bro! Wanna kill me?
Today, you're gonna make
a delivery for me.
It won't take long.
Barata, you'll stay
at Massul's tonight.
I'll pay you good money.
Or do you want to sleep forever
in that shitty shack?
Saci, come on in,
goddamn it!
Here it is, almost gone.
What is your problem?
Maria Lúcia, you can't stay home
for the rest of your life.
Chris, I'm not going out.
Maria Lúcia.
-Get rid of it, get rid of it!
-Will do.
Just tell you I'm home!
Did you bring the money?
Police!
Hands on your head!
On the floor!
Fucker.
Here you go.
This is enough! Go on!
You, little thief! Put it back!
I saw you taking it!
Take your hands off him,
you son of a bitch.
Put it back, boy!
You like hitting children?
I don't want my son to be
a thief, understood?
Did he hurt you?
When we get home
you help your mother pack.
We are living tomorrow, first light.
Okay.
Let's pedal, we're too slow.
Climb on.
Run into the woods, go.
Hurry up!
I'm telling you!
Go, kid.
Who do you think you are to hit my
brother, your nigger, son of a bitch?
-Gee, the nigger is fast...
-Goddamn it, yeah!
You go to the entrance.
Marco Aurélio.
Look around here,
I'll check the back!
This guy is surrounded
on this block.
Chris.
-What's up, you loony?
-Have you forgotten?
Renato, come back
the guy is not here.
Gimme a smoke, man.
Don't scream! Don't scream!
Don't scream! Some guys are chasing
me. I'll just hide and I'll leave.
Calm down...
Maria Lúcia, I told you
I'm home already.
Maria Lúcia.
-Yes?
-Good evening.
-Good evening, Mr...?
-Ney.
Mr. Ney, I'm detective
Marco Aurélio.
There's a crook at loose
in the neighborhood.
We're warning the residents
to keep their doors...
No, there's nobody here.
-Mr. Ney, if I could at least just...
-Senator...
Right.
Sorry to bother you, sir.
Maria Lúcia?
I'm changing clothes, dad.
-Close your window before bedtime.
-Okay.
My name is João.
Mr. Jeremias, that man's
here to see you.
Say it, Bones.
Go!
-Marco Aurélio. Titties!
-Hands off, dude.
-What's wrong? Had some milk?
-I like your haircut.
Come, I got a gift for you.
-Really?
-Yeah, come on.
-Please.
-Ladies first...
My share I want in cash.
Look, there's a fortune
there, little girl.
Here.
This here is the one
I told you about.
I got it from the
two-bit drug dealer.
Have some fun here,
while I roll up a joint there.
What do you mean? I'm
no Bible-thumping preacher.
I wasn't either,
until read Luke's Gospel.
I found Jesus.
-I saw it in a movie.
-Look, a little pen tube.
So you can underline
the parts that touch you deeper.
Oh, my freaking God!
So, who was my competitor?
It was a two-bit nigger selling
for a couple of rich kids.
The bastard ran like hell,
but never mind.
I know he, bastard, is from Ceilândia
and if he shows up again...
-I'll bring him to you.
-Good for you.
Chill out, man.
Come on, your old man
always trusted me. Didn't he?
So that shit I apprehended...
This is any, but shit.
This isn't the first time that
fucker messes up with us.
Always on that Plano Piloto.
I'm tired of losing.
This time, you didn't lose.
-Here's the money.
-At least this.
Your cut. Now, go
rent your shack.
It comes from abroad.
I only deal with the best.
What do you want from me?
I came to thank you.
-This time, I'll call the police.
-No need.
It's all cool.
Here.
You're cocky, you know?
-Did you like that?
-Pretty.
But no, thanks.
I'd like to invite you
to go a cool place.
-No.
-Come on.
You have nothing better
to do, anyway.
You're really crazy, you know?
Okay, fine.
Hey!
-Is this the place?
-Not yet.
Not yet?
What are you doing?
I'm gonna dive in.
Come on, baby.
Come in! Are you
afraid of the cold?
Come.
Have you ever been here?
-Not like this.
-So you never knew this place.
-It's cold.
-I'll warm you up.
No, let's get out.
You're one big pothead.
And you are a thug.
-I'm not a thug.
-Yeah, right.
I own a carpenter shop.
What were you doing in my
neighborhood that day? Selling wood?
That's my cousin's business,
but I won't do it anymore.
What about you?
Where do you work?
I don't work.
I'm studying to
be an architect.
That's hard.
I'm an architect, and
you're a carpenter.
Yeah...
The rich plan it, and
the poor build it.
That's awful!
Do you think it's like that?
Now, I'll pin you down.
No. No, no, no.
I'm a thug, ain't I?
Yeah...
No.
Small time thug.
-Is this how you like it?
-No.
I like when you tell
the truth.
-Pablo?
-Yep.
I need a little weed.
-Are you hooked already?
-No. It's for a girl.
Give the chick any crap.
She'll like it fine.
She's from Asa Sul. What they
smoke down there is pure shit.
Why do you think I sent
you down there for?
I can pay you.
Come with me.
Good morning.
Have you changed your mind?
You're the only one who
refuses to pay the taxes.
I don't even pay taxes
to the government.
I take care
of the people around here.
Everybody knows that.
Why aren't you grateful too?
I hate ungratefulness!
-Enough, Pablo.
-Shut up!
The money, now!
Are you insane, motherfucker?
I'm the boss here.
Damn.
Barata, gimme some weed.
For your chica.
No need to pay.
What's this?
What?
A term project,
I presented today.
I brought you a joint,
if you want s hit.
No, it's risky here. We'd better
smoke in the car.
Give that to me.
-I'll help you.
-No thanks. It's okay.
It's the Anthropology Building
back here.
I'll minor in Anthropology too.
I'll toss here.
-Let me...
-No, that's okay.
You drive. I'll stick it here,
but it won't hinder the gear.
Let's go.
The key's upside down.
Okay...
Can you drive?
Of course I can!
Careful with the reverse gear,
it's a little...
What are you laughing
about, girl?
Slowly.
Oh, my God!
-I did it, I did it!
-It isn't raining...
Turn around here.
Turn here.
-Here! I can do it!
-No, no!
I hit my head.
Look...
Maria Lúcia brought her
father's bodyguard.
You're here.
Do you smoke weed, man?
No, not this kind.
It tastes of cow shit.
Hey, Jeremias!
This dude says your
weed's like hay!
-Stop man.
-It's like cow dung!
He said he can find us
much better weed.
Really? Where does
his weed come from?
If it is good I
want some too.
Say something.
You offend me in my house.
Cat ate your tongue?
-Who invited you here... Pelé?
-I invited him...
but he's on his way out.
Let's go, João.
Maria Lúcia, let me know shall
you bring the doorman's son.
-Let's go João, please.
-Go away, Pelé!
Let's go.
Holy fuck!
This is good stuff,
isn't it, Betão?
The best.
Who's that cheeky fucker
with Maria Lúcia tonight?
Maria Lúcia's nuts.
She's insane.
Who was the dude?
-Who? Beto?
-The other sucker. Your boyfriend?
Of course not?
I don't date crooks.
He's a lowlife playboy dealer.
He's an army brat,
his old man is stationed abroad.
He was a classmate, nothing more.
Goddamn...
finally, some good
weed in this town.
Fan-fucking-tastic.
Enjoy it while you can,
cause this is the last one.
You can get some more,
can't you, João?
Don't bother him, Chris.
I think I can manage that.
Why did you bring me here?
This good land is for sale.
Why would I buy that?
-I hate woods.
-I miss a good field to farm.
All I had to do, then,
was fulfill my need to plow.
If the soil is good, you harvest
wherever you plant.
As the President João Figueiredo
used to say:
"Plant it and João ensures it."
But for Maria Lúcia...
I reassured I was
only a carpenter.
I was making money and she taking
care of the future.
Soon, the city¤s potheads
were aware of the news.
Oh yeah! There's a
good stuff for sale.
If anyone remembers smoking
an excellent weed in the 80's...
I most certainly didn't
buy it from me.
Because, if it was, he wouldn't
remember anything.
But there are things you want
to forget, and just can't.
Nice and cold beer.
Can I ask you something?
-Ask.
-You're not going to get mad.
Where did you get the money
to buy this car?
Are you back in business
whit your cousin?
I told you I own
a carpenter shop.
Don't lie to me, João.
There always a moment in your life
when we have to tell the truth.
This car is borrowed.
Let's dance.
Or life itself
will tell the truth.
It's not our fault
We were born blessed
-What's up, João?
-Were you waiting for me?
For the bad distribution
With so many richness out there
Where is it?
Where's its share?
With so many richness out there
Where is it?
Where is it's share?
Wait until when
If you want, I'll stop it.
I swear, I'll stop.
But I'm making money.
Don't you smoke?
Don't your buddies smoke?
What the fuck, João?
You lied to me,
you swore!
I don't want it for me.
I don't.
You left harvest aside this week.
Are you leaving the weed
to the bugs?
This is all wrong, Pablo.
Wrong?
But you have a house,
a fridge, a stove.
I think you're doing fine.
Nothing's going fine.
I'll start to work on my own.
Work?
How are you gonna work?
You're form Santo Cristo.
You're black, you're poor, you're
illiterate. Here, you're shit.
I'm out.
Ungrateful.
I'm here to be your partner.
I wanna talk with you.
What is it?
This is João, dad.
he's a friend of Beto.
But he's on his way, aren't you?
Beto isn't here.
Bye.
My dear, what did that man want?
He was looking for Beto.
You are not some sort of
trouble, are you?
Just because he's black?
Watch your mouth, young lady!
There¤s a limit for everything!
What are you doing?
I'm not dealing anymore.
Now I'm a partner in the shop.
Again?
I want to do things right,
Maria Lúcia.
I want to get married and
have a kid with you.
You go to the living room and ask my
father for his permission to marry me.
Where are you going?
-I'll talk to you father.
-You're not going...
Stop it.
You won't talk to him!
Stop it! Stop it!
You'll believe me?
-I'll talk to your father.
-No, you won't!
Enough! Enough!
I can't stand it anymore either!
I can't stand it!
Hands on your head!
Hands on your head, fucker!
Now! Hands on your head!
Assume the position!
Look at that!
This is the bastard who's
giving me a hard time.
I told you.
Look.
This is the cuffs' little key.
I told you.
So, Maria Lúcia's boyfriend.
Are you the one who's screwing
up with my business?
Are you?
Come here.
Does she know you're a dealer?
Let him go.
Is good enough, Santo?
Did you understand who's boss here?
Shit.
Come here, come here.
Do you wanna fuck this nigger's ass?
Nigger!
DISCO
What a lame party
you brought us, bro!
Telmo! Holy fuck.
What are we gonna
do now, Jeremias?
Let's go to my house.
Come on, Telmo.
Let's go, Telmo.
Goddamn.
Let's go!
There are things that life
imposes to you.
It never asks if you want,
it throws you there.
And then, it's up to you.
You're smoking too much.
Holy fuck.
The bastard blew up
my friend's head.
-Yeah, that's right.
-So, what now?
-You're a bunch of assholes.
-Assholes?
Yes, assholes. I gave you
the guy on a silver platter.
You should've killed him.
I'd disappear with the corpse.
Game over, Jeremias.
I'm out of this shit.
You're out my ass, baby.
Come on, let's not go crazy.
Let's not go crazy.
-Do you want to be my partner?
-What do you mean, "partner"?
¤0¤?
I'm leaving.
If you them over,
that's fine.
Fuck.
Won't you say anything?
You disappeared, never
showed up again.
It says you who sought me out.
What's going on, João?
You'd better go.
This is a dangerous place.
What's up, Santo Cristo?
You've been hiding, huh?
-Fuck off, playboy.
-Come on, man.
I need some good weed.
For you there is no more.
Look this shit comes from aboard.
It's worth a bundle.
This is great, Santo Cristo.
Will you show up at the
Rockweed party tonight?
Don't you know about that?
Jeremias is putting it together.
Here. It would be nice
if you showed up.
If not, at least you can
roll up that shit.
-It's done.
-Watch my jacket, you junkie.
Sorry.
The invitation's delivered.
-How did it go?
-I had to give the bastard my watch.
-Did you give anything else?
-That was all.
Here, Beto. This is what
you want, right, Beto?
-I'm not giving it to you.
-Don't do that, man.
What? Here...
Here you are.
Behave, okay?
I'm watching you.
João.
-Maria Lúcia is here?
-No, she is at home.
Hey, look that!
Run away.
-Beat it.
-Are you mad?
Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch.
Hey, faggot!
Can you sit yet?
You won't be able to sit anymore.
Because I'm gonna blow up
your ass, motherfucker.
Lower your weapons!
Lower them!
Come on, motherfucker.
-What's going on, Pablo?
-What the fuck is this?
-Lower your weapons!
-Lower them now!
This is my Rockweed, nigger!
Motherfucker.
Scram.
-Be strong, Pablo.
-The party is over, herma¤o.
I came for the nigger.
Drop the gun and get out.
I owe you one, cousin.
Why did you come here?
I don't wanna lose you.
I don't deserve this, João.
Who did this?
With you.
Get out of my house, you thug!
Get out of my house.
-Get out of my house.
-Wait a minute.
-Calm down, dad.
-What do you mean, calm down?
-I love your daughter.
-Love my ass, motherfucker!
Come on, João, getaway.
Get out of the car.
Hands on your head.
I want you out of my house.
That's the one, sir.
The sun-tanned one.
João de Santo Cristo,
the Ceilândia killer.
He won't be missed.
Look, there will be no
killing in my precinct...
but if you wanna teach him
a lesson...
Is the police doing that to you?
If is not the police, who is?
Talk!
Forget about it.
Don't come back here, anymore.
Tell me, João.
Hey, were you looking for me?
Okay, spit it out! Shoot.
-It's about João.
-Who?
-João.
-João? What João?
There are lots of them
in this town.
-Santo Cristo.
-Oh, Santo Cristo, yeah.
He's having a good time in jail,
isn't he? Tell me.
I'm here to ask you
a favor.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
You'd like me to help
you out, right?
You came here all dressed up
to ask me for a favor.
Is that right? Tell me. What about the
cock-teasing you threw my away...
all my life?
Isn't it enough?
"I don't date dealers. I'm a
decent girl." Fuck yourself!
Now, you humiliate me, hooking
up with a two-bit-dealer.
-It is about me?
-Yes, it's about you!
I want you for myself.
Help me.
Please.
Okay.
I'll help you.
When you visit hi m next. I
promise he'll be feeling better.
Okay?
He said he doesn't want
to see you.
-How come?
-He just doesn't.
But I want to see him.
Get in.
Come in.
You're looking beautiful,
beautiful.
Come on, motherfucker,
get up.
Get up, Santo Cristo,
I'm talking to you.
Come here.
Hold the newspaper here.
-What for?
-Shut up and keep it still.
That's it. One hand here,
the other one here...
You're so fucking smart.
Here, that's it.
Son of a bitch.
Get up, fucker.
-They came out great.
-Very good.
You're looking great in this one.
João de Santo Cristo. Today,
there's no photo shoot.
I brought you a present,
to keep you entertained.
Okay?
I'll see you next week.
Hey, baby, out the shirt on.
I don't have the whole for this.
Good looking guy.
-Can I read it?
-You're illiterate.
Let go.
Keep looking at the
picture I gave you.
Hey, what are you doing?
Open the door!
Open, now!
Wait, wait.
Now, on your knees.
On my knees, my ass,
you nigger, son of a...
Hey, Jeremias!
Holy fuck.
Calm down, man.
Where's the coke?
That stupid fool left
the house wide open.
Dudu, buddy.
Fuck it, Dudu.
CEIL¤NDIA
LOT ¤ 14
He took all my coke.
He took it all. Fuck!
He took my coke!
He took my coke.
Let's see who's gonna get
fucked over there.
This is war, now.
This is war.
He thinks he'll fuck me over.
He'll fuck me over?
We shall see.
We shall see who's
gonna get screwed.
It's here.
João!
Easy...
Was it me...
or the destiny?
What if I had done it
differently?
Would it change my path?
Would my dreams became fate?
The end is not where
the road ends.