Where can you swim?
Barney,
on the other side of the street.
I agree with you.
Let me, Brockie!
I do not want to kill you!
What is the matter?
Since when are you aiming at the back?
Griff? ... Is that you?
You promised
to wear glasses!
If we pray long enough
there's something going on.
It is not prayer
scares you.
That bother you?
A greenhorn,
really bad.
He was drunk ...
Did he tell you damn scared, huh?
He gave me one hour
to leave the city.
So go away!
Help me!
I'm not here
to spank a kid.
If he draws the first
I'm lost.
Your view is even worse,
is not it?
I'm broke.
I am forced to keep my job.
We have a profession.
What can we do?
He has a good eye doctor in Prescott.
I can not run away like that!
You have no choice.
You must be a reason
not to help me.
- It does not concern me.
- So what are you doing here?
Flee before being blind!
And if the doctor can do nothing?
Thou shalt be blind
instead of being dead!
She is a woman who rides,
armed with a whip.
A woman that all men
wish.
But no man
can not tame.
It is called
Women with a whisk.
It controls
and men obey ...
They are only puppets
in his hands.
When she rides,
the wind in your hair,
her eyes are full of fire.
But if anyone can tame,
and snatch the whip
a tall man, a hard man,
a strong man
we can see
Woman with the Whip
is a woman after all.
Put it, Barney!
It's you, Wes?
How are you, Barney?
I make lots of money
in this city!
You see, Griff!
My brother, Chico, California will.
With the opportunities that there are here?
Our family is there.
I saw the name
on the warrant.
You can not stop Swain.
Where can I find it?
The Dragons.
We saw a woman
and riders.
You've seen Jessica Drummond.
The song I just sing
was on it.
To Dragons
it is forbidden to sing it.
She, Drummond!
It controls the Cochise County.
She and her 40 riders.
A beautiful woman ...
Swain is one of his 40 thieves?
Yes.
Hello, Sheriff.
Going somewhere?
I stroll.
Chisholm!
Where are you?
You get the hell?
Give me your coffee.
Was scared, Sheriff?
Brockie, you're crazy!
You talk instead of fight!
No one here, do
to stop this ...
What a great sheriff!
Come on, Charlie, we'll have fun!
- How is it doctor?
- He will live but will be blind.
Why did not you listen?
I've heard.
You want a revolver, Griff?
No ... This is not my business!
I'll stop it!
I will not let
demolished my shop!
He can not fight!
Mr. gunsmith.
Where is your shop?
I'll show you, Mr Bonell.
Let's break the shop!
Which one?
It's.
Give me a gun.
What do you want?
I draw.
You are ill, Charlie?
One type works like that.
If approached, I guts!
What do you have?
Pull up!
I warn you!
Thank you, Mr. Spanger.
Here for the ball.
It will be 75 cents
to clean the gun.
You should review this rifle.
My almost killed him.
It is very well
in overalls.
Built like a 40-40.
I would stay long enough ...
Farmer you see me? Me?
I got the teeth
of a gun.
Baby teeth!
Remember what Dad said!
"Workers of the earth
are the Chosen of God. "
I do not want to be "chosen".
I will be the third gun Griff.
Let me show it!
You never made duel.
You, you ever afraid?
Always.
Here's your ticket.
Do not lose it.
I read that there was plenty
attacks on stagecoaches.
3 or 4 a week
all passengers killed.
They do not kill women
and youngsters!
Be careful what you say.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
which of you is Bonell Griff?
Can I help you?
I'm Ned Logan,
Sheriff of Cochise County.
It is you, Wes?
Sorry
whether they are worthless
you have received in the city.
You stay?
Long enough.
Brockie is a spoiled child.
This correction had to sober up.
It's yours now.
I do not want him.
Thank you for having put in prison.
I was not there
Chisholm to help ...
I had to go across the border.
With all of your assistants?
Well, I'm Sheriff
collector and at the same time.
I need help.
The cowboys lie
their herds.
It's hard to avoid the Apaches
and file input acts
on ranches, mines,
sawmills.
You are in an official capacity?
You must be very busy.
You will explore
in the hills?
No, I'll send a telegram.
It's here.
Tex will look after you.
A friend of mine wants to send
one message.
I saw you wander the city.
Even more slowly
at Dodge City.
A Bonell Nicholas ...
I knew
a Captain Niki Bonell
47 in Mexico.
He was wounded in the leg.
There was 34 years ago.
It was my father.
His leg is getting better?
The cable will do him good.
"All in good health"
"Chico from Saturday"
"Write after finishing
business here "
"Signed! Griff and Wes"
M. Bonell,
I am at your disposal.
It has a small bump.
Where is he
that attacked my brother?
Why is it free?
You know who he is ...
Perfectly. Killer legal!
I'm surprised
he attack my child.
It was large enough
to shoot a blind!
What is he accused?
Of disorder!
Disorder?
He shot a defenseless man.
You saw?
No, but everyone knows it.
The meeting was called.
This discussion
was personal.
19 witnesses testified
self-defense.
You are guilty of disorder.
$ 50 fine.
Release the prisoner.
Give him his weapons.
He left us alone,
he was blind!
Why did you shoot?
Because of the girl?
What are you talking about?
They come complaining to me!
I'm tired of paying for you.
She came to see me.
You have so many friends.
Give me your revolvers.
It is necessary that I enjoy!
If you can not mount
you do not need a horse.
Your guns!
Why did you go whining
my sister, too?
I do not like the others!
Run home ...
You are very similar to others!
Who would I went to Brock?
You know I'm alone.
You refused to see me.
He has had.
You know what you gonna do?
Tell my sister
I've never touched.
No, I'm not going to lie.
It was good to me.
She gave me money.
She said she would help me.
Tell him that you lied!
I should throw you down.
Do it and you'll cut your food.
If Jessica was not your sister ...
You do not get,
you are too weak.
You do not have enough guts
for her.
I could kill you
for the harm you do him.
Stop messing with the girls!
You could be someone
with the help of Jessica.
We pay $ 300 Chisholm.
For the name of Bonell,
we will go to 500.
For the size,
it takes between 5 / 8 and 11/16.
There are jobs worse than sheriff.
Height of arch, between 1 and 1.58.
It is time
as you settle, Wes.
This is a good wood for the butt.
This is not what you need.
Give me the hazel, Dad.
One?
This is the 1st time
that makes me a gun to measure.
You have the shoulders down.
It complicates your work?
I can get.
How long,
for this rifle?
Lot of time.
A fitting day.
It's time I settle down.
But this city
resembles other.
A gun Spanger
resembles other
unless one knows.
That's a good job.
I've never seen anything better.
For a gun like that,
it's worth it to stay.
I had never kissed
gunsmith.
Step back?
I have a mandate
for one of your men.
Could you do without?
The Governor is he aware?
He has not heard of.
This mandate is not here.
Is it legal?
Certainly.
It comes straight from Washington.
Mr. Logan, you are challenged.
A deputy is accused
theft of mail.
I'm sure he will go
the authority of the Government.
What do you mean?
Are you the assistant Swain?
You know what I mean.
You heard Mr. Bonell.
Follow him.
One moment, please.
You are not afraid
an ambush?
I am always afraid of losing
what is the state.
It is not
I have heard you.
And what I heard
you!
What have you heard about?
We apologize, gentlemen.
Whisky is in service.
My reputation will suffer
the deputy sheriff
flying the mail!
I have already decided on Governor
horse thief.
Remember this.
I have many more.
For my guests?
There are other
who stole the mail?
What do you want?
Logan wearing the badge
but he is afraid.
This job pays well,
there are commissions, etc..
We can get rich on the "etc"?
You offer me this job?
You would be elected immediately.
- With your help?
- With or without.
You are a killer hot!
This work is not size
for me.
It would be the size you want.
You do not care, Mr Bonell.
This is your brand ...
Can I touch it?
Just curious.
It can blow in the face.
I take the risk.
You almost break his head.
I could if I wanted.
Fortunately,
you were not paid for the kill.
I do not kill for money.
I'm sure it is not
for fun.
I'm sure you are safe.
You asked for whiskey.
Whiskey is good, Logan.
Try it!
Put him in jail, Wes.
See you at the hotel.
I have been uncomfortable
to leave the party
but, as a sheriff,
my place was here.
Of course, Sheriff.
Give the prisoner what he wants
account of Uncle Sam
Swain, I do not believe.
Honestly ...
A man like you
well paid, that flies in the mail!
You must be a little disturbed.
How long ...
this idiot will it stay here?
2 or 3 days, Sheriff.
Save money from the state.
Hang him now!
I would like,
but it is outside my field.
He acted alone?
I know how you feel.
It's a shame
for all other sheriffs.
It's true.
So much for the back
the Chief Justice.
We must all read and sign.
The whole. It's the rule.
I will take it later
with the prisoner.
Where is Chico?
He went for a drink.
He never drank in his life!
Griff Bonell's up there?
We have your brother Chico.
Where should I put the body?
1st Division.
We came here to have fun.
Your brother drank the whiskey.
And he demolished the house!
Help me, Barney.
I understand that Brock.
He was born coward and violent.
- But you, Chico!
- I am old enough to drink.
But you do not want alcohol.
- It will come!
- Why?
That's my business!
What's wrong?
Why did I come with you?
For me wandering?
You set this matter
without letting me help you.
And if something happened to Wes?
You never work without
covered by a second fuses /.
You did not let me help you
either the Dragons.
I feel too.
Do I hurt you?
I will never be a farmer,
Griff.
I'm not interested.
You taught me to shoot.
You have learned all too well.
You know what happened
Chisholm?
It could happen and happen to me.
You remember the gladiators
Roman I told you about?
You thought it was funny.
Soon people will laugh
men like me.
In several cities
we went
I know they looked at me
as a phenomenon of the past.
This is a new era
started it.
My way of life
is already exceeded.
You talk too much for justice.
I am one phenomenon, Chico.
I do not want
that thou mayest be one too.
I'm tired of passing
for a youngster.
I do not
for agriculture!
I know.
Brand new! A Colt 45!
Nickel! With an ivory butt!
For me?
To kill rattlesnakes,
on the farm.
Tell him that from me.
I do not care about money!
I will not be a target!
There is no boundary
Bonell for Griff!
He will find me wherever I go!
Listen, Swain.
You know she has influence.
She will use it when necessary.
It will be too late!
I want out now
and legally!
I want tomorrow
always be 1 assistant.
It can do this.
It is the Patron.
Otherwise ... I know all about her.
You want me to tell him that?
Are you sure?
Some.
Who shot you?
You saw?
Tell me. I am your friend.
If you have seen,
we will take care of him.
I can not move his legs.
Rest in peace.
I think he knows who shot.
He tries to speak.
Did you see that shot?
If you saw, you must tell us.
We will find the one that did it.
Does he tell you
something?
He told you who it was?
Remove the ball Wes.
He died.
Have you ever seen the ball?
She comes from a new rifle
Sharps-Bourchardt.
There are here?
Only one man has one.
Who is it?
Howard Swain fire.
We just take that ball
of her back.
He had to be killed
with his own gun.
Who is the best killer
of the state?
I did not kill him.
No, after you, that makes the best?
Charlie Savage.
You are in full panic!
I had to go fast. Charlie Savage
is the best shooter.
You have decided for me?
Sometimes a partner ...
I am the boss,
not a partner.
I did not
you take it as that.
How Griff Bonell
will take it there?
Do not worry, everything is arranged.
It's over for you.
It was you who
Swain killed, not me.
I had no choice.
You have passed the rope
the neck.
Go!
Go, like a dog
tails between their legs!
Take your killers and fly ...
now!
You must feel naked
without your army.
What name on your list
today?
One of your riders, Charlie Savage.
It has damaged that belonged
the Government.
I do not monitor my men
I am not responsible
of what they do far away.
There must be many
shelters here.
I show them to be happy.
I want to see if you find it
on my land.
You want to spank him?
I want to see
if you can take it.
This is a good cache.
A snake bit me IA
when I was 15.
I bet he died.
Well, you do not have much
esteem for me?
On the contrary.
It will be hard if your brother
is in the game.
Murder is not in his blood.
He is your brother, right?
You seem unhappy.
I was born like that.
Up to 8 years
I thought all that had
Four legs of cattle was
and all that had two, a man.
At 9 years, I learned the difference.
Not between cattle and humans
but between race and the rest.
At 10, I scored the calves,
matais horses
I was riding,
I slept on the floor.
My father was absent
when Brockie was born.
I was alone with my mother.
I was 12.
He was born in this cabin.
My mother died
by keeping the world.
I buried her.
I went to get milk
for Brockie.
He was able to live.
At 15, a guy tried
bothering me right here.
My father knew poorly drawn.
He was killed while trying
to protect me.
You're fired?
My father built
the cabin of his hands.
You kept
in memory of him?
In memory of the past.
At 18,
I had my flock to me.
I found Logan, I hired him.
I became interested
in politics.
I spent well
of this country.
I funded mine
sawmills.
You've come a long way!
You too.
My men talk a lot
you.
Have they said my trouble
with them?
Those who are still alive, yes.
You have advanced
with a revolver.
You are at the point.
The border is finished.
There are more cities,
more men, to be submitted.
It is time for you to stop.
Other building peace
on graves!
Your life can not be made
that of fire!
Direct the Dragons for me.
Come work with me.
Me and my revolver?
It's time to throw.
He will one day.
I give you the opportunity.
Why me?
I need a strong man
to transmit my orders.
And a weak
to accept them.
My throat is dry.
I talk too much.
What do you want?
She does not see you
bring these guns!
You do not give more orders
for her.
I want to see Bonell kill you
but she wants me.
I'll be the one who will kill!
Nobody wants to kill him
but we must cope.
It will be like before.
Give them to me!
I did that once given ...
to it!
This is the case of Charlie Savage.
If we were in on it,
it would be too.
Give me your revolvers.
Go to the other side and wait for me.
That will bring Bonell Griff?
Wiley. Now, get out of there.
It does not please me, Sheriff.
There is nothing to fear.
Wes will forward
as usual
with a gun,
to see the situation.
Then he will move somewhere
Griff back to cover.
So Griff arrives.
It will stop here.
He paid attention.
Do not worry about anything.
You'll be there ... the corner.
He can not see you.
Griff will cry! "Charlie Savage."
You say! "Yes ...?"
He will cry that he has a mandate.
You say!
"Come get me!"
He will say! "Okay!"
Listen!
Griff will be that way.
He will see that I'm not Savage.
It will be dead.
So what?
Nothing, no one has seen or in Phoenix
or Prescott.
And Tucson?
We think it went to Mexico.
I was looking for.
Savage is in town.
He is waiting for a duel.
Across from the dealer.
Who told you that he was waiting for me?
Savage himself.
It does not seem to be afraid.
Go for it!
Can I help you?
I'll call you
If I need you.
Okay, do not forget me ...
Good. Let's go.
Expect more
that Chico is gone.
Barney was looking for you.
What is the matter?
No.
Monte.
Thou shalt maybe 2 days
to know where he is.
Maybe even a week!
I can not stay so far?
Tell the parents
that we will come soon.
In a few weeks maybe.
Say I have a surprise for them.
He could have
a good third gun.
What's the surprise?
I'm getting married.
Few women know
make a gun.
You stay here?
Yes.
I will be sheriff.
The pay is good?
Better than the Government.
The name of Bonell
they want.
When you have made Savage,
you will have a second gun.
It's true.
I have a warrant for you.
Throw down your weapon.
Get out, hands raised.
Do you hear me?
Get out of here!
Come and get me!
CHORUS FREE
FOR BURIALS
You could do without me!
He thee in plain view.
Who is it?
Barney said he was here.
I jumped out of the diligence.
I got it in the head.
All of a sudden!
I, a farmer!
What have I done?
You killed a man!
Assassins!
Calm down, boys!
I will destroy!
No fighting personal
now that you're
my second gun.
Got it?
They are beautifully arranged here!
The last man I killed,
he was a young.
As your brother.
He was very young and I killed him.
I could only hurt him.
I did not.
Have you ever seen eyes
death of a boy?
The shooter safest in the West.
I hate to fight.
I never miss.
I talk too much?
I apologize if I kill
even an animal.
You can not ask later.
It's too late.
But I came
Brockie to talk about.
He put the body of Savage
in a display case.
Someone who does that
is practically dead.
But there is still time.
You think it was
in the ambush?
I do not know what to think.
Wes my brother is getting married.
I go after the ceremony.
That's why I came.
I know you like it
as a son.
I know.
I have a brother the same age.
Spy on your own
before having to bury him.
I had to kill him.
Was the only way.
Why did you not kill?
It took you for my brother.
Nobody wants to be involved
a murder?
Swain and Savage died.
The Government lets you down.
Everyone leaves the ship.
Captain dark.
It's the end of the Dragons.
He is our enemy.
That's why I wanted to kill him.
To find your job?
Are you crazy?
My job!
Why do I lied, stole, cheated?
For my job? For money?
I am a man.
I have feelings.
You can not buy
what I feel.
I can not always
keep this hidden.
I thought, patience, remember yourself.
She will understand.
But I can not wait
all this time.
I must do something.
Let my heart speak.
What do you do with him?
No.
I do not pay like the others.
I'm sorry.
You know why
he wanted to kill you.
He knows that I love you.
It's true,
Dragons collapse.
But I do not care. I could
save them, I do not want.
I know how he feels.
The same
I feel for you.
We can not forget
he and the rest.
The boy you killed,
the life I led, all that.
Do not leave without me.
This happened to us
is like the war
Easy to start
difficult to stop.
I have never known friendship
before love.
And I have a friendship for you,
Griff.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Let's see.
I want the bells ring.
Do not worry.
They will ring.
And you, do good work!
First time I wash my
for a wedding photo.
You have a lot of rice?
All we could find.
You do not embrace the bride?
It's all your fault.
If you had not embraced
the bride
my ball is in your head.
I will do anything for him to live.
The Government will be fair.
As you cooperate,
he gave up the charge.
I am your advocate
and I repeat
you did not give them so much.
Half would have sufficed.
Your project has amazed
the politicians.
You could keep the boss
if you want.
They know that you have kept
tax money
but the state received of you
2 times more than before.
You know what to do?
They will take your land
your cattle, your home
all you have built, everything.
Where were you? Bonell with?
You've got money
to beat you to me?
The fight is over.
You've always bought people.
Get me out of here!
I spent every penny.
I could not buy
the judge and jury.
Am calling!
We can still win!
We lost.
We! It's my neck!
I can not do anything more.
You killed a federal sheriff.
Without his brother,
you get me out.
You must be hanged.
Come on, the state does not
you to be hanged here.
You're right.
You got me out of the woods all my life.
Forgiveness.
I accept the punishment.
Do not do that, Brockie.
Throw down your weapon.
Throw down your weapon and raises his hands.
What are you afraid of?
Get out!
What are you waiting for?
Shoot it!
He had!
A doctor! She will live.
What are you standing?
You heard the doctor ...
I'm fine.
Go back to your room.
I can not let you out.
Thank you, that's fine.
Fortunately
it was Griff Bonell.
He shot right where he wanted.
I know that, Mr. Spanger.
I can not say or do
which brings it to you.
It's hard to forget
the man you love.
I know.
You have a thing for you,
Ms. Bonell.
The youth.
A woman rides
armed with a whip.
A woman
that all men desire.
But no one can tame.
It's called the Whip Woman.
It controls
and men obey.
This is not to bother you.
He loves this song.
You did not listen, Sheriff.
I leave for you.
In California.
Drummond and Jessica?
I want to talk about her.
You have done for her
what you would have done
for anyone else.
You lost your head.
You have not killed a policeman.
You have exploded!
You did what you taught me
not to do.
You must love him for killing
his brother that way!
You do not speak more as a youngster.
Then go see it!
I want it.
But it will never me!
If she had killed you,
I would not have forgiven him.
You know why?
I'm not big enough.
It must be great to forgive.