THEY CALL HIM CEMETERY
He's coming, Mister.
He's at the north pass!
One more hour.
For 15 years. For 15 years
I've been waiting for this day!
- Pedro! Chico!
- Yes, Mister?
How long will it take you
to saddle the horses, damn it?
Well, quite long, Mister.
You're supposed to arrive
at the village before the coach does.
I want my boys to get
some fresh horses.
These are no horses, Mister,
these are devils!
They have to feel
the whip first!
My boys will tame
your devils!
With one hand they'll
show them who's the boss.
- Hey, stay here!
- Go!
Come on!
Let's go, boy!
How will we
recognize them, Mister?
That'll be very easy,
you can't miss them.
They are two strong, young lads
with shoulders that big.
Blue eyes and arms that
could break your horses' neck.
They are two oaks,
two strong Irish oaks!
You know what, George?
I found the virtue...
...of this tobacco:
It eases that horrible stench.
- Do you want some?
- No, thank you.
Oh, beg my pardon, reverend,
I should have offered you some first!
- Would you like some tobacco?
- No, thanks.
May I?
- Please, Madam.
- Thanks.
I'm not a reverend, even though
we work in the same department:
Them the souls,
me the corpses.
I'm a gravedigger and
I'm going to Arlington...
...to take over my friend
Samuelson's business...
...who's retiring to enjoy
the fruits of his work.
You'll get rich
in two years!
Ah, Arlington you said!
Has there been an epidemic?
Yes! And there still is!
And hopefully it will stay for a while!
- Good grace! What is it?
- Chronical... plumbism!
Now, now, don't cry!
Look... what your
mama's got for you!
That's good, good!
John, take a look around!
They're bristled
with weapons!
Withal, the war's been over
for quite a while now.
But you, my dear little sons,
don't you carry any weapons?
- Absolutely not, Madam!
- Maybe we're the only ones.
- Except for you.
- Oh yes.
But I just don't trust
these modern weapons.
This one belonged to my husband.
He shall rest in peace.
Sure, back then
I was a better shot.
But nowadays,
you know...
...the eyes are a little worse,
the hand shakes a bit.
Will you stop that?
Can't you once keep
your fingers off your guns...
...until we arrived
at the station?
- Are we there yet, boss?
- Almost.
10 minutes until we
change the horses.
Quick stop in Arlington -
that's more healthy for everybody!
Arlington! The lucky ones who
journey on may go for a short walk.
- Look! That must be the two!
- Virgin mother, gigantic oaks.
- Quick, let's go!
- Yes, yes.
Welcome, gentlemen!
I'm Pedro and that's my brother Chico.
We're the employees
of Mr. McIntire.
And who gives a damn?
Get out of the way.
That's not really...
...what I expected, but...
- Hey!
If you don't like
the view, get lost.
Let go! I want to teach him
some manners, these peasants!
That would take too long, George.
I'll take care of that.
- Well? A nice animal, isn't it?
- Well, a nice animal, but too expensive!
- What?
- Good manners are not your strength.
But there's still
some time to learn.
- You think so?
- Yes, I mean you.
There are two ways of teaching
good manners to someone.
But for you, I obviously
have to use the quicker one.
- So?
- So what? Listen, silly billy.
I don't know how you take care
of things where you come from...
...but over here, we do it with this.
- Come on, let him go.
Can't you see
they're two unarmed kids?
Well, but they are some bigmouths.
Give him your gun.
I'll just give him
a tiny scratch.
No, no!
Just a second.
A gentleman can't fight
with a savage.
- We're from Boston.
- Who cares?
Hey, nag!
Get out of the way!
Hey you!
I told you to get lost!
And yet another master
of good manners.
Are you deaf?
Turn around!
Turn around,
you bastard!
No, my friend.
You don't think you'll
get away with that, do you?
Come on, don't make me beg you!
You're no mama's son.
And you have
a gun, too.
Are you mute?
Let me hear some
or I'll deflate your ass!
Mister?
I'm asking you
to listen to me.
My name is
John McIntire.
Pedro!
They are the oaks.
I have to remark that your
behavior wasn't very polite.
The total opposite, I have to say
that we did not agree with it at all.
Your interference was...
Hey Mister!
Welcome, Masters!
I'm Pedro and this
is my brother Chico.
We're the employees
of your father, Mr. Rhett.
We came to accompany
you to the ranch.
Okay. You can get the bags and
the suitcases, they're on the coach.
- Chico! The luggage!
- Alright.
Just a minute, we have a
surprise for you, Masters!
What kind of place
is this anyway?
These, Masters, are wonderful
full-breds, full of fire.
- Take a look!
- Yes, very nice, Chico...
...but maybe another time.
- But they're for you!
- Your father is sending you them.
- I understand, Chico. Thank you.
- I'm Pedro.
- Alright, Pedro.
Surrender!
Hey come on,
now it's my turn!
- But... that's a proper mania!
- Certainly seems so.
John! I surely hope you're not planning,
to present yourself to our father like that.
- In this condition!
- That would be inexcusable...
- Ah, Pedro!
- But I'm Chico, Master.
- Yes, sure, Chico. We're going to the hotel.
- To the hotel, Master?
- A harborage. Do you know what that is?
- But your father is awaiting...
- To the hotel, Pedro.
- But I'm Chico!
To the hotel, Chico.
You two, wait for us.
They're no oaks, Chico,
they're two blockheads!
And don't you ever shove
your dirty mugs in here again!
Get up, you boozer!
I'm with you in a minute.
And don't you ever show up
here again, understood?
I have the impression that someone
at this table cheats mighty big.
I won't name
any names.
But I swear,
if I catch him cheating...
...I'll also shoot
his good eye away!
- What are you trying to say by that?
- I'll tell you when I caught you.
Hey, hey, let's rather gamble instead.
Deal the cards, buddy.
- Something to drink?
- Beer, my friend, beer.
Here's the first one!
But this time you won't get away
with that little game of yours!
You asked these two bastards
for help! Didn't you?
Come on, boys, stop it,
be good! Be good!
Quit it, stop...
Hey! What the hell?
You're destroying all my stuff!
Damn it!
My beautiful hotel!
- It's enough, I said!
- My goodness!
They don't exactly
follow the boxing rules...
...but these friendly peasants
do have a big temper.
- No, really.
- Look, look at him.
You madmen!
Just go away!
And you!
Come here...
One moment!
Help!
Young gentlemen!
I think we better leave.
Your father is expecting you
and they are starting a brawl!
You're right, Pedro.
I also think our father...
...would not agree with
our presence here at all.
- Daddy!
- Boys, no sentimentalities, alright?
Ah, boys, what a joy.
Finally you're home.
Hey, no
sentimentalities, Dad!
- Your words, you remember?
- Yes, you're right.
How lucky she
would be right now.
- Do you still remember her, John?
- Only very vague, Dad.
You can't remember
her, George.
She left us before
you learned to walk.
Her only wish was to see you
growing up in a different place.
And I fulfilled her wish.
It's been hard, I missed you a lot.
But she was right,
it was better that way.
Chico,
the flowers please.
Thanks, Chico.
Put some on this
grave too, John.
- Who are they, Dad?
- A poor family of pioneers...
...who came here
many years ago.
They were attacked
by bandits.
The wife and the kids
were murdered.
The husband
was wounded.
Your mother came here often
to put flowers on the grave.
- And where is the husband?
- I have no idea.
We cared for him until he recovered
and soon after, he left.
This man had
lost all his faith.
And they say, his gun talks more
and more frequently ever since.
But let's go now, boys.
It is late already.
Tonight, you'll meet the Demorlays,
our neighbors, respectable folks.
Guns and rifles everywhere.
Infants sucking on bullets.
Duels - yes, we had
an eventful arrival.
Yes... this is not Boston, but there's
lots of good people around here as well.
Mister!
There he is...
The collector is here.
- What's so secret?
- I'll explain it to you later.
Mrs. Carmen, may I ask you
to go upstairs for a moment.
- And you, too.
- Yes, Mister.
And now, whatever happens,
stay calm, boys.
- Understood? Stay calm.
- Good day.
- Come with me.
- I'm coming, too.
Then I won't have to
see him once more.
Let's go.
Listen, Pedro!
Your father will
explain it to you.
What's that all about?
Who's that guy?
Look, Mr. John -
...your father didn't
want to tell you...
They battered him
like that!
- Shot him to pieces!
- For God's sake, Pedro!
- Why did they do it? Why?
- I'm Chico, Mister.
Hey you blown-up cock!
Wait a second!
- Are you talking to me, youngster?
- Don't call me youngster!
As you wish, junior.
And now tell me what you're up to.
- But do it quick!
- These are my sons.
They came back home
from the east today.
They don't know anything
about the issue.
- That's better.
- I wouldn't say that!
We demand
an explanation!
You hear that?
Calm.
Stay calm.
You must know, it's not like
it is in the east over here.
This here's a
wild piece of land...
...where only a few
real bright people get by.
Also the breeders,
you know?
There are some thugs
wreaking havoc around here.
Fellas who shoot the cattle,
poison the wells, set houses afire!
Fellas...
...who kill.
But your father and his friends
are lucky enough...
...to have us.
And we -
for a fistful dollars -
...make sure that
those things won't happen.
You can tell your boss
that the party is over.
Oh, excuse me, Mister,
that wasn't on purpose!
You just made a big mistake.
You'll pay for that.
- Kick him out!
- At once!
Here you are, Mister.
- Not on purpose!
- Out with him!
Mister...
Very nice, boys.
Good work.
Forgive me, father, but I couldn't
take that humiliation.
You can't fight anymore,
but we young folks can.
Alright, my son.
The McIntires...
...are back in the ring.
Let's hope that this Toland
won't back out.
If he's like Pedro described him,
then he won't.
Let's go.
- There are the racketeers.
- Quick, George!
Let's try to
reach the house!
So young and so stupid
to think...
...it would save your life
if you came here unarmed.
But your boss
miscalculated a little.
But... Mr. Toland,
we, we're not...
We're the sons of
Rhett McIntire.
The sons of McIntire.
Oh, then you're the ones
who kicked out the collector.
- Yes, that was me.
- Bad move.
You should have shot
him like a jackal.
You can go, boys.
We want to bring back peace
to this piece of land.
And it has to start by
enforcing the law without killing.
- It can't go on like that...
- If you came to me...
...to ask for help then you
made this trip for nothing.
I only know one way to live
in peace around this area.
But Mr. Toland!
You can't hold a gun in your hand
for the rest of your life.
- Join us!
- And what would that be good for?
After the very first shot, you'd
keep on paying just like before.
Boy, they also sent
a collector to me.
Look, he lies over there,
underneath the cross.
Ever since
I have my peace.
Wake up!
This here is the only law.
Fine, I do what I can, judge.
Sure, it's not going well.
The boys are right.
But I'm just a single man...
...all alone against these coyotes.
- Now we're here.
That's right, George!
Son, faith and enthusiasm alone
won't be enough for this.
Unfortunately, that's the way it is.
The people here are scared.
They even come to
these jackals' defense.
That's exactly the point.
We have to convince the people...
...to revolt against
these criminals. United.
Once we are united,
these bandits will tremble with fear.
Without having
to kill someone.
I don't really believe it,
but one can try.
We must, Sir, we must force
these murderers to show themselves.
Fine.
Bring me the culprit
and I will be implacable.
We will.
Even if we have to turn the
whole country upside down.
It's no use, Mister,
we have...
We've been talking to
everyone around here.
But they're slamming
their doors into our faces.
And they also
make strange signs.
- What kind of signs?
- That kind.
They don't talk because
they're afraid of the bandits.
Well. Except for Toland.
And he's violent.
Then we have to
do it on our own.
- Mister, I have an idea!
- He has an idea! Him!
Instead of walking around and
asking questions like some peddler...
...why don't we
look for the collector?
He's right!
If we manage to catch him...
...we could
make him talk!
I hardly believe that
after last time's incident...
...they'll be sending him to us, right?
- Are you looking for me?
I saved you
some efforts.
After all, we still have
a score to settle, right?
I told you from the start
that you'll pay for that!
The river will
make you disappear.
I've always been a friend of
clean work without witnesses.
Get out!
Or do you believe you can
still swim, filled with lead?
One minute.
Hey you, freeze!
- You're talking to me?
- Yeah, you. Get off.
- Put down the belt and come here.
- And why?
Put it down!
Come here and stand
next to the others.
You, get out there!
You don't mind
joining the party, do you?
No.
- But who invited me?
- What do you mean?
That I like
to know my hosts.
And why should you
know our names?
I do have to write something on it -
on your graves, right?
A bad day, right?
Mister, I feel obligated -
I mean, we'd like to, well...
If it causes you that much trouble,
you don't have to thank me.
- I can do it, Mister. I'd love to!
- George!
Mister, it's my duty
to thank you.
But you should know that I don't
approve of your methods.
Of course, everybody may
think what he likes.
- But if I may give you an advice...
- That would be a pleasure, Mister!
I wouldn't run around
naked if I was you.
Something could easily
catch a cold - forever.
This man seems
right to me.
We also have to arm ourselves
if that's a tradition around here.
- We're no killers.
- Why?
Is someone who defends
himself a killer?
He was fast as lightning.
Quick as a viper.
They all pissed
their pants.
But I went to
challenge him in his room!
Jazz, I said, get out of
the door if you got courage!
Hey you, I'm not done yet.
So, he said to me...
Take this bag.
Who, me?
And carry it upstairs.
Me!
- Me...
- Please.
- Me...!
- You what?
I'll take
the bag upstairs.
Fine, I like
helpful people.
- Is my room ready?
- Yes, yes, yes, it's ready, Mister.
- Something to drink for my friend.
- A drink for your friend.
And bring me a bottle
to that table.
There it is.
Only the bottle.
A nice cup if you
allow me the remark!
I do.
It's the only remembrance
of my father.
He was a nobleman or something.
Never met him.
My mother though,
was a little slut.
I'm more like her.
- Give us some good whiskey.
- At once.
- And a deck of cards.
- Okay.
Let's see if there's
a free table.
- Ah, there!
- Very good.
Do you mind if I shake these poor fellas
down of a couple dollars at this table?
If you like, I could
relieve you of some, too.
You see, boys, what only one cup
too much can do to someone?
Let's sit down,
he won't even notice us.
No, my friend,
I don't like that at all.
And I really fancy
a little game right now!
Then we will see
if you like this game.
You're lucky, man.
I don't kill
if I don't profit from it.
That applies to you, too.
Buzz off! The party is over.
Work with
tactfulness, Duke.
But please.
A barbarian without style.
The world
is quite small, right?
Yes, yes. Too small.
Well, then you better
change the spot!
You do know
the rules, don't you?
- Never in pairs at the same feeder.
- Yeah, I know the rule.
But I have to take care
of some things here.
And you know
what it's like in our job:
The customer is king.
- Why don't you change the spot?
- You see...
I also have to take care
of some things here.
- You know how it is.
- May I?
Yes, you're right.
The customer is king.
If that's so...
...there's no other choice.
- I think so, too.
Take your hands down!
You too!
- If you allow?
- I don't allow it!
No, no, no, gentlemen,
I don't allow it!
If you don't mind,
that's on the house!
You'll let me know if you
need some ammunition, alright?
You'll thank me for this,
I'm sure about that!
- See you very soon!
- Bye, see you!
How the hell
do you fix that?
Two beers, please.
Okay. But drink up fast
and listen carefully:
If you never put another foot in
here again, you'd do me a big favor!
You can put your mind at rest,
we only have the best intentions.
One could think
you're afraid of us, aren't you?
In the end, you're friends
with these racketeers.
Me?
I'm friends with everyone.
I say with everyone,
but not with them!
No, I just handle
my own stuff.
- Hey boys!
- Yes?
The price tag.
A nanny.
That's precious.
You, Stranger, are playing
the nanny for these two kiddies.
Duke, did you ever think
about your reputation?
You can't shoot at two kiddies,
as you call them!
Two kiddies who still have the
price tag hanging from their colts.
You're right.
My client
should have told me.
But what should I do now?
I accepted that assignment.
I can hardly wait
for them to grown up.
I, on the contrary,
really like that.
I like watching them
growing up.
- I hope it's not for nothing.
- But no, Mister.
Manuel knew the collector.
He's from our village.
He's the brother of the cousin
of the wife of Pedro's godfather.
No, he's the cousin
of the sister!
That's enough.
They saw you, tramp.
Come down.
Yes, Mister.
But, Mister, I,
I didn't do anything!
I... please, Mister!
But...
We'll take care
of him later. Quick!
When they arrive at the
tree over there, you shoot!
Yes, damn...
Kill them!
Mister, I'd like...
You see, we'd like to...
We'd like to
tell you that...
- You see...
- So?
We're really grateful for everything
you have done for us.
For saving our lives.
And most of all that
you've shown us that you...
...even if you just want
to enforce the law...
...you have
to use a gun.
- We owe you...
- You're up to your neck in shit.
- Isn't it so?
- Yes, yes! That's right, Mister.
- Yes, that's right! But...
- You want to keep your tails up, right?
Right! Even if they
tear us apart!
And you almost
accomplished that.
- Is that all?
- Er, no, in fact...
...we wanted to ask you
to help us a little.
We must learn
to defend ourselves...
...if we want to get out
of that situation.
We do know that you
have no reason to do it.
The bandits
didn't harm you.
Before you speak you should
bite your tongue seven times!
- I just wanted to say...
- I know what you wanted to say.
I'll help you.
But to one condition:
Nobody may
find out about it.
Be quick when you draw.
And precise when you shoot.
Widen your belt a little.
It must sit deeper.
Next to your hand.
Like this.
Alright, Mister.
I'd really love
a sip of coffee, too!
Not during the training.
Only makes you nervous.
And...
never face the sun.
How often did I tell you,
you must have the sun in your back.
So. Come on.
Let's do it, men.
If you keep going like this, boys,
you can only hope...
...that your opponent
will die of fear.
Give me that gun.
It's like a butterfly.
If you squeeze it
too tight, it'll choke.
If you don't hold it
tight enough, it'll fly away.
Clear?
Take one more look at
how to draw and how to aim.
It's quite easy.
You cock while you draw
and shoot while you aim.
Good.
And now you keep trying.
- Like this?
- You take too long, John.
The guy opposing you won't wait
for you until he shoots.
And you, Irishman,
don't pull a show for pretty girls.
It's quite
alright already.
- Can you see this can in the center?
- Yes.
Good.
Imagine, it was a man.
And if you don't
want him to kill you...
...you must think
of three things:
First of all, you mustn't
hate this man.
You just have to try
to shoot him one moment...
...before he shoots you.
- That's very noble, Mister.
No, that's not noble at all.
That's just practical.
Hate paralyzes the reflexes.
It's an advantage for your enemy.
You shoot with the brain first,
then with the gun.
If I shoot him in my mind,
the hand will be quicker.
Quicker than his.
Like that!
You see?
Very simple.
- Simple, he said.
- And now:
Practice, practice
and practice.
Fine, men,
now it's your turn.
- Yes, Mister!
- You, Pedro...
Can you see that can?
- I can see it! I can see it very well!
- Fine. Go ahead.
Shall I shoot?
Now!
No, not like this.
- Try it again, come on.
- I'm sorry, Mister...
...but this is not meant for us.
- That's right!
We're better with these!
Look!
And Pedro is much
better than me, Mister!
- You want to see it?
- No, that's enough.
But you also have to shoot
with guns, like the others.
No, Mister, not with guns.
With these, if there's any need.
They make lots of holes
with one single shot.
- And do you know how to use them?
- Sure, Mister!
Like this and then...
Watch, how it's done.
I'll do it slowly, so you understand.
Clear?
Clear, he asks!
I load these with
a special powder!
I heard about that.
And I hope it's true - for you.
I especially came to this
damned village because of them.
Hey, I advice you
to serve him well.
He's someone who
knows these things.
- Hello, Cobra Ramirez.
- Hello, Stranger.
- You're here because of a job?
- Because of these.
What do you
think of it?
- They're a blast!
- I'd like to try them.
Not with me, I hope.
You're not lucky enough
to be my friend -
...but you're also not that
unlucky to be not.
You're in real good shape, Cobra.
You're one of the great ones.
I already said that in the
saloon yesterday evening.
And I told them
about these, too.
What are these?
Scalps?
So to speak.
When Cobra Ramirez kills someone
he always cuts off a strand of hair...
...to serve the bill, right?
But there's a guy jumping up and he said:
"Then why doesn't he
become a hairdresser...
...instead of a gunslinger?"
- Who?
Ah, don't mind it, Cobra.
Those people are just jealous.
Spit it out.
Tell me who it is!
So!
It was you?
Answer me!
You said it?
For the last time,
did you say it or not?
Listen, I didn't say it.
I don't give a shit about
what my colleagues do.
And now I'd like to drink
my whiskey in peace.
- See you around!
- You're a filthy pig!
- A coward. Scum!
- Yeah, possible.
Listen, would you mind
stepping aside?
I'd like to see if someone else
is standing back there.
Defend yourself!
- Defend yourself, son of a bitch!
- Ah! So you knew her?
The next one will get a
little closer if you don't get up!
Compliments.
You pushed
the right button.
You don't know how much
this cup means to me.
It took you long
enough anyway.
- Would you like one last whiskey?
- No.
Let's do it then?
Where would you like to do it?
I don't care.
Then back there.
We'll shoot
at three, okay?
Step a little back.
That's good.
- Whenever you're ready.
- Okay.
One...
Two...
Three!
Hey.
Where is the Stranger?
He left
all of the sudden.
Almost exactly in the moment
when you, so to speak...
This son of...
A real brother.
- And, did we hit it?
- Did we hit it?
- That was all me!
- No, me, me!
- Mister, once more, okay?
- Okay!
What do you think about
walking two steps with us?
Well, don't you want to know
where we're going, gunslinger?
Over there, at the hills,
we'll kill you!
At the the hills,
you won't kill anybody...
...otherwise, you would have
tried already.
Oh look, your boss is
already waiting for us.
He wants to see me.
Is that supposed to be
the big surprise?
Seems like it wasn't that hard
to catch the Stranger.
As you can see,
you're not irreplaceable.
Good day!
To you too!
I offer you a deal.
A good deal.
I came to think that
it's nonsense...
...to set two of the best shots
in the country on each other.
That's the coalition,
gentlemen.
The coalition!
Right, Stranger?
Fine. I need the both of you.
To punish the rebels.
I know your price,
Stranger.
I'll double it,
triple it!
That's an
interesting offer.
But the thing is,
I already have a client.
And you know what
it's like in our job, Duke:
The customer is king.
- I knew it.
- What do you mean?
If he came,
then because he wanted to.
Stranger! Show us what you got
back there, underneath the blanket!
Stop!
What did I tell you?
He knows the job!
And never betrays a client.
- What does that mean?
- Don't you understand that he has a plan?
Ah, you talk
too much, Duke!
He's making
a monkey out of you.
Well, I'm leaving then -
you'll surely come to visit me again.
And that will cost you
quite something.
Because I'm no
small-time crook.
What 's up? Does shaving against
the grain give you goosebumps?
Okay,
you can go, Duke.
- You're staying a little, huh?
- Sure.
The offer is tempting.
- Does he feel insulted?
- He can go to hell.
- I want to bargain with you.
- Fine.
But I like to look
my client in the face.
You know,
as a guaranty for my pay.
Sounds plausible.
You'll pay for that!
Fortunately, Pedro saw...
...that they took you away!
- Yeah, that was real luck.
- We came exactly in the right moment!
- Very good, exactly in the right moment.
- Just one more second...
- They simply would have killed you...
...like a greenhorn!
- Sure.
Just one more second
and I could have found out...
...who's the boss of the blackmailers!
You damned botchers.
- But we wanted to help you.
- Come on, stop it!
I had enough
of playing your nanny.
The world was already invented
before you two arrived.
And if she's shitty then it's definitely
not you two who will fix her.
Thanks for everything
you have done.
But in future,
we'll make it without you!
We're even, gunslinger!
Attention,
there he comes.
Let's go.
No, no coffins
made to measure.
The tallest of the three
fits in there perfectly.
I just wanted him to
look good, you know?
I don't think that
this still matters to him.
Hello Camposanto!
Did you know that they call you
that around here now, cemetery?
- My compliment.
- You can compliment yourself.
Now your boss won't do
without you anymore.
By the way, thanks for
the collaboration yesterday.
Well, you did that
favor to me.
- Now I'm the only one far and wide.
- Well.
Now you can
make the price.
Look, there's
something big going on.
The breeders allied.
Stranger, may I
ask you a favor?
A... what?
Fa-vo-r.
You had your fun.
Now go and leave the finale up to me.
Do you know
what I mean?
That they'll pay you plenty
if you stay the course, right?
If it matters,
the others count no more.
I have to do my work, Stranger.
Whatever comes my way.
I know, Duke.
But whatever
comes my way -
...I'll make you sweat.
Silence, gentlemen!
Let John McIntire speak.
And why?
Hasn't he caused enough trouble already?
Exactly! Ever since they revolted against
the collectors, they're ruining us all!
They poisoned
the well on my ranch!
Yesterday, they shot
ten of my cows.
And twenty today!
And it's getting worse!
It's all their fault.
Aw, stop it already!
We let them milk us like cows.
They already relieved us
of thousands of dollars!
What's the McIntires fault?
That they made an end to this?
Shut up,
you didn't get it yet!
He's absolutely right!
Seems like he
wants them to kill us all.
- He's right!
- Silence!
Silence! Please.
Gentlemen!
This won't
get us anywhere!
We're here to make a decision,
not to fight each other.
Let Toland speak.
Toland, you asked for
this meeting. What now?
Friends.
I'm the first one to respect
the courage of these boys.
Once, I was
courageous, too.
- And you know what I got out of it?
- Yes! Yes! Keep talking!
- Yeah! Keep talking!
- Alright.
And you know why
that happened to me?
Because these
jackals think...
...I'm acting in collusion
with the McIntires.
Listen, boys.
You too, Rhett.
I was always playing tough,
that's true.
But I never stepped
on anyone's feet!
Toland! You know damn well that
my boys acted in everyone's interest.
Maybe.
But now we have to pay for this.
Toland! Toland!
These pigs set the repositories
on your ranch on fire.
- I tried to follow them, but...
- Yeah, sure, Sheriff.
You tried to follow them.
You never succeed beyond trying!
- Am I right?
- Oh yeah?
And I'm supposed to catch
some bullets for you?
The two dollars they pay me
a day aren't worth that.
- Here, take it back.
- Come on, Sheriff, nobody's doubting you.
You better tell us
what happened.
I saw the smoke
and rode there.
There was a
whole bunch of them.
I tried to cut off
their way...
...but they
shot at me.
And then, at the ranch of the McIntires,
they suddenly disappeared.
What are you
implying, Sheriff?
- Stay calm, my son.
- John...
...I'm just saying
what I saw.
I lost their track
on your ranch.
Where, by the way,
nothing ever happened, right?
Exactly! He's the only one
they didn't mess with.
- Don't you think that's strange?
- Silence!
You have to take back
what you just said, right now.
Do you think,
I'm afraid of you, junior?
Well! You're not that brave
when you're facing the bandits.
Did you hear that?
- Now they're calling us cowards!
- Cripes...
Take your hands off!
- Just stay calm!
- Stop it!
- It's enough!
- Will you...
Stop it now!
- You'll wreck my whole place!
- Silence!
Will you stop it!
- What's going on in there?
- A brawl! Let's go!
- That should be better.
- But no. In there, man!
- Do you want to abandon the Masters?
- No!
Hey! Where are you going?
This way, coward!
Who's going to repair all this?
Stop it!
- Stop!
- No, please don't, leave that...
No!
Attention!
Damn it, those idiots!
- Hence with it!
- Here he is!
- Not to me!
- I don't want him!
In the name of the law,
stop it!
- Oh, excuse me, my friend!
- You son of a bitch!
My clavus!
Thanks, Dad!
Bravo, Dad!
- Is that yours, by any chance?
- Yeah! But I still have another one.
Thanks, judge!
That's enough now!
Hey! Hey!
Pedro!
- But, who hit me?
- A gringo! But I crushed him.
Ouch, that hurts!
That little blood...
Hey! And?
Yes, John, that's
the Sheriff's saddle.
But are you sure
that you're alright?
- Oh, Mister...
- Ah, Chico!
- I'm Pedro.
- Good, Pedro...
- How much does a saddle like this cost?
- Chin up, John.
We'll go to pick up Daddy
and then we'll go home.
- A nice bath will do you good.
- But, don't you understand...
...what I'm trying to say, wise guy?
How much, Chico?
Pedro...!
- This saddle - well, about 400 dollars.
- 400 dollars...
Listen, George, you're good
at maths, aren't you?
If someone earns
two dollars a day...
...how long will it take him
to afford a saddle like this?
But who earns
two dollars a day?
Hello, Sheriff!
How are you?
What do you want?
You didn't wake me up,
to wish me good night, did you?
Do you know
what time it is?
- Yeah, Sheriff, but...
- So get lost and go to bed.
- Yeah, I know, it's just, me and, um...
- You and who?
Spit it out, what the hell
do you want?
Well, we've been asking ourselves,
well, how you manage...
How I manage
to do what?
Well, two dollars
aren't that much, I think.
What are you
trying to say?
What does that mean,
two dollars aren't much?
Yes exactly,
that's precious little.
That's why the calculation
didn't work.
Okay, Pedro.
Go to bed...
...and come back tomorrow,
when you've slept out your flush.
It crossed our mind
that you, Mister...
...that you act in collusion
with the bandits.
Well, that you are, so to speak,
part of the band.
But what a thought, Pedro.
Is that your personal or...
But yes, yes, yes, Mister,
my very personal!
And that's why you came in the middle
of the night, to tell me that?
- Is that it?
- Of course, Sheriff.
All alone and
in the middle of the night.
Why don't you
come in?
We'll have a little drink and you
tell me some more about your funny idea.
Thank you very much, Sheriff!
Please, after you.
Aw, come on, get in,
don't cause yourself inconvenience.
Hey... Pedro!
I think, you're
a little loco, my friend.
Another hit
and I sure am.
How come, you suddenly
forgot your good upbringing?
You wanted to go inside
in front of the gringo?
- Chico! What did you do to him?
- We just exchanged some caresses.
Untie me, boys!
Stop this drunken madman!
You shouldn't have
done that.
Listen, Mister.
I'm just a poor workman.
I can neither
read nor write.
But if I look into the eyes of someone,
I know what's in his heart.
And I'm telling you, that gringo
would have shot me...
...after I told him,
what I think of him.
Don't listen tom him,
he's a liar!
He couldn't shoot me
in the street...
...so he politely invited me
into his house.
You don't believe that a gringo
invites someone like me into his house.
No, those people only need us
to muck out their pig sties.
You don't believe the gibberish
of this unlucky fellow, do you?
Look at him, John.
He's at the end of his ropes.
Let's let them
sort this out their way.
He has no choice, Mister.
If he won't talk -
...I'll kill him!
- You're an American, just like me, son!
You're not going to
allow these dirty savages...
...to lay their hands on me, right?
- He's all yours.
You dirty pigs! I want to see you
with folded hands inside a coffin!
Listen closely, Sheriff.
You see these knifes?
I'll pick up one
after another, randomly.
And whenever I count to five
I'll throw one of them in your direction.
One of them
is marked -
...and that one will make you
meet your Maker.
So, if you're lucky,
you'll live four times until five.
If you're not, you'll only
hear me count once.
You'll pay for this!
- I'll kill you all!
- Sure, that's what you would do.
You would have done that to them, too.
You would do everything for the money.
- What money?
- You know that very well.
The money you stole from my father
and the other breeders!
We want to know
where you hid it.
I don't know anything!
As you wish.
Chico!
One...
Two...
- Three...
- Stop him!
Four...
Five!
Good grace,
you're damn lucky!
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five!
- So, will you make up your mind?
- I don't know a thing!
- I know nothing! I swear!
- You really are a lucky devil.
Maybe you'll live
once more until five.
- One...
- Yes, it's true!
- Two...
- I'm part of the plot!
Three...
- They made me do it!
- Four... Five!
They would have shot me.
I'm no hero!
I didn't want to die
for two dollars a day!
That's much better, Sheriff.
But there has got to be a boss.
- If you're not it, who is it?
- If I talk, they'll kill me.
But what difference
does it make?
If you don't talk,
Chico will kill you!
Chico!
Hey man!
Your time has come.
No. I don't want to die.
I don't know where the money is!
One...
- Two...
- Stop him!
- Three...
- No!
- Four...
- Stop! I'll talk!
- I'll tell you where the money is.
- So, you're the boss!
Only he would know!
Where did you
hide it, bandit?
Now listen closely.
In the meantime, my men
will have searched for me.
Forward, go!
You don't stand a chance.
They will shoot you like dogs.
A little faster, Mister.
Or the first one who dies
will be a dog with a star.
Be sensible for once, boys.
Now you got what you were after!
- Take the money and let me go.
- Sheriff...
...you still didn't
realize that you're...
...not in the position
to make proposals.
Very true, John.
Where is the money?
It's up there.
Help me.
Go!
- Chico! Take care of the Sheriff.
- Trust me, Mister.
I'll take care of him.
Careful, Mister!
- Up!
- Thanks, Mister!
We did it!
Chico!
He's up here!
The money, Chico!
We found it!
Thank God!
Damn it,
he outsmarted us!
What are you
doing here?
I told you
not to come here.
Something happened.
Those damned jackanapes
McIntires sniffed everything out.
They thought I was the boss
of the band and tortured me!
Now calm down.
Have a drink.
- Where are the boys?
- I took them to the monastery.
To the monastery!
Are you crazy?
What else should I do?
But I was clever,
they're stuck up there!
- Right next to the money!
- Yes, but they can't get away!
Another one.
And we can shut their trap
before they can alert the others.
Tell the Duke he should hold up
the Stranger and everything's fine.
One more, please.
By the way, partner, your killer couldn't
manage to lure the McIntires into a trap.
- Don't you think I'm in for a bonus?
- Sure, partner!
Don't like it.
Dead sheriffs aren't my cup of tea.
That's bandits' business.
What? You are telling me this!
A killer!
- A bastard of a killer!
- Sure, but by birth.
Someone like you becomes that
by pulling a heap of trickery.
Alright, Duke.
Let's not fight.
- I need you.
- That's better.
- But this time, I'll set the price.
- I'll give you another 5,000 dollars.
- But you have to hold up the Stranger.
- But of what use is it to you...
...if I only hold him up for an hour?
- An hour! What does that mean?
You know, the Stranger...
...is a tough case.
- You're a thief, Duke!
But of course!
Like any other respectable professional.
10,000. But you have to
hold him up until the crack of dawn.
The crack of dawn?
Crack of dawn is 20,000.
Ten.
That's my final offer.
I don't think your money will be
of much use when you're dead.
Don't you think?
20,000.
Agreed.
Let's go.
In advance, please.
Something tells me, as soon as
the work's done, you'll leave for Mexico.
And I don't plan
on running after you.
Do you think the bandits
will come here?
Yes.
You can be sure that the Sheriff
was in a hurry to get them.
Stay calm.
We will defend ourselves.
If only the Stranger
was with us.
- We should have walked back by foot.
- But no, George.
They would have caught us out there
which would have been much worse.
At least,
we have cover.
And also, how should we
have taken Chico with us?
We couldn't have left him behind.
They would have killed him.
Admittedly,
now they'll kill us all.
Chico! Stop clattering your teeth.
You're making me nervous.
I'm thirsty.
Have you seen some water
around here, by any chance?
- You're not afraid, are you?
- Um, no!
The Stranger will surely
be here on time.
- Are you sure about that?
- Well, so far, he came every time.
- Nobody notified him, Pedro.
- The other times as well.
That man
needs no notifications.
Nobody can stop him.
- Duke!
- Yes, Stranger!
I'm in a hurry, Duke.
I won't be able to stay.
Sorry about that, Stranger.
But you won't move a bit.
I'm very sorry, Duke,
but I have to move on.
- I can't hear you.
- Then listen to this.
Can't help it, friend.
I can't hear you.
- Did you hear me?
- Of course I heard you!
Take a look around.
- Who! Me?
- No! My grandpa! Go!
Take cover!
Go!
Forward!
Fight them back!
Shoot! Shoot!
It's useless.
They're covered in there.
We'll drag them out of there then.
Come with me.
John!
I got him!
If you stick your nose out there one
more time, it'll get a nice little scratch.
- John! Give me some bullets, quick!
- I can't, George!
I only have
three shots left.
- Chico! Ammunition!
- I only have these.
- Stranger!
- Yeah?
Very nice.
You decided to be good.
Like an angel.
A guardian angel, Duke.
Damn...
And what now, Duke?
May I go?
Just go, Stranger.
My contract just applies
until dawn.
And the sun is rising.
This is the moment, Fred.
They must have
run out of ammo.
We all shoot at the same time
and then we go!
- Tell the others!
- Alright.
Pedro! The knife.
What are those damned
bastards up to?
Why aren't they
shooting?
Shoot! Shoot!
Give me the bullets!
Attention.
They're coming.
Pretty Irishwoman! John!
Take them.
- That's Toland!
- He mustn't escape!
Hello, folks!
- The Stranger!
- Finally!
- Thanks and all that.
- Don't mention it.
Hey Chico!
- I need you for a minute.
- Me?
- Oh, the young Masters...
- Come!
Attention, George!
Nice shot, dear brother.
Where is the Stranger?
Ho! Ha! Mister!
Chico! We've done it!
We made it!
- The Stranger!
- Over there.
Come on! Let's go.
- Good. Nice work, boys.
- Thanks to you.
Because once again you arrived
at the right moment, Mister...
Camposanto, right?
That's what the bandits call you!
- Cemetery! But for them!
- Exactly!
Enough with the
compliments for now, boys.
You annoy the hell
out of me.
Get lost now.
- But Mister, in there is still...
- I know, the breeders' money.
I'll take that.
For the efforts.
But we risked our lives
to get it back.
We won't let you take it
away again that easy.
However, it looks pretty
much like I will keep it.
Go ahead, pick it up.
I'll give you one minute
to lop off.
Mister?
Yes, yes,
that'll be better.
And don't stop until you reached
your father's house!
Very friendly, Duke.
But they're
not that heavy.
Oh yes, they are.
Twice as heavy as you might think.
Toland is dead, Duke.
You don't have a contractor.
You don't have to represent
anyone's interests anymore.
Maybe not his.
But now I attend to mine.
This money is mine, Duke.
You may keep the other, friend.
I'm fine with one half.
No. I don't share.
This stuff caused me
enormous work, understand?
And besides,
I'm too tired to fight.
But if you downright
force me to...
- I'm pigheaded, Stranger.
- You're too greedy.
The money you took from Toland
isn't enough for you.
Money is never enough for me.
I just have too many vices.
I'll teach you
a little modesty.
Forlorn hope.
Many have tried that.
And they're dead.
Do you have
one final wish?
Yeah.
I'm out of cigars.
You want it
with golden handles?
- What, the coffin?
- Of course! I want you to look good.
You're a professional
with style.
- When it stops, okay?
- Alright.
When it stops,
we'll shoot.
Farewell.
That's the amusing part
of our profession.
I could have sworn
that you didn't see him.
I thought
you didn't see him.
Good!
Then the next time.
Sometime, we'll have to know
who's the quicker one, right?
Um, sure.
And maybe then it's about something
more valuable than a few stones.
A few stones?
But... but where
did all the dough go?
In there.
He told me
to hide it in there.
Lo and behold!
Let's hurry!
The Duke
could follow us!
And we took him
for a bandit.
- What a man.
- He should become supreme sheriff.
Or even governor!
Oh, no, Mister George,
that's impossible.
Governors are all thiefs.
To rob a colleague -
...out of sheer
sentimentality!
- You're the shame of our guild.
- I did tell you though...
...the old McIntire
once saved my life.
You risked your life
for this comedy.
Seems so.
Where are you
going now?
Where will I go?
Wherever they pay me!
In Abilaine they're looking for people
who are quick with the colt.
They want to show
some rustlers the ropes.
You're going there?
Might throw
a glance at it.
Abilaine is
up north, right?
Hey Duke!
- This way leads south!
- Exactly, brother.
- If you're heading north...
- The important thing is that you're happy.
- Concerning the "brother"...
- You just resemble me so much.
You're just like me,
a true son of a bitch!