1849.
A NATION POURS WEST
IN A MAD FLOOD.
GOLD - GOLD IN CALIFORNIA.
GOLD IN THE STREAMS.
GOLD AT THE GRASS ROOTS.
GOLD IN THE BLOWING DUST.
YELLOW, MALLEABLE, FRIABLE,
SPENDABLE GOLD!
1865.
THE DAYS OF '49 ARE GONE.
PICK AND PAN
HAVE GLEANED THE SURFACE,
AND THE ADVENTURERS
HAVE MOVED ON TO NEW DIGGINGS.
THE DOORS
OF THEIR DESERTED SHANTIES
SWING IDLE ON BROKEN BOLTS.
BUT STILL A WAR-WEARY,
LAND-HUNGRY PEOPLE
SWEEPS WESTWARD WHERE A NEW GOLD
IS COME OUT OF CALIFORNIA.
THE PLOWS RIP THE FALLOW LAWN.
FOR THIS IS THE NEW GOLD,
THE FLOWING YELLOW GOLD
OF WHEAT.
IN '68 THE SEED IS SOWN.
ITS ROOTS SUCK
THE DARK RICHNESS BELOW.
ITS TOPS STAND GOLDEN
IN A GOLDEN SUNLIGHT,
AND THE GREAT WHEAT EMPIRE
IS BORN.
FOR 10 YEARS IT FLOURISHES.
THEN AGAIN THE NEWS
FLASHES EASTWARD - GOLD!
GOLD ABOVE THE VALLEY
OF THE SACRAMENTO.
GOLD AND A WAY TO GET AT IT.
AGAIN THE ADVENTURERS
RUSH WESTWARD.
BUT THIS TIME,
THEY COME IN PUSHING PULLMANS.
NO MORE PICK-AND-PAN SCRATCHING.
THIS IS 1877.
THIS IS BEDROCK GOLD.
GREAT SQUAT HYDRAULIC MONITORS,
WITH THE PRESSURE
OF THE MELTING SNOWS
OF THE HIGH SIERRAS BEHIND THEM,
RIP THE MOUNTAINS APART.
MONEY AND MACHINES -
A NEW MIDAS TEARING APART
THE QUIET HILLS,
LEAVING A RAW WELTER.
GOLD AND YET MORE GOLD.
OUT OF A SINGLE SLUICE BOX
IN A SINGLE SPRING
IS SNATCHED A MILLION DOLLARS.
GOLD FOR SHIPS AND SCHOOLS
AND CITIES.
GOLD FOR GUNS
AND THE SINEWS OF WAR.
POURING EASTWARD, IT CHOKES
THE CHANNELS OF COMMERCE.
IT TRAVELS THE WEALTH
OF THE WORLD.
AND FOR EVERY
PRECIOUS YELLOW OUNCE,
TONS OF MUD, GRAVEL, AND RUBBLE
ARE DUMPED INTO THE STREAMS
THAT FEED THE GOLDEN
WHEAT EMPIRE BELOW.
THE FLOODS SPREAD.
THE WHEAT RANCHERS PROTEST.
BUT UP IN THE MOUNTAINS,
THE MONITORS LASH OUT
THEIR YELLING TONGUES.
WHERE THERE IS GOLD,
MEN ARE GOING TO GET IT.
KNEE-DEEP
IN THEIR FLOODED FIELDS,
THE RANCHERS WATCH THEIR GOLDEN
ACRES STRANGLE AND DIE.
DIKES AND LEVIES BREAK
AND ARE PATIENTLY,
DESPERATELY PLUGGED AGAIN.
AND SLOWLY, SULLENLY,
THEY SET THEMSELVES
FOR THE LONG, BITTER FIGHT
AGAINST THE POWER OF GOLD.
THOSE TWO IN THE MIDDLE!
MUCH OBLIGED.
YES, SIR.
HEY, WATCH OUT.
HOWDY, SIR. WELCOME TO TENSPOT. YEAH.
MR. WHITNEY.
DRUMMER, I TAKE IT?
WELL, YOU CAN TAKE IT STRAIGHT
OR WITH WATER.
IT'S A FREE COUNTRY.
YOU MIGHT BE
AN EASTERN TOURIST?
MIGHT.
WHERE'S THIS ROOM?
THE SECOND FLOOR, FRONT.
OH, SAY.
DID YOU SAY YOU WAS A DRUMMER?
WELL, NOW, YOU KNOW,
I USED TO DRUM -
PLAYED THE BASS DRUM
IN THE TOWN BAND.
BUT I LOST IT ONCE
PLAYING FOR A PICNIC.
THREE WHISKEYS.
THIS STUFF TASTES
LIKE VARNISH.
WHY DON'T YOU GET SOME
DECENT WHISKEY?
GIVE ME ANOTHER ONE.
MR. LANCE, DON'T YOU THINK
YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH?
NOBODY ASKED YOU
WHAT YOU THOUGHT.
ALL I WANT FROM YOU
IS THAT BOTTLE OF RYE,
AND I WANT IT QUICK.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE FERRIS' BOY,
AREN'T YOU?
YEAH, WHAT ABOUT IT?
TAKE IT EASY, LANCE.
GO ON HOME. THIS IS NO PLACE
FOR DRUNKEN LITTLE BOYS.
WHY DON'T YOU MIND
YOUR OWN BUSINESS?
YOU MIND
YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
ALL RIGHT, BOYS.
THE FIGHT'S OVER.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM.
HERE. HAVE A DRINK.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
SOBER AS A JUDGE.
WHY DID YOU HIT ME?
BECAUSE I THOUGHT YOU WERE
TOO YOUNG TO DIE.
THANKS.
COME ON.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
HERE'S YOUR HAT.
HOWDY, MR. LANCE.
HOWDY, JOSHUA.
COME ON IN, MR. WHITNEY.
COME IN, MR. WHITNEY.
THANKS.
HE'S ALL RIGHT.
DOWN, BOY.
COME ON.
MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME.
LET ME TAKE YOUR HAT.
THANK YOU.
LANCE, WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHY - OH.
THIS IS MY SISTER SERENA,
MR. WHITNEY.
HELLO.
HOW DO YOU DO?
BUT -
WHY DON'T YOU WIPE YOUR
MOUTH? IT'S ALL OVER APPLE.
YOU WAIT. YOU'RE GONNA CATCH IT,
MR. FERRIS.
OH, LANCE,
WHAT DID YOU DO TO CZAR?
HE CAME HOME
THIS MORNING LAME.
I KNOW. I KNOW.
I'M SORRY.
LISTEN, SPRAT, HOW ABOUT TELLING
FATHER WE'RE HERE?
TELL HIM I'VE GOT A GUEST.
YOU KNOW, KIND OF HONEY HIM
A LITTLE.
THERE'S A SWEET KID.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
HE'S AWFULLY MAD, LANCE.
WELL, TRY.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL TRY.
SHE CAN GENERALLY
HANDLE HIM.
I HOPE SO.
LOOK. DON'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN THE BAR.
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
THANKS.
LANCE.
LANCE, HE WANTS YOU.
UH-OH.
THANKS, SPRAT.
BE NICE, LANCE.
PLEASE.
DON'T WORRY. I'LL BE NICE.
WELL, HERE GOES.
GOOD LUCK.
I'LL NEED IT.
WELL, I HOPE YOUR FATHER
WON'T BE TOO HARD ON HIM,
MISS FERRIS.
LANCE IS SO TRIFLING
SOMETIMES THAT...
HAVE AN APPLE,
MR. WHITNEY.
AN APPLE?
YES.
OH. OH.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
WHY DO YOU DO THAT?
OH, THAT?
HABIT, I GUESS.
BACK HOME IN VERMONT,
WE TEST THEM THAT WAY.
YEAH, IT'S CALLED
APPLE-KNOCKING.
WELL, HOW CAN YOU TELL?
WELL, IF IT SOUNDS - PLUNK
- LIKE THAT, IT'S MELLOW.
BUT IF IT JUST CLINKS,
WHY, IT HASN'T SET YET.
HERE, YOU TRY ONE.
SEE? THEY BOTH PLUNK.
I NEVER KNEW THAT.
WELL, KIDS, YOU KNOW.
WELL, THAT IS -
THAT IS, VERY YOUNG LADIES -
THEY DON'T GENERALLY BOTHER
ABOUT THESE THINGS.
YOU KNOW, THEY GENERALLY
TAKE THEM AS THEY COME,
GREEN OR OTHERWISE.
I'M NOT SO YOUNG AS YOU THINK,
MR. WHITNEY. I'M 17.
NO.
WELL, ALMOST 17.
OH.
AND I'VE GOT A 50-ACRE
FRUIT ORCHARD OF MY OWN.
YOU HAVE?
YES, I HAVE.
THAT IS,
IT'S ON MY FATHER'S LAND,
AND I USE HIS TEAMS
AND LABOR.
BUT I PAID FOR MY OWN TREES,
AND I DO MY OWN PRUNING,
AND I RUN
A TWO-HORSE HARROW.
YOU DO?
PERHAPS YOU TELL ME
WHAT'S SO VERY FUNNY?
WELL, I WILL, NOW,
IF YOU PROMISE NOT TO GET MAD.
PROMISE?
YES.
THEY SAY THAT CALIFORNIA
HAS THE SMALLEST STOVES
AND THE BIGGEST LIARS
IN THE UNITED STATES.
I THINK LANCE WILL BE BACK
IN A FEW MINUTES.
NOW, PLEASE, MISS FERRIS.
YOU SAID YOU WOULDN'T GET MAD.
I'M SORRY.
YOU DON'T
HAVE TO BELIEVE ME.
OH, SURE, I BELIEVE YOU.
50-ACRE ORCHARD.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE IT?
YES,
I'D LIKE IT VERY MUCH.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SHOW IT TO YOU.
50 ACRES, HUH?
LET'S SEE.
THAT OUGHT TO BRING IN
ABOUT A...
A 1,000-BUSHEL CROP,
HUH?
1,500, MR. WHITNEY,
WHEN THE TREES ARE REALLY SET.
WELL, MAYBE.
YOU KNOW, THIS OUGHT TO BE
PRETTY GOOD FRUIT COUNTRY.
THESE ARE VERY GOOD APPLES.
WEREN'T GROWN HERE, WERE THEY?
NO, THEY WEREN'T.
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
THEY NEED SNOW.
NITROGEN GOES IN THE SOIL,
BUT POTASH REALLY GIVES THEM
THEIR FLAVOR.
WELL, YOU DO KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT FRUIT, DON'T YOU?
MM-HMM. A LITTLE.
MR. WHITNEY.
LANCE HAS BEEN TELLING ME
ABOUT YOUR KINDNESS.
HAPPY TO MEET YOU, SIR.
PLEASURE, SIR.
FATHER, MR. WHITNEY'S BEEN
TELLING ME ABOUT CALIFORNIA.
HE SAYS WE HAVE
THE SMALLEST STOVES
AND THE BIGGEST LIARS
IN THE UNITED STATES.
WELL, I NEVER NOTICED
ABOUT THE STOVES.
ANYHOW, WE DO HAVE
THE BEST NATIVE BRANDY.
DARE SAY WE COULD FIND A USE
FOR SOME.
COME ALONG, MR. WHITNEY.
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
LANCE TELLS ME YOU'RE
A MINING MAN, MR. WHITNEY.
USED TO BE A FARMER,
BUT THEY SENT ME TO SCHOOL,
AND SOMEHOW I CAME OUT
AN ENGINEER.
AND SOMETIMES I THINK THAT'S
GETTING TO BE THE TROUBLE
WITH THIS COUNTRY -
TOO MUCH EDUCATION.
YOUNG FELLAS LIKE YOU
START DRAWING LINES ON PAPER,
THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN
THERE'S A SNORTING TIN TEAKETTLE
RUNNING ABOUT ON RAILS,
RUSHING PEOPLE FROM ONE PLACE
TO THE OTHER AND BACK AGAIN.
SAY IT SAVES TIME.
MAYBE YOU CAN TELL ME,
MR. WHITNEY -
SAVES TIME FOR WHAT?
MORE LINES ON PAPER.
AND THEN THE NEXT THING
WE KNOW,
THERE'S A MACHINE THEY CALL
A HYDRAULIC MONITOR
TEARING A MOUNTAIN
TO PIECES.
DON'T LET FATHER
GET STARTED ON SLICKINGS
OR WE'LL BE HERE ALL DAY.
WELL, I'M SORRY IF THEY'RE
MAKING TROUBLE FOR YOU, SIR.
OH, THERE'S NOTHING PERSONAL
IN IT, MR. WHITNEY.
WON'T YOU SIT DOWN?
OUR QUARREL ISN'T WITH YOU.
IT'S WITH YOUR BOSSES.
THEY'RE CALLED PIRATES
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WELL, I DON'T THINK
IT'S THEIR FAULT EITHER, SIR.
IT'S A MATTER
OF PUSHING AHEAD.
NO ONE WANTS TO HARM
THE RANCHERS.
BUT THE STUFF'S THERE,
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET IT OUT.
IF WE DIDN'T,
SOMEONE ELSE WOULD.
IT'S SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T STOP
ANY MORE THAN YOU CAN STOP
FROM PUTTING RAILS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
MATTER OF PROGRESS.
WE'LL STOP IT,
MR. WHITNEY,
WHEN THE COURTS
GET AROUND TO IT.
I'M READY, MR. WHITNEY!
READY FOR WHAT?
MR. WHITNEY WANTS TO SEE
MY ORCHARD.
YOU SAID YOU'D LIKE TO SEE IT,
DIDN'T YOU?
WELL, YES -
JARED'S GOING WITH ME.
WE'VE GOT SOME THINGS
TO TALK OVER.
WELL, I'D LIKE TO SEE IT
VERY MUCH.
GO ON OVER TO YOUR ORCHARDS,
SPRAT, AND LEAVE US ALONE.
COME ON, JARED.
WELL,
I'M SORRY, BUT...
IT'S QUITE ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, WELL, MAYBE WE COULD
MAKE IT SOME OTHER TIME.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WE'RE IN A HURRY, SPRAT.
GOODBYE.
IT'S UP TO YOU, ED.
I'LL BET 4 RIGHT
INTO THAT ONE-CARD DRAW.
I'M OUT.
I'LL JUST STAY.
HEY!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN HERE?
COULDN'T YOU READ THAT SIGN
ON THE GATE?
I DID READ IT.
WHO'S IN CHARGE HERE?
YOU'RE LOOKING
AT THE HEADMAN RIGHT NOW.
I'LL RAISE
YOU 4.
WELL, IF YOU'RE IN CHARGE,
WHAT'S -
NO, WE AIN'T HIRING NOBODY
TODAY, MISTER,
SO BE SURE YOU CLOSE THE GATE
ON YOUR WAY OUT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH THOSE MONITORS?
THEY'RE NOT WORKING.
SAY, WHO ARE YOU -
CYRUS McCORMICK
ON A TOUR OF INSPECTION?
WHITNEY'S THE NAME.
I'M THE NEW SUPERINTENDENT.
SUPERINTENDENT, EH?
I BETTER CLEAN THOSE FLUMES
ON THE NORTH END.
"INTRODUCING
MR. JARED WHITNEY."
LOOKS LIKE WE GOT
A WHOLE NEW SUPERINTENDENT.
I BET HE WAS
EVEN TO COLLEGE, BOYS.
ONE OF THEM NEW
DUDE ENGINEERS, HUH?
I ASKED YOU A QUESTION.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THOSE MONITORS?
YONDER THEY LIE.
MAYBE YOU CAN FIGURE OUT
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THEM, WILLIE.
MAYBE.
AND THE NAME ISN'T WILLIE.
IT'S WHITNEY -
MR. WHITNEY.
WHY, YOU...
IS IT TIGHT?
YES, SIR.
THE BOLTS WERE LOOSE.
THAT'S WHAT HELD
YOUR PRESSURE BACK.
ALL RIGHT! TURN THEM ON!
FULL PRESSURE!
AIM HER HIGH.
WATCH THAT KNOB, NOW.
GIVE A HAND.
NOW, LISTEN, MR. MINTON.
THE COMPANY SENT ME DOWN HERE
TO TAKE CHARGE OF THIS MINE
BECAUSE
YOU'RE BEHIND SCHEDULE.
CONSEQUENTLY,
YOU CAN GET YOUR TIME
AND GET OUT, OR GO TO WORK.
AND THAT GOES
FOR THE REST OF YOU.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT IT?
YOU HEARD WHAT HE SAID.
GET BACK TO WORK.
MY, MY.
ALL RIGHT, MORE WATER!
TAKE IT OFF THE OVERBURDEN
AND HIT IT ON THE GRAVEL!
AND DO IT RIGHT!
THE NEW BOSS WILL MAKE YOU
GO TO COLLEGE AND LEARN HOW!
LOOK AT THAT -
MUDDYING UP THE RIVERS
WITH THEIR DIRTY MESS,
RUINING OUR FIELDS
WITH THEIR SLICKINGS,
SPOILING THE COUNTRY.
THE LAW DON'T LET YOU STAND UP
ON A MOUNTAIN
AND FLING MUD IN THE FACE
OF A MAN DOWN BELOW.
CALIFORNIA'S A GOLD STATE,
CHRIS -
ALWAYS HAS BEEN.
THAT HYDRAULICKING CROWD'S
GOT MONEY AND SMART LAWYERS.
I TELL YOU,
WE CAN'T STOP THEM.
SMARTEST LAWYERS
IN THE WORLD
CAN'T CHANGE WHAT'S RIGHT
AND WHAT'S WRONG.
THAT'S WHAT SUTTER SAID.
HE THOUGHT THE LAW WOULD PROTECT
HIS PLANTINGS
AGAINST THE GOLD RUSH.
THAT WAS YEARS AGO, RALPH,
BEFORE ANY LAW WAS OUT HERE.
WELL,
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
SUTTER SAW CALIFORNIA FOR WHAT
IT IS AND OUGHT TO BE -
THE FINEST PLANTING COUNTRY
ON EARTH.
AND LOOK AT SUTTER NOW.
BROKE AS A JAYBIRD.
WHO ASKED YOU,
YOU MEDDLING OLD FOOL?
BRING EVERY HAND ON THE PLACE
DOWN HERE
AND FIX THESE LEVIES
LIKE I TOLD YOU.
YES, SIR, COLONEL.
TIME FOR DINNER, RALPH.
ENOCH, GO PICK UP MISS SERENA.
YES, YOUR HONOR.
COME ON, JOSHUA.
BETTER TAKE A SEAT
IN THE BACK THERE
WHERE YOU'LL BE SAFE
FROM THE RISING WATER.
COME ON, JIM!
WHOA.
DINNERTIME, MISS SERENA!
YOUR FATHER AND YOUR UNCLE RALPH
HAVE ALREADY GONE AHEAD.
ALL RIGHT, ENOCH!
JUST A MINUTE!
WHOA, JIM!
HO, HO, HO!
COME ON.
COME TAKE THE LINES.
HOW DOES MY ORCHARD LOOK?
LOOKS SORT OF LIKE YOU DID
THAT AGE - ALL LEGS.
WELL, YOU JUST WAIT
AND SEE.
IN TWO MORE YEARS,
THEY'LL BE THE BIGGEST TREES
YOU'VE EVER SEEN.
MAYBE SO, IF THEM SLICKINGS
DON'T COVER THEM UP.
GIDDAP.
DOWN, THOR.
OH, I'LL NEVER BE FOOLED
BY A GAL
NEVER BE FOOLED BY A GAL
WHEN SHE LOOKS AT YOU
AND WINKS HER EYE
THEN YOU KNOW DARN WELL
IT'S JUST A LIE
I'LL NEVER BE FOOLED
BY A GAL
LANCE, YOU SAMPLED THAT BRANDY
PRETTY WELL BEFORE DINNER.
THANKS FOR THE CHECKUP,
AUNT ROSANNE.
LANCE, IF I -
WELL, THERE NEVER
WAS A FERRIS
WHO COULDN'T
HOLD HIS LIQUOR.
I'LL JOIN YOU.
RAMON, THE BRANDY.
DOWN, THOR.
YOU ALREADY BIT HIM ONCE.
THAT ANIMAL PETRIFIES ME.
IT ISN'T SAFE AROUND HERE.
SERENA CAN USE HIM
IN THE ORCHARD.
SHE'LL NEED
SOME PROTECTION THERE.
HA. FOOL ORCHARD.
TAKING UP 50 GOOD ACRES OF LAND
TO MESS AROUND WITH FRUIT.
WELL, AT LEAST THEY'LL BE
PEACHES AND PLUMS IN THE HOUSE.
I RECKON YOU'LL BE GLAD ENOUGH
TO EAT THE FRUIT.
I'LL HAVE 1,000 BUSHELS
NEXT YEAR,
AND THEY'LL BRING US $800.
YOU'LL SAVE THE FAMILY FORTUNE
AT THE EXPENSE OF YOUR LOOKS.
IT ISN'T WORTH IT, SERENA.
LOOK AT YOUR HANDS.
THEY'RE LIKE WHIP LEATHER.
SHE'S MAKING A FOOL OF HERSELF.
GOES AROUND LIKE A LABORER.
HMM. LOOK AT YOU. IF YOU'D
EVEN LOOK LIKE A DECENT LABORER,
INSTEAD OF
A MISERABLE DUDE.
IF YOU'D QUIT
LIQUORING UP -
SHUT YOUR HEAD, SPRAT!
LANCEFORD, YOU'LL APOLOGIZE
FOR THAT REMARK.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
I'M SURE
YOU DIDN'T INTEND IT.
AND, SERENA, YOU LEAVE THE TABLE
FOR LOSING YOUR TEMPER.
BUT YOU DO LOOK LIKE A DUDE,
AND YOU DO LIQUOR UP!
SERENA.
AND YOU WON'T WORK.
CHRIS, I DO WISH YOU'D CHAIN UP
THAT AWFUL BEAST.
WHAT'S THE GOOD OF A DOG
LIKE THAT ANYHOW?
FOR ONE THING, TO SCARE OFF
THAT MINING RIFFRAFF
IF THEY EVER SET FOOT
ON MY LAND AGAIN.
THE TROUBLE WITH YOU,
FATHER,
IS THAT YOU'RE NOT WILLING
TO ACCEPT ADVANCEMENT.
GOLD IS UNDER THE SOIL,
NOT ON TOP OF IT.
FARMING WAS ALL RIGHT
IN ITS DAY.
LANCEFORD, THAT DOG
AT LEAST HAS BREEDING.
IT KNOWS A MINE-MUCKER FROM
A GENTLEMAN EVEN IF YOU DON'T.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT ME
TO BE, FATHER?
I'M SURE THAT LANCE
ONLY MEANT TO BE -
THAT'S VERY KIND OF YOU,
AUNT ROSANNE,
BUT I'LL DO MY OWN EXPLAINING -
IF I HAVE TO.
YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, SIR.
OH, BE FAIR
WITH THE BOY, CHRIS.
YOU CAN'T EXPECT HIM
TO BE A PLASTER SAINT.
ONLY ONE THING BOTHERS ME.
HE'S A LOT LESS INTERESTED
IN THIS RANCH
THAN HE IS
IN THAT MINING CROWD.
I WOULDN'T MIND HIS KICKING
AROUND WITH HIS OWN CLASS,
BUT THIS SCUM OF THE EARTH
FROM THE MINES.
HOLD ON, CHRIS.
SOME OF THE BIGGEST MEN IN
CALIFORNIA CAME OUT OF MINING.
WITH THE IDEALS AND TRADITIONS
OF HIGHWAYMEN.
THAT SAN FRANCISCO
MINING CROWD -
CHRIS, YOU DARE SAY THAT.
WHY -
WHY MY OWN FATHER -
THERE, SWEETHEART.
I'M SURE CHRIS DIDN'T MEAN
YOUR FATHER.
OF - OF COURSE NOT.
I NEVER FIGURED YOU'D THINK
I MEANT A MAN LIKE HIM.
WHY, HARRISON McCOOEY, ROSANNE,
YOUR FATHER?
EVERYBODY RESPECTS HIM.
THANK YOU, CHRIS.
I SUPPOSE IT WAS SILLY OF ME.
FORGIVE ME.
DON'T BE LATE, DARLING.
WELL, I SUPPOSE I'LL BE ACCUSED
NOW OF LOSING MY TEMPER.
HAVE A CIGAR, RALPH.
YOU KNOW, CHRIS,
SERENA TAKES AFTER YOU.
SHE'S STUBBORN.
BUT LANCE WAS RIGHT
IN ONE RESPECT.
ABOUT WHAT?
WHEAT'S A THING
OF THE PAST.
THERE'S STUFF IN THE GROUND
OF CALIFORNIA
YOU NEVER PLANTED,
AND IT'LL SWAMP YOU.
WHEREVER THERE'S GOLD, CHRIS,
MEN ARE GOING TO FIND IT.
NOT AGAINST THE LAW.
THE DECISION WAS AGAINST THEM
IN THE COURTS LAST YEAR.
NOW HOW LONG WILL IT STAND
WITH ALL THAT MONEY STACKED UP
AGAINST IT?
HERE, THAT'S NO WAY
TO CUT A CIGAR.
IT'S MY WAY.
WHY, 10 YEARS FROM NOW,
THE WHOLE SACRAMENTO VALLEY
WILL BE UNDER MUD AND SLICKINGS.
QUIT MAKING SPEECHES AND TELL ME
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND.
CHRIS, I WANT TO SELL.
I'VE DECIDED
TO GET INTO GOLD.
YOU'D SELL YOUR LAND?
MY OWN BROTHER?
YOU'RE TALKING CRAZY.
IF YOU THINK SO,
MAKE ME AN OFFER FOR MY SHARE
OF BANNOCKBURN.
NOW, LOOK HERE, RALPH.
I USED TO PUT DIAPERS ON YOU.
I'LL DO IT AGAIN IF YOU DON'T
QUIT THIS FOOLISHNESS.
WHY, IN 200 YEARS,
NO FERRIS HAS SOLD HIS LAND,
EXCEPT TO BUY MORE LAND.
COME ON.
HAVE A BALL OF BRANDY.
AND TELL ROSANNE
I MEANT NO OFFENSE.
I'VE ASKED YOU TO MAKE ME
AN OFFER, CHRIS.
WELL, THEN, EVEN THOUGH WHEAT
IS SELLING LOW,
AND JUST TO SHOW YOU HOW WRONG
YOU ARE, $100,000.
IT'S A TRADE.
RALPH,
YOU WOULDN'T SELL YOUR LAND.
I SAID IT WAS A TRADE.
CASH OF COURSE.
CASH?
I THOUGHT MY CHECK
WOULD BE SUFFICIENT.
STILL, IF YOU INSIST.
CHRIS, DON'T BE SILLY.
OF COURSE YOUR CHECK IS GOOD.
I ONLY WANTED TO GET -
YOU'LL GET YOUR CASH.
ALL I ASK IS THAT YOU'LL BE GONE
FROM HERE BY THE MORNING.
HI, YOUNGSTER!
WELL, HELLO.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
AREN'T WE ON SPEAKING TERMS?
HELLO.
OOH.
WELL, PERHAPS I BETTER COME BACK
SOME OTHER TIME
WHEN YOU'RE NOT SO BUSY,
TO SEE YOUR ORCHARD.
OH. SO YOU DID REMEMBER.
YEAH.
WELL, NOW THAT YOU'RE HERE,
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF IT?
LET'S SEE.
IT'S GREAT.
YOU'RE DOING A FINE JOB.
BUT YOU TOOK OFF
QUITE A CHUNK, THOUGH.
OH, I DON'T DO IT
ALL MYSELF.
STILL, 50 ACRES.
THAT'S A LOT FOR A MAN.
OH, I CAN DO IT.
IT'S NOT WORK FOR ME.
IT'S FUN.
AH, PRETTY DIRTY FUN.
OH, MAY I HELP YOU?
NO, I CAN USUALLY MANAGE.
OH, JUST ONCE.
ALL RIGHT.
I WANT TO
SHOW YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO SHOW ME?
SOMETHING I THINK
WILL SAVE YOU
A LOT OF TIME
ON YOUR IRRIGATION.
OH, GOOD.
NOW, WATCH THIS.
NOW WE'LL MAKE A TRENCH
BETWEEN THESE TWO TREES.
A TRENCH, EH?
YEAH, CONNECTING THE TWO.
YOU WORK ON THAT END
AND MAKE IT A LITTLE DEEPER.
DEEPER THAN YOUR END.
IF YOU LIKE.
I SEE.
THAT'S THE WAY.
WHAT'S THIS GONNA BE FOR?
I'LL SHOW YOU IN A MINUTE.
YEAH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
NOW, HERE. WATCH THIS.
WELL!
SEE THAT?
NOW, YOU CAN DO THAT
RIGHT THROUGH THE ORCHARD.
SEE THE TIME
IT'LL SAVE YOU?
WHY, THAT'S PERFECTLY
WONDERFUL!
SIMPLE, ISN'T IT?
I SHOULD SAY IT IS!
NOW WE'LL DO IT OVER HERE.
WHY, NOBODY AROUND HERE
HAS EVER THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW,
I ALWAYS PRIDED MYSELF
ON KNOWING
ALL ABOUT ORCHARDS,
BUT I SEE I'VE MUCH MORE
TO LEARN.
COME TO THINK OF IT,
I HAVEN'T SEEN ANOTHER ORCHARD
IN CALIFORNIA.
BUT I MUST SAY,
THIS IS THE FINEST FRUIT-GROWING
SOIL I EVER SAW.
I'M SO GLAD
TO HEAR YOU SAY THAT.
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T GET ANYBODY
AT THE HOUSE
TO PAY ANY ATTENTION TO IT.
THEY JUST LAUGH.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
YOU'LL HAVE THE LAST LAUGH.
MR. WHITNEY,
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IT MEANS
TO TALK TO SOMEBODY WHO REALLY
UNDERSTANDS AND WHO -
WELL, WHO DOESN'T
MAKE FUN OF YOU.
I SUPPOSE
WHEN YOU FIRST MET ME,
YOU THOUGHT ME
AN AWFUL SPRAT.
I'D LIKE TO APOLOGIZE.
OH, I'M SORRY.
OH, DON'T WORRY.
I'M USED TO DIRT.
BUT DON'T MEN LIKE WOMEN
WHO HAVE NICE WHITE HANDS?
OH, WOMEN, YES,
BUT IT REALLY ISN'T IMPORTANT,
YOUNGSTER.
I'M NOT A YOUNGSTER.
THAT'S RIGHT. I FORGOT.
YOU'RE A GROWN WOMAN.
LET'S TRY THE NEXT ONE.
812 SACKS,
ALL FROM THE LOWER 40.
"812"...
BEFORE THE SLICKING HIT HER,
IT WAS AT 1,560.
"1,560."
THAT WAS TWO YEARS AGO.
WELL,
WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO?
NOW YOU'VE GOT ME
ALL CONFUSED.
WELL,
DID YOU FIND MR. LANCE?
UH, HE'S COMING.
WHERE WAS HE?
IN THE BED, SOUND ASLEEP.
GET LOADING,
YOU LAZY IGNORAMUS.
YOU BET YOUR LIFE.
412 SACKS.
"400 AND... "
LANCE!
YOU CALL ME, SIR?
11:00 IN THE MORNING,
AND YOU'RE STILL IN YOUR BED.
HAS BEEN OUT HERE
SINCE BEFORE DAYLIGHT.
YOU KNOW WE'RE SHORT
OF HANDS.
MOST OF THE MEN HAVE GONE
TO WORK IN THE MINES.
HARDLY BLAME THEM
FOR WANTING TO EARN MORE MONEY.
BESIDES, THEY LIKE MINING.
THEY'RE PROBABLY AS SICK AS
I AM OF WHEAT FIELDS. LANCE.
THIS IS NOTHING NEW, SIR.
YOU KNOW I NEVER INTEND
TO BE A FARMER.
I'D LIKE TO GET AWAY
FOR A COUPLE OF MONTHS.
IF YOU COULD LEND ME $400 OR $500. WHAT?
OH, DON'T WORRY ABOUT THE
MONEY, SIR. I'LL PAY YOU BACK.
EVERYBODY'S MAKING MONEY
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
SAN FRAN- WELL, SIR,
YOU'VE GOT YOUR NERVE.
WHY, YOU CAN ALMOST PICK UP
MONEY IN THE STREETS THERE.
LOOK AT UNCLE RALPH.
WELL, LOOK AT HIM.
SOLD HIS BIRTHRIGHT FOR A MESS
OF MINE STOCK.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
I WANT TO GO SOMEPLACE
WHERE THERE'S SOME LIFE -
SOME FUTURE FOR ME,
THAT'S ALL.
FUTURE?
WHY, MY BOY,
ONE DAY THIS WHOLE RANCH
WILL BE YOURS AND SERENA'S.
AND BY THAT TIME,
IT WILL BE UNDER 3 FEET OF MUD.
ASK ANYBODY.
ASK JARED.
I'M NOT ASKING
ANY YANKEE MINER
TO HELP RUN
MY FAMILY AFFAIRS.
JARED'S MY FRIEND, SIR.
OH.
SO HE'S THE ONE
WHO'S BEEN PUTTING IDEAS
OF SAN FRANCISCO
INTO YOUR HEAD.
IT WAS MY OWN IDEA.
AND IF YOU'D ONLY LEND ME
THE MONEY, I'D -
I'M NOT FINANCING ANY WILD-GOOSE
CHASE TO SAN FRANCISCO. BUT, SIR -
AND THAT, LANCE, IS FINAL.
WHOA.
MORNING, MacKENZIE.
FETCHING TO GET YOURSELF
RUN OVER, CHRIS?
OH, I WAS THINKING
OF SOMETHING ELSE.
RECKON WE'RE ALL DOING A LOT
OF THINKING THESE DAYS.
LEASTWAYS THIS YEAR,
YOU'VE GOT A CROP TO HARVEST.
MORE THAN I CAN SAY.
MINE'S FLOODED OUT - 600 ACRES.
YOU'RE NOT
THE ONLY ONE, MAC.
NO ONE SEEMS TO KNOW
WHERE IT WILL ALL END.
SOMETHING'S GOT TO BE
DONE MIGHTY SOON, CHRIS.
GIDDAP.
NOW, WATCH.
IF YOU OPEN THE VALVES TOO FAST,
YOU'LL WRECK THE PIPE.
FASCINATING!
WHAT?!
I SAID IT'S FASCINATING!
I CAN'T HEAR YOU!
I DON'T BLAME YOU!
HEY! EASE UP
ON THAT PRESSURE A LITTLE!
WHAT IS IT, LANCE?
I'VE FORGOTTEN NOW.
HOW CAN ANYONE THINK
WITH THE ROAR OF THOSE CANNONS
SPLITTING
THEIR EARDRUMS?
ANYWAY, IT'S ACTION.
WELL, IF YOU FEEL SO STRONGLY
ABOUT IT,
WHY DON'T YOU DO
SOMETHING?
I AM GONNA DO SOMETHING.
I'M ON MY WAY NOW.
WHERE?
TO SAN FRANCISCO.
SAN FRANCISCO?
YES, I WANT TO GET AWAY
FROM HERE.
I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF WHEAT.
YOUR FATHER KNOW
YOU'RE GOING?
NO. HE WOULDN'T STAKE ME.
SO I'M GOING ON MY OWN.
BUT JUST WAIT
TILL I LAND THERE.
YEAH. BE SURE YOU LAND
ON BOTH FEET.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA
DO WHEN YOU GET THERE?
I DON'T KNOW YET.
UNCLE RALPH WILL GIVE ME
ALL THE HELP I NEED.
UNLESS ONE OF THE YOUNG
LADIES TAKES YOU AT HAND FIRST.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT WOMEN.
SURE, YOU DO,
AND HORSES, TOO.
ELEPHANT.
THERE'S MY TRAIN.
I GOT TO HURRY.
GOODBYE, FELLA.
GOODBYE.
LOOK ME UP WHEN YOU GET IN TOWN,
WON'T YOU?
FIRST THING.
WHERE WILL I FIND YOU?
AT THE POODLE DOG BAR.
YOU KNOW,
ME AND JOHN L. SULLIVAN.
GOODBYE, FELLA!
GOODBYE! GOOD LUCK!
HURRY UP, JOSHUA!
WE GOT TO MAKE THAT TRAIN!
WAIT FOR ME, MR. LANCE.
STEP ON RATHER LIGHT
AND NIP MY HEAD OFF.
WHOA. WHOA.
WAIT FOR ME NOW.
WHOA.
COME ON!
COME ON, JOSHUA!
I'M COMING!
DOROTHY! GENE!
WELL, I-I SUPPOSE
I SHOULD BE GETTING ALONG.
I'D ASK YOU TO STAY
FOR DINNER,
BUT FATHER
SEEMS TO BE LATE.
OH, THANKS, BUT I -
RAMON?
RAMON, DIDN'T MY FATHER SAY
WHEN HE'D BE BACK?
NO, MISS SERENA.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
THEY'LL SAVE ME SOME DINNER
AT THE CAMP.
I'LL SEE YOU SOON.
I HOPE SO.
HERE HE COMES NOW.
DON'T GO.
FATHER, I WAS BEGINNING
TO WORRY ABOUT YOU.
SORRY, SERENA.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
GOOD EVENING,
MR. WHITNEY.
FATHER, WHAT'S HAPPENED?
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
I JUST LEFT JOHN MacKENZIE.
HIS WIFE AND CHILD
WERE KILLED.
MRS. MacKENZIE?
AND GENE?
WHERE? HOW?
THE GROUND WASHED
FROM UNDER THEIR HOUSE,
AND THE ROOF CAVED IN.
THEY BROUGHT THE BODIES
INTO TOWN.
WHERE'S LANCE?
FATHER, LANCE ISN'T HERE.
HE'S GONE.
GONE? WHERE?
TO SAN FRANCISCO.
DON'T WAIT DINNER FOR ME.
YOU TWO GO AHEAD.
AND SO I SUGGEST WE FOLLOW
THIS ORDERLY PROCEDURE.
TALK ALL THE LAW
YOU WANT TO, CHRIS.
BUT WHEN YOU SPEND
ALMOST A LIFETIME
OF CLEARING A HOMESTEAD
AND PUTTING IN A CROP
AND THE SLICKINGS SPREADS
DOWN OVER IT,
I TELL YOU, YOU FEEL
ALMOST LIKE KILLING SOMEONE.
LISTEN, MEN!
WE WAIT FOR THE COURTS,
AND WHAT'LL HAPPEN?
NOTHING!
NOTHING! NOTHING!
THEY GOT LAWYERS AND MONEY
BEHIND THEM.
THEY'LL KEEP PUTTING US OFF
TWO, THREE YEARS -
THEN WHERE ARE YOU?
JIM, IN THE LONG RUN -
THE DEVIL
WITH THE LONG RUN.
I'VE WORKED, SAVED,
PAID MY BILLS REGULAR,
AND I DON'T PROPOSE TO GIVE UP
20 YEARS OF HARD WORK
WITHOUT A FIGHT!
THIS IS A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH
TO YOU, TO ME,
TO ALL OF US!
I CAN'T STAND ANOTHER
HARVEST LIKE THIS LAST ONE,
AND I DON'T INTEND TO!
WAIT A MINUTE!
I'M A MASSACHUSETTS MAN,
AND I BELIEVE IN LAW AND ORDER.
BUT THE ONLY WAY
WE'LL GET LAW THIS TIME
IS THROUGH THE MUZZLE END
OF A RIFLE.
I SAY TAKE A GANG UP THERE
WITH GUNS AND CLEAR THEM OUT!
NOW, WAIT. LISTEN TO ME.
I WANT TO SEE THAT RIFFRAFF
DRIVEN OUT OF HERE
AS MUCH AS ANY MAN AMONG YOU.
BUT KILLING AND MOB RULE
NEVER GOT ANYBODY ANYTHING.
WHATEVER WE'VE LOST NOW
IS NOTHING TO WHAT WE'D LOSE
BY TAKING THE LAW
INTO OUR OWN HANDS.
THAT WOULD BE PLAIN SUICIDE.
WHAT -
WHAT'S THERE TO CHOOSE
BETWEEN SUICIDE
AND MURDER, CHRIS?
WHAT MORE CAN A MAN LOSE
THAN I HAVE?
I'VE SEEN MY WHEAT FLOATING
DOWN THE RIVER,
WATCHED MY CATTLE STARVING
TO DEATH IN A CLOVER PASTURE,
AND MY WELL CHOKED UP
WITH MUD.
SO HAVE I, MAC.
I KNOW THAT. WE ALL HAVE.
BUT HAVE YOU SEEN YOUR WIFE
AND BABY
KILLED IN FRONT
OF YOUR EYES?
HAVE YOU HEARD THEM
SCREAM FOR YOU
AND THEN WATCH THEM
BEING CRUSHED TO DEATH
UNDER YOUR OWN ROOF
BEFORE YOU COULD GET TO THEM?
HAVE YOU SEEN THAT?
WELL, I HAVE.
AND BEFORE GOD I TELL YOU
I'M GOING TO GET THE MURDERERS
WHO DID IT
IF I HAVE TO GO UP THERE ALONE!
WE'LL GO WITH YOU, MAC.
SILENCE! ALL OF YOU!
SIT DOWN A MINUTE!
IF YOU'RE SET TO DO IT THIS WAY,
GO AHEAD.
BUT BEFORE YOU RUSH UP THERE
AND COVER YOURSELVES
WITH BLOOD AND GLORY,
LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO LOSE.
NOW, YOU MAY KNOW ME,
EVERYONE OF YOU.
HAVE I EVER LIED TO YOU
OR ADVISED YOU WRONG?
NO. NO, YOU HAVEN'T.
MOST OF US CAME OUT HERE
TOGETHER IN '65.
WE FOUGHT AND WORKED TOGETHER
TO MAKE THIS VALLEY A HOME
FOR OURSELVES
AND OUR CHILDREN -
YEARS OF WORK.
EVERYTHING ON EARTH, WE OWNED.
AND NOW YOU WANT TO THROW IT
AWAY IN ONE HOTHEADED HOUR,
GET YOURSELF SHOT OR HANGED,
JUST AS THE LAW ITSELF
IS GETTING READY
TO DRIVE THE MINERS OUT.
IS THAT COMMON SENSE?
YOU MEN ASKED ME HERE
TO HELP YOU ORGANIZE.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL HELP.
I'LL WORK WITH YOU
ANY WAY YOU DECIDE.
BUT TRY IT MY WAY FIRST.
GIVE THE COURTS A CHANCE.
IF THEY TURN US DOWN...
I'LL FIGHT WITH YOU.
I'LL LEAD YOU UP THERE.
I PROMISE YOU THAT.
ALL RIGHT, CHRIS.
WE'LL WAIT.
IS THAT ALL RIGHT
WITH YOU, MEN?
I'M WITH YOU, CHRIS.
AND I HOPE WE'RE RIGHT.
BUT THERE'S A TIME ELEMENT
AGAINST US.
THESE MEN WON'T WAIT LONG.
GOOD NIGHT, CHRIS.
GOOD NIGHT, DOC.
DID YOU HEAR ANYTHING?
NO. WHAT'S THE MATTER?
ARE YOU NERVOUS?
NO.
TIRED?
NO, I'M NOT TIRED.
WELL, THERE'S SOMETHING
THE MATTER.
I'M WORRIED ABOUT FATHER.
HE SHOULD HAVE BEEN BACK
LONG AGO.
OH, PLEASE DON'T WORRY.
HE'LL BE BACK PRESENTLY.
YOU MUSTN'T UPSET
YOURSELF.
I CAN'T FORGET THE LOOK
ON THOSE MEN'S FACES
WHEN THEY CALLED
FOR HIM TONIGHT.
AH, YES. I REMEMBER.
I SAW SOME OF THEM
COMING OUT OF TOWN.
DID THEY SAY ANYTHING
TO YOU?
WELL, NO, NOT OUT LOUD.
JARED, THEY WERE TALKING
ABOUT THE MINE,
ABOUT GOING UP THERE AND -
AND CLEANING IT OUT.
WELL, IF THEY DO, THEY
BETTER COME UP THERE SHOOTING.
OH, SERENA.
WE'RE NOT ASKING FOR TROUBLE.
BUT WE'RE NOT RUNNING AWAY
FROM IT, EITHER.
OH, JARED,
EVERYTHING WAS SO RIGHT
THE OTHER DAY
IN THE ORCHARD -
WORKING TOGETHER AND HELPING
THE TREES TO GROW.
WHY CAN'T IT STAY
THAT WAY?
I'M AFRAID
THERE'S GOING TO BE TROUBLE.
OH, JARED.
POOR DARLING.
WHOSE HORSE IS THAT,
ENOCH?
IT BELONGS
TO MR. WHITNEY.
PROMISE YOU WON'T WORRY?
I PROMISE.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD EVENING, MR. FERRIS.
MR. WHITNEY,
I'LL HAVE TO ASK YOU
NOT TO COME HERE
TO BANNOCKBURN AGAIN.
WOULD YOU MIND EXPLAINING JUST WHY, SIR?
IF YOU INSIST.
I DON'T CARE FOR YOUR ABUSE
OF MY HOSPITALITY.
AND I DON'T CARE FOR THE USE
YOU'RE MAKING OF IT
TO FURTHER YOUR AIMS
WITH SERENA.
I HOPE MY MEANING IS PLAIN.
IT'S PLAIN ENOUGH,
BUT IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
I HAVE THE OPPOSITE
IMPRESSION.
FURTHERMORE, SINCE WE'RE
TALKING PLAIN, I'LL TELL YOU
THAT I'M NOT GOING TO HAVE
A FORTUNE-HUNTING MINER
HANGING AROUND
MY DAUGHTER.
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH OF YOUR KIND
TO LAST ME.
THERE'LL BE
NO FURTHER ASSOCIATION
BETWEEN YOURSELF
AND MEMBERS OF MY FAMILY.
MR. FERRIS, I DON'T LIKE
YOUR WORD "FORTUNE HUNTER."
I DIDN'T SAY
WHAT I MIGHT HAVE
BECAUSE I LIKE YOU
AND RESPECT YOU,
AND BECAUSE
YOU'RE SERENA'S FATHER.
BUT I WILL SAY THIS NOW -
I LOVE SERENA.
I LOVE HER, AND I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU THINK.
MR. WHITNEY, I'M GIVING YOU
WARNING TO KEEP AWAY FROM HERE
AND TO KEEP AWAY
FROM SERENA.
YOU CAN KEEP ME FROM SEEING
SERENA - FOR A WHILE.
BUT SHE'LL BE OF AGE
BEFORE LONG,
AND THEN YOU AND THIS WHOLE
VALLEY CAN'T KEEP US APART.
GOOD NIGHT, SIR.
71,000.
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH, WHITNEY.
I KNOW
IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
AND I'VE BEEN YELLING ABOUT IT
FOR MONTHS.
DON'T ANY OF THAT BUNCH
IN SAN FRANCISCO
EVER READ MY REPORTS?
I DON'T KNOW. THEY DON'T
READ MINE HALF THE TIME.
IT SEEMS ALL
THEY WANT TO KNOW IS,
WHY AREN'T YOU
SHIPPING OUT MORE?
SURE, I'LL SHIP THEM MORE.
JUST GIVE ME A DECENT
WATER PRESSURE UP HERE,
AND I'LL SEND THEM ENOUGH
TO PUT IN THEIR EARS.
I'M NOT BLAMING YOU. I'M JUST
TELLING YOU WHAT THEY SAY.
THE WATER'S HERE
IF THEY'D ONLY LISTEN.
I DRAW OUT A DETAILED PLAN
FOR A NEW DAM
IN EVERY REPORT
I SENT UP THERE.
WELL, I'LL REMIND THEM,
IF YOU WANT.
NO, YOU WON'T.
I'LL TELL THEM MYSELF.
GOING TO TO SAN FRANCISCO
IN THE MORNING.
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S THE PUNCH.
POSITIVE.
NO GREATER MARE IN THE COUNTRY
CAN BEAT HER AT SIX FURLONGS.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH
THE STANFORD MARE WALKAWAY?
HASN'T GOT A CHANCE.
I'M GETTING 3 TO 1
ON BALDWIN'S BAY GELDING.
BEST TOUR THAT EVER COME
TO OAKLAND - BAR NONE.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
DOWN IN PANAMA THEY'RE THINKING
OF BUILDING A CANAL
FROM THE ATLANTIC
TO THE PACIFIC OCEAN?
TIMES ARE CHANGING.
JARED.
LANCE!
I TOLD YOU YOU'D FIND ME
AT THE POODLE DOG BAR.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I REMEMBER.
BUT, UH,
WHERE'S JOHN L. SULLIVAN?
HE'S RIGHT OVER THERE
IN THE TOP HAT.
HERE, THIS CALLS
FOR A CELEBRATION.
SIT DOWN. FRANK?
YES, SIR.
WOULD YOU BRING
SOME MORE CHAMPAGNE?
OH, NOT THIS EARLY.
WHY NOT?
GO AHEAD, FRANK.
IN SAN FRANCISCO,
THEY DRINK IT FOR BREAKFAST.
HOW DO YOU LIKE SAN FRANCISCO?
I'VE NEVER HAD SUCH A TIME
IN MY LIFE, JARED.
WHY, PEOPLE ARE ROLLING
IN GOLD UP HERE.
IT GROWS ON TREES.
YEAH, I KNOW. I KNOW.
WE HAVE TO SHAKE THE TREES
FOR THEM.
BUT HOW ABOUT YOU?
ARE YOU UP ON BUSINESS?
YES, I CAME UP
TO SEE MY BOSS.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO LOCATE
HIM FOR THE LAST THREE DAYS.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
HARRISON McCOOEY.
EVER HEAR OF HIM?
HARRISON McCOOEY?
AND YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR HIM
FOR THREE DAYS?
OH, YOU KNOW HIM?
DO I KNOW HIM?
OH, HERE THEY COME NOW.
I THOUGHT YOU GIRLS
WOULD NEVER COME BACK.
LANA CRABTREE,
AND SHE'S EVEN MORE BEAUTIFUL
OFF THAN SHE IS -
OH.
ROSANNE, THIS IS JARED WHITNEY.
I JUST STUMBLED INTO HIM.
PLEASURE, MA'AM.
NOT THE JARED WHITNEY?
LANCE HAS SPOKEN OF YOU
SO OFTEN.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE SORT OF
A HERO TO HIM.
OH, WELL.
WE'RE OLD FRIENDS.
OH MOLLY, DARLING,
I'M SO SORRY.
MR. WHITNEY, MAY I PRESENT
MISS MOLLY FEATHERSTONE?
DELIGHTED.
HOW DO YOU DO?
COME ON, GIRLS.
LET'S SIT DOWN.
JARED'S BEEN IN TOWN THREE DAYS
LOOKING FOR HIS BOSS.
HE'S BEEN SITTING IN HIS OFFICE
FROM MORNING TILL NIGHT,
WAITING FOR HIM
TO COME IN.
WHY, WHO DO YOU THINK
HIS BOSS IS?
I GIVE UP.
WHO?
THE HONORABLE
HARRISON McCOOEY.
YES, HE'S MY BOSS,
ALL RIGHT.
I USED TO THINK
HE WAS MINE, TOO.
WHAT? HE'S AUNT ROSANNE'S FATHER.
OH, NOW, I -
BUT YOU'VE COME
TO THE RIGHT PLACE
TO FIND HIM, MR. WHITNEY.
HARRY'S ONE OF THE ORIGINAL
FIXTURES AT THIS BAR.
ISN'T HE, DARLING?
YES.
FATHER'S ON HIS WAY
HERE NOW.
WE'RE ALL DRIVING
TO THE RACES.
WHY DON'T YOU COME ALONG
WITH US?
OH, THANKS VERY MUCH,
BUT -
OH, SURE YOU CAN,
JARED.
THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM
FOR US ALL.
WELL, PERHAPS MR. McCOOEY
WOULDN'T LIKE TO MIX
BUSINESS WITH PLEASURE.
THAT'S THE WAY EVERYTHING'S DONE
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WHOA.
EXACTLY 7 MINUTES FROM THE TOP
OF NOB HILL.
SOME FOOL LUCK
WE GOT HERE AT ALL.
I THINK THAT DESERVES
A DRINK, EH?
DON'T YOU THINK ONE IS ENOUGH
AFTER THAT WILD RIDE?
THREE OF MY SPECIAL.
ALL RIGHT, MR. McCOOEY.
OH, HERE'S FATHER NOW.
HI, BOYS.
BETTING ON YOUR HORSE TODAY,
HARRISON.
YOU CAN'T LOSE.
HELLO, GIRLS.
YOU ALL READY?
HELLO, MOLLY.
YOU LOOK LOVELY.
FATHER,
THIS IS JARED WHITNEY.
HE'S AN OLD FRIEND
OF LANCE'S.
HOW DO YOU DO, SIR? HOW
ARE YOU, MR. McCOOEY?
MR. WHITNEY'S BEEN LOOKING
FOR YOU FOR DAYS, FATHER.
NOT LOOKING FOR A JOB,
ARE YOU?
HE'S ALREADY
WORKING FOR YOU.
WORKING FOR ME?
WHERE?
GOLDEN MOON MINE, SIR.
I'M IN CHARGE THERE.
WHITNEY?
OH, OF COURSE. TO BE SURE.
ANYTHING WRONG
AT THE MINE?
SOMEBODY DOWN HERE
SEEMS TO THINK SO.
I CAN GUESS WHO IT IS.
COME ALONG, DARLING.
WE DON'T WANT TO BE LATE.
MR. CROCKER GAVE ME A TIP
FOR THE FIRST RACE.
MR. WHITNEY, I WANT YOU
TO MEET MY PARTNERS -
FRANK CROUCH, MAJOR WALSH.
HOW DO YOU DO, SIR?
MR. WHITNEY IS SUPERINTENDENT
OF OUR GOLDEN MOON MINE.
OH, IS THAT SO?
AH, THE LIFESAVER.
WHITNEY, YOU'LL HAVE TO GRIND
YOUR AX WITH CROUCH HERE.
HE'S THE ATTORNEY
FOR THE FIRM.
BEST LAWYER WEST
OF THE ROCKIES.
HADN'T WE BETTER
GET STARTED, FATHER?
THE RACES BEGIN SOON.
DRIVE YOU THERE
IN A HALF AN HOUR.
I GUARANTEE IT.
YOU KEEP YOUR EYE
OFF HIM, MOLLY.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA
BE SELFISH ABOUT IT?
COME ON.
I'LL PROVE IT.
MR. McCOOEY, REALLY, I HAVE
A LOT TO DO THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU'RE GOING WITH US.
OH, NO, THANK YOU.
OH, SURE YOU ARE.
WE SETTLED THAT.
WHY, OF COURSE
YOU'RE COMING.
BUT, MR. McCOOEY, I CAME HERE
TO TALK BUSINESS WITH YOU.
OH, LET BUSINESS WAIT
FOR THE OFFICE TOMORROW.
COME ON, BOYS,
I GOT THE GREATEST HUNCH
ON THE THIRD RACE
YOU EVER SAW.
MRS. FERRIS, I'VE WORKED
FOR YOUR FATHER FOR A YEAR,
BUT NEVER HAD THE OPPORTUNITY
OF MEETING HIM.
THEY SAID HE WAS HARD
TO REACH.
OH, WELL, THAT'S ABSURD.
WE'RE THE FRIENDLIEST FAMILY
IN THE WORLD.
OUR WATER SUPPLY
COMES FROM THE MOUNTAINS,
DOWN THESE RAVINES,
THROUGH THIS NATURAL BASIN,
ALONG ABOUT 3,000 FEET
TO OUR DAM.
HERE AT THE NECK OF THE BASIN,
THE OPENING IS 360 FEET.
NOW, IF YOU THROW A DAM
ACROSS HERE,
YOU'LL HAVE A RESERVOIR
CAPABLE OF HOLDING
3 OR 4 MILLION GALLONS.
SOUNDS ALL RIGHT
THE WAY YOU TELL IT,
BUT HOW MUCH WOULD A DAM
LIKE THAT COST?
ROUGHLY A QUARTER
MILLION DOLLARS.
IT'S OUT OF THE QUESTION.
THE GOLDEN MOON WOULD NEVER
BE ABLE TO WORK IT OFF.
WHY NOT, MR. FERRIS?
THE INSPIRATION AND SUNSET
GET THEIR WATER
FROM THE SAME SOURCE.
AND IF YOU CONSOLIDATE
THE THREE MINES,
YOU BUILD YOUR DAM,
YOU CAN OPERATE WINTER
AND SUMMER, 24 HOURS A DAY.
YOU SAY THE INSPIRATION
AND THE SUNSET BOTH USE WATER
FROM THE SAME SOURCE
WE DO?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHERE'S OUR PRESENT RESERVOIR? HERE.
I THINK THE IDEA'S
MIGHTY SMART.
SOUNDS GOOD TO ME
IF WE CAN CONSOLIDATE.
IF IT'S GOOD,
WE CAN WORK IT OUT.
WHITNEY, I'M THINKING
YOU'VE BEEN WASTED
OUT THERE IN THE FIELD.
YOU BELONG RIGHT HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WE'LL FURNISH YOU
WITH AN OFFICE
AND A REASONABLE
EXPENSE ACCOUNT.
WE NEED BRIGHT FELLOWS
WITH GOOD IDEAS.
GENTLEMEN,
THE MEETING'S ADJOURNED.
LET'S ALL GO DOWN
TO THE EXCHANGE
AND HAVE A DRINK ON IT.
THE PLAN TO CONSOLIDATE'S
THE BEST THING I'VE HEARD.
THAT'S A GREAT
SUGGESTION.
SURE, WE BUILD A DAM
AND SHUT THOSE OTHER TWO MINES
OFF FROM THE WATER.
THEN THEY'LL HAVE TO SELL.
WHY DIDN'T WE THINK
OF THAT OURSELVES?
WE'RE NOT ENGINEERS.
OH, DON'T MENTION
THIS SQUEEZE-OUT TO WHITNEY.
HE MIGHTN'T UNDERSTAND
MODERN BUSINESS METHODS
ON THE STOCK EXCHANGE.
WILL YOU GET THIS OFF
ON THE NIGHT TRAIN IF POSSIBLE?
YES, SIR.
I'LL TAKE IT DOWN MYSELF.
THANK YOU.
I WISH I COULD HELP YOU, MA'AM,
BUT MR. WHITNEY'S GONE.
HE'S GONE?
LEFT - QUICKER THAN THAT.
SAN FRANCISCO, I THINK.
ALTHOUGH HE DIDN'T
TELL ME.
YOU KNOW, HE ALWAYS
WAS KIND OF CLOSEMOUTHED.
I NEVER DID HAVE MUCH LUCK
GETTING HIM TO TALK.
WELL, UH, HOW LONG AGO
DID HE LEAVE?
OH, TWO OR THREE WEEKS AGO,
MAYBE MORE, MAYBE LESS.
YOU KNOW, THE DAYS, THEY START
TO ROLL INTO ONE ANOTHER,
AND THEY - THEY GET ME
ALL MIXED UP.
WELL, UH, THANK YOU.
OH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
NOT AT ALL.
HELLO, SERENA.
OH, FATHER.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU WERE HERE.
WELL, I WAS JUST CLEARING UP
A LITTLE BUSINESS.
IT'S NEARLY DINNERTIME.
I'D ALMOST FORGOTTEN.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE, HONEY?
OH, NOTHING, FATHER.
NOTHING AT ALL.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL ME.
I KNOW.
IT'S THIS WHITNEY FELLOW,
ISN'T IT?
YOU PROBABLY FOUND OUT
HE'S GONE AWAY.
DIDN'T YOU?
YES.
HE MIGHT AT LEAST
HAVE SAID GOODBYE.
OH, WELL,
YOU KNOW THESE MINING MEN -
HERE TODAY
AND GONE TOMORROW.
YOU CAN'T DEPEND MUCH
ON ANY ONE OF THEM.
SIT DOWN, SERENA.
NOW, MY DEAR, I KNOW HOW
EMBARRASSING IT IS FOR YOU
TO DISCUSS THIS MATTER.
WELL, IT'S EQUALLY AWKWARD
FOR ME.
I'D FAR SOONER HAVE YOU TALK
ABOUT THIS IDEA OF YOURS
OF GROWING FRUIT IN CALIFORNIA.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU CARED SO MUCH
FOR THE FELLOW.
SERENA, YOU CAN'T BE IN LOVE
WITH A YANKEE MINE-MUCKER.
I AM.
BUT IT'S RIDICULOUS!
WELL, IN THE FIRST PLACE,
YOU'RE NOTHING
BUT A LITTLE GIRL.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT
BEING IN LOVE ANYWAY?
LISTEN, HONEY.
I KNOW WHAT'S BEST FOR YOU.
I COULDN'T HAVE A MINING MAN
IN THE -
YOU SENT HIM AWAY.
HOW COULD I HAVE SENT HIM AWAY?
THE MAN'S A FREE AGENT,
ISN'T HE?
WELL, THEN,
WHAT DID YOU MEAN?
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN AS MUCH OF LIFE
AS I HAVE, MY DEAR,
OR OF MEN LIKE WHITNEY.
YOU'LL GET OVER THIS.
FATHER, I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED,
WHAT MADE HIM GO
LIKE THAT!
WELL, I SORT OF
TRADED WITH HIM.
TRADED?
FOR HIM TO GET OUT
AND TO STAY OUT.
HE WOULDN'T DO A THING
LIKE THAT.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
SERENA, I WANT YOU
TO UNDERSTAND -
DINNER, SIR.
MR. FERRIS.
YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, FATHER.
SELL 700 SUNSET.
YES, SIR.
BUY THE SHARE OF GOLDEN MOON
THAT'S OFFERED. ALL RIGHT.
WANT TO PICK UP 600
GOLDEN MOON AT 260?
TAKE IT.
SELL 500 INSPIRATION.
INSPIRATION FELL
18 POINTS ALREADY.
SELL INSPIRATION.
KEEP ON SELLING IT AS LONG
AS YOU CAN FIND A BUYER.
500!
598!
398!
PUT AT LEAST THAT ON SUNSET.
5,000- GOLDEN MOON!
IT'S UP 260.
I'LL PAY 500!
500!
I'LL PAY 800!
1,000.
DARLING, IT'S THE TINIEST
LITTLE ROOM.
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
WE WEREN'T EXPECTING YOU, AND
WE'RE REALLY QUITE CROWDED -
WHAT? - WITH LANCE AND -
MOY, YOU MAY GO.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF MISS
SERENA. YES, MA'AM.
OH, AND BRING HER
A COOL DRINK.
SHE MUST BE VERY FATIGUED
AFTER HER LONG JOURNEY.
YES, MA'AM.
MY DEAR, WHEREVER DID
YOU GET ALL THESE DRESSES?
OH, I HAD THEM MADE
IN TENSPOT. WHY?
WELL, THEY'RE RATHER PRETTY
FOR THE COUNTRY,
BUT THEY'RE NOT QUITE WHAT
WE'RE WEARING IN TOWN THIS YEAR.
OH.
YES. YES,
THAT'S RATHER PRETTY.
BUT, UH, I THINK
WE CAN IMPROVE IT.
OH, AUNT ROSANNE, I HOPE
I'M NOT INCONVENIENCING YOU.
I SHOULD HAVE LET YOU KNOW
I WAS COMING OF COURSE,
BUT I-I DIDN'T DECIDE
TILL THE LAST MINUTE.
MY DEAR,
WE LOVE HAVING YOU.
OH, THANK YOU,
AUNT ROSANNE.
I REALLY CAME BECAUSE -
WELL, FOR ONE THING,
I WANTED TO TALK
TO UNCLE RALPH ABOUT FATHER.
YOU'LL PROBABLY SEE HIM
ON THURSDAY NIGHT.
WE'RE ENTERTAINING IN HONOR
OF GENERAL GRANT.
OH, THAT REMINDS ME.
WE MUST DO SOMETHING
ABOUT FINDING AN ESCORT FOR YOU.
LET ME SEE -
THERE'S THE POPE BOY -
PLEASE DON'T BOTHER,
AUNT ROSANNE.
I DON'T NEED ANYBODY,
REALLY.
MY DEAR, YOU CAN'T GO RUNNING
AROUND TOWN ALONE.
THIS ISN'T TENSPOT,
YOU KNOW.
AND, SERENA, DEAR,
YOU'RE NOT A CHILD ANY LONGER.
FORGIVE ME.
MORNING, WONG.
GOOD MORNING,
MR. WHITNEY.
HELLO, JARED.
HELLO, THERE.
FLOWERS AGAIN.
JARED, DIDN'T I TELL YOU
YOU WEREN'T TO DO THIS ANYMORE?
OH, THEY'RE LOVELY.
HOW SWEET OF YOU.
OH!
OH, I'M SO SORRY.
SERENA, COME DOWN,
DARLING.
YOU KNOW JARED WHITNEY,
DON'T YOU?
OF COURSE YOU DO.
LANCE TOLD ME HOW YOU TEASED HER
ABOUT THE APPLES.
THEY WERE APPLES, WEREN'T THEY,
DARLING? I CAN NEVER REMEMBER.
SERENA, I HAD NO IDEA.
WHEN DID YOU GET HERE?
JUST AN HOUR AGO.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
SHE WAS HERE?
I- I DIDN'T REMEMBER
THAT YOU KNEW EACH OTHER.
OH, AREN'T THEY RAVISHING?
HE JUST SPOILS ME TO DEATH.
DARLING, TELL HIM HOW NICE HE IS
WHILE I PUT THEM IN WATER.
SERENA, WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
YOU WERE COMING?
I WOULD HAVE MET YOU
AT THE TRAIN.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
WELL, I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW HAPPY
I AM THAT YOU'RE HERE.
THERE'S SO MUCH TO ASK YOU
AND TO TELL YOU AND -
WELL, IT'S -
IT'S BEEN SO LONG.
JARED?
HAVE WONG OPEN A BOTTLE
OF CHAMPAGNE, WILL YOU?
Listen, Serena, I've simply
got to see you alone.
But Aunt Rosanne.
Never mind Aunt Rosanne.
Let's get out of here.
JARED?
Hurry up! Quick!
IT'S A DIFFERENT LIFE,
SERENA,
BUT IT'S FUN AND CRAMMED
FULL OF EXCITEMENT.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
I SOMETIMES MISS THE MINE
AND THE REAL WORK
OF GETTING THE GOLD OUT.
I'VE MISSED YOU,
TOO, SERENA.
HAVE YOU, JARED?
ARE YOU SURE?
WHY DO YOU ASK THAT?
BECAUSE I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED,
WHY YOU LEFT
WITHOUT A WORD.
I WANTED TO SEE YOU.
I TRIED, BUT I COULDN'T.
IT WASN'T ALLOWED.
YOU SEE,
IT'S HARD TO SAY. I -
I UNDERSTAND.
BUT YOU MIGHT HAVE EXPLAINED.
YOU COULD HAVE WRITTEN.
BUT I DID.
DIDN'T YOU GET MY LETTERS?
NO.
OH.
WELL,
IT DOESN'T MATTER NOW.
SERENA, EVER SINCE OUR LAST
NIGHT AT BANNOCKBURN,
I FOUND OUT SOMETHING I
SHOULD HAVE KNOWN LONG BEFORE.
I LOVE YOU.
I'VE KNOWN IT
FOR A LONG TIME.
THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS,
ISN'T IT?
MR. AND MRS. PAUL.
MR. AND MRS. HUNTINGTON.
MR. AND MRS DRUCKER.
THESE WOMEN
OF THE BLACK TROUPE COMPANY
ARE UTTERLY SHAMELESS.
THEY ACTUALLY WEAR TIGHTS -
THEY'RE SO REVEALING.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
THESE NEW INVENTIONS.
A FELLOW BY THE NAME OF BELL
CALLS THE THING A TELEPHONE.
THE HONORABLE
GEORGE HEARST.
SENATOR HEARST,
WE'RE DELIGHTED.
MRS. FERRIS, YOU'RE JUST
AS CHARMING TONIGHT AS EVER.
YOU'RE SUCH A FLATTERER,
SENATOR.
GEORGE,
GLAD YOU'RE BACK.
JARED?
JARED, I'VE BEEN SEARCHING
EVERYWHERE FOR YOU.
COME ALONG. I HAVE SOME
IMPORTANT PEOPLE YOU SHOULD MEET.
SENATOR HEARST,
MAY I PRESENT MR. WHITNEY?
HOW DO YOU DO?
SENATOR.
MR. WHITNEY'S IN CHARGE
OF OUR NEW MINE AT TENSPOT.
OH, REALLY? I HEAR YOU'VE HIT
A RICH FIELD UP THERE.
WE THINK SO, SIR.
WELL, WHEN YOU FIND ANYTHING YOU
THINK'S GOLD, THROW IT AWAY.
WHEN YOU FIND GOLD,
YOU'LL KNOW IT.
EXCUSE US.
CERTAINLY.
HOW'S ALL THE FAMILY,
GEORGE?
OH, FINE, FINE.
ONLY I'M A LITTLE WORRIED
ABOUT THAT BOY OF MINE -
WILLIE.
HE'S GOT AN IDEA
THAT HE WANTS TO GO
INTO THE NEWSPAPER
BUSINESS.
HE WANTS US TO BUY
THE EXAMINER.
YOU FIGURE HE CAN
MAKE ANY MONEY OUT OF IT?
I DOUBT IT. THERE'S NO
REAL MONEY IN NEWSPAPERS.
I'M INCLINED TO AGREE
WITH YOU.
OH, AUNT ROSANNE.
I CAN'T THANK YOU ENOUGH
FOR THIS LOVELY DRESS.
DO I LOOK ALL RIGHT?
DARLING, YOU'RE LOVELY,
OF COURSE,
BUT YOUR HAIR, IT'S RATHER
PROVINCIAL, DON'T YOU THINK?
SHALL I GO BACK AND CHANGE IT?
OH, NO, YOU HAVEN'T TIME.
YOU'VE BEEN FUSSING FOR HOURS.
AND, SERENA,
PLEASE DON'T CALL ME "AUNT."
CALL ME ROSANNE,
THE WAY LANCE DOES.
ANOTHER THING, SERENA -
STOP THROWING YOURSELF AT JARED.
HE'S IN LOVE WITH ANOTHER WOMAN,
ONE OF MY CLOSEST FRIENDS.
ROSANNE, GENERAL GRANT.
GENERAL ULYSSES S. GRANT.
MRS. FERRIS.
MR. FERRIS.
GENERAL,
IT'S A GREAT HONOR.
DELIGHTED TO BE HERE,
I'M SURE.
GENERAL,
THIS IS INDEED A PLEASURE.
THANK YOU, MRS. FERRIS.
MAY WE PRESENT YOU TO SOME
OF OUR FRIENDS, GENERAL?
I'D BE GLAD TO MEET THEM.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
GOOD EVENING.
I MUST SEE MR. FERRIS.
YES, JUST A MOMENT, SIR.
HELLO, MR. CROUCH.
HELLO, LANCE.
WHERE'S YOUR UNCLE?
I'VE GOT TO SEE HIM.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
WELL, COME WITH ME.
I'LL TAKE YOU TO HIM.
RALPH?
YES?
AH, CROUCH, GLAD YOU COULD COME.
HAVE A DRINK.
LATER.
SOMETHING WRONG?
YEAH.
WHAT IS IT?
LOOK AT THIS.
"GOLDEN MOON CASE MOVED UP
FOR IMMEDIATE HEARING
IN FEDERAL COURT."
OH, THAT'S BAD.
LANCE?
YES.
YOU JOIN US THERE, TOO.
I'LL NEED YOU.
AND THE BANKERS BACK EAST
WERE TELLING ME
ABOUT A YOUNG FELLOW
NAMED EDISON
WHO WAS TRYING TO INTEREST THEM
IN A NEW LIGHT
THAT LOOKED LIKE A RED-HOT
HAIRPIN IN A BOTTLE.
HARRY,
MEET ME IN THE LIBRARY.
UNCLE RALPH.
I- I DON'T MEAN TO DISTURB YOU,
UNCLE RALPH,
BUT YOU'RE SO BUSY I NEVER GET
A CHANCE TO SEE YOU.
WELL, WHAT IS IT, SERENA?
WHAT'S SO URGENT?
IT'S ABOUT FATHER.
HE'S ALMOST DESPERATE.
UNLESS YOU HELP HIM,
UNCLE RALPH,
WE'LL LOSE BANNOCKBURN.
LISTEN, CHILD,
THE LOSS OF BANNOCKBURN
IS ONLY A DROP
IN THE BUCKET
COMPARED TO THE MILLIONS
WE STAND TO LOSE
IF THAT BULLHEADED FATHER
OF YOURS HAS HIS WAY.
FINE TIME TO ASK MY HELP.
FATHER DIDN'T KNOW MY REASON
FOR COMING HERE.
WELL,
RALPH, WHAT IS IT?
SORRY, DARLING.
I CAN'T DISCUSS IT NOW.
ALL RIGHT, GENTLEMEN.
IN MY STUDY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
NOTHING.
HOW ABOUT A DANCE,
SPRAT?
SIT DOWN, GENTLEMEN.
WELL,
WHAT'S THE COMMOTION?
SOMEONE IN SACRAMENTO
SLIPPED UP ON US. WHAT?
THE FEDERAL COURT'S
GOING TO HEAR
THE RANCHERS' CASE
ON THE 2nd.
THAT'S WEDNESDAY.
EXACTLY.
YOU HAVE FOUR DAYS.
HOW DID THEY GET AWAY
WITH A THING LIKE THAT?
THAT CROWD AT BANNOCKBURN
MUST BE DESPERATE.
THEY'LL TAKE ANY CHANCE.
WHAT WILL THAT MEAN
TO THE MARKET?
IT'LL BE OFF FOR A
WHILE, BUT IT CAN'T LAST.
YOU BETTER SCUTTLE UP
TO SACRAMENTO
THE FIRST THING
IN THE MORNING, CROUCH.
I CAN START TONIGHT.
WELL, THAT'S BETTER.
YOU GO WITH HIM, WHITNEY.
HE'LL NEED YOUR HELP
IN PREPARING OUR CASE.
WELL, GO AHEAD.
GET STARTED.
THERE'S A TRAIN AT 11:40.
IF YOU HURRY,
YOU CAN CATCH IT.
THAT'S GOOD.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE'LL SEND UP ORDERS
TO BARRICADE THE MINE
AGAINST ANY HOT-HEADED FOOLS
THAT MIGHT TRY
TO JUMP THE GUN ON US.
WE'LL OBLIGE THOSE RANCHERS
COURT OR NO COURT.
NOW, LISTEN.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT WE'LL DO.
PARDON ME, LANCE.
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO SERENA.
DO YOU MIND?
I DON'T MIND.
AND I'M SURE SHE DOESN'T.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
I WANT TO SAY GOODBYE TO
YOU QUICKLY. YOU'RE LEAVING?
WELL, JUST FOR A FEW DAYS.
I'VE GOT TO GO TO SACRAMENTO.
JARED, IS THERE
GOING TO BE TROUBLE?
TROUBLE?
WHY SHOULD THERE BE TROUBLE?
PLEASE TELL ME THE TRUTH.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, WE'VE GOT A BUSINESS,
AND WE NEED TO PROTECT IT.
OH, AND THIS IS WHAT YOU MEANT
AT BANNOCKBURN
WHEN YOU SAID IF THEY COME UP,
THEY BETTER COME SHOOTING?
OH, IT WOULDN'T GO AS FAR
AS THAT.
PLEASE BELIEVE ME.
I KNOW THESE MEN.
JARED, I'VE TRIED TO SEE IT
YOUR WAY.
I WANTED TO.
BUT I CAN'T.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT MY FATHER
AND ALL THE PEOPLE I'VE KNOWN
SINCE I WAS A CHILD ARE WRONG.
THEY'RE HONEST,
HARDWORKING PEOPLE,
AND ALL THEY WANT
IS THEIR LAND.
WHAT DO THESE MEN WANT?
MONEY AND MORE MONEY.
AND THEY DON'T CARE
HOW THEY GET IT.
THEY'RE WRONG, JARED.
AND IF YOU STAY WITH THEM,
YOU'LL BE WRONG, TOO.
OH, DARLING. YOU'RE TAKING
THIS THING MUCH TOO SERIOUSLY.
NO, I'M NOT.
I CAME UP FROM THE VALLEY
JUST A FEW DAYS AGO,
AND I KNOW
HOW THOSE MEN FEEL.
IF YOU PUSH THEM TOO FAR,
THEY'LL FIGHT,
AND THERE'LL
BE MEN KILLED.
AND YOU'LL HAVE THAT
ON YOUR CONSCIENCE
ALL THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE.
NO, DARLING,
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THERE ISN'T GOING TO BE
ANY KILLING.
IF YOU GO ON
WITH THOSE MEN, JARED,
THERE'LL NEVER
BE ANY HAPPINESS FOR US.
CAN'T I MAKE YOU UNDERSTAND
THAT IT'S MY RESPONSIBILITY?
MY JOB?
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
WE'VE GOT TO HURRY, WHITNEY.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M SORRY, DARLING.
WE JUST GOT TIME
TO MAKE IT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT IS IT, SPRAT?
I'M GOING BACK HOME,
LANCE.
I CAN'T STAY HERE ANY LONGER.
I JUST CAN'T.
SURE, IF YOU WANT TO.
I'M SICK OF THIS PLACE
AND THESE PEOPLE.
THEY'RE NOT REAL, LANCE.
THEY'RE NOT OUR KIND.
DID SOMEBODY HURT YOU,
HONEY?
WELL, THEN,
WHAT IS THE TROUBLE?
I'M GOING BACK TO FATHER
BECAUSE HE NEEDS ME.
UNCLE RALPH AND JARED AND ALL
THE OTHERS ARE FIGHTING HIM.
YOU SEE, LANCE, YOU AND I
HAVE ALWAYS QUARRELED
WITH FATHER BECAUSE -
BECAUSE HE DIDN'T SEE THINGS
THE WAY WE DID.
BUT HE'S STANDING UP
FOR SOMETHING
THAT HE KNOWS IS RIGHT,
AND IT'S NOT IN OUR BLOOD
TO LET HIM FIGHT IT OUT ALONE.
I'M GOING BACK TO HIM.
THERE'S A TRAIN
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
I'LL GET A CARRIAGE -
NEVER MIND.
I CAN MAKE IT MYSELF.
DIDN'T YOU ALWAYS SAY
WE FERRISES STAND TOGETHER?
LANCE.
AND I GUESS
WE STILL DO, SPRAT.
THIS HEARING WILL DECIDE
A GREAT ISSUE.
PROCEED.
YOUR HONOR,
I'D LIKE FOR MR. FERRIS
TO CLOSE OUR CASE
IN THIS HEARING,
SPEAKING HIS MIND
FOR US ALL.
JUDGE CLAYBURN, WHAT ELSE
CAN YOU NEED TO KNOW?
YOU'VE HEARD BOTH SIDES.
TO THEM, THIS INJUNCTION
WE'RE ASKING FOR
IS ONLY A MATTER OF DIVIDENDS,
A LITTLE GOLD, MORE OR LESS.
BUT TO US RANCHERS,
IT MEANS LIFE OR DEATH.
OUR LAND IS ALL WE'VE GOT.
WE BOUGHT IT TO MAKE HOMES
FOR OURSELVES AND OUR CHILDREN.
BETWEEN US,
WE'VE CLEARED 100,000 ACRES
THAT ONCE WAS WASTELAND,
SCRUB, AND DESERT.
ON IT, WE RAISED WHEAT -
10 MILLION BUSHELS A YEAR,
AND IT GOES OUT
TO FEED THE WORLD,
EVEN TO FRANCE AND ENGLAND.
EACH YEAR, A MILLION MEN,
WOMEN, AND CHILDREN
DEPEND ON US
FOR THEIR DAILY BREAD.
WE HAVE ONLY ONE QUESTION
TO ASK -
DOES THE LAW OF THIS COUNTRY
GIVE ONE MAN THE RIGHT
TO RUIN ANOTHER MAN'S LAND,
TO STAND ON A MOUNTAIN
AND THROW MUD IN HIS FACE?
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT THE MINERS
ARE DOING TO US,
AND THAT'S WHY
WE'VE COME TO YOU,
BECAUSE WE TRUST IN THE LAW,
AND WE TRUST A COURT
ACTING UNDER IT
AS WE TRUST IN GOD HIMSELF.
YOUR HONOR, I'M GLAD
WE FINALLY FOUND SOMEBODY
WHO COULD ADD UP THE COMPLAINTS
OF THESE GENTLEMEN,
SOMEONE WHO COULD
SPEAK HIS MIND FOR ALL OF THEM.
NOW WE KNOW
WHERE WE STAND.
NOW MAYBE WE CAN GET DOWN
TO CASES.
MR. FERRIS, YOU SAY THAT YOU
AND YOUR MEN BOUGHT THIS LAND.
YES, SIR. WE DID.
YOU PAID THE SPANIARDS $8
AN ACRE FOR IT, DIDN'T YOU?
BUT, YOUR HONOR,
THIS MORNING IN COURT,
HE PLACES A VALUE OF $800 AN ACRE ON IT.
NOW, THAT'S QUITE A NEAT
LITTLE PROFIT, DON'T YOU THINK?
WHEAT ALONE'S WORTH THAT.
OH, YES. WHEAT.
OF COURSE.
I FORGET YOU FEED A MILLION
PEOPLE IN FRANCE AND ENGLAND.
BUT OUR GOLD FEEDS 10 MILLION
TO YOUR ONE,
AND THEY ARE
10 MILLION AMERICANS.
NOW, YOU FARMERS HAVE BEEN
STUCK UP THERE
IN YOUR HILLS SINCE 1867.
YOU DON'T KNOW
AND YOU DON'T CARE
WHAT'S HAPPENING TO THE REST
OF THIS COUNTRY.
GREAT CITIES LIKE CHICAGO
AND NEW YORK,
RAILROADS LIKE THE CENTRAL
PACIFIC, SHIPS, MACHINERY -
ALL OF IT BUILT WITH GOLD.
BUT WHAT DO YOU CARE
ABOUT PROGRESS?
YOU'VE GOT A PIECE OF LAND.
AND GOLD - MONEY - THE VERY
LIFEBLOOD OF THIS COUNTRY -
THAT MUST WAIT,
BECAUSE THERE'S BEEN
A LITTLE DAMAGE DONE
TO A FEW BUSHELS OF WHEAT.
MR. FERRIS, YOU SAY
THAT YOU AND YOUR MEN
HAVE RECLAIMED 100,000 ACRES
OF WASTELAND,
BUT I SAY TO YOU
GOLD HAS RECLAIMED A NATION,
KEPT THIS COUNTRY GOING
THROUGH THE CIVIL WAR
AND WON IT IN THE END.
YOUR HONOR, IF YOU CUT OFF
THIS GOLD SUPPLY FROM AMERICA,
YOU'RE CUTTING OFF
HER VERY LIFE,
JUST AS SURE AS IF YOU CHOKED
A WOMAN'S THROAT
BETWEEN YOUR HANDS.
AND THAT RESPONSIBILITY
IS YOURS.
I WILL TAKE THIS MATTER
UNDER CONSIDERATION.
I WILL SUBMIT MY DECISION
TO BOTH PARTIES WITHIN 24 HOURS.
COURT IS ADJOURNED.
IT'S SACRAMENTO.
"CHRISTOPHER FERRIS,
"TENSPOT, CALIFORNIA.
"SACRAMENTO VALLEY FARMERS
ARE GRANTED INJUNCTION... "
"GOLDEN MOON MINE.
JUDGE CLAYBURN."
WE'VE DONE IT!
WELL?
GENTLEMEN,
WE'VE LOST THE SUIT.
IMPOSSIBLE.
HYDRAULICKING'S BEEN JUDGED
A PUBLIC NUISANCE.
WHAT USED TO BE A CIVIL SUIT
FOR DAMAGES
IS NOW A CRIMINAL OFFENSE.
PUT IT IN PLAIN LANGUAGE.
WHAT'S IT MEAN?
IT MEANS IF WE KEEP ON,
WE'RE BUCKING
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
YOUR BROTHER'S TAKEN OUT
AN INJUNCTION
AGAINST
THE GOLDEN MOON MINE.
THEY HAVEN'T HAD TIME
TO SERVE IT.
NO, AND THEY'RE NOT
GOING TO SERVE IT.
IF THEY WANT A FIGHT,
THEY'RE GOING TO GET IT.
WHITNEY, YOU GET UP THERE
AND HOLD THEM OFF,
EVEN IF YOU HAVE TO SHOOT.
CAN'T DO IT, McCOOEY.
IT WOULD MEAN OPEN WAR.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
IT'S WAR.
BUT YOU DEFEND THAT MINE
AT ANY COST.
HAVE YOU FIGURED OUT
WHAT THE COST WILL BE?
DON'T BE A FOOL,
WHITNEY.
A FEW MEN MIGHT GET HURT,
OF COURSE. WE CAN'T HELP THAT.
IT ISN'T A MATTER OF A FEW MEN.
I KNOW THOSE RANCHERS.
THERE'LL BE 300 OF THEM
UP THERE
AT THAT BARRICADE
IF YOU REFUSE SERVICE.
THAT ISN'T A FIGHT.
IT'S A MASSACRE.
CALL IT ANYTHING YOU LIKE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO ACCEPT
SERVICE, AND THAT'S FINAL.
IN THREE MONTHS, WE'LL HAVE
THAT DECISION REVERSED.
IN THE MEANTIME, THE GOLDEN
MOON'S GOING RIGHT ON OPERATING
IF WE HAVE TO BLAST OUT
EVERY RANCHER IN THE VALLEY.
NOW, LISTEN, McCOOEY.
HYDRAULICKING IS OVER,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
THAT'S FOR US TO DECIDE,
WHITNEY.
NOW, YOU LISTEN TO ME,
ALL OF YOU.
I STRUNG WITH YOU AS LONG
AS YOU WERE ACTING LEGALLY.
BUT WHEN IT COMES TO REBELLING
AGAINST THE LAW
AND PLANNING WHOLESALE MURDER,
I'M THROUGH!
AND ANOTHER THING -
AS LONG AS I'M IN CHARGE
OF THE GOLDEN MOON MINE,
THEY'LL BE NO KILLING.
AND YOU CAN TAKE IT
OR LEAVE IT.
GENTLEMEN, WHEN YOU WANT TO
REACH ME, I'LL BE AT THE MINE.
I WAS AFRAID
WE COULDN'T TRUST HIM.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT WHITNEY.
I'VE MADE OTHER ARRANGEMENTS.
MR. MINTON.
GENTLEMEN, THIS IS MR. MINTON,
OUR FOREMAN.
HOW ARE YOU?
HOW DO YOU DO,
GENTLEMEN?
HAVE A CHAIR.
THANKS.
WELL,
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
GET THE REST
OF THOSE RIFLES.
TAKE AS MANY AS YOU CAN
AND FILL UP YOUR POCKETS.
GROGAN, YOU KNOW HOW
TO USE THAT THING?
SURE. BUT I'D FIRST LIKE TO KNOW
WHY I'M USING IT?
TO KEEP YOUR THICK HEAD
IN ONE PIECE.
ALL RIGHT. COME ON.
OH, HE'S HAD TIME ENOUGH
TO GET UP THERE
AND BACK TWICE OVER.
MAYBE HE'S NEVER
COMING BACK.
MUST HAVE GOT COLD FEET,
JUST LIKE THE LAST TIME
HE COME HERE
AND SERVED THE INJUNCTION.
IF I HAD MY WAY,
WE WOULDN'T WAIT
FOR A FEDERAL INJUNCTION.
WE'D GO UP THERE
OURSELVES.
MAC, WE SAID WE'D WAIT.
BESIDES, THERE'S NO SENSE
IN ALL OF US GOING UP THERE.
THEY MIGHT TAKE IT
THE WRONG WAY.
HERE HE COMES!
WELL, WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT HAPPENED?
I WOULDN'T GET MIXED
UP IN A THING LIKE THIS
FOR ALL THE MONEY
IN THE WORLD.
AS A RULE IT'S EASY.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
GIVE THE MAN HIS PAPERS.
BUT THESE MINERS -
THEY DON'T CARE ABOUT THE LAW.
THEY'VE GOT BARRICADES,
AND THEY'VE GOT MEN WITH GUNS,
AND THEY INTEND TO USE
THEM. ARE YOU SCARED?
WELL, WHY SHOULD I GO UP THERE
AND LET THEM KILL ME?
I HAVE A WIFE
AND THREE CHILDREN.
AND IF YOU RANCHERS
WANT THIS INJUNCTION SERVED,
YOU'LL HAVE TO SERVE IT
YOURSELVES.
HERE. LET ME HAVE IT.
I'LL SERVE IT.
MY JOB AS MUCH AS YOURS, LANCE.
I'LL GO WITH YOU.
MINE TOO, MAC.
OPEN THE GATE!
IT'S MR. WHITNEY!
DO YOU EXPECT THE UNITES STATES
ARMY TO ATTACK?
WE AIN'T AIMING
FOR NO ONE TO SNEAK IN
AND GIVE US
A SURPRISE PARTY.
YOUR HIDES WILL BE SAFE.
YOU BET THEY WILL.
I MEANT WHAT I SAID,
HARRIS.
THE FIRST MOTHER SON OF YOU
WHO STARTS ANY TROUBLE
WITH THESE VALLEY PEOPLE
WILL ANSWER TO ME.
JUST REMEMBER THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT!
STRETCH OUT ALONG DOWN THERE!
COME ON! GET IN THERE!
HEY, YOU TWO! FILL IN DOWN THERE
ALONG THE LINE!
MINTON!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO TOLD YOU TO ISSUE
THOSE GUNS?
I GOT MY ORDERS THE SAME PLACE
YOU GOT YOURS.
YOU KEEP OUT OF THIS, WHITNEY.
YOU BEEN FIRED.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
HEY!
ALL OF YOU,
DROP THOSE GUNS!
YOU GET YOUR TIME
AND GET OUT.
THIS MINE IS BEING CLOSED
BY A FEDERAL LAW.
IT AIN'T CLOSED YET, WHITNEY,
AND IT AIN'T GONNA BE CLOSED.
THIS MINE WILL KEEP RIGHT
ON OPERATING, LAW OR NO LAW.
IF ANYBODY LEAVES HERE,
IT'S GONNA BE YOU!
THERE'S YOUR DISCHARGE,
MISTER!
TELL THOSE MEN
TO KEEP THEIR EYES OPEN!
SOME OF THE RANCHERS
ARE COMING UP THE ROAD, BOYS.
YOU SURE ARE COMING
TO THE RIGHT SHOP, OLD-TIMERS!
OLD MAN FERRIS' KID -
HE'S PROBABLY DRUNK AGAIN.
STOP IF YOU KNOW
WHAT'S GOOD FOR YOU!
WHERE'S JARED WHITNEY?
HE AIN'T SEEING
NOBODY TODAY.
WELL, WE'RE GONNA SEE HIM,
AND WE'RE NOT LEAVING
TILL WE DO.
I'VE GOT A GREETING
FROM THE FEDERAL COURT FOR YOU.
HEY! DROP THOSE GUNS!
OPEN THAT GATE!
TURN AROUND AND GET GOING!
STOP, LANCE! HE'LL KILL YOU!
LANCE.
KEEP BACK!
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO LANCE?
DON'T BLAME WHITNEY, BOYS.
IT WASN'T HIS FAULT.
THE BOY NEVER HAD
A CHANCE, CHRIS.
WHITNEY RAN DOWN
TO WARN US,
BUT THEY FIRED
BEFORE HE COULD REACH US.
BRING HIM INTO THE LIBRARY
AND PUT HIM ON THE COUCH.
THERE.
SPRAT.
I...
I WOULDN'T
TRY TO TALK, SON.
I'VE GOT TO.
IT WASN'T JARED'S FAULT.
HE TRIED TO TELL ME,
BUT... I WOULDN'T LISTEN.
HANG ON, BOY.
US FERRISES DON'T QUIT.
GATHER YOUR MEN TOGETHER,
MacKENZIE, AND GET YOUR GUNS.
JARED -
WHY DID THEY SEND HIM,
SERENA - A KID LIKE THAT?
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN THE SAME
FOR ANYONE ELSE.
WHOEVER WENT UP
WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED.
AND NOW FATHER AND THE OTHERS
ARE GOING. NO. THEY CAN'T.
AND THEY'LL KILL
AND BE KILLED,
AND EVERY HOME IN THIS VALLEY
WILL BE LIKE THIS ONE.
WELL, THEY CAN'T!
THEY MUSTN'T!
COME ON.
GIDDAP!
MISTER,
MY FEET SURE IS HURTING.
AFTER THE FIGHT, MAYBE THEY
NEVER WILL BOTHER YOU AGAIN.
HERE THEY COME, WIDE OPEN.
WHEN THEY GET WITHIN RANGE, PICK
OFF EVERY LIVING SON OF THEM.
I'M GOING OVER
TO THE NORTH BARRICADE.
EDDIE, YOU AND JOE
COME WITH ME.
HALT.
JIM.
WE'RE DIVIDING THE FORCE
INTO THREE PARTS -
ONE TO SPREAD UP ON EACH SIDE OF
THE RAVINE TO COVER THE FLANKS.
THE MAIN BODY HERE
FOR A FRONTAL ATTACK.
ED, YOU LEAD ONE FORCE -
30 MEN UP THAT SIDE.
JIM, YOU TAKE THE SAME NUMBER
OF MEN UP THERE.
AND KEEP UNDERCOVER.
WAIT!
WHEN THE MINERS START SHOOTING,
KEEP THEM BUSY
WITH A RUNNING FIRE
WHILE WE GO UP THE HILL.
AND IF WE DON'T GET UP,
YOU KEEP TRYING UNTIL YOU DO.
START UP.
THIS HERE'S EXACTLY
THE SAME SITUATION
WE HAD AT GETTYSBURG,
REMEMBER?
JOHN ON CEMETERY RIDGE.
LOUISIANA BOYS ON THE LEFT.
LONGSTREET ON THE RIGHT.
AND US -
WE MAKE PICKETT'S CHARGE.
I HOPE WE HAVE BETTER LUCK
THIS TIME, ENOCH.
PSHAW.
ME AND LULA BELLE HERE -
WE'LL STILL BE
THE FUSSINGS UP.
NO, ENOCH, YOU STAY BEHIND.
NEED A GOOD MAN TO TAKE CARE
OF THE HORSES.
WELL, WE'LL WIN, JUST LIKE
WE WON AT CHICKAMAUGA.
YOU BOYS ALL WON?
WELL, IF WE HADN'T, YOU WOULDN'T
BE RUNNING AROUND LOOSE.
COME ON, BOYS!
LET'S GET THESE HORSES
UNDER COVER!
COME ON!
THEY'RE COMING UP
IN THREE DIRECTIONS.
THERE'S A BUNCH IN THE MIDDLE
AND A BUNCH SNEAKING UP
EACH SIDE.
GET READY, MEN.
THE PARTY'S ABOUT TO BEGIN.
FELLAS, WAIT!
THERE'S ANOTHER WAY IN THERE,
A BETTER WAY.
PLEASE BELIEVE ME
THAT THIS IS SUICIDE.
JUST GIVE ME 30 MINUTES,
AND GET YOUR MEN OUT
OF THIS RAVINE AT ONCE.
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
CAN'T YOU SEE THAT I'M WITH YOU,
MR. FERRIS?
PLEASE BELIEVE ME
WHEN I TELL YOU
THAT LANCE
WAS MY BEST FRIEND.
WE'LL WAIT.
GET UP IN THOSE HILLS
AND KEEP UNDERCOVER, MEN!
WONDER WHAT
THEY'RE WAITING FOR.
MAYBE THEY WANT
A PERSONAL INVITE.
I'LL GIVE THEM ONE.
NO, DON'T SHOOT.
YOU'LL LIABLE
TO SCARE THEM AWAY,
AND WE'LL MISS
ALL THE FUN.
I CAN'T STAND THIS WAITING
ANY LONGER, CHRIS.
LET'S GET MOVING.
I SAID WE'D WAIT.
HEY, SLAG,
THERE GOES WHITNEY.
WONDER WHAT HE'S DOING
UP THERE.
HE'S GOT A BUNDLE OF DYNAMITE
AND HE'S HEADED FOR THE DAM.
THERE'S THE SIGNAL!
WAIT, MEN, WAIT!
YOU GOT HIM THAT TIME.
GET TO THE BARRICADE!
I GOT TO MAKE SURE I GOT HIM!
ENOCH, THE HORSES -
CUT THEM LOOSE!
THE WATER! GET OUT OF HERE, MEN!
THE DAM'S BREAKING!
IN THE CASE OF
THE SACRAMENTO VALLEY FARMERS
vs. THE GOLDEN MOON
MINING SYNDICATE,
SUPREME COURT OF CALIFORNIA
DENIES THE APPEAL
OF THE DEFENSE.
COURT FULLY REALIZES
THAT ITS DECISION
IS OF FAR-REACHING IMPORTANCE,
NOT ONLY TO THIS STATE,
BUT TO THE ENTIRE NATION.
FROM THE EVIDENCE WE HAVE HEARD,
IT IS CLEARLY ESTABLISHED
THAT THE DEBRIS FROM THE MINES
HAS CHOKED THE RIVERS
AND SPREAD OVER THE VALLEY,
DESTROYING THOUSANDS OF ACRES
AND COVERING A FRUITFUL LAND
WITH BARRENNESS.
NO SYSTEM OF LAW ON EARTH
TOLERATES THE USE OF ONE MAN'S
PROPERTY IN THIS WAY,
SO AS TO DESTROY THE PROPERTY
OF ANOTHER.
UNQUESTIONABLY,
THE ACTS OF THE DEFENDANT
CONSTITUTE A PUBLIC NUISANCE,
AND AS SUCH THEY ARE UNLAWFUL
IN THEIR INCEPTION
AND IN THEIR CONTINUANCE.
THEREFORE, THE SUPREME COURT
CONFIRMS THE DECISION
OF THE LOWER COURT
AND GRANTS THE PLAINTIFFS
THE RELIEF AS CLAIMED.
WE ORDER THAT THE DECREE
BE SO ENTERED.
LET THIS ALSO BE RECORDED
FOR THE FUTURE.
THE CLAIM OF THE DEFENDANT
MAY BE TRUE -
THAT GOLD IS THE BLOOD
OF THE NATION -
BUT THE EARTH IS ITS HEART
AND ITS SOUL.
THE LAND IS FOR THE PEOPLE.
IT DOESN'T CHANGE.
ITS FRUITS ARE MORE PRECIOUS
AND INEXHAUSTIBLE.
AND, GOD WILLING, MAY IT
CONTINUE TO SURVIVE ITS SPOILS.
BUT THERE'S ANOTHER GOLD
HERE, A GOLD WE COULD NEVER SEE.
SOMEDAY, ORCHARDS
WILL COVER THIS VALLEY,
THE ONE BEYOND,
AND THE ONE BEYOND THAT,
CLEAR DOWN TO THE OCEAN.
AND THERE'LL BE LONG ROWS OF
TREES AS FAR AS A MAN CAN SEE,
ALL GOLD AND GREEN
AND HEAVILY LADEN WITH PRUNES
AND GRAPE VINEYARDS
IN THE HILLS.
AND SOMEDAY, SOMEHOW,
THEY'RE GOING TO SHIP IT
ACROSS THE CONTINENT
TO ALL THE WORLD.
THAT'S THE FUTURE
OF CALIFORNIA -
NOT GOLD.
AND IT WILL BE OUR FUTURE,
TOO, JARED.
ISN'T THAT SOMETHING TO LIVE
AND WORK FOR?