Come in.
Excuse me, sir.
You won't know me.
Cyrus Finney,
North Bay Nugget.
Um, that's a newspaper.
Three minutes, Mr. Grey Owl.
This won't take a moment.
I'm trying to trace a fellow
by the name of Archie Belaney.
Mm-hmm.
Do you know him?
Yes, I know him.
-What took you so long?
-I had to be sure.
What do you want to know?
Whatever you want
to tell me.
Not much to tell.
He was just a kid with a dream
of livin' in the wilderness.
And no one suspected,
even when you were working
as a guide?
-See anything?
-Sh-sh-sh-sh.
Aw, geez...
Did I get him?
I got him. Didn't I, Archie?
Well, Mr. Champlin,
he sure is dead.
You're real good
at what you do, Archie.
You know what?
So am I.
I'm sure you are,
Mr. Champlin.
I own a paper mill
and a printing business...
and a couple
of book-publishing firms.
I am a rich man, Archie.
-Wouldn't you like to be rich?
-Why would I want to be rich?
What you do is,
you write a book:
An Indian's Life
in the Forest.
Same as your magazine pieces, only
longer. That would make you famous.
Hmm.
Being famous doesn't
interest me, Mr. Champlin.
You know how hungry
people are out there...
for your world?
The authentic voice
from the wilderness.
-Congratulations, Harry. Tres bien.
-I haven't seen you in a while.
Couldn't make it last year...
too busy.
Here's to my first bear.
-You want bear, you want Archie.
-Salud, mon ami.
Here's a little something
to remember me by.
Here you are.
Archie Grey Owl.
Your guide wrote this?
"The still hunt is an art
perfected by the Indian,
"who has learned from childhood
to move like a shadow,
"his actions smooth as oil,
his senses set to a hair trigger;
for the forest is argus-eyed."
This is an Indian,
writing in a magazine?
You want to know something?
I'm not here just to hunt bear.
This fellow could be
a gold mine.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Something for the dancers?
Thank you very much, sir. Good evening.
-Thank you, sir.
-Oh, I never pay till I see the goods.
How do I know if this war dance
of yours is authentic?
The more you pay,
the more authentic it gets.
-Terrific! Well done, boys.
-Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
We call that
"The Dance of the Dead Men."
When the dance is done
and the drums fall silent,
we hurl ourselves
upon the hated white man...
and we kill.
But that costs extra.
Ladies and gentlemen,
mesdames et messieurs,
I hope you've enjoyed
our little show.
May I welcome you to dinner?
I read what you wrote
in that magazine.
You can write.
I'm impressed.
You can read.
You booked today?
You want to go huntin'?
No. I want to learn
about my people.
-Who's your people?
-Mohawk... Iroquois Confederacy.
First Mohawk I seen
dressed like that.
Then you've never been in
downtown Val d'Or on a Saturday night.
Two bucks for the day.
Maybe something at the end
to show your appreciation.
Oh, I can't pay you.
So why should I take you?
-Men always do what I want.
-Sure.
Men jump in the lake
for just one of your smiles, right?
Right.
Be back in an hour.
Jump in the lake and
I'll give you 50 cents... right now!
You got it, Pony!
Hmm.
-The world of your ancestors.
-My ancestors wouldn't have done that.
But that's not
where we're going, is it?
No. Up ahead.
Bear Island... Ojibwa village.
See how our people live.
-Your village?
-Could say that.
Chief kind of adopted me
a long time ago.
Can I meet him?
He'll think you're my woman,
and I brought you for him to inspect.
Then we can inspect each other.
He's up here.
I'll lead the way.
This what you wanted?
It's not what I expected.
It's a hard life they have here.
Shh. Hey.
Hey!
You young devil!
Where've you been for so long?
Oh, earning a living.
Good to see you.
Oh, Ned.
My young brother.
Hello, Ned.
Some dancing.
-Who is this you bring to see me?
-Mmm...
My name is Gertrude Bernard.
Chief Pete Misabi.
-I'm honored, Father.
-Lovely. Very lovely.
She's your wife?
No, no, no.
Just a friend.
When the time is right,
you tell him...
he bring you to me,
and I make the wedding.
Uh, Pete,
no one's marrying anybody.
-He's kinda old, you think?
-Well, he does look kind of old.
Well, with the life he leads,
what do you expect?
He's a great hunter, great trapper.
He'll provide well for you.
You think he's the kind of man
a girl can rely on?
That I cannot say.
He's a wanderer, you know.
That's why I gave him his name:
Wa-Sha-Quon-Asin... Grey Owl...
he who walks by night.
-Can you manage?
-Yeah, sure.
Are you really called
Gertrude?
You think I'd make up
a name like that?
So what do they call you?
Gertie?
Do I look like a Gertie?
I wouldn't know.
I'm called Pony,
my father's pet name for me.
-Don't ask me why.
-Hmm. I won't.
How about a good-bye kiss,
to show my appreciation?
Sure.
-That was it?
-Takes two to kiss.
Hmm?
See you around,
Archie Grey Owl.
Ned, come on.
Get a move on.
There's a wind comin' up.
I want to get back before dark.
I can only stay here
five minutes.
Hey, you!
Don't I know you?
-Do me a favor. Where am I?
-You're in Elk River.
What the hell am I doin'
in Elk River?
-It's as far as the railroad goes.
-Oh, end of the line, eh?
-Yup, end of the line.
-Hurry it up, you guys!
-Friend of yours?
-Never seen him before in my life.
Are you the fella
they call Archie Grey Owl?
That's me.
I'm Jim Bernard,
Pony's father.
What can I do for you?
Well, sir,
Pony's been offered a job
in Montreal.
She's supposed to start
next week.
-Sounds good.
-But she says she's not going.
Got this Indian bug.
-Wants to live like her ancestors.
-Hmm.
It's all moonshine.
Can't turn back the clock.
That life's over.
-Nobody lives in the forest anymore.
-I do.
How the hell
do you survive up there?
Oh, I don't need that much.
The forest looks after me.
Brave talk.
-Got my daughter all fired up.
-She wouldn't last a week.
Then why is she planning
on goin' up north with you?
Oh, I never said that.
What Pony wants, Pony gets.
Of course, you could always strike camp
and go before she knew it.
Then you'd be gone.
Yeah.
Archie!
She told me you said I could bring her.
Are you out of your bloody mind?
What am I gonna do with her out here?
-Hell, I thought you'd want her here.
-Don't think!
Just take her back with you
in the morning. Get her outta here.
-Sure, Archie, if that's what you want.
-That's what I want.
-You're goin' back with Ned.
-No.
I didn't invite you here. I don't
want you here. I'm telling you to go.
-I'm telling you I won't.
-I don't have time to nursemaid you.
-Fine. Don't.
-Then you'll die.
-So I die.
-I mean it!
You don't know
what life's like here.
It's hard, and it's dangerous.
Tell her, Ned.
Sure is hard and dangerous.
-This is no life for a woman.
-I'm not going.
So either you tie me up
and have Ned carry me back,
or I stay right here.
What are you doing?
Making a torch.
What for?
Huntin'.
-Can I come?
-No.
If you don't like it,
you don't have to watch.
I'm okay.
My people were hunters once.
-Do you have a Mohawk name?
-Yes.
I'm named after
my great-grandmother, Anahareo.
How come you're called Archie?
I'm a half-breed.
How else do you think I got these
blue eyes? My mother was Scottish.
I didn't know that.
You have a problem with that?
-No. No problem.
-That's all right then.
-You want some?
-Huh?
Yeah, okay.
You ever been married, Archie?
Twice.
-What happened?
-Oh, nothing.
We spent some time together...
and moved on.
Why get married if you know
you're going to leave?
you're gonna stay?
That's the old way...
marry when the time comes
to part,
like a warrior going to war,
a hunter leaving
on a long journey.
Just put it down there.
Thank you.
That way you keep
a piece of each other forever.
I love it when you tell me
about the old ways.
How do you know
I'm not just making it up?
I know when you're faking it.
Oh?
Like when?
When you grunt at me like you
don't want me around,
and I know you do.
This used to be a beaver dam.
Some stinking white men,
call themselves trappers,
been using dynamite
in my territory.
No Indians would do this.
We don't take the kittens.
We don't destroy the lodges.
Soon there'll be no beaver left.
-How much further?
-A good way yet.
I'm getting cold.
We'll go across the lake.
It'll get us back before dark.
Snow's coming.
Spread your weight, slide.
-Don't get too near now, okay?
-Okay.
Whatever you do, don't stop.
May be some soft spots.
You're going too fast.
I can't keep up.
Will you wait?
Archie!
I can't go on!
I have to rest!
Archie!
-Don't move!
-Archie!
Don't move!
You'll make the hole bigger!
Don't move! Don't move!
Help me!
-Don't move. Stay still.
-Help me.
Look at me.
Look at me, Pony.
Don't struggle.
Don't struggle!
Stay right here.
Stay with me, Pony.
Grab this belt. Grab this belt.
Pony, hold on.
Don't move.
Grab it! Come on.
-Pony. Pony.
-I can't.
I can't feel my legs.
Come on. That's it. You're free.
Come on. You're gonna be...
-Help me! Come on!
-Come on.
Shh. Shh.
Hold this. Come on.
Come on! Stay with me!
-I can't. I can't get up!
-Get up. Get up, Pony!
-Get up! Get up.
-I can't!
Pony, get up.
Come on, Pony, please.
Come on.
Walk!
Don't stop or you're gonna lock up!
Come on, run!
Run! Get up!
Get up! Get up!
Get up.
Run. Run. Run!
Pony, keep moving.
Keep moving, Pony.
-Get up! Get up! Get up, Pony!
-I can't!
You're gonna freeze. Keep moving.
I'm so sorry.
Pony, don't die on me.
Don't...
Pony.
Pony, I'm such a fool.
There we go, Pony.
There we go.
Stay warm.
Nenemoosha.
-Archie?
-Right here.
I guess I'm not
as tough as I thought.
You did fine.
You're still alive.
You were stroking me.
Trying to get you warm.
I liked that.
I like that too.
I swore I wouldn't.
Why not?
I don't know.
You're afraid
I'll fall in love with you.
Don't worry.
I can look after myself.
I guess I've always been alone.
But it's okay,
me being here now.
-Isn't it?
-Yes.
Better than okay.
If we can make
each other happy, Archie,
let's do it.
It's not as if
it's so easy to find.
Yeah.
What was that word
you called me?
Some Indian word.
Nenemoosha.
What's that?
It's just a word.
I like it.
What's that?
What?
That.
It's called a dream-catcher.
What's it for?
You hang 'em up for babies,
newly-married couples.
Bad dreams get caught
in the web,
good dreams go through.
-Do Mohawks have dream-catchers?
-Sure.
And all I have is a Mohawk name.
I need more.
Best of all, beaver.
So few left,
they fetch good money.
But the season's over.
You said.
What's here won't even
pay off my loan.
We have to live too, you know?
There's no guarantee
anyone will buy my book.
Why won't you let me
read what you're writing?
It's not done yet.
Am I in it?
Why would you be in it?
If I was writing a book,
you'd be in it.
Yes.
You're in it.
Laid a trap here this morning.
Bit of luck,
got us another beaver pelt.
The one up in the dam there.
That's it. This side.
See what we've got here.
-Ah, bitch!
-What is it?
-Trap and chain broke free.
-The beaver got away?
No, it'll be down there
with the trap.
Ten bucks shot to hell.
Aw, damn!
Come on. Come on.
Ahmik.
Beaver kittens.
Where is their mother?
She's down there in your trap,
isn't she?
She's drowned, isn't she?
Most likely.
-How are they going to live without her?
-They're not.
They aren't weaned.
They'll slowly starve to death.
Archie, no.
Don't look.
Never... Never do that again!
You'll get yourself shot.
Shh.
Don't worry.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, baby.
Come on.
They don't want it.
Why would they?
You're not their mother.
Can't you even look at them?
What for?
I'm a trapper.
Remember?
I'm not trying
to get at you, Archie.
You said it yourself...
soon there'll be no beaver left.
We can't just leave them to die.
Everything dies.
Flies get eaten by fish, fish get eaten
by otters, otters get eaten by wolves.
I've seen a bear kill a wolf...
rip out its guts to eat.
I've seen men kill bears,
and I've seen a man
three weeks dead covered in flies.
Kill a deer for meat...
I understand that.
Kill beaver to make yourself a coat
so you don't freeze to death...
I understand that.
But killing as a trade,
to make money?
You're better than that, Archie.
Forest Indians have
always been trappers.
-Did they always trap animals for trade?
-Sure.
Archie, that's not true,
and you know it.
The old Indian way was
you killed only what you needed.
It was the white traders
who taught us to kill for money.
We never even had money
before the white man came.
You're a woman.
You're town-raised.
You wouldn't understand.
Whatever you say, Archie.
Go back to sleep.
I don't believe this.
He likes you, Archie.
Well, I don't like him.
-Then put him back on the floor.
-Mmm.
I don't think he knows
you don't like him.
You better make it clearer.
Get lost, fuzzy face.
That's telling him.
Archie. Archie!
-Yeah?
-I can't find one of the micks.
-He'll be around somewhere.
-It isn't.
I've got one,
but where is the other?
Mick, mick.
Mick!
Come on.
Mick. Mick.
-Mick, mick. Mick.
-Pony.
-How far could it have got?
-Oh, quite a way.
-Can't you track it or something?
-In snow, maybe.
Now it could be anywhere.
Might it get as far
as the trapline?
No. No way.
Oh, God.
No!
No.
I'm sorry.
Oh, dear Jesus, I'm so sorry.
Archie, I found him.
He came back.
-They're playing in the cabin.
-You found him?
What happened?
You thought it was...
Oh, yes.
Oh, Archie.
I've quit.
I know.
No more trapping.
I love you, Archie.
You all set?
Sure you got everything?
I'm sure.
All right.
You said they hang them up for babies
and newly-married couples?
That's right.
What happens when you aren't
a baby anymore or a new-married?
I guess you handle
your own dreams.
Hear you got a girl.
News travels.
-Good winter?
-You tell me, Gus.
So where'd you find these?
Out Abitibi way?
Hey, squaw man,
I'm talkin' to ya.
-You have a problem?
-Yeah, I have a problem.
Some thievin' redskin's been
trappin' our territory.
-Now, where'd you find these pelts?
-Seventy-two.
Hey, squaw man,
don't turn your back on me.
Hey, boy, step out.
You've been raiding
our traplines?
No Indian does that to m...
You boys better leave.
Be seein' you around.
Ignorant savage
shake in shoes.
So, uh, Archie,
by my tally,
you tally up 290.
You owe me another 20.
Do me a favor, Gus.
Make it $20 and the postage
for my book, okay?
Sure.
They're the bastards
that've been poaching my traplines,
wipin' out the beaver.
Poison, dynamite...
it's all the same to them.
You take care of yourself
up there, okay?
-That's it. Step right up, please.
-Pony.
Pony.
Thank you very much.
You'll have to hurry now.
-You didn't get enough for the pelts?
-Couldn't even clear the debt.
A whole winter's work.
-Still 20 bucks down. Sorry.
-There's a pile in there to the right.
Stack it right inside there.
-I don't know what we do now.
-There ya go.
Come along now.
Step up, please.
You like to move up now.
I do.
-Feathers?
-Why not?
Most Indians are like my dad...
ashamed of what they are.
Put a feather in their hair, you're
saying, "I'm Indian and proud of it."
I know that what brings
you good people to Wabikon Lodge...
is not only the fine cuisine.
Or the friendly service.
The man who's going
to speak to you...
is an Ojibwa Indian who's lived
all his life in these forests.
I can't do this.
-He's paying cash. Think of the money.
-Ladies and gentlemen.
Mesdames et messieurs.
He's also the guide
who wrote those terrific articles...
in Forest and Outdoors.
Pretty good, aren't they?
Just talk the way you write.
So, ladies and gentlemen, mesdames
et messieurs, I give you Grey Owl.
Thank you.
I've not done too much
speakin' in public before.
To tell the truth, I feel like
the snake that swallowed the icicle.
Oh, look!
Hello, you two.
You come to help me out?
These little fellas
live with us.
We call them the micks.
The Ojibwa name for beaver is ahmik,
"little talking brother."
And they do talk too.
Can you say "hi" to everyone?
Beavers are family-minded,
you know.
A beaver pair will stay together
for life, just like us... some of us.
We're not planning on
holding on to these kittens too long.
As soon as they've grown,
we'll let them go back into the wild,
have some babies of their own.
The fact is...
I used to trap beaver.
But a few weeks ago I quit.
Never thought I would.
Now I know it's wrong.
They're almost extinct.
Too many trappers,
not enough beaver.
When the beaver have gone
from the north...
Maybe you don't know, but these little
fellas make the north the way it is.
They build their dams,
make their ponds...
where the moose feed,
the muskrats, the waterfowl.
Come the spring, they open up
their dams, let the meltwater run...
and you've got an irrigation system
a thousand miles wide.
Take away the beaver,
and you break the chain.
So I'm speakin' up
for the beaver now.
If we don't watch out,
there'll just be
another extinct species.
I guess I feel it
more than most because...
well, people like me are pretty much
an extinct species too.
I can guess you can
get along without me,
but these little fellas... the world
would be a poorer place without them.
What do you have to say?
Never ask me to do that again.
You were great, Archie.
You really got to them.
How 'bout a curtain call?
Thank you.
It's wild country,
way north of the Saskatchewan River.
We build you a cabin
just the way you want it,
and the National Parks Department
pays you a monthly salary.
-National park?
-Yeah.
All 3,000 square miles of it.
Why would I want to go there?
You want to save the beaver?
You could do just that.
Establish a colony...
no danger, trapping's forbidden.
Jim wants the same as you, Archie...
to save the beaver
before it's too late.
We need to get
the public on our side.
We need politicians to vote
funds for the parks.
And you could
really help us, Archie.
And you'd be free to write.
What's the problem?
It's made for you.
You know why I love
the forest?
I love the forest because it's
the last place men aren't in charge.
The last wilderness.
Why would I want to be
a park keeper?
Excuse me.
My name is Finney,
Cyrus Finney.
I was very taken by what Grey Owl
had to say this afternoon.
You obviously know him quite well.
Would you mind if I join you?
Did you know
he played piano?
I've heard him play.
Gimme that.
Where'd he learn that?
I mean, what else can he do?
Why doesn't he
tell me anything?
I've known Archie since I was four,
when my father adopted him.
I'd do anything for him,
but I'll never understand him,
even after all those years.
Watch out.
So he'll never
tell me anything.
Maybe not, but I'll tell you
two things:
Archie's past belongs
to him and only him,
and you... well, you've lasted longer
than any others.
Night, Dave.
See ya in the mornin'.
Take it easy, Charlie.
Come on, hurry up.
Hey, Archie!
It's me, Sim Hancock.
-Hey, Archie, it's that drunk again.
-Hey, wait a minute!
-Hey, it's me!
-What's happened to this place?
-Never used to be full of bums.
-I know it's you, ya bastard!
-Remember me, Archie?
-Where's Pony?
I'll see ya, Charlie!
You may have gone native,
but I know you!
-I know it's you!
-Go find Pony. Find her now, Ned.
It's time to get out of this place.
Tell her we're leaving.
Lake Ajawaan.