There it is.
$40,000 just sitting
there waiting for us.
All we have to do
is ride in and get it.
Now, this is the
main teller's cage.
He's got a sawed-off
shotgun under the counter.
Farley, you'll see
he never gets his
hands on it.
Rem, you keep one eye
on the Sheriff's office
across the street,
And the other on
the bank guard.
Here, once we're
inside, I'll move
straight to the vault.
Farley, you cover me.
Shouldn't take more
than five minutes,
If everything goes right.
What if it doesn't?
Then it's every
man for himself
And we'll get back
here to the cabin
the best way we can.
Let's get moving.
Rem, are you sure
you want to go
through with it?
Too late to
back out now.
What if something
goes wrong?
Nothing is going to
go wrong, Jan.
We get our hands on
that money, everything's
going to be all right.
Oh, Rem.
MATT: Come on, Rem.
You be ready to leave
as soon as I get back.
Be careful, Rem.
(GUNSHOTS)
Get those saddlebags
and canteens under the horses.
Right.
What happened?
What does it look like?
He's lost a lot of blood.
We'll have to...
There isn't time.
We've got to take time.
I killed a man
at the bank.
I couldn't help it.
The fool went
for his gun.
The whole town
came alive.
There was a lot
of shooting.
He can't be moved.
That we know.
Then we'll have to stay.
Don't be crazy. There'll be
a posse riding down on
this cabin in a few minutes.
You're not going
to leave him.
Well, we can't take
him with us. If we do,
he'll slow us down.
We'll all be caught.
What'll that prove?
He wouldn't leave you.
Maybe not,
but we got our hands
on a lot of money,
And I'm not
going to spend it
at the end of a rope.
I won't leave him.
Then stay. Stay and watch
them drag him out to the
nearest tree and hang him.
No, Matt. I won't
leave him!
You're going with us.
I've always
admired this horse.
Besides, Remmy ain't
going to need it.
I'm not going
to leave him.
Yeah, that little
affair's over.
Now it's my turn.
Oh, you...
Hold it, Farley.
Two of us might
get together to
spend this money,
But now's no
time to decide it.
Let's go.
(COMMANDING HORSE)
(HORSES APPROACHING)
Still warm.
Let's go in.
I heard someone in
the bank say those three
got away with over $40,000.
Poor old Bill.
They shot him right
through the middle.
Well, you wouldn't
catch me going for
my gun the way he did.
They could
have the money.
Slim says he thinks
he hit one of them as
they rode out of town.
One of them has
got a hole in him.
That'll slow 'em down.
Come on.
SHERIFF: They'll be
traveling slow.
One of them is wounded.
SHERIFF: Come on.
Sheriff.
Tell us, where are they?
It's no good, Sheriff.
You and Charlie get
him in to Doc Turner.
The rest of you,
come with me.
Any luck, Sheriff?
They headed south
of the Pedro.
We lost them
in the dark.
He's one of them, all right.
Well, what do you
have to say for
yourself, mister?
There's not
much I can say.
You plain-face admitting
you rode with them
that held up the bank?
Would it do me
any good to deny it?
What about
the others?
What about them?
They rode off
and left you,
didn't they?
Did they?
Man did me that way,
I'd get even if I could.
I plan to.
What names they go by?
Who?
Now, you look
here at me, mister.
Only thing keeping you
from a hang rope,
Is that bank teller
being too ornery to die.
But that don't mean
we can't turn that key
And keep you jailed
up here till hell freezes.
Look, young man,
those others, they
got off with $40,000.
So having you
means very little to us.
The important thing
is the money.
Meaning?
Meaning that folks
about here had almost all
they owned in that bank.
Just natural they'd
take kindly to you
If you was to tell us
who the others were
and where to find them.
I can't do that.
You mean you won't?
I mean I can't.
I don't even know
where they are.
You asking me to believe
that you outlawed
with those gents?
I'm not asking you
to believe anything.
But you could give
the Sheriff here
their names.
Their description.
If I did that,
he might catch up to them
Before I did.
Well, mister,
you ain't leaving
us much choice.
Facing a robbery
charge alone,
gonna go hard on you.
Not as hard as it's
gonna go on them.
(WHINNIES)
I see him.
Hello, Rem.
Hello, Billy.
Ain't seen you
around much lately.
I ain't been around.
That could be a reason.
Coffee?
Yeah.
Lot of lonely
country out here.
Peaceful, though.
Makes a man quiet inside.
You still killing, Billy?
I'm alive.
Are you?
Much as you.
I dug a grave for a man
back in Palace City
a year or so ago.
Folks there were
saying words
about a holdup,
And how the others
rode away rich,
Left you in jail.
That a fact?
Something like that.
You found him yet?
Who?
Matt Rankin.
(SIGHS)
You make good
coffee, Billy.
You know, that's the trouble
with this territory.
It's too big.
Man goes looking
to find somebody,
It can take him
near forever.
Yeah.
Thanks for the coffee.
Rem, you tried
Gunther Wells?
Sun ain't half high,
already we got us
a scorcher.
Yeah.
It's just too blamed hot
in this country.
Getting hotter
all the time.
Sure seems that way,
don't it?
One of these days,
so help me, Lee,
I'm going to ride north.
Up toward Montana
and that way.
They say a man
can freeze out there.
That sure
would be nice.
Yeah.
Well, leastways the heat
keeps the peace.
Too blamed hot
for people to go
breaking laws.
See you at
the office, Lee.
Sheriff?
Look.
Know him?
Never saw
him before.
Morning.
Town seems deserted.
Everybody's in the shade.
That sun pours down
on a man.
Yeah, I hadn't noticed.
I'm Sheriff Morton.
This is my deputy, Lee.
Howdy.
You got a name?
Anderson.
Remington Anderson.
Heard of you.
Where's your hotel?
Down the street
on the right, just
past the saloon.
Well, be seeing you.
That's more than likely.
Yeah. It's gettin'
hotter all the time.
Thought I told
you to knock.
Rem's in town.
What?
I said, Rem's in town.
Then you're crazy.
I tell you,
I saw him.
What are we
going to do?
That's up to Rem.
Well, we can't
just sit here.
You got any
better ideas?
Maybe.
Maybe if you
went to him.
Sure. Sure,
I'll go to him.
Walk up, slap him
on the back, and say,
"Remember me?
"I'm the one who left
you behind. The one you
went to jail for."
What about the girl?
Well, leaving Rem
behind, that was
bad enough,
But when he
finds out that Jan
and you have been...
Been what, Farley?
Look, he has a
fair quarrel with me.
But I'm not about to
get myself dead for
somebody else's woman.
I'm pulling out.
You ought to
do the same.
I wonder how far
he'll get.
What was
that all about?
Rem's in town.
You haven't forgotten
him, have you?
I tried.
You're a witness to that.
Yeah, I guess I am.
Not now, Matt.
Jan.
If you've got any ideas
about going back to him,
forget them.
There's probably only
one person in the world
he hates more than me.
You.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
Hello, Farley.
Look, Rem...
Shut up.
Where's Rankin?
In the saloon.
Jan...
Jan's with him.
All right,
you get back there,
and you tell him
They're not going
to have a chance to
run out on me this time.
Sure.
Sure. I'll tell him.
What was that all about?
He was riding my horse.
Just a minute,
young fellow.
This town may not look
like much to you, but we got
laws and I enforce them.
You going to
arrest me, Sheriff?
I figured on it.
What for?
I seen that Farley
fellow riding this horse
for near a year.
Well, I got a bill of
sale on this animal.
Description,
markings, brand.
He's even got my initials
on his saddle.
You saying Farley
stole your horse?
I'm saying he
was riding him.
Meaning you don't
intend to charge him
with horse taking?
That's right.
You need me,
I'll be at the hotel.
What do you
make of him, Sheriff?
I ain't at all sure.
Well, I guess
we better go over
to the saloon
And find out if that
Farley's got a bill of
sale for that animal.
No need.
No need?
No.
Maybe that Anderson
fellow was lying.
Maybe.
Still wouldn't do
no harm to check.
Look, I figure if
Farley had a bill,
He would have come storming
into my office, demanding
I do something about it.
Anderson beat him
clear of it.
Say, that's right.
Never thought of that.
It's sure a mighty
funny way to let a fellow
know he's riding your horse.
Tell you what, Lee,
You keep an eye on
the saloon and that
young fellow in the hotel.
I'll be in the office.
Let me know if you see
anything out of the ordinary.
Sure thing, Sheriff.
It's sure going to
be a scorcher.
Are you sure
that's all he said?
Well, ain't
that enough?
You ask me,
come dark, we ought
to pull out of here.
A day will put us in...
No.
But why can't...
Shut up.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
RANKIN: Yeah?
He still hasn't come
out of the hotel.
He will.
Look, Rankin, I don't
know about you,
but I want to get...
Jake.
Yes, sir?
Can you find Billy Deal?
JAKE: Guess so.
Why don't you just
shoot him in the back
and get it over with?
What am I supposed
to do? Run?
You did, once.
Well, Mr. Rankin?
Find him.
Sheriff?
That woman, that Miss Janice,
from the saloon,
She just went in the hotel.
She did, eh?
Well, you told me to
let you know if anything
out of the ordinary happened.
That's right, I did.
Thanks, Lee.
Say, you don't suppose
she knows that Anderson
fellow, do you?
She probably does.
Well, maybe I'd
better get back and
keep my eyes open.
That's a good idea.
I'll be out in front
of the hotel if you
need me, Sheriff.
Right.
(SLAMS)
I had to see you, Rem.
Get out.
Rem, I can explain.
Explain?
You mean, there's a
reason to run off and leave
a half-dead man to a posse?
There's a reason for that?
I didn't want
to leave you.
But you did, didn't you?
Why?
I...
I've asked myself that
a thousand times.
Couldn't have been
the money, could it?
You can't believe that.
Can't I?
I should have left you
where I found you.
In a saloon?
Is that what you mean?
Now, look...
No.
No, you look.
I'm every dirty thing
you think I am.
Only worse.
All right,
so I ran out on you.
You think you're the first man
I played for a sucker?
I've rolled drunks
in every cheap saloon
in this territory.
I've cheated and lied
my way, ever since
I can remember.
And there's not one
sin I haven't done
at least once.
But I loved you.
You're the only
clean thing that ever
happened to me.
You wanted to settle down.
Live respectable.
You wanted to own
your own ranch.
Then you had to ruin it
by throwing in with
Rankin and his kind.
You wanted to own
your own ranch, all right.
But you wanted to steal
the money to buy it.
You're no better
than the rest of us.
I'm sorry I came up here.
Why did you come, then?
Why?
Because Rankin
sent for Billy Deal.
He's going to blow
your head off, Rem.
And you don't have
to believe that, either.
Sheriff?
Slow down, Lee.
Billy Deal's in town.
Billy?
Just rode in,
big as life.
Bigger.
Wonder what
brings him to town?
He tied up and
went into the saloon.
You suppose that
Farley sent for him
'Cause he's sore
about that Anderson fellow
doing him like he did?
Well, it's a thought.
Farley's the kind of man
who wouldn't fight
his own fight.
Yeah, Farley's also
the kind of man who
wouldn't have enough money
To hire Billy to gun a man.
How old is that
boy of yours, Lee?
Huh?
Oh, uh, he's six.
Say, you don't
think Billy might be...
Six, huh?
Nice to be six.
Six? Well, yeah,
I guess so. Six.
Nice day today.
Why don't you
take him fishing?
Fishing?
Yeah.
There's a great big
bass that just sort
of lazes around
Under that bridge
at Higgins Crossing.
It's about the
biggest bass I ever
seen in these parts.
Oh, now, Sheriff, look...
You be back
before it's dark.
Every doggone time
there's trouble, I always
have to take the kid fishing.
Son,
This town's going to
be here a long time
after I'm gone.
You can take
care of it then.
You understand?
Yeah. I guess so.
You be back before it's dark.
Good luck.
You know I hate fish.
Hello, Billy.
Rankin?
(SPURS JINGLING)
You want to see me?
You heard of Rem Anderson?
Yeah?
He's in town.
So?
He's here to kill me.
There's $5,000.
Well?
It's a lot of money.
I like living.
Where is he?
RANKIN: He's staying
at the hotel.
One thing, Rankin.
Rem.
You better see
he's buried real good.
He's a friend of mine.
(SPURS JINGLING)
(TICKING)
Hiya, Billy.
Rem Anderson.
In the hotel, is he?
He was. He ain't now.
Went out.
Where to?
Didn't say. Just went.
You sure?
(STAMMERING) Yes, Billy.
Much obliged.
Thank you.
(TICKING)
(CLATTERING)
REM: Hello, Billy.
Been looking
to find you, Rem.
You found me.
Yeah.
Unbuckle your
gun belt, Billy.
Throw it down.
Now, I can't
do that, Rem.
I've been paid
to kill you.
I heard.
Five thousand.
That's a lot of dollars.
Drop your belt.
You don't stand a chance
against me, Rem.
You know that.
Unless, of course,
you already got
a gun on me.
What makes you
think I don't?
Oh, I know about
gents like you.
Always give a man
a full chance.
(CHUCKLES)
Even a man like me.
Don't do it.
(GUNSHOT)
(PORCH CREAKING)
(SOFT FOOTSTEPS)
(FOOTSTEPS GETTING LOUDER)
(COINS RATTLING)
That your money?
Should it be?
Well, I guess I'll have
to check the bank,
See if there have
been any big
withdrawals lately.
Billy made a mistake.
He drew, but he
wasn't fast enough.
Well, since you say
this isn't yours, and Billy
had no relatives,
We'll try to use it
to make sure
We don't raise any more
Billy Deals in this town.
I don't like you,
Rankin. I never have.
I don't like what you
and this saloon stand for.
You going somewhere?
Yeah. Somewhere.
You went to see
Rem, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Did you think
for one minute
that I wouldn't?
No, I guess not.
Did you tell him about us?
No.
And he still
wouldn't have you?
Do you blame him?
Yes, I blame him.
He knew all along
what you were.
What am I, Matt?
Just what am I?
A woman.
A full woman that's
had to make her way
the best she could,
Right from the ground up.
And doing it got
a little dirt on her.
You're not all Sunday
school and lace, but
that's not your fault.
Isn't it?
Look, Jan...
It's no good, Matt.
I can lie inside
about a lot of things.
Even leaving Rem
like we did.
But us, I can't even
explain it to myself.
How can I
explain it to him?
So you're going to run.
As far as I can.
Then you go right ahead.
I never forced you
to stay here with me.
I never will.
But let me tell
you this, Jan.
If you walk through this door,
You'll have to walk right back
through another just like it.
If it isn't this saloon,
it'll be another one.
And if it isn't me,
it'll be another just like me.
You may get away living with
the high-minded for a while,
But you'll be back.
Think about that, Jan.
Think about it real good.
Mr. Anderson?
Coffee?
Yeah, I don't mind.
Thanks.
I, uh, sure am sorry
about this, us having to
lock you up and all.
Here you go, doing
Billy Deal like you did,
And us treating you
like a common outlaw.
Truth is, we've been trying
to get rid of Billy Deal
ever since I can remember.
Same goes for Rankin
and his crowd.
I ain't at all narrow
thinking, Mr. Anderson,
But some of the things
that goes on up
in that saloon
Make a man blush all over.
You wouldn't believe this,
But there was a time
when Gunther Wells was as
peaceful and quiet as Sunday,
Every day in the week.
Then this Rankin
comes along.
Next thing you know,
folks start drinking,
Playing cards,
fighting,
Cahootin' all over
the doggone place.
Saturday nights,
He used to send a whole
wagonload of them gals
from Indian Springs.
It was worth
a man's life to walk by
them swinging doors.
I been after the sheriff
to close the place up.
He claims there's no law
that says a man can't
run a drinking hall.
Maybe he's right.
Where is the sheriff now?
Seeing to it
that Billy's put
under proper.
Reverend Black
will probably read
words over him.
Few holies ain't
going to help Billy
too awful much, though.
More coffee?
No, thanks.
Lee.
Huh?
Oh.
Leave it open, Lee.
I thought that preacher
would never get
through talking.
Anderson?
Yeah?
You drew in self-defense.
I can't hold you.
Thanks.
There are things
that sure keep
bothering me, though.
That so?
You ride into town,
and you find
a missing horse.
Then all of a sudden,
Billy Deal comes along
and draws on you.
Why?
I wouldn't know.
Wouldn't you?
Can I go now?
Door's open.
Young fellow.
Yeah?
Keeping the law
in this town is
my business.
I intend to do it,
no matter what.
Meaning?
Meaning that gunning
a man like Billy Deal in
self-defense is one thing.
Plain killing is
altogether something else.
I'll remember that.
You'd better had.
I'd hate to have
to hang you.
(HORSES APPROACHING)
I brought the horses.
They're out back.
Good.
Where's Jan?
I don't know.
You don't know?
That's what I said.
You mean, she's not
going with us?
That's what I mean.
I thought you two
were straightened out.
Yeah, so did I.
(HORSES WHINNYING)
I'm going with you.
You don't have to run.
He won't hurt you.
I don't think anyone
could ever hurt me again.
Coffee?
You thinking about Rem?
Leave me alone.
We get to Sonora,
I'll make you forget
all about him again.
May take time
and money, but...
I said, leave me alone.
It's no use
getting upset.
You could have stayed
behind, and Rem, he might
have even taken you back.
Would he?
What difference
would it make?
You weren't cut out
to be a ranch woman.
It ain't a fit life.
(SCOFFS)
This is, I suppose?
It's all in how
you look at it.
Take Farley, there.
He hadn't met me,
he'd probably
gone through life
Honest, upstanding
and poor.
By this time,
he'd have more
than likely
Worked himself
to death for
somebody else.
And they'd have to
take up a collection
to bury him.
Same goes
for Rem, too.
But you and me,
we like nice times.
Like back there,
we had everything.
Money, clothes,
each other.
There was a while
back there, I thought
you'd forgotten
All those crazy
ideas about settling
down respectable.
Yeah.
So did I.
That's what I like
about us, Jan. We want
something, we take it.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
Listen.
Rem, look out!
(GUNSHOT)
(GUNSHOTS)
RANKIN: I got him, Farley!
Rem.
Hold me.
Rankin do this to you?
Rem,
Whatever you think of me,
You were the one.
Only one.
We would have
been respectable,
wouldn't we, Rem?
Sure.
Sure, you bet we would.
(SOBS) Rem.
(GROANS)
Sheriff!
Sheriff! Sheriff.
What are you doing
up this early?
They've gone,
Rankin and the others.
Pulled out
during the night.
What about Anderson?
He's gone, too.
Jake the bartender
says he thinks they
headed for Sonora town.
They'll never
get there.
They got a good
head start on us.
When that sun goes high,
it'll sure slow 'em down.
Come on.
Hey, Sheriff.
Yeah, I know.
They swung south here.
Now I know where
they're headed.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
They cut off here.
It looks like.
Well, guess we better
find us some shade.
Shade?
I'd uncinch
my animal if I was you.
Give him a breather.
Sheriff.
Ain't we going
after them?
There's no hurry.
Beats me.
Fellow tries to
do a good job.
Got you traipsing all over
the doggone countryside.
They're all up there
in that canyon, and you
can't get them out.
Next thing he'll wanna
do is want me to go
fishing with him.
(MUTTERING)
Sit down, Lee.
Get out of the sun.
Sheriff, why...
Lee.
That bass at
Higgins Crossing.
Didn't catch him,
did you?
My boy doesn't
like fish either.
Come tomorrow,
what say we both
take a crack at him?
Look, Sheriff,
Us just sitting here,
ain't they getting away?
Nope.
You know,
I hunted all through
this country.
Know the ground.
Look, that there's
a box canyon
they rode into.
It's about a mile
deep and wide.
It's got walls so steep,
a bird has all he can do
to get out of it.
Meaning they'll have
to come out the same
way they went in.
One of them will.
(GUNSHOT)
Get up.
Wait a minute, Rem.
Sheriff?
Yeah, Lee?
You didn't mean it
when you said
You were going to
do that Anderson fellow
that way, did you?
Didn't I?
Don't seem at all
right to me.
Nice fellow like that.
Probably he had
a reason for all this.
Probably.
But there ain't no reason
for killing, Lee.
Well, I don't
guess there is.
I'd sure hate to
have to hang that boy.
He dead?
Partly.
What am I supposed
to do with him?
That's up to you, Sheriff.
He killed my woman.
And you
brought him in.
Why?
I kind of figured you
meant what you said
about plain killing.
You did right, Rem.
Finally.
Take good care of him.
I will.
He's going to
be all right.
He'll make
a good citizen.
Wish he was
in our town.
Yeah.
Yeah, so do I.