Hi!
Listen, I have few certain passions
another is playing "foot-flagon"
and another is...
Is it ok?
-Of course.
Thank you.
How much is it?
Nothing at all.
Dinner card covers it all.
Unhanged Ones
"For money I'll do anything."
"Closed during renovation."
Gonzales, look!
"Office open"
It's 10% for me.
5%!
How much?
Thank you.
-Buy some paper and paint with it.
"Wanted Speedy Gonzales
-Alive in the town of Three Coins"
Is this you?
Well, what do you think?
I am the Lonely Rider.
Lonely? Don't you use deodorant?
"self service"
I am Tonto, assistento.
It's your turn now.
It says alive.
They won't pay for a corpse.
I can't see!
Look!
We did it.
I did it.
Let's pick up the guns.
Here it is.
With this fist I knocked out Gonzales.
Or was it so?
-I guess so, can't remember.
Gonzales must be pissed off now.
Are you?
You won't be smiling anymore
when they hang you, Gonzales.
We love horses and women!
Never shall we abandon them!
Everything goes just well...
Tonto doesn't suspect anything.
And when we get to the town
I'll kill him and take all the money.
You're in good mood.
-You're right.
Great...
When we get there
I'll chop his head with an axe
And I take all the money.
What a pair of idiots.
They do all the work and I'll get the reward.
I need to say something friendly
to Tonto so he won't suspect me.
It's a beautiful weather.
Really fine.
He won't suspect me if I'm friendly to him.
I think... oh, it's dazzling.
I'll take a little nightmare after a hard day.
Mom, give me my mask!
Boys are teasing me!
Boys are teasing me again!
Why I have a nose like this?
Tonto, you remembered. Thank you!
Oh, wait a moment.
Here you are.
Oh my.
Good morning.
Would you like some bread mr Gonzales?
Surely you would like!
For me? This is too much.
A soft packet too. I'm getting excited.
A party mask.
Polarized.
What's this?
Winter mask.
Thank you very much.
Let's go then.
Put out the fire, will you.
Oh...
You just poured our drinking water there, boy.
And we only have 400 miles to travel.
Damn indian!
If we die of thirst, I kill you!
I wouldn't shout like that.
This is Indian territory.
What?
You shut up! I know where the ind...
But now there's a bit inside.
Don't worry. No-one will see it.
I just figured out something.
What is it?
I don't remember it anymore.
-It doesn't matter then.
You have some junk on your back.
Take it off then, please.
Thanks.
Where's the rope?
Can you tie me up again?
I won't tie you anymore.
Do it yourself!
Yeah, do it yourself!
Do you think we have time
to serve you all the time?
Well, I won't do it myself.
Won't you?
-No.
Tying is one thing you can't
expect a prisoner to do.
I got it.
We will sell you a part of you.
What?
Look, we'll get 10.000$ when we
get him to town for hanging.
And if you promise you won't
escape, we will give you 50$.
100$.
Let's make it 75$.
It's a deal. I won't escape.
But I'll be your guest with full
upkeep for the rest of the journey.
Yes.
-Water!
What?
-Water! I'm thirsty.
Tonto, you never went to school
so I want to tell you...
Look, this here is moraine.
And here's sand and below that comes the silt.
Then it's clay. Can you tell
me what comes after that?
You don't know?
Groundwater.
I'm thirsty.
And guess why?
Because I poured all our water to ground.
Right. It must be that.
Tonto!
Do you see what I see?
-No.
You see me and I see you.
No, no. There!
I use my indian gaze.
-Right!
Well, what do you see?
Two men.
-What else?
Water!
-I thought so.
Right...
We'll take this water.
It's 3 against 2.
There's only 2 of you.
You're not gonna...
-Well, what do you think?
I'm a guest with full upkeep.
Go and get me some water!
Ok then...
We'll do this nice and easy
without any bloodshed.
Tonto, go there with white flag
and give them this.
What is it?
It's my business card.
It says "Lonely Rider, professional killer".
When they read it they will
surrender immediately.
That doesn't look like a white flag
to me. Or what do you think?
I think it's black.
They demand a real white flag.
Hey, come on guys!
This used to be white.
It's just little bit dirty now.
Tell him to wash it.
Wash it!
We have no water.
-Come and get it!
Excuse me.
Soap.
Let's try it.
It's a pretty good now.
We accept it!
Accepted!
I'm Tonto, a messenger.
Read this.
You read the name?
-Yep.
Surrender then!
It's all clear.
They surrender now!
I told you.
Let's go, Silver!
Drop your guns!
I got one and my friend has one.
There's 2 of them.
You read my card. I'm Lonely Rider.
Hands up!
Your pr-man already gave us your ad.
I don't think we have a choice.
On your back!
And now we'll drink.
No!
What are you doing?
Fourteen.
We have already traveled 2 weeks now.
You don't have any water
to lend, do you?
I suddenly became so thirsty.
Really, I pay you back.
Hey ho, Silver!
So fast pace.
Shut up!
I gotta go...
-Again?
I knew it!
Petroleum!
I can still taste the difference.
How can you drink that?
We indians like firewater.
Tonto, I'm changing the subject but...
I can't deny it. Trips like this are
kinda interesting and broadening.
Of course, these aren't anything
compared to those package trips.
The possibilities to board and
wash are pretty weak for example.
But here. If you just let things come to you-
you can learn much about nature.
For example, we have seen so much...
All kinds of great things.
To name few...
I could mention among other things...
That...
Which should I pick first of all those...
Well, sand dunes, for example.
They've made great impression on me.
And the most important thing is
that you meet lots of new people.
Yep, that's correct. Very soon we
might meet many new people.
What?
Well, I have certain feeling.
And I've seen few of them too.
Do you mean those with red
faces and feather up here?
Right, good description.
Tonto!
What?
Let's delude them. First some
merry singing and then...
Two little elephants were
marching on the sunny road...
Well, and you're just sleeping.
Everything went fine.
They all ran away.
You just take it easy, boy. We keep
you alive till we get the money.
Damned. It's gone.
Here's wagon trail.
Let's follow it.
Damned. Do you know what I expect?
-No.
-The worst. Read it.
Where are you?
-In the end.
Translate it!
Thanks for the horse.
I must confess something.
-What?
I don't get bored with you guys.
-Oh.
That was too much!
You gonna walk. You walk!
No, I won't.
-You walk or I'll shoot you.
You won't shoot me. It's no use.
What do you mean?
To me it's all the same if I die
here or in the gallows-
-but to you it's not.
You'll get 10.000$ if you bring me there.
Well, how much do you want for walking?
Let's say 2 cents per step.
Do you mean length of the step or price?
Both. Step of 2 centimeter costs 2 cents.
You won't rip us off.
What a lively dream.
I could hear the purling water.
Let's go!
Damn truant!
This was the last drop!
Last drop here too.
Who the hell drank my water?
Water! What water?
Goddammit! Confess!
I mean my petroleum.
What water? Water!
Tell me truth!
You need to press button here to
get water instead of petroleum.
Tonto.
Forgive me for being so pedantic
because of that water-
-but you're making it up now.
Faster!
What now? You don't like to travel?
Or has someone told you to have a break?
Tonto can't manage anymore.
I haven't drank a single
drop of water in 2 hours.
Gosh, I can't believe it.
You haven't drunk for 2 hours?
Everyone should splash with water
at least once in every hour.
Damn coyote! I haven't drunk in 2 weeks.
Not a drop.
So far I've been just
watching as you guys drink.
But now it's gonna change.
Now I drink and you will watch.
What's this? It's a map!
And it's damn accurate.
Look! Actually Wild West is just
like land of thousand lakes.
Look, this blue here is water, isn't it?
And who can navigate will find water.
This means one with the map.
And I have one.
Sidu, said the swede.
That brown here is hill.
It might be that.
And lake is 5 miles that way.
Sidu.
Have a break.
And not much of summer camping
around the shores either.
Why don't you play some
hide and seek while I'm gone.
I'm going swimming now.
I might sip some water too.
Here it is. Very accurate map.
Lake is just behind this knoll.
I'll just take off my clothes
and then it's bath time.
Scarf.
Still...
Map was right. Looks like a low tide.
It doesn't matter. I'm not that
good swimmer anyhow.
I can practise.
It's damn good place to float.
Who has a hollow head?
His name is Tonto.
Do you have any water?
-No.
Throw it away then.
Let's take a match.
-What match?
Foot-flagon match.
-Yes, let's play.
Here's the goal line.
-Right.
You remember? It's not allowed...
-Yes. I'll start.
Go away! what are you doing?
Gonzales!
Go away!
-I wanna play.
Gonzales! Stop! Stop!
Go away! You can't play with us.
Let me play. I used to play in
commercial school's team.
Dont lie to me.
-No. Really.
But you can't play with our flagon.
If I can play foot-flagon,
I'll get sip of water for both.
Is it a deal?
Of course you can play!
-But...
Wait!
Water first, then game.
Thus it is.
-Ok.
Water!
There's a shower for both.
Sit down!
It's a mirage.
What's that?
Mirage. It's a scientific thing.
Do you know what science is?
It's like a... ray of light.
It goes like... Do you know prism?
Do you know it?
Ray of light comes downward.
And then there's solar prominence.
Sit down on your arse!
It's a mirage.
Let's look elsewhere for a moment
and it will go away. Look!
There's a bird.
Water!
I didn't get water.
Hey!
Hey, woman.
What?
-There's a woman. Look!
What's that?
Oh, is it like one with boobs?
-Yes. Look!
Hello.
How's your trip going?
If I can say so, green really
looks good on you, miss.
I'm the Lonely Ridder.
Well, how's your trip going?
I must say, this color
looks good on you.
I'm Lonely Rider.
Hello.
Gonzales.
-Margareta.
I must apologize as my
friend is in such state.
Has he been drinking?
-No, on the contrary.
Futhermore I'm very handy with the pistol...
Horses are very important to me.
When I was 3 years old my parents...
Hello there.
They put me first time on the back
of Silver. And that was the start.
Can I propose you to come with me?
Feisty girl.
My parents said I'm gonna be a brisk man.
Be quiet, I'm Tonto.
Damn. Are you trying to
come between us? What?
It's a...
It's been lovely weather.
-Yes.
You know miss...
Gonzales doesn't seem to be
much of womanizer either.
That style won't work for sure.
How did it go?
I'm the Lonely Rider.
Womanizer.
Hello dear.
You can roll it here with finger.
And again.
And other way around too.
It's a nice spur, isn't it.
-Really nice.
I can put it back and walk around.
It will make nice jingle.
Now it's good.
This man is criminal. Beat it!
Beat it, I say!
Hello.
Where are you traveling?
To Njetponimaj-stad
-Njetponimaj-stad.
It's a long journey, girl.
We came from there.
Four week travel.
No, one day walk.
-One day? What?
It's one day walk.
Right, right.
We have to transport and
take care of this prisoner...
When man is a criminal, he's a criminal.
It's so hard and takes a lot of time.
One day walk? Right.
I'm the man of straight action.
So let's move on to business.
What's your name, miss?
-Margareta.
No, I mean surname.
-Smith.
Right, in that case I propose
you to come with me-
-to the alders to cool off.
Goddammit!
You a very pretty girl.
You're good to Tonto's old eye.
You look ahead in life.
I'm a rich man.
Boy just tries there.
But we had everything settled.
how about going to the alders?
I give you many presents.
You won't get away with
this without a duel.
You.
If I don't return alive,
will you wait for me here?
I mean... well, you got the point.
10 paces, turn and shoot.
Now!
Did you say: first 10 paces and then turning?
Or was it vice versa?
Listen, it doesn't matter anymore.
Here you are.
-Thank you so much.
I got to go now, boys.
I have a violin lesson tomorrow.
There's no more water.
Hey.
Gonzales.
Life's a like circuit.
One day one man drinks and
on other day others drink.
And today the others drink.
We just go for little drink.
Lest you won't get bored in the
meantime why don't you dodge these.
Tonto.
Do you remember when
I told you about mirage?
It's a scientific thing...
-Yes, yes. I know.
But the most important thing is
that Gonzales must not know.
One, two, three.
Did you notice that guys drank water.
And it tasted like a nectar.
And then we go.
Can you move away?
You're blocking the sun.
Goddammit!
Are you sure it was "alive"?
-Yes it was.
They don't pay for dead?
-I don't know.
But if we take the chance.
Right, it was "alive" after all.
Look, what the hell I got.
I have similar.
I grabbed a girl from the throat
that way. I'm so shamed.
Actually we are very popular among women.
They have invited us to their
home for coffee many times.
What a lovely place. Let's sit there.
Yes, as it looks like we can't
find suitable alder forest-
-maybe we can camp here,
make fire and eat some lunch.
And we can arrange some show.
Let's go here.
Let's lounge here.
Sitting is another option too, of course.
Let's change places.
We already made some pairing.
Just a moment.
Oh, you don't have any water by chance?
Forget it.
Now as we have pairs we
don't have to compete.
Let's just praise each other. Yes?
And then let's arrange some show.
And after that...
Ladies. To liften up the moody atmosphere
we have decided to arrange a little show.
So, great Indian chief, Tonto. Who,
by the way, is very good friend of mine-
-will perform us his very funny
and talented rain dance number.
Tonto, please.
I must say, you indians are so
much better in sports than us white.
You have the rhythm in your blood.
Faster pace!
Thank you.
And next my lonely friend.
Sing us a song!
-No, I won't...
He's a big star.
Would you like to hear?
-Yes.
Maybe I then...
I could sing one song.
Can you give me little rhythm?
And now!
Lonely avenger, he went to avenge.
From the Rio Grande, Ohio.
And his horse was called
Papu-Rikko-Reino.
And he traveled towards
the Mexico. And there he...
And he went to back of Mexico
where came kiss, kisses...
Lyrics...
And his horse was indeed
this Papu-Rikko-Reino.
Horse with really strange pace.
And he has a woman in every port.
Indian girls were crazy about him.
Lyrics...
It didn't went as good as like once
in that place, you remember?
Yes. Yes.
Were you talking about me?
-No...
What was so funny then?
-I only told a funny story.
What story?
Well... It's not that good...
Now as we have cosy ambiance,
we could start what we agreed, Tonto.
Well, good night then.
Get up, Gonzales!
You just sleep here but we
were with girls. What a night!
We ate and drink. There was
water and dancing and singing.
But then we got lost.
You haven't seen two indian
girls around here?
Let's try again.
Hell with it!
Gonzales, get to the wagon!
We leave now.
Stop. I come a board.
No we walk...
-Except me.
Get to the wagon.
You mean you're not gonna walk?
-No.
It's your decision.
Yeah, you just sit there, mister.
But we go again.
Stop! Stop! Damned!
-What?
Allright, damned. I'll walk.
I hear as if water splashing.
Tonto, so do I.
My friend, sit down here and wait,
please. I'll go and check it.
Tonto!
-What?
You hear alright. There's water.
Come!
Could it be real?
Sounds right at least.
Reflection...
It's a beautiful phenomen.
You Tonto, as a uneducated
person don't fully understand-
-what reflection is, for examle.
I can tell you this though...
that it's caused by gravity.
Reflection...
Goddammit! I won't spoil my good thirst!
One, two, three!
To the saloon, to the saloon!
Gonzales, come for hanging.
We take the man to
gallows to be hanged.
Sheriff. We... prisno, prisoner...
Sheriff?
-Yep.
Aren't you a bartender?
Oh, you noticed?
You really noticed?
What a clever boy.
Damned! I'm also clerical officer,
pimp, vicar and the midwife.
Is it enough?
Ok, the sheriff of town of Three Coins.
-What?
Sheriff of the Town of Three Coins.
No, it's not.
This is Njetponimaj-stad.
Yes, it is. 6 weeks ago we left Njetponimaj-stad.
Now we are in town of Three Coins.
Don't talk bullshit. I oughta know.
Bloody hell...
Have we traveled in circles for 6 weeks?
What the hell it's to you?
It's our finann-cial loss.
You might think so.
I just lost 10.000 $.
What do you mean?
Those 2 are wanted with that
price in town of Three Coins
Wait a moment, sheriff.
This is all sucks...
That's just funny.
And you're wanted for 10.000$.
It makes 20.000$ in all.
Dammit! Everyone against the wall!
Listen, sheriff. I'm not wanted man.
-Really?
What's this then?
I made that poster myself.
Self-made? Really?
We go to the gallows now.
And I take the reward.
Aren't you pissed off?
Subtitles by Bastard80