tetrao: 30/05/2010
http://friendsharept.org/phpbb/portal.php
-You the railroad agent?
-l am.
l'm Sheriff McCullough.
Sure is a cold one tonight.
Anything wrong, Sheriff?
Nothing l can't handle.
lf you gentlemen are finished
with your business...
l need to get this train
out of here.
lt's up the Sheriff.
lf you think there's gonna be
trouble, we'll hang on awhie.
No need.
Friendly cuss, ain't he?
Jack, the Sheriff.
Get the bag.
Get the money bag.
Come on!
What happened, Ben?
Shilogh, come on.
He ain't got no face no more.
Pick him up.
-Pick him up and drag him...
-What for, Ben? He's dead.
Drag him to the end
of the train, let's go.
Do what l tell you Jackass.
Let's go.
Get him in there. Get in.
Get in.
What's the matter, John?
l heard a shotgun blast.
Damn fool drifters.
You're the damn fool.
Get back into bed.
Ain't gonna change the world...
if a few drunken cowboys out
having a good time.
You know the boys can raise
hell all they want to...
but not at this hour of
the morning, and not in my town.
Now, you stay right
where you're at...
my little desert flower...
because l Just ain't quite
finished with you yet.
And this shouldn't take long,
l'll be right back.
Now, ma'am, everything's
gonna be all right.
-What's going on here?
-Been a holdup, Marshall.
-Paradise payroll?
-Yep.
-Where's Sheriff McCullough?
-Over there.
Took a shotgun blast full on,
about took his head clean of.
My God, Will.
Have a couple of this boys
take him over to the undertakes.
Teel him to put Sheriff in a box
and nail the lid down.
Wouldn't do to have his wife
see him looking like this.
l'll take care of it, Marshall.
Thank you.
Marshall. Marshall.
Look here.
Look over here.
-Look here.
-Well, it looks three horses.
Does that fit?
Were there three of them?
That's all l saw.
Three drifters in the saloon
last night.
l knew they were up to no good.
Well, one of them
ain't too healthy anymore.
That lady cracked his skull
open for him real proper.
Well, good, maybe that'll slow
them down a little bit.
Looks like they went south
right out into the prairie.
Ain't no place for a man
to hide out there.
Bill, get the boys together,
get them saddled up...
-meet me in front of the Jail.
-Will do, Marshall.
All right.
Marshall, do you need to hold
the train here any longer?
You can take her on
down the tracks.
Thank you, sir.
Sure hope you catch
those three, Marshall.
Will McCullough
was a friend of mine.
You're not one of the girls
from the saloon.
Where you from? Who are you?
lf you don't mind my asking...
what are you doing out here
at this hour of the morning...
dressed like that?
l've got a lady friend
up at the saloon...
who'll look after you
until l get back.
-We'll look after her, Marshall.
-Thank you. You'll be alright.
That was a brave thing you did.
All right, boys,
let's get after them.
Well, boys, it looks like
we've been made fools of.
Where you reckon they are?
Well, my guess they're
on that damn train.
What are we gonna do now?
Well, we'll get
on the telegraph.
Ain't no place they can get off
before Rock Springs.
We'll set up a nice
warm welcome for them.
Charlie, run those horses
back to town. Let's go.
When we gonna get
to a town, Ben?
Tonight, l figure.
What'd we bring him along for?
Three men robbed a payroll,
three horses rode out of town.
-Jack's dead, Ben.
-Yeah, but they don't know that.
And it's gonna take them forever
to figure it out.
She sure did make
a mess out of him.
Well, you know what,
let's get rid of him right now.
Grab his legs.
When l say three.
One, two, three.
Well, that was
a nice thing you did, Ben.
What are you talking about?
You Just provide Christmas dinner
for a whole bunch of buzards.
Sleep in heavenly peace
Well, mister Sam.
Looks like we found us
a dead man.
Saints be praised...
looks like we found us
a rich dead man.
What we gonna do about this?
What'd you reckon
he'd be doing...
if he was standing here
looking down at me?
Yeah, you're probably right.
Still...
a merciful man doeth good
to his own soul.
lt's all right.
Tell you what,
my name is Joshua. All right.
And there'll be plenty of time
for talking...
when you're feeling
a little better.
Just calm down.
Just go on back to sleep.
There you go.
Well, mister Sam...
looks like our dead man's
gonna make it after all.
Thank you, Lord.
You remember anything?
Your name?
lt's yours.
Fell out of one of your boots.
That's a lot of money for
a dead man to be carrying around.
Last stop that train made
was Jericho...
wild little town
up in the mountains.
l'll Just call you that,
for the time being.
lf you don't mind.
Closest town to here is
a place called Silver City.
Soon as you fit to ride,
we'll head up there.
You can buy yourself
some decent clothes...
and get yourself a horse.
Here you go.
Well, least ways
it's place to start.
Here's your money.
They probably got
better food, too.
You boys sure you got
everything you need?
Yes, sir. l believe we do.
He's looking a little better now.
-Well, you all have a good day.
-Thank you, sir. Apprecite it.
Would hurry up, man.
lf l had any help from you,
l might do a little faster.
Yeah, well, the good Lord
helps those who help themselves.
Let's go get a drink.
Alright, Just a moment.
Well, what's taking you so long?
Get out of our way, boy.
Something wrong
with your hearing?
lf you ain't aiming
to get yourself killed...
you better get out of your way.
'Cause we ain't never in our lives,
stepped aside for a pole-cat.
No problem.
'Cause l always do.
Looks like he never missed
a meal in his whole life either.
You're right,
lets go get a drink.
Whiskey.
Don't want no trouble
in here, mister.
l didn't bring any in.
l'm buying you a drink.
All right.
Well, here's to you, friend.
Happy New Year, Jericho.
What does that damn fool
think he's doing?
Bringing that nigger in here?
Bartender, kick that
pile of shit outta here.
Take it easy,
it'll be all right.
Tell you what, mister,
we're not bothering you...
and we're not
looking for no trouble.
l ain't talking to you,
l'm talking to him.
But you're talking about me and
l don't like what you're saying.
-Listen...
-Take it easy, it's all right.
l can handle this
Just all by myself.
Appears you need
to be taught your place, boy.
Are you sure you're
the one to teach me?
''Who ever shall smite thee
on the right cheek...
turn to him the other also.''
Well, l'll be damned.
A Bible spouting nigger.
What does the good book say
you should do...
if l smite your other cheek?
lt's okay.
The Lord had the good sense
to leave that up to me.
Not you, mister.
You're gonna wish
you hadn't done that.
lt's my turn now, boy.
l'm gonna whoop you good.
All right, you've had your fun,
now it's my turn.
-Go get your gun.
-l ain't got a gun, mister.
Somebody give him a gun.
l don't fight with guns.
-Take the gun.
-No.
l have had enough of your mouth.
Put that gun on.
No.
Gonna give you a choice, mister.
Take the gun or six-foot of rope.
Jake?
lt's not you l want, mister.
You got a name, bluebelly?
l like to know who l'm killing.
Jericho.
My name is Jericho.
Jericho?
You mean ''dead man''.
Let's get outta here, fast.
How'd you come to handle
a gun like that?
l don't know,
Just seemed right.
You don't reckon
you was a gunfighter, do you?
We shoulda Just walked away.
You can't Just walk away
from a thing like that.
Mister, you can walk away
from anything, anything at all.
We Just better move on.
What's the matter?
-What's the matter?
-Nothing.
Just trying
to remember something.
You know...
there's a lot
of lost souls out there.
Without a little help...
not many ever find themselves.
Where did you learn
how to talk like that?
Well...
when l was a slave
back in Georgia...
my master used to hire me
out to the preacher.
A good man,
always quoting from the bible.
Tried to save my soul.
Poor fella.
Well, where we going now,
preacher?
We?
l'm headed to Texas.
Texas?
Yep, plan to being there
for the spring roundup.
But we got plenty of time.
When we're done eating breakfast,
we'll head for Jericho.
Jericho? Why Jericho?
That's where
that train come from.
And if you was a passenger on it,
they'll know you there.
Suppose they don't?
Then we'll talk to the Marshall.
Sure he'll know what to do.
Shall we gather at the river?
HalleluJah!
Well, if it isn't
the wandering minstrel.
Joshua,
can you give us a hand?
''Only ask and you
shall receive.''
You ladies enJoy your baptism?
You ain't a damn bit funny,
preacher.
Yeah, l am.
When you boys stop laughing.
You can climb down from those
ponies and build us girls a fire.
Where's your man?
Gone on head. Gotta find a place
to relocate our business.
We'll build you one.
Joshua, what'cha doing
up this way?
Just a little work of the Lord.
l'd say there's a little too much
work of Lord going on in these parts.
ls that why you're all on the road?
-Yep.
-About what l figured.
-Where you two headed?
-We're headed up to Jericho.
We wore out our welcome there.
What do you plan to do?
Find some answers.
And that was a Christmas day and
he still can't remember nothing.
Joshua, this is none
of my business...
but if he really
is a friend of yours...
l wouldn't go anywhere
near Jericho...
and l'd sure stay clear
of Paradise.
What you getting at?
There's was a holdup in Jericho
the day before Christmas.
The Sheriff from Paradise
got himself killed.
What's that got to do
with my Jericho?
There's a witness,
a schoolteacher.
Well, somehow she got a hold of
a hunk of a two by four...
and went after the killer. With it
and opened up
his head real good.
Three men were involved
in the holdup...
and somehow they got on the train
and got out of town.
Two of the men were gunned
down over at Rock Springs...
the third one wasn't with them.
Hasn't been seen
or heard of at since.
The one that got away
was the killer.
The one with his head
smashed in.
l'm not going to Texas,
that's all there is to it.
Well, go anywhere you like,
as long as it ain't New Mexico.
l'm going to Jericho, Paradise,
every town within a...
You won't have to go
past Jericho.
There's a schoolteacher there
knows who you are.
But she's more at
to tell the law than you.
What do you mean?
You took place in a holdup.
Killed a lawman...
the Sheriff from Paradise.
Well, how do you know?
The madame, she was there.
You're a wanted man
with a price on your head.
You've gotta get outta here.
l'm headed for Texas.
l don't think l did it.
Well, you can be a dead man
in Jericho...
or you can ride with me.
Walk through darkness,
l don't need no light
My faith in Jesus
gonna be my guide
Ain't afraid of nothing
'cause l believe
l gotta sky full of angels
watching over me
Watch your, Johnny-O.
Come on, there,
you got them rode.
Come on! Come on!
Don't let him throw you, Johnny.
That's it.
Muy bueno.
-Got him?
-l've got him.
There you go.
Peace to you, friend.
You must be the preacher.
Heard you might be riding in.
This here's Jericho.
l'm Johnny. Johnny-O.
Pleased to make
your acquaintance.
-Where can l find Pap Dooling?
-Pap Dooling?
Chuck wagon.
Come and get it, boys!
Just right up there.
Hi.
-Howdy, Pap.
-Where you been, preacher?
Just chasing the wind.
Doing a little of the Lords work.
-Well, how you been?
-Good.
l was wondering when
you were gonna get here.
Yes, sir.
-Chasing the wind?
-Just chasing the wind.
That be why you're traveling
with a fast iron?
Jericho?
He ain't no gunfighter.
He's Just an old cowboy
looking for a little work.
Just a cowboy... ls that why
he's packing that iron?
Don't look like
no cowboy to me.
Pap, you know l don't run
with no gunfighter.
Besides, he don't hire on,
l don't hire on.
l didn't say l wasn't hiring.
Jericho, you and Josh
can go slop some grub.
Appreciate you throwing in with us,
we need all the help we can get.
Appreciate it, pal.
-Thank you.
-Obliged, partner.
Johnny-O...
these boys finish eating...
snake them on down
to the remuda.
Have Carlos pick them up
a string.
Cowboys...
Yes, yes.
Jericho, you any good
with that gun?
He ain't no gunfighter.
Sure, preacher.
-Grubs getting cold.
-We'll be there.
Keep an eye out
for bunch quitters.
lf you mean cattle,
l haven't seen any around.
Yeah. How long a time
you spent in the calvary?
-What makes you say that?
-The way you sit a horse.
Just feels natural.
Yeah. What part of the country
you hail from, son?
Here and there.
-Yankee?
-Yeah, l suppose l am.
You running
from something, son?
Everybody here's running
from something.
l Just came here to work, Pap.
That's all that counts.
Don't matter where you're from
or what you've done.
l guess l'll go find
some of those brunch...
-Bunch quitters.
Stray cattle.
Get over.
That calf don't know
where he's headed.
Probably doesn't know
where he's from either.
Maybe l'll take this one.
Yeah.
Good morning, vaqueros.
Good morning.
A few cattle won't be missed.
l can't let you take them,
they ain't mine to give.
You not wear pistol,
how you stop us?
Leave the cattle and move on.
ls he so fast
he can kill us all?
There's no need for gunplay.
The good Lord giveth
and the good Lord taketh away.
This ain't our battle,
this battle's the Lords.
Hey, pistolero!
Drop your gun belt or we'll send
the preacher to his Lord.
Easy.
Just do as he says.
What's going on, boys?
Not much, Pap. Just having
a friendly little discussion.
Friendly?
You're plopping me
a mule turd, Josh.
Good afternoon, friends.
These old boys are
about as friendly...
as a grizzly bear with an
apache arrow stuck up its ass.
What do you think, Johnny-O?
l think we got
a maJor problem here, Pap.
What with Jericho's gun
on the ground and all.
Pap, keep your hand off
that pistol...
unless you want
to get us both killed.
What the hell's the difference?
They gonna kill us, ain't they?
We might as well take
a couple of them with us.
Well, l was figuring on sending
them on without us...
-if it's all the same to you.
-That's what l'm talking about.
-Pap?
-Not now, preacher.
What is it you think, gringo?
l'll tell you what l think.
l think you have to squat
when you piss.
That was slicker than a snake
sucking eggs, Johnny-O.
Thank you, Pap.
You and these cowboys
bring the herd back on in.
-Pap, what about them?
-What about them?
You ain't gonna leave them here
for the buzzards.
You're a better man than that.
l'll send Mud and Peewee
back to bury them.
You'll get over it, preacher.
They only had two choices.
The other one was hanging.
A rustler's a rustler.
God bless you.
Pick up their horses, preacher.
You owe me one.
Yeah, l reckon l do.
40 dollars, AleJandro.
-Thank you.
-Thanks.
Joshua, 40 dollars.
Jericho, 40 dollars.
Joaquin, 40 dollars.
Johnny-O...
So, how much we gonna have
by the end of this drive?
l figured...
about 300 dollars.
-That's a pretty fair stake.
-Yeah, it is.
What are you gonna do
with yours?
Been giving a little thought
to homesteading a piece of land.
California?
No, North Texas.
Why there?
'Cause California don't border
on the indian territory...
and if a man's gonna
settle down...
there might oughta be
a woman in his plans.
So, anyone special
in your plans?
lndian girls are all special.
Her name's Calypso.
Yeah, l'm looking forward
to settling down again myself.
Again?
You boys going to town?
lt's your last chance.
Heading outta here
day after tomorrow.
No, Pap, l believe
l'm gonna save my money.
Sure you won't change
your mind?
l'm sure there's at least one
little Juanita...
Just waiting for you in town.
He takes all that money
to town with him.
Your pockets will be emptier than
a whore's hope chest come morning.
You maybe right,
but it'll be money well spent.
Now, if you do decide
to come to town...
l'll be at the saloon.
-Joshua?
-Yes, sir.
l don't know if Jericho's
a gunfighter or not...
but l know Johnny-O
is itching to find out.
So, if you go to town,
keep them separeted.
Well, l reckon
l better go to town.
-Thank you, Pap.
-Thank you.
-God bless you.
-Same to you.
l'm gonna go whiskey
pickle my bladder.
What's the matter?
l don't think l did it.
Did what?
Killed that Sheriff.
-Do you remember something?
-No, Just a feeling.
l want to go back.
Well...
after the drive,
we'll go back.
Let's go to town.
Pretty good when a preacher
says that to you.
l think mister Sam's
about to throw a shoe.
l'm gonna go on down
to the blacksmith.
l'll meet you here at the store.
All right.
Almost didn't recognize you
without your shadow.
Come on.
Bartender,
whiskey for my friend.
Johnny-O, l need to see
some more money from you.
You all right?
You're Jumpy, l scared you.
No.
Well...
if it ain't the boys
from Brown County.
Don't turn around.
They're over by the door,
there's two of them.
Gunfighters.
Who are they looking for?
Me.
l want no part of this.
You owe me.
Look at them,
lined up like ducks on a pond.
l have to say
that's real considerate.
Hey, you there...
move away from that bar.
l believe he's talking to you.
Unless you've changed your mind,
l'd say now is time to go.
All right.
You finish that drink,
go ahead and make your move.
Well, have it your way, stranger,
makes no never mind to me.
Johnny-O, you get your hands up
and turn around.
You lrish piece of shit.
You take loud mouth
and l'll get the other one.
Johnny-O, burn in hell,
you son of a bitch.
l'll see you there, old man.
You riding with me?
No.
Suit yourself. l'd be
getting out of Texas though.
We Just killed the Sheriff
from Brown County.
Come on.
Come on, we gotta get.
You may have killed that lawman
in Jericho and you may not..
but that don't matter now.
l told you l didn't know
he was a Sheriff.
What difference does that make?
There ain't a Jury on Earth
that's gonna believe you.
You a ripe candidate
for a hangman's noose...
-and we know that for certain now.
-Yes, we do.
So where do we go?
Jericho, if you're gonna
ride with me...
you take that gun off
and you keep it off.
l mean it.
You put that gun on again
and it'll be over my dead body.
-l Just wanna do right.
-And you think killing is right?
Righteousness is sewn in peace
by those who make peace..
and we won't find it
in Texas now.
Preacher man talking
about the end of time
Lord knows l'm ready
Don't worry in my mind
How come you're so happy?
'Cause there's a sky full
of angels watching over me
When are you gonna learn
how to sing?
Mister Sam
kinda likes my singing.
-He told you that, did he?
-Yeah.
When are you gonna learn
how to find gold?
-l know how to pan for gold.
-Yeah. Fools gold.
You're boots aren't wet.
Why don't you start singing
that darn song again?
You can take
all my possessions
You can take all my gold
But nobody but Jesus
gonna take my soul
No, no ''shissing''.
No ''shissing''.
You're too young for that.
Now, Just give me the gun.
That's it, Just give me the gun.
You're gonna be okay.
Okay, come on, come on.
May God have mercy.
Are you sure
there's a God out there?
You be careful now, son, okay?
You be careful.
-Good bye, ma'am
-Thank you.
-Peace to you, ma'am.
-l thank you.
lt'll be all right.
-You take care of your ma, son.
-l will, mister.
You all right?
Yeah, yeah, fine.
You, madame...
have been an absolutely
marvelous traveling partner.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
-What's the matter?
-l think he recognized me.
-You're Just Jumpy.
-l'm gonna go find out.
That's a US Marshall and you
ain't had much luck with them.
Well, l haven't had
much luck with you either.
Let me see your fist.
You didn't hit me with that...
You hit me with a rock.
You know the good Lord
didn't deliver you to me...
to see you get hung.
Yeah, He didn't deliver you...
to hit me in the head
with a rock either l don't think.
-lt wasn't a rock.
-lt felt like one.
Where'd you say
we where headed, anyway?
lndian territory.
You know, my Calypso,
she ain't gonna wait forever.
Besides, l got
enough gold right here...
l can buy her
from the chief now.
And that's where we're headed.
-lndian territory?
-Yeah, come on.
That's a good looking sign.
Joshua...
come to eat.
Joshua and Jericho.
Nope, it's Jericho and Joshua.
Well, don't Joshua come first?
Listen, you made me
the ranch foreman...
l'm supposed to make
these important decisions.
Don't l own this place?
That's why you made me
ranch foreman.
Well, Joshua comes
before Jericho.
Not in the alphabet
l'm used to using.
You what?
Joshua?
Come here.
Well, we can
finish that tomorrow.
Nope, l gonna finish this Job
then l'm headed into town.
Sorry, Calypso, but l'm gonna have
to miss your good cooking tonight.
-Heading in to town?
-Yep, got things to do.
When you gonna get yourself
a real woman?
The marrying kind?
Don't know.
Well, why don't you Just
come on down to eat a bite...
before you go on in to town?
No, l'll see you later.
l'll be back tomorrow.
All right.
Good night.
Come on eat a bite with us.
How about it?
Save some leftovers.
Might be some.
Mary?
l'm sorry.
l got a sky full of angels
watching over me
Let's go.
Joshua? Joshua?
Joshua?
Why?
'Cause he killed
a white man, that's why.
Mister, there's three of us.
Just who the hell
you think you are?
l don't know.
''l will fear no evil...
Thou art with me...
Thy rod and Thy staff
they comfort me.''
Peace, friend.
-Jericho?
-Yeah?
Where will you go?
New Mexico.
They'll hang you there.
At least l'll know
who they're hanging.
You gonna stay?
l'm gonna go back
to my people.
l want you to take the mustang.
Mister Sam's days
are numbered.
Want a whiskey?
You got a place
where l can keep my horse?
Livery stable.
Cost you two dollars.
You rub him down with a gunnysack
and give him some oats.
Horse out front?
You gonna want a bed?
-Yeah.
-Top of the stairs, room 2.
You won't need a key,
locks don't work.
You're too late, mister.
Too late for what?
There won't be another train
until the end of the week.
How do l get to Paradise?
Take the west road out of town.
But it's a good days ride.
They're Just a bunch
of drunk men.
No way. Shoot!
Well, whatta we got here?
Ya'll suppose it's Santa Claus?
Santa? How about you haul your
rosy ass cheek on outta my way...
before l put a bullet
through you.
Well, how about it,
Santa Claus?
Son, you've got a big mouth
and it shall be your undoing.
Merry Christmas.
Hold it right there, mister.
All right, folks, on your way.
You've all got better things to do.
l'd say you were
pretty lucky, Luke.
You better go over to the Docs
office and have that hand seen to.
This ought to cover it.
Do l know you?
You all right?
Look, it's Christmas eve,
so l'm not going to hold you...
if l can have your word
you'll leave the town.
l'll show you to your horse.
You look awfully young
to be a Sheriff.
Just a deputy. My father
used to be Sheriff here though.
Maybe you heard of him,
Will McCullough.
So, what's your father
doing now?
He was killed
in a holdup over in Jericho.
Did they catch his killer?
No.
Any witnesses?
Yeah, a woman.
She's our school teacher now.
Folks hired her in a way of saying
thanks for what she did.
You gonna be all right?
l'll be fine, son.
Came as quick as l could, Will.
That him?
Yeah, strange man.
l swear l've met him before.
-Where's he heading?
-He didn't say.
Well, don't matter.
As long as he's gone.
Ma says l was supposed to make
sure you'd be on time for super.
l hadn't missed one of your ma's
Christmas dinner in yers.
She knows that, now get.
-Who is it?
-Open the door.
What do you want?
Who are you?
My God.
You know me.
l've never seen you before
in my life.
No, no.
Why don't you take another look?
Take a good long look.
Seven years ago today.
You remember?
Remember?
Who am l?
Tell me who l am.
You're Sheriff McCullough.
-So, when are you coming back, pa?
-Day after tomorrow.
l should be arriving about
the same time as Saint Nichols.
Well, suppose the baby
comes by then.
Don't worry, the Doc says
you're not due for another week.
Besides, Tom will be here
to look after you until l get back.
Baby, what does Tom know
about delivering a baby?
Probably more than l do.
Sure wish l cold ride
with you tomorrow, pa.
Well, not this time, son.
We're gonna need a man
around the house...
to look after your mother
until l get back.
lt's a big Job, you probably need
a lot of sleep for it too.
-Good night, pa.
-Good night.
-Good night, ma.
-Sleep tight.
She sure can kick.
So, what makes you so sure
that it's a girl?
Well, l Just know.
Well, in that case, l better shop
for a doll before l start home.
Why don't you get Tom to take
that prisoner into Jericho?
No, the bank wants me to pick up
the payroll for the mines...
and l want to pick up
that reward money...
so this year you and Will...
and whoever this is
can have a real Christmas.
You Just keep that candle burning
until l get back.
Here's that letter
so you can pick up the payroll.
Thanks, Tom.
l suppose l'll need that.
-Good think.
-Yes, sir.
-Keep will out of trouble.
-He'll be fine.
-You ain't gonna get me there.
-Shut up, Dorland.
Tom, look after Mary
until l get back.
You know l will.
You ain't gonna keep me
in here.
Now, whatta you think
you're gonna do, Dorland?
Your gonna gnaw
your way out of here...
like the little rat that you are?
Sit down.
Will, there's your
reward money.
Thank you, Marshall.
Now, Will, l wouldn't be
flashing it around so much.
This town's still pretty
wide open.
l know, Jericho's
got a reputation.
No, not for long. City council
passed some new laws.
January we're gonna have
to run out the gamblers...
then we're gonna have
to run out the hookers.
Then, they're gonna have
to run you out.
Yeah.
You know, folks in Paradise
don't seem to mind that too much.
Well, you built
a real nice town...
for the good folks
over there, Will.
Built a good reputation
for yourself in the doing.
l Just for the life of me
can't understand...
how you can enJoy being
the Sheriff in such a quiet town.
You take care
of yourself, Marshall.
l always take care
of myself, Will.
Merry Christmas.
Happy New Year.
You be careful.
How are you doing tonight?
What'll it be?
l'll take a room for the night,
bedding for a couple of hoses.
Number two, top of the stairs.
You won't need a key and all told.
Four dollars.
This should cover it.
-A hundred? Smallest you got?
-Yeah.
Tell you what, cook me up one
of those nice Juicy steaks.
Run it by the fire on the way
to my table, okay?
What about the change?
You can bring that
to the table, too.
Jack, some yokel Just paid for his
room with a hundred-dollar bill.
A hundred-dollar bi...
lt was the smallest
bill he had.
He'll be down
in a few minutes for dinner.
You ready to go to work,
Millie?
-What do you want me to do?
-Whatever it takes.
lf he likes to gamble,
you bring him to me.
lf he likes to drink,
get him drunk.
lf he's a lover...
Jack, you don't really
want me to...
Millie, Just this once, baby.
For us.
Whatever it takes, do it.
May l sit down?
You look like the only
gentleman in the room.
My name is Mildred Flynn.
Check his room.
Shilogh, keep me company.
l'm pleased to meet you.
My name's Will McCullough.
-You from around here, Will?
-No ma'am, from Paradise.
Paradise? Now, that's a nice name.
Sounds rather heavenly.
lt is.
Well, sort of.
May l buy you a drink?
lt's almost Christmas and l
would love to toast the season..
with a nice gentleman like you.
Champagne, please.
Look, l have to say...
that l really appreciate your
hospitality, miss Flynn, but..
Thank you.
Call me Millie.
Millie.
So, where you from, Millie?
l'm from Texas.
But l'm going to San Francisco.
l'm a school teacher.
You know you should really stop
by Paradise on your way.
And why's that?
Well, we Just built
a new schoolhouse.
They're gonna be looking
for a teacher.
That's mighty nice of you to offer.
l might have to takeup on that.
We hit the Jackpot.
That yokel's the Sheriff
from Paradise...
and he's here
to pick up a payroll.
Well, it's been
a pleasure, Millie.
Do you really have to go?
We were Just getting
to know each other.
Well, l have to meet a train
tomorrow at 5 AM...
and it's a day Journey back
to Paradise. So, good night.
-Good night.
-Thank you.
My pleasure.
What happened?
Nothing.
Did he tell you anything?
Not really. Only that he's from
a small town called Paradise...
and he's meeting the train
at 5 AM in the morning.
No...
he isn't.
l am.
Give him a couple of hours.
And then l want you to go up
to his room, get his clothes..
his badge and his gun,
set outside in the hallway.
Then l want you
to keep him busy while l...
or rather, while the Sheriff
meets the train.
Jack, if you really
loved me you wouldn't...
lt's because l love you, baby.
With this money l could give you
everything you ever dreamed of.
This our big chance,
yours and mine.
Please, do it for us.
Go on, now.
Now, l'm gonna fix
a bottle of champagne...
that'll put him
to sleep forever.
What about Millie?
She might drink some of it.
Now, wouldn't that be
Just too bad.
Will, l brought champagne.
Who are you?
Why did you wait until now
to come after me?
That's a long story.
Your son's
the Deputy Sheriff now.
They say he's Just like
you used to be.
Have you seen your wife?
You have a daughter,
did you know?
She turns seven tomorrow.
She's born in Christmas day.
The day after you were killed.
Sheriff?
What about me?
Merry Christmas.
Tom, lets sing Silent Night.
Silent night, holy night!
All is calm, all is bright
Round yon virgin mother
and child
Holy infant so tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly peace!