This is that part of Afghanistan
where the people...
...comprise of 2 tribes that
are bitterest of enemies.
Like every year; today, the tribes
are meeting for a local sport.
lt may be considered a sport, but
it's no less than a brutal war!
The tribe who lifts the goat, and
takes it to a certain point, wins.
Every rider, in an effort to win
strikes the foe so horribly...
...as though it's a question of
life and death, and not a game!
Victory is ours, Badshah Khan.
What have you done? Turned
a victory into a defeat!
l'm struck by lightning.
l've not lost a contest,
but my life itself!
You've always solved my problems.
Solve this one too.
How do l win her?
- There's only one way to win her.
- What's that? - Death!
Your actions make me mad, and...
...and surprise me too!
This madness of yours...
...could prove to be a
lesson to both the tribes.
My war's with beauty,
not the tribe, Benazir.
His tongue wags too much!
lt must be cut off.
Before you do that, l'll cut your
sword in so many pieces...
...that you'll spend your
lifetime, in gathering them all.
An answer to an ignorant is silence!
You call me an ignoramus?
Benazir, l'll marry you.
- That's impossible!
- l'll make the impossible, possible.
- For this you'll have to sieve
grains of sand in lndia. - Fine.
- What madness! - You'll have to
bring the head of my father's killer.
- l'll get it for you.
- Careful now. - ln this test...
- ...you may lose your life.
- l've already lost that to you.
lf you do that, then...
l'll be yours.
Benazir... you are already mine!
May Lord fulfill your wish.
Son, your friend is going faraway,
and you're keeping silent?
Stop him, else he'll die
in trying to search that killer.
Nothing new in it. What
kind of love is it...
...which isn't sacrificed
for love? And which moth...
...doesn't kill himself on
a flame? Am l right or not?
Come on, my dear friend...
l'm going so far away, and
you get cross with me?
Do you take me to be
a statue of stone?
You're inviting death, and you
ask your friend to embrace you?
Dear friend, the heavens
decide about life and death.
Don't think so seriously. lf you
do that, it weakens the decisions.
lndia is a huge country.
Your destination is miles away.
Look through my eyes. There
stands my destination.
At the feet of Benazir.
Khan, take a good look at
the killer's photograph.
Don't bring an ass's head,
in a hurry to win Benazir!
- You swine!
- Keep quiet!
lf l wanted to present an
ass's head to Benazir...
...l'd have cut your head off
a long time ago!
- l don't think you'll return!
- lf God...
...wills light, then lamps
burn even in storms!
- l beg your leave, my beloved.
- May God keep you, Khan.
- Just a question of a smile.
- lt'll be difficult.
Ease that difficulty
for me then.
l won't go without it.
Just one smile.
Broader...
A bit more broader...
Slightly more now...
Wonderful, dear friend.
Sacrifice!
Symbol of love!
ln the name of beauty!
Whenever you look at this
flag, you'll touch me.
Whenever it flutters, you'll hear
my heart beating in yours.
Whenever your delicate hands
touch this flag...
...their fragrance
will reach my soul.
Goodbye, Benazir.
Goodbye, dear friend.
Goodbye, Kabul!
Goodbye... Goodbye...
O land of lndia,...
Greetings to you.
My name's Badshah Khan.
Love is my faith...
Love is my religion.
Love! for which Farhad...
...cut open the mountains, and
got milk to flow from them!
Love! for which Majnu searched
every grain of sand in a storm.
For that very love,
this Pathan from Kabul...
...has come to this soil of
lndia to acquire that love.
lt's a trying test.
A difficult test. But
the confidence is strong!
Love her always been victorious.
lt's been so for centuries.
And it'll always be so too!
God is witness.
For one whole year,
in search of Habibulla...
...Badshah Khan left no
stone unturned in lndia...
But he was unsuccessful.
Forget him, Benazir. Nobody
returns from the jaws of death!
He won't find Habibullah.
And even if he does...
...Habib's brother, will chop
your Khan to pieces. Forget him!
He has let you down!
Why did you do that?
You've fanned a dormant fire.
l had come with the intention
of proposing to you.
Now l'll put my seal
to that intention.
l sent the swine to hell!
lt's a whole year now.
There's no news about Badshah.
He will come, won't he?
He's gone like a storm, he'll
return as one! And when he does...
...l'll not call you Benazir...
but ''sister-in-law'' !
- May God keep you, Badshah.
- Same to you, dear boy.
- How do you know my name?
- Mummy says, a customer is a guest.
And every guest should be served
like a '' Badshah'', a king!
That's a noble thought. Your
mother guides you well.
- Greetings brother. - Greetings.
- Badshah, this is my mother.
- My respects. - You called me
''brother'', l'm very glad.
By God! l'm really happy.
l don't have a sister, that's why.
l also don't have a brother. May
God bless this relation. Come in.
Greetings, Habibullah Khan.
Forgive me. l took
you for somebody else.
Sorry. l thought you
were somebody else.
Why have you come here?
- To meet my son.
- l won't let you, in this state.
My son is sleeping with such
a dream in his eyes...
...in which you are an honest,
righteous person. l won't...
...let you spoil
that dream of his!
l'll die, but l won't let your
evil shadow fall on my son!
- He'll live like a human, not
an animal like you! - Animal?
You call me an animal?
Shame on you, you devil!
You strike a woman?
Who's he? Your lover-boy?
You swine! You call
a brother, a lover?
A lover?
You call him a lover?
You lifted your hand at me?
An officer?
- l'll have you arrested in 2 days.
- How can you do that to a good man?
Now get lost. Go on... Out!
Better go, else l'll debone you!
- l'll show you!
- What will you show me?
Go, sister. Go.
He won't come here again.
Pray to the Lord and sleep.
No noose on earth
can reach my neck...
...while my brother is living.
He'll take me out of this cage.
His name is Pasha.
My God! This area is as terrible...
...as the man who owns it! The
name too is apt. '' Burial ground''.
This is the pigeon who challenged
me and held his head high!
He looked in my eyes!
l was betrayed! Betrayed.
- But l didn't do any treachery.
- My brother's in your jail.
Did you allow him to escape?
No! Well, that's betrayal!
The rest is all fine.
What's fine, Pasha? You men
are piling earth on me.
l tried my best to help him escape
but the jailer kept a tight security.
- l want my brother! - l'll sneak in
4 of your men in the police guard.
l'll steal the uniforms, and you
shoot down the jailer from afar.
- That'll be fun.
- Your brother will then escape.
Take him out.
Don't defy fate.
Forget Habibullah...
- ...and go back home.
- My dear sister...
A spent arrow, a falling star...
...and a spoken word, never return.
Habibullah's found. See this.
He's jailed here.
Dear child, you brought
Habibullah to me.
You've obliged me greatly.
And l'll never forget it. Never!
- Who are you?
- l'm Badshah Khan, from Kabul.
- What do you want? - Habib's
head! - This is a Br. Jail.
Not a cage in Kabul to hand
over a fowl or a goat to you!
You son of a gun! Why do
you talk nonsense?
l'm a Pathan. l'm not used
to being talked to impudently!
l'm a Rajput too, Khan.
l'm also not used to it!
Rajputs are courageous men too.
Then talk like a Rajput.
- Bring that useless being out.
l want his head. - He's not a goat...
...for you to carry him away
on the tip of your sword from here!
Every convict is my responsibility,
who either serves his term fully...
- ...or dies! - Before he became
a wanted man in your country...
...he's wanted in mine! My nation
and this sword will, punish him!
Khan, Habibullah has already
got his punishment.
Tomorrow, he'll be hanged
before dawn, in public...
...in the village square.
Then; by God's Holy
word, O Rajput Khan...
...either this Pathan will take
him back, or the sun will not rise!
Wonderful! How you defeated
Death, by saving me!
My brother will reward you of course
but l too will reward you. Shake!
You goon! Life wishes to
shake hands with death!
- Death? Death is miles behind us.
- lt's in front of you too, rascal.
- What do you mean by that?
- Justice!
- What justice? - By stabbing
Benazir's father in the back...
...you brought enmity in the two
tribes. l'm hoping to change that.
By severing your head!
Don't worry, Habib.
Don't you worry.
Why do you wish to kill my brother?
Pasha, l think he too
is Benazir's lover-boy.
He wants to kill me and win her.
Shoot him! Kill him!
Shut up! Kill him, indeed!
Put your rifles down.
This Pathan is our friend.
One of us.
- Who are you, Pathan?
- Who are you?
At your service, Pathan!
And name? A small one. Pasha.
But l do very dangerous deeds.
- Hey you! This is my prey.
- Forget him! Else...
- Else what? - Else, not one...
...but 2 heads will be severed.
Better worry about your own head.
Better show your back and go.
Else your head will fly to Kabul!
Damn you!
Not his, my head.
You talked too much, eh?
Why don't you speak now?
Go on, talk.
Talk!
Thank you very much.
You saved my life.
l'll be obliged to you.
Okay then. Goodbye.
- What's this?
- Handcuffs. To arrest you.
Oh God! You save my life,
and you'll handcuff me too?
l saved you, as a fellow being.
But it's my duty to arrest you.
- What duty? - ln the eyes of our
law, you've committed a crime.
What law?
Your law was to hang him.
He was to die anyway.
- You didn't kill him, l did.
We're quits. - That's your crime.
Rajput Khan, l'll take
his body to Kabul.
Nobody can stop me. Nobody!
A Rajput stands before you.
He too knows how to bid.
- Sorry l can't permit you to go.
- l didn't ask you permission.
- l just told you my decision.
- Then l too have spoken of my duty.
lt's better if our
principles don't clash.
Because of this traitor, our 2
clans have become bitter enemies.
He's a murderer. He killed
Benazir's father...
- ...and sowed seeds of enmity
in our tribes. - Who's Benazir?
She... who has become a
part of Badshah's heart.
lf l take this corpse to her,
she'll accept me.
- That was her promise.
- No, Badshah. No.
- My duty forbids you from
doing this. - Look Rajput Khan...
Try to understand me.
lf l go back, our 2 clans
will come together again.
There'll be peace. Hatred
will turn into friendship.
l'll be able to wed Benazir.
Look, Rajput Khan.
l give you my word.
Let me go now. l'll come back
to you within 30 days.
You can do your duty then.
This is a word of a Pathan.
A Pathan.
Okay. You may go, Badshah.
Go for now. But, remember...
A Rajput has trusted a Pathan.
30 days from today,
we'll meet again.
Long live Badshah Khan.
Sister-in-law!
Dear Lord! You called
me sister-in-law?
Yes. He has come back.
Badshah Khan is here.
ln this very place;
ln this very earth...
...hadn't Badshah Khan spilt
my brother's blood?
Remember this spot.
Never forget it.
l too shall spill that bastard's
blood in this very earth!
This line is the border line
of Badshah Khan's life.
He shall repay my brother's
life with his own!
Everything else is fine.
Badshah, if you don't keep
your word just once...
...what difference will it make?
Benazir... How can
you say that, love?
Being a tiger's cub,
you talk so cowardly?
You know very well that
l'm not a coward.
But, what can l do?
l'm so very scared.
That this separation may not drive
me mad! How do l convince my heart?
Control it. Convince it. There's
something beyond the heart too.
One who can betray his own word,
can betray anyone.
Even God, or you too.
Treachery is a crime, sweetheart.
l don't mind this crime.
For your Benazir,
commit this crime too.
For you l can commit 100 crimes,
but then, l won't remain myself.
l'll die of shame.
That courageous Rajput,
trusted this Pathan's word.
And l should break my own word?
Take this dagger, and thrust it
in this ungrateful being's heart.
For God's sake!
Don't say such things.
Badshah Khan, we're quits now.
Jailer, Ranvir Singh. The Sun
will set in 5 minutes.
And with it will set, the time
limit of 30 days you gave.
ln the eyes of the law,
you too will be a criminal.
There's still a distance of 5 mins.
between the truth and a lie.
How can 5 minutes bridge a gap,
that wasn't bridged in 30 days?
Aziz Mirza. Badshah Khan is a man.
He'll give his life, but
he'll never betray.
And, even a moment is enough,
for luck to turn the table!
Better remove your pips.
That Pathan has betrayed you.
A Pathan has kept his word.
Here, sir.
This is called a ''Rakhi''.
My wife has tied it on your wrist.
We lndian ladies tie this
on our brother's wrist.
- And they protect our marriage
from harm. - Which you have.
You've saved a Rajput
from humiliation.
What nonsense you talk. That
two-penny worth Pasha...
Had he beheaded me, l'd have
come with my head in my hand!
What an illness love is!
No hope of her husband's return.
Yet she lights lamps
everyday, and awaits him.
She has no sense of day,
or night, the crazy girl.
What news do you have?
When is my Badshah coming?
- After 5 years!
- 5 years?
Why? Why? Why not today?
- Why not?
- The lndian law...
...has proved him to be a
criminal and sentenced him.
Sentenced him?
Punished a lover?
Doesn't lndia have a heart?
Hasn't it heard of Love?
l had heard that lndia
is an ocean of love.
Why didn't they think? How can
two lovers live without each other?
A thousand days and nights,
without my beloved Badshah?
O God! Why did you do this?
Why? Why?
Give alms to the poor.
Your sister-in-law is pregnant.
- Your Badshah Khan will be
a father soon. - God's grace.
Have some sweet-meats. Our
jailer is blessed with a child.
Yes. A girl. And l christened her.
Give me that. l'll distribute it
for my friend's joy. - What joy?
- Hurry up and tell me.
- You've become a father, friend.
Congratulations!
- Father! - And coincidentally,
on my daughter's birthday...
...your Benazir has given
birth to another Benazir.
- What are you saying?
- lt's true, Badshah.
What have you named my daughter?
- Hena. - And do you know
what l've named your daughter?
- How will l know?
- The same name in Hindi.
Mehndi?
Hello! l'm here. How do l look?
- Wonderful! Lovely!
- Come with me. - Where?
- To play. - Oh! l can't come.
- You won't come, eh?
l won't listen to you anymore!
Jailer Ranvir Singh...
l have your daughter.
lf you want to see her alive,
handover Badshah Khan to me.
O Rajput Khan.
You're a funny father!
He has kidnapped your child and
you sit here. Order me...
l'll stake my life and bring
Hena darling. l'll bring her.
l can also go and get my daughter.
- But l'm held back by my duty.
- What duty are you taking about?
Which holds back a father from
saving his own daughter. Tell me.
That duty which is expected of
a jailer towards his convict.
That duty which is between 2 pals.
How can l risk my friend's life...
What are you hiding there?
Give it to me. Come on.
They want me, and you...
Okay. Badshah Khan will himself
come to you, you curs!
No! No, Khan.
- l won't let you go.
- What are you saying?
lf l don't go, those fiends
will kill my darling girl.
Khan, l'll not agree to
a life for a life.
ln 4 days, you'll be a
free man to go back home.
Damn you! lsn't this my home?
This is my home too.
Hena is my child too, and,
l'll die willingly for her.
Look Khan... l...
l'll not allow you to buy death
for my daughter's life. No!
For a friend, you're willing
to sacrifice your daughter?
What do take me for?
What do you think l am?
Will l be able to live with
such a huge burden? l'll die!
- Get aside. That child needs me.
- No fuss. l won't let you go.
- Get aside. God forbid, but if
something happens, it'll be the end.
Forgive me, friend.
Don't get me wrong.
But it's my duty to keep you
within these walls.
And l forget all other relations,
where my duty is concerned.
- Forgive me. - This Pathan too
can forget anything before duty.
Rajput Khan... forgive me.
- Khan Uncle. - My dear girl.
- Hold on, Khan.
You dare! Else before we severe
your head, l'll behead her!
- Save me, Khan Uncle.
- You fiend!
You kidnapped an innocent kid to
seek revenge on me! Shameless!
One has to achieve one's aim
by hook or by crook!
Throw that sword away.
Go on, throw it!
Now it'll be a confrontation
on equal terms.
You're unarmed, and so am l!
Pick up the dagger. Go on.
- Mercy! Mercy, Pasha.
- Not mercy, Khan.
Your neck! A neck for a neck!
Mercy, Pasha, Mercy!
Let my kid go!
Else l'll have your head!
Let the child go!
Let her go, l said!
Leave the girl.
- Nobody move!
- Rajput Khan! You?
- Don't worry. l'm here now.
- You see to your daughter.
Save my daughter, Khan.
l will, friend. l swear on God!
- Remember the slap?
- Damn you!
Your wife was right. She's better
off as a widow, than as your wife!
l won't spare you! l'll
kill you, you rascal!
Take a step forward, and
l'll kill this girl.
l've changed my plan.
Now l'll not kill him.
But l'll make him lead
a life worse than death!
Now he'll understand
Pasha's language!
Do you plead guilty, or not,
to the crime you're charged with?
''Save my Hena, Khan.
Save my daughter.''
Guilty!
l killed jailer Rajput Khan.
Yes! l killed him.
After taking into consideration
all the proof and statements made...
...this Court sentences you
for life imprisonment.
My darling girl...
Sister-in-law...