Are you Goolic?
- I've been waiting for you.
Looks like you've had a long trip.300 miles.
We left Texas fast.
So fast we killed our horses. Another
mile of walking would kill us, too.
But we've got the loot here.
Problem is that Corbett's back there,
just behind us.
Ah! Don't be a fool.
We're in Colorado now.
And Corbett can't cause trouble here.
What do you say? Have the times
been good or bad here, Goolic?
- Bad for outlaws.
Especially if they're wanted for murder.
They hang them
just like they do in Texas.
And, if you don't believe me,
ask Goolic.
Who are you?
- Don't you understand, you idiot?
When we thought we had him behind us!
He was in front all the while.
That's him! That's Jonathan Corbett.
If I had one bullet.
Just one.
I don't think he understood my rules:
How about you?
Arrest? Or gun?
I challenge you, Corbett.
Don't shoot me, Corbett! I'm innocent!
I didn't shoot during that robbery!
I'm only 30... Don't kill me. Please...
Unbuckle your belt!
I never thought,
I'd ever see that wall empty.
Yes, sir.
Any good man can live in our state.
All the bad ones will meet
the great Jonathan Corbett!
He's so smart,
he doesn't have to chase the bandits.
They come gunning for him!
Let's celebrate!
Now you can decide
if you want to be a senator.
No more showdowns,
no more bullets whizzing by.
No more chasing bandits in the mountains.
And best of all... no more killing.
How much more do we have to wait?
We're done now, Mr. Brockston.
Don't move...
Hello, Corbett. How are you?
- Fine. Thank you.
May I present Mr. Brockston?
- I've heard a lot about you.
Oh? Really? Not as much
as I've heard about you.
Miller, as father of the groom, I would
imagine you'd have some advice to offer.
Hm? Oh, yes. Yes. Excuse me, gentlemen.
Well, this is my secretary, Mr. Lynch.
And this is Captain von Schulenberg,
who's a genuine Austrian Baron.
My bodyguard.
- Your name is well-known in Texas.
In Austria we also know of it.
- Huh! Professional courtesy.
You're being complemented.
The Baron was the best shot in Europe.
Twenty-three duals, twenty-three widows.
- My complements.
Thank you. I'm sure you've done better.
- Hm. I think,
the Baron is anxious to have you
demonstrate your skill against his.
I stopped playing with guns
when I was a boy of ten.
When I use my gun it's because
I have no other choice.
Well... have you met everyone else?
Ah, Melissa.
She's a graceful beauty, don't you agree?
Perhaps you've seen her in theatre.
She's the rage of vaudeville.
As you see, I surround myself
with the best in every field.
Shall we take a walk?
Corbett, I've heard
that you have political ambitions.
Some of my friends want me to run for it.
But I don't think, I have much
of a chance.
- You don't value yourself enough.
Why, in Texas you're more popular than
Davey Crockett. You've cleaned out
this whole area of outlaws.
It's entirely at your own policing.
Also, one time you were the Sheriff.
- Not officially.
And then, not for long.
My saloon with the gambling tables
was more profitable.
- Oh? I didn't know you had a saloon.
A saloon but no luck.
I always lost at poker.
I also didn't know
that during the war you made Colonel
in just 10 months!
- That didn't last long either.
I punched the General's son.
Became a soldier again within the hour.
Well, there's light and shadow
in the life of every man.
But, history preserves the light
and cancels the shadow.
Corbett, I've got a feeling.
With your reputation,
you'd have without a doubt
a chance for a position in the Senate.
You know what you need?
You need someone to buy you
a campaign of high-level proportions.
- You mean someone like you?
Exactly.
- Why?
Corbett, I'm not trying to buy you.
You and only you
can help me realize a great project.
The building of a railroad from
the United States to Mexico
through Texas.
The only thing I need
is a man like you in Senate
to support me with the government.
My railroad would advance this state
up to twenty years in one day.
Are you really interested
in the progress of this country?
Well, let's say I construct
this railroad
and make millions of dollars.
But I do construct it.
And only I can.
What do you say, Senator?
Alright. As long as we understand
one another, Brockston.
I'm interested in progress.
Not your personal profit.
Fair enough.
Photographer! A photo here.
And so... shall we?
- Don't move, please.
Hey, Chet!
- Well, I'll be! The McCoy brothers!
Where've you two been keeping yourselves?
- Sorry, interfering the festivities.
We've been to Lonely Corner.
- Baker's little girl, only 12 years old,
she's been raped. And stabbed to death.
We found her body a couple of hours ago.
Do you know who it was?
- A Mexican. A young barman
called Cuchillo. "Sanchez, the Knife".
We followed him for twenty miles.
But he was too smart to catch.
- He's heading South.
Probably making steady tracks
for that Mexican day labourers camp.
We're going after him.
- Surely! The Sheriff will organize
the posse. Where's Jellico? Jellico!
I'm here.
- Have you heard about this!
Yes, sir.
But the office of the Sheriff
is closed for tonight.
- Jellico!
You carry the star, understood?
Miller, what's the sense of us
sending out a thirty man posse
when we've got one man
who can do it all by himself?
All honest men would be
grateful to the one
who brings this murderer to justice.
I'll bring you the Mexican. I'll bring
you the Mexican for a wedding present.
Ah, grand. Very generous, Corbett.
All fingers point to you, hm?
This will make you my honorary deputy.
- What do I need this for?
The star becomes your life...
A life with the law.
You will become a legend, my friend.
Wear it.
The star can come in handy.
- And shine brightly on your plans?
Hasta Manana.
Don't you need information about him?
- His name is Cuchillo Sanchez
and he'll be headed South.
Who is he?
- Jonathan Corbett.
He's a manhunter.
- What he's doing?
He's looking around.
- Is Cuchillo here?
He, Senor!
Maybe I could help you.
When someone talks to me
I want to see his face.
Be careful, Signore.
He's quick with a knife, as you can see.
Where is he?
- He's sitting in the barber's chair.
Get back, barber!
I want the man in the chair.
Get up, Cuchillo!
You're the barber aren't you?
Then give me a shave.
March on, brothers!
And hear the Word of God! Onward!
Hey, gypsies! A pack of pigs, all of you!
Take my wife too! I'll give her to you!
- Hey, fellas. Look over there.
Well, well. Look who's in town
The great, great Corbett with a pig.
What have you caught? A big one?
- Not very.
His name is Cuchillo Sanchez.
I would have taken him in alive.
But he put up a fight.
It isn't Cuchillo. The boy just happens
to look a lot like him.
This is Paco Molinas. Sentenced
last month for robbery and murder.
Sentence is paid in full. Amen.
But you happened to get the wrong man.
Because his clothes were the same.
And when I found him,
it was my horse he was riding.
- Well, if things were like that,
you can stop looking around for Cuchillo.
This one here found him first.
Right now, the vultures have turned
your Mexican in to a heap of bones.
By the way, aren't you missing something?
- Yeah. A Sheriff's star.
You must have lost it...
or maybe threw it away.
Something like that.
- What's wrong?
You look bothered, Corbett.
- I am.
I thought, this kid was Cuchillo.
Well, I'm going to find a hotel room.
I'll be leaving tomorrow.
There ain't no hotel anymore.
There's nothing left. After the gold
played out of here, those that could
pulled out and left everything standing.
But as a favour I'll let you have
the bunk in the front cell. Of course,
for friends there's another arrangement.
The best thing about my work is,
you soon become acquainted with all kinds
of people. Yesterday I had a Mexican
who said, "If you know anyone around here
who could pass for me, I'll give him
a gun and a horse." "Why?" I say.
"Because I want to have some fun."
And, would you believe it?
He did!
- Come here!
If you think we've talked enough.
Hm?
Where did you get this?
Who gave you this?
The Mexican. The one I told you.
- When?
Yesterday. Some time around noon.
- What was he like?
Better mannered than you are!
That's for sure. He had a nicer face
than you have, too! So there!
More sympathetic, more gentle.
And he's much richer, too. And if he
hadn't been set on going with the Mormons
he could have stayed all night, too.
Then I could convince him
to stay with me. What a man...
Hey! What a nerve!
...and here you will stay,
for this is the Promised Land.
Let these words comfort us
for the rest of our journey.
May Divine Providence protect us,
and peace be with you.
Go. Go, my children.
If I take my hand away from your mouth,
will you be quiet?
Tell me.
Is there a young Mexican with you?
Yes. A good fellow
who respects the law of God.
Which wagon is he in?
- Why, I put him in mine.
But, right now he's at the spring
getting water with little Sarah.
Little Sarah? How old is little Sarah?
- Thirteen. Why do you ask?
Because this boy is wanted for rape
and murder of a little girl.
Hey, Sarah! Sarah!
Come in the water and play.
Come! See the little fishes!
Come on, Sarah!
Come on! The water here is shallow.
You can touch the bottom.
See? Come on!
No! No, no!
- Sarah, Please! Come on!
Don't make me come. Sarah!
Hey listen, we play a game!
You be the Mormon girl
and I be the wolf, hm?
Oh, what a pretty thing you are, Sarah!
Come over, Sarah! Let me see!
Sarah, come on! So, that's it,
you want to play, hm? Ok!
Get up, Cuchillo!
I could easily kill you right now.
- Please, don't! Don't rob me, Signore!
I swear, I'm a poor Mexican!
By the virgin of Kuala Lumpur!
Have mercy! Don't kill me!
He wants to rob us! Please!
Don't let him! Don't let him!
- Come on!
Please say you meant that.
You meant it, didn't you?
He did mean to rob us, I thought.
He was a bandit-please, say so!
- Si. Si.
He was a bandit.
But, worst of all, he was an idiot.
Adieus, Chica. And gracias.
Adieus!
Sarah! Sarah, what happened?
- I had to shoot him. He was a bandit.
He was going to rob and kill us!
- Be quiet, Sarah.
Just let me look at him.
Doesn't seem serious.
Cuchillo? Where's Cuchillo?
- The boy's escaped.
At least I got here.
Before he hurt your daughter.
My daughter? Sarah?
Sarah's my fourth wife.
Hey! Who are you?
Just a poor man
who doesn't bother asking names, Signore.
I'm here because my stomach's empty.
- Go on! Clear out!
Go on now. Get moving!
- Si, Signore. But if that man's job
is open now, maybe I could do it?
You don't have to give me much,
but please, I need work.
- We don't have jobs for Mexicans here.
Vamoose!
- No, wait!
There's a job if he want. It will take
a while for Mike to get patched up.
Is there anything you're best at?
I'm best in all I do, Signora.
Perhaps. We'll see.
The man is hungry. Get a plate.
Huh! Not me.
- That's an order.
Right away.
Feel like working now?
I could stop a bull with my two hands.
- Alright. You show us
what you can do.
Now, who's got an idea?
Well, we've got old Barney
who's big and he's sure mean.
He's right back there in the old stable.
- Aye. We've got old Barney.
We've been waiting for you, wrangler.
That's old Barney. You said you could
stop a bull with your bare hands,
didn't you? Come on! Prove it!
I showed you!
Come in the house with me.
You can rest. I'll take you there.
Go to hell!
- Come here!
As I order. It must be at my orders,
just like the others.
What are you doing, Mr.?
- I'm taking this man with me.
He belongs to us.
He's wanted by the law.
In these mountains
we've got no law
but the bullets in our guns. Drop dead!
I said, I'm taking Cuchillo with me.
You've been told
he's not going back there.
Go back, or die!
- 1...
2...
...and 3.
- Stop it!
Stop it! Men, put away your guns!
I blame my men for what happened.
They shouldn't have provoked you...
- Corbett.
I rather think, I owe you an apology.
But, I don't want you to believe
that this place is so backward
and so barren that the rules
of hospitality have been forgotten.
That one, he'll go back with you.
Put him in a safe place!
He'll be quite alright, I assure you.
May you burn! May your own mother mourn
your birth and pray that you will die!
You'll have some tea? So, I found myself
a widow and alone on this isolated ranch.
It's very lonely for a woman.
Especially because I was educated
for finer things.
You both may go!
These men talk and act
just like beasts, you see.
It's hard to keep on
holding their respect.
You're doing alright.
What are they doing?
She's got him alone.
- See? She has a new one, you poor idiot!
I bet she didn't wait a minute
as soon as you got out of the room.
Shut your mouth!
- Well, I feel sorry for you poor boys
because you're sharing this time
with me while they're alone.
Now that I've been displaced as you have,
I look as stupid
as I thought you were. Hah.
Now he's kissing her soft, white neck,
while she runs her fingers up his back.
Soon, there's nothing she won't
give to him. And so he reaches out...
- I'll kill you if you don't shut up!
The best thing that's happened in this
place is our meeting one another.
What are you trying to say?
Some things are obvious.
Intimate games.
But to play them
I'd have to take off my gun.
Can't you see, though, now?
It's just beginning.
He's quick with a gun.
He can take what he wants.
And she'll try to keep him here.
But, if he stays he'll be your new boss.
He'll be here forever. And he'll get rid
of you all, one by one.
Well, I'm in it too.
You know what he came here for.
If I go back there to the gringos
they'll make me hang.
But, if we all go after him we can
stop him. Or else, we'll beat them.
And if we do?
- I tell you,
it's in your hands.
We wait for him to come out,
then we shoot him first.
Give me a gun.
We can kill him together.
What do you say?
Listen, Amigo! You'd better be right.
We'll keep an eye on you.
You watch me. You'll see me kill him
even before you can shoot.
Well... a nice idea, hm?
- You keep hoping that. You keep hoping.
We need a man here. A man of strength.
A man like you. Stay here, Corbett.
No. You wouldn't be satisfied
with just one man.
You enjoy being queen bee too much.
I saw you look at that Mexican outside.
You saved him only for one reason:
So you could kill him yourself.
You've got one purpose only!
Why is killing so important!
Thanks for the tea.
I can stop them!
Next it's you, Mexican,
if you don't start shooting.
I'll try to get around behind him.
If you can keep him busy in front.
Right! Go ahead!
- Keep him under fire!
Adieus Cuchillo!
Adieus Americanos!
You fool!
It's a kid's trick to make you shoot
and waste all of your ammunition.
Where are you?
- Here I am.
No! No, wait, please!
I beg you! I'm afraid!
Please don't leave me here alone!
Please! Please!
Don't leave me here alone!
Good water, hm?
Tastes good, hm, Cuchillo?
- It tasted better a minute ago!
I've been waiting for you.
It's the only water around.
For a hundred miles.
Next time you steal a horse,
make sure there's a canteen.
Get down! Take it easy!
Ah, you stink!
If the pistol didn't make you brave,
you couldn't do this to me.
- You talking to me?
And, if it weren't
for those stupid pigs back there
you wouldn't have even a chance
to catch me. I would have made you run.
You will never get me by yourself!
Understand? Never!
By yourself,
you couldn't catch a limping snail!
Go ahead. When I've finished breakfast,
I'll get the horse and catch up with you.
You must have come out
of your mother rotten!
Hungry?
Well, I guess even animals
have to eat. Here.
What bothers you about me?
- I've got nothing against you.
It's the law you broke that counts.
So that's it. And why does the law count?
- You mean, you don't know?
I do know a law. The one that says
most of the words in two parts,
the masters and the obeyers.
In my country, there was such a law.
And no-one ever knew who wrote it.
But we lived under it.
Then, one day we listened to Juarez.
And he said we should change it.
Everybody should be nice
and people should stop hating
each other and let the men go free.
Oh boy!
We thought it would work for a while.
But nothing really changed
So, you started running again.
- What was the use?
Because I always get stopped.
You don't see, what cares I've got.
Bet you don't know, I've got a family.
I've got three children! No money
to feed them. My wife is a saint.
She works from morning to night
as a maid to a priest.
And if I was in your place, I bet,
I would say,
"This man should be free to go."
If I was in your place,
I'd say the same thing.
But, I wouldn't be foolish enough
to expect another man to believe me.
Listen, don't you think, you owe me
some gratitude? I helped you
at the ranch, remember?
- So you could run.
You needed the extra time to escape.
- But, if I hadn't you... Besides,
I'm not able to kill a man unless
it's a fair fight. I couldn't do it.
But a girl of twelve! Her, you could?
Bravo! Bravo!
May you rest in peace, little snake!
You saw it?
- You got a bite.
If you want, I can draw it out.
The only way to get rid of the poison.
It's that fast, hm?
Don't think you have a lot of time.
In another minute
it could be too late.
Well?
- It still isn't enough, you know.
Now it should be burnt
to close up the wound.
Ah, yes. We really should burn it.
Get up!
Turn around!
No tricks!
Not me. I told you I couldn't kill a man
in cold blood. Now, maybe you believe it.
Go ahead. I'll be dead
in a couple of minutes anyway.
See? This is what bit you.
Here. It's yours. You want it?
If you don't kill me right now,
it will be the last mistake
you ever make.
- Ah, but to kill you
is a bigger mistake. If I kill you,
they'll just send another man after me
who's much smarter-much.
Anyway, now you'll owe me something.
I could have killed you, I didn't.
From now on we have an account to settle,
you and I. Next time, remember that.
But there won't be a next time.
Because you'll never get me!
Easy. There's plenty here. Don't gulp it.
Thank you.
- You look like someone
who took the wrong turn by mistake.
How long have you been out here?
Four, five days. I don't know.
- Take it easy.
You've got to rest.
I'm after a man, an outlaw.
You've got to give me a horse and a gun.
- You're pulling my leg.
He's headed towards Mexico and I've got
to catch him before he reaches
the border. I haven't any money on me.
But any Sheriff in Texas will vouch
for me and pay you.
My name's Corbett. Jonathan Corbett.
Alright, Corbett. I'll try to be of some
help to you. You can climb on my wagon
and get some rest. But, as soon as you
get to the first town, you can...
Oh, I'm losing time. I need a horse now!
- A horse? You expect me
to part with one year Loca, here?
You expect me to put my family in danger
and risk all I own
so you can chase a bandito?
To hell with your bandito!
Let him escape.
Someone else will catch him.
- If he gets in to Mexico...
Don't you understand? He's free.
- No. I don't understand.
You can come with us. We can write up
an agreement if you want...
I'm sorry.
Leave...
Leave him alone!
Ah! You should make some kind of sound,
coming through the door.
One more minute and I'd have hit you.
May I see that knife?
- Of course. But, I ask that you please
don't show it to Brother Smith. He
doesn't like us to play around like this.
Who gave it to you?
- A Mexican boy.
Where is he?
- He's not here. He departed yesterday.
Gone to Mexico. We're at the border.
- You mean, he crossed it?
Yes. And realize that the hunt is over.
- Because you say it is?
You don't have the right to cross.
- He belongs to the law of my country.
I'm not talking about the law.
When you cross over that line
you'll be as bad as he is.
It becomes a personal matter
and you know it.
- It's my job to bring him in.
And you know it.
That pistol's been hanging there...
In time, its weight always changes a man.
What do you know about such men?
- Do you mind giving it to me?
These days they seem much lighter.
Oh, did you see that? It's an old habit.
And yet, it's been thirty years.
When I first came here, the brothers
promptly made me Brother Smith & Wesson.
But mine was in the holster.
I was running.
Anybody who can shoot like you
doesn't have to run.
I hated the mad man that I had become.
And, if it isn't too late, Corbett,
you must stop running. Don't think,
it won't happen to you. Understand?
You must stop running. Don't think,
Yes, I'm sure you do.
But, you don't care.
I'm sorry.
- And I'm sorry also. For you.
Murdered a child?
- Yes. A little girl.
How old was this girl?
- Twelve.
Was she good looking?
Was it your sister? Was it your cousin?
I never saw her.
- I don't understand.
Why are you following after
this Cuchillo? You must be a Sheriff.
No.
- I don't get you.
Captain, in my country, even a private
citizen who believes in justice
can help out the law.
- But now you come to Mexico.
That's right. Now I'm asking you
to help me find this man.
Hm. I'm not sure I should.
You can't even prove to me who you are.
There's a telegraph office, isn't there?
Ask San Antonio. They'll tell you
who I am!
- Do you think they'll help you?
Who I am!
Look!
You must have heard of this Cuchillo!
I know he lives in your town, Captain.
He said his wife worked for the Padre.
That's a big laugh!
The Padre's never let her
enter a church. Rosita's worked
in a bordello since she was fifteen.
Yes, I know Cuchillo.
I know that one well. He's one of those
pieces of trash who stood with Juarez.
- Then you're looking for him, too?
Pieces of trash who stood with Juarez.
Maybe I am.
But, I'm not doing it for you.
In that case, I'll find him myself.
Goodbye, Captain.
You know, Signore,
there are people I hate even worse
than followers of Juarez.
I despise all Americanos.
So you go ahead. It makes no difference
to me who kills who. But, be careful.
You do anything in this town to cause
me trouble and I'll cause you more!
I'm looking for the wife of Cuchillo.
Her name is Rosita.
Are you Rosita?
Twenty. You pay it now.
- Cuchillo. Are you the wife of Cuchillo?
Don't talk to me about
being the wife of that pig!
How long has it been since he was here?
- Three months he doesn't think about me.
Promised to stay here with me,
then stole all I had. Took my Madonna.
Where's he gone now?
- How do I know? He's probably out drunk,
giving another woman what I earned.
But I pray he'll come back.
And then I scratch his eyes out!
- Alright! Calm down! When I find him,
there won't be a next time.
There won't be a next time.
Why do you say that?
- He won't bother you anymore
because he'll be hung for murder.
- Hang my man?
Yes.
- You... you want to hang my man?
I'll kill you! Filthy scum!
You're defending him?
A rapist! A murderer!
Don't you understand?
Help! Help! Stop him! He's a thief.
He tried to go without paying me!
Do you hear? Don't let him get away! No!
- Wait a minute!
I said, no trouble from you.
And you didn't listen.
Signora, I'll take you now.
And next you come, and you come,
and then, you...
One moment. This one comes with us.
- That is, if you have no objection.
No problem, Signore. I don't object.
After all, I'm a peaceful man.
Damned! Since when do you out a man
in prison because he drank a little?
Is it now a crime for a man to be happy?
- It's a crime to knife people
and then to knife a policeman when he
tries to stop you burn down the place!
And then to knife a policeman when he
No! No! It was those two who provoked me!
And the damn lamp fell out of my hand.
And the policeman
put his hand in my mouth.
I only closed it! I swear!
- Stay there! Now, you be quiet.
You're a brave man
when there are bars between us! Coward!
Guard! Come back!
- What's wrong?
Help! This man is mad! Let me out!
I want to get out, away from this maniac!
Tell me what he did to you!
- As soon as you turn your back,
he'll go for me again!
- Better cut out that shouting!
He'll go for me again!
No! I'll keep shouting all night long!
And if I hear you breath again,
I'll shut your dirty,
stinking mouth for you! Understand?
No. You're the coward.
I'm not afraid of you,
if that's what's bothering you!
Here's the reason for wanting
my cell changed.
I've been in this jail before. And the
last time, no-one bothered to search me.
Why don't you make a racket?
Do you know, you're a strange person?
If I was in you, I'd have the guard
at that door without batting an eye.
It's fortunate for me that my country's
walls are made of mud and dried spit.
I'll get you.
You can't run fast enough
for far enough.
I'll hunt you down and kill you
like the rotten beast you are.
Beast? But, what about what you are?
Yes, I'm a beast, alright,
because I have to keep running.
But, can I stop to explain myself
without being killed? But, you must
have proof, hm? No, not you!
They told you I was guilty and right
away you start running after me.
You're the beast because you didn't
even ask if it was true or not.
But what if I give you a big lie, hm?
What if I tell you,
I didn't murder that girl?
It so happens, I know who did.
You'd laugh too if you knew
who that person really was.
Because if you know the truth,
from now on, you'll be the one
who's hunted. And you'll find you had
much more fun when you were the hunter.
Adieus, Amigo.
You'll never get me, Amigo!
Open up!
You're free now! You've been cleared.
San Antonio sent a telegram.
You're Corbett, alright.
Now, watch out! I'm not forgetting...
That dirty swine, Cuchillo!
Who else could escape in half an hour?
- So you can continue the hunt.
Don't worry. No-one will stop you,
you know. As I already told you,
here in Mexico, the Americanos
and the dogs of Juarez
can make trouble for each other
with the approval of the authorities.
Isn't it wonderful to visit
such a liberal country?
May I buy it for you?
Baron, ask him,
where in the devil he's been!
Corbett, I have been looking for you
for two days.
No, Brockston, I don't buy your idea.
Listen to me. When the telegram
from the Mexican police arrived,
So, I took the effort
to come here personally. And I did so,
not to listen to your opinion,
but to clear up this matter.
In amongst all this is a matter of
a million dollars that never gets billed
because of a despicable Mexican.
The despicable Mexican means more to me
than all your money, or the election!
But, you also belong to me, Corbett.
Your influence will touch every corner
of the state and everyone will know
that behind you, is my money.
We are in the same boat, Corbett.
You'll never become shipwrecked.
I'll be there to anchor you.
To achieve strength like that,
I need you to eliminate the Mexican.
I've my own method, Brockston.
- But your own method has failed.
Now we'll use mine. And I guarantee you,
this two-bit Mexican won't get
away from me!
Oh, our gentle owner of the house
is not easily offended.
After all, he hopes to participate
in our railroad transaction.
And, furthermore, he doesn't
always understand our language.
I've prepared all my men, Signore.
They're all waiting outside the house.
I trust you're still decided on it?
- Well, at least as sure
as you are of wanting to enter
in to my business.
Yet, I understand he's a Mexican,
just like you are.
Oh, no. This man's a bumpkin.
Now, listen to me!
Each one of you will be paid
one hundred pesos. Is that clear?
And the one who catches him
will be paid...
one thousand pesos. And remember,
I want this Cuchillo caught!
All you have to do is find him.
But, turn this country upside down
if you have to. But, find him!
Alright now, clear off!
How long will you be gone this time?
I don't know.
Where'll you go?
Somewhere, I guess.
Bet you don't know, what you can see
when you look out over the Sierras?
A big ocean.
Just how big is it?
- Big as a... big as...
So big, you can't see to the other side.
I'd even have you come along with me.
Even to the city?
- Sure. Who knows?
If you come perhaps
we could both steal a boat, hm?
No, no, no.
This isn't Cuchillo, you fool!
Sorry, Captain Segura. We seem
to be having a lot of trouble tonight.
What is it?
- Don Serrano's riders
are all over the town,
armed and looking for someone.
Oh! Don Serrano!
Ah, he's a big gentleman.
A proprietor.
Pays a big tax and puts out much money
for the church.
- What would we do?
Do what I'm going to do, sleep.
Those who sleep
don't see and don't hear.
May I ask you a question, Corbett?
When you are about to kill a man,
what do you look at?
I've asked this question of other men.
And do you know what they always say?
They look at his hands.
I don't.
I look at his eyes.
Because a moment before he moves
his hand, his eyes betray him.
And you can always read death.
Yours.
Or his.
Don't you have too much already?
For once, please don't, Chet.
- Cut it out! Go to hell! Leave me alone!
Lizzie! Lizzie!
What's happened?
- I'm packing. I'm going home.
Why?
- Can't stand it anymore. Not with Chet.
You do something like that
and I'll wring your neck!
But, our marriage is...
- Yours isn't a marriage.
It's an optional Miller's land,
over which my railroad must pass.
Now, that's a lot of capital.
And you know, I don't want anybody
to touch that capital.
You! Hey, you!
- Si, Signore?
No!
No, Signore! No!
Damn you! You bundler! Didn't you
learn anything the first time?
Did you have to try it once more?
- What are you...
You know damn well what I mean!
- When did you know I was the one?
When it was too late,
after you'd married my daughter.
And when those two red-headed friends
of yours showed up at the party.
You pretended you'd just saw them.
I knew for a fact that you'd seen them
the night before. So, I had
a little talk with them like this.
And what did they tell you?
- The truth. That you got drunk and you
raped and killed that little girl
and the Mexican saw you do it. So you
got frightened and you blamed him.
- What will I do if they talk?
Don't worry.
They won't say anything anymore.
Did you ask yourself
why you haven't seen them lately?
I thought they'd just gone away.
- They did.
With Baron Von Schulenburg.
- Ah, go ahead.
You idiot! You think I did it for you?
I did it for my daughter.
I did it because I don't want anybody
to know that my daughter is married
to a murdering violator!
Now, there's only one left.
And when it's over tomorrow,
after the Mexican is dead,
then I begin to think about you.
I don't know! I haven't seen him!
I don't know! I swear it! I swear...
- Where is he?
You bitch! Where is he? Talk!
No, no, no, no, no, no! No!
Let her go, you pig!
What is it?
Did they hurt you?
- No, no. But, go!
Please, Cuchillo. Run!
- Yes.
Go now! Be careful!
We'll be together. You'll see.
- Go now.
I designed this holster myself.
I originated it.
When I realised that in America,
the swiftness of the draw
is more important
than the precision
of the shooting.
I'll go and see
if they've saddled the horses.
The sun is rising.
It looks like a big ball of blood.
I say, that's an omen.
What to choose...
Not those.
These.
You know, with one of these you can
stop the charge of a mad buffalo.
It explodes inside of the body like that.
You didn't know that hunting
was my passion, did you?
After making money. I've been
to Africa and India looking
for all types of animals to kill.
But, there's still one type of animal
that I haven't hunted-not with a gun,
that is. The hunting of man.
Should be interesting.
It seems he's hidden in the cane fields.
They don't seem able
to pick up his scent.
Alright. Keep them here, then. Come on!
Stop!
No! If we stop, we'll never catch him.
- It's better if we spread out.
Brockston, you take the Baron
and go around that side.
Chet, you come with me.
You men here, go to Signore Brockston!
Where is he?
Better go on foot.
You seem nervous.
- What are you trying to say?
I'm saying, don't make any mistakes!
Got that?
Over there. Go on!
Hold it!
What a stupid idiot I've been.
I always thought you were an honest man.
And now I see how blind I was.
You will kill me to cover up the truth.
Go on!
- You know, what I'm talking about.
Yeah. I know now.
Drop the rifle.
No. The blade.
What's happened here?
- You're not blind!
Alright. Kill him!
Pull the trigger! Kill him!
I could have killed him several times,
Brockston. But, something seemed wrong.
And when you involved yourself
personally in this thing,
I knew it was wrong.
You thought, I'd shoot first
and then think, is that it?
That was your mistake.
Alright. You're really
too damn smart to be a Senator.
Alright, Baron, he's yours.
Brockston, there's still a bullet
left for you.
Fun's over, Brockston!
Come on!
It's not over yet, Corbett!
I'm the man in charge!
You'd miss at that range.
There's been enough blood shed,
Mr. Corbett.
His adventure is over.
Come on!
I go in that direction.
- I go lower.
Adieus!
- Maybe we see us again.
Corbett!
You never would have got me!
Never! Never!