Vengeance.
It is enough to keep you going
through anything-
through fear,
through pain,
through hell itself.
Because until you have
vengeance,
it has you.
And it won't let you go.
It won't let you live.
It won't even let you die.
You have something for me?
Answer the question,
señorita
Or do I use this ugly edge
on your pretty face?
Take it.
What are you hiding there?
I'm not looking
for trouble.
I'm looking for a man,
that's all.
Well...
look no farther.
I may be a woman,
but I'll be your man,
senorita
No.
You're not him.
You don't want to be,
neither,
'cause when I find him
I'm gonna
blow his balls off.
I came from Hell's Crossing.
They told me
to come this way...
said a Mary Black might be
looking for him too.
I thought I might help.
Mother Mary doesn't need your help.
A taste of what I got in that bundle
might change your mind.
No more, pl-
Take this offering
as communion with her,
Mother Lord.
I can guess what happened
to our two lookouts.
How about you tell
all of us who you are?
Clementine Templeton.
I'm looking for this man-
the same man I hear
y'all are looking for.
Maybe I can help you find
the son of a bitch.
Maybe you can.
So what's Sentenza to you?
Back home, he left a girl,
abandoned her.
Took all her money
and left her
with nothing but his baby
in her stomach.
This is my daughter
Michelle.
Sentenza fucked her,
left her like this.
He raped her?
Love sometimes makes you do things
you don't want to do.
You think what he did
to you was love?
They're on the same trail-
Mary Black,
her followers.
Their path started out
in a town ruled by women-
a way of life
threatened by a man.
Now they're afraid
of where the trail ends-
All of them are worried
that if the ghost stories are true,
the day of reckoning
with Mobius Lockhardt
awaits them.
The name's Rosa Hodge-
Sheriff Hodge to you and everyone else.
I uphold the law
in Hell's Crossing-
Mary's law.
Yeah, a town run by women.
We were through
waiting for men
to give us our rights.
Crack Shot, a fast shot.
One shot- that's all
Dora really needs.
Be glad you ain't
dueling with me.
Any gold you've got
or find, I get.
If you don't make it,
that is.
Name is Olie Almarich.
Lads call me Goldie.
See, I love gold.
I've heard there's a lot
of gold hidden in Amnesty,
scraps from back before
the mine was abandoned.
I intend to claim it all
for me and Mother Mary.
Quite the posse
you got here.
That girl
Sentenza left behind-
is she a relation of yours,
your sister?
How'd you come by
your skills?
My father Eli-
he had a ranch,
a dead Mexican wife
and three little girls.
For most of us
it's a vision.
For me, it was her,
bestowed on me
out of nowhere- Michelle.
Wait, so you're saying
your pregnancy was?
Immaculate.
You'll be lucky to survive one more
night before becoming a mother.
Mother Lord
will keep you well
long enough
to cleanse the sin
and see Blake Sentenza
pay for it.
But, Mama, I don't
want him to pay.
This Sentenza-
he raped you, right?
He led you on
and he left you.
And you don't want him
to pay for it?
I don't want him
to pay for it with his life.
I'd just like him to say
that he still loves me.
What makes you think
he ever did?
Blake could have run away,
but he loves me too much to leave.
Why else would he stay
until a price was put on his head?
Where is it?
Where's the God damn town?
We need him alive.
Well, I figured it's best
to bring him back dead
than not bring him back at all.
A cemetery.
Lost souls, baby.
Just like
the ghost story says.
Amnesty Town.
If you figure
that's safer.
He come this way.
My hand!
Mobius Lockhardt-
a spirit of vengeance
left to roam this world
after death,
thirsty for blood,
hungry for revenge,
just like
the ghost story says.
Let's get the hell
out of here!
Stinking cowards.
Shooting at their own shadows.
Bushwhacking bastard.
Piece of shit shot my paw.
Let's shoot him
in the gut.
It takes days to die
from that.
It wasn't me.
I don't have a gun.
No no no no, please.
Don't, don't.
Please please please.
Don't shoot me, Mobius.
Just trying to take
a piece-of-shit
rapist back to justice.
Seeing as you've gone
so suddenly quiet,
I guess they call you
Blake Sentenza
Yeah.
Yeah, but I didn't
rape that girl.
Very few live
to tell their story
about this camp,
about me.
You could be one of them,
but it means doing
something in exchange.
Great. Great.
Very few get to live.
Deliver a message for me...
...about me.
That's so you don't forget.
Señor Sentenza.
A holy servant once
said to God,
"My life was filled
with pain and suffering
and ended
in horrible tragedy.
I renounce you
and my place in Your kingdom."
And God said
to the servant,
"Then your suffering
shall continue
in the service of Satan
and your reward will be
a place in Amnesty."
And therewith,
Mobius Lockhardt...
...rose from the grave
to serve a new lifetime...
...bringing souls
of the damned to hell.
I didn't rape that girl.
Many people come here
looking for something,
some for gold,
others for a refuge,
land, maybe even me.
But all any of them
ever get
is their epitaph.
And now, now they'll be
coming here for you,
Blake Sentenza
You know...
that's my last cigarette.
I don't want
to puff it alone.
Been years,
15 of them
since I last had one.
It's a friendly gesture.
Been 15
since I had
one of those too- a friend.
Most chant Bible at me
and run away.
I know his belly's
torn to pieces,
but he still looks lively.
You can see him twitching.
Takes days to die
from a stomach wound.
I also have a lady.
Left her back east
for the gold rush.
Mine's dead.
Maybe it's time I gave you
a friendly gesture.
This devil hoard was forged
with hellfire.
A Dixie roll.
I've seen the trick.
You catch it,
you twirl it around
and blow me to hell.
Maybe you're already there.
I'm sorry. I was just trying
to be friendly.
I give myself to Lucifer!
This grave was dug today.
We should have burnt it to the ground.
Looks like somebody's
fiancee is trying to scare us.
- Run us the hell off.
- Shh. Listen.
Now we know what happened
to our bounty hunters.
No.
Blake didn't do this.
No, he isn't vicious like this.
He isn't-
Don't get on your knees for him.
Not for him!
Never do that for a man.
Go. Go back. Go.
He's dead.
He killed Sentenza.
I heard the shot.
Blake's dead?
Please save me.
Blake's not dead.
This heathen was
just too scared
to face him again.
Think of this piece of shit
before you fail me.
Give me your gold, cowboy.
Good taste, picking me.
Slim pickings, but you would be
my first stop too.
I chose you because
I know what you're after.
And you know
what I'm after.
You're after him?
Sentenza?
Any gold goes to you,
big payola or otherwise.
I expect the same
in return
if you find
what I'm looking for.
Huh-uh, I'm going this way.
Your ass is mine, Blake.
Been here long enough?
There's only two places
you can be safe
from Mobius Lockhardt-
beyond the graves
and inside this church.
I'm sorry I scared you.
I thought you were one of them.
Know what I came here for?
You came to save me.
All right.
Give me one reason not to.
I just did.
Need another kiss?
Want some more?
You'd better try another reason.
All right.
That's your
wedding dress, right?
Been patching it up.
After what you did,
you and me, I don't think
that can be patched up.
It's about the girl, right?
It's all lies, Clem.
I didn't spend
any time with her,
not even words.
I only love you,
with my eyes,
with my heart.
I'm all yours.
Then where's your ring?
Where's yours?
- Hey hey.
- So where is your ring?
I was just sweet-talking him
so I could bring him out nice and easy.
A punch would do it.
One punch from... you?
Are you prepared
to make good
on your promise
to my little girl, Blake?
You fucking whore.
Each time you say "No"...
we pull the hook.
We'll let you hang until the skin
peels clean off your bones.
Ever seen a man's bones
slide out of his flesh?
Even for you,
I don't know
if I can stand
to watch it happen again.
Lucky I don't have that problem.
You can put it
on my finger now,
like you always said.
Don't let them hurt you
like this, Blake.
You're crazy.
That's because your lover boy
hasn't slipped it on you
or because he slipped it on hers.
That badge don't place you
above nobody.
You're just one of Mary Black's
teet suckers.
We'll see who
a teet sucker is shortly.
You raped my daughter
and you left the mark
of your perversion
in her belly, you bastard.
I didn't do it!
If I have to,
I will baptize this baby
in your blood.
Just say "I do"
Say you love me.
Please say it like before,
or they'll make it hurt.
Never said that.
Never felt that.
And nothing can make me.
Nothing?
Are you sure about that?
Clementine.
We believe to do unto others
what is done to us.
- An eye for an eye.
- A tooth for a tooth.
A rape for a rape.
This your idea of law?
Mary's will is the law.
Spit out the words, Blake,
the ones I want to hear.
Then I'll say the ones
that you want to hear.
Listen, Mary,
all the stories are true
about Mobius.
They are true.
He's just been waiting for us
to come out of the church.
There is no Mobius.
She doesn't have time.
Any gold is mine
and I'm taking
what's mine.
Hiding your gold
wedding ring from me, huh?
I knew you'd want a piece
of what was down this shirt.
This is fool's gold,
like the one Sentenza
gave Michelle.
Clementine Templeton...
Always had trouble dropping
the maiden name, Madre.
...it's a sin for a bride
to share her spouse
with another.
Well, then you'd better
tell your girl
to find another man
to walk that aisle,
'cause I'm hitched
to the one hooked up!
I'll see what I can do
about issuing a divorce.
It's Mobius.
- Michelle.
- Please, no!
- Blake!
- Come!
That's what it feels Like
being the broadside of a barn.
Not a thing can stop him.
You didn't even hit him
with a single slug, crack shot.
Told you it will take
experience.
If anyone can put
the bastard down, I can.
Dirty little lass.
Blake.
Hold on.
Dora, what are you
waiting for?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
We've got to
get out of here.
I don't know if I should
save your neck or stretch it out.
Shoot him, Dora, shoot!
Come on.
Mama, wait wait.
No!
Please, don't shoot.
I'm nothing,
harmless without my gun.
Well, what were you
with them?
Forgotten your past?
Mobius.
Your past hasn't
forgotten you.
It's not fair.
I haven't got my calling yet.
I was supposed to see.
Hell, you are lucky,
sister.
Oh, Lord.
Most don't want
to see it coming.
But since you can't see,
I want you to listen
real close.
Mama, I thought you couldn't
come into this place.
Oh, isn't this just cozy?
Are you okay?
Didn't hear me?
Nobody with the whore
leaves here alive.
So where were you
going, Sheriff?
I can't get used to it,
that sound.
Well, you'd better
get used to it.
I believe I remember you
back in the old days,
still full of
grit and spit, Rosa
But now
I've got something
for you to chew on.
Mother Lord
will show us the way.
I'd rather put my faith
in someone that actually
exists, Madre.
Like that other girl
Blake left behind,
the one you said was
abandoned and pregnant?
What are you
talking about?
I didn't leave
any girl pregnant.
Me.
You're kidding, right?
We tried all those times.
You said that-
I thought
you couldn't carry.
Well, I guess that night
before you left
was the lucky number.
You're not shaped
like you're pregnant.
If what you say is true,
then- then where is
the baby?
Right, where is it?
You lost it, didn't you?
I hadn't heard from Blake,
so I took off for him.
But the fights
slowed me bad.
The worst one came from
some boys in grey dusters.
Grey dusters?
That means-
Those bastards.
The beating sidelined me
for months.
I had aches
in bones I never
even knew existed...
blood dripping
from places
that it shouldn't
have been.
But I survived.
I wanted you
to meet your son, Blake.
I was gonna name him Eli,
after my father.
They deserve to die...
suffer horribly
and then die.
They should all die...
just that way.
They did.
They all did.
If I'd known, I would have came back.
You know that.
What happened to your ring?
I lost it.
After I lost the money you gave me
for the trip to Sonora
You didn't quite make it
to the gold rush.
I had to stop off
in Hell's Crossing
and earn some money
to make it the rest of the way.
It wasn't all
you stopped off for.
No. No! No!
No!
If you wouldn't have forced me
to look for gold,
this never would have happened.
You needed to stand
on your own two feet
instead of stepping on mine
all the time!
I'm sorry you had to pay my debts...
and had to support me.
I'm sorry.
I will always be thankful.
But there's nothing I can do
to change it.
Nothing.
Why her?
I am a man.
We're not built
for just one woman.
That's the problem.
Here, you need me
to fix the problem?
Be careful Clem.
Why her, huh? Why?
She needed me.
I never felt you did.
It was nice, Clem.
She wears dresses.
The only dress you ever wore
is the one you got on now.
And after all...
After all, Clem
I've never loved her.
Then why did you stick
so close to her, huh,
instead of getting away
and coming back to me?
I was waiting for the baby...
...for the baby.
I wanted to take him as
soon as he was delivered.
You've seen her Clem,
she's too weak to raise a child.
I just wanted to bring back
something better than gold for you.
That's it.
Found what you're
looking for?
I give up.
I'm sorry.
I'm not like the others.
I'm not like Mary.
I'm sorry.
- Want a smoke?
- A friendly gesture?
Yeah, sure sure.
Here.
Mobius.
Is it over?
Is it, Mama?
Here you go.
He's gone.
It's my gold!
Hey, everybody,
come out!
Olie killed the ghost!
I stabbed him
in the stomach,
like the legend says.
He's dead.
He's dead!
I don't know.
You don't think he's dead?
No.
You can have this back.
I thought you were dead!
You must really hate me.
I got us into this.
Messed around with Blake
when you swore him off.
I'm not the one
that hates you.
Who are you talking about?
Blake doesn't hate me.
Your father hated you...
for what you
remind him of-
of me.
My father?
I don't have a father.
You said I never had
a father.
You're putting too much
stress on the baby.
That's it.
Remember that time-
that time we went fishing
at Eagle Creek?
Yeah.
We used all sorts of bait-
bread, sardine, minnow,
but the fish didn't care.
They just let that stuff
float on down the stream.
Just takes
the right bait.
Mary- she's the bait.
And we're the stuff that
floats on down the stream.
My father was a preacher?
He made bad places good,
swore never to leave them
until they were,
even tried to tame
a wild mining town
called Amnesty
with faith
and not with force.
Your father sinned
when he fell in love
with me,
when he made love to me.
He had a wife
waiting at home for him.
And everyone found out
when out of the blue
she turned up in Amnesty.
Mama?
It was in that bad time
that I had a vision.
Mother Lord told me
what I had to do.
I banded
all the women together...
and we put Amnesty
to death.
- Mobius!
- Marisol!
No more, please.
Please, no more.
Please.
Keep what you took from me.
Let's trade.
Mother Lord
show you a way yet?
- What's your plan?
- Mobius can't be stopped,
but Olie showed us
we can slow him down.
- Right.
- I can keep Mobius busy from here
and give you enough time
to get to the bridge and out of here.
Blake...
take this.
Once you reach
the front gates,
be sure to hit Mobius
with enough trigger music
so I can join you.
Mary here will be
going out first.
Why am I to be first?
Blake and Michelle
are going out after you.
She needs his help
getting away.
If I'm covering his ass,
I'm covering hers.
Keeps it all honest,
wouldn't you say?
Coin flips both ways.
You could go first.
I could go last.
Being last means
trusting Blake and me
to help you out
once we're at the gates.
Besides,
you're in a bad way.
You need a puff
of Mother Lord soon enough
or you won't be
no use to anyone.
Are you ready
to carry your bride
across the threshold?
Let's go.
Just in case
we don't make it,
maybe we should all
cleanse our souls.
Anything to confess,
Blake?
He didn't rape me.
Blake didn't do anything.
Well, other than
what I begged him to do.
You slut!
I just thought
if she forced him
to marry me,
it would force him
to love me.
The look
Blake gives you-
he never lent me
a stare like that.
Oh, no,
he's after Mama.
Hey, it's better
that you don't see this.
Whore.
Is it working?
Yeah, it is working.
Go on, Blake, now!
Right.
Now it's time
to let the bait
slip right off the hook.
They screwed you.
You should be
used to that by now.
Can't blame them for putting some
bullets in you.
I sure am glad
they saved
the last ones for me.
I want to hear you beg.
Wait wait wait,
where's Mama?
- I can't leave her.
- Shh.
Keep looking for her
and all you'll see is
the bastard's gun
in your face.
All right?
Don't go too far.
It's hurting me awful!
We have to keep moving.
So I see that you're
a whore's daughter.
Don't call her that,
you son of a bitch!
Didn't tell you, did she?
Your mother was a whore,
the biggest one
in this town Amnesty.
Every man took a dip
or two or three
in your mom and
your mom's little whores-
Rosa, Cota,
the whole slutty bunch.
Couldn't you
smell it on her?
You never lose that stink,
whore stench.
Some of that smell
rubbed off on you, little girl.
Tempting married men
just like your mom,
just like the whore
you are, huh?
That collar-
my father wore one.
You killed him.
Did you steal it
from him?
Is that his?
Yes,
it belonged to your father.
All right. It won't do
much good anyhow.
Think I won't shoot you
because you aren't armed?
I think you won't
pull a trigger on a friend,
even if he stands
between you and revenge.
There.
Now I don't have a friend
standing between me
and revenge.
His gun!
It hurt him!
Blake, are you all right?
Sometimes the answers
aren't so easy.
How do you think I feel?
You didn't even see
the end.
I wish I could see
anything else,
but those sights are burned
deep into my eyeballs.
I made his wish come true.
I gave him
something else to see.
Michelle, that's it.
Everything's
gonna be fine.
Feels like life
is being squeezed
out of me.
We aren't gonna make it
to the front gates.
Hey, try to stand up.
Okay, now follow me.
I can't make it.
Just leave me behind.
Oh, God.
Keep on yelling
like this
and Mobius won't need eyes
to find us.
Haven't you heard
the stories?
Nobody leaves here alive
unless I let them.
I'm sure as hell
not letting you go
this time.
It hurts!
Shut her up, damn it.
We've got problems.
Shh.
Come on, shh.
Come on, come on, come on.
Breathe breathe breathe.
Shh. Shh, breathe.
Is my mom dead?
Come on, Clem,
you can tell me.
I don't care.
Is it wrong
if I feel like this?
It'd be wrong
if you didn't.
Sounds like
she treated you awful.
Your mom's dead, hon.
It's okay.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
These tears
are not for her.
They're for me.
Because now I won't know
how if feels to have
a mother, you know.
I feel like
I'll never know
what it'd be like
to be one.
Maybe it'd be like this.
Take this.
No, I can't.
He promised
to get me away from here,
out of Hell's Crossing.
I loved him.
But he loves you.
Thank you.
Oh, God.
Take this.
There's about three
sheets left, okay?
Save it for when
you're in the peaks.
Don't waste it all
on the valleys.
Shh. Shh.
Where's Blake?
Why? Where are you going?
We still have to help Michelle
push that baby out.
How long did it take
for my wife
to bleed to death?
I asked you a question.
How long did it take
for her to die?
Do you remember my wife?
I don't know.
Shh. Shh.
You'd better polish off
that bald face I gave you.
Maybe we should save it
for the next one,
the next peak.
Michelle, honey,
you ain't headed back
to the valley, okay?
Come on.
Quiet down.
Okay, hold on.
Bite down, bite down.
Bite down hard.
Okay, come on, Michelle.
Keep it going.
Are you ready?
Let's start pushing.
Start pushing.
Come on, push.
Push hard, come on.
Blake, it's time.
Get up the chute.
Come on,
get down at the chute.
No. You go down.
Women are more used to this.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you're the one
that broke the saddle, you stud.
So get your ass down there.
You see anything yet?
Quiet down.
Quiet down, okay?
- I'm here. Quiet down.
- I can see his head.
I'm gonna need
one more big push, okay?
Yeah?
Let's go, okay?
One, two, three, go.
I'll get you
nice and pretty
for the next customer.
How can I make him quite?
Mobius will hear us.
Looks like you have
a baby boy.
He kind of looks
like you, Blake.
Blake...
take Michelle and the baby.
Take him.
Run out of here.
I can't raise him.
You have the time
it takes me
to spend nine slugs.
Okay?
No Clem.
I don't want to do it.
I can't do it.
There must be another way.
Please.
You feel that?
It's my grip, all right?
I'm holding you now.
This don't seem fair.
Yeah, it don't seem fair.
Was that one of hers?
Yeah.
It was her tenth shot.
Now your shooting arm
is just as ugly as mine.
Fair would be giving me
one of your shooters.
They call this a Dixie roll.
Blake.
No. No!
You looking for this, hoss?
I never asked anyone
for help,
but I asked then.
What good has God
done for me, though?
He gave you another chance.
By stranding me in this camp
that I can't leave,
with that whore
still alive?
After all the corpses
you put in the ground,
no wonder you don't
step in that church.
Everything was
taken away from me, you'll see.
So tell me,
what would you do
if the same thing
happened to you?
You wouldn't turn this whole world into
one big graveyard?
Who do you think that is
lying on the ground
over there?
He's everything to me.
And I'm just putting one corpse
in the ground for it- you.
God, I fucking hate you!
I renounce you!
I renounce Christ!
I give myself to Lucifer!
Go on.
There's nothing left to see.
Hey hey hey.
You didn't believe me.
I told you.
I just wanted to leave with you.
Is there anything else
I can do?
Yeah.
Take me to the doctor.
To a med?
But you're shot bad.
I don't think you're gonna
make it there.
Don't worry, baby.
The belly
is the most painful spot
to take a shot,
but it takes days
to die from it.
Vengeance.
It is enough to keep
you going through anything-
through fear,
through pain,
through hell itself.
Because until you have
vengeance,
it has you,
and it won't let you go.