Maddy, honey, your shirt.
-Jeff. That boy can sleep through anything.
- Where's my rosy cheeks?
- There's your good girl.
There you go.
- Mommy's in a hurry.
I need you to put your shirt on.
- Matthew.
Thank you.
-Jeff.
- Sorry.
- Cookie had to milk the cow again.
- I lost track of time.
Come here, baby.
Oh, my.
Good girl.
- Morning,Jeff.
- Morning.
Well, it's not rare beefsteaks...
but you should eat
your breakfast anyway,Jeff.
- Mornin'.
- Mornin', Scottie.
Well?
For what we are about
to receive-
Lord, we are grateful.
Amen.
You might as well slow down.
It's not like they can start without you.
It sets a bad example to the students
if the teacher's late.
Cookie, would you, please?
Oh, yeah. Come on here,
you little sweet baby.
- Now, baby.
- You and I need to hurry as well.
- We've gotta move those cows
to that creek on the south side.
- I'm comin'.
- All right now, Maddy.
You listen to Cookie, all right?
- Yes, ma'am.
You mind him. Take a nap when he tells you to.
Stay out of trouble.
And all day long, we gonna be
chasin'rabbits and pickin'flowers.
Just havin' a good ol' time.
See your daddy over there?
Missie?
What's the matter?
Did I forget something?
No.
I...just wanted to let you know
to have a nice day.
"Have a nice day.''
Well, thank you.
Same to you.
What is it you really
wanted to say, Mr. LaHaye?
I hate that we need the money
from the teaching job.
But between the drought
and the cattle plague...
the herd's much smaller
than it should be.
Well, only the good Lord knows
how big our herd should be.
Let's let our faith rest in him.
- You're right.
- I know I am.
I'd better get goin', or Tettsford Junction's
gonna start lookin' for a new teacher.
I love you.
- Have a nice day.
- You too.
Bring 'em up!
- Come on,Jeff!.
- Help me up.
Bring 'em up at the back here.!
- Move 'em!
- Hyah!
Come on! Move!
- Get on up!
- There they go.
Come on!
Move 'em along!
- Scottie,Jeff!.
- Yeah?
Drive the herd to the creek.
I'll meet you there.
- All right.
Whoa.
Afternoon, Mr. LaHaye.
Mayor Doros. Abel.
- What brings you out my way?
- Always cut to the chase, don't you?
That usually suits me best, Sam.
That's why we came
to see this man, Abel.
Always directly to the point and...
honest to a fault.
I don't think you rode all the way out here
just to pay me a compliment.
It's official business, Willie.
We need a sheriff
in Tettsford Junction.
If you're here for my official position
on the matter, I'd have to say I agree with you.
- I'm here to offer you the job.
- I'm no lawman, Doros.
Hear me out, Willie.
This job doesn't come without
its, uh, share of bonuses.
You get a good, steady paycheck.
- Why me?
- 'Cause people like ya.
And you could be persuasive
keepin' the peace, get the job done.
I appreciate it, but...
not interested.
See, I got my hands full lookin' after my herd
until we take 'em to market.
Well, I will be hirin' a sheriff, Willie.
And I'd like for that job to go
to a man with integrity, like yourself.
That way,you could help
your family and the town.
Just think about it, Willie.
I have a surprise for you today, boys and girls.
Someone has donated brand-new readers
for our whole class.
- Yes, Annie?
- Are they for our very own to keep?
Everyone will get
their very own copy...
to borrow for the rest of the year.
Would you like to help me
pass them out?
There you go.
That's right. Over there.
Now, I'd like for you
to open up your readers...
and write your name
on the inside cover.
Use pencil and use
your best penmanship.
- Mrs. LaHaye?
- Yes.
My reader's already
got a name in it.
It's says "Samuel H. Doros."
That's because it was Mayor Doros
who donated these readers.
Without his generosity,
we wouldn't have these new books.
All right, class.
I would like to start
with our penmanship.
Now let's begin.
Turn to page three.
Whoa.
Hey, Mandy.!
How much longer?
It should be any minute now.
- Look who's up from her nap.
- Oh.
Miss Kathy never wants to miss the fun.
Isn't that right?
Now I want you two
to be on your best behavior.
Just because we live in the Wild West
does not mean that we have to act like it.
I see 'em.! I see 'em!
Oh, he's here!
He's here!
Pa!
Whoa.
Come here, sweetheart.
Oh! Pa! You're here!
Oh, you're finally here!
I'm here.
I'm here, sweetheart.
Oh, you're a beautiful sight
for these eyes.
I promised your mother...
I would memorize this very moment.
Oh, Pa, I can't tell you
how much I've missed you.
Mama and the boys are fine,
and they wish they were here.
The cost of the trip
was just too much for all of us.
I wish they could've come, too...
but I am so glad that you
didn't wait any longer.
Your mother and I agreed that the timing
was right for me to make the journey.
And we know
that God's hand was in it.
"Cause suddenly
everything just fell into place.
And I'm here...
with you- my baby.
- Oh!
- My angel.
I missed you so much.
Oh! Come meet
all your grandchildren...
I've been writing to you about
all these years.
- You are still so beautiful.
- Hey, Grandpa. Hey.
- Hey.
This is Maddy.
Stagecoach was rough.
- I think I'll walk back, tell you the truth.
- Kathy's down for the night.
- Sounds like she gave up without a fight.
Oh, she's worn out from all the excitement
of meeting her grandpa today.
Well, it's been
pretty exciting for me too.
Marty and I have been
very grateful...
to get to know all of you
from Missie's letters.
But it's so nice to finally be able
to put the faces with the names.
All of us bein'apart,
it's been hard.
And I know you've had
some hard times.
But God's with us.
It's been a tough couple of years
for all the ranchers in the area.
Little or no rain
made the grazing scarce...
and the cattle plague
swept through the valley.
Thankfully, we have my teaching job
to help make ends meet.
We're just lookin' to hold out...
till we can drive the herd
to market in springtime.
Pray for a big payday.
Catch up on things.
I'll pray for that myself.
In the meantime,
I'm just thankful to be here.
How do you always manage to skedaddle
before you're finished getting dressed?
- Come here.
- Stir it around.
I might take your pa
and show him the herd this morning.
Not before I see
that baby granddaughter of mine.
- Rosy cheeks.
- I'll go get Kathy up.
It's a rare thing
she sleeps in this late.
- Morning.
- Mornin'.
Willie!
- Keep stirring.
- Willie!
Bring it over in here.
- What's wrong?
- She's not breathing.
- Kathy?
- Willie.!
- She's not breathing.!
- Kathy?
- Oh, my God!
-Jeff, get out! Kathy?
- Oh, my God.!
- Oh, baby, please!
- What?
- Kathy! Kathy, please!
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, God, no!
- No, Kathy. Please.
- Come here, son. Come here.
- Kathy.! Come on.!
Come on!
- Hold me tight.
Grief consumes us.
Emotions betray us.
Somehow, Lord...
let us rest in your promise...
your promise that Kathy
is safe in your arms...
safe in heaven...
where there are no tears, no pain...
no sudden death.
Only joy and peace...
and love.
Lord, please be with Missie
and Willie and their family.
Walk with them in their grief.
Hold them up when they falter.
Sustain them...
when they feel like...
giving up.
- Amen.
Watch your step.
- God bless you both.
I-I'm all right, Willie.
Really.
I'll be okay on my own.
You take good care of Kathy, Sonny.
Don't let her be scared or nothin'.
She's little, and she could
be awfully lonesome...
thinkin' that she's
missin' out on all the-
I'm Colette Doros.
I'm so sorry
about your little sister.
I'm afraid I don't know what to say.
- Me neither.
- I'm sorry.
Please accept my condolences, Mr. Davis.
It is such a tragedy.
I am sorry.
Thank you.
- Hello, sweetheart.
- Hi.
Uh, Mr. Davis,
this is my daughter, Colette.
Colette, this is Mr. Clark Davis-
Mrs. LaHaye's father and...
little Kathy's grandfather.
- I'm so sorry for your loss.
- Thank you.
- It's awful.
Colette is, uh- She's on break.
She's been refining her ways
at the Millington Finishing School back East.
Very good.
You know how it is with daughters.
They sure can break
their fathers'hearts.
In more ways than one.
The words were just right.
Good.
It's strange...
how in an instant
everything can change.
Makes a man unsure about...
anything and everything.
Mmm. Tough times all over.
I gotta say, when you hired me
a few years back...
I was workin' as a hand for ya-
It was a mite easier on the nerves
than having my own spread.
Now that I'm married
and Melinda's expectin'...
I realize how much is at stake...
how bad I want it to work out.
I put her to sleep just like always.
And then I checked on her right before
I went to sleep, and she was fine.
Then in the morning, I-
I went to get her up, and she-
she wasn't
She wasn't breathing.
I just want her safe...
and protected.
Missie.
I'll be fine.
That was a beautiful service, Henry.
Thank you.
Perhaps...
you should have stuck
to your previous vocation.
Judgin' by those
glorious words you spoke...
you know God a lot better
than you know cattle.
- Is she new?
- Gift to my wife from her father.
What a fine gift.
Where's Kathy?
Don't you remember?
- We told you. She's with the angels.
- In heaven?
- Yes, sweetheart.
- Why?
I don't know.
- Morning.
- Morning, Missie.
- Is Maddy asleep?
- Yes.
What are you doin'?
It's a school day.
I'm getting an early start for once.
Jeff, will you get my horse?
Missie, it's too soon.
Jeff, get my horse.
Missie, all right.
I didn't think you'd go back
to teaching quite yet.
Look, this is not my choice.
We need to work.
We need the money.
- Cookie. Will you keep a close eye
on Maddy for me today?
- Yes, ma'am.
Will you please move her cradle
and the rest of her things up into the barn?
I'll see you later.
Ho.
So? You're out here all alone?
Uh, I don't mind.
Helps me think things through
while I get my work done.
Moby Dick?
I think it's the best thing
Melville's ever written.
Yes. Ishmael and his whaling voyage.
As far as authors go,
I prefer Dickens.
I'm halfway through
Great Expectations.
"So the evening mists
were rising now...
"and in all the bright expanse
of tranquil light they showed to me...
I saw no shadow
of another parting from her."
Those are the last few lines
of the book.
I didn't mean to spoil
the ending for you.
You should keep reading though.
You shouldn't run full out
like that.
There's wheel ruts
and prairie dog holes.
You shouldn't worry about me.
I'm a very accomplished rider.
I was worried about him.
How's your father and mother?
Oh, they're-
- They're not my parents.
- They're not?
No. The LaHayes adopted me
when I was 1 1 ...
right after my older brother,
Sonny, died.
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
- Uh.
This horse- Looks familiar.
Mmm. Isn't he beautiful?
My father just bought him for me.
Will you be ready
for an adventure tomorrow?
What? Oh.
Yeah, probably.
Good.
See ya.
Mrs. LaHaye.
- Oh. What?
- You didn't get my picture.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's lovely.
It's your little girl
going up to heaven.
Why?
I'm done teaching.
I tried to do it today,
and I just... couldn't.
We'll be just fine.
Well, we might.
We might not.
I just know I can't go back.
Who is it, Abel?
It's LaHaye.
Willie.
I came about the sheriff position,
if the offer's still on the table.
Offer still stands.
Come on in.
Talk about the particulars.
"And Samson called
unto the Lord and said...
"O Lord God, remember me...
"I pray thee, and strengthen me.
- I pray thee, only this once, O God."
Pa!
Mmm! Hey, little man.
Pa, you're squeezin' me.
Cookie left some supper
on the stove for you.
Mayor Doros offered me a job today.
- What kind of job?
- They're needin' a sheriff.
- We didn't discuss it.
- Well, we need the money.
- Keep the ranch goin!
- Who's gonna run the ranch?
Scottie.
Missie, your finger's bleeding.
I didn't feel a thing.
William LaHaye, as sheriff
ofTettsford Junction...
your duties
will be wide and varied:
not limited to, but including,
keeping the peace...
executing court orders
and warrants...
seizure of debtors' property
when liens are due...
serving papers and posting notices
when called for.
Do you promise on your honor...
as your word is your bond
and the Bible is your conscience...
- to uphold these duties?
- I do.
As mayor ofTettsford Junction,
I declare you duly sworn in.
Congratulations, Sheriff LaHaye.
- Hi.
- Hello.
You look like someone
who could use a little adventure.
- Do I?
- Come on. Come with me.
- I- I can't. I've got a job to finish here.
- Do it later.
A man just doesn't up and quit
in the middle of a job.
A man is the master ofhis own day,
his own hours.
Makes up his own mind.
Come on.
Cookie.
You got some grub
I could take out to Scottie and Jeff?
I'm workin' on it as we speak.
- Maddy down for his nap?
- Yes, sir.
How's she doin'?
Well, sir, she won't eat...
and she won't come out of that room.
- It's like she just-
- It's like she just stopped.
It's like she just stopped.
Why don't we try to give her
some of your soup?
- It smells so good.
- Oh, yes.
Missie?
I've been praying...
for God to give you comfort.
- I brought something for you to eat.
- I can't.
Please. You gotta try,
even if you don't feel hungry.
Please, Pa,just leave me alone.
I can't do that, darlin'.
I love you too much.
Hi, Roy.
- Doros!
- Doros.! Get out here!
- Doros, you coward! Get out here!
Are you gonna run and hide...
or face me like a man, Doros?
You can't hide behind your money now,
can ya, huh?
Joe Paxson?
Is that you?
It's me. Who's that?
It's Willie LaHaye.
I'm the new sheriff.
Do some sheriffin'
and lock up that crook Doros.
Why don't you put the gun down?
We'll talk about that.
Talkin' don't save a man's land.
Bullets are the ticket!
Come on,Joe.
I got some coffee in my office.
And we can straighten this out...
get to the bottom
what's troublin' you.
- Doros is at the bottom of it.
Samuel
"Sell Me Down the River" Doros!
Listen,Joe.Joe.
You don't wanna give your-
your plan away like this.
He took my family.
Hey. You gonna help me, LaHaye?
Yeah. I'm gonna help you inside...
to some coffee and a good long nap.
It's all right.
You got one bad man
left in town, Willie.
Soup's gettin' cold.
- Stubborn.
- Yep.
Must be hundreds.
My mother had them shipped over
from her home in Boston.
Father always said
she lived and breathed books.
"The Complete Works
of William Shakespeare."
-Have you read much Shakespeare?
-Missie had me read Romeo and Juliet.
- It's so romantic, isn't it?
- Well, I read it a few years ago.
And at the time, I was more interested
in the poison and the dagger.
Well, perhaps if you read it now...
-you would be more interested in romance.
- Maybe so.
If you read it now,
you would see that...
though they're young,
they both knew their own hearts.
They knew that theirs was true love.
You can borrow it if you'd like.
- Really?
- I don't see why not.
I mean, I'm gonna
see you again, aren't I?
I'm afraid that some of those
are too fragile to be let out.
Jeff and I were out riding,
and I wanted to show him the library.
It's- It's like nothin'
I've ever seen.
Well, as you can see, this is also my office.
I have work to attend to.
Father, there are just a few more titles
I'd like to show Jeff.
I'm afraid it's gonna
have to wait, Colette.
- But, Father-
- It's fine.
Your father's a busy man.
- Good-bye, sir.
- Good-bye.
I am so sorry about that.
My father's not usually so rude.
Don't worry about it.
- I'll bring you the book next time I see you, okay?
- No. Better not.
It might upset your father.
I have been upsetting my father...
since I was old enough to tell him
what dress I wanted to wear.
You sound like a girl
who likes to be contrary.
I'm a woman
who knows what she wants.
And what would that be?
I'd like to spend
more time with you.
Uh, unless you don't want to.
I- I'm sorry if I'm coming off
like a spoiled brat.
- I-
- No.
No, I'd like that.
Colette.
Please, sweetheart, come on in.
Have a seat.
So, are you in the habit of, uh,
spending your time with strange young men?
He's hardly a strange
young man, Father.
I met him with you
at the LaHayes' ranch.
You been spending time
with him ever since?
I've seen him a couple of times.
Is being at home so tedious...
to where you have to spend your time
with the likes of him?
You just have to give him a chance.
He knows books
and ranching and horses.
You'll like him
once you get to know him.
That's hardly somethin'
that's likely to happen, baby.
'Cause you'll be goin'
back to school...
and he'll be goin' back to doin'
whatever it is that he does.
You're home late.
I didn't mean to wake you.
You didn't.
I'm just lying here thinking.
Willie.
Have you been able to cry
ever since Kath's-
No.
Come on in, Sheriff.
Mr. Doros been expecting you.
- Boys.
Sheriff LaHaye.
Hope you brought your appetite.
Pull up a seat.
All right. Thanks.
-Juanita.
- Sí?
- Más vino, por favor.
- Sí, señor.
I may have some pressing issues that, uh,
will need your attention shortly.
Seems that Henry and Melinda Klein
have me between a, uh
Shall we say a rock
and a hard place?
Henry and Melinda
are good friends of mine.
I'm sure they're good people.
But they gotta pay their debts
just like everybody else.
Had a bad spell last year.
See, Klein borrowed
a lot of money from me...
using his land and his livestock
as collateral.
They've missed several payments.
- How much does he owe?
- Enough.
He needs to pay me, or you need
to remove him from the premises.
LikeJoe Paxson?
I know about that ruckus
with him in town.
Drunken fool.
The man lost everything.
Even had to send his wife and daughter away
'cause he couldn't provide for 'em.
You know, when I was a boy...
I could remember goin' for days
without anything in my stomach.
And when I did have a meal...
hell, I couldn't even enjoy it...
because I was too busy worrying about
where my next meal would come from.
All because I had a father
that was weak.
He'd built everything up...
only to let someone
come in and take it from him.
I'm not my father, LaHaye.
You're sitting in the biggest house
for a hundred miles.
You know, the gap between me...
and the chance of poverty
will never be big enough to suit me.
And if that means tossing people
like Paxson off his land, then so be it.
And I refuse...
to let life take
a sucker punch at me.
See, we all make choices, LaHaye.
You know, take you, for instance.
You made the choice
to become sheriff...
keep food on your table
for your family.
Now, Paxson...
he chose to raise cattle...
which ended up
on another man's table.
- What?
- Oh, yeah.
When you get back to the jail...
you can thankJoe Paxson
for that steak.
Lunch was on him.
Gotta get back to town.
Oh, Sheriff.
Aren't you forgettin' something?
Now, those papers-
They give me the legal rights to claim
Henry Klein's property if he should default.
If he's got the money to pay me,
well, that's fine.
If not, then you do yourjob,
Sheriff...
and you give him notice.
Seven days,
and they vacate the premises...
leaving all their possessions-
including livestock- behind.
Well, you tell Doros...
I'll pay him
when I drive the cows to market.
That's still a month away.
Listen. The loan contract says
you gotta pay him something now.
You need to make
at least one payment.
Maybe something you could sell.
I sold everything
that's not tied down.
And, you know, Melinda's expecting.
Why didn't you tell me
things were so bad for you?
I guess I was praying for a miracle.
Doros will force this issue, Henry.
- He'll take your land.
- Over my cold, dead body.
That kind of talk
won't do your family any good.
The law says you've got seven days,
or else I have to remove you from your property.
- Hi, Pa.
- Mornin'.
You're up and out early.
I tell ya. Scottie-
He sure is one tough old man.
He's keepin'me busier than a farmer
with a broke plow and a lame horse.
You all right?
Trying to be, Pa.
Most times I just feel like there's
a dark cloud hanging over us...
I can't get out from under.
Just nagging doubts and...
shaken faith.
I feel like-
like Willie and I are pulling apart.
Losing a child-
That's the hardest pain
any parent can go through.
You just have to make sure...
that you don't let that dark cloud
overstay its welcome...
steal your joy, make you bitter.
It'll whisper lies
disguised as truth.
It will attempt to divide you...
from those that you love.
You know that you and Willie...
are both welcome back home
if you decide not to stay.
We will do everything in our power
to make sure you get a fresh start.
- Thank you, Pa.
- Hey.
You two have been working so hard
to make sure everything else gets done.
I guess that's it.
Well, you know where he is.
What do you mean?
I'm saying it might be high time
that you went to visit your husband.
The sheriff.
Now,you go freshen up,
and I'll saddle your horse. Okay, darling?
I can't stop, Colette.
How can I help?
Want to hand me
that hammer and a nail?
Well, you were right.
Colette and the LaHaye boy
been getting pretty cozy.
They're together right now.
He's gonna regret that.
Oh.
- Hey.
- I hope I'm not intruding.
- If this is a bad time to visit, I can come back.
- No. No.
It's really nice to see you, Melinda.
Please come in.
I'm sorry I haven't
stopped by until now.
- I've been an awful friend.
- Oh, no.
No. Please don't say that.
To be honest, I don't think I could have
dealt with the company before.
How are you and Henry...
and the baby?
Fine. Except for,
you know, the ranch, but-
- The ranch?
- Willie hasn't told you?
I don't really see Willie
that much nowadays.
Not since he's been working as sheriff.
Did you know that?
Mmm. He came by the other day.
What happened, Melinda?
Henry owes Sam Doros some money...
and he sent Willie
to come by to collect.
I'm sorry.
Really sorry, Melinda.
Last year, after the drought, um...
Doros paid Henry a visit...
and he made it seem like...
he wanted to help Henry
get back on track.
And like everybody,
we were hurting financially, so...
we took him up on his offer.
And now we're behind
on our payments.
And, uh-
And since Willie is sheriff, he's the one
who has to force us from our land.
- Willie won't do that.
- The sheriff doesn't have a choice.
What happens to Henry and Melinda
if they don't pay Doros on time?
Doros will foreclose on their ranch just like
he done toJoe Paxson and probably others.
I know this is awful for you.
I've been thinking
about going back to teaching.
- Oh.
- If I go back...
then you wouldn't have to do this
and be in this situation.
- You can't go back to teaching, Missie.
- Yes, I can. I can reopen-
No. No. Not now. Please.
Why? I don't understand.
I can't explain it.
I just need to know
you're here, safe.
I'll stay, Willie.
I'll stay.
Have you been praying for his help?
I can't seem to.
Maybe we should try
praying together.
What exactly would we
be praying for, Missie?
The only thing we both want...
we won't ever see again.
Don't let this be happening.
Oh, God, please.
Hey, Mandy.!
As you can see, Mr. Taylorson, everything
I brought with me is of the finest quality.
I'm sorry, Mrs. LaHaye,
but $1 3 is all I can do.
That still leaves me two dollars short
of what I need.
Well, that's entirely up to you.
But if it's worth
two dollars to you-
Watch your backs out there.
- What?
Okay. Wait.
Jeff? Jeff.
Jeff.
Jeff, what are you doing?
- I need to talk to you.
- How about a moonlight stroll?
I was hoping you'd say that.
I'm glad you could make it, Sheriff.
We both think
we're standing on our own land.
Henry, you knew this day was comin'.
You should have packed something...
gotten your goods together
so he couldn't have 'em.
I'm not goin' anywhere.
Come on.
Is this gonna take all day?
- Please.
- I know you're just doing your job, Willie.
Seems that me and Klein
have come to an impasse.
Abel.
You're too full of yourself
to realize...
that the user you are
is indeed being used.
To the grave you'll be dragged
by the seducer of your greed.
And when you're an old man...
you'll live off the memory of your usury
and your escapades...
too full of pride to admit...
you're nothin' but an empty shell.
I know men like you,
despising reproof.
Not that you were made that way.
But you rejected
what you were made for.
Here, Doros.
Here's enough
to keep us on our land.
Gives you another 30 days.
Oh, and by the way...
I used to be a good pastor.
But now I'm a rancher.
So why don't you get off my land?
Thirty days.
Ladies.
Abel.
Are you all right?
- I would have had to do it, Missie.
- I know.
Will you ride home with me?
I gotta get back to town.
Colette? Is that you?
- Hello, Father.
- Hey. Where you been?
-Just out riding.
- By yourself?
I'm gonna be surrounded by girls at school
in a few days, so I don't mind the solitude.
- I see.
- Well, if that's all, I'm gonna go change.
Well, there is one more thing.
It's a matter of conscience.
I had a change of heart
about that, uh, new horse I got you.
- You mean the one you took from the Kleins?
- Yeah. It's been, uh-
been on my mind
for the last couple of days.
I think the only right thing to do
is to give it back.
Father, that's wonderful.
Just find myself in a bit of a bind
as exactly how to do that.
Just give it back.
I am a businessman,
and I have a reputation, Colette.
Can't appear soft or indecisive.
I think the best way
to handle this situation is that...
if you were to give the horse
to that friend of yours,Jeff LaHaye, and...
well, have him return it
to the Kleins.
One more thing.
I'd rather nobody knew
it was my idea.
I won't tell.
Thank you, Father.
You're doing the right thing.
I know I am.
Missie.
Missie. Missie.
Come on out of the rain now.
You're gonna get pneumonia.
Come on now.
Come on inside.
Let's go.
Pa, no.
- Come on. Come on now.
- Pa, no. Le- Let me go.
Come on. You gotta go inside.
What's this about?
Please let me go.
I can feel it!
It's the rain! It's the drops!
I can feel it for the first time!
Why her?
I just don't understand.
Well, we're not always meant to.
You didn't even get to know her.
She was as sweet as an angel.
- I know.
- I just don't know what I'm doing anymore.
You're doin' it, little one.
- No, please.
- You're doin' it.
Whoa.
Frank. That china come in?
- Oh! Uh-
- Missie.
- I didn't know you were comin' in to town today.
I'm a little surprised myself.
Is it all right?
Um, yeah.
It's- It's fine.
Looks good.
It's just leftover ham.
- We-
- How's Maddy?
Keepin' Cookie on his toes.
That's good.
Lord, for the time
that we had her...
we thank you.
For all the days of our lives
that we will miss her...
we ask that your love
helps ease the ache in our hearts.
Amen.
-Jeff.
- Whoa.
I'm so glad you came.
You knew I'd come to say good-bye.
- It's only good-bye for a little while.
- I'm gonna miss you.
I'll miss you too.
- Oh, I brought you something.
- Oh, but I don't-
It's two things, actually, but they're
not gifts in the traditional sense...
because you can't keep them.
Here.
- Oh, Colette, I can't take this.
- Please take it.
Read Romeo and Juliet again.
For me.
Thank you.
Oh. Here.
Here.
I want you to take my horse
and give it back to Mrs. Klein.
- But, Colette, your father-
- My father gave me this horse.
Now I want to give it back.
I should go.
Oh. I- I'll give you a leg up.
Okay.
Thanks.
Come on.
- Write me.
- But I don't have your address.
Shakespeare does.
Huh!
Bye, Father.
I'll see you in a few months.
Looks like we got us a horse thief.
Let's go get him, boys.
Oh.
Get up.
-Jeff. Is that right?
- You know my name.
Abel here tells me he caught you
stealing one of our horses- red-handed.
Like I told him...
Colette gave me the horse
to return it to the Kleins.
This must have been a conspiracy
that you made up with the Kleins.
I mean, them being as good a friends
to your family and all.
Henry and Melinda don't know
anything about this.
Listen to me, son.
I can't help you
unless you get honest with me.
You wanna know
what we do to horse thieves?
We're gonna handle
this one by the books.
I'm taking you into town.
That sheriff ain't gonna do
nothin' to one of his own.
William LaHaye is a man of the law.
And, uh, I don't have any doubt...
he'll do the right thing.
Now get this trash out of my house.
Whoa. Steady now.
I think we're gonna have a healthy crop this year.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Did you seeJesse?
Be sure he gets the chain where he needs it.
Get on down, sonny.
Come on. We got a long day ahead of us.
Git.
Jeff.
Well, I got another prisoner
for you, Sheriff.
You need to lock him up
until the federal marshal arrives.
Get your hand off my boy.
My men-They caught him
dead to rights on a stolen horse.
Oh, it's true enough.
I'm an eyewitness along with my men.
And the last I heard, horse thieves-
They get the noose around these parts.
But I might be willin'
to drop the charges as long...
as he leaves and never returns.
Just slow down, Doros. I mean, there's
gotta be some kind of misunderstanding.
No. No, there's no misunderstanding.
I mean, the boy- He took my horse.
That's my property.
You both would swear to that
in front of a judge?
- On a stack of Bibles.
- You're gonna take my boy away from me?
I'd send my own daughter to jail...
if I knew she was a thief.
You can't let something like family
interfere with the law, LaHaye.
You know, Doros...
for once I agree with you.
Well-
How could you?
Colette, baby.
I put you on that stage myself.
Oh, I stopped the stage.
I can, you know.
When I happened to see the horse
in my corral, I asked Jeff about it.
He told me Colette wanted to give the horse
back to the Kleins.
See, I knew a snake like you
just might be up to something.
Something that might
get my boy into trouble.
So I went after Colette
as a witness.
Just in case there was
any kind of misunderstanding.
Looks like I make a better sheriff
than even I knew.
What are you gonna do? I mean,
do you honestly think you could get...
my daughter...
to testify against me?
Colette.
It's like you said, Father.
You can't let something like family
get in the way of the law.
Colette.
What do you want, LaHaye?
These are my terms.
That's one of my favorite dresses on you.
Thank you.
I think you forgot somethin'.
Turn around.
Oh!
Now you look perfect.
- How?
- Well, you stopped wearing the locket...
about the time Henry and Melinda
came up with the money for Doros.
I just figured it out.
- You didn't tell Henry or Melinda-
- No.
No. That's still your secret.
How did you get it?
We don't have any money.
Got my first paycheck.
Couldn't think of anything else
we needed more.
Thank you.
Thank you for getting it back.
- There you go, Cookie.
- Thank you.
Oh, everything looks so good.
Everything looks good.
All these nice rolls and
- How are you?
- Good, Melinda. How are you?
- Nice party.
- Yeah. Lots of happy folks.
Yes,you batter that chicken up
with some nice cayenne pepper-
- Smells so good.
- Hey, you boys! Get out of here!
You come around here
stealing all of my chicken.
You're worse than
an old fox in a henhouse.
You gonna come round here
gettin' the best part of my chicken too.
Excuse me.
Mr. Paxson.
Can I get you anything?
Well, I'd say you and your husband
done plenty for me, ma'am.
I'm back at my ranch.
- Oh, I'm so happy for you.
- Yeah.
I telegraphed
my wife and daughter...
told 'em we got a roof
back over our heads again, and, uh...
got a message back
saying they're coming home.
- That is so wonderful.
- Yeah, it is.
Excuse me. Please.
Sure.
Tell you what. It's gonna
take me a month of Sundays...
when I get home for me
to tell your mother about my trip.
Oh, well, you could make plans
to stay and make some more memories.
Oh. There'll be future visits.
I promise you that.
Now, in the meantime,
I seem to recall...
that I taught my little girl
how to dance once upon a time.
- Oh!
Whoo-hoo!
Take care of yourself, son.
Come here, you.
Oh, my goodness.
You're gettin' big.
- You mind your folks.
- Okay.
- I love you.
- I love you too, Grandpa.
Thank you for all the help.
Made a huge difference
when all of us were in a bad way.
I seem to recall
you doing it for me once.
- You have a safe trip.
- You too, son.
- Say hi to Marty for me.
- I will.
That was bound to happen.
- Give Mom a big hug for me.
- I will.
And Arnie. And Aaron.
Oh, I will.
Oh. I'm so thankful
that you were here with us, Pa.
- I don't know what we would
have done without you.
There are no mistakes, Missie.
God's timing is always perfect.
Even if we don't
realize it at the time.
Come here.
I don't want to let go.
You keep those cards and letters comin',
you hear?
Especially now that I can place
those beautiful faces with the names.
I love you, sweetheart...
- more than anything in the world.
- I love you too, Pa.
Bye.
Go get your sister.
- Bye, sweetheart.
- Bye.
Hup, Lucy! Hup, Dobbin!