[ Bird Cawing ]
Subtitle by: R3V0LV3R
[ Horse Whinnying ]
Good-bye.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
[ Snorting ]
[ Hissing ]
[ Whinnying ]
Wha- [ Grunts ]
Hyah!
[ Grunting ]
Whoa, boys! Whoa!
Whoa!
[ Panting ]
Whoa.
Clark?
What on earth happened to you?
I'm afraid my day wasn't much productive.
- You all right?
- Snakes spooked the horses...
so l lost most of the water.
I'm sorry, Clark.
Pa, you're home!
[ Grunts ]
it's okay. I'm fine now though.
I'm gonna unhitch the wagon
and get washed up for dinner.
Good, 'cause supper's almost ready.
Okay.
Who is that?
Missy, go on inside.
Why?
Mr. Davis. Mrs. Davis.
Mr. Harris, what brings you out here?
I figured I'd come out here after the bank
closed and discuss a few things with you.
Now, as you both know,
you've fallen behind...
on paying back the loan
that you took out with the bank.
Yes, sir, we're aware
we're a few payments behind...
but l can assure you
that when the weather shifts...
we're gonna make
those payments and then some.
You've missed more than a few payments.
We don't intend to be a burden on you.
We would much prefer to make
those payments on time.
I trust that is the truth,
but l can't be leaving it for any longer.
Now, make the payments or the bank
will be forced to seize your land.
- Mr. Harris, please understand-
- There's nothing to understand.
You signed a loan, which clearly states...
that you would make
the agreed upon payments every month.
Good night, pumpkin.
Good might, Ma. Love you.
Things will turn around.
This farm has been in my family for a long time.
We need the rain, Ellen, and rain soon.
I want you to know how much l appreciate
all the hard work you do for Missy and me.
I'm not real sure what we're gonna do next.
I could take the job that Mr.
Connor offered me as a seamstress in town.
Absolutely not.
I don't want you working in town.
We've discussed this.
It's the man's place to provide.
Clark, you can't control the weather.
When l took that loan...
l just assumed it was gonna rain
and things were gonna turn around.
This drought won't last forever.
Things will get better.
I have faith in that.
Well, l hope that faith holds up
when my folks get here.
I know my ma can be a bit
of a handful sometimes.
[ Laughs ]
[ Rooster Crowing ]
You're gonna be just fine.
[ Man ]
Playing poker tomorrow night!
Hey, Jed.
Good morning, Mr. Connor.
Ellen. Good morning.
Let me help you with that.
Come here, boy.
Thank you.
How are you?
I'm well. And you?
I'm excellent.
So, are you, uh...
ready to begin a wonderful day
of work, l trust?
I'm absolutely ready.
That's good, because l already have
some projects for you to work on.
- Well, I'm looking forward to it.
- That's good.
Please. After you.
You can work here.
Wow.
[ Sighs ]
What a beautiful work of art.
I wanna thank you again, Mr. Connor.
Would you please call me Bruce?
Well, then, thank you once again, Bruce.
[ Chattering ]
[ Man ]
Let me give you a hand, Dave!
Whoa!
All right?
Ben, how are you? Clint, Ronnie.
We're good. Thanks.
What brings you to town?
Well, Ellen's working at Connor's,
and my folks are in town.
Been a while since l seen them.
Sarah.
You know Ellen Davis, don't you?
Of course.
Bruce, this is a small town.
Don't you think everyone
knows everybody who lives here?
Okay, since you two are
already acquainted...
then, Ellen, you must know
how quiet and shy Sarah is.
Quiet and shy.
[ Laughing ]
Bruce told me someone else
was coming to work here.
He didn't say that it was you.
Well, Clark and l could use the extra money,
and, frankly, l don't mind the work.
I love sewing. I always have,
ever since l was a young girl.
Well, that's a good thing
since you will be doing plenty of it.
I thought you mostly did midwife work.
Well, there hasn't been much of a call
for a midwife lately.
I pick up work here when things are slow.
[ Doorbells Jingle ]
[ Clark ] Mr. Connor.
Clark.
[ Door Closes ]
- What a pleasure to see you.
- You as well.
I just came by to see Ellen
for one moment if that's okay.
Yeah, of course.
Clark. Where's Missy?
She's with Ben and the boys
down at the general store.
Your folks are gonna be here soon.
- l came by to see if their room's ready.
- Oh, isn't that wonderful?
A son making sure that his folks
are taken care of.
- [ Clark ] Sarah.
- Hello, Clark.
- It's good to see you.
- You as well.
Come on. Let's go see your mama.
How's the first day going?
I made a pattern for a new dress,
and l already started sewing it.
Well, that is impressive.
Mama!
Hello, pumpkin.
[ Missy Giggling ]
Did you miss me?
Of course l did.
Missy, let's let these ladies
get back to work.
I'll be home as soon as l can.
- Bye, sweetheart.
- Bye, Mama.
Ladies.
Ben.
Good-bye, Mr. Graham.
Pa, they're here!
Come on, Missy.
Whoa, baby. Whoa.
Clark, my dear, sweet boy.
- [ Grunts, Laughs ]
- [ Kisses ] it's good to see you.
- How are you?
- Grandma!
Oh!
Oh, my goodness,
how you've grown, like a rose.
Yes, but I'm all grown up now.
Oh, l can see that, my darling.
- Well, don't l get a hug?
- Grandpa!
Yeah, look at you! [ Laughs ]
Oh, look at you. [ Laughs ]
Well, Son, it's been far too long
since we've seen you.
Good to see you, Pa.
Let me grab your bags, help you get settled.
- Where's Ellen?
- She's at work.
- Work?
- At home?
At the tailor's.
- We've been waiting for you.
- I can see that.
Hello, sweetheart.
Mmm!
Come here.
[ Kisses ]
Your folks get in all right?
[ Sighs ]
They're actually already here.
I'm late?
And I'm the wife who didn't make supper?
Your ma's gonna have
something to say about that.
[ Clark ]
Oh, she'll be fine. Don't worry about her.
- You all washed up?
- Yes, ma'am. Pa made me.
Then what are we waiting on?
Let's go eat.
- So, how was your first day?
- I enjoy working with Sarah.
- Yeah?
- You know she's a widow.
Yeah.
- You know Ben's a widower.
- Mm-hmm?
- Yeah, he has two kids too.
- Mm-hmm.
Ellen, don't get any ideas.
Well, hello, Lloyd.
Ellen. Oh! So good to see you.
- It is so good to see you.
- [ Chuckles ]
Look at you.
- How was your trip in?
- Oh, not bad. Not bad at all.
I do have to admit though.
The old back does need a good night's rest.
Irene, it is so wonderful to see you.
Ellen.
- I'm sorry I'm late.
- I understand you're working.
I am. Today was my first day.
You know, in my time,
a woman really wouldn't...
- Mwah!
- Oh, my! [ Laughs ]
- Stop.
- What do you say we eat?
- Just go sit down.
- [ Chuckling ]
Are you sure you're gonna be okay
staying in town?
Oh, my, yes.
We don't wanna impose.
[ Gasps ]
I almost forgot.
I brought you something.
I'll be here in the morning.
- No, Pa, you don't have to do that.
- Now, look, look...
I've been around long enough to know
that if the wife has to take a job...
things aren't going as
well as they could be.
- 8:00?
- I'll be here.
There.
She's beautiful, Grandma. I love her.
- Thank you.
- Oh, good. I'm so glad.
- Look, Mom.
- She's lovely.
Thank you. I made her special for you.
I will keep her with me always.
Thank you so much, Grandma.
Oh!
Pa, look what Grandma made for me.
- I see that. What's her name gonna be?
- I don't know. I just got her.
[ All Laughing ]
Come on. We better get going.
It's a long way into town.
[ Kisses ] Time to get up.
[ Laughs ]
- Mm.
Just give me a little bit more time.
I'm so tired.
I'd let you sleep as long as you'd like...
but as soon as l do,
the rooster you hate so much...
[ Rooster Crowing ]
gonna start crowing.
[ Crowing ]
One of these days, you're gonna come back
from working in the field...
and you're gonna find
that rooster's your supper.
[ Both Laughing ]
Just give me a little more time to sleep.
- I'm so tired.
- Okay.
Missy and I'll go grab some milk, and then
we'll wake you when we come back.
I do love you so.
I love you too.
- Go back to sleep.
- Mmm.
Son, why didn't you tell us
you were having trouble with the land?
A man's gotta stand on his own.
I didn't wanna come begging for help.
Yep, a man does have to go off and...
find his way, make his own life.
But he shouldn't forget where he come from.
I didn't want you to think
l couldn't take care of my family.
Son, l would never.
- So, how long has this well been dry anyway?
- It's been a spell.
Just had enough for the garden
and the animals from the creek.
But... it's been
barely enough to sustain us.
Well, have you tried
digging a little deeper into the well?
Yes, sir, but... l hit rock.
Yeah, well, l noticed you, uh...
you dug another one out in the field
in front of the house.
- Yes, sir, same problem.
- Well, l think l may know of a way...
to get you some water without having
to dig wells all over creation.
Your old man knows a thing or two
about dealing with a drought.
What do you think, hmm?
Oh, it's beautiful.
You are truly an artist.
Why, thank you.
- Can l ask you something, Sarah?
- Certainly.
- Your husband, he passed on a couple of years back.
- Yes.
He's still in your heart?
He will always be in my heart.
What l meant was...
do you ever see yourself
with somebody else?
Remarrying, l mean?
At first l didn't.
No, the pain was so strong.
I couldn't imagine a time...
when l could be open to someone else.
But time has a way of changing things
without you knowing.
[ Laughs ]
it took some time, but, uh...
l think the Lord has allowed
my aching heart to heal.
Ben Graham lost his wife.
He's a good man, a good father.
And he is a rather
handsome man, l must say.
So you said your well is,
what, about 25 feet?
Well, l was able to dig five more,
but then l ended up hitting rock.
All right, so that's about 30.
I figure, uh, this land
being more elevated like it is...
we'll have to go down about 40, 45 feet...
in order to even have a
hope of hittin' water.
That deep, huh?
Well, let's get to it.
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
[ Both Grunting ]
So, how's that neighbor of yours, Ben?
- He having a tough time of it too?
- Well...
- the drought hit him pretty hard, but...
- Yeah?
Somehow he was able to hit water though.
Well, we will too.
- l hope so.
- [ Grunts ]
Lord, this ground is hard.
- Bye, Sarah.
- Evening, Ellen.
- See you in the morning.
- Good night.
Mr. Harris.
- l have good news for you.
- Really?
Yes. Be making payment on Friday.
I heard about your job
over here at Mr. Connor's.
You- [ Coughing ]
Mrs. Davis?
I'm fine. It's just this dry weather.
Ah. Well, evenin'.
Evening.
[ Coughing ]
- Good night, pumpkin.
- Good night, Ma.
What time in the morning
do you want me out here?
- l think Ben's gonna be over around 7:30.
- All right.
- See if Ben and the boys wanna come
to supper on Saturday. - I will.
- l could help you with that if you'd like.
- That would be wonderful, lrene.
I could help with the eating of it.
Now, there's something you're good at.
If y'all excuse me,
I'm feeling a bit tired. I'm gonna turn in.
If you're so tired, maybe you shouldn't
be working at that tailor shop.
No, I'll be fine, really.
It's just gonna take some getting used to, is all.
- You look pale.
- Really, I'm fine. I just need some rest.
We should be going. Uh, it's getting late.
We got a long ways back to town.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night.
- Good night, dear.
- Good night, lrene.
Son?
Ma.
[ Ben ] it was mighty nice of Ellen
inviting us over for dinner Saturday.
I haven't had
a good home-cooked meal in a while.
Except the ones l cook.
I'm not sure how good those are.
[ Laughs ] So I've heard.
- Ben, l appreciate you coming out here.
- It's in my own best interest.
I think l might try this out in my far
field before l start digging another well.
Whew!
- How's Ellen doing working?
- She seems a little tired.
Well, then you make her stay home
till she feels better.
Oh, she won't do that.
I learned a long time ago
l can't tell Ellen what to do.
Well, as long as she ain't too tired
to cook dinner on Saturday.
[ Laughs ]
That was mighty kind of you.
Well, I'm just saying
I'm looking forward to that dinner.
Will you two stop clucking away
like a couple of hens?
We got work to do here.
I invited someone else.
- Who?
- Sarah and her young'uns.
Thought it'd be nice for them to play
with Missy and Ben's boys.
Sure you did.
I thought we talked about that, Ellen.
We did. I just didn't agree to anything.
I guess you didn't.
- It sure looks good, Ellen.
- Aw, thank you.
- [ Horse Whinnying ]
- Looks like your other guests are here.
Huh! Huh! Huh!
Sarah!
So glad you could make it.
- Well, thanks so much for invitin' us.
- Of course. It's my pleasure.
- Here. We brought you a little something.
- Thank you.
Oh, these are Clark's folks.
- lrene, Lloyd, this is Sarah.
- Nice to meet you.
- It's a pleasure.
- [ Lloyd Chuckles ]
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
Kids, come on! Supper's on!
I ever tell you the story
of the hunting trip l did with my pa...
- up in the mountains back in the early days?
- [ Children ] No.
- He had these two hound dogs-
- Oh, thank you, darling.
You're welcome.
- [ Laughs ]
- Your Laura's a lovely girl.
Right. She is.
- She reminds me a lot of her father.
- Really?
How so?
She has his eyes.
I can still see him when she looks at me.
They make a handsome couple,
don't they?
Yes, l suppose they do.
Aren't you glad l meddled?
- I'm not gonna answer that.
- [ Laughs ]
You still miss him?
Well, there was a time
when all l did was miss him.
At some point, you just gotta get on
with the business of livin'.
Yeah.
How about you?
You still think about their mama?
Every day. But you're right.
Time has a way of healing that pain.
I miss her differently now than l did.
It's more- it's more peaceful.
Yeah.
There before me was a
gigantic black bear...
standing up on his hind feet.
- He looked like he was 10 feet tall to me.
- [ Children Gasping ]
l was about your size, you know.
What could l do?
[ Labored Breathing ]
You're up.
No sense in letting
a perfectly good day go to waste.
Your folks, are- are they here yet?
No. No. Uh, not yet.
- Are you feeling any better?
- A little.
Tired, is all.
Feels like you're running
a little bit of a fever.
Feel a tad warm.
Feels more than a tad warm.
Won't you go rest?
And I'll make you some tea.
And then I'll head into town
and grab some fixings for supper.
Okay. Thank you.
[ Clark ]
Yes, sir. Well, you have a good day now.
- Afternoon, Clark.
- Ben, how are you?
- Good, good. Good to see you.
- Good to see you.
Looks like you and Sarah
got along pretty well the other night.
Yes, we did.
She's a fine woman.
She certainly is. Uh, excuse me.
Yeah.
Good afternoon, Sarah.
Ben.
I was hoping to get your permission
to call upon you sometime.
Why, Mr. Graham,
how very forward of you.
And it would seem
that you are calling on me right now.
I'm sorry, ma'am. It's just l...
- l was teasing you.
- Oh.
You can certainly call on me sometime.
I look forward to it.
[ Ellen ] So you put the two
pieces of fabric together...
and you cut out the pattern...
of the shape of the head
and the arms and the legs...
and then l sew it,
and then l stuff it all with cotton...
to make it all filled out.
You feel any better?
I'm feeling a little tired still, but...
l think with a little more rest,
I'll be fine to work in the morning.
Work in the morning?
- Mm-hmm.
- Like you're in any condition.
- Clark, we need the money.
- But you can afford to miss a day or two.
We'll see how l feel in the morning.
Okay. Go back to sleep.
- I love you, Clark.
- I love you too.
Okay.
[ Coughing ]
Well, about there.
- Good morning, lrene.
- Good morning.
- Have a good day.
- You too, Ellen.
Whew!
Oh, it's better now.
Ellen!
- Ellen, sweetheart, can you hear me?
- Ellen.
Ellen. Ellen.
All right, Son,
let's get her in the house. Come on.
- Come on. You got her?
- Up we go.
Pa, what happened?
- Pa!
- Ma!
What happened?
Oh, my- What happened?
- I don't know.
- [ Irene ] Put her down.
[ Clark ] The doctor's away.
Sarah's a midwife.
She knows a little about medicine.
I'll-I'll get some cold cloth.
You sit with her.
All right.
Ellen. Ellen?
Pa!
Is Mom gonna be okay?
Missy, I know you're scared.
She's gonna be fine. I promise.
- Hyah! Come on!
- Pa!
Pa!
She's on fire.
Sarah. It's Ellen.
I don't like how this looks.
You know, uh, l am not a doctor...
but that looks to me like scarlet fever.
Scarlet fever?
I thought she looked awful peaked.
- What can we do?
- She needs rest.
Keep her warm.
Only time can tell.
Keep Missy away from her.
She's younger, weaker.
Don't let her near Ellen.
Is there anything else?
Just rest and prayers.
Mine will be with her.
I'll let you two be.
Come on now.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Mm-hmm.
Missy, can l talk to you for a second?
Yes, Pa?
Missy, you wanna sit down?
[ Sighs, Clears Throat ]
Missy, uh...
Ma's very sick right now.
She may be, uh, contagious.
Do you know what that means?
That other people can get sick too?
That's right.
I'm afraid you're not gonna be able to go
and see her until she gets well, okay?
I won't get sick. I promise.
I know. Um...
She just needs all the strength
she can get right now.
I won't make her tired.
I can help take care of her.
Missy, l need you to do this for me, okay?
Please.
You think that I'm just a little girl
and l can't do anything.
But l can help. She's my ma.
[ Owl Hooting ]
You're gonna be fine out here?
You know you can go stay with
Grandma and Grandpa in town if you want.
I'd rather be in with Ma.
I know. As soon as she gets well,
you better go in there, okay?
Okay.
I love you, pumpkin.
Good night.
Go back to sleep.
I've been sleeping all day.
I know, but you need your rest.
Has Missy gone to sleep yet?
Yeah.
She's off to bed.
[ Ellen ] Well, l...
[ Clark ]
Try not to think about her.
[ Ellen ] l hope it doesn't
feel too strange to her...
out there in the dining room area.
[ Clark ]
Just get yourself better.
Get a good night's sleep.
[ Ellen ]
l know you've done your best.
[ Clark ]
l think you're gonna be just fine.
[ Ellen ] How is she taking it?
Does she seem all right?
[ Clark ]
She's doing just fine.
She's a little girl,
and she's just worried about her mama.
She was upset when l told her
she couldn't be in here.
- ls she still upset?
- Of course.
She wants to help her mother
the same way you've always helped her.
You shouldn't be taxing
yourself about this.
Just get some rest, okay?
- [ Door Opens ]
- Clark.
Please don't go.
I need you.
Will you stay a while?
I will forever be by your side.
Missy.
Honey, you know you're
not supposed to be in here.
I'll be as quiet as a field mouse.
I won't disturb you. I promise.
I know, pumpkin.
But it's for your own good.
I can't have you getting sick.
Go on.
Your pa has his hands
full taking care of me.
We can't both be sick.
Missy, go on now.
Missy, what did l tell you
about coming in here?
But, Pa, l was just trying to help!
Clark, don't be mad at her.
I'm not mad. I'm worried.
You all right?
You're upset 'cause they
won't let you see her, huh?
They won't let me do anything.
They're just worried
about you gettin' sick, pumpkin.
- Pa's in there all the time.
- I know.
But that's what your pa is here for.
And it's hard for him to do
what needs to be done...
and still be worrying about you.
You know what l think
you could do for him...
that would probably help him the most?
No. What?
You can be strong.
Do what he says...
even though it hurts
your feelings right now.
Can you do that?
I'll try.
Good girl.
Your supper's getting cold.
I'm gonna check on Ellen.
[ Softly ] Clark.
Sorry we woke you.
It's okay.
There's some things l wanna tell you.
What things?
I wanna thank you.
You've given me so much love in my life.
Clark.
You're gonna be okay.
I've lived a great life.
And it is because of you.
And l don't have any regrets.
I'm gonna be all right.
I just need to know that
you'll be all right.
I need you to promise me something.
I need you to promise me...
that you will keep your heart open.
You are one of the most
loving and giving men.
And l couldn't bear
for that part of you to die with me.
Don't talk about dying.
Promise me, Clark.
I need you to promise me.
Not just for me...
but for Missy's sake.
She'll need someone to show her...
that love doesn't leave this world...
with the passing of just one person.
Please, Clark.
I promise.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Lloyd ] For as much as it hath pleased
Almighty God of his great mercy...
to take unto himself the soul
of our dear Ellen here departed...
we therefore commit her body to the earth.
Earth to earth, ashes to
ashes, dust to dust...
in sure and certain hope
of the resurrection to eternal life.
Anyone who knew Ellen would know...
that... she was one
of the most special people...
you could ever have the
good fortune to know.
Strong-willed, certainly.
Kind...
beyond words.
She was a friend to a great many...
but even more so a
blessing to her husband...
and a true light to her daughter.
To say that we shall miss her dearly...
doesn't even measure up.
But it is the truth.
We will all miss you, Ellen.
God bless you.
[ Ellen ] This is our home.
And it will always be.
You are a wonderful man.
I love you, Clark.
Clark?
Yeah, Pa.
[ Sighs ] Uh...
[ Sighs ]
l can't seem to get any sleep.
[ Sniffs, Clears Throat ]
[ Sighs ]
Something on your mind?
Yeah.
I want to make an offer to you.
Now, l know how hard all of this
must be for you, and...
You know, if it's too much to bear...
you and Missy are more than welcome
to move back home with us.
I am home, Pa.
But, Son, this place might be filled
with too many memories.
That's why l can't leave.
Ellen...
She loved it here.
This was our home.
Pa, we'll be all right.
What'd he say?
He says he's stayin'.
Well...
guess we'll be staying a while too.
We're family.
Well- [ Sighs ]
we'll get our things tomorrow, huh?
There you go.
Shouldn't take us long
to collect our things and check out.
Mr. Davis, can l have a moment?
[ Sighs ] Ma, will you take
Missy inside for a minute?
Everything all right?
Just take her inside.
Yes, dear.
Now- [ Sighs ]
l know this is a difficult time.
But, uh, this is rather a discreet matter.
I'm his pa.
Whatever you need to say,
you can say it in front of me.
All right.
Now, you're well aware
that you went for some time...
without making a payment on your loan.
Then Mrs. Davis took a job in town
and you were able to make one payment.
Now, with her passing...
l need to know how you intend
to repay your debt.
My wife passed only days ago,
and you're gonna come to me with this?
I cannot let this continue...
without some way of knowing
how the bank will be repaid.
Now, quite frankly...
don't have much faith that you're gonna
be able to make even the next payment...
now that your wife is deceased.
[ Man ] Whoa, boy.
Whoa, now. Come on. Easy.
This doesn't change anything.
Payment is due the first of the month.
[ Lloyd ]
You did the right thing.
- Need a break?
- Actually, that's a good idea.
I wanted to talk to you...
about yesterday.
Should've never touched him.
- l let my emotions get the best of me.
- Yeah, that's true enough.
But I'm more interested
in what that banker said.
I mean, you told us that
you had money problems, but...
according to that bank man
you could lose your land.
We want to help you.
What can we do?
I appreciate the offer.
Your being here's a big help, but l have
to pay back that money, plain and simple.
Plus, l know you and Ma
are struggling to get by too.
Yeah, that's the truth.
You know that if we had the money we'd be
giving it to you straightaway.
I know.
I'm gonna figure something out.
I don't want you worrying about me.
That's what parents do.
Can you imagine a moment
when you won't be worrying about Missy?
Hmm? Course not.
No, a parent's job may be over when...
children have gone off
to make their lives, but...
you never stop worrying.
Or caring.
It's like breathing for me and your ma.
I know you're right.
I just don't want...
Hey.
Come on. Enough of this chitchat.
Let's get back to work. What do you say?
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
Got a lot of water to haul in.
Come on.
Missy, you haven't touched your food.
I'm not hungry.
You should try and eat something.
May l be excused?
Yes.
That poor child.
Clark...
have you thought that maybe this isn't
the best place for her right now?
I don't follow.
[ lrene ]
I'm worried about her.
She's a little girl.
You're gonna be out on
the farm all day long.
And there are so many things
that have to be done around here.
Look, maybe, um...
maybe she could come stay with us,
if need be.
At least until things pick up around here.
Would you think about it?
Morning, Pa.
Pumpkin, what are you doing up so early?
Oh, well, l thought l could help.
What you want to help with?
Cathy thought we could
help around the house more with chores.
- ls that her name? Cathy?
- Yep.
Why don't you and Cathy go see if Grandma
has some chores for y'all to do?
- We can?
- Sure.
- Thanks! Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- Grandma!
- Morning, Pa.
Good morning, Son. Let's get to it.
[ lrene ]
Well, we got a lot of work to do.
First thing we're gonna
do is sweep up in here.
I already know how to sweep.
- Oh, you do?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, good.
I'm gonna relax.
[ Sighing ]
l might even take a nap. Yes. Mm-hmm.
[ Chuckles ]
Grandma, don't be silly.
What?
Me silly?
[ Chuckles ] Come here, you.
- Oh, I love you, my girl.
- I love you too.
- That's a good thing.
- Why?
- 'Cause we have to get to work.
- [ Chuckles ]
Oh.
[ Blows Raspberry ] Forgot my broom.
[ Both Laugh ]
Get that on tight.
- l got it up here.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
- There we go.
Here we go.
Couple more turns now.
Here we go. Couple more.
Just about there.
- [ Grunts ]
- There we go.
There you are.
Whoo!
Come on. Come on now.
Help us find it, Lord.
Help us find it.
Come on, Lord.
Nothin'!
Well, it just means we have to try
some wheres else is all.
You know what, Pa?
I think we've looked just about everywhere.
Well, just about everywhere
isn't the same as everywhere.
Oh, giving up hope is for the hopeless.
Pa, l know Ellen
would want me to have faith right now.
I'm having a tough time.
Your grandma used to tell me that when
things would seem to overwhelm me...
to slow down and focus on the task
in front of you.
Take care of it and move
on to the next one.
Things don't seem so impossible.
That's great advice.
As long as you can control things.
My task is to get water, and l can't!
Well, sometimes, Son,
you can't always have control.
Sometimes you just have to accept it...
let it go.
Let it go, Son.
Coat the chicken in the
egg, just like that.
Then you roll it in the bread crumbs.
'Cause that's how it makes that nice crispy
stuff we like on the outside of it.
All right. Now you try one.
- Grandma?
- Mm-hmm?
Do you think l did good on my chores today?
Oh, you did better than good.
You did exceptional.
I believe you could do
just about anything you set your mind to.
- Do you think Pa knows that?
- Course he does.
Oh, that's perfect.
I'm gonna let you finish up here...
and I'll go get the boys
and have 'em come in for supper.
When l get back, I'll fry up that chicken.
And I'm gonna tell your pa
what a good job you did today.
[ Horse Whinnying In Distance ]
[ Fat Sizzling ]
Gentlemen?
Well, Mrs. Davis...
what brings your beautiful self out here?
Well, l just came out to report that
Missy did a tremendous job today.
- Really?
- Don't look so surprised. She's smart as a whip.
- Got gumption too.
- [ Chuckles ] That she does.
We're gonna have the best supper ever.
Pa's gonna be so proud of me.
[ Chuckling ]
it's gonna be so goo...
[ Gasps ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Whimpers ]
Pa! Grandma!
Grandma! Pa!
[ Whimpering ]
So, um, how about fried chicken for dinner?
Oh.
That sounds good to me.
[ Chuckles ]
- Don't be long now.
- [ Lloyd ] Nope.
Oh, dear God, Missy! Clark!
Pa! Grandma!
Pa! Pa!
- Missy!
- [ Irene ] Missy!
Pa. Pa!
Ma, take her!
[ Crying ]
[ Gasps ] Okay.
[ Grunting ]
- Clark!
- [ Coughing ]
Here.
It's okay. It's okay, hon.
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Crying ]
Come out of there, boy!
Clark!
Pa.
He'll be all right. He'll be all right.
Clark!
Clark! [ Coughs ]
[ Coughs ]
[ Clark Coughing ]
Pa, I'm sorry.
- What were you thinking?
- I was just trying to help.
To help? Burning the house...
and almost getting yourself killed
is not helping.
Pa, l said l was sorry.
If something bad happens to you,
sorry doesn't fix it.
I'll talk to her.
Clark, please.
Don't be hard on her.
She could have been hurt, Ma.
Or worse.
But it was my fault.
I was the one that left her.
She has to understand
that one day you and Pa won't be around...
to help me look after her.
Why can't we have the pillows?
Everything's all smoky, honey.
Gotta air out the mattresses
and the pillows- everything.
Pa, I'm sorry.
Hey.
Don't you give it another thought, okay?
I love you. Come here.
Ooh, yeah. Hoo, yah.
- Oh.
- Lloyd and lrene.
Well.
Let's go say hi.
- Come on there.
- [ Gasps ]
How are you two doing today?
Well, not especially good. We, uh...
- We had a fire out at the house yesterday.
- Is everyone all right?
- Clark? Missy?
- They're all fine.
All fine. Um, we just come into town
to get some lumber and other supplies.
Well, you don't need the wood.
I got a bunch left over from
when Clark helped me fix up my barn.
- I'll bring it over.
- Well, we can't ask you to do that.
Nonsense. I know times are tough for Clark.
Besides, that's what
neighbors are for, right?
- Bless you, Ben Graham. You're a good man.
- He certainly is.
As you may have guessed,
Sarah and l are courting.
No.
I can head back to my place,
pick up the lumber.
Be back at your place in no time.
That's mighty kind of you, Ben.
Mighty kind.
[ Horses Whinnying ]
Pa, you need to come see.
Get up now. Get up.
Get up, girl. Get up now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa.
[ Chattering ]
Let me help you, ma'am.
- What is all this?
- [ Child ] Hi, Missy.
Your pa told us what happened.
I told a few people.
Sarah told a few people.
I guess they told some people.
Well, here we are.
I got the lumber, left over from
when you helped me rebuild my barn.
That's mighty kind of you, Ben.
But l can't ask you to do this.
Well, you didn't ask. We offered.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Chuckles ] Come on.
[ Chuckling ] Come on.
Grab a trowel, boys. Let's go.
[ Lloyd ]
All right. There we go.
That's it.
Wanna hand me that? Thank you.
All right, let's start with the barn,
work our way around this place.
[ Chattering ]
- Hey, you mind if l join you?
- Okay.
[ Sighs ]
What are you doing all the way up here?
Just thinking.
Yeah? Is there something wrong?
I know Pa's mad at me.
It's my fault. I started it.
Did you tell him that you were sorry?
Yeah.
Missy.
Honey, your father loves you.
Now, he may be upset
with something that you done...
but, sweetheart, he will always love you.
- You gotta trust in that.
- You sure?
I couldn't be more sure.
[ Chuckles ]
l think those boys could use two strong
girls to help them load up them wagons.
- What do you say?
- Sure.
Come on.
[ Chattering ]
l think it turned out well.
- Mr. Connor, l really appreciate this.
- It's my pleasure.
- Can't thank you enough.
- Don't have to.
Just know if something similar happens
at my place, l expect the same thing.
And with the trouble Clint gets into,
it may just.
[ Laughing ]
Fair enough.
- Sarah, you about ready to go?
- I sure am.
- Come on now.
- We'll see you all. God bless.
- [ lrene ] Thank you, Sarah.
- You're welcome.
- [ Lloyd ] Take care now.
- Bye, kids.
- Bye.
- [ Ben ] See you all.
- Bye-bye, y'all. You have a good night now.
- Come on now. Get up.
Come on. Come on. We still have
one more length of pipe to try.
It says in the Good Book
that the good are rewarded...
and the wicked are punished.
Why am l being punished?
Well, we don't always understand
why things happen.
We just need to... have faith...
and endure.
How am l supposed to endure this?
Almost lost my house in a fire.
Missy could have been hurt.
I'm about to lose my land- land l can't
grow a thing on because it'll never rain.
But it's mine, and l fight for it every day
to keep it and make it work.
And then, most of all, l lose Ellen.
The only woman I've ever loved.
I miss her so much.
Son, l want you to come with me.
- Where?
- Just come with me.
Whoo.
- l wanted to bring you up here.
- Why?
What do you see?
Hills.
Trees. Our house. l...
Barren fields.
Is there anything special
about what you see?
- It's just where we live.
- [ Sighs ] it's more than that, Clark.
That's your home.
This place has been a partner to you
throughout this trying time.
You see the burden
that comes with living here...
when you could choose to see
the blessing that it is to have this...
this wonderful thing right beside you.
I mean, if all you see
is the downside of everything...
Son, you miss the truth of life!
What truth is that?
There are wonders all around.
Things to be thankful for.
God blesses us with so many special gifts.
What do l have to be thankful for?
That he took away
the only woman I've ever loved?
That he's gonna take away all my land?
You know, if God's so wonderful,
why do l always feel like he's forsaken me?
You are so very wrong.
The truth of God's love
is not that he allows bad things to happen.
It's his promise that he will be standing
there right beside you when they do!
God loves you like you love Missy.
Like your ma and me love you.
No matter how hard things get, Clark...
we will be there right beside you.
And so will God.
[ Nickers ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Ha!
Whoo!
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Well, for heaven's sake.
[ Gasps ]
l have something to tell everybody.
- What is it?
- Where's Missy?
- She went down to the chicken coop to get some eggs. Why?
- What's gotten into you?
[ Clark ] l have two things l
want to talk to you about.
[ lrene ] All right.
I've been thinking a lot
about what you said...
about this not being a good place
for Missy to grow up.
- And?
- And you're right.
This is not the ideal
place for a young girl.
Living here, the two of us would probably
not afford Missy the proper childhood.
I know that living with you two would
make life easier for Missy.
I can speak from personal experience just how
wonderful it was to grow up in that house.
- [ Sighs ]
- Are you sure about this, Son?
I've never been more sure about
anything in my entire life.
Well, if that's what you want.
You didn't let me finish.
I know it would be easier
on Missy living with you two.
But Missy's my daughter.
And I'm her father.
And she belongs here with me.
I know we may deal with
some tough times ahead...
but the good Lord's gonna show us through.
Yeah.
Well, l just have to say that
I'm so happy that you said that.
- Really?
- Yes.
Of course.
Missy needs her pa.
She needs a pa that's gonna love her.
And l...
l was just worried about the farm
and the work and the issues.
Well, that brings me to
my next bit of news.
I was gonna wait till everybody was seated
for dinner to say this, but...
- l hit water.
- [ Irene ] What?
You did?
I put the last piece on.
It just started flowing. I almost gave up.
- [ Chortling ] That's wonderful!
- I'm gonna go tell Missy.
Hey, hey!
Mr. Davis.
Mr. Harris, uh...
please let me apologize for the other day.
I understand, considering
all that's happened.
And l regret how l may have handled things.
Mr. Harris, l hit water.
I'm very confident l can pull in
a full crop before harvest time.
If you would just give me that time, l
could make those payments and then some.
I know this drought's gonna raise prices.
I appreciate your situation, Mr. Davis...
but the bank cannot wait till harvest time.
Please.
I can make those payments. If you...
The bank is firm on this matter...
which is why it's such a good thing
that l am not here to see you.
- You're not?
- No. I'm here to see them.
- My folks.
- Steven.
- Lloyd, l have the papers right here.
- Good.
I don't understand.
Your folks have offered to
put up a parcel of their land...
as additional collateral on your loan...
if we grant an extension.
Pa, you could lose your land.
I told you, a parent will do
anything for their child.
Just make sure you get
a real good crop this year.
Clark.
Come on in.
Um, I'll see if l can find her.
Missy?
Missy.
[ Clucking ]
Missy?
[ Nickering ]
- l can't find her anywhere.
- Can l be of some assistance?
No, but l- l do thank you. I appreciate it.
You don't think maybe she overheard us
talking about her coming to live with us?
- Pa, you mind riding over to
Ben's, see if she's there? - Hmm.
I'm gonna go the opposite direction.
Will you stay here in case she comes back?
[ Blusters ]
Giddyap. Yep.
[ Whinnies ]
[ Sighs ]
Missy?
[ Child ] Pa, look.
Ben.
- Whatever brings you by?
- Whoa. Hey.
Missy's gone off somewhere.
She didn't come by here any chance?
No. But, uh, me and the boys
will help you look for her.
I'd sure appreciate it.
Get up, Pete.
Come on now.
Missy?
- [ Whinnies ]
- Missy?
Missy?
Pa doesn't want me here, then l won't be.
[ Whinnies ]
- [ Whinnies ]
- Missy?
Ooh, Pete. Missy!
[ Sighs ]
Where is that girl? Come on, Pete.
[ Nickers ]
Any sign of her?
I don't know where she could be.
[ Groans ]
- l can't find her anywhere.
- It's gonna be dark soon.
Will you give me that lantern?
Will you stay here?
I'm gonna go look for her.
You take care of yourself.
Go on. Yah, yah.
Go on.
It's all right.
Missy!
Missy.
Missy?
[ Whinnies ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Whimpering Continues ]
Missy?
- [ Nickers ]
- Missy!
- Missy?
- Pa!
Missy.
Why did you leave?
'Cause you told Grandma and Grandpa
that I'd be better off living with them.
I told them you were my daughter, and you
were staying here with me no matter what.
- You understand?
- Mm-hmm.
- Do you understand?
- Yeah. I love you, Pa.
I love you, pumpkin.
Come here.
[ Whispers ] Hey, baby.
- Grandma.
- [ Gasps ] Oh.
Oh.
[ Sewing Machine Whirring ]
Well, what brings you here today?
- For me?
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, they look lovely.
[ Chuckles ]
I've been doing some thinking.
Last night, Missy ran off on Clark.
Oh, dear. Did he-
Did he find her? Is she all right?
Yeah, she's fine.
But you got me to thinking...
the people we love can be
taken from us at any time.
You and l, we-
we know that better than most.
I suppose we do.
And l- l know we talked about
taking things slow, but, um...
What is it?
I'm mad in love with you...
and l- l don't want to waste
another minute taking things slow.
I don't want to lose a minute with you.
What are you saying?
Uh...
I'm asking for your hand in marriage.
Uh- Ben, l was not expecting this.
Neither was l.
But, uh, here l am...
asking you to say yes.
Yes! Of course I'll marry you.
[ Groans, Sighs ]
[ Moans ]
I'm never gonna let go of you, Sarah.
[ Connor ] Ben.
Well, what is it?
Mr. Connor.
What's going on?
We're getting married!
- Really?
- Yes, sir.
[ Laughing ]
Then congratulations are in order.
Thank you, Mr. Connor.
- Congratulations.
- Oh, thank you.
I'm happy for you.
- We better- We better go tell Clark.
- Ben.
Darling, don't you think
we oughta tell our children first?
Right. Good idea. Sorry.
I'm a bit scatter-shot right now.
- Don't forget your hat.
- Thanks.
Well, come on.
Whoa. Whoa.
Hey, Clark.
Clark, we got a big announcement.
- What's the big announcement?
- We wanted you to know...
[ Clearing Throat ]
Right. Please, you tell him.
- Go ahead, please.
- Thank you.
We're getting married.
- [ All Laughing ]
- I knew it.
- Congratulations.
- That's wonderful. Oh.
- Thank you.
I was hoping you'd agree to be my best man.
I'd be honored.
I hope you two can stay for the wedding.
Well, l don't know.
I suppose maybe we could stay a few days...
if we're welcome.
Grandma, are you silly.
You are always welcome.
- [ Thunder Rumbling ]
- [ Gasps ]
What?
- [ Thunder Rumbling ]
- Wow!
It's raining.
Ah!
- It's raining.
- Yes, it is.
Oh, my goodness, it's raining.
- Come on. Let's get out of here.
- My gosh!
[ Missy ] Pa, it's raining!
[ Lloyd ]
Glory be! Look at it come down.
[ lrene ] Boy, don't you have
enough sense to get out of the rain?
No, ma'am!
- [ Laughing ]
- Ah!
[ All Cheering ]
[ Sighs ]
Whoo!
Yes!
Ah!
Oh.