The man 's badly injured.
lt was a terrific blow.
The crowd is very jumpy.
Projectiles are landing onstage.!
Please, gentlemen, calm down.!
Bottles are being thrown.
They're setting fire to the stage.!
What's the diagnosis?
He's not moving or complaining.
He's swelling up like a balloon.
One rib's stuck in his lung,
his tibia's exposed,
a concussion, most likely.
He landed on the seats, doctor.
Sorry, but l think it's spinal,
whether it's fractured or not.
WORLD CHAMPlON JACOB VAN OPPEN
lN SANTA MARÍA
l didn't do anything because
there's nothing to be done.
You'd have to toss a coin
to know where to start.
-That bad?
-l'll tell you.
Multiple traumas,
deep coma, pallor,
weak pulse, severe tachypnea
and cyanosis.
The right lung has collapsed.
Crackling sound
and right sixth rib bent.
Tumefaction in the lower lung.
The coma's deepening
and acute anemia increasing.
Possible broken ribs.
lsn't that enough?
lf l were you, l'd leave him be.
My patients die on the table.
Get him ready.
Alright.
BAD DAY TO GO FlSHlNG
Hey, friend?
Hey, pal?
You got a cigarette?
The man about to come out is
the top wrestler of his generation.
World Heavyweight Champion,
Gold Medal at the Spartakiada,
before being rescued
from the claws of communism.
Boxers, wrestlers,
judo fighters, karate experts,
tennis players, dancers...
We take on anyone.!
Where's the brave man who'll
risk his life
for 1 ,000 dollars?
1 ,000 dollars!
Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
life is an adventure
without end.
And now, a big hand...
for the World Champion,
Jacob Van Oppen!
lt'll be seven days.
How long does a call
to Germany take?
Germany... two or three days.
Depends on the operator.
May l? lt's to the lnternational
Wrestling Federation.
When they answer, ask for
Herr Mallwitz, please.
-You pay in advance here.
-Yes, l'll go to the bank tomorrow.
Here's my card.
-Ronco.
-Ronco?
-That's me.
-Nice to meet you, Ronco.
He trained in the Leipzig school,
the best in the Democratic
Republic of Germany.
He won a gold medal
at the Spartakiada.
He didn 't win at the Olympics
because when he escaped
he became stateless.
He lost his crown...
well, he didn't lose it,
it was stolen from him in Gstaad.
A bad ruling.
The appeals board
has it as an open case.
Next year he'll regain the title.
That's him with President Honecker.
They were on informal terms.
He's never been better.
He may have put on a few kilos,
but that's why we're on this tour
of 27 South American cities.
And how could we forget
Santa María
on this lead-up to
the world championship?
Prince?
Yes. Prince.
l could help...
But this is
fishing week and...
the baptisms are today.
l've got all my journalists out.
But l thought your paper,
the temple of culture and wisdom
in this town,
would like an exclusive on
the visit of a world champion.
Not to mention the 1 ,000 dollars
-we're offering on Saturday.
-What was that?
The champion challenges anyone
to last 3 minutes in the ring.
Do you smoke?
Yeah, sure. Thanks.
l only smoke because
it bothers them.
An excellent reason.
Jorge!
Well... When can we take the photo?
The champion wants to pay tribute
to this nation's freedom fighter.
From hero to hero.
Mrs. Lima, l presume.
-Yes?
-l've come to see Ronnie.
ln the gym they spoke highly of you.
l know you were
a good middle-weight.
Maybe a bit unlucky, Ronnie,
but l can see that
you're a good man,
That's why l'm giving you
this chance.
Thanks, Ronnie.
-l don't know.
-Ronnie,
this isn't like lying.
lt's like the movies:
a guy dies, and later on
he appears in another movie.
lt's like magic.
See this handkerchief?
Look at it.
l pull it through.
l put it in my hand.
l blow...
lt's vanished.
Now check your pocket.
lt's magic.
Wrestling's the same.
A great wrestler has to
conceal his tricks.
Because everyone wants him to.
They want to believe it's true.
Just go to the paper
and make the challenge.
And then stay away.
lf people see us together,
the magic's gone.
And if you run into Jacob,
stay away and not a word,
because he respects
a pro who knows his job.
What'll my dad say?
We said we'd only think about us.
Oh, Juan Andrés.
Oh, Maria Victoria.
-You're so wonderful.
-So are you.
Kiss me, darling.
Where?
Right here.
Like that?
You're so romantic.
Afternoon. Everything alright?
ls everything alright?
On requesting baptism
for your children,
do you know that you must
educate them in the faith?
Do you promise to spurn
the temptations of evil?
Yes, l promise.
Do you promise to renounce the Devil,
the source of sin?
Yes, l promise.
Then we shall proceed.
Hey, stop! You're 30 short!
You're 30 short.
-Relax, here's my card.
-l've got it. Gimme the money.
Here.
And the rest?
l just got here.
You're leaving me with nothing.
The money.
-Alright?
-Okay.
Ciao.
Hey, pal!
-Yeah?
-Where is there a florist?
FLOWERS, URNS, CANDLES
Unless my memory fails me,
the proscenium
is smaller than in Trieste.
Do you know?
La Duse worked there.
La Duse herself.
The first woman to play Hamlet.
Three people are asking after you.
They're from the gym.
Good. Let them in.
Any doubts? Any questions?
-When do we work with Van Oppen?
-Easy does it, boys.
As the champ gets to know you.
When do we start?
Start?
Now.
He looks bigger in person.
-Who?
-Jacob. Barely fits through the door.
-What door?
-The church door.
God bless.
Our father who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name...
WORLD CHAMPlON
CHALLENGE
Thank you.
Can l go now?
No one else is coming. Can l go?
Yeah, sure. Go.
Someone was asking for you.
-Ronnie!
-Hey, Prince...
Come up.
l went to the paper.
Come up!
-You know what they said?
-Grab a beer and come up.
-Where are they?
-Get up here!
l'll come round in the morning.
Take my card.
But l want the money now, l need it.
-Later, Ronnie, we agreed.
-But l want it now.
-You know l need it.
-Go home.
l went there and said
what you told me to say.
Gimme the money l need it.
Go home and don't talk to anyone.
Go on.
-Anything else?
-No, thanks.
Oh, yes, the bill.
-Gloria.
-No. Jessica.
Gloria doesn't work here anymore.
You'll be Gloria to me.
lt's on them.
-Cheers, gentlemen.
-Cheers!
-Do you want to play?
-No, thanks.
-One hand?
-No, no. Thanks.
Miss, are you alright?
-Excuse me.
-May l see you home?
-Where were you heading?
-Me?
l'm in no hurry.
-Are you sure you're alright?
-Yeah.
lt got late and started raining.
''Adriana.''
May l?
-Where did you say you were going?
-l didn't.
Straight ahead.
-Do you want to stop for a drink?
-No.
-Do you want to go to my hotel?
-What?
-What did you say?
-No, nothing.
Just thinking out loud.
Thinking gets you into trouble.
lt's here.
You can come in for a drink.
You didn't tell me your name.
Orsini. Prince Orsini.
Prince...
What kind of prince?
A prince, prince?
Descendent of the Orsinis,
the Republic of Sienna,
a Byzantine family.
What happened to the family?
The 15th century, signorina.
-1500?
-That's it.
...34 times the distance between
the Earth and the Moon...
And now, tonight's last request.
from Braulio to Marta,
''Nights Without You''.
What time is it?
Nine o'clock.
l saw the poster in the square.
ls it true?
-ls the 1 ,000 dollars true?
-What are you talking about?
My fiancé is going to
fight the champion.
lt's no joke.
He'll fight, but first you have to
deposit the money.
Fight the champ?
You'll be left without a fiancé,
miss.
l saw him in the church. He's old.
-Your fiancé, does he know about this?
-No.
Better that way.
Besides, there's already a contender.
-Who?
-A boxer. Ronnie Lima.
Ronnie? Our Ronnie?
Now you're talking crap.
He's a drunk, everyone knows.
-Why him and not my fiancé?
-That's how it is.
-Why?
-There can only be one contender.
Why?
Out of respect.
The ceremony, miss...
Or do you bury men
without a wake here?
Your beauty and youth is your excuse.
Ronnie's a drunk.
Everyone knows
he'll be tanked on Saturday.
Goodbye.
That's enough for today, Ronnie.
That not good enough?
There's another mistake here.
Bravo, Jorge. Beautiful photo.
-Good day to you.
-Hello, boys.
No, there's no 'h' in it.
-Prince!
-Ah, Heber!
l came to thank you for the headline.
l'm sorry, your contender had
some trouble with the police.
He'll be held for a few days.
-But luckily, this lady came...
-Adriana.
My friend Adriana. We've met.
She came to accept the challenge
in her fiancé's name.
Yes. l myself asked her to come.
Then you agree?
Yes. Of course l agree.
-So your fiancé's up to it then?
-Where's the money?
l know the paper's
sponsoring the challenge.
This evening or
tomorrow morning at the latest.
ls tomorrow morning here
at the Liberal alright?
lt's alright with me.
We'll validate the challenge.
Heber, does the death penalty
exist in Santa María?
Why?
Because a man
just got a death sentence.
Ladies and gentlemen, don't miss it!
One time only in Santa María,
world champion Jacob Van Oppen!
This week in the Apollo Theatre,
from 6 to 8 pm!
A prodigy of nature:
Jacob Van Oppen!
A once-in-a-lifetime event!
A superman.
Half price Wednesday!
Don't miss it! Wednesday half price!
You look lovely, madam.
Thursday and Friday, two pesos!
No one can beat him!
ln Europe or both Americas!
What a man, look at those muscles!
A force of nature!
A once-only,
extraordinary event in Santa María!
Morning, sir!
Wednesday half price!
Don't miss it!
Wednesday, Thursday and Friday,
two pesos!
One time only in Santa María!
Once only, gentlemen!
Jacob Van Oppen!
Good afternoon.
Radio Santa María here.
Lorenzo García speaking,
broadcasting this unique event
for our city.
The newspaper El Liberal,
-organizer of this superb event,...
-Bingo cards!
takes pleasure in presenting
this exhibition by
the German wrestling champion,
Jacob Van Oppen.
-Check your blood pressure!
-Popcorn! Coffee!
Bingo cards!
Jacob Van Oppen,
sportsman, is tough,
difficult and rather prickly,
so we ask spectators
to take care to avoid any gesture
that may bother or infuriate
this great sportsman.
l recommend that
you remain in your seats
and enjoy this splendid show,
ladies and gentlemen.
A tractor tyre.
lncredible.
An oxygen tank.
Amazing.
A bathtub.
Wonderful.
And you have
50 cents discount
on the St. Maria Bingo.
First number of the night.
1 , 8: 18.
21 : 2, 1 .
41 : 4, 1 .
14: 1 , 4.
Bingo!
Since word spread about the fight,
the theatre's been filling up.
l raised ticket prices to keep
pressure off the champ,
but people keep paying.
All thanks to you.
Did you deposit the money?
l want to see the money.
-When can l see it?
-Miss, what's your problem?
We need the money to get married.
You love your fiancé?
Then go home and forget about it.
Don't push your luck.
Don't make him look ridiculous.
My fiancé is 23 and l'm 26.
Right now he's working in the store.
Porfilio Brothers. Go and see him.
They call him The Turk,
but he's Syrian. He has the papers.
How much does a wedding cost
in this part of the world?
-1 ,000 dollars is a lot of money.
-Single and widowed.
A sad fate for a woman
so young and beautiful.
Single, no.
We can marry with that 1 ,000 dollars.
And l won't be a widow.
Your champ is very old.
Who said he was an ordinary man?
What if he can still
break arms, legs,
ribs, collarbones?
And if he's not that old?
You don't know
what he's capable of.
Even schoolgirls jump better.
Yes, but when it really starts,
he's an animal.
l swear to you, he knows his job.
World Champion.
And in all the weights, miss.
-Hello.
-ls everything alright?
-Everything's fine.
-You don't need anything?
-No.
Excuse me, Mr. Prince...
Have you got the money?
No. Tomorrow morning.
l had a problem with the bank,
but it's sorted out, don't worry.
-What's that?
-Nothing.
''Nothing''? What is it?
lt's cyclical, although l don't
understand the cycle.
One day he'll strangle me
just because l'm nearby.
-My card.
-No, please, Mr. Prince.
l'll take one.
THE MATADOR VERSUS THE STRANGER
Come in.
Look who's here,
the new business champion.
l came to thank you, Heber.
Ever since you've backed this,
everyone wants to watch
the champ in training.
-l'm glad. Very glad.
-l read your front page.
Great headline: ''The Matador.''
-How did you come up with it?
-lt's not mine.
They've called him that
since the incident.
-lf you can call it an incident.
-What do you mean?
Right, you're not from around here.
lt was a couple of years ago,
when he worked in the country.
The girl, who was unattached then,
went to a hairdresser,
a friend of hers from school.
She fell asleep
while she was waiting.
This friend, as a joke,
shaved her head.
When she woke up,
she got hysterical and ran out.
The whole town laughed.
The Turk was passing by,
they told him about it,
he found the hairdresser
and with a razor...
he sliced off the man's ears.
The guy can still hear...
through the holes.
-That's that.
-What happened?
''What happened?'' The guy's crazy.
He barely even saw me.
He said,
''l don't like being called 'Matador'''.
He knows we all call him that.
lt's not the same as
seeing it on the front page.
l said it's freedom of the press,
we're in a democracy...
The girl saved me.
She kicked him,
spat at him and calmed him down.
He put on his fishing shorts
and l got a shot of him
-lifting Ramirez's cow.
-A cow?
She watched him,
proud as a mother, smoking away.
He put the cow down
and started running,
non-stop from Bartolomé Mitre
to Saravia Square,
doing laps behind the park.
l get it, l do.
Poor kid,
l've seen so many cases like this.
Character is a mystery.
lt doesn't come from big muscles.
Tasty toffee apples.
-Yes?
-Your call's ready.
Good, pass it to me.
Thanks, Gloria.
You should get some sun
on those legs.
Why don't you find a friend
and we'll go to lsla Paraiso?
l'm taking the champ.
How about one of those in the back?
-Judi, do you want to go to the beach?
-Alright.
Gloria...
Open up some bottles.
We're going to celebrate.
Gentlemen!
A round for everyone!
lt's on me!
Cheers!
l saw you this afternoon
at the Apollo.
Straight away l see
what people are like.
-ls he alright?
-Yeah, it's cyclical.
Are you sure?
What's wrong with him?
ls he sick?
Shall l call a doctor?
He can't breathe.
Something's up. Why not?
-l'll call a doctor.
-No.
-You sure you don't want me to...?
-No, no! Get out! Now!
ldiots.
No, no...
l told you clearly
1 -0-7-6, not 1 -0-3-6.
Yes, l know we're friends.
But one thing is friendship
and another is business.
Yes, it's the first time
it's happened, l know.
You have to understand,
it's making me nervous.
No. That's no excuse. l requested
the transfer four days ago.
Please, check it again.
1-0-7-6.
Hello!
-Are you sure? Tomorrow morning?
-Who is this?
Alright. Perfect.
No, your word does reassure me.
Hello. Hello.
No. Thank you, Mr. Ramirez.
-Bubi?
-No, thank you. Ciao.
At last. Tomorrow morning
we'll have the money.
A setback with the bank,
but midday tomorrow
l'll have the money.
Alright.
Excuse me. Sometimes l laugh
and l don't know why.
Yeah, l understand.
-l'm going. Things to do...
-Sure.
Sometimes l forget you're so busy.
l've got so much spare time.
lf l were a smart guy
instead of a cut-rate journalist,
l'd think all this was a sham.
What's that?
No, l know that's not the case.
l'm just supposing.
l know lots of foreigners
who think they're clever,
stick their noses where they
don't belong, talk non-stop...
My friend...
You're pale. Are you okay?
Shall l open the window?
No, wait a second.
l think you need help.
Someone to lend you a hand.
And that could be me.
-Help with what?
-With what, Prince?
With the deposit.
lf it comes to that,
l can say that l've got it.
Let's see if l get this.
-You'll handle the deposit?
-The deposit? What for?
lncredible.
This is unbelievable.
You couldn't arrange it with the girl,
you don't have the money,
and you don't think you can win.
What do you take me for?
For God's sake, Prince.
What have you got yourself into?
That girl
wants to see the money.
She'll kick up a stink here.
Tomorrow could be a very tricky day.
Why don't you go to your hotel?
Take a shower and pack your bag.
There's an early morning bus.
Hello?
Mario?
l'm the impresario, Orsini.
Prince Orsini.
Manager of Jacob Van Oppen,
the World Champion.
Oh, yeah. At your service.
lt's about the money,
the 1 ,000 dollars.
To put your mind at ease.
lt was transferred this morning,
and will be deposited tomorrow.
Good.
But l wanted to talk about
some other things too.
Excuse me. l have to finish up.
-What's it about?
-Nothing in particular.
Everything's been said, Mario.
But l consider it my duty
to say it straight out.
The truth. To you.
l'd like you to look at this.
lt's in other languages,
but you get the idea.
The photos help.
Golden Belt, World Champion.
Eight columns, front pages,
the Spartakiada...
60,000 people watching, Mario.
That's a champion.
No one can beat him.
No one can last
three minutes with him.
One minute would be a miracle.
l don't mean you're not
stronger than the champ.
You're younger, more vigorous.
l'd sign a paper saying that.
lf the champ bought this business,
in 6 months he'd be begging.
You, on the other hand,
will be rich in two years.
Why? Because you understand business.
The champ doesn't.
He was trained
to break ribs,
to bend you at the waist and knees
and put you on the mat.
Each to their own profession.
Mario, my friend,
look me in the eye.
You're the one
getting into the ring.
who's going to get hurt.
lf you get up there,
the champ will break
some of your ribs,
a bone... He'll have you
on your back in thirty seconds.
There'll be no 1 ,000 dollars
and you may have to spend
more than that on doctors.
Who'll run the business
while you're in hospital?
To say nothing of the shame,
being made a fool of.
You said if l got up there
on Saturday...
l said?
l think l gave you some advice.
At any rate,
if you withdraw from the challenge,
there could be a deal,
some compensation.
-How much?
-Chief,
pour a drink for us both.
l'm buying, of course.
Whatever you like.
Cheers, Mario.
He doesn't drink.
Adriana, l do drink vermouth.
Mario, my friend, let's continue.
Friend Mario and l
already talked about tomorrow.
1 ,000 dollars, exactly.
We're not going to lose it.
-Mario, we're closing.
-The grass,
l have to haul the grass down.
lf you don't go tomorrow,
everyone will know you're afraid.
l'll tell them,
house by house, person by person.
Just a second, Mario.
l thought about that too.
About comments around town
if you don't go to the Apollo.
But it can all be sorted out.
Suppose you do climb into the ring.
Don't get the champ mad,
because that'd ruin our plans.
You'll soon see
what the champ can do
and you'll be on your back,
without a scratch.
l get it.
l go and l lose. How much?
How much? Let's say 100,
-200...
-1 ,000.
1 ,000 dollars.
We need the money
and he'll win clean on Saturday.
No tricks, no deals.
People will be proud of him.
My husband's no idiot.
No one's stronger than him.
No one can beat him,
especially not that old man,
however much of a champion he was.
Mario, let's close up now.
Miss, l'm getting tired of you.
l came to warn my friend Mario
of the danger he's in.
And l will not be pressured!
You don't know
what you're talking about.
You made a public challenge,
and the money had better
be there tomorrow!
-Mario, we're closing!
-l have to haul the grass.
Then haul it!
Prost.
-Yes?
-Did you miss the bus?
Or don 't you even have
the money for tickets?
-What are you still doing here?
-The fight's on.
-What?
-You heard me.
-When do we see the money?
-There's been a change of plan.
The money will be handed in
tonight at the Apollo.
But that wasn 't the deal.
Forget the deal.
l'll take the money myself.
ln case the Turk's hospital bills
have to be paid.
A funeral you'll have to pay if
you don 't come up with the money.
Be careful, Prince.
People don 't like being tricked.
He's buying.
-Cheers.
-Do you want to play?
-Yeah, sure. Why not?
-What are the stakes?
-20 pesos a chip.
Fine.
Gentlemen, why don't we get serious?
What do you say to 50?
Fine by me.
What are you drinking? Grappa?
My friend,
a bottle of grappa, please.
Here from the Apollo,
we're broadcasting
one of Santa María's biggest,
most important sporting events.
The challenger's brute strength
versus the champion's skill.
Cheers.
Sorry, friend.
You know what they say:
lf you're out of luck,
don't go fishing.
-The bottle. Can we drink that?
-Yes, of course.
Let's cut the small change.
Two hundred?
Fine.
Our dear friend Alcides now
with his accordion,
playing a beautiful melody.
Are you alright?
You want to stop?
No.
500 more.
Listen, tomorrow l'll come
and pay for the round.
Ever since you came in
l've wanted to ask you...
Grappa,
is it better here, or in Europe?
l'll go find him.
No. Stay here until l say.
236?
There are 400 people at least.
How can that be?
They sneak in.
The lights go down now,
ladies and gentlemen,
and coming out is Prince Orsini.
Thank you.
Thank you, good evening,
and welcome to
this extraordinary event.
Today...
you'll witness a unique
event for your beautiful city.
The man about to come out is
the top wrestler of his generation,
from the finest
wrestling school in history,
World Heavyweight Champion,
Golden Medal at the Spartakiada,
before being rescued
from the claws of communism.
Ladies and gentlemen,
a big hand for the World Champion,
Jacob Van Oppen!
And now, the challenger,
a brave man who has put his life
in the clutches of the champion
for a prize of...
1 ,000 dollars!
This brave man is the Turk,
Mario Porfilio!
What are you doing there?
Come on! Get out!
Turk! Turk!
The Turk, loudly applauded
and supported by the crowd...
Now let's hand it over
to the gladiators.
Your arms!
Lower your arms!
What is he doing? lsn't this illegal?
Lower your arms! Lower them!
Get up!
DOCTORS ROOM
So?
Pulse, breathing
and cyanosis improved.
Sporadic recovery of lucidity.
As for brain recovery,
we'll have to wait.
Dimas came a while ago. Can l go?
-Yeah, sure.
-See you.
Brother,
don't give me that false modesty.
lf that brute hasn't died yet,
he never will.
You did it, boss.
The best doctors in the capital
couldn't have done better.
How is he?
Alive.
l was going to have a baby.
Now l'm going to have to
look after two.
May l?
You should quit smoking.