Narrator: montana territory, 1 879,
where cattle was king.
Where the law was a gun...
... and the men who drove the great herds
up from texas...
... made the rules.
They were hard men.
They had to be hard to keep alive.
The ground they took with their guns,
they held with their guns.
Held it against the indians.
Held it against cattle rustlers.
It was theirs by right of conquest.
They meant to keep it.
Then came what they believed
was a new enemy.
It came as a slow white tide...
... rolling north from the prairies
toward the grasslands of montana.
Sheep.
And with the sheep rode men
who also lived by their gun.
They swept north slowly, steadily...
... searching for range, grass, water.
Cattlemen claimed
there was death in this tide.
They said no steer could live
where a sheep had grazed.
They warned the sheepmen to keep off.
Then they turned to their guns
and there was war.
They rolled back the first attack
and buried the sheepmen where they fell.
They buried some of their own too...
... and marked the spots for all to see.
They put up signs as a warning.
Signs that promised death
to any sheepman...
... who might look at this ground
and want it for his own.
And that's how it was
when morgan lane rode north years later...
... driving his sheep
into the cattle lands of montana.
[Baaing]
Man:
What's on yon sign, mr. Lane?
Oh, it's sort of a friendly warning, mac.
It says that any sheepman
crossing this point will get shot on sight.
Mackenzie: What are you gonna do?
- We're going across. What else can we do?
Wait a minute, laddie.
The sheep's all played out
and they need water.
- The nearest river is five miles ahead.
- The sheep can't go a step further this day.
We'll have to bed down dry for the night.
Well, it will not be the first time.
And you call montana the promised land.
That's what it is to me, mac.
I promised myself
i'd come back here one day...
...ever since the cattlemen
drove my father off the range.
Australia, where your father took you,
is a fine, fine country for sheep, mr. Lane.
It would have been far better to have
stayed there from the look of this.
Not me, mac. This time, i'm here to stay.
Well, cheer up.
Tomorrow night, you can wet your whistle
at fort humboldt.
I'll be wetting my whistle tonight, mr. Lane,
if it's all the same to you.
- Where did you dig that up?
- San francisco.
I purchased it the day before we left.
And you mean to tell me
you've had that all that time?
Aye. Come desert and mountain,
rain and blizzard...
...i've treasured this bonny wee bottle
in my bedroll.
And you know something, mr. Lane?
When you laddies were freezing,
the very thought of this kept me warm.
So long as you're gonna open it up tonight,
i better start rounding up the boys.
- Hey, fellas!
- Mr. Lane, mr. Lane. Please, mr. Lane.
Mr. Lane, let's talk this over,
friend to friend.
Laddie, there's barely enough
for the two of us.
Mr. Lane, you cannot do this to me.
[Man playing guitar
and singing in spanish]
[Hoofbeats]
[Cocks]
[Gunfire]
[Sheep baaing]
[Barking]
[Men yelling]
[Whistles]
Let's go.
Morgan:
"Thou preparest a table before me...
...in the presence of mine enemies...
...thou anointest my head with oil,
my cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me all the days of my life...
...and i will dwell
in the house of the lord for ever."
- Amen.
Men: Amen.
When miguel go, he says he want you
to send this saint christopher medal...
...back to his mother in spain.
Well, there will be
no turning back now, boys.
- That grave should tell you that.
Jose: Aye.
Whoa.
Good morning, gentlemen.
No wonder little bo-peeps
couldn't find her sheeps, heh.
You've got them.
All the sheeps in the world in one bunch.
[Chuckles]
What a fragrance. I, the...
something not so happy here?
Well, wha...
why the sad faces?
You know who shot up our sheep
last night?
I don't know. Some...
some people don't like sheeps, but i do.
- I loves them.
Morgan: Uh-huh.
You familiar around these parts?
Fort benton, yes. Helena, yes.
Fort humboldt, not so much.
- How much?
- You know, it's a cow town.
Plenty of money, i hear.
That's why i am going there, you know?
Gone.
Why don't you come
and have a cup of coffee, uh...
..."papa...? Papa schultz"? Is that it?
Help him down, mac.
I wanna have a talk with him.
Come on, lads. Help him down.
Papa:
Don't break it.
Sit down, papa.
Tell us a little more about fort humboldt.
- Here.
One man, one woman boss the range
and run the town.
- The biggest cattle people in montana.
- That's interesting. Go on.
I only know a sheepman
in fort humboldt.
It's bad medicine.
You're not implying that they don't exactly
care for sheepmen around here, are you?
- Mm-hm. Only to shoot at.
- Uh-huh. How do they feel about peddlers?
If i don't sell sheep dip for sale,
i'm welcome. I hope.
You know something, mac?
I got great news for papa.
Papa: Good.
- I'm riding into fort humboldt with you.
- As your partner.
- Partner?
- Uh-huh. Mac.
Throw a little grub into my new partner.
I'll see you in a few minutes.
- I am partner with sheepmen?
- Just for the looks of it.
And i get shot like your sheeps last night
just for the looks of it?
Aye, maybe. I'll not deny it.
But it's for the good
of your adopted country.
What better could a man ask?
Papa:
I could die in a bed.
Mackenzie:
You'll die here if you give us an argument.
If i don't take him with me, i die here.
If i do take him, i die there.
- Woe is me.
- Shame on you, man. I'll hear no more.
Back to your wagon now.
There's a possibility
we might purchase something.
But just a possibility.
Just a possibility. You, all right, let's go.
I, the papa schultz, have some bargains,
bargains for the people.
Is open for bargains.
Bargain in shirts. Bargain in goods.
Bargain that good. Bargain shirt good.
- Look this shirt. What with you?
Man: No.
No. I will tell you what.
The hat, you don't want,
the shirt, you don't want.
The boots, you don't want. The fine
imported music box, you don't want.
But the money in your pockets,
you do want.
Mr. Papa schultz...
...i keep telling you i don't want to buy
the boots, the shirt or anything else.
- I only wanna buy this bird.
Mackenzie: Name your price for the bird.
I let him go for $2 and i lose $2. no.
Let him go for $ 1 and you'll only lose $ 1.
Papa:
That's better. All right, $ 1.
I would starve in scotland.
Well, you have the bird.
Take care of the bird.
Very fine bird, a brand-new bird.
Jeannie, you're gonna be a good girl,
aren't you...
...and take care of all the strays
while i'm gone, hmm?
Are you, hmm?
Watch the strays, now.
- Let's go, partner.
- Partner.
Mac, be sure you keep the sheep
well-bunched.
- Don't let anybody on horseback near them.
- All right, mr. Lane.
Come on, papa. Hurry up. Hurry up.
Sheepmen don't talk much, no?
Hmm? No.
Peddlers talk too much, yes?
Yup.
- Then i keep quiet.
- Good.
You have no pistol gun?
- No what?
- You don't carry a boom-boom? No?
No. I don't like them.
They make me nervous.
Uh-huh.
You are going to shoot the murderer
who killed your men?
Mm-hm. I see. Later, later.
You've got another business before?
Mm-hm.
You're kind of curious, aren't you, papa?
So am i. I wanna find out
what's wrong with sheep.
I think sheep are pretty important
in the world.
I'd like to know
why a few cattle barons in montana...
...think they can keep sheep
off the open range.
Morgan:
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
[Bell ringing]
Step right up, ladies and gentlemen...
...and listen to one of the most
amazing discoveries...
...of the medical world.
None other than dr. Otto schwartz's...
- schultz. Schultz.
- Dr. Schultz's amazing "tiger-marrow fat."
Extracted from the wild beast
in its native lair.
And, as the doctor will testify,
it cures every human ailment.
It cures..."fallen arches"?
"Fallen arches, flat feet,
warts, corns, bunions.
And it also cleans and tightens
loose teeth."
Remember, reeves,
have the boys back at the ranch at 4:00.
- And try to stay out of trouble.
Reeves: We'll do our best, miss singleton.
[Men hollering]
Who are they?
They act like they own the town.
They do,
and most of the range around here.
That's maria singleton and rod ackroyd.
Come on, sheriff.
[Bell ringing]
[Fiddle playing]
[Singing]
Oh, dan, he went down to the mill
to get some corn to have his fill
the miller swore by the point of his knife
he never saw such a man in his life
so
all [singing]:
Get out the way, old dan tucker
get out the way, old dan tucker
you're too late to come to supper
- supper
[cheering]
- Those boys are pretty good, aren't they?
- Yeah, very good.
Go on, reeves,
tell about that fight you had.
Well, sheriff, i tell you...
...you should have seen
them sheepherders run.
All but one of them.
It sure breaks my heart every time
i hear of a sheepherder getting killed.
[All laugh]
Well, i don't like shooting,
but this is cattle country.
Maybe it will learn them
they ain't wanted here.
- Thanks for the drink, slim.
- You're welcome, sheriff.
Hello, stranger.
You're new here, ain't you?
Oh, sort of, sheriff.
But i get acquainted fast.
- Well, be sure you meet the right people.
- Oh, sure.
That goes for both of us.
- Give me some whiskey, will you?
Bartender: What kind?
Drinking whiskey.
- Do you boys care to join me?
- Why not?
Whiskey's whiskey,
no matter who pays for it.
You never said a truer word.
Fill them up, will you?
What's your business, mister?
- I'm a peddler.
Reeves: Peddler?
Yeah, wagon's down the street.
Well, good luck.
- Hear you fellows had a little trouble.
- You heard wrong. Not us.
Them sheepherders and the sheep
had the trouble.
Oh.
Say, i'm a stranger around these parts.
Uh, like to ask a question.
- What's wrong with sheep?
Hey, listen, this dude wants to know
what's wrong with sheep.
[All laugh]
- I'd like to know what's wrong.
Co yne: I'll tell you, mister.
They chew up the grass by the roots
so it won't never grow again.
Did you ever smell them?
Cattle won't set foot
where a sheep's been.
Hmm. That's funny.
Just across the border,
i saw plenty of sheep and cattle...
...getting along together fine.
No trouble at all. Around here,
there seems to be plenty of room for both.
You talk like a sheepherder.
- How does a sheepherder talk?
- Like you're talking now.
I'm asking you again,
what's your business?
I'm telling you again. I'm a peddler.
You're all dressed up, but you're
a dead ringer for one of them dirt-eaters...
...we traded shots with last night.
- Where's your gun?
- I don't carry a gun.
Some men don't carry them in gun country
because they're afraid.
That's right.
Tecumseh: Ordinarily, i don't get
mixed up in other men's feuding.
But i couldn't help
but overhear you talking.
Son, that trigger's tied back
with rawhide...
...and if you don't know
how to fan a gun, don't put it on.
Either buckle on that gun
or get out of town.
All right, my friend.
Start counting, will you?
When you get to three, we'll shoot.
One.
Two.
Morgan:
You never learned to count, mr. Reeves?
Now, pick up that gun
and we'll start all over.
I take back what i said.
No sheepherder
can draw and fire like that.
Will you have a drink with me?
I do believe i will.
Very neighborly of you.
The man's buying, fellows.
[Men chattering]
- How about that same song?
- Through with that gun of mine, son?
Oh, yeah, thanks a lot.
Sure shoots fast, doesn't it?
Bartender: What will you have?
- Just a drink of whiskey.
[Men chattering]
[Bell ringing]
Lady, please, please, just for a moment.
Come back. Come back.
Look, lady, this is a antimacassar.
You lay it back on the chair like this.
Your husband lays his head back like this.
And it catches the macassar oil
from his hair.
He don't use macassar oil on his hair
no more
then i sell you a bottle.
Fine macassar oil, no?
He ain't got no hair, neither.
Oh, wonderful.
Then he needs a fine toupee.
Camel hair, huh?
Mister, i laid my husband under the sod
seven years ago
...come 4th of july.
Better for him.
See you back at the ranch, maria.
Sober, i hope.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Papa schultz's wagon's open.
- Where are the customers?
- You got any musical instruments?
I'm looking for a guitar.
Guitars we ain't got.
Guitars we never have.
But maybe i can offer you something else.
Look, look, madam, i have music boxes.
- A fine imported music box.
- No, thanks. Nothing else.
Good morning, miss singleton.
- Find what you wanted?
- No, i was looking for a guitar.
A guitar?
Papa, didn't i tell you in chicago
you should order guitars?
You tell me in chicago?
You tell me nothing in chicago.
I'm sorry, miss singleton.
We'll order one specially for you.
Never mind. By the time it got here,
i'd forget i ever wanted it.
- Say, i'm curious about something, mister.
- Oh?
How'd you know my name?
Well, i'll tell you.
I was curious, too, so i asked someone.
Curiosity killed the cat, you know,
mister, uh?
Lane. Morgan lane, ma'am.
Good day, mr. Lane.
- Make yourself at home.
- Always do.
- Don't think i got your name.
- Tecumseh.
Mine's lane.
Mr. Lane, i figured out your brand.
Have you?
You had a killer's look in your eye when you
stood up to reeves in that saloon today.
You knew that cowpoke killed your man...
...and you were out
to square accounts with him.
What do you want?
Well, a sheepman is poison
in this country...
...and i'm the only one that knows
for certain that you're one of them.
And i'm out of drinking money.
Oh.
Well, i tell you, tecumseh, i'm sort of...
...short of drinking money myself,
but, uh...
...think that will keep your mouth shut?
Till it runs out.
Well, try to make it last, will you?
Mister, i ain't no sheepman...
...but i sure admired the way
you handled yourself in the little big horn.
But don't crowd your luck.
Thought i'd tell you.
Thanks.
- Say, you been around this country long?
- Since '51.
The buffaloes and the injuns run it then.
[Chuckles]
Ackroyd and singleton run it now, huh?
Yup. And what they don't hold,
the forsythe company does.
Between the three of them, they just about
put the little cattlemen out of business.
Going someplace?
I'm gonna ride to singleton ranch,
see that girl and her partner.
You're a dead man already, mister.
Too bad.
A nice young fella too.
[Neighs]
I don't see what makes you think
you have to outshoot...
...outdrink and outride every man
in the territory.
For the same reason makes you put on airs
because your name happens to be singleton.
All right, turn him loose.
[Men cheering]
You hurt, boss?
Huh? No, i'm all right.
Sooner you find out that horse'll kill
anybody that tries to ride him...
...the better off you're gonna be.
- Lf i don't kill him first.
Miss maria, you'd better marry that man
while he's still in one piece.
Maybe i could handle him better
if he was broken up a little.
He'll never be gentle, that's sure.
Or you, either.
[Knocking on door]
Oh, how do you do?
- Is miss singleton here?
- What is it?
- I, uh, brought this out to show...
- we don't want any.
- Yes, but miss singleton ordered it.
- We still don't want any.
- Just...
maria: Who is it, kitty?
- It's a man with a...
- guitar.
Maria: A man with a what?
- Guitar.
- Hello, miss singleton.
- Oh, the peddler.
Uh-huh.
You see, by a strange coincidence,
after you left town today...
...i started rummaging
through our music department.
And what do you think i found? A guitar.
- Won't you come in?
- Why, thank you very much.
Well?
Maria: Nice tone.
- Thanks.
- Oh, wait till you hear it when it's tuned.
- But it doesn't look new.
New? Well, i should hope not.
- This is probably 1 25 years old.
- That's what i thought.
Perhaps you're not aware, madam,
that guitars are something like violins.
The older the instrument,
the sweeter the tone.
As a matter of fact,
you happen to be looking at a genuine...
a genuine gonzales papa schultz.
Don't be foolish. It's a lyon & healy.
Mrs. Maynard's husband was a musician.
Oh.
- Congratulations.
- He blew the bugle at gettysburg.
Did he?
Well, now, that's very interesting.
You know something, mrs. Maynard?
I've always been of the opinion that
the blowing of that bugle at gettysburg...
...was the main factor
in the union victory.
My husband was on the confederate side.
Didn't i say confederate?
Maria:
After that one, i think you'll need a drink.
- Well, if you insist.
Maria: Kitty?
- So, uh, you're a peddler, mr. Lane?
- Among other things.
And you rode all the way out here
to sell me a guitar?
Among other things.
Heard about you beating reeves
to the draw yesterday.
Pretty fast with a gun, aren't you?
- Among...
- yeah, i know. Among other things.
- Just who are you? Where are you from?
- Originally, australia.
Recently, california.
What are you doing in montana?
Frankly, i'd like to live here.
I'd like to buy some land.
You've come to the wrong section.
We're not selling.
That's too bad.
Have you thought of the advantages...
...of having me for a neighbor,
miss singleton?
Why, i could even teach you the guitar.
Among other things, of course.
It's not a question of wanting you.
It's just that we don't take kindly
to strangers, that's all.
Oh, but i had no intention
of remaining a stranger, if you don't mind.
Uh, ahem. Among other things, of course.
[Playing guitar]
Anything else i can play for you?
Do you know "i reckon i'm in love"?
"I rec..." are you?
That's a song.
Oh, a song.
Well, i reckon i might. This it?
[Playing "i reckon i'm in lo ve"]
[Singing]
The same old moon looks new tonight
reckon i'm in love
the same old stars are twice as bright
[singing]
You won't believe the crazy things
i've been dreaming of
i feel as though my spurs are wings
reckon i'm in love
i met a certain someone who
makes me feel that way
and ever since i met her
i'm a-singing in the saddle
skedaddle doodle-daddle all day
he saw my pa and pa said, " sir
whatcha thinkin' of?"
He said, " your daughter's spoken for
reckon i'm in love"
i find i shave most every day
reckon i'm in love
on any ol' trail i lose my way
i haven't slept the way i should
darn that moon above
and yet i wake up feelin' good
reckon i'm in love
just one sweet kiss and i saw stars
do i kiss that way?
Oh, and ever since i kissed you
i'm a-singing in the saddle
skedaddle doodle-daddle all day
i promise i won't let you down
morgan:
Whatcha thinkin' of?
Maria:
I run the finest ranch in town
maria & morgan:
Reckon i'm in love
[maria laughing]
Oh.
Rod, this is mr. Lane. He's a peddler.
A, uh, guitar peddler.
With lessons?
Uh-huh. With lessons.
Care to plunk a string?
How many for supper, please?
- There will be three.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Ackro yd:
So together with george forsythe...
...we control the biggest
and finest range in montana.
Who's forsythe?
Oh, he represents
the imperial canadian cattle company.
He's my neighbor on the south
and rod's my neighbor on the north.
I see. Tell me, how did you ever
come to settle in montana?
When the homesteaders
overran our property in texas...
...our families just packed up
and moved to montana.
Our families have held this range
ever since 1 87 1...
...and we intend to go on holding it.
[Chuckles]
- Sort of a two-family empire, huh?
Ackro yd: One family, mr. Lane.
Maria and i are engaged to be married.
Oh.
Is it too late to congratulate you?
Mr. Lane's not interested
in our personal affairs, rod.
He's looking for some range land
for himself.
Why don't we sell him
the bear creek range?
We never use it.
What makes you think mr. Lane
could run a cattle outfit?
Come right down to it,
what makes you think i couldn't?
Running a cattle spread is a man's job.
- Rod.
- Oh.
You'll have to excuse rod, mr. Lane.
- He's just had a bad time with a horse.
- Oh, sure, that's all right.
Matter of fact, i always did think
horses knew a lot about human nature.
What do you mean by that?
Well, for instance, i think they know
who can handle them and who can't.
Another very important factor is once you
get into the saddle, you gotta stay there.
- Evidently, you overlooked that.
- I suppose you could do better.
Morgan: Well, i wouldn't say that.
I might try, though.
Especially if the stakes were right.
I wouldn't mind trying to ride anything
you've got for that bear creek range.
If you mean that, mr. Lane,
you might just wind up with a broken neck.
Morgan:
True enough.
On the other hand,
i might wind up with a range.
You wanna bet or don't you?
It's a deal.
Good.
What were you saying about texas?
Well, there's an awful lot of it.
- Morning, sheriff.
- Morning.
- Looks like the whole town's out here.
- Yeah. News sure travels fast, tecumseh.
- Who you betting on, the man or the horse?
- The horse. I know that animal.
Any man stays on him,
i'll throw my badge away.
I got $ 1 0 that says
the stranger stays up on him.
I'll take that bet.
Step in close, everybody.
Papa schultz takes all the bets.
One suit of clothes,
one pair of shoes, one hat...
...one suit of underwear against $ 1 5
that my partner stays on the horse.
- I'll take that bet, mister.
Papa: Thank you.
- I'll take some of that.
- Thank you. Money. Thank you, thank you.
Now for the ladies.
One skillet, one washtub...
...one bottle of perfume against $ 1
my partner stays on the horse.
- Here you are, mister.
- Sold for the lady. Thank you.
Step in close, everyone.
- Everything all ready, reeves?
- Yup, he's ready.
- Morning.
- Howdy, sheriff.
More ways than one
to get rid of a man, huh, rod?
Yes. Why don't you try it sometime?
All right, bring him out.
[Horse neighing]
You understand the rules, mr. Lane?
In order to win, you have to stay
in the saddle one full minute.
Well, look, i don't want to appear curious,
but how will i know when the time's up?
I'll blow this whistle.
Oh.
Well, don't be afraid to blow it real loud,
will you?
[Chuckles]
I hope i'm around to hear it.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Mr. Tecumseh, what do you think?
Will my partner stay on this horse?
If he falls down, i am bankrupt.
- How much you got bet on him?
- Don't ask me.
Everything in the wagon.
Everything on my back.
Shoes too.
[Blows whistle]
[Crowd cheering]
- Hang on, son. Hang on.
- Is he still on? Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
Stay on him, son.
Stay on him.
Come on, boy, ride him.
Partner, we are out of business.
Are you all right?
Morgan, are you all right?
Get him some water.
Now, don't move.
I had no intention of moving.
Come on, get up.
We should've driven out in the buckboard
after the toss that bronco gave you.
Yeah. Ouch.
He's quite some animal.
- You're quite some horseman, for a peddler.
- Peddler?
What a lovely spot.
If that horse had known i was riding for this
as a prize, he wouldn't have been rough.
Well, you only lost by a couple of seconds.
Yeah, but he didn't have his watch.
That will always be
the longest minute in my life.
- It's been an interesting life, hasn't it?
- Mine?
You said you came from australia,
didn't you?
Yeah. Say, there's a lovely country.
I guess there isn't very much
that you haven't seen.
Oh, yes, there is, plenty.
- You wanna hear about the things i have?
- Where would you begin?
Well, let's see.
Uh... a moon over the andes.
Oh, now, we have
pretty tolerable moons over montana.
Well, all right.
Let's say surf along a coral beach
in the tropics.
Oh, no.
Give me 1 0,000 head of cattle
at roundup time.
Tell me, morgan...
...why did you leave all these sights
and places to come to montana?
Well, i guess every man's got a sort of
special dream of his own.
What's yours?
Simple enough.
A sheltered valley, good green pasture.
Hot in the summer, cold in winter.
A place to build a house.
A woman.
That's a good dream, morgan.
Do you, uh, think you could
make your dream come true in this valley?
Oh, yes.
Better than any place i ever saw.
And to think i only lost it
by a few seconds.
No, you didn't.
This isn't bear creek.
This is sunset valley.
It belongs to me.
It isn't part
of the ackroyd-singleton range.
Runs clear down to those foothills.
My brother would've built his house here
if he'd lived.
I'm gonna lease it to you.
You're gonna?
Why?
Because i want you to have it.
Yes, but why?
Well, because i think you're the kind
of cattleman we're gonna need on our side.
This fight's gonna be tougher
than the last one.
Tell me, why do you have to fight?
Some idiot's bringing sheep
on the range again.
Yeah, but it's only one man.
No, listen, when there's one man
low and greedy enough...
...to bring sheep onto country like this,
others will follow.
We found that out in the last sheep war.
You won the last one.
I lost my father and brother doing it.
I see.
I guess this valley means a lot to you.
A part of you, huh?
Maybe that's why i want you to have it.
Among other things.
What other things?
Well...
look, um, we'd better be getting into town
and drawing up that lease.
Looks like a sheepdog.
Smells like one too.
- He acts like he's looking for somebody.
- Yeah.
When he finds him,
we'll find us a sheepherder.
Well, this lease seems to make me
a montana landholder, at least temporarily.
That's right.
May i be the first to congratulate you...
...on the beginning of your dream?
Thanks, miss singleton.
- Miss singleton?
- Maria.
[Dog whimpers]
[Barking]
Jeannie. How did you get loose, huh?
How did you get loose, huh?
Poor old girl.
What did you do, break your rope?
Morning, miss maria.
What are you men doing in town?
Ackroyd's orders, ma'am.
That dog seems to like you, mister.
Mm-hm. She should, i raised her.
That's a sheepdog.
Yeah. Good dogs.
You ought to get yourself one.
Sheepdogs mean sheepherders
in this country.
I thought i recognized you before.
Now i'm sure.
That dog of yours cinched it.
Mister, you're a sheepherder.
You heard what he called you?
Uh-huh.
He's right. I'm a sheepman.
Now get back to those filthy sheep of yours
and get them out of the country.
No, ma'am. I'm staying right here.
I'm gonna move my sheep
into the pasture i just leased.
Wait a minute, mister.
You tricked me out of that lease.
There's no law in this territory
that will hold me to it.
Move your sheep
into that valley of mine...
...and every cattleman in the country will
ride against you with every gun they've got.
Reeves: So miss singleton's dude friend
turned out to be a sheepherder, huh?
[Men laugh]
Listen, lane.
You read that warning sign, didn't you?
Yeah. Sure.
It said any sheepman
crossing the line gets shot on sight.
Well, why doesn't someone
start shooting?
We don't shoot unarmed men.
Maybe you figured on that.
You're a liar.
Your men shot down my sheepherder...
...a young kid
who never carried a gun in his life.
Yeah. Any other sheepherder who crosses
that line will get the same as he got.
He never crossed your deadline.
Reese:
No, but you did.
Listen, sheepherder.
Either you get out of town
or you'll get the same thing.
[Crowd cheering]
Man:
Get him, reeves.
[Gunshot]
Drop that gun...
...or i'll squeeze this iron
as sure as you're born.
You better get back to your sheep, mister,
while you're still alive.
[All laughing and jeering]
Here's some hot milk, dear,
to quiet your nerves.
Hot milk? I'm so mad i could drink hot...
milk will do. I'll set it right here.
A sheepman.
The lowest, vilest, most contemptible
creature on the face of the earth.
If you could've seen him
standing there smirking...
if i'd had a gun,
i'd have blown him in two.
Next time you go out with him, dear,
be sure to carry your gun.
Next time? Next time i gotta get even.
Oh, what a fool i was.
Every girl is entitled
to make a fool of herself once.
Yeah, but not with a sheepman.
[Crashing]
Well? If you can think of anything
more contemptible to say...
...than i've already said to myself,
say it and get out.
You must feel mighty proud
of the singleton name tonight.
You've just handed the richest-watered
range land in the whole territory...
...to a song-singing sheepman
in fancy clothes.
Well, what if i did?
It's my land.
I can do what i want with it.
You idiot.
You played right into lane's hands.
With that lease, he can move in.
He's got the law on his side now.
Listen, if morgan lane
moves sheep on my land...
...i'll personally shoot every one of them
and him too.
Oh, that's fine, brave talk
now that the damage has been done.
Besides tossing away
everything our family's fought for...
...you've made a laughingstock out of me.
- You a laughingstock? Ha.
So that's what's hurting you, your pride.
How do you think it looks
for the girl i'm to be marrying...?
If that's the way you feel,
you can call that off right now.
Uh-uh.
Right now,
i got more important things to do.
Like what?
I'm gonna get that lease back.
Wait a minute.
I gave morgan lane that lease
and i'll get it back.
There's no more than a trickle of water
in the creek, laddie.
You got this lease from the girl
just in time.
Yeah.
Hated to get it that way, though, mac...
...but it had to be.
Well, what about the sheep, mr. Lane?
They've got to have water.
We're driving them across tomorrow.
That means fighting and killing.
Yeah.
Too bad she's gotta be mixed up in it.
All's fair in love and war, mr. Lane.
Who said anything about love?
[Gunshot]
Morgan:
Hello there, tecumseh.
A fine greeting
for a friend who comes a-visiting.
I'm sorry. Weren't expecting any friends.
Gave my boys orders
to shoot anybody on horseback.
Next time, i'll walk in.
Might be safer for you at that.
Come on over and squat.
I'm glad you came out.
I wanted to thank you
for what you did for me in town.
Shucks, weren't nothing i done.
Well, if you really wanna thank me,
let me join up with you.
I figure it will be healthier for me
in the long run.
Join up?
You've got something going on back here.
What is it?
Well, here it is.
The big cattle outfits run the country.
With their loud talk,
their riding and shooting...
...and their hatred for sheepmen.
- Tell me something i don't know.
- All right, i will.
There's a lot of little cattlemen around here
what can't make a living...
...because they're being pushed
and squeezed by the big outfits.
Do you know
many of those little cattlemen?
I know every one of them.
You do, eh?
Morgan:
All right, let's get to the point.
You small ranchers are getting
put out of business by the big outfits.
There's no secret about that, is there?
You're fighting for your very existence.
All right, the way i see it,
there's only one thing to be done.
You've got to start running cattle
on the same range with sheep.
It can't be done.
You're wrong. It can be done.
Swing with me, i'll not only show you how,
but i'll give you the sheep to start with.
Pedro:
People's coming.
[Hoofbeats appro aching]
Whoa.
It took a bit of persuading, but i finally got
mr. Clark, the banker, to drive out with me.
Morgan:
Good to see you, mr. Clark.
Hello, lane. Hello, joe, barry.
What are you boys up to?
I've just been trying to tell our neighbors
that they don't have to stay broke.
Well, i'm certainly glad to hear that.
Lane wants us to go in with him
on his sheep deal.
He's willing to cut us in on shares if we'll
back him up when he crosses the deadline.
That sounds good
from a financial standpoint.
And i know you can use the money.
But these people are all friends of mine.
You're asking them
to start a fight they can't win.
Wait a minute, mr. Clark.
I'm not asking them to start anything alone.
But if i can guarantee that one
of the big outfits will swing along with us...
...would you advise us to take a chance?
You don't mean forsythe?
- Who else?
- Splendid.
Well. If forsythe's in,
i'm all for the deal.
Count me in too. I like it.
Boys, it's a deal.
I'll tell you when we move.
I want to thank you for riding out here.
- We'll be waiting.
- Good night.
How about a cup of coffee?
Thanks, i will.
With forsythe on our side,
i don't see how we can lose.
- When did you see forsythe?
- I didn't.
You don't know him?
Uh-uh.
Then how do you expect
to sell this deal to him?
I don't know.
[Chuckles]
First, you tell the little fellows
you've got forsythe on your side.
Now you're going to tell forsythe
you've got the little fellows lined up.
Lane, you ought to be a politician.
Say, do you think it would be too late
to see forsythe tonight?
Too late tonight?
Sure. You're gonna introduce me to him.
Good health.
Man:
All you gentlemen say is quite true.
Everything you've told me is confirmed here
in my company's quarterly statement.
We're facing an alarming situation
if the price of beef continues to decline.
Mr. Lane, i see your point.
With sheep, we'd have two markets,
wool and mutton.
The price of both is up.
Maybe you're right.
There's just one hitch.
You're asking me
to turn against my neighbors...
...to make enemies of men
who've been my friends for years.
Look, mr. Forsythe,
here it is in a nutshell.
If you can convince your friends
of your faith in this plan...
...you'll be accomplishing two things:
You'll bring prosperity back to the range...
...and you'll put an end
to all of this fighting and shooting...
...that's been going on around here
for years.
It might work, gentlemen.
It might work.
It will work.
Just get them together
and give it to them straight.
And i want every wagon road and trail
that crosses our property closed.
Cut some cedar posts and string new wire.
Have the men ride the line...
...and check every foot of fence
between here and blackstone canyon.
Reeves, i'm holding you responsible
for anything that gets through.
Yes, ma'am. All right, boys, let's go.
- Good morning, maria.
Maria: Morning.
- Things seem to be popping this morning.
Maria:
They've just begun to pop, mr. Clark.
Say, what are you two doing
in my neighborhood?
Well, george here insisted on driving over
to personally invite you and rod...
...to a little gathering
at his house tonight.
Well, i can't speak for rod,
but i'm in no mood for social affairs.
It won't be altogether social, maria.
There will be business discussed...
...that concerns you
and every rancher in this section.
- You make it sound mighty important.
- It could be, maria.
Maria:
What's it all about?
I can't very well tell you that
until we all get together.
But it will be a sort of surprise.
Well, i've had enough surprises lately.
Thanks for the invitation.
Maybe next time.
Maria:
Wait a minute.
- I'll come to your party on one condition.
- Name it.
Invite morgan lane.
Morgan lane will be there, i promise.
I'd like to know what's behind
forsythe's idea in giving this shindig.
Said he had a surprise for everybody.
Why don't you go in and find out?
You got an invite.
Uh-uh. I got more important business
in town.
You got more chance
of getting shot in town too.
If that's your idea of humor,
keep it to yourself.
Now get on down there
and keep your eyes open.
If anything important happens,
you know where to find me.
Oh, darling, please be careful.
Careful of what?
Just because your name's rod ackroyd,
you needn't be so reckless.
Reckless?
You know, sometimes i think
you're still in love with that sheriff.
- Don't tell me he's still hanging around.
- No, but i don't want any trouble.
There won't be any.
Be careful, rod.
[Playing waltzing music]
Here's hoping we can sell them the idea.
We had better or we'll all go broke.
Maria:
Oh, here you are.
Well, we're all on pins and needles
waiting for that surprise.
And we're just waiting
for them all to get here.
Are you sure you invited everyone?
Everyone.
[Crowd applauds and chatters]
[Applause and chattering stop]
Forsythe: Hello, lane.
Morgan: Good evening.
Glad you could be with us.
Uh, you know maria, miss singleton,
don't you?
Not this miss singleton.
Then perhaps
we should get better acquainted.
[Playing waltzing music]
Am i holding you too close?
No.
You sure?
We're supposed to be dancing.
Oh, i forgot to mention,
i never learned how to dance.
Well, maybe we ought to
sit this one out, then?
Well, it is a little warm here, isn't it?
Well, aren't you surprised
to see me here tonight?
No, no. You belong here.
Let me ask you the same thing.
Surprised to see me?
Not at all. I expected you.
You did, huh?
Didn't bring your whip, either.
No, i left all my weapons at home.
Uh, not all of them.
You must be surprised
that i'm being so nice to you.
No, no, not at all.
You want something.
If we're going to be
that frank about it, i do.
Let's see. Couldn't be, uh?
Couldn't be that property of yours,
could it?
Yes.
I want the lease back.
Why did you do that?
You said you wanted it.
And let's say that...
let's say i happen to like you.
You don't expect me to believe that,
do you?
That's what you wanted, wasn't it?
Yes.
What about your sheep?
Oh, they'll get along. You know sheep.
You make me feel
a little ashamed of myself.
No, you shouldn't feel ashamed.
All right.
Then i'll feel grateful instead.
That's better.
How grateful?
Well, let's say, uh...
...grateful enough to want to hear more
of the moon over the andes.
That moon over montana's not bad.
My friends, i know you're all curious
as to why i've invited you to this party.
It's no news to any of us
that the cattle situation here is critical.
For years, we've watched
this situation overtake us...
...and we've done nothing to stop it.
Now, last night, a young man
named morgan lane brought the answer.
He definitely proved that sheep can be run
on the same range with cattle.
Man:
That's a lie.
[All chattering]
You don't mean that, george forsythe.
This is cattle country.
Cattle built our homes, gave us a living
ever since our fathers settled here.
"No sheep"
was the cattlemen's law then.
Well, it's still the law.
And we'll back it up
with every man and every gun...
...in the singleton-ackroyd outfit.
Where's your loyalty?
To your friends, your families,
your fathers?
To the tradition of the range?
If those graves that mark that deadline
mean nothing to you, they do to me.
Our fathers died in a war
to keep montana cattle land.
Well, now it's war again.
And whatever it costs in lives and property,
you can blame it on one man:
Morgan lane.
Jack: Everybody on the cattle side,
let's get out of here.
Well, lane...
...iooks like
the young lady's declared war.
Looks like it.
- Does that change your decision?
- Not at all.
[Gunshot]
[Woman screams]
Ackro yd: I'm gonna tell this
to all of you once more.
Monte, you take your men
and round up the cattle on the ridge...
...and start them rolling.
- Yes, sir.
Kane, you and your men will meet them
at the foot of the ridge with the valley herd.
Allen, you join them at the same place
with the steers from the mesa.
You all drive through the draw.
That's where you'll be, canby,
with the river herd.
I want every head of cattle on the range
at the north end of blackstone canyon...
...and i want them there fast.
That's an order.
Your friend morgan may know
something about sheep...
...but today he's gonna learn
about cattle.
Mackenzie, start them moving.
This ain't no official call.
I heard you aimed to get your sheep
onto the forsythe range.
- So i rode out to warn you not to try it.
- We don't need any warning.
I'm talking to you now outside my badge.
Outside my office too.
Your sheep will never get through,
nor you neither.
We'll see.
The ackroyd-singleton outfit's
been rounding up all their cattle...
...and they aim to ride you down and stomp
you to death in blackstone canyon.
Thanks.
You heard what he said, boys.
You still with me?
Man 1: Yeah.
Man 2: Sure we are.
Let's go and stop that stampede.
I'm riding with you, lane.
Officially?
No, for personal reasons.
Come on, let's get a-moving.
[Men shouting]
Let's get going.
- They all here now?
- This is the last bunch coming in.
Ackro yd:
Get them down to the canyon.
All right, let's get these cattle moving.
Rod, riders coming!
Head them off!
Go on, head them off!
Morgan: Tecumseh, you and chuck,
that way. Come on, sheriff.
We've gotta turn the point.
[Clicking]
[Grunting]
Keep turning them, partner.
Slow down, you critters!
They've turned the herd.
I'll ride to the ranch
and tell them what happened.
That's a mighty fine job, boys.
Let's get back to the sheep
and we'll take them in.
Which way?
Right through town.
What's happened?
Where's rod and the rest?
Rod was killed when lane and his outfit
turned our cattle back.
- Did the sheep get through?
- Yes, ma'am.
Lane's heading them toward town
and there's nobody left to stop them.
Our cattle's spread all over the hills.
It will take us two days to round them up.
Give me a gun.
[Sheep baaing]
Man: The sheep are coming, fellas!
Thousands of them.
The sheep are coming.
Hey, boys.
I told you if you brought sheep
on this range, i'd kill you.
Morgan.
Morgan. Why did you keep coming?
I warned you. Why didn't you stop?
Stop? You stopped me.
Well, why did you have to be
so stubborn?
Me?
- Me, stubborn?
- Yes, you.
You saw that gun.
I told you i was gonna shoot you.
You knew i'd shoot you.
You wouldn't listen to me...
[muffled speech]
I'm gonna have a lot of trouble with you.
Among other things.
[English sdh]