Do everything
just like I told you, old man,
and you'll live to make some more
of these bone boxes.
Open the gates!
Hey, Jonas!
Hope you made 'em extra long.
We got a couple of big ones.
Bring 'em out.
Keep cool, old man.
Graber, look at that.
Ned Cawley, Frank Graber...
Joe Maxwell, Jesse Barton.
You've been found guilty of murder
in the first degree...
...by the people
of the territory of Arizona
and on this thirteenth day
of January
in the year of Our Lord 1891...
I am hereby ordered
by this warrant to have you...
hanged until dead.
You boys wanna make a...
You boys wanna make a statement?
Hurry it up, fat boy.
We have a date in hell for dinner.
Shut up.
Why don't you go...
Hang the warden,
hang the warden,
hang the warden...
Shut up!
Shut up in there!
Quiet! Cut it out!
This one's holding on.
Can't last much longer, though.
You're gonna see a lot of men
hang before you get out of here, Wes.
Oh, yeah?
You've been good to me
in this hole, Cain, and I like you.
But let me tell you this.
I ain't gonna sit in here
for 18 years and rot like you did.
No pen can hold
Luke Santee's brother.
You'll see.
It's all done.
Bring out the wagon.
Swing the wagon over
to the gallows.
I'm gonna fill these things up.
They're already filled!
Come on, Luke, over here!
Luke, Luke,
come on down this way.
Here I am!
- Hurry up!
- Damn it! Come on down here, Luke!
You've each got six shells apiece, boys.
Make 'em count!
Come on, Luke!
Boy, am I glad to see you, Luke!
Go for the gate!
Gimme the gun!
Come on, Cain.
We can use a man like you.
Don't do it, kid, even if you make it
out of here, they'll get you.
Wes!
Hank, get over here!
Cain...
you bastard!
You dirty bastard!
Cain's a rehabilitated man.
Well, that's a credit to you
and your institution, Warden.
Oh, no, it's a credit to Cain.
And that's why the court saw fit
to release him.
Cain will never
pick up a gun again.
The hell he won't!
He'll have to.
Cain spent half his life right there
in the cell where loud mouth is standing.
Cain was a tough kid
when he came here in '73.
Now he's a mellowed man
with dreams
of making an honest life for himself.
Do you have any idea
where he might have gone?
Why don't you try Las Rinas?
It's the nearest town.
Hey, look out!
Bobby?
Bobby, bring those crates
right over here.
- Can I help you?
- No.
Hey, whatcha doin', mister?
I'm just looking, son.
Never seen you around here before.
You just passing through?
I don't know.
Are you a cowboy?
No.
- A miner?
- Nope.
It's Ruffalo!
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
Step right up.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
See the spectacular shootin' show
and death display.
See the world's greatest gunslinger.
His firearm's first fiddle, folks.
He's a sharp one, folks.
He's a shootin' shark!
And see the world-famous collection
of macabre curios inside.
The little lump of lead
that was removed
from Jesse James' back.
And the number noose
that nicked Nick Norris's nasty nape!
It's the biggest little show
in the territory.
And no lesser person than the great
Mr. Twain himself said, "It's the best!"
All right, step right up,
ladies and gentlemen.
Now here's your change, sir.
Thank you very much.
All right, thank you, go right in.
There's plenty of room for everybody.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is one of the
best shows you've ever seen in your life.
There you go, two of you.
Enjoy yourself.
Thank you very much.
Don't miss the shootin', kid.
Don't miss the death display!
Betcha never thought
you'd see that again, did you, Cain?
No, I...
I never did.
I won it in a poker game.
I heard you were gettin' out and...
Well, I hoped
that our paths might cross.
I figured you might be lookin' for a job.
Well, I am, mister, but...
Not Mr. Butt, Mr. Ruffalo.
Dan Ruffalo.
Listen, Cain,
I have a proposition for you.
If your proposition involves this,
I ain't interested.
Oh, now, don't be so hasty, man.
I think you might like
what I have to say. Sit down.
- Have a little drink?
- Yeah.
I know how tough it is
for guys like you to find a job.
It's a shame folks feel the way they do
about people who've served a little time,
but, well, it's a fact.
And I might help you.
What do you mean?
Well, I've got a pretty good
little business drummed up
in this here territory.
You can hear that.
Billy and me,
we make pretty good money.
And the work ain't hard and...
Well, I kinda figured you might have
a hankering to... join up with us.
What do you need me for?
Well, you know, I kinda figured
that folks might enjoy seeing Killer...
There, you see?
I almost said Killer Cain,
well, damn it all, I did say it.
Killer Cain.
I think people might really have
something to talk about if they could...
Well, if they could see you...
...using this notched Colt of yours.
Yeah, I see what you mean, but...
No, thanks.
I know you mean well,
but I just ain't interested.
There's good money in it.
I just don't want to be
around guns, mister.
I think you can understand why.
Well, what do you figure
on doing then?
Oh, I don't know, I...
I'll find work.
Cain, listen to me.
The West is...
a lot different than it was back in '73,
when you were part of it.
A whole lot different.
The railroad and the telegraph,
they've changed everything...
or almost everything.
The only fact that you can be sure of
is that you're Cain.
A man to be feared.
Certainly not trusted.
No, it's gonna be real rough for you
to find a job.
It is for all ex-cons.
Well, maybe you've noticed
that men don't wear guns anymore,
unless they're on the road.
No, things have
settled down out here.
And that makes for a lot of...
Easterners coming out west.
And there ain't
enough jobs for them.
Let alone, you.
I hope you're wrong, mister.
I ain't.
They didn't like me,
they love me.
Billy.
This here is Killer Cain.
This is...
This is the man, right here?
The genuine article.
Thanks for the drink, Ruffalo.
I guess I better get going
and find some work.
Sorry we couldn't make a deal.
Say, I'm sure glad to have met you.
All right, men, form a group.
Right around here.
I need four men only.
Big and strong.
You, there.
You.
You there with no hat on.
I'm sorry, Cain, it's...
it's company policy.
Let's go, men.
Hey, mister.
I see you're looking for work.
- I sure am.
- See that wagon?
Two bucks if you drive it
to Cragston's mine.
Put the stuff inside, and I'll give you
another two bucks when you get back.
You know where it's that?
You just point me
in the right direction.
Morning!
I wanna be able to do this again.
You're gonna have it
a lot rougher out
than you did in.
Hello!
Anybody here?
I just needed a little water. I...
I didn't mean any harm.
I hollered but nobody answered.
I...
I guess I don't look too good.
I had a little accident.
May I?
There's some rags
in back there, too.
My name's Cain.
Just Cain.
Justin Cain?
No, ma'am.
Just...
Only Cain.
What happened to you?
Well...
I guess you could say I got fired.
You're going back to... Las Rinas?
Dry Wood.
I came out here this morning.
Be going back
as soon as I finish my painting.
They say this town was abandoned
when the stage line
stopped making its run.
Guess you know all about that.
That does it for today.
- That sure is good.
- Thank you.
I was wondering, miss, if I...
could ride in with you?
To Dry Wood?
We'll make a deal.
You help me get my supplies in the
buckboard, I'll get you into Dry Wood.
Yes, ma'am.
By the way,
my name is Monica Alton.
Things have changed around here,
haven't they?
Yes, ma'am, they sure have.
That's why I'm out here.
I'm doing a series.
Not just sketches,
but paintings, as well.
I hope to capture pictorially
what Bret Harte and Mark Twain
were able to put into words.
"Local color,"
if you know what I mean.
No, ma'am,
I can't says I do.
There's no reason why you should.
Well, you've got local color,
you belong out here.
You have a very interesting face.
I'd like to paint it some time.
Who are you?
I told you, my name's Cain.
I mean, what do you do?
I didn't mean to pry.
It's really none of my business.
I don't blame you for wondering.
Why don't we...
get moving and we can talk about it
on the way to dinner.
- Is that an invitation?
- Yes, ma'am. I've got two...
What's the matter?
Well, I had two dollars.
I guess I not only got fired,
I got robbed.
I went to Vassar.
That's a school back east for women.
I detested it.
So of course I didn't do very well
in my studies.
I flunked out.
But I didn't care, anyway.
'Cause all I wanted to do
was come out west and paint.
My father thought
I was running away from failure.
He tried to encourage me by saying
that it wasn't what happened
in the past that mattered,
it was the future.
You're trying to encourage me by...
telling me that I should forget my past.
Well, I'd like to, but...
it seems like most people
remember too hard.
Why do you help them?
I don't understand.
Why did you tell me your name?
Why didn't you say it was Crane,
or something else?
It isn't what people think you are
that matters. It's what you are.
Would you promise
an intuitive woman something?
I'll make a deal with you.
If you say yes,
I'll treat you to that dinner.
- You sure like to make deals.
- Well?
Well, it sounds
mighty tempting, but...
You can pay me back later.
Say it's a deal.
All right. It's a deal.
Why don't you get out of here?
Why hang around small towns
where people will remember?
Go east or north
to a city like Prescott.
- That's Killer Cain.
- I know.
I I heard he was here in Dry Wood
a couple months back.
This winter.
Do you... happen to know
where he went?
No.
It's getting dark in here.
I never saw Cain.
I bought that sketch off of Joe Kirby
over at the boarding house.
Some girl left it behind
when she decided to move on.
Round and round she goes,
and where she stops nobody knows.
Two to one, gentlemen.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Sorry, place your bets now.
Place your bets.
Last chance.
- Night, Justin.
- Good night, Bruce.
All right, folks.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Step right up and see
the spectacular shooting show
and death display.
See the world's
greatest gunslinger.
He's sharp.
He's a shootin' shark.
So step right up and get
your tickets here, ladies and gentlemen.
Justin.
He sure is loud.
There's a kid in there
that's pretty good with a gun.
You've seen the show?
A couple of months ago
in Las Rinas.
...show, and the death display,
ladies and gentlemen.
Place your bets,
Yes, sir,
you can place your bets.
Place your bets.
Round and round she goes
and where she stops nobody knows.
Everybody down.
Place your bets.
She's stopping.
Two to one!
Here you are,
here you are, thank you.
Thank you, young lady.
Everybody down.
Place your bets, all right?
You know what I want, Jim.
Right away, Sheree.
- Could I ask you something?
- Yeah, sure.
How's that thing work?
I don't know much about that.
It's simple.
Why don't you come over when
I'm on the wheel and I'll show you.
Oh, I...
That would be fine.
I sure would like you to do that.
Anytime.
Say, aren't you that kid
from the shooting show?
I'm the star.
Well, I didn't see the show,
but I sure heard it.
You did?
Say, honey,
you sure do make a lot of noise.
Fix me a drink.
Sorry, son.
I got a tough boss.
All I can serve you is a sarsaparilla.
- A... a what?
- Sarsaparilla.
You kidding me?
There's nothing I can do,
they made it a law.
I see, they made it a law.
Well, look, I'm not interested
in a civics lesson, mister.
I'd just appreciate
if you'd just fix me a drink, there.
Can't you read?
Let's see.
"No minor persons served."
Now, I can read that sign,
but I don't believe it.
I would appreciate it if you would
not worry so much about my schooling
and tell your hands to do their stuff
or I'll blow 'em off your wrists!
You got any ideas about using
that gun in here, son, forget it.
Cain!
"Cain"?
What are you talking about, kid?
That man's name is Justin.
I don't know about that.
That... that's Cain. That is Mr. Cain.
"Killer Cain."
l... I was just playing,
just messing around, you know.
I sure wouldn't mess with you.
I sure wouldn't mess
with Killer Cain, would you?
That's Killer Cain.
Cain? Or is it Justin?
I witnessed you at work tonight.
I told you it would be tough
finding a job.
Like you said,
you witnessed me at work. I got a job.
But how long did it take?
You know, I've been in a lot of those...
those towns where you've been
in the past few months.
And I... well, I know
how hard it's been for you.
I ain't complaining.
No, you didn't complain
when you were slopping pigs in Bisbee
or cleaning spittoons in Tulsa.
Oh, let's face it, man,
you weren't even able
to hold those jobs,
and you won't be able
to hold this one, either.
I told you once before.
I ain't interested in your proposition.
All right.
I just wanted to let you know
the offer still stands, if and when.
Billy and me'll be pulling out of here
in the morning, for Redrock.
In case you change your mind.
And I was so cock-sure
that I could get Cain to join up with us.
I thought he'd be tired
of those chicken feed jobs by now.
Listen, we are doing all right, Rufe.
Good as folks say he was...
How much better
could he be than me?
If only you hadn't lied to him
in the first place.
Why didn't you just tell him
who you were?
You know,
he probably wouldn't have cared
if you had leveled with him
right from the beginning.
And why did you say
your name was Justin?
It's a long story, Sheree...
Good-bye and thanks again.
For what?
For trying.
Good-bye.
Well, it looks like
everything's in place.
- Your offer still stand?
- Sure!
We were just about to pull out.
Billy, lock up that wagon.
You come with me, Cain.
All right, Billy, let's get rolling.
I gotta stop over at my place
and get my gear.
Eighteen years in prison made me
think I'd never touch another gun.
That gun's gonna earn you
a lot of money, Cain.
Good money.
Yeah, yeah, it sure will.
I bet you're pretty...
pretty good with that.
What I love are those 12 notches.
- Those were the good old days.
- How would you know?
I've heard.
I've heard how every man
would wear a gun
and if he wanted to have it out
with a guy, why, he did.
Today you're lucky
if you can get a guy outside to fist-fight.
Here, load up.
I'll...
see if I can trim
that branch back a little.
Looks like I need some practice.
I never miss.
Well, Cain,
you just got yourself a free show.
Now, I know what you're doing there,
you're holding back, aren't you?
- No.
- Yes, you are.
I know you killed 12 men. I know
you must have been sharper than that.
I was.
How'd you do it?
How'd you kill 'em, I mean?
Different men, different ways.
"Different men, different ways"?
But you always let 'em
draw first, right?
No.
Not if there was a chance
I might get beat.
The only code I had
was to let 'em know I was coming.
But you never
bushwhacked anyone, did you?
Well, like I said, they knew
I was coming, so they all had guns
and none of them got it in the back.
Well, see, I thought...
You thought that
I marched down the street,
called 'em out
and waited for 'em to draw?
No, Billy, I...
I was hired to use my gun and I did.
Well, l...
I'd let anyone draw first.
'Cause I can outdraw anyone.
It's... it's hard for me to believe
that you never were as good as I am.
Good at what,
Billy, hitting branches?
Or killing men?
There is a difference.
Eighteen years ago
a man never holstered an unloaded gun.
You're just playing games, kid.
Let me ask you something.
How old were you
when you killed your first man?
- Sixteen.
What was he?
A sheriff or a marshal or what?
- Soldier.
- Soldier?
How much you get paid?
I didn't get paid anything.
It happened in a fist-fight.
Oh, well.
No, I mean, what about when
you had that first notch on your Colt?
What about it?
I didn't get paid anything
for that, either.
I killed a bounty hunter
who was after my hide.
Well, the first time
you got paid, how much?
- $50.
- $50!
$50.
Fifty bucks
don't mean much to him, Cain.
He's spoiled.
He don't know what it was like
out here in those days.
Well, it was different.
A lot different.
My father was a sergeant
in the Fourth Cavalry,
and they were always out
chasing Indians.
I never saw much of anything
except the inside of army forts
till I killed that soldier.
All my life I'd seen men die.
The ones that lived brag about
killing others, so life was cheap to me.
And $50 was a lot of money.
Especially when you were on the run.
Yeah, you make it sound lousy.
It was.
Hell, I just wish... I just wish
I'd been living in those days.
'Cause the way
I handle a gun, boy, I'll tell ya.
The way you handle a gun,
you'd been a dead man.
Somebody would have
shot you in the back
because they were afraid
to face up to you.
That's the way it was,
and don't you think different.
Mr. Cain.
How come...
no one went for your back?
It's a big enough target.
Well, a fella did once,
but his aim was low.
I got a scar on my ass to prove it.
Here, try that on, for a start.
Go on, man, put it on.
Put it on.
Yeah, it looks good.
It looks good.
Everything's gonna be black.
Black Stetson, black bandana.
Everything black but the silver.
Here, a black jacket, black jacket,
black pants...
Look at this.
Look at that buscadero belt.
Ain't that snazzy, huh?
It's just what a killer's supposed
to wear, ain't it, Cain?
I guess so, but... I sure never
wore nothing like that.
Well, think maybe we better try
some of this on, huh?
We might have to make
some alterations.
You're a big son of a bitch.
Look, here's some black boots.
Killer Cain. Killer Cain.
We stay here for a couple of days,
and then we'll hit Tempe,
and Phoenix, and Higginsville
and Liberty, and...
by the end of the month
we'll be in Valseco.
Mornin', Linus.
Seen The Epitaph?
Well, something in here I think,
uh, will interest you.
Says Cain's coming back to town.
According to the article, Cain's been
with Dan Ruffalo's shootin' show
for almost a month.
He'll be here today or tomorrow.
Ha kee.
I thought we made a deal.
Hi.
I want you to know I tried.
I believe you.
Oh, I'm not kiddin' myself.
I know it's not the best life, but...
it's better than anything
I've ever known.
Then I'm happy for you.
I better go finish my sketch.
It was nice seeing you again.
Wait a minute.
I owe you these.
I had a feeling I'd get these back.
Be seein' ya.
Be seeing you.
All right, folks, step right up.
It's the biggest little show in the territory.
Hurry, hurry, hurry. Thank you, sir.
I hope you enjoy yourself.
Step inside, folks, and see
the spectacular shootin' show,
starring the infamous Killer Cain.
Step right inside,
ladies and gentlemen, if you dare,
and let the Killer show you
the 12 notches on his Colt
and how they got there.
All right, folks, step right up.
Come on, folks,
you got a treat inside. Let... what...
What the hell are you doin'?
All this shouting
about "The Killer," "The Killer".
Now, look...
Listen to me.
- Billy, calm yourself.
- Now, you should listen to me.
You said that I was the star.
I was the star!
Billy, this is my show,
and I'll bark what I damn well please.
Now you get your butt back in there
and do what I pay you to do.
Go on, git, git!
All right, folks, I know you don't wanna
miss this spectacular event.
Here's your change, sir,
thank you very much and...
Carson?
I'm glad to see you!
You come to see the Killer?
You know, I think you and I
might work something out.
What are you getting at?
Well, seein' as how you and Cain
have met before and right out here,
I think folks might, uh, well,
they might enjoy seeing a little... encore.
I'll make it worth your while.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
step right up, let me see
the color of your money.
Mr. Cain,
would you take a challenge?
Three shots apiece for a dollar?
Sure.
It looked easy.
Well, thanks anyway.
It sure would have been great
if I could have said I'd beat you.
I'm the best shot in town, Cain.
You wanna take me on for a dollar?
Well, I guess we can't see
the Killer back down.
There you go.
Son of a bee!
Cain...
best of six...
on the wheel.
Three out of six.
Six out of six.
Can't beat that.
Mr. Cain, what'll you have?
Well, I'll try some of that rye.
All right.
Say, here, it's the next one,
right here, that's on me.
And, uh... you can pour me...
pour me the same.
At least I don't see any signs around
that says I can't, do you?
Thanks.
Listen, I was... was going
to ask you something...
Oh, yeah. What do you...
what do you think about Rufe?
He's a good man.
Yeah, well, that's...
That's what I thought at first, too.
I really did.
But l... I don't think so now.
When I first met him, he was...
he was moving about the territory,
doin' nothing, I mean, he was selling guns,
but folks weren't buying 'em.
Course, then one day he sees me.
And I'm...
you know, shooting bottles off the fence,
you know how I shoot.
Well, he gets the idea
of trying to drum up a little business
with me showing off his hardware,
so I said, "All right," I said,
"I'll go with you, I'll go along with you."
And one thing led to another.
After a couple of months,
he stopped selling guns
and began selling admissions
to see me shoot.
It seems to me,
he's been pretty good to you.
Hell, but not good enough,
not good enough, shoot!
He treats you a helluva lot better
than he does me!
And I've known him
a lot longer than you,
and I'm a helluva lot better
with a gun than you.
See, what I don't figure
is how he could bark to townsfolk
that I am a shootin' shark,
but forget himself
that I could blow him apart
if I got the urge.
See, people ought to realize that
the same thing I do to those targets
I could... I could do to them.
You're talking awful big, Billy.
Draw against me.
What?
You heard me.
Draw your gun.
You see, when you are a little bit afraid
and not quite sure of yourself,
even the fastest gun can be beat.
Things are different
when the target can shoot back.
You remember that.
You're still playing.
Yeah, well, you just stand up
and try that again.
I couldn't do that, Billy.
You're dead.
Well...
I've waited a long time, Cain.
Carson.
I was wondering when I drove in here
this morning if you might still be around.
Get up.
No.
Why don't you sit down?
I'm calling you outside, Cain.
Go on, Cain!
Last time I stepped outside
with a lawman,
it cost me 18 years of my life.
I can't afford any more time.
You forget I'm not
a lawman any more.
And I'm not a gunfighter.
You owed your life.
A court settled for 18 years, Carson.
Eighteen years don't pay
for all them murders.
So maybe you paid for one,
but you got a dozen notches
on your Colt.
I'm a free man, Carson.
I don't want any trouble from you
or any other man.
I would've paid you for that performance
this afternoon, Carson.
You just didn't have what it takes
20 years ago.
Twenty years ago, Cain was young
and fast, like the kid here.
But now he's older and slower,
like I was when he called me.
When he called you?
He didn't call you, Carson,
and you didn't go out willingly.
You were forced into that shootout.
Forced? I was the Marshall!
The way I heard it,
the people of this town forced you.
You're a liar, Ruffalo.
Oh? Somebody stop me
if I'm wrong.
- Now, there's no need to...
- No one forced me!
The thought that Cain was here
in Valseco back in '71
sent a chill through this town.
I knew he was here to kill.
- Yes, but nobody knew who.
- I was the Marshall!
So they shoved you out of that door
to stop Cain before they could find out.
- I did my duty!
- And he winged you.
Because of that,
your marshalin' days were over.
No one forced me!
Now you know that Cain
could have killed you that day.
Lucky for you that he just went
for your shoulder.
Now, you listen to me, man.
Forget about that revenge, hear?
I'll buy you a drink.
Come on,
I'll buy everybody a drink.
Say, Rufe,
who did he come gunnin' for?
Oh, some cattleman.
Yeah, yeah, but did he get him?
Does an outhouse stink?
Well, he sure ain't
the same man, I tell you.
I was kinda hopin' to see he
and that old buzzard get into something.
Oh, that'd been great.
Either way, we would have lost Cain.
Cain?
Makes you feel
like a big man, huh?
Travelin' around the territory.
Showing everybody
your 12 notches.
I'm not proud of what I was.
Huh? Why else you doin' it?
'Cause it's the only tool I know.
I'm not hurting anybody, and I'm
earning an honest living for myself.
Ain't no way for you to be honest, Cain.
No way at all.
I haven't got a gun...
or a mind to draw against you.
Cain... here you go!
Well, now, that solves
half your problems, don't it?
That's right.
Go ahead, shoot him.
Stick it in your belt, that'll do.
Just stick it in there
and just... blow his head off.
Ruffalo claims
that I was forced last time.
Well, this time I'm forcing you.
Go ahead, blow it.
- Damn you! Pick up that gun!
- He means it, I tell you.
He almost blew my toe off.
Now pick up the gun.
- Just go ahead and blow his head off.
- Stay out of this, Billy.
Well...
Well, if he... if he won't pick up
the gun, just shoot him.
Go ahead and shoot him.
Pick it up, you hear me?!
Now, I tell you, if I were you...
if you look at his eyes now...
I would just take hold of this little thing
right here and blow his head off!
Listen, if I were you,
I would just right now
blow one bullet,
right in him, right here.
Right here. Just blow his head off.
Now you want to, don't you?
Don't you want to?
Shut up, you!
He's getting away.
You kill him now.
Now, damn it,
you go shoot him in that back!
Why did you let him get away?
I want you to tell me that.
But... no, no, I know.
l... I know.
I know you were just...
you're just waiting for him to turn around
so you can shoot him
in the back, weren't you?
See? You don't know that I know
that's the way they do!
They... they wait, and then,
ah, they... turn around
and they shoot them in the back!
That's what they do.
My God...
That's... I know,
that's what you waitin' for.
If he... if he would have just...
got this gun!
Damn near as crazy as you are.
You... you just seek him, you know,
you just pick it up and go pow!
Cain?
It is Cain.
You livin' around here?
I have my own place now.
- Still painting?
- Still painting.
You still look hungry and beat,
just like the first time I saw you.
What happened
with the shooting show?
Oh, I left.
Are you sure
you weren't fired again?
I need help
unloading my buckboard.
It's filled with a month's supply
of shopping.
Your services for all you can eat?
Is it a deal?
It's a deal.
If you'll unload the stuff,
I'll get supper ready.
I haven't eaten that good
in a long time. Thanks.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Your face is so difficult to draw!
It's so complicated!
Like my life.
And yours.
Why mine?
Well, it seems to me this is a hard life
for a lady like you.
Must be a reason you live like this.
- Like what?
- Alone.
The only reason is
because I like it this way.
Heaven knows I don't have to.
Don't you miss
those big cities back east?
No. I was born out here.
My father came out here in '49,
first gold rush.
Took him ten years,
he finally struck it rich.
So did my father.
Came looking for gold, I mean.
What happened?
The only gold he got
was three chevrons on his sleeve.
- I mean, what happened to you.
- Me?
I was raised around army forts.
The only time I saw my father
was in between details,
and usually he was just soberin' up
when it was time to leave again.
And then one day
he didn't come back.
The Major said he died,
but I think he deserted.
What about your mother?
I never saw her, that I remember.
How different...
My father sold his mine interests,
packed up my mother and me,
and took us back east,
where we lived in complete comfort.
Imagine what
it would have been like
if your father had struck it rich
and mine hadn't.
I can't.
Well, l... I guess
I'd better be going.
- Thanks again.
- You're welcome any time, Cain.
What are you doing?
Morning.
Hold that end up, will you?
I thought you left last night.
Well, I started to,
but you filled me up so good
that I didn't much feel
like making the ride back to Las Rinas.
You're lettin' it drag.
Raise it higher.
You know, this place could be fixed up.
The land around here
could support stock.
There you are.
I was thinking last night...
or maybe I was dreaming, but...
I know I could do something
with this place.
That would mean a lot to you,
wouldn't it, Cain?
I'd pay you rent as soon as I could.
That wouldn't be good business
on my part.
You'd have to pay me first.
- You know I can't do that.
- Oh, yes you can.
Would you please hold still?
I'm sorry, Cain, but it just isn't right.
Damn it, Monica, I'm not posing anymore.
There's work to be done.
If you don't pose, you can clear out.
For Heaven's sake, of course!
- Look, I think I'd better do the shaving.
- No, this is fun!
Mr. Ruffalo.
Mr. Ruffalo!
- Mr. Ruffalo!
- Yeah?
- I'm looking for Cain.
- So am I.
He up and left me
a couple of months back.
Would you have any idea
where he might have gone?
Who's askin'?
An attorney, huh?
Well, it's like I told you,
I'm looking for him, too.
I think you've made
a little mistake here.
Clay Allison died
under the wheels of a wagon.
- He was drunk.
- You don't say.
You're an attorney?
Who's got himself hung recently?
Need anything from town?
No. Is that where you're going?
I gotta pick up some nails and a flint.
Say, those flowers are looking great.
Everything around here does.
When will you be back?
I'll be back in time for dinner.
I've been working out there
for over a month.
All I can say is I'm sorry,
but we require some collateral.
But it's fertile land!
With a small amount of livestock,
I know I could make it
a good ranch in no time.
I'm sure you could,
but we can't loan you the money.
Because I'm Cain.
To be frank, you'd be a poor risk.
But that's not the main reason.
We ask collateral of everyone.
If Miss Alton would put up her deed
on the property,
we'd be glad to make the loan
for livestock.
No, sir, she's got nothing
to do with this.
It's her land.
But it's me that's gonna
make something out of it.
Tell me something, Cain, what
have you done since you got released?
Possibly I can find
some related work for you.
Well, I've had a lot of odd jobs,
but only two things that lasted
for any length of time.
I was a bouncer,
and I did some shooting on a show.
With Ruffalo, of course.
You know Ruffalo?
We loaned him the money
to buy that circus wagon of his.
Do you happen to know
where he is now?
As a matter of fact,
I ran into him last week in Prescott.
Well, kid, he's back with us,
starting tomorrow.
- He is, is he?
- Yeah.
Say, listen, uh,
what'd he have to say?
I mean... did he... did he go into, uh,
any reasons why he left...
No. No, I didn't ask.
All that matters is that he's back.
And we're gonna start
taking in that big money again.
Where's the big box
we put the spent shells in?
It's behind the barrel.
Cain?
What'd you come back for?
For money.
Wait.
Did you...
...say anything to Ruffalo
about what happened?
No, I didn't.
And I don't intend to.
You know,
I wanna tell you something.
I can't see how both you and me
can be in this show.
I was hoping old man Carson
would fix things once and for all,
but he didn't, so I guess
I'll have to call you myself.
Now go get your gun.
What's the matter, old man?
I'm calling you! Go get your gun.
It's back there on the wagon.
Now go get it!
Go on, old man, go get your gun.
Put that thing away, Billy.
Well, okay, I will put it away.
I will put it away.
It is put away.
'Cause I'm just playing.
Hey, you aren't afraid of a kid
who's just playing, are you?
You know, you're right,
it doesn't have to be right now.
But it's gonna be.
"Killer."
"Killer Cain."
What'd you do?
You shoot them all on the back?
You're breaking my hand!
That's right, boy.
I could break your hand right now.
And then where would you be, huh?
Don't you ever try me again.
I've had it with you.
I'll quit this show
when I'm damn good and ready.
And the next time you talk to me,
you say "Mr. Cain." Understand?
Why didn't you tell me
you were leaving?
I didn't plan to.
It just worked out that way.
When you didn't come back,
I went in to Las Rinas and asked around.
Bill Grayley at the bank said
he thought you might be here.
You don't have to do this,
you know?
It's the only way I know
to earn money.
I'll stake you.
No. I couldn't do that.
One wouldn't know it,
looking at you in that getup.
You're a very proud man.
I love you.
You know that.
And I love you, too.
But please try to understand
why I have to do this.
It's not the best way for a man
to make a living, but it's honest.
I just want to make enough money
to buy some livestock,
and then we'll be married.
Who ever would have thought
back in Boston...
...l'd be saying "yes"
in a cheap hotel room in Arizona...
...to a tall gunslinger in black.
Listen, that's the southbound.
I'll make you a deal.
You catch it, go back to Las Rinas,
and I'll come back to you
as soon as I can.
It's a deal.
Keep your hands off of that.
That's Cain's share!
That's Cain's share, yeah.
And which one is mine?
Don't tell me!
The little one is mine.
Yes, that's yours.
- Big one is yours.
- That's right.
This is my show, Billy,
and I pay a man exactly what he's worth...
no more, no less.
It may be your show,
but I am the star, and you know it.
You was, Billy, you was,
until Cain come along.
Twice as many people
are paying to see him.
He's earned his share.
I wanna tell you something.
You know why he came back?
He's in here for just one big one.
Then you know what that scarred-assed
son of a bitch is gonna do?
He's gonna take a walk!
No, he ain't gonna walk away
from all that money, Billy.
The only one who's gonna walk
is gonna be you,
if you don't like the way
I'm running things.
Hell, I can find me half a dozen
sharp shootin' youngsters.
But I'm never gonna be able
to find me another Cain.
Hell, you know
there's no one better than me.
Maybe not, Billy, maybe not.
But you ain't a killer.
How many times
do I gotta tell you, kid?
People want to see a killer.
They pay to see Cain
because he's a killer.
Now you...
you ain't nothin'.
Just a little pissant.
So that's what I gotta be, huh?
A killer!
All right, Rufe, I'll be a killer.
If that's what I gotta be, I'll be one.
Killer.
Oh, God...
I am a killer, Rufe.
Ruffalo?
I come for my money.
All that yours?
Yeah, it sure is.
That's a lot of money
for a kid like you.
I could sure use it.
You know, I don't think
that you know who I am.
Nope.
Billy Valen.
I'm Little Boy Blue.
I like that! I really do.
I really like that.
You're a very funny man.
Now, Mr. Funnyman...
Have you heard of, uh...
...Dan Ruffalo's Shooting Show?
I...
...just happen to be the star.
That's right, I'm the star.
Now you say
that you can use that, huh?
Is that right?
There it is.
Now, if you think
that you can take it, why...
...take it.
Have you ever seen anything that fast?
Didn't anyone ever tell you, boy?
Never holster an empty gun.
You're not... you're not
gonna shoot me, are you?
You bet your ass I'm gonna.
l... I don't wanna die, mister...
He-help me! Help me...
Now laugh.
Go on, laugh.
Like you did in the mine, uh?
Everything around here
looks real nice.
Your husband's done a great job.
Thank you, Mr. Grayley.
We're very happy.
I'm sure you are.
You know, folks up north
sort of consider him as a hero
for bringing in Luke Santee
like he did.
It's ironic, isn't it?
Well, looks like you have company.
I'll be going.
Thank you for dropping by.
- Bye now.
- Bye.
Is your husband around, ma'am?
Why, yes, he's in the back.
Here he comes now.
Hi, there.
What can I do for you?
It's what I can do for you.
I've been looking for you
for quite some time.
Why?!
- Why, why?!
- Why?
All right, I'll tell you why.
Because 20 years ago,
Cain killed my father.
He served 18 years in prison.
No, that was the price of one life.
Cain took 12.
Oh, no!