www.titlovi.com
Leaden rainstorms
Bring disasters upon us.
We carry on our shoulders
war and hardship.
The civil war is raging
all day long.
There are many paths in the fields,
But the truth is only one.
The Civil war is raging all day long.
There are many paths in the fields,
But the truth is only one.
To young heroes of the Civil war
Do you want to say anything?
Or ask for something?
Red dog.
Dad!
The Uncatchable Avengers :-)
- Chieftain, protect us... The cow...
Robbers took the last cow!
- What did you think, you dumbhead?
That your freedom can be gained for free?
She suffered when she bore her children,
And now a new world is born,
and she wants it without pain.
You want it without pain?
- I have children, the last cow...
"Last"! And do you know, you stupid,
that today they took one cow from you,
and tomorrow they will return back ten?
- How can it be?
- Exactly so!
Whose cows were they? Whose?
The lords', the landowners'.
and now they will be yours.
All. Bulls, cows, chicken, pigs -
all will be yours.
- Give me back my cow!
- Wait, sister, we'll give it back.
We'll give everything back.
A free woman.
A citizen.
- So he was buried.
And in the morning they came there and saw:
The grave is dug up and the coffin is empty.
Since then whoever goes past
that cursed cemetery - a trouble happens.
- But people go there?
- No, only in daytime.
- But how did Petro go there at night?
*cuckoo!*
- Did you hear?
Chief, look there!
*Avengers*
- Oh my God, is that true?
- Of course!
- Ilyuha is lying!
- I couldn't believe myself,
but then looked around: the coffin
with the dead was flying above the gravestones,
and along the road were standing corpses with scythes.
And silence...
- Stop. Today you are doing better.
Only when you hit and throw,
push harder with your foot.
- Clear?
- Yes.
The last performance of an actor, lead singer
of the Emperor's Drama and Comedy Theatre!
Here were some clamorous markets,
in these lavish lands! And now...
Freedom. With our chieftain:
cheer up, folks! Gather in your bellies!
Everyone is trading and having fun!
No one is sleeping!
I will tell you, my dear: get everything from
your cellars, or they'll take it for free!
Hey, granny, look! This is the last
performance, I am only passing by.
Today I take the night horse and go
to my beloved city - Odessa.
The city of chestnuts and performers.
I am Buba Kastorsky,
the original performer,
I am singing patter songs,
And I sing them pretty good.
I am singing to my left,
I am singing to my right,
And nodody can sing it the way I do.
And why?
Because I am...
Buba Kastorsky, original performer!
There are gossips going around,
And I've heard from one old woman,
That early in the morning
you hear here and there: cuckoo!
And I am Buba Kastorsky, original performer!
I sing patters, and I sing them pretty well...
- And I see: my Nurka stands there,
and a paper on her horn, and it says:
"We give you back the cow, aunt Darya.
Don't be afraid of robbers,
and if they mess in again - they'll be dead."
- It is their sign: a cuckoo cries and
a rooster answers.
They say, Budenny himself invented that sign.
I swear by God.
They are coming...
And now, the blonde Josie!
This night will stay
forever in our memory.
This night of tamed and
burning heart.
You whispered me until dawn
So passionately and tenderly
that you will marry me.
The night passed,
and grey morning started again.
Again, the rain,
bad weather and fog.
The night passed,
And I can't believe
that my last romance ended this way.
More, more!
- What are you laughing at, stallions?
You've hit the boy and you're happy?
- Your father was more agile!
Are you hurt?
Well, let's go, lad,
have some kvass.
Do you think, lad, that Sidor the Terrible
does not feel sorry
for each orphaned child?
I do.
But this time is such
that we can't help it.
Do you know, how many of my friends
were killed by your father?
I know!
I would hang him even after he's dead!
Your father was such a bastard, lad.
Here, drink.
- Danka is late.
- Don't worry for him!
- Wait, Valerka!
Listen, they are shooting in the village!
- So what?
- Maybe something happened with Danka!
And I think that you are a bad psychologist,
Yashka.
They shoot at random.
So to say, to reassure themselves.
You understand? Cranky.
Why so long, Danka?
- What happened?
- I hit my back.
Burnash's people are in Zbruevka.
- Are there many of them?
- Looks like many.
- For how long?
- I don't know.
- Why did you come back?
- I couldn't stay.
The Terrible recognized me.
- What do we do now?
- We'll find out.
- I'll go, have a look.
- Where will you go?
There are 40 families in Zbruevka, and no guys.
Ones are with Budenny, others with Burnash.
If one of us appears there - they'll find us out.
Ksanka has to go.
Ksan, Ksanka!
Dress up, you'll go to Zbruevka.
Maybe we shouldn't let her go
alone, Dan?
Find out, how many of them are there
and for how long are they staying.
Yashka, bring her to other bank and back.
Understood?
You'll go to auntie Darya.
Good luck, Jeanne D'Arc.
Why does he call you Jeanna Darca?
What for a word is it?
He is kinda psychologist.
Knows different foreign words.
No, Valerka said that she was burned.
Рe would not scruple to tell a lie.
- Ksan, you look better with a scarf.
- Yeah right!
- Certainly.
- What's with you?
- I won't let you alone. We'll go together.
What, do you want to give me away?
There is nothing to discuss, go!
Ksan, wait, wait!
- Did you hear what Danka told?
- It's not that.
- Why is it?
- It is my grandpa's cross, it draws the trouble away.
- I'll go.
- Go!
Cuckoo...
You left her.
Do you hear? You were a coward.
Why do you keep silent?
Well, tell me, you chickened out!
- Don't make noise.
- It comes out, everyone is for himself?
- Yashka couldn't help.
- And you would leave her? - And what's the use?
I wouldn't save Ksanka
and would go for nothing.
Wait for me here. If I don't come back
before night, you go, Valerka.
- Who is there?
- It's me, father Mokey.
Danka, goeie genade.
And I thought that you were... with your father.
I'm alive.
They became angry.
Threw a bell ringer from the church tower.
The bell is silent since Christmas.
Silent.
- Why did you come?
- I am looking for my sister.
Why look for her?
She is in the bar. As a servant.
The Terrible is staying there
with his gang.
Hide my freedom behind a grate,
I will steal it with a grate.
A moon went out and
hid behind clouds again.
Lock a black horse with five locks,
I will steal it together with the locks!
I knew God and Devil,
I was devil and god.
Hide a girl behind a high fence,
I will steal her withthe fence.
Dance!
Give him a guitar.
We are weak, for we are men...
Give me gorilka!
You are a trickster, a rascal.
An unhandled mare, but of good blood.
- How do you know?
- From the teeth.
I looked to the side: a coffin with the dead is flying
above the gravestones,
And along the road -
corpses with scythes.
And silence...
Drink, culprit, get used to our food.
Drink, scrounge, you can't hold
in your hands anything except a guitar.
How are you going to fight with it?
His horse will hold a sabre for him.
Give me gorilka in a mug!
Hey, brothers, hold my hands!
Why are you breaking my dishes, brat?
Why do you interrupt our fun, God-seller?
More gorilka!
A, Ksusha, come here, daughter.
- Hello, uncle Sidor.
- Do they trouble you? - No, not at all.
- I brought you a present, You like it?
- Yes.
- Good, take it.
- Thanks for present.
- Any visitors?
- Not a soul.
- Did she go anywhere?
- Not once.
If something happens - I'll tear your skin off.
She acts as a fool. I feel that
she is together with them.
Any day now they will crow.
If you notice anything, let me know.
So I can't hold anything except a guitar?
Brothers, friends, don't bring me to ruin...
- Maybe it's time, Danka?
- He must give a sign.
- Give me a bullet!
- No bullets!
Father-philosopher, the last bullet.
That's right!
Drink... drink... everybody drink.
*Avengers*
Ksushenka, daughter, do you
want to kill me?
Yashka!
Burnash's people!
Quickly, behind a stand!
Korney, pour a glass for us!
Mikola...
Don't beat him, he is an actor!
black eyes, burning eyes...
Passionate and beautiful.
How much I love you...
Good evening!
Korney!
Where is Terrible?
- Does it hurt? - It's OK.
- Darn you!
What? I am really...
I would walk wounded for all my life.
Sit still, don't move.
- So?
- I killed the bastard.
Comrade Danil, what shall we
do with them?
Go to the church tower, call the people.
The people will judge.
Once the satan walked,
the satan was bored,
He knocked on the door of one soldier girl.
He said: I won't say a word,
He said: I just sit for a while.
I will rest, he said, won't say a word,
I will just sit next to you.
And a girl lives alone for many years.
Satan rested at her place,
And a year later, next to stove,
are banging with spoons
maybe five or maybe seven baby satans.
I would go back to my dearest long ago,
But devil Mahno is standing on the way.
And while I am there in the war,
you, Marusia, don't trust the satan.
Comrade commander!
An urgent message,
comrade commander.
Village Zbruevka is freed
by a squad of some avengers.
- Some... who are they?
- We don't know exactly.
- Do you have any connections with them?
- It is impossible.
- Why?
- They are not there.
- Who? - Avengers.
- And Zbruevka? - Zbruevka is there.
I don't understand.
*cuckoo*
Avengers...
Red avengers!
*To Chieftain Gnat Burnash.*
Valera, have a look.
"Hey, godfather Gnat.
I send you my son Grigory.
I feel that he will be a good cossack.
Don't think that he's too young.
He will cut red robbers,
just like me.
If you knew, how I sometimes want
to ride a horse,
but my arms lost their strength,
and my legs don't walk as before.
Farewell, friend chieftain. Your old
cossack Semyon Kandyba".
- And that Grigory, he is as high as me.
- What do you mean?
I mean, it is a good time to pay a visit
to chief Burnash!
- It is too risky, Danka!
- With this letter there's nothing to be afraid of.
- And if they recognize?
- Who?
Terrible is dead,
And no one else knows me.
With great love and joy
People meet their liberators -
the free army of chief Burnash.
In their impotent rage red comissars
send their hirelings,
to trouble people.
And thus I declare
...that for capture of "red avengers" gang
from chief's own funds will be given:
Money...
Is it Sidor came back?
...in Tsar "katenkas" - 100 roubles,
in "kerenks" - 1,5 meters...
In soviet roubles - 2 thousands
and 5 thousands in cheque from chief himself.
This will be announced over all
villages in two days.
Chieftain Gnat Burnash,
Year 1920, month of May.
You must be mistaken, Sidor.
I know his dad, good cossack Semka Kandyba,
for 10 years.
Did you ask that son of your friend
for any papers?
Put his shirt up and read yourself.
His back is all written over with a whip.
He will carry that "paper" for a long time.
I did it, Gnat, you understand, I did it!
If you want more, chief, I have a full pot.
- Grinya! - What, chief?
- Nothing, go.
And if you need anothe paper, there is
a letter from his father.
You became suspicious, Sidor.
Even me you don't believe.
- I believe my own eyes!
- Sidor!
How long does this cossack stay here?
two weeks?
And now think,
what happened in these two weeks?
A squad of Ilyuha was ambushed.
You will say that this is an accident?
We sent people for bread in the old village -
not a grain, as if there was a secret deal.
And that plaque among the horses -
their water was poisoned.
Your cossackling is planted.
He is a spy.
You are tired from the road, that's why
you see enemies everywhere.
Go have a rest.
Good, doog, chieftain...
And you, lad, thought that you'd buried me?
What are you talking about, uncle Sidor?
You mistook me for someone.
Maybe I mistook.
Ignat!
Saddle my horse.
And keep an eye on this cossack.
if he disappears, I will tear your skin off!
- Why would he disappear?
- They might steal our Grinya.
- Who?
- Red bastards. Understood, fellow?
I couldn't believe myself!
And then looked -
A coffin with the dead flies over gravestones,
And along the road stand corpses with scythes.
And silence...
Watch out!
Horses went mad!
Go!
Grinya, are you hurt?
Goodness.
Bastard, your yeys, parasite.
I'll tell the Terrible...
Uncle Ignat! Come here! What a joy!
Our cossack's father came here!
He's waiting in the headquarters.
Grinya...
- What?
- Chief is calling.
- Something happened?
- Yes, happened. Go!
Grinya, treat is on you!
Go, you'll see yourself.
Go, go.
Birthday child.
You called, chief?
Called.
What are you waiting for, fool?
Hug your dad.
Where is Grinya?
Where is my son?
Grinya!
Don't touch!
That was smart.
Order to guard him properly.
And now I believe. I swear, I believe.
- We have to attack at once.
- No, too much noise.
- And if it won't do, we'll die together.
- Wait with dying.
Maybe we'll think of something better.
- And what if he won't fit?
- He should, if only the rope is strong enough.
- Lies.
- Wait, you. What was next?
And along the road stand corpses with scythes.
And silence...
Lies.
...lies.
- Run, Ksanka is waiting in the ravine.
- Wait, I have a debt here.
It has to be returned.
Lie down!
A chief's cossack, and appears
to be planted.
Throw a lad some potatoes,
what is he dies from hunger.
Unclean... unclean... brothers!
Unclean!
Unclean force here!
He ran!
Ran away!
Unclean! Run for your life!
Brothers... he ran away!
- Ride towards crossroad.
- I'll catch up with you.
- The Reds! - He ran away... - A gun!
Get on your horses, quick, you dogs!
There is he, bastard! Get him!
A horse, give me a horse!
Get him, take him alive!
- Hey, good man,
What is happening here?
- I don't know myself, wait!
- Where are you going? What's happening?
- Fire!
- Run, brothers! Save your lives!
- The Red squads!
- Where do they shoot from?
- Aim!
- Treason!
- He ran! He ran!
Get him! Take him alive!
Go!
Dogs, they rob Budenny's train!
What if we swipe it?
- How?
- I don't know yet.
Wait. It's Grinya, chief's cossack.
Put your gun.
- Throw the bags back!
- Why is it?
Are you waiting for death?
The Reds are just behind us.
The Reds are coming.
In the carriages, quick, fellows!
Set the defence. Machine gun in the cave.
Well, cossack, go in the cave.
Treason!
Burnash's are on the roof!
- Let them get closer.
Yashka!
We'll get to the bridge.
They won't go further. There are our people.
The bridge burns!
Burnash's set it on fire!
- Can we make it?
- We'll try, son.
Fire! The bridge is on fire!
Fellows, jump!
So, guys, let's get acquainted.
- Commander Budenny.
- Danka Shus.
- Sister.
- Ksanka Shus.
Valerka Mesherakov.
- Yashka the gypsy. No surname.
- How can it be? Did you hear, no surname.
Gypsy. Yakov Gypsy,
Do you mind?
He don't mind.
I won't ask about your deeds.
I've heard about them.
You will tell them later,
in peaceful times.
You'll dramatize a little bit, as you should.
If you don't lie a single bit - you won't
tell a story. But later with that.
For now you are soldiers of the regular Red Army.
Let the sinister raven
not hover over the heaths.
Because we are going
to live for a whole eternity.
And if a disaster falls over the world again,
and the sky bursts with fire,
Just whisper us a word,
We'll come to help.
If a disaster falls upon the world,
And the sky bursts with fire,
Just whisper a word to us, we'll come to help.
-=The End=-
Subtitles provided under GNU Public Licence :)
Preuzeto sa www.titlovi.com