Old SureHand
Volume l
Towards a story of Karl May
Hurry.
Outwards.
Go into the next wagon.
Back to the top, you guys.
Make that not too short fuse.
Take special care.
We still have road
may come.
Clint, I'm waiting opje.
Come on, get out.
Eropaf.
Day, gentlemen.
Come quickly to the outside.
Come on.
Yeah, okay.
Clint, get what bison
shooting with Frank.
Those are the Coma Chen.
-I give the orders.
Then come the Coma Chen
down in revolt ...
so that the train robbery is
forget.
Go you not?
-I 'go to' the General '.
Bud and Vic went along.
Use these horses.
BedanM again.
Goodbye.
Frank, look over there.
Get out.
What is it, Bob?
-lndianen, father.
Who are you?
Why are they angry?
They are crazy.
-Here they are. That is fight.
I do not shoot at my friends.
I go with 't talk chief.
Do not, Bob.
Maki-moteh, Maki-moteh ...
Bob, come back.
Maki-moteh ...
why you fall to us?
He wanted them to do no harm.
Not bad. If my head higher
had sat, there was now "in a hole.
Why are you hiding?
I'm Prospector. A gang
has stolen my horse. Poor me.
After they were gone,
I heard gunshots.
Oh yeah?
-Yes, over there.
When I saw you, I loved you for
a bandit and hid me.
How hot you?
Ben-O'Brien.
I'm on the road to Mason City,
but without a horse.
I want that horse do you buy.
I will pay with gold.
Love you but gold. I also go to
Mason City. Gaje with that?
Gold found by Skop Devil?
Yes. How weetjij that?
Doorje best ie red boots.
Wipe them off quickly.
You have a good set of eyes
in your head.
If I had a gold mine, I would
also have eyes in my butt.
Here.
Go ahead.
Welcome to the tenth anniversary
of Mason City
Discarding high hat
of his head. Throw and win.
Welcome to 's tenth anniversary
of Mason City
Can you read?
-No. What's there?
That we are welcome here.
General-Treme we here?
Not mention that name, fool.
Peace Judge
We are very proud of
our large population.
And when it comes track ...
-Does everyone our beautiful city.
Well. I send them now 'n telegram
on that country in the river.
Where you staying? Stupid question.
By Molly, of course.
That 's all good hotel here.
After h.
-Thank you very much.
If it looks administration is
I come back.
Axel ...
What is Mac Hara?
That bastard previous Coma Chen ...
The Coma Chen
have killed his son.
Bob?
Go inside.
Excuse me.
I can 't believe it.
-We 've seen itself.
They are bad.
Burn all white people.
No, Kipko. That is not true.
Alsje chief, I know that.
Some are friendly.
They do not die.
All whites are bad
and they should all die.
Tuwan says no.
We must discover why
our friends on bison hunting.
They are our bison. That is
in a signed paper.
Is miserable moteh-maki inside.
Manitou may protect you.
I live there.
Gaje with me?
My cousin makes
a delicious stew.
She is a lean beetie ...
Hey, moetie that.
We would just like to watch.
How do you like that?
Where is my prize, sir?
I want the 1st prize.
I've beaten 3 times.
2 times. Can not you count?
Love you still.
Come on, get out.
I believe you can not count.
Come on, give her the prize.
Stay out of this.
That had you not to do.
Put me down, put me down.
Three times.
-Yes, and without cheating.
Thank you very much.
-Good.
Please.
-Thank you!
I get no more kiss?
-O, Uncle Ben.
I deje barely recognizable.
She said that you were dead.
-lkke not hear.
What do you think of my niece?
Well, I think its not so skinny.
What have you gotten big,
Toby.
The city is committed trob opje.
I'm right help.
-If you look too.
Sir, you are legally
now guilty of mistreatment.
I think he deserves a kiss.
-Judith, right.
For her, I dug 2jaar
in the mountains. And I've geboft.
You mean ...
-Yes, at Devil head.
At the foot of the mountain.
Enough for a dowry.
Only alsje uncle's claim
submitted on time ...
voorbiipraat and not his mouth.
Uncle, who is this man?
-I do not know.
Since I am still behind.
I'd like a cold beer.
Hey, I'd like a beer.
Only when the Twilight incident.
Miss Molly that has so determined.
Can I perhaps
what music?
Listen, there is now
no music.
There he is.
You do spunky. You scratch now.
We are closed.
I would not zatlappen.
Listen, was scratched.
How are you, Molly?
-Johnny.
How you doing, honey?
That is a long-ago.
Where have you been?
-Yon.
And soon vert rack again.
You're nothing changed.
One door in
and the other door.
Who heeftje slain brother now?
-No idea, I still search ...
but the court seems
want to speak.
You know Molly, you are
to the day younger.
Chen have Coma
Mac Hara's slain son.
Who were there?
-A couple of strangers.
They reported it now before the courts.
-They 're actually seen.
How it happened, does not matter.
It's done.
That attack surprised me.
What was the purpose?
They had no purpose.
Ikjuist say that, Judge.
Seventy Indians started
just to shoot.
Are you sure?
-Yes, of course.
Sir, Indians never fall
without reason.
Moreover surprised 't me
you're away.
You are right, right.
That is very strange.
It is the good Chen Coma
Since it Convention.
You can then just as well say
that they have robbed the train.
What do you say now?
The train with wage lists
was robbed at St Creek.
The passengers also?
-Yes, but I would send aid.
Toby, this is the man to whom I
had requested.
You know what you should do.
Go to the sherim.
Good stranger,
my assistant will arrange everything.
_jk, a Comanche.
-Come on, we seize him.
Those bloody red skins too.
Fuck this town.
Get out.
You, murderer.
Murderer, I kill you.
Give me your weapon.
But he was unarmed.
Let him speak.
Day, Tuwan.
Murder by getting your son
not returned.
You do not know how it is to keep your son
to be murdered.
He is innocent.
I am for him.
Are you satisfied now?
Welcome to Mason City.
It says' Welcome '.
Maki-motehs son
believed those words.
You have an unarmed
man killed.
"The tenth anniversary
City of Mason. "
This will allow you el! Birthday
are never experience.
Come inside.
-Are you alone, right?
Ah Johnny, I understand
that you wanted to remain incognito.
Hi, Dick.
-Good to see you.
Unfortunately, we have now
trouble.
Problems search me.
I'm looking really no problems.
I had the murder of that poor
kid but can occur.
Would you be the case with the Indians
can soothe?
You know them through and through.
Would you oveMregen?
-No, right.
I am not here for.
Why would you see me?
I know where Jeremy Sanders is.
-Jeremy?
That has my brother
not murdered.
That thought the rest, but I do not.
There 's a premium on his head.
A very big.
The government is searching for him all 3jaar.
They see him as the perpetrator.
Jeremy was practically family.
Find him
and go talk to him.
Well. Where is he?
-That will tell ikje now.
There is already 3 years' n hermit
on the Grizzly Mountain.
An Indian tree
has recognized him.
That is our man: Jeremy.
From now on I will win.
I'm broke.
You have a lot of money
of me winning.
This is perhaps sufficient.
Can I see?
-Of course.
Shuffling the cards than you
again?
This should not be found.
There's still mud on.
Yes, those golden eggs
are given fresh today.
Where is the chicken in these eggs?
-Here.
That you would like to see, HC?
This is the man I've seen.
How do you know so sure?
He seems not even to Jeremy.
I have seen his face.
He is.
Well. Judge
we begin morgenòchtend.
Yes, Schneider?
-The corpse of the Indian is gone.
Wait here.
Come on.
Where the corpse was, is now this stuff
like a kind of card.
Indians who are really mad.
Maki-moteh has his son
fetched.
The funeral will take exactly
three days.
And then?
-Then there will be war.
Unless you are the offender
brings to the chief.
What should I do?
Start at the bison poachers who
IOGEN on the Comanche attack.
But Bob Mac Hara
has been shot dead.
From the front or rear?
-MaaM that?
Help us with this case.
-No, right.
Schneider, more than this.
If something happens, I go to.
lndianen have my mom
and 3 brothers slain.
I've still only Uncle Ben.
-And me.
That is liefvan you,
But you can not even shoot.
I can still learn?
That be_ijfel-I.
You can learn sewing,
Like Webartikelen ...
but to shoot
talent is needed.
However, I can tell, though.
Silence again.
What is it?
No movement.
Goodbye, Judge.
Watch out.
Thank you, young lady.
-You 're welcome.
That is number one bison hunter.
Want to bet?
What is wrong?
I heard a shot.
You're right.
But why he wanted you
murder?
Maybe did my face
him, or something.
And the other?
-Will we arrest him?
For just as it ends like this.
Tom? Williams?
Bring him to the sherim.
Say that I come out.
Folks, go back home
and forget this.
Zoieb vergeetje not.
Good night.
-You also judge.
Good night, kids.
-I 'm coming.
Nothing.
You go to bed where you belong.
If they had been in bed,
was now dead.
That is true, young man.
So thanks again, jumrouw.
Why not show your thanks
clearer what?
What should I do that, ju_rouw?
You are a man
and I am a girl.
Judith, though.
You remind me of somebody.
What did they look?
O, she was just as nice as u.
Toby.
-That you still want him?
Listen, if someone you coast,
I am.
You know not.
He is a real man.
You are a book worm.
Toby again, this shooting
has established consequences.
Hello, Ben.
-Good evening.
Get out of here.
You've just killed someone.
He deserved the death
because he was a criminal.
Criminals must stiff you.
From whom is this correct
Opinion?
My name is O'Neal.
Jack O'Neal.
My company wants here 'n branch
settle.
What makes your company?
Weapons and machinery.
-What a combination.
Destruction and construction.
Moetjij not go to court?
That can-tomorrow too.
It also said the overnight flight.
These are all gentlemen, you know.
-Men, did you say?
Hey, gotta see that again.
Put your money down, mister.
You're a cheat.
-Toby.
Hebje that is not needed.
S what I saw ...
Here we go again.
Guys, stop.
Kappen, I said.
Help.
-Come.
_jk go.
Fast. Stand up.
-Judith, beware.
Everybody out.
The champion.
That fell against HC?
-For 's book worm was' t it.
Please.
That is free.
Hello, young man. You fight well,
but please note on your chin.
I wish you best give some tips.
-I 'm do without. Thank you.
Uncle Ben.
They have 't gold
and the card stolen.
Did he 's recognized?
Was it an Indian?
-No.
Toby ...
-Yes, Ben?
Soon it is up to you ...
Why so nervous?
-I 'm not.
That's a sign.
Manitou does not want ikje initiated.
That is not Manitou.
-The pass is there. You can find him so.
Hey, come back.
Hurry. Come on.
Calm down. Ho, kid.
Come here.
Come on, kid.
What a onhangst, HC?
Jeremy.
Jeremy, I know you there
within it.
Get out. Leave me alone.
Been scratched.
Jeremy, put the gun down.
Be not afraid.
I am. Johnny Garden.
Hold on,
maaM you scared my horse.
Why Do you believe me?
I'm Johnny Garden.
That is what you say.
Johnny is my buddy.
And if his voice sounds not.
And now opgerot. Get out.
You stubborn donkey. I tell you anyway
I'm Johnny Garden.
Prove it then.
Johnny was from 300 meters
from the heart 'n bait shooting.
Oh, you ...
Well, then.
Come on, kid.
I'm ready.
Johnny.
-Yes, whom do you expect?
Hello, Johnny.
I am.
My god, old man.
Doin 'what have they done?
Hebjeje razor lost?
-Yes, you see.
Come, we'll just
refurbishing.
Look, that's better. So I know
Wobble my old again.
Thanks, Johnny.
Sorry old man, that thing
I have nothing to do.
But after the murder of my brother
's money away and you, too.
So when the state thought
datjij something to do with it.
Dachtjij that?
Dachtjij that it was me?
Come on, say.
You know better.
But why are you when
disappeared?
I would not go away,
but I was Estimated.
I fell faint in the bushes
and when I return bij_am ...
said the sheriff:
I want him dead or alive.
He thought I
the killer was.
They would not believe me anyway
So I raaMe in panic.
And when I go here.
Poor-old Wobble.
Al diejaren on your own
for nieb.
Toe old man, tell me
Who has killed my brother.
I really do not know that.
You've seen yet
how he looked?
I do not know anymore.
They were all masked.
I therefore do not recognize.
I really do not know.
I'm sorry.
I know it.
Then I'm back to square one
and I still know nothing.
I swore
that I would avenge my brother.
Now I will have my word
break.
No, do not.
We start immediately.
Why? Now?
Yes.
Now hebje me
to the affairs.
That is true, old man.
Without you I am nothing.
Are you really?
-Of course.
Jii is my talisman.
Come on.
-Wait a minute.
First, my hat and gun yet.
But her take longer than expected.
-No?
Sure Hand. Hey, Sure Hand ...
I just remember something.
-What then?
They were masked, but
I have 'a name heard.
Which name?
-I forgot.
Do not be silly. Which name?
-Listen, that name was ...
What was that name?
They called someone
the general.
A General, HC?
Sure Hand, why this man wanted
murder me?
Perhaps he wanted not
that you would betray his name.
Yes, of course.
That's a good point.
Say, if I go metjou ...
and they see that I am still alive
try it again.
Yes, but not maakje pressure.
I note opje.
On second thoughts
my cave like me actually.
I like living here.
I'll stay here. I am not them.
Wobble.
Had you thought Wobble
IAF was?
What? Who said that?
Listen, I'm happy here.
I would really love to help you ...
but your one horse
We can not both contribute.
I'm sorry.
But understand it, HC?
Look what it says?
Oh, there is a horse.
, In the saddle.
Crazy guy.
I am a super spoorzoeker.
These are Comanche Trace.
Coma Chen, HC?
Come on, tell more.
There is also little to tell.
There is someone.
I feel that my water.
How do you know it?
-Well, I'm afraid.
Look, I beef altogether.
-That says nothing. You always tremble.
But you are right.
We are viewed.
Where is he?
-Oh, you do not need.
Winnetou Okay, come now
appear.
I knew that my friend the tracks
my horse would recognize.
Comanche Trace, HC?
-Oh ...
You come for the drums.
Maki-moteh collect aid
for a war against the whites.
We must stop them.
I was going to Maki-moteh.
Listen, there are now whites
in the camp of Maki-moteh.
She promised him 100 guns
for a piece of barren land.
You know how that whites are called?
-No.
But the oldest of the _ee
General was mentioned.
Maybe he will.
-I told you I would regulate it.
Good old Wobble.
My talisman. Come on.
And, Toby?
-This is more fun than the office.
What begins' t Comanche Country?
We are al -
Before we go stroomopwaarb,
equip us. Good?
I got hungry and we are only
after dark at Devil head.
Hopefully we find route
the killer remains.
I want that card back.
-And if he does not want to give?
We need him dead.
That murderers deserve.
No Judith, even murderers
deserve a fair trial.
You were great.
I had never thought of that.
Why do not you shot?
-Because he can not lap.
What do we do with him?
You would really have to question
: what do they do with us?
Fast.
Come, bukje.
She let them dry in the sun.
That is bad. I once three days
led to some doubt.
Liar,
that means nobody vol.
Now I think about it, can
days have been included.
What should we do?
We have to swim there
and liberate them.
What is it?
-Eh, I can not swim.
Come on.
You, stupid ...
Wait here.
Forgive me, Judith.
It's all my fault.
I never got to Haj
take.
It is not iouw debt, Toby.
You have to blame me,
because now we are ...
perhaps killed.
Come on, hurry up.
Whatever happens,
you need to know ...
I altiid you've taken.
Toby O,
I love you, too.
No matter what happens.
We are not yet dead.
Hey, you. Get your head.
I want him to talk.
He will get him.
Go to the chief.
Zieje what I see?
Do not come up.
They can not play.
Resistance is useless.
It can not face turned away.
Our rope is too strong.
Thank you.
-Take the boat.
And you?
-I 'm so. Haastje.
Wobble, get the horses.
If I 's chief released
He Iaat me finish?
I give you my word.
Speak.
They say it's Maki-moteh
son wants revenge with a war.
That is true.
-To the death of a man ...
many tribal members die.
So be it.
-And just because it is your son?
If I bring you the offender ...
Then there will be peace,
Old Hand Sure.
Can you?
-I will bring you the man.
If you're not back
for the drums silence ...
we will attack.
I will do my best.
Time is running out. Remember that.
-I know.
This is only a real man.
Moetjeje not dress
for he is?
My clothes are still wet, and I want
see how he reacts to me.
He will laugh as he introduces you
ant hill that looks lie.
Please.
Sure Hand, you were great.
Forget it.
What do you still here?
We are looking for my Uncle Bens
and his killer.
You never find my Bens
in them days. This is madness.
This is no place for a girl.
-I know.
That moetie say to her.
Hey, Wobble.
-Here I am.
Well done.
Fine. Are good, HC?
Stop.
Wait here a minute.
Is there any news?
Poor nieum:
Fort Brighton send soldiers.
Maki-moteh will you be in debt
and then there will be war.
The cavalry is
always a bad time.
Can you stop them?
-I will do my best.
Winnetou has more
nieu_.
General who you want,
Here is nearby.
The Coma Chen have
100 guns from him purchased.
He sits in the old post office.
Two hours drive to 't west.
I look forward to all three years that
meeting.
BedanM, old friend.
Winnetou is pleased
that he could help.
Fort Brighton has soldiers
sent.
Someone should stop them.
Why look at me?
-You have to do. Go soon.
Say you do that to me
to come?
It's a male job.
You can find it sometimes too dangerous?
Well, I do it.
General Brown say on my behalf
that he pulls back its soldiers.
Do not worry, I do.
Fine.
He has no weapon.
-Wobble?
Come on.
-What? My arms?
Thank you.
Be careful.
-I 'm so.
Will he care of yourself fit?
Come on, we are going to the General
search by the post office.
Well, you know.
Really?
I told you:
With me there Lum it.
Would anybody be?
-You must.
My nose says that there
chicken soup on the fire state.
The coast is clear.
You scared me.
We thought this house
was uninhabited.
Come on.
I'm pleased with the company.
The best is lonely.
Do you live here alone?
-Most of the time.
My husband is opjacht.
-Check this out, Johnny.
My friend has quite hungry.
Stay still eat.
-Please. You can 't miss it?
I always make too much for
the case my husband comes home.
Where can I find the signs?
-Here.
I am eager.
Have you recently
seen strangers?
We are looking for a friend.
No, I've been over 'n month
nobody seen.
Strange. I thought outside
to see fresh tracks.
Right. That is crazy, because I have
nobody has seen weeks.
The soup looks good,
hc Wobble?
So can I 'm not create.
We were still only, you said?
All-forgotten.
My father is sick upstairs.
He is crippled.
Eat more reassured.
I look just what he wants. See you soon.
She is very gashrij, HC?
Would it really her father ZiiN?
For a lame
he makes a lot of tracks.
What is this a delicious soup.
If you schranst,
you get abdominal pain.
Who knows when we again
Iekker eat.
Is it that big?
-Yes, you doetje job well.
The next step, you know.
-Yes, Jim. The bottle of wine.
When they sleep, I care
that they never get up.
You can not force me to him
to murder. That is common.
But Della, this is all
for you.
I don 't alone
if we get out here.
I nevertheless promised hebje
that we here?
Well Jim,
I will do what you say.
Everything good?
-Yes, sure.
He wanted to know
who was there.
That chicken soup was delicious.
Can I still 'n portion?
Go ahead.
But it was rattlesnake soup.
That is my specialty.
You to fine him was nice.
Rattlesnake ...
Hey pal, have some soup?
No, thank you so.
My belly rattle quite.
Come on, a little bit. Here.
-No, no.
I want celebrating your arrival
with a bottle of wine.
What a gashrijheid.
Now refurbished on my belly.
Well, cheers.
-Shame Wobble. Ladies first.
Relax, soon to become drunk.
No, never Wobble
drunk.
Thank you. Good wine.
Rattlesnake soup. Unbelievable.
It works really well.
Wobble what are you doing
on the ground?
Wobble, you're drunk.
Nothing thereof. I'm just tired.
-Moe, HC?
Do you have a room where my friend
can sleep? He is tired.
That way.
-The rattlesnake.
Excuse me.
I'm so sober ...
as it can.
Rattlesnake soup, HC?
Killing your friend always chairs?
-Excuse me.
The wine was certainly very strong.
So I know him not at all.
Mr. Garden, I ...
I do not know what to do with me
going on ...
Here we go again.
That was me the wine did.
Wobble, sliding once again.
Rattlesnake soup ...
Tell me, what was in that wine?
-What a stupid question, Sure Hand.
Go on, go in again.
Keep moving.
Jim.
Jim?
Jim, come on down.
It is governed.
For the security Blijfjij
but here.
Jim ...
-No panic.
The General gives us
$ 2000 for our work.
So there it is.
What a beautiful sight.
I make him in his sleep.
If I murder him go,
I can 't do better now.
Now you are the person
who has not killed me.
I hebje wine data. Your
must have been drinking.
I actually drink
only beer and whiskey.
Doeje hands but slowly
up.
I do not shoot at women.
-As you get sorry.
You would want You to me
was murdered. Filthy pig.
I kill you slowly
and I will enjoy your suffering.
Do eerstje hands
but it 's up.
What is that noise?
How can I sleep well
with all that geknal around me?
Fort Brighton is there?
What should you do?
-Are you nothing.
Isn 't that way?
-You need something polite questions.
It is that way.
Come with us.
We go to the general.
I got a important message
for General Brown.
Come, then we go.
Squadrons, halt.
That did hurry.
-Yes, quite.
It is a white and
with others. A woman.
Is my message is not on_angen?
-What message?
Who are you?
I Sure Hand-hot.
Right. I've heard of you.
-I bring you quickly up to date.
Should this Fort Brighton
proposals?
Dirty dogs.
You are here
in the labyrinth of death.
Foryou comes only from
alsje the road well.
The General is waiting inside of you.
-Get inside, you.
92, 93, 94, 95, 96, 97, 98, 99.
Exactly 100.
Why hide your card
for me?
Let 's see where Ben took gold.
Look, Joe.
Turn not such a tone with me.
I'm the boss here,
So you do what I say.
Wii still share everything?
You can even view the map.
-I am done talking.
General, General. ..
-What is it?
The boys have a strange
brought.
On whose authority is he here?
-He was abducted on Pofters warrant.
Who is the boss? Potter or I?
Wind-you do not like.
This guy had a message for
General Brown.
Since you supposedly
General re ...
I was a lieutenant in 's army
of the confederation.
Come and get out.
Where is Pofter now?
-That 's hand Surefire back to Old.
Then he must be careful.
But let 's op. He is a hard.
Oh, I kenjou.
-That 's correct.
You work with Judge Edwards
in Mason City.
By chance I am his assistant.
You had a message of Sure Hand
for General Brown.
What was that message?
-I say nothing more.
You sense, but knot in your ears
I'm the boss here.
You have a half hour waiting period. As
you want to talk to you and that is down ...
but you call a guard.
Guard?
How are you, young man?
Besefje that you do
no chance?
Time is running out.
Would you tell me something?
Fine, ste_je then.
Too bad that you
on the wrong side.
If 't Indian army field
enters ...
is not to prevent a war.
But I must Chen Coma
to watch them in action.
You bet
that they will do so.
I got my orders.
-Toe, captain.
Sometimes it eerzamer
to 'n order not to perform.
What would you do in miin position?
Do you know the Valley of Skeleften?
No. Maybe my tree.
Boniah, come here.
Is it reliable?
One hundred-percent.
Boniah, this man he wants to speak.
Boniah? So called hunters
in Coma Chen.
Are you a Comanche?
-No, a Pueblo.
I've always lived here.
Ken JII the Valley of the Skeletons?
Yes, on the edge of the area
Coma of Chen.
He knows what it is.
-Good, Boniah. You can go.
You go over there and watch.
Whatever you do,
In no case open fire.
If your men stay calm,
this battle is won.
Well, I do what you want.
But if it goes wrong ...
I come before the firing squad.
Please adhere to my friend and she?
Thank you.
You stay here.
I am looking for Toby.
Find him, please.
It is my fault that he is here.
Quietly, I bring him back.
Really, I still prefer cutting
my tongue off.
Explain why you agree Caucasian
brothers hate.
It was a trifle.
I cheated at 't play poker ...
and when I had 's army from.
-Maki-moteh snaptje.
The horses are loaded.
If you keep your word, you get
one tenth of Devil head.
It is yours.
Take it.
Toe, inwards again.
A nice commodity.
-I hope you 're right.
What do you mean?
-There is still a problem.
Soon is it is not gold.
Listen, I was a lieutenant.
I can read the map.
Four eyes see more than that.
Well, I've Maki-motehs son
Estimated different from 100 meters.
Did you hear that? He is the offender.
-You heard it too.
My words have
much authority among the Indians ...
but in a rechbzaal be
only whites believed.
You can 't post
find?
Sure Hand I say it
where the General is.
Tuwan say that he has slain.
-What are you gonna do?
I'll follow the killer.
Sure Hand must be quick,
because at dawn ...
silence the drums of death.
-I will be blazing fast.
Wait a minute.
I have no horse.
Look.
The horse is best for you.
Sure Hand.
What doejij there?
-I am in the water cases.
There is but one waterpoel
and you fall in it.
Why are you not 't Fort?
-Listen, I've discovered something.
What then?
-The General Tuwan killed.
Can you prove that?
-He seized on there.
Well done.
That should Maki-moteh know.
And the general then?
-That we find later.
I wait for three years,
So three hours there may still be at.
There they are with their new
guns.
What do you know?
-The Squadrons attracts a fight.
They wait for Maki-moteh.
Where are they?
Their goal was
the Valley of Skeleften ...
So I got them to the Valley
Gil brought the Lost.
Good. They will not
Maki-motehs escape revenge.
We must warn them.
Come on.
Where is that gold?
-That I am not saying.
We want to see that map.
Where is it gold? Speak.
There, in exactly crucifixion.
-Look out.
Are you crazy?
-No, I did everything in their hands.
That map is now in my head.
There should be nothing over me.
Avoid that I become sick, give
me to eat me and my gun alone.
Your fear that I 's secret
take in my grave ...
is the best life insurance
I can wish.
My dishonor onblag
they may regret.
Wobble Oh, thank God
he is back.
Not bad.
-Toby.
Where is your tree?
-No idea.
It is a traitor.
He is now in Maki-moteh.
I have them shoot traitor.
Otherwise, I do okay.
How are you doing, old man?
I want to go back to my cave.
Since I had to be maintained.
This valley was still your idea?
I said the Valley Skeletons of.
Not the Lost Gil.
Do you have the killer?
-No, but I know where he is.
Say that but against Maki-moteh.
Easy-General.
What? If the Coma Chen us
here are surprised we lost.
Unfortunately, they surprised us all.
Look.
Mlm on, old man.
That is the martial.
If I still alive.
Not give up, captain.
I will see what I can do.
Good luck.
No, you stay here to
to protect these people.
Hear Blazer ...
bladder "alarm".
Come on.
Maki-moteh Yes, you're right.
It would be murder.
They have no chance.
Road weapons.
Old Hand Has Sure nieu_
Maki-moteh for?
Chief, I am a traitor
execute.
I do not like traitors
or they just white or red.
Boniah was useful, but weak.
Sure Hand has acted properly.
And? Did you killer
by Maki al-motehs son?
No, but I know who he is,
and also where he is.
The drums of death remain silent.
My warriors want to fight.
Who is the killer?
-It 's your arms supplier.
It is the general.
-Not true.
I never lie.
You tried to hebtje
the murderer of your son.
Hii was not.
You're no friend,
but a traitor.
If whites in emergency screening,
they always lie. I am now.
Maki-moteh want to Winnetou
Iuisteren?
Winnetou is a white friend.
He will die with the rest.
That makes for moteh-Maki.
What awaits Maki-moteh
still on?
Would he like revenge ...
that he is the difference between
good and evil no longer see?
Why shoot Maki-moteh not?
That he never dum.
Winnetou take too much risk.
-I know why.
Friendship is everything for him.
Schietje why not?
Maki-moteh is sometimes cowardly?
Maki-motehs hand trembles.
So I will give the order.
Listen, Chen Coma ...
I am here.
Hurry.
Questions jullieje off
why Winnetou still alive?
The General wanted more
than a piece Devil head.
He gafjullie loose flodders
and hoped opjullie death.
Then he would very Devil Skop
beziften, including the gold mine.
Yes, he has the map
in his head.
Winnetou has come for you
to prove that this is true.
I thank Manitou
I'm not too late.
I am pleased with your arrival.
I am sorry.
Then enter the heart of swab.
Maki-motehs grief maaMe
him blind. He embarrassed.
That does not.
To err is human.
Chief,
I got a nice idea.
Let your men and loose
flodders shooting.
Then shoot 's army in the air.
-Simple.
If the soldiers then
lie ...
the crooks will definitely
the 'similar' to rob.
Then we tackle them.
-Good idea.
Have fun.
I have an appointment now
with the general.
Winnetou is doin 'it.
No, I am waiting here for three iaar on.
This is a family matter.
Do you understand?
Listen to my advice.
Take 't path along the river
and barring the secret exit.
Thanks, Winnetou.
Sure Hand ...
Doin 'Can I come?
Yes. You're practically family.
Goodbye.
Come on.
That sounds like me music
in the ears.
Go there. Who is still alive, make
you. Then the mine of us.
I am not going. That is too risky.
Like a lost ball hits me,
the gold mine is nowhere to be found.
You're right.
It is a lot better ...
if someone you bewaaM.
Mike, Blacky ...
monitor our good friend
and leave him alone. Understood?
Maakje not worry, Joe.
We will 'm not offend her.
After you, General.
Liiken who rob, guys.
Grab what you can tackle.
Let your arms fall.
Hands opje head.
Listen well, a joke
and it is over.
Come on, give me a reason to
fire, that is because I love.
Your turn.
Here you are arrested.
How did you let the General
escape?
Well, hebjii as lucky.
Sergeant, who on_apen men
and buoy them.
Collect the weapons.
Mii shoot would be foolish.
That we need gold
man with a lot of parts.
Put away those weapons
and tell me where Satan is Skop.
What do you mean?
-We are with his three.
If we share, we can
quiet lifestyles.
So that mean you.
Now we divide it among ...
That never?
Right? General?
Sorry, Blacky. Now it 's mine.
Who would still life, denkje?
-The General.
I take that side.
You stay here.
And if he comes out then ...
I may not doin 'it?
-No, you stay here.
If necessary ikje have, I call it.
What did I make? I now hebje
needed. Gotta come see me.
You stupid idiots.
Not so fast.
Get your arms out.
Very slowly.
High in the air.
Throw it away.
Come on.
Brave boy.
I will me introduce myself.
I'm Johnny Garden.
The brother of Paul Garden.
Do you remember?
The man you back in his lap.
I wait here all times ...
And now ...
-Can we nieb regulate?
I do not have that gold
and there is a lot.
Only I know where it lies.
-Interesting.
Let me live, then we share it.
I do not kill you. I am not dead
unarmed people.
No mister, you'll hang.
Hang out.
But first I have
ieb do otherwise.
Come on.
Ah, there he is al
Sure Hand, Sure Hand ...
What is it? Are you sick sometimes?
Maybe you
drinking too much.
Hey, what doeje now?
Let me go.
Wobble?
Ofje friend gun down vote.
Hurry, Sure Hand.
Maakje not worry about me.
Old man, I'm afraid
that we have been.
He is too smart for us.
Teach me too 's shooting
without focus.
Without touching me, of course.
Blood ...
You okay?
-Am I dead?
No idea,
but I'm not an angel.
Squadrons, forward.
Well captain,
end well, all right.
Thank you. I've learned a lot
in the last few hours.
Not only here but also there.
-You will be fixed soon colonel.
Formatted your promotions
but out.
Guys, where is Winnetou?
-Yon.
This is only a man.
He-he?
He of course. We get married.
-Really?
I like the mine search
of Maki-moteh.
Congratulations doin 'millionaire, Toby.
Without-card 't difficult.
I can determine.
Here is my wedding gift.
The General had the map
copied.
O Sure Hand, he're great.
How can we thank you?
-By happy to be.
Say, sometimes wachtje
on the coach?
HC? You mean I can join?
Of course. What am I without you?
Come on.