- Martin speaking.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I was sleeping.
- It's 2 p.m., sleepyhead.
I was working on the script
all night.
I have good news.
I heard about an expert
on Frank Lowies.
I've arranged to meet him.
- We get the story for 5000 kroner.
- 5000? Have you lost your mind?
- Who the hell is this guy?
- He's called Crazy Uffe.
But we better not call him that.
He hates it.
- You're late.
- I had to get the money.
- Do you have it?
- 3000.
- He wants 5000.
- I'm a student. When is he coming?
He's sitting right over there.
Christ, he's a drunk.
Will he want to talk to us?
Come on.
My name is Camilla.
I'm the producer
of the short we're making.
- Who's this joker?
- Martin, the director.
He's also writing the script.
Oh. Do you have the money?
We have 3000.
Then forget it.
Fine. We're leaving.
I'll take the 3000.
- But you're buying the beers.
- That's a deal, Crazy...
I mean...
What should we call you?
Just call me Crazy Uffe.
All the assholes do.
I'll pay the bill later. Okay?
Have you ever heard
of Frank Lowies?
I've done some research on him.
Frank was the toughest guy
in Copenhagen.
And because he was the toughest,
people always challenged him.
So my sons stole some motorcycles,
and you're going to beat them up?
It's because you owe us money,
you bastards.
- Brian?
- You had fucking six months to pay.
When you owe my sons money,
you pay up. And I don't like threats.
Let's take this outside. Now!
Come on, guys.
Shall we get started, ladies?
Get him, Dad.
- Aren't you exaggerating a bit?
- He beat up at least 4 or 5 guys.
I suppose you want to hear the story
about the money Frank stole and hid.
- Isn't that just an urban legend?
- You want to hear it or not?
I got mixed up in that shit
because I owed Yugo Ivan money.
- Did you know Yugo Ivan?
- I worked for him.
Here's the story that I told Ivan.
Tell me the story
from the very beginning.
Frank Lowies, the smuggler
from the '60s. Remember him?
Sure. He buried 10 million kroner
somewhere or other.
- It's an urban legend.
- No, it's true.
Frank robbed a money transport
vehicle 7 years ago.
Together with Ramirez,
a South American,
and a guy called Shameer.
Paki Shameer? And the seven
Dalton brothers from Pakistan.
Hand over the money!
This isn't a joke!
Open the register!
What was that?
Don't give me any lip.
Those are my kind of guys.
Shameer got greedy in the getaway
car, and they had an accident.
They fled, but were caught
and put away like that.
All the money wasn't recovered.
Frank was released first...
...and rumor has it
that he hid some of it.
- 10 million?
- No, only 5. But it's money.
- 5 million?
- Frank is said to have a tattoo.
On himself?
Frank has one, and three
other people have one, too.
Together they show where the money
is hidden. Like a treasure map.
Shameer got out of prison
two weeks ago.
He came straight here to get
the money he'd been cheated out of.
He'd heard the South American
had a tattoo.
He visited him first.
I've been looking forward
to this day for a long time.
But I'm kind of happy.
So I'm giving you a chance.
What are the other numbers?
Hey, Latino. Try cheating death
just like you cheated us.
Sorry to interrupt,
but who fired the gun?
Shameer's little brother. Pucha.
Aren't you listening?
Sorry, do go on.
Frank didn't know
Shameer was back.
I have always been
the best card player. Three.
Not so fast, kid.
- What the hell?
- There goes your welfare check.
- You cheated. I'm sure of it.
- The hell I have.
Relax, Frank.
You're just a fucking bad loser.
Screaming Pete, you saw him cheat,
right? Why don't you ever talk?
He hasn't talked since Christmas.
I'm leaving before you rob me
of my last 50.
- Hi, brother. Can I have a word?
- All the smugglers are back together.
- Hi, Brian.
- What the hell? It talked. It spoke!
- You guys been popping Viagra?
- Shut up. What are you doing here?
- Aren't you picking up Sonny?
- He'll be released tomorrow, Dad.
- Uncle wants to talk to you.
- Need to borrow more money?
No. At least not right now.
I need to talk to you. It's important.
Keep your hands off my whisky.
I heard that Paki Shameer is out.
He and his crazy brother
are looking for you.
- Him as well? Who told you?
- It's the talk of the town.
- You cheated him out of some money.
- I've never cheated anyone.
- He says he'll blow you away.
- Those punks don't scare me.
The five are still there,
aren't they?
Yes, sure.
- How much have you taken?
- Not much.
- How much, you fat slob?
- 200.
- 200?
- Two hundred... thousand.
Keep your hands off it.
You got that?
The two Pakis know
about the tattoos.
What will you do now?
I'm going for a meal.
- Good idea.
- Alone.
What's up, Shameer?
What idiot let you out?
Can't say that I've missed you.
I heard about what happened inside.
Your dad's a fucking thief.
Sonny has a hot temper.
Hand over our money.
"Our"? What does the jerk
mean by "our money"?
Come on.
Show us your tattoo.
Where's Ramirez?
Do what you came to do, Shameer.
The only thing you'll get
out of me is blood.
Shit!
Sonny will get you,
you Paki bastard.
Hey, Sonny!
Free as a bird!
What's up, little brother?
You look good for a jailbird.
- Your bike's ready at the shop.
- Did you get hold of Dad?
- He's probably on a binge.
- What about Ramirez?
Shameer almost killed him.
What does he want?
- Where's my hash, you fag?
- Come on. Let's find Dad.
Dad?
- Open up. It's Sonny.
- And Brian.
Open the damn door!
What do we have here?
My two useless brats.
Call an ambulance.
Forget it.
I'm done for.
Shut up, Dad.
Call a fucking ambulance now!
Did Shameer do that to you?
Get hold of Michelle.
Get the money before that Paki...
Sonny...
- What's he saying?
- Okay.
The ambulance is on its way.
Don't talk.
Dad! Don't die.
Don't die, Dad!
Shit!
- What did Frank whisper to Sonny?
- In a minute.
Ramirez kept his word to Frank
and stayed away for two years.
But now he wanted to find the money
and get back at Shameer.
- Who do you go to for spare parts?
- Tuki.
Tuki? Tuki?
Ramirez, my friend!
How are you?
What happened?
Did you get hit by a truck?
Funny, Tuki. Very funny.
Come on.
Do you want some tea?
Or food?
I just made some farsouli.
Tuki's best.
No food. Spare parts.
Come, I'll help you.
Tuki always helps his friends.
Bullets?
I heard that Shameer
is in Copenhagen.
Tell me, Ramirez,
is there really any money?
Everyone talks, but no one knows.
Michelle, the English girl.
Know where she is?
Frank's old lady?
I saw her at the new strip club.
- The one that black guy owns.
- I know the guy.
By the way,
did you hear that Frank is dead?
You know too much, Tuki.
Do you need help?
Shameer is dangerous.
He's like a snake.
Shameer's days are over.
- What the fuck?
- Where's Crazy Uffe?
Taking a dump.
Get the boys! Now!
Hey, Sonny!
What do you want?
- Where does Michelle live? Don't lie.
- I haven't seen her for ages.
She's a stripper in town. She dumped
me just like she dumped your dad.
Fucking whore.
- Then what the hell did you run for?
- I still owe you that money.
- You bum. Where's Shameer?
- I don't know.
- Where is he?
- He's looking for Michelle, too.
Sonny! Let him go!
You're a dead man.
Not like in the old days.
Guess we showed you, ladies.
Fucking punks!
Howdy, boys!
How y'all doing?
- Y'all looking for some action?
- Where's Michelle?
Michelle? She's a wild one, all right.
Yes, sir. Whoa!
But it ain't going to work out. Sorry.
She only dances for the big boss.
Shut up, Lucky Luke,
and get Michelle.
What the fuck?
These bastards wanna talk
to Michelle.
Sorry, boss.
They whupped me good.
Whoa, whoa!
Easy, man. Easy.
Shameer?
I haven't seen your ass in years.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Cat got your tongue?
Oh, yeah.
Frank's kid gave him a nice cut there,
so this asshole can't talk.
You know these fuckers?
Yap, yap, yap.
You talk too much, bitch.
Speak, when spoken to.
- Frank gave you a tattoo, right?
- What's it to you?
Yeah.
Frank paid for this stupid tattoo.
I don't know what the fuck it means.
Five and five. 55.
Draw Michelle's tattoo.
What?
What the fuck is that?
55...
What the hell are you doing,
Michelle?
Are you showing him
your fucking ass?
Shut your face!
You got my money?
Frank owes me money,
and I got shit.
- You got it?
- You ain't getting jack shit.
- Who the fuck is this?
- Ramirez?
- Going to kill your girlfriend?
- Let her go, chico cabrón.
You can only
cheat death once, Latino.
You fucking bastards!
- We'll take what we need.
- Of course! Help yourselves.
This is better than Christmas, man.
That's a quality piece.
Smith & Wesson.
Wise choice.
- Tuki, bring the bullets.
- They're in the case.
Sonny.
I'm sorry about your father.
Frank was a good man.
I never liked Shameer.
Tell me, Sonny,
did Frank cheat him or what?
Watch what you say about my father,
you dirty dog.
Easy.
Brian, blow the bastard away.
Do it now!
Sonny, your brother's been playing
with bandits behind your back.
What the hell is he going on about?
Christ, Sonny.
There are 5 million out there.
And I want my share.
Dad told me about it
when he was drunk.
He said you'd know where to look
when you figured out the tattoos.
And you told that rat?
I was always left out.
Where is it?
He killed Dad.
This isn't part of the deal, Shameer.
Brian...
Sonny, where's the money?
Think fast.
I'm sorry, Sonny.
- I'm sorry.
- Wait.
My uncle... My uncle's wrecking yard.
That's where the money is.
Brian?
- Find the money before it's too late.
- I don't care about the money.
- I want Shameer to die like a rat.
- Can you forgive me?
Brian? Brian?
Not you, too.
I got it!
It's an American car.
A '55 Cadillac.
And it's at Uncle's Wrecking Yard.
Is the money there?
- Don't you want to hear the rest?
- I'm asking. Is the money there?
In the fucking '55 Cadillac?
When the sun rose the following day,
things got busy at the junk yard.
- Can I help you?
- I'm looking for a '55 Cadillac.
Oh, no. Are you one of the idiots
on a treasure hunt?
Where is the Cadillac?
There's something of mine in it.
Listen.
I only have old junk cars here.
There isn't a Cadillac.
And there isn't a treasure.
Just get the hell out of here.
And that toy doesn't scare me.
- Take it easy, for Christ's sake.
- Do you love your dog?
Pingo?
Bang!
Look at him.
Buy some more beers.
Camilla, you do it.
- Are you taking all of this down?
- Of course.
Brian was a creep.
He betrayed his own family.
- I'll get the beers. Got any money?
- No, I'm broke.
You directors never have a cent.
I don't have time, Krelle.
I'm talking to some movie people.
- What movie people?
- Hey! What did I say about cameras?
Can't you see he's filming me?
No one wants to see your ugly mug.
Making a movie?
How about using me?
- Here are the brews.
- Great.
Your producer
has a handle on things.
- Are you a producer?
- Yes.
Hi.
My name is Krelle.
Call me Krelle.
And you can call me Camilla.
- Can I be in your movie?
- Shut up, Krelle. Beat it.
If you can use him,
you can use me.
- Crazy Uffe isn't going to be in it.
- Uffe's telling us about the money.
- Everyone is looking for it.
- Is he telling that same old story?
Jesus Christ!
Why didn't you come to me first?
Shut up and leave, Krelle.
I bet he didn't mention Frank's heist.
They don't want to hear it.
Beat it.
I do.
- Me too.
- Your movie should be about it.
- I'll tell you for a beer.
- What about the rest of my story?
In his heyday, Frank had
everything a man could want.
Money. Power.
Beautiful women. Cars.
Frank was sitting at this table
when he heard about the heist.
Frank, are you sure
we should include Shameer?
He can't be trusted.
- He's an idiot.
- Let's hear what the man says first.
- I don't like him. He's a snake.
- A little shit.
And he smells of curry.
- Yes, he's a slimy bastard.
- Speaking of curry.
A big homemade burger
with lots of dressing...
Shut up.
You and your food.
Hey, Shameer!
How are you doing?
- What's up, Frank?
- So, son.
- What's this? You smell good.
- Fats. Go feed your face.
I'm hungry anyway.
See you later.
Fuck off!
Move over. I hate people
sticking to me like glue.
- Long time, no see, Ramirez.
- Not long enough.
What's on your mind?
What do you think of 20 million?
I know where we can get it.
And we split it three ways.
Why us?
Why do you need us?
You're the best in the business.
And there's your niece. Interested?
20 million is a lot of money.
There she is.
Hi, honey.
Have a word with Uncle Frank.
- I have a job.
- Give me a second, uncle.
- You haven't called in a week, jerk.
- I've been busy.
Do you prefer this whore?
Don't call me a whore!
Shut the fuck up, Tina.
She's my lady.
What the fuck are you doing, bitch?
Well done, Tina. That oughtta hurt.
Shut up, Dad.
What's this job
you're talking about, uncle?
- Frankie, aren't those your boys?
- Stop, Tina.
- We have to be at Shameer's soon.
- When I say stop, you stop.
- Hurry up.
- I've almost got it.
What are you morons doing?
Hi, Dad.
What are you doing here, old man?
Are you trying to steal this car?
No, we forgot our keys.
- No wisecracks. All right?
- Okay. We're trying to steal it.
- But I can't jimmy the lock.
- This is a bit embarrassing.
What would my friends think?
Did you lure Sonny into this?
No, he was the one...
I don't want to see this again.
You got that, you brats?
- Yes, Dad.
- Give me that.
This is the last time
I'm showing you. Watch carefully.
- Did you get that?
- Way to go, Dad.
Damn brats!
- Hi, Shameer.
- Hi, Frank. Ramirez.
- It's not like you to be late.
- He had to help his kids steal a car.
Shut up
and make some coffee, Tina.
- You're sure the money is there?
- It will be smuggled out tonight.
20 million.
The money is just waiting for us.
- Where does it come from?
- Tonight at midnight...
- Who the hell is that?
- Blondie.
Don't you remember me?
- My little brother Pucha.
- Do you want the money or not?
- I'm all ears.
- Tell him.
Once a year
money is transported to Germany.
And tonight
it is the largest sum ever.
I saw it while I was at work.
I recognized Yuri at once.
Yuri is Albanian.
I did his little sister,
so I understand some Albanian.
Every year there's
a Wild West Show in Hamburg.
Yuri supplies all the props
for the show, including an old safe.
I did some research and found out
that the safe has been camouflaged.
It looks like a prop,
but inside there's a real safe.
The 20 million are smuggled
to Hamburg tonight.
This time we'll score
a fucking jackpot.
Isn't this just our kind of thing?
Yeah.
What about the car?
I've got one, and Pucha will drive it.
Why Pucha?
If anyone's driving that car, it's me.
- What about dynamite?
- It's all set. But Pucha's driving.
What's wrong with Tina?
- She's on Antabuse.
- Bullshit!
Antabuse, schmantabuse.
Never heard of it. Tina is a cow.
- Plus, I'm a better driver.
- You're not driving. Tina is.
Got that?
Unless she breaks her foot,
she's driving.
Son of a bitch!
What was that for?
Now her foot's broken!
Who the hell brought
that psycho here? This is ridiculous!
Are you all right, baby?
- You're out. We'll do it ourselves.
- If anyone's out, it's you.
Don't threaten me, Paki.
If it wasn't for me,
you'd still be a dishwasher.
I came up with the plan,
so it's my plan.
Easy, Shameer.
We're not at war.
We're working.
We're professionals.
Comprende?
Frankie, qué pasa?
This is our big chance. 20 million.
Don't just stand there!
Help me, you assholes!
Relax, Frank.
Okay.
We'll do it.
Get the dynamite.
- How is she?
- What the hell does it look like?
Get her foot seen to.
You're driving the car.
I don't ever want to see
your little brother again. Got that?
We'll meet here at exactly 11 p.m.
You dickhead!
All right, handsome.
What do feel like having today?
Well...
I think I'll...
I'll take the usual.
I think I can pretty much guess
what that is.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Get your ass up on stage.
You're up next.
Go and get ready.
Sorry, Frank.
I didn't see you. I thought...
That my girl was on some jerk's lap?
Is that it, faggot?
My mistake.
How about a drink on the house?
Michelle, get...
- No, I'll get you a Jack Daniels.
- Get the drinks and stop kissing ass.
Fucking asshole!
Don't worry about it, baby.
After tonight we won't need
to be in this fucking dump no more.
Are you sure about that?
Trust me, baby.
You're gonna be rich.
Yes, finally. Diamonds,
and a fur coat. I want it all.
Dad? What's the job tonight?
Shut up, Brian.
You know we don't discuss that.
- More?
- I'd like some more.
- Where's the car?
- Sold.
- Sonny needs the money for his bitch.
- She isn't a bitch.
I want to get her
a nice birthday present.
She's fleecing you.
Just like Dad's women.
You're so gross,
you can't even get a girlfriend.
I don't need a bitch. Fuck them.
Nothing but headaches.
Quiet! Let's have a quiet dinner.
Sonny's right.
Treat the ladies well.
I taught him that.
What are you getting her?
I'm thinking of a ring.
I have a picture.
- Cool, isn't it?
- A gay ring.
Shut up! It's too expensive anyway.
I'll find something else.
- No. How much do you need?
- Five.
- Here's 5000.
- Thanks.
What about me, Dad?
Here's 50.
Buy a porn mag and some
toilet paper, you little wanker.
- Fuck you.
- Brian, wait.
Of course 50 isn't enough.
Here's another 50.
Go buy some lubricant
and a wrist protector.
- Hi, uncle.
- My little wanker!
Fuck you, too.
Been teasing Brian again?
He can't take it.
Hi, Sonny.
- What's up, uncle?
- What's up?
What the hell are you doing here?
These are damn good.
You should be a chef.
Instead of those stupid heists.
You're too old anyway.
Stop stuffing your face!
What do you want?
Leave us.
- What?
- I need some cash.
I knew it.
I know, but it's for gas
and some hot dogs, you know.
- Here's 100.
- That won't fill the septic tank.
Here we go.
I knew I could count on you.
Yes, but you're a fool.
- See you. Thanks a lot. Kiss, kiss.
- Put the main key back.
Hello, darling.
I know I haven't been here
for a while, but I've been busy.
I miss the sound of your voice,
and I miss you telling me off.
Especially tonight.
I'll come back soon.
Bye, darling.
You've got to be kidding.
What happened?
- She drank a whole bottle of tequila.
- And you let her, you idiot?
I'm not her father.
- Give me that bottle.
- No! Give it back!
- Shut up, Tina!
- Get me out of this shitty car!
What do we do? She isn't
capable of blowing anything up.
What about Shameer?
Did he get any dynamite?
Shameer can't get jack shit.
No car, no dynamite.
- Give me that bottle!
- I'm going home.
Shameer mentioned a name.
Let's go now.
I've got it under control.
- I'll show you.
- He's okay, Frank.
Look. Panasonic. Best in town.
Code-free. No code.
You can see in every country.
Clint Eastwood. Bang, bang!
Thanks, but what I want is...
This?
Very good. Try. Gypsy King.
I give for you. 200.
- No thanks.
- For you. Special. 150.
Listen, we want a big boom-boom.
- I have, you want.
- He understands.
Christ, forget it.
- Where did you find that camel rider?
- He's a friend of Shameer's.
I know some Arabic.
I can try to speak to him.
We need dynamite.
We are Shameer's habibis.
- Do you know Shameer?
- Oh, Shameer...
Dynamite. Big boom.
Best boom.
- Show off.
- Give me that.
- Tuki always has the best.
- Okay. Thank you.
I have this.
No drinking? Party!
Here. Thank you.
More money.
Shut up. That's plenty.
Tina, have you lost
your fucking mind?
What the hell
are you two morons doing?
What are you waiting for?
Come on!
Come on, Tina. Get up.
You've got to be kidding!
Give me a hand, Shameer.
Pull yourself together.
Shameer, over here!
- It's true! It's a safe!
- We're rich, my friend!
You pig. You won't see a cent.
I hate you to the bone.
Wipe that smile off your face.
I'll take it all,
and you'll rot in jail.
Are you going
to blow the safe or fuck it first?
Let's do it.
And Tina?
Tina is drunk as a skunk.
You do it.
- Are you crazy? I can't.
- Then I'll do it.
I'll check on Tina.
She's swimming in her own vomit.
- Are you sure you can do it?
- What am I? An amateur?
- What?
- It's ready.
I need water.
- It's going to blow.
- We have five minutes to empty it.
- Give me some water.
- What do you think this is? A hotel?
Hey...
- Where's the tool bag and weapons?
- Where are they?
Did you use all the dynamite?
- Huh?
- The whole lot.
Fuck.
- Shit!
- What are you doing, you idiot?
Fuck.
Holy shit!
It didn't get a scratch, Frank.
- Move! Is it open?
- Let's get out of here.
- No way! Not without the money.
- Are you planning on carrying it?
The cops will be here
in five minutes. It's over.
I'm going home.
- What did I tell you?
- We're rich!
We're going on vacation!
I love money!
Hide, for fuck's sake! Hide!
I'm going to jail!
I hate money!
Shut up, Tina!
What do we do now?
- Shameer, what are you doing?
- What do you think?
Since I blew it up, I get two bags.
See you, boys.
Let him go. He won't get far.
Take the two bags and hide them.
See you at the meeting point.
Stop whining.
We have to get out of here.
Frank! Frank! Shit!
- Pucha.
- Trying to steal my money?
- Where have you been?
- I said to meet at the parking lot.
This is it.
- Shameer, you bastard.
- I'll send you a postcard from Spain.
Come on!
Get him!
Deck him!
Let me go, pig!
Get up, Tina! Come on!
Run, Frank!
Get him on the ground.
Damn!
Over here!
He went this way!
What?
Stop! Kurt, stop!
- What the hell is this?
- It's like a rocket. It's a Diablo.
- Where's the fucking car?
- The tank was empty.
You idiot!
Let's get out of here.
Move, fat ass.
I can't get on.
If you touch a cent of that money,
you're dead meat. Go!
Move it!
Hands up!
Step away from the car!
Listen, girls.
If he drops his toy gun, I promise
not to kick you in the balls.
- Shut up, Frank. You're under arrest.
- Take it easy!
They arrested the whole gang.
But the police
never found the last bag.
According to the tattoos,
the money was in the '55 Cadillac.
I'll tell the rest.
The greedy Tuki took off
to look around for the '55 Cadillac.
You're not that fast, Tuki.
Ramirez, my friend.
There are five million here.
Let's split it.
2 million for you, 3 million for me.
I scratch your back,
you scratch mine.
What do you say?
Ramirez! You know what you are?
You're a son of a dog!
Tuki.
Wasn't I just your best friend?
I'll shoot you! I will!
That's my money, Ramirez!
You son of a big chamuta!
Is the money there?
Answer me!
Are the 5 million there?
Is the money in there?
Ramirez, my friend.
Your mother isn't a chamuta.
Of course, she isn't.
I like your mother.
I've had dinner at her place.
She makes great empanadas.
Ramirez, let's split the money.
You and I.
There's plenty for both of us.
You're my best friend. My brother.
You and I are partners,
and we're rich now.
Here's your money.
- You're shitting me.
- Good-bye, Tuki. Have fun.
Ramirez, my friend! Ramirez!
Was the money there?
The money is still there.
They didn't find it.
- Where is it?
- In a different car.
Michelle had two tattoos.
I've seen one of them.
The first time she danced for me,
I found out that the old bandit
gave her two tattoos, not just one.
It's in an old Peugeot.
If we get it,
we could pay off my old debt.
- The 400,000.
- You totaled my Mercedes. 200,000.
You came back from Thailand
without 242,000.
My 242,000.
Add the two amounts,
and that makes 442,000.
- Then you'll get 442,000.
- Thanks.
There's 5 million.
I only want half.
You're an idiot, Crazy Uffe.
A big idiot.
Did you forget what I told you
about people and money?
I'm people, too.
- What do you mean, Ivan?
- Have another shawarma on me.
- What's going on?
- Stay here. I'll be back.
Look who's here. Tuki.
Hey, Tuki!
Come have a brew.
Come and have a beer.
- Can I film him?
- Sure. He's high, but harmless.
- Tuki. Sit down and have a beer.
- I can't. I have to leave.
I don't have time.
Important things to do.
Have a beer. Relax.
This is Tuki.
- Have a beer.
- Thanks.
Tuki, this guy wrote a movie
about Frank
and the money
and all that shit you got up to.
Isn't that cool?
This is Martin.
Hi, I'm Camilla.
I'm the producer.
- Tuki's the expert on the story.
- I know a lot, too.
You don't know jack shit.
You make it all up.
Tuki was there.
- He almost got the money, right?
- I know the money's still there.
And I'll find it.
I know it's there somewhere.
What about Ivan?
Didn't he find it?
Wasn't it in the Peugeot?
If Tuki's fan club will shut up,
I'll continue.
Cadillac!
[Ivan swears uncontrollably]
What the hell? Ivan, old boy.
What are you doing here?
- Did you think there was money in it?
- Crazy Uffe said it wasn't the Caddy.
- It was supposed to be in here.
- There isn't any money in there!
Christ, Ivan. There isn't any money.
It's an urban legend.
I'll only ask once.
Where's the money?
You just don't get it, do you?
Sleep well, fatso.
Crazy Uffe...
- What about you and Ivan?
- Luckily the police arrested him.
And the guy in the shawarma place
fell asleep, so I took off.
- What happened to Tina?
- And the Mexican and Sonny?
I haven't heard.
I think they moved abroad.
- I think Ramirez moved to Paris.
- No, that's not true.
You don't know a thing.
Are you all stupid?
- Did you forget about Yuri?
- Yuri? Were the 20 million his?
He smuggled the money to Germany,
and Frank stole his money?
Yes. Yuri wanted his money back.
He went to Copenhagen to find Frank.
That was a couple of days
before Shameer, the snake,
and his damned brother
stabbed Frank.
Are we interrupting something,
Frank?
What are you up to?
The town is buzzing with excitement.
Now all the robbers and conmen
are looking for my 5 million.
I want my money back. Pronto!
Find it and give me a call.
- I don't have your money, Yuri.
- Three days, Frank.
She's hot, isn't she, Sonny?
You know why I'm here.
I'm giving you one chance.
If I tell you where your money is,
will you take your old mug away?
- Maybe. There's no guarantee.
- I didn't think so.
I don't know where your money is,
and even if I did,
I wouldn't tell you.
So take your girlfriend and beat it.
Do you have to be as stubborn
as your father, Sonny?
I'll beat it,
but my girlfriend will stick around.
Have fun, you two.
That's the end of the story,
and all the assholes are gone.
And the money's still there.
I have to go.
I'll find it.
It's only a matter of time.
I have to go.
See you, Tuki.
- You got yourselves a great story.
- You bet.
- Are you guys looking for the money?
- Frank took it to Spain.
- Isn't Frank dead?
- Yes. He's dead.
- Is not.
- Is too!
Frank is alive and kicking.
I have to take a piss.
- Want to come?
- No, thanks, I'm fine.
Don't come back, you sponger.
- Camilla!
- Wait a minute.
- Isn't that guy in the corner...?
- Who?
- Come on! Quick!
- What's up?
- What are we looking for?
- I thought I saw...
It could have been...
Never mind.
Another beer?
Yes.
IF YOU SCRATCH ME, YOU DIE!
Stop it! I told you not to film me!
You got that, dickhead?
- Tina, I was reading that.
- I'm sweating bullets, Dad.
- Can't we go? I hate sitting here.
- Break it off, Sonny. We're leaving.
Brian, get out of the car now!
I'm the only one who drives this car!
- No one else. You got that? Out!
- Take it easy, Dad.
- Dad, can I drive to Hamburg?
- Of course, my boy.
- Why will you let Sonny drive?
- It doesn't matter who drives.
Stop it, or I'll smack you.
Don't go more than 120 mph
until we hit the motorway.
Hand me that bag.
Brian, pay for the gas.
Dad wants all the change back.
Did you get that? Did you?
Brian, get a couple of hotdogs
for uncle. Brian! I'm hungry.
No more food for you.
We're going to the beach in Spain.
I don't want to lie
next to a beached whale.
I haven't eaten all morning.
I'm hungry.
- I think I've lost some weight.
- You haven't lost an ounce.
- Tina, I love you. Give us a kiss.
- Forget it!
- Tina, baby...
- Ramirez! Knock it off!
We're leaving, Brian.
Get in. Hurry up.
I only let you come along
if you wouldn't film me! Hand it over!
- My camera!
- Fuck the camera!
I need it to make my movie.
- Your mother told me to watch you.
- She gave me the camera!