THE OIL, THE BABY AND THE
TRANSYLVANIANS
Romi....
I think that Ion is drunk
somewhere.
Maybe he's at the theater.
What's that mean?
It was a joke.
Please forgive me.
I forgive you.
Hey...
Why did he take his gun if he was only
going to collect his money?
I don't know.
Maybe it is the tradition around here.
- Shepherd?
- Yes? - He's not coming.
I can see that.
I hope that he doesn't...
That he doesn't what?
Do something foolish!
What sort of foolishness?
How do we know that he'll find...
the one who owes
him money.
C'mon, we're going
to the fire.
To get warmed up.
- Romi.
- Yes?
I miss Bob.
I liked him a lot.
You liked him, but it
was necessary for him to marry.
Ion, is that you?
Thank God that you're
here.
What's wrong with him?
Have you brought it?
- What?
- The money.
Yes.
My dears, I think I'll change
my opinion about America.
It looks like you can find
honest people here too.
And now I'm wondering
why you're late.
Maybe it took time while that
man earned the money he owed.
How could he know that
you needed it?
Like you said.
How the fuck could he know?
Girl, up!
We'll take the mail coach.
Romi, go and buy some
tickets!
Ion, give him some money!
What is it?
What "please"?
This happens when you take
women with you.
You don't know what you're talking about.
Can't you see that she's tired?
- So shut up!
- Thanks brother, for the lack of respect.
What is your opinion?
A few days wait wont
be the end of the world.
Maybe for you, because
you're young.
But if you really want to,
then we should stay.
Take the money,
shepherd.
You keep hold of it.
Take it.
Give it to him.
He thinks that he is smarter than
the Pope.
Yeah, yeah.
No, no.
Look at you!
So, how do I look?
10 dollars.
????????
Shepherd, you'll be surprised.
Here is some tobacco for you.
Light your pipe, because
I have something to tell you.
What?
I've done a deal.
What have you done?
I bought 10 acres of land.
Acres?
"Acres", it's English.
Around 1 hectare in Romanian.
1?
And a house.
And a house?
How do you say "casa"
in English?
You bought them from a shop.
Where did you find a shop
that sells land and houses?
I found a man who said
that he was moving.
He's moving elsewhere.
It was like this:
17 dollars for 1 acre,
170 for 10.
200 dollars for the house and
the outhouses.
2.5 dollars the tobacco,
10 dollars the clothes.
Well my dear, I think that you gave
the money to that man, and he left.
You think that I'm stupid?
I don't think, I know.
Here is the document.
We h-h-had...
witnesses,
and in 10 minutes everything
was done.
That's why I like Americans.
Everything is fast.
Ok.
You bought land.
But, where is it?
And, have you seen it?
Did you ask the neighbours what
kind of land it is?
How you will work it?
And, who allowed you to buy land?
Is that why we're here?
To buy land?
Or, to earn some money,
to get back home,
where our land already is?
You deserve a few slaps!
You've gone crazy since
coming to America.
But it's not a big deal.
Let's find that man who sold you the land,
and stole your money.
- Come!
- No!
What did you say?
I said no!
Please, repeat.
No!
We can't leave until
next year.
Why, moron?
Because...
in 8 months...
I'll be a father.
What are you saying, "Mucho"?
You're no better than him!
This is the last shame that could
happen to me.
Come.
I knew that you'd be exactly
like your uncle Virgil.
- When he was seeing a female, he also....
- She's not a female!
She's my woman!
Well....
shame on you.
Immoral.
If Father Iosif finds out?
He must know that I'm
very mad at you.
I should beat you up.
Heeeeeeeeey,
the ones from Poplaca!!!
Our family name will
never die!
So what?
If I wasn't able...
what did you think?
That our name will die?
Who? Us?
Our family?
Hey girl,
I mean woman...
Come here so I can kiss you.
But we...
You, nothing!
You've done your duty.
I'll take care of the rest!
But you know what I'm thinking of?
How should we tell Ion?
He gets angry quickly.
- What?
- Ion knows.
He knows...
Nice.
But, it's not too bad.
I realise...
Now is the time to step up.
To wash the baby's ass,
and make him toys.
But it's good.
It's really good.
- Are you sleeping?
- No.
- Is something bothering you?
- Yes.
Ion...
This story with the debt...
Was it true?
How did you earn that money?
You know...
Instead of finding the one
from our family who owed you...
you'd better not have got
it the wrong way!
Shut up, please!
Sleep!
I won it fair, believe me.
What have you done for it?
A lot of things.
Will we reach Poplaca ever?
We will, we will, why not?
Well, my brother...
If you bought land, you must work it.
Otherwise...,
why would you buy it?
But for this, you need tools.
So, you must earn some cash.
To get us on our feet.
Check the map for the location
of the house,
since we haven't even
seen the place yet.
I'm not scared of work.
And you should also not be afraid.
I'll try.
Well, goodbye.
See you soon.
Romi, let's go.
Wait.
Ioane, maybe you'll find a christian
priest.
Let's go now.
Well my dears, we will raise
chickens and turkeys...
Because eggs are very important
for you, girl.
And if Ion earns money,
we will buy a cow too.
And we will take the cow to a bull...
The first calf we'll keep for ourselves.
We will make provisions,
and when the child grows up a little,
We'll go back home.
We must face reality.
As long as...
the child is little, we can't leave.
Have you thought about his name?
And, if it will be a girl?
- Impossible!
- Impossible.
Romi, look on that map.
I don't want to get lost
on someone else's land.
Here is it.
Seriously?
Romi, my son, it's good.
But I haven't slapped you in a long
time.
Watch out, don't demolish it.
Romi, are you remembering the
words from the Bible?
Which ones?
What happened on Day 1?
Making food and cleaning.
Goddamnit.
Are you missing my slaps?
What's up with these horses?
They're the horses...
of the one who sold the farm.
Water.
- Go to the well.
- Which well?
Congrats Romi.
We have free horses, but what would
they drink?
Stop talking.
You'd better fix those harnesses,
we will find something.
Thank you for your advice.
Without it, I would be a dead man.
Where are you Romica?
There must be water.
There must be water in America.
You left Romi alone.
96...
100.
Here.
Hold this.
And you!
Don't be worried about anything.
Because Romi, our little brother,
your husband,
is a trustworthy man.
Well, well.
Are you crazy?
Fuck you, idiot!
Stupid motherfucker!
Stupid motherfuckers.
Neighbours?
And they won't let us
take water from the river.
Romi, we can't go on like this.
No.
I'm going to have a few words with them.
Please teach me the english:
We are your new neighbours,
can we get some water?
Ok.
Repeat.
Shut up!
Are you my teacher?
I will say to you a few words!
Is anyone home?
Yes there is.
I am "home".
- Oh, you mother....
- Don't talk like that!
[ Hungarian ]
I thought you were a thief.
[ hungarian ]
Because he didn't want too.
- Hey!
- What?
You know Romanian.
From hell, not heaven.
Orban Peter.
Traian Brad.
Hello.
Let me show you...
my house.
I have "tzuica".
- Made from plums?
- Yes.
- Not whiskey?
- No.
It's my pleasure then.
Madam, Traian Brad from Poplaca.
Emek Forkoszloki.
I know every corner of Transylvania.
Let's eat some bacon.
It's from plums, I made it myself.
Nice color.
Will there be enough?
Nice.
It's nice, but this is nicer.
You're woried about something.
Well Romi...
I will tell you the truth.
It would have been better if we drank the money.
What do they want?
To sell them the farm.
How do you say in english
Go?
I'll shoot you!
Well, you can teach me more of these
short words, I like them.
You hear?
What do they want from us?
I can't wait to meet Ion.
Maybe you'll be good for him.
And because I like you,
everything is ok.
It's a shame, girl.
You came here, and forgot
your own language.
Hello my dear.
I came here to ask you,
our brother Brad Ion,
has he left some money for us,
because we need tools.
But I don't think you understand me,
because you have a weird look.
Yeah, "understand, understand'',
this is all you know.
Ask him:
What is Ion doing?
Are you a priest?
Yes.
I shaved my beard to not be
recognized.
You're talking in Romanian.
I grew up in Braila, ( Romanian region )
of course I know Romanian.
Oh shit. Please forgive me,
but this America....
Wait a moment.
God may forgive his sins...
Brother Romi, I found a priest
too.
It's true, he's a little crazy,
but it's good.
He talks Romanian.
"ION, YOU MUST COME TO ROMI'S WEDDING,
I'LL BREAK YOUR BONES IF NOT, DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
Now, your Holiness,
you may start.
Lord have mercy!
Have mercy on us,
and us on one another.
And all your life, be like this,
with your neighbours.
May God....
You must love each other, your home,
and your child.
And you Romulus, it's necessary
to be faithfull.
Do not fall in temptation!
Kiss her!
Like that.
Now, the ceremony must continue.
I don't know how.
What do you mean?
I only know the funeral ceremony,
which is not suited for now.
- Father, I realise that you're here for nothing.
- Not necessarily.
Miss Orban...
You wanna dance?
Why aren't you dancing?
Look at her,
how beautiful she is.
Stop talking about your
prince!
You don't want me to start talking about
Iancu ( Transylvania's first and only prince )
Iancu your Highness...
This is how your prince was praying
for mercy.
How can you talk like that about
my prince?
But how can you talk like that
about Iancu?
Like that.
- Like that!
- Me too!
Your Iancu is stupid.
I'll kill you!
You're not my friend
anymore!
I'm leaving too, shepherd.
What?
What a nice wedding this was.
Nice, nice.
- Let's drink something.
- Of course.
What is that sound from your coat?
The Bible was lost.
Do you know this game?
I know all games, father.
At Braila, if you scored a double
6, you were dead.
Look.
Double 6 again?
What did I do wrong, God?
6 6.
4 2.
Why are you awake so early?
Hey "Mucho".
Before opening your mouth,
which talks only nonsense,
take care of your own sleep, not mine.
What are you doing here?
I'm digging.
I see, but what are you digging?
A well.
I don't want to go again
to that Hungarian.
If there was water, don't you think
that those before us would have dug one?
They were lazy.
I'll have my water,
our water.
It's impossible.
That's not logical.
What?
That your brother scores
what he wants.
That makes no sense.
What he does, is called
sorcery.
Look.
Again.
6 6.
You see what I see?
I see.
A very good time is prepared
for Mr. Berkovich.
- Who is this man?
- This is the one who makes coffins.
He builds coffins.
When a man dies, he "sleeps"
in a coffin of his size.
I'll explain.
I'll build 2 for you.
Do you like it?
- Isn't it too big?
- No, maybe we'll have twins.
Shepherd!
- Who came?
- Orban's boys, they brought water.
Water?
Charity?
For us?
- We need water.
- Shut up!
I don't need your water!
Look what I'm doing with it.
You're cra...
How dare you talk like this,
"Mucho"?
You want a few slaps!
And you, what are you doing?
Let it flow!
Please forgive me,
I didn't want to hurt you.
Put her there.
There.
Remember.
And tell it to the kid
if I'm dead.
We do not accept charity.
Do you understand?
Ok then.
Romi,
where is thatsmell coming from?
Maybe there was a toilet there
before.
You're crazy.
After so much work,
you find a toilet?
Romi, what toilet was here?
Ion, I'm glad that I found you.
We have a big problem!
It's not about Julie.
- It's burning!
- They set you on fire?
- The ground is burning.
- Are you stupid?
You want some slaps.
Are you deaf? The ground is burning.
I dug a well and that's what I found.
Fucking oil!
If it's a treasure?
Uncle Nicolae said this:
When it's a treasure
it erupts.
Hello, father.
- When are we playing again?
- I'm not playing with you anymore.
- Why?
- Because you're lucky.
Ion!
Explain this to me!
Ion...
Since I'm here with you,
please translate your words.
I was saying...
I was saying that Orban should
be our leader.
What?
Orban to be the leader?
How is that possible?
Leave me alone!
Come down.
- Traian!
- No Traian, this man leader,
NEVER!
He, the one who insulted Iancu?
Leave me alone!
You, to command me?
Traian Brad?
NEVER!
As long as I live.
- What does he want?
- What does he say?
I'm saying nothing,
it's your business.
An Orban shall never command me!
Ion, you should be ashamed.
What is that word?
We go!
Come.
- It will be a solution?
- What solution?
Let's go and talk with McKellan...
You do the talking, and I'll
make a nice ceremony.
Come, the circus has began.
You're not some ladies in front of a mirror.
McKellan has gone to kill Orban.
Come!
You're here my dear
Transylvanians.
Hello Peter.
How could I leave you
like this?
Ion, go there.
Romi, there.
Peter, come here.
Take care.
You've messed with the wrong people.
- Where did you get that?
- From Plevna, year 1877.
- What is wrong with these guys,
they only want my head. - Cover me!
Ion, be careful!
If that Turk ever found out
what his weapon is doing here...
God's yard must be huge.
Romi....
I think we're done.
Let's go.
Put your finger.
Did you understand?
Well, only God can illuminate that man.
He's a stubborn Transylvanian,
like me.
Goodbye.
It's a boy.
- He looks like me.
- Like me too.
- And me too.
- He looks like us.
Thank you my dear.
Scream my boy, scream.
So it can be heard in Poplaca.
Subs by Pinhead
exclusively for CG.