Jeb?
Jeb, where are you?
Oh!
Are you all right?
I'm all right.
I brought you some things
- some meal and beans and a good canteen.
Is that what kept you-
getting those things?
I came as soon as I could.
I brought you a map too.
Look.
If you work up north through the
gloriettas, you can hit the skin road.
If I work north? What about you? Yes, jeb.
Where will you be?
I'm not going with you.
I knew it as soon
as you came in...
By the look on your face
and the way you walked.
You've always been like that-
Able to think with my thoughts
and feel with my feelings.
But there's something
that keeps us apart.
Oh, jeb, what happened to us?
Why did everything go wrong?
I don't know all of it,
but I know some.
I've been thinking
and figuring.
This is where it started, this
is where it's going to end.
You see that rise?
He'll be coming over that.
He'll come killing.
Come out,
or we'll come in after ya!
You hear it?
Jeb, honey,
there's no one out there.
You're imagining.
I'm not imagining.
Remembering.
Putting together what happened-
what I guess must've happened.
Thor, it's all coming
back, strong and clear.
There's an answer in it.
There's something about me
that explains everything.
Jeb, I don't understand. I'm
gonna make you understand.
I've got to
before they get here.
Do you know why
I came to this place?
No, jeb, but...
It's not a good hideout.
They're sure
to trail you here.
I came for another reason.
I was here before,
long ago.
I was a baby then.
I was scared the way
only a kid can get.
I was in a dark,
cold place.
I had my eyes closed to get
away from some bad dream-
The same dream
I'd been having all my life.
I've never understood it. There
were boots running, flashes.
Daddy? Daddy?
but my father wasn't there.
Instead, a strange woman
was lying on the floor.
She crawled toward me.
That was the first time
I saw your mother.
Get up, son. No, jeb,
you can't go to sleep now.
Get your clothes on, son. We're
going away from here. Who is that?
That's jeb rand. Now, pay
attention, adam... And thor.
This is jeb.
He's going to live with us.
Come on, now.
Help your sister.
They've gone,
every danged one of 'em.
They've moved away
somewhere.
Grant, if you ride with
that arm, you'll lose it.
I'll find 'em if it takes me
to the end of my life.
The idea that I was hiding or
running away never quite died out.
It should have, I guess, because
the next seven years I wasn't hiding.
Your ma was
taking care of all of us.
I was growing up
with you and adam,
Going to school, helping to build a
house in the new place we moved to,
Having the whole outdoors
for a playground.
I'd about stopped having nightmares until
one day when I was about nine or ten-
Look, jeb!
A little black chick.
I found him under the house.
- What's the matter with you?
- You know what's the matter! You shot the colt!
Shot what colt?
Are you crazy?
Mom!
Jeb, stop!
Stop!
Mom! Mom, they're fighting again! Mom!
Now, stop that fighting, boys!
Stop that fighting!
Now, stop it!
Stop that fighting, boys!
Thor, pump some water.
Now, stop it! Come on, boys!
Now, stop that fighting!
Come on!
Stop it!
Adam! Jeb!
Now, what's it all about?
He shot the colt.
I didn't!
You did so! You mean
somebody shot our colt?
Said it was his.
He said I couldn't ride it.
But I rode it anyway.
He took a shot at it.
Or maybe me.
I don't know.
But anyway,
he killed the colt.
No. Somebody may have killed
him, but it wasn't adam.
He's been here all morning
greasing the buckboard.
You say somebody took a shot at
you? Who could it have been, ma?
Well, I don't rightly know.
Matter of fact, there were some
deer hunters hanging around.
Yes, sir. They asked me if
they could hunt down our fence,
And I told 'em yes.
You go and get your supper off
the stove, and no more fightin'.
You gonna see those men, ma? That's right.
Put that wheel
back on.
So, you found us.
You covered up
your trail pretty well.
As soon as the boy told me
somebody tried to kill him,
I knew it was you.
Being a lawyer hasn't done
your shootin' any good, grant.
Yeah. Maybe losin' this some
years ago didn't help any either.
You owe me for a colt.
Doggone critter
was too lively.
When he crawled off,
he spoiled my aim.
You can't start it all over
again, grant. I won't let you.
You're gettin' kind of uppity, ain't you?
He's a rand. I knew it the
first minute I laid eyes on him.
He brought to mind that you
was married to my brother.
And a score still isn't
settled for his death.
You lost a brother,
I lost a husband.
I don't want
any more vengeance for him.
I never figured
that you would.
That's why I swore that
I'd kill every rand on earth.
And he's
the only one left.
How in tarnations
you get him?
Let's say the lord
gave him to me.
Let the boy alone, grant.
He's innocent.
That night
ended it for him.
A night like that
don't have an end.
What happened to him there
will make him do things just-
Just like spirits were
whispering in his ear saying,
"kill, kill.
You've got to kill."
Spirits may talk to you, but they won't
to him. I don't believe in your spirits.
Maybe not, but someday you'll wish
I hadn't missed my shot today...
Down on the draw. That's
one day that'll never come.
He's a good boy.
I love him like my own son.
What makes you think
that boy loves you?
Well... I'll go back
to santa fe.
I swear I think I'll leave that
rand alone, let him grow up,
Just to see what happens to you when
he's big enough to start asking questions.
Don't forget your money
for the colt.
Thanks for reminding me.
This'll help me
bring him up.
Did you find 'em, ma?
Did you talk to 'em?
Why, sure I did. It was
them deer hunters all right.
They shot the colt.
Put the team up, adam, and
feed 'em. You help him, thor.
Come in the house with me,
son. I want to talk to you.
Jeb, how much
do you remember...
About coming
to live with us-
About the night
I brought you here?
You must remember something. Not much.
You can tell me, jeb.
I get mixed up
when I think about that.
I remember flashes...
And boots runnin'.
You know your parents are
dead. That's why I took you in.
Yes, ma'am.
But you don't remember them?
No, ma'am.
Sometimes I try to think
about it. I don't know.
My head hurts.
It gets all blurred.
Sometimes
the lord protects us...
By letting us know
only what's needful.
What you don't remember
doesn't matter.
You belong here
with us now.
Don't ask questions
of the past.
It has no answers
for you.
Grow up strong in the love
that's here for you.
As long as you love in
return, nothing can happen.
And you do love us,
don't you, jeb?
I'm sorry
I started the fight.
Well, son,
After today you boys won't
have anything to fight about.
Adam, thor, come here.
Now, pay heed to me,
you children.
I'll have no more arguments as
to who owns what on this ranch,
Colts or anything else.
Everything we have
or ever will have...
Belongs to you three
from this day on.
You mean, everything has
to be that way? Yes, adam.
Have you any objection
to that?
Not for thor and me,
but I have for outsiders.
There are no outsiders here.
You three are together.
You yourselves...
Are the best and finest
thing there is- a family.
You promise
not to forget that?
I mean all three of you.
All right.
Thor, stop scratching.
Go in the house and get some coal
oil, put it on those chiggers.
Adam, you find
the sheep scissors.
I'm gonna cut yours
and jeb's hair tonight.
Jeb, we've always called you
by your right name- rand.
Would you like to use
our name instead?
If you don't mind, I'd like to use my own name
- jeb rand.
All right, jeb.
You know how it was
after that.
Ma's idea worked like she
wanted it, pretty near.
Anyhow, we seemed
more like a family.
We were close,
the four of us.
That lasted
for a long time.
It lasted until that day
I rode into town.
detail, halt!
Right face!
About face!
Order arms!
Hey, what's all the shoutin' and
drum beatin' about? Ain't you heard?
The territory's fightin' Spain, and it looks
like we're gonna have a real shootin' war too.
Hi, jeb.
Good morning, doctor.
Hello, prentice. That's quite some
excitement you've got around here.
Sure is.
Gotta beat them spaniards.
Sure wish I could fight,
but dad won't let me.
Meanin' I won't lie about
his age so he can join.
I fought in one war. He don't
know what he's stayin' out of.
Here's your mail, jeb.
Thanks, bam.
That dress and petticoat
thorl sent for came in.
Hope it's what she wanted.
I've been keeping it for her.
She'll be obliged to you.
I'll tell her I saw you.
How's my credit, bam?
I need some tobacco.
Never heard anything wrong with
the credit on the callum ranch.
Thanks.
Mr. Rand?
Yes.
I heard him mention
the callum ranch.
I'm, uh, state provost, down
here to supervise recruiting.
Every outfit around about
here is sending in a quota.
One man apiece
to fight the spaniards.
I was sort of interested to see if
anyone was coming in from your ranch.
Oh, I guess this is what you
mean, sir. It came a little late.
Some of the outfits are sending
in every danged rider they've got.
Except the aged
and unfit.
We'll let you know tomorrow which one it's gonna be
- me or my brother adam.
Is that soon enough?
I guess so,
Unless you'd like the pleasure
of riding home tonight...
And telling the folks
you've just joined up.
Fill this out and sign it
and hand it in when you report.
If I'm the one that reports.
If not, adam will have to do it.
Give me two. The provost
seems bound and determined...
To get you
into this war.
It sort of appeared
that way to me too.
Who is that fella anyway?
What's his name?
heck, I figured
you knew him.
Ain't he some kind of kin
of yours? No kin of mine.
I have no kin. His name's
callum, just the same.
There's a whole slew of 'em up north.
halt! Order arms!
The recruits are ready to be
sworn in. Is that right, boys?
All right.
Raise your right hands.
Repeat after me. I, a citizen of
the United States, do solemnly swear-
"I, a citizen of the United
States, do solemnly swear...
That I will bear true faith and
allegiance to the United States of america.
That I will bear true faith and allegiance
to the United States of america."
is that package for me?
Yes.
The dry goods you ordered.
Oh, good.
Maybe it's my dress.
Hey, adam?
Hello? When you finish up
there, come on in the house.
I got some business to talk
over with you. All right.
What is it?
"... As a soldier in
the volunteer army...
"of the United States of america for a period of two years, unless sooner discharged
The first company's
leaving in the morning.
I told him we'd let him
know by then. It's not fair.
Why can't they get soldiers from the big
ranches, where there have plenty of riders?
Can't be helped, sis. Them
spaniards has to be beat.
I won't let either of you go. I'll ride into
town and explain we need both of you here.
You can only keep
one of us at home, sis.
But you can help pick which one it's
gonna be. That's a job I don't want.
Should we tell ma,
or decide without her?
Decide for ourselves,
I say.
Tell her after.
Well, ad, what do you say?
How are we gonna settle it?
I'm agreeable
to anything you suggest.
All right, I'll draw numbers with
you, run you a race or cut cards.
That would be your way
of deciding it.
This isn't a game. It's
serious. I'm serious.
How about a toss? That's the
quickest. That's fine with me.
Then let me toss it.
Flip it high.
If it's tails, ad goes.
Heads, it's jeb.
It's heads.
Jeb, you're the one.
It was a fair toss.
So be it.
Well, there's no use
stalling around any longer.
Adam, will you cut out
a horse for me? Sure.
I'll get going tonight. I
better go to ma now and tell her.
Don't let anything
happen to you, jeb.
I couldn't stand that. If
anything happened to you-
Nothing's gonna happen, ma.
I'll come back.
Why, sure,
I know you will.
One of you had to go.
Perhaps it's best
this way.
Good-bye, jeb.
Good-bye, ma.
So long.
Come home, jeb.
Until I do, maybe you'd
like this for a keepsake.
I guess it sort of
slipped out of your hand.
Right through the window too.
It didn't slip.
I threw it.
I don't blame you. You wanted to keep
adam here, so you lied about the toss.
I wanted to lie,
but I didn't.
If I had, it would've been
to keep you here,
Not adam.
You felt that way too?
The same way I felt.
I was supposed
to be your sister.
That's how it's been
ever since we were kids.
Only I stopped being
your sister,
And you've never been
my brother.
But I had to go on
every day pretending,
Watching you all day,
letting you touch me,
And at night
going in my room,
Lying there,
thinking about you.
I wish I had lied.
I wish I had cheated about
the toss and kept you here.
Wait for me.
You know I will.
I'll leave him at the ace high livery
stable. Pick him up in the morning.
So long. Give them spaniards
heck for me. I'll do that.
Come on!
Feel any better?
I feel all right. Well, I don't
know whether you were lucky or not.
You were sure
dreaming something.
I've heard a lot
of fever chatter in my time.
Don't bother with it much when it's
concerned with war, but yours was different.
Seemed to come from way back
somewhere when you were a kid.
- What'd I say?
- Something about boots and flashes of light.
Somebody hurt
or killed.
Does that mean anything
to you? I don't know.
But you gotta tell me what I said,
doc. Every word. I wanna know.
Don't upset yourself.
Your fever's gone,
And the nightmare is with it
wherever they came from.
That leg is gonna
get you home.
Home?
The stage is in!
No, no. The provost wants to pay for it.
Oh, thank you, sir,
for the treat.
It's a pleasure to treat a man who takes
so little interest in today's occasion.
See, personally, I too have
small interests in a doggone hero.
We think a great deal of jeb
out at the ranch.
Too bad they don't have a brass
band for a good cattle tally.
Understand you've been doing
a fine job out there.
I don't believe
I know your name, sir.
It's the same as yours
- callum. I'm the prosecutor at santa fe.
We're kin, you know. Then I'm
glad to make your acquaintance.
listen to that.
The ladies deprecate killing, but
my, how they admire a war hero.
Jeb, you know, comes by
his instincts naturally.
He inherited them.
Is that so?
I don't believe I ever talked to
anyone who knew jeb rand's kinfolk.
Sometime, take a little ride for
yourself up into glorietta township...
And see what the records have
to say about a family named rand.
Good luck.
"for this meritorious
and exceptional action,
"I now award you
the medal of honor...
Of the United States
of america."
Good to see you, ma. My,
you're looking fine.
Hello, thor.
Hello, jeb.
Welcome home, jeb.
Thank you, adam.
Glad to be home. Come on. Ride up here
with me. Let's get on out to the ranch.
Once you're sleepin' in your own bed
and eatin' at your own table, jeb,
Maybe you'll forget all about the killin'
and shootin' the general talked so much about.
Don't have to forget it,
ma.
Never think about it.
Giddap!
I was savin' this
for thanksgiving.
I guess we're havin' a
kind of thanksgiving anyway.
Thank you. Welcome to my son, jeb.
Thank you, ma.
To you, jeb,
and you must drink to me.
It would be fittin'
to have some music.
Remember, boys?
"the londonderry air."
Why, you used to
sing it.
once more, I'll awaken
the sweetness of
thy slumbering strain
in tears our last
farewell was taken
and now in tears
we meet again
yet, even then
while peace was singing
her halcyon song
o'er land and sea
though joy and hope
to others bring ye
she only brought
new tears
to thee
Yes, jeb, you'll find
changes, and good ones too.
We got four new sections of the
richest fillery you ever saw.
I guess any kind of cattle talk's boresome
after you've been away from it for a while.
Like a fellow
said to me today:
"they don't play
brass bands for cattlemen."
Speaking of cattle, jeb, you're
entitled to read this tally.
You'll find all the operations in
here written down, clear and legal.
I don't have to read, ad.
I can trust your tally.
Well, it's there
for you to see.
I've got your share
all marked off.
I call it the rand share.
Sit down, ad. Won't you
have some more coffee?
No, thanks.
Well, it's been a big day. One
day's the same as another to me.
I gotta be
in the saddle at sunup.
Good night, ma.
Good night, son.
Good night.
Good night, adam.
I'll finish up. You go along. No, you-
Well, all right.
I'm all tuckered out.
Good night, jeb.
Good night, ma.
All these trips to town
tire me out.
jeb?
You know somethin'?
What?
There's a moon out.
Wait till
I get my shawl.
Jeb?
Jeb, sweetheart,
is something wrong?
Thor, we ought to go away.
We will.
I mean right now, tonight.
Let's hitch up a horse
and not tell anyone.
We'll wake up a preacher over
in town and make him marry us.
You know I'll marry you.
What are we waiting for?
I want you
to come court me.
I know that seems silly when
we grew up together, but...
I want to pretend
we didn't.
That's why you've got
to come sparkin' me.
Do you mind? You can get
dressed up real fashionable.
So will I. I'll have two
chairs out in the gallery.
I'll bring out
some lemonade.
We'll sit there
and talk.
You can ask me if I'll let
you smoke, and I'll say yes.
I'll have
a piece of sewing.
What'll we talk about?
Oh, sort of
parlor talk.
The words will be like stitches that
sew and pull on our lives together.
After a while,
you can hold my hand.
You're not supposed to kiss
me till you bought a ring.
Oh, jeb,
can you understand?
Can you see it
in my way?
Thor, I've never
belonged here.
I don't know why. I always have
a feeling something's after me.
It's a bad feeling
I can't explain.
Lots of times I'm happy,
but it's still there.
Thor, I've gotta be with you.
We've got to have a chance. Let's
get away before something happens.
Please, sweetheart.
We're gonna get married,
jeb.
We're not gonna spend the rest
of our lives doing crazy things...
Because you think
something's gonna happen.
We're not gonna run away at night
like a couple of stagecoach robbers.
I love you, jeb.
But if we're gonna get married,
can't it be the way I say?
Please, sweetheart?
I only hope
it turns out that way.
after that, I had to be alone
and think things out.
We hadn't really quarreled,
and yet somehow we had.
It seemed as if we couldn't
understand each other anymore.
One day, I rode up
into butte country.
Came straight to this place,
just as if I'd known the way.
There was something in my life
as ruined as that house.
That house was myself.
I'd seen it
a million times before-
The fireplace,
The trap door.
Out back,
there was some cattle bones.
And then as I walked around the
side, I came on some unmarked graves.
All of the sudden,
I couldn't breathe.
If that house was me, what part
of me was buried in those graves?
Some folks has me beat.
When there's work to be done,
That's the time they decide to go
ridin' all over the countryside.
Honey, I was worried about you.
We didn't know where you were.
I'm sorry.
I just took a little ride.
How long since
you've had something to eat?
I don't know, but I'm not
hungry. I'll fix you some coffee.
That'll be fine.
Right now I wanna see ma.
You got no more sense
than a duck.
Well, I had sense enough
to come home.
Why, thor was fit to be
tied worrying over you.
I was sort of
worried myself.
I got halfway lost. I strayed
away up in that rimrock country,
Up bear paw butte way.
Bear paw butte? Now, what
crazy thing made you do that?
You and thor
have a nip up?
Thor had nothing to do
with my going.
I wanna ask you
something, ma.
I've been wondering about
that old ranch up there.
a goat couldn't live
in that range.
A burro would starve.
People lived there once
though.
You know the ranch
I mean?
I just remembered.
Seems to me there was...
Someplace up there
long ago.
Seems to me
I've been there before.
Ma callum, does that ranch
have to do with me?
Don't ask me questions,
jeb.
Did I come from there
as a boy?
Is that where you took me
from all those years ago?
Is that why
I remember it?
I told you not to look
backward. Look ahead.
I obeyed you.
I've lived like you said.
All my life, I've known
I didn't really belong here.
I couldn't love. I couldn't
return your kindness.
Is there something
the matter with me?
I wanna understand, ma.
You've gotta tell me.
There's nothing the matter
with you, jeb.
That ranch might mean
more to me than it does to you.
Anyway, I get upset
talking about it.
A person's gotta find
his own answers.
We're alone, each of us,
and each in a different way.
I won't be alone.
I'm gonna marry thor.
I want you to.
But when you do, you've
got the future to live for.
I've got the past
to live with too.
My children will have to live
with it. Stop vexing me, jeb brand.
I'm giving you my daughter
for your wife.
Isn't that enough for you? Doesn't
that show you that you're loved?
Go away from me with
your doubts and your-
Your bear paw butte
and your crazy long rides.
Leave off vexing me.
You told me once
not to question you,
But the questions
keep coming back.
If you won't answer me, I'll have to
look somewhere else for the answer.
Goin' out, jeb?
Thought I'd go and see if mr. Dingle's
faro game is still as crooked as ever.
Good idea.
What'd you say?
I said it was
a good idea.
How'd you like to take two or three thousand
dollars along, stake you in the game?
Maybe one of us is crazy,
but I don't seem to follow you.
The tally book would've made it kind of
simple if you'd taken the trouble to read it.
That's why I gave it to you
when you came home.
Only now, I got
this year's crop added.
Two or three thousand would be no
more than your share of the profits.
A third
to each of us,
The way ma wants it.
That's mighty generous. More than
I deserve, least ways expected.
Thanks. Here's something
else you don't know.
All the time you were in the army,
we've been banking money for you.
Fifteen hundred dollars. There's
just one thing wrong with it, jeb.
That money came out of the
ranch, and you didn't earn it.
I've been workin'
my share and yours too.
I don't aim to
keep on doin' that.
I never asked you to. No, but
you never tried to help me either.
Your foot's been well for a month,
and you've been drawin' that money...
For lyin' in the shade.
I was lucky if I didn't have six of my riders
stretched out alongside you playin' pitch.
Oh, sure, I know
you were a hero once,
But I've had my belly
full of that too.
We don't pay off
in medals around here.
It was too bad
I came home at all.
If I hadn't, you would've had
the ranch and the tally money...
And my share of everything
all to yourself.
This "share and share alike" doesn't sit
any better with me than it does with you.
I'm thinkin'
the same way you are.
This ranch isn't big enough
to hold the two of us.
There's a way
we can settle that.
Jeb, you promised me
there'd be no trouble.
I wanna hear
what he has to say.
How can we settle it?
I'll buy you out.
Suppose I don't wanna sell?
Then you buy me out.
Now, you know I can't
do that. Adam, please.
Jeb, don't say anything more.
Won't you do that much for me?
Thor,
you keep out of this.
Well, what's your notion,
if you don't like mine?
When I went to war,
we settled with a toss.
I kept this.
Maybe if it suits you,
we can spin it again.
There might be some luck
in it for me this time.
I'll toss you. My share against
yours. One of us stays, and one goes.
Oh, you can't!
You either!
It's wrong and crazy.
Ever since we were little, we've all been here together
- the three of us.
This is no way to change it
if it's going to be changed.
One toss.
You wanna spin it?
Adam, I beg you!
And you, jeb,
don't do it!
Winner take all.
One toss.
Call it.
Heads.
I might've known
that cartwheel was bad luck.
Well, I'll be ridin'
in town.
I'll hire a rig tomorrow
and come back for my things.
No, you won't.
You ain't got no things,
Exceptin'
what you're wearin'...
And this!
Tomorrow I'm coming back,
And you're coming with me.
If he tries to stop me,
I'll kill him.
ma'll never let you do this.
Maybe she'll have to.
Then I'll go with him
in the morning.
When he comes, I'll be ready. You'd never.
Not if it meant
leavin' the ranch.
The ranch isn't everything
to me. It isn't a husband.
"the ranch be a husband."
you're talkin' crazy.
It's been a wife
to you, adam,
Because you don't have
a wife.
You just have the ranch.
Well, I don't belong to it.
You can take me off that dogeared
tally book you carry around.
You hate me then?
I love you.
I always thought the three
of us would never be apart.
Three. Three!
You're always sayin' that!
But why does he count?
It's you and me.
Now you're the one that's talkin'
crazy. I want a home of my own.
Grant callum knew him.
Knew his people too.
Told me to look up the records
in glorietta county.
And did you? Sure I did,
and I found something.
A family named rand
did live there once.
I found out
enough for me-
A reason why I'll
never let you marry him.
I don't care
what your reason is.
You're talkin' like
a back-fence gossip.
Do you think that kind of
talk means anything to me?
Nothing in the world
can change the way I feel.
I always knew
you cared for him.
I guess...
I never knew how much.
Looks as if we're gonna have
to set things right.
You'll-
you'll go after him, then?
You'll ride in town
and bring him back?
I'll do it.
I'll ride in town tonight.
Mr. Dingle, can you take
this man's I.O.U.?
Yes, I'll take it.
Now throw him out.
Yes.
Keep your hands off me,
will ya?
What's the matter, jake? Don't
you take money in here anymore?
Any money you put on
this bar is counterfeit.
I'm saving you
for the wheel.
Did you run into a fellow who
nearly convinced you? Well, he tried.
You know, I flipped this dollar
twice with adam. I lost both times.
Last time, I went to war.
This time, I left the ranch.
You left the ranch?
You mean that?
Maybe you've played
into a cold deck.
Well, I guess it's all
for the best. Oh, sure.
A man's luck's bound to change
sometime. You appear lucky to me.
Don't you want some action for this
dollar? It's kind of a keepsake.
Oh. Well, many a man's been
down to his last dollar...
Before the change
does come.
I guess you just
want this dollar.
All right,
go ahead and take it.
Hey, jeb, you won.
Let it ride. Oh, no. Too
many angles at this game.
I'd rather play poker.
You've had a run of good luck,
jeb. Why don't you pull out?
Oh, once more.
Oh, brother.
Luck's sure riding on your shoulder.
Probably clean this place out.
Oh, I've got a feeling
you're through.
Well, I've got about $1,500 here
that says you've got a wrong feeling.
Joe, get me a new deck.
Well...
There it is.
I'll tell you what I'd do with that money
if I were you. Don't tell me. Let me guess.
I'd buy into this business.
I'll sell you a piece of it.
You don't mean that?
Yes, I do.
You know why?
Why?
Well, because
people trust you...
And, well,
I'm just honest jake dingle.
You know, I might
take you up on that.
I'll be looking for
a business by and by.
Well, you think it over and let me know.
We'd make a great combination, you and myself.
And if you do come in, I'll
teach you how to handle cards.
It don't hurt anything.
Good night.
Good night, partner.
And take good care
of that money.
as I walked out
on the streets
of laredo
I walked out on
laredo one day
I spied a cow puncher
wrapped up in white linen
wrapped in white linen
as cold as the clay
beat the drum slowly
and play the fife lowly
play the dead March
as you carry me along
take me out to the prairie
and lay the sod over me
for I'm a poor cowboy
and I know I've done wrong
and lay the sod over me
Adam.
Now, let us continue.
I disagree with the learned
corner. I still maintain...
We're a legal body,
properly impaneled.
Sit down, grant.
This is my hearin'.
I don't need no county prosecutor
to tell me how to run it.
Furthermore,
since it so happens...
Said prosecutor's name
is callum,
I wouldn't want to say he's prejudiced
'cause I'm clean-minded, I am.
It's my duty to see
the law administered...
Regardless of family
or anything else.
Gentlemen, I swear from
the bottom of my heart...
I never felt more like
quitting my job than right now.
Because I well know what
this case may cost a family-
A sorrowing mother
and sister-
Who have already lost
one son, one brother...
And, if my guess is right,
may lose another to the law.
Miss callum,
On the night
in question,
Did you witness a quarrel
between your brother and jeb rand?
Yes, I did.
And did you hear the accused utter
any threat with regard to adam?
Yes.
You may repeat
what you heard.
Jeb said he was comin' back
next day to get me...
To take me with him
and marry me.
He said if adam tried to
stop him, he'd kill him.
Perhaps you fellers
might like a spot of tea.
now, here's the size of it.
Here's two men that had
no use want for each other.
All that's been testified, but that
ain't what we're here to decide.
It looks like jeb
shot him down like grant said.
Hold your horses. It's grant's
word against jeb's, he way I see it.
Jeb never was no murderer. I figure
there's plenty of doubt on both sides.
The heck you say. Nobody
can get along with ad callum.
Let's get somethin' done. I gotta
get home and look after my stall.
Shut up!
You fellows saw the general
pin a medal on jeb.
Ah, he weren't decoratin'
no ambusher...
But a man that fought
fair and square for his country.
It don't stand to reason that a man that
shot down a dozen fellows in battle...
Would shoot down his own brother
without givin' him a chance.
If he had to drill him,
he'd do it right.
Uh-uh-uh! And if he done it
right, then it ain't no killin',
But a lawful fight.
And hereabouts we ain't
so danged uncivilized...
A man can't win a lawful fight without
gettin' his neck in a noose for it.
Pass the tea.
Thank you.
May I speak to you
before you go, mrs. Callum?
I know you don't hold with the
verdict of the jury, but it was fair.
I never murdered adam.
You'll be shorthanded
at the ranch.
If you'll permit me, I'd be happy
to come back and help you out.
I make this offer
most sincerely.
Get away from me,
jeb rand.
I know how you
must feel about me,
But I was hoping that
in time I could change that.
It's too late
to change anything.
Mother, let's go.
No. I'll
have my say.
You may have cleared
yourself in there,
But not with me.
With me you're walkin'
up the gallows steps.
I built that gallows.
I tied the noose.
All the love I had
for you is dead.
Stay out of my sight.
If you cross my section line,
I'll set the dogs on you.
Is that the way
you feel?
you'd made pretty clear
how you felt,
So that fall
I put in with jake.
I found out how dull gambling could be
when I stood on the other side of the table.
Once or twice we got some news about you
- come on, baby!
How you'd been sick,
How you were living out at
the ranch and not seeing anyone.
I watched for you to come
into town, but you never did.
It was fall again before I heard
young prentice, the storekeeper's son,
Was taking you and your mother
to the dance.
do-si your daughters
and do-si your old men
do-si your brothers to the
ball and do-si back home
allemande left
and the old left hand
meet your partner
and promenade
it's on fire
and I don't care
and park your gal
in an easy chair
Would you like a glass
of punch? I'd love it.
Excuse me a minute.
Thanks.
and now, ladies and gentlemen,
the next will be la varsouviana.
May I have the pleasure?
Please go away.
Better dance, or people
will look at you.
I'd rather have people look at me
than dance with somebody I hate.
What a coward you are.
A coward wouldn't have
come here to dance with you.
hold it. All right, folks,
that's enough of our slow dance.
Here's a chance
to swing your ladies,
So get your partners
for a chicken reel.
Uh... You saw thor dancin'
with jeb, didn't you?
Why, yes. Come on, son. Let's
you and I have a little talk.
Now, you forced her. Jeb rand, the
man she hates most in the world,
Forced her to dance with him.
I was getting her some punch.
You're escorting her this
evening, aren't you? Yes.
Did you bring her here so she could be
insulted? No. I wouldn't let that happen.
Well, it's happened.
What are you gonna do about it?
Pardon us, gentlemen.
Mr. Callum, all this
started long ago.
It isn't my fight. Then you're
not the man I took you for.
I'll do what's right.
If you let him get away with it,
she'll never speak to you again.
Did she say that? If she
didn't, she's thinking it.
And there's something else
she's thinking of.
It's the death
of her brother.
Mr. Callum, sir...
I'm not much good with a gun.
Maybe you'll have some help.
Go up to the alley.
If he's an honest wheel, you'll
find him in the back room.
Shoot him
through the window.
No, sir, I-
I can't do that.
But I'll make him
come out to me.
What's the matter, jake?
Couldn't you find any partner?
You found one you
shouldn't have- thor.
Young prentice is comin' over
after you for it. Prentice?
He's on his way over here now. Get
the drop on him, jeb. Go on out front.
First adam, now prentice.
Man, you
gotta get going.
I don't wanna get
the drop on him, jake.
What are you gonna do?
Step out in the alley
and make myself scarce.
Mr. Rand.
What do you want?
I've come because
of what you did to thorley.
Go on home, prentice.
I don't want to hurt you.
Defend yourself,
mr. Rand.
I wouldn't try that
if I were you, grant.
Let's get him
in the office.
I- I did it
for thorley.
I'm sorry, prentice.
it was self-defense
just as they said,
Yet he was one more part of
the mystery of people hating me.
How I saw the boots
of the pallbearers,
The flashes of light.
I had that feeling some lost and
awful thing come over me again.
I wasn't sure whether killing
prentice was my fault,
Whether it was due to some
badness locked up in me.
But I was sure
of my love for you.
That was the only hope
and the only answer.
If love could come out of all this,
we might still have some chance.
We might live.
Right then I knew
I had to have you.
I'd have to climb across
two graves to get to you,
But nothing in the world
could hold me back.
Who's that comin'?
It's jeb rand.
He's comin'
to call on me.
Jeb rand?
Callin' on you?
I knew he'd come.
I've been expectin' him.
You've no right to expect him,
much less to see him.
I'm askin' him in.
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Won't you come in?
Thank you.
It was kind of you
to receive me.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
Would you like
some coffee?
I don't want to put you
to any trouble.
Oh, it's no trouble.
We were just going to have some.
I'm sorry we have
nothing else to offer.
In this house all we have
is a little wine.
That's just for christmas
and holidays.
Seems to me I remember
something about that wine.
That's a music box
ma had sent from santa fe.
I know. It plays
"the londonderry air."
It's an old-fashioned tune.
Some people don't care for it.
May I smoke?
Or would that annoy you?
No, of course not.
This is a sampler I'm makin'.
I'm not very good at it.
Here we are courting, the way
you asked me to long ago.
But it's all different.
You sitting there.
Me smoking, you sewing.
Just like
any ordinary people.
It's worse than fighting
or yelling in the street.
- Don't you want your coffee?
- No, thanks.
Perhaps later. Why don't you sit
down in the comfortable chair?
Company always
uses that one.
I tried to figure out what crazy
game you were playing with me,
And I couldn't.
But I knew I'd play it out
with you right till the end.
Am I seeing things?
Well, I declare!
Good night, jeb
I'll see you tomorrow?
Of course.
Thor.
Thor! Come here!
- What is it?
- Come closer.
Turn the lamp up.
That's right.
I want to look at you.
I haven't changed, mother.
What have I taught you that showed
you how to bring dishonor on us?
I've brought you
no dishonor.
Jeb gave me this tonight.
I'm going to marry him,
mother.
What's in this that I don't
understand? Do you love him then?
I have only one thought
every minute of my life:
How much I hate him.
But you wear his ring.
If I were a man,
I would've killed him long ago.
After adam's death.
Then he killed prentice
and came courtin' me.
All of a sudden,
killin' wasn't enough.
I had to have more-
Much more- to use up
all the hate I have in me.
Thor, I'll sell this place.
I'll go away.
I won't stay here
and see this thing happen.
Perhaps that may be best.
You go away for a while.
We'll be together again soon.
No woman ever lived...
Who could go through
with what you're planning.
No woman but me.
'cause it's taken all my life
to teach me what he is.
He put shame
and grief on us,
And now he'd like to squeeze out
the last drop of it by havin' me.
He wants me...
And I'll marry him.
That moment when he thinks he
has me, he'll lose everything...
Because that's when
I'm going to kill him.
For richer,
for poorer.
For richer, for poorer.
In sickness
and in health.
In sickness and in health.
Until death
do us part.
Until death do us part.
What made you do that?
I don't know. Such fine young
folks, and nobody at the wedding.
I have a surprise for you.
I've bought you a house.
All right, charlie.
Well, now you've seen it.
That's why I sent for you.
Bein' as we're all callums here, I don't
have to tell you what we're gonna do about it.
Sure enough, you'll get
yourself in trouble, and us too.
Yeah. Times have changed
since all this started, grant.
You can't ride herd
on the law no more.
You're telling me about the law? No, sir.
You thinkin' like him, that
you're not goin'? That's right.
I think we're all goin'.
When I heard
about the auction,
I figured it'd be better for me to buy
it than see it pass on to strangers.
Allow me. I know it's a
custom to carry the bride in,
But perhaps
we can let that go.
I always figured when I got
married I'd have all the trimmings.
You may notice some changes. There are some
fixings I brought here from kansas city.
Mighty pretty place
you've got here.
Charlie, would you take mrs. Rand's
bags into the front bedroom, please?
I sure will.
Come in.
You're very beautiful.
Thank you.
I hope you'll
be comfortable here.
In this house it takes very
little to make me comfortable.
I brought you some wine.
It's customary, I believe,
to drink to a bride's health.
You're very gallant.
So you know.
You and I are much alike.
There are times when
I can read your thoughts...
By asking myself what I'd do
if I were in your place.
I know that's an irritating
quality in a husband,
But it may help
to make things easier for you.
Don't come any closer.
You sure
this is all right?
Prentice missed
because the light was bad.
Adam was too anxious.
I'm glad you don't suffer
from those handicaps.
No, I don't.
Do you know
why you missed me?
Because I hate you so,
my hand shook.
Your hand shook,
but not because you hate me.
Put the gun down, thor.
Oh, jeb. Hold me.
Hold me.
Jeb? What is it?
What's the matter?
I've gotta leave. There are men
outside. They want to kill me.
It's all
grant callum's doing.
I don't know why, but he's wanted
me dead ever since I can remember.
Oh, take me with you. I can't, but
we can be together in a little while.
There's an old ruined ranch up
by bear paw butte. Meet me there.
How do I find it? Take the trail through
rimrock canyon, across the county line.
Oh, I'll be there.
Looks like he jumped clean off this
bluff here. Aw, he just outrun us.
Let's give it up. I got a
hunch I know where he is.
Russ, go fetch ma callum
and bring her to bear paw butte.
It's all going to happen again,
but I don't care now.
I know there's one big answer
I've always looked for:
Why I was alone;
why everything went wrong;
Why I had hate in me
instead of love.
There was a black dog
riding my back and yours too.
I guess we've lost our chance, but
there's nothing we can do about it now.
Oh, but there is. We've got to
get away from here, both of us.
Jeb rand, we know you're
in there. Come on out!
We'll give you
two minutes!
Are you hurt?
I remember now. Those dreams I've
been having ever since I was a kid.
the flashes were gunfire,
And the man shooting
was my father.
My sister lay on the floor dead,
and my brothers were dead too.
The boots and spurs,
they were my father's.
Then he was hit.
I saw him fall.
I knew he'd been killed.
I was too scared to yell,
so I just stayed there.
Then a man came in-
grant callum.
He was dragging a woman
with him. She was your mother.
He told her
to look at her rand now.
I remember those words-
"your rand."
He asked her if the love she had
for him was worth what she'd done.
Then he threw her down
and dragged my father out.
Jeb, darling,
how horrible.
It must mean
that my mother-
One minute! Come out,
or we'll come and drag you out!
Come on.
I won't.
You're doing this for me because
you're afraid I'll be hurt.
I don't want to live without
you. We've gotta fight.
we're comin' out.
Don't shoot.
Throw your gun out!
Put your hands up.
Oh! Oh, I told him to fight you,
to die fightin' if he had to!
Let me go!
Oh, mother, you won't
let them do this!
So, grant, you're gonna
have it your way at last.
I told you I'd wait
until he was grown.
Well, now he's growed and he gets
his legacy. Only it's made out of him.
He earned it just as his
father earned the lead he got...
When he stole
my brother's wife.
Then it was jeb's father!
You loved him.
Yes, only she forgot she
was married to a callum.
Bring a horse here.
Get me a rope.
Jeb told me
about the feud.
Now I understand
the part I didn't know.
It all started because
of your love, your guilt.
That's why you'd like
to see jeb hanged.
You don't know what you're
sayin'. This is none of my askin'.
You never gave jeb a chance. You never told
him the truth so he could protect himself.
- I was trying to protect you.
- That's a lie.
- You were ashamed.
- I've paid for what I did.
I gave the boy a home.
I took him in.
That paid for all the killin's? For the
way my father died, and jeb's father?
Well, it didn't!
You loved his father.
Or are you ashamed now
to remember how you loved?
No. I loved his father.
You failed him, mother,
and you failed yourself.
You lost the man you loved.
He died here.
But my man won't,
unless they kill me too!
You can't!
I'm sorry, jeb, for all the wrong I did ya.
Forgive me. You didn't have to ask me that.
You've given me back my life. Oh, mother.
I told you once, jeb,
never to look back.
Look ahead.
I tell you that again now.
You couldn't then.
But now I can and will.
Take your wife
home, jeb.