Dolan? Dolan!
- Sorry about that bump.
- Bump? What bump?
Now you're awake, you gonna come
up here and trail me or not?
I'm a passenger, not a driver.
Jump!
Huh, took you long enough
to get him.
Didn't. He moves like an Apache.
- You must be getting old.
- Must be.
- Let's see the damage
- I've had worse.
Shut up and lean back.
Tie this thing, will ya?
How do you figure it, Ben?
Why the bushwhack?
That's it, ask fool questions
while I bleed to death.
Well, he didn't try to kill us.
Mean anything to you?
Means you're figurin'
on buryin' me here.
Get that coach up on its four
legs and get me-
I hope you've fainted,
but I doubt it.
Who is it?
It's Claire, Mr. Flood.
Hi!
I told you to be here
when I got back.
Don't be mad.
Look what I bought.
The latest thing from the east.
Sorry, I wanted to surprise you.
When I say do
something, you do it.
- I thought-
- I'll say when to think.
I just wanted to look
especially nice for you.
That's all it was, Mr. Flood.
I swear.
All right, Claire, honey.
How you gonna look especially
nice if you cry, huh?
I wouldn't ever do anything
against you, Mr. Flood.
That's the honest truth.
What'd you buy, honey?
Can I show you?
If it's something
to put on, put it on.
- Mr. Flood?
- Yarbrough.
Glad you're back.
We run into a little trouble.
Go on.
This mornin', one
of the new men, Toby Wheelock,
started roughing up
that storekeeper, McGivern.
That's your job.
I know, but sometimes
them young fellas
is always tryin'
to make a name for themselves.
How bad is McGivern?
It ain't McGivern,
it's Wheelock.
That storekeeper killed
him with a pitchfork.
McGivern knew Wheelock
was one of my men.
Now that puppy-dog deputy's
tryin' to take hisself serious.
Says he's gonna
hold McGivern for trial.
That's good enough.
He's entitled to a fair trial.
- Whatever you say, Mr. Flood.
- That's the law.
How long will it take you to
round up a jury?
Oh, 10, 15 minutes.
Make that a half-hour.
Right, Mr. Flood.
Jace! You see anything?
I swear, I just don't know
what got into me.
Stupid, that's what I am,
just plain stupid.
No argument from me.
I was just mindin'
my own business...
and he comes in,
he starts shovin' me around.
Like a fool, I...
I lose my temper and-
Here they come.
I should've left town after
the sheriff got bushwhacked.
But you didn't, Jace.
Remember that, you didn't.
Just wishin', Charlie,
that's all.
Open up, Jace.
I want McGivern.
He's my prisoner,
Mr. Flood. Nobody gets him.
You're proteCTing
a murderer, Jace.
That's my job.
He gets a fair trial.
Good. The town's
gonna try him right now.
No, sir. The 1st of the month,
when the circuit judge comes.
That's fair enough.
I mean... Well, a week or so
won't make too much difference.
Will it, Mr. Flood?
Hear that, Jace?
McGivern's got friends out here.
Sure. But I gotta
wait for the judge.
You've got exaCTly one minute
to open that door, Deputy,
or Ned will drop this package
down that chimney...
and open it for you.
50 seconds.
40 seconds.
30 seconds.
Jace! Give me a gun
and let me out!
20 seconds.
Can't, Charlie. I'll do my best,
I promise you that.
10 seconds.
You pointin'
that Winchester at me, sonny?
I'm orderin' you
to leave, Mr. Flood.
You drop that gun
and get out of my way now.
If your men kill me,
I'll take you with me.
Then we'll both be dead.
Your choice, sonny.
You make it.
Looks like this tin is a little
too heavy for you, sonny.
All right,
that's enough.
Folks, a town without
a duly-eleCTed sheriff...
becomes a lawless town.
I propose we eleCT
a sheriff right now.
I nominate Jess Torrey.
- Simms, you wanna second it?
- Yeah, I second it.
Good. Any other nominations?
Ryan?
You wanna nominate anybody?
You're a man that usually
has something to say.
Got any suggestions?
You?
Well, it looks like
it's unanimous there, Jess.
Congratulations. Do a good job.
I aim to Mr. Flood.
Startin' now.
Yarbrough, Simms.
I'm deputizin' you.
Murderer in there wants a trial.
All right, let's pick a jury.
Johnson, Ramirez...
No. No! NO!!
The law says you gotta
give me a trial!
McGIVERN: Jace! Jace!
For God's sake,
stop 'em! Stop 'em!
Jace!
All right.
This man killed Toby Wheelock.
In self defence.
A man's got a right to defend
himself and his property.
Sheriff.
Jury?
Guilty!
No! Jace! I told you, I was
just tryin' to defend myself!
Jace! Somebody help me!
Turn him loose!
Now, Molly, honey,
a hangin's no place for you.
There won't be a hangin'.
Jury says there will.
It's all legal.
Tell your men
to turn McGivern loose.
You're interrupting
justice, Molly.
Not one more step.
Now, turn him loose.
Oh!
Feels just like
old times, honey.
Let me go!
Ooh! Let go!
Get on with it.
SIMMS: Right, Mr. Flood.
Boys?
Whoa.
Yee-hoo hoo hoo!
Hey, friend?
Yeah?
Where's the Lang & Hickman
stage office?
Huh?
Do you know where
the Lang stage office is?
Down that street, goin' south.
Much obliged.
I'm sure glad
to see you, Mr. Hickman.
My name's Dolan. Hickman's
been shot. Get a doCTor.
Oh... Well, how bad is he?
- Get a doCTor.
- Oh, yeah.
The top of the stairs,
the room to your right!
HICKMAN: Uhh... Oww!
He'll need some tendin', Molly.
I'll take care of him.
Lots of beef broth with barley.
That's one dollar, Mr. Dolan.
She'll pay it.
I have some money downstairs.
Tell me, doc. Do you have
many hangin's in this town?
Can't say.
The fella strung up
in the plaza, what'd he do?
I wouldn't know.
He oughta be up in a week or so.
Hope so. D'you always
leave them dangling overnight?
Never noticed.
Any particular reason
you never noticed?
Yes, Mr. Dolan.
My wife and children.
Oh, Ben.
You've been had.
Thanks for coming, Dan.
Not at all, Molly. Don't you
worry, he'll be all right.
I helped myself to a cup
of coffee. Hope you don't mind.
- How long since you ate?
- This morning, King City.
I've got some cold ham.
Thank you, that'd be fine.
Good.
I'm sorry about Mr. Hickman.
Ah, those things happen.
I know who did it.
Looks good.
Don't you want to know?
- Not particularly.
- Oh.
Ma'am, do you know what you do
when you walk into a bad bar
and the hairs
behind your neck stick up?
Get your drink, pay for it,
turn around and walk out.
And this is a bad bar?
Yes, ma'am.
Jericho is a bad bar.
As soon as Ben's up to it,
him and me'll be leavin'.
But he shot Mr. Hickman.
He's been shot before.
All right, if it'll
make you feel better, who?
Flood. Alex Flood.
- Is he in Jericho?
- Do you know him?
Yeah, I heard of him.
Why did you
write Ben that letter?
I knew his reputation
as a marshal before he retired.
Ben's past sixty.
He didn't decide to retire,
they retired him.
- I didn't know that.
- True.
But I never lied to him.
I told him the line
was in trouble.
He didn't tell you?
Not a word.
Oh.
Sure knew your man, though.
Tell Ben there's trouble...
and he's 20 years younger.
He couldn't wait to get here.
Did he mention
he had an ex-deputy with him?
Yeah.
So you figured I'd come along...
and you'd get two
for the price of one.
Yes, I thought of that.
Thank you, ma'am.
Mr. Dolan, when we pick up
the passengers...
at the relay station,
we'll be back in business.
How? Piggyback?
We'll patch up the coach
and start Monday.
We can do it.
I've got $400 invested in that
coach. That's as far as I go.
No sense throwing
good money after bad.
I'm a gambler,
I play the percentages.
And I don't like the odds.
Then there's nothing
more I can say.
No, ma'am.
What happened to your husband?
Husbands.
I've been widowed twice.
They die in bed?
My first got hit by a stray
bullet in a drunken gunfight.
Frank got his head
kicked in by a colt,
out in the corral.
Your husbands don't seem
to have much luck.
They thought different.
They say so?
I know so.
Been a widow very long?
Not long enough
for it to bother me.
So don't let it bother you.
I wasn't going to.
Any more questions?
Yes.
Where do I sleep?
The spare room's
to the left. The bed's made.
Thank you. Good night.
Mr. Dolan?
Good night, Miss Lang.
How you feelin'?
Hmph. Lousy barley.
Man can't eat this slop,
'lessen he can wash it down.
I'll see what I can do.
Howdy. False rumor, Jess.
We heard Molly's
new partner was shot.
You heard right.
Ben Hickman, he's upstairs.
The old marshal? One of
the greats in his time, Jess.
Still better than most.
- A good friend of yours?
- Sort of partners.
- My name's Dolan.
- Oh, I'm Flood.
This is Sheriff Torrey.
Molly's in town.
Looking for a wheel
for that coach.
- Back watchers?
- Deputies.
Jess always keeps 'em handy.
How many you got, Jess?
14, Mr. Flood.
We need 'em to keep the peace.
No guns allowed in town.
You lookin' for something?
- Whiskey.
- Not there. Try the cupboard.
No, on the right. Second shelf.
Thanks.
Want me to question
the old man now, Mr. Flood?
I don't know. Dolan?
How's the Marshal feeling?
Good enough.
Well, ask him if he's up
to answering some questions.
Sure.
Ben.
The sheriff's downstairs.
Wanna see him?
Why, sure. Why not?
What the hell you call that?
That's no drink. Give me
my regular three fingers.
You want it or not?
You're rattlesnake-mean, Dolan.
The sheriff's with a friend
of Mrs. Lang's named Flood.
- You owe me two fingers.
- She mention him to you?
I never talked to her
before this morning..
- You didn't answer me.
- You didn't give me my drink!
HICKMAN: Her comin' home.
Did you give her the money
to buy a new wheel?
She got us a new wheel?
Get out, Flood.
- That's no way to talk.
- I said get out.
And take your hangman with you.
I think this batch of cookies
has too much vanilla in, honey.
Mr. Dolan, kick him out.
Never step in between close
friends or argue with the law.
You can't blame her
for being excited, Dolan.
Longest run
of tough luck I ever saw.
And Molly,
you just say the word,
I'll have you
a new coach for that run.
That's a nice offer.
For 51% of the line?
Go to hell, Flood.
I'll be rolling
on schedule without you.
I hope so, Molly, I really do.
But the way your luck's been.
My only bad luck
is you're not dead yet.
Miss Lang.
You have a sick man upstairs.
At least take care of him.
Do I go along, Mr. Flood?
He's fit.
"Do I go along, Mr. Flood?"
"Do I go on breathing,
Mr. Flood?"
"Do I go on living, Mr. Flood?"
Feisty, but loveable.
Sit down, Dolan.
Thanks, but...
I like the view
better over here.
Of course. Have one.
All right.
You swing a lot of weight
around here.
Only 51% of everything I touch.
Except the Lang Stage Line.
Lang & Hickman.
Oh, the paint'll wear off.
Hickman's deputy
in Santa Fe, weren't you?
Used to be.
40 a month, every month
you're alive to colleCT it.
Is that why you quit Abeline?
Oh, I got 50 a month.
Now I got a town, Dolan.
Town, cattle,
part of a mine, territory...
It brought me entertainment
and I stayed to take my profits.
It's tamed?
I don't think you'll
hear any complaints.
With one exception.
Don't you think
she can be tamed?
Hadn't thought about it.
No? After sleeping under
the same roof?
- It's a big roof.
- Small town, Dolan.
I tell you what,
the hotel's full up-
- Your hotel.
- Only 51%.
I'll tell 'em
you're comin' over...
and they'll fix somethin'
special for you.
Real thoughtful.
Ex-lawman to ex-lawman,
it's my pleasure.
Mr. Flood?
Seems the old man didn't
see the bushwhacker.
But he said maybe he did.
Ex-lawman to ex-lawman,
I wouldn't recognise him...
if I was sitting
in the same room with him.
But you know something,
Flood? You're right.
A little too much vanilla
in those cookies.
Dolan, when you get in town
you look me up, huh?
Ace Deuce Palace.
GIRL: Try your luck?
Maybe later.
I'll take three.
Just looked over your 51%.
Very nice.
Hotel says you didn't show.
Couldn't.
Ben worried about his health.
Oh, when Hickman worries,
you worry?
Used to be the other way round.
Like to sit in?
Uh-uh. Buy you a drink instead.
Uh-uh. My place,
I'll do the buying.
I was hopin' you'd say that.
What's that "uh-uh" mean?
I don't like the odds.
banana nose deals sliders.
Sure?
It's my business to be sure.
Harv!
Yes? What?
Table Five, Joey Ross.
He's all thumbs. Fire him.
- Fire him?
- Yeah, fire him.
Yes, sir.
Have you found out yet
who ambushed you?
Injuns? Hold-up crew?
I figure Indians,
or somebody with just
about as much know-how.
Ever do any Injun fightin'?
Little.
You know, I was thinkin',
you walk like an Indian.
Lived with them
a long time back.
May I?
Certainly, Claire. Have a drink.
Thank you, Mr. Flood.
This is Dolan.
Pleased to meet you, Mr. Dolan.
Likewise, Miss Claire.
You like my friend, honey?
Do you want me to like him?
No. Dolan knows I share
nothing with nobody.
'Cept whiskey and cookies.
Joan?
Would you like to
meet a girl, Mr. Dolan?
Thank you, ma'am.
I'll let you know if I do.
Here's to fun and-
You hear
what he's sayin', Curly?
Hand it over.
And who's gonna make me?
Just obeyin' orders.
You gotta check it.
- This gun stays.
- Hey, big man.
The law says no guns.
You the law?
No, I am.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Well, I don't see no badge.
I don't need no badge, bigmouth.
It's up there on the ledge.
He levellin', Curly?
He's levellin'.
OK, friend, you win.
All of 'em, mister.
Under the coat.
Sure, why in the hell not?
- You.
- Clean.
The knife inside your boot.
Flood!
Harv?
Ditch him.
Boys! Get him out of here.
The louse cut you.
Go get me another jacket,
will you, honey?
- Are you all right?
- Fine. Grey jacket.
Thanks for the yell, Dolan.
Old habit.
Man's back's a tender spot.
You did all right.
Is that why you didn't step in?
Steppin' in's a habit I outgrew.
Smart.
Helps a man
stay alive a long time.
Phil?
Lock him up. We'll hang him
after the trial.
Jericho's a law-abidin'
town, Dolan.
Here's to law and order.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, sir.
What would you like
for breakfast?
Same as Ben. His plate's so
clean, I can't tell what it was.
Just ham and eggs.
Ben, he goes for home cooking.
You don't?
No, ma'am.
It's Frank Ryan and his boy,
they have the general store.
They're good friends of mine.
They'd like to meet you.
I won't be around long
enough to make friends.
We can beat him, Mr. Dolan.
Believe me, we can.
You can't.
I saw the town last night.
Monday, Ben and me'll be gone.
Oh. Ben say so?
He will when he hears the count.
And I
can go to the devil?
Or to Flood. All you have
to do is say the word.
I have. The word is never.
It wasn't always.
No, not when he first came here
to do a job that needed doing.
Stopped all the killings
and stealing.
Everybody in this town
looked up to him.
We were mistaken.
Me most of all.
49% of something is better
than 100% of nothing.
No.
Your choice.
If I get help, six men
or more, good men,
then will you stay on?
Merchants?
We're gonna have a meeting
at Ryan's place.
Sheep against wolves.
Talk sense.
You have two choices,
give Flood what he wants
or pack up and move.
Everything inside your head
are odds, percentages!
You know Flood shot Ben,
but that doesn't matter!
You don't like
the odds, so you run!
You aren't much
of a man, Mr. Dolan.
Miss Lang,
you're burning breakfast.
Oh, damn!
Just as well.
A man who gets attached to home
cooking can't think straight.
I'll eat breakfast in town.
Mr. Dolan?
Hold off telling Ben
till after the meeting.
Give me a chance
to change the odds.
I'm sorry, Miss Lang.
Why won't Pa
let me stay up tonight?
Your Pa has his reasons.
Now don't you ask again, hear?
Come back to try your luck?
Yes, ma'am.
- Pass over for five.
- Without me.
- Call.
- Two, five and ten.
Fold.
Pass.
Call.
- Cards?
- One.
Dealer takes one.
- Better odds tonight?
- Much.
Bet ten.
Call.
Kings and treys.
Beats jacks and nines.
Looks like you know
your business, Dolan.
It's a living.
Carl?
Yes, Mr. Flood?
How much you got
in your bank, Dolan?
$462.
Bring me $462 out of petty cash.
Yes, sir.
Out.
Five five.
Fold.
Buy you a drink?
No, thanks. Never drink
when I'm working.
Your deal, Mr. Flood.
Didn't expeCT to see you
here tonight, Dolan.
Why not?
Figured you'd be
tied up in a meeting.
55. What meetin'?
Call.
Raise 10. Secret meetin'.
Ryan's house, ten o'clock.
Call or raise.
Don't know any Ryans.
How much longer do you
intend to wait, Molly?
Miller's usually ahead of time.
It's nothing.
I'm sure Miller'll be here soon.
Maybe he ain't comin'.
Likely he ain't.
His wife's dead set against it.
I don't want this to take
any more time than it has to.
So let's get started.
You talk, Dolan.
Right, but softly.
20.
I'm feelin' charitable,
in a small way. Raise you 20.
Down the street. Ryan's store.
Alterations.
It's been raised.
You callin' or foldin'?
Callin'.
40 more.
Confidence.
40... and 60.
Go.
Two.
Same.
That's a nice-lookin' watch.
Runs a few minutes fast.
How much you got there?
$646.
That's the bet.
Sounds to me like
the meeting's adjourned.
That's 646 to you, Dolan.
She's all right. Things that
belong to me never get damaged.
You callin' my hand?
I'd never face myself
if I didn't.
Your call.
- Three of a kind.
- Same.
Tens.
Queens.
Can't win 'em all.
Your turn to buy.
I'm glad you won, Dolan.
That'll give you and the old
marshal travellin' money.
And the sooner the better.
Or first thing I know,
you and me are liable to...
wind up being friends.
Miss Lang?
Are you all right?
Go ahead and cry.
You got a right.
The last thing I need
is your advice.
Easy, it'll knock
you on your ear.
It's my ear.
Yarbrough and Simms
really had a great time.
They dragged us
out of the house.
Aggie Ryan fought like a tiger.
They blew her home to bits.
Years of scrimping and saving,
everything they owned.
Do you know that...?
Ah, you wouldn't.
Maybe I would.
The hell, you would.
They made us stand there
while they took Ryan...
and in front of his wife and
son, beat him and beat him...
and beat him.
First one, then the other.
Laughing all the time.
I'm sorry it happened.
Hooray for being sorry.
Mr. Dolan, you stink.
Go ahead, get it off your chest.
Damn right.
I've got some things I wanna say
to you, Mr. Dolan. Just a few.
I'm not in any hurry.
You can't wait to hightail it
out of Flood's sight.
Right.
You've got a yellow streak
down your back this wide.
- This wide?
- Right.
That's what I said.
I just don't understand you,
Mr. Dolan. Ben, I understand.
Frank and Aggie Ryan.
People all over the world.
Even a louse
like Alex Flood I understand.
You really are
a stinker, Mr. Dolan.
I know what you're thinking.
"I told you so. "
That's what you're thinking.
Sheep.
Wolves against sheep.
Go on. Why don't you tell
me how right you were?
I just don't
understand you, Mr. Dolan.
Ben, Aggie, Frank Ryan,
I understand.
People all over the world
Even Alex Flood.
Mr. Dolan, you are a bastard.
Mm-hm.
I'm going to bed.
I'm gonna kiss you.
You didn't have to do that.
Just can't figure you, Dolan.
Just can't figure you.
- Mr. Dolan?
- Mmm?
Somebody oughta
put dynamite down your chimney.
Good morning. I'm sorry
I'm late getting started.
You and Ben must be starved.
Ham steaks and fried
potatoes all round.
Get me a jug of that
bacon grease, will you?
I could do with
some more firewood,
if you're up to chopping it.
Any time.
Mr. Dolan, if you can't handle
whiskey, you shouldn't drink it.
Who put who to bed last night?
Hmm?
Oh!
We'll have your breakfast
going soon.
No hurry.
- Rough night?
- Yeah.
Dolan told me you're pulling out
when you're strong enough.
Thanks for offering
to leave the coach.
Don't thank me,
that was Dolan's idea.
Kind of a hard fellow
to figure out, ain't he?
Yes, he is.
What would you do,
if you were him?
That's even harder to figure.
Miss Lang?
You know something?
I wish I was ten years younger.
So do I, Mr. Hickman.
Thanks, I'll have breakfast
ready in no time.
No, thanks. Think I'll go
into town, get some whiskey.
Ben'll be wanting
his three fingers.
And we're fresh out.
Comes from having
a drunk in the house.
Two.
Visitors.
Hired killers.
Badge gives them the license.
Mrs. Lang!
About this coach. Got some
things I wanna tell you.
You mean ordered to tell me.
Yeah, that's right.
I've been looking forward to it.
This paper here says you ain't
paid your bills or the bank.
They'll be paid.
Hey, get away from that coach.
Some coach!
Sure is torn up inside.
Don't touch it!
- Sure is flimsy, ain't it?
- Leave it alone!
You wanna bet I can't
tear this off with one hand?
You wanna bet you don't?
You interfering
with the law, Dolan?
Uh-uh. I wouldn't think of it.
Just proteCTing
private property.
That coach is mine.
That's not what this paper says.
Read it yourself.
Drop your gun belts.
Any time.
I never hurry a man
who wants to die.
You won't get out
of town alive, Dolan.
My problem. Yours is gettin'
out of here. Now, drop it.
You too, Yarbrough.
Come on.
Now, throw 'em
in the horse trough.
You must be crazy, Dolan.
You know who we work for.
Mm-hm.
It's your turn, Dolan.
Throw the gun in the trough.
Just a little more tightening's
all she'll need.
Ahh!
Agh!
Urgh!
Ride him, Mr. Flood! Yahoo!
C'mon! Ride 'em, there!
Nice riding, Mr. Flood!
Sure likes to jump.
Nasty enough to be mine.
Don't look like
she'll stay busted.
Well, we'll go round
and round again.
And I hope he likes
it same as me.
Whoa!
You said last night,
nothing that belongs
to you ever gets damaged.
That's right.
You forgot to tell your men.
What'd you use on 'em?
Single tree.
Oh... Where's Simms?
I don't know.
Probably at the doCTor's.
That man was a deputy.
The way I look at it,
a man starts choking a woman...
is lookin' to go
to hell in a hurry.
All I did was oblige him.
Same as you do, Mr. Flood.
Well, the problem is
you're you and I'm me.
Different privileges.
Majority rules.
Why don't you clear out?
Can't wait to,
soon as Ben's fit.
He's fit enough.
Why don't you just leave the way
you came in, in this coach?
Tomorrow.
About nine or ten o'clock.
Whatever's best.
Nine o'clock. It's earlier.
You want me to take him with me?
You killed him, you bury him.
Oh, and Dolan?
One minute after nine
and I'll hang you.
Yah! Yee-ah!
Ahh, no question
about it, Dolan.
You gotta pull out like he said,
or he'll hang you for sure.
A sick man like me, even
Flood'll give me a day or two.
No, Dolan, too much
light hurts my eyes.
I figured you'd
ride out with me now.
Ahh, I wish to God I could.
But I'll meet up with
you wherever you say.
- Waco.
- All right.
Ooh... I could sure use three
fingers to kill this pain.
It's that bad, huh?
Uh... It comes and goes.
No, don't touch... You can't-
I ain't leavin' and I ain't
meetin' up with you.
You gave me your word!
I know I did.
But I gotta break it.
And nothin' you say
will change my mind.
Come Monday, that coach is gonna
do what it's supposed to do.
- It'll pull out on schedule.
- Stop talking like a fool.
If you wanna commit suicide,
get in bed and shoot yourself.
At least you'll die comfortable.
I came because you asked me.
Now I'm askin' you to leave.
You owe me that much, Ben.
More.
Much more.
But I owe myself too.
Any man has to have a reason
to get up in the morning.
That's very touching.
We'll put it on your tombstone.
"Here lies Ben Hickman,
who needed a reason
to get up in the morning. "
What's the matter with you?
Can't you admit you're too old?
This isn't Tucson 15 years ago,
this is Jericho.
You're 63, in a town full
of guns. Those are the faCTs.
You're thinking with this
instead of this.
That's when they bury you.
And you know it!
Now, get your gear
and let's get out of here.
So long, Dolan.
Nothin' but the best to you.
We're obliged to you, Mr. Dolan.
I never thought
I'd see you again.
What are the odds?
- You got a glass?
- Got three of 'em.
I told Molly we'd be needin'
'em when you got back.
Molly! Molly?
See?
I told you, never argue with the
best friend of a best friend.
You know he'll hang you, Dolan?
Probably.
- Over my dead body.
- Most likely.
Your friend Ryan, will he fight?
Oh, he'd die trying.
That brings the odds way down.
Only 10 to 1.
Jace. He was aCTing sheriff...
until he tried
to stop a lynching.
Anybody else?
Nobody that I can think of.
Four guns makes it 9 to 1.
8 to 1, you forgot me.
Yes, sir.
Just ten years younger.
HICKMAN: Ho!
Well, I see you're eight minutes
ahead of a rope, huh?
To bad we never
got together, Marshal.
From what I've been hearing,
it's my pleasure.
You got yourself a pretty
hard partner, Dolan.
There's still time
to buy you a last drink.
Only minutes ahead of a rope
makes swallowing too tough.
Maybe we'll run
into each other again some day.
You run into me again, you
still won't like the odds.
Certain plans I've made
don't include you.
We understand each other?
Majority rules.
Why'd you have to say I was
63 in front of Mrs. Lang?
-64, come August.
- Huh.
Yah! Yah!
Cheer up. We'll be
at Flood's herd pretty soon.
You're still not
too old to rustle.
Molly, why don't
you simmer down?
Why don't you get out?
Now, wait. I came here
real nice, hat in hand-
I'm not interested.
Molly, I have to treat
everybody the same here.
You don't really think
I care about this place?
All I want is you, dear.
- For better or worse.
- That's all over, Flood.
It used to be Alex, honey.
You used to be different.
Different? A hired gunslinger?
No, a lawman, proud of his job.
How can you be proud
on 50 a month?
- Is that what you want?
- I did.
But not now?
- That's right.
- Well, let's find out.
Well, you didn't help much.
You turn my stomach.
- Dolan?
- Is that what you think?
I'm asking you.
That's why you ran
him out of town.
I didn't like him living under
the same roof with you.
Not just under the same roof.
And I loved every minute of it!
Ohh...
- That's for lying.
- Am I lying?
Did he or didn't he?
You'll never know.
You lousy tramp!
Yes or no?
If you want that stage
to roll, come see me.
Only don't walk, crawl!
Yah! Yah!
You like for me to shave you,
don't you, Mr Flood?
Among other things I like, yes.
Can I ask you
something, Mr Flood?
Barber's privilege.
Did she ever shave you?
I changed my mind.
I don't like you to shave.
I'm sorry.
Who is it?
Jess Torrey, Mr Flood.
Come in.
- Please, Mr Flood, don't-
- Shut up!
What's the trouble?
50 head are missing from
your south range, Mr Flood.
- When?
- Hour or so ago.
I just sent six men
out to track 'em.
You know, it sure don't figure.
Who'd be crazy enough to
run off any of your cattle?
Sure makes a man
wonder, doesn't it?
HICKMAN: I count six.
That's a start.
You make a fine cup
of coffee, Mrs Lang.
Thanks. I've got some
hard tack, too. Like some?
Mmm, yeah!
- Molly.
- Dolan.
Torrey sent six men
after the cattle.
We saw them.
Who did that?
Flood.
It's not important.
It is to me.
Howdy, Ryan.
How are ya?
You're Marshal Hickman.
I heard about you-
Don't say it. Even if you
heard about me from your daddy.
No, sir. I won't.
- Glad you're here, Deputy.
- Ex-deputy.
Talk like that upsets me, son.
A man puts himself down,
sounds to me like an amateur.
Probably fights like one.
Difference between
an amateur and a professional,
professional figures out a way
to cut the odds before he moves.
Now, me and Dolan,
we're professionals,
that's why you
and Ryan here are lucky.
You're about to become the
beneficiaries of our experience.
Right, Dolan?
Right.
One of Marshal Hickman's
shorter leCTures.
I'll fight, Mr Hickman.
How much dynamite you got, Ryan?
Plenty.
Jace, you and Ben hit
the main ranch house.
- Ryan-
- Flood owes me a house.
All right, Ryan.
That leaves you the granary.
I'll take care of the mine.
All right. Let's move.
Hey, Dolan?
What about me?
- You go home.
- Damned, if I will!
But first, douse the fire. I can
smell that coffee for a mile.
Can I get you somethin'
to eat, Mr Flood?
Eh?
- Can I get you-
- No, no, no.
There oughta be some word
on my cattle by now.
I'll go check.
Any word?
No, not yet, Mr Flood.
But I said they'd better not
come back without your cattle...
so I'm sure-
Sounded like dynamite!
That's not far off.
ExaCTly one mile.
Your granary.
That first one
was my ranch house.
What the hell's going on here?
They're workin' me
over in a circle.
Start north with the cattle,
ranch is east, granary south...
so next is west.
The mine.
I want a dozen men
in five minutes. Come on!
Come on!
Listen.
Someone's back!
I told you there was
nothing to worry about.
Probably want a drink.
It's Jace.
You all right, Jace?
Scared, but I'm used to that.
No Dolan?
Nope.
This is gettin'
to look like a wake.
I think I'll
stretch out upstairs.
Doesn't look too good, does it?
He's not worried,
why should we be?
- Got his horse.
- He's there.
There he is.
Dolan! It's hangin' time!
He's trapped.
We'll go down after him.
Suppose Dolan doesn't make it?
He will. Relax.
Yeah, like you?
How come you didn't sleep?
I wasn't tired.
It's Dolan.
We haven't got much time,
it'll be daylight soon.
- Drink up.
- Thanks.
Took you long enough
for a simple job.
Worried about me?
Me? Not a fraCTion.
Mr Hickman? Do you always put
black queens on black kings?
Sure. I cheat.
And win.
Congratulations. All right,
Jace, give me the run down.
11 men left in town,
counting Simms.
Three patrolling,
two at the jail.
This where I check
my gun, gentlemen?
Joe'll take it, pop.
- Are you jokin'?
- Do I look like it?
All right.
Peel 'em off. Hurry up.
...quietly at the bar,
I look over my shoulder-
I just wanna drink.
Some other time.
I don't want another time.
Mister, we got laws-
All right, what's goin' on-
Now, turn around easy.
Very good.
Anytime.
There's no sign of 'em.
They couldn't
have gotten far.
- Yeah. Where's Phillips?
- Well, he's right back-
Phillips?
We're short one man
and one horse.
Let's get back to town.
Wait here. If we don't
come out, you're on your own.
Uh!
He said to wait here.
Try it again.
The set-up's like you said.
Good. Remember, don't move
until you get to 40.
Look who's teaching
me how to suck eggs.
Difference between a
professional and an amateur.
1... 2... 3... 4... 5...
Johnny!
Hey, grandpa! Turn in that gun!
Hey!
This belongs to you.
Thanks.
Go ahead, Sheriff.
Give 'em hell.
Just stay where
you are, all of you.
I got things to say,
and you best listen.
You just got up off the floor
and you're stayin' up.
We been livin'
on our knees long enough.
Damn you! Look at me!
We've been given a chance
to take back our town.
Now, who's gonna stand up
and take that chance?
You figure to start
us off, Miller?
- Count me in.
- Me too.
- I'll go along.
- So will I.
Ryan.
You go to the Ace Deuce
and wait'll it's over.
All right.
Ryan? Can you get a team
and hitch this buckboard?
Sure. Right away.
We're all set.
These men are willing to fight.
Better than I expeCTed.
Sir, I've changed my mind.
I've got think of my family.
- You wanna go home?
- Sure do.
Get.
All right, you two
boys come with me.
You, you, get
in the wagon. Jace?
Get this rig ready
to block the street.
Right.
Get up on that roof.
Take the middle window
in the hardware store.
You all set?
I'll tell you when.
Evening, Mr Flood.
Quiet enough.
Yeah. Let's split up.
Meet you in front of the hotel.
All right, Mr Flood.
Mr Flood! Go back!
It's a trap! Go back!
Yah!
Ben! Get back!
I- I...
I... fought for you...
Hold 'em high!
- Off your horse!
- Step down.
Come on!
Give me that real easy.
Dolan! It's all over!
We're the-
Hyah! Hyah!
Flood!
Dolan...
Don't take less than... 51%.
Hold me
Now and forever
And say that we never will part
My darling, hold me
Always be tender
And I will surrender my heart
Your love is a wondrous thing
Like the sound
of springtime calling
Hold me
End now my sorrows
And make these
tomorrows seem bright
Tell me that you love me tonight