Here we go again.
One day they are going
to hurt each other for reaI.
This time you win.
I won.
That's right, he won.
Now he is your boss.
I'm leaving. This gang,
doesn't make any money.
I'd rather look
for a honest job.
So long, boys!
Now let's see what you do.
Back to schooI, old man.
Don't worry.
Let it go.
SamueI!
Where's the treasure map?
Tell me where it is!
Speak up!
I want my share.
The gold is mine
and I'm keeping it.
I paid you well
for what you did.
And now,
get out of the way.
Speak up.
Give me the map
or I'll kill you, old pig.
Why do you treat
an old man this way?
We are friends, aren't we?
I'll give you a minute to answer.
Where did you hide it?
Hey, you. That's no way
to treat an old cripple.
Thank you, my boy.
I don't even know him,
and he saved my life.
And the rest of you didn't
even lift a finger!
You're just a bunch of drunks.
If I wasn't crippled,
I would have shown him...
Let's tell the Reverend that
Samuel has got a hidden treasure.
Yes, but who's going to make
him tell where it is?
The Reverend could make
the dumb speak.
Let's go.
To your health, my boy.
To your gold.
I don't believe
I've seen you before.
What's your name, stranger?
My name is Roy Colt.
And I'm looking
for an honest job.
I have an honest job for you.
"Dear Winchester,
and Jack as well,
since the gang couldn't get
dishonest enough
to make any money,
I went looking for an honest job.
Yesterday
I punched out a cowboy.
How sad!
I miss our fistfights
very much.
I read about your latest
train robbery in the papers.
I'm sorry you didn't
get anything out of it.
Nowadays, there is nothing
to score with the railroad.
Say hello to everybody for me.
So long.
Signed, your friend, Roy. "
He's getting to be
pretty funny.
But I wonder what he means,
by "an honest job. "
Hey, Jack!
Someone's coming.
Put out the fire.
Let's go.
Hey, what's up with you?
Let us go by.
Who is that Indian woman?
None of your business, stranger.
I asked you a question.
We're taking her to the sheriff.
She killed her man.
What do you care?
Are you the dead man's relatives?
No, but we want
the reward.
Turn your horses around
and get going.
We'll meet again, stranger.
Aren't you going to thank me?
Tell me.
Is it true
that you killed your man?
Come on.
Hold this.
Clean up around.
Hey, boys,
what are you looking at?
Come on, start working.
Get going.
And now...
You know what's next,
don't you?
You have to get along,
otherwise I lose face
with those guys.
Yes, I'll do it.
But for that,
I know a more comfortable place.
Come on, will you?
You know, this is
a nice little place here.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Is it yours?
- No.
An old lady from the tribe
loaned it to me.
It was kind of her,
don't you think?
So, you kind of took advantage.
Can I do the same?
We'll see.
Why not?
- Now, take off your clothes.
- Just a minute, you go first.
- Go ahead, don't act so shy.
- All right.
But don't look, okay?
Okay.
Did you really kill a man?
- Don't look!
- Well, he tried to kill me first.
I just defended myself.
I don't even know your name.
What is it?
Manila.
Can I turn around?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Now it's your turn.
Are you out of your mind?
Now, go downstairs.
All right, but watch out...
that thing's loaded.
I'm... I'm going.
I'm going down.
Watch out.
That really puts holes in you.
Be quiet and keep moving.
Who said something?
I didn't say anything.
Get in there.
Where?
Me, in there?
Are you insane?
Go on, get in and wash up.
Why should I wash up?
No, I'd rather forget
the whole thing.
Certainly not.
Get in the tub!
What are you doing?
Taking a bath in your underwear?
Take them off, before you get
the water all dirty.
Come on, stop wasting time.
You're embarrassed?
I'm not a man.
Stay down!
It's freezing, damn it!
Rub yourself good,
it'll warm you up.
Oh, yeah.
Damn! Why did I have
to get with this woman?
I'm going to make you pay for this!
You'll see.
- And use the soap.
- Yeah, the soap.
Where's the damn soap?
It fell in the water.
Look for it.
Soap. Soap.
Where's the damn soap?
Ah, here it is.
Manila.
I'm so clean
that it's disgusting.
So much better.
Well, when do we start?
We'll start
once we are married.
Married?
You don't want
to get married?
Then, it's... $10.
What? $10?
Let's make it $9.
Okay.
I'll make
a speciaI price for you.
- Well, get undressed.
- Undress?
That's another $2.
There you are.
This is the first time I've seen
and Indian girI with a bra.
Why do you wear it?
To get $2 more.
That's all I've left.
You're not a woman,
you're a slot machine.
Do you have a charge
for those too?
Well, of course.
But, what do we do now
that you're out of money?
I'll show you what we do now.
It just isn't fair.
He's having a good time with
the Indian girI while we're freezing.
Well, when you'll become
the boss...
- What's that?
- The "tab. "
The tab?
What's it for?
To keep track
of what's owed to me.
Now, I'm erasing everything,
and opening up a new account.
Ah, there.
If I'm right, you owe me $2.
You give credit?
Well...
since we're at it...
If the stagecoach is on time,
it'll be here any minute now.
Who do you want?
You go,
Bellatreccia.
Choose four men.
Go!
What's going on, a war?
What does it take
to stop a stagecoach?
I only know one man
who shoots like that.
Hey, Roy, come out.
I recognized you.
Hello, Winchester.
What are you doing in there?
I'm working,
what do you think?
I'm taking some gold
to the bank.
Some gold?
Why don't we divvy it up?
Like old times.
No, it's too little.
Besides, I have something
much bigger in mind.
All right,
do as you like.
You killed the driver!
Now I've got to drive too.
Well, didn't you want
an honest job?
Yes, but there are limits.
After you.
- So long, Colt.
- So long, Winchester.
- So long, Bellatreccia.
- Damn you.
See you later, boys!
Who is that?
Someone who'd suit you to a tee.
He's always got money.
So why didn't you rob him?
Because he wouldn't have
given it to me.
Hey, Jack!
The Reverend
and all his gang
are in Karton City.
The Reverend?
We're all going to Karton City.
Hey, blasted cripple!
Get down here!
Let's put an end to this.
Stop it!
Stop shooting!
If you kill him
it'll be a waste of time.
Someone's coming.
- Where's the Reverend?
- In the saloon.
Damn!
This is not whiskey!
It's soda pop.
Bring me something good.
Damn it!
Calm down, boss.
If I'm not calm, how can I
make good dynamite sticks?
Your mother is a slut!
Now, let's try this.
Reverend!
Don't move.
This could give you
a bellyache.
Here.
Take these away.
Why are you after SamueI?
By the Czar of all Russia!
20 gunmen held off
by an old cripple...
it's enough
to eat you inside.
So then,
he won't give it to you?
Give what?
What business is it of yours?
- Not good?
- Not good. It's disgusting.
Damn you!
I'll send you to Siberia.
I'll get him to talk.
But it will cost you half.
Oh, what is it?
What's going on?
Back off, you deviI!
Tell me, SamueI.
Did you like the explosion?
You're a bunch
of spineless cowards.
You're not scaring me.
Go away!
All right.
There are other bombs
placed around your house.
There's also a bomb
at your bank.
In 10 seconds
we light the fuses.
What's my bank
got to do with it?
- The bank, what does it matter?
- It matters.
Okay.
I'm ready to make a deaI.
Faithless bastards!
I'll hold onto this map,
if you don't mind.
I've done some good
things myself
- due to the circumstances...
- Allow me, Reverend.
There you are.
That's much better.
That's really
a good show of trust.
Let's go.
Today is a very important day.
And remember,
if we don't find the gold,
I'll skewer you like a roast.
Go, you wretch!
Manila, where are you?
Don't touch me.
I don't need your help.
What I don't understand,
Reverend,
is what are you going to do
with the gold once you get it.
- Me? I'll take a wife.
- No! Get married?
I'm a romantic.
All right, my friend.
Get your horse. Let's go.
You hear that?
You should follow his example.
All right, boys,
on your horses.
There you go,
deserting the one
who did you good.
I'll stop feeding you.
You're disgusting,
spineless cowards!
You abandoned one
of your fellow citizens
to the hands
of that gang of pigs.
You son of bitches!
You chased away
the mayor,
because he was
a friend of mine.
And now we are without defense
and without leadership.
Mission accomplished.
Good, young man.
How did you get through?
You'll never guess
what happened.
If you'd gotten here sooner...
The bandits
got the map from SamueI.
- Where did they go?
- I don't know.
They went out of town,
to the north.
All right, let me go!
Let me get them.
No, my son, don't.
You must not go alone.
Hold him back.
Don't let him go.
Listen, you can't go
like this, as a common citizen.
We hereby elect you
our sheriff.
We'll give you the star,
and all the able men
in the village.
Citizens, we cannot
allow bandits
to run free over our land.
I'm going to need
at least 50 men...
50 brave men.
50 men who are
ready to die
in a full battle against
the vicious outlaws in this area.
I know I can count
on all of you,
but I want only 50 men.
I know none of you
is fearfuI of dying,
because we are fighting
for a just cause.
I'm proud of all of you.
But it is my duty
to warn you...
that only few
will make it back.
For that reason,
I will select single men.
I don't want
to transform this town...
into a place
of widows in tears.
Excuse my emotion.
The Reverend...
is a bloody-thirsty animaI.
First he tortures his prisoners,
then he blows them up.
And those who can
escape the Reverend,
won't escape
Jack Winchester.
He can kill a man
300 yards away
with only one shot.
Friends,
I know that these things
won't frighten
brave men like...
You're a gusty boy.
You're not afraid at all,
are you?
Yes. It's the same as
the one I gave to those two.
Only there's something
I didn't tell them.
This is the bridge
over Okay Creek.
- I know the area.
- You ride 200 miles to the red rocks.
Take Vulture Canyon
to the ocean, right here.
When you get to the coast,
the treasure is near.
Follow the coast to the left
back inland towards
the Scorching Sands.
But I warn you,
the thirst will be terrible.
At this point,
you'll go in the direction
of the Indian cemetery.
And you'll find the gold there,
in the place I told you before.
You've got to get it back here,
and get rid of those two gangs.
I have faith in you.
It won't be easy, SamueI.
But I know only someone like me
can pull this off.
I'll fight them
with everything I've got.
With God's help.
- I hope so.
- So do I.
You will defend that gold
as if it were yours, won't you?
As though it were mine.
Will you stop
shaking like that?
I'm trying to write.
"My darling Conchita,
soon I'll be very rich.
Don't worry about your husband,
I'll take care of him. "
Oh God!
Here we go again.
- Will you stop shaking?
- Stop shaking?
I have over 100o fever.
Malaria,
the runs, what else,
I don't know.
But you write to my Conchita.
- Grub's ready.
- We'll be right there.
Those guys only think about eating
while I'm dying.
"We will always...
be together... "
It's the same old act.
Good.
"And we will always
be very... happy. "
Tell her of her
beautifuI features.
"Your...
huge mouth. "
BeautifuI.
You should have been a poet.
" And your eyes are brown. "
Say also she's marvelous
without clothes,
you understand?
Oh, I am cold,
like in Siberia.
" And seeing you...
looking at you all beautifuI...
looking at you
and kissing you.
Perfect!
Who can understand women?
How could a boor like you
find a woman that even reads?
No, she can't read.
She's illiterate, like me.
The sister at the Mission
reads the letter to her.
You should see,
she's such a nice nun.
You are lucky.
You have found a house.
A sweet woman.
That will teach you to keep
your hands to yourself, you pig!
- You rotten little...
- Stop it.
Stop it!
That's enough.
Enough! Enough!
My men on one side,
the Reverend's on the other.
Catch it.
- Throw it! Throw it!
- What?
Throw it, or it'll explode!
It's dynamite.
No, not, in my hand!
If there's one thing
I can't stand is a revolution.
Stop it!
That's enough!
Enough!
I'm sorry, my boy.
Let's go.
You go on ahead, eh, Jack?
And you'll follow
10 miles behind.
I still have
half of the map, eh?
Go, go.
Take the woman
and make many
little brats together.
Reverend, don't tell me
you're still cold.
I swam across
the Don River
with the Czar after me.
Cold to the bone.
So cold.
You talk like this because
you have never been in Russia.
Now only dynamite
warms me up.
I learned from
a great friend, Rasputin...
Reverend, someone's coming.
I know who it is.
Let them come.
Roy, come in.
I have recognized you.
Take from behind.
Well, Reverend,
I'm coming with you.
I know everything
about the gold.
Your map is false.
Stop it! Hold it.
Don't shoot him.
He's a friend.
He knows all about
the gold, eh?
Come in, Roy.
Come into my little home.
Very comfortable.
I shake your hand,
you shake mine.
Hey, lend me your ears.
What did you say
of the map?
Why did you say
my map is false?
It's false and there are
too many of us.
First, we need to get rid of Jack.
I don't want to cut it in three.
But Jack is your friend.
He was.
Besides, this is business.
I still have a bullet he gave me,
here in my butt.
I don't want to take a risk
now that I'm retiring.
Does he still have
that terrible Winchester of his?
No, there's absolutely
no danger.
Here's what we have to do.
There is a shortcut.
If what you say is true,
it should be child's play.
But I only have
one half of the map.
I'll tell you something.
If I wanted I could arrest you.
I'm the new sheriff
of Karton City.
I'm the only one
with the reaI map.
I always said you are
one big son of a bitch.
Are you mad at me?
But then,
when we find that gold...
Gold, it's all about the gold.
Ever since you got that map,
that's all you think about.
Meanwhile, it's been days since
we've made a mark on the tab.
Tonight?
Okay.
But as of today
the price is doubled.
If you keep that up,
I'm going to go bankrupt.
Jack...
Jack, will you marry me?
No, never.
Well, all right.
So, that's another 10...
20...
30... and 40.
My tab.
Bring it back.
Jack.
You have a visitor.
Roy!
Son of a gun,
where are you coming from?
What are you doing
in these parts?
You have room
for me too?
- In the gang?
- No, in the sleeping bag.
Stay inside.
Greetings from the Reverend.
We spoke yesterday,
and we're partners again.
I know all about the treasure.
- You, too?
- Down, girI.
You know about the treasure?
I showed the Reverend
a shortcut,
so that he can beat you.
Thanks a lot, partner.
By comparison,
Cain was an angeI.
As usuaI,
you understood nothing.
There, there's
a narrow passage.
There...
you could give them
a nice welcome.
Should I ambush him?
You're an outlaw,
aren't you?
Look, I just want
to know one thing.
Whose side are you on?
Well, on the side
of the law, of course.
After all,
I've been appointed sheriff.
You know,
sometimes you scare me.
You know...
sometimes I scare myself.
Damn!
We've been betrayed!
We're surrounded.
So...
what's the score?
11-0 for now.
As long as they shoot horses
and not men, it will never end.
Why aren't you fighting?
What kind of man are you?
Well, I'll show you.
Are you one who pays?
I've been paying all my life.
But never for love.
I'll be damned.
Everything all right, Jack?
Well? Where's the reverend?
He got away
with some of his men.
We are going to have problems,
you'll see.
You need Roy Colt,
but he doesn't need you.
- Don't be stupid.
- You'll see.
As soon as we get there,
he'll take both gold and woman.
Why don't you talk?
Jack won't let you?
If I were you, I wouldn't
waste time with that idiot.
You need a reaI man.
A man...
a man like me.
Reverend!
They're almost here.
- Please go back.
- They're coming.
- Boss, don't you understand?
- Just wait!
- Wait for what?
- One minute.
Either you're freezing
to death or you're...
Go! Go! Go!
But you don't pay.
I can't pay.
It wouldn't be right.
I love you.
Oh, then you'll marry me.
Four.
One by one,
they'll be all dead.
- Let's go.
- Wait.
But they need our help.
No, they'll take of themselves.
Where's Roy?
I want to kill that guy.
That one you don't touch.
He knows the way.
When we get to the gold,
he will get his share.
- His share?
- Of bullet, imbecile!
Retreat!
It was a really good idea you had.
That rotten bastard
will kill us one by one,
if we can't get out of here.
So what?
There'll be less to share with.
Then why
don't you kill me too?
Kill you?
That's not such a bad idea.
It's crossed my mind.
Stop!
Don't move.
- No.
- Bastard.
Stay still.
The Reverend is getting
to be too dangerous.
We'll never get rid of him.
We need to do something.
We'll head south.
It's the long way around.
That's right. The Reverend will
expect us to take the shortcut,
but we'll be on the longer route.
And we'll go through Wimpy City.
Wimpy City...
Wimpy City!
Come on, speed it up.
The customers want to have fun.
Hi! How are you?
Come on, dance.
Everybody have a good time.
Leave that alone.
Pay up first.
Mammola,
these two have not paid.
Mammola, how am I supposed
to deaI with them?
All right, ladies, we're here!
Ah! Mammola, sweetheart!
Hi, boys, it's nice to see you.
No, no, come on now.
Stop it.
Move out of the way,
we're going to dance.
- Hey, beautifuI!
- Boys...
Treat those girls
like ladies.
Come here.
You know the house rules.
You are always the most
beautifuI flower
in the garden
of this house, Mammola.
If you don't behave
I will throw you out. Understood?
- Drink some.
- No, I don't want to drink.
And now,
let's have those guns.
This is a respectable house
and they're not allowed.
And you, too.
Go on, take it off
and hand it over.
There, keep them.
Look, he's a sheriff.
Yeah, it makes me laugh
just to think about it.
- Yeah, me too.
- You damn well ought to.
Oh, how beautifuI.
Someone has made money!
Spurs of silver...
I know them
when I see them.
Now, first some money
and then some fun.
I thought Mammola loved me.
Well, all right, Mammola.
Let me see,
let's see where I put the money.
Here you are, see?
Here you are.
I'm not selfish, you know.
It is Lincoln's portrait
that gets me excited.
Is that so?
No, no no. Give that back,
you mean...
Bad boys.
Are these
all of your girls?
I have two Irish girls.
- Two Irish girls?
- Irish? My goodness.
But they are too delicate
for the likes of you.
- Where are they?
- In there.
Boys, now remember,
be good and wait your turn.
This is a respectable place, eh?
Yes, of course.
- See you afterwards.
- Yes, later on, Mammola.
Have a nice time!
I can't stand it another second.
That guy's never coming out!
Oh, good.
- So can we go inside?
- He paid.
I've been here two hours.
He has paid
and he is full of energy.
- This isn't fair.
- He got in two hours ago.
When are we going
to get in?
- Tomorrow morning?
- Just a minute.
He's a sheriff.
He has the badge.
- I'm the sheriff.
- I don't give a damn.
No offense meant,
of course.
Well, no offense,
you don't care. Jack, come on.
Hey, stop that.
Stop.
He has the right to stay there.
$2 each 15 minutes
he can stay there as much as he wants.
Stop!
I said stop!
First like this,
and then like this.
Is another 15 minutes up, pimp?
I'll pay more for the girls.
The dirty old man.
You two again?
Ambush in the warehouse!
I can't believe this!
I paid for two Irish girls,
not for you two!
- Boida!
- Yes, boss?
- Kill them!
- With pleasure!
One, two, three...
Charge!
Can't you do right?
Take that.
I'll break your heads!
Charge again!
And here it comes...
BeautifuI!
It's going down and up!
Did you like the trick?
You wouldn't... You wouldn't!
One, two, three...
What a bad day.
What the hell is going on here?
Even in the Great Russia,
this would have never happened to me.
I paid!
I wanted women not cow-boys.
Let me go!
No, not in underwear!
This is scandalous!
This is a respectable
establishment.
Get that man.
- Would you like a rose?
- I don't want roses!
Out!
All of you! Out!
It's an order!
They have never
seen a woman!
Take this.
I'm coming!
I'm coming! I'm coming!
Why are you ruining my party?
I'm going to stuff your hat
down your throat.
That's what I'm going to do.
Hey, hey.
Let me through,
get out of my way!
Stop it!
No!
No, not the picture,
not the picture.
Hermaphrodite.
Turn around, gorgeous.
A transvestite.
You've ruined everything!
No!
Stop it!
Stop it! Let me through!
I'm coming.
What do you want?
You ugly, I hate you!
I can't stand you.
Ladies, here I come!
All for you!
- Go away, Reverend.
- What is this? BetrayaI!
All right,
where are they?
Stand aside, let me through!
You pigs!
You, go away.
- Mammola!
- I'll show all of you!
After you.
Fools rush in,
but this Russian is no fooI.
Back to old Siberia,
where it is better for this boy.
Let me through!
So this is where you went.
So this was the secret
of last night.
You two bastards!
Spending your money
on these women
instead of saving it for me.
Disgusting.
I've been waiting.
Is it true
what you told me yesterday?
What was that?
That you love me.
More than my horse.
Jack told me that
you have a lot of money.
If I don't kill you,
will you marry me?
Hey!
Don't you know
that's Jack's woman?
- And so?
- And so you don't touch her.
I always hated you,
Roy Colt.
It is my time now.
Don't move!
Commend your souI
to the deviI,
I'm going to shoot you.
Bellatreccia!
Fire! Fire the cannon!
That will teach you!
What's this,
a dynamite factory?
Get down!
- Are you wounded?
- No.
- How many are left?
- Just us.
Give me your gun.
Go to the horses.
Oh, my hat.
I'll cover you.
Get going.
Retreat! Retreat!
Restroom break!
Take off your holster, now.
What do you mean?
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
With the other hand.
Satisfied, boss?
Now, get going.
You can't
send him away unarmed.
The Reverend is nearby.
In that case,
we'd hear the shots.
So long.
And let the vultures get you
and the Reverend.
I always knew you were
a damn bastard,
but I never thought
you'd end up like this...
for a woman.
You, go with him.
She won't come.
You've got the rifle...
you're the strongest.
Here.
- Stop it, Roy!
- Put the gun down!
So?
Whom are you going with?
With the strongest,
of course.
I think the shots
came from there.
Let's go, Morella,
let's go.
Stop!
Three less men.
I'm delighted.
Let's make sure.
Calm down, calm down.
You always want to shoot.
I need to think.
You see,
the noise distracts me.
Good, Morella, good.
Freezing...
the desert.
Son of a bitch.
Son of a tramp.
Son of a slut.
Don't move, traitor.
Now I'll show you.
You're going to tell me
where you're hiding the map!
Because if you don't,
I'll kill you!
Is that clear?
You deceiver.
One minute, wait.
I'm going to hurt you.
- Leave him alone.
- Stop it, woman!
Let me work.
I want him to talk.
Want more?
Now, tell me where the map is.
I ate it.
You ate it?
I'll give you a laxative
and you'll shit that map.
I already did.
- Where?
- In the desert.
Then, I'm going to kill you!
Damn you!
- Reverend, no. Stop it!
- Get away from me, woman.
He knows how to find the gold
even without the map.
Walk, walk, a nice morning walk
is good for your health.
Walk!
Stop.
Don't you see,
she can't go on?
If you don't put her
on a horse...
I won't show you
where the gold is.
Never, not even if you kill me.
Courtiers of the Czar
are always very kind
towards women.
Little lady.
You know, you're
a beautifuI man up close.
You don't say.
With a wonderfuI,
rugged masculine perfume.
You don't say.
Where will be camping tonight?
I am not saying.
You like women, don't you?
If it hadn't been for women,
I would have been
Pope of all of Russia.
20 years in the seminary,
I'm very devoted.
And devoted to women,
of course.
That means you like me,
doesn't it?
Very much.
Then, you'd marry me?
In Russia,
we always marry first, then...
Down to the end,
then we have to turn left.
I hope for your sake
it's true.
If you don't bring me my gold,
I'll smash that pretty face of yours.
You must not lie
to a man of the cloth.
I'll kill...
What is this?
This wooden banana
around your neck?
I too am very devout.
This is my totem.
Each scratch is a prayer.
I see.
You pray a lot,
very devout.
I'm not giving you
the treasure.
I drink, but for you,
I'll only wet your pants.
Hey, what are you doing
wasting the water?
For us,
there's always water,
but none for this traitor.
Now, come with me,
woman called Horse.
Come with your master.
Walk, good. Come on.
Walk slowly, like this.
With delicacy.
Here you go.
Now relax.
If you're good,
I give you a sip of water.
Here you go.
Just a sip...
Just a little sip.
Just a little.
There. Enough!
Too much water
is not good for you.
is bad at night.
Now we sleep
like sweethearts.
There. Good.
Enough of this touching.
Sleep.
What is it, Manila?
You're finding
any excuse to kiss me.
Damn!
It's raining! It's raining!
Everybody take cover!
Oh, accursed woman.
You betrayed me!
Come here.
I gave you everything, water...
and this is the way
you treat me.
When the sun shines
in the left eye of the skull
with the gold colored band,
wait untiI it is exactly 2:00.
If your watch isn't right,
we could end up many yards off.
Don't you worry!
I stole this watch
from the astronomicaI observatory
- In Peters... burg.
- So much the better.
I don't want to be blamed
if you dig in the wrong place.
Now, turn the skull
60o to the right.
10 and five...
10 and seven...
10... 10...
10... 15...
20...
Mama, it is Death!
It's only me.
Boida!
It's always you.
- Everywhere I turn. Shit!
- Reverend!
If you're finished
playing games, I'll continue.
Excuse me. Just a few words
among the dead, you understand?
Have you got the stick?
Yes, I've the stick, see?
Good, stick it through
the left eye in the skull.
Wait, one moment.
Don't you move,
bad woman,
the dead are watching you.
Now measure six lengths
with your hand, after the skull.
One... two...
three... four...
Boida, get out of the way.
- The place is here!
- Dig.
Dig! One moment.
One moment.
I'll break the ground.
Reverend, there's
nothing down here.
If there is no gold,
I'll put out your eyes.
Do I look like a traitor?
Do you think it's funny
for me to sit here,
and watch you guys work?
I hope you're telling the truth.
Reverend!
There's something here!
It's gold!
Throw it up here!
Throw it to me!
- Gold, Reverend!
- My gold!
My gold!
Throw it! Throw it!
Ah, the smell of gold!
Gold.
My gold.
Come on boys,
load up the wagon.
We're done here, Reverend.
Well,
do we get moving or not?
Let's go Reverend!
Come here, Boida!
My gold fell down
in the hole.
I have lost a thousand
down there.
I'm ruined! Poor Reverend.
Go down there.
Good. Get the gold
for the Reverend.
Here, catch.
You give me the gold,
and I'll give you a push, like this.
Say hello do Boida.
- Reverend, what the hell are you doing?
- I pull up the rope...
Reverend!
We're all friends!
...and I throw you a stick.
Everyone's dead, but you!
And now it's your turn.
No, just a minute.
Woman, woman, where are you?
Take shelter now.
Now I'll create the biggest
explosion in history!
Look out! It's going off.
It's the end of the world!
I thought we were partners!
Not anymore.
The association is dissolved.
I'm breaking it up
with this dynamite stick.
If you come across Boida,
give him my regards.
And now, count one...
and count two...
Oh, no.
BetrayaI!
Who is shooting my gold?
My gold. You beautifuI thing.
I'll pick you up.
My gold is spilled,
all mixed up with the dirt.
Damned you.
Traitors!
Traitors.
In hell you will be
as warm as you want.
Amen.
We meet again.
Now what do you think
of your old friend Jack, huh?
If I hadn't gotten here in time,
the Reverend would've
blown you to a million pieces.
I'm not sure.
Come to think of it,
you should thank me.
Why?
The gang has been destroyed,
the wagon is loaded with gold,
and it's just standing there.
I know the Reverend was going
to kill me with the dynamite,
but I figured to give it back to him.
How could you do that?
You're all tied up like a salami.
With my hands, that's how!
You think the spurs
are only good on horses?
Hey!
You found my hat!
Thanks.
Oh, no.
Not the hat.
The hat, no.
The gold we'll split,
but I found the hat and I'm keeping it.
Hat thief.
Give it back, right away.
- Did you call me, "hat thief?"
- Yes.
It's mine!
No, mine!
Enough!
Stop. Stay where you are
or I'll kill you.
Stop, I said.
Did you think an Indian wouldn't
know how to feign ignorance?
This gold is mine.
You know how hard I worked for it.
Take this,
as a souvenir.
You can use it
when you are lonely.
Here, you can keep it.
No, I'll take the hat.
If it hadn't been
for that Indian of yours...
My Indian?
That was your Indian!
Your Indian!
She was yours!
DVD subrip by:
Tantico (Croatia)