Ain't that Traveller?
I said, ain't that Lee's horse?
- Yes.
What's Lee doing here?
He's surrendering to Grant.
Lead looks close to the heart.
That's the first Yankee
I've missed in 4 years.
Bet it's because the bullet's warped.
Why didn't you cut it out yourself?
- I didn't want to dirty my hands!
Why didn't you leave him
to bleed to death?
There's General Lee.
He's still got his sword.
Grant must have let him keep it.
- Maybe he wouldn't give it up!
We lost the war, soldier.
Lee has struck his last tent.
So there he is, the great and
glorious General Grant.
If you're gonna shoot Grant,
you'd better shoot Lee too,
else the shame'll kill him.
Just like I said.
Like I said from the beginning,
the bullet's warped, warped.
It's the last bullet
shot in this war.
# I'm an old rebel soldier
# And that's just what I am
# And for this Yankee nation
# I do not give a damn
# I hate the starry banner
# It's stained with Southern blood
# And I hate the poisoned Yankees
# And I fought 'em all I could
# I hate the Yankee nation
# And the uniform of blue
# I hate the constitution
# Of this great republic too
# I hate the mighty gold
# With all its brass and fuss
# Oh, those evil, lying Yankees
# I hate 'em worse and worse
# I can't take up my musket
# And fight 'em any more
# But I ain't gonna love 'em
# And that is mighty sure
# And I don't want no pardon
# For what I've done around
# And I won't be reconstructed
# And I do not give a damn! #
Let me get out of this thing.
Thank you.
Well, he went and done it.
General Lee got right down
on his hands and knees
and begged President Johnson
for pardon.
But if it's good enough for them,
I reckon it's good enough for me.
He never begged.
He never begged?
I wish you was right.
What makes you so sure?
When I went back to town to get that
bullet, I heard it official
that
he swallowed his pride and begged.
What bullet?
The bullet you had
cut out of that Yankee Lieutenant
you shot
the last day of the war.
How'd you get this?
- Your ma gave it to us.
Why?
- Well...
...look at that.
That ain't the bullet. That's new.
- All but the head. It's been fixed.
There's writing on it.
Writing? What kind of writing?
- It says...
"Private O'Meara,
Sixth Virginia Volunteers,
"who shot this last bullet
in war...
"...and missed!"
It's a little token.
It's a little token from us to you.
But the best news...
the best news was when your ma said
that you'd come home in one piece.
Best news I got was when Lincoln
was dead. What's the matter, Mama?
A man shows respect even for
a dead, damn-Yankee President.
Lost your reason?
The baboon was shot too late.
The bullet that killed him may prove
worse for us than for the North.
You sound sick in the head.
He said he'd take us back in the Union.
Who cares about the Union?
- Lots of us do, son.
I know it's a shame to take
the Oath of Allegiance to
become Americans again...
Jeff Davis is in jail.
Lee's begging in the mud. A fine
way to take us back into the Union.
No man's beaten without some hatred.
And I hate, Mama.
I hate!
I don't understand you, Ma.
Pa was killed at Chickamauga.
Jed had his head cut off
at Fredericksburg.
Eli. Eli lay with his belly
in his hand,
bleeding to death
in the wheat fields of Gettysburg.
Mama, I know. I seen them.
I seen their skin and blood
and I buried them.
I had to bury 'em, Mama.
I buried 'em, you didn't.
What am I supposed to say now
to the Yankees?
"Welcome home, sir?
"I love you Yankees?!"
How did you... how did you
expect me to come home?
I expected you to come home
a man with honour.
A man with honour?
You expected me to come home
with honour?!
What's the matter with you?
What's the matter with all of you?
They came and took our land!
They chased us when we had no legs!
They stuffed their mouths with our
food when we were starving to death.
Where's your pride?!
What's happened to all of you?
We had to take a lickin' and not cry.
You don't have to fight
for the cause no more.
Mama, I don't have to do anything.
I don't have to do anything.
I am a rebel because I want to be,
not because I have to be.
Wherever you go,
there's gonna be Yankees
and you gotta learn to live with them.
Not the place I'll be.
What place?
- The West. The Far West.
Where the savages live?
Savages or no, they
have more pride than us.
There's no hiding place
for what ails you, son.
We're all under one flag now.
I want to tell you something, Mother.
I'll hang.
I'll hang before I recognise that flag.
Maybe a broken neck is the best
answer for what ails you.
Maybe, Mama.
Maybe!
What a darn fool way
to waste good whisky.
That's fine whisky!
The buzzards was all prepared
to peck your eyes out.
Take it from an old army scout. Any
closer, I'd have bit their heads off.
A Sioux scout for the damn Yankees?
Confederate States of America.
Still fighting the war,
Mr Johnny Sore-Loser?
I want to tell you something.
You'd better get one thing straight, old man.
You may be old, but
you're not ready to be buried yet.
Maybe, but I will be
when I run out of whisky.
I'm carrying a bad heart.
Going home to die.
Where you heading?
- Anywhere.
Now "anywhere" can be with me
until I run dry.
US Cavalry. That's a nice piece
of Yankee horseflesh you got there.
That's right.
Plenty of land out here
in this Sioux country.
Not for the white men.
Maybe they could use an
unemployed Confederate sharpshooter.
That's renegade talk.
My name's O'Meara.
What's yours?
- Walking Coyote.
What outfit? Georgia Cavalry?
No, it's the Virginia
Infantry. Let's get that straight.
Infantry?
- That's right.
Well, what's so funny?
- Only squaws walk.
Get up, boy. Hey!
What was the name of that tune
you just played?
It's a love song.
It's a darling tune,
in spite of the way you played it.
It's for lovin'.
Have you got a squaw?
- No.
You?
Sometimes I feel it might be better
to curl up with a squaw around
a fireplace rather than a saddle.
Well, I wouldn't argue with you
on that point.
Listen, erm... how many tribes
are there in your nation?
We're divided into three divisions.
The Santee, the Yankton
and the Teton.
I'm an Oglala. That's one of the
seven tribes of the Teton Sioux.
Every tribe has a lot of bands.
Every band has a chief.
I could have been a chief.
What's Sioux mean in your language?
It's a French word.
- French word?
Yeah. Our real name is Lakota.
Before scalping was the thing to do,
we used to slit our enemies' throats.
What's that got to do with the French?
- We fought the Chippewa,
and when they tied up
with the French,
they told 'em we were...
Sioux. Sioux means cut-throat.
Why are you so interested in Sioux?
- I don't know.
I'd like to be one.
Why?
- Because.
Because cut-throats
should stick together.
You serious?
- I'm serious.
Nah!
- I'd like to learn your language.
I'd like to learn it to
you, if St Christopher
will keep you in one piece.
You like St Christopher?
- Yeah.
Are you a Christian?
- No. My religion is Yawippe.
Yawippe?
Hey, Yawippe.
That's sort of a denomination?
- Yeah.
You said you could've been a Sioux chief.
That's true.
- Why didn't you?
I can't stomach politics!
Get up, boy.
Let's go now.
What's the horse's head for?
That's so he'll have
his pony to ride when
he gets to the happy hunting ground.
Oh, look!
What's that there?
Another Sioux post office?
- Yeah.
Three more babies born
to the Minneconjou tribe.
You picked up our customs quick.
It's not so difficult, you know.
Wait a minute.
It's the sign of a small party.
8 or 10 riding light.
Sioux ponies.
I don't see a sign of 'em.
When you can't see 'em,
they're looking at you.
Don't touch your gun.
- What, leave myself wide open?
- Don't touch it.
Turn around, slow like,
and keep your mouth shut.
Turn.
That man is no enemy of the Sioux.
- His horse wears the US enemy brand.
Who are you?
- Walking Coyote. One of your tribe.
Walking Coyote.
- Yes.
I've heard about you. A renegade
paid by the whites to kill us.
Me kill a Sioux? I'm a Sioux.
I came home to my tribe.
You have no tribe.
That's up to Blue Buffalo to decide.
He is still your chief?
Yes, but it's up to me to decide.
Me, Crazy Wolf.
We're gonna hang you, old man.
- I demand a hearing!
Drunk and mean, all of 'em,
and painted for trouble.
In my day we showed
a little respect for the aged.
I don't know what the world
is coming to nowadays.
These young bucks run wild,
drink whisky, loot lodges, attack girls.
They look like they're
getting ready to hang you.
You learned our lingo good.
Too good. Otherwise I wouldn't be
sweating out the fact
they're gonna skin me.
You're lucky to be going that way
even though it takes longer dying.
I wish they'd carve me alive.
- What?
In my religion, you don't
get to heaven if you're hanged.
We're faster
than the Run Of The Arrow!
- YO!
- It worked.
They ask for the Run!
Come on.
Why'd they let us go?
- Save your wind.
Put that arrow down!
Even to a renegade and a white,
we do not violate the Run!
What's he mean "violate the Run"?
A man could get skinned alive from
sunset to sunrise if he violated it.
This game is called Run Of The Arrow.
When we get to the spot where
his arrow fell, we start running.
They run after us.
On foot?
- Yeah.
Except they're not barefoot like us.
He fired it quite a way. Maybe
we've got a chance.
That's the idea.
They torture us with the chance
to make an escape.
You can't outrun them.
You're too old.
You ain't.
There's one thing
I gotta tell you, son.
Nobody ever made the Run,
and lived to tell about it.
Now if we can just keep
this distance between them and us,
stay out of bow shot,
we've got a running chance.
But you see what Crazy Wolf
can do with an arrow,
so don't let
him get a bow range on you.
Well... I want to say...
...I think it's a shame that...
Yeah, it's a pity.
Well... just pray to God
and start running!
Have you seen a white man running?
Have you?
Have you seen a white man?
You speak our language
without an accent.
You do not speak Sioux like an American.
I'm not an American.
I was running...
- You must be quiet.
How many guards are there?
No-one knows you are here.
No-one knows but Silent Tongue.
He can't speak.
He was born without voice.
Is that your son?
- No, his people are dead.
You know what it means
to violate the Run?
I know.
I wish... I wish to speak
to your chief, Blue Buffalo.
I'm Blue Buffalo.
I've lived the Run Of The Arrow.
Is this the man who outran you?
Yes.
- You're the first to live the Run.
You'll never die by the hands
of the Sioux. Give back his horse.
You speak like a Sioux, not a white man.
- My teacher was Walking Coyote.
Oh, that poor renegade.
He's sick with the fever.
Our law prevents us from killing
any man who has lived the Run,
but we have no law
to help him live.
The choice is yours. Who among you
will help him through the night?
I will.
I will help him through the night.
They're heading through
the wheat field. Use the rifle.
Pick up his head.
That's my brother!
Lee begged. Lee begged.
Where's Pickett?
Where's Longstreet?
Watch out, Pa!
Bury the bodies, Ma.
If she can keep him in there all night
and steam that fever out of
him, I think then maybe he'll live.
Bury Pa.
And bury Jed.
And bury Eli.
Bury them bodies, Ma.
Is that for me?
Thank you.
What's the matter with him?
Among our people,
when one takes something,
one gives something in return.
Oh.
Blow.
That is the first sound
to ever come from his mouth.
What does it mean - "honeymoon"?
Honeymoon, huh?
- Yeah.
Why are you laughing?
- You wanna know what it means?
- Yes.
Honeymoon?
- Well, honeymoon is, er...
Yeah. Honeymoon
is a white man's word...
Honeymoon is a white man's word
for the...
...for the private passing of time
between two people after
they've been married.
Understand, huh?
- Yes.
He's here.
He wants to become a Sioux,
to take Yellow Moccasin
as his squaw
and to adopt
Silent Tongue as their son.
But his skin is enemy.
- I'm not an American.
But your skin is white.
- But my heart's with the Sioux.
Why?
Because I love your people.
I've learnt from Yellow Moccasin
that a man can't live alone.
He must have allegiance
to a people, to a nation.
In my heart my nation is Sioux.
Would you kill the Americans
in battle?
Yes.
Are there any objections?
Mix the blood.
Before you mix the blood,
I must speak of my faith.
Faith?
- Yes.
- What do you mean?
I'm a Christian.
I will live as a Sioux.
I will hunt as a Sioux.
I will fight.
I will even die as a Sioux.
But my God is a Christian God.
I can't serve your greater spirit.
We respect a man
who respects his faith.
This God of yours, is he the giver
and creator of all life?
Yes.
Do you look to him for the
cure of disease and illness
and to make you strong and healthy?
- I do, yes.
How many Gods do you serve?
Do you have more than one?
- No, no.
Just one.
- Just one.
Americans - are they all Christians?
No, some are. Some are of other
denominations like your religions.
You are a Christian.
Would you kill Christians in battle?
Well...
...My nation fought for liberty
against the United States...
...and Christianity is always
the brother of liberty in all wars.
We have the same god
but with a different name.
Mix the blood.
The things you feel in your hearts
for one another
will mark your
feelings for the rest of your life.
Marriage is the beginning
of life for both of you.
Death is the final parting.
Now you are two bodies in one blood.
So many times I've asked.
Why won't you tell me
what you carry in that?
I'll tell you.
It's a bullet.
It's a bullet that was used
in the war with the white men.
Why do you carry it?
Because it was a trophy
that was given to me
by the people of my village -
a war trophy.
It's got writing on it.
- Writing?
Writing
- like the signs on our tepees.
Wanna hear what it says?
- Yes.
It says, "To Private O'Meara,
Sixth Virginia Volunteers,
who
shot this last bullet in the war...
"...and missed."
Uncover the guidon and flag!
Sound the bugle
and put spit into it!
Lieutenant Driscoll, commanding
B Troop, Second Cavalry,
First
Division, reporting to Col Taylor.
Glad to meet you. Compliments
for being selected for this mission.
Nothing complimentary about wet-nursing engineers
and carpenters.
- Itching for combat?
That's what I'm paid for.
- You're paid to escort
a non-combatant train.
Capt Clark is the boss of that train.
May I ask about the area?
- If we can come to terms with the Sioux,
that area will be designated by
Chief Red Cloud and General Allan.
I thought we had that Indian on
his knees begging for terms.
You've read too many
Eastern newspapers.
B Troop can make that Indian beg.
A young officer at Port Phil Kearny
had the same sickness you've got,
Lieutenant. His name was Fetterman.
He said he could ride through
the Sioux nation with 80 men.
He tried it.
81 men were massacred by the Sioux.
Capt Fetterman was infantry, sir.
It would've been different if he'd
had some cavalry to back him up.
For your information, we're the ones
asking Red Cloud to meet our terms.
See to your men.
- Yes, sir.
We break our backs making
peace with the Indians
and they send us
men like that, scratching for combat.
I guess he's not the only
frustrated Custer in the army.
Like you, General Allan,
we're tired of fighting.
Why can't we come to terms?
Your request?
Permission from Chief Red
Cloud to build Fort Lincoln...
What has the United States
promised your people?
To keep the road open
to the Montana goldfields.
I can't give you permission
to build this fort. - Why?
If I let you build this fort,
you will frighten away our buffalo.
We'll have to eat dogs.
- We do not go through your hunting territory.
And the fort?
It will be built where you and I agree.
- There is one condition.
What's that?
One of my warriors must
scout for your people.
We already have 3 Indian scouts.
But they're not Sioux.
They're Delaware, Kiowa, Kwahadi
Comanche, but they're not Sioux.
Then you don't trust them, eh?
- No.
My warrior knows the country.
He knows where our buffalo is.
He speaks your language
like a white man,
and he is not like your Indian scouts.
What's most important - he's a Sioux.
This is the scout I've selected.
He'll be my voice on the expedition.
He has no love for the Americans,
but his word is the word of a Sioux.
Every officer, soldier and civilian
will obey his instructions as to
trails to follow, where to camp,
and where to build the fort.
General Allan speaks for the
President. You have heard his words.
Glad to have you scout
for the American Govt.
I scout for the Sioux.
It's the first time I
ever met an Irish Indian.
ever met a Yankee General.
This is Captain Clark, army engineers.
He'll be in command.
Lieutenant Driscoll, commanding B
Troop, will escort the expedition.
There's a wire cut on this hock joint.
I treated that cut
myself. This is my horse.
I know.
- What?
- I took him from you.
You took him from me?
- That's right.
I'm the Johnny Reb that fired the
last bullet of the war right there.
Was there any trouble?
- No. No, there was no trouble.
Red Cloud agreed to build a fort.
I think he's making a big mistake.
I've got to go scout with them.
Make sure they stay
out of our meat country.
Will there be many soldiers?
- No, it's a peaceful expedition.
Then we don't have to be
left behind in the village.
I don't think so.
You know what a bad cook I am!
Is something wrong
between you and that man?
- Yes.
Do you know him from the war?
- Yeah.
I shot him with that bullet.
Does he know it was you
who shot him? - Yes.
When you wounded him,
why did you bring him
to your medicine man to be healed?
I don't know.
A Sioux wouldn't save an enemy.
- Well, you saved me, didn't you?
I didn't try to kill you.
- That's right.
Wheeler got hit.
- What's that?
Wheeler's hit.
Arrow in his back.
He was killed inside the corridor.
- That's right.
What report do I send back now?
That this is an arrow belongs
to an Indian named Crazy Wolf.
Is he a Sioux?
- Yes, yes, he's a Sioux.
And he's a renegade.
Red Cloud didn't waste any time.
Crazy Wolf was acting on his own.
Why?
- He doesn't trust the white man.
Do you?
- I just don't trust Yankees, that's all.
We haven't broken our word.
I'm here to see that you don't.
- I'm gonna run down Red Cloud...
He had nothing to do with it..
- I'll go along with that.
How can you take the word of this Reb?!
String him up, and his squaw.
I'll tell you when to hang a man.
Do we go after them?
- No, we don't.
I came up from the ranks, Captain.
I had respect for West Point.
I didn't know they turned out
officers to be Indian lovers.
You trust Red Cloud, don't you?
- Yeah.
More important right now, I trust you.
Come on.
We've still got a fort to build.
All right, look now.
We'll bivouac here.
And stay away from the quicksand
there. Quicksand right there.
I don't understand Driscoll.
Putting cowpokes in B Troop.
Nothing cavalry about them.
They don't ride cavalry like us.
Driscoll wants fighters.
- He's got 'em.
- Yes, he has.
I wish that kid would stop
playing that mouth-organ.
Let's get some grub.
Take it easy, boy.
Take it easy.
Give me your hand, boy.
Come on. Give me your hand.
Wait a minute, Corporal.
- Yes, sir.
I don't care why they
made it this way.
It's a medieval torture rack.
My stern can't stand it one more day.
You see that?
- Yes, sir.
The McClellan saddle
favours the animal.
We in the cavalry...
I don't care about the
cavalry! Just fill up that hole.
Put something in it!
See what you can do to make it
a little friendly, Corporal.
Yes, sir.
Horses.
How's the boy, all right?
- He's fine, fine.
About the Sergeant, sir... I'd like
to say something about that, sir.
I'm sorry I didn't...
I guess there's just some
things I don't quite understand.
Well, Yankees are human.
You're not the only Johnny Reb
fighting a one-man war against
the United States, you know.
Some of them went down to
South America. - I know, sir.
Why didn't you?
I guess because I consider this country
not being part of the United States.
Not now, but it will be pretty soon.
What was your outfit? Sixth...?
- Sixth Virginia Infantry.
- Infantry!
I don't have to tell you how
to fight a war,
but it's why there's
fighting. That's what's important.
Think we were wrong?
Blood and kin and home are
worth fighting for,
but no man
can put that above his country...
You don't understand, sir. We had
a right to fight for our rights.
Lincoln had to keep the Union together.
- No, Union be damned.
You Northerners don't understand.
We don't like you making up laws.
We never liked it. Telling us what
to do and think, who to live with.
We'll fight it. We may
go down fighting,
but we'll go down like
a free, white, Christian country.
Free, white and Christian, huh?
Burning crosses and hiding
under pillow-cases
and terrorising families,
free, white and Christian?
- I don't know anything about that, sir.
Oh, yeah, it's always
the other fella.
Captain, I'd like you
to understand something.
No matter what you believe,
no matter how good you think it
is, you'll never make the South...
Nobody's asking you
to be a Fourth Of July patriot,
but living like an Indian,
fighting your own people,
that's not gonna cure you.
Cure me of what?
- Hate.
Blind hate.
You ever hear that old story
about Philip Nolan?
No, sir, I never did.
Well, Philip Nolan was a officer
in the American army back
in... 1807, something like that.
He got himself mixed up with Aaron
Burr. You know Burr, the traitor?
Yeah, we read books in the South.
Anyway, he was like you.
Hated all the Americans...
for some reason or other.
So one day he upped and said,
"Damn the United States.
"I wish I may never hear
of the United States again."
And he got his wish.
They hang him?
- No, it was worse.
They kept him alive
on an American ship. 55 years.
55 years. He was known
as the man without a country.
Never saw his country again.
Died at sea.
What do you think of that?
I don't know, sir.
I'm a Reb.
And I'll die a Reb, even if
the North considers Lee's
surrender the death of the South.
Let's get one thing straight -
Lee's surrender was NOT
the death of the South,
it was the birth
of the United States.
What's the matter? Something wrong?
There's nothing wrong. Whoa, boy.
This is as far as I go, that's all.
- I guess we'd better get to work.
Stockwell.
- Yes, sir?
We build here.
- Yes, sir.
You're not serious?
What's that?
- Not gonna pitch that fort here?
This is the site they agreed on.
- 'Fraid of losing your bars?
Meaning what?
If I was running this picnic, I'd
high-tail a courier back to Taylor
and tell him this area stinks.
You're not running this
picnic, so you'll take
orders or clean up after the mules.
Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Order your troop to be at the
disposal of the engineers.
That all?
No, stagger your men so some of 'em
hit the grub pile while the rest work.
Is that all, sir?
- That's all.
Excuse me, sir. I think we're
about ready to pull out now.
Oh, well...
I won't say thanks.
You don't have to say thanks.
Nobody's obliged anybody, sir.
What are you gonna do now?
Go back to your Sioux village?
That's right.
Remember Nolan?
Yes, I don't think it
hurts me the way it hurt him.
For your sake, I hope it doesn't.
Thank you.
You got plenty of grub?
- Yes, we'll manage nicely, sir.
- Good.
Well...
- Thank you, sir.
The wood train's been attacked.
Six civilians and three troopers
killed. They took Private Dean alive.
The smoke signals that Reb sent to
his brass didn't stop any sniping.
Can you read smoke signals?
You're playing into their hands.
Don't use me to start a war.
Don't move. Don't move.
- Well, what are you waiting for?
Take your moccasins off.
Come on.
Take them off. Take them off.
You violated the Run.
- What do you mean?
I gave him a chance
to run for his life.
A disgrace to our nation. He killed
Americans inside the corridor.
Are they building the fort?
- Yes.
I'm assuming full responsibility
for the change of area.
If you pitch your posts here, every
detail will be ambushed.
You wanna
build your fort or your grave?
I'll give you five minutes
to make up your mind.
There's nothing out in front, sir.
It's all clear.
Tell them to push forward
another five miles.
- Yes, sir.
Let's go!
I understand why Driscoll broke the pact
but I don't know why the others agreed.
It was always their plan!
- What plan?
To drive our buffalo away
and starve us to death!
You think that killing them
will solve everything?
At least it'll serve as a warning
to all the others.
And you? What do you think?
Would you kill the Americans
if we should go into battle?
Well, they're in our meat country.
They've gotta be stopped.
- Yes, but would you kill them?
I'm a Sioux.
- Are you?
I demand to lead
the first attack against them.
You are a man of two countries,
but you can't kill Americans.
If you kill or do not kill, you will
always be unhappy as a Sioux.
A man must choose to live
with his conscience.
In my heart you were never a Sioux.
To all of us you were never a Sioux.
I was accepted as one.
- But never tested as one.
You were born an American
and what you were born you will die.
I'll die a Sioux.
You'll never get Captain's bars
looking for a scrap.
Never get 'em dodging one.
They must've had a good reason
for holding you down to one bar.
I should have my own
regiment by this time.
The brass don't agree with me.
After this little picnic explodes,
I'll put myself in for Captain.
Three sides natural protection.
Rear and flanks impossible to hit.
One way to attack and we'll cover
that so well a division of Sioux...
It's outside the corridor.
Perfect observation.
Look at that field of fire.
We passed water and timber
you could spit at.
What happens when Taylor hears?
- No, I'll come up fine in this.
You know why?
Because what I'm doing is right.
Find your best defensive position,
keep your troops in one fat piece.
That's how this site'll pay off.
That Johnny Reb's coming back again.
Is he alone?
- Yes, sir.
Corporal.
You've got five minutes
to surrender Fort Lincoln
to the Sioux nation.
Hey, Trent, you see any Sioux?
- No, sir.
My look-out sees nothing.
When you can't see 'em,
that's when you're looking at 'em.
You got brass for a Johnny Reb.
- I'm speaking for the Sioux.
What happens if we surrender?
- You'll be escorted to Col Taylor.
Maybe you want my
trumpeter to play "Dixie"!
This ain't Appomattox.
Four minutes to strike your flag.
I never strike my flag
for an enemy, or a rebel.
Now put that in your peace pipe
and smoke it.
Grow up, man and stop playing soldier!
Give your men a chance
to save their scalps!
I'll give you the same chance
Grant gave Lee.
You've got 60 seconds
to ride out of rifle range.
There's two men you can listen to.
One is me
and the other is Driscoll.
You listen to me and I say move out
now if you want to save your scalp.
Listen to Driscoll and we'll have
your scalps in our belts by tomorrow.
He came under a flag of truce.
Hang him.
- For what?
- For treason.
The left rear of the outpost is dead!
Cover it!
Judson, give me a hand!
For violating the Run,
I saved your life for this ceremony.
A Sioux can watch
an American skinned alive.
An American cannot watch.
They had a right, but not like that.
Someone had to be an executioner.
"They"?
You said, "they."
You didn't say "we"
had a right to his life.
This is your flag.
- It's not my flag.
Is your tribe in this flag? Is it?
Yes.
Then it's your flag.
"Lee's surrender was not
the death of the South.
It was the birth
of the United States."