You better put on that lamp, too.
$100,000.
You can believe me...
the bank at Daugherty never had
that much cash in its safe at any point.
- Don't worry about it.
- Good night.
- You and Ed, you stay inside.
- All right.
Take it easy, Bill.
Hey, Stafford...
send two guards to the back
and put two on Main Street.
- And make it fast.
- Okay.
Close the door.
You enjoy sitting up there and
I'm like a piece of crap in the road?
Scrawny Alley Cat.
Speak right up. I dare you.
Big noise sitting there, aren't you?
And I, Carrincha, I say the Holy Virgin
and all the saints...
they know the truth.
That at the Battle of Richmond that
took nine days, I killed how many?
What's the difference? At least 20.
And what do you want?
Don't you believe what I say?
I was a trumpeter in the Seventh Regiment,
that's who.
I could blow up an elephant
with the breath in my body.
But the regiment took my trumpet from me,
I don't know why.
Like my bottle of whiskey.
That Alley Cat up there
thinks they were right.
And all I have left...
was my medal, which I thought was enough
to buy me a bottle.
But they said it was no good.
What are they good for, medals?
In war, they're all compañeros...
then when they get home,
they aren't worth a damn.
Not you, though.
You're a man who knows?
How are you?
Now, watch.
Seven again.
Let's go.
You know what to do. Hurry.
Evening.
Get him out of here.
Stafford.
Stafford, Sergeant, where are you?
Milt! Jones!
- Hey, Ed, can you see the others?
- No, not from here.
- Another seven.
- Seven.
Nichols, didn't you lose enough?
Forget it, Nichols, don't bet that.
Make up your mind.
This isn't worth anything.
That's a different thing...
I'll buy it from you
as long as you throw her in, too.
That's a good watch.
I paid a lot of money for it.
Okay.
Sit down.
Sit down and eat.
Your dice are loaded.
Try those.
He told you to eat, didn't he?
Quiet.
- Don't you like music with your supper?
- Just don't try it again.
I'm sorry.
Five.
It's your turn, stranger.
You show them, hey, boss?
That's it.
Seven.
- You won.
- Thank you.
He's a friend of mine.
And he's generous, too.
No one can beat him to the draw
with dice or with pistols.
At Cuenca one night...
you couldn't see
your hand in front of your face...
- and he got 20 men in ten seconds.
- Liar.
There is nothing to laugh at.
- You're always talking big.
- I'm telling the truth.
Maybe there weren't 20 of them,
but there were at least ten.
If you couldn't see,
how could you count them?
Alley Cat could. He can see in the dark.
Okay...
we did a good job for you, Ferguson.
The wagon's gone already.
The bank...
they killed them...
everybody.
The safe...
they took it away.
Get the doctor here right away.
Stand down. Stand down!
Come on, move it.
Calm down.
You can't get in here,
now stand back, everybody.
It's impossible until the sheriff gets here.
They did a thorough job.
- Professionals, for sure.
- No doubt about it.
What did you expect them to take?
Small change lying around outside the safe?
I know, but where does that leave all of us?
Get back, all of you.
What is it?
They took the safe. Come in here.
I didn't hear a thing when it happened.
Oh, come on, Jane. Let's take a walk.
You never give a damn about anything,
do you?
And I chose you out of the crowd.
Now, don't take it to heart.
I'm just passing through.
Quiet! Quiet! Quiet, please. I'll explain.
Mulligan, you go to the
commander of the regiment...
and tell Col. Rafferty
to come here to see me immediately.
All right. Look out. Let me through.
We'll need volunteers.
I know.
Harriman's already rounding them up.
If they cross into Mexico, it's over.
Hey, must you call
the Commander of the Regiment in?
- That safe had $100,000 in it.
- It belongs to the Army.
Hold it.
Collins, you head for Los Palos.
You others ride with me to the border.
- They cleaned out the bank, Jane?
- Yeah, that's right.
I wish I had the money.
I'd drink whiskey till I drown in it.
Hey, you, on the wagon...
turn back.
There isn't a Winchester going
that can shoot half that distance.
Virginian Brothers.
The greatest acrobats in the world.
In St. Louis, maybe.
We have combed the entire place, Colonel.
Not a trace.
I've nothing else
but to notify General Perkins.
Colonel, let me keep looking for them
one more day.
Gentlemen.
Somebody around here lose a safe?
They didn't act very friendly
when I told them to bring it back.
All in order, Colonel.
It was a real stroke of luck, Colonel,
getting the safe back.
They're not from these parts.
Hey...
they're from St. Louis.
Sir, you've got a reward coming to you.
Look after him. See about his money.
Here...
you must be thirsty
after all that hard work, right?
A wagon, a two-ton safe?
And seven men? A fine day's work.
First there were seven men,
then seven bodies.
Seven, like on the dice.
Was loading them up any trouble?
I don't like to bury anyone,
but next time I'll lend a hand.
You keep firing and I'll load, okay?
Hey, compadre,
Carrincha isn't afraid of bodies.
I saw lots of them die, those soldiers.
What about that?
At Richmond, the battle took nine days
and the army gave me a medal.
What good
do these medals do anyone today?
- Life today is horse droppings.
- You already said that.
- Well, how much do you want?
- You tell me.
$2,000?
$5,000.
All right.
Sgt. Keller will bring you the money.
Hey, you could've got more money
than that.
After all you had all their money in
your hands, the whole $100,000.
And Mexico so near, you could be there.
And you bargain like a woman
and end with a lousy $5,000...
selling yourself to the law.
It might be lousy, Carrincha, but it's legal.
Yeah, but if I, just imagine...
I plan this robbery, carry it out, get
my money and you come along to stop me.
A knife like that would be better as a friend.
If it's friends you want...
- would you like to have two?
- Two?
Hey, Alley Cat.
Oh, don't you like him?
Hey.
How about that? All right?
This way.
Sign here.
A new man who blows into town
and already has picked up $5,000...
is interesting.
Number seven.
It's the best in the house. Next door to mine.
- You staying on long?
- Just passing through.
You never know.
You passing through, too?
Yeah.
Sabata.
I don't hardly recognize you anymore.
Because of the safe?
And if you were in my shoes,
what would you have done?
Me?
I'd have kept the money.
You were out of tempo.
Stengel, this time you made a mistake.
Trying to steal $100,000 from the Army
to buy land...
that the railroad must purchase
to come through.
All because of your greediness
and to satisfy your mania for grandeur...
you took this foolhardy step.
The risk was too great to take.
I'm dishonored by all this, of course.
And so is Ferguson.
Aren't you?
All I know is, I'm leaving this town.
No.
The Colonel won't drop this whole thing.
He'll investigate, of course.
And he'll start right at the top.
Just a minute, Judge O'Hara.
You are never leaving Daugherty.
Stengel, don't.
All right.
That's better.
You'll be here with the rest.
- Well, l...
- Oswald...
I want the Virginian Brothers
and their wagon taken care of.
Yeah.
- It didn't go so well, Oswald?
- Bad business.
Which is exactly why I'm here.
- But we did our part like we said.
- Oh, yeah.
Don't worry, my boss always pays up.
- Oswald?
- Yeah.
- Got to get rid of that wagon.
- I sent three men.
They know how to get rid of it.
Hey, what are you thinking so hard about?
A seesaw and an acrobat,
you get into the bank.
- Acrobat?
- The upper window.
You cash the Army reward and get out.
Don't look for trouble.
Those acrobats took part in that robbery.
And then disappeared.
Hey.
- Get away from that wagon.
- Who the hell are you?
Could be your pallbearer?
- He's one of Stengel's men.
- That makes it all clear.
Come in.
"All men gifted with superior talent...
"and thus with superior powers...
"must command...
"and use inferior men."
- Well?
- It's all been done.
So the Virginian Brothers
and the men from St. Louis are dead.
You're the only person
who knows about the robbery.
But are you safe?
I won't talk.
Four chances, Oswald.
Three to depart.
One to stay.
Hey, cut it out, Stengel.
You won't play? You want the alternative.
All right.
You don't really think anyone like you
can put one over on me.
Oswald...
I like living at the peak of excitement.
For life is only worthwhile...
when you can face death
without showing any fear.
In fact, I enjoy it.
600 feet! That's impossible.
A wise man keeps his distance.
Stengel...
that acrobat's wagon
is positive evidence against you.
So if you'd like to have it,
it'll cost you $10,000.
Come here and you'll get them.
I'm coming.
Stengel...
don't try any tricks!
You'll be shooting at the wind!
Don't shoot at ghosts, Stengel.
Don't shoot at the wind!
You shouldn't have done that, Stengel.
Now the price is $20,000.
Hey.
Now where the devil did he go?
There he is.
You really gave them a run for their money.
I haven't budged from here.
You better keep your horse tied up, then.
Or else people might say:
"He's been up,
playing around with his fillies again."
Where're you going now?
To play around.
- Hey, Sabata, the Alley Cat?
- We better be off then.
- I got a feeling he needs us.
- Right.
Alley Cat's done it again.
London, Paris...
I dream about them.
Ever since I was a kid.
And I still do.
A better life...
and money.
That's all we need to get us out of here.
Eh, Banjo?
If you'd gotten your hands on that money,
we'd be on our way to Europe now.
You and I together.
Always together. Always.
- No!
- Banjo, what's the matter? Are you sick?
- No, it's nothing. I was dreaming.
- Yeah, dreams, dreams.
We're a great pair, you and me.
At least I've always got something
I can make money on.
You strumming away on that stupid banjo.
The sun's up.
Where are you going?
Banjo?
See you.
Hi.
Can't tell you like that.
How much is what you want to tell me
gonna cost?
$200.
I had a run-in in Denver
and they're looking for me.
That's why I'm here.
I know everything that goes on in this town.
Stengel doesn't want to pay that $20,000.
He doesn't?
How would you know?
Women talk a lot when they're making love.
The fact is, not even Judge O'Hara
or Ferguson will pay.
Oh, yeah?
They figure your demands...
are going to go higher and higher.
Like everything that was in that safe,
maybe?
What are you getting at?
I'm not getting at anything. It's your idea.
It's too risky.
And you don't want a partnership.
You owe me $200.
Being around is useful.
Sorry, lady.
If Stengel wanted to invite me to supper,
why didn't he come right out and say so?
You are here because that's what I wanted.
Stengel, sit down.
That $20,000 I wanted isn't enough.
I'd like to get a hold of more money.
But you won't like it. That's too bad.
But business is business.
Now it's $30,000.
$30,000?
But you can buy all of Texas for that.
Well, hardly,
but that does seem to be your intention.
Now, you're obviously interested
in buying land...
that will soon be worth twice as much.
Because sooner or later
the railroad will be passing over it.
So, shall we agree the price is settled?
It's not worth it, Stengel.
If I don't get out of here alive...
Col. Rafferty will be informed
of everything.
Take the $30,000 to Judge O'Hara.
You've got until 8:00 in the morning.
Very generous.
I think so.
You see, Banjo,
I told you not to worry about him.
I know this hombre.
I said he'd be back. Where's my money?
Soon there'll be enough cash for everyone.
All I got to do is believe in you, right?
You don't trust Sabata?
What do you think they'll do?
Nothing. I'm waiting.
You better walk
or I may have to pay for your funeral.
The only man who could betray us
to the Army was Oswald...
and he's been eliminated.
No reason to fear anybody.
That man has no proof against us.
You're wrong, Ferguson.
He knows everything about us.
I know what I'm saying.
If he is a government official, then...
He's nothing.
He's a drifter who's after our money.
First, $10,000, now $30,000...
It'll cost a lot less to get rid of him.
What we need is somebody
from the outside.
I think I know somebody.
Just the right boy.
Sharkey, you filthy slob.
You answer when your mother calls,
understand?
Sharkey!
Sharkey, how long you gonna wait?
I'm expecting you to get the Mallorys.
You better go out right now
and shoot them, you hear?
They stole your woman, didn't they?
And you don't do nothing about it.
Listen to me! This whole business must end
or they'll shoot us.
Well, what are you going to do about it?
Why must I stand here...
But it was you who sold her to the Mallorys.
Ain't that something?
You want to get me arrested?
Come on, Ma!
Hey, what is this?
I just have a little job for your son.
I'll do the talking.
What'll you pay the boy?
$1,000.
Five hundred now...
and the rest when the job is done.
What are you waiting for? Go on.
And come back today.
With the money.
Sharkey, word's gotten around
that you've been drinking a lot.
Alcohol can make your hands shaky.
See those twigs? Watch.
One would have been enough.
Mister, I must tell you, till you got here
Daugherty was nice and quiet.
The devil rides with you.
I alone don't say it. Ask Padre Brown.
Ask the Alley Cat here.
Hey, Sabata.
When I stop laughing, you're dead.
Like manure, eh?
Makes the grain grow taller, right?
Just a minute, you.
Sheriff, I was there.
It was self-defense, I saw it.
Well, you stick around till I need you.
Hey, wait!
I wonder where he'll end up?
And where do you come in?
I'm on his side. For the moment.
I'm waiting.
I curse my mother who bore me,
and my father...
and my brother and my whole family.
How about? I'll throw it in.
I won it at Richmond.
The Battle of the Seven Days.