Name?
Juliano dos Santos.
Father's name?
Don't know.
Mother's name?
Georgina dos Santos.
- Profession?
- Miner.
And before?
Before that I was nothing.
I boxed for money.
It says here
that you're some big shot.
Claim boss, gold smuggler,
drug trafficker.
I'm a miner sir.
You ever kill anyone?
You ever have anyone killed?
Are you related with
drug trafficking?
And the guy in the hospital,
he's in on the scheme too?
No, he's my friend.
Serra Pelada breaks
a new record in production.
The mine located in southern Para,
where only last week
the larges gold nugget found
in Brazil for over 100 years,
is going to extract over
7 thousand kilos of gold this year.
The gold from Serra Pelada
reaches the Presedential Palace.
The two largest gold nuggets
found in Brazil.
The largest weighs
over 30 kilos
and is worth over
370 million cruzeiros.
The nugget worth
16 million cruzeiros
was put on exhibition today
in Belem in Para.
It weighs 7 kilos 400 grams and
was found last Sunday in Serra Pelada
by miner Lindomar Natal.
The nugget is 86% solid gold and worth
16 million 149 thousand cruzeiros.
Technicians from the Federal Savings
and Loans Bank confirm the information
given by the Minister of Mining and
Energy that this is the larges nugget
But, why'd they fire you?
What'd you do wrong?
I didn't do anything.
They're cutting costs.
I wasn't tenured, I had to leave.
But, any way you look at it,
it doesn't make any sense trying to get
by on a public school teacher's wages.
I'm happy with you here,
with the way we live. Aren't you?
That's not the question, lzabel.
This is our chance.
I'm talking of gold, real gold.
Any gold nugget I find is worth
more than a whole year's salary.
I'm not going to stay here
by myself, Joaquim.
No way. You have a pregnant wife,
house installments to pay,
and you're going off,
running after some illusion.
Izabel I grew up in poverty, and I
don't want the same thing for my son.
- You can find a better job.
- No, I'm going to find gold.
AMAZON FOREST
The world's going to end and we still
won't have got to the fucking place.
Stop complaining Juliano.
This is the biggest gold
mine ever found in Brazil.
But it sure is fucking far away.
- Oh yeah? You wanta go back?
- Yeah.
Let's go Juliano.
It was easy for Juliano
to leave São Paulo.
There was nothing there for him.
Just some debts and no options.
I left everything behind.
BEGINNING OF MINE
Yeah professor, seems like
everyone read that newspaper
of yours and they all got
the same idea.
If they all came, it's because
there must be some truth in it Juliano.
The news of the gold spread
through Brazil like wildfire.
In 10 days there were 30 miners.
In one month, over a thousand.
You understand what
I was saying now big shot?
I understand now.
You see the size
of that thing?
Let's go get ours.
In the beginning, the place was divided
up in around three hundred claims.
Each claim had an owner,
the CAPI TALIS T.
He was the one
who financed the mine.
The claims were called "dAMES".
And each dame had a king.
The Capitalists are king
of the Mountain.
The middle-class at the mine
is called "meia-praça".
They act like they own the mine,
but don't own jackshit.
They think they're the
Capitalist's partner.
But, in the end, the only
thing they do is work for him.
The last guy on the supply
chain is the Ant.
Ant's spend their lives carrying
bags on their backs.
30 kilos of dirt and mud.
When a Miner finds gold,
he's called a "BAMBURRAdO".
They're the lucky guys who find
the gold everyone is talking
about at Serra Pelada.
Lot's of guys struck it
rich at the mines.
And a lot of stories about guys
who made fortunes
and then spent it all
in one day.
Like José da Silva,
who bought a different car
for each day of the week.
And Caboclo, for example,
when he struck it rich,
he decided to hire
a plane all for himself
and went to Belem
and the nightclubs.
Nego diamante never missed
a night at the Tropical,
one of the better known
nightclubs in Marabá.
He loved to slap his money
onto the dancers' asses.
What Nego couldn't imagine was
that when Serra Pelada closed down,
he'd be flat broke and
that dancer over there...
would become a successful
businesswoman in the capital.
But things changed real quick
at the mine.
I'm gonna hit China soon.
- You miss São Paulo Juliano?
- Oh yeah.
Why don't you go back?
You think I'm crazy?
Your friend the loanshark
is waiting for you.
Precisely why I don't go back.
Come on big shot.
Let's get to work...
- Hi.
Everything OK?
- How's the rates today boss?
- They're good today.
400 grams.
Alright, I thought it was less.
Check to see
if anything's missing.
Better check right here,
if we have to complain...
There'll be food,
good grub with meat,
a hammock, place to sleep...
But, that's a lousy deal.
It ain't easy without a salary.
Yeah, but nobody's paying
2% around here.
Go look for yourself,
nobody'll give you that.
But they'll guarantee
you something at least.
But the other mines are paying
1% and we're paying 2%. The double.
That's the way it's gonna be here.
Take it or leave it, you understand?
Everybody will be happy when
we find gold. So?
Let's get to work?
Alright then.
OK. And if it were up to me,
we wouldn't be paying 2%.
It'd be 1, but the professor
here is a communist...
OK then. This is the deal:
2% with no salary. Right?
And another thing:
We'll give you a pair of sneakers,
shorts and 3 T-shirts.
Anybody get drunk and lose
his sneakers will work barefoot.
Now, let's get some rest.
Give me your papers.
Get some rest so
we can start tomorrow early.
See you tomorrow.
It's all working out, Big Shot.
You're too soft professor.
You're in Serra Pelada!
Listen,
I wanta tell you something:
We're going to get everything
we want, together.
A brother's pact.
Brother's pact.
Big Shot had been my friend
since we were young.
We were a good duo.
Juliano had always been hot-headed,
always liked to give the orders.
Josias, where's Mudinho?
He has to take these bags on up
by the end of the afternoon.
We don't think this
is right, no way.
Too much land for tool
few men.
- You talking to me?
- You deaf or something?
I said it's too much land
for only a couple guys to be working.
You took over this whole area while ther
are a lot of other people wanting to dig.
What you gonna do?
We didn't just take over buddy.
This claim is ours.
I have the deed.
The deed?
He has the deed to the claim!
The only good deeds are in the bible,
and the bible only has saints...
and I don't see
no saints around here.
What you want?
I want what everybody wants, man.
Land.
Land or blood.
Take your pick.
Let's settle this
some other way man.
We can talk this over...
Drop the knife and let's talk.
Juliano!
Come here!
That's enough.
Let's go.
Come on, quick!
What you assholes looking at?
Help me here man!
What you playing...
What's it called?
Fuinha.
- Know how to play?
- No.
Thanks for saving
my life Big Shot.
I killed a man.
I never killed anybody before.
It wasn't your fault,
he started it.
I liked it.
Let me tell you something,
Big Shot.
Look at me.
This place brings out
the worse in us.
Just the way it is here.
That's the way things happen.
Here's to the "bamburrados"!
One month later we struck gold.
Happy now huh, professor.
Sure am!
Let's drink more
so our mine won't run dry!
Me and Juliano struck it rich.
Take another one.
My friend, my brother.
My friend, your brother.
Buddy and buddy,
Son of a bitch and son of a bitch.
People began talking about
Serra Pelada all over Brazil.
Since its discovery in early 1980,
the mine at Serra Pelada has already
produced around six tons of gold.
It wasn't long before the government
took over the mine.
All gold was to be sold directly
to the Federal Savings and Loans Bank,
who paid a fair price
for the gold.
The government also set up
a health center for the miners.
But, on the other hand,
they prohibited women,
liquor and fire arms in the mine.
Lots of people didn't
like the changes,
but at that time everybody had
to dance according to the music.
Izabel?
Joaquim? It's been so long since
you last called. Over two weeks!
How are you?
And the baby?
Is everything alright?
Yeah, everything is alright.
Listen honey, I have to tell you.
We found gold.
- Really?
- Really. We struck it rich, honey.
That's wonderful!
That means you'll be coming home,
right Joaquim?
I'll send you some money
as soon as I can.
- Aren't you coming home?
- No.
I'm not going honey, I can't go back now
that I've found gold.
I have to stay now.
But, if you've already got some money,
you can come back, Joaquim.
I'm not going back with
"some" money, no way.
I'm going back a rich man.
That boy of ours is going
to be rich.
But, honey, I need you here.
The baby's going to be born soon.
No, I can't talk now,
I have to get back to work.
I love you, lzabel,
I love you.
Very much.
Why don't you just shave it all off,
huh tough guy?
Because it makes me look
like a baby.
Always playing
the tough guy, huh?
Fags were welcome here.
They were called the Marias.
In a place without any women,
the guys who couldn't control
themselves wound up adapting.
But not all the Marias were
sweet and delicate.
Hi João.
I'll be right with you Marcelo.
I ain't got all day.
I think that'll about do it,
shaky scissors.
Get this off of me.
How much is it?
200 for the hair,
200 for the beard... here...
200 for being nice.
How's that?
Thanks, João.
It didn't take long before Juliano
found out that the Maria he had killed
was Marcelo's big love.
- What'll it be today?
- The whole treatment, João.
I'll make you look like
a million gal.
Shake that thing, Maria.
What's the matter,
you never seen it before?
I'll let you fuck me and I'll give you
a blow job. But don't go hassling me!
If you get me pissed off
I'll cut off your balls
and stick them down your throat,
you son of a bitch.
I've got my eye on you...
When you see me coming you look down
and ask for my blessing!
I've got my eye on you too!
Take it easy man,
you're too uptight.
Leave me alone.
Don't look so sour.
Come on, have a drink.
Let's go driver,
let's get this show on the road.
Won't fit anymore back here.
As the government had outlawed booze
and women at the mine,
the owners of the bars and
the whores had to go somewhere else.
A place 30 km. From the mine,
called the "30's"
where everything went,
the Las Vegas of the Amazon.
Look Juliano.
Look at that car.
You gotta have money
for a car like that, huh?
- You give discounts for virgins?
- Sure.
He's a virgin.
Go on, Professor.
Hey, Josias, the professor
struck it rich.
- It's loaded right?
- Yeah.
I'm screwed if it doesn't
have any bullets man.
Go on, take a look.
You really into this
thing now, huh.
Into what?
You going to go around
packing a gun now?
Professor, it's like this here,
either you give the orders
or you take them.
And I'm not the kind
that takes them.
Come on, don't look so glum,
it's not all that bad here.
Let's have some fun,
go dance "forró".
Hey man, give me two more
of these here, please.
Thanks.
Holy shit.
Did you see that girl?
- What?
- No... don't look.
Look now. There, at the table with
the short guy, some big shot.
All dressed in gold.
Jeez, she's beautiful.
Beautiful was my mother,
that there is a goddess.
Let's just drink up these
two here and leave.
We've spent too much money
already.
Stop talking about
leaving and money.
There's a saying at the mine:
Anybody who doesn't spend
their money with girls or booze...
Won't find any gold.
Here's to us!
Well, I'm crazy then.
- Stay here professor.
- Watch your step Big Shot.
Hey!
A wildcat.
I like that.
Hey, what's going on here?
These two were fighting
outside sir.
And she wants to talk to you.
This macho man here was
trying to kill me.
She was pawing some other guy.
And I had asked
her to marry me, sir.
I was going to marry this whore,
in the church and everything.
Why honey, you going to let a good deal
like that get away from you?
He's one big loser.
Doesn't have a penny to his name.
She took my gold, spent it all and
now she's going round with other guys.
She's gotta pay.
With her life.
Yeah... two-timers are better dead,
you're right.
But, any guy that falls in love
with a whore deserves being two-timed.
Don't you think?
Listen Romeo,
take this money here
and go find some other Juliet
to ask her to marry you.
Go on!
He won't do anything
to you honey.
Go on now.
Get them out of here. Beat it.
Get that whore out of here.
Here's my precious nugget.
My diamond nugget.
How much is it to close
this place for a private party?
With women and drinks.
The whole place?
It's a deal.
The place is mine.
You can stay.
You leave. You stay.
You stay too.
You there, you leave.
Hey partner,
let me stay, partner.
Partner?
I ain't got no partner.
I told you already, beat it.
Come on buddy, the girl got all
dressed up for tonight.
- Put on her best clothes...
- The place is closed.
Beat it.
- Just to stay here.
- I told you already, beat it.
Listen buddy, you struck it rich,
but you're not the only one.
How much is he paying you,
Ednardo?
15 grand.
Great. Listen partner.
Here's 20, just for you to leave.
You take your money
and leave.
Don't do this man,
you're wrong partner.
Hey partner.
Kiss my ass.
Why'd you do that for?
You shouldn't have done that.
What'd you do that for?
Why would anybody do that,
everybody drinking...
I'll leave this here for you,
OK Ednardo,
leave this for you.
No need for him to have done that,
none whatsoever.
That guy scare you?
No need for that,
totally unnecessary.
You're the one who killed my man,
didn't you, you sack of shit?!
- Yeah, I'm the one.
- So now it's your turn to die.
Oh yeah,
and who's going to kill me?
Who's going to kill me, you?
I'm going to kill you,
you can be sure of it.
Drop the knife.
I'll get you when
you're least expecting it.
- Drop the knife.
- I'll get you, you sack of shit.
Let's go, Maria.
Juliano listen to me!
Listen, let's go.
You're swearing you're going
to kill me, is that it?
Yeah, that's a promise,
son of a bitch.
That's enough! Let's go!
You see what it's like here, professor,
this is the way it is here.
And like they say:
During the day it's the "30's",
at night "38's".
When you coming to live
with me, sweet pea?
- I've already got my man.
- Who, the midget?
I'm engaged to be married, Juliano.
I'm getting married in one month.
What you going to marry
him for? His money?
- Yeah.
- I have money too.
It's not just that.
He takes care of me.
You want a father,
or a husband?
I can take care
of you too Tereza.
You sound like some miner
who just struck it rich.
Wildcat.
I don't trust men, no way.
For me, you and the midget
are just the same.
Yeah, but he's a midget.
Hey buddy,
any letters for me?
- What's your name?
- Joaquim Francisco Souza da Silva.
Thanks.
"It's a girl!"
- Thanks buddy.
- For nothing.
Things at the mine got better
and me and Juliano started
finding lots of gold.
The only father my daughter had
was the check I'd send every month.
But it wasn't enough.
I wanted more money.
And Juliano wanted more power.
- Did you talk to Juliano?
- No.
I'm the one giving
the orders here today.
Nobody is going to die
on my claim, no way.
Listen up everybody.
I've got something to tell you.
Due to the landslide over
at the "milharinha" claim,
you get the day off today.
Joaquim, Joaquim,
no way,
you can't go giving
these guys a day off.
What are you going to do with
the two guys who died up there then?
They died. They've gone up to heaven,
we keep on working here.
And how we supposed
to get to the top?
We'll go the long way around,
go up "Goodbye momma".
And who's going
to be responsible for that?
I'll be responsible, if anybody
has to be. I'll be responsible.
Well then you can be responsible
for this too then.
He's the responsible one now.
Joaquim I don't know how
to do this shit here, no way.
You can learn then.
Josias, you keep track here.
Josias, my ass. Shit.
Listen man, some son of a bitch
dies everyday here.
What you gonna do?
Hold mass, send the widow flowers?
Have a funeral? Don't be stupid.
Let's get moving, the shovelers
shoveling, the carriers carrying...
let's get working.
- You're going to be responsible for this.
- Yeah, I know.
You assume all the fucking
consequences.
Put it in that little notebook
of yours. Let's get working.
I hope you know what
you're doing.
Gold was shipped out of Serra Pelada
by the official route,
with a police escort
to the airstrip.
But it was still being taken out
another way too...
Juliano began playing the game.
He'd sell gold to the smugglers.
Guys who would take the gold
over the border.
And anybody smuggling
didn't smuggle just one thing.
The car that took the illegal
gold took drugs, guns...
The ants did the hard work,
but the guys who got rich
were another group...
and it was this group
that Juliano wanted to be part of.
The criminal organization headed
by Carvalho was in charge
of dozens of gold mines scattered
around the Amazon area.
- I'll sink the 12 ball.
- Nope.
Sure I will.
If I sink the 12 ball,
what'll I get?
My asshole.
- And if I don't?
- What'll you give me?
The world.
- How many tries do I get?
- One.
Beer.
Well I'll be, if it isn't
the guy with the tiny claim?
Tiny claim? Alright.
I want to buy it.
I wasn't really thinking
about selling man.
No?
Everything is for sale
in this world.
I've already bought
all the claims around yours.
I've heard...
Tell him the names
of all my claims.
Babylonia,
Old Plain,
Black Rock,
Milharina,
Igrejinha,
Malvinas,
Tight Pussy...
Widow's Hole,
Catarina...
X eréu, Nigger's Head,
Yellow House,
I know all your claims.
Yours is the only one
I don't have.
You've got a lot of claims,
don't you sir.
What you want so much gold for?
Our claim ain't for sale.
Joaquim...
Thanks for your hospitality sir.
I'm not going to sell
my claim to that guy.
It's not just your claim,
Juliano.
Why do you think
he wants our claim?
I don't know. All I know is
that claim is running dry.
But he knows there's
more gold further down.
He's the type of guy who has
geologists working for him,
he pays them to study these thing.
He knows, Joaquim.
And what do you know
about shit like that?
You didn't even hear
the guys offer.
I didn't hear it because
I'm not going to sell anything
to that son of a bitch.
You're blind man,
completely blind because of that girl.
We could both be rich
with the money he pays us.
Is that your problem?
You want to be rich?
Yeah, I want to be rich.
I want to get back to lzabel,
to my daughter, back home,
lzabel is has been
a saint up to now...
No, lzabel hasn't been no saint,
no, you know what she is,
I'll tell you,
lzabel is a single mother.
You watch your mouth...
It's no use arguing with me,
no use for us to fight.
All I have to say is this:
There's more gold further down.
Lots of gold Professor.
I've had enough.
I want to get out of this place.
This place brings
the worst out in everybody.
I'll take whatever
I can get for that claim.
So, this is what we do then...
we'll dig for a while more,
if we don't find gold,
we'll sell the claim,
you take your money and leave, go be
happy with your wife and your kid.
Because I'm going to stay.
I ain't leaving.
I thought we were
in this together.
We were, but you don't have
ambition Professor!
I sure as hell do.
Well then, yours is
a lot different than mine.
That's where the problem is.
OK, we'll do it your way then.
I know.
Come on over next to me,
come on.
I can't do this anymore,
Juliano
What'd you come here
for then?
I came to tell you that.
I can't take it any more.
Don't be stupid.
Come here...
I can't do this to him.
Tereza, you can't do this to me.
Come here now.
If you're here just to waste
my time, go on back then.
Go on back to your midget,
I saw the way he respects you,
spreading your legs like
that right in front of me.
Shut up.
I won't put up with no whore
hitting me in the face like that.
No whore, because that's what you are,
a whore. A two-bit whore.
That's what I used to be.
A slut.
But you don't go shooting off
the mouth about Carvalho.
You don't know anything about him.
You don't know anything about me.
He took me out of the whorehouse
when I was 13 years old.
Everything I got I owe to him.
I like him.
I'm going to marry him.
You're going to marry him.
Go ahead and marry him.
I'm going to marry him.
Marry him, go ahead.
Hello.
I came to check out
my claim personally.
This claim isn't yours.
No?
I don't remember having made
any deal with you.
Well my boy, everybody here
is standing on gold.
The only problem is finding out
where it'll surface.
And that's why I bought
all the claims around here.
I bought Milharina,
Widow's Hole,
Pedra Pedra,
I bought Tight Pussy...
The same thing again, huh?
You didn't even hear
my offer, boy.
And I don't intend to. There's gold here.
I ain't selling anything, no way.
We're not interested
in selling, sir.
Well I guess we'll have
to be good neighbors then, right?
Because everything, everything,
everything around you...
is mine.
Don't listen to him Juliano.
You don't know if it was him,
Juliano.
I know it was him.
You know it was him.
- And he knows it was him.
- You're just jealous. You blind?
You going to stand there and defend
a guy who's out to get me...
- Who tried to kill me?
- You don't know if it was him.
- And how do you know it wasn't?
- Nobody knows who did it, Juliano.
There's no way we can know.
Learn how to lie better.
You're going to have to choose.
Look at me, you're going to have
to choose Tereza.
You're going to have to choose,
you hear me?
What's happening to you, Juliano?
Are you crazy?
He was going to kill us.
- You've turned into an assassin.
- And you into a chickenshit, Joaquim.
Why? Because I don't go
around killing people?
- Assassin.
- Chickenshit.
After Carvalho was killed,
power switched hands.
Juliano took care
of all his enemies.
Some by his own hand,
others by destiny.
AldS had found its way to Serra Pelada
and the Marias were blamed.
The Marias were all kicked out
of the mine.
Among which was Marcelo,
who had always been talking
about killing Juliano one day.
Let me go,
I'm a working man, let me go!
Keep moving.
Shut up.
- João Maria stays.
- And why's that?
Because he cuts my hair.
And because
of my automatic pistol here.
Beat it João Maria.
You'll have to disappear
for a while.
Everybody is out
of their mind here.
Let's go,
get down from there.
Let me go, shit.
What the fuck you doing
in this whorehouse?
I'm working.
You ain't no whore
to be working here.
Yes I am.
You forget?
You ain't no whore.
You're my girl.
My girl, Tereza, my girl.
- Let me go.
- What?
Only Northern Chapel
doesn't have any shares for sale.
But over here... Babilonia 1,
Babilonia 2, Malvinas...
all of them are up for sale.
Lindo...!??
Lindo Rico.
Lindo Rico!
I forgot man...
I knew it was some kind
of singer's name,
I just could remember.
This here is the Claim's Market.
Which I put together...
Me and... Joaquim.
Why don't you get him some coffee?
Coffee... Get him some...
A cup of coffee.
Fresh, just made, go ahead,
get him some...
And, it's like I say,
you put money in the claim,
you'll be buying a share, a percentage
of what the claim produces.
Like if the claim produces
100kg of gold, 1 kg is yours.
Well let's just imagine...
partner...
I buy a claim,
a percentage of a claim,
and the claim I buy into is dry.
Man if you find a claim in
Serra Pelada
that doesn't give you any gold
you show it to me,
because I've never seen one.
But, it's the same old story,
an investment is always a risk.
A guy can have some bad luck.
But you won't be putting
your money into only one claim.
The question isn't if it'll produce
gold, but when the gold will be found
and that means digging.
Let's start digging?
I'll think it over
and give you an answer.
Great, that's it then.
Who's coming with me?
Maranhão?
- But, it's a great idea.
- I know.
Partner.
I was just thinking here about
what your boss said.
Who?
Juliano isn't my boss, no way.
He's my business partner.
We've been friends since we were kids.
I've been here two years now.
I've got claims, "damas",
the whole bit.
And I see that when people
start making money...
He's your friend...
good guy.
The way he talked to you back there,
I thought that...
- What are you talking about?
- I don't like that.
- You don't like what?
- That, what I said.
- The way he talked?
- Of what I said.
That's your problem.
It's his problem, partner.
How'd you like to work
with me?
No, no thanks.
I'm not talking about you being
my errand boy, to get coffee and shit.
No way. I'm talking about
you being my partner.
For real.
I can see that you...
I don't want to work with you.
You don't like money?
You don't like money, huh?
Think it over.
I'll be here...
you'll look me up.
I'll be around...
It's two in the morning.
What are you doing here?
I came for a little talk, brother.
To show you
a little piece of paper.
Joaquim Francisco Souza da Silva.
That's you, isn't it?
So professor,
I'm the dumb guy around here.
I don't know
how to read no books.
But there's one thing
I know how to do, numbers.
What you want Juliano?
- You robbing from me, Professor?
- No.
I'm your partner, you forget?
You're robbing me you clown.
What's your plan?
Grab the money and run?
I'm going to take my part
and get back to my family.
That's what I'm going to do.
Show me the money, Professor.
I can't believe you're doing this.
Put that gun down.
Get me the fucking money, Joaquim.
Go on, move it.
- This money here is mine.
- Put it on the table.
You want to go back to São Paulo,
go on. But the money stays here.
Now, if you want to work for me,
I need a good accountant.
I think you might be
the right person.
Your business is illegal,
you know that, don't you?
There's some guys in Marabá
who take care of that part.
But I need someone here.
I need you.
Brother's pact.
You know what's best.
It's either this or nothing.
Starting tomorrow, at the claim,
you don't work there anymore.
Juliano, where's my money?
- What money?
- The money you stole from me.
I didn't steal your money.
Yes you did, and I want my money.
Where is it?
I think you've been out
in the sun too long.
You're the one who stole me,
Joaquim.
- I'm your partner, where's my part?
- That's where you got it wrong.
You're not my partner anymore.
You robbed me.
This claim isn't yours anymore,
the house isn't yours,
our partnership is over.
It's over?
Yeah right, asshole!
Son of a bitch! Shit!
Fucking traitor.
Clown, chiseller.
Stick the knife in,
Josias, go ahead!
Get him out of here.
Beat it man.
Traitor.
Got no ambition.
You haven't heard the end
of this.
Serra Pelada turned into the biggest
concentration of manual labor
ever since the pyramids in Egypt.
The only difference was
that the miners
built an upside-down pyramid.
Serra Pelada, which used to be a hill,
turned into a hole.
Over 60 thousand men moved
the mountain from its place.
This is no toy.
Sit up straight
and close your legs.
You looking at that
guy over near the counter?
What?
That clown over near
the counter.
You think I'm like that midget
with the horns.
I'm not looking at anyone,
no way.
That clown over near the bar.
- You think I'm stupid?
- No, I think you're crazy.
Stay put.
You, beat it.
Go on asshole, beat it.
Juliano, what'd you do?
What?
What'd you do to that
guy that was there.
I removed him from my sight.
Let me go!
Aww, my little runaway...
Let her go.
- Let me leave, Juliano.
- No.
Why do you want me around?
I don't like you anymore.
You don't like me. Let me leave.
You kidding with me, Tereza?
You trying to piss me off?
You're only leaving when
I say you can go.
And I don't want you
to go right now.
I don' t like you anymore.
Let me leave. It's over.
Let's go home.
Get my bag.
You crying?
Don't go pouting like that,
it's your fault.
It's my fault?!
I didn't tell you
to run away...
It's your fault, Juliano.
You're all alone now.
Everybody left you.
Who's all alone?
The place is full of people.
Wake up Juliano.
There's nobody left here.
You're the loneliest man
in the world.
- I pity you.
- I don't need your pity.
Where's your friend?
Didn't you have a friend?
Where's your friend, Juliano?
You're all alone, huh?
Where's your friend?
- That's it, hit me.
- Shut up.
- Where's your friend?
- Shut your mouth.
Shut the fuck up.
You think I won't kill you, huh,
you two-bit whore? You think
I won't kill you?
You think I'm scared
of killing you?
Go on beat it.
Get on with your life.
Ice!
That was fantastic.
Clap your hands.
I like that song a lot.
Here, one grand for every time
you play that song.
One, two... play it again.
Just that song.
Go on...
You two, sit down.
There's a guy singing here,
show some respect...
- Go on, play it again.
- You're the boss.
I know. You play only
that song tonight.
Go on, sing, shit!
That was better huh...
One more time.
Malaria was pretty common
at the mine.
Malaria fever was
like gold fever.
Pull!
I almost died that night.
After the fever had gone,
my dream came true.
Hey.
Here you go buddy.
I'm leaving now.
Hold it a second,
I'll get the money...
OK.
Thank you.
I'm leaving.
I'm going to see my family.
Thank you.
Joaquim!
Can I sit down?
What happened to you Joaquim?
Go buy yourself some candy.
Juliano robbed me.
Ohh.
I had struck it rich and
I was leaving.
Now, I'm back to zero.
You sure it was him?
It might not have been him.
- This place is full of crooks.
- Lf it wasn't him, who was it then?
Cesinha, what is it that
I'm always telling you.
Tell him, go on...
Trust... tell him.
When these guys got here, they were
the biggest buddies, like brothers.
Didn't I tell you?
Juliano is screwed.
You were the one who supported
that asshole.
You have to come work with me.
I told you that before.
I don't know what you want.
I just want to teach him a lesson.
I want him to pay.
You know Eduardo Ramos,
the sheriff over in Marabá?
No.
I've known him since I was a kid,
I'm the one who got him his job.
If you want to help...
He'll be really grateful.
- What do I have to do?
- Aren't you the bookkeeper?
Joaquim, this here is Marcelo.
Joaquim is going to tell you
exactly what you have to do
when you get there.
Pay attention.
You have to get a cashbook that
is in a bookkeeping firm in Marabá,
on Remedios St.
You the bookkeeper?
We want Juliano's book.
Is this guy here the bookkeeper?
The cash book,
from inside the safe.
Go on honey,
get the fucking book.
If I don't have any patience
with guys, imagine with women.
You know where it is.
Go on get it, quick.
You know it's in the safe.
Move it bitch!
A black book
with orange corners.
We have this one here...
- Black or orange?
- Black with orange corners.
They'll try to give you another one,
but don't let them.
You trying to fool me
son of a bitch!
Get me the fucking book, fast, if not
I'll shoot your face full of holes.
It's inside the safe.
The black one with orange corners.
That's it.
- Any questions?
- No.
You want me to make
a drawing for you?
Let's go!
Don't try anything stupid!
Hey, what do I get?
Don't you want revenge?
That's my own business.
How much do you think I deserve.
Greedy.
That's life.
DUDINHA!
This chocolate is great,
only it all melts in this
fucking heat.
Here. This is for you to be
awarded cop of the year.
Don't forget that I'm the one
who gave it to you.
Trophies don't fill
anyone's belly.
And what about this?
Can you eat this?
Can you?
Can you feed your face
with this, huh asshole!?
Can you eat this, you fat ass.
Can you eat this?
This here...
- How's your wife?
- Alright.
- And the kids, alright?
- Yeah, just fine.
The important thing is health,
isn't it?
Get the book there.
Hold it close.
Where'd you buy this chocolate?
Here in Marabá.
It's good, only it melts.
Boss, you know
who ratted on us, right?
It was your buddy, the professor.
He's in cahoots with Lindo Rico.
Lindo Rico.
Juliano, we've got to get out
of here, right now.
It's all over.
There's an airplane on the airstrip
waiting for us. Let's go.
No.
And when the smugglers
and the big shots realized
that everybody was going down,
they started knocking off everybody.
Put some music on,
for everyone to dance.
I was the one who gave them
the cashbook.
- I know.
- You here to kill me?
No, it's an idea,
but I have a better one.
- I came to get you out of here.
- Fuck off, Juliano.
I was already leaving
this fucking place.
But you stole my money.
You stole my dream!
You had them stick me up after you
found out I had struck it rich.
What are you talking about?
- You going to tell me it wasn't you?
- Of course it wasn't me.
And you're going to tell me
that you believe in Lindo Rico,
in the son of a bitch
who wants my place?
Do you know what he's going to do?
He's going to come here and kill
both you and me.
Let's get out of here Professor.
- I'm not going anywhere with you.
- Let's get out of here professor.
I'm not going anywhere with you.
You crazy?
They'll be here any minute.
Listen to me you piece
of shit, listen.
I promised your wife
I was going to get you out of here,
take care of you...
and that is what I'm going to do.
You're leaving with me.
We got into all of this together,
and we're going to get out of
it the same way.
- Let me go!
- We're leaving this place together.
Shit Professor.
- Were you the one who robbed me?
- No. I didn't rob you.
You ruined my life, Juliano.
I know,
but you fucked up mine too.
Stupid!
Come on,
let's get out of here.
Hold it...
Can you walk? Go, go...
It's over Juliano.
Hey driver,
I'm leaving.
In a way, leaving Serra Pelada
was harder than leaving São Paulo.
Chasing after a dream is
always easier than letting it go.
But, if there's one thing the mine
knows how to do
is teach you to face reality.
What each person chooses to do
in face of reality varies a lot.
And it is this choice which
determines who you really are.
And my choice,
I already knew what it was.
How you doing at school?
Alright.
What's your favorite food?
- Rice and potatoes.
- Rice and potatoes?
Like that?
Like those?
Pass them would you honey.
And the guy in the hospital,
he in on the scheme too?
No.
He's my friend.
Last question miner.
How much are you willing
to pay to get out of here?
Thank you.