From the great spirit
comes a unifying force
that flows through
all living things.
Through this,
we are all relatives.
As I dance,
I remember my friend.
Most men knew him
as James Conners.
I know him
as Shadowheart.
This is the most beautiful place
in the whole wide world.
How do you know?
You've never been anywhere else.
I don't need to go anywhere else.
I just know.
Not me.
I'm gonna see the world.
Well, better get back to town.
Let's go.
Come on.
I'll race you to the horse.
Okay!
- James!
- Yes, Father?
I've been looking
all over for you.
I'm right here.
Yes, I can see that.
Bring me that can
of paint, would ya?
- Goodbye, Mary.
- Bye, James.
Matthew... Chapter 6,
verse 14 and 15. Go.
"For if ye forgive
men their sins,
Your heavenly Father
will also forgive you."
Go on.
"But if ye forgive not
men their sins,
neither will your heavenly
Father forgive your sins."
You know King James
almost as well as I do.
Do you understand it?
If I did, we wouldn't
need preachers.
Fair, fair enough.
Your mother,
God rest her soul,
would be very
proud of you, James.
Yes, Father.
All right.
Go on back to the house.
Finish your chores
and come back here.
Come straight back here.
I need help
with the cross.
Go on.
Hey, not bad.
- How many tries?
- Eh, I stopped counting after 12.
Hey, James, let's see who can stick
the knife in the post
the most times
without missing.
Can't.
Got chores to do.
Come on.
Here, you go first.
Hey, James.
Dang!
Why do all churches
have to be white?
Tunney.
I mean, why not blue?
Red? Why not
a red church, Preacher?
It's not what's
on the outside that matters.
It's what's
on the inside.
It's the inside,
I like that.
Yeah.
You might want to include that
in your sermon, Preacher.
What do you want, Tunney?
Well, you've been paying
the note on this property
to a Mr. Rusty Knudsen, yeah?
Right.
- For about five years now.
- Uh-huh.
And it appears
that Mr. Knudsen
had himself
what you might call
a stroke of bad luck
last night at the poker table,
and I had me
what you might call
a streak of good luck.
And I now own that deed.
Rusty was a patient man.
Gave me time
to pay it off.
I never been one
for the whole...
patience thing.
It just kinda slows down the future
and in my future,
I can see in my future...
that I'm foreclosing
on your property
if you don't pay me in full
in the next two days.
You can't do that, Tunney.
Well...
I can even do it
in one day, Preacher.
I built this church with my two hands.
Yeah.
And fine job
you done too.
Except for the lack
of color...
and the fact that you
built it on my land.
This is a struggling parish.
Where are we gonna get that kinda money?
Well...
you could try praying.
I am not gonna
lose this church...
to a man who runs
with prostitutes!
Not a lot of running,
mostly lying.
Yeah.
You know what?
You just got yourself one day, Preacher.
I'm thinking-
I'm thinking a nice
burgundy red.
Yeah.
What was that?
Oh
You
Father!
I'm sorry, James.
I'm so sorry.
Remember what I taught you.
Forgive men their sins
and the Almighty will forgive you yours.
Seek not vengeance.
No good can c...
Father, no! No!
I'm sorry, folks.
Let me through.
Oh God.
- What happened here, Tunney?
- It was an honest mistake, Sheriff.
You see...
me and the preacher,
we was having a powwow
about uh... uh...
some money he owes me.
And then I turn my back,
he pulls out his hammer.
I think he gonna throw it at me.
I mean, we all know
what a temper he has,
So...
I shoot him in self-defense.
I wasn't aware that Preacher Conners
had a temper problem.
Well, he did.
Yes, sir. So am I
under arrest, Sheriff,
or what?
We have any witnesses?
We have any witnesses here?
- Anybody see this?
- I saw it, Sheriff.
- Me too.
- I seen the whole thing.
- It happened exactly like he said.
- Just like Will here said.
You sure?
Yes, sir.
- Yep.
- Well, that be that then.
Mind if I have
my gun back?
Sheriff?
Merci beaucoup.
And you know
where to find me.
Uh, boys,
I don't know your names,
but I'd like
to buy you a drink.
All righty.
Whoa whoa whoa.
Lord have mercy,
look at you.
Just come here.
You're an angel
from above, hmm?
Mighty fine
bone structure.
Tell me, what's your name,
little girl?
Come here.
You come see me
in a few years.
Right over
at the saloon, okay?
He just murdered my father and you're
not going to do anything about it?
He claims he acted
in self-defense
and he's got two witnesses
to back him up.
I'm sorry, James.
I really am.
I'm sorry.
I'm innocent.
- It was self-defense.
- Yeah, and pigs fly.
Wait wait wait.
Oh-oh-oh-oh.
Oh, you wanna
kill me, boy.
You wanna hurt me bad.
Come over here.
Come on, boy.
That's right.
Step up.
How you doing, hmm?
Awww.
You're hurtin' bad.
Well, see, my daddy...
he taught me
to keep this knife razor sharp
for a day like this.
Go on, take it.
Take it, boy.
Ah! Now you cut
my throat. Go on.
Just like a pig.
You cut me.
Take a man's vengeance.
Come on!
Come on! I'll even
closed my eyes for ya.
Come on.
I can feel it coming.
Awww!
Good boy.
I'll tell you what, boy... now shoo.
Come back when
you're man enough.
And we'll finish this.
Hear?
For that rainy day!
Hey! Rainy day!
To that rainy day.
Yes, sir!
I knew that you'd be here.
The whole town's been
looking for you, James.
Let 'em look.
I'm not going back there.
You can stay with us.
Thanks the same.
Are you coming
back to Legend?
When I do,
it'll be to kill Will Tunney.
- But, James, your father said that...
- My father's dead.
You better go back,
it'll be dark soon.
- Where will you go?
- I don't know, I...
I have an aunt and uncle
in Mobile, Alabama.
That's a thousand
miles away.
I don't care!
- I best get going.
- James, wait!
So that you'll
remember me.
Come on, now.
Run, little boy!
Boy, where are ya?
Why don't you come home...
so we can finish this...
...boy?
A little bit
jumpy there, Conners?
Seems like you got
something on your conscience.
Now me,
I sleep like a baby.
Shut up, Haines.
Good night.
Sangre de Cristo
Mountains, Conners.
The blood of Christ.
I know
what it is, Haines.
Yea, though I ride through the valley
of the shadow of death
I shall fear no evil
for thou art with me, Conners.
Thy knife
and thy gun comfort me.
You ain't much for religion,
are you, Conners?
See, that concerns me.
I'm worried
about your soul.
How do you
know I have one?
Go go go!
Bringing these hostiles
out of Canyon de Chelly,
putting 'em
on a reservation.
They don't look
very hostile to me.
Neither does he.
We're gonna put
8,000 of them there...
if they're smart enough
to surrender.
Give 'em five-minutes' rest.
No water. And watch out
for that buck over there.
If he gets half a chance,
he'll slit your throat.
Yes, sir.
''The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He leadeth me
by still water
for His name's sake.
Thy rod and Thy staff
comfort me.''
Put an end to it, Preacher.
These heathens
don't need religion.
They're gonna be farmers
if it kills them...
and it probably will.
Hey, what are you doing?
What'd you do that for?
That's my lucky knife.
Well, I don't think
you'll need it, Haines.
Long ride, Conners.
How about you buy me a drink?
We'll call it sort of
a last request.
What are you in such
a hurry for, huh?
What, you gonna catch up
with that Injun party?
I saw that look
you and that squaw had.
What's going on here?
Got a wild one here.
Yeah, well,
who's collecting?
James Conners.
- Conners.
- That's right.
Well, I'll be damned.
You're one lucky man.
Conners here usually
brings 'em in more dead than alive.
Yeah, real lucky.
All right, let's go.
The suspense
is killing me.
Why don't you
get to the point...
where I give a damn?
Yes, Mr. Mayor. It looks like it will
now come out of Denver,
head directly south
via Pueblo,
skirt the eastern side
of the Sangre de Cristos
through Cimarron
and then southwest
to Santa Fe.
And come thundering right through
our lovely little town of Legend.
When the tracks are laid,
the Pacific Railroad
will deliver more
business to this town
than you've ever imagined.
Right at my doorstep?
- More or less.
- More or less?
- You better hope more than less.
- Yes, of course.
You see, I have bought
every single piece of
property here in Legend
based on your advice.
And some people have died
based on your advice
here in Legend.
Accidentally, of course.
I can assure you,
their value will
more than triple.
However...
However.
There ain't no howevers.
Your 10% lawyer fee don't
include no howevers.
15%, actually.
How... how... regardless,
I do have to point out,
there is still a parcel of land
that you do not yet own.
- You didn't make 'em an offer yet?
- Oh, yes, I did.
Howev...but they seem
to be stalling.
I fear that if they
see the surveyor,
they may raise
their asking price.
Yeah... Spider'll
take care of that.
- Who?
- Spider.
Spider. Pleasure
to make your acquaintance...
Esquire.
Aw, relax, Garrick.
The future's on its way.
And l'm gonna make sure
you catch the bouquet
at my wedding.
I'm supposed to eat this?
I'm just saying,
I don't know what part
- of the chicken that is.
- Okay, stop it. I'm trying to...
- Can I eat my dinner in peace?
- What would you say that is?
I would say it's something you don't
have to eat, that's what I would say.
- Every town, it's the same thing.
- It's not every town.
No, you pick something out
on your plate you can't identify,
- and suddenly, it's like poison.
- But it's not every town.
But see, I'm also eating with you.
So we eat together.
I know, but you
seem to enjoy it.
Thanks, ma'am.
- It is every town.
- No, it is not.
- I mean, two stops ago...
- How's your supper, gentlemen?
- Just excellent.
- Thank you.
Definitely the best
we've had since, um...
Reno.
For your entertainment
after supper,
there are games
of chance in the back.
And if you wish for some
female companionship,
that's available upstairs.
Just inquire with Billy
at the bar.
Just ask Billy?
Oh, well then...
excuse me, I was just
wondering if, um,
- if you were...
- You might be...
- I mean...
- I only work downstairs.
Of course.
I'm sorry.
She only works
downstairs.
It was an embarrassing question,
but I asked it for your sake.
More for you two?
You know that this stuff's
real strong.
I'll be right back.
Evening, Mary.
You look tired.
You want to take the weight off,
to make up?
I'm... I'm fine, thanks.
I'm busy.
Well, I was, uh...
Hey, piano man!
Stop playing that music!
Can't hear myself think.
Now, Mary... Mary...
I... I was looking for you this morning
before your shift, you know.
- I went ridin'.
- Yeah, you always go ridin'.
- I like to ride.
- Yeah, so do I.
- It's fun.
- I like to ride alone.
Yeah, well...
soon that will change.
You're only gonna wanna
ride with me, yeah?
- Look, Will...
- Yeah?
I'm only workin' here
to keep you from throwing my brother
out of the livery
that we own.
Owned.
And there are some
benefits to being owned.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't plan on sticking
around to find out.
Oh yeah?
Someday...
soon...
I'm gonna stop
asking politely.
My angel.
I gotta... I gotta get to work.
- What the hell are you looking at, Tom?
- Nothing, Will.
Then eat your damn food.
What's the trouble, Will?
The trouble is...
I...I put this
woman on a pedestal
and now I can't
reach her.
Then knock it down.
Make her crawl
back up.
Get off, Velma!
Go make me some money.
I'll be upstairs...
if you care.
Without any pedestals.
You reshoe
our horses yet?
Hey there, Mr. Finch.
Yeah.
I'll get to it,
right when I'm done
finishing off the real
customers' horses.
Mr. Tunney is
your real customer.
And he's also
your boss.
Really?
Well, I thought
this was my livery.
Handed down to me
by my father.
- But...
- And taken by my boss.
You don't like it,
you can always leave.
Without your lovely sister,
of course.
Come on, stable boy,
take your best shot.
Not as dumb as you look.
Wish I could
say the same for you.
What?
Hmm? Hmm?
Huh, boy? Huh?
- What?
- Nothing.
Mr. Tunney and I are
riding out come daybreak.
You have his gray
and my sorrel ready by then.
Yes, sir.
Anything you want,
Mr. Finch.
Just tell Tunney
I'll be right here.
Right where you need me.
Well, hello, stable boy.
Conners.
Look at you.
You're all grown up.
And you're...
and you're hairy and...
and you're kinda scary lookin',
tell you the truth.
So what you been
up to all these years?
Nothing worth talking about.
How's your pop been?
He died about
four years back.
Sorry about that.
Better he ain't around,
seeing his son lose his livery.
- What happened?
- Ah...
it was a weak moment.
Will sent a couple of women of a...
questionable profession
over to my place.
And, uh, there was free
whisky and all that, so,
you know,
stumbled into a saloon,
lost the deed
in two hands.
- You gamble?
- Never.
Those whores had
gotten the best of me.
Yup.
Tunney had it painted
the day after you left.
Well, I should say
Mayor Tunney.
Mayor Tunney?
Yes, sir.
Hmm...You seen Mary yet?
No.
Don't know if I plan to.
Mm...hmm.
Course you don't.
Come on, let's go
get some grub.
Evening.
If you're looking for Velma,
she works out of the saloon.
I'm not looking for Velma.
Let's get
this next reading.
Okay, I just walked
the last two miles.
Fine, then I'm
on the transit.
I am on the transit
in New Mexico,
You are on
the transit in Utah.
Did you just
make that up?
- We'll flip for it.
- Fine, let's flip for it.
- Heads or tails?
- Heads.
- Wait. Tails.
- Tails.
Heads! Heads. Heads.
- I'll take heads, definitely.
- Are you sure now?
Yeah. Wait.
What did I say?
- Heads.
- Fine, heads.
- Heads it is.
- No more go-backs.
Morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning.
- Howdy.
Which one of you
is Griffiths?
- That'd be me.
- That must make you O'Toole.
That's right.
How do you know our names?
Well, you're staying
at my hotel.
Well...
I...I'm hearing that you boys
are running some kind of...
railroad through here?
We're just out here doing
some preliminary measurements.
We're in negotiations
with the person who owns this land
to possibly cut through.
Yeah, well,
negotiations are over.
Landowner signed over dinner.
The steak was a bit rare.
It looks like you drew
your line wrong here.
No. Uh, based
on elevation and incline,
rock and soil samples...
you know, science?
Uh, that is the best place
to lay railroad tracks.
- Best.
- Yeah, well, I'm no surveyor,
but it seems to me...
like the line needs
to go right through here...
town of Legend.
Actually, because
of our instructions, we...
In fact, I'd bet
your life on it,
the both of youse.
And my best advice to you
would be to take
your pencil... go on.
You draw a line
right there.
Go on.
Just move it over
a half an inch.
Oh, that's good.
That's a really good line.
- How do you like it?
- I do, I like it.
Yeah, you do fine work
with that pencil.
Mr., uh...
"Davinky."
- Actually, it's Da Vinci...
- Mm-mm-mm.
- What's that?
- Never mind.
Yeah, well, you just
make sure that the line
stays right where it is.
I'll take this.
Took me almost a year
to make my way back to Alabama
and find
my aunt and uncle.
Things were okay
for a while...
till the war came.
Our farm didn't
have slaves.
We were part of the confederacy
just the same.
Had no choice
but to fight for the gray.
How long were you
in the war?
Too long,
I suspect.
Long enough to know
that God doesn't favor man.
James.
Mary, I...
I've seen too many
terrible things...
terrible things that no God
could just stand by and watch.
- Man is on his own.
- How can you say that, James?
Your father
was a preacher.
And God really favored him.
Do you really believe that?
- I've done too many things, Mary.
- Shh.
Just let go.
Now you do sound
like my father.
Your father
was a great man.
Hey...
I have an idea:
What if we just start over
and we pretend
like you never left?
All these years,
we just stayed the same
in our hearts.
I never did forget, Mary.
All I had to do was
hold onto your ribbon
and I was back home.
That's back here.
I came out here
every day since you left...
just hoping and praying
that you would come home.
I should've came back
a long time ago.
I've gotta ask you...
did you come back
to kill Will Tunney?
'Cause that's the last thing
I ever heard you say.
There's going
to be justice.
But I don't want
no more killing.
I just want to make up
for lost time.
How do you propose
we do that?
Oh, yes, sir.
I think she needs
a new coat...
of paint.
Whoo!
Things are back
on track, Garrick.
I'm gonna take this town
into the 20th century
if I have to drag it
kicking and screaming.
Kicking and screaming.
Excellent, Mr. Mayor.
How wonderful.
Did you know, Garrick,
I never rid
a railroad track before?
Why wait, Tunney?
I'm sure you can catch
a ride anywhere but here.
Ah. And you are?
I'm here to buy
this church.
Well, it ain't for sale.
And it ain't no church.
It was a church.
It was my father's church.
Do you know who this is?
Conners...
Good God Almighty.
All grown up and...
whiskers and all.
I didn't ever think
I'd see your gutless hide
in this town
of Legend again.
That's the amount
my father owed you
on the note
when you killed him.
Take it, count it,
and leave.
Well...
I ain't going nowhere.
You see, I own
this town now.
Yep, all of it mine.
And I'm the mayor,
and soon-to-be husband
of your long-lost Mary.
I suggest you be gone
by sundown, Tunney.
Oh, sundown.
Sundown. Sunny side up.
No, ain't going nowhere.
Okay.
You want to see
what that is? Go on.
What have we here?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I...I remember
that night.
Yeah.
That...that fellow
was in the wrong place
at the right time,
just like your daddy was.
I'm glad to see you
took care of my knife.
You can leave town
now, lawyer.
Uh-uh!
Without those.
Yes, sir. I...I'm leaving
straightaway.
You tell me something, boy.
When you woke up this morning,
did you know
you were gonna die today?
How about you, Tunney?
Did you get up this morning
knowing you were gonna be aired out
like the morning laundry?
No more free drinks
for you tonight, Samuel.
What's the meaning
of this, stranger?
This man is wanted
for the murder
of Nathan Carnes two years ago
in Jamison County.
It was self-defense, Sheriff.
It's no more in self-defense
- than when you murdered my father.
- James? That you?
Your daddy...
was a self-righteous fool
who thought he was better
than the rest of us townsfolk.
Yeah. Jesus was
the son of God.
Your daddy
was a son of a bitch.
Go ahead, shoot.
Finish the job.
Truth is this town needs me
more than it needs you.
I'm the future.
You're the past.
Should have killed you
15 years ago, boy.
Bounty's good
dead or alive, Tunney.
I think I'd prefer dead.
Hey, hold it.
Hold it.
I'm waiting, boy.
I'm waiting.
Don't do it.
Yeah.
You still don't
have the stomach.
Lock him up.
Mary...Mary, what the hell
you doing with him?
Mary, you come
here now. Mary!
Marshal in Jamison
confirmed the killing
of Nathan Carnes
by Mr. Tunney.
Said if we wait a couple days,
he can meet us halfway.
How far is halfway?
You know I get the piles
if I have to ride too far.
Reckon a day and a half,
maybe two.
- All right, we'll wait.
- Whoo!
- Want me to...
- Come on there, Brian.
No no. That's all right, Brian.
Forget it.
- Good night, Sheriff.
- Night.
Night. Mind the bedbugs
don't bite.
If they do,
get a shoe, beat 'em
till they're
black and blue.
Oh, that's
a dumb move, Sheriff.
Sheriff? Sheriff?
Why don't I just get you
a nice "checkmate"?
I'm thinking...
tall,
European,
Velma's the best in town.
No, thanks.
Why not? Not like you
haven't partaken before.
Fortunately, that part of me
no longer has a say in the matter.
How old are you?
- 60? 65?
- 71.
71.
Well, I take
my hat off to you.
You have fulfilled
your civic duty.
It's time for you to, uh,
experience the financial
ease of your twilight years.
10 years ago,
I would have taken you up
on your first offer.
Five years ago, I would have taken
you up on your second.
But right now,
in my twilight years,
all I've earned
is a life of regret.
Checkmate.
I should have locked you up
15 years ago.
Now shut the hell up
or I'll hang you myself.
Let's go, Tunney.
It's judgment day.
Sheriff!
Hold on, hold on.
Let me grab my horse
and I'll ride with you guys.
Well, that's okay, James.
Uh, I'll take it from here.
Hey, he's still my prisoner.
Not anymore.
He's with the law now.
You make sure you
ride straight through.
You can change its color,
but it's still my property.
Load 'em up.
Let's move out.
Mary, don't you do
anything foolish now
that gonna stop you from
wearing white at our wedding.
Mary had a little lamb.
Little lamb.
You'd better go.
Why?
Bad luck. Go!
The barber's waiting
for you. Get!
We are gathered here today
to celebrate the marriage
Of James Conners
and Mary Cooper.
It is a time to rejoice.
And it is also a time
to give thanks to the Lord.
- Okay, hold it up! Hold up! Hold up!
- Whoa.
I gotta rest a minute.
Hey, Sheriff, how's that
long ride treating your behind?
You know something?
Why don't we just turn around...
head back to town for a nice
little drink in my saloon?
Let bygones be bygones.
Turn the other cheek.
What do you say?
Hey, Brian.
Another peep out of him,
you got my permission to blow
him out of the saddle.
Brian, live
and let live, right?
Do you have the rings?
Yes, sir.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Whoa!
Whoo! Six shots, Sheriff.
It's time for you
to reload, by my count.
Now my boys here
would be happy to sit by
and watch you
refill your pistol,
But Spider up there,
you see, he ain't
so obliging.
I now pronounce you,
James and Mary,
husband and wife.
You may now kiss the bride.
Now I'm a decent
Christian fella,
so I'm gonna abide by the law
of live and let live,
turn the other cheek,
if you hand over the key
to these handcuffs. Finch.
Ah, yeah.
Much obliged, Sheriff.
Much obliged.
You know all that stuff
about turn the other cheek?
Well, I lied.
- Congratulations, sis.
- Oh! Thanks, Johnny.
James.
Come here!
Oh. You know,
he don't clean up too bad.
- No, he doesn't.
- Yeah.
You take good care of her.
I will.
So, um, y'all two
headed back to town, or...
No. No, not tonight.
We're not?
I have a surprise for you,
Mr. Conners.
- All right.
- Night, Johnny! Night!
Night!
Time to leave.
Finch, am I still mayor
of this ungrateful little town?
- Yeah, boss.
- Yep.
Then I'm appointing
you sheriff!
Ha ha! That makes you
my deputy, huh, Charles?
Yeah. And your first job is to find
Conners and arrest him.
For what?
For the murder of Sheriff Sanders
and his deputy.
Will!
- Hey! How're you doing?
- Hey!
And where is my lovely
little wife-to-be?
What?
Mary.
I asked you a question.
Where's Mary?
She's celebrating
her wedding.
- Hey!
- Hey.
I guess it's
just me and you.
Me and you, Ruby.
Now you better not
go off and get married.
I'm gonna be the one
that gets married next, if anybody is.
Hey, stable boy.
We interrupt a little
something with your mare?
Oh no, she stopped
listening to me long time ago.
Well, that's a smart horse.
Can I help you fellas
with anything?
Where's your sister's horse?
Don't know.
It's kind of late to be
out riding, isn't it?
I guess.
So where'd they go?
Where did who go?
We're not gonna
play that game.
He doesn't know.
- But I do.
- Yeah? What?
I followed her once,
see where she rides
off to every morning.
That's kind of
disturbing to me, Spider.
Yeah.
You don't want to do that.
Guess who's gonna
win that game.
Spider, why don't you
take that from him?
Easy now.
Whew.
Give me your hand, boy.
Give me...
your gun hand.
I'm pretty good
with either one.
Show me.
I'll take this one.
We...we could have been
brothers-in-law,
you know that?
You know what, Mr. Tunney?
You're gonna get yours.
Maybe not in this life,
but you're gonna get yours.
Yeah.
You son of a bitch.
Spider, take care of that.
Good evening,
Mr. Conners.
Good evening, Mrs. Conners.
This is quite the honeymoon spot
you picked out for us.
Yeah. Yeah,
I thought you'd like it.
I do.
Let's never
leave here, James.
- From this spot?
- Yeah.
From this spot.
Let's build our house here
and raise our children
by this creek,
grow old together.
Okay.
Can we wait till the morning?
Yes. I love you.
I love you too.
Am I too late?
What...what are you
doing here, Will?
I asked you a question, Mary.
Am I too late?
Will, leave us alone.
Once upon a time,
there was a little girl called Mary.
And she could
have had a future.
She could have been...
Mrs. Mayor Tunney
because he loved her
and he'd have
given her the world.
But Mary,
well, she had
a little lamb...
a little lamb.
Little lamb.
Don't...Will!
Will, stop! Don't...
So then the big bad wolf
came to town...
and he huffed,
and he puffed,
- and he made her a widow.
- Don't! Will!
- Will!
- He made her...
Don't! Will, stop it!
- ...A whore!
- Stop it!
Just like he should
have done a long time ago.
Will, no! No! Don't!
Stop it!
Leave him alone!
Please please
please please!
You say hello
to your daddy for me.
- You want to save him?
- Yes.
- Go.
- No!
No!
Mary?
Ma... Mary?
You kill him... slow.
You make him feel the pain.
Make him feel the pain.
It's time,
bounty hunter.
Oh no.
Oh no, Mary.
He's dead now.
Well, uh, sun's coming up.
Sun's coming up, babe.
You wake up.
You sleep awhile.
Yeah, you...
He'll bleed a long
slow painful death.
You sleep good.
Miakoda.
Miakoda!
No!
Stop it!
- Whore! Whore!
- What's going on in there?
Leave me be.
Come on, Velma.
- Mary! Mary!
- It's all right. It's all right.
He... he wants
another bottle.
He's been drinking
for days.
Don't look to me
for pity.
Wait. Wait, Velma.
Velma.
Velma!
Your fever has broken.
You rest.
Mary.
Where is she?
I am Miakoda.
I'm James.
James. The bible
by King James.
You speak English
very well.
I learned
on the reservation.
Life is not good there.
Many Navajo have died.
That was you
who helped us.
There were several others
that escaped as well.
Thank you.
Your husband doesn't
seem to like me very much.
Washakie is my brother.
He is not trusting
of the white man.
Our parents were killed
at our home in Tsegi
by your Kit Carson.
I'm trying to forgive them
for what they have done.
"Turn the other cheek"
as your god says.
I've tried that.
It doesn't work.
- You are still weak.
- I'll be fine.
What did he say?
I said you are
foolish white man...
and we should have
left you to die.
What's going on?
Hey, boss.
How're you feeling?
I asked you
a question.
We haven't been able
to find Garrick.
And, uh, all the deeds
have been given back
to their original owners,
So I'd say
we're pretty much, uh...
Do not even dare
to venture an opinion.
Okay, sorry, boss.
Yeah, well...
Pacific Railroad...
and them bigwigs
coming into town
to do their dog
and pony show,
we're gonna need
to get them deeds back.
From everyone in town?
Does that answer
your question?
We're gonna need more men.
How many?
Many cockroaches
as you can find.
Turn over every rock
in this town.
Yes, sir.
I have decided
that this town
and the people in it
do not deserve
what I am gonna
bring to them!
Anyway, I'm gonna...
uh, clean up.
You'd better hope I'm
in a better mood tomorrow.
She was beautiful,
the woman who passed.
She was my wife.
I am sorry.
There are wonderful things
in your God's book about death
that are like
my people's beliefs.
I'm sorry,
but I'm all out of beliefs
for one lifetime.
We have all suffered
a great loss.
But it is the valleys
that we learn from...
and not the hills.
Sounds like poetry, Miakoda.
When I hold this ribbon
in my hand,
all I see
is blackness in my heart.
It is not blackness you see.
It is only a shadow.
You saved my life.
We saved each other's.
I am grateful.
It was you who
gave us the knife.
It is an old
Navajo saying.
It means he who
saves a life
shares his debt
with those he saves.
Well, that doesn't
sound too bad.
It is for him.
You'll do what is right
for your heart.
I know.
Goodbye, Miakoda.
Hey hey... wha... wha...
It's me.
How'd you two
get away?
Where's Mary?
Huh-uh. No. No.
Look at me.
- Mary, no.
- It ends here.
Okay. Wait.
Wait. James.
Hello there.
- Hi.
- Come on, Penny.
- What, Mother?
- Not yet, all right? Just wait.
Come on.
I know, come on!
You need to cover
yourself up, James. Here's a coat.
- Where's your horse at?
- Out behind the general store.
We can reach the marshal
up in Jamison.
Maybe by tomorrow morning,
but we gotta leave right now.
I'm not going anywhere.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna take them all on by yourself?
Sheriff Sanders is dead;
his deputies dead.
Will killed them all.
Without the law,
Tunney and his men,
they control
the whole damn town.
Not for long.
Hey. Hey!
You promised my sister.
What?
I told her
not to marry you.
What did you say?
I told her she'd
be making a mistake.
You ain't the same
person we once knew.
I told her you ain't a man
who settles down to a family.
She said I was wrong.
She said that you'd changed
your old desperate ways.
She said that
you promised her,
and I believed her.
Listen to me, James.
If you go against everything
that Mary believed in
and you get yourself
killed doing it,
well, then you destroy
any chance you have
of being together
at your end.
I'm sorry, Johnny.
Well, hold up. Conners, all right,
I'll make a deal with you.
Just... just ride
with me to Jamison.
We'll talk to the marshal.
And if he don't agree
to take in Tunney, then...
well, we'll take him
down together.
All of them. I promise.
Finch!
- Let's go!
- It can't be.
Yeah?
Hey, boss!
James is still alive.
You want to repeat
that for me?
Him and, uh,
Mary's brother
rode out of town,
and they were in a heck of a hurry.
Well...
they're heading
for Jamison to get the marshal.
Why don't you go
get them first?
And find me Spider.
Hey! Hey! Whoa!
We need
to rest them some.
And we need a place
to bed come nightfall.
Got any suggestions?
I ain't never been
out of town this far before.
Fine.
Come on, Ruby.
James, what are
you doing?
What's she doing?
Hey, did you see Mary's horse over here?
No no no no no no!
Washakie, Washakie, he's my friend!
- Washakie!
- Please, let him go.
You know this savage?
No! Ow!
He didn't mean that.
He didn't mean that. Apologize!
Are you serious?
- He understands English.
- For whatever I said, I'm sorry!
See?
Washakie, he's sorry.
Please please,
let him go. Let him go.
Ow!
What did I say?
Howdy, ma'am.
Mm.
This is some pretty
amazing stew there, Mia...
Uh, Mida? Mayday...
Miakoda.
Miakoda. Hm, that's...
that's a pretty name.
If you head straight,
you will come to a creek.
Once you pass twin rocks,
follow it to Jamison.
The moon will show you the way.
- They should stay the night.
- No.
It is dangerous for all of us
if they do not keep moving.
He's right.
Thanks again, Miakoda.
I'll come back here
after I see the marshal.
It is time for us to move on.
We will be gone by then.
Here.
You keep it.
You are doing the right thing.
Mia... koda?
Miakoda?
Thanks again for that stew.
It really hit the spot.
And, uh, thanks to both
of y'all for...
Johnny! Johnny!
We got 'em.
James, don't go! Don't!
Stay here.
Hey hey hey hey hey!
Stay with Miakoda.
She will be fine.
This is not your fight.
Your fights
are now my fights.
- Where are they, Finch?
- Shh.
- Finch, where are they?
- Shut up.
Finch? Finch!
We took care
of Mary's brother,
but, uh, Charlie
got killed.
Well, I am deeply
saddened by that news.
Where's the body?
I want to see James's body.
Had to leave him there.
But I... I scared off his horse.
Yeah, well,
he won't be needing
that horse no more, will he?
What I'm trying to say is
James is still alive.
He had this Injun with him.
- That's who killed Charlie.
- He what?
He had this Injun with him,
and that's who killed Charlie.
So I had to leave him.
How many men you got
rustled up for this meeting?
Should be half dozen.
Yeah, Spider
counts as six.
Okay, we'll go after James
after the meeting.
Where are the people?
Shh shh.
They must all be
in the church.
What's your plan?
We go on in there to take down
the man who murdered my wife.
I'm not used
to being the hunter.
Usually I am the hunted.
That is why
I like this plan.
Evening, fine folks
of Legend.
I am T.S. McKinley,
the Pacific-West representative
for the Pacific Railroad.
Thank you, thank you.
As you know,
the Pacific Railroad
is laying tracks
in this area,
which will make Legend
one of its many stops.
Uh, that means that there will
be a whole lot of new people
and products coming
to your businesses.
- Furthermore...
- Beg your pardon, sir.
Yes, sir?
This is the first
we've heard of the railroad.
Yeah!
Well, th...
that's impossible.
We sent word months ago
with several updates.
To who? We didn't
hear about it.
That's right!
Now now, calm down. Calm down.
We sent them to your mayor's office.
All right, we gotta
take out these two guys.
Where are they going?
- Miakoda!
- What is she doing?
Let's go.
Hey there.
Lose your way off
the reservation camp?
My partner's talking
to you, lndian girl.
She doesn't understand
a word we're saying, do you?
Man, oh man,
you are a pretty one.
I'm looking for a light-haired
man named James.
Well, look at that.
She can talk.
Can you tell me
where to find him?
Sure. Climb off and I'll
take you right to him.
You can handle things
while the little redskin and I
go look for her friend?
Now my lawyer
and political adviser
Mr. Garrick Haring
advised me to buy land.
Like everyone else
in this town, I am also a businessman...
And a thief!
Is that true, Mayor?
Well, now obviously
Mr. Garrick Haring
was keeping
the information, uh,
of a railroad deal
to himself,
and benefiting from
my personal investments,
of which he was to make
a very generous 50%
However, I was
falsely arrested,
thrown in jail, Mr. Garrick Haring
was run out of town,
and these townsfolk have
reneged on these contracts
which you all signed,
handing over your properties to me.
I now own your land by law.
I get her
when you're done.
If there's
anything left.
You should not
have come here, Miakoda!
This is wrong, Washakie,
and you know it.
This is his destiny.
You mustn't do this.
James, if you do this,
you will have nothing!
Washakie, get her
out of here.
I will not run or hide
from my beliefs.
Then that's your decision.
You will stay here.
We were forced to sell
our land to the mayor!
Yeah! Yeah!
Why don't you sell us
the land back?
Well, my friend,
I would like to help you out,
from the bottom
of my heart.
But I only own
50% of your properties.
And I never
go back on a deal.
What deal?
However, you may
rest assured
that your businesses
are gonna prosper
because of all
of this new currency
which is a-rolling in
from out there...
- through Legend.
- To your pockets!
Not if you overcharge
us for that land!
- That's right!
- Well, I don't see that happening
in the foreseeable future.
All right, break it up!
Sorry, folks.
Just want to say support
our mayor 100%.
Why, thank you, Spider.
Uh, as you can see,
Mr. McKinley,
we are all very excited
about the prospect
of a railroad coming
through Legend.
And we look forward to Legend
being your favorite stop.
In fact, you are now
standing in what will be
Legend's railroad depot.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I am going to go
to the saloon
and get drunk, and celebrate
this momentous occasion.
If anybody would care to join me?
Please, the drinks are on me.
For half an hour at least.
I remember you.
Let's raise hell!
Yeah! All right!
We need a bottle!
Where is everybody?
Phil and Bob, customers!
Where the hell
is my piano player?
I didn't give nobody
the night off.
Velma! Velma!
Get your
daddy longlegs down here!
There was supposed to be
six men with us.
One, two, three, four
was obviously enough,
- with Spider.
- Yeah, where is Spider?
Spider... Spider don't drink.
Finch, whiskey, now!
Make sure it ain't that
watered-down public swill.
Come on.
I feel lucky tonight.
Yes, sir, which one of you
is new to the game?
Oh, yeah.
Will.
Yes, sir.
- Will!
- What?
Get up, Tunney!
That sure was exciting.
Dang, you've gone
and shot all my men.
And I had the winning hand.
I sure done raised hell
when I killed your pappy, boy.
Why won't you
just let me be?
I'll tell you what...
you name your price,
anything you want
in the world, it's yours.
Just name it.
- I only want one thing.
- Anything.
I want Mary back.
Will she do?
She'll do. Yes, sir.
Nice and easy.
I'm just gonna
take my coat here,
catch me a breath
of fresh air, right outside.
Nice and easy does it.
Spider, if I weren't so cheap,
I'd give you a raise.
Well, what have we here?
Huh? I don't normally
get requests for redskins,
but my own personal tastes,
oh, they run wild
like the west wind. Mm.
Easy does it.
Okay.
Spider...
I want you to give me
a good head start here.
We're not going
anywhere.
Well... adios.
Okay, Chief.
No more Injun talk.
Chief?
Shh.
Here we go.
- That was not nice.
- Hyaa!
Washakie!
I will be fine.
- Washakie.
- What you do now
must be done on your own.
Only friendship,
my brother.
James!
I've been looking
all over for you!
James!
Bye, James.
Your mother,
God rest her soul,
- would be very proud of you, boy.
- Yes, Father.
Remember what I taught you.
Forgive men their sins,
and the Almighty
will forgive you yours.
Come on, boy!
Whoo-hoo!
That was a lucky shot.
So! Still ain't got
the guts to kill me, huh?
This ain't your town
no more, boy.
This is my town now.
What the hell are you
still doing here?
Your daddy, your wife,
your daddy's church...
they all gone.
This is my town.
It's my future.
Yeah!
I am the decider here,
and you are history, boy.
What was it your daddy
said to you before he died?
He said...
"Forgive men their sins
that He may
forgive you yours."
Now, tell me something,
can you find a little
forgiveness for me...
in your heart,
before I blow
a hole in it? Hmm?
You look at me, boy.
Look at me.
You look deep in my eyes
with all that hate.
Yeah.
You can't hide
from me, boy.
Come on, do it!
I know you got it there.
Bring it on, boy.
Yeah!
You can't
kill me, boy.
You just can't kill me.
You want to know why?
Huh?
Well, your daddy said it.
He said to you, killing me,
that don't make you
any better than me.
You understand?
You don't want to disappoint
your daddy, do you?
You don't want to fail
our lovely Mary?
You want to see them
in heaven, right?
Or you want to walk
down my path?
No.
No, you don't.
Better say your prayers, boy.
What the...
I guess I failed.
Subtitles by Bishop
Hungary 2009.
Dedicated to Arthur H. Ament
Justin Ament's Grandfather