FILMMAKER: RAYMOND CHOW
PRODUCER: LEONARD HO
SCREENPLAY: MA WU, ANTHONY CHAN
ALFRED CHEUNG, BARRY WONG
DIRECTOR: SAMMO HUNG
The war game is over.
Who are you? Where are you from?
No, it is only a misunderstanding.
What has happened?
He stole my pocket watch.
And he stole my gold ring.
No, there must be a misunderstanding.
Take him back.
Start dancing.
Come on.
Let's have a smile.
Stop him, quick.
I'm going to be rich.
Ching Fong Tin, forgive my action.
I did that so you won't escape again.
You have a thick layer of fat.
You won't freeze to death.
Polar bears
don't freeze to death, do they?
Polar bears do starve to death though.
- Have some coffee.
- Thank you.
Loi Fook, take the bag of money
to buy a piece of land.
Release me now and then arrest me later.
It makes no difference.
My main weakness in life
is that I value justice and honesty.
The money is the evidence
to guarantee you a life sentence.
Ching Fong Tin?
Let me go! Let me go!
Let me go right now or we will both die.
This is very dangerous.
I won't let go!
We are both going to die!
Ching Fong Tin,
I will catch you one day. You watch out!
Listen up, wait for me at the riverbed.
I'm going to Shanghai to catch the train.
Hijack it when it arrives at the riverbed.
We coordinate from the inside
and attack from the outside.
- Remember, avoid monkey business.
- Yes.
You lot come with me,
and you go with them.
Let's go!
Brother Jen,
I hope we didn't come all this way
to watch your brother
playing with the model train.
Shi Yu, please explain
your plan in detail to the brothers.
I need a simple way to explain it. You
might not understand complex details.
We've led a rough life since youth,
pretentious words mean nothing to us.
I am grateful that
brother Jen has found good people
like you from such a class to help out.
I don't have to worry now.
What do you mean? We have always been
honest and open to brother Jen.
- How dare you distrust us?
- Not at all. I was just a bit worried earlier.
Now that I know you all are so outspoken,
my worries were unfounded.
Shi Yu, just get to the point, can you?
A train will be arriving at Chengdu,
from Shanghai, in 20 days.
Everyone on it is either wealthy
or of high status.
Most importantly, there is
a Japanese ambassador, Yukio Fushiki.
He will be carrying a map
of Qin Emperor's Terracotta Army.
Yukio Fushiki is pretending
to be sightseeing in Chengdu.
His real aim is to smuggle
the map to Guangzhou.
He'll bring the map back to Japan
through Hong Kong.
Once we get the map,
we'll give it to Shi Yu.
We don't ask
what he's going to do with it.
The reward is that you will get
100,000 dollars once you finish the job.
100,000 dollars!
Correct. You will also get
all the valuables of the passengers.
Tell us your plan immediately!
I'll go to Shanghai with you
and catch that train.
Your brothers,
who are waiting under the bridge...
Train robbery attracts the attention
of the police and guards quickly.
Don't worry. There is not a living soul
within a ten-mile radius of the bridge.
11 or 12 miles
before approaching the bridge,
there is a small town called Han Shui.
However it is poor and isolated,
it will not create any threat to us.
If robbing a train
will turn us into millionaires,
I won't care if we are chased
by the government army.
Good. Let's make it a deal.
About 350 miles to the west is a town
with magnificent scenery and great talent.
Can you walk slower?
Take your sisters and come with me
to make your living there.
Whatever you say.
I miss you. Do you know that?
You have lost a lot of weight.
You will be rich
after working there for a year or so.
You can even go straight and get married.
I can't wait that long.
I want to get married now...
Calm down.
Calm down!
Someone is watching.
Never mind me, go ahead.
Haven't you seen this before,
you nosy man?
To be honest,
I really haven't seen it before.
I am sorry. We are finishing off,
not warming up.
No need to be so polite.
It is at your discretion after all.
I didn't intend to pay anyway
so don't worry about it.
I'm going home to sleep now.
Stand there, Ching Fong Tin.
What do you want?
Me to owe you for the rest of my life?
What do you owe me?
The kindness of loving.
You just saved five of us.
At least let me offer myself to you.
You are not a man if you
wouldn't accept such a simple thing.
Let me tell you this, I've slept
with every woman I know except you...
and my mother.
Let me keep this dream alive.
I assume you are sincere.
Do I have to wait for you until I am 60?
Am I happy to have head lice
and make out with old ladies?
Go home and get some sleep.
HAN SHUI TOWN
Clear sky and windy, as usual.
Chief, they are all set and ready.
An order from you to light up a match
and the big fire starts.
The firemen are all fast asleep,
so who will put the fire out?
No need to care about that.
We just need to "set" advantage and rob.
It is "take" advantage and rob.
When everyone is trying to put out the fire,
we'll take advantage and get rich.
I will decide when a good time is.
Chief, we are all ready.
What do you mean?
You told us to start a fire.
We are all ready.
To start a fire?
I am the one and only
security chief of this town.
Would I ever
ask anyone to start a fire here?
Chief, Madam Qi is deaf.
There are no other people around
for you to worry about.
She really is deaf?
Ask her about it.
Madam Qi, I am talking to you.
Can you hear me?
Nothing. I can't hear a word.
So, be more careful next time.
- What are you doing?
- There is a fire!
Don't be bothered by it.
Let's mind our own business.
The fire is big. Look!
I only care if it spreads here.
Go back to work.
Fire! Fire!
Fire. Come and put it out quickly.
Let's go!
Get out of the way!
Be quick!
Wild Bull, go and find the source.
Sand bucket team,
put the fire out from the left.
Duvet team, rescue people from the right.
- Where is the ladder?
- We took it to catch sparrows last night.
- Find it immediately!
- Yes.
Help! Help! Help!
Prepare the emergency net.
Jump down quickly!
Jump down.
- I am scared!
- Jump down.
Get the stretcher.
Don't worry, I'll get you out of here!
The fire is too big.
Then use the rope.
Catch it.
Siu Lan, you'd have closed your eyes
if you were afraid.
It would make no difference
if I closed them or not.
Get ready!
One, two, three.
- Siu Lan, are you alright?
- I am fine.
Put out the fire quickly.
Get changed and start our operation.
What are you doing?
Covering my face
so no one can recognize me.
Shut up and go!
We'll be rich, very rich!
Things are set and now
you just have to be smart.
Grab as many valuables as you can.
Go now!
What are you doing?
- What do you want?
- Don't move!
- True, what do we want by the way?
- Wait for Big Brother to give the order.
Big Brother, come in.
We have taken control of the situation.
- You are having bad luck.
- What do you want?
Too much. I want your mum
to call me her son-in-law,
I want to sleep with your older sister
and have a baby with your younger one.
But I only want to rob the bank right now.
Get on with it.
Siu Hou! Ka Lok!
- What is it?
- Help pump the water!
Quickly, quickly.
Robbery! Robbery!
Come quickly.
Be quick! Be quick!
- Let me help you.
- I can easily stride over, you dumb fool.
- Where are the horses?
- They are all gone!
- What should we do?
- We'd better go too.
Catch them. Don't let them go!
- The security team?
- Why are you so surprised?
I agree.
Chief did it, why couldn't we?
- What should we do?
- Lock them up. Deal with the fire first.
It is as dusty as the Silk Road here.
Didn't you say we were catching the train?
I didn't say that.
I said "jumping on" the train.
We will jump on the train
and go to Chengdu to make a living.
- Are things ready?
- Yes.
Be ready for it but be calm,
the train won't arrive for a while.
- The train doesn't stop here.
- That doesn't mean we can't jump on it.
He is ridiculous.
Mayor, say something,
something that will inspire people.
Like what? It will only be a lie anyway.
There'll be a riot soon
if you don't say something.
Dear brothers
and senior members of the town,
what happened today is a tragedy.
The money that everyone earned
by working hard is all gone.
Your dreams are all destroyed.
The hope of arresting Jook Bo to get
your money back is nearly non-existent.
Han Shui Town has little to offer now.
This is not a place to build a future.
There has to be somewhere else to go.
I hope everyone stays calm
in this disheartening situation,
and goes their own way,
searching for their own path.
Finished.
What's wrong with you?
Those words were discouraging.
I just want to be honest.
Let me say something.
Be quiet, be quiet!
Being our security chief,
Jook Bo should have set us an example.
He is now our enemy.
Yes.
The money Jook Bo took
was earned through our hard labor.
- The money is ours!
- Yes.
We have to defeat our enemy
and get back our money.
Yes.
The problem is we need people
who are not afraid of losing their lives
to participate in this mission.
Who do you think we should ask?
- Mayor, who shall it be?
- You!
OK.
- From now on he is the one in charge.
- Good, good.
My dear,
I'm worried I may get a headache,
traveling for over ten days on the train.
- Headache?
- Yes.
Don't worry,
I will get you some dried prunes.
Be careful. This is Shanghai,
not a rural small town. Act appropriately.
- Don't attract attention.
- OK.
Miss, can I buy
a packet of dried prunes please?
- Of course.
- Thank you.
See you on the train later.
Buy some tangerines.
Miss, I want a tangerine.
- You...
- No need to thank me.
Dear, here come the dried prunes.
What is wrong with you?
I'll get thirsty with so many of them.
Thirsty?
Of course you will.
I will buy you some tangerines.
- I need to buy some tangerines.
- There aren't any more.
Forget it. Here is your ticket.
I'll visit you when there is a chance.
Han!
- Dear, there are no tangerines left.
- Don't worry. Let's go over there.
- What a lovely coincidence, Master Wong.
- Of course, Master Sek.
You are just very lucky.
Fei Hung, greet Master Sek.
Master Sek.
Kin, greet Master Wong.
Master Wong.
Your dear son has grown so much.
What an intelligent lad he has become.
- Father, he has an evil look.
- Shut up.
Sorry, Master Sek, my son has always
been so unscrupulously honest.
Kin, give them a smile.
- Are you keeping well?
- Thanks to the good fortune you brought.
"Stealing peaches"?
- Fei Hung!
- Father.
- Suppress your anger.
- Yes.
- Your attention please, the train...
- Kin, don't be impolite.
- Yes, father.
- ... minutes will be leaving.
- All passengers, please board the train.
- Master Sek, after you.
- Master Wong, after you.
- In that case, we will go first.
Silly boy, a monkey steals peaches
like this, not like that.
- Remember this from now on.
- I will, Father.
Where have you been? Get on now.
Let me tell you this,
I want a seat, and a bed to sleep on.
Fine, fine, just get on the train.
- Give me the ticket?
- No need. Just get on.
Chief Inspector, do we really
have to search every compartment?
Of course, this is our job.
Chief Inspector, Shanghai City.
I am conducting a routine search.
You can't carry weapons
unnecessarily on the train!
Did you hear me?
If it's useful, then it's a different matter.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Why has the train started?
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Excuse what, I'm the train chief.
Why has the train started?
Of course it has.
Why else would people get on it?
I don't care. I have to get off.
- You want to get off?
- Yes.
I am the Chief Investigator of Shanghai
City. I have many cases to solve.
Let me get off immediately.
You couldn't get off,
even if you were the Emperor.
Then I will book you
for interfering with police duty.
You must get off then.
- I don't care how you do it, I must get off.
- Fine.
Get off then.
What's wrong with
Jook Bo and his people,
their underpants
were considered a public expense?
- Are you done?
- Yes, we are.
Then let's go.
- Curry, you are on night watch.
- Again?
There's nothing to do
except feed the mosquitoes.
That means you have been skiving
every night to catch sparrows?
This is a small town
with everything in sight.
No one from out of town
will bother to come here.
Well, there might be ghosts.
Don't let me see you skiving
or your wage will be deducted.
Yes.
Wild Bull, watch the town gate.
Ga Lok, patrol the streets.
Chief, it is unbearably windy
at the town gate.
And the streets are full of dust.
- How about swapping duty?
- Good...
- It was your fault.
- It was you who screwed things up...
Chief, what should I do?
- Pack up things at the fire station.
- Sure.
Big sister,
this is what you called "a town of
magnificent scenery and great talent"?
Whether the scenery is magnificent
or not is a matter of opinion.
But this is definitely
a place of great talent,
otherwise it wouldn't have produced
someone as talented as Tin.
Love is blind, didn't I say so?
Watch your mouth and your behavior.
From now on, pretend that you're
from good and prestigious families.
Where is Siu Chui?
Don't play around or they may be
able to tell you are a lady of the street.
- Come on, get in, get in.
- Let's get in then.
Anyone in here?
Is there anyone in here?
- It is so dusty...
- Very dirty...
- How can anyone live here?
- Clean it and it will be fine.
- Do you want a room?
- Five rooms, please.
- Sure. Please come with me.
- Follow him upstairs.
- Tin!
- Go upstairs.
Uncle, I was going to look for you.
Why have you come back here?
You didn't even come back
for your mother's funeral.
Do you know how much the town folks
had to suffer because of what you did?
I promised Mother a triumphant return.
I assume this is the emperor's gown?
Let me through.
- Chief.
- This is Ching Fong Tin?
No, he is just my friend.
No. I am Ching Fong Tin.
Were you the one who blew up the dam?
I just wanted the town folks
to have more water to use.
- What happened afterwards?
- They had no water to use.
You are not welcome here.
Please leave immediately.
This is my home town.
Where else can I go?
I don't care. Leave immediately!
Chief, I heard that he is very good.
It would be an embarrassment for you
if you lost to him.
Go now. They won't forgive you.
Chief, let's not make it a big issue.
No!
He should be punished
for what he has done!
Slap, slap.
Now I have punished you. Let's go.
I have taught you a lesson for now.
Watch yourself or I'll arrest you.
- Let's go!
- Let us through.
Don't play with fire.
Don't do that.
You'll hurt yourself and others.
What are you doing here?
Do you really believe
that things will get better after my return?
Yes, I always believe you.
- Help her to get up.
- Yes.
Chief, chief.
Ching Fong Tin bought all the shops,
including butcher shops, hotels...
You have said them all.
What is the fat boy trying to do?
- Cancel the shift system.
- Are we on holiday?
In your dreams. From now on,
everyone has to work all shifts.
That's impossible.
Siu Hou, follow Ching Fong Tin day
and night. Don't let him out of your sight.
Yes.
He must be plotting something.
Wealthy people and their money
will be passing here so be prepared.
Remember, it is quality over quantity.
It is better to rob a bank
then to rob ten grocery stores.
Chief Tsao, can I help you?
As the security chief,
I am just doing my routine inspection.
- Please come in.
- All right.
Chief Tsao.
- Chief Tsao.
- Why don't you get a chair for the chief?
- Yes.
Let me.
Chief Tsao, please sit down.
Chi, come back over here.
I would like to but I can't.
Chief Tsao is leaning on
my hand with his muscular back.
- I am sorry.
- Thank you.
I don't understand why you ladies
came all the way to this poor town?
Obviously, we would like to broaden
our knowledge by traveling here.
Chief Tsao, even though we are women,
times have changed
and we must broaden our knowledge
to serve society in future.
- What a great aspiration.
- Not me.
I'd like to get married to a good man
and be a good wife and a good mother.
- I bet you do.
- What did you mean by that?
Sorry to have bothered you.
I am going now.
- Bye.
- Come by when you have time.
Everything is arranged now.
The big customers are coming soon.
From now on, wear more make-up and
perfume. Prepare for future business.
- You bring all these girls to...
- Doing business is not a crime...
- One occupation is as good as another.
- Yes. After all, we run a beauty salon.
That's a prestigious business.
Isn't that right, Chief Tsao?
True.
Chi, keep him occupied
so that he doesn't have time to bother me.
I'll make sure
that he even has to find time to breathe.
Be careful,
I treasure my status of lady.
Chief Tsao.
Tsao Cheuk Kin!
Tsao Cheuk Kin, I haven't seen you
for 15 years and you haven't changed.
Miss, when have I ever met you?
I didn't say that.
I just said I hadn't seen you for 15 years.
15 years?
You don't remember this.
We met in a dream 15 years ago.
We were holding hands
and strolling in the rain.
It was so romantic.
Unfortunately it was in a dream.
You remembered we met in a dream
for all these years?
Miss, are you all right?
Yes. Only my heart may not be.
Miss, I think you have a high fever.
Not really. I just have a fever for you.
- I am in love with you...
- Stop there...
I am busy
and I shall leave you to your dreams.
Don't go away!
By the way, no one
would believe you if you were crazy.
But if you were just after lust,
I assume I have satisfied you.
But I am sorry
if you wanted to become rich.
Working for the government,
I'm only paid peanuts.
Give me a kiss.
Truly after lust.
I'll rape you, you bitch.
What did he just say?
Who understands English? Tell me.
He said the Chinese are sons of bitches.
Chief ordered us not to get into trouble.
Give me some face.
No way, he insulted the Chinese.
Insults are made
to those who deserve them.
We clearly saw all that happened.
We are brothers and we shouldn't fight
each other over small disputes.
He was right to do this
but he was a bit rude.
He will be punished for that.
Be more polite next time.
Go back to where you were working.
Don't ever start any fights again.
Master Sek,
no need to lose your temper.
Of course, of course.
- Fei Hong, suppress your anger.
- Yes.
- Fei Hong.
- It wasn't me, it wasn't me.
Little boys aren't that strong.
It's shameful to kick
when you're wearing leather shoes!
An eye for an eye.
Gentlemen,
food will be ready at the canteen soon.
- How many more tunnels will there be?
- No more, no more.
If there were,
I would have changed into a short tunic.
How can you panic
at such a crucial moment?
How can I trust you?
You are not even as good as a horse.
What about you? You rode me instead
of a horse. I got so many injuries.
I didn't want to injure my horse.
It'll be useful when the train arrives.
Stupid!
Then pray that the horse doesn't panic.
The horse won't collapse like I did when
you fell, so you'd roll under the train,
would be cut into pieces,
your eyeballs gauged out,
your limbs dismembered
and your head chopped off.
Your ears cut off
and your nose ripped off. Your brain...
Shut up!
Spit out all the bad luck and say it again!
Big brother,
why are you polishing rusty metal?
It's not the rusty metal, it's a magnet.
What is it for?
So that I don't have to worry
if the horse panics or whatever.
I'll definitely be able
to get on the Chengdu train.
Are you done yet?
- Yes.
- Hard work?
Let me see.
Give them all to me.
- Are you done yet?
- Yes.
Ready?
I thought only opposites attract.
- I think only one person can use them.
- You are right. You are definitely right.
- How have I been treating you?
- Good, like a real younger brother.
You will give them up
for the younger brother?
Are you crazy? The younger brother
should always respect the older one.
Shut up and stop arguing.
It could damage our good kinship.
- Good view up here.
- Yes, it is quite beautiful up here.
For how long can you follow me?
How clever of you to uncover
my expert shadowing technique.
I am now going to vanish immediately.
Chief!
I had been following him very closely...
- You let him off.
- Yes.
You fat boy!
I will catch you sooner or later.
Ching Fong Tin, I have always known
you are up to no good.
Do you not know how many lives will
be at risk if you blow up the track?
Do you know how many people
live in Han Shui Town?
I want the train to stop here
so all passengers from the Millionaires'
Express stay in Han Shui town,
and stay in our hotels,
buy our products and the food we make.
And spend money on hookers.
The money is not for me. The money
stays here when there is a profit.
The town folks would rather starve
to death than promote a hooker business.
Tsao Cheuk Kin, this is my only
chance to pay the town back.
Don't even think about stopping me.
Come on.
You want to escape?
Come on!
We'll be arriving at the riverbed soon.
Everyone go and get ready.
Check how many passengers
there are on the train.
Walk on the roof.
Stop the train when you get to the front.
Yes.
Hold, hold, hold...
Hold, hold...
Han, why are you holding?
Hold...
Use the toilet if you are desperate.
There is no need to hold it.
Of course. I didn't think of that.
Han.
- How are you?
- I am fine. And you?
I am fine.
- But I have to leave now.
- So soon?
It's stolen love, after all.
I am leaving now.
- I'll be back soon.
- Be careful.
See you later.
Feeling much better?
- Why are you making that sound?
- I couldn't go before.
- I think I can go now.
- Then go to the toilet right now.
- Remember not to get so close to me.
- Fine.
It is coming!
Ride, ride. Get away from me.
I told you not to get that close to me.
Don't worry, I'm not magnetic.
You're still putting me off.
Go away.
My feet are caught.
Help!
Help! Help!
- Someone is here.
- Don't worry, he might not see us.
And even if he did,
he might not know what we want to do.
You two, what are you doing?
See, he really doesn't know
what we are doing.
- We are just taking a stroll.
- Taking a stroll?
Be calm. He might not have
seen that we are handcuffed.
Even if he has,
he won't know what we want to do.
Go somewhere else to break the chain.
Damn, he knows.
So what? He might not understand why.
Go further away.
Move over here.
Move back over there.
Lie down straight.
Excuse me, something doesn't seem right.
- What is it?
- There are two rail tracks here.
How do we know
which one the train will come on?
Stupid, left is for coming
and right is for going.
So is the train coming or going?
- It could be either.
- Of course.
Excuse me, excuse me.
On second thoughts, let's stay on the
same side so we'll be in the same boat.
- As you wish.
- Good.
BEWARE OF TRAINS
- It is getting very loud.
- Put some stones in your ears.
Why the hell has the train stopped?
What has happened?
Help! Fat lady, come
and help me down please, quickly.
You are the fat one.
My dear?
I am here, my dear.
- What are you doing there?
- I am coming.
You said you were going to the toilet.
The toilet stinks
so I went over there instead, you know.
Help! Help!
- Thank you very much.
- My pleasure.
Get up!
Chief, they escaped from the prison.
What shall we do to them?
Catch them too.
Welcome to Han Shui Town,
a place of magnificent scenery
and great talent.
Despite being held up on your journey,
the town folks have already
prepared food, accommodation
and entertainment for you all
so that you can relax and enjoy.
Please come with me.
- Shall we go with him?
- We might as well.
Please come with me.
It is very near. Please come with me.
Watch them and I'll catch him.
What shall we do now?
Send someone to the riverbed
and bring the brothers here.
We will carry out the plan
in Han Shui Town.
Wai, you go.
Get someone to watch the Japanese.
Get on the train and watch them.
He is trouble. He always gets in the way.
I'll get rid of him.
Since when have you become
so heartless?
A woman will do whatever she can
to ensure her happiness.
Everyone has a room but me.
Don't worry. I will sort that out.
Drink some tea first. Come on.
Where is it?
Sir, where is room five?
- Room five.
- Room five?
Probably at the other side.
- Thank you.
- Han.
- Who was that? You know her?
- Not really.
- She asked me where room five was.
- Idiot. Come this way.
Yes.
- What are you doing?
- Sorry.
Getting rid of the mosquitoes.
Go back to the room.
I have found out
the Japanese are staying in room seven.
Room five is next to room seven,
which is occupied by a single female.
It'd be easy to spy on the Japanese
if we could swap rooms with her.
Let me deal with it.
- What is your plan?
- Rape first, murder later.
I thought that was your plan.
This is not our territory. Hold back
until the brothers from the riverbed arrive.
Kung, go and check out the town.
Kung, you will only see into the distance
if you stand on top of the roof.
My dear, I want to have a bath.
Let's have it together.
Come on, let's play in the water together.
- Together?
- We used to do that all the time.
My dear, have a look.
The bath tub is that big...
As big as me.
You are growing bigger everyday.
The tub will not expand to fit both of us.
OK, stop whinging.
I'll let you have it first.
Hi!
Who are you...
The smoke really works.
Get her into the bathroom.
Get him into the bed.
How are things?
- What are the Japanese saying?
- Do you understand Japanese?
- No. What about you?
- Nor can I.
Anybody in there?
Just checking the room.
- Quickly, quickly
- Anyone in there?
Come in. There's no one in here.
- Do you usually steal things?
- Only love.
I haven't slept in a bed
for a whole week.
- Have a bath first.
- Do you really have to be that hygienic?
Did you fall out of the bed?
Another one?
Come out.
My jacket has caught on something.
Lai, I am coming in.
Quick, hide!
Leave me alone.
Are you angry that it took me so long?
It was difficult to get out.
Come on, don't be angry with me.
- Be quiet.
- How dare you do this behind my back!
I will kill the vixen first
then I will my husband.
My dear, calm down.
I caught you having an affair
and you give me no explanation.
- You bitch!
- My dear.
- Stop shaking her.
- Mind your own business.
- How dare you?
- Han.
Shut up!
We cannot lie to her anymore.
You are right.
Are you all right?
Our country is important,
but so are our families.
We sacrifice ourselves
only to protect thousands of families.
Han, what do you mean?
My dear, I am a special agent
from the Central Office, 002.
Han, you are a special agent?
Correct. Do you remember
we saw the Japanese on the train?
I do, I do.
They are smuggling our national secrets
out. Me and 003 came here to stop them.
Dear, don't do it. It is extremely
dangerous for two people to stop them.
Dear, don't worry.
We also have 004 and 005.
And also 006, 007 and 008,
who will all join in to help in the mission.
- I am 006.
- And I am 007.
008...
- 009.
- 0010.
- 0011.
- 0012.
0013.
Reporting to 002.
He was the one
who used the smoke on me.
0013 had no choice.
Everyone, get back to their rooms.
- Let's forget about the whole thing.
- Yes sir. Let's go.
I've checked the situation outside.
0014 never releases national secrets.
- Go now.
- Who's 0014?
Go now.
You might as well save energy
and keep warm, Jook Bo.
I know what you are like.
Chief, it is so chaotic out there
and we cannot catch Ching Fong Tin.
Let me deal with him.
I will definitely catch him.
- Go out and patrol.
- Yes.
- Let's go.
Curry, watch them.
Who the hell is Ching Fong Tin?
Why don't you let me help you?
Shut up. I will catch him
so you will have company.
Ching Fong Tin, do you know it is a crime
to kill a security chief?
Who are you?
Do you know you get life imprisonment
if you injure a government agent?
Do you know what this is?
- No.
- No? It's is an international license.
- But you know about this one, right?
- Interpol, CIA.
I'm glad you can read.
I came to arrest Ching Fong Tin.
- So I am.
- Not anymore.
You have to assist me.
Ching Fong Tin is resourceful and tricky.
It is hard to catch him.
Don't be so pessimistic.
Let's cooperate. Ching Fong Tin
is good at hiding behind peoples' backs.
Expose yourself to him.
And I will catch him afterwards.
Isn't my role a bit passive?
That suits your talent and intelligence.
Let's go. That's an order.
- Brother Tin.
- Try hard.
That is a bit too stupid.
I'll go see what Tsao Cheuk Kin is up to.
- Long time no see.
- Don't move...
or you will get a hole in your head.
Make sure it's locked.
Is it real?
- Should I try it out on you?
- That's not necessary.
I was the security chief for ten years
and I only ever used knives.
I have never seen a firearm before.
Can I take it and have a look?
Thank you.
Shoot him, it was him who taught me.
He deserves it.
This has nothing to do with us.
We are only morons.
So am I.
I want my mum.
I want to go home, I want my mum...
Get more people to watch them.
They are tricksters.
Commander,
we only have a few guards altogether.
- It is also chaotic out there.
- You and I will deal with it.
I am going to gather more evidence of
the crimes committed by Ching Fong Tin.
That will put him away
for at least 200 years.
200 years?
You will be a fossil by then.
- What do you want?
- Our big sister has something to say.
- Ladies, what can we do for you?
- What would you like?
Tell them, big sister.
Yes, sister. These gentlemen are
officers and they must be reasonable.
Please tell us.
- I...
- Let me tell them.
Sir, my big sister was betrothed
to Ching Fong Tin when she was born.
There were so many difficulties,
and they rarely managed to get together.
And now that Ching is in prison,
who knows if he'll ever come out again.
So big sister wants to go to him
in the hope she will bear him a boy
and produce an heir for the Ching family.
It sounds ridiculous but there really
isn't a choice. It has to be done.
I hope you gentlemen will let her do this.
What a joke. In any event, we don't have
the authority to release Ching Fong Tin.
We are not asking you to release him.
Just to let big sister into his cell.
There are many eyes watching in the cell.
Please. Maybe you can order
the other prisoners to face the walls?
As for you officers,
you can always turn a blind eye.
Ladies, we are not logs.
To watch them being together we may...
Get too happy? That's why
we will all accompany big sister.
To accompany her
and to be your company.
- What do you think?
- I have an open mind.
Well, we really should
allow an heir to be produced.
Follow me.
Tin.
- Siu Hon.
- My dear Tin.
No need to be so subdued.
Ching Fong Tin, work hard on this
and score in the first round.
- I can't work this out.
- No, you are making out, with her.
Stop watching!
Everybody face the walls.
Leave immediately.
Not you.
- Big sister, you should leave too.
- OK. I'll leave.
Siu Hon, I have no choice. I have to leave.
I am not changing my mind.
I am coming with you this time.
It is better to be separated
then to be fugitives together.
There is a chance of reunion
if we are separated.
Think about it. If we are separated
for another three years,
we will be so excited
when we see each other again.
Ching Fong Tin,
fate always seems to separate us.
Fate is God's will,
but people can change their path.
Maybe this is a chance
to once again test fate
so you'll know if we belong together.
I hope you will think of me
whenever you see this.
Take good care.
Goodbye.
Big sister.
You are quite a character after all. Get in.
Why come back?
How could you let this happen?
You let a few girls save Ching Fong Tin.
What should we do now?
It will take a long time to get him back.
You go that way.
Follow me.
Sir, do you need a room?
Surrender the map of the Terracotta Army.
Don't discuss it.
Don't move, this is a robbery.
Give me all your money.
Don't move.
Ask yourself this. Are you asking
someone to wait for you her whole life?
Who do you think you are?
The God of Romance?
What more do you want when you have a
devoted woman hanging around for you?
You can't hesitate for too long.
What shall I do?
What to do?
Go back for her and love her.
It makes more sense to love her
when she is in love with you
than to beg for her love
when she has already given up.
Less effort is needed.
There really is no reason
to make more effort than is necessary.
Hey, fat Tin.
Heaven, heaven...
Shut up. Stop.
Tsao Cheuk Kin.
- Use the saw.
- They will hear us.
That's the intention.
Do it now.
- Attract their attention.
- OK.
Officer. They're sawing the gate
and trying to escape.
- You want to escape?
- So what?
- Give me the saw.
- No way.
- Have a go.
- Yes.
Don't do that. Give me the saw.
- Give me the saw immediately.
- I don't have it.
- Come in and help me.
- Go and help out.
- Here it is.
- Give it to me immediately.
I don't have it.
- Give it to me.
- I don't have it.
Ching Fong Tin.
Do it quickly.
Are you really such a moron?
Come quickly.
- Why did you...
- Because of you.
It is chaotic out there.
There must be over 100 mountain thieves.
They took all the hotel guests.
So we have to work as a team
to save Han Shui town.
- Allow me to command.
- So who is in charge for this town?
Him.
Right, it is you.
You, bring your team
to save the travelers.
You go with him. And you work with
those two to lure the thieves into the trap.
As for you, you should leave here
and go as far away as you can.
Don't worry. I am not
arresting you now and I will help you.
Come on.
What about us?
Take them to hide somewhere safe
and don't get in the way.
What is that?
You are lucky. It was meant to be
used against you. Let's go.
We will show them that
women can protect themselves.
We are free, we are free...
Freedom, freedom. We are free now.
- Freedom, freedom. We are all free...
- Catch them immediately.
Stop right there!
Get down.
Load the gun.
Damn, the barrel has overheated.
Do you have any water?
Water?
Yes.
They are running out of bullets.
Charge, charge.
Come on, shoot them.
- Have you got any more?
- I don't think I have nephritis!
So what are we waiting for?
Be quiet. Untie them.
Leave quickly now. Quickly.
Be quick.
Go that way. Be quick.
- We must get the map back.
- Yes.
- Get them.
- He looks tough.
- Then let's fight him together.
- Very tough.
- Let's go.
Give me the map.
Catch them.
Chase them.
Harder.
Still want to escape? You little bastards.
Attack him.
We'll crush you to death,
we'll crush you to death.
- What next?
- Push him out.
We'll crush you to death,
we'll crush you to death.
Why have you become a thief, killed
people and burnt down their homes?
Don't do it ever again.
Yes, OK? Forget it.
We are on the same side.
Are you all right?
- Fine.
- Let's go.
- You can't take the map with you.
- What?
- That map belongs to the Chinese people.
- So you can't take it away with you.
- What?
The map belongs to the Chinese so
you can't take it away. It must stay here.
Give it back.
- Are you giving it to me?
- "Are you giving it to me?"
Yes or no?
Haven't you got hold of it?
Why are you asking him?
If he didn't want me take it and I took it,
I am just a thief.
- Are you going to give it up?
- Yes, are you?
Let's leave.
What did you ask him to give you?
Why didn't he want to?
This is the map of the Terracotta Army.
Please give it back to the government.
I'm going to be rich!
Ching Fong Tin, I was meant to arrest you.
Since you have rendered a great service
to the nation, I'll let you go.
I am leaving now.
There are less people in this town now.
Don't worry, we can start making some.
Yes, she goes with you
and I keep these four.
You don't have a chance.
- How about us?
- No.
It's lonely watching the train
leaving on the never-ending rail tracks
How many turns do you have
to make on the dusty journey?
Quietly watching the train
vanishing into the darkness
Only the night, a shadow
and the long sighs are left behind
Perhaps you are trying to escape
from yesterday's burdens
or maybe
he is looking for a better tomorrow
Tired eyes are yearning for
the unknown future
The journey may be never-ending,
a lifetime spent exploring it
The unending journey, mountain valleys,
the sharp wind and stone-cold rail tracks
The tearful farewell erased happy
memories, it was disheartening
When will we meet again?
So that we will hold hands
and talk and kiss away the tears
Station after station,
they all seem familiar
Yet untold tears were shed
when each train departed
Did men build the railway to reduce
the distance between one another?
Or did they build it to prolong the swelling
sentiments of each departure?
The unending journey, mountain valleys,
the sharp wind and stone-cold rail tracks.
The tearful farewell erased
happy memories, it was disheartening
When will we meet again?
So that we will hold hands
and talk and kiss away the tears
Ripped by:
SkyFury