Proverbs,
chapter 18, verses 1-24.
Through desire, a man,
having separated himself,
seeketh and intermeddleth
with all wisdom.
Seeketh and intermeddleth
A man hath no delight
in understanding
but that his heart
may discover itself.
These iniquities
called moving pictures
are nothing more than
one of Satan's tools
for blinding the eyes
of the poor lost souls
who would look upon such images.
It is not unlike lot's wife
who was tempted by Lucifer
and drawn to look back
upon sodom and gomorrah.
These sad, stray lambs, too,
as shall most
of the sons and daughters
of this once God-fearing nation
be turned to pillars of salt
and lost in eternal fires.
Be turned to pillars of salt
Take refuge
in this, his holy word,
while there is still time.
How long will your marshal
allow this flickering den of sin
to rob the poor wandering sheep
in this plague-ridden little
Hamlet of their clear sight?
These are the things I've
been telling you of, my people,
these iniquities.
This is what happens
when you do not
this is what happens
follow the word of our lord.
Stupid idiot...
...Scared everybody
half to death.
Take refuge in that.
I'm going' to Texas.
Ain't no good.
What's going on in there?
You're goin' to jail.
You earned yourself
a trip to jail.
He broke my movin'
picture box, clete.
You gonna make him pay for it?
Come on. It cost me $50.00.
He broke it!
I ain't even had it a month.
If he ain't got no money,
I want his boots.
Can I have his gun belt,
or his gun?
And I want the cartridges
in it, too.
And his coat.
Whatever he's wearing.
He's gonna pay for my box.
You gonna pay for it, ain't ye?
Huh? Well, ain't ye?
You gonna pay for it!
I'll take
his hat and his coat...
Go on.
...and everything he's got.
You know where you goin'.
Go on.
Hold on a minute.
Excuse us, marshal.
There you go.
He's goin' to the back.
Are you gonna make him
pay for my movin' picture box?
That thing
was brand new, almost,
and it cost me a lot of money
and I want it paid for.
Eli, you want a cup of coffee?
Clete, would you
get Eli a cup of coffee?
I surely will.
Marshal...
Is there any likely
I could leave early today?
Well, yeah, clete, that's OK.
Surely appreciate it.
Sure gotta
get my wife a present.
Surely do.
I ain't got so much thought
on what to get a woman.
Surely don't.
I don't know what you'd
get a woman either, clete.
I suspect they'd
want the one thing
you didn't get 'em.
Oh, I surely hope not.
I ain't so sure no more
why I married up to her.
I sure ain't.
I suspect it's nice
to have someone
to go home to at night,
isn't it, clete?
Well...
Yes, sir, that's right.
It surely is nice
to have someone to go home to.
That's why I done it, marshal.
Sure is.
Hello, clete.
I sure wish you
a merry Christmas,
miss Tess.
You have a merry Christmas, too.
And say merry Christmas
to heddie for me.
I will.
Yes, ma'am, I surely will.
Nice seeing you.
That's a lot of gifts.
Almost doesn't
leave you any room
to be a marshal, does it?
It doesn't really
take that much space
to be a marshal, Tess.
Um, that's lucky
that you don't need
much room to work
so you can have lots of gifts.
Isn't it kinda hard to breathe?
This one's got a lot
of perfume on it.
I'm not breathing very well.
Can you feel it?
Do you feel faint, Tess?
I mean, you look OK.
Well, looks
can fool you, marshal.
I think I do feel faint.
Is there anything
I can do, Tess?
If I could just
get some fresh air.
That perfume's bothering me.
Do you want me to open a door
or a window?
Yeah, that would help a little.
Well, I gotta help you
more than a little, Tess.
Hey, Tess?
Tess?
Hey, Tess, maybe I better
go get the doctor.
Should I go get the doctor?
Hmm?
Hey!
Goddamn!
Just kissin'. Just kissin'.
I forgot about you
and your coffee, Eli.
You wanna go home?
Got a little piece of news
I believe is just
gonna tickle you.
Appears to be that the marshal
in this piss pit might just
be an old friend of yours.
Oh, I--I can come back later.
No. Come on in.
He loves pie.
Thank you, Jenny.
That's sweet.
Would you
like a piece of pie, Tess?
Feliz navidad, ma'am.
Good afternoon.
Reckon I better
go down and see Sandy.
Check on how bad that fella
shot up the livery.
How many pies does this make?
Well, that would've been 3.
Why don't you just
put your fingers
in the middle of it, Tess?
That'd be quicker
than working your way in
from the outside,
don't you reckon?
From the outside,
I'm not much of a cook.
Who said anything
about your cookin'?
You don't care if we
have dinner or not?
No.
Marshal?
Yeah, what?
Good afternoon, marshal.
Hello, Taylor.
Good afternoon,
Mrs. Casey, is it?
This is Tess bonaventure.
She's a friend of mine.
Mmm.
You're a long way
from amarillo, Taylor.
Got ourselves a ranch
out across yonder,
in old Mexico.
It's real nice.
It is indeed
a pleasure to meet you,
miss bonaventure.
A pleasure.
This is Taylor Henry.
My family ranched
near Taylor's family.
Daddy wants you
to bring Valentine outside
so's they can talk.
Leland's here.
Arvid, you didn't even say hi
to your brother, here...
The marshal.
What's it been, val,
about 11 years?
A long time, Taylor.
Really?
Sure doesn't seem all
that long to me, val.
These are your brothers?
No.
I didn't mean to shame you, val,
by bringing up
old family ties and all.
You didn't shame me, Taylor.
We're not brothers.
No?
Ok.
Not by blood, but--
You know, I figure daddy
raisin' you and all...
That ought to
count for something,
shouldn't it, val?
I guess, Taylor.
Between me and leland.
Let's go.
"And the lord sayeth,
I and my father are one."
"And the son sayeth unto him...
"Father, I have
sinned against heaven,
"and in thy sight
I'm no longer worthy
to be called thy son."
Valentine, come over here
and take my hand.
Sissy, mind yourself.
Leave Valentine alone.
Sissy!
You're lookin' well, boy.
We read about you
in the newspaper,
being wounded,
being in Cuba.
We were real proud
when we learned
you'd made lieutenant,
were we not, boys?
I bet you was real handsome
when you was shot.
Were we not, boys?!
Daddy was all tore up
about that, val.
What brings the Henrys
to Los tragos, leland?
We have business up in tuscon.
Never knew you to travel much
during the holidays.
I came through here
hoping to find a chemist.
We got one, but he's not here.
He's gone back east
till after the new year.
You still use the laudanum?
Yes.
It, like my chair, I remain
shackled to, Valentine.
I was hoping, uh,
you'd ride with us
just a little ways.
We could catch up a bit.
Well, you caught me
at a bad time, leland...
With Christmas tomorrow.
I'm disappointed.
I'd looked forward to talking.
Daddy, maybe I could
stay here with Valentine
and you could pick me up
on y'all's way back through.
We're not passing
through here again, sissy.
Now get up in the wagon.
Oh, let him have her.
The rest of us are
tired to damn death of her.
We'll be leaving you
now, marshal.
Git!
I love you, Valentine.
Yah! Heh! Let's go! Let's go!
Val, val.
Drop it!
Hey, clete!
Stop, clete, wait!
Giddy up! Giddy up!
Stop!
Stop the wagon, sissy!
What the hell is wrong
with you, sissy?
Turn this wagon around
so I can see
that bastard's face.
Daddy, no,
please don't kill him.
Turn, turn, turn!
Val, you run! Run on, val, run!
Leland!
Don't make me shoot you, leland.
I swear to God I'll
shoot the living--
Heddie!
Out, then! Out, I said!
Hyah, hyah!
Nice doggy.
Don't be beatin' on
that goddamned door!
Come on in here, goddamn it!
Vamonos, pachuco!
¡Andele, andele!
Don't stand there
like a bug in his shit!
¡Andele!
I'm agent otts,
from the war department.
I trust you received
a wire from judge combes.
Good.
I'm damn glad of it
that you're here.
When you quit chewing the cud
with that ass boil back there,
I'm gonna hang him.
I would have already hung him
if it hadn't have been
for that court cable.
I'd have hung him 2 weeks ago.
That lowdown cheat...
Killed my sister's man.
Now she's back livin'
with me and mine.
Well, the department
thanks you, sheriff,
for keeping
your emotions bridled.
Pardon me.
I need to speak...
To Mr. Sanchez...
Regarding a family
named Henry he rode with.
They robbed a bank.
They murdered several people
Christmas Eve last year.
What are you doing there?
What's that stink?
I'm sorry.
Oh, excuse me.
Clove oil.
A marvelous gentleman
on the train gave it to me.
Been experiencing some
difficulty with a tooth.
I do apologize.
It's rather pungent.
Actually, I've been receiving
a small measure
of relief from it.
Uh-huh.
I, uh--
I cabled Santa Fe, and...
When I made his capture,
he had not a nickel on him
except what he cheated
off my sister's man.
Except what he cheated
I understand,
but it's not the money
that we're concerned with.
Good.
What I need
is the information
regarding marshal Casey.
Uh, it is of
the utmost importance.
When you get through
jawboning with him,
we're gonna have
to work on that rope.
I want to make him
hop and squeal.
Bills!
Huh, bills.
What?
Go back and open up
that bull turd's cell.
Have you got a gun?
No.
Well, yes.
I mean, I guess.
Actually, I have an issued
small caliber revolver,
but it's out in the trunk...
By the dog.
Uh, I--I believe it's unloaded,
but if you like, I'll go and--
But if you like, I'll go and--
No, no, no! Hell, no.
Take that key...
And go out there and
wait by that cell door.
And don't be foolin'
with that lock.
Not until my man gets there
and holds a gun
on that pus weasel.
Thank you, sir.
Get on up!
There's a government man
here to talk to you.
You rot in hell.
Go on.
Hey, don't. I'm sorry?
Not there.
I beg your pardon. Ooh! Oh!
That's the shit hole.
Oh, my God!
Hey, don't sling
that around, goddamn it!
I'll knock the fuck out of you!
Now, just stand the fuck still.
Now, what do you want?
Take that fucking rag
off your mouth.
I can't hear
a goddamn word you sayin',
you silly-ass bastard.
I can't. I'm gonna throw up.
Hey, I don't give a shit!
Don't even think
about throwin' up.
I hope you damn choke on it.
I've been smellin' it
for a damn month,
and I didn't
ask you to come here
and stomp the fuck
around in it, neither.
Now, who the hell are you?
And what the fuck do you want?
They don't cut
your hair here, do they?
What?!
No, I didn't mean it
the wrong way.
I'm just saying, I--I--
I have not been able
to find anyone to cut
my hair, you know,
since St. Louis.
Uh, listen,
I'm sorry I stomped
around in your messings.
I--I--I really--
Look, I'm with
the war department.
I'm trying to find out
about Valentine Casey.
He was reported alive
and marshaling in Los tragos
when you were ridin'
with the Henrys
during that Christmas
payroll robbery massacre
last year.
Who you calling a massacreer?
No, no, nobody, no, no.
It's just
there were some killings...
And I need to be clear on
wh happened, that's all.
Yeah? Well,
I'll just clear you up
on old val Casey.
Everybody makes him out
to be somethin'.
Act like he's all up
and above everybody else.
He ain't no better than
the rest of them damn Henrys,
because that's what he is, too.
One of 'em.
Yeah, a Henry.
I bet you didn't
know that, did you?
Huh, government man?
Bet you didn't know that.
I--we, uh,
well, yes, we were aware
that he did live with the Henrys
when his own family died.
Well, were you we all aware
that when he lived with 'em,
he rode with 'em
when they went and burned
those people alive
at the tuttle ranch?
Huh? No, sir.
No, sir. You weren't, were you?
I think there's something
on record in our files
about an incident and a fire,
but as far as I know,
there was no indication
that he was either
on the premises
or involved in any way.
Well, I'm indicatin' it to you,
government man.
I'll note that.
Have you come across him
since the robbery?
Hell, no. I ain't seen him.
Well, do know if anyone--
Even the Henrys, perhaps--
Might know where he might be?
Oh, no.
Oh, come on.
Give some to daddy.
Oh, my God.
Oh, no, no. Don't do that.
Oh, goddamn.
Oh, no. Oh, please.
Oh, hey, hey! No, stop! Stop it.
Oh, deputy! Oh, no.
Bills!
See if that beaner bitch
of his is out yonder again.
For Christ's sake,
I can't sleep.
Get on out of here!
Damn you, little bitch!
Go on, now, git!
Go on!
Goddamn you, Harris!
Goddamn it!
I didn't get my nut off!
You worthless cocksucker!
I'm gonna kill you twice,
Harris!
I'm gonna kill you twice!
Goddamn you!
You so much as flinch
or even worm wiggle...
You done with him?
Fine.
Are you done yet?
Damn it, I ain't got time
for this horse shit.
Goddamn you, Harris!
Ahh.
Oh...
My shoe is ruined.
Oh, excuse me, ma'am.
I wonder if I could
get cleaned up in here?
Do you speak English?
Um, I...
Oh--oh, my God.
Boy, I think I'm gonna faint.
Hey, goddamn it!
Hey!
Goddamn it, shut that shit up!
Goddamn it!
I said shut it up now!
Well, you simple-assed bastard!
I ought to knock hell out
of you into next week!
I'm talking to you,
you mule-eared shit brain!
Where's my watch?
Hello? Hello?
Were those gunshots?
Excuse me.
The girl.
Buenos días.
And... My pants?
Have you seen my "pantos?"
My "panto-titos?"
Uh, "pantos."
Afuera.
What?
Hey, hey!
Oh, yeah.
I'm gonna scald your ass
till you ain't got a piece
of hide left on your balls.
That's it.
Don't.
Don't?
Who said don't?
Is that what you said, "don't"?
Hey.
The government man.
What the hell are you doing?
I just--I think--
It's just the man seems
hurt something terrible.
Not you, you leech-lipped
yankee bastard.
What's my whore doin' between
your cum-slinging legs?
I don't know!
I'll make you squat to pee.
Bring this cunt sniffer
over to me now.
Hey, bitch. Give me
that belt and my jacket.
I didn't know!
Yeah? Well, maybe
you ought to find out
yeah? Well, maybe
who's you a-fucking.
No, mommy! Mommy, no!
Mommy! Mommy, no!
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
I'm gonna spank you.
Uh-huh.
Mommy's gonna whip the dog shit
out of her little
government man.
Well, come on in
or get back out.
Would you be so kind
as to direct me
to the man called
Angus dunfries?
To the man called
He's across the road
in the livery there.
What are you needin' with him?
Well, I'll be needing
to speak to him presently.
Thank you for the information
as to his whereabouts.
Who's that with you?
That would be
your daughter, adalyne.
Where you been, addy?
Hey, who the hell are you?
I'm the man who brought her here
to speak with her Uncle,
your brother,
the man they call Angus.
Well, he ain't gonna talk to you
you call him Angus!
Nobody calls him Angus.
Helluva lot you know!
His name's doc.
Well, go on, walk away!
You'll come back and find me
if you want to speak to him,
you will.
No, no, no.
I will not!
Some...
Far off place
where nobody knows...
How to be with her.
And--and--
And look what that other place
caused you.
The place didn't do that.
Well, all I know is
you was fine...
When you left here.
You was fine...
It's not why
it happened, Uncle Angus.
I don't want to talk about me.
I don't want...
Whatever caused that to happen
to happen to her.
She don't need none of 'em.
Goddamn it, she ain't deaf!
Maggie!
Margaret Nora!
Now, you see?
She hears me fine.
Maggie, come on.
I know, I know...
Come with me.
Mr. dunfries?
I've got, uh, some horses
we need to board with you.
I've got a couple
saddle horses here
and 3 green-broke that
we got up in your corral
with saddlers we need
to put inside.
Would that be all right,
Mr. dunfries?
Yeah. Uh...
You can put 'em in--
In that barn in the--
In the second stable.
Here you go, val.
They rent rooms at
that depot over there?
Oh, yeah.
Uh...
That's my, uh,
brother's railroad hotel.
Yeah, uh, 2 bits, uh, each.
That's fair.
And, uh...
You can use the tub.
All right.
Well, thank you.
Hey!
Uh...
If you're gonna have supper,
it's 10 cents extra.
It's 10 cents extra.
Now...
You have to tell 'em
that, so they know
to charge you 10 cent extra.
All right.
Ok, thank you.
Chief, we got a wire here
from shoshone bill.
He crossed back
over the border again
this morning.
It says, um...
"Will possible make dunfries
tomorrow A.M.--stop.
"No luck Mexican rough stock.
"Still need cattle, horses,
riders, dancers--stop.
"Please inform
Mr. Valentine Casey
"our impending arrival--stop.
Yours, major
William s. Guthries."
Well...
Nathan, I guess you better
get them girls, squaws,
and them young buck riders
for 'em to take a look at.
You're Casey, right?
Mm-hmm.
You heard what I read?
Yes, thank you.
You want to see it?
No, that's not necessary.
I understand.
He returns tomorrow?
Mm-hmm.
Those his cattle cars
up the rail?
Yeah, a spare train's
gonna take them
and his Pullman's
up to the main line when
we're done with business.
Mr. dunfries, I'd like
to order a round of cognac
for you and your associate...
As well as Mr. Casey here...
In anticipation
of a successful conclusion
to your business transactions
with shoshone bill
and his frontier show.
And I might add that
I did see his show
in St. Louis...
And indeed, it was, uh...
An extravaganza
of Western performance
unequaled by anything
I've run across yet.
And that includes New York shows
and circuses from Europe.
Well, I ain't got no cognac.
Napoleon's Brandy.
Now, I got that.
It's a $2 bottle
if that'll suit you.
Of course, that's fine.
Brandy's fine.
Well, good.
Actually, alcohol goes
straight through me.
No, thank you.
Oh, yes.
I'm surprised
you were able to keep
that bottle back there
long enough to gather dust.
Well, there might be
a whole lot about me
that would surprise you,
little girl.
Thank you.
You came from Canada?
What?
Excuse me, I was--
I didn't mean to interrupt you.
I was just gonna
thank the gentleman
for the Brandy.
Oh, you're quite welcome.
I'm brigadier smalls.
And this is my associate,
Mr. Babcock.
And may I introduce you
to adalyne dunfries.
Valentine Casey is your name,
am I correct?
Yeah, that's correct.
Miss dunfries, it's
a pleasure to meet you.
Gentlemen, this is
my partner, U.S. Christmas.
Mr. smalls and Mr. Babcock, yes,
and miss dunfries.
How do you do?
Howdy.
I saw on your trunk Montreal.
I thought you must be
traveling from Canada.
Yes. Yes, I was in Canada.
My daughter's just
returned from Canada
and doesn't seem
to approve of our
cordial consumption
of libation, chief.
What was that like?
What?
Uh, Canada.
I'm sorry.
I've just never known
anybody that came down
from Canada. I'm curious.
Well, it was pleasurable,
invigorating,
inspirational.
The people there
are very civilized.
Oh, dear, we may not
be civilized enough
for my daughter's taste, chief.
Was it, uh, cold?
Oh, I--I--
I don't know, I--I--
I was there doing a play
and I didn't go out
in the daytime.
In the evening,
they sent a coach
to take me to the theater, so--
Whoa, the theater!
The theater.
Well, now, we're gonna have
to be on our best behavior
and try and be civilized, chief.
Otherwise, she might
leave me again,
and I don't think
I could stand that.
I may not survive the way I done
when she left me that last time.
Did you have
a chance to look out.
a chance to look out
your hotel window?
W-why?
Well, were the people
outside wearing coats
like it was cold?
Yes. Yes, they were
wearing coats.
Yes, it is--
It's very cold
in Canada in the winter.
But it's very beautiful
if you're in love.
Now, burl.
Oh. Oh, I did survive,
though, didn't I?
You know I did, chief.
I done just fine without her.
Settle down.
Did you come back
to hurt me some more?
Burl, stop it.
You're scaring Maggie.
She come back to haunt me
is what she done.
She's a damn ghost.
Well, she ain't gonna haunt me!
No, she ain't gonna torment me!
No, not no damn ghost! Uh-uh...
Go on, get the hell away
from me, damn ghost!
Put that goddamn sword down!
Go on, you damn ghost!
Put that goddamn--
Oh!
Oh, God.
Oh, it's adalyne! No...
Daddy, you've got to stop.
You've got to calm down.
It's not mama, it's me.
It's addy!
Grab him.
Come on. Come on, damn it.
Shh...
Edgar, would you please tell doc
that I've taken Maggie up
to stay with me tonight.
Sí.
You all came back
for the little girl?
Well, miss dunfries did.
Mr. Babcock and I escorted her.
She intends
to take her with her?
Indeed.
I believe that's what she'll do.
Her journey brought her
back here for that reason.
The child's father doesn't
seem willing to allow it.
Well, her Uncle Angus
is lost on his own path.
Adalyne's tribulations
rose like sea billows
and crashed into her heart.
She fell loose from this life
and slid across
to the other side.
But her time was not now,
and she was led back...
And lovingly compelled
by her soul's divine conscience
to complete
this earthly passage.
To complete
How long was it?
She was gone, I mean?
Unlike you and I,
she retains her sense of smell.
Excuse me?
My olfactory recall
is limited to...
Axle grease from
the wheels of a train...
Leather seats
in a Pullman car...
And tonic
on the hair of porters.
Hair tonic?
Well, these were the objects
that I was in
the closest proximity to
at the time of my mortal demise.
I believe that you and I
share in common
this olfactorous malady.
Well, if you gentlemen
will excuse us...
Babcock and I have had a long
and exhausting journey.
So, we'll bid you good night
and retire to our rooms.
And retire to our rooms.
Good night.
Now, he's an odd bird.
Yeah.
Good morning, Mr. Casey.
Good morning, miss dunfries.
How are you?
I'm fine, thank you.
Is the little girl all right?
Margaret. Yes, she's doing
much better this morning.
You had a restful sleep?
Not altogether,
but thank you for asking.
She seems very fond of you.
You're wanting
to take her with you?
Yes, to the Berkeley school
for the deaf and the blind.
It's near San Francisco.
Well, I hope her father
allows you to.
Well, it seems Uncle Angus
had a change of heart
during the night.
We spoke this morning,
and he's agreed
to let me take her.
Well, if there's any hope
for her salvation,
it would appear to be you.
I'm not much of a savior,
but I love her,
and I'm gonna try
to give her a life
that means something.
I think you can probably
save her just fine.
Well, I wish you the best.
Have a good day.
Thank you.
Was no risk at any time
of men on the stairway
of that sweet little balloon
because I practice
3 to 6 hours every day.
I have honed my skills.
I will use this third
tomahawk and take it
and throw it in between
the first 2 tomahawks
and burst that little balloon.
Now if you'll looky here,
well, there's not much room left
between these first 2 tomahawks,
barely 2 fingers,
but with my skill I can do it
from 10--no, let's make
that 13 paces just for luck.
Some folks says 13's
a unlucky number,
but I say no. That's a lucky
number for jesco lynch,
the tomahawk hatchet thrower,
the legend of all
the great plains
and the Indian territories.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me introduce...
Valentine Casey.
Mr. Casey, allow me
to buy you breakfast.
How ya doin', bill?
Just great. Val, gettin'
that cable last month
was like hearin' a voice
from the grave.
Was like hearin' a voice
Luke, this indeed
is the gallant lieutenant Casey.
Or what's left of him.
How you doin'?
Fine, thank you.
Honey, show the clippin's
out the Tulsa newspaper
to Mr. guthries here.
After you get finished here,
do you mind
takin' those horses down
and let him look at 'em?
Sure.
Thank you, Mr. lynch.
At 13 paces, I call my throw
to take this tomahawk hatchet
and put it in the middle
and burst that little balloon.
Well, not bad
for an old bushwhacker.
Well, mister, if you're ready,
I reckon we can go
move them horses now.
All right. That's fine,
and, bill, I thank you
for the breakfast
and I'll see you back at camp.
And I'll see you back at camp.
You're welcome, Luke.
See you down there in a while.
Your friend has
a strange sense of fashion.
Yeah, he's kinda
sentimental about the dress.
How's that?
Well, his family used
to work coolie camps,
and when he was about,
I don't know,
3 or 4 years old, I guess,
there was this renegade band
of mescalero apaches
that broke off the reservation.
They started raidin' camps.
And one afternoon they
raided his family's camp...
And his mother was
quick enough thinkin'
that she put him
in a little girl's dress,
and they kidnapped him along
with the rest of the women,
and he stayed alive that way
long enough for an army detail
to catch up with 'em
and rescue 'em.
Well, that might could
make a man have a fondness
for wearin' dresses.
Yeah, I guess.
He's not too much stranger
than the rest of 'em
out here, though.
Is this fella an Indian?
I have no idea.
No, that's probably enough.
Are these calientes?
Son muy picosos.
Do you have a sack, a tote?
Yes, yes. ¿Sophia,
donde está LA bolsa?
Sí, LA bolsa.
Oh, yeah, that's good.
That'd be great.
Good morning, Sophia.
Good morning, Edgar.
Buenos días, señorita.
That's good. I'll come out there
and get that other thing
in a minute.
Mr. Casey.
I understand you're
a friend of major guthries'.
Yeah, bill and I are friends,
but please call me val,
miss dunfries.
Oh, then, I'd like it
if you'd call me adalyne, val.
And if it wouldn't
be an imposition,
could you introduce me
to Mr. guthries
so that I might pay him
to take Margaret and me
on the spur train to where
it joins the mainline?
It's not an imposition.
You're not traveling
with brigadier smalls
and Mr. Babcock any longer?
No. No, they're gone now.
They left earlier this morning,
so I guess I'm gonna have
to do that saving on my own.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to pry.
No, I know you didn't.
When you're finished
with breakfast there,
I'll take you down to meet bill.
Thank you.
You're welcome... Edgar?
Hey, bill.
Hey, val.
Margaret, you come on now.
You're gonna have a little
float in the balloon.
I rode one once.
Montreal.
Uh-huh. Was it cold?
I don't recall.
I was in love at the time.
So you said last night.
Miss dunfries, why
don't you join Margaret
for a little float
in the balloon?
Excuse me.
Pretty wild rig.
Yeah, it's a lot of fun, though.
Where you headed after our
finish our horse tradin'?
I've got some business
with some folks
I think are nearby.
I suppose it couldn't wait.
No, not really.
I was thinking that
a trip to California
might be pleasurable for you.
You could see
the whole frontier show
you could see
before we go on tour
to South America and Europe.
That'd be nice, but I just
can't do it right now.
Well, truthfully, I was
surprised to hear from you.
I think I was a bit confused
about what happened
to you after Cuba.
Yeah.
Cuba gets sorta foggy
for me after I was shot.
It was good down there
until then. Most of it.
You think?
Seemed like.
Gustoff!
Gustoff, put it down.
How did she get to know smalls?
I'm not sure. I don't know.
She came down
from Canada with him.
He and that other gentleman
were having breakfast
when I walked in. I don't
think he ever remembered
meeting me before.
When I knew him he was
a big railroad gambler.
A couple of years ago,
I heard he got killed
a couple of years ago,
over a cheat he
got caught in in cards.
You ever been up
in one of those things?
They're magnificent.
I don't know why,
but you seem to care
less about things,
anything really,
when you're up in one.
Come on, Valentine.
Let me have gustoff
show you how to float
one of those balloons.
You fellas got hold of this?
Hang on now.
Oh...
Hey.
Hey, how ya doin'?
Mr. Casey, you fellas
did a real fine job
breakin' these horses.
I reckon we're
gonna take 'em all.
U.S. and me, we been hagglin'
and fussin' over prices.
And we finally came up
with $50 around
for those saddle horses
and 25 for the broncs.
That'll be OK, Luke.
We'll take the price.
How far you plannin'
on goin' in that thang?
Not very.
Begins now.
Hey, hold it pardner.
What--where you goin'?
Hey, now. Hold up there!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hang on!
What are you--how--
Wait a minute. I ain't
got the hang of this.
Hang on there! Hey, hold on now!
How hard do I pull this?
Hey! Whoa! Whoa-whoa!
Whoa! Wh-what?!
Hey, that's enough!
That--that's enough.
Stop right there.
Hey, bill. Bill,
how long's that rope?
Yeah, I wouldn't, uh--
That's probably enough.
Use your megaphone to tell us
how high you want to go.
This is! No more! That's enough!
You have about 50 feet out now.
We'll give you more.
Could you--could you
hand me that?
Are you all right?
Uh-huh, yeah.
Bill, stop!
Just stop right there!
No, right there! Right there!
Stop! That--that--
That's enough!
Ok, we'll stop.
Ooh. Are you sure you're OK?
Uh, yeah. Uh, I mean--
I just--I think maybe
if I just sit down here
for a minute, I'll be OK.
Wow, we're up here now, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Was your last balloon ride
anything like this?
Not exactly.
Yeah.
'Cause it's beautiful
when you're in love?
It's beautiful here.
Yeah.
Well, if it--if it
should ever come up
when you took this balloon
ride, it--it wasn't cold.
When you took this balloon
I might have
a hard time recalling.
Well, I doubt that
I'll remember too much
about the weather...
Probably just the things
that were beautiful.
You ever been to
San Francisco, val?
Is it cold there?
Well, according
to Samuel clemens,
well, according
the coldest winter he ever spent
was the summer he
lived in San Francisco.
I'm not too sure about
balloon rides anymore.
I'm sorry.
And that poor tormented
wretch down there
and that poor tormented
thinks that I can save him...
But he wouldn't let me
even if I could.
Yeah, I guess we all hope
for someone to save us.
I used to wish so bad that
I could have saved my family,
it made my side sore.
They're gone?
Yeah. Mmm.
My mother...
My father...
My sister and little brother.
Influenza killed 'em all.
Me, I didn't even get sick.
All anybody can do is try
to save themselves, val,
and most of us
have forgotten how.
And most of us
I'm pretty worthless
as a savior,
but I wish you'd come with us.
I guess maybe I could buy a coat
out in San Francisco, huh?
Yes.
Them dang chi chis is hot!
Why don't you throw that out?
Uh-uh. Too dang good!
It's like swallowin'
lit kerosene.
Ahh!
Chihuahua!
It's like eatin'
a mouth full of hot ashes.
You reckon--
You reckon
Chinese food'd be hot?
I suppose we'll be
eatin' a lot of that
out in San Francisco, huh?
Yeah, probably.
You cookin' somethin'?
It smells like
somethin's cookin'.
Do you smell gunpowder?
Yeah.
That's all.
Well, major, here's
to a successful tour.
Edgar?
Edgar! Who told you
to turn them
goddamn lights out?!
Que?
What?
Where the hell are you?
Right here!
Ohh!
Hey!
Good evening, gentlemen.
Whoa! Wha--
Sorry, arvid. I didn't mean
for that cork to get
that close to ya.
Ouch.
Then I allows to tell ya
you shouldn't oughta done it.
Pick that dang bottle up
'fore you spill any more
liquor none of us
won't be able to drink
and wipe your damn front
off with that rag.
You look like
you pissed yourself.
Well, God! Shit, arvid.
I said I'm sorry,
goddamn you to hell.
Goddamn you to hell.
Arvid, where the hell is Taylor?
Back in that old man's
office, seein' to business.
Hey, nogal. Where you goin'?
Taylor didn't say
for you to come in here.
Hey, that woman
and that little sick girl's
up there.
The hell he will.
I seen her in that window.
Can I help you with something?
Mm-hmm. Oh, yeah.
You can come over here
and give somethin' to daddy.
Yeah.
Hey, 'gales, Taylor said
you supposed to wait outside.
Goddamn it, I already
waited out there.
I'm tired a-waitin' on you all.
Harold, go down and tell Taylor
that Nogales come inside,
ain't nobody watchin' the front.
You damn bunch of
inbred sons of bitches.
You go tell that fuckin' Taylor
that if he ain't got
some goddamn money
down there in
the next 15 minutes,
I'm gonna leave all
your worthless asses.
Now get the hell out of my way.
Fuck the bunch of ya!
That's $1.00 bottle of whiskey.
I reckon Taylor'll pay
for it when he come back.
He's gettin' our money.
You know, she ain't just
your girlfriend, arvid.
I seen her, too.
She gets to be
my girlfriend, too.
I can just watch you
be with her, arvid.
Ohh, damn, arvid!
You supposed to get me
to lay with a woman.
That's what your daddy said.
He said I could help
pick her out, too!
Now, goddamn it,
I picked that one!
All right, Uncle jude.
Ok, I'm gonna let
you have her first.
Harold, you can just
sit there and watch.
I want you to lay down
with my Uncle jude here.
I just bet you can
make him feel real good.
Then you and me,
we gonna have us a poke.
You can do it right here.
Harold take that
little split leg
over there with you.
Uh, arvid, I don't
wanna mess with
that little afflicted bitch.
Goddamn it! Take her
over there with you!
Harold, go get that little bitch
'fore Taylor sees her!
Come on, Uncle jude.
Get them pants down!
Aah!
Daddy, they're after Margaret!
Ahh!
Harold!
Bring me them damn bank sacks!
What the hell is
goin' on out there?!
Can't get my button undone.
Wait a second.
You dirty piece a--
Well, I can't get
to her through you.
Move your arm, arvid!
God! Ohh!
You bitch!
Ow!
Goddamn it, Harold!
Why the hell am I
waitin' on you?
Aah!
Oh, you bitch!
You fuckin' bitch!
You--you cut off
my fuckin' nuts!
Help me!
Aah!
Come back, sheba bitch!
I'm gonna hurt you hard!
Damn it! Lookit
what you done to me!
No!
Aah!
Aah! God almighty, Taylor!
You damn near shot me.
Aah, you damn sure did!
Oh, my God! I can't hear!
Oh, my God almighty, Taylor!
You struck me deaf!
Go get the sacks.
You all are worthless.
I never seen
anything as worthless.
You can't even rob
a goddamn old man
and his daughter
without pissin' yourselves.
And his daughter
Now I want you to listen...
With that good ear.
Do what I'm sayin' to ya.
I want you and that
addle-brained Uncle of ours
to get on a pair
of horses and go,
and if Harold and I
catch up with you two
before y'all reach spits,
I'll shoot you myself.
You understand, arvid?
Where is he?
He's upstairs all cut up.
I don't think he can ride.
Cut up how?
That bitch, she burned me!
She like to nearly
cut his nuts off, I think!
Then you and Harvey get a horse
and tie Uncle jude to it
and tell Nogales to find
that tooth-pullin' blacksmith
so we can bring him with us
back down to spits
so he can sew that old
bastard back together.
Now can you do that, arvid?
Of course!
I mean, yeah!
Let's go, Harold.
Hey, Harvey!
Harvey!
Mmm.
Good mornin', doc.
Grab your boots.
Hey, Mr. blacksmith.
Look what we found
out in the kitchen
hidin' in the stove.
Oh, you son of a bitch!
Goddamn it!
Goddamn!
What the hell's goin' on?
Where's addy?
Well, I shot her...
What?
In there, behind the desk.
And now I think
I'm gonna shoot her...
Oh, Jesus.
Unless you do what I say.
Oh, yeah, I will. Yeah?
I'll do anything you say.
- That's good.
- Yeah.
I want you to go
with my burnt up
brother arvid here
on over to spits
and see what you can do
about sewing that other one's
manhood back together.
I'll finish up here,
and I'll come down there,
and if everything
looks all right,
then you can come back here,
and Nogales and these boys
will let your little girl go.
But in the meantime,
we'll see to it
but in the meantime,
that she doesn't run off
and go hide in any stoves.
Please don't do that.
Connie, come over here
and wet nurse this little bitch.
Arvid, take the money,
put doc on a horse.
Get goin'.
Come on!
I'll see y'all in spits.
Come on, Harold.
Leave that bastard to bleed.
Let's go.
Hey, I don't like you...
'Cause I don't like Indians.
Come on.
Hey, Connie, me, Tim, and Paul
is gonna go on down
to Josie's place.
You wait here
about 10 minutes...
Then kill her and come on.
Hey, mister.
Touch this.
Ho! Ho!
Ho!
Edgar, what went on here?
They shoot and
they kill everybody.
Addy?
Is she all right?
Probably not...
But she'll be better
but she'll be better
the sooner I get her
away from here.
Are you all right?
Probably not,
but I won't die from this.
Where's Angus?
They made him go with 'em
to tend to the one
that was cut up.
Shoshone?
They shot him, but he'll live.
He's on the train.
He needs treatment soon,
so we're leaving
he needs treatment soon,
as quick as we can bury daddy.
Are you coming?
Who did this?
It doesn't matter.
I saw Luke.
He paid us for them horses.
They're loadin' 'em as we speak.
He get caught up in this?
No. Time he heard of it,
it was all over with...
But I know who did it, though.
Who?
Nogales kid and some
of them damn Henrys.
Part of 'em took the blacksmith
and that, uh, one that
was cut up real bad
and took him off to spits
to tend to him.
You get the rest of those horses
down to Luke and let's go.
All right.
That won't save anyone.
I know you can't wait,
but I'm gonna finish this...
Then I'm comin'
to San Francisco.
Vengeance won't give
you back what you lost.
This isn't vengeance.
It's justice.
I'm gonna bring 'em back
to stand trial
for what they did here
and Los tragos.
You're right. I can't wait.
I've gotta go.
Ow!
What's that on your face?
Axel grease.
It keeps the sting off.
Where's Uncle jude?
Inside. That Smith's
doctorin' on him.
Why don't you stay here
and see to it that
Uncle jude gets sewed up.
I'm gonna drop back
across the border
and catch some cattle
that guthries has
comin' up here.
Harvey, you come with me.
We'll meet y'all
back at daddy's.
Hey, Taylor,
hey, Taylor,
can't I watch a minute
him getting sewed on?
Get on the horse.
Hey, that weren't empty.
What?
That's OK.
Aaaah!
Aaaaah!
Oh, shut up!
Good lord!
My, my grandfather had one loin,
my, my grandfather had one loin,
and he had one sewed up
in the war,
and he sired 7 children.
Goddamn it, count 'em... 7.
Quit movin' so damn much
or I'm gonna get
your other ball.
No! Mommy!
Aah! Aah!
Unh!
Damn!
No!
Oh, yeah! Oh, yeah!
Shh!
I want you to hear this.
T-Taylor and arvid done it.
They done all of it.
I ain't done nothin'.
Where are they, jude?
They went down
to leland's place.
Where's leland?
Leland's in Mexico.
Get him on a wagon and let's go.
Come on!
No!
Come on, goddamn it!
The pain's too much to move me!
Come on!
Hey, val!
Looky yonder!
What'cha reckon?
Well, it's the marshal
and his whore.
Buenas días, amigos.
Y'all know assaulting
a U.S. marshal
is a federal offense.
Probably hang ya.
Yeah, but he ain't
no marshal no more.
Are you?
Nah. He gave that up
after we rode
through Los tragos.
After we rode
No. Uh-uh.
He's been reassigned
to temporary duty.
Yeah, and what the hell
kind of duty might that be?
Trackin' y'all down
and killin' ya.
I'm deferring the execution
of that order
to my deputy here.
Corbett, show him your badge
before you shoot him.
Corbett.
Who's corbett?
Why, hell fire.
Looky here, amigos.
Old corbett there
is all badged up.
I showed them
the badge, marshal!
Thought I didn't see ya!
They're not back down there yet.
It looks like it's leland
and a couple vaqueros.
I'm gonna go on in.
If I'm not back here
by tomorrow morning...
You ride down there
and kill 'em all.
My pleasure.
See ya.
¡Alto!
No haga eso!
Cómo esta, Valentine?
Not very well, leland.
The prodigal son returns.
Luke 15, verses 11-32.
Or should I say,
"Lazarus this day
raiseth from the dead"?
I don't know, leland.
I reckon it could be
a little bit of both.
It's a peculiar way to state it,
especially concerning
the information
I've just been reading
from a satchel
delivered to me
from the war department
by the gentleman
out there that's, uh,
about to perform self-dentistry.
Agent fishburn otts!
This is lieutenant Casey
this is lieutenant Casey
in question throughout
the documents.
Val, agent otts.
I've come to arrest you, leland.
Take you back to stand
trial for Los tragos.
Taylor and the boys
are gonna face trial
for Los tragos and what went on
in dunfries yesterday.
Sissy! Bring me those papers!
Sissy! Bring me
those papers about val!
I'm bringing 'em.
Sissy! Sissy!
I can't reach this.
Hand it to me!
What the hell is wrong with you?
I'm tryin' to fix
my face right, daddy.
I guess, uh, sissy's
a little excited
that you're here, Valentine.
See that fellow over there
with the tooth problem, val?
He's a government man.
He's had trouble with that tooth
ever since he came to us,
so, uh, I had Alejandro
and the boys
teach him how to take care of
that problem the Indian way.
Ain't that right, agent otts?
Mr. Henry,
since Mr. Casey has arrived,
perhaps I can be on my way now
and seek out a proper dentist
upon my arrival at Tucson.
I--I really don't think
that anything
this extreme is necessary.
The tooth feels
immeasurably better now.
And--and you mentioned
that I might be able
and--and you mentioned
to get my wedding ring back.
I would appreciate that.
But feel free
to keep the crucifix
as a token of my appreciation
for your graceful hospitality.
No, I think we better
take care of that tooth problem.
A thing like that can turn on ya
and just give you fits.
Nogales come across him
when old Sidney
had to stay in a lockup
up across the border.
How are your arms
holding out, agent otts?
It appears to me you may be near
the end of your agony.
The odd thing is
he was looking for
Valentine Casey's next of kin.
So Sidney thought
he'd be his personal escort
and give him safe conduct
through this, uh, hostile
territory surrounding us
so that he could bring us
these urgent documents.
Now...
It says here in this letter
in these documents
that you were mortally wounded.
I guess that means
you were killed, val.
In the course of an action
when your company was ambushed
near the town
of Santiago de Cuba.
You ever been
to Santiago de Cuba, val?
Yeah, near there.
My God, boy.
You look like a ghost
just brushed up against you.
See this, val?
A U.S. stamp right on it.
It's official.
"To the next of kin
of lieutenant Valentine Casey,
"and to whom else
it may concern,
"let it be known that second
lieutenant Valentine Casey
"died under conditions of valor
"in the course of hostile action
"near Santiago de Cuba on
or about the first July, 1898.
"Lieutenant Casey
was posthumously promoted
"to the rank
of first lieutenant u.S.R.A.
"To the rank
"And decorated
for acts of bravery.
"Now, please accept
my condolences
"and deepest sympathies
on behalf
"of the United States
government and its citizens
"for this monumental loss
of your loved one.
"The remains of lieutenant Casey
held from October 12, 1898,
"U.S. army headquarters morgue,
uh, fort meyers Virginia,
"shall be remanded and/or
interned as per your wishes.
"Shall be remanded and/or
"We respectfully await
further instructions.
Russell Alexander alger,
United States secretary of war."
It's official. You can see it.
Fact of business,
it's downright queer.
Aaaah!
Aaah!
It appears your war
department friend's
been relieved
of a tooth, leland.
Been relieved
How are you, Mr. otts?
Ohh!
You must be feeling
enormous relief, agent otts.
Don't speak to me now.
No need to thank me.
We can talk later...
Over supper.
Aaah!
Reckon we oughta feed him?
I don't think I could stomach
watching that
son of a bitch eat.
All right, I'll wait
until you go to sleep, then.
There's a lot of
good people out there.
But not many.
You want some more beans?
You think little Margaret
is OK on that train
with 'em, uh, guthries?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
They was fine except adalyne
was kinda shot up real bad.
Was kinda shot up real bad.
Uh, well, not that bad.
She just sorta was.
The way I had to come up
when I was a kid just...
Took the desire out of my heart
to ever have a little child.
And she was...
Born deaf, 'cause Satan
made her that way.
I--I know that's what it
is, 'cause see,
I'm not supposed to ever
have anything I like.
I'm not just supposed to.
And...
And I...
I look at her sometime--
I look at her sometimes
and, uh...
I love her so much.
I love her so much
and I know I shouldn't.
I know I can't, I know
I won't, I know I...
I just can't do it.
And--and then...
That's why she be born deaf.
And then I had
these mangled ideas.
I...I was gonna choke her.
And then--and then
I had that vision
and then--and then
and I...
I talked to Jesus.
And he...
He laid my hand
to those bellows...
And we worked
the bellows together.
He and I.
And, and we, we worked 'em
and we worked 'em
and worked 'em and worked 'em
until the hellfire burned Satan
right out of me, ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
What?
Hey!
Whoa!
Aah!
Shit!
Arvid! Harvey!
Come on back here
and let those bastards
bleed to death!
And let those bastards
Evenin', Uncle jude.
Unh.
Arvid, Harvey!
Goddamn it, come back here!
I have to tell ya, val.
A whole range of emotion
rushed over me when I read
that letter in those papers.
I was distraught for awhile
but then, God help me,
I was overwhelmed by
pride in you, boy.
At the thought of what you
must have carried yourself like
down there in Cuba.
And the papers
must have been mistaken
because here you are.
Are you not?
Val, I was so scared when
that damned old government man
brought them papers
that told us you was dead.
I hope your rotten old tooth
still hurts!
Sissy, mind yourself.
Stop it!
Sissy, stop it!
Valentine doesn't
need to see you
behaving in this manner.
Besides, I have
things to talk about
much more important
than this love-sick
cow eyeing of yours.
Now, agent otts
was just doing his job
for the government.
He was a courier
of some mixed up information.
Now we're aware of that,
and it's all straight.
Just like val, here.
He took on the weight
of a marshal's badge.
Now he's come here
with an enormous burden
because of that weight.
But it's mixed up, too
because he just
doesn't realize that
his obligation
to see justice done
can be overlooked
and forgiven to us
because we're his family.
The same rules of honor
don't apply to family
as they do
to the others out there
in this pagan world.
Now, I hope you
can open your heart
to this simple truth, Valentine.
They shot three people
and killed two of 'em
in dunfries yesterday, leland.
In dunfries yesterday, leland.
Oh, that's just temperance.
Temperance and restraint
at all times, val.
But alas, my boys have
fallen short once again.
I've come for you
and the boys, leland.
I thought you'd retired
from marshalin'.
Leland!
Val's killed one of the twins!
Leland! He killed Harold!
Good evening, marshal.
If y'all ain't killed him yet,
I wanna be the one to do it.
What in hell happened to you?
He got his balls tore
nearly clean off
by some woman him
and arvid tried to have.
Well, him I can forgive
on the basis of pure "d" stupid.
But you? You oughta
have enough of this
took to your back
to lay a lick of sense
into that carnal-consumed
maggot mind.
Taylor, what the hell happened?
All you were supposed
to be doin'
was scouting over at the Wells.
Where were ya?
I took 'em.
We ran on something
I had going over in dunfries.
What something you had going on
over in dunfries?
Since when have you
had something going on
anywhere without
telling me first?
And that's why val's
had to come down here,
looking for you and your
worm rot brain brothers.
I don't reckon you
can turn your nose up too high
to found money anymore...
Can you, daddy?
As far as val...
I don't really concern myself
one way or the other
with whatever the hell
he has to do.
Well, you'd best
concern yourself
with what I have to
do because of you, boy.
Now I have to con him
from wanting to take us to jail
and see through
some kind of trial.
Let me see if I'm clear on this.
You want me,
daddy, and everybody
to go back up there
and stand trial
and be hung, right?
Now, that don't sound like much
of a decision to me, val.
You're either comin'
or goin', Taylor.
I don't really
care which anymore.
You choose.
Val!
Get away from there,
sissy, goddamn it,
or I'll shoot the--
Ow! Damn it!
Harvey, you put that pistol down
or I'm gonna come across there
and shoot you
with every goddamn gun
in this room, 'cause I'm having
to think real hard right now
about why the hell I
need the useless half
of a worthless set of twins.
None of ya are killing anybody.
I still decide
who dies around here
and who don't.
And who don't.
Now, you two get
up off the damn floor
and take Valentine
out to the barn
and tie him up.
Hey, daddy.
You all heard daddy.
Take Valentine out to the barn
take Valentine out to the barn
and tie him up.
Now, goddamn it!
Daddy?
Daddy, daddy.
Daddy.
Daddy. Daddy!
"Lord, hear thee
in the day of trouble.
The name of the God
of Jacob defend thee."
"Send thee help
from the sanctuary
"and strengthen thee
out of zion.
"Remember all thy offerin's
"and accept thy burnt sacrifice,
"salah.
"Some trust in chariots
"and some in horses,
"but we will remember the name
"of the lord, our God.
"My God, my God,
"my God, my God,
"why hast thou forsaken me?
"Why art thou so far
from helpin' me?
Hear the words of my..."
You looked like you's thirsty.
Sissy, you gotta--
You gotta untie me, honey.
Do you love me, Valentine?
What?
I've always had love
for you, sissy.
Untie me, sweetie.
What are you doin'?
What are you doin', sissy?
Well, I'm marryin' you.
Oh, honey, that's not how you
get married to somebody.
I love you, Valentine.
I need you to want me.
I know I ain't worth much.
You're worth more than they
ever let you believe.
Just untie me, sweetie.
You'll go off with my brothers.
I wanna take 'em back
to stand trial, sissy.
Then I'll come back here
and help you
after I straighten things out.
You're gonna come back?
Yeah.
Hey, sissy!
What the hell are you
doin' over there?
You get up off him, sissy,
so I can kill him,
you damn whore.
Get off of him!
You shut up!
We're gettin' married.
You can't get married, sissy.
If that's all there was to it,
you'd already
be married to arvid.
Now get out of the way,
or I'm gonna blow
your ass off, too.
Goddamn you,
you get out of the way.
Ow! Goddamn.
Goddamn you!
I told you
to get out of the way.
Arvid, go see what that was.
Then bring Valentine
back out here
so I can kill him.
Bury him in that pit with daddy,
where he belongs.
Uncle jude, yelling:
In here! Arvid!
You heard me tell her!
Sissy?
Hey, sissy?
Ow!
Sissy? Hey, sissy?
Hey, sissy. Sissy, honey? Honey?
Taylor! Taylor!
Hey, honey.
I'll kill you,
you little son of a bitch!
Goddamn.
Come here!
Sissy, sissy, come here.
Come here. Sissy?
Sissy, sissy.
Arvid, she was in the barn
lettin' Valentine loose.
No, wait up, arvid.
I seen that little bitch
do it, too.
She let him loose,
so I shot her.
Ha ha! I shot
that little bitch good.
Whoo!
Doc!
Aah!
Whoa!
Doc!
Wha--whoa!
Go! Doc, run!
Ho, ho, ho!
Blind!
Ho ho!
My eyes!
I'm blind!
Run, doc!
Can you run?
I can't see.
Ho!
Goddamn it, Taylor,
you blew up Uncle jude.
Well, shit, goddamn it,
I saw it.
Come on. Hurry.
Unh!
Shit!
Uhh.
Harvey, get that son of a bitch
off our wagon
and bring that gun back here.
Now, goddamn it!
Aw, shit.
Harvey. Harvey!
Take the goddamn dynamite
and go help arvid.
I can't, Taylor, I--I can't.
Now, goddamn it,
or I'll shoot you
where you stand.
Blind!
Oooh.
Ow, I'm shot!
Hey, Taylor.
Yeah?
What was that that blowed up?
Harvey, goddamn it.
Harvey.
Shit!
Throw me that belt, there.
Ah... Ah... I can't see.
Ho, ho--
Val! Ho, ho,
val! Ho, ho,
goddamn it, ho!
Val, where are ya?
Val?!
Ho, ho, ho!
Goddamn it.
Ho!
Come on, you son of a bitch!
Aah.
Ah!
Oh.
Valentine!
Yeah?
You still want to arrest me
and take me back down there
to stand trial, don't you?
That's why I
came down here, Taylor.
Daddy would have
been real proud of you, val.
You know that even through
all this emotional
turmoil and bloodshed,
you maintained
your sense of purpose.
Well, Taylor,
I guess if you just
throw your guns down
and come on out here,
we'll ride back up to Los tragos
and see if we
can put a jury together.
That's a real comfort, val.
I sure wouldn't want
to go back up there
and stand trial without ya.
Oh, I surely wouldn't.
You know an odd thing, val?
That government man
with the letter
about you bein' dead?
That's downright queer.
What do you make of that, val?
I don't know if I'm certain
of my existence, Taylor.
Only my intentions.
Can you make it out here?
I don't know if I can.
I mean, I want to,
but I'm hurt awful bad.
It's kinda hard for me
just to let things go.
It's all right, Taylor.
Ah...
I'll just come on
in there and get ya.
I truly admire your
sense of duty, marshal.
Come here, Taylor!
Goddamn it!
Damn it, val,
get the hell off me.
I figured you
to be dead, soldier.
Death has been all around me,
but it's yet
to take a hold of me.
Well, let's see if we're able
to walk among the living.
We'll probably be havin'
to eat it in San Francisco,
huh?
Chinese food.
Yeah, I guess.
Son of a gun.
You know something?
You're kind of an odd bird.