Speedy Gonzales
- The son of the approximately
seven brothers
a bottle of whiskey and a coke for the kid.
Another ones, water suffices.
I can't believe I missed you.
- Maybe you just can't shoot?
Or maybe I dodged?
Speedy Gonzales?
- Yeah.
I pay for the bottles.
- No, they're free.
On the contrary: do you want
some more? On the house.
How about the tip?
- Of course.
By the way, why did you shot at me?
- Wrong guy.
Yes?
Right! Pour me a beer, sonny.
You're just passing by I suppose?
I'm afraid that you have gone
too far away from home now -
- and you might never find your
way back unless you leave soon.
Okay, okay. This New York
is still a small town
but I can assure you it will get bigger
and I can't protect all the passerbys
- unless they pass by very quickly
like you surely will? Right?
How about it?
I didn't hear your answer.
Ok, sheriff. Who killed my brother?
Who?
Moses Gonzales. Someone here
shot him in the back. Who was it?
Well...
The investigation is still going on...
- Yes, and I'll continue it.
What's up, Clyde?
You recognised me again?
It was nothing. Bye.
- Bye then.
Goddamn boys! The End of the world must
be near as the horses are shrinking.
Maybe it ate something bad.
Or maybe it has too small hide.
Let's unbutton it so it can grow more.
Maybe it's a kangaroo since it has
bags under the eyes.
Yes, and there's bags on the knees too.
It must be a kangaroo.
Those are good at jumping, I tell you.
Here's the stick. Try to jump over it!
Go on! Go on!
I think that the owner of this kangaroo
is reaching to see over the saloon door.
He must be leaving town soon.
Hey, animal. Do you eat some hay? I'll give
you some. - No, don't give so long canes.
Such a small animal can't eat so long canes. We have
to cut 'em shorter. Here you go. Eat some short hay.
If you're the owner of this draisine I'll
tell you it's ready to go.  -Thanks.
We haven't introduced ourselves yet.
I'm Speedy Gonzales.
Goddammit!
Yes, gentlemen. He's called Pony.
And you're? - Rud...
No, no. To him. Shake hands!
Jesse.
Rudolf!
Tell me something!
- About what?
About Moses.
- Ask her!
Tell me something about Moses!
For a moment I thought he's back from dead.
- He's my brother.
Did you know him well.
- Quite well. I was his wife.
Hello, "Slowest of the West".
- Hello, Bat Masterson.
Give me one more.
- Pay first the previous drinks!
Couldn't I have just one more.
I'm thinking of going to bank tomorrow.
Whisky.
How many?
- a couple.
Two normal sizes. Crude planks.
- Yeah.
Shot dead... it makes 30$.
Ten of spades, jack of spades, whor...
Queen of spades, king of spades
and a ace of spades.
Bat, you're playing honest.
- What do you mean?
I won! I have five-of-a-kind, aces!
Damned. You're cheating nevertheless.
Two ace of spades!
I never cheat. Draw!
Fine. Who's dealing?
- You are.
That's Manolito's chair.
- I raise 2$.
I raise 3$.
- 3$ more.
I raise 3$
- 4$ more.
Manolito will check how's your biting.
- 5$ more.
I still raise 5$.
5$ more!  - Actually, the drinks last
night were not on the house.
How much was it?
Nevermind. They were on the house anyway.
Do you want more?
I bet all in.
Do you know anything about Moses?
Everything is little messed up in this town.
I advice you to leave and forget it all.
You're fast. Ok. But there's too many of them
- Who do you mean?
One large teak coffin! My pa died finally!
-That's so sad, Hoss.
One large size. Teak!
Hey! Pa just died, drinks for everyone. I'll pay!
Finally I can start having some good time.
I was so pissed off herding the cows all the time.
Hey! Where's all the girls?
- How about your kid brother, Joe?
I guess he bit the dust too.
Rosa! Music!
a couple of 2-meters long, crude plank!
Don't let me die laughing!
Thanks!
Don't move!
You wanna know who killed
your brother? It was me.
I don't believe you.
You better stop digging this case
and leave this town.
Then I have to shoot you too.
Raise your little hands up!
Same goes for you, missy!
And for you! - And for you!
-And you!
What's happening here?
- I don't know. Join the queue.
Right!
Money or your life!
- I got nothing. They just took everything!
What? - 3 men just came
and took everything.
It's true!
I can't believe it.
- Oh, it's you, Clyde?
What a rotten luck!
You didn't recognise me?
- Not at all.
Damned! First time you don't
recognise me and I'm too late!
Well. Come on Clyde. Let's see if
anything's left. You never know.
Oh no, no. I don't think there's even
a cent left. They made a good job.
They were professionals, you see.
What are they doing here in our place?
- Don't be sad, Clyde!
I give you something from my own
pocket, so it's not a futile visit.
Here you go, something for you too.
Don't put your gun away during
the robbery. Someone could see.
Sorry.
Right!
Put the money on the desk!
-Yes.
Here, here. No sudden moves!
Thank you, I'll visit you tomorrow.
- You're welcome. Bye!
I saved your life again.
Have you ever seen a man hanged
with the guns still on his belt?
You could be the slowest of the west...
- but I'm even slower.
Are you picking a fight with me?
I only said that I'm the
slowest of the world.
I won...
Goddamn!
Senorita is very heated.
Can Manolito give a you
a little advice, senorita?
Senorita would be very wise if she'd take his
boyfriend with her and leave this town.
But before that Manolito and
senorita will...  - Hmm, why not?
Caramba!
There you go. Have a little bath.
Yes?
2 coffins, crude plank.
2 more!
One!
And one more!
A bottle of hooch.
We've run out of the crude planks.
It's clean now.
Can I go now?
And what's there?
Dust... and shells.
And what about there?
Dust.
Listen Claudia...
Can I go now? I was supposed to rob
a bank and it's almost their closing time.
Is it, really? Damn, I'm getting tired
of you playing a bank robber!
Be once a man and rob a train or something!
Go on now! And if you're not improving with
your jobs I shall change to real bullets!
It's a quiet bunch here.
They're getting nervous. Believe me,
you better leave here.
What the hell is going on here?
There's too many of them. Can't you
just leave before it's too late?
It's already too late.
One of you boys killed my brother.
Maybe it was you. Or you.
Or you.
I'll find out eventually.
Even if I have to shoot you all.
One by one.
Why can't we tell him who it was...
Ok, then.
You're beginning to be a quite
a nuisance, Speedy.
Of course we could deal with you differently.
Right?
Why do you always forget the women?
But we are gentlemen and
we don't like killing.
Well? How does it look?
It's a clean bottom, sonny.
What else?
It looks like someone shot you
with saltbullets to the ass.
Claudia
- What? Your wife?
Dammit. It was a real cardinal
mistake to marry Claudia.
No, no. Look, we can arrange
a divorce for you.
We can accuse her of mental cruelty
and the holes in your ass.
This is a robbery. Hands up
and go against the wall!
Not today. I got things to do.
I said: hands up and
go against the wall!
And I said: I got things to do.
Come again some other day!
Right! The jury seems to be
ready sitting in their right place.
This trial can be started.
Bring in the defendant!
Right! Slowest of the West,
you'll be the prosecutor!
And what's the charge?
He shot banker to his belly because
he was too slow to turn his back.
And what the defense has to say?
The late banker was known as...
should I say: unsocial man.
He was very negative towards
poor bill forgers.
Besides...
You had to be very fast
to shoot him in the belly -
- because he cowardly always
tried to turn his back.
Clyde has proved with his many former
robberies to be a proper bank robber -
- who didn't harm the personnel.
So if a man happens to miss
a shot with his gun -
- I don't think that's so aggravating.
I think that's very sensible.
So, shall we hear more witnesses
or shall we let him go?
As a prosecutor I want to hear more
testimonials so we can have a laugh.
Manolito, could you say a few words?
I think Clyde is innocent.
Banker's death was a result of
a wrong choice of a career.
It's wrong that one man keeps
a lot of money locked up -
- while people, amigos. People are
living in poverty and misery.
Although with all those pesos
we could build a better society.
Or amigos, drink some good tequila!
If banker had chose to be a farmer -
- he would be tending a little sheep
on his little farm right now, loved by all.
And he'd live today and with good luck -
- also tomorrow.
I think that...
- Yes, yes!
You agree with us!
Any other witnesses?
Hoss.
I think we all know that Clyde
was banker's best friend.
If there was no money in the bank when Clyde
was robbing it banker gave from his own purse.
That was true friendship, my friends!
But he went too far with it -
He couldn't stand watching
Clyde suffering from his failures.
When Clyde once again fumbled with
his gun and couldn't hit with it -
- banker wanted to prevent
Clyde feeling incompetent -
- and shot himself in the belly thus letting
Clyde feel some well deserved joy of killing.
That was true friendship, boys.
That's right!
The court has decided that
the banker committed suicide.
Strange thing is that such a bad shooter
could hit from such a short distance.
Let's go for drinks everyone.
Clyde is free to go.
190 cm, planed teak.
And now, drinks for everyone, my treat.
Now he'll be buried next to his brother.
Goddammit, I thought he
began to discover it all.
Amigo, it was a close call.
I wonder who shot him.
- At least it wasn't me.
Really?
- It's true. Believe it.
In any case, let's hope we're
finally through with this.
Moses needed to be killed. And only one
interested will be soon six feet under.
It's best to hold our tongue on this matter.
No one knows who killed Moses Gonzales
if someone happens to ask about it.
Amigo, you need to remind the
sheriff and the bartender too.
Also, no one knows who
killed Speedy gonzales.
But we don't know who did it anyway.
Tom, bury him deep!
I don't like ghosts.
Bat, why don't you offer
me a glass of whisky.
Well, boy. Buy your own drinks.
Hey, don't fight, boys.
Well, now's there a bullet hole ready.
I'll be the boss around here from now on.
If someone has something against
it, he's welcome to draw.
You pulled it off?
- Yep.
Whisky. I got taste of
dirt in my mouth.
I don't exactly know what has happened
and how you're here again -
- but you better drink that
whisky and hit the road -
- before you end up like your brother.
A bullet in the back, right?
You might guess what I want to ask?
- I know nothing about death of Moses.
Well? - They'll kill me if
I tell you anything.
I doesn't matter who kills you and I'm
the first one in the queue of killers.
I wasn't there myself but the others.
It happened like...
Moses Gonzales, you know me?
- Well, what's the problem?
This is a delation.
- I see.
The train robbery yesterday. It was
done by men from our town.
I was eating strawberries on the
railway and i saw the whole thing.
Did you recognise anyone?
I clearly saw Manolito,
Masterson, Hoss and Clyde.
But not others?
- No, but maybe this is enough.
This information was worth of gold.
- I thought so.
And you'll be rewarded
with some metal too.
I hope it's not nickel.
Right, there's our strawberry picker.
Amigos, who'll do it?
It's difficult to hit a moving target.
Clyde couldn't hit him anyway.
- Yes I could.
At least if I go nearer.
- I don't believe you.
What did I say? Second one hit
already but I made it sure.
I've always said that strawberries
are dangerous to your health.
That's so.
No one speaks nothing about this then, guys.
We're under the threat of death penalty
Otherwise we'll be all hanged.
That's how it was.
Even if you shoot me.
My feets are getting numb.
What are we waiting for?
Bomb is placed now and
they're both inside.
Yep, the vultures will have
a flying lunch soon.
Shall I do it yet?
Follow them!
Let's split up!
You go there! And others there!
I'll go that way. And you there.
Reaper has arrived.
Say hello to your pa!
I've run out of bullets.
- Me too.
Stay here.
Normal size, planed planks.
For once I drew fast.
Last one again. - Same here.
And now we run!
Come on!
I can't swim.
- Climb aboard then.
Amigo, your last meal.
Go on and chew it!
Fortunately we get more
men tomorrow.- Shut up!
I just said that we...
- I said: shut up!
I just said...
Cowards. I kill you all!
Nothing's gonna stop me.
You won't shed ash to my hand
anymore, Speedy Gonzales.
Come here, you coward!
Ok, guys. Now we'll make
a plan for tomorrow.
In the morning we'll go to the shore
of Indian pond to ambush Speedy.
What are you thinking?
I have a feeling that they'll go to the
shore of Indian pond to ambush us.
But I think that Speedy knows that we're going
to ambush him in the shore of Indian pond.
So he'll go to the mountains.
But sheriff will figure that I know they'll
ambush me in the shore of Indian pond.
So they go to the mountains. but we'll go -
We'll go to sleep. Good night!
Turn off the light, please.
It's your final moments now.
You can't shoot because I have the girl.
It's easy to shoot when
there's a hole already.
It's your turn now, Speedy.
Why haven't you shot me until now?
I missed you on the first time.
And it was fun to watch you kill a
bunch of bandits during this time.
Only one left now.
- Who?
You.
- What do you mean?
You shot Bill last year.
Did you know who he was?
Your fiancee.
I had to choose between Bill
and me. And I chose Bill.
On the dark stormy night
seven bounty killers ride.
They know where to find an outlaw
worth 10,000$ reward.
The vultures are hunting again.
1428 $ for each one
They're crossing the ford
when one is left behind
He falls from his horse
and there's six men left anymore.
The vultures are hunting again.
1666,6 $ are waiting them now
There's a streak of shadow in the forest.
Two men saw it but not the rest
They turn around, a twig crackles,
and both men fall dying.
The Vultures are hunting again.
Bounty is up to 2,500 $ now.
They ride until their horses are whacked.
In the morning they arrive at the canyon
A big boulder falls from the cliff
crushing two men underneath.
The vultures are hunting again.
It's 5000 $ for both of them now.
Those two keep riding on
and they stalk each other
The mountain path is dangerous.
Why did the other one fell down?
Last one arrives to the mountains
he finds a abandoned campfire.
He hears a whistle or just a wind?
He looks but no-one's there.
He stands on the top of the crag,
can almost feel the money in his hand.
He draws his gun, shoots and fall.
There's no-one left to collect the reward.
The vultures are hunting again.
You all know what's the
wage of the greedy men.
Speedy...
Oh, it was you.
Wake me up again!
What the hell? Hero died.
I thought so...
That was for Moses
Yes. Who called me?
Moses?
Yes.
Rosa was hiding me in the cellar
for two months, you see.
They tried to kill me and it was close too.
But now I got out of the cellar.
So, thank you, Speedy.
Let's go for drinks, I'll pay. Rosa!
And there goes Speedy Gonzales.
A man who killed Bat Masterson -
- Hoss, Manolito, "Slowest of
the West" and sheriff.
And all this because his brother happened
to pick strawberries on the railway.
He also killed Clyde.
- Bonnie died later.