CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
TURNER ENTERTAINMENT GROUP
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS,
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN I WAKE WITH THE BLESSED
IN THOSE MANSIONS OF REST *
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS
IN MY CROWN? *
* I AM THINKING TODAY
OF THAT BEAUTIFUL LAND *
* I SHALL REACH
WHEN THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN THROUGH WONDERFUL GRACE
BY MY SAVIOR I STAND *
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS
IN MY CROWN? *
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS,
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN I WAKE WITH THE BLESSED
IN THOSE MANSIONS OF REST *
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS
IN MY CROWN? *
* OH, WHAT JOY
IT WILL BE *
* WHEN HIS FACE
I BEHOLD... *
Man: HEAR THAT?
MIGHT SAY I WAS RAISED
ON THAT SONG.
HEARING IT TAKES ME BACK--
BACK TO THE OLD TIMES
WHEN I WAS YOUNG,
BACK TO WALESBURG.
ACCORDING TO THE WORDS
OF THE SONG,
WE'RE PROMISED A CITY OF GOLD
IN THE HEREAFTER.
I USED TO THINK THAT WAS
A LONG TIME TO HAVE TO WAIT.
BUT I KNOW NOW THAT
THERE IS A CITY OF GOLD
RIGHT HERE ON EARTH
FOR EVERY ONE OF US--
THE CITY OF OUR YOUTH.
WALESBURG'S ONLY ONE
NAME FOR IT; THAT'S ALL.
WALESBURG NOT AS IT IS NOW,
BUT AS IT USED TO BE.
I JUST HAVE TO SHUT MY EYES,
AND I'M THERE.
NOTHING'S CHANGED.
EVEN I HAVEN'T CHANGED.
I'M ALWAYS A BOY
IN WALESBURG.
AND THERE AT MY SIDE,
JUST AS HE'LL ALWAYS BE,
IS THE PARSON--PARSON GRAY.
AND PASSING BEFORE ME ARE
ALL THE PEOPLE WHO WERE
A PART OF MY GROWING UP--
PEOPLE LIKE MRS. BELCHER,
WHO TOOK IN BOARDERS,
AND HER NIECE FAITH SAMUELS,
THE DISTRICT SCHOOLTEACHER.
SWEET, PRETTY
MISS SAMUELS.
DID YOU
HEAR THAT, JOHN?
GRANNY GAILBRAITH,
WHO COULD REMEMBER
SEEING GEORGE WASHINGTON.
THAD CARROLL, WHO HAD
SERVED AS DRUMMER BOY
AT THE FIRST BULL RUN.
LON BACKETT, WHO KEPT
THE GENERAL STORE AND HAD
A FINGER IN EVERY PIE.
EVEN CHLOROFORM WIGGINS.
HIS MA HAD NEVER HEARD
OF CHLOROFORM UNTIL HE WAS BORN,
AND SHE THOUGHT IT WAS
A MIGHTY PRETTY NAME.
AND ALL THE OTHERS,
WALESBURG PEOPLE.
GONE NOW, MOST OF THEM,
AND YET AS CLOSE TO ME STILL
AS PEOPLE IN A FAVORITE STORY--
A STORY THAT HAD ITS BEGINNING
BEFORE I WAS BORN
ON THE DAY THE PARSON
ARRIVED IN OUR TOWN.
OF COURSE, THIS WASN'T
MUCH OF A TOWN THEN
IN THOSE
FIRST HARD YEARS
THAT FOLLOWED
THE WAR BETWEEN THE STATES,
BUT IT SUITED
THE PARSON
RIGHT FROM THE MINUTE
HE STEPPED OFF THE TRAIN
AND STARTED
TO LOOK AROUND.
[TRAIN WHISTLES]
HE MUST HAVE ATTRACTED
PLENTY OF ATTENTION
AS HE WALKED DOWN MAIN STREET
FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN HIS BRAND-NEW
BLACK PULPIT COAT
AND FADED GRAY
CAVALRY BREECHES
AND HIS BIG OLD
BIBLE IN HIS HAND.
BUT HE JUST KEPT ON WALKING TILL
HE GOT TO JERRY HIGGINS' SALOON.
[MEN TALKING
AND LAUGHING]
HE DIDN'T HAVE
TO CALL FOR QUIET.
IT JUST FOLLOWED HIM THROUGH
THAT ROOM LIKE A HOUND DOG.
BOYS, I'M YOUR
NEW PREACHER,
AND I AIM TO GIVE
MY FIRST SERMON
RIGHT HERE AND NOW.
[LAUGHING]
THANKS.
NOW, SEEING THAT
THIS IS AS NEW TO ME
AS IT IS TO YOU...
I RECKON
WE'D BEST BEGIN
AT THE BEGINNING.
"IN THE BEGINNING
WAS THE WORD,
"AND THE WORD
WAS WITH GOD.
AND THE WORD
WAS GOD."
Narrator:
FROM THAT DAY ON,
WALESBURG AND THE PARSON
KIND OF GREW UP TOGETHER.
HE PREACHED AROUND
IN BACK ROOMS,
AND HE PRAYED
IN PARLORS,
AND HE LED
THE SINGING IN BARNS.
* SHALL WE GATHER
AT THE RIVER *
* WHERE BRIGHT ANGEL FEET
HAVE TROD *
* WITH ITS CRYSTAL LIGHT
FOREVER *
* FLOWING BY
THE THRONE OF GOD *
* YES, WE'LL GATHER
AT THE RIVER *
* THE BEAUTIFUL,
THE BEAUTIFUL RIVER *
* GATHER WITH THE SAINTS
AT THE RIVER *
* THAT FLOWS
BY THE THRONE OF GOD *
Narrator: AND BY THE TIME WORK
STARTED ON THE PARSON'S CHURCH,
HIS VICTORY WAS WON.
JUST ABOUT EVERYBODY
IN WALESBURG TOOK A HAND
IN THAT CHURCH BUILDING.
AND IF EVER A HOUSE OF GOD
OR MAN WAS PUT TOGETHER
WITH LOVING HANDS,
THIS ONE WAS.
YES, THE PARSON'S CHURCH
IS ONE OF THE NICEST PARTS
OF THE PARSON'S STORY.
AND NOW I WAS IN THE STORY, TOO.
HAD BEEN EVER SINCE
I COULD REMEMBER.
MY PARENTS HAD DIED
WHEN I WAS SMALL,
SO I'D COME TO LIVE
IN THE PARSON'S HOUSE,
SHARING THE PARSON'S HEART
WITH THE PARSON'S WIFE,
WHO WAS MY AUNT HARRIET.
[HUMMING]
WHAT'S THIS?
DINNER NOT READY YET?
GARFIELD, WE BETTER
GET A NEW COOK.
ENJOY THE SERVICE
THIS MORNING, HARRIET?
HUMPH.
WELL, NOW I'M
GLAD TO HEAR THAT.
EVERYONE ELSE WAS SAYING WHAT
A GOOD SERVICE IT WAS, TOO.
JOHN KENYON,
YOU KNOW,
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO DO EVERYTHING
THE PARSON DOES.
YES'M.
YOU KNOW,
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I THOUGHT IT WAS A PRETTY
GOOD SERVICE MYSELF.
DON'T YOU LAUGH
AT ME, MR. GRAY.
WHY, HARRIET, HONEY,
WHAT GIVES YOU THE IDEA
I'M LAUGHING AT YOU?
HERE I AM STANDING AROUND
WITH A BIG SMILE ON MY FACE
JUST 'CAUSE
I FEEL GOOD,
AND YOU--
YES, WELL, ALL
I HAVE TO SAY IS,
YOU OUGHT TO FEEL
ASHAMED OF YOURSELF.
I WAS BROUGHT UP
TO BELIEVE
THAT A MAN WHO BROKE
HIS SOLEMN PROMISE
TO A LADY
WAS A PRETTY POOR
SORT OF A MAN.
OH, HARRIET, I GUESS
YOU FOUND ME OUT.
I AM A PRETTY
POOR SORT OF MAN.
I WAS INTENDING
TO MENTION IT SOONER.
SOMETHING ALWAYS
CAME UP.
THIS MORNING WAS
JUST THE LAST STRAW.
YOU KNOW YOU
PROMISED ME TIME
AND TIME AND AGAIN
THAT AS LONG AS
I PLAYED THE ORGAN
FOR THE SERVICES,
I COULD CHOOSE
THE HYMNS.
SO I HAVE.
YES, AND PROMISE
IS ALL YOU DO.
NEVER MIND WHAT
I WANT TO SING;
WHAT ANYBODY ELSE
IN WALESBURG WANTS
TO SING.
OH, NO, WEEK IN,
WEEK OUT,
IT'S THAT OLD
STARS IN MY CROWN.
I LIKE
OH, I KNOW YOU DO,
MR. GRAY.
I ASSURE YOU, IT'S
COMMON KNOWLEDGE.
NEVER HEAR THE LAST
OF IT IN THIS WORLD.
AND I SUPPOSE
IF YOU HAVE YOUR WAY,
IT'LL BE THE SAME
IN THE NEXT.
JOHN, YOU PUT THOSE SHOES
AND STOCKINGS RIGHT BACK ON.
THEY MAKE MY FEET HOT.
I DON'T CARE.
YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO RUN
AROUND BAREFOOT
ON THE SABBATH.
IT ISN'T
RESPECTFUL.
SHOO.
John:
AW, GARFIELD.
LANGUAGE?
NOW, JOHN,
DO EXACTLY AS YOUR
AUNT HARRIET SAYS.
ANY WOMAN WHO CAN
BAKE A CHOCOLATE CAKE
AS GOOD AS THIS
DESERVES ALL THE
CONSIDERATION
SHE CAN GET.
NOW, HARRIET, HONEY,
ABOUT THIS
HYMN BUSINESS.
IT'S FOR YOU TO SAY
WHAT YOU WANT DONE
AND FOR ME
TO DO IT.
DON'T BE SHY
ABOUT EXPRESSING
YOUR DESIRES.
JUST SPEAK
RIGHT UP,
AND I WON'T OPEN
MY MOUTH...
EXCEPT TO DO
THE PREACHING.
IF THE DAY EVER COMES
WHEN YOU DON'T
OPEN YOUR MOUTH...
THAT'S MY
LAST WORD, HARRIET--
EXCEPT TO DO
THE PREACHING.
* WILL THERE BE
ANY STARS *
* ANY STARS
IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN I WAKE
WITH THE BLESSED *
* IN THOSE MANSIONS
OF REST *
* WILL THERE BE
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN? *
Narrator: AFTER THE PARSON
AND MY AUNT HARRIET,
THE MOST IMPORTANT PEOPLE
IN MY WORLD
WERE UNCLE FAMOUS PRILL
AND HIS OLD DOG BELLE.
UNCLE FAMOUS KNEW EVERYTHING
ABOUT HUNTING AND FISHING,
AND I DON'T GUESS THERE WAS
A BOY OR MAN IN WALESBURG
WHO HADN'T HAD HIM
FOR A TEACHER.
John: * ANY STARS,
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH-- *
Man: HELLO, JOHN.
HELLO,
CHLOROFORM.
UNCLE FAMOUS.
WHERE ARE
Y'ALL GOING?
FISHING.
THAT'S WHERE
I THOUGHT
YOU WAS GOING.
WELL, GOOD-BYE,
JOHN.
BYE, CHLOROFORM.
BYE,
UNCLE FAMOUS.
CHLOROFORM.
[DOG BARKING]
BOY,
POSSESS YOURSELF.
LEAVE MR. FROG BE.
HE AIN'T GONNA HELP
YOU CATCH NO FISH.
OH, THEY AIN'T
BITING TODAY.
MAYBE THEY AIN'T,
AND MAYBE THEY IS,
BUT I JUST SEEN
A BIG OLD CATFISH
COME SNEAKING
THIS WAY.
I KNOW JUST WHAT
HE'S THINKING.
HE'S THINKING,
"UH, THAT OLD MAN,
HE'S TOO SMART FOR ME,
"BUT THAT BOY,
HE'S SO TAKEN UP
WITH MR. FROG,
I'M GONNA GRAB
HIS DOUGH BALL AND
JUST SCAT AWAY."
NOW, HOW'D YOU KNOW
HE WAS THINKING THAT?
I BEEN ON CLOSE
TERMS WITH CATFISH
EVER SINCE I WAS
BIG ENOUGH
TO SCRATCH MYSELF
WITH MY LEFT HAND.
IF I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THEY'S THINKING,
WHO DOES?
WHERE'D HE GO TO?
HE DIDN'T SAY.
OH, THERE HE IS NOW!
GET OUT THE WAY.
OH, THAT'S A BIG ONE.
STAND BACK, NOW,
STAND BACK.
WELL, BANG MY TIME.
I DONE SPAKE IN PRIDE,
AND THE LORD HAD
HIS EAR OUT AND HEARD ME.
GO ON HOME.
YOUR MAMMY WANTS YOU.
[HOOFBEATS]
WHOA, WHOA.
FAMOUS, I'D LIKE
TO TALK TO YOU.
HOWDY, MR. BACKETT.
HOT.
YES, SIR.
FAMOUS, GOT SOME
GOOD NEWS FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW THAT MICA VEIN
I'VE BEEN WORKING
ON MY 60 ACRES
OVER THE HILL
FROM YOUR PLACE?
AND MAKING A MIGHTY
GOOD THING OUT OF IT, TOO.
WELL, THAT VEIN HAS
RUN SMACK-DAB INTO
YOUR PROPERTY LINE.
FOUND OUT ABOUT IT
FIRST THING THIS MORNING.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU
SAY TO THAT?
WELL, SIR,
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T SEE
IT'S ANYTHING
TO DO WITH ME.
WHY, IT'S YOUR PROPERTY,
AIN'T IT?
IT AIN'T
MY PROPERTY.
IF I DON'T GET TITLE
TO THAT LAND,
I'LL HAVE TO CLOSE DOWN
THE MINE.
SO, HERE I AM
WITH A LITTLE PROPOSITION.
60 CENTS AN ACRE,
CASH IN HAND,
OR YOU CAN TAKE IT OUT
IN CREDIT AT THE STORE.
DONE?
SELL MY LAND?
THAT'S THE TICKET.
MMM. WELL, SIR,
THANKS ALL THE SAME,
BUT I BEEN MAKING OUT
ON THAT PLACE A SIGHT
OF YEARS NOW.
YES, BUT THAT ISN'T
WHAT I ASKED YOU.
YES, SIR.
WHAT I MEAN IS THAT--
WELL, I--I RECKON
I'M JUST TOO OLD
TO MAKE A CHANGE.
NOT ENOUGH MONEY
FOR YOU, HUH?
SIR?
NOW, NO HARD FEELINGS.
MIND YOU, I LIKE
A SHARP TRADER,
I ALWAYS DID.
ONLY WISHED I
WAS ONE MYSELF.
I'LL GIVE YOU
80 CENTS AN ACRE,
PROVIDED YOU TAKE OUT
HALF IN CREDIT AT THE STORE.
WELL, SIR--
80 CENTS AN ACRE,
THAT'S 80 TIMES 20.
THAT'S $16, FAMOUS,
MORE MONEY THAN
YOU EVER SEEN.
MR. BACKETT,
LET ME ASK YOU
SOMETHING.
I GOT THIS HERE
SUIT OF OVERALLS,
AIN'T I?
YEAH.
I GOT A LONG-TAILED
COAT FOR SUNDAYS.
UH-HUH.
A HOUSE,
GOT A BED,
AND I GETS
MY VITTLES
3 TIMES EVERY
GOD'S DAY,
DON'T I?
YEAH.
MR. BACKETT,
WHAT DOES I WANT
WITH $16?
NOW, YOU LOOK HERE.
THE BOYS I'VE GOT
WORKING FOR ME
AIN'T GONNA
BLAME ME
WHEN THE MICA MINING
HAS TO STOP
AND THEIR GOOD WAGES
ALONG WITH IT.
IT AIN'T ME THEY'LL
BE THROWING DOWN ON
WHEN THEIR WOMEN
AND CHILDREN HAS
TO DO WITHOUT.
NO, SIR,
I WOULDN'T WANT
SUCH AS THAT
ON MY CONSCIENCE.
THINK IT OVER,
FAMOUS.
YES, SIR.
GIDDAP.
WATCH YOUR POLE, BOY!
GET AHOLD OF IT!
GET AHOLD BEFORE
HE TAKES IT AWAY!
HOOK HIM
OUT OF THERE!
PULL 'IM!
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT!
THAT'S A CAT.
CATCH HIS MOUTH
AND WATCH HIS FINS.
IF HE PINCH YOU,
HE'LL POISON YOU.
YOUR HAND WILL SWELL UP
LIKE A PUFF ADDER BIT YOU.
GET AWAY FROM THERE, BELLE!
Famous: THAT'S
A NICE ONE.
WELL, WELL, MANY HAPPY
RETURNS TO THE DAY, SON.
HOWDY, FAMOUS.
HOWDY, PARSON.
JUST MET LON BACKETT
DRIVING OFF
LOOKING MAD ENOUGH
TO BITE HIMSELF.
IS THAT TRUE WHAT
I BEEN HEARING
ABOUT THAT MICA VEIN
OF HIS GOING OVER TO
YOUR SIDE OF THE FENCE?
I RECKON IT'S TRUE,
RIGHT ENOUGH.
PEOPLE ARE TELLING IT
LIKE IT'S A BIG JOKE.
MYSELF, I DON'T THINK
IT'S SO FUNNY.
I DON'T WANT
TO MAKE NO TROUBLE
FOR NOBODY, PARSON,
BUT THAT'S MY PLACE.
I AIN'T NEVER
HAD NO OTHER.
WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO ME
IF I HAS
TO SELL MY LAND?
UNCLE FAMOUS
DOESN'T HAVE TO SELL,
DOES HE, PARSON?
YOU'RE
A FREE MAN, FAMOUS.
THAT'S RIGHT,
UNCLE FAMOUS,
'CAUSE THE LAW SAYS.
JUST SAYING
A GOOD THING
DON'T MAKE IT SO.
LON BACKETT
PUTS ME IN MIND
OF AN OLD FOXHOUND
I USED TO HAVE
NAME OF GOVERNOR DOBBS.
OLD GOV HAD A VOICE
LIKE A $12 BUGLE,
AND HE LOVED
TO USE IT.
SEEMED LIKE HE
JUST WASN'T HAPPY
ENOUGH TO LIVE
UNLESS HE COULD TELL
EVERYBODY WHAT TO DO.
GOT TO WHERE EVERY TIME
I TURNED HIM LOOSE IN THE PACK,
HE'D START
GIVING TONGUE
WHETHER HE PICKED UP
THE SCENT OR NOT,
JUST TO PROVE
HE WAS TOP DOG.
HA HA HA!
SOME FOLKS ARE LIKE HOUNDS
IN THAT RESPECT, I RECKON.
GOOD STORY.
DON'T RUSH ME.
TROUBLE WAS,
WHEN IT COME TO TRAILING,
OL' GOV NEVER DID KNOW
A BUCK RABBIT FROM A BUMBLEBEE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THAT FOOL DOG DID?
HE LED THE WHOLE PACK
PLUMB INTO A FLOCK OF SKUNKS.
[LAUGHING]
AH, I GUESS LON BACKETT
WILL HAVE TO KICK UP
AN ALMIGHTY BIG STINK
BEFORE HE LEARNS HIS LESSON.
YOU READY TO GO, JOHN?
I THOUGHT WE'D STOP
BY THE ISBELL PLACE
ON THE WAY HOME.
COME AGAIN SOON.
Gray: WE'LL
SURE DO THAT.
HEY!
JOSH!
Narrator:
I GUESS THE PARSON AND I
HAD BEEN OUT TO THE ISBELL PLACE
A HUNDRED TIMES.
THE PARSON USED TO SAY
THE ISBELL FARM WAS
EVERYTHING A FARM SHOULD BE.
Gray: HEY, JED.
JED!
MY!
Narrator: WHAT'S MORE,
HE ACTED LIKE HE THOUGHT
JED ISBELL HIMSELF
WAS EVERYTHING A MAN SHOULD BE--
ANYWAY, ALMOST EVERYTHING.
WELL, NOW!
CLIMB DOWN!
GET A DRINK OF
THE BEST WELL WATER
IN THE COUNTY!
HOW'S THAT GAME
LEG OF YOURS?
OH, JUST TOL'ABLE,
J.D., JUST TOL'ABLE.
Narrator:
A LOT OF FOLKS THOUGHT
JED ISBELL WAS A STRANGE FRIEND
FOR A PREACHER TO HAVE,
BUT THEN, THE PARSON
AND JED HAD FOUGHT SIDE BY SIDE
FROM FORT DONELSON
TO MISSIONARY RIDGE.
THE WAR HAD WELDED BONDS
THAT NOTHING, IT SEEMED,
COULD BREAK.
HOW YOU
BEEN THERE, J.D.?
FINE, FINE.
GUESS YOU AIN'T
HEARD THE NEWS.
[MEN WHOOPING AND HOLLERING]
HEY, JED!
[LAUGHING]
JED, YOU'VE GOT ENOUGH
TOW-HEADED SONS
TO START A SWEDISH
SUNDAY SCHOOL.
HOWDY, PARSON.
WHAT WAS
YOUR NEWS?
OH, NOTHING SPECIAL,
I JUST BOUGHT 40 ACRES
OF BOTTOM LAND
FROM THE WIDOW MATTHIAS,
THAT'S ALL.
MORE LAND?
YES, THE BOYS HERE SORT
OF TALKED ME INTO IT.
I GUESS THEY FELT
THAT I WASN'T KEEPING
'EM BUSY ENOUGH.
OHH! HA HA HA!
IT WAS A GOOD BUY,
PRIME SOIL.
I FIGURE WE'LL GET
A BALE AN ACRE
OFF OF THAT LAND.
YOU'LL DO IT,
ALL RIGHT.
YOU GOT THE LORD
ON YOUR SIDE.
DON'T YOU KNOW
THAT BY NOW?
WELL, NOW LET
ME SEE, PARSON.
I DON'T REMEMBER
TAKING ON ANY
EXTRA HANDS LATELY.
JUST ME AND THE MISSIS
AND THE BOYS
AND TWO GOOD MULES
NAMED SAM AND IKE.
[LAUGHING]
I THINK WE'LL
GET ALONG
WITHOUT ANY HELP
FROM THE LORD.
WELL, FOLKS CAN GET
ALONG WITHOUT EYES, TOO,
BUT THEY CAN'T SEE.
COME ON, JOHN.
YOU BOYS OUGHT TO
TAKE BETTER CARE OF
THIS OLD BILLY GOAT--
KEEP HIM OUT OF FIGHTS
HE CAN'T WIN.
Boys: SEE YOU, PARSON,
GOOD-BYE, NOW.
John: OW!
HOW ARE YOU,
SARAH?
JUST FINE AS SILK,
THANK YOU, PARSON.
MY, DON'T
THEY GROW!
THEY SURE DO.
THESE ARE
FOR HARRIET.
THANKS.
AND IF YOU'RE GOING
BY HARRIS' PLACE,
I'D BE OBLIGED
IF YOU LEAVE THIS SOUP
FOR OLD DOC.
TELL BESSIE JUST
TO ADD WATER.
CAN YOU
REMEMBER THAT?
REMEMBER THAT,
JOHN.
WHEN YOU COMING
TO CHURCH, JED?
JUST AS SOON AS YOU
GET GOD TO PLOW THAT
BOTTOM LAND FOR ME.
SHAME.
I'LL SEE
WHAT I CAN DO.
HA HA HA!
GET ALONG, JOSH!
[BOYS WHOOPING AND HOLLERING]
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
CHLOROFORM?
YEAH, WHAT ARE YOU
RUNNING AWAY FOR?
HE'S NOT
GONNA HURT YOU.
DON'T YOU LET HIM
HURT YOU, CHLOROFORM!
NOW, PERRY, I DIDN'T SAY
YOU COULDN'T KNOCK IT OFF.
I JUST ASKED YOU
NOT TO DO IT.
YOU SAID
I COULDN'T.
ISN'T THAT WHAT
HE SAID, BOYS?
THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
SURE DID, HE SURE DID!
WOW!
DID YOU SEE THAT?
OW!
[LAUGHING AND LASHING]
HE'S SCARED!
HE'S RIGHT SCARED.
NOW, PERRY, I WAS JUST JOKING
ALL THE TIME. PERRY, I--
I THINK I'LL JUST DRAW
YOUR PICTURE ON THAT WALL.
NOW, NOW, PERRY,
NOW, PE--
Man: SAY, PERRY,
DON'T YOU THINK
THAT'S ABOUT ENOUGH?
IT'S ENOUGH WHEN
I SAY IT'S ENOUGH.
PICK UP YOUR HAT
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
Men: OHH!
[LAUGHING]
PERRY PUTS ME IN MIND
OF A COLONEL I HAD ONCE.
HE NEVER LEARNED
TO PROTECT HIS REAR.
[LAUGHING]
DOC?
OH, DOC?
WELL?
WELL, DAN HARRIS.
YOU JUST GET HOME?
I ARRIVED IN WALESBURG
LAST NIGHT.
I TAKE IT YOU CAME
TO SEE MY FATHER.
I HAVE A PRESENT
FOR HIM FROM
SARAH ISBELL.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO ADD WATER--
WELL, HE'S RESTING.
HE CAN'T
BE DISTURBED.
HE'S NOT WORSE,
IS HE?
HE'S TIRED OUT.
SO AM I; HALF THE TOWN'S
BEEN HERE TODAY,
AND THE OTHER HALF SENT
WORD THEY'D COME TOMORROW.
WELL, HE CAN'T
IMPROVE UNDER THAT
KIND OF TREATMENT.
NOBODY COULD.
I'D APPRECIATE IT,
MISTER...
IF YOU'D
SPREAD THE WORD
THAT WE'RE NOT HOLDING
OPEN HOUSE HERE.
WELL, DON'T GET
EXCITED, DAN.
WE WANT HIM
TO GET WELL AS
MUCH AS YOU DO.
GIVE HIM A CHANCE.
PLEASE STAY AWAY
FROM HIM.
IF THERE'S
ANY MESSAGES--
Man: DAN!
YOU, DAN, WHO YOU
CLAMORING AT?
THAT THE PARSON?
KENDALL!
YES, SIR,
IT'S THE PARSON.
WELL, SEND HIM
OUT HERE.
IT'S ME HE COME
TO SEE, NOT YOU.
SIDE PORCH.
WELL, GOOD TO SEE YOU
AT THIS HOUR.
SIT DOWN, SIT DOWN,
PUT YOUR FEET UP.
I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T STAY.
OH, YOU DON'T
WANT TO PAY NO
ATTENTION TO DAN.
I WAS TREATING
HEART CASES BEFORE
I MET HIS MOTHER.
PUT YOUR FEET UP
AND BE COMFORTABLE.
YOU SURE
THERE'S ANYTHING
WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU LOOK SPRYER THAN
A JAYBIRD TO ME.
THE FACT IS,
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW IT,
I'VE WALKED OUT
OF MY FRONT DOOR
FOR THE LAST TIME.
NEXT TIME
I MAKE THE TRIP,
I'LL BE RIDING
IN STYLE,
AND YOU'LL BE HELPING
TO CARRY ME.
FOR ONCE, DOC,
I HOPE YOU'RE WRONG.
WELL,
FOR ONCE I AIN'T.
HERE'S DAN COME
TO CHASE YOU AWAY.
CALLS HIMSELF
A DOCTOR.
WELL, I LEARNED
MORE MEDICINE
HOLDING OL'
DOC GILBERT'S HORSE
THAN HE'LL
EVER KNOW.
HERE, WHAT--
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M ENTITLED TO ONE
PIPE A DAY, AIN'T I?
ONE PIPE
A DAY, PARSON.
HA!
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
IT'S WARM.
YOU AIN'T NO DOCTOR.
YOU'RE A DADBLAMED
DETECTIVE.
AND QUITE A STRANGER
IN WALESBURG AT THAT.
WE'RE HOPING THIS TIME
HE'LL TAKE OFF HIS HAT
AND STAY AWHILE.
OH, DAN'S HOME
TO STAY THIS TIME,
AIN'T YOU, DAN?
IF YOU
SAY SO, POP.
YES, EVERYTHING'S
READY FOR YOU--
READY AND WAITING.
YOU WON'T EVEN
HAVE TO CHANGE
THE SHINGLE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO TALK
ABOUT IT NOW, DO WE?
WALESBURG WON'T BE
NEEDING A NEW DOCTOR
FOR YEARS YET.
WELL, DON'T DO NO HARM
TO MAKE PLANS, SON.
I REMEMBER THE DAY
YOU WAS BORN.
I RAN UP AND DOWN
THE STREET LIKE
A SHORT-PANTSED KID,
TELLING EVERYBODY I MET,
"GOT ANOTHER DOCTOR
IN THE FAMILY NOW."
I NEVER DID MAKE
A PLAN THAT DIDN'T
HAVE YOU IN IT.
BUT SOMEHOW LATELY,
MY FEELINGS FOR YOU
ARE KIND OF GETTING
ALL MIXED UP
WITH MY FEELINGS
FOR THIS TOWN,
THE FOLKS IN IT.
I'VE LIVED
SO CLOSE TO 'EM
AND TAKEN CARE
OF THEM SO LONG,
THEY'RE ALMOST AS MUCH
MY FAMILY AS YOU ARE.
WELL, YOU LOOK
AFTER THEM FOR ME--
YOU AND THE PARSON HERE.
NOW, PA, DON'T--
YES, BESSIE,
WHAT IS IT?
SOMEONE WANTS
THE DOCTOR.
I TOLD--
YOU TELL THEM
THE DOCTOR'S RESTING.
WELL, WHO IS IT,
BESSIE?
THE WIDOW SMITH,
SHE'S GOT THEM PAINS
IN HER CHEST AGAIN.
SHE'S BAD.
ANNIE SMITH?
YEAH.
RECKON YOU'D
BETTER GO, SON.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THAT, SIR,
THEY ASKED
FOR DR. HARRIS.
BESSIE,
YOU'RE A FOOL!
YOU GO AND TELL THEM
DR. HARRIS IS COMING!
WELL, SON...
I JUST--
I WISH IT WAS ANYBODY
BUT ANNIE SMITH.
THAT'S ONE CASE
HE AIN'T LIKELY TO WIN,
AND IT'S GOOD TO WIN
THE FIRST TIME.
I RECKON I DON'T HAVE
TO TELL YOU THAT, PARSON.
I RECKON YOU AIN'T
FORGOT THE FIRST TIME
YOU GOT UP TO PREACH
DOWN YONDER
IN JERRY HIGGINS' SALOON.
COME TO THINK OF IT,
DAN'S WORSE OFF THAN
I WAS.
AT LEAST I DIDN'T HAVE
YOUR SHOES TO FILL.
YEAH, HE'LL FILL 'EM,
ALL RIGHT.
RIGHT NOW,
HE'S A LITTLE
LONG ON EDUCATION
AND A LITTLE
SHORT ON SENSE.
HE'S GOT
A LOT TO LEARN.
EVEN WITH THAT,
HE'S A BETTER
DOCTOR THAN I AM.
DON'T YOU TELL HIM
I SAID SO.
GOT A MATCH?
UH-UH.
WELL, I MAY AS WELL
SMOKE HERE.
NO SMOKING
IN THE HEREAFTER.
[SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
* MY SAVIOR COMES
AND WALKS WITH ME *
* AND SWEET COMMUNION HERE
HAVE WE *
* HE GENTLY LEADS ME
BY HIS HAND *
* FOR THIS IS-- *
[ORGAN STOPS]
* OH, BEULAH LAND,
SWEET BEULAH LAND *
* AS ON THE HIGHEST MOUNT
I STAND *
* I LOOK AWAY
ACROSS THE SEA *
* WHERE MANSIONS ARE PREPARED
FOR ME... *
PARSON, YOU'RE WANTED
OVER TO THE WIDOW SMITH'S.
[LABORED BREATHING]
Gray: HOW'S ANNIE?
Woman: NOT SO GOOD,
I'M AFRAID.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I'VE COME TO SAY
A PRAYER FOR ANNIE.
MRS. SMITH'S
VERY ILL.
IF YOU REALLY
WANT TO HELP HER,
YOU'LL GET OUT
AND LEAVE HER TO ME.
PARSON?
I'M RIGHT HERE,
ANNIE.
PARSON...
[BREATHING STOPS]
IT'S ALL OVER.
NO, DOCTOR,
IT'S JUST BEGINNING.
YOU CAN GO IN NOW.
THE REST OF YOU
HAD BETTER GO HOME.
HERE, YOU,
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
TO YOUR HAND?
DROPPED THE STOVE LID
ON IT 2, 3 DAYS AGO.
DON'T AMOUNT
TO NOTHING.
WELL, IT WILL
AMOUNT TO SOMETHING
IF IT ISN'T PROPERLY
ATTENDED TO.
WHY HAVEN'T YOU
SEEN A DOCTOR?
DOC HARRIS IS SICK,
AIN'T HE?
YOU CALL AROUND
TOMORROW. I'LL
TAKE CARE OF IT.
DON'T AMOUNT
TO NOTHING.
DAN?
GOOD NIGHT.
DAN, I WAS THINKING
OF A SAYING
YOUR FATHER HAS.
HE SAYS IF THE LORD
WANTS A PERSON
BAD ENOUGH,
IT'S NOT UP TO HIM
TO STAND IN THE WAY.
MR. GRAY,
WE'D BETTER GET
SOMETHING STRAIGHT
RIGHT NOW.
I LOVE AND ADMIRE
MY FATHER,
BUT THAT DOESN'T
MEAN THAT I HAVE
TO ACCEPT HIS WAYS.
AS LONG AS I'M DOCTOR
IN THIS TOWN,
YOU'LL OBLIGE ME BY
ASKING MY PERMISSION
BEFORE YOU INTERFERE
WITH MY PATIENTS.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT INTERFERING.
I CAME OUT HERE
TONIGHT
BECAUSE I WAS
SENT FOR,
SAME AS YOU.
WE'LL BE MEETING
LIKE THIS RIGHT
ALONG NOW,
AND YOU MAY AS WELL
GET USED TO IT.
SOULS DON'T ALWAYS
ENJOY PERFECT HEALTH,
YOU KNOW,
ANY MORE THAN BODIES DO.
WELL, I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN SOULS, MR. GRAY.
AND WHEN I WANT A SERMON
ON THE SUBJECT,
I'LL COME
TO CHURCH FOR IT.
GOOD. I'LL BE GLAD
TO PREACH YOU ONE.
WELL, THAT'D BE
A WASTE OF YOUR TIME...
AND MINE.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT,
DR. HARRIS.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
Bessie: YES,
HE'S RIGHT HERE.
SOMEONE
TO SEE YOU--
[CHILD SCREAMING]
DR. HARRIS,
THIS IS BOBBY SAM CARROLL.
BOBBY SAM,
QUIET DOWN, DEAR.
THE DOCTOR ISN'T
GOING TO HURT YOU.
WE'VE HAD
A LITTLE ACCIDENT
WITH A FISH HOOK.
YES, WHERE?
WHY, AT THE SUNDAY
SCHOOL PICNIC.
OH! OH, IT'S CAUGHT
IN HIS LEG.
YOU SEE, IT WON'T
COME OUT THIS WAY
BECAUSE OF THE BARB,
AND IT WON'T COME OUT
THIS WAY BECAUSE OF THE EYE
FOR THE FISHING LINE,
YOU KNOW?
YES.
[SCREAMING]
BOBBY SAM!
I'M AFRAID SOME
OF THE OLDER BOYS
HAVE BEEN FRIGHTENING HIM.
WITH STORIES
ABOUT ME?
NEVER MIND.
NOW, JOHN, WHAT
DID I TELL YOU?
NOTHING TERRIBLE'S
GOING TO HAPPEN.
JOHN WAS SHOWING
BOBBY SAM HOW TO CAST,
AND THE FIRST THING--
[SCREAMING AND CRYING]
DR. HARRIS!
LET ME HAVE ONE
OF YOUR HATPINS.
LOOK HERE,
STOP THAT!
NOW, LOOK.
THIS IS YOU,
AND THIS IS
THAT FISHHOOK
STICKING
INTO YOU.
NOW HERE'S
THE EYE.
THAT'S FOR THE
FISHING LINE,
YOU KNOW.
NOW, I'M GOING
TO TAKE AND CUT
THE EYE
RIGHT OFF THAT
HOOK LIKE THIS.
THEN I'M GOING TO
PULL THE SHANK OUT
WITH ONE PULL,
LIKE THIS.
SEE? THAT'S ALL
THERE IS TO IT.
NOW, YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO MAKE A FUSS
ABOUT A LITTLE THING
LIKE THAT, ARE YOU?
[SCREAMING]
* 10 GREEN BOTTLES
HANGING ON THE WALL *
* IF ONE GREEN BOTTLE
SHOULD ACCIDENTALLY FALL *
* THERE'D BE 9 GREEN BOTTLES
HANGING ON THE WALL *
* 9 GREEN BOTTLES
* IF ONE GREEN BOTTLE
SHOULD ACCIDENTALLY FALL *
* THERE'D BE...*
Bobby Sam: 8!
* 8 GREEN BOTTLES
HANGING ON THE WALL *
8 GREEN BOTTLES!
SOME OTHER TIME,
BOBBY SAM.
COME ON,
PINHEAD.
OH, AND WE'RE VERY GRATEFUL
TO DR. HARRIS, AREN'T WE?
PLEASE DON'T
MENTION IT, MISS...
SAMUELS,
FAITH SAMUELS.
I GUESS I WAS STILL
IN SHORT DRESSES
WHEN YOU WENT
AWAY TO STUDY.
I'M THE
SCHOOLTEACHER NOW.
I LIVE NEXT DOOR.
MISS SAMUELS,
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
I NEVER SAW A FISHHOOK
BEFORE?
WHY, I DIDN'T SAY--
DO I IMPRESS YOU AS
THE SORT OF MAN WHO--
WELL, WHO ISN'T THE SORT
OF MAN WHO GOES FISHING?
WELL, YOU--
DO I, OR DO I NOT,
MISS SAMUELS?
YES, YOU DO.
I SEE.
THANK YOU.
[SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
Boy: I HAVE TO GO IN.
All: AW!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[GIRL SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
[OTHERS JOIN IN]
WHY, DR. HARRIS.
MISS SAMUELS,
I CAME TO INQUIRE
IF YOU WOULD CARE
TO GO DRIVING WITH ME
SOME MORNING FAIRLY SOON.
I THOUGHT MAYBE
WE MIGHT TAKE A LUNCH
AND GO AS FAR
AS TOM'S CREEK.
WE MIGHT EVEN DO
SOME FISHING.
WHY, I--
[CLOCK STRIKING]
I WOULD BE
DELIGHTED.
GOOD. WE'LL START
TOMORROW AT 8:00.
Narrator: FOLKS WONDERED
WHAT A SWEET GIRL LIKE FAITH
COULD SEE
IN YOUNG DOC HARRIS.
I GUESS THE ONLY PERSON
WHO KNEW THE ANSWER TO THAT
WAS FAITH HERSELF.
AS FOR YOUNG DOC,
WHEN HE DROVE HER HOME
THAT AFTERNOON,
HE DROVE SLOWLY,
AS THOUGH HE DIDN'T
WANT THE DAY TO END.
Man: ALL ABOARD!
Faith: * 10 GREEN BOTTLES
HANGING ON THE WALL *
* 10 GREEN BOTTLES
* IF ONE GREEN BOTTLE
SHOULD ACCIDENTALLY FALL *
* THERE'D BE--
Faith: * 9 *
Narrator: BUT THE HAPPY DAY
WAS FORGOTTEN
WHEN HE SAW THE SILENT CROWD
IN FRONT OF HIS FATHER'S HOUSE.
[TRAIN WHISTLING]
[CHURCH BELL TOLLING]
[DOGS BARKING]
DON'T THEY SOUND PLAIN
ALL OF A SUDDEN?
WIND'S FRESHENING.
I KNOW IT.
PA HAD
A HOUND ONCE,
CHASED A FOX
FOR 10 DAYS.
ONLY GIVE UP
WHEN HE DIED
OF STARVATION.
PA SAYS I'M NAMED
AFTER HIM--CHASE.
AW, THAT'S
JUST A JOKE.
I KNOW IT.
SOUNDS LIKE
THIS OLD FOX
IS WORKING
HIS WAY AROUND
THAT HOLLOW
IN BACK OF
UNCLE FAMOUS' PLACE.
MOST LIKELY GOT
HIS HOLE UP THERE.
MOST LIKELY
FIXING TO HOLE UP.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO TELL ME
EVERYTHING
THAT'S HAPPENING.
I WASN'T TELLING YOU.
I WAS JUST SAYING.
ALL RIGHT.
ON THE WAY HOME,
YOU WANT TO STOP BY
AND SEE UNCLE FAMOUS?
WHAT FOR?
AUNT HARRIET
MADE A BIG PAN
OF GINGERBREAD
YESTERDAY.
I BROUGHT HIM SOME.
MAYBE IT'S
ALL GONE.
IT WAS A BIG PAN.
[DOGS BARKING]
SOUNDS LIKE THAT FOX
CHANGED HIS MIND
ABOUT HOLING UP.
SOUNDS LIKE HE'S
DOUBLING BACK ACROSS
UNCLE FAMOUS' PLACE.
I KNOW WHAT
IT SOUNDS LIKE.
I WAS JUST TALKING.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO LISTEN.
[DOGS BARKING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[WHISTLES]
[DOGS BARKING]
[GUNSHOTS]
Backett:
WHOA, WHOA. FAMOUS!
COME ON OVER HERE.
FAMOUS, WHAT IN TOBIT'S
BEEN HAPPENING HERE?!
SOME KIND OF ACCIDENT?
NO, SIR, I RECKON IT
WASN'T NO ACCIDENT.
TOLD YOU HOW IT'D
BE WHEN I HAD TO
CLOSE DOWN THE MINE.
NO, SIR, T'AIN'T
IN NATURE FOR MEN
TO SIT QUIET
WHILST THE BREAD'S
TOOK OUT OF
THEIR MOUTHS.
FAMOUS, I TELL YOU
WHAT I'LL DO.
I'LL MAKE YOU
ONE MORE OFFER FOR
THIS LAND OF YOURS.
50 CENTS AN ACRE,
CASH ON THE BARRELHEAD.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
MR. BACKETT,
THAT'S UNCOMMON KIND.
AW, NO,
IT AIN'T NOTHING.
BUT I TOLD YOU BEFORE,
I COULDN'T SEE NO REASON
WHY I SHOULD SELL MY LAND,
AND THERE AIN'T NOTHING
HAPPENED TO CHANGE MY MIND.
NOTHING'S HAPPENED?!
NO, SIR.
WHY, YOUR STOCK'S GONE,
AIN'T IT?
YOUR STORES IS GONE.
YOUR FEED
AND GREEN CROP,
YOUR CORN CROP.
WHERE YOU FIXING
TO GET MONEY TO BUY
SEED TO PLANT AGAIN?
HOW YOU AIM TO
RESTOCK AND REBUILD?
HOW YOU GONNA LIVE?
WHERE'S THE MONEY
COMING FROM?
WHY, YOU OLD FOOL,
YOU'LL STARVE TO DEATH!
TOM...
GO ON HOME AND FETCH SOME
SEED CORN OUT OF THE CRIB.
CABE, TELL YOUR MA
WE'LL BE WANTING SOME CHICKENS
AND ALL THE BACON AND MEAL
SHE AIN'T GOT ANY USE FOR.
JEB, WE'LL BE NEEDING
THE MULES AND THE PLOW.
ROLFE, YOU AND ME BETTER START
CLEANING UP THIS FIELD.
[LAUGHING]
MR. ISBELL?
JUST DON'T MENTION IT,
DON'T MENTION IT.
NO, SIR.
YOU'S A REAL CHRISTIAN, SIR.
WHEN YOU COMING
TO CHURCH, JED?
HUP! GET ALONG THERE!
HEY, IF YOU WAS GOD,
WHAT'D BE THE FIRST
THING YOU'D DO?
HEAP OF THINGS.
NO, I MEAN
THE FIRST.
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT'D YOU DO?
WELL, FIRST OFF,
I'D MAKE IT SO
IT WAS SUMMER
ALL THE TIME.
NO CHRISTMAS?
OH, I'D HAVE IT
IN THE SUMMERTIME.
I'D HAVE EVERYTHING
IN THE SUMMERTIME--
'CAUSE THAT'S
ALL THERE'D BE,
JUST SUMMER
ALL THE TIME.
GEE, WHAT ABOUT
SCHOOL, THOUGH?
OH, THERE WOULDN'T
BE ANY SCHOOL.
WHOEVER HEARD
OF HAVING SCHOOL
IN THE SUMMER?
WHOEVER HEARD OF
HAVING CHRISTMAS
IN THE SUMMER?
WELL, GOD COULD DO
IT IF HE WANTED TO.
GEE.
ANOTHER THING.
IF YOU WAS GOD,
AND IT WAS SUMMER
ALL THE TIME,
AND THERE WASN'T
ANY SCHOOL,
WHAT WOULD THE
SCHOOLTEACHERS DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
I HAVEN'T COME
TO THAT YET.
BUT I KNOW ONE THING.
THERE'D BE WARS ALL THE TIME--
FIGHTING EVERY DAY,
BUT NOBODY'D GET KILLED.
WHO'D WIN?
WELL, MY SIDE,
OF COURSE,
AND I'D BE
THE GENERAL.
AND I'D RIDE AROUND
ON A WHITE HORSE
JUST LIKE
ROBERT E. LEE,
AND I'D NEVER
WEAR ANY SHOES.
THAT AIN'T FAIR.
YOU'D HAVE
ALL THE FUN.
WHAT'S THE GOOD
OF BEING GOD
IF YOU CAN'T HAVE
ALL THE FUN?
PINHEAD.
HA HA!
HEY, HERE
COMES SOMEBODY.
HURRY, CLOSE
THE WELL UP.
IT'S THE ENEMY.
HURRY UP!
WHOA, WHOA.
I'LL ONLY BE
A MINUTE.
FAITH, CAN'T I
HAVE AN ANSWER--
A REAL ANSWER
THIS TIME?
LOOK, I'VE DONE
EVERYTHING YOU SAID.
I'VE WAITED.
I'VE TRIED
TO BE PATIENT.
DAN, PLEASE.
I KNOW WHAT
I'M ASKING.
I'M ASKING YOU
TO LEAVE THIS TOWN,
YOUR HOME WHERE YOU'VE
LIVED ALL YOUR LIFE
AND WHERE YOU'RE
LOVED AND SECURE.
I'M ASKING YOU
TO GIVE ALL OF THAT UP
JUST TO BE
WITH ME.
ALL I WANT IS
TO BE WITH YOU.
YOU KNOW THAT.
* OH, THEM GOLDEN SLIPPERS, OH *
* THEM GOLDEN SLIPPERS *
* GOLDEN SLIPPERS,
I'M GONNA WEAR *
* 'CAUSE THEY LOOK SO-- *
Harriet: JOHN!
YES'M?
HAVE YOU GOT
YOUR NEW SHOES ON?
WELL, LET ME SEE
YOU WALK IN THEM.
HURRY UP, NOW,
I WANT THOSE SHOES
BROKEN IN BEFORE
SCHOOL TAKES UP.
WHY DO I HAVE
TO WEAR THOSE SHOES
TO SCHOOL ANYWAY?
THEY DON'T MAKE ME
ANY SMARTER.
WELL, WE CAN
ALWAYS HOPE. WALK!
[KIDS CHEERING
AND MUSIC PLAYING]
Man: WHOA!
HERE'S THE PARSONAGE,
PROFESSOR.
GOOD MORNING,
BUCKAROO.
YOUR PA TO HOME?
HE AIN'T MY PA.
WELL, WHOEVER HE IS,
TELL HIM I WANT
A CHIN WITH HIM.
YES, SIR,
I'LL FETCH HIM.
HOLD ON, THERE.
WHAT'S THAT STICKING
OUT OF YOUR EAR THERE?
PARSON? PARSON?
PARSON! PARSON!
A MAN JUST PULLED A
WATCH OUT OF MY EAR.
[HARMONICA PLAYING
CAMPTOWN RACES]
PARSON GRAY?
YES, SIR.
YOUR SERVANT,
MA'AM.
PARSON, I'M
SAM HOUSTON JONES
FROM THE PANHANDLE
OF TEXAS--
A BUSINESSMAN, SIR,
AS YOU CAN SEE.
MY LINE IS
TO MAKE FOLKS HAPPY
INSIDE AND OUT.
NOW, IN PURSUIT
OF MY POLICY,
I AIM TO PUT ON
A LITTLE ENTERTAINMENT
TONIGHT IN TOWN,
AND I'D SURE BE OBLIGED
IF YOU'D COME ALONG AND
SHARE IN THE FESTIVITIES.
I'M PREPARED TO GIVE
YOUR CHURCH 10% OF
THE PROCEEDS IF YOU DO.
ISN'T THAT
A LITTLE UNUSUAL?
NOTHING UNUSUAL
ABOUT IT--
JUST STIMULATES
CONFIDENCE.
SEE, IF I CAN TELL
THE FOLKS IN THESE PARTS
THAT THEIR PARSON'S
PLANNING ON COMING,
THEY'LL KNOW IT'S
ALL RIGHT FOR THEM
TO COME, TOO.
WHAT DOES YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT
CONSIST OF?
WELL, SIR,
THERE'S A BAND,
THERE'S
FRANK ZEKE THERE.
PLAY ANY KIND
OF MUSICAL INSTRUMENT
YOU CAN MENTION.
FRANK SINGS, TOO,
HE'S GOT A VOICE
LIKE A CROSS-EYED
MEADOWLARK.
I'M THE FEATURED
ATTRACTION.
I DO MAGIC TRICKS
AND GIVE
EDUCATIONAL TALKS,
ILLUSTRATED.
WITH A FREE SAMPLE.
WHAT DO YOU SAY,
PARSON?
WELL, I'M,
UH, SORRY, MISTER--
UH, PROFESSOR JONES.
I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T ACCEPT
YOUR KIND OFFER.
Children:
AW!
HOWEVER...
IF YOU SHOULD DECIDE
TO COME TO SERVICES
AT MY CHURCH NEXT SUNDAY
AND PUT SOMETHING
IN THE COLLECTION,
THAT'S YOUR BUSINESS.
AND, OF COURSE,
IF I DECIDED TO
BRING MY FAMILY
TO YOUR SHOW TONIGHT,
THAT'S MY BUSINESS.
I WON'T PROMISE TO BUY
ANY MEDICINE, THOUGH.
HA HA HA!
OH, COME HERE,
BUCKAROO.
COME HERE, SON.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
HAVE YOU GOT
IN YOUR OTHER EAR?
WHY, IT'S NOT
IN YOUR EAR AT ALL,
THERE IT IS
RIGHT THERE.
[LAUGHTER]
[TRUMPET PLAYING DIXIE]
UNCLE FAMOUS.
GOOD EVENING,
FAMOUS.
Man: EVENING.
Woman:
EVENING, PARSON.
Man: STEP ASIDE,
FOLKS, AND LET
THE PARSON PASS.
Woman: EVENING,
MRS. GRAY.
GOOD EVENING.
OH, IS THAT
A NEW HAT,
MS. GRAY?
NO, IT ISN'T NEW.
IT'S JUST MY OLD ONE
WITH A DIFFERENT
RIBBON ON IT.
Man: STEP
THIS WAY, FOLKS.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
LET THE PARSON
IN THERE, PLEASE.
HEY, JED.
HEY.
HOW'S THAT GAME LEG
OF YOURS?
Jed: TOL'ABLE,
J.D., JUST TOL'ABLE.
MAYBE YOU OUGHT TO BUY
SOME OF THAT MEDICINE.
THEY SAY IT'S GOOD
FOR OLD FOLKS.
DON'T SEEM TO HELP
YOU MUCH! HA HA HA!
I DON'T THINK
THAT'S VERY FUNNY.
[MUSIC STOPS]
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
YOU FEELING BAD?
[FANFARE PLAYING]
NOW, AIN'T THIS
A SILLY WAY
FOR A FULL-GROWN MAN
TO MAKE A LIVING?
[CHEERING]
ALL RIGHT, NOW LET'S
GET IT NICE AND QUIET
HERE, FOLKS.
QUIET DOWN.
NICE AND QUIET.
MY FRIENDS,
YOU ARE ABOUT TO WITNESS
FOR THE FIRST TIME
ON ANY STAGE,
A FEAT OF BLACK MAGIC,
LEGERDEMAIN,
AND SLEIGHT OF HAND
TAUGHT TO ME BY
AN OLD INDIAN FRIEND.
A FEAT ASTOUNDING, CONFOUNDING,
AND PRETTY NEAR IMPOSSIBLE--
YOU WAIT AND SEE
IF IT AIN'T.
[WHOOPING]
NOW I'M GONNA REQUIRE
THE ASSISTANCE
OF SOME YOUNG GENTLEMAN
FROM THE AUDIENCE.
HOW ABOUT YOU,
BUCKAROO?
YOU'LL LEND A HAND,
WON'T YOU?
COME ON UP HERE.
DON'T BE SHY.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO GO UP THERE
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO.
THAT'S IT.
WELL, IT'S THE PARSON'S BOY.
MY GOODNESS SAKES.
FINE HUSKY BOY
YOU GOT HERE,
PARSON, YES, SIR.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
HAVE YOU GOT IN
UNDER THERE NOW?
JUST A MINUTE,
LET'S SEE.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS THIS?
JUST LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT!
[APPLAUSE]
DOES THIS BELONG
TO YOU?
NOW, DON'T YOU
LET IT WORRY YOU.
YOU JUST STAND--
NOW, HE'S GOT
SOMETHING
IN HERE, TOO.
NOW WHAT
IN THE WORLD
IS THIS?
HOLD ON.
LOOK AT THAT--
SAUSAGES.
3 SAUSAGES,
4 SAUSAGES,
5 SAUSAGES--
A WHOLE CROCK
OF SAUSAGES.
[LAUGHTER]
OH, WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
HE BROUGHT HIS SUPPER
ALONG WITH HIM.
YOU HUNGRY,
BUCKAROO?
OF COURSE YOU ARE.
I NEVER SEEN A BOY
YOUR AGE YET
THAT WASN'T.
AND WE'RE GONNA
DO SOMETHING ABOUT
THAT RIGHT NOW.
BRING ON
THE FIXINGS, BOY.
YES, SIR.
LOOKAHERE,
BUCKAROO,
ARE YOU GAME
TO SAMPLE SOME
OF MY CELEBRATED
SPECIALTY--
PROFESSOR JONES'
POPULAR 'N PENETRATIN'
PICKAPOO PUDDIN'?
WON'T TAKE
BUT A MINUTE
TO THROW IT
TOGETHER HERE.
WE'LL JUST PUT
SOME FLOUR AND SOME
WATER IN THERE,
THEN SOME FINE OLD
AGED PICKLE JUICE.
PUT THAT
RIGHT IN THERE.
PULVERIZED
APPLE CORE,
AND SOME ESSENCE
OF OLD RUBBER
OVERSHOES.
[SNIFF]
ANY OF YOU LADIES
OUT THERE LIKE
A RECIPE OF THIS
UNUSUAL DISH,
YOU'RE
MIGHTY WELCOME
TO COME AROUND
AFTER THE SHOW
AND ASK FOR IT.
JUST BRING ALONG
YOUR PAPER
AND YOUR PENCIL
AND SOME
SMELLING SALTS,
THAT'S ALL.
NOW A PINCH
OF BAKING SODA.
WE'LL PUT THAT
IN THERE.
SOME MELTED
CANDLE WAX,
AND HOW
ABOUT IT, MEN--
WOULDN'T YOU
LIKE TO SEE
SOMETHING DIFFERENT
ON THE TABLE
FOR A CHANGE?
Man: SURE WOULD!
WELL, YOU JUST ASK
FOR DELICIOUS,
PERNICIOUS
PICKAPOO PUDDIN'.
NOW I WILL
FINISH IT OFF
WITH A DASH
OF THIS FAMOUS
PICKAPOO EXTRACT.
WE'LL GARNISH IT
WITH A TAIL FEATHER
OF A TOM TURKEY.
WE'LL LET IT
SIMMER AWHILE,
PUT THE LID DOWN
ON IT TIGHT CLOSED--
HOLD THAT,
BOY, WILL YOU?
NOW WE'LL REPEAT
THE MAGIC FORMULA--
ABBADICKADABBA
DUZZA DUZZA BUZZA
DA BUZZADABALOO
PRESTO CHANGO,
AND THERE'S
YOUR PUDDING.
WELL, DON'T YOU
WANT TO SEE HOW
IT TURNED OUT, SON?
COME ON, LET'S
HAVE A LOOK AT IT.
[LAUGHTER]
THAT'S ALL TODAY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NOW, IF YOU FOLKS
WILL GATHER IN HERE
A LITTLE BIT CLOSER,
WHEN YOU HEAR
THE NAME OF MY PRODUCT,
OLD JONES'
LODESTONE TONIC,
WELL, FRIENDS,
THERE ARE JUST 3 WORDS
I WANT YOU TO REMEMBER.
WHAT ARE THESE 3 WORDS,
MY FRIENDS?
"THERE IS HOPE,"
THAT'S WHAT THEY ARE.
NOW, FRIENDS, I DON'T CARE
WHAT'S YOUR AILMENT--
BE IT THE LIGHTS
OR THE LIVER,
BE IT THE NERVES
OF THE ORGAN,
BE IT RECURRING,
MALIGNANT, EPIDEMIC...
Gray: FETCH
YOUNG DOC HARRIS.
HE DIDN'T EAT
MUCH SUPPER
TO SPEAK OF.
WE THOUGHT IT WAS
JUST THE EXCITEMENT
OF THE SHOW.
I'M AFRAID
IT'S TYPHOID.
SLOW FEVER?
WHAT CAN WE DO?
NOT MUCH.
KEEP HIM
AS COMFORTABLE
AS POSSIBLE.
GIVE HIM
A SPOONFUL OF THIS
IF HE GETS RESTLESS.
AND ICE WHEN
THE FEVER'S BAD.
NOW, LISTEN.
HE'S YOUNG,
AND HE'S STRONG.
HE'S GOT EVERYTHING
ON HIS SIDE.
WITH A LITTLE LUCK,
THERE'S NO REASON
WHY HE SHOULDN'T
COME THROUGH THIS
ALL RIGHT.
John: LET'S GO DOWN
TO THE CREEK.
LET'S GO SWIMMING.
LET'S HAVE
A DRINK.
I'M THIRSTY--
AWFUL THIRSTY.
THE SUN'S SO HOT.
LET'S PUT OUR HEADS
IN THE WATER.
YOU HAVEN'T
SLEPT FOR DAYS.
I'M GONNA
PUT YOU TO BED.
I'M NOT TIRED.
JUST LIE DOWN
A LITTLE WHILE,
HONEY.
I'LL BE
RIGHT HERE
ALL THE TIME.
I'LL CALL YOU
IF ANYTHING--
REMEMBER WHAT
THE DOCTOR SAID?
IT'S UP
TO JOHN NOW.
THAT'S THE WAY.
DAYS SURE SEEM LIKE YEARS
AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
[SOBBING]
ALL I CAN THINK OF
NOW IS THE TIMES
I WASN'T SWEET
TO HIM;
THE TIMES I SPOKE
SHARPLY TO HIM.
I DON'T KNOW
IF HE ALWAYS
UNDERSTOOD.
A LITTLE BOY
DOESN'T ALWAYS
UNDERSTAND THAT
YOU LOVE HIM
AND STILL SPEAK
SHARPLY TO HIM.
IT'S SO HARD
TO KNOW.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
JUST THE SAME
AS MY OWN TO ME--
JUST EXACTLY
THE SAME.
MAYBE IT HASN'T BEEN
THE SAME FOR HIM.
I SUPPOSE
IT'S FOOLISH OF ME
TO THINK IT COULD
EVER BE THE SAME.
DON'T TALK, HONEY.
I JUST WISH
I'D BEEN SWEETER
TO HIM, THAT'S ALL.
HE'S SUCH
A GOOD BOY.
HE'S NEVER
DONE ANYTHING
REALLY BAD.
I JUST WISH
I COULD TELL HIM
WHAT A GOOD BOY
HE'S BEEN,
WHAT A BLESSING.
HARRIET!
AUNT HARRIET?
YES, DEAR?
I'M HUNGRY.
[RINGING]
Gray:
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS,
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN *
[HUMMING]
YOU'RE GOING TO BE
LATE, MR. GRAY.
COME ON,
UP, UP, UP.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU GOING TO CHURCH
LIKE THAT?
I'M PLAYING HOOKY
TODAY, LIKE YOU.
MR. GRAY...
PLENTY OF TIME,
HARRIET,
PLENTY OF TIME.
OH, YOU ALWAYS
SAY THAT. HERE.
I DECLARE, MR. GRAY,
I COULD GET
YOUR WHOLE...
CONGREGATION READY
FOR CHURCH...
BEFORE I COULD YOU.
WELL, HARRIET,
YOU HAVE TO ADMIT
THE RESULT'S
WORTH THE BOTHER.
HMM.
YOU DON'T SOUND
LIKE YOU MEAN IT.
MAYBE YOU'RE STILL
LOOKING FOR THAT
STRAIGHT STICK.
THAT'S SUCH
AN OLD JOKE.
GONNA MISS YOUR
SWEET VOICE TODAY.
SOMETIMES YOU
SOUND JUST LIKE
A RIBBON DRUMMER.
NOW, GO.
JOHN, YOU MIND
YOU KEEP
YOUR WINDOW OPEN,
YOU CAN HEAR
THE SINGING.
ARE YOU GONNA SING
STARS IN MY CROWN?
I THINK THAT MIGHT
BE ARRANGED.
OH, DON'T YOU CUT YOUR EYES
AT ME, YOU TWO.
I KNOW JUST WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING,
AND IT WON'T DO YOU
A PARTICLE OF GOOD.
GUSSIE LOU LYLES IS
GOING TO OBLIGE YOU
AT THE ORGAN, MR. GRAY,
AND THE HYMNS ARE
ALL PICKED OUT.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT THEY ARE?
YOU SEE, JOHN?
YOU CAN'T GET
AHEAD OF YOUR
AUNT HARRIET.
STRAIGHT STICK,
INDEED.
STRAIGHT STICK
WHAT?
OH, IT'S JUST
AN OLD STORY.
I NEVER HEARD IT.
IT'S ABOUT
THE YOUNG MAN
WHO USED TO COME
CALL ON ME.
TELL ME THE STORY,
AUNT HARRIET.
WELL, YOU SEE,
BEFORE I MET
THE PARSON,
I WAS NEVER
SATISFIED
WITH ANY
OF THE SUITORS
WHO CAME CALLING.
I USED TO LAUGH
AT THEM
AND MAKE JOKES ABOUT
THE WAY THEY ACTED.
FINALLY, MY MOTHER
SAID TO ME,
"HARRIET,
I ONCE KNEW A MAN
"WHO WENT WALKING
IN THE WOODS
"LOOKING FOR A GOOD,
STRAIGHT STICK
"TO MAKE INTO
A WALKING CANE.
"HE HADN'T GONE FAR
BEFORE HE FOUND
"WHAT HE THOUGHT WAS
THE PROPER OAK LIMB.
"BUT AS HE WENT
TO CUT IT,
"HE NOTICED
IT WASN'T QUITE
"STRAIGHT ENOUGH
TO SUIT HIM.
"I'LL JUST LOOK
A LITTLE LONGER,
SAID THE MAN.
"AND IT WAS THE SAME
WITH EVERY TREE
IN THAT WOOD.
"THE FIRST THING
HE KNEW,
IT WAS DARK,
"AND HE'D SPENT
THE WHOLE DAY
IN THAT WOOD,
AND HE DIDN'T HAVE
ANYTHING TO SHOW
FOR HIS TROUBLE."
MAMA SAID,
"HARRIET, THAT'S
THE WAY YOU ARE
ABOUT MEN."
"WHY," SHE SAID,
"EVERY MAN BORN
"HAS SOMETHING
THE MATTER WITH HIM.
"AND IF YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR
THE PERFECT MAN,
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND HIM."
BUT THE MINUTE
I SAW THE PARSON,
I KNEW MAMA
WAS WRONG.
AUNT HARRIET?
YES, DEAR?
YOU KNOW,
I'M GLAD
I LIVE WITH YOU
AND THE PARSON
INSTEAD OF
WITH A MA AND PA
LIKE OTHER BOYS.
DID YOU HEAR
WHAT I SAID?
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS,
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN I WAKE WITH THE BLESSED
IN THE MANSIONS OF REST *
* WILL THERE BE
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN? *
Narrator:
I WAS STILL IN BED
WHEN SCHOOL OPENED,
BUT THE PARSON
WENT DOWN AS USUAL
TO START THE TERM OFF
IN STYLE.
NOW, THERE'S ONE THING MORE
I'D LIKE TO ASK YOU.
HOW MANY OF YOU SAY
YOUR PRAYERS REGULAR?
FINE, FINE.
THAT'S FIRST-RATE.
JUST SO YOU DON'T GET
TO LEANING SO HARD ON GOD'S HELP
THAT YOU FORGET
HOW TO HELP YOURSELVES.
PUTS ME IN MIND
OF A TIME--
I THINK IT WAS IN THE BATTLE
OF CHATTANOOGA IN '63--
MY HORSE FELL
WITH ME, SEE,
AND I HAD TO MAKE
A DIVE FOR COVER.
WELL, I LIT
RIGHT ALONGSIDE
THIS OLD
TOBACCO-CHEWING
LANCE CORPORAL.
HE LOOKED AT ME
LAYING THERE
ON THE GROUND,
AND HE LOOKED AT
THE BIBLE STICKING
OUT OF MY POCKET.
HE SAYS TO ME,
"SON,
"JUST 'CAUSE
YOU'RE A PRAYIN' MAN
DON'T MEAN YOU
DON'T HAVE TO KEEP
YOUR HIND END DOWN."
[GIGGLING]
WELL, I KNOW
IT'S BEEN
A LONG SUMMER,
AND YOU'RE ALL
ANXIOUS TO GET
BACK TO YOUR BOOKS.
[GROANS]
Faith: I THINK
THOSE BOOKS WILL KEEP
FOR ONE MORE DAY,
DON'T YOU, CHILDREN?
CLASS DISMISSED.
[CHEERING]
MR. GRAY,
I'D LIKE A WORD
WITH YOU.
MAY I ASK WHAT
YOU'RE DOING HERE?
MAY I ASK
WHY YOU'RE ASKING?
USE YOUR HEAD,
MAN.
THERE'S TYPHOID FEVER
IN YOUR HOUSE.
IF YOU DON'T WANT
TO SPREAD IT
ALL OVER TOWN,
YOU'D BETTER GO HOME
AND STAY THERE.
NOW,
WAIT A MINUTE.
LAST I HEARD,
SLOW FEVER CAME
FROM BAD DRINKING
WATER, NOT FROM
BAD PREACHING--
OR EVEN
FROM GOOD PREACHING.
KINDLY ALLOW ME
TO KNOW MY BUSINESS.
DID YOU VISIT JOHN
THIS MORNING?
YES.
YOU STOOD AROUND
TALKING TO HIM?
SAT ON HIS BED--
TOUCHED HIM?
YES, I SUPPOSE
I DID.
WELL, THAT MAKES YOU
A POTENTIAL CARRIER.
DON'T YOU
REALIZE THAT?
DON'T YOU REALIZE
THAT BY COMING
DOWN HERE TODAY,
YOU MIGHT HAVE
EXPOSED THESE
CHILDREN
AND MISS SAMUELS
TO INFECTION?
YOU CAN STOP
RIGHT THERE.
SURE, I'VE BEEN
GOING IN AND OUT
OF JOHN'S ROOM.
SO HAVE YOU.
I'VE BEEN GOING
ABOUT MY BUSINESS,
PAYING CALLS
AND MAKING SPEECHES.
SO HAVE YOU.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING
IN WHAT YOU SAY,
I RECKON THEY OUGHT TO
LOCK US BOTH UP.
HOW LONG DO YOU
SUPPOSE THIS TOWN
COULD MANAGE
WITHOUT ME
OR SOMEBODY LIKE ME
WHO'D DO MY WORK?
WHO'D DO MINE?
Narrator:
SCHOOL HAD HARDLY OPENED
WHEN IT HAD TO CLOSE AGAIN.
FAITH SAMUELS
WAS DOWN WITH SLOW FEVER.
AND IN NO TIME,
LIGHTS WERE BURNING
TILL DAYLIGHT
ALL OVER TOWN
AS THE SICKNESS SPREAD
AND KEPT ON SPREADING.
YOU'RE LATE,
MR. GRAY.
I STOPPED BY
THE ISBELL PLACE.
CHASE HAS GOT
SLOW FEVER.
CHASE TOO?
DON'T SAY
ANYTHING TO JOHN.
I NEVER SAW JED
IN SUCH A STATE.
HE'S SCARED.
WANTING TO YELL
FOR HELP,
NOT KNOWING
WHO TO YELL TO.
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I'M SCARED MYSELF.
COME AND EAT.
7, NO, 8 CASES
THIS WEEK.
FAITH SAMUELS,
KIM ALDRIDGE,
EFFIE MEYERS--
BOTH
THE WARE GIRLS.
LITTLE CAROL BOWIE,
BOBBY SAM.
AND NOW CHASE.
AND TOMORROW,
SOMEONE ELSE--
UNLESS WE FIND
THE SOURCE.
WE'VE GOT
TO FIND IT.
WHEN MR. BACKETT CAME BY
WITH MY PROVISIONS,
HE SAID HE THOUGHT
IT MIGHTY STRANGE
THAT YOU HADN'T
THOUGHT TO EXAMINE
THE SCHOOL WELL.
IF LON BACKETT HAD
HALF THE BRAINS
HE WAS BORN WITH,
HE'D KNOW
IT COULDN'T BE
THE SCHOOL WELL.
JOHN CAME DOWN WITH
THE FEVER FIRST.
THAT WAS
BEFORE SCHOOL
EVEN STARTED.
THAT'S SO.
THIS CHICKEN PIE
IS GOOD.
CHICKEN PIE?
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
WHY, MR. CARROLL.
WHAT IS IT, THAD?
THE MISSIS
SENT ME, PARSON.
IT'S OUR BOBBY SAM.
HE'S--PARSON,
WILL YOU COME?
OF COURSE I WILL.
OH, GO IN
IF YOU WANT TO.
I'VE GIVEN UP
TRYING TO TELL YOU
WHAT TO DO.
BUT THERE'S A CHILD
DEAD IN THAT HOUSE
WHO MIGHT BE ALIVE
AND WELL IF IT
WEREN'T FOR YOU.
YOU'VE SAID ENOUGH!
HE'S DEAD.
OH.
I'LL GO
STRAIGHT OVER.
NO, WAIT.
I TOLD YOU,
DIDN'T I,
ABOUT HAVING WORDS
WITH DAN HARRIS
DOWN AT
THE SCHOOLHOUSE?
HAPPENED AGAIN
TONIGHT.
HE HAS A NOTION
ALL THIS IS
MY FAULT.
HE'S PRETTY
NEAR GOT ME
BELIEVING HIM.
HOW DOES HE MEAN,
YOUR FAULT?
HE MEANS I PICKED UP
THE FEVER FROM JOHN
AND PASSED IT ON
TO THE OTHER KIDS
SOMEHOW.
EVEN GAVE IT
TO FAITH
AND NO TELLING
HOW MANY OTHERS.
IT ISN'T TRUE.
WHO ARE WE TO SAY
IT ISN'T TRUE?
HE'S A DOCTOR,
HE'S A GOOD DOCTOR.
HE KNOWS
HIS BUSINESS.
I GUESS I SHOULD
HAVE LISTENED
TO HIM THAT DAY,
BUT HE RILED ME,
KIND OF.
NOW I KEEP THINKING
MAYBE HE WAS RIGHT.
MAYBE HE'S
BEEN RIGHT
ALL THE TIME,
ONLY NOW
IT'S TOO LATE--
TOO LATE
FOR BOBBY SAM,
ANYWAY.
HARRIET,
WHAT AM I GOING
TO DO?
YOU'RE GOING
TO KEEP ON,
OF COURSE,
THE SAME AS ALWAYS.
WHY, NOW, WITH ALL
THIS TROUBLE,
NOW'S THE TIME
WHEN PEOPLE
NEED YOU MOST.
THEY--
YOU KNOW WHAT
DAN HARRIS TOLD ME,
RIGHT OFF?
"GO HOME
AND STAY THERE."
I WASN'T MAN
ENOUGH TO DO IT.
I CAN'T SAY WHETHER
I'M MAN ENOUGH
TO DO IT NOW, BUT--
I AIM TO FIND OUT.
TOMORROW, THOUGH.
THE SERVICES?
THERE AREN'T GONNA
BE ANY SERVICES.
Man: "SERVICES WILL NOT
BE HELD AT THIS CHURCH
"UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
"WE ASK YOUR PRAYERS
FOR THE SICK.
J.D. GRAY,
PASTOR."
Narrator:
WHEN THE PARSON CLOSED
THE DOOR TO THE CHURCH,
HE ALSO CLOSED
THE DOOR ON HIMSELF.
IT WAS ALL
HE COULD DO NOW
FOR THE FOLKS
WHO TRUSTED HIM.
THE REST WAS UP TO
YOUNG DOC HARRIS.
SO, IN A WAY, YOU SEE,
THIS UNHAPPY TIME WAS
YOUNG DOC'S REAL HOMECOMING.
NOW, FOR THE FIRST TIME,
HE KNEW HOW GOOD IT WAS
TO BE NEEDED;
GOOD TO BE WATCHED FOR
AND WELCOMED LIKE
A TRUSTED FRIEND.
IT WAS EVEN GOOD TO GO
RED-EYED AND DOG-TIRED,
SNATCHING SLEEP
WHEREVER HE COULD
ON THE ROAD
FROM HOUSE TO HOUSE
IN ORDER THAT OTHERS
MIGHT SLEEP EASIER
BECAUSE OF HIM.
HE JUST COULDN'T GO ON
FEELING A STRANGER
AMONG FOLKS WHOSE LIVES
HAD SUDDENLY BECOME
A PART OF HIS LIFE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE'LL RECOVER.
OH, THANK GOD.
Narrator: THE LUCKY ONES,
LIKE THE ISBELLS,
WHOSE FACES SPOKE
THEIR THANKS TO HIM
BETTER THAN ANY WORDS,
AND THE OTHERS,
LIKE KATE AND HARRY WARE,
WHOSE SORROW WAS
HIS SORROW.
[SOBBING]
I DID ALL I COULD.
I KNOW, DOC.
I RECKON WHAT
WE NEED NOW
IS ANOTHER KIND
OF HELP.
Narrator:
THEN IT BEGAN TO SEEM
TO YOUNG DOC THAT PERHAPS
HE, TOO, STOOD IN NEED
OF ANOTHER KIND OF HELP.
BUT BEYOND THAT LIGHTED WINDOW,
IF HE'D ONLY KNOWN IT,
WAS A MAN
IN DEEPER NEED THAN HIS.
ALL THAT WE HAD
IN THOSE DAYS CAME
FROM THE PEOPLE
OF WALESBURG.
THE HOUSE
THAT SHELTERED US,
THE FOOD WE ATE,
THE CLOTHES WE WORE.
BUT WHAT WE LEARNED
TO VALUE MOST WAS
NONE OF THESE THINGS.
IT WAS THE LIVING FAITH
IN THE HEARTS
OF THOSE WHO GAVE THEM.
WE'D NEVER BEEN RICH--
EXCEPT IN THAT.
AND NOW
WE WERE POOR INDEED.
FOR DAYS,
NO ONE HAD COME KNOCKING
AT THE PARSONAGE DOOR.
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE I COULD REMEMBER,
THERE WASN'T
ENOUGH TO EAT.
IF YOU'RE GOING
OUT, PUT ON YOUR
OTHER COAT.
DID I MENTION
I WAS GOING OUT?
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
BE GOING UP
TO THE BURYING
GROUND AGAIN.
THEY BURIED
THE WARE CHILD
TODAY.
I--I SAW
THE RIGS GO BY.
I THOUGHT I WOULD
GO UP THERE.
MR. GRAY,
IT'S BEEN NEARLY
TWO WEEKS NOW.
WON'T YOU WRITE
THE BISHOP
TO SEND SOMEBODY?
SOMEBODY TO DO
MY JOB FOR ME?
IT'S STILL MY JOB.
IF THE FOLKS
AROUND HERE
WANT A CHANGE,
THEY'LL ASK FOR IT.
IT'S FOR THEM
TO SAY, NOT ME.
I RECKON
YOU'RE THINKING
THEY'LL DO JUST
THAT BEFORE LONG;
MAYBE EVEN HOPING
THEY WILL.
NO.
JOHN BELIEVES
IN YOU, THE SAME
AS I DO.
THAT OUGHT TO BE
ENOUGH FOR ANY MAN.
ANY MAN EXCEPT YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO MAKE ANY PRETTY
SPEECHES TO ME.
IF JOHN AND I WERE
ENOUGH FOR YOU,
YOU WOULDN'T
BE THE MAN
THAT YOU ARE--
I KNOW THAT.
AND I KNOW
THAT WHAT
YOU WANT NOW
IS SO MUCH MORE
THAN WE CAN
GIVE YOU.
MORE THAN FOOD
OR SHELTER
OR PRAISE OR LOVE,
WHAT YOU WANT
IS YOUR TOWN
BACK AGAIN.
[HUMMING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
* IT WAS GOOD ENOUGH *
* FOR MY FATHER *
* IT WAS GOOD
ENOUGH FOR ME *
WELL, BOY,
COME IN THIS HOUSE.
I AIN'T LAID EYES
ON YOU IN SO LONG,
I WAS NEAR
'BOUT 'FRAID
YOU'D FORGOT ME.
I'VE COME FOR BELLE.
IS SHE HERE?
MY BELLE?
WELL,
YOU AIN'T FIXIN'
TO GO HUNTIN'
THIS TIME
OF NIGHT, IS YOU?
YES, I AM.
WE NEED--
WELL, AUNT HARRIET,
SHE WANTS ME TO.
HMM. WELL,
YOU BETTER
STEP INSIDE.
I'M STANDING
IN A BREEZE.
I'VE JUST COME
FOR BELLE.
WELL, BELLE,
SHE AIN'T ACCEPTING
INVITATIONS JUST NOW.
LOOK AT WHAT'S HAPPENED
SINCE YOU WAS HERE LAST.
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE,
BOY?
WHO TOLD YOU
ABOUT ANY TROUBLE?
YOUR FACE IS
DOING THE TALKING.
WELL, I CAN'T HELP IT.
IT'S AWFUL AT HOME.
IT'S JUST LIKE
BEING IN JAIL--
ONLY IT'S WORSE
THAN BEING IN JAIL,
'CAUSE WE AIN'T
DONE NOTHING.
COURSE YOU AIN'T.
WELL, WHY DOES
THERE HAVE TO BE
SUCH A THING
AS SLOW FEVER?
WHAT'S IT GOOD FOR,
EXCEPT TO HURT PEOPLE?
WE CAN'T KNOW
EVERYTHING, HONEY.
MIGHT BE GOOD
IN IT YET--
WE'RE JUST OBLIGED
TO WAIT AND SEE.
BUT I'VE WAITED,
AND I STILL
DON'T SEE.
WELL, THE SLOW FEVER
AIN'T NO NEW STORY.
I RECKON IT'S KIND OF
LIKE THE SOW THISTLE
IN THE FIELD--
JUST BOUND TO CROP UP
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
I'VE KNOWN WATER
JUST AS SWEET
AND CLEAN-LOOKING
AS YOU'D WANT TO SEE
GIVE FOLKS THE SLOW FEVER.
SEEM LIKE THAT FEVER
WILL GET INTO A CREEK
OR A WELL
IN SPITE
OF EVERYTHING.
COULDN'T BE
THE CREEK.
I NEVER DRANK ANY
OF THAT CREEK WATER.
I AIN'T SAID
IT WAS THE CREEK.
FACTS IS, WHEN
I FIRST HEERED
ABOUT ALL THEM
CHILDREN TAKING SICK,
I SAID TO MYSELF
RIGHT OFF,
"THAT SCHOOL WELL
IS DONE DISEASED."
BUT I RECKON--
WHAT?
I SAID--
NO, I MEAN ABOUT
THE SCHOOL WELL.
I MEAN,
MAYBE THAT WAS
THE CAUSE OF IT.
OH, I RECKON NOT.
I RECKON
THEY EXAMINED
THAT WELL--
WHAT'S AILIN' YOU?
BOY, WHERE ARE
YOU RUNNIN' TO?
JOHN KENYON!
JOHN?
I KNOW WHAT
GAVE EVERYBODY
THE SLOW FEVER.
TAKE IT EASY,
SON.
IT WAS
THE SCHOOL WELL.
UNCLE FAMOUS GOT
SOME PUPPIES.
CAN I HAVE ONE?
IT COULDN'T BE
THE SCHOOL WELL,
DEAR.
THE PARSON THOUGHT
OF THAT FIRST THING.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER
YOU WERE TAKEN SICK
A WEEK BEFORE SCHOOL
STARTED?
BUT I DRANK
OUT OF THE WELL.
SAY THAT AGAIN.
HONEST, I DID.
I WAS UP
THERE ONE DAY
WITH CHASE ISBELL,
AND, WELL, WE DIDN'T
KNOW THE WELL HAD
SLOW FEVER IN IT.
HARRIET,
WHERE'S MY HAT?
NOW, WHO'S GONNA
NOTIFY GENE CALDWELL
TO BOARD UP THAT WELL?
I'LL NOTIFY HIM.
GOOD. TELL HIM
TO MEET ME OUT THERE
AS QUICK
AS HE CAN MAKE IT.
WE'LL DO
THE JOB TOGETHER.
AND, JOHN,
AS SOON AS YOU'VE
DONE THAT, I WANT
YOU TO HELP ME
SPREAD THE WORD
AROUND TOWN.
YOU, TOO, HONEY,
IF YOU WILL.
WE'VE GOT
TO MAKE CERTAIN
THAT WELL'S DONE ALL
THE DAMAGE IT CAN DO.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
PARSON,
THEY WANT YOU OVER
TO MRS. BELCHER'S.
I RECKON
MISS FAITH SAMUELS
IS A-DYIN'.
FAITH?
JOHN AND I WILL
TEND TO THINGS.
YOU GO.
SURE.
WHO SENT YOU,
CHLOROFORM?
THEM OVER
TO MRS. BELCHER'S.
BUT WHO?
WAS IT MRS. BELCHER?
OH, NO, PARSON.
YOUNG DOC ASKED ME
TO FETCH YOU.
THANKS.
EVENING,
MRS. BELCHER.
MR. GRAY,
I SENT FOR YOU
BECAUSE I KNOW
SHE'D WANT YOU
TO BE HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE
I CAN DO FOR HER.
PLEASE WAIT OUTSIDE.
ONCE YOU ASKED ME
TO LEAVE A SICKROOM.
NOW I'M ASKING YOU
TO LEAVE ONE.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
[HOOFBEATS]
"THIS IS
YOUR LAST CHANCE.
"YOU'VE GOT
24 HOURS TO CLEAR
OFF THIS LAND.
"GET OFF,
OR GET A ROPE
AROUND YOUR NECK.
WE MEAN BUSINESS.
THE NIGHTRIDERS."
LET ME SEE.
CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT.
JUST CAN'T
UNDERSTAND IT.
WHY, THERE AIN'T
A MAN FOR MILES AROUND
THAT I AIN'T KNOWED
AS WELL AS I KNOW
THIS BOY HERE.
YOU STILL DON'T
WANT TO SELL?
I DON'T SEE HOW
I CAN DO THAT, PARSON.
THAT'S MY PROPERTY.
EVERYBODY KNOWS IT.
IF I'VE GOT TO DIE,
I'LL DO IT ON MY PROPERTY.
MR. BACKETT?
I'M HERE TO TELL YOU
THIS PERSECUTION
OF UNCLE FAMOUS
HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
YOU CALL--
NOW HOLD ON,
PARSON.
I'M
A CHURCHGOING MAN,
AND YOU KNOW IT,
BUT THAT DON'T
GIVE YOU THE RIGHT
TO COME BUSTIN'
INTO MY STORE
AND INTERFERIN'
IN MY BUSINESS.
RIGHT NOW, MR. BACKETT,
YOUR BUSINESS IS
INTERFERING WITH MINE.
I'M ASKING YOU,
BEFORE GOD--
DON'T YOU REALIZE
WHAT YOU'RE SETTING
OUT TO DO HERE?
MURDER ONE OLD MAN,
STEAL HIS PROPERTY,
TAKE YOUR CUT,
AND THEN CALL
THE JOB DONE?
IT WON'T END THERE.
DON'T THINK IT.
YOU--ALL OF YOU.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN
IN THE LAST WEEKS?
HAVEN'T YOU SEEN
THE SLOW FEVER AT WORK?
ONE POISONED WELL
SPREAD GRIEF AND TROUBLE
THROUGH HALF THE TOWN?
DON'T YOU REALIZE
THE POISON IN THAT WELL
WAS CATLAP
COMPARED TO THIS?
IF THAT POISON'S
ALLOWED TO START,
IT'LL SPREAD
UNTIL THERE ISN'T A WHOLE SOUL
OR A HEALTHY CONSCIENCE
LEFT IN WALESBURG.
WELL, I AIM TO SEE--
YOU WAIT AND SEE.
THERE'LL BE
NO ROPE AROUND
ANYBODY'S NECK
AS LONG AS THERE'S
ONE MAN OF US
LEFT TO STOP IT.
NIGHTRIDERS.
YELLOWBACKS
IN FANCY DRESS.
YOU SHAME ME,
AND YOU SHAME
THE LORD THAT MADE YOU
AND CALLED YOU MEN.
AND IF I WASN'T HIS SERVANT,
I'D TAKE A BUGGY WHIP
TO THE LOT OF YOU.
WE GONNA TAKE THAT
FROM HIM?
WE DON'T WANT
NO PREACHER--
SHUT HIS MOUTH
FOR HIM.
IF HE WANTS A FIGHT,
LET'S GIVE IT TO HIM.
KIND OF LOOKING
FORWARD TO TONIGHT.
ROLFE HERE TELLS ME
YOU RUN INTO TROUBLE
WITH LON BACKETT'S CROWD.
THAT'S ONE WAY
OF PUTTING IT.
WELL, IS THERE
ENOUGH TROUBLE
FOR 6 OF US?
OH, JED,
YOU NEVER CHANGE,
DO YOU?
HA HA!
JUST LIKE OLD TIMES.
WELL, I BRUNG YOU
A HORSE,
SO GET YOUR PISTOLS,
AND LET'S GO.
I'M NOT TAKING
MY PISTOLS
WITH ME THIS TIME.
AFRAID I MIGHT
FORGET MYSELF
AND USE 'EM.
WELL, THAT'S
WHAT THEY'RE
FOR, AIN'T THEY?
MAYBE,
BUT IT'S NOT
WHAT I'M FOR.
LORD KNOWS,
I WANT YOU
BOYS ALONG--
WANT YOU BAD.
BUT IF YOU
WANT TO COME,
YOU'LL HAVE TO COME
LIKE I TELL YOU,
AND ON MY TERMS.
SO I'LL JUST
TAKE CHARGE
OF THOSE GUNS.
OH, NOW,
LOOKIT HERE.
YOU AIN'T GOT A FRIEND
IN THAT CROWD
SINCE THIS MORNING.
AND IF YOU'RE AIMIN' ON
SPOILING THEIR PARTY,
YOU'RE GONNA NEED
SOME CARE TAKEN OF YOU.
I FIGURE I'LL BE
TAKEN CARE OF,
ALL RIGHT.
OH, J.D. GRAY,
I DON'T KNOW YOU
NO MORE.
WHEN ARE YOU GONNA
SHUCK OFF
THAT LONG TAIL COAT
AND BE A MAN AGAIN?
WHEN YOU COMIN'
TO CHURCH, JED?
OH--COME ON, BOYS.
TAKE CARE.
Narrator: I'LL NEVER FORGET
HOW I FELT THAT NIGHT
AS I WATCHED THE PARSON
SET OUT, LEAVING ME BEHIND.
BUT I KNEW THE WAY
TO UNCLE FAMOUS'
AS WELL AS HE DID.
AND IF HIS TOWN
HAD FAILED HIM,
THAT WAS NO REASON
FOR ME TO DO THE SAME.
COME ON OUT, FAMOUS,
OR WE'LL COME IN
AND GET YOU!
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S FETCH HIM.
YOU'RE WASTIN'
YOUR TIME, PARSON.
HE AIN'T GOT A CHANCE.
STAND ASIDE.
STAND ASIDE,
PARSON.
COME ON OUT,
FAMOUS!
[MEN YELLING]
WAIT! WAIT A MINUTE,
ALL OF YOU!
AND BEFORE YOU MEN
GO ANY FURTHER,
THERE'S SOMETHING I'D LIKE
TO TAKE UP WITH YOU.
MIND YOU, I'M NOT
OUT HERE TO TRY
AND TALK YOU OUT
OF ANYTHING.
IF YOU'RE STILL DETERMINED
TO DO THIS THING,
I DON'T KNOW OF ANY WAY
I CAN STOP YOU.
I CAME OUT HERE TO--
[INDISTINCT YELLING]
UNCLE FAMOUS!
DON'T LET THEM
DO IT, PARSON.
DON'T LET THEM!
LET GO OF ME!
PARSON! PARSON!
WHY DON'T YOU STOP THEM?
YOU GOTTA STOP THEM!
YOU GOT TO!
Man: HE DON'T
BELONG HERE,
ANYHOW.
YOU DIDN'T
LET ME FINISH.
I CAME OUT HERE
TONIGHT
BECAUSE UNCLE FAMOUS
ASKED ME TO COME.
HE KNOWS
HE'S GOT TO DIE.
BUT LIKE
EVERYBODY ELSE,
HE WANTED TO GET
THINGS STRAIGHT
WITH GOD AND MAN
BEFORE HE GOES.
WE'VE PRAYED
TOGETHER,
AND WE'VE
TALKED TOGETHER.
UNCLE FAMOUS HAS
EVEN MADE A WILL.
A WILL?
WILL?
WHO'S GONNA GET
HIS PROPERTY?
YES, WHO'S GONNA
GET THE MICA VEIN?
Gray: WAIT A MINUTE.
JUST SO THERE WON'T BE
ANY ARGUMENT ABOUT THIS,
I'M GONNA READ
THE WILL TO YOU
RIGHT IN FRONT
OF UNCLE FAMOUS.
AND AFTER YOU'VE
HEARD IT AND KNOW
IT'S REALLY HIS,
YOU CAN GO
ABOUT YOUR WORK.
THE WILL IS IN UNCLE FAMOUS'
OWN WORDS.
IT ISN'T IN LAWYER FORM,
BUT JUST AS HE SPOKE IT.
"I AIN'T BEEN ABLE TO PUT
MUCH BY IN THIS LIFE,
"BUT THE THINGS I HAS,
"I WANTS TO GO
TO MY FRIENDS.
"MY HOUSE I LEAVES
TO MR. ERNEST CUMBERLY,
"WHOSE DADDY GIVE ME
MY FREEDOM.
"I COULDN'T GO OUT
OF THIS WORLD
WITHOUT LEAVING
"SOMETHING TO OLD
MR. CUMBERLY'S SON,
"AND NEXT TO MY FREEDOM,
MY HOME IS THE THING
I VALUES MOST.
"I WANTS
MY FISHING POLES TO GO
"TO MR. CLEM ELKHART.
"WHEN HE WAS
A LITTLE BOY,
"I TEACHED HIM HOW
TO CATCH SUNPERCH.
"HE DIDN'T HAVE
AS GOOD LUCK AS I DID,
"AND I TOLD HIM IT WAS
'CAUSE I HAD A MAGIC POLE.
"HIS EYES USED
TO SHINE AT THAT.
"MAYBE NOW
HE CAN CATCH SOME FISH.
"I SURE WANTS
MR. PERRY LOKEY
"TO HAVE
MY WATERMELON PATCH.
"HE WAS A FULL-GROWED MAN
AFORE HE QUIT SNITCHING
MY MELONS,
"AND HE KNOWED
I SEEN HIM, TOO.
"THAT OLD SHOTGUN OF MINE,
I WANTS TO LEAVE
"TO MR. LEN CHILDERS.
"WHEN HE WAS
A LITTLE BOY,
"HE SHOT IT OFF
AT A COTTONTAIL
"AND KNOCKED IT PLUMB
OVER A RAIL FENCE.
"I RECKON HE'S BIG
ENOUGH AND MAN ENOUGH
TO HANDLE IT NOW.
"I WANTS TO LEAVE
MY HOGS AND CHICKENS
TO MR. THAD GABRY.
"MY, HOW THAT BOY
DID LOVE BARBECUE.
"HE COULD SMELL IT
A MILE OFF.
"I WANTS HIM TO GIVE
A BIG BARBECUE
"AND INVITE
ALL OUR FRIENDS.
"MR. BILL COLE
CAN HAVE MY RAZOR.
"EVER SINCE HE WAS
KNEE-HIGH TO A HOP TOAD,
"THE THING HE WANTED
MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE
"WAS A BEARD.
"NOW I RECKON HE'S GOT
MORE BEARD THAN HE WANTS.
"EVERY TIME
HE HONES MY RAZOR,
"I HOPES IT'LL REMIND HIM
THAT THE LORD WILL PROVIDE.
"MY TOOLS I LEAVES
TO MR. MATT GIBSON.
"ONE TIME HELPIN' ME
CHOP WOOD,
"HE LIKE TO CUT OFF
HIS BIG TOE WITH MY AX.
"NOW I RECKON HE'S THE BEST
SAWMILL BOSS IN THE WORLD.
"MY OLD DOG BELLE,
I LEAVES TO MR. JUSTIN BRILEY.
"HE DIDN'T HAVE
NO DOG OF HIS OWN
"WHEN HE WAS
A LITTLE BOY.
"I WANTS HIM
TO LET HER RUN FREE
AND NOT KEEP HER ON
NO ROPE."
"I WANTS ALL THE MICA
ON MY PROPERTY
"TO GO
TO MR. LON BACKETT.
"SEEMS LIKE HE WANTS
THAT MICA POWERFUL BAD.
"NOW HE CAN HAVE IT.
"THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
I WANTS TO LEAVE
TO MR. BACKETT.
"I WANTS HIM TO HAVE
MY BIBLE.
"IT AIN'T FANCY.
"I GUESS IT'S
ALMOST WORE OUT.
"BUT I WANTS
MR. BACKETT TO HAVE IT.
I HOPE HE READS IT."
YOU CAN HAVE HIM NOW.
THERE'S
NO WRITIN' ON HERE.
THIS AIN'T A WILL.
YES, IT IS, SON.
IT'S THE WILL OF GOD.
* OH, TO GRACE
HOW GREAT A DEBTOR *
* DAILY I'M CONSTRAINED
TO BE *
* LET THY GOODNESS
LIKE A FETTER *
* BIND MY WANDERING HEART
TO THEE *
* PRONE TO WANDER,
LORD, I FEEL IT *
* PRONE TO LEAVE
THE GOD I LOVE *
* HERE'S MY HEART, LORD,
TAKE AND SEAL IT *
* SEAL IT
FOR THY COURTS ABOVE *
* AMEN *
[ORGAN PLAYING]
* WILL THERE
BE ANY STARS *
* ANY STARS
IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN I WAKE WITH THE BLESSED
IN THOSE MANSIONS OF REST *
* WILL THERE BE
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN? *
* I AM THINKING TODAY
OF THAT BEAUTIFUL LAND *
* I SHALL REACH
WHEN THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN THROUGH WONDERFUL GRACE
BY MY SAVIOR I STAND *
* WILL THERE BE
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN? *
* WILL THERE BE ANY STARS,
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN *
* WHEN AT EVENING
THE SUN GOETH DOWN *
* WHEN I WAKE WITH THE BLESSED
IN THE MANSIONS OF REST *
* WILL THERE BE
ANY STARS IN MY CROWN? *
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
TURNER ENTERTAINMENT GROUP
CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE
--www.ncicap.org--