[ howling ]
[ howling continues ]
[ grunting, wheezing ]
[ grunting ]
[ baby crying ]
What's the matter, baby ?
Come on, baby.  Ooh.
[ coughing ]
[ sighing ]
I think she's croupy.
Oh, that's not the croup.
It's a dry cough.
You ought to know
the difference by now.
Give her to me.
Guess I'm just
the worryin' kind,
now I'm a pa.
You been a pa for 15 years.
You were the worryin' kind
long before that.
[ fussing ]
ohh, ohh.
Seems like every time
I get set to go off,
somebody around here's sick.
[ scoffs ]
she just got a cough.
You're goin' off to get shot at.
We're the ones gonna worry.
And you don't even have to go.
Just goin' 'cause
the captain asked ya.
Be off
to check the stove.
Here, honey.
Take her with ya.
She's hungry.
And wake the boys
while you're at it.
You can sleep
a minute longer.
I can't sleep a minute longer.
I'm a schoolteacher,
remember ?
[ man ]
Jack comin' through
with broken reins.  Get him !
[ man #2 ]
yo, back here.  Come on, curly.
Curly !
[ man ]  get the rope on him !
[ man #2 ]
whoa, put a rope on him.
come on, Clyde !
Come on, Clyde !
[ man ]
get up there, now.
Come on, get behind him, now.
Thought you went to work
before dinner, Charlie.
I'd be at work,
if I wasn't afraid to
go off and leave the help.
If I do, most of them will
just get lost and I'll have
to waste time lookin' for 'em.
Put the rope on
the horse's neck,
not the damn horn !
You're a little tardy
yourself today, ain't ya ?
Yeah, this Yankee...
I'm meetin' must like
to sleep late; I'm not due
to the railroad till seven.
Who you goin' after
this time, Woodrow ?
Name's Joey Garza,
train robber.
They say he's swift.
Has he give you
a fancy gun yet ?
Who ?
Colonel Terry.
Ain't he still president
of the railroad ?
Man I'm dealin' with
name's Brookshire.
I don't know
who owns the railroad
this boy's been robbin'.
I expect he'll offer you
a fancy gun.
I've no use
for expensive weapons.
[ laughs ]
you let somebody give you
a fancy gun,
And he'll tell
everybody in five counties
he's your friend,
When in fact
he may despise you.
[ cowboys yipping,
shouting ]
Plan to work before noon,
you better give your hands
a help catchin' the horses.
This is a pointless
conversation.  Good-bye.
Bye.
Come on, boy !
I'd hate to let Woodrow call
beat me to work.
[ man ]
here comes a tough cowboy !
[ bleating ]
[ chattering ]
[ gunshot, groaning ]
what the hell was that ?
[ baby crying ]
Eat your breakfast.
August ?  Hold--
put her in the crib,
would you ?
B-b-but pa,
I ain't finished yet.
Will you just do it ?
[ baby cries again ]
I wish you'd learn
how to drink out of a cup,
like the rest of us.
Well, saucerin' coffee
is a habit I picked up...
In the ranger days
when I was a bachelor.
I was a bachelor
most of my life.
Same as the captain.
You're never
the same as the captain.
Well, maybe not.
You know, I hadn't learned
how to be a husband yet,
not in those days.
You know, things
like bein' married--
[ chuckles ]
You still
don't know a thing
about bein' married.
I have to
teach you every day.
Was she wet ?
[ August ]
no, ma.
I don't like that old man
keepin' you away from us.
Why can't he find somebody
younger if he needs help
chasin' a bandit ?
Pea ?
Somethin' the matter ?
No, I 'spect I'll worry
about all of you the whole way.
[ door bangs ]
I worry but I like
gettin' paid cash money.
[ girl ]
you don't have to worry, pa.
I'll help ma while you're gone.
Oh, I'm sure you will,
in what time you spare
from Roy Benson.
She kisses him, pa !
You hush, Georgie.
Ma ?
Don't you be hittin'
your brother !
I won't have
my Georgie beaten up over
a silly boy like Roy Benson.
Ma, he ain't silly.
Don't talk about him like that.
I wish all of you
would leave me alone.
She beats up on me all the time.
Well, you deserve it,
you little snitch.
Will you hand me that rag ?
Ben's nose is runny.
[ children arguing ]
- It's a dish rag.
- Well, it's not now,
it's a snot rag.
Hold still.
Okay, children.
Go on up and
get ready for school.
[ mother ]
go on !
I wish pa
didn't have to go.
I don't like it
when pa goes.
[ Ben ]  ma, Georgie pulled
my suspenders this morning.
[ Georgie ]  no, I did not !
[ mother ]
boys, stop pesterin' each other
and get upstairs.
- [ footsteps receding ]
- [ sighs ]
They don't deserve you.
We do.
We'd love you.
He just works you.
Lori, I been with the captain
a long, long time--
You been
with these children
their whole lives !
They got no other father.
He can get another corporal,
and that's all you are to him.
He don't even like you neither.
He's mad at ya 'cause
you married me.
Doesn't like it
that Gus liked me,
neither.
Now that we're married,
I've taken two men from him.
Don't like it
that I'm a teacher, neither.
Guess he don't think
that whores ought to
become school teachers.
[ door closes ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ wagon approaching ]
[ man ]
hee-yaw !  Hee-yaw !  Come on !
Hey, Henry.
Howdy, Ben.
Excuse me, sir.
Would you be
Mr. Brookshire ?
Well, yes.
At your service.
I'm call.
Glad you're prompt.
I despise laggards.
I imagine you were expecting
someone younger.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Actually, you see,
I'm just an accountant.
They don't usually send me
on these trips; they usually
send Jimmy Roberts, but...
He swallowed a wine cork
and choked to death not an hour
before he was to leave.
Train robbers ain't smart.
Five smart train robbers
could bust every railroad
in this country.
Well, this young Mexican
is smart.
That's why colonel Terry
expressly ordered me
to hire you.
You've got
a very fine reputation.
Fine reputation ?
Well, I say he does.
This here's captain call;
he's the greatest ranger
that there's ever been.
I'd prefer
my coffee hot and
my conversations private.
Say, sweet-tempered
he ain't, but you'll find
that out if you hire him.
Of course I have to hire you.
Temper isn't the point.
How many trains
this Garza boy rob ?
The count was seven.
You say
he's a guero ?
He's what ?
Guero.  That means
a blond-haired Mexican.
Blue-eyed too.
Oh !
I forgot the gun.
[ sighs ]
so windy out, it just about
blew my wits away.
Colonel Terry
sent you this gun.
It's a gift.
Thanks,
but I'll pass.
You mean
you don't want it ?
Well, good Lord-- why--
wh-wh-what'll I tell
colonel Terry ?
This engraving
is hand work, you know.
It doesn't come cheap.
Well, then,
the colonel can keep it
for himself, Ned.
I have no place to keep
a fancy weapon.
I'd just have to deposit it
in the bank, and I prefer
to avoid banks.
[ sighs ]
well--
I don't know what the colonel's
gonna say when he finds out
you didn't want his gun.
He'll be mad enough
to bite himself.
Well,
if he bites himself,
that's his concern.
If you want me
to catch this boy,
I'll give ya my terms.
Pea !  Could ya hitch up
the buggy, honey ?
Claire’s running late.
[ Claire ]
who has the wire brush ?
[ boys ]  Ben !
[ Ben ]
no, I don't.
[ boy ]  yes, you do.
[ Claire ]
just hand it over, okay ?
[ arguing continues ]
If you don't hand it over,
I'm gonna tell mom.
I don't have it !
Mom !  Ben has my hairbrush
and he won't give it back !
[ Lori ]
honey, we have
your hairbrush down here.
How do you expect me
to get ready for school
if you have my hairbrush ?
Where's your guns ?
Well, I never finished
cleanin' 'em.
Well, you cleaned 'em enough
to smell like gun grease
all night.
Whoa, boy.
You smell like
somethin' different
every night, seems like.
Well, I guess it just
depends on what I spill
on myself during the day.
Mean you're goin' off
to chase a bandit
without even bein' armed ?
Don't need to be armed
'cause I ain't goin'.
- You ain't, pa ?
- No.
I'm scared
one of you might die
while I'm gone.
Besides, this chasin' bandits
has gotta stop sometime.
What about the captain ?
Well, I gotta
go over to the railroad
and tell him I can't go.
Well, he'd better not
be rough on ya.
If he is, he's gonna
have me to deal with.
You sure this is what
you wanna do, pea ?
Yeah.
I hope so.
I don't want ya
mopin' about it later.
Hey, Charlie !
Step up !
Mom, you're so mean to him.
You think I'm mean
to your father ?
You don't know
what mean is.
[ Claire ]
well, I think
I know what mean is.
And I think
you're mean to pa.
[ passengers chattering ]
Oops !
Aw.
[ laughing ]
Wind's not like this
back home.
I'm not visitin' Brooklyn,
but when you're travelin'
here on the plains,
You can count on wind.
Got off the train
here yesterday ?
Been chasin' my hat ever since.
Might get a piece of twine,
tie it on your head.
[ thunder ]
[ groaning ]
[ moaning ]
[ screaming ]
[ train whistling ]
[ whistling continues ]
Mr. Brookshire ?
Mr. Brookshire !
Mr. Brookshire,
are you ill ?
[ train braking ]
I'd like to get on
the train, now.
Maybe I would perk up
if I was on that train.
Let's go get on
the train.
[ conductor ]
'board !
Next stop, San Angelo.
Right there.
Just step right up.
[ gasps ]
okay.
All right.
Just go right through there,
and you get settled down.
Would you take that ?
Where are you going ?
Goin' back for
the rest of my gear.
I'll be right back.
Uh, do you mind
if I came with ya ?
I thought
you wanted to be
inside the train.
I did.  I do.  I did.
But, uh, I-I'm--
I'm afraid I'll blow away.
Like a tumbleweed.
I know it's windy.
I never seen any wind
bad enough to blow a fellow
out of a railroad car,
And besides, if you
don't mind my saying so,
You-you're a bit heavier
than a tumbleweed.
- You sure you're
gonna come right back ?
- I'll be right back.
Unless a big gust comes up.
Is that your man ?
Hmm.
He forgot his weapons.
How could he forget
his weapon ?
You forgot your arsenal.
Well, no, I didn't forget it,
captain.  I left it home.
Who's that fellow
with the derby ?
That's Mr. Brookshire.
He's with the railroad.
Spends most of his time
chasin' after that derby hat.
A man that can't keep
his hat on ain't gonna be
much help in Mexico.
Well, I expect I'm not
gonna be much help to you
in Mexico either, captain.
I got me a wife, now,
and five children.
One of 'em's a baby.
I got-I got a farm
won't work itself.
I-I reckon it's--
it's time for me to stay home.
Well, I guess I stopped
this train for nothin'...
If you ain't gettin' on.
What's wrong
with your man ?
- Is he sick ?
- No, he ain't sick.
He's married.
- Are you a cardplayin' man ?
- No.
I didn't think you were.
[ train whistles ]
Older children
copy the math problems
on the board...
As your assignment
for tomorrow.
Younger children,
take home your readers
and study chapter 15.
That's page one-forty--
[ whispering ]
what ?
[ mumbling ]
captain left without me.
Did he fuss at you much ?
No, just...
Shook my hand and left.
[ laughs ]
[ giggling, whispering ]
Claire !
Mind what you're doin',
this is a school room.
Finish your addition.
[ children chattering ]
Quiet, children.
Are you sick,
honey ?
No.
- Are you havin' one
of your headaches ?
- Yeah.
It's kind of a pain
in the neck like your horse
has a stiff trot.
It's not the stiff trot,
it's the stiff wife.
Go home with your father.
He's feelin' poorly.
Roy and I was
going to study together--
And when you get there, fix him
some soup, and put him to bed
till his head feels better.
But ma--
don't "but ma" me,
Claire.  Go !
Roy Benson ain't gonna
melt between today
and tomorrow, honey.
You'll see him again.
Pa, do you like Roy ?
Ma don't.
Roy ?
He's gangly.
So am I.
[ man ]
you ought to retire, Willy.
You're losin' your eyesight.
[ man #2 ]
nah.  Jus' in the lef' eye.
Man as blind as you
oughtn't to be
ridin' that River.
You're liable to fall
in a hole and get
swallowed up.
You're blind drunk
nine days out of ten.
What's to keep you from
stumblin' off into a hole
and gettin' swallowed up ?
The fact is, I hold court
nine days out of ten.
And I am too busy to wander
out there and find myself
a hole big enough.
I particularly hate thieves.
A man who would steal
50 cents off ya...
Will steal a million dollars.
Ain't too many
folks around here
got 50 cents.
[ chuckles ]
much less
a million dollars.
I've got 50 cents.
And I aim
to keep it, too.
If I stole
your 50 cents,
would you hang me ?
I'd hang you as soon
as I could find my rope.
Now, I may not
be able to put my hand
on my hangin' rope right off,
So if you was quick,
you might escape.
Who said you could be
a judge, anyway ?
I'd wanna
see some papers...
Before I'd let you
hang me.
If you could see,
you'd see that we're
west of the Pecos,
And out here,
if you wanna be a judge
bad enough, you can be.
[ spits ]
and I wanna be one
bad enough.
What if it was
a dime I stole ?
Would you still hang me ?
I cannot tolerate
the loss of any sum !
Officially.
Hmm.
You want to put this whisky
you been drinkin' on your bill,
is that correct ?
Put it anywhere
you want to put it.
Watch out
for the Garza boy.
[ chuckles ]
Joey ?
I know Joey.
Why would I wanna
watch out for him ?
'cause he's a cold killer.
Just 'cause you fancy
his mother don't mean
he won't cut you down.
He won't
cut me down !
Well, if you make it
for a month or so,
you might survive !
- Why a month or so ?
- They've hired call to get him.
You mean Woodrow call
is after Joey ?
Who told you ?
John Wesley Hardin.
Huh.
John Wesley.
Now, there's a fellow
you ought to hang.
As long as you're hangin' folks.
Why ?
Never stole a cent off me.
Mr. Hardin was headin'
for Crowtown.
'spect he's killed
a few rascals lookin'
for a place to hide out.
Well, Crowtown's
the place to hide out,
all right.
[ sighs ]
missed two.
[ laughs ]
It's the sweat, you see.
In Germany, it's not so hot.
Uh, the sweat fogs up
my telescope.
Still, I think
I beat you.
Thank you for
letting me shoot.
I like your gun.
%% [ singing in Spanish ]
%% [ singing continues ]
Mama !
[ speaking Spanish ]
what did you do ?
I beat your man.
He can't shoot.
He is not my man.
I have no man.
Mama, you always
have a man.
Teresa, I forgot the basket.
Go and bring me a basket.
[ Spanish ]
[ laughing ]
[ shrieks in pain ]
You whore !
You cut me !
Hombre, if you put
your hands on me again...
I'll do worse
that cut you !
[ muttering ]
Mary !
Mary, I got news.
- Where is your horse ?
- Aw, that dumb son of a bitch.
He let some pigs spook him.
I had to walk a good five mile.
I hope it sobered you.
You look red in your face.
Like you do when you drink.
[ Spanish ]
Yeah, well, all I need
is a little whisky.
A little love...
And a few frijoles--
I can give you
the frijoles.
Can do nothing
about the rest.
Yeah, well, what
I really need is
a bottle of beer.
I seldom walk
in the heat, you know.
You do not walk at all.
Or do anything else but talk !
What the news ?
Oh, God,
my brain is boiled.
I'm so hot.
I near forgot.
Mary,
they've hired call.
I come as quick as
I could to tell ya.
Go to the house.
Clean yourself.
Teresa will give you
the frijoles.
[ weeping, shouting ]
Come on, mules !
We caught these men
with 30 stolen horses.
Old vaquero up on the River
told us they were
from this village.
They are from this village.
They are my son
and my grandsons.
We caught 'em
with 30 horses.
The law is the law.
So we hung 'em,
we cut 'em down.
Brought them home here.
[ shocked chattering ]
[ hysterical crying ]
Captain !
What's the point of
the eight-gauge ?  Take a whole
pack mule to carry the shells.
Well, the man who sold it
to me said it would be
useful for self-defense.
I won't dispute that.
If you survive the kick,
You won't have to worry
too much about the enemy.
[ gate creaks ]
thank you.
- Let me see the pistols.
- Oh.  They're said to be
the newest model.
Well, I'll allow
they're the most expensive.
I'm glad your colonel
don't mind expense.
Oh, but he does.
Colonel Terry hates expense.
Well, maybe I could
sell them back,
when we get through.
[ nickers ]
you know, I hadn't expected
this extreme weather.
I all but froze in Amarillo,
now I'm all but cooked.
Aren't Amarillo and Laredo
in the same state ?
Well, more or less.
There's some folks
think Laredo’s
still in Mexico.
You don't get
weather like this
in Brooklyn.
[ train whistles ]
it's just weather.
If I was you, I'd go into
the telegraph office...
And see if there's
any more trains been robbed.
Well, what'll you be doin' ?
I'll be packin'
the horses.
[ dog barking ]
[ rifle cocking ]
[ whinnying ]
Where have you been ?
I thought you were going
to help us with the corn.
I am not a farmer.
Where's Billy ?
He's driving
the wagon to the mines.
He'll be back in three days.
Good !  I'm glad he's gone.
That old man smells.
He's kind to me.
That is because
he wants you.
That is the reason he comes,
and that is the reason he stays.
[ slapping ]
Any man can want.
It's how a man behaves
that counts.
Don't hit me
again, mama.
[ whimpers ]
[ bleating ]
[ bleating like a goat ]
[ bleating continues ]
[ cowboys yipping,
whistling ]
It's seven telegrams.
If the colonel's mad enough
to send out seven telegrams,
He's ready
to call out the army !
Sounds like
an impatient man,
your colonel.
[ sighs ]
impatient men
make mistakes.
The only mistake he's gonna
make would be to kill me.
Only he won't think
it's a mistake.
Yeah, four more trains
been robbed, one of 'em
carryin' an army payroll.
Another payroll.
Lord spare us.
The army'll be mad for sure.
Mm, it's the passengers
the Lord should have spared.
Sixteen folks were shot
in them four robberies.
Sixteen ?
That's the count.
Whoever done it--
doin' it for the killin',
not the robbin'.
- How do you know ?
- Fought in the civil war,
didn't ya ?
Well, I was there.
I was quartermaster, mostly.
You were still there.
How many men did
your company lose ?
'bout ten.
There you go.
I fought the Indian wars
of Texas for 24 years,
and I lost six men.
Sixteen men killed
in four robberies ?
That indicates a killer,
possibly two.
Well, what makes
you say two ?
The distance.
Train was robbed in
van horn, Texas one afternoon,
Another in Deming, new Mexico
before dawn the next day.
No robber could have made it
from van horn to Deming
that quick.
He couldn't have done it
even if he rode the train
he just robbed.
[ whinnying ]
I'm gonna have to talk
to the sheriff in this town.
We can't afford to be
shorthanded, with all
these train robberies.
Whoever robbed
the train outside of
Deming had a gang.
Garza boy works alone.
Now how does he
stop those trains
if he works alone ?
[ sheriff ]
well, he ain't lazy, captain.
Works at night.
Piles rocks on the tracks.
Builds kind of a wall.
Surely a locomotive
going full speed could bust
through a few rocks.
Maybe.
But the train might derail,
And if it derailed,
you'd be in a pickle.
If Joey Garza’s after you,
you're in a pickle anyway.
If it was me, and
I was drivin' the durn train,
I'd pour on the steam--
Ted,
who consulted you ?
I'll consult him.
He's makin'
more sense than you.
Well, I guess
the engineer could
plow on if he wants to.
Well, Joey Garza,
it's either run or fight.
Me, I'd run.
You employed steady, or would
you consider accompanying us
on this chase ?
Well, it's steady.
But it's warm here.
I wouldn't mind gettin' off
to higher country, where there
might be a breeze.
Ted, who invited you
in this conversation ?
If you leave,
who's gonna
sweep out the jail ?
Well, if captain call wants me,
I expect I better go.
He's captain call, bob.
He's captain call !
He knows my name, deputy.
- You goin', or ain't ya ?
- I sure am, captain.
I'm with ya.
Go get your bedroll.
We're ready to leave.
Much obliged, Ted.
Captain.
[ sniffling, crying ]
Stop pattin' me
on the back like that.
Like what ?
Like you was in a hurry
and wanted me to stop cryin'
so you could leave.
Baby, I got to get
this gear together quick.
Captain's ready to leave.
He ain't gonna like waitin'.
The captain.
You know that's all
I heard come out of your mouth
since you got home,
Just "the captain" this,
and "the captain" that.
I mean, who is he anyway ?
He's just some old man
I ain't never heard of.
The most famous
Texas ranger there's ever been.
He's captain call.
Everybody on the border
knows who captain call is.
I'm on the border.
I ain't never heard tell of him.
But if he's important enough
to break up our marriage
with our baby comin',
Then you can just go !
Why have you said anything
about breaking up our marriage ?
I'm just goin' off
with captain call.
I'll be back long before
little Joe is born.
Or little Josie,
whichever it is.
[ sighs ]
What if
ya don't come back ?
Why wouldn't I do, huh ?
This is where I live.
I know.
What if you don't live ?
Then what'll me and
Joe or Josie do then ?
My gosh.  I'm not
goin' off to get killed.
You've gotta get
that notion out of your head.
[ sighs ]
You will lead that
second packhorse
back there, deputy.
[ rattling ]
[ neighing ]
Uh, captain ?
- Where are we gonna
be sleeping ?
- On the ground, sir.
You plannin' on
nestin' in a tree ?
[ Brookshire ]
no, no.
No, it's just that the--
The ground's a little--
well, I mean...
There are snakes.
[ laughing ]
O-ho !  Whoa.
Well, well, well.
Now, hold on, Jethro.
[ laughing ]
Ohh.
Hey, puta !
Wait up a minute.
When I tell a whore to wait,
you better wait.
How 'bout a drink, puta ?
I am no puta, senor.
- You're not near as pretty
as you used to be, Jethro.
- [ men laughing ]
- Senor ?
- Yeah, what do you want, mex ?
[ gunshot, screaming ]
¿ que paso ?
Hah !
Hyah !
What have you done ?
Now the hard sheriff is going
to come from across the River.
He's going
to beat us all.
No, he will
only beat her.
She made it happen.
What have you done ?
I killed
a gringo, mama.
I only like gringos
when they're dead.
He is bad, that one.
He is bad.
I made you coffee, mama.
Me and Rafael are here.
We will
take care of you.
Teresa,
You'll have to stay
with grandmother
for a few days.
No--
bad men will come.  I do not
want you or Rafael here.
But I don't want
to go !
Teresa !
You can take
your chick with you.
[ makes bleating sound ]
c-can Rafael
take his goat ?
Rafael can take his goat.
[ man ]
Rico !
[ screaming in Spanish ]
You senora Garza ?
[ speaking Spanish ]
senora Maria Garza.
Where's that
murderin' son of yours ?
[ man #2 ]
speak up, woman !
Sheriff Donovan
asked you a question.
Where's Joey ?
This is Mexico.
It's my country.
You are not the law here.
Lady's got
a point, boys.
What do you mean, sheriff ?
We can do what we damn well
please with Mexicans,
wherever we are.
No, senora Garza’s right,
boys.  This is Mexico.
We ain't the law here !
So what do you say we take
her back across the border
where we are the law ?
No !  Stop !
Stop !  Stop !
Ouch !
[ sighs ]  God, if you
scrape me one more time
with your toenails,
I'm kickin' you
out of this bed.
Why don't you cut
your toenails, like
other folks do ?
Well, they're way
down there in my socks.
I forget about 'em.
I'm sorry
I nicked ya, honey.
Nicked me ?
I'll probably be
the first person
to bleed to death...
From bein' cut by
her husband's toenail.
You're wishing you'd
gone with the captain,
ain't ya ?
No.
I just wish
he hadn't gone hisself.
I wish he'd just quit.
Quit and do what ?
He doesn't know how
to do anything but kill.
Just an evil old man.
Now, that ain't fair, Lori.
In the Indian days,
he didn't have no choice.
[ sighs ]
I mean, look what
blue duck did.
[ scoffs ]
I don't want to remember
what blue duck did,
'cause he did some of it to me !
I wanna forget
what blue duck did.
Captain call was
one of the folks
that helped me.
[ wolf howling ]
I was just a kid when
he took me in the troop.
Now he's askin'
for my help,
and I can't go.
Just feels wrong to me.
I mean, it--
feel more wrong if I went off
and left you and the tots--
Well, go after him,
then.  Go on.
I want you to.
[ sighs ]
I'll never really
have you as long as
that old man's alive,
And neither
will the children.
Don't be worryin'
about me and the "tots."
we'll do fine.
Go on, get killed.
And good riddance.
I don't want to go.
I'm here.
Here's where I want to be.
It's just I can't help
feelin' bad about leavin'
the captain shorthanded.
[ sighing ]
I know.
[ sighs heavily ]
I'm sorry I said that
about good friends.
I was just mad.
I get mad every time
we talk about him.
It's worse than
the toenails, ain't it ?
[ chuckles ]
I feel scared, Lori.
Don't know why
I feel so scared,
I think
I'm gettin' a chill.
God, you're clammy.
Maybe you have
what Georgie's got.
[ whispering ]
I'll warm ya,
honey.
It ain't cold on the outside,
it's the inside.
[ breathing ]
It's like I dread
somethin', Lori.
Well, I don't know
what you dread, but...
You're my husband;
I know what you need.
[ fierce yelling ]
Damn, that was
our best packhorse, too.
What happened ?
[ sighs ]
bad dream, I expect ?
Indians.  I-I-I thought
we were being
attacked by Indians.
[ gun cocking ]
[ horse wheezing ]
[ sighs, deeply ]
Better make an entry.
How much
did that horse cost ?
Twenty-five dollars.
Plus the shotgun shell.
I'd be sure and list
that shotgun shell,
if I was you.
[ rooster crows ]
He's an old man, Lori.
I better go find him.
Least we'll
be paid cash money.
Cash money can't hug me.
Can't do what
we did last night.
Can't make me a baby,
And it can't be a father
to the ones we already got.
But if you have to go,
go now, so I can start
gettin' used to it.
You won't have
to get over nothin'.
I'll be back.
I suspect it
was too good for
the both of you, pea.
He'll kill you
and the captain,
And I'll get old
and wouldn't have you.
And neither
will the children.
Come here, buddy.
[ muffled speaking ]
Oh !
[ sniffling ]
Take care of mama.
I love you too.
What makes you think
you can find the captain ?
You can't even track
the milk cow half the time.
I'll find the campers.
Folks don't forget him.
I'll just ask folks
as we move along.
Hang on, children.
We don't want
to be late for school.
Hey, Charlie !
Back soon, papa !
Bye, pa !
[ cawing ]
[ cawing continues, louder ]
Are there
any empty houses
in this town ?
- [ man ]
no.  And who are you ?
- I am Joey Garza.
Well, if you want
a domicile in this town,
all ya gotta do is...
Find a house you like,
kill whoever's in it,
Then drag the victim
up on the sand hill,
and...
The devil pig
will do the rest.
Excuse me, senores.
[ door closes ]
[ speaking Spanish ]
Guess we got
a new landlord.
He's better looking
than the old one.
That don't mean
he'll be easier
to get along with.
Captain,
do you ever get worried
before a fight ?
Nope, I can't
say I fret much.
Well, that's brave.
When I was in the war,
I was scared all the time.
And I was only
a quartermaster.
Still had nightmares.
What did ya dream ?
Ah, mainly of having one
of those big shells come
in low and knock my head off.
You know, that very thing
happened to a man I knew.
Fellow from Hoboken
named Johnny Rowe.
Bad luck, I suppose.
Terrible luck.
Man gave me
his biscuit that morning,
and rode out on a scout.
I--
why did he give ya
his biscuit ?
Well, he said he was
too nervous to eat.
[ pouring ]
So I ate the biscuit,
and off he rode.
And while I ate the biscuit,
general Grant rode by.
That was the one time
that I saw general Grant.
Anyway, after a little while
the shells started whistling in,
So we all squinched down
and went on up the road,
And... There was a bunch of boys
standing around a horse.
We thought they were looking
at a dead reb, but...
No, we were
looking at Johnny.
His head was gone.
It was just a red bone
sticking up between
his shoulders.
Lord.
Just a red bone ?
Yeah, a red bone.
I expect
it was his spine.
Lord.
Just a red bone ?
You know,
they say that Garza
boy can hit you...
Between the eyes
from a mile away
with that rifle of his.
All this is just
the effect of reputation.
A bandit gets a reputation,
folks get to thinkin'
he can do no wrong.
[ swallows ]
if he had any sense,
he wouldn't be shootin'...
Between the eyes, he'd be
shootin' at the trunk.
It's bigger.  It's
the intelligent target.
How was general Grant ?
I've always been curious
about the man.
Well, he looked
drunk, to me.
The man won that war,
and he was drunk the whole time.
My God, famous shoes.
How'd you get here ?
My day starts early.
I saw your track
in the creek
and I followed.
I thought you
had become a farmer.
[ sighs ]
I was surprised
to see your tracks.
[ groans ]
why, I used to travel
all the time.
You had no woman then.
Now you have a woman.
Who will give her
children if you are
traveling ?
Well, I expect she'll
be willin' to hold off on
the children till I get back.
What are you doin'
way up here on the Brazos ?
I'm a kickapoo.
Kickapoos lived here
until the Comanches came.
Comanches
did not like us.
Comanche don't like
anybody very much.
Except other Comanches.
They wanted our part
of the world
and they took it.
We are not fighters,
though we are
the best trackers.
Do you think captain call
would pay me to help him
find Joey Garza ?
Well, he'd most likely give
you something.  How much
do you expect to get ?
You said
your woman teaches.
Does she know
how to read tracks
in books ?
- What ?
- Tracks in books.
- Tracks on paper ?
- Oh, you mean, words ?
You bet she knows
how to read words.
Well, she teaches
young'uns their letters,
that's her job.
She taught you ?
Well, she been meanin'
to get around to it.
I know one or two letters.
I know "p," and I know "y."
I expect I'll study up
some more on the letters
when the crops come in.
I can track any animal.
I can track spiders.
I can track
lizards and snakes,
I can even track
fleas and bugs.
But I cannot follow
the tracks in books.
But if your woman will
teach me how to read,
I will help the captain
find Joey.
Well, that saved
on expense.
Don't you have
anything to eat ?
Well, I just shot me
a big jackrabbit
here last night.
Why didn't you kill
that antelope ?
Didn't see no antelope.
He's about
a half-mile from here.
I'm surprised
you didn't see him.
If I take you to him,
will you shoot him ?
Well, I'll shoot at it.
I mean, antelope are jumpy.
I saw him a while ago.
He was layin' down.
If you walk quietly,
I can bring you close.
[ man ]
come on, boys !  Don't take
all day to build a scaffold.
Sheriff's burnin' mad.
[ men's chattering
continues ]
Mary ?  Mary ?
Mary ?  That you ?
Mary ?
What's happening ?
What's happened to you ?
Come here.
It's me.
No !
It's me, Billy.
Billy.
[ moaning ]
Wh-what is it ?
Aw, te--
tell me what
happened to ya.
Joey.
He killed a man,
a gringo.
Now the hard sheriff
he wants to know
where to find him.
Where is he ?
I don't know.
It's all-- just a boy.
He can be Miles away
from here.
[ Billy ]
I despise them lawmen.
I just hate
their stinkin' hearts.
Hey, Billy !
I didn't know
you fancied Mexican whores.
Well, a fancy time
is to cut your
stinkin' heart out.
And I expect
I'll come back and do it
once I take Mary home.
[ laughing ]
You old-timers
got rough tongues.
Tell me
somethin', Billy.
You fancy
all Mexican whores ?
Or just this one ?
[ screams ]
[ groans ]
Could just as easy
have been your
stinkin' heart.
Come on, Mary.
We're goin' home.
[ man ]
he's crazy !
[ tapping ]
Good God, Tom.
Where's your ear ?
It's in my pocket.
In your...
Pocket--
You almost missed
this antelope.
If I had, we wouldn't
be eatin' him now,
would we ?
[ sighs ]
you'll have to shoot
better than this...
To kill Joey Garza.
He shoots better
than you do.
No doubt he shoots
better than the captain.
Ah !
They will never
find him without me.
Captain usually
finds the bandits that
he sets out looking for.
Not Joey.
So you know him then.
I know
his mother, Maria.
She fed me when
the hard sheriff put me
in jail in presidio...
For eating
a dead horse.
I didn't know it was
a crime to eat a dead horse.
Hard sheriff
thought I stole it
before I killed it.
He was going
to hang me...
But a big fire almost
burned the jail down,
and I escaped.
Maria Garza hid me
until I could go back
to the mountains.
Well, if she's so kind,
how come her son
turned out bad ?
I don't know !
Nobody knows.
It'd be a curse,
wouldn't it ?
Have a child
go bad on ya ?
How about you ?
How are your children ?
They were
good children.
Comanche killed
all of them.
I came back
to the Brazos
to be near...
Their spirits,
and the spirit of
their grandfather.
But I didn't
find his spirit.
What about your children ?
Did you find their spirits ?
Nah, they were
too young.
Their spirits
were too light.
They had blown away
to another part
of the world.
[ man, Irish accent ]
I seen Ben Lily yesterday.
[ man #2 ]
Ben Lily ?
He still around ?
Of course he's still around.
He sold me an antelope haunch.
He sold ya an antelope haunch ?
Why didn't ya cook it ?
I don't cook.
Beulah cooks, but she ain't
been around lately.
Must cost you a bunch
with the young killer here.
Been in town two days,
and he's already corralled
half the whores.
No, he's corralled
all the whores.
[ door bangs ]
Hardin, it's gonna
cost me 50 cents to bury
that helper of mine.
Now, you shot him,
The least you can do
is chip in the 50 cents.
Why waste money
buryin' a nigra ?
We all got to be buried.
Hardin, that boy cost me $50.
That $50 for the boy,
50 cents for the grave.
That's $50.50 you owe me.
Don't stand there
talkin' nonsense
to me...
While I'm workin' hard
at gettin' drunk.
Just drag him in.
I'll find a sand hill.
Big pig'll eat him,
and save you 50 cents.
- I want my money.
- [ sighs ]
Anyway, you're a fool
if you paid money
for a nigra.
It ain't even legal
to buy one anymore.
Abe Lincoln
seen to that.
[ laughing ]
You owe me !
Now, you give it over,
you give it over now.
You son of a bitch,
I heard you.
Now, if you want
to live, get gone.
If you'd rather die,
flip that damn hammer
one more time.
[ cawing ]
I doubt you're the killer
you claim to be, Hardin.
- I don't claim nothin'.
- I'd like to smash
your ugly face,
But I guess I'll leave
that pleasure to captain call.
Woodrow call ?
Woodrow call's
comin' to Crowtown.
[ laughing ]
that's bold, for
an old turd his age.
Yeah, he's comin',
but he ain't comin' for you.
You're not important enough
anymore, Hardin.
You're just an old killer
waitin' to die.
Well, why is he comin' ?
He expect to clean out
the town ?
[ laughing ]
no.
He's comin'
for the guero here.
for this Joey.
Now come on, Hardin,
give me the money !
Ain't got no reason to give you
a free helper to kill.
I hate idiots like you.
[ Hardin ]
now, wait a minute.
Don't die on me.
When's captain call
due to show up ?
Soon, I reckon.
[ coughs ]
Now don't sit there.
Go outside and die.
Nobody wants you dyin' in here.
This is a proper saloon.
Lordy, it hurts !
[ gasping ]
I expect so.
[ laughs ]
That's what a .44
slug's meant to do.
[ laughs ]
[ coughs, chokes ]
[ weak breathing ]
[ bartender ]
he's dead.
[ birds cawing,
horse clopping ]
You drag him
out of here, boy.
Did you hear me, pup ?
Drag this man out of here.
[ scoffs ]
what the hell ?  Is everybody
stubborn in this town ?
Why would they send call
after a pup like you ?
They didn't
send him after me
because of the killings.
They sent him after me
because...
Gringos don't like
losing money.
[ laughs ]
That's right.
It's the money,
not the murders.
It don't cost them
damn pigs one cent...
For us to kill
one another off
out here in the baldies.
Why would they care ?
Out here on the Pecos,
It's fine for us
to steal from one another.
We better not rob
no trains from the east,
Where them damn Yankees
keep their money.
How much did
you get, guero ?
I heard
it was a million.
I heard it was
the army's money.
Bein' a little closemouthed
today, are ya ?
You'd do better to talk
to yourself, Wes.
My ears get tired just
listenin' to ya cuss.
It doesn't take any--
be glad you can hear me, pat.
It means I ain't shot ya yet.
You remind me of myself,
When I was younger and...
Better lookin'.
I'll give ya a little
free advice, killer.
You said it yourself.  Stealin'
is a more dangerous habit
in these parts than killin'.
But if you have a tendency
to steal, you best stay
clear of judge Roy bean.
He can't abide a thief.
If he catches ya with
money in your pockets,
He'll hang ya promptly
and keep the money.
No.
He won't hang me.
But I might hang him.
For sport.
Por nada.
[ Hardin chuckles ]
[ all laughing ]
That's original.
That would make
the papers.
Call, he might get
fired over that one.
[ bartender chuckles ]
[ sighs ]
no, my advice
is to...
Let Roy go and...
Kill famous shoes.
You heard of him,
ain't ya ?
Why should I kill
that old man ?
Because famous shoes
is on his way south
to track for call.
If you don't shoot
him first, he's gonna
lead call right to ya.
Famous shoes don't miss.
Bueno, viejo,
Neither do I.
[ door slams ]
[ call ]  we best go straight
to the telegraph office,
Mr. Brookshire.
I expect
there'll be news.
I hope so.
I'd like to know who
the second robber is,
if there is two.
I'd like to know that myself.
You can be sure there's two.
I'm hopin' they don't
keep multiplyin'.
[ speaking Spanish ]
Now, Mr. Brookshire.
Your color ain't good.
If I was your doctor,
I'd recommend you stay away
from telegraph offices.
Every time you go in one,
you come out lookin' ill.
Yes, and for good reason.
Here's four telegrams,
and not a word of good news
in any of them.
Well, what's the worst ?
Well, the worst is...
My wife died.
[ sobbing ]
Katie died !
I never expected it.
She was healthy as a horse
when I left Brooklyn.
I never expected it, captain.
[ call ]  well, that is
bad news, Mr. Brookshire.
I'm sorry to hear it.
I wish now I'd sent
you home the day
I left the panhandle.
[ sobs, sniffs ]
oh !
It's too late now.
She's gone.
[ chattering in Spanish ]
Mary !  Mary.
[ speaking Spanish ]
can't you knock ?
This is my house.
I ain't got time
for niceties, Mary.
Call, he's headin'
this way.
He can come.
He will not find
my son.
He will
if he sniffs around.
Picks up his scent.
Joey's in Crowtown,
and Crowtown ain't but
two days from here.
How do you know this news ?
I know it 'cause
I frequent saloons.
If there's news,
it passes through
the saloons.
A vaquero
spotted call.
He's with two men.
Billy ?
Hmm ?
I want you to stay
with my children.
Take good care of them.
Well, you know
I'd take good care
of them, Mary.
Where you gonna be ?
I'm going to Crowtown,
to warn my son.
You-- Crowtown ?
[ scoffs ]
How long you think
you're gonna last
in a place that rough ?
I don't plan
to move there.
[ rattling ]
I can last long enough
to warn Joey.
Mary, let me go.
No !
I have more
than one reason
for wanting to go.
Mm ?
I do not want to be here
when call comes.
He killed my father,
remember ?
He killed my brothers.
If I see him,
I might kill him myself.
Then my children,
they will be lost.
Ah, this youngster
is bad.
What now, captain ?
He killed six railroad men
just east of the Pecos,
Left 700 sheep on the train
to die of thirst.
Good God.
Here's a telegram
from Charlie goodnight:
"mox mox is alive.
He is your man burner.
"your deputy is on his way.
Famous shoes tracking for him.
You may recall mox mox
burned one of my men.
Available if needed."
Well, we know who
the second bandit is,
at least.  Mox mox.
He burnt one
of goodnight's cowboys, and
who knows how many other folks.
[ clicks tongue ]
well, Mr. Brookshire,
There are
two killers out there,
just like I suspected.
- Which one do we
go after first ?
- Joey Garza.
He's the one
I been hired to stop.
Well, what about
this man burner ?
Uhh, last news was
he was in new Mexico.
New Mexico has law of a sort.
Let them handle it.
[ laughs, sobs ]
well, that will please
the colonel.
And your colonel is a man
who expects results.
Despite the bad news,
can you travel ?
I can travel.
In fact, I think
I'd rather travel.
Then let's go.
We can reach the Rio Cacho
by tonight, if we push.
Rio Cacho'll take us
right to the boy's village.
If we're lucky,
the boy might be at home.
Maybe we can catch him there.
[ chattering in Spanish ]
%% [ organ ]
- Ma ?
- No.
No, what ?
I ain't said nothin'.
No, you can't have a gun.
That's all you been
askin' for lately.
Ma, I didn't
ask for nothin'.
I just came to tell you
there's an old man
at the door.
A tramp, or a cowboy,
or what ?
I don't know, just
an old man.  I think
it's Mr. Goodnight.
Mr. Goodnight ?
Are you sure ?
He's old.
He's got a moustache.
I think it's him.
Mama !
It's Mr. Goodnight.
Okay, ask him to wait
a minute.  I'm coming.
[ crying ]
But ma, he's already waiting.
Don't scold me, Claire. I've
been scolded enough already.
Ma, Georgie’s been askin'
Mr. Goodnight for a horse.
Well, I need a horse !
Hush, hush, hush.
I hope my boy hasn't been
pesterin' you too much.
No, I like him.
He's got spunk.
If I ain't
careful, he'll have
all the horses.
[ chuckles ]
would you come in ?
I can offer you some buttermilk.
I hesitate to bother you,
but I'll take the buttermilk.
Ben,
[ door creaks ]
[ gasps ]
Mr. Goodnight.  I'm sorry
I sent you out in this wind.
Ma, now Ben's been askin'
Mr. Goodnight for a horse too.
Charlie's been askin' for one,
and I need one too--
- Where y'all are going,
there'll be plenty of horses.
- Wh-where are we goin', mom ?
August, you boys
go out to the barn
and finish your chores.
Claire, it's time
for the baby's nap.
Mr. Goodnight ?
Won't you come back inside ?
I'll put on a pot of coffee.
[ baby fussing ]
[ door slams ]
If I had known mox mox
was alive, I wouldn't
be livin' nowhere near here.
[ sighs ]
he said he'd find me.
And if I had children,
he'd...
Burn 'em, just like
he burnt that little boy.
It was the last thing he said
before he left bodunk.
I thought all
the mean wolves in this country
was about cleaned out.
But he's as mean
as any I ever knew.
I'm sendin' my children
to Nebraska.
Claire'll look after them
till this is over.
Now, my husband's out there
somewhere huntin' a killer,
and it's my fault.
He ain't a killer,
Mr. Goodnight.
And he's got
no business huntin' killers
with captain call.
I better go find
the man myself.
This time
I'll keep at it
till I know it's done.
Let captain call
do it !
[ sighs ]
I've got no right
to give you orders,
But you came here
to ask me
what I know,
So I'm gonna
tell ya.
I've seen that man,
and you haven't.
Let captain call do it.
It's my cowboy he's burned,
not the captain call's.
I-I expect you think
I'm too old to subdue the man.
That ain't it.
You have killed to survive,
but you ain't a killer.
Captain call
is a killer.
Send a killer
to catch a killer,
I say.
[ cabinet slams ]
Mr. Goodnight,
I've got to start packin'.
I'm gonna start
for Amarillo tonight.
I want my children
out of here.
I can stop the train
at Quanah, and I can send...
A couple cowboys with a wagon
to take you to the railroad.
I'd be much obliged.
Can you lend me
a weapon ?
All my husband left
me was a shotgun.
I can lend you several guns,
but I doubt you'll need 'em...
Once you're
on a train to Nebraska.
I'm not goin' to Nebraska,
Mr. Goodnight.
Just my children
are goin' north.
You're not goin' ?
No.
Ma'am.
You're the one
he nearly burnt.
Now, you have
every right to be scared.
Why wouldn't you go ?
Because I gotta
find my husband
and bring him back.
I should have set
my heels and kept him
here, but I didn't.
It's my place
to bring him home.
Now that's rash.
I can send an experienced man
to go find your husband,
and bring him home.
None of your cowboys
married him.
I married him.
He's a good man,
and I need him.
Besides, he won't mind
nobody but me.
'cept captain call.
[ sighs ]
I'm gonna find him,
and he's gonna mind me.
Particularly now.
Take good care
of your brother.
Si, mama.
Take good care
of Billy too.
If he gets drunk
and falls asleep
outside,
Cover him so
he wouldn't freeze.
[ Spanish ]
I will take care of him too.
Adios.
Mm.
Vaya con dios.
Now, you're on the wrong side
of the Pecos River, you know ?
You're gonna have
to cross it.
And cold as it is,
You're going to have
to build a fire
and thaw yourself out...
Soon as you get across.
Billy.
I have crossed rivers before,
and I know the kind of risk
I'm gonna face.
Well, Mary, can
I ask you somethin' ?
If you hurry.
I cannot be here talking to you
and ever get to Crowtown.
Well, uh, I like keepin'
track of your husbands.
It's kind of
a hobby of mine.
[ chuckles ]
And I ain't seen
that Senor Sanchez lately.
Now, why did he run off ?
I-if I ain't pryin'.
You are prying.
Well, my feet hurt.
Tell me anyway.
Senor Sanchez left me
because he did not like me.
Well, he married you,
why wouldn't he like ya ?
He liked the way I looked.
He mistook that for me.
When he find out
who I am, he left.
Oh, well, I sympathize
with the man.
I've often made that
same mistake myself.
[ laughs ]
And I guess
I'd make it again,
if I could see better.
[ horse whinnies ]
liste-listen,
uh, Mary.
Um... Since you ain't
got a husband,
Well, h-how about me ?
Billy, are you keeping me here,
when I have so far to go...
In this cold wind,
just to propose ?
Well, that's--
that's about
the gist of it.
I will not marry you.
But I'm happy
you're my good friend.
And I'm glad
you take good care
of my children.
Right.  Okay.
Okay ?
All right.
Mm.
You take care
of yourself.
Adios, hombre.
Teresa ?  Rafael ?
[ children, indistinct ]
I been tryin'
to tell you, we are here
to meet captain call.
We're both deputies,
we've been hired to help him
catch Joey Garza !
You heard of him ?
I don't give a tinker's damn
who you're here to meet.
That old Indian's
a horse thief.
He escaped me once.
He will not do it again.
Now, look, his name
is "famous shoes"
'cause he walks everywhere.
He wouldn't steal a horse
because he ain't got
no use for a horse.
Only use he'd have
for a horse is to eat one.
Stealin' horses to eat
is still stealin' horses.
Well, I never stole
a horse in my whole life.
What'd you arrest me for ?
Because you were
with a horse thief.
You just might be
a horse thief yourself.
- I am not a horse thief !
- When I hang the old kickapoo,
you can go.
Look, you've had us here
all day long.
And he has not had
a thing to eat.
Now, why are
you starvin' him ?
All he did was
eat a dead horse,
and that was years ago.
He evaded the law.
My law.
He deserves worse than
starvin', and he's gonna get
worse than starvin', too.
Besides, why waste food
on an old kickapoo...
Who's good
as hung anyway ?
Claire, August, take
care of the little ones.
[ baby crying ]
Now, get on inside.
Hurry up.
[ crying continues ]
[ no audible speech ]
[ crows squawking ]
[ squawking continues ]
Senora Maria Garza.
Is Joey here ?
He's here,
but he ain't awake.
Wake him.
Tell him his mother
is here.
You can come in,
but I ain't gonna
wake him up.
He don't like it
when people wake him up.
Joey.
[ speaking Spanish ]
wake up.  Wake up !
You must leave here.
Mama ?
[ grunts ]
Would you wash my clothes ?
These girls, they don't know
how to do it.
We don't have time
to do the laundry.
Captain call is coming.
I want you to do my laundry.
He will kill you, Joey.
He killed your grandfather
and your uncles.
I do not a-want a-him
to kill you.
This is my room.
I don't like women in here.
[ speaking Spanish ]
Do not talk to me like that.
I'm your mother.
Get up !
Get up and leave !
They have sent
the great killer
after you.
Get out of here
quickly,
Or you're dead !
You leave.
You are a stupid woman.
You've ridden all this way
to tell me what I already know.
I know about captain call !
I'm not running
from an old gringo.
Then you're dead,
if you think that way.
I'll go home and tell
your brother and your sister
that you are dead.
You'll be lying.
I will not die.
Call will die...
Even before he knows
his death is coming.
Is there anyone
who can make him leave ?
Shh.
John Wesley Hardin, maybe.
John Wesley's killed
over 50 men.
I think Joey likes him.
'course, John Wesley's crazy.
He's apt to kill anybody
when he's in a mood.
Where is this man ?
He's in a saloon.
He never sleeps.
You'll be takin' more
than your life in your hand
if you go in that saloon.
There's rough men in this town.
In fact, there's none
that ain't rough.
[ scoffs ]
they'll not be the first
rough men I ever seen.
[ grunting ]
[ yelling in Spanish ]
[ gunshot ]
[ woman ]
what's going on ?
You kill that pig ?
What kind of a wild slut
are you ?
Senora Maria Garza,
Joey's mother.
And if you are his friend,
I wish you would tell him
to leave.
Captain call's coming.
I don't know where he is,
but he's close.
How close ?
[ speaking Spanish ]
I don't know.
His deputy is over
by the Pecos.
Famous shoes is taking him
to meet the captain.
I knew it.
The last thing I told your boy
was to shoot that old Indian.
She just killed the pig.
We have hundreds of people
come here, try to take shots
at that pig.
You walk into town one day
and kill it dead.
This woman's a witch.
¿ hombre, que paso ?
What's wrong with your foot ?
I stomped it.
[ chuckling ]
Son of a bitch
is a card cheat.
It's too cold to stand around
worrying about a dead pig.
Let's go inside.
What's the news,
other than Woodrow call's
coming to Crowtown ?
The snake who did not
seize a-life.
Mox mox ?
That little squint
don't bother me.
Now there's a bed
over there in that corner.
You crawl in there with me,
and these others,
they can wait their turn.
[ chuckling ]
you're a fine one.
Your son's got
all the whores.
You come into town,
kill our pig.
And now you won't even
crawl into bed with me
after I ask you polite.
You watch it.
I don't like being
in small rooms with whores
who shoot pistols.
Maybe the killer instinct
runs in the family, Wes.
I came here to find out
if you would help my son.
[ exhales ]
no, thanks.
I live for myself.
Captain call
will kill him.
And for all you know,
he might kill you too.
That ain't likely.
He ain't gettin' paid from me.
He's gettin' paid for your boy.
Call's economical.
He don't kill anybody
who just needs killin'.
Him and famous shoes,
they make a good pair.
Famous shoes only tracks
when he's paid.
Call kills for the same reason.
Hell, all right, a dollar then.
Red can pay ya.
He owes me money.
He can have seconds,
and you'll be two dollars richer
before breakfast.
[ yelling in Spanish ]
What did she say ?
A dollar and a quarter then !
She's a lively one.
Got some spirit.
[ people chattering ]
[ man ]   damn.
[ woman ]
she's so mean.
She's crazy.
She's running now.
[ crying ]
[ panting ]
Where is he ?
He's gone.
Where's my horse ?
He took it.
Maybe he thought it needed
a fresh mount.
He'll need more than a horse
when I find him.
[ door slams ]
Whoa.  Whoa.
This sleepin' in the saddle
won't do, men.
We're headin' into
Joey Garza’s territory.
Up to now,
there's been no danger.
That changes now.
[ horse whinnies ]
You think
the Garza boy knows
we're coming, captain ?
I expect he does.
Well, let's ride.
If we're lucky,
we'll catch that boy
while he's home.
This all could be over
in three or four days.
[ chattering ]
Hi, bob.  Is there
any news about Ted ?
Wasn't any news
yesterday,
And there ain't
no news today.
I know I'm a pest, sheriff,
but it's just, I've never been
without Ted before.
With the baby comin' and all,
I'm just a little worried.
You know, I'm gettin' real tired
of you comin' to my jail
askin' about Ted.
Ted ain't got the brains
it takes to cross the street.
That ain't fair, sheriff.
My husband is just as smart
as the next fella.
You know,
You keep comin' here...
Bob.
And you keep comin' here.
Bob !
Stop it.  Bob.
Don't.
You're hurting me, bob.
[ screams ]
Shut up.
Bob, please,
don't hurt me.
No !
My turn.
[ wind gusting ]
[ sniffling ]
[ hoofbeats clattering ]
Oh, Teddy.
[ sniffling ]
I just went there
lookin' for news.
I never meant
to disgrace you.
[ crying ]
[ horses whinnying,
hoofbeats clattering ]
[ squawking ]
I hate these crows.
They bring bad luck.
[ neighing ]
Ain't you
John Wesley Hardin ?
Mind your own business,
you cross-eyed runt.
You're too big
to be inside.
You go outside and drink,
or else sit down.
You're blockin' my light.
Ain't no chair for me.
Then sit on the floor,
you damn kraut barrel.
Be friendly, Hardin.
I got six men here.
We aim to kill
the Garza boy.
[ laughter ]
six ain't enough.
Well, countin' me,
it's seven.
Well, you gotta subtract
the Mexicans 'cause they
undoubtedly can't shoot.
Then you gotta subtract
this sack of sausage
who's blockin' my light.
The reason you gotta
subtract him is because...
I'm about to kill him
if he don't sit down !
- Sit down, Garth.
Don't you hear Mr. Hardin ?
- Ain't no chair.
Goin' outside
would be even better.
Then I wouldn't have to look
at 300 pounds of stupidity
while I'm tryin' to concentrate.
[ chuckling ]
I'm out.
I'll play,
if you're short for a game.
I guess you would,
you damn Cherokee.
Or are you Choctaw ?
Is the Garza boy here ?
He took three payrolls.
Should've been ours if he left
them damn trains alone.
I mean to see
that he don't get the fourth.
The boy ain't here.
Neither is his mother.
Now why would I care
about his mother ?
You oughta care.
She can whip
the whole bunch of you.
[ laughter ]
you are one rude
son of a bitch.
This ace don't belong
in this deck.  It's got
six or seven already.
I got a mind
to kill you, Hardin.
Well, I doubt if I'll be killed
by a squint like you.
- [ laughter ]
- or Choctaw boy.
Or an ignorant amble
of a German
you brought in here.
Give me one, two.
You know, if you got a mind
for killin',
Maybe you oughta get
old Woodrow call
while you're gettin'.
Woodrow call ?
Yeah.
The railroad sent him
after Joey Garza.
That was like
whackin' an ox.
I hope
my weapon's intact.
You got no idea
how mean I am,
You son of a bitch.
I'm gonna kill
that young Mexican,
Then I'm gonna kill
old call.
He never caught blue duck,
and he ain't ever gonna
catch me.
Did you know that we're
in the newspapers, Hardin ?
They say we're the worst gang
to ever hit the west.
I rarely bother with folks
who read the papers.
Personally, I wouldn't give
a nickel's worth of horse meat
for the whole bunch of ya.
[ laughing ]
Now if you boys
wanna sit in here and drink,
do it quietly.
I don't wanna risk damage to
my weapon by having to whack you
like I whacked that lunkhead.
Well, I guess
if we're not wanted,
We'll depart.
Sorry you came with me,
Mr. Brookshire ?
No, I'm not sorry.
Katie's gone now.
Might as well be here.
- How 'bout you, deputy ?
- I'm with ya, captain.
[ woman speaking Spanish ]
Billy Williams.
Hello, Billy.
That is you, ain't it ?
Woodrow, where you been ?
We've been expecting you
for about a week now.
Why would you be
expectin' me ?
Everybody knows
you're huntin' Joey Garza.
It's the talk
of the whole west.
I wish the whole west would
keep their mouths shut then.
You know this wild boy,
Billy ?
I know him.
These your children,
Billy ?
They ain't.
No.
That's a pretty child.
She's Joey's sister.
She's blind, ain't she ?
Yeah.
Blind from birth.
This, uh-- this house--
this is the house that--
Yeah.  Yeah, you hung
Maria's father and her brothers,
And you brought 'em
to this house.
If you're here
with these children,
I expect
their mother's gone off
to warn their brother.
I 'spect.
Guess we'll be goin' then,
since the news is spread.
Don't forget
to take your man.
What man ?
Your man, pea.
Your corporal.
Pea's here.  Goodnight
informed me he was coming,
but he didn't say--
He's over
at sheriff Jonathan's jail
across the River at presidio.
Famous shoes is with him.
What are they doin' in jail ?
Some years back,
sheriff caught that old
kickapoo eatin' a dead horse.
Besides, it was stolen.
Sheriff ain't forgot.
Why was pea arrested ?
Consortin' with a horse eater,
I guess.
[ chuckling ]
That you're here watchin'
after his brother and sister,
You must be a friend
of this Joey's then ?
If Joey has friends,
I ain't met 'em.
When he was a youngster
he was likable enough,
But once he come back
from the apaches,
he wasn't likable no more.
He ain't been likable
since either.
Boy part Indian ?
Nah.  One of Maria's husbands
didn't like having brats
under foot,
So one day he just took off
and sold Joey to the apaches.
Maria was gone at the time.
She was off helpin' her ma
on her deathbed.
He was with the Indians
three years.
I tried to buy him back
a couple of times myself,
But they wouldn't trade
with me.
He was about 12
when he escaped.
He outran them apaches.
They couldn't track him
neither.
Explains why
he's hard to track.
She's a pretty little girl.
I'll say that.
Who is that man, Billy ?
His name is call, honey.
Woodrow call.
He said I was pretty.
Well, he's right.
You are pretty.
Real pretty.
Just like your ma.
Is he a king, Billy ?
Well...
A king of sorts.
I guess you could say that.
I think he must be a king.
Sheriff ?
I think we got trouble.
There's a man coming.
I think it's old call.
I never seen the man,
but I think it's him.
Why would that mean trouble ?
He's a lawman.  I'm a lawman.
He's kind of got
that stiff look.
Ever since you got
your ear shot off,
you're imagining things.
Captain.
Let these men out.
You have no authority
to arrest them.
They were sent here
to help me bring in Joey Garza.
You ought not
to have interfered with them.
I reckon I know
who to arrest.
That Indian's gonna be hung.
He's a known horse thief.
I'm sure you hung a good many
just like him yourself.
Famous shoes never
been known to ride a horse,
much less steal one.
Pea eye Parker's
been my deputy for 30 years.
He's never been a lawbreaker.
He came to town
with a criminal,
And that's breakin'
the law for me, by God.
Here.  I heard
you were stubborn.
So I got a telegram
from the governor of Texas.
Mr. Brookshire's boss,
president of the railroad
that hired me.
He sent the wire
to the governor his self.
Now, I done this
to save time.
We're provisioned.
We're ready to ride.
Sheriff, it is
from the governor.
- Wanna read it ?
- No, I don't, by God.
When I wad something up,
I want it to stay wadded up.
Damn the governor
and damn you.
You don't just walk in here
and order me to let criminals
out of my own jail.
They ain't criminals,
and you've overstepped.
Your man can go...
The day I hang the old Indian,
And I'll hang the old Indian
in my own good time.
They're dead men,
they step out of them cells.
I will not tolerate escape.
You son of a bitch !
[ grunts ]
Captain, he's subdued.
Stop it.
Get off me.
By God--
[ grunting ]
Help me !  Help me !
Somebody help !
Get a rope !
Get a rope.
Get a hold on him.
Somebody get a rope.
Get me a rope.
- Get me a rope.
- Come on.  Get it on him.
[ pea eye ]
get that rope on him !
Let go of the saddle.
Pull.  Pull.
All right, all right,
all right, all right.
All right.  Stop !
Stop.
That's enough.
[ dog barking ]
It's over.
It's all right, pea.
It's all right.
When he comes around,
you tell him...
That if he ever points
a damn pistol at me,
he had better shoot.
I won't tolerate
rude behavior.
Yes, sir.
Remind him I was following
the governor's instructions.
Read him that damn telegram.
We need an experienced tracker
to help us locate the Garza boy.
Are you available ?
- Yeah.
- Hired then.
Don't stand there like targets
lined up in a shooting gallery.
Let's go.
You know, when I first met
captain call,
I wasn't sure he oughta
been hired to take on
an assignment like this.
Why's that ?
Well, he seemed old
and kinda stiff.
Well, after seein' what he did
to that sheriff,
I'm bound to say colonel Terry
clearly chose the right man
for the job.
[ train whistle blowing ]
[ people chattering ]
%% [ singing ]
%% when they ring
the golden bells for you %%
%% [ continues ]
%% don't you hear
the angels singin' %%
%% is the glory hallelujah
jubilee %%
%% [ continues ]
%% just beyond
the shiny weather %%
%% when they ring
the golden bells %%
%% for you and me %%
%% [ continues ]
Lori, could that
really be you ?
Lori, it's me,
Tinkersley.
It is you, ain't it ?
Tell me it's you.
I'm married now, Tinkersley.
I'm here lookin'
for my husband.
He's with captain call.
Whose funeral ?
Doobie Plunkert.
She was well-liked
in the town.
I liked her myself,
even though I only
met her once.
That's why I lent my whores
to sing at her funeral.
I kept two back
for business.
They got scratchy voices
anyway.
So you're still
runnin' whores, huh ?
Yeah, mostly.
I'm surprised
they let whores
sing at a funeral.
Was she a whore ?
No, no.
She was married
to the deputy sheriff.
Only about 16.
He went off
with old call, too,
just like your husband.
Yeah, it's a filthy shame.
Sheriff Jekyll raped Doobie.
Did he kill her ?
No.
She was pregnant.
She felt so bad
about the matter...
That she took rat poison
and died.
She must've felt hopeless.
Lori, you didn't know her.
You ain't expected to attend
the funeral.
I know hopeless though.
I'd rather you didn't
accompany me.
You didn't even know
the woman.
Get away from me,
Tinkersley.
You done nothin' but hurt me
when we was together.
I don't want you
to be walkin' with me.
I'm here to find my husband.
Oh, but I bought you
pretty dresses.
Yeah, so you could sell me
at a higher price.
Get away from me.
I don't like rememberin'
nothin' about that.
Lori, look.
I just thought we could
visit a little bit.
I never thought
I'd see you again.
I'd come down there
to lonesome dove
lookin' for you,
And you'd already gone north
with old McCrae--
he wasn't that old.
You can bet
old Donovan deserved it.
[ laughing ]
Is that dogs ?
Dogs.
Who'd be runnin' hounds
in a country like this ?
That lion-killin' man.
Those are his dogs.
He has nine of them.
That's Ben Lily.
Forget that old man's
still alive.
Prefers bear,
but he can't find bear.
He'll kill lions.
[ gunfire ]
Those dogs were chasin'
a mule deer.
Doesn't take that many shots
to kill a mule deer.
I'll go see.
All right, let's--
let's keep close guard
tonight, huh ?
I heard six, seven guns.
It's night.
Who'd be hunting at night ?
Oh, probably some vaqueros
on their way home.
Old Ben Lily,
he's cranky.
We might've
made him mad.
[ animal screeching ]
- What's that ?
- Be quiet.
I've heard a lot of sounds,
captain, but I ain't ever
heard no sound like that.
You don't suppose
that could be an eagle.
I've heard that eagles scream.
'course, I never heard one.
I wish it would get light.
[ screeching continues ]
Mr. Lily ?
He burnt my best dog,
captain.
Killed all nine of my hounds
and burned old flop alive.
Mr. Lily, you're lucky
he didn't burn you.
I'd suggest you follow along
with us for a day or two.
[ grunts ]
I'm goin' to Santa Fe.
Gonna get me some new dogs.
[ captain call ]
we're goin' to judge Roy bean's.
He usually has a few dogs.
I don't know.
Don't like judge bean.
His dogs nothin' but hounds.
That killer done killed my dogs.
I got to get to Santa Fe.
You be careful then.
[ mumbling ]
My dogs.
Old flop is gone.
Do you reckon
he's loco, captain ?
Old Ben Lily's
always been loco.
Damn few left like him.
Killer done
killed my dogs.
[ sighs ]
like him how,
captain ?
Oh, like him,
like Gus, like Hickok,
Old kit Carson.
They done what they wanted.
They went where they wanted.
Wasn't always good,
but at least they lived
free lives.
You're a farmer yourself,
corporal.
Respectable.
Charlie goodnight's
got his ranch.
Ah, just the killers
and a few like old Ben Lily...
That kept to the old ways.
Well, and you, captain.
What ?
You kept
to the old ways.
[ Maria yelling ]
That's it.
I will kill him today.
He'll be with the fishes.
I go see them again tomorrow.
Mama, you've come back.
Mary, where you been
so long ?
Mama, there was a man here.
I think he was a king.
He said I was pretty.
Where'd this king
come from ?
What a-was his name ?
Call came through, Mary.
Down in Cacho.
Came through
and went where ?
To Maravilla canyon, I think.
He done you one favor
before he left though.
He ruined that sheriff Donovan.
Beat him nearly to death
with a rifle.
As soon enough as that sheriff
was strong enough to hold a gun,
Son of a bitch shot himself.
[ chuckling ]
Did famous shoes bring him ?
What did you tell him
about Joey ?
Famous shoes didn't bring him,
and I didn't tell him nothin'.
Hell, there wasn't
nothin' to tell.
Rafael.
[ goat bleating ]
If this king ever come back,
you come to the house.
Do not let him look at you.
He's a bad man.
He wants to kill Joey.
Do not ever let him
look at you.
Do you understand ?
Yeah.
But he didn't do
anything bad.
He said I was pretty.
He was right.
You are pretty.
[ horse whinnying ]
This Indian
owes me a nickel.
He's on your payroll.
Cough it up.
I didn't know
you served drinks
for a nickel.
Liquor ain't
that cheap.
He come up lame.
I rubbed some lotion
on his foot.
Lotion kills all ills,
except for a weak pecker.
Let me have a nickel,
Mr. Brookshire.
Put it in your ledger.
I'm sure your colonel
will approve.
You expect a war party ?
You seem to be
thoroughly armed.
I expect perdition.
Always have.
Perdition can come
in the form of a bullet.
That's why I'm ready.
I wanna be prepared
to shoot back.
Well, we've had a norther
at our back.
If this is still a saloon,
we'd like whiskey.
I expect perdition will come
in the form of a disease.
I'm susceptible
to diseases.
Can't shoot a damn disease.
[ snoring ]
hope you catch the Garza boy
next week.
This week wouldn't be
too soon neither.
I'll catch him, but I doubt
it'll be this week.
Depends on when famous shoes
picks up his track.
There are very few
competent marksmen
in this part of the country.
And that boy--
that's my chair.
The Garza boy
is a competent marksman.
He's affected my profits.
Shootin' people
who might be comin' here
to drink.
Besides, I'm not as tranquil
with myself as I'd like to be.
Used to, I could sit out there
in that chair and concentrate
on business matters.
So now I got to worry...
That somebody on a hill
a mile away is gonna plug me
while I'm concentratin'.
No hill
within a mile of here.
And a half mile
is more likely a distance
for a rifle shot anyway.
I've never seen a rifle
that could shoot accurate
more than a half mile.
You're not a competent
marksman neither,
And you don't know everything.
Charlie goodnight thinks
he knows everything.
So do you !
I've never known you
to worry about killers
before, judge.
There's a lot safer
places to live
along this border...
If you're the sort
to let killers
disturb your naps.
I weathered many a killer,
But I resent
a Mexican boy with a rifle
that'll shoot that far.
Oh, that boy ain't
the only reason you ought
to start nappin' indoors.
Ain't you heard of mox mox ?
Who'd the lunatic
singe now ?
Ben Lily's best dog.
Not flop.
Why would the son of a bitch
want to burn a dog ?
Why would he want
to burn a person ?
'cause he likes to,
that's why.
I'll serve your deputy again
when he wakes up.
[ horse whinnies ]
I hate to do it,
but I'm gonna split off.
Why's that, captain ?
Well, we got two different
threats to deal with now.
We got mox mox
and the young killer.
Mox mox ain't too far.
I think I can catch him
if I go alone, travel fast.
Well, it's gonna upset
Mr. Brookshire.
Yeah, I expect so.
He's a grown man.
He knows how to make a fire.
Where do you want us to go ?
You go back to Orinaga,
where we were.
Joey Garza will have to
show up at home sometime.
Don't you challenge him
without me.
You camp on the Cacho,
oh, about a half a day
from the village.
But you ought to take
one of us with you
to help the odds.
I appreciate your concern,
But we ain't got
much choice.
Deputy Plunkert
and Mr. Brookshire,
they oughtn't be sent off alone.
They're too green.
Joey Garza shows up,
They'd stand no Chance.
I might not stand
much of one either, captain.
I expect you
to hold your own, corporal.
Well,
Good luck to you then.
Good luck to you.
Keep those men close.
You set a decent guard
at night.
What's wrong, corporal ?
You shouldn't have
no hard trip.
Just across the River,
follow it to the Cacho.
Wait a few days.
Doubt if I'll be very long.
I ain't worried about us.
I reckon we'd stay
pointed south.
River's right there.
Can't lose it
unless we go blind.
What is it then ?
Well, it's you, captain.
That mox mox has got six men
with him.
One of them is
that quick Jimmy Cumsah.
He's a wily Cherokee.
Hard man to take.
If I was you,
I'd read my paper inside.
Don't neglect
any killers now.
See you there, men.
You oughtn't leave
that pistol cocked.  You know,
you might have a bad dream...
And jerk it,
shoot your knee off.
Might rain whores
out of the Sky, too,
but I doubt it.
[ gunshot ]
[ grunts ]
Shoot.
Shoot, damn it.
Rusty--
Rusty son of a bitch.
Are you plannin'
on hangin' me ?
Get away from my saloon,
you damn pup.
I'm the law west of Pecos,
in case you ain't heard.
I'm the one that does
the hangin' around here.
[ indistinct ]
Wild person.
That's what you are.
[ grunting, gagging ]
You son of a whore !
---continued---