Blackfeet.
Smoke.
Do you smell it, sir?
They certainly made
a thorough job of it.
Aye, they did that,
sir.
- You'll probably find shovels
in one of the wagons.
- Yes, sir.
What-
No! Don't touch me!
Go away!
Please! Please go away!
- We're not going to hurt you.
- Leave me alone!
- The Indians will come back and kill me too!
- There, lassie.
- Let me go!
- There, there.
You're perfectly safe now.
We won't let anyone harm you.
They'll come back!
I know they will!
They killed my grandfather.
He's over there under that wagon.
- Shh! Shh! Come on.
- No.
- Come on now. That's it.
- Please! Please!
Everything's going
to be all right.
There now, now.
Shh. Everything's
all right.
I'm afraid.
Now, listen, Sue.
You and I are going to have a little talk.
You know, there never was
anything to be afraid of...
that couldn't be cured
by one little word.
Do you know what
that word is?
" Courage.'' It can beat the toughest
situation that ever happened.
You see,
when you're afraid of things...
the more you think of'em,
the bigger they get.
But if you just throw
your head back and say...
" I won't be scared
of anything anymore,'' then you're not.
Aren't you ever afraid
of anything?
Well, uh,
let's put it this way:
When I meet up with something
I'm not quite sure of...
I decide first of all that everything's
going to come out all right.
Whatever it is,
I'm going to lick it.
And usually it does
come out all right.
- You know what does it?
- Courage?
Courage.
Now, let's forget everything
that made us unhappy.
Let's learn to smile again,
because we know everybody's...
gonna do all they can to help us,
so we'll help too.
- What do you say?
- I'll try, Mr. Monty.
That's the girl.
Now, back to sleep.
- Good night.
Easy.
Dismissed, Mac.
- Welcome home! Praise be you're safe and-
- Shh!
- What have you got there?
- Quiet. Quiet.
- Where in heaven's name did you get her?
- You'll hear about that later.
- Is the superintendent still up?
- He is.
- And if I told you the half of it-
- I can't escape it.
Give me a quick brush.
I want to report in.
Beggin' your pardon, sir.
You can't go in them clothes.
- I've your other uniform all laid out.
- Why should I change uniforms...
- at this time of night?
- The others, sir.
Every one of'em is dressed up like a widow
at a wake. If you knew who was there-
- I wouldn't dandy up tonight to meet Lily Langtry.
- But it's the O.C. 's daughter.
- Will you stop thatjabbering and brush me off?
- I'll do it!
- I'll do it. Please let me.
- Now look what you've done with your shouting.
You're the worst old fishwife
ever came out of County Kildare.
He's otherwise known as
Patrick O'Hannegan.
- This is Miss Susannah Sheldon.
-Just call me Sue.
Now, young lady, we'll have to arrange
sleeping quarters for you.
- Where will that be, sir?
- Your room.
- My-
- Do I sleep in with him?
No. Pat can sleep
out here on the couch.
But I wouldn't wanna take
Mr. Pat's room.
That's all right. He'll be very
comfortable out here, won't you?
- Oh, yes, sir. Very.
- Give this a lick.
Let's see.
What about sleeping things?
Use one of my nightshirts.
You might have to cut it down.
- Now, young lady, off to bed with you.
- Oh, wait.
There's a hair on your shoulder
the brush didn't get.
- Good night.
- Good night, Mr. Monty.
Come on.
I'll fix the bed for ya.
I'll help you.
dd
- Excuse me, sir.
- That's quite all right, Monty.
- Glad to see you're back.
- I didn't mean to intrude, sir.
- I've come to make my report.
- Come in, won't you?
I want you to meet my daughter.
She's come out from Toronto for a visit.
Well, I'm-
I'm hardly presentable, sir.
Perfectly all right.
Come along.
- Look who's here.
- Hello, Monty.
- Hello, fellas.
- Hi, old boy.
Vicky, this is
Inspector Montague.
- I'm very happy to know you, Mr. Montague.
- It's a pleasure, Miss Standing.
Won't you join us?
Perhaps you'd like a glass of sherry.
- Not a thing, thanks.
- You'll need something to fortify you.
- We'll probably have more singing.
- If I know Monty...
- he'll be right along with us.
- He's just the baritone we've been looking for.
- We really are having a little baritone trouble.
- I say, now,just a moment.
I'll be glad to
as soon as I make my report.
- That won't take long.
- Excuse me?
Certainly.
- Doctor, do you mind getting my hat for me?
- Certainly.
- You're not going?
- What's left for me?
- It's baritone or nothing.
- Good night, old boy.
It's nothing.
Pat, you old pirate, why didn't you
tell me to change uniforms?
- Why, she's a beauty!
- Tell you? I did tell you.
You didn't tell me anything of the kind.
Those are the things you should tell me.
But you said you wouldn't
dandy up for Lily Langtry.
Lily Langtry couldn't hold a candle
to her. Get off these boots...
- and get me a clean shirt.
- Yes, sir.
- Come on.
When did she get here?
You didn't even tell me she was young.
- Two days ago, sir.
- And I had to be away on patrol.
Why, she's beautiful.
She's as pretty as a picture.
What the-
Why aren't you in bed?
I'm helping, sir.
Here's your shirt.
00, and regulations
for enlisted men are lights-out at 10:00?
- Get.
- Yes, sir.
Good night.
Good night. Run along now.
Here, unbutton that shirt.
You let me go over there looking like
a hayseed to meet the most beaut-
Not that I care how I look,
but out of respect for her.
I'm sure she'll understand, sir.
You didn't even tell me she
had blue eyes. And deep blue eyes at that.!
- dd
- You know, Dad didn't think
I should come, even for a visit.
- But I'm here.
- You might find it a little rugged.
- You know, I've been wondering.
- What?
Well, whatever made a man like you
take a job like this?
There are times when it's rather humdrum.
But right now, you're here.
And I'm going to change things.
Inspector Montague, we're going
to give a dance on Wednesday night.
- A real one. Dress uniform and frills.
- A dance?
- Well, you do dance, don't you?
- Well, I- Oh, yes. Yes, of course, thank you.
Splendid. And being the only woman
in the vicinity, I'm bound to be popular.
Whoa!
- Hello, Chambers.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello, Inspector.
- What's the trouble? Anything wrong?
Indian raid. Four of my workmen wounded.
And they've stolen 20 head of horses.
If we hadn't caught them in time,
they'd have cleaned out the whole corral.
- Inspector, turn out 10 men.
- Yes, sir.
- Mr. Randall, you'll take out the patrol.
- Sir.
- Go to the construction camp
and track down the raiders.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll need your doctor too.
- Then come inside. We'll get him.
- Call the doctor.
- Harlan.!
Why, Vicky, what on earth
are you doing here?
- Came out for a visit.
- Well, why didn't you let me know
you were coming?
I didn't even let Dad
know I was coming, did I?
No. As a matter of fact,
she didn't. Oh, Doctor.
- Yes, sir.
- Go back to camp with Mr. Chambers.
- You're needed there.
- I'll get my kit, sir.
- Mr. Churchill, check the guard.
Prepare for any emergency.
- Yes, sir.
- You may be able to assist him, Mr. Williams?
- Good night, Miss Standing.
- Good night. Anything serious, Dad?
- Good night.
-Just a little Indian trouble at my camp.
- Nothing for you to worry about.
- It's hardly the best time...
for you to have come out here, but I can't
tell you how pleased I am to see you.
Don't tell me I leave you speechless, Harlan.
You always did. Superintendent,
why didn't you give me notice?
I'd have met her at Winnipeg
and brought her out here on a special.
You didn't give
the Canadian Pacific a chance.
We'll see what can be done
about that in the future.
- You bet we will.
- The patrol's ready, Mr. Chambers.
Thank you. I'll be back for a real visit as soon
we've settled with these horse thieves.
- Good night.
- Good night and good luck.
Thanks. We need it.
Thank you, Superintendent.
- Not at all. Good night.
- Good night.
Probably the same band that
attacked the wagon train, sir.
This will give the railroad people another
opportunity to clamor for government troops.
I hope not, sir.
We'll try a direct hit.
I wanna get Big Eagle in here for a talk.
It's only a three-hour ride
to his camp.
- If you like, I'll have him here in the morning.
- Good.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
dd
Good mornin'.
You're up mighty early.
- Mr. Monty hasn't come home yet, has he?
- He has not.
- Where did he go?
- On duty.
- Where else would he be goin'?
- When will he get back?
I not be knowin' that.
- What are you making?
- Never mind now. Never mind.
Curiosity killed
the cat, you know.
You shouldn't be sewing.
That's a woman's work.
Not in the army, darlin'.
That's where I learned it.
You men on the fort should have wives
to do things for you.
Wives, is it?
Heaven pity the poor girl
that'd marry a man in this outfit.
- Why?
- 'Tis a no-good lot of heartbreakers, they are.
- Are you a heartbreaker?
- Well, I've had me day.
Of course, I did have certain
disadvantages in the way of a face, but-
Hold your hush now.
Stop your questions
till I get this last button sewed on.
- Is Mr. Monty a heartbreaker too?
- Isn't he, though?
You oughta seen him at Regina
when he was there.
Who was he talking about last night
when he said she was so beautiful?
- And who'd be askin'?
- Oh, I was just wondering.
You know very well
who he was talking about.
But don't you bother.
She'll be goin' home soon.
We'll have Mr. Monty
all to ourselves.
There.
It's finished.
- And I hope it fits ya.
- Is it for me?
And who else would I
be sewin' for all this night?
And there's these
to go with it.
- I be makin' ya other things
when I get around to it.
- Oh!
Now I'm goin' to the mess hall
to get you some breakfast.
Thank you, Mr. Pat!
Thank you!
That's all right, darlin'.
That's all right.
What are those Indians
coming here for?
Don't worry. They won't hurt you
while you're with us.
- Mr. Monty's bringin' 'em in for a powwow.
- Oh.
Come along now.
He looks all right though,
doesn't he?
Of course he's all right.
Come on. Inside with ya.
"The sun has shone on us many
days in peace, my brothers.
Now a cloud
passes over the sun.
Two days ago,
a wagon train was destroyed.
Last night, the Iron Horse camp
was attacked and many horses stolen.''
Indians who kill wagon train
steal horses...
not from camp of Big Eagle.
They were Blackfeet.
But if you mean, Wolf Pelt...
that they were from
some other part of your tribe...
that does not lessen
the responsibility of your chief.
If Blackfeet Indian
make trouble...
we'll send guilty ones
to white chief.
- I'll hold you to that.
- Give word.
I believe that, Big Eagle.
And I'm willing to admit that these raids
may have occurred without your knowledge.
But so that we shall have
a clear understanding in the future...
I have prepared a paper,
a fair and honorable bond...
between the white
and the red man.
We'll speak in council
with my chiefs.
And I'll expect your answer
within five days.
In the meantime,
I'll need some guarantee...
that you'll keep
your warriors in check.
Huh?
The white chief means he has great
responsibility to the queen mother.
He must have some token-
the guns of your young braves
or your running horses-
to prove that you'll
keep your promise.
Huh.
If white chief think Big Eagle
speak with forked tongue...
will give something
more close to heart.
Little Chief stay here.
Token Big Eagle's word
is straight.
That's more
than I'd ask for...
but it will do no harm for your son
to learn the ways of the white man.
And you may be sure he'll have the best
treatment that we can offer.
Go now.
Send word soon.
- The Indians are coming out.
- Oh?
What do you suppose
they were doing in there?
Probably gettin' blue blazes from the O.C.
for the devilry they've been up to.
There's something
I'd like to tell them too.
Where ya goin'?
Come back here. Come back here!
Are you the chief Indian?
Hmm.
Me Big Eagle.
Well, I certainly hope Mr. Standing is going
to make you Indians behave from now on.
And if you got what you deserved,
he'd send you all to jail.
That's where you belong for what you've
been doing. What right have you-
Here,just a minute, Sue.
You must forgive her, Big Eagle.
This little girl was the only survivor
of the wagon train.
Golden Hawk,
little spirit of the sun.
Big Eagle sorry
you have trouble.
Will not happen again.
I don't see why you want to fight
the white people anrway.
They haven't done anything to hurt you.
Will send present
to little Golden Hawk.
We be good friend now.
- Do you really think he's sorry?
- Yes, I'm sure he is.
But where did you
get all this? Mmm!
That's quite an outfit.
You're a regular cowboy.
- Isn't it beautiful?
- Mmm.
- Mr. Pat made it.
- Monty?
- Yes, sir.
- I'll turn Little Chief over to you.
- Arrange for his care, will you?
- Very good, sir.
Well, so, this is
the little girl you spoke of.
Yes, sir.
This is our other guest, Sue Sheldon.
- This is Superintendent Standing, Sue.
- How do you do, sir?
How do you do, Sue? I hope you'll
enjoy your stay here with us...
until we can find
a home for you.
Now, you go with Inspector Montague,
Little Chief. That's right.
Mr. Monty, is he
gonna send me away?
Oh, we won't worry
about that now.
We'll need you to help
entertain Little Chief.
I'll go see about quarters for you, son,
while you two get acquainted.
It's very nice weather
we're having, isn't it?
Uh.
" Uh''?
Is that your pony?
I guess Indians learn to ride
when they're babies, don't they?
I suppose you don't understand English...
so there's no use
my talking to you.
You're wonderful.
I mean, you're a wonderful rider.
- Squaw ride?
- Well, I, um-
Oh, you think I'm a freak, do you?
Come on.
Help me on.
Well, aren't you
going to help me?
Brave never help squaw.
You're not very polite, are you?
All right.
I'll get on by myself.
Oh!
Well, I could get on
if I had enough time.
You never ride horse.
You just papoose.
Papoose?
Don't you ever call me that again!
Stop grunting at me!
And you apologize too!
- Papoose.
- Ooh!
Ooh!
Where's Little Chief?
Didn't he wanna play?
Mr. Monty, do you know
what he called me?
A papoose!
That's Indian for " baby,'' isn't it?
- I'm afraid it is.
- I thought so.
- Excuse me.
- Wait a minute, Sue. Come here.
Come on. Sit down.
Let's talk this thing over.
I'm sure Little Chief
didn't mean to be rude.
Indians always treat their women
with a superior air.
- The women seem to like it.
- Well, I don't.
You know, even if he liked you a lot,
he'd act just the same.
You see, we're supposed to be much
more grown-up than they are.
There are some things
you just can't put up with.
Papoose!
But, uh, it's our job to understand them
and make allowances.
Would you like me
to make allowances for him?
He's our guest.
So, if you two had a little spat...
I think you oughta make a treaty
and smoke the pipe of peace.
All right.
I'll try.
I'll give him
one more chance.
- But only for your sake.
- That's right. For my sake.
I doubt if I can do much
with him though.
I've come to make allowances.
I didn't ever expect
to speak to you again.
But Mr. Monty says
I'm much more grown-up than you are...
and I should try
to understand you.
- So we'll smoke the pipe of peace.
- White squaw smoke?
Well, I, uh-
I never have.
But we're going to make a peace treaty,
and you have to smoke on that, don't you?
I guess that means yes.
So how do we start?
Thank you.
I only hope I've got
enough allowances to hold out.
Now, the first part of our treaty is
that you're to stop pushing me.
You're not
to be rude anymore.
- I mean, uh, any ruder than
an Indian can't help being.
And the second is that you teach me
to ride as well as you do.
- Much work.
- There you go.
- Are you going to make a treaty, or aren't you?
- Make treaty.
And the third part is that you're not
to call me " papoose'' again.
Do you hear?
Does that mean yes?
Can't you stop grunting? Say yes when you
mean yes, and no when you mean no!
Now, do you understand that?
What's the use?
I guess you mean yes.
Well, I can't think of anything else
just now, so we'd better smoke on it.
I expect you'd
better light it.
Here.
Now squaw smoke.
It isn't bad!
Anybody can make a treaty like this.
Oh, dear.
Must find Indians
who raid wagon train...
and steal from
Iron Horse camp...
so redcoat chief know
we speak with straight tongue.
Think ones who make war
on white man...
are from camp
of Lone Buffalo.
Huh? Why you think that?
Know they make medicine
to sun god for war two moons ago.
I go find out
if they ones who do it.
All right.
You go.
If find guilty ones,
take to redcoat chief...
so he know Big Eagle
keep word and speak truth.
Mmm.
dd
- Get me a handkerchief.
- Yes, sir.
dd
You look, uh,
very nice.
Thank you, Sue.
- How do you think I look?
- You look very nice t-
Mm-mm! Where did
you get that dress?
- Mr. Pat bought it for me.
- Well, well. Good for Pat.
Thank you, sir.
It would be a nice dress
to go to a party in, wouldn't it?
-You'd be the belle of the ball.
-If I was invited to a party.
Glory be. Where in
heaven's name are they?
- Now what's the matter?
- Your handkerchiefs, sir.
I put 'em in the top drawer here where they're
always put, but there's never a one of'em.
Oh, the handkerchiefs!
You had them in with Mr. Monty's
shaving thing, so I changed them.
I put the shirts in where the socks used to
be, and I put the socks in with the underwear...
where the nightshirts used to be, and I
put the nightshirts in with the sheets.
- But where did you put the handkerchiefs?
- In with the socks.
And it's taken me two years to educate
himself where to put his hands on things.
- I was only trying to help.
- Ohh!
What are you doing?
Give me that!
It's only a piece of old buffalo skin I've
been using to rub up Mr. Monty's boots.
- Ohh!
- Why, Sue, that's Pat's pride and joy.
- It's his toupee.
- Toupee?
- Sure. Show her, Pat.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, no. Put it on.
Oh, it's your hair.
I'm awfully sorry.
I didn't know.
It makes you look so handsome.
You oughta wear it all the time.
Oh, yes.
He's a lady-killer with that on.
He wears it on leave, and uses it
to fool the redskins too, don't you?
Yes, sir.
If any of them comes after me...
it's the toupee he'll get
and not me scalp, I hope.
- Your handkerchief, sir.
- You'd better get another one.
- You'll need two for dancing.
- Two? Why?
An extra one to hold against
the lady's back.
Faith and help. She's right, sir.
I'll get you another one.
You seem to know
a lot about dancing, Sue.
I do. My grandfather
was a wonderful fiddler.
- I learned how to dance from him.
- Here you are, sir.
Sue, come here.
Sue, uh, between you and me,
I'm in an awful hole tonight.
- I don't know the first thing about dancing.
- Oh, I can teach you.
I'll go with you to the party,
and you can dance with me until you learn.
Mm-mmm. That wouldn't be so good,
because they might catch on.
Besides, it'd keep you up too late.
Couldn't you show me right here?
Yes. But it would be better
if I went with you so we'd have music.
- I can whistle.
- Well, what dance will we start with?
Well, uh-
Why, is there more than one?
Of course. The waltz, the schottische,
the two-step, the polka-
Whoa. We'll just
concentrate on one.
That, uh-That waltz sounds familiar.
How does it go?
Come on.
I'll show you.
Now, put your arm
around me, like this.
- Wait a minute. I want my handkerchief.
- That's very important.
- Now, give me your other hand.
- Like this?
- Yes. You start with your left foot.
- Left foot. All right.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
One, two, three.
-Just glide on easy. One-
- One, two, three. Oh!
- The main thing is to dance very smoothly.
- Uh-huh.
Here. Try this.
Now, stoop down.
Don't let it fall. That's the way
they teach you in dancing school.
I don't know.
I hope I can keep it up there.
You can.
Now, let's try it again.
One, two, three.
You're doing much better.
One, two, three. That's fine.
Just glide along like you were rippling
over water. Oh!
Oh! We sort of
went overboard, didn't we?
You're getting a little
mixed up with your feet.
Maybe I'd better show you how it goes
first, and then we can dance together.
- Maybe that would be better.
- Now watch me.
dd
Now with me.
- dd
dd
You must be very fond of that piece.
They've played it every time we've danced.
Well, uh, the boys
know it's my favorite.
That's the music
I learned to waltz to.
- I see.
- I can remember it just as though it were tonight.
dd
Time Little Squaw
go sleep.
I guess if everybody else can stay up
dancing, I can stay up and watch them.
- Redcoat make her his squaw?
- He will not!
Funny. Dance like that
and not make her his squaw.
He's only doing that
to be nice to her.
Indian dance better.
Use feathers.
- Oh, let me try it on!
- No. Only brave wear feathers.
- Well, I've got one anrway.
- Mmm.
- Where did you get all these things?
- Warrior bring.
Bring teepee too.
Little Chief no sleep white man house.
You could sleep anrwhere
if you were tired enough.
Mmm. Forgot.
My father sent pony. Present for you.
A pony for me?
Where is it? Show me!
- Aren't you coming?
- Brave always go first.
Squaw walk behind.
Walk behind?
I will not!
Then brave not go.
If we hadn't made
a peace treaty-
Well, all right.
But this is just about
the last of my allowances.
Mmm.
All I can say is that
if Indian women put up...
with being treated like this,
they must be-
Squaw keep quiet
and walk behind brave.
dd
- Make mine a two-step, boys.
- Give me a minute, Harlan.
- I'd like a glass of water.
- I'll get it.
Thank you.
- Now we'll have him back on our hands.
- Why not?
- Making three a crowd, aren't you?
- Everyone's my crowd tonight.
You know, with all this attention,
I'm beginning to appreciate...
the advantages
of being a pioneer woman.
That's great
while the fun lasts, Vicky.
But you won't feel that way
when the going gets rough.
That's bound to happen
out here, you know.
And you think I couldn't
stand up to it if it did?
I know you couldn't.
Look, will you tell me why everybody wants
to rush me back to Toronto?
Well, I was really
thinking of myself.
You see, we'll be stopping
construction soon because of the snow.
And, naturally, I'd like you there when I
go back home for the holidays.
But suppose I
have other plans?
I might decide to become
a pioneer woman at that.
- Don't you think I could, Mr. Montague?
- Beg pardon, Miss Vicky?
Don't you think I could
become a pioneer woman?
I'm sure you could...
if you set your mind to it.
There you are.
That's one vote for me.
dd
Isn't that a tom-tom? It's getting closer.
You stay here, Vicky.
dd
- What was it?
- Sue and Little Chief are on the warpath.
dd
No more dance. Squaw laugh.
I'm awfully sorry. Honest.
I won't do it anymore.
Please don't stop dancing.
We're enjoying it.
Maybe one day
you'll teach me an Indian dance.
Isn't he rude?
These Indians
certainly are a problem.
You don't seem to have much difficulty
handling Little Chief.
It took time for me
to understand him.
But it was worth it, because I
expect to be here for a long time.
- Really?
- Yes. But it wouldn't be worthwhile...
for you to go to all that trouble,
because you're going home soon.
- Am I?
- Aren't you?
Mr. Pat said you were.
And I'm sure you wouldn't...
- like it out here anrway, because it's full of-
- Sue.
- Good night.
I'll wait up for you. You'll need someone
to put your clothes away.
And if someone is up when I get there,
they'll be off to bed with a slipper.
Come on.
Kiss me good night.
- Now what do you say?
- See you first thing in the morning.
- Good night, Sue.
- Good night, Mr. Monty.
I hope you're not offended.
She's a very strange child.
Strange?
I don't think so.
- She adores you.
- Hmm?
It's just that you're slow
to notice things like that.
- Perhaps.
- I say, are we men supposed
to dance with each other?
Come on.
What's the matter now?
You have a face as long
as the old woman that kissed the cow.
- He's in love with her.
- Me darlin'.
'Tis one of the delightful misfortunes
that overtakes the male of the species.
'Tis me that knows.
I wish she'd go back
where she came from.
Oh-ho.
'Tis jealous, you are.
I am not. But she couldn't take care
of him the way we do.
I'll bet she couldn't
even make his bed.
- And you're not doing it right either.
- I'm not, ain't I?
You haven't the covers up
close enough around his neck.
- Oh. Huh.
- And you should unfold his nightshirt...
and have it
all laid out for him.
What are you tryin' to do, spoil him?
Here, me bucko, I'll take that.
Oh, Mr. Pat! And I taught him
how to dance with her.
Heaven help us.
I know, I know.
'Tis a terrible thing
to be a woman in love.
- Oh, Mr. Pat!
- Ah, yes, I understand.
Never you mind.
Never you mind now.
And it's
a heartbreaking ruffian he is.
He is not a ruffian.
I won't let you say that.
Oh, well, have it
your own way, me darlin'.
Have it your own way.
Close them pretty eyes now.
dd
Good night, Miss Standing.
It's the jolliest night we've ever had.
- Good night.
- Certainly a lovely party.
- What's this?
Chief Big Eagle say here bad Indians
who make trouble for covered wagon...
and steal horses
from Iron Horse camp.
He send to you.
Show redcoat he keep word.
Take them
to the guardroom.
- This fellow's dead, sir. He's been stabbed.
- They're all dead, sir.
Order out a detail
to bury them.
Well, this looks as if Big Eagle
is showing his defiance.
He knows the dispensing of justice
belongs to the Mounted Police.
I'll take that up with him
when he comes to sign the treaty.
If it's ever signed.
Chambers, if I should decide
to send Vicky home...
could you do anything for me
in the way of transportation?
I certainly could, sir. There's a supply
train up on Sunday morning...
that'll take her as far
as Winnipeg.
From there, she can connect
with the Eastern Limited.
I agree with you. It'd be wise
to get her away from here.
- I'll let you know.
- No, thanks. I won't come in now.
I better get back to the camp
to see that everything's all right then.
- Good night.
- Good night, Chambers.
Won't you eat your eggs, sir?
They're that fresh...
I just saw the cook take them
from under the hen with his own hands.
Oh, no, thanks.
- Good morning.
Here's your baked apple and milk.
All ready for you.
- I'm not hungry this morning, thank you.
- Heaven help us.
There's more than one sufferin' from the
same complaint this morning, I'm thinking.
Well, I'll get
a bit of work done. Sir?
Hmm? Oh, yes.
Go ahead.
Was it a nice party?
Yes, very nice.
Is she a good dancer?
Very good.
- Better than I am?
- No, I wouldn't say that.
- Are you going to marry her?
- Marry her?
Well, I was watching you
dance together last night.
And the way she looked at you, and the way
you looked at her, I thought maybe-
Don't you think you
ought to have your breakfast?
Yes, sir. But I supposed that when people
were in love, they always got married.
She's going home tomorrow.
Even Little Chief-
- She is? She's really going home?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, isn't that a shame? Won't you sit
over here in the rocking chair?
- It's much more comfortable.
- No, thanks.
I'll get you your pipe.
Would you like your pipe?
Here's-
Here's some matches too.
I guess you smoke more matches than you do
tobacco. Can I get you anything else?
No, thanks. You'd better run along
and play with Little Chief.
- If you need me for anything,just send Mr. Pat.
- I will.
Hello, Mr. Pat!
Hello, Mr. Pat! Hello!
- Hello!
- Hello, Susannah.
- Hi, Carruthers.
- Good morning.
Oh, good morning, Miss Vicky.
I was hoping I'd see you before you left.
I'm sorry we have to say good-bye, but Dad
isn't in favor of my becoming a pioneer woman.
He's right, Miss Vicky.
This really isn't the place for you.
Are you going to keep it
a man's country forever?
It's apt to be that way
for quite a while yet.
Well, I suppose if we're ever to see each
other again, you'll have to come to Toronto.
I'm afraid there's not
much chance of that.
- Why?
- We'll be pushing farther west every year...
and by the time I get back to Toronto,
you'll probably be married...
- and have a family of grown-up children.
- And what about you?
Oh, I guess I'll just end up
being the old man of the mountain.
Well, good-bye.
I'll always remember the fun we've had...
and I'll probably find myself wishing I could
hear you sing that little waltz song again.
And I'll find myself wishing
it wasn't so far to Toronto.
Good-bye, Vicky.
Squaw ride faster!
I'm coming
as fast as I can!
- Squaw ride like-
- Don't you dare say it!
- White man buy?
- Take your time.
If they're sound,
we'll make a deal.
What are they doing
over there?
Wolf Pelt sell horses
to railroad.
Let's go watch.
Come on.
Oh, all right!
Go ahead.
I'm getting used to being a squaw.
Aah! No have to look.
How much pay?
- We'll settle that later.
- You'll buy now. All good horses.
Sure. Three of them's very good horses.
They oughta be.
They're three that were stolen in the raid
and wasn't brought back with the others.
White man lie.
Indian ponies.
Yeah? Well,
there's Bully Boy...
that's LadyJane,
and there's Steamboat.
And I'll prove it.
They didn't even make
a good job of dyeing it!
More of
your thieving tricks.
I wouldn't do business with your breed
if I had to go without horses!
You leave those animals here
and clear out.
- White man pay.
- I'll give you nothing.
If you got what you deserve,
I'd take it out of your hide.!
- Let us handle him, boss.
- We'll take care of him.
- Wait a minute.!
- You've been babied
by the redcoats long enough...
but you're at the end
of the rope with me.
I'm going to have the railroad bring out
government troops to deal with you.
Iron Horse bring soldiers?
Yes, plenty of them.
They'll keep you in order... with bullets.
All right.
White chief has spoken.
Don't let 'em get away!
Hold him up.! Get him.!
- Hang him.!
You kids better clear out.
This is no place for you.
- White man no right beat Indian.
- Run along before you get hurt.
Come on, Little Chief.
Natosi,
sun god, not answer.
Three suns pass
since talk to redcoat chief.
He wait for our answer.
Natosi turn face away from our medicine.
My fathers, see what white men
have done to your children.
This is what they do when
go their camp in friendship.
- Take them to squaw.
- White man's words are sweet, but heart bitter.
- Who has done this, my son?
- Men who make trail for Iron Horse.
And now their chief has spoken. Iron Horse
soon bring soldiers, kill our people!
Will we wait while
white warriors come like locusts?
Drive off people
from land like buffalo?
I say not listen redcoat chief who talk
peace and give us lies on paper...
who take your son
and call himself your brother.!
I say make war
while able!
- Destroy trail of Iron Horse.!
-dd
Drive out white men!
All white men!
Medicine answered.
Natosi angered. Natosi say war.
dd
It looks like war on a big scale.
The signal fires are burning...
and the tribes are gathering
from every part of the west.
Mr. Monty! Mr. Monty, I'm so glad
you're back! I was so worried.
- You shouldn't be up this late, Sue.
- But I had to tell you.
Little Chief said the Indians are going
to kill all the white men in redcoats...
because of what happened
at the railroad camp.
- At the railroad camp?
- What happened, Sue?
The Indians tried to sell Mr. Chambers
his own horses back.
He got so mad, because they
were trying to cheat him...
he said he was gonna bring soldiers
out to make them behave.
The Indians didn't like that.
When they tried to leave...
the workmen pulled them off their horses
and started hitting them.
I can try to reach Big Eagle and explain that he
has nothing to fear from Chambers's threats.
I'm afraid it's too late for talk now.
- What is it, Father? More trouble?
- Yes, Vicky. Plenty.
And our friend Chambers
started it.
Let's take a look
from the tower.
dd
- Now squaw put out finger.
- And let you cut it? I will not.
- Squaw afraid?
- Well, no.
Oh, you did!
It's bleeding!
Now put together.
Make Golden Hawk and Little Chief
blood brothers.
You mean this will
make me an Indian?
Mm. Indian now.
- Will my face turn red?
- No. You stay paleface.
I'm glad of that.
Oh, but if I'm a member
of your tribe...
they'll all be my relations,
won't they?
Not Wolf Pelt.
He bad Indian.
- Him steal horses from white man camp.
- He did?
Then why didn't your father send him
to Mr. Standing, like he did the others?
Father not know.
Wolf Pelt lie.
Say he not one of them.
Other Indians not tell.
- Well, I'm going to tell.
- You belong to tribe now. Must keep secret.
- But he should be punished.
- We catch him Wolf Pelt right time.
Not tell now.
We put in treaty.
Oh, dear.
Come on! Get ready!
They're coming this way! Hurry up!
Come on!
- Superintendent in?
- Yes, sir.
- What's happened?
- Our camp was raided.
We had to fight our way out.
I told you weeks ago that you couldn't keep
order in this territory without troops.
Now we're trapped. The tracks are torn
up behind us, and the bridge is burned.
The telegraph lines are down. They probably
killed half the men in my camp by now.
Mount a detachment
to go to their aid.
Bring the workmen here if the situation
warrants and have Churchill take charge.
- Yes, sir.
- The few men you send won't stop
2,000 bloodthirsty savages.
We wouldn't be facing this situation,
Mr. Chambers...
if it weren't
for your unreasonable conduct.
- My unreasonable conduct?
- Your presuming on our authority...
threatening to bring the militia
here to make war on the Indians.
Well, I- Perhaps
I was a little hasty.
You were more than that.
Your stupidity is responsible...
for endangering lives
and property in my charge.
In the future,
keep to the building of your railroad...
but leave dealing with the Indians
to the mounted police.
Inspector Montague?
Have the gates closed and see that the men
are prepared for any emergency.
Yes, sir.
Redcoats go to Iron Horse camp.
Now we get Little Chief.
Sound the alarm!
dd
Keep Sue in there,
and you stay with her.
All right. Come on.
Vicky, quick!
Inside!
- Here's some more ammunition, Mr. Pat.
- Thank you, darlin'.
Get down. Get down.
Get down.
Get behind me.
Get behind me. That's it.
I got it! I got it!
Here it is.
Thank you.
That's it.
Mr. Pat, I've looked everywhere, and nobody
seems to know what's become of Mr. Monty.
Never you mind now.
You've had no rest all night.
Sit down there, and as soon as I finish
this, I'll get ya a bit of breakfast.
I couldn't eat. I'd better
go back out and keep on looking.
Oh, well-
Sergeant MacGregor,
are you all right, sir?
Aye, lassie.
Just a wee nip in the hand.
- Have you seen Mr. Monty?
- Well, no. I can't say that I have.
He isn't in the hospital with the wounded
men, the guardroom or the stables.
- I've looked almost every place.
- D'n' worry your head, lassie.
Mr. Monty can take care of himself
under any circumstances.
Thank you, sir.
Take him to the stables.
Inspector Randall?
Inspector Randall!
- Yes, Inspector?
- I was taken prisoner while on patrol, sir...
and held
at Big Eagle's camp.
Just before dawn this morning,
Inspector Montague was brought in.
- I was released to bring you a message.
- Go on.
Big Eagle demands that the railroad
leave his territory within two days...
or Inspector Montague will not be returned
and hostilities will be reopened.
What will you do, Father?
You must send some word.
There's only one answer
refusal.
Thank you, Randall.
Mr. Standing, aren't you going
to try to save him?
- Of course, Sue.
- Well, there must be some way to rescue him.
There aren't many of us. If we tried and failed,
they'd put him to death immediately.
We'll need help. I'll get a message out
to the nearest post.
They may get here
in time.
Iron Horse still go on.
If don't go away, you die.
Iron Horse won't go away,
Little Chief, not for me or anyone else.
Chief redcoat big fool.
All white men be killed.
If they do,
many more will come...
and it'll be very bad medicine
for the Indians.
Big talk.
Indian kill them too.
- I get cold water for sick head.
- Thanks. That would be a help.
Do it for Golden Hawk.
She your friend.
Too bad you die.
Make her feel sorry.
You know I'm not a very good rider,
but you go as fast as you can.
I'll stick on some way.
Hold still.
You oughta know which way the Indian
camp is. You used to live there.
Maybe you're thirsty.
Have a drink.
Hurry up.
Oh. Oh, hello.
- Would you please tell me the way
to Mr. Big Eagle's camp?
I've gotta go there.
It's terribly, terribly important.
- It's all right for me to go there,
'cause he's a friend.
He gave me this pony.
We know each other very, very well.
Won't you take me to him, please?
Thank you very much.
May I see Mr. Big Eagle now?
- Not now. You stay here.
- But-
Why, Sue!
Oh, Mr. Monty,
have they hurt you?
I'm all right, dear.
How did you get here?
I came to see Mr. Big Eagle,
but they won't let me talk to him.
- You shouldn't have come.
- I had to.
Mr. Standing sent
to another post for help...
but they can't get here in time,
so after dark tonight...
he's coming with a few men
to try to rescue you.
But he's afraid that
if the Indians see him coming, they'll-
- I have to see Mr. Big Eagle somehow,
before it gets dark.
- It won't do any good, Sue.
It will.
I know it will.
- Please, Mr. Indian, won't you let me talk to-
- You go back.
Come over here, dear.
Stay near me.
Oh, Mr. Monty...
if they do anything to you,
they'll have to kill me too.
dd
Redcoats on way!
They are coming!
Signal say redcoat leave post.
On way here.
Make ready now.
dd
You come now.
- Please! What are you going to do?
- Stop it, Wolf Pelt.
- But they can't take you!
- Sue, remember? You promised.
- I'm not crying. Please. Let me go too.
- You'll stay.
Then bring Mr. Big Eagle
here so I can talk to him.
Sure. He come.
But not now.
Oh, Mr. Monty-
We're not giving up, you know.
I'll talk to Big Eagle. But now...
let's pretend this is
just like any other night.
Kiss me good night.
Now, what do you say?
See you first thing...
in the morning.
I can't! I can't!
No!
No! Wait! Please! No! No!
dd
Mr. Monty. Mr. Monty. I won't let them hurt you.
- Now, Sue.
- No! Don't! Don't! Please!
No! Let me go! Let me go!
Mr. Big Eagle, please.
Don't let them hurt Mr. Monty.
- No listen to white devil child.
- You have to listen to me. Please!
Don't touch Golden Hawk!
She my friend.
I'm your friend too, Mr. Big Eagle,
and so are the redcoats.
- That's what I came here to tell you.
- Redcoat no friend now.
Let Iron Horse chief bring
soldier to kill all Indians.
No, they won't.
Mr. Standing won't let them.
And you shouldn't hurt Mr. Monty
because of what Mr. Chambers said.
I won't let you.
White child lie to save redcoat.
All tribe know soldiers come.
The redcoats are the only ones who can
speak for the great queen mother.
- The soldiers will not come to your lands.
- Redcoat lie!
White men beat Indians!
Sun god say kill all white men!
No, you won't! It was all your fault anrway!
You deserve to be whipped! If you hadn't
tried to cheat Mr. Chambers when you-
Right time now.
You tell.
The only reason Mr. Chambers said
he'd bring out the soldiers...
was because Wolf Pelt tried to sell him back
the horses he had stolen from the railroad.
Not true. No listen.
Devil child have forked tongue.
Golden Hawk speaks straight.
You one who lead braves who steal horses
and let others take blame.
Little Chief lie too. Since live with
white man, he have forked tongue.
Stop!
Why you not tell redcoat
about Wolf Pelt?
Because Little Chief and I
made a treaty to keep it a secret...
so I couldn't
break my word, could I?
You make treaty
with Golden Hawk?
Yes.
Make her blood brother too.
No make treaty now.
Too much talk.
- All lies.!
- Wait!
I've told you the truth,
Mr. Big Eagle.
Honest, I have.
On my word of honor.
Little Chief give word too.
They try to fool you
till redcoats get here.
No wait.
Wolf Pelt tell truth!
Bring medicine.
dd
Who lying?
You one who lie.
Take him away!
No! No lie. No.
Devil child lie!
Set free!
Little Golden Hawk
show white man and Indian...
how to live
as brothers.
She smoke too.
Oh, here I go again.