Good morning.
Good morning, Mr. Garms.
After you.
Garms!
The name is Nesbitt.
You must have the wrong fellow.
Oh yeah?
We don't care for bounty hunters, Mr.
So why don't you just get on your
horse and ride on out?
I don't care what name you call him. Harry
Nesbitt is a good friend of mine.
Look, it was along time ago.
I was just a kid.
Them days are behind me.
I got a whole new life here.
A damn good life.
That's just about finished.
- They move along good, Mr. Morgan.
- Keep at them.
Hey-up. Hey-up.
Hi Kiefer.
So you found them... after all.
Yeah. No thanks to you.
Sheriff, you knew him?
Lots of people around here
thought he was a good man.
- A wanted man, that's all that matters.
- To you.
To the law.
- The law is my business.
- Yeah. But you didn't do it.
You don't kill a man for 200 dollars.
Every man has his choice...,
..he made his.
One of these days, Kiefer...
...you're gonna go too far.
If I do... it would be for a hell
lot more than this.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, sir.
First time I ever saw you
two move fast.
- What about the bonus?
- You got it.
Even though you didn't earn it.
- Oh Mr. Pike, Will was really sick.
- Yeah, terrible pain right here.
Wouldn't wish it on a rat.
Figure .. we deserve a drink too.
Well, Pike...
Here's to us!
My God.. here's to us.
You always knew that we were gonna make it,
Mr. Morgan?
There were times when I wondered.
Wondered plenty. Maybe I was
biting off more than I could chew.
- How does it feel to be rich?
- Damned good.
But Hell, Pike, this money
is for all of us down in Sonora.
We're gonna do things down there.
All those things we have been
talking about all those years.
That sounds mighty good to me.
We're gonna make us a place where everybody
can live...
...without anybody to tell us
what to think, what to do.
A place where a man can be what he is.
Some good folks down in
Sonora, Mr. Morgan.
- Best I've ever met.
- Well, Pike, that is your home now.
You're as much a part of the
Morgan ranch as I am.
Mrs Linda Morgan, ranch
Dos Rios, Sonora, Mexico.
Everything is fine here. Stop.
Coming home with Pike. Stop.
Your loving husband, Bob Morgan.
- How long is that going to take?
- Not long at all.
She ought to have it in a day or so.
Get this out a soon as you can, will you?
- Can we send this right now?
- I will take care of it.
- Well, she knows we're headed home now, sir.
- Yeah. Yeah she ought to.
What is it?
It must be.. I am little tired.
- I'll take you to the hotel.
- No, just give me a minute.
Take it easy, Mr. Morgan.
No time, Pike.
You listen.
No one but you.. you are gonna
get that money back to the ranch.
All the people are... counting on you.
You are going back, Mr. Morgan.
Give me your word, Pike!
Give me your word.
No matter what happens... you get that
money back down there.
Everything depends on that.
For everybody.
All our plans...
You got my words.
- Then I...
- Mr. Morgan?
Card?
Well, Mister dealer,
I certainly would call this a fine hand.
Lacking only one thing which, I
trust, you will now deliver unto me.
What the Hell are you talking about?
One card, sir.
Three.
And one for the dealer.
Ah.. one.
I believe one of you gentlemen
have the bet.
Here's your two. I'll
push you for two more.
Your name wouldn't happen to be Pike?
I've been called a lot of things, sir
But that ain't one of them.
Thought it might be my lucky day.
Do you know that buck that's
driving to Sonora?
The one with 86,000 dollars.
You tryin' to tell me that story
about the Morgan payroll is true?
I swear, Mr.
My cousin Billy's seen it.
Play the God damn cards.
Excuse me.
The man is anxious to give me his money.
If you could beat this hand...
...I'll kiss my nose.
Ah...
- Snake!
- Snake! Kill it! Kill it!
Hey come on. What the Hell's going on?
Thought we was playing cards?
You was telling us about...
kissing your nose?
You would have to have to beat
a king high straight.
I guess you better...
...pucker up, man.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Mister. You're the luckiest man alive.
Or the handiest.
- Keep this for me until I get back.
- Where are you going?
Fishing.
Hey, boy!
All we want is a share. We will leave
you plenty.. how about it?
Why draw and die? There
is enough for everyone.
It's only money. In Hell...
..it ain’t even yours.
Kill the bastard!
Hold it. What the hell are you doin'?
What are you shooting at?
Wait until you can see him.
Look out! Snakes!
A man with a cigar in one hand and
a horse in the other can do you no harm.
Seems like those fellas back there had you in
a lot of trouble. Figured I saved your hide.
Would have it done anyway. All you do
is you save me some time.
You're welcome I'm sure...
My momma always taught me manners.
So. How'd yu do.
- My name: Tyree.
- Tyree.
Yeah... I've heard of you.
That's all I need.
I figured it will take some time
to convince you that point, but...
...I'm kinda glad you’d see it right off.
All I see is a fast talking nigger..
..In a fancy shirt.
That it?
Why don't you get back on that horse..
Before your ideas get outta hand?
I figuring on getting rich too.
But my momma always taught me
to look ahead.
Let's say I killed you... took the money...
They would just come looking for me.
But you got the right idea...
...make it to Mexico, spend the
rest of your days spending.
- Is that your proposition?
- You got it.
We ride together from here to Mexico.
I protect your tail.. you watch mine.
- And when we get there?
- Once we cross that big river..
...all bets are off.
- Why should I trust you anymore than them?
- Because they're dead.
And you wanna stay alive.
Dying is way of life for
some people, Tyree.
Make sure you won't have that problem.
You know something, Pike?
We are practically... invisible.
I mean everyone is out looking for only one darky.
And now there is two of us.
How are they gonna know you now?
You always carry a pack of snakes with you?
- That's a story that have never been told.
- Well I've seen you throw snakes...
...but can you shoot?
You'll just have to wait to find out.
Seems like... somebody’s gotta move.
Seems like.
Now friend...
..we can't tell which side you're moving on.
That one or this one?
I haven't made up my mind yet.
You ehh..need any help making up your mind?
Never have.
All right.
He seemed to want something more
from you than just money.
There are they
...lets ride after them!
- Well what do you think?
- They have shown the way.
I still do not know if you can shoot.
Hey, look at them spurs!
Yeah.. these two are shot up pretty bad.
I told you that we were
coming up behind Pike.
Yep, , and so were they.
This one was married.
Too bad his widow ain’t around.
- Are you a gambling man, Pike?
- I do no gambling.
Do you think it's going to be
like that all the way, Pike?
What's wrong? Smell of that
money loosing it sweetness?
Ahh. It's getting sweeter all the time.
It's just like with a woman, Pike.
Once you start to like them.,
Always hungry.
- How about a cigar?
- I do no smokin', neither.
Tell me something. When I'm not near
are you thinking of keeping all that money?
- You mean..eh... splitting with you?
- Now, that ain’t a bad idea.
Well, don't get your hopes up.
You think about it though, don't you Pike? I
mean it wouldn't be natural if you didn't.
You're the same as me.
Maybe... before...
..but..it's different now.
I'm just practicing.
I hope so.
Oh my darling, Oh my darling.
Oh... my dar..ling... Clementine.
You were gone out... Forever.
Dreadful story, Clementine...
Finished?
- I am now.
- Let's go.
Please.
What the hell are you doing?
Shit, Mr! We ain't got nothing.
- You rode with Pike?
- Yeah, but wasn't the only ones...
...I mean he was a lot better than us.
- But little eyes like you gotta see a lot.
- We didn't see nothing, Mr., I swear.
- Are you going after Pike too?
- I might be just the one that's gonna kill him.
Pike he don't die so easy.
The dead is dead, and that's my problem.
You two are gonna ride with me.
Or?
With him.
Hey Pike. You know something?
I've been thinking.
I know why I'm risking my hide.
Why are you doing it?
- Because I told Morgan I would.
- You gave your word to a white man?
Where I come from that ain’t exactly
binding.
Not even 86,000 dollars worth.
I gave my word... to a man.
Help! Arrrgh!
Let go!
Come on. Come on!
Lucas!
- Stop it! What more do you want?
- Get her.
- Stop it!
- Hold her tight!
Help! No!
Feel like being a gentleman?
This your husband?
Where were you headed?
To a little town, near the Rio Grande.
We're headed that way you can ride with us
I'll round up a couple of horses
for you and your friend.
One. He doesn't need.
He was raised by the Tarahuma Indians.
Two blacks, a women and
Indian on foot.
Don't you think anybody is going to
recognize you, Pike?
Now that I know you can shoot, Tyree..
..we won't get no problems.
What's your name, amigo?
His name is Kashtok. He can not
speak. He has no tongue.
Who did that to him?
Men.. like those.
We do not need him. We can
can catch up Pike by ourselves.
Bushwhack him and keep all the money.
He wouldn't give us much anyway.
This way we got it all.
And spend it before he evens knows it.
- You haven't seen a nigger riding by?
- Maybe.
Maybe a couple of them.
Is that right?
- The man says he seen the big nigger.
- Not far up ahead.
Well... that's fine.
- Depends on what you got in mind.
- Sounds like you got something in mind, mister?
If you're gonna go riding out after him,
you are gonna be riding with me... or..
- Or what?
- Or you ain’t riding at all.
- You got some kind of claim on him?
- You could put that way or put it ..
...any way you want it.
I happened to be first in line.
Well, he's is going to move over.
Thank you.
I mean.. for before... what you did.
"Thank you" is very difficult
for you to say isn't it?
I don't think I will
be sorry that I said it.
Well, just thought you might like to talk.
That depends about what.
I don't know.
I thought it might made you feel better.
I came from New Orleans.
And before that France.
You know about the crypt in New
Orleans, where the girls are?
I was there for three years.
Until Lucas, my husband,
came and brought me away with him.
He was a kind and gentle man.
Perhaps you can never
understand, but he did.
He never asked me about
what it was like there.
He didn't have to know.
Lucas made me feel...
Sometimes... almost believed
that it never happened.
Almost?
Is that so strange?
It can happen that a man can trust you. With those
you are carrying without being no doubt before.
Yeah, I know about that.
When my husband found Kashtok
left to die in the desert,..
...he brought him home to care for.
Lucas were that kind of person.
Sound like you loved him.
No.
That was the only thing I
could not give.
I tried, but it was not there.
- Perhaps it is something that I have lost.
- Well..maybe you'll find it again.
Where? Back in the crypts of New Orleans?
No.
I am not going to chase rainbows
...as they say in your country.
- This ain’t my country.
- No?
I was told that you
fought a war about that.
What's she say?
She said that we won the war.
Is that so? Why are they still
shooting at us then?
If they ever stopped, I
figured something is wrong.
She tell you a sad story?
What makes you think so?
It kinda figures, Pike.
I have known a lot of ladies,
Been to a lot of places.
Including New Orleans.
Everybody got sad story
in their past.
Some people more that others.
It ain’t no different.
Don't you ever shut up?
Talking makes me feel... I'm alive.
Lets me know I'm here.
You've always been a loner, Pike?
You kinda got that look in your eye,
tells people to stay away.
Depends on people.
- You don't like me much do you?
- Oh, I like you, Tyree.
But ain’t you the fella that's
gonna try and kill me
...when we cross that river into Mexico?
Yep..that's right, Pike.
I told you that we ain't gonna
find nothin' else.
But you're so Goddamn stubborn!
But you'll eat rabbits if you get
hungry enough!
- So high and mighty.
- I will eat no skunk.
All you have to do...
...is to skin it up, wash it, put it on
the fire, call it " prairie dog."
If we wait for the chicken,
we starve to death.
- I told you.. I don't eat no skunk.
- Hold it!
- Hands up! Where is it?
- I ain’t got it.
Don't make a move.
There were supposed to be only one of them.
The fact is that we are gonna kill
you both in about 3 seconds from now.
- What for?
- The money you got.
What money? We've got 16 cents between us!
But you are welcome to it all...
- Only chicken here!
- Chicken? You son of a bitch!
Skunk is good enough for me,
You got a whole Goddamn chicken.
Hey, neither one of them is him.
And I'm expecting to see 86,000 dollars.
What?
What? You mean there's a nigger
riding around with all that money?
That's right.
Too bad you ain’t him.
Come on, let's go!
You dumb bastard! We got
better things to do!
86,000 dollars!
You see, Mr. Kiefer,
Just like we've been telling you.
Old Pike he's been this way.
He didn't take nothing off these fellas.
Wouldn't take us long.
Lot of stuff here.
He left it all for us.
Ladies things.
When are we gonna get him?
Why hurry? They are only carrying the
money closer to where we can spend it.
Cangey! Look!
Come on!
Don't let them get away!
Come on! We got them now! If we get
across the bridge, we'll be rich men!
They did it! Move your ass!
Hey!
Come on, give me your foot.
Come on.
Hold on.
Do you want me to fall down!
I give you my foot!
More..more..
Come on. Hurry!
Hurry up, come on!
Hold on to my foot.
Hold on to my foot. Don't let go!
Hang on. Up with you. No!
You came because God sent you here.
He means for me to ride on this crusade.
It's not money, Kiefer, it's what
they plan to do with it.
The Devil's work.
Ohh, they claim they will be delivering it,
protecting it for others.
But we know, don't we Kiefer?
But that's a lie.
This is just a test of your purpose.
- Like when I first met you at the end of the war.
- That's right.
Then called us marauders then, didn't they?
Because we no longer obeyed the rules
of war.
But I knew I... I obeyed the rule
of God.
- When I took revenge on His enemies.
- It's coming to you again.
And I hear His call.
Well...
Listen to me...
Do you drink?
Do you chew? (Tobacco)
What about women?
- What about them?
- Well you know, do you... eh...?
They are... sisters in Christ.
Amen, brother.
- Angel.
- Yes, sir.
Sent through the Lord,
His own thunderbolt...
He been given into my hands to
smite the unredeemable sinners.
Show him, Angel.
They are heathens. Black heathens.
Black is the Devil's colors and they
are riding on the Devil's mission.
Goodbye 86,000 dollars.
And it's all your fault.
Because if you done what I told you...
All you know to do is give orders
and complaining.
The best way for us to
do is just..separate.
Oh wait a minute, Cangey.
Don't be that way.
Hey money isn't everything.
Hey listen, Come on you know those two
blankets you wanted? I got them here.
Come on.
Look out! Run!
Goddamn, Cangey, they killed us!
- The money isn't here.
- What?
They looks like them, but there
ain’t 86,000 dollars.
Maybe it's just a story.
No, it's no story.
Everybody knows about it.
- So where's the money?
- We just been following the wrong ones, that's all.
But we've been crossing a lot of trails
all leading to the border.
I figure that's where the money is.
All for the the money.
All of a sudden you got big eyes.
And I was just figuring you were different.
Thinking about joining up
with the other side?
- Do you believe I think about that?
- Oh, yeah.
I forget about your recent bereavement.
I hope I don't mind me saying, but..eh
For a fresh widow and all..
...you don't seem too broken up.
You would prefer that I cry?
Is that what you mean?
I figured a man should always
have someone to weep over him.
- Guess I'm just kinda sentimental.
- Tears are not gonna bring my husband back.
No, but they do have sanctimonious way.
My momma always taught me manners.
- He's talking too much.
- It doesn't matter.
Well, I don’t wanna going in an up fit.
,..but he do what he likes.
And you? What do you like?
The money you carry?
Well, ehh. I'm just holding it.
For a lot of people down in Sonora.
They worked a lot of years for it.
- Are you are taking it to them?
- That's right.
I'm sorry, I didn't understand.
- You are a lucky man.
- Well, It didn't seem that way lately.
You found something worth living for
I envy you.
Come on!
Come on. We gotta get closer. Come on!
In the cave!
Tyree!
Take this.
See if there's a way out.
Come on! Faster!
Faster! Faster!
Are you crazy?
Next time you get an idea like that, Pike..
..you keep it to yourself.
We made it didn't we?
Let's get out of here.
- Why has she done it?
- Something you'll never understand.
- What did you say to her back there?
- I said nothing.
'Cause she are just looking
for a reason to live.
Well, she found one...
.. good enough to die for.
No, no good.
Guess he ain’t no where to go.
You haven't come up against them yet.
So you don't know.
But I do. Also know what you're after,
Kane.
It's not exactly within the law.
What we are after is none of your business.
- Your are not wearing your badge anymore, Kane.
- I don't go anywhere with you.
You are damn slight smarter.
When did you start sharing your bounty?
This time I'll be making an exception.
Sounds like you're the one
that need help, not me.
Two niggers and an Indian.
I can handle that myself.
I've already buried a dozen
men that said the same thing.
Equal shares to every man
who rides with me.
You got a few minutes
to make up your minds.
You can't have my men, Kiefer.
That's for them to decide.
It wouldn't be safe to go on without me.
- Is that a threat?
- That's a fact.
They shot our wagon to shit...
Goddamn!
Won't you ever get tired?
You never told me about it.
Save your breath, Tyree.
You're gonna need it.
We are gonna make it.
Do you hear me? We are gonna make it!
Yeah. We... are in the middle of nowhere..
Not even a Goddamn horse and he
he says we're gonna make it.
You are seeing butterflies.
Women with... laces.
Hey.
What?
Look. Look!
- You son of a bitch!
- The men have a right to decide for themselves, Kane.
They decided to ride with me.
What are you gonna do?
I meet up with you in Calvera's camp.
Are you sure you don't wanna try some?
I don't chew.
Calvera's camp. Good.
Good mexican food.
Hey, Chico, how are you doing? You learned
how to handle that buck I got for you?
Yes, sir.
Hello, old man.
It's been a long walk, right?
Yeah.
- Do you have two good horses we could buy?
- At least you can ride them.
Hey, Tyree, there's one for you.
Hey Tyree, I think you better
try that one..
Well, old man, how much are you
gonna charge these two miserable thieves?
They are probably stolen anyway.
Like only a horse thief would know, senor.
- This one needs a shoe. We won't get far that way.
- There is a blacksmith in town.
I'll tend to it myself, Chico.
Is there a any place in this
town where we can eat and drink?
Only for those who can pay for it.
Well, that ain’t no problem,
just see my friend there.
Where the Hell is that
indian going this time?
Tequila?
- You killed many men with this?
- Only if they shot at me first.
- I wish.. I wish I had a gun.
- Why? Who're you gonna shoot?
The man who killed my father.
What are you doing out here, Chico?
I followed you, senor.
Well, you better be going
back to the house now
before you get in trouble
with your grandfather.
He is not my grandfather.
I just work for him. I have no one.
It's past your bedtime.
I never remembered you for 10 years, Pike.
Well, that took you long enough.
- Is all the reason you're here?
- You still a wanted man.
Yeah.
- What about the money?
- The money stays here!
10 years ago, I would have shot you.
But I learned that every man
needs a second chance.
- That could be your failing, Pike.
- Could be.
- I'm not surprised that you didn't shoot him.
- That would have been kind of difficult.
I pay $ 100 a man.
$ 100 for a two day ride.
I'm very busy man.
How much money do they have these men?
Enough.
Enough...
for them...
for you...
and... us?
I need a little more.
These must very dangerous these men...
...if you need so many of us to catch them.
A little challenge for you, isn't it?
You'll get paid. If you do exactly
as I say.
Exactly as you say?
- But you guarantee it?
- You got my word.
Pfff... your word!
To us a word is a very valuable thing.
Good...
I accept your guarantee.
We will ride with you and your word.
But...
If you don't pay us,
Then we'll ride after you.
Did you hear that?
Now, he's is gonna give 100
dollars to these Mexicans!
We're not any closer to that money
than we started!
Look who's here. No drink, no smoke,
no chew. No sleep?
Someone in the camp!
Mr. Kiefer! Over here!
Looks like some kind of work camp.
Yeah.
I figure this is about as far as we go.
Kinda thought you’d remember that.
kept the first half of my promise.
- Helped you to get here.
- That's right.
And you are planning on
keeping the rest of it, huh?
You wouldn’t respect a man who
didn't keep his word now, would you Pike?
After all..you're the man who
gave his word to Morgan?
- ain't you had enough fighting?
- ain't the point.
Do it on foot?
That's right.
We do it on foot.
That's real sneaky, Pike.
Real sneaky.
I never figured you for a low down
trick like that.
But I figured you’d.
Fighting you don't please me, Pike.
It's the money I want.
Senor!
Senor! Senor!
Senor! They are coming! They are coming!
- Chico, what's wrong?
- Many of them. An army.
- Where are they?
- Over there. On the hill.
Chico, I want you to ride ahead..
Go to Sonora and ask where
Morgan's ranch is. Do you understand?
Si, senor. Morgan ranch.
I understand.
What about the men?
I'll take care of men.
I'll catch up with you in a little while.
Now, keep on riding no matter what...
...and give no one this money except
Mrs. Morgan.
Chico...
...you tell her that Pike sent you.
I tell her that I said to
give you home.
Si, senor.
Kashtok.
You'll go on with him, understand?
I want you to take care of him.
- You go too.
- I kind of figured doing that any way.
Ain't you kinda scared?
I'll take my chances.
Amigo!
G'luck.
Those are the men with the money?
Then why we've stopped?
- Not all that simple.
- No?
To me that dosen't look very hard...
...easier than robbing a bank.
Lot of dead men thought the same thing.
Move in when I say.
We ain’t gonna see none of that
money the way he's giving it away.
Yeah. First there were three of us.
Now there's more than I can count.
Remember what he said. Dead is dead.
You ain’t got the guts.
Mr. Kiefer?
Mr. Kiefer, sir.
I heard some talking last night
at Calvera's camp.
Something you should... know about.
I don't know who was talking.
I could not see his face.
I heard someone said he was
gonna shoot you.
Yeah, shoot you.
Shoot you in the back.
I remember now.
It was Dumper.
It was his idea.
I didn't have anything to do with it!
I figured you might start worrying.
Oh Hell.. I ain’t figured
you’d give a damn.
Then I guess we both were wrong.
Amigo...
You shouldn't go shoot in the
wrong direction.
Those we want are there.
Now, senor Kiefer...
...I think my men will do it alone.
Vamoose!
It's too late.
No.
Only for you.
We don't wait anymore.
- How many do you figure out there?
- Couldn't be more than 40
40 against two.
Pretty bad odds.
For them.
It's shame that you never had any
of my fine cigars from New Orleans.
How come you never tried one before, Pike?
Making a round I was doing no smoking.
But I guess I will now.
Haul up there, Tyree!
We've got three seconds!
Hey, how come you didn't tell me
you couldn't swim?
You can't do everything perfect, Pike.
Besides I was just trying to
keep my gun dry.
Well...
Are you ready to take
this long hard... Walk?