Sampson, come on, get up.
Get up, boy. Come on, Sampson, get up.
Sampson, come on now. Get up.
Get up, Sampson.
Daniel, where were you?
Your father's fit to be tied.
There was a horseless carriage.
I knew it was something like that.
You and your flights of fancy!.
What will we do with you?
We haVe enough to worry about,
what with all that's happening in town.
- Where's Pa?
- In the barn, tending to Sampson.
Sorry, Pa.
Sorry ain't good enough.
Just lucky Sampson didn't break a leg.
Pa, there was a horseless carriage
right here in Paradise Valley.
This is a farm! Work's got to be
done when it's supposed to be done!
- I hate the farm.
- What was that?
I hate the farm!
I wish you'd sell it. I hate it!
- You don't know what you're saying.
- Yes, I do.
It's nothing. It's just a dried-up,
miserable piece of ground!
You hold your tongue!
There's wood needs splitting.
You go on. Get to it. Go on!
A man works and slaVes to giVe
his son something worth haVing,
and he throws it back
like it don't mean beans!
He's just a boy, Jonas.
He's 12 years old.
Sun will be setting soon.
Trout will be near starving.
I eVer tell you about the time
Pecos Bill wrestled John Henry
at the Upside Down Mountain?
At least 100 times, Pa.
That many?
Well... What about that morning
Pecos Bill spiked Paul Bunyan's
flapjacks with hot chilli peppers?
Bunyan's breath
came spurting out like fire.
Burned down an entire Arizona territory.
I reckon I told you that one, too.
What about the time old Pecos Bill
took on, single-handed,
50 of the toughest, meanest outlaws
this side of the Rockies?
A person would haVe to be a fool
to take on 50 men.
Them 50 Varmints slapped leather,
but before you could say,
"Pass the peas",
Pecos Bill emptied
both his six-shooters.
- Shot off their trigger fingers.
- Their trigger fingers?
It was Sunday.
Pecos neVer killed on a Sunday.
- Pa, it's just a tall tale.
- That don't mean it ain't true.
- It's crazy talk.
- Then Pecos Bill swung his lariat,
roped a passing twister
and rode off into the sky.
- Pa, Pecos Bill ain't real.
- He's out there.
Where there's still enough
elbow room for a man to wander.
He's out there, where the land's
still young and wild.
You don't belieVe me.
I swear to you
by the Code of the West.
Pecos Bill is as real as you and me.
Now, you know the Code of the West,
don't you?
Yeah, Pa, I know.
Respect the land,
defend the defenceless,
and don't you neVer spit
in front of women and children.
Do you want me to bow down
and sell like the rest of 'em want to?
If it means staying aliVe, yes.
Why is it always you that's the hero,
you that sticks his neck out?
Because somebody's got to.
Jonas, no guns!
This isn't a story you tell to Daniel.
It ain't that bad.
You're so quick to risk your life.
What about your family?
What about us?
That's why I'm doing this.
I'll be back before you know it.
Be careful.
I'm selling. Stiles ain't a man
to take no for an answer.
He can't make us sell.
Not if we all stick together.
My pa was a farmer.
I know what it's like to work the land
till your hands are blistered and raw,
hoping the weather won't turn bad,
praying the crop'll come in,
hanging on when it don't.
Oh, yeah...
I know what it's like to be a farmer.
And I got out.
Hallelujah!
Now I'm giVing you all the same
chance I made for myself.
A way out.
50 dollars an acre.
Cold cash. With that kind
of pocket change, my friends,
you can buy yourselVes
a nice new house in town.
Fill it with all the modern conVeniences.
Industry makes them things.
Factories going round the clock.
Oil wells to power 'em.
- That's the future!
- And then what?
And who might you be, friend?
The name's Jonas Hackett.
And you ain't no friend of mine.
What happens after Mr Stiles
and his partners from back east
are all done tearing and ripping
apart Paradise Valley
just like he did in GraVity Valley?
I'll tell you what happens.
Jefferson County will be next.
But, Jonas, 50 dollars an acre!
That's a lot of money.
No question about it.
This is the deed to my farm.
My farm!
It's got my sweat in it.
My blood, too.
It's where my children were born...
..where my father's buried
and it's where I want to be buried, too.
That's worth a lot more to me
than 50 dollars an acre.
It's worth a lot more to me
than any price.
I ain't selling.
Goodnight, Jonas.
- Daniel?
- Howdy, Pa!
- I just heard you and Ma.
- Be quiet and listen to me!
Take this deed. Take it and don't
let anybody haVe it, no matter what!
- Pa...
- No matter what! Understand?
Now go! Go on!
- Pa, listen!
- Go, blast you! Go!
- He don't haVe it.
- The deed. Where is it?
I told you. I ain't selling.
Don't play games with me!
You had it at the meeting.
The kid!
He must haVe giVe it to the kid.
Find the brat. If he giVes you
any trouble, kill him.
Pa!
I'Ve done all I can do.
It's in the Lord's hands now.
Jonas is tough.
He'll pull through.
I'll tell you one thing.
I'm selling. Pulling out.
No piece of ground is worth dying oVer.
Where am l?
Stick 'em up!
Hands aboVe your head. Now!
Zeb, search him.
Search him!
- Get out of this boat, boy!
- Hands aboVe your head!
- What haVe we got here?
- That's mine! GiVe it back!
- That's his. He wants it back!
- Hands up!
I hear some jingle!
We got 16 cents. Hot spit.
Any gold in his teeth?
Open that mouth, boy.
Open it.
I count one... Wider!
Two... Four fillings.
Somebody ain't been brushing!
Grub...
Let me kill this one.
You killed the last two in a row.
That's 'cause I'm better at it than you.
What's fair is fair! How am I gonna
get good at it if I don't practise?
All right. Go ahead.
No!
Should I shoot him
right between the eyes?
So long, kid. Sorry to stunt
your growth!
Now, don't you moVe!
My trigger finger!
Somebody done shot off
my trigger finger!
- Who are you?
- I'm a ring-tailed roarer.
I draw faster, shoot straighter
and drink longer than any man aliVe.
- I ride cyclones...
- Got a name, don't you?
I'm getting to that.
I am the rip-snortingest cowboy
that eVer rode north, south,
east or west of the Rio Grande.
I'm Pecos Bill.
- And I'm Santa Claus!
- Friendly cuss, huh, Widowmaker?
My name's Daniel Hackett.
Well, Dannel Hackett,
I belieVe them Varmints
got something that belongs to you.
Come on, mister. Let us go.
We was only fooling!
We wasn't gonna hurt the boy.
Just one bullet.
That's all it would haVe been.
I ought to plug you two right now,
but I neVer kill a man on Sunday.
But today's Wednesday.
Wednesday?
Please don't kill poor harmless
old bandits like us!
So where you headed, Dannel Hackett?
- Where am l?
- Texas.
- Texas?
- Where did you think you was?
I don't know. All I remember is
falling asleep in Paradise Valley.
My boat must haVe gotten loose.
Drifted all the way down
from Paradise Valley?
I can't explain it, but it's the truth.
Where are you going?
South, down Mexico way.
Mister, I gotta get home.
My pa's bad hurt. I gotta take care
of my ma and my little brother.
You stay here and you're gonna fry
like a bug on a hot skillet.
You best come with me.
Put some muscle into it!
Paradise Valley. My idea of heaVen!
Iron, coal, oil, copper.
Riches beyond the imagination, just
waiting for a few rugged indiViduals
with the Vision, the strength
and the means
to make their dreams come true.
Gentlemen, we stand
on the edge of history.
- What about the deeds?
- We'll haVe them tonight.
- You still don't haVe the deeds?
- It's under control.
What happens if we finish the tunnel
and the farmers still haVen't sold?
This is the West.
Things are simple here.
There's only one law -
winner take all.
And I plan to take it.
You best be right, otherwise
you'll end up back where you started -
just another gun for hire.
By the time that tunnel
breaks through, I guarantee you,
we will haVe the deeds
to eVery inch of Paradise Valley...
..one way or another.
Whoa, Widowmaker.
We'll make camp here.
Good boy, Widowmaker.
Whoa, Widowmaker. Easy, son.
Widowmaker's kinda particular about
folks taking liberties with him.
Last man who tried that,
Widowmaker kicked him so hard
he ended up halfway to the moon.
Name of Lanky Hank.
He bounced up and down
for a month of Sundays until finally
I just had to shoot him down
so he could haVe a proper burial.
The moon's thousands of miles away.
A man could neVer bounce that high.
You sure do know a lot
for a half-growed piglet.
In plain English, stay away
from the horse or he'll kill you.
- I'll try to remember that.
- See that you do.
Kinda makes it all worthwhile,
don't it?
- I ain't going to Mexico.
- Who said anything about Mexico?
We're headed north.
- Paradise Valley?
- You got business to settle.
But why? Why would
you go out of your way for me?
Are you coming or ain't you?
Hackett's farm, right smack
in the middle of eVerything!
Without that deed,
I won't haVe a bucket to spit in.
Well?
Hackett's kid's disappeared.
And the deed with him.
In other words, you let him get away?
Me?
No. The kid got hold of a boat
and he slipped down south.
I want that kid!
I ain't looking for a fight with Stiles.
I just wanna get home.
Sometimes a fight comes looking for you.
Finds you, too,
no matter where you hide.
It would be 100 to one.
Nobody can win against those odds.
100 to one?
Job like this calls for a big man -
Mr Paul Bunyan.
Paul Bunyan? Yeah, right!
Bunyan?
- NeVer heard of him.
- That's 'cause he don't exist!
You ain't heard of Paul Bunyan,
the greatest logger of 'em all?
No.
Come on. Let's haul freight
out of this manure wagon.
Come here!
I hear that you're looking for Big Paul?
- You know Paul Bunyan?
- Know him? By cracky, yeah!
I'Ve flipped more flapjacks
and slung more hash
than you can shake a fist at,
trying to fill the belly of that fella!
- I neVer could, you know?
- Do you know where he might be?
Paul pulled up stakes when
the first machinery moVed in here.
The last I heard, he'd settled
in the Great Redwood Forest.
Well, I'm much obliged to you,
old fella.
Appreciate it.
- Thank you, sir.
- Good luck to you.
He's just an old geezer.
What does he know?
More than you.
Howdy.
We'll take that deed, kid!
Pecos!
- Pecos!
- Hang on, Dannel!
Help!
Pecos!
Let's go, kid. This way.
We gotta get you out of here.
All right now, come on out.
Attaboy, Widowmaker!
Get the hell outta here!
Go down the pipe and keep going.
Say hi to Big Paul, and good luck!
- Get back here, kid!
- What are you waiting for? Jump!
What I can't understand is
how did they know we was coming?
- Maybe the telegraph.
- The what?
They're strings of wire which allow
a man, say in San Francisco,
to talk to a man in New York City.
You're telling me a tall tale!
No Voice can carry that far!
They don't actually talk to each other,
but word has it that that's coming, too.
This man named Bell is claiming that
people can be hundreds of miles away
and hold a conVersation like
they're as close as I am to you!
EVerybody'll know eVerybody else's
business?
There ain't gonna be a single place
left a man could find any priVacy.
I'll tell you about eVerybody -
eVerybody and their dog's
probably after us by now!
It used to be when a man got
a head start, it meant something!
Least we got away.
NeVer enough for you termites, is it?
You swindled me out of my camp,
robbed me of my trade,
now you want my woods, too!
I'm making my stand!
At least if I go down swinging,
I go down like a man!
Hush up, you log brain!
Pecos?
Let me take a gander at you.
You steamin' pile of buffalo pucky.
You're still ugly!
I told Sam.
They're not loggers. They're butchers.
Fancy machines cuttin' down eVerything,
the weak with the strong,
the sapling with the full-growed
so nothing could eVer sprout again.
Sam said I was behind the times.
Me! Paul Bunyan.
The man who inVented logging!
Who thought up
the double-bladed axe? Me.
Who dreamed up the log flume?
Me again. It ain't easy. My head
hurt for days thinking up that one.
What about the grindstone?
Flapjack contest, wedge cuttin',
three point stands? Me, me, me, me!
Maybe I'm just old-fashioned,
but in my day, we didn't kill
the land, we just borrowed from it.
- What are you gonna do about it?
- I'll do as I darn well please.
- The rest can go to the blazes!
- lncluding Paradise Valley?
Paradise Valley? No concern of mine.
You're not Paul Bunyan.
Who says I ain't?
My pa told me stories about Paul Bunyan.
He said that Paul Bunyan was a giant
of a man. He could tame a continent.
Look danger in the eyes
and laugh in its face.
He got those parts right.
Not from where I'm sitting.
Seems to me you're just hiding out,
feeling sorry for yourself.
Pecos, who is this kid?
Seems to me
that you're just plain scared.
You are not the Paul Bunyan
my pa was telling me about.
How old are you, kid?
12.
Do me a big, sequoia-sized faVour.
Stay out of my way if you wanna be 13.
Is that ox really blue?
Of course he is. He was born
during the winter of the blue snow.
MoVe it, Pecos.
- He's feeling frisky.
- You moVe it!
Big blue bag of beef oughta be
haulin' logs, not haulin' ass.
Pardon my French.
Don't you worry, pretty baby.
Papa's here.
He won't let the bad man hurt you.
Watch your mouth, Pecos!
Baby's Very sensitiVe!
We'll catch the ferry at Liberty City.
Home to eVery horse thief
and con artist in the territory!
Who will try his hand against the
latest miracle of modern technology?
I'm offering ten to one odds
that this new machine can driVe
steel faster than anyone aliVe.
Now, come on! There's gotta be
someone here man enough to try!
You, sir? Come on! There's gotta be
someone man enough to try!
My name's John Henry.
And, mister, you got yourself a bet!
I'm offering 12 to one
the machine wins.
It'd be a sucker's bet at 20 to one!
$100 eVen money says he whips
that gol' dang contraption!
EVen money, Pecos?
You can do better than that!
That thingumajigger
looks like it means business.
We'll see.
- You ready?
- I'm missing my shaker.
- Can't driVe steel without one.
- Who'll hold for this man?
And be squashed like a tin can
by his hammer?
There ain't nobody that dim-witted!
Somebody's gotta haVe the gumption!
You can forget about it!
Widowmaker!
- Pecos!
- Sorry, Dannel.
I gotta protect my inVestment!
That's a braVe boy!
How about a round of applause
for this courageous young lad?
May the Lord haVe mercy on his soul!
Mister...
I can't do it.
You don't know what you can do
until you try. Come on.
Come on, boy.
GiVe this drill a shake and a turn
after each time I hit it.
- What if you miss it?
- I neVer miss.
- Leastwise, I haVen't yet. Ready!
- Ready!
Come on!
Four-foot jumper, son.
Make it snappy!
Come on, John Henry!
Paul Bunyan! As I liVe and breathe!
LiVe and breathe later!
You got a race to win!
Time to get serious. Come on!
This 20-pound hammer
Shine like silver
But it ring like gold...
Six-foot jumper, son. Go! Hurry!
Hurry, boy! Hurry!
- I can't do it!
- Come on!
- They're too far ahead!
Come on, son! Come on!
Get up, Dannel! Get up, boy!
The machine wins!
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you
for your time and your money!
- I'm sorry.
- You gaVe it your best shot.
If you gaVe it your best shot,
you ain't got nothing to be sorry for.
Go ahead, Widowmaker, might as well
get your licks in, too!
Looks like the boy's been through here.
Hey! Look at this.
Somebody's finger.
Somebody's trigger finger.
My record was perfect before today.
Now you are foreVer tarnished
with ignominious defeat.
- Come on, fellas. He's just a kid.
- He's bad news, Bill. In britches.
He ain't that...
- What is it?
- Sarsaparilla.
- To the Code.
What do you know about the Code?
Plenty. My pa is always going on
about it.
Knowing about the Code
ain't the same as liVing by it.
Good enough.
To the Code of the West.
- Code of the North.
- The Code of the South.
Respect the land,
defend the defenceless,
and don't neVer spit
in front of women and children.
You just stepped oVer the line, boy!
Well, howdy, friend.
How 'bout me buying you a drink?
Sure. Just as soon as I'm done
skinnin' this marmot.
Holler if you need a hand!
This little saddle sore
ain't worth your time.
- I'll be the judge of that.
- I'd take that drink if I was you.
- So, what are you drinking?
- Whisky.
Jasper, let me haVe some whisky.
Shucks.
Gentlemen, to Texas!
The nearest thing to heaVen
on God's green earth.
You from Texas?
I do haVe that honour, sir.
I thought I smelled something funny
in here.
Easy. Can't scrap
on an empty stomach, you know that.
Mister, are you insulting
the great state of Texas?
The great state of two-bit tinhorns,
you mean?
Mister, you can insult me
and you can insult my friends.
As a matter of fact, you can eVen
insult my mother and my horse.
But don't you eVer insult
the great state of Texas.
You eVen hit like a Texan!
All right. Party's oVer.
Anybody else?
Anybody make a moVe
and I'll fill 'em full of lead,
or my name ain't Calamity Jane!
Jasper...
..who started this confabulation?
Them two.
Where did that other one get to?
Well, paint my toenails and curl my hair!
Calamity?
My cactus flower!
Don't cactus flower me,
you double-crossing dog!
I missed you, darlin'.
If only you knew how much!
I know too well,
you flea-infested little weasel!
Calamity, you look
mighty pretty tonight.
Sweet talking me?
You oVergrown, mealy-mouthed,
two-faced sniVellin' snake!
You gutless, brainless,
heartless sidewinder!
You ain't still sore about Amarillo,
are you?
You had to bring up Amarillo?
What's she got agin you anyway,
Pecos?
I run out on her.
Now, Bill, why would you wanna go
and do something like that?
Calamity's a mighty handsome woman,
Pecos.
Oh, I know.
Well, in her own way.
Buy me a drink, big boy?
Maybe some other time.
What's the matter?
Is it past your bedtime?
The kid ran away faster
than a scared rabbit.
Amen and good riddance.
He bothered me.
Why shouldn't he run? You been agin
that boy since you set eyes on him!
It's Dannel!
Ox! Baby!
How does it feel to be on the wrong
side of the law?
Fine, as long
as my ma don't find out.
I didn't know you had it in you!
That's my ox!
- What's that noise?
- It's coming this way.
Faster, you dumb ox!
- Ox!
- Run, Daniel! Run, boy!
Come back, you lily-liVered cowards!
Stupid ox! Why ain't he pullin', Paul?
Why did he quit pullin', Paul?
It's Very simple. If you insulted him,
you haVe to apologise.
- Paul?
- Mr Pecos Bill.
I ain't apologising to no ox.
Babe, Uncle Pecos thinks you're
the prettiest blue ox he eVer did see,
and he is Very, Very sorry
for any hurtfulness he may haVe
caused you. Now pull!
Yeah! Go, baby!
- Yeah!
- Timber!
Spread out. If you find the boy,
head to the ferry.
Oh, dear!
Timber!
Take that, you pissants!
I'm Paul Bunyan!
I'm 300 pounds of raging fury!
You're in trouble now! Don't point
your gun at me, you sissy!
I can out-eat, out-swing
any one of you! I'm Paul Bunyan!
I got him!
Hold on, you little bandit!
GiVe me that deed!
Nobody's gonna hurt you, son.
Just hand oVer that deed.
- You shot Pa!
- Son, your pa's a fool.
He's stuck in the past and
he wants you stuck there with him.
That ain't what you want, is it?
You don't wanna waste your life
behind a plough!
You want more than that!
You hate that farm.
It ain't nothing but a dried-up,
miserable piece of ground! Now...
GiVe me that deed!
Son, you're trying my patience!
GiVe me that deed
like a good little boy!
Kid, trouble seems to follow you
like a bird dog.
Lucky for me I got my friends!
We ain't that good friends.
Get your carcass off me!
- MoVe it!
- You can't get away from me!
Get 'em!
Come on, boys!
Come on! Come on, Pecos!
Come on! Hurry up!
Timber!
This ain't oVer, kid!
Not by a long shot.
Thinking about your pa?
I used to bait a line with my daddy
when I was a young 'un.
NeVer caught much,
but that was neVer the point.
Seems like fishin's the only time
me and Pa actually get along.
You two lock horns, huh?
As far as Pa's concerned,
- I can't do nothing right.
- My daddy was the same way.
Always telling me what to do like
I didn't haVe no mind of my own.
Exactly.
Although I know I should haVe
finished the ploughing.
I now see he only bothered on
account of how much he cared for me.
Daddy was just doing the best
he knew how.
That's why it grieVes me
I neVer got the gumption
to tell him how I felt about him.
Why not?
Daddy got sold down riVer.
Sold?
We was slaVes.
It's too late for me.
Let's hope it's not too late for you.
First a blasted ox, now a jackass!
Might as well be riding turtles!
- Cold Molasses is a mule!
- I wasn't referring to her!
Shake a hoof! Come sun-up,
we hit the endless desert.
Meanest stretch
of desolation this side of hell.
- Sure is dark.
- Sure is.
I once seen a picture
of New York City at night.
It's all lit up with electric light bulbs.
We could use a few now.
- Electric light ball?
- Light bulbs. Balls of glass
which light up 100 times brighter
than a candle.
- Go on.
- Soon, people won't need lanterns.
Won't haVe to chop wood
to make fires.
You turn a knob and these electric
light bulbs just come on.
But I like chopping wood.
Pretty soon, there won't be
no darkness.
It'll be like noontime at midnight.
How are folks gonna see the stars?
They just won't see the stars, I guess.
Well, I don't like it. No siree bob.
I don't like it one...
If you ask me, I think he's telling
us a tall tale!
Yeah, that's a tall tale for sure.
It's the God's honest truth.
Not see the stars?
It's hotter than a June bride
in a feather bed.
This ain't nothing - not compared
to the summer of '88.
It was so hot that all the chickens
was laying fried eggs.
- Babies was crying sawdust.
- We're out of water!
Things got so bad that the whole
state of Texas lit on fire.
- I hightailed up to Kansas...
- Does this story haVe a point?
Or does it just go on and on and on
like this stinkin' desert?
Yeah, this story has a point.
I blew out the dang fire!
I'm tired of you complaining
and whining all the time!
I'm in the middle of a giant barbecue pit!
I don't know
what will kill me first - the heat,
the thirst,
or your incessant yammering!
Shut up! Shut up!
You oVerblown tub o' lard!
You stay out of this, you contest loser!
What did you call me?
Shut up! You're nothing
but a big fat tub! Quitter! Quitter!
Big fat quitter! Quitter!
Pa?
It's all right, Dannel. Just a mirage.
He was there.
It is amazing, the things
that heat'll do to a man.
I just wanna get home.
Things can't get no worse than this.
- Pecos!
- Good morning!
Early to bed, early to rise,
makes a boy healthy, wealthy...
..and aliVe!
- Touch him and you're dead!
- I got no quarrel with you.
Or your friends.
You got a peculiar way of showing it.
- The deed.
- You can't haVe the...
We don't haVe a prayer.
We neVer did.
If that's your way of thinking,
then we don't.
You don't stop progress, cowboy.
That's the difference
between me and you.
I can adjust to the times.
You can't.
- Don't listen to him, Daniel.
- We can beat this thing.
You just got to belieVe, boy.
Where do you get off
telling me what to do?
Where do any of you get off
telling people how to liVe?
- That's the spirit!
- Don't lose the dream.
You don't know
what you can do until you try.
You are all nothing! Just a bunch
of tall tales that my Pa made up!
And you are nothing but hot air.
I ain't got all day, boy.
Time is money.
Don't do it, Dannel.
I am a ring-tailed roarer.
I draw faster, shoot straighter...
This 20-pound hammer
Shine like silver!
I can out-eat, out-swing any man aliVe!
I just wanna get home!
I'm the rip-snortingest cowboy
that eVer rode north, south,
east or west of the Rio Grande.
I am Pecos Bill.
Pa?
MoVe it!
No!
Ma!
Daniel!
I'm back! I made it back!
Your father, he's gonna be all right.
Pa?
Daniel.
Pa, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
It's all right. I knew you didn't
mean any of those things you said.
But I did, Pa.
I told Pecos you were stupid
for standing up like you done,
but I was the one who was being
stupid, Pa. I was being a fool.
- Pecos?
- Pecos Bill.
You had a talk with Pecos Bill?
Pecos Bill, Paul Bunyan
and John Henry were all there.
They were just like you said, Pa.
Well, now, where was this?
It was in the desert.
Redwood Forest, Liberty City.
- The Great CaVerns.
- You coVered a lot of territory.
We had to. Stiles and his gang
were on our tails the whole ways.
JP Stiles?
But it's OK,
because the deed's right here.
The Valley's still right here
and we still got a chance to saVe it.
Daniel...
- You don't belieVe me?
- You fell asleep on the boat.
But, Ma, they were there.
They was as real as you and me.
Pa, you belieVe me, don't you?
Yes, son. I belieVe you.
We still got the deed, Pa. I don't
know how, but we still got it,
and JP Stiles ain't getting this farm.
Son, you did fine. You did just fine.
Not that it matters any more.
Pa, it does! It does matter.
It matters all the world!
We're selling.
No piece of land is worth dying for.
I guess it's about time
you faced up to that, too.
You're giVing up?
Wisin' up.
No, Pa.
No, Pa. The land's defenceless!
Pa, if you giVe in, you don't know
what's gonna happen here!
Daniel, you heard your father.
Now let him rest.
Ma, somebody's got to do something!
Daniel, please.
Gentlemen, to your health.
The West, indeed!
That kid's blocking the tracks.
Well, I see your pa's sent
a boy to do a man's job!
I come on my own accord.
The time for deeds is oVer, kid.
Get off the track.
I'm telling you to get
out of Paradise Valley.
A little speck of dust like you.
You really think you can stop all this?
Well, maybe not, but I sure
am gonna giVe it my best shot.
All right.
HaVe it your way, then.
Run him oVer!
I said run him oVer!
Get off the track, Daniel!
Don't be a fool!
- Daniel!
- Help!
Help! Help me!
God help him.
What the hell?
John Henry! Where haVe you been?
Just waiting for you
to make your moVe, Daniel.
to make your moVe!
Kill them and be done with it!
Hold it right there!
I got no fight with you.
No, defenceless young'uns
and farmers are more your style!
Mister, you just killed yourself.
My trigger finger's gone!
Well, come on!
What are we waiting for?
More steam!
100 dollars an acre!
I'll pay you 150 dollars an acre!
200 an acre!
300! 500 dollars an acre!
One more oughta do her.
Boy! Be reasonable!
You know we're gonna win in the end!
Stop!
Just stop.
All right. I admit it.
You got me oVer a barrel.
My back's to the wall.
Name your price.
I ain't interested!
You fool!
There'll be others just like me!
And more after them, and after them.
Long as there's a profit to be made,
we'll neVer stop.
We're coming!
Not through our land!
Daniel!
- We did it.
- We sure did!
Kinda makes it all worthwhile, don't it?
It's a right nice sunset, huh, Pa?
Yes, Daniel.
It's a good one.
Well, time to call it a day.
Come on.
Let's get washed up for supper.
You coming?
You go on.
Think I'll just stay here a piece.
Pa?
I loVe you, Pa.
I loVe you, too, son.
We come to say goodbye, Dannel.
I knew you would.
- Thanks, Paul.
- Thank you, Daniel.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
Thanks to you, I got my old appetite
back again.
Baby and I are gonna head
up to the Alaskas.
Hear they got some little tiny
forests ain't eVen half-growed yet.
What about you, John Henry?
I'Ve been thinking about a rematch
with that there steam drill!
- Well, if you eVer need a shaker...
- I'll keep you in mind!
I'm much obliged, too, Dannel.
To the Code!
You done right. I thought it weren't
possible to do right no more.
- Now, 'cause of you, I know it is.
- You're the one who did eVerything.
Widowmaker.
So long, Widowmaker.
So long, boy.
Well, hop on.
- Me alone on Widowmaker?
- Lessen you don't haVe a mind to.
OK, up you go.
He's all yourn, Dannel Hackett.
Pecos!
So long, Dannel!
Take good care o' Widowmaker!
- Pecos, don't go!
- Don't worry about it.
You can handle things from here!
I am a ring-tailed roarer!
I draw faster, shoot straighter
and drink longer than any man aliVe.
I'm the rip-snortingest cowboy
that eVer rode north, south,
east or west of the Rio Grande.
I'm Pecos Bill!
So long, Pecos.