Come on, boys, yah, yah!
Let's go!
Look at 'em, Cage!
Ready to bust loose!
Pretty soon they'll be jumpin' fences
Tomorrow we'll let 'em run, not today
A little rustle in the air, boys,
time to get inside!
Ain't they somethin', Billy?
Have you ever seen horses like 'em?
Not quite
Come on, get inside!
Let's get into town
and out before this hits.
Jacob! How's the missus?
Glad to see ya!
Hey, sir. Hey!
Hello, Mr. Ballard
Howdy
My God! Looks like half the association's
shown up. We appreciate it, gentlemen
Mr. Ballard, we're gonna win this fight!
Thank you! And you, sir
Good luck to ya, Ballard, for cuttin'
Carey Sartin off from water.
You just bought that tract to spite him
Morgan! Pete!
Well, lookey here
Ya didn't need it!
Hope it makes ya fell good
You sayin' a man can't buy land when he wants to?
I'm sayin' Carey's hard workin'
I think you've gone a little bit too far this time
Ballard
Now come on, Shelby
Let's be friends, huh? Nobody wants
that old rock garden of yours anyway
Be friends. Hm?
C'mon!
Kermit Dover! Get out here!
Excuse me a moment on a sweet Sunday when I
oughta be home restin' my poor old bones
and you makin'
a fuss over a petition for statehood
Where'd you get this idea?
Oh, it's in from Cheyenne, all official
Henry
Who says it's official?
Judge Wilkins seen it,
that good enough for you?
There's a delegation comin' in from Washington
in a month to make Cheyenne the capital city
Look who signed up, Slater!
Hunter Jarvis
Big and bold like a John Hancock
That Slater
Morrison looks like he's sideways on alcohol
Now you suppose
he just forgot the good turn we done him
when he got flooded out last
Spring and the bank said no?
Hunter?
I need to remind you of somethin', Hunter!
Hunter has gone!
Oh, he probably heard
I was gonna come and reason with him
What do you think about that, Ollie?
Look like a three-dollar bill to me
Mr. Ballard
Uh, Myrl, how 'bout you?
You're a smart young man with a future,
where do you stand?
Statehood ain't worth fussin' over
Cora, let me help you
Thank you
Is that so?
It's gonna happen. No matter what next year,
five years from now
I wouldn't waste your sweet Sunday
worryin' about it, wait it out is my thought
And the vermin'll sweep in like a grass fire
The only people I see around here
are hard workin' Eye sores and riff-raff
You talkin' about me?
Whadya say, Cora, do I look like an eyesore?
No, sireeee, you're a handsome man
and my sweetheart forever
Smart little lady
Honey, Cage is waitin' for us.
We gotta get movin'
Hey, you're a horse trader?
You pull your weight in town
unlike some other folks
But I don't need no strangers
from Cheyenne come in
and tell me who I got to neighbor with...
...Where to put my road, my fence
tell me what's mine, and what ain't
I founded Rawlins, I made it!
I thought Indian traders
and trappers come here first
I put my roots and my law done here, boy,
when you still just a pup
I got a wife and two sons in the ground
Now your bein' new to the territory
Maybe you oughta plant your feet
and take a stand
Well, to say the truth, I wasn't gonna...
sign the petition for statehood
I didn't think it was that important
But since you put my character to the test,
y'hand me that paper you got there,
Kermit, and a pencil
Sure
Here you go
I'm a free man like you, Ballard
I can say yes, and I can say no
I say yes to statehood
I bought a lot of horses from you, boy
From now on, maybe you oughta try
to sell 'em in Cheyenne
If you can get there
Doesn't matter one way or the other where
I sell 'em, Mr. Ballard
I give you the same fair price
I give everybody.
Now if you got some other stand you'd like me
to take I'd be more than glad to accommodate you
Let's go, Myrl. Will ya, please
let's go!
Good afternoon
Thanks, Myrl
Myrl
See ya, Myrl
Bye, Cora
Take care, Myrl
You didn't sell no horses today
I said what was true
You don't always have to say what's true
I'll do better at the auction in Casper
That man's sure got a bug up his twirl
He's runnin' for somethin', isn't he?
You showed him up in front of town,
he ain't gonna forget that
Ah, he'll get over it
Come on, boys.
Right over here!
I know how ya feel
But that's the way it is with
the horse trade, Cage
Grow to love the animals you raise
but there comes a time
when you gotta sell them
We need cash to run the farm,
pay wages, y'know?
That's the way it is
You got it, that's the way it is
But be happy with what you and Billy did,
theses are beautiful stallions,
beautiful horse flesh
You're gonna make Clay Williams happy
and we're gonna earn
a profit to buy the land we need
Right?
Yeah
Y'see that dog? You wash him
I'll sell him, too
Come on, now! Get on it!
Safe trip
Be back in few weeks, sooner if
the weather holds
Take care of your momma, Cage
Sure, Pa
Surprise me with a present, Myrl
Like what?
Ooh, like, uh, uh, some nice soap
uh, maybe something sweet, and, uh...
Oh, uh, uh, a bicycle!
And, and some of those fancy bloomers
from the Sears Roebuck catalog!
And, and an Otis elevator like they
have at the World's Fair in Paris
Oh! And don't forget lamp oil!
What?
Don't forget lamp oil!
Lamp oil!
Otis Elevator!
Come on, now! Step up!
Hey, Myrl!
Has Woody always been a dusty old cuss?
As far as I know
Hey, Billy, I was thinkin'when
I get to Casper, I just might grab me a bath
Come on now, step up! Here we go!
Step up now, come on!
Straight on through, come on now step up!
On time, straight on through now
Step up! Come on, get on up there!
How you figure that, Myrl?
C'mon
Good lookin' fence you got,
Slater, what's it for?
Keep rustlers out, mistah
I didn't know Ballard owned this land
Yeah, he bought a new parcel,
it's all official. Paper 'n all
It's cost you ten dollars to come through
Ten dollars?
Yes, sir
This pass is closed, Mr. Redding
You ought not got too far, Ballard
How's that?
Puttin' up a fence and chargin'
Well, rustler like to slip in pick off strays
I get the fence, all right
but what about the ten dollars?
Keeps the riff-raff out
You're makin' trouble, is all
Look, I got no cause with you horse traders,
you come and go as you like
Where are you headed?
Casper, for the auction
Mind if I, uh, take a look at what you got?
Lookin's free
How much for these blacks?
They's sold
A little knot-headed, but put a pistol to my head,
I'd give ya... fifty each
What do you think, Ollie?
We need work horses
Yeah, we do, and since you ain't
heard the new rules 'till now
I'd be willing to let you come and go two
no three times, for one of them blacks
No sale
Then it'll cost you ten dollars to pass,
pay Slater
I ain't got ten dollars to give cause
I gonna pay for food and lodgin' in Casper
Then go around
I go around and the auction's over before
I get there!
That ain't my doin'. Ten dollars
Ooh, I near forgot
You're gonna need a permit
You gotta have one, gotta be... official
I musta crossed here
fifty times without a permit,
where am I supposed to get a permit?
Well, you can see Judge Wilkins in Rawlins,
or you could, uh get one in Casper
Yeah. Elmo Whitaker
in Casper he'll write you one up
You know Elmo, dontcha?
I'll give you five down, the rest when
I come back. Good enough?
How do we know you're comin' back this way?
Because I said I would
Maybe the horse dealer
could put up some security
Hm. Now that is a good thought, Ollie
You know, uh, I try to be a reasonable man
I'll go along with ya.
Just leave the two blacks
and pick 'em up on your way back
Take it or leave it, I ain't got all day
Billy, cut the blacks off the string and leave 'em
Don't leave the stallions here, Myrl
You can put up the roans if you have to
the blacks is promised to Clay Williams
Leave 'em, or go the long way around
Don't do it, Myrl
I ain't got no choice
I ain't got the money,
and the auction's in a week
You stay with them, Billy
we'll pick you up on the way back
I ain't feedin' no Crow
Naw, he gotta sleep in the barn
Take what you need from the pack horse
Been a real pleasure doin'
because with you, Mr. Redding
Let 'em through, Slater
Son of a bitch!
Hey, come on now! Let's turn this thing over
and get this outta the way!
Mr. Redding's gotta come through
No way! He's gone too far
Pretty soon we'll be goin' around
the Rio Grand to get to Casper!
I mean, if he thinks...
Hey, Myrl?
What?
Y'know, there ain't no use payin'
Attention to that old man
Whadya make of all this?
Like a church with no roof
Got the Almighty braggin' his head off
Yeah. Whadya figure he's sayin'?
Remember who did this?
Don't get too big for your britches.
I guess
Fair enough
CASPER
Hey! 171, 80. Look at this...
Now 80, now 90!
One, two hundred dollars...
Howdy, Browder!
Myrl!
Seen Elmo Whittaker?
He's over there, somewheres
Whadya say, Partner?
Woody!
Good to see ya!
Here we go, there it is
Hey
Yes indeed-y
Yes
Where's the stallions?
Henry Ballard got 'em
I thought Myrl promised them to Clay Williams
Oh, well Ballard's holdin' onto them
as security 'till Myrl pays him
a toll for crossin' his property
I heard about that gate.
That one's crazy tryin' somethin' like that
Yeah. Myrl's pretty angry about it
I don't blame him
Hey, Browder, you...
...you ever hear tell of one of them
English dogs, one of 'em
Jack Russell Terrier dogs?
Can't say I have
Well, they say,
if'n you get 'em riled up enough,
and they sink their teeth into ya, well now
you're just gonna have
to saw theirjaw apart 'fore they let go
Well, that right there
is Myrl Redding right about now.
A man with a bull head and a Jack Russell jaw
Quite a sight. I'll see ya
Come on!
See ya later
He told you to see me?
That's what he said
He's fuckin' the dog on ya, Myrl
There ain't no such thing as
a pass for a pass.
He owns the land, all right,
he been buyin' land like
it's goin' outta style, but I don't know
what this permit crap is all about
Includin' that parcel around the pass?
Oh, yeah
So he can do what he wants with the land?
Unless the Governor steps in,
but that's a long wiggle down the road
How's business, Elmo?
Pretty good
Cheatin' the hell outta them, are you?
Only them that tries to cheat me
Take care
One hundred twenty five
and one half, one sixty, one seventy.!
Hundred and fifty seven, hundred
and sixty, hundred and eighty...
One hundred, two hundred and fifty
That's it, and I got mine
Okay
What'll I tell Clay Williams?
Tell him I'll be back in the Spring,
I'll have the horses for him
if he still wants them
He still wants 'em all right
Tell him I mean to keep my word
All right
Pleasure doin' business with you
Have a safe trip
Take care, Woody
Browder
Slater! Slater!
I come for the horses, Slater
You owe me five dollars!
Pay him
Billy! Billy!
Where are they?
They're around
Billy!
They ain't in here, Slater!
I said they're around!
Woody, check the corral
Billy!
Easy now, easy. Easy now boys
Bastards
Easy now, boy, easy. Easy, easy
It's gonna be all right,
it's okay, all right
It's all right. Easy now. Easy now, boy
Ho! Easy now, boys
Come on, come on. It's okay. Com on
Oh, Christ!
It's alright
Easy now
Slater!
Come out here, boy, I wanna talk to you!
Those are not my horses!
What'd you do to my horses?
Oh! Jeez!
Huh? What'd you do to my horses?
I didn't do nothin'
why don't you ask your Crow!
I will when I find him, where is he?
Jesus, I don't know!
He was makin' trouble!
They have sores on them!
Tied to a pig sty!
Cause your Crow took off
I can't take care of 'em by myself
You been workin' in the fields, Slater!
What's the trouble here?
Listen,
I shoulda put the dogs on him, boss!
What did you do to my animals?
Now, he's bitchin'
about me workin' his horese too much
He says they ain't his.
Maybe he wants you to buy 'em
I wouldn't sell you a coyotel!
Did you get his five dollars?
Yeah, he's paid up
Then get your horses and git
I can't move 'em cause they can't walk and
I ain't gonna injure them any more!
I left you with well fed and healthy horses
Ballard, and I want 'em back that way
Them is all you gonna get!
These are not my horses!
I don't even recognize them!
You got two weeks to put back into condition!
Two weeks! Two years!
I ain't gonna condition nothin'!
Two weeks, old man!
You got somethin' you wanna say to me?
Yeah, I'm tired of your
statehoodin' mouth in your spittin' image
Ballard, healthy and fat!
Git!
Myrl...
Where's Billy?
He's inside
Where is he?
He's, he's in the kitchen
Billy
Myrl, sorry about the horese
What happened?
Slater. Sl-, Slater run me off
Why?
Long as I was there
he couldn't work the blacks to death
I told him they were young
and and they'd never been in harness
He, he tied them to a pig sty
in the mud wouldn't take the harness off
After a week they were filthy
And one day I came out,
and he had 'em hooked up to a log pull
Come on, now! For Chrissakes!
What the hell is goin' on here?
Get over here!
What the hell is goin' on!
Then that old Slater
and Ollie they beat me
Then he set them dogs on me
Get him! Get him!
No!
They mighta killed me if
I'da went back there
You did rigth leavin'
Why don't you let Billy eat
I oughta kill him
Boy!
What?
Why don't you let Billy eat
Yeah
Rest easy
DAMN IT!
What're ya gonna do?
Get my horses back the way I left them
And damages for Billy
Ballard ain't gonna do
that cause you tell him to,
and pay Billy to boot.
He'd be the laughin' stock of Rawlins
You're settin' yourself up for a fall, Myrl
Ballard ain't gonna do
what you want him to he just wont'!
Yes he will!
You got chores to do, boy?
Yes, sir
Then get to 'em!
I dunno, Myrl.
Ballard's got a lot of friends
I wanna know what the law says I can do
Well, you could sue him
Then I wanna sue him
It's not as simple as that
Why not?
Well, you gotta figure on things like
how much it's gonna cost you, can you win?
I don't care what it costs
Myrl, you go up against Ballard in
this town you're gonna go through Judge Wilkins
Now Wilkins got shares in
Ballard's cattle association
I want my horses back in the condition
I left them in! And damages for Billy!
Do you wanna handle it?
Jesus, Myrl! You're askin'
Wilkins to rule
for you against Ballard in an
Injun against a white man?
I believe that God
is to man as man is to animal
You treat them with respect
You set dogs on a man, you pay for it
Now the law upholds these ideas
And I mean to see the law has its day
Do you wanna handle it?
I'm tryin' to tell you somethin'
here if you'll listen.
You're wastin' your money!
I'll file if you want me to file.
It'll cost you twenty dollars in advance
Twenty dollars
In advance
Half now, and the rest when
I see what you come up with
Now you file it!
Sure
Two boxes, here we go, Myrl
Good to have you back
I think you paid up last time
so we're gonna start fresh
Okay
Mr. Redding!
You got two swaybacks stinkin' up
Mr. Ballard's stables
I appreciate it if you pick 'em
up real soon, y'hear?
Otherwise, we're liken to...
chop 'em up for slop or somethin'
All right, Slater
You wanna take it on back to the room?
Kermit, next time
Ballard or one of his fools comes in,
tell him the law will take care of Ballard.
And if the law don't take are of him,
I'm gonna take care of him
One way or the other,
there's gonna be justice I will have it.
Ballard himself is gonna feed
and groom my stallions,
make 'em shiny and beautiful,
just like I left them
And no matter what it cost
me that's gonna happen. Sure as sunshine
Will you tell Mr. Ballard that if you see him?
Yeah
Hear me, I speak the truth!
And poker as usual, at my place
Tuesday night
I appreciate the help, Judge
Ah, you're welcome
Oh, Judge! Judge Wilkins
I was just comin' up to see ya!
I don't have time for you today, Rayborn
Come around next week
But... but I'm w-, w-,
waitin' on your decision, Judge
It's been a couple of weeks, now
It's been a coupla weeks now, Judge
My client's getting'
awful nervous about this
Sit down, Rayborn, you make me nervous
Yes sir, Judge
Just waitin' for you decision, Judge
I uh, I hope the petition
is in proper legal form...
...and where a justice
of your integrity is used to seein'
Nothin' special, it was okay
You talked this petition over with
Redding?
Yes, sir
Seems like a pissy ant fuss to me
Redding wants to file a suit or
is that your idea?
Oh well, no
I gave him counsel to the contrary, Judge
His mind's made up
Tell him to take his horses home and forget it
Well, you see,
my client views them as prize stallions, Judge
Prize is in the mind, counselor
Ballard don't want 'em,
so what's
Redding gonna do, leave 'em there?
Well, it's like the charges says...
I know what the charges say
Yes, sir
Follishness,
prideful follishness is what this is
If I was you, I'd talk sense into him
I got five towns to cover,
counselor and you bring me this
I don't have time for a hearing
Fifty dollars for Billy Redwood, a Crow?
Jesus
Yeah, well,
I gave him honest realistic counsel on that
You did, uh huh
Uh huh. He wants it filed
Uh, just, uh, just wondering
when you want a hearing, that's all
Uh, well, you don't have
to decide right now just when you get a chance
Ain't gonna be one
I'm throwing the case out, lack of evidence
I advise you to tell Redding
to pick up his horses and get on with his wife
Yes sir, Judge
And I advise you
to pick your clients more carefully
if you want to do business in this town
Yes, sir
You're haulin' shit up a mountain, Rayborn
Careful it don't spill on you
Shit up a mountain. Thank you, sir
Hey, Myrl, word is Ballard's still
workin' them horses out in the field
Where'd you hear that?
Mac Turnage comin' through Casper
Says he saw 'em, thought they
were yours maybe not, though
Just take him longer
to put 'em back into shape
Well, there ain't nothin' more
I can do, Myrl
Except, maybe... uh, Billy!
Leave the room, would ya
I wanna say somethin' private
Anything you got to say
to me you can say in front of Billy
Well, word I get is
Ballard wants to do business with you
He wants to settle with you
on the horses but he won't pay Billy
Why not?
Well, Billy gave him trouble and run off
Billy didn't run off!
Ballard's fools run him off!
The suit stands the way it's writ
Well, then he won't settle with you
it's gonna be a standoff
Not to my mind
Well, what else you gonna do?
Whatever it takes
Cage, you want more stew?
Please
Are we ever gonna get our horses back?
I don't know, Cage
Now you sleep tight
you let me worry about it
I'm goin' to Cheyenne to see
the Governor before any of this happens
Or whoever runs the law and...
if that don't work, I'm thinkin' about it
Doin' it all over again, ain't ya?
Don't ya know me?
You know there's no way
I can let a man do what that man did
That is not possible!
I know you
If people are gonna kick me
I'd rather be a dog than a man, Cora
So if justice is to be done
don't deny me the freedom I need to get it!
No! This is not just about you
and what you think is right!
I'm a part of you and so is Cage
We just get thrown in, is that it?
Cora, please, keep you voice down
Cage is listenin'
I'm not sayin'
you shouldn't go after Ballard
but... you're doin'
exactly what he wants you to do...
to scare people away
Let me try somethin', Myrl.
My way. Lf, if it don't work, then
Then you do what you have to do
I'll stand with you, no matter what
What are you talkin' about, Cora?
You know
I'm better at politicin' than you are
Let me go to Cheyenne for us
I know the Attorney General's wife
Judith Metcalf
I met her at the Statehood Rally last year in Casp
I spent the whole afternoon with her
She'll get the petition to her husband
That'll be the end of it
You get the horses back
the way you want 'em, and somethin' for Billy...
Cora, this is not your fight
IT IS MY FIGHT! It's my family!
Look out that window
If you don't stay here and fix the barn
we're gonna be livin' hand
to mouth before you know it
I've been prayin', for a miracle
So there'd be peace between
Ballard and me
But nothin' comes back. No answer
No ways to go, nothin'!
I'm your miracle. I'm what you prayed for
What sort of woman is she
the Attorney General's wife?
She's a fine woman
Her husband?
Mm, I'm sure her husband is fair
I don't know, Cora, what you're askin'...
The truth is...
I got a terrible fear you go off chasin'
Ballard, I'll never see you again
You're getting' sassy with your old man
is what I'm hearin',
you better watch that
So it's all decided
I'll be back in two weeks
I'll take Woody with me
I'll see the Attorney General
and I'll get the lamp oil you always forget
Two weeks is a long time
Mm, nothin' like a little separation
to make the heart grow fonder
Also, I'm smarter than you
when it come to politicin'. Di...
Or did I say that?
Yeah, I think you mentioned that one
You're a miracle, all right
Take care of my bride, Woody
You betcha
If I meet a handsome cowboy,
I may go right on to Phil-l-del-phi-ay
Well, if you do, send Woody back
I need him for the roofing
Wouldn't be jealous, would ya?
No
Better come back, hurry up, lose my man
Get down offa there, son!
Cage, kiss your mother, get off there!
Cage, go on now,
get outta here. Go on, now!
You go work on that barn
See ya, Myrl
Bye boys
Come on, come on
Haul it in before you let go!
Push it up again!
Cora, I'm gonna go over to the blacksmiths
All right
I'll come find ya
I'll be here
These the original documents in the case?
Excuse me one moment, Mr. Crawford
You're next! Now, okay
I will take these under
consideration for the Attorney General
You are Mr. Wakefield, is that correct?
Mr. Wakefield? Okay
You might wanna take a seat,
we'll get to you as soon as we can
Look! Look!
We started to,
we started to go off to the one side
as we were comin' up over the last hill
Hey, I think we gotta go visit
an old neightbor of ours
Mr. Metcalf, please
You have an appointment?
No, I don't
All these folks have appointments, ma'am
You need to write ahead so
we can give you a time
Mrs Lipton, you're next!
I come from Rawlins to see Mr. Metcalf
Do you, do you think you could make
an excption in my case?
This week is outta the question
He's across town with the statehood people
Judith Metcalf said any time
I was in Cheyenne to come look her up
Sorry. Nothin' I can do
My name is Cora Redding, from Rawlins
My husband is Myrl, the horse dealer
Maybe you know him
No ma'am, I surely don't
Well, Mrs. Metcalf does
And she would want to know that
I'm in Cheyenne
So, could you please see
that she gets this?
I'm staying at the Wainwright Hotel
It's important that she get this message
Thank you, Captain
No end of 'em
Yes?
Well, we rode that up
a little way, didn't we?
You okay there, hoss?
Hey! Hey, get the hell outta here!
Woody!
Someone get a doctor!
She's still breathing
Cora?
Call Doc Patterson
What happened?
She got run over
Who is she?
Her name is Cora Redding, from Rawlins
She come here to see the Attorney General
Well, sir, I'm the Attorney General
She come here... to give you this
Hands are warm
Okay. Okay. Okay
Crazy bastards out there!
It hurts awful, Woody
Oh, I know. I know. I let you down, Cora
I'm so sorry
Don't let me die here
Oh no, you ain't gonna die
I won't let you die. We gotta go home
Hang on, and go home
Everything's gonna be okay now
The Attorney General's go Myrl's petition
Everything's gonna be okay
Uh, this petition doesn't belong here
It's under, send it to Wilkins
Judge Wilkings in Rawlins
Yes, sir.
Private!
Yes, sir?
Put that in the pouch to Rawlins
Hey, everybody! Ma's comin'!
Hey, yeah! Look at that, right on time!
I swear, your mother clocks
better than Union Pacific, Cage
What happened to my wife?!
Oh... Cora, Cora...
Cora?
What happened?
I'm so sorry I wasn't there for her
I'm so sorry. I should never have left her
It's all right
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry
You weren't lookin' for trouble
I'm so sorry
Be, be praised my Lord for those
who forgive through your love
and bear sickness and tribulation
Blessed are those whoe endure in peace
for they will be crowned by you, Most High
Be praised, my Lord for our sister bodily
death from whom no living thing can escape
Blessed are those whom
she finds doing your holy will
for the second death cannot harm them
Ante up! Nickel ante
Mr. Ballard, five-card draw
Then what happened, Ollie?
Woody started it
He said I smelled like pig slop
I stroked him a good one
Oh! It woulda pleasured me
to have been there to see that
Yes, sir
Take my advice, you steer clear of Redding
Sent his own woman to
Cheyenne to beg for him
Yeah, yeah
What kinda man do a thing like that?
Keep buyin' as we been doin'
and next year there'll be nothin'
but pasture form here to Landers
No way they can stop us, even the statehood
Accordin' to you, Mr. Ballard
Keep the land rollin' in, that's the ticket
Calm everybody down
That means you, Ollie
You and Slater. Good things are happenin'
we don't need trouble
Uh, is that a quarter to me,
or to the Judge?
Your quarter
A quarter to you, Judge
Another one?
Shelby!
Hey, bro
How are you?
Shelby, this is your chance
I know you been wantin' to expand
You wanna sell out?
Maybe
After all you put into it?
Well, yeah
I'm interested, Myrl, I'd be a fool not to
but I gotta, I gotta think about it
You come on me all of a sudden
The whole lot
You seen this
you know what I'm talkin' about
I know it's prime, all right
The whole lot
Gimme a hand
All right, Hattie
You're serious
I got Rayborn workin' up the papers now
You've been a good neighbor, Shelby
I wanna give you first crack
You're talkin' the whole spread?
And what's on it
Well, Myrl, I am gonna tell you up front
I don't have a need for all them horses
No, no, the horses ain't part of the deal
I got plans for the horses
So what we're talkin'
is the price of the land
And what's on it
I come up with three dollars an acre
Three dollars an acre?
Tha's a fair price, Myrl
You betcha, that's awful good
As long as you understand. Cash on sight
Why are you doin' this, Myrl?
I mean, you got water.
You got one of the finest
tracts of land in Rawlins
I mean,
if it's all because of Ballard, hell
I mean that land is your future
There rae bigger things than land
I'll haop you out
Want a cup of coffee?
Thanks
Myrl
Edsel
Hello
Hello, Mr. Rayborn
Cage
What did he say?
Well, Attorney General
sent you petition back
I mean, he's awful sorry about
Cory and everything,
but he had to turn you down
He says it's a local matter
and it's up to Judge Wilkins to decide
That's the law, see,
and he's gotta obey it
Just like you
What are you tellin' me?
Well, uh, Wil-
Wilkins already ruled, so... that's it
I put in a lot of time on this, Myrl
Have you?
Yeah
How much do I owe you?
Twenty-five
Plus what you already owe
Hi, boys
That's all I got,
I'll give you that rest later
I won't be needin' you any more
I'm awful sorry about what happened to Cora
That's an awful thing to happen
Just awful. Whole town's upset about it
If there's anything I can do, just...
I wrote somethin' I want you to read
Tell me what you think
I, Myrl Redding, by authority in...
born in me as a free man...
A free man living in a free territory
...demand that Henry Ballard
within seven days of receiving this not...
...bring to my stables
the horses he took from me,
groom and fatten them with
your own hands to the condition I left them!
And to injuries caused to
Billy Redwood who did nothing to you,
pay him fifty dollars!
It is signed
Myrl Redding owner of the horses!
Let the law take care of it, Myrl
There's no way Ballard's gonna do what
you tell him to do just because you say so
Yes he will. And if he don't
I got plans to convince him
Anyone want to hear
the particulars come to spread at sundown
and I'll spell it out for you
I hold no man responsible for
the death of my wife but me.
I let her go
And I gotta live with that
the rest of my wife
Judge Wilkins!
In a town where there's no law,
a man is obliged to make his own
Isn't that the way it works around here?
Wouldn't you say, Judge Wilkins?
Seven days
Henry Ballard! Come talk to me!
I'm delivering a notice of law on you!
You got sever days to read it, and answer it
Seven days, and I'm comin' for ya
I shoulda killed him
Now, Shelby'll deposit the rest of
the money in your name in the bank in Casper
If I need any, I'll come to you
But remember, it's your money
Why can't I just go with you?
Well, I need you to stay here with
Mr. And Mrs. Dykes do I don't worry
All I want is to go with you, Dad
It's yourjob now to hold down
the fort 'till I get back.
I mean somebody's gotta
take care of the spread
Now that's a big responsibility,
do you understand?
Sure
Cage, do you understand?
Well, but, but all I want is to help you
I know. I know
Hell, we all know it!
Ballard's gone too far
Yes, he has
Puttin' up a toll gate
Decidin' who's to pay, and who ain't
If he can get away
with what he done to Myrl
then he can do whatever the hell he wants
It's time we all woke up!
I know you're all real busy
so I'll get right to the point
I'm invitin' you to ride
with me against Henry Ballard
No. Wh-, what Ballard did to
Billy and your horses sure was bad.
Now I'd like to help,
but this ain't my quarrel
You're right, Dewey, it ain't your quarrel
But there'll come a time
and this toll gate is just a start of things
when Ballard decides to box you
in some more, maybe take some of your land
or cut you off from water
like he did Cary Sartman
Then you'll come and say
Looky here, Myrl, look what Ballard's doin'
I need you support.
And I could say to you
Dewey, it ain't my quarrel
I run a horse farm. I live over there
Two hour ride
But until statehood comes along
all we got is Ballard's law!
That's right!
And there's no future in it!
And I did not come fifteen
hundred miles to tolerate that!
I ain't lookin' for a shootout!
Well, neither is Myrl!
That's right!
Overpower him with numbers that's the idea
scare him into doin' right
Folks like you and me comin' after him
No bloodshed
What if he runs?
Let him. We'll follow till we find him
Damn right
How long will it take, Myrl?
Maybe a day, maybe two, maybe longer
I don't care, I'll provide
the horses and grub as long as it takes!
It takes money, Myrl
My spread's for sale
Shelby and I worked out a deal
Every man Jack of ya gets
fifteen dollars a month
for as long as it takes to bring that
man in alive and workin' in these stables!
Myrl means business!
I'm for it! I'm sick of Ballard beatin' us!
I know men who'd ride against him
Bring them along.
Now if you don't wanna go, it's okay with me
I'm goin' after Ballard anyway
And if you don't wanna go
on principle then go for money,
cause I pay cash on the barrel head!
Fifteen dollars!
He ain't comin'! Who's he gonna come with?
Well, he's got Woody, and an Injun
He shows, he goes home in a pine box
Hey! Hold up there!
Mr. Ballard! It's Redding
and he's got a whole army with him!
He's got a hundred men with him
Mr. Ballard, get outta here! Go!
Get 'em up in the bunkhouse tell
them to et their guns on! Hurry up!
Go on! Get the hell outta my way! Git! Git!
Hey, get back here! Get back here!
Get back here you sons of bitches,
where you goin'?