THE OKLAHOMA KID
Subrip: Pix
The gentlemen of the press, Mr.
President.
Good. Let them come in.
President Cleveland will
receive you now, gentlemen.
Gentlemen,
I'm at your service.
Mr. Cleveland, we'd like to
know what you're going to do
about the Indian
appropriations bill.
During my previous
term in office,
I was opposed of the opening
of any Oklahoma territory
to white settlement
because I felt the terms
were unfair to the Indians.
The cherokee strip
contains 6 million acres
of the finest
farming land in America.
It is our last
free frontier.
It's 180 miles long
and 50 miles wide,
but both houses have
now approved the measure,
and since I happen to believe
that the will of the people
is properly expressed
through the congress,
I will sign the bill, and I'm
issuing this proclamation.
That's it, boys. They pay off
the injuns, and we move in!
Get that cherokee
silver, Joe. We're in.
Right.
Who'll sign
for this money?
I will.
Hear that stuff clink
when they set it down?
Yeah. I kind of
like that sound.
Good luck.
All right, throw down
those guns. Get 'em up.
Now fork over
those moneybags.
Unhook this lead horse.
All right. Come on.
Come on. Get up.
Hey! Hey!
Whip, it's a holdup!
All right,
get cover, boys!
Come here.
I've had time to survey
the whole cherokee strip,
and as most of you know,
the section we've chosen
is perfect for a town site.
It's flat, and there's
plenty of water.
The Texas cattle trails
run down through here,
and the sante fe railroad can build
their line down here from Wichita.
And they will
build it, too.
We'll give them a decent town
and decent trade.
All around are thousands of acres
of the richest land in Oklahoma,
and it'll all be peopled
by this time tomorrow...
Folks that will need doctors,
lawyers, merchants.
It's a new start
for all of us,
but it's going to mean
a lot of hard work,
and it's going to mean sticking
together for the common good,
and it's going to mean
getting there first tomorrow.
Now, there
may be some trouble
because I've been watched
and trailed by men
who probably aim to beat us
to our town site,
but they won't,
for when that shot is fired,
my son and I,
with our fastest riders,
will race across prairies
and stake a claim.
The rest of you can follow
with wagons and camp equipment.
Now, is that clear?
Yeah.
All right, then.
Good luck to everybody.
Let's take
a look at that map.
John, you know
I envy you.
It's a great plan. I wish
I could be with you.
You will be
later, judge.
Pop's counting
on you bringing law
into this territory,
judge.
That's going to
be some job,
judging from the scum of the
west I've seen drifting in here.
Won't be too big
a job for you, dad.
You think one poor old judge can make
the whole robber's roost behave?
If anybody can.
Seems I've raised
an optimist, ned.
Come on, John.
There'll be a lot of changes
in our lives after tomorrow.
First, you'll be riding
circuit with your father,
and I'll be helping
to start a new town.
Aren't you thrilled?
I would be if it didn't
mean us being separated.
Tulsa will spring up
overnight, ned,
and we'll soon be settled there
with father holding court
and sending dangerous
outlaws to jail.
I soon as I get there,
I'm going to claim the most
beautiful spot of all for us.
Ned,
isn't it wonderful?
A whole new life
ahead of us,
a whole new city,
and soon
a new state,
and it all
begins tomorrow.
Get your partners
for a dance!
Ned, let's dance.
One more couple
right over there.
That's it.
Well, here we go!
Salute your partner.
Forward dance,
swing on the right.
Swing on the left.
Hold the man proud and tall,
and swing him round.
And forward and back,
swing on the right,
now on the left.
First lady and last gent,
forward dance.
Do-si-do.
The next lady and the last gent,
forward dance.
Do-si-do.
Now, then...
All join hands
and circle to the center.
Grab right, then left.
When you reach your partner,
everybody swing to the right.
Now to the left.
Have...Have you
seen who's here?
Take her to your arms
and swing her all around.
Who's the stranger
with Jane?
I wouldn't know.
How'd we get
in here?
Well, I don't know.
Beautiful
night, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Just feel that air.
Feel that air. Go on.
What?
Feel that air. It's
like velvet, isn't it?
What's the matter
with you?
Can we go,
darling?
So soon? Let's
stay a little longer.
Hello, ned.
Surprised?
Hardly. I expected you to
show up sooner or later.
You know each other?
Yes, but ned's a very
funny kind of fellow.
Doesn't
like to admit it.
Your father's
waiting for us.
Wait a minute. I haven't thanked
the lady for the dance.
Thank you, milady.
May I look forward to again being
favored next time we meet?
You're a lunatic.
'S crazy.
Did ask you
to feel the air?
Why, yes. Who is?
Someone I'd like
to forget.
But I told you, we ain't
got no rooms left.
I didn't ask
you that.
I asked you which was the
best room in the house.
Number 6, and there's about 18
boomers sleeping in it right now.
But that's our room.
I told you we couldn't
hold nothing, miss.
I told you, you had to
sit in it to keep it.
The town's overrun
with boomers,
and if you ain't there,
they are.
What's this
about our room?
I told you we couldn't
hold nothing.
I'd be glad to let you
have my room, ma'am.
Well, that's
very kind of you.
Thank you, but
we couldn't put you out.
Wouldn't be
putting me out.
Just a minute. What room
do you think you have?
Number 6, and you're
very welcome to it.
See here. I told you who
was in number 6...
About 18 boomers sleeping
on the floor, 3 deep.
That's all right. They'd be
glad to do a favor for a lady.
That's awfully
generous of you,
but I really don't
know how to thank you.
Not another word.
Just leave it to me.
Hey, what's
going on here?
Come on, you mavericks!
On your feet!
The land rush is on!
Come on!
They've fired
the starting gun! Come on!
'S taking me home
to his house.
The soldiers are all bunched
on the immigrant line,
but on the other side
of the creek,
they begin thinning out to
one soldier every 50 yards.
Two.
We can slip through
there tonight
and be on the inside,
waiting for them.
What about this
"sooner" law?
Once we've staked out a claim,
they can't prove a thing.
Well, what are we
waiting for?
We're waiting for the line to
thin out so we can slip through.
Bet $10.
That's brand-new
money.
Where'd you
get it, mister?
Minted it myself
this morning.
Well, aces always
beat kings.
Whip, I just seen
one of the fellas
that took that
Indian money off us.
Yeah? You sure?
'S playing with a lot
of new-minted money.
Play that for me,
will you?
Sure.
Where is?
That little fellow
over there with the piano.
Say, do you know, I don't
want to play in your yard?
They don't
want that tonight.
Play it.
Not tonight,
brother.
Play it.
Sure, that's
one of my favorites.
Yeah, it would be. You
know who that is?
No.
That's
the Oklahoma kid.
Handley.
Tell that little squirt
over by the piano
I want to see him.
Put it away,
handley.
Kid, I want
to talk to you.
Keep on playing.
I said I want
to talk to you.
Well, go ahead
and talk.
My name's
whip mccord.
That mean
anything to you?
How's that?
Mccord.
Mccord, mccord,
mccord....
I don't like it.
Do you?
I want that
Indian money.
Well, go and get it
from the Indians.
Kid, I'm giving you a break
'cause I'm pressed for time.
Don't you raise
that bottle at me!
Give me
that bottle!
Go on.
Get over there.
Get over.
That's a boy.
Play, professor.
Hi, sheriff. I'm
glad you got here.
What's it about,
mccord?
You looking for the man
that held up the stagecoach
and got that
Indian money?
Naturally. What's that
got to do with it?
That's him
just left here.
I called him on it,
and started shooting.
How'd you know him?
How else would a man
get new-minted money?
'S been spreading it
all around the joint.
That's right.
We all seen him.
Who was?
The Oklahoma kid.
The Oklahoma kid,
yeah.
Let me take a look
at that silver.
I'll show you.
Let's compare
watches, captain.
Here's ned.
Hey there!
Well,
how are you, judge?
Get there first, ned.
We will, and don't be too
long coming to our city.
Get it built first.
It's almost time to sound
the warning signal.
Sound the attention.
Good-bye, ned,
and good luck to you.
You're my good luck.
Bye!
Come on, ned.
Starting gun goes off
in 5 minutes, boys.
Wait a minute, pop.
Wait a minute.
What's your
best whiskey?
Kentucky bourbon,
11 years old.
I'll try some of
your bar whiskey.
Want to catch
that stampede?
Go ahead.
I'll hold down the bar.
Thanks. Have a drink
on the house.
Squad, ready.
Squad, fire!
Hello, young fella.
Never got to thank
you for the rooms.
Don't mention it.
Where's
the bartender?
Outside watching
the rush, I suppose.
It was a great
sight, wasn't it?
I don't know.
I didn't see it.
You didn't see it?
No. I thought I'd have me a
quiet little drink instead.
What'll you have? I'll serve
you. It's on the house.
Here, try some of this
uncut moonshine.
Got some taste to it.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
How come a strong, healthy
young fellow like you
isn't out there up to his
neck in this land rush?
Why? I'm doing
all right.
Those people are going out
there to build a new empire.
Fine.
Let them have it.
You mean to say you've got
no feeling for the country,
no pride in seeing a civilization
carved out of a wilderness?
What sort of
an American are you?
I like
the country fine.
As for civilization, I've got
nothing in particular against it.
I can take it
or leave it alone.
What sort of folks
did you come from?
The most god-fearing,
law-abiding,
land-grabbing, empire-building
fellas you ever saw.
Suckers for this land-rush
stuff, too, but not for me.
I crave a nice easygoing
existence, and I've got it.
I see. No responsibility.
No ambition.
None of this get-up-
and-get-it stuff
that regular
folks have.
Exactly, and that's why my folks and
I have been on the outs for years.
You seem like a very
antisocial young man.
But I'm not. I'm as
social as a setter pup.
I like all kinds
of people,
but I don't take
to this itch
for plowing up
new empires, that's all.
But why not?
I'll tell you
why not.
Now, look.
In the first place...
The white people steal the
land from the Indians, right?
They get paid
for it, don't they?
Paid for it?
Yeah.
A measly
$1.40 an acre,
price agreed to
at the point of a gun.
Then the immigrants
sweat and strain
and break their hearts
carving out a civilization.
Fine. Great.
Then when they get it
all pretty and prosperous,
along come the grafters and
land-grabbers and politicians
and with one hand
skim off the cream
and with the other,
scoop up the gravy.
Not for me. Listen.
I learned this about human
nature when I was about so high,
and that is that the strong
take away from the weak,
and the smart take it
away from the strong.
I suppose you never
heard of the law
that protects people's
rights and property.
Yeah, I've heard of it.
I've seen it work, too.
Sometimes,
it's all right.
In the cities,
maybe fine,
but here,
you can't trust it.
This is the only law
that I know
that's worth a hoot in
this part of the country.
The only law.
This is wasting time.
Come on. Let's have a drink.
Hands up.
Hello, Abe.
Hello, Sam.
Howdy, judge.
Will you kindly remove
those irons, please, sir?
Why, certainly.
Excuse me, son.
This young fellow
a friend of yours?
Well, not exactly. We're just
having a drink together.
'S got some very original
ideas about life.
I wouldn't wonder.
Just keep them up, son.
Don't start any trouble.
Well, what's up?
I'm Abe Collins.
Who?
Abe Collins.
Is?
Yes.
'S the sheriff.
Now, look here. You dropped
some new-minted money
last night in a Blackjack
game, didn't you?
That's right.
What of it?
Nothing, only it happens to be
part of that Indian consignment
stolen from the stage
yesterday evening.
Well, it seems like law
won out, even out here.
We've been waiting a long
time to pick up this boy.
Is that so?
Well, 's
an amiable thief.
So pleasant about it all.
Who is?
We don't know his right name,
but throughout the territory,
's known as
the Oklahoma kid.
All right, kid.
Good morning, ma'am.
Good morning.
Lovely morning.
Father,
what's happened?
Seems that our young friend
is the Oklahoma kid.
Whip,
here they come.
Sorry, gents.
I'm afraid you're trespassing
on private property.
Sooners?
No. We just got here ahead
of you. That's all.
We led the field all the
way, nobody else in sight.
We'll have you sited
at the land office.
Now keep
your shirt on.
There's no sense
in starting any trouble
when everything can be
settled quiet and peaceful.
The only way to
settle this
is for you
to get off our land.
Your land?
Here's our claim stake
sticking right up here
in front of you.
You won't get
away with this.
I think we will.
We've already got a man halfway
back to the claim office.
You're licked, Mr.
Kincaid, and you know it.
Hey, what are
you after?
Nothing much. We just heard you were
figuring on building a town here.
That's all right with us.
All we want's
a part of it
and the exclusive rights
to any saloons
or gambling houses
the town might need.
Who are you?
Where are you from?
Whip mccord
from the panhandle.
What's
your proposition?
You go right ahead and build
your town and attract settlers.
So you can take away their
money at faro and roulette?
Yeah, that's the idea.
You take care
of their virtues.
I'll take
care of their vices.
That's simple, ain't it?
We'll fight you through
the courts first.
You aren't going to do
yourself any good in court.
You can't start building
until the title's cleared,
and you know how long
that'll take.
Meanwhile, some other town
will be years ahead of you.
Anyway, why fight?
What's a few hundred
foot of business frontage
to an empire builder
like you, Mr. Kincaid?
All right.
Pick out your ground.
Right here, and here's a
waiver of right to protest
under the sooner law,
so that everything
will be fair and square.
Hey!
All right, boys.
'S only a floater.
Get on with your play.
Shootings, killings,
robberies,
and a mighty orgy of
drunkenness, gambling, and vice
all directly traceable
to mccord's influence.
Why, owns our mayor, our
sheriff, and half our deputies.
Yes,
they make arrests,
just enough to save
their faces,
but we can't convict
because, despite my efforts,
juries are bribed and
witnesses intimidated.
I say we need
a showdown.
Either mccord
and his crowd
run this town
or we do.
It's time
to find out.
I know.
I've been wondering how much
longer this could go on,
but we made a mistake
in the first place
in making a deal
with him.
Now, what do you
suggest?
I say we should form
a vigilance committee.
No, no. That would only be
one mob fighting another.
We represent
law and order.
We've got to take control
away from mccord legally.
We've seen these gamblers
and criminals make our city
the nesting place
for all the scum of the west.
We've seen vice
and corruption flourish
and our officials
do nothing about it.
We've seen murders committed in
our streets and public places
and the murderers
go unpunished.
We can't tolerate
this condition any longer.
It's up to you, men, as voters,
to stop this lawlessness.
I ask you to elect me mayor
so I can clean out mccord and his
gang of thieves and murderers.
I ask you to elect
my son sheriff.
All right, boys,
break it up.
Mccord!
Breaking up
a few speeches
isn't going
to save you.
In the end, I'll see
that the law gets you,
and it won't be just to
run you out of town.
It will be at the
end of a rope.
We ought to do something
about Kincaid, whip.
'S likely to get up the vigilantes
like they did in dodge city.
We'll do
something.
We'll get him on the
end of that rope,
and it'll be
in his own
law-and-order
fashion, too.
What's the matter, Jose?
You don't like music?
You don't like
the music?
All right,
come on.
Come on over here
with me.
I'm going to sit
down here.
I'm going
to sing to you.
Come on.
Ho ho ho.
All right.
You don't mind
if I sing, do you?
Hey, now.
Once again, now.
How's that? You like it?
All right. Come on.
Everything's all right.
Come on. We're going to get
a nice sleep?
We're going to get
a nice rest, aren't we?
That's a good boy.
Callate!
Shut up.
It's Pedro.
It's all right.
You get everything,
Pedro?
- Si, senor.
- Everything.
Here's the dinero,
senor.
Gracias, senor.
Pedro...
Pedro, saddle
my horse.
Si, senor.
You go?
Si, manuelita.
You no stay
for dinner?
No, gracias.
You come back soon?
Yes, very soon.
Manuelita, take care of these
things for me, will you?
Adios.
- Adios.
Morning, friend. Where's the
jailhouse in this town?
Right up the street.
You can't miss it.
Glad to hear that.
How's that?
Is that where they're
keeping old man Kincaid?
Yep, smack-dab in the
front cell upstairs
where folks
can stare at him.
All right. Thanks.
You're a stranger
in town.
That's right.
Seems like I've seen
your face someplace.
Well, I wouldn't
know that.
I've been
a lot of places.
Hyah! Come on!
Holy smoke!
Now, son, I wouldn't
worry too much.
Who was that?
Why, it was the kid.
Who, the kid? It couldn't be.
Wouldn't dare.
Why, i...
I guess
you're right, ned.
I must have been
mistaken.
Now, about the trial.
With judge hardwick on the bench,
there's nothing to alarm us.
Dad, you're covering up.
It was him, wasn't it?
Sheriff, the Oklahoma
kid's in town!
I knew it!
I saw him myself!
Where are you
going, ned?
I think I know
where 'll be.
Wait. Don't do anything
you'll regret.
What are you doing here?
Hello, ma'am.
Came here to see you
and talk to you.
You shouldn't be
in Tulsa.
The whole town is
plastered with posters
offering a reward
for you.
I saw them... every one an
insult. A measly $500.
Well, you'd better
come inside
before someone tries
to collect it.
Won't you come in?
You're still
as crazy as ever.
Thank you, ma'am.
I...
Very pretty.
This is aunt Maggie.
How do you do,
aunt Maggie?
The hem
got loose, and...
I see.
Well, excuse us,
aunt Maggie?
We'd like
to be alone.
There you are.
Now you can stop
blushing.
Did you say you
wanted to talk to me?
Yes, I did.
As a matter of fact, I want
to talk to your father.
Isn't here. I don't know
where I can reach him.
You could help me
if you wanted to.
They tell me that the candidate
for mayor is in jail.
Is that why you came?
Yes, strangely
enough, it is.
I don't like to see
anybody in jail.
You can understand
that, can't you?
I never know whether to
take you seriously or not.
I'm absolutely
on the level.
I'd really like
to help him.
It's not going
to hurt anything
if you tell me what you know.
Please.
Well, they say killed
a man, a Mr. bates.
Let's not mind what they say.
What does say?
Says that bates
sent for him.
When arrived at bates'
house, found him dead.
A few moments later, mccord and
some others of his crowd came in.
They've sworn that Kincaid had the
gun in his hand when they entered.
Why?
Because they want him
out of the way.
Thank heaven my father
will be the judge.
Then you don't think they'll be
able to get away with anything?
They most
certainly won't.
Well, that's all
I wanted to know.
'Cause if
you're satisfied...
I mean, you and your
father are satisfied
the old man didn't
do the killing.
Of course didn't.
'S not that kind.
My kind?
Yes, your kind.
Thank you, ma'am.
Why are you making this
your business, anyway?
Because happens
to be my father.
Your father?
Hey, hey, hey.
Go out this way,
through the back door.
Here's a chance
to get yourself 500.
- Good-bye.
Jane, I want
to talk to you.
What's the matter,
ned?
Where is?
Who?
Sorry, aunt Maggie.
I'm looking for
the Oklahoma kid.
I don't know who
you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
You remember him.
Danced with you that
night in cherokee city.
Yes, I remember him,
but...
Well, 's here.
In Tulsa?
In this house.
Why, it's ridiculous.
Isn't.
Jane, look at me.
I told you
isn't here.
Don't you
believe me?
I'm sorry.
Ned, why didn't you ever tell
me that was your brother?
How did you know that?
I'd rather not say.
Then was here!
Yes, was.
Why did you deny it?
Because was your brother, and
I wanted him to get away.
Are you sure that's the only
reason you wanted him to get away?
Yes.
Where did go?
I don't know.
Ned, why didn't you
tell me about him?
It's just that dad and
I don't think of him
as a member of
the family anymore.
Is that bad?
Wasn't as a kid.
We were great pals then.
But as grew up,
everything changed.
Got so thought
the law was meant
for one thing...
Just to be broken...
So finally dad had
to throw him out.
Why are you
so interested?
I'm not. It's just that
's your brother and...
Jane, you know how
I feel about you.
Of course I do.
I would have spoken sooner, but I
wanted to get myself established first.
Please, ned,
not now.
Jane, will you marry me?
Ned, let's not
talk about it now.
Come back later,
tonight.
You are upset
about Jim, aren't you?
Jim?
That's the kid's name.
Perhaps it is,
ned.
I don't know,
but please go.
All right.
Think you ought to
take him up on that.
I thought
I told you to go.
And miss all that wonderful
lying you did for me? No.
I wasn't lying
for you.
Now you really are lying,
like a gentleman.
Then it's lucky there's
one gentleman present.
You mean I didn't thank you?
Well, I do thank you.
I really think you ought to grab
ned off. Make a great catch.
Sober, serious-minded, industrious...
Law and order himself.
Good-bye, ma'am.
Where are you going?
I'll be around.
I'm going to give your father's
justice a chance to work,
but it had better work.
We haven't got
a case.
I've known this fella
hardwick for years.
You can't get
to him.
Hasn't bothered
us much so far.
That was different. We were getting
people off, not convicting them.
It's easy to fake
a prosecution,
especially when
the witnesses are fixed.
Why not? We own the
jury, don't we?
It won't get to the jury.
If we'd used some cleverness in framing
this thing, we might have had a chance,
but with the case we've got,
hardwick will throw us out of court.
Well, then, we'll
get rid of him.
Use sense,
whip.
I am.
Regardless of hardwick,
Kincaid's going to swing.
We'll start a run
on that bank of his,
and when it goes down,
we'll take it over.
We'll get the rest of those upright
citizens one way or another.
When we end up, this will
be my town, wide-open,
with more money pouring in
than you ever saw before.
In the meantime, we've still
got to worry about hardwick.
Yeah.
How long
have you known him?
10 or 12 years.
'S from Kansas City.
There's nothing on him.
I've tried that before.
Has got
any relatives?
Yeah, a brother. Feed
merchant in Kansas City.
All right. We'll get
hardwick out of the way.
You have the trial moved
up a couple of days.
I think
I can do that.
That'll give us
Morgan for the judge.
Doolin, get me a boy
we can trust...
Somebody that isn't
known around here.
All right, come on.
Get moving.
All right, write a
letter to hardwick.
We'll make it look as though
it came from his brother.
I'll have a friend of mine
mail it from Kansas City.
This is bad news,
judge, very bad.
I'm extremely sorry.
Well, of course,
I'll leave immediately.
I'll catch this morning's
stage for Kansas City.
Yes, I suppose you must,
but what about Kincaid?
I'll have plenty
of time
to get to Kansas City and
back before the trial.
Watch over things while
I'm gone, will you?
Of course.
All right, boys.
Everybody up!
It's on the house...
A celebration!
Here's to Mr. Ringo, the
smartest lawyer west of Chicago!
And the trial set up for tomorrow
with judge Morgan presiding.
Hooray
for Mr. Ringo!
This can't be true.
I just received a postcard this
morning from uncle Stephen.
'S not dying, and 's
not in Kansas City.
'S in Montreal.
You think
him trick?
Of course it is, to get
father out of town.
When did
the stage leave?
Maybe 4, 5 hours ago.
Get my horse saddled,
quick!
Good morning, ma'am.
Kind of a hot morning
to be riding so fast.
Please don't stop me. I've got
to catch father. The trial...
Just a minute. Get those
words out one at a time
so I can
understand them.
Yes, you should know.
Somebody's tricked father
with this letter.
It must be mccord.
Not a word of it's true. It's
just to get him out of town.
Why?
Mccord owns judge Morgan,
that's why.
They've moved the trial up to
tomorrow. Morgan will preside.
And they'll railroad
the old man.
Unless I can bring father
back in time.
Look here, you go on,
get back to town.
Back to town?
Get hold of the old man's
lawyer. Show him that.
Tell him 's got
to delay that trial
if you got to pull a trick out
of the bottom of the bag.
But father...
I'll go after him,
bring him back.
I'm kind of handy
at stopping stages.
All right. I'm so
glad you saw me.
I see you more often
than you know.
I said I'd be around,
didn't I?
Hello! Hey, wake
up in there!
Hello in there!
Hey, wake up!
Who is it?
What do you want?
- Stage go by here?
- Yeah.
- How long ago?
- About two hours.
Put up the gun. I want
a change of horse.
I'm willing
to pay for it.
Which...
Hyah!
All right, boys.
Throw them down.
The rest of you
can take it easy.
All I want is judge hardwick.
Come on.
Well. You?
Yep. Put them down, judge.
This is no holdup.
Well, what is it,
then?
This may surprise you, but right now
I'm working for law and justice.
Your brother
isn't sick at all.
Mccord sent you that note
to get you out of town.
How did you know
about that note?
- Your daughter told me.
- My daughter?
Yeah. She didn't like the looks of it,
and I did a little investigating.
Mccord has had the trial moved up,
and judge Morgan is presiding.
- Morgan?
- Yeah.
That sounds like him.
What's your interest
in this?
My name is Jim Kincaid.
Are you
John Kincaid's son?
Yeah. But this is wasting a
lot of good time. Come on.
Have you got
another mount?
No, but we can pick one up at a
settler's cabin down the road.
All right, boys,
on your way.
Hyah!
Handley,
take the stand.
Raise your right hand.
Do you swear to tell the
truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the
truth, so help you god?
You say that Mr. bates was
alive when you left the house?
Yes, sir.
Showed us out.
Ned tolley
can tell you that.
Saw bates come to the door
and say good night to us.
I object, your honor, to the
witness testifying that...
Overruled. Proceed.
Mr. tolley saw bates
see you out.
Yes, sir.
What did you do then?
We walked on down
toward the square.
I happened
to turn around
just in time to see Mr.
Kincaid go into the house.
Then?
Well, that kind of
worried us.
We knew Kincaid had
it in for bates...
I object, your honor,
to the witness...
Overruled. Proceed.
So we went back.
Just as I got to the
door, I heard a shot.
We busted in and
found Mr. Kincaid
standing in the
center of the room
with a gun
in his hand
and Mr. bates lying
on the floor dead.
What did you
do then?
Naturally, we looked
to see if was dead.
Was.
We took the gun away
from Kincaid
and sent for
the sheriff.
Not ned... the old sheriff,
hartley.
Kincaid came up the steps to
mccord and said to all of us...
Well, anybody could tell you
what said.
I object, your honor, to the
witness testifying that...
Overruled.
Proceed.
Well, said, "I'm going
to get you, mccord,
"and I'm going
to get bates, too.
One way or another,
I'm going to get you."
So, gentlemen, if you think the
defendant did shoot and kill Mr. bates,
you can find him guilty
of murder in the first degree.
On the other hand, if you think
did not kill him
and there's any reasonable
doubts in your mind,
you'll find him not guilty.
The jury will retire.
Your honor, I don't think there's
any need for the jury to retire.
We can take a vote
right here.
I'm so glad
you're back.
Where's dad?
Stopped at the bank to see Mr.
Martin. Well, what's happened?
Has the trial started?
It's all over.
They found him guilty.
It was the worst kind
of a farce.
They'd hardly let
Mr. Martin speak.
Well, I guess
I'll be moving along.
Don't do
anything foolish.
It seems to me that's just
what I've been doing,
riding around trying to catch
the law by the coattails.
Perhaps dad can get
a new trial.
Perhaps can prove that
this one was illegal.
Perhaps, but you can't expect him
to lean on any of these people.
Jim, think of your father
and how feels.
'S an honorable man.
'S lived with the law.
Yes. I think
's very lucky
to have a no-good son to
see doesn't die by it.
I don't think 'd
get much satisfaction
out of having
your father, the judge,
read blackstone
at his burial.
Hyah!
Get them up.
Over here.
All right, out.
Come on.
Is that cell empty?
Yeah.
Now, where's
my old man's cell?
Who?
- Kincaid.
- Your father?
Where's his cell?
Upstairs, in front.
Get in.
John Kincaid?
Hello! Here!
Hello, pop.
Jim!
Come on, pop. I'm taking
you out of this tin can.
No,
you're not.
Come on,
get into that coat.
I don't need
your help.
Wrong again.
If you're going
to depend upon the law,
you're going to wind up
on the end of a rope.
Hey!
Go to the bank
and get the sheriff.
The kid is breaking
Kincaid out of jail.
And here's one for you...
The kid is Kincaid's son!
What's that?
Yeah. Now, get going!
I know you mean well, but there's an issue
in this town you wouldn't understand...
Law or anarchy.
I represent law and order.
You don't. You never have.
I'm not here to argue
right from wrong.
Do I have to hit you over the
head or carry you over my back?
That's the only way you'll
get me to go with you.
If I let you take the law in your hands,
it would be an admission of my guilt.
You see, Jim,
it isn't only my freedom
that I'm fighting for.
But they've
got you framed!
Sheriff, the kid's
got the keys.
Went upstairs
to the old man's cell.
Come on!
So long, pop.
Good luck, son.
Locked the deputies
in the cell
and went upstairs
to get Kincaid.
What do you think? Kincaid
is the kid's old man!
Say, that makes it easy.
That's a jailbreak.
This time, we'll be
the vigilantes.
Men, come over here!
Come in close!
You all know
the Oklahoma kid?
Yeah!
Well, I just heard that the Oklahoma
kid is old man Kincaid's son.
And what's more,
the kid's in town right now,
trying to break
his old man out of jail!
Old man Kincaid
was convicted of a murder.
A jury made up of you men
said that should hang.
Yes, of course should!
Are you going to stand by and let an
outlaw take a murderer out of jail?
No!
If the law won't
stop him, we will!
Right. And if the law won't hang
Kincaid, then it's up to us!
And if we get the Oklahoma kid,
we'll hang him, too!
Are you with me?
What are we waiting for?
Let's go!
Go with them
and keep them hot.
Come on, boys,
for old man Kincaid!
Looks like
a hanging party.
Mccord gang's
in the lead.
Think this will
fit him, boys?
Let's go up and try it
out on old man Kincaid.
They're on their way
to the jail.
Come on, boys!
Come on, where
are those keys?
Come on, boys!
Here is!
Where's the kid?
I don't know.
Was here,
wasn't?
Yes.
Helping you to escape.
Wanted me
to go with him.
That's all
I wanted to know.
Listen to me, in
the name of the law!
Shut up!
Hello, Jane.
Do you know where
my old man is?
'S in there.
Jim, they've killed him.
The mob broke
into the jail, and...
Who was it?
Mccord?
No, his gang, but
mccord wasn't there.
Do you know
who was there?
There was doolin, curley,
Indian Joe, and handley.
Doolin, curley,
What are you going
to do about it?
I'm going to the territorial
governor in the morning
and insist put this
town under marshal law.
A little bit late
for that.
Then we'll go after the ringleaders
and bring them to trial.
You better do it fast if you
want to get there ahead of me.
Father stop him.
Stop him!
'Ll be killed.
You couldn't stop
him now, Jane.
I don't know as I want to.
Come on,
get over there.
Over.
Now,
where's mccord?
Ain't here.
And curley,
doolin, and handley?
They ain't here either.
Indian Joe?
Where's mccord?
I don't know, kid.
Who did the hanging?
It was mccord, wasn't it?
Was in on it.
I don't know, I tell you.
I don't know.
All right.
Come on down here.
Now, you can tell mccord
and the rest of his gang,
I'll be calling
on them, too.
Great bunch of quitting rats,
the whole crowd of you.
A couple of hundred men,
and the kid walks in
and picks off Indian Joe like
it was a shooting gallery.
We didn't have
a chance, boss.
Now, look, get out!
The kid said was going
to get us all, whip.
Named every one of us.
Are you
turning yellow, too?
No, but don't you think
we ought to duck,
at least till
the law gets the kid?
No.
I'm staying here.
This is my town, and nobody's
going to run me out of it.
The kid wants to shoot it
out with me, I'll be here.
How do we stand
legally?
Just like I told you,
you weren't there.
You're all right unless somebody
can prove you started it.
They can't prove that unless
somebody says something.
No.
There ain't nobody
gonna say nothing.
But the boys here are not
in such a good spot.
There was a big
crowd there,
and some of the citizens
must have recognized them.
I'm going to
hit the trail.
Might be best
if they all did.
I don't want any
part of that kid.
I'm with doolin.
I think we better go.
- All right.
- Go ahead, run out.
If anybody talks, you won't
have to worry about the kid.
How far is it
to burden?
That's over the Kansas
line about 30 miles.
You figuring on getting
there tonight?
How many horses
you got?
None. Just a mule,
and 's lame.
Go on. You two better get
out of here. Go on. Go.
Where's doolin
and handley?
How should
I know?
You were in on the hanging,
weren't you?
No. Give me
a chance, kid.
I'll give you the same chance
I gave Indian Joe.
Go on, reach for it.
Well, if you don't reach
for it, I can't shoot you.
What'll it be?
Whiskey.
Right.
Come out
and get me, kid!
Aha!
I didn't do it, kid.
I didn't...It was mccord.
Mccord...Water...
It was mc...
It was mccord...
First Indian Joe...
Then curley.
The list dispatched from
Kansas City simply says
they found handley's body
in the freight yards
with the neck broken.
Yeah, but, judge, you
know as well as I do,
the kid got him
just the same
as got curley
and Indian Joe.
Yes, I know.
And one of these
days we'll hear that
doolin has gone
to his reward...
Whatever that
may amount to...
And then we'll chalk up
another for the kid.
Yes, it's a puzzle to know
how to feel. A man's torn.
One side of him says it's a
frightful thing for a lad
to be piling up such
a record of bloodshed,
and the other side of him
says, "go get him, kid.
Get doolin next."
If only we could get
evidence against mccord
and bring him
to trial.
Martin, you know,
that ned has worked as hard
as any man possibly could
these past few weeks.
It's impossible
to get evidence.
The mccord gang is a closed
corporation of closed mouths.
If we don't hurry up,
the kid won't leave anybody for
us to get evidence against.
Jim.
Hello, Jane.
Is your father in?
'S inside
with Mr. Martin.
I've got something
that'll interest him.
Jim, you shouldn't
come here.
Do you realize there's
a price on your head?
Yeah, yeah. Look, I've
got doolin outside.
- Doolin?
- Dead or alive?
A little bit of each.
But I think may be revived
enough to bring his voice back.
What did you get
out of him?
The whole story, and I don't
think I'd like to hear it again,
so I'll leave him
in your hands.
Take doolin down to the jail
with ned. I'll be right down.
Well, in that case,
I'll be going, too.
Jim, what are you
going to do?
I've got a date
with mccord.
Son, I know
just how you feel.
In that case, you won't hold me
up with a lot of talk, will you?
Haven't you
done enough?
I haven't done anything,
except kill a lot of
coyotes in self-defense,
if you want to
put it in law talk.
Please wait.
It's no use, Jane.
Would it mean anything to you
if I asked you not to go?
Don't talk like that.
You and ned are...
I love you, Jim.
You don't know
what you're saying.
I'm no kind of a man a woman
could tie her bonnet to. Ned is.
Women are crazy.
That's why they fall
in love with the wrong men.
But they do.
Now will you stay?
No, no. I've started
a job, Jane.
I've got to finish it.
It's a small point
of honor
that maybe a woman
wouldn't understand.
All right, Jim.
I'll try to understand.
There's only one thing
I want, really,
and that is for you
to come back safely.
Give me some of
that water, will you?
Take it easy, doolin. Tell me one more
thing, then you can have a drink.
I'll tell you everything,
only give me a drink of water...
Mccord responsible for
that lynching or not?
Water, please.
Mccord responsible
for that lynching?!
Yes, of course was. Was
behind the whole thing.
Excited
the boys to do it.
That's all
you need, ned.
Here's our witness.
Give him a drink.
I'm going down
and arrest mccord.
Water.
Whip, I saw the kid.
Brought doolin
into town.
'Ll be
coming here next.
All right, fine.
I'll be glad to see him.
Now, you two boys
go outside,
and when the kid shows up,
make sure you draw first.
Make sure your aim
is good.
Leave it to us,
whip.
We'll watch him.
Mccord, you're
under arrest.
Get your hands up
and walk toward me.
Look out, kid.
Good work, ned.
Good work.
Yeah. We make a good team
when we're working
on the same side.
Now, don't talk
anymore.
You're not hurt
much.
I'll go and scare up
a sawbones. Come on.
No, wait.
I must tell you now.
I wrote the governor,
said you'd been working
on the side of the law,
asked him for
a pardon for...
Never mind that.
You'll be all right.
Just get up here,
and I'll get you.
I'll get you.
Remember when
we were kids,
you fell out
of the apple tree?
I had to carry you home
that time.
Yeah, sure, ned.
I remember.
One good turn deserves another.
Come on, now.
Easy. I'll
get you home.
I'm sorry, ned.
We should have gotten
together sooner.
Where are you
going, Jim?
Chasing the moon.
I hear there's a lot of new
territory out Arizona way.
Oklahoma's
practically new.
Couldn't you
just stay here?
No, I don't like
the country around here.
Why, it's
beautiful country.
I know the scenery's
all right,
except those
placards.
Every time I look at one
of those $500 insults,
I get madder and madder.
Get around!
But they're coming down.
Father says it.
Down or not, I'd always
remember where they'd been.
I understand.
A new country, a new leaf.
Me, turn over
a new leaf?
I'd have to turn over a
whole public library.
Well, after
you've done all that,
you think you'll ever,
ever be back this way again?
Well, maybe,
maybe not.
It all depends on the
way things turn out.
Well, good-bye, Jim.
Good-bye.
Jim, is Arizona
an awfully big place?
Yeah, yeah.
So they tell me.
Then I'll have a hard time
finding you, won't I?
Look here, Jane, you don't
want to let yourself...
I just mean if you're empire-building,
it would save time...
Who said anything about
empire-building?
I just mean it's a difficult
thing to do by yourself.
For an empire,
you've got to have people.
For people, you've
got to have children,
and for children...
By authority as judge in the
crying need of this situation...
Just a minute,
judge, you...
Jane, do you take
this man to be your...
Yes, I do, dad.
Yes.
Just a minute...
Jim, do you take
this girl to be your...
You don't want to get
yourself into this.
Takes me, father.
Whether likes it or not.
Very well, then.
I pronounce you...
Hold that hat.
Man and wife.