Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Mesito!
I have a job for you.
But you might not be Mesito.
The Mesito from whom I heard
was a man.
Not a keeper of hens.
That's better.
Ehh, you animal!
Just quickly with these chickens
and come here!
Lots to do!
Did you hear me?
What kind of work?
You'll know when we are
with the Dutch.
Is the Dutch?
Yes, I was commissioned to come and see you and you
said that the case is $ 1000 for you.
Need to know more?
What?
Are you deaf?
Finally, it was time!
I have already fired.
Three.
You?
I just want one.
- Do you?
- Give me three, but they are good.
What do you, friend?
I want two gentlemen.
I feel that it's going to win.
The giving, going for three.
Still have not won,
and I speak first.
You will need to put 4 weights
if you want to see me.
- Augustus.
- No, not now.
Vah, is too much for me!
And for me.
- Augustus!
- I said not now.
I will not.
The Dutch have a job
for you.
Is the Dutch?
- Where is it?
- In Mexico.
You talk, man.
Do you play or not?
What kind of work?
Do you still know how it is used dynamite?
I mean, for $ 1,000.
Ehh!
I see.
Three tens.
- Come on.
- Your winnings, friend.
Ah, yes!
Still arrive in time to see
the incredible!
The unique samurai!
A legendary hero
the mysterious East,
is here,
in our fabulous West!
Only for 10 cents miserable
will enjoy the ...
chilling spectacle of the samurai
teacher in the ancient art ...
of throwing knives,
and a target of flesh and blood!
The Lotus funny!
No time to lose, gentlemen!
The function is about to begin!
Believe what I tell you,
is something to see to believe!
Go ahead, put your money
on the drum!
Insignificant 10 cents!
Forward gentlemen!
Come here!
Come gentlemen!
That is great!
Quick, quick!
The show will begin!
Do not miss it!
Please do keep
complete silence!
This is a terrible moment!
The samurai should point
with absolute calm!
A moment of distraction and Lotus Flower
meet with their honorable ancestors!
See how precisely
sharpens your aim!
If you knew how to shake
for the life of his wife!
I have a job for you.
$ 1,000.
I said $ 1,000.
I sent the Dutch.
Ehh!
Hey what are you doing?
You can not leave!
Have a contract with me!
That's where we expect the Dutch.
Bring out the prisoner!
Platoon!
Forward!
Bring him!
Out!
Depart!
Forward!
Silence, damn!
Get up, dog!
Silence!
Rascals!
To the wall, soon!
Ready!
Aim!
Mesito!
There seems nothing serious.
Will heal soon.
Thanks, my friend.
Still not what I'm here,
and I've won a battle.
Long time no see, Captain.
Too, Dutch.
Thanks for coming, samurai.
Luis,
good job.
Hello, old Dutchman!
And this why?
When I tell you to come, come.
I need you alive, not dead.
Okay, Dutch.
Although you have a very rare
greeting.
Years have passed, but you do not
have changed, Dutch.
Then you will not need to remind you
he who gives orders here I am,
and I'm willing to do anything to get it.
Is it clear?
There is something that is not what it looks in
that old Mexican in there?
Is what we pay.
We work for him.
But is that how you will give us $ 1000 per head?
A peasant!
For your information, the farmer knows where
gold is worth half a million dollars
just waiting
apoderemos we it.
A bank?
Not exactly.
A bank on wheels.
A train. A nice train
with a rich cargo.
Well folks, now eat.
Well, now tell us what's
that train laden with gold.
What matters, is a train!
It will be easy.
You may not opine you so
when you know how that train.
I do not care.
For half a million dollars by me
his back and I'll take it myself.
No, not that simple, Luis is right.
Is not a train either.
- Not be easy.
- What's so special?
I'm going to explain.
Toma.
First, the locomotive.
Immediately
a closed van.
- I do not see the difficulty.
- Full of soldiers.
- Soldiers?
- After an open car with 2 machine guns.
And with more soldiers.
Nobody told me you had to
faced with an army.
Next is our coach.
Fully shielded.
And within it, 8 armed men guarding
jealously half a million dollars in gold.
- And finally, another open wagons.
- With more guns.
No friend, no,
with a cannon.
You've gone mad, Dutch.
You need to wise men, not us.
No, you are exactly
men need.
But, hey, how can we solve
the canyon for example?
Vah, do not worry friend!
The Dutchman has it all planned.
Listen you do not stop to smile and say
Amen to everything, and still do not know who you are.
What does it matter who I am?
The important thing is what I am.
What are you?
Young, for example.
Enough to not be afraid!
What did you say?
Simply, freeze!
Let go, Mesito!
And you, Luis, keep your mouth shut!
None of these men will lie behind
when the time comes.
Well, it's time to
you may know each other.
As I am the only one who knows all,
I will make presentations.
Augustus, spent five years together
in the army. Captain Benet and me.
The genius of dynamite,
they called it.
He was able to fly anything and say
a few pieces would be reduced.
During the War of Cuba, entrusted
fly the mission of Fort Manareta.
It was a good job,
blew up the fortifications, the arsenal,
and to the safe
Cuban army.
And then he escaped.
The United States Army
even goes looking for him.
Now Mesito. It was not for money
so it got into difficulties.
But for food.
400 head of cattle to be exact.
Anyway, did not agree with the
pay given to him as rail,
and stole a train of meat
ready for sale.
The trouble was that man who tried
sell was the same owner.
You will not need to say that he was caught
and jailed.
Two weeks later escaped.
And walk fugitive.
Caring for chickens.
I told you to shut up.
The samurai.
Exalted master in handling the sword.
And in the release of knife.
Fled the country the night with his sword
6 men was sliced ​​in 4 seconds.
In three seconds, sorry.
Does not talk much.
But when it acts,
do not fuck around.
Once they interpreted jeans
its silence as cowardice ...
began to sneer at his slanted eyes.
And eight of them settled before
that no one would notice.
What about the boy?
What can you do?
Louis. Luis Dominguez,
of Trapecistas Dominguez.
Circus acrobats.
Mom and Dad Dominguez
and his son Luis.
Only one night Dad fell from 3
0 m.
without a net and that's the number.
Luis found himself without work,
and found that robbing banks was
which was more on account.
The trouble was that he threw down the gauntlet
several times.
The first had it locked
6 months.
The second 6 weeks.
- And the third Louis?
- 6 minutes.
Yes, it sold off the two guards
who carried him prisoner.
His portrait now walks
all over the walls of Mexico.
Now, will you tell us what
your plan to seize on that train?
No time for that, I will tell
during the trip.
For how the trip?
Yes, the New World.
We start now.
Why leave all?
After the killing of soldiers
Do you want to stay?
Thank you. During the first stage
trip, join us.
When we part,
carry them with you.
If they had the height,
better simulate that go with your family.
Why will you not,
but when I take my hand
that half a million ...
When I have my $ 1,000!
You know what I'm going to spend?
Let me guess.
Probably in a top hat,
an elegant ruffled shirt,
and one of those lace handkerchiefs
who get into the sleeve.
You have not given one, Dutch.
I thought I knew your tastes.
Well, that proves you can never
boast of getting to know a man.
Come on, no joke. You know that
I am not one of those smug.
I'll join with 200 head of cattle.
But honestly now!
- I can give you some advice?
- Of course.
Buy yourself something you can not eat.
What? Are you going YOU ARE
nervous as old maids?
Do not start again, Luis.
How about out there?
If the guard duty of Augustus
is as quiet as mine,
will have to work hard
to stay awake.
Anyway, not who
hell could discover here.
We are alone with cacti and wind.
I do not trust, since General Huertas
came to power,
soldiers are lurking
everywhere.
Have you heard? What do you think?
And speaks to me of soldiers!
He is not stupid enough to let
captured by them three times.
Neither I was stupid enough to sell
its owner ...
Just the two!
KEEP weapons
for when the case!
He believed that there would
need to shoot.
Did not you have a plan?
And I have it, but in any plan
complications can occur.
Complications?
Do you begin to doubt the result perhaps?
I have not hesitated in my life.
And do not come if you had done was not
sure my plan will succeed.
Dutch, you know me.
I'm a little slow when it comes to thinking.
And there is something that has me on tenterhooks.
Still have not said how
is the work!
That half a million gold send it to
General Huertas some friends in Europe.
It's kind of contribution to
protect their interests here.
If gold does not come to Mexico City, will
to give many axplicaciones their masters.
What this pint in the old peasant
Morales Town?
The old farmer is Manuel Esteban, a
of the leaders of the revolutionary forces.
Wants to take the gold to buy
weapons and ammunition.
What we expected environmental apoderemos
million to deliver it later?
You said it, buddy.
That expected.
Luis Dominguez.
Well, Dominguez.
I waited a long time now.
I'm Captain Gutierrez
and have been caught in my jurisdiction.
I must warn you that as you were
found in the company of rebels,
I suppose you are rebels,
You know what happens in these cases?
You shall be shot!
Except you, Dominguez.
You,
you will be hanged slowly.
If you want to release for you,
you have to tell me your names,
What were you doing with those rebels,
what you came to Mexico,
who called you,
and who gave you hospitality.
That's it.
Be advised that I have tried
with many stubborn
and perhaps more stubborn than you.
All ma sooner or later
have spoken.
Some after several days
without sleep.
Other for leaving them without water.
And others having lost an eye.
When the Captain is in a good mood
torture her mother.
Do not listen to your friend.
Is doomed.
While you can you
stay alive.
Come on.
Speak!
What do you think, Captain?
Had not ever come
with real men?
Take them away!
I will give some time for you to think
how to save his skin.
Ehh, you!
Bring these men!
Tie them to the sticks!
No!
Go! There is a romance
between Japanese and the girl.
Forward!
Stop!
Left!
Attention!
Load!
Aim!
Fire!
In!
Sentinel!
Dominguez is dying.
Was it the blow to the head.
He's dying!
Back!
Mesito!
Take the gun.
And when the shooting starts,
salt firing.
A thin sheet of steel.
Too beautiful
East for a vile.
The saber will keep to use as a gala
when I make general.
Is not it good idea?
Of course if I get to find out what
have come to do in Mexico these men,
could ...
show my gratitude setting free
the eyes oblique, and his companions.
Ohh!
How much loyalty!
You do not want to reveal his secret even
that this could cost you your life and yours.
Note that heroism
is a man, girl!
It is much easier to persuade
a woman to forget her ideals.
Much ...
Much easier
And much more enjoyable.
For pity's sake!
No!
Out of here!
Thank you.
Well, here we parted.
Return to your people.
I leave with a gun, you know
how it handles.
And do not worry,
soldiers will follow us.
Stephen!
We are friends of Manuel were!
Soldiers chase us!
We take care of it.
Maybe I'm wrong, but not
can cope with all these soldiers.
I know, and they know it too.
But resist
to give us time to flee.
It will cost them their lives!
Yes, kill them all.
We also know it.
And are willing to die for nothing?
They must be crazy!
There are men who die for money,
others for a cause.
And they die for us.
Breathe
for each one of us.
- Impossible!
- We shall see. Take a look down there.
What the hell is that?
The train of exploration.
Precedes the other in 20 minutes and check
if there is damage on the tracks
or explosive charges.
If you find any obstacle alerts
immediately to our train.
Have you seen enough?
Dutch, are you sure
you get it?
Never be sure until the
work is finished.
For me over.
I retire.
That could not work out or a month
time and we have only 4 days.
No, we only have three.
I do not like Dutch!
Why not?
You have a plan. It will be good,
but not for that train.
Listen to me! My plan is on paper
and result in practice!
Now the train is going for gold, within
3 days we take possession of half a million.
To give to the revolutionaries,
of course.
The next time you see it,
be ours.
Sorry gentlemen, this bandit
tried to rob me.
But I managed to capture him.
Do you want to take him prisoner?
Dutch,
What about that house?
Is abandoned
As the station.
These rails seem
in good condition.
Instead the ties are broken
as crackers.
That does not think any more than food.
How much do you think can they hold?
The passage of a wagon once or twice.
Well, enough said.
Enough of shooter!
- To hit the target there is nothing like this.
- Nobody hears you shoot the pots.
But along the train route is
platoons of soldiers every 6 miles ...
willing to intervene
the first shot.
And do not forget the soldiers
going in the cars.
Keep working.
I ordered a Mesito
I did them.
I hope these will coviertas
to reduce the noise.
Operate with dynamite
like a cannon.
I have not given a full charge, but
will give you an idea of ​​how it works.
It works great!
Keep worrying about noise.
Do not worry, you can cover your
with the train whistle.
How about Captain?
Will he all right?
I'm too old to think, well
you're the one who calls the shots.
But if you want my opinion,
I think they'll kill us all.
It's not like before, Dutch,
when you and I were together there.
No more ...
romantic adventures.
Reflect. Today we are only 4 old and
a boy against at least 100 soldiers.
Against an armored train.
Against a cannon that can be turned off
a candle to 5 km
5 men against guns
and automatic rifles.
Before there were all those things.
We finished, and you know it.
Then why did you accept?
Because we are already dead
long.
Our time has passed.
He left.
Look at me for example.
After leaving the army
I became a professional player.
He played very well before.
But when you've spent years manipulating
dynamite feel inside ...
as a vacuum.
It is what it is, but do not let live.
And suddenly,
when you marcándote a bluff,
hand ... you and trembles
sweat like hell.
So I ended up plucking
the poor devils.
And the others are no better. Mesito no longer
knows what he is sleeping in a bed.
The samurai throwing knives in a shack
fair for a dollar a day.
And Louis ...
Who is Louis?
A petty criminal
like a hare.
And you yourself, Dutch. A man without a country
the service of these ragged.
No, my case ...
is different.
Different?
No, we are all equal!
So we have embarked
in this case.
This time we cleared them all.
Everyone!
And you know it.
Samurai ...
Shoes, belts and what knives?
Very good.
Louis.
Shoes, belts,
and handle.
And the clock?
Shoes, belts, fuses, covers,
cable channels, what about the dynamite?
It appears that you have everything.
Except encouragement.
There, you will, Captain.
Mesito.
- Is this what it is?
- To let us all a drink.
Save it for when we
something to celebrate.
Is the clock?
- Huh?
- Do you watch?
- Ah, I have.
- Let me see it.
- I have it!
- Show me!
Cuélgatelo neck, so you may not have
sit on top of it.
Come on, put it on.
Instructions.
- Again!
- Yes, again and as many as fit.
20 minutes for open wagons.
3 minutes to move from car to car.
5 minutes for contingencies.
Total 34 minutes.
Mesito.
At 6:45 the train of exploration.
20 minutes after the convoy.
I have 20 minutes to attach the rails
and changing needles.
All in 20 minutes.
They are more than enough.
Not when the last
that fit one of life.
Places, everyone!
Come down!
Get in!
- There he is!
- Half a million dollars.
Now!
Attention!
Exit the train of discovery!
Raise the escort!
Guard to train!
Lord Mayor.
Lady.
- Have you come to see the train?
- Yes, Captain.
Kindly.
As you can see is well protected.
Heavily armed.
General Huerta has thought of everything.
Even men have been
carefully chosen by their officers.
All guarantees absolute security.
- Do not you think, Mr. Mayor?
- Yes, of course, Captain.
This is the car of gold.
Apart from the armed escort
traveling inside ...
is externally protected by a
sand-filled cushion.
Impressive.
Present arms!
Peter!
What will you do?
I do not want that gold
General Huerta arrives.
- Is it against Huerta?
- Right.
Then I help, I
I'm with the Revolution.
- What about your partner?
- He is with them.
Maybe tell me the truth,
but might not.
Do not do stupid things.
Hey, look!
What is it, Captain?
Hurry!
I can not do.
Why not?
I dropped a cover.
And you can not do without it?
Sure! Want to hear the explosion
up in Mexico City?
Or that stifle the noise
with your hands?
Listen genius!
You will blow up loads!
I do not care how!
I do not care who loses a hand,
or half-face!
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant, here is water!
Refrésquense!
Take!
Inside these guns or I'll shoot
one on!
Throw them down!
And raise your hands!
Now?
No, not yet.
We will provide when we get to ...
where we go.
Everyone knows the path to take.
So on!
Mesito!
Go into the truck!
Luis!
Tie them in that corner!
While the gold charge.
Come on!
Ah, come on!
Come on, give me a hand!
Mesito!
Are you okay?
Beautifully!
One for me,
One for the Dutch and Luis.
Augustus and the samurai.
One for me.
He is very busy.
One for Augustus and the samurai.
One for me.
One for the Dutch.
Louis.
Augustus and the samurai.
- Come on, cut the jokes!
- I'm not kidding.
Hebérmelo had figured.
Stand there, Mesito!
Louis reloads in the truck.
Have you imagined?
- Why not?
- Because I'm so stupid like you.
You can not take it all, Dutch!
All no!
No, not everything, my friend.
Here are the $ 1000 that you owe.
The rest comes with us.
With us, no.
Me.
Dutch ...
You said ...
We agreed.
We gold repartiríamos
between you and me.
What you played well,
I never said that.
I listened to me,
but your ambition, like everyone else.
I promised $ 1000 and there they are.
Yours too, Louis.
Dutch,
has been a masterstroke.
You made us risk our skins.
You made him believe the boy
who would you go halfway,
and had perfectly planned
the stay with it.
Not for me, Captain.
I told you it was for the revolutionary
and to them will go.
A few years ago I was a hunted man
in the United States.
So I came to Mexico.
I found good people who shook my hand.
And I met a girl.
For a time all went well.
Then one day,
soldiers came,
saying that his father and brothers
were revolutionists,
and that she was his accomplice.
I knew nothing about the Revolution and did not know
the problems of farmers, so ...
I was released.
But they shot the other,
even the girl.
It was my wife.
No Captain, gold is not for me.
It is for Manuel Esteban, for farmers,
for the Revolution.
I did this for my wife.
Now you listen to me.
You can hide, go to another country,
rename.
But wherever you are
I'll find you.
No matter how long it takes.
But I will find you.
I know you will, Captain.
I will leave the horses for a day
from here.
Soldiers!
You two, come with me.
Are you with him?
No, I am with mine.
Dutch!
Did you succeed?
Ehh ..!
Yes, we succeeded!
Viva!
Thank you!
Transcription of audio  Spanish by
The Wild Bunch
Riders
www.fdlwest.com
Best Watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player