(Music:''The Hanging Tree''
by Marty Robbins)
RIVALS ON GOLD RIVER
(Theme song goes)
The Gold Trail''''
Montana 1873
Look at the gallows tree. This is the
The only respect that here.
(ominous music)
(Music is lively, triumphant)
Is the house for sale?
Yes, I need money
f r is a   Ausr stung.
Dr ben and the house as ?
The צ rt'm the owner of
Village shop, but not sold.
- How much do you want?
- What w rden  you give?
- If you ask me: 5 cents.
- Let's agree to 1,000 gold dollars?
- $ 500
- But the house is worth much more.
500. Yes or no?
Come, let's go!
$ 1 more
and you get to the woman.
No, thanks.
(upbeat music)
(Gun click)
(Shot)
(Man screams) Hey, a Goldr ה about!
(Dramatic music)
(Shot)
Come on, guys, we have!
(Shot, calls) Goldr ה about! Goldr ה about!
I have seen him only fl chtig .
Fits on blood stains!
(all mixed up excitedly call)
(fast music)
Quick, guys, hurry up!
A Goldr ה about!
(Music is dramatic, faster)
(Music sounds slowly)
I hardly think
that you will help me.
(Call about) A Goldr ה!
- Goldr ה about? How do I get it?
- I am wounded.
(st צ hnt)
- Where is my shirt?
- I've burned.
Why? I have only one thing.
If they see you so,
h ה nts it for you.
- How do you f  HLST you?
- Hurt.
No wonder.
The ball sat  quite deep.
If the wound is large ?
Yes, but it will heal.
- How hot  t you?
- How hot  you en?
Doctor Joe Frail.
I hei  e rune.
- What's next?
- Nothing. Only Rune.
- Where are you from?
H צ r put on, always counter-questions.
Well, then h צ ren
lhren with questions!
How will you pay me?
I can pay  berhaupt nothing.
Do you think if I had money ה h tte,
w rde  I steal money?
Do you think I treat you for free?
However, k צ nntest you work off it.
I k צ nnte use you.
A servant
of the boots and the house cleaning.
- Can you cook?
- No! I am not a shoeshine boy.
All animals can learn k צ.
Even Fl צ he.
You'll f  r me work
and do everything I say.
You can go to hell!
Wei  t you know what that is?
The ball that I have gotten to you.
A ungew צ hnliches caliber.
This ball gt  gen alone,
to bring you to the gallows.
And how long must I remain,
quit until we are?
As long as I ה gef llt.
Perhaps  f r forever.
If I bleed you let h ה tte,
w ה rst du tot
F  r forever.
At first you will the house
clean up from top to bottom.
Then go to the village with a bell
and k  ndige my office.
(calling): A doctor in the village!
Up there is a doctor.
(M ה girl laugh)
What are we going to a doctor?
You're a nice guy.
Come here.
How old are you?
(Rune calls)
A doctor lives on the mountain top!
A doctor has arrived!
Hours day and night.
(l ה rung bell)
Hey, wait a minute!
- How hot  t the doctor?
- Frail.
- Joe Frail?
- Yes.
Gr   him sch צ n Tom Flaunce.
- Thank you.
(laughs go ה ssig)
A doctor has arrived!
A doctor is in the village! (L ה GIocke rung)
A doctor is in the village!
- How hot  t he?
- Dr. Frail. He lives on the mountain.
(ominous music)
Let me see your teeth Z ה.
Ill she is not.
But it has deficiencies.
What is it, Doctor?
A sign of
inadequate ה Ern hrung.
I have been on the river no  Gl ck.
We  m ssen very save.
I have a cow,
the k צ you can have.
Then enter
the little milk.
I can not afford a cow.
I lend it to you.
Yes, but ...
Thank you very much.
What do we owe you, Doctor?
Give me a kiss.
- We are quits
- (M ה girl) We're even
So you see,
that was not so bad.
Who is that N ה chste?
H צ to rt, my  the Br!
Your patient dies, if you do
the cow doctor surrenders.
The devil lives in this house!
If you are sick,
come to me!
I will tell you my hands hang H ה
H ה and my hands will heal you.
Avoid this house! Fall is not his
Teufelsk  nsten a victim!
Day Crubb.
Do not judge
sen b צ your eyes on me, Joe Frail.
Br  which, I warn you!
The Bible says ...
This is his Bible!
Joe Frail, h te  you.
Anyone who digs the grave of another,
will be self directed.
So who is the N ה chste?
I, Doctor. Do you know me?
I was last year already with you.
Frenchy. Are you sick
or you need money?
No, I have a carbuncle.
This costs
an ounce of gold dust, or $ 20
- Have you money?
- This is just enough.
Come clean.
- You now have a helper?
- Quite right.
Pull your pants down once already.
This is Frenchy Plante.
He  l gt, when he opens his mouth.
The m צ I do not chte
encounter in the dark.
- The doctor is a very cautious.
- I  wei.
- If only I nnte schie en k צ  like him.
- Shut your views about  the flame.
The m  sstest you
times schie  s see, boy.
Doctor! I thought you wanted me
and help not kill me.
When I s k צ  schie nnte,
k צ nnte me no what, in all of Montana.
Ow! Doctor!
People w rden  run away from me.
But, boy, not afraid of Frenchy.
(shouts) Oh! Ah!
(screams and st צ) hnt pain
(Piano)
H צ r on yet, but rt h צ any one.
(Music stops)
300.
Gentleman is 300th Red
- This is too expensive  f r me.
- F r  me too.
- I see it in me.
- And with the 300th gt  berschl ה
I see and exceeded location
with this title on this gold mine.
- Where is the mine?
- Dr  ben on the other side.
Is accepted, 2,000.
- What is it?
- Everything.
Let's just time, Doctor.
How  hei t es: BL ה st the wind too strong,
bow to the Hume st ה ה rksten B.
A moment.
Prelim ה often available, the tree still.
I see.
An Ass
A pair of deuces.
(M ה male laugh)
What do you do
with all that money?
To go to Illinois  ck
and nd a house num ?
They are
not provoke me, doctor Frail.
Take the money, Rune.
What were you trying to say:
Nd num ''A House''?
The Red Beard has done nothing
and h ה tten almost killed him.
Saddle my horse from
and bring it into the stable.
He said only a little
of a burned house.
So you  w rden
a man killed?
Rune ...
Tomorrow we begin a new life.
We get up at 4:00 clock,
working in the mine until 8:00 Clock.
Then we patch up our patients.
Got questions?
Any questions to me
fr heren  or my life?
- No.
- Good. Go unsaddle the horse.
This quack was right.
If you are not even the devil,
He will certainly sits in the neck.
(exciting music)
(Sch  sse fall
Horses neighing uneasily)
(Woman screams)
(rapid dramatic music)
- 15,000. What do you say?
- Agreed.
(Frenchy), Hey, Doctor!
Doctor!
In the village, one that is needed
Their urgent assistance, a coachman.
- He is half dead, was 3 days on the road.
- And the passengers?
- It was an  berfall, all are dead
- Au  he a woman.
- She is gone.
- Says The driver, a real lady.
Mr. Flaunce, you know what they do.
K צ nnten you are looking for the woman.
- Yes, well.
- And others are looking for the bandits.
Come not, Doctor?
No. The coachman needs me
and other patients.
Want to ride with us?
I have no horse.
Take mine.
You trust me?
And if I did not come back?
No matter where you go,
the scar w rde  you ever betrayed.
Which party do you ride?
- Find The Lost Lady.
- I thought so.
Take good care of that, my property
not come to harm.
Do not worry, I adjust to the fact
and also on the horse.
There's something!
She is not in here.
But there is a bag.
Yes, the bag seems to her to go ren צ
You  t hei Elizabeth Mahler, comes from
Sweden. Here is a letter to them.
Wei  the sky,
what direction it has taken.
H צ to rt! It is better to
we split into several groups.
In the dark
We meet in Stump Meadow.
She is now long the sun
At night, the K ה lte suspended.
If she is dead;
Give 2 SCH  from sse if they live 3rd
- A track?
- No.
- How many people are still on the way?
- Approximately 12th
Then we will
tonight are stored here.
In this country, br t ה one day
At night it freezes.
We have at least
Ceilings and a fireplace.
But she?
We no longer find alive.
- You're bleeding, yeah, my son.
- I  wei, that was a thorn bush.
- Are you long for Dr. Frail?
- Not very long.
Then, you use.
Thank you.
I know the doctor about 5 years.
We then searched for gold.
Sp ter we made ה ה Done forces.
The doc itself tte h l ה ה ngst
k צ can put to rest.
But he can not
inseparable from his black bag.
- Maybe he has his soul in it.
- If he has a soul.
I've even asked the Doc,
where his name herstammt. Frail.
He said ...
... does the name
from Norwegian.
Du wei  t
It is not his real name.
No.
- A strange man, the doctor.
- Yes.
He challenges force of death.
The other day he's going to one,
him because of an
ה has spent nselt go home.
A miracle that he did
has not killed.
Why would he kill him?
One ה erz hlt the wildest stories.
By a man named Temple
even the doctor was.
He lived in a city
where the Ohio into the Mississippi flowing  t.
He is there a sch צ nes House
H  have had on a gel.
And one night
something happened in that house.
A man and a woman ...
... there should have perished.
And the doctor should
nds have the house angez .
Can still be the charred
Walls dividing the pastures to see.
- Have you seen it?
- I think a rattlesnake.
Schie  t you like to snakes?
I ja! (laughs)
Lady!
I have water. I have water!
Water, lady. Water.
No, no.
Not so fast, little lady.
Please, lady. I ...
... I'm going
A few Sch  like sse.
Lady, please ...
Lady, would you not be afraid.
I shall now give a few Sch  from sse.
As a sign  f r my friends,
I found you.
Believe me, now everything is good.
Frenchy, it promises you.
(Horses)
- Come here!
- Is she alive?
Yes, but it has hit them hard.
Come here. Look, how they
my water bottle festh ה lt
You do not want to let go.
It is more dead than alive.
There is not much
it  brig remained.
But what is still there,
does not  from bel. (laughs)
This ought to
only be a compliment.
There's nothing to it.
Come on, we put them on a stretcher
and bring them to Stump Meadow.
I ride with Dr. Frail and ore ה chairs,
I found it.
(laughs) Just see here.
It should be h  bsch?
(Frenchy calls)
Hey! I've found it!
(general tumult, yelling)
I! Frenchy has found it!
In the gorge.
I! She's alive!
I've found the woman doctor.
M ssen  once you come too.
I have a patient here.
What makes the Red Anna with you?
She is waiting for death.
She did not die down there.
- The Lady sees it from צ b se.
- I'm coming as fast as I can.
- F Anna  r k צ you can do anything.
- No, that has probably never done one.
But I'll leave it alone.
- How long will it take?
- 2 hours, I think.
Should I turn around her neck,
make it faster?
No, doctor, no.
I say nothing.
I have done my duty,
Their you do if you'd like to m צ.
(Man) Glad you're here, Doctor.
She lies dr ben .
We
alternately kept watch, Doctor.
She has
the whole night, ger  hrt.
(Frenchy)
Is scraped off the Red Anna?
(Man)
Glad you are finally here, Doctor.
- Go צ you  tte rt H?
- Yes.
- Who has aufgeschmiert her car grease?
- I.
Well, that was right.
Rune, fetch the lamp  r calc
It occurred to anyone,
here to make time to clean?
I need a lot of clean water.
Where the water bottles empty.
(Female st צ hnt)
You always talks to her father.
He is killed when berfall .
- How hot  t they?
- Elizabeth Mahler.
That's my water bottle, doctor.
Whining (Female, incomprehensible ה ndlich)
She has severe burns
and Gehirnersch  tterung.
Perhaps internal injuries.
It is probably blind.
- You will never see again can k צ?
- I can not say yet.
It was probably the whole day
unconscious in the sun.
- First, they need time to get out.
- We ask the trapper to the car.
We still have a small house,
against  ber of baby's.
Then k צ nnten bring them.
N Sch צ, I'll get the car.
Do you have enough water, Doctor?
Yes. Put it beside the stove,
We  m ssen it boil.
And you, do that, you get out.
Doctor, you will not have time,
to st ה ndig mmern to them k .
When I had finished the housework
and her man
bring the food must ...
The m צ chte I love to do.
Well, Rune. Thank you.
Hey, boy!
What need of all the water?
He has to wash them, yes.
berall?
The z ה not yet selected, to a doctor.
(Shouts) You've found it!
You've found it!
It should be migrated quite fresh.
Wom צ so resembled a loose woman.
What does this have to do with it? It is
a stranger here, blind, and severely wounded.
Dr. Frail? My husband has given you
rashly offered to our house.
- You will not die here.
- You will not die.
They will live, Ms. Mahler.
It'll get better.
We are  ber den Berg.
They (st צ) hnt
- I do not ה gef llt the.
- Wir m ssen  down again, come.
(she sobs, crying)
Take the L to the ה.
The space must remain obscured.
(she cries)
Elizabeth. K צ can you understand me?
The coach was berfall .
The horses have bolted.
- But now you're safe.
- I need to  ck. My father ...
- (Sobbing) They are t he צ Ten.
- You  m ssen remain calm.
(screams, cries loudly)
(Storm, thunder)
I have found some tea.
Do it in the pot.
I never go rt צ,
that it imposes someone tea.
BL צ of the book.
There stands a loss of consciousness may
by a blow
be on the head triggered צ st.
The further I  from personal experience
when I first fell from his horse.
Why erkl ה rt us any that
what in the interior of K צ RPER happening?
Bring the lamp.
(Rune) You already looks almost
like a man out.
Why is it lt blo  ה h
the canteen so tightly?
If you through so much h ה ttest,
w  rdest you do not let go too.
She's awake.
Only half awake.
The other H ה HALF
is still somewhere else.
We've done it.
I think you can you now
the canteen away.
- But daf  r h ה now you find lt.
- She is calm.
I'll sit here,
until I losl ה sst.
Go to bed.
Who are you?
I'm a doctor.
Why are my eyes are connected?
The sun has burnt your eye.
The sun.
- Can I see you?
- Not yet.
Before  mountain above,
You understand me, Elizabeth,
They are blind to  mountain above.
My father ...
... is dead, right?
Yes.
He was berfall get where  tet צ.
And he had
around me so afraid.
Where is he buried?
On the road  enrand, where was the  berfall.
I will now
get something to eat.
F  you do not rchten before the
Alone. I live next door.
Doctor, is there someone f  me r?
I mean, a woman?
No.
What I have to?
We have found Their travel bag.
- I have rausgenommen a nightgown.
- Thank you.
You do
to worry about.
- Good morning, Rune.
- The  Fr hst ck  is ready.
- Is it enough to even f  r 3?
- Nat  rlich.
Is she better now?
She needs rest.
It d  rfen no strangers to her.
Bring the bell above the entrance to ,
so that they can call us.
(sweeping, fr צ hliche Music)
(M ה male call and sing)
- Is that all, Mr. Flaunce?
- More gold, we have not found.
- The vein of gold seems to be the exhaustion.
- With the never busy.
Here in the area is no one
become rich. Well, good trip!
Good morning, Rune.
Where did you get the horse from?
The doctor took it in payment.
He l ה sst ask
if you have fresh eggs.
I have saved you, ck 3 St .
How is our beauty Sch צ?
She now sits on the 1.Mal,
but is still weak.
- Still blind?
- The doc says it may take yet.
Very fresh eggs.
They are rare here drau  en.
- We f dr cken   r Lady thumb.
- I tell her much.
That makes $ 3, pay at the checkout.
Is not that a bit steep,
$ 1, the St  ck?
That is just so.
The eggs come from far away.
Their doctor is safe
his practice very determined ה ftigt.
Yes, very.
Well, you go to your Damenkr ה nzchen?
We women want us
mmern the M ה k  girl.
If the Doctor needs help
they will contact.
Maybe she needs help.
A saint he is not straight.
You there is not a compound, Edna.
A cancel a anst ה ה M dchen
צ as rt does not go out above.
We will soon know
where we are with her.
It was a b צ ser winter.
My mother died this year.
My father said:
''Come, let us emigrate.
In a country
which offers us a new future.''
Oh, it was wonderful.
The train to St. Louis.
Then the river steamer
the Missouri River and up.
And then the coach  about the mountains
and wide across the steppes.
A wonderful country
just as in our ה umen Tr.
''And now,''said my father,
''Elizabeth, now we  m ssen
Find the right place''.
Did you think
Here w ה re the right place?
If I can see again,
wei I  it.
What you will see is a small
poor gold-ה Berdorf.
It sweeps away the first Windsto ,
when the gold dried up here.
The dregs of humanity
click here.
- Here w rden  you do not want to live.
- Why are you here? And Rune?
- Maybe we'll go צ ren here.
- I m not  sste where else
Tell me, what is Rune?
And you, Doctor Frail?
How do you like?
Rune? The slightly cross-eyed
and has a little too long fingers.
(laughs)
And the doctor has
a gray beard and no teeth Z ה.
I further  that is not true.
Rune is certainly a Bscher h  boy.
By Dr. Frail I can
no idea what to make.
I only know of his H ה nde.
They are tanned by the sun
and gentle.
And terribly long legs he has.
He's coming in 3 steps to a T  r.
As patients arrive
or unexpected visit.
One woman go צ rt the house here.
The ladies w nschen ?
- 4 Women Need a doctor?
- We come to Miss Mahler.
- Miss Mahler Receive ה not ngt.
- Did she say anything?
No, until she is healthy,
I decide  about their welfare.
The inhabitants cancel a anst ה ...
But what can you afford?
Do I make you a farewell.
So if you
no help rztliche ה צ ben tigen,
I suggest that you
hren in baby's own pot r .
- Am I a prisoner, Rune?
- Nelly, w ה r 'ne small loan in?
- From me you will get a cent.
I further  who I can pump what.
(Piano music, voices)
(quiet, peaceful music)
(eerie music)
Rune? Is anyone there?
Only the good old Frenchy,
to make his respects.
I was the one you drau  s
has found, you can not remember?
I wanted to ask if I
can have my water bottle.
Excuse me,
I am not prepared to visit.
But nat  rlich, Ms. Mahler.
I do not look down.
Hey!
Almost w ה ren fallen lady.
Since I have you
2nd Time saved.
But enough of that. There you ה h tte
well someone else can find k צ.
But perhaps sp ה t
- I  w rde mich gerne gratefully show.
- The k צ you can.
I wanted to ask you
if you help me out a little nnten k צ.
- Nat  rlich, like what ...
- Sit down.
I found the place where
the yellow pebbles are waiting
that they ausbuddelt,
but unfortunately I lack the funds.
Pebbles?
They talk about gold?
In quantities as
here no one has tr ה umen leave.
- W ה ren you do not like rich?
- Sure.
Who helps me to Ausr  pation,
which nothing else can happen.
- Ausr  pation? So you need money?
- That's right, lady.
I am sorry to you uschen entt ה.
My father had all our money.
I w ה re so gl  cklich,
If I can help you k צ nnte.
Let's not talk more about it.
I wanted to visit so anyway.
But maybe you can me k צ
another pleasure to do?
For example?
- Mr. Plante was because of the canteen.
- Yes, yes.
Yes. He has now.
- I think I'd better go.
- Good night, Mr. Plante.
- Is everything all right, Elizabeth?
- Yes.
If you no longer need
I do not what to do.
Rune! Rune!
Bring the bell in order,
He has cut the cord.
From tomorrow
ה schl fst ben du dr  outside the house.
(ged ה mpftes voices, music)
(Music and voices are getting louder)
Joe! Pick up the f  me r.
(Music stops)
I'm not afraid of you.
And I have no gun.
Their are all witness.
I have no gun.
I visited his lady,
he seems to take  bel.
(Gel ה chter)
Take the razor
and I put away my gun.
You will not at a
I do like the H ה hands dirty?
Yes.
(Man 1) The doctor ה schl gt him k.o.
(Man 2)
I bet he schl gt ה him down.
(Uproar, shouts)
If you
even look up sst l ה ...
whether with or without a gun ...
I will beat you dead
H צ rt me, my  of Br.
I warn you again.
This cow doctor
is possessed by the devil.
Their m  sst to chase him out of the village!
The doctor wants the little lady
probably quite f r  claim him.
Only wait. I
The final word is still out.
My time will come.
The yet to come.
- Did you get him צ tet?
- No.
- She says he has done nothing to her.
- That I do not care.
- I want to see anyone here.
- It is not lhr property.
Was not it always thus?
Have not you always
rule the people want?
Come on, Doctor.
Why do not you beat me?
I'm Their property!
Take the L to the ה.
To be expected lhren eyes are not too much,
We darken the room.
And now you put me against  calc
Plug the lamp.
I
The  ה u eren Association declined.
Turning up the wick a little deeper.
And now
I take off the second association.
Please do not expect
You can immediately see that k צ.
Now, only
the swab on lhren eyes.
I will
softened in cold water.
Turning up the wick to the bottom, Rune.
And right now they think of me.
Are you ready, Elizabeth?
Pray f  r me, Doctor.
Hold the lamp h צ ago, Rune.
יי now Open your eyes.
K צ can you see anything?
No.
Now go with the lamp out and  ck.
Nothing.
That's not entirely true, Elizabeth.
Their eyes follow the light.
- Tell me what you see.
- Please, try it.
- I see some light as if through fog.
- Something light? That's a lot.
That is more
seeing as most of us.
And tomorrow you will see a lot more.
I can not see.
But I thank you.
(Horses, whip cracks)
(dramatic music)
(Sch  sse)
(screams)
What do you have?
(she sobs)
My eyes!
She says her eyes hurt her to do.
They burn! Like fire!
When was the start?
(sobbing) I went to the T  r
and it was f צ additional dark.
(sobs, crying)
I further  it! I'm going blind!
Now go out.
- I want to have a look your eye.
- No!
Let me see your eye.
Let us go out
and try again.
- No, I can not.
- Why not?
There was a stagecoach
is davongerast.
A man began to schie  en.
- I want to see again.
- I think you can k צ see very well.
Take Their H ה hands down.
Now h צ ren me too well.
If you keep your eyes closed,
h צ ה ren Ger usche and think
st rzt  one of the world.
But if you keep them open,
You see things as they are.
I can not.
I'll leave you here alone.
You are on the brink of an abyss.
I'll give you some advice:
Do not go
with eyes closed through life.
(Rune) You can see them.
It is free.
Why do not you go home?
I wait until you go.
Take your time not be too long.
Please, sir.
It has f  r us home
the food prepared. Come on.
I apologize to her.
Tell her I'm ftigt decided ה.
You k צ they can not be treated.
You k now  mmerst
a bit too much for me.
You seem to have forgotten that
who who go צ rt.
Cards, Doctor?
Do you want tickets?
Yes, 2
- We have been waiting for you.
- I could not come sooner.
Are you afraid of me,
because I'm healthy?
No, I am pleased
that you are healthy.
Excuse me.
Good night.
- You h ה tten should not come here.
- The further I .
Go back  r calc
And tomorrow, take the stagecoach.
Coach? Where should I go?
To New York. And then home.
Then you should go.
- And what I do there?
- You have relatives.
Here you have no one.
This is no place you  f r.
K צ, you can not stay here.
Why do you do?
Because you go  m ssen.
And because I want to stay here.
Please send me away.
They will pack up tomorrow.
I'll take you to the coach.
No, you do not.
And you will never tell me again,
what am I to do or not do.
I take
Tomorrow fr  h not the coach.
I have come
to make me a home.
And I want to do.
At 6 weeks, the can
to be a ghost of Ernest.
I'll be here!
I plant wheat f  r ghosts
and z  chte cattle f  r ghosts.
- And build my haunted house!
- With ghosts of money?
Do I obtain money.
Somehow I managed it.
And if only to sufficient
You pay my debts.
Give me the ball to  ck,
They have lifted.
I have thrown away a long time.
Thrown away?
I f you worked  r,
without it  m ssen?
- Looks like it.
- I am not free?
Who of you wants to be smart,
must be the first born.
Rune?
You can also keep the horse,
that you may not go on foot  m sst .
Good morning. My name is
Elizabeth Mahler. Thank you very much.
Day, Rune.
And that is the missing Sch צ ne?
- My name is Elizabeth Mahler.
- Very pleased.
Thank you, all mine.
- Welcome, Ms. Mahler.
- Thank you.
It sends you is not f  r
Addressing strangers.
Talk to me and I answer.
Good morning.
- May I?
- We do not need help!
Thank you very much.
My name is Elizabeth Mahler.
- Come on, finally.
- It was a joy to me gen
(Elizabeth) Good morning.
- Are you Mrs. Flaunce?
- Yes.
- I m צ chte talk baby's husband.
- I'm here, Miss Mahler.
Excuse me. Thank you.
Good day.
Rune has told me
how helpful they were.
Glad
that you are healthy again.
Thank you.
I m צ chte one Minenausr  pation.
Excuse me?
Rune and I
want to go fossicking.
I see.
Fits for the f r  a woman?
- I'm still there.
- I f rchte  hard work is not.
W  you rden me
then a Ausr  pation borrow?
It is very valuable,
one Familienerbst  ck.
The stones are really very rare.
This is an exciting St  ck.
I have a magnifying glass in the apartment.
Do you have any objection
n ה me when I look at her?
Nat  rlich not. Please.
- Doctor, she wants a Minenausr  pation.
- I thought so.
She wants to borrow money then.
This should be an old Erbst  ck.
Do you think
That is more than $ 20 worth?
Tell her that you are her
umen an open credit Einr ה.
All right, Doctor.
If you daf  r underwrite.
Well?
Your Frenchy was not lying!
Give me the money
and it can go to work.
No, first
We discuss the events ה products.
It's embarrassing, with a lady
Done ה  ber fte speak.
- Mr. Plante, we get down to business.
- Substance.
To the point.
What do you think of 20%?
Gro  z  giger as I can be.
I can at any time Ausr  pation
get to 5 or 10%.
Why do you do it then?
No, 20% is too little.
We want 50%.
- The k צ you can accept or ...
- Reject.
Yes, or reject it.
- 50%.
Because you are.
Here's my hand on it.
No, first we go to Mr. Flaunce
and make the contract.
And then we shake hands.
Agreed?
''... erkl ה ren to indemnify,
that if one partner
in the above-referenced Mine
ckziehen from work to  will ... ''
Brrrrrrr!
I catch the groove
up there at the waterfall at
and f  them down hre
behind the tree in the creek.
I'll beat the sh  Geb.
Well, the proud owner of mine?
Sit down there in the shade.
Frenchy does everything alone.
I will participate as you are.
Please consider me as a man
(laughs)
That will not be easy.
A better verbal ה EMPLOYMENT f  r lts
H ה hands will help you cause.
Well, you are 'ne number, you know.
They are really 'ne dolle number.
Go up
and f ה lle wood f  r the gutter.
(euphoric music)
Rune! Rune!
Go up to the water!
So now we are ready
to wash the sand.
Down with the water!
(Cheers)
(Laughter)
K צ Now we can begin to dig.
Now we de rei  Earth
the gold from the body,
here
lies hidden for millions of years.
10 meters of cotton fabric.
Whoever gets the child?
The wife of Russell.
How I know she wants to 4 dozen
Diapers. Since we prefer to take 12 m.
Tell me, have Flaunce, you
which go from the river above צ rt?
Do you have some nostalgia?
No, I just wanted to know
how's ben since  dr.
- The mine is in operation.
- With Success?
Not likely.
Only 5 ounces to 3 weeks.
That hardly covers the interest.
It takes time.
It has
f  r  about $ 1,000 of goods taken.
- And I will continue to give her credit?
- Yes.
- Even if nothing comes out?
- Even if I lose every penny.
It is indeed nothing to me, Doctor.
When Done ה ftsmann I do not understand
how do you come to Their Costs.
I am not an event ftsmann ה and
therefore accountable to no one.
Thank you
the matter be kept confidential.
Not even my wife wei  them.
I promised Russell
I watch him think.
He was probably more scared than his wife.
M ה Men are funny.
How many M ה male by their wives
the G ה ngelband let f hren .
(Baby cries)
The k  rzeste  way is via the comb
and then along the river, Doctor.
MINE LUCKY LADY''''
OWNER: E. MAHLER, F. PLANTE, RUNE
In about one months
we have found almost nothing.
I'm just not  Gl ck.
- We have  m ssen patience.
- Patience is something I have not.
Good day, Doctor. I am pleased
that you can look at times.
I visited a patient.
- M צ you'd like some coffee?
- Yes, please.
Thank you.
Do not tell a doctor weight צ hnlich:
''How are you? ''
And:''You see once your tongue''?
I see how you feel.
Is it me good?
- Show me nde Their H ה.
- They're dirty.
Maybe I should ask
how are you?
Come stop by on occasion.
I'll give you what f  r lts H ה nde.
Thank you, Doctor.
Lucky Lady''''.
Have Eq  ck?
No, but a little bit of hope
can not hurt.
How is Rune?
They are missing two of us.
What do you want?
Spying on us?
What's the matter,
what he can not see?
Well, Rune?
To work, Rune!
Ren you go צ only 50% of this hole.
I will certainly
not more than 50% dirt digging.
Why do not we cut the crap go?
Do it all. But then
צ go mine rune and my rt.
My share k צ nnt have it cheap.
And why  w rde Mr. Plante
so much money vorschie  s,
if he does not believe in the mine?
Why you must  m
Watch a woman like that?
If a partner is not certain rights?
So take a look but does not hurt.
You have to be well doctor
in order to rfen the d .
As you probably nnte k צ
allow even more.
You really are a tough old boot.
But wait a minute.
That's better than nothing.
Rune!
I walk into the village.
I m צ chte that you come with me.
K צ you can stay calm here.
It happens you nothing.
See you tomorrow, Frenchy.
From today I'm going at night
stay down in the village.
I come here just to work.
(Sob)
I have the plague, eh?
The plague.
For a moment,
I'll just change.
Good evening.
Good evening, Mrs. Flaunce.
Our vorr ה te come to an end.
I ask for an advance or
my needle.
Their Unsch ה tzbare needle!
The sack of potatoes is not worth it.
Excuse me, what do you think?
I've seen lhr account register.
The needle
ה h tte I have borrowed a penny.
- What do you want?
- Do not play the innocent.
So you know: Dr. Frail
has advanced to you the money.
K צ us we can well imagine
She told him how to ckzahlen .
I have it in black and white :
$ 1119, you were worth it so far.
Running up like a whore!
L  gnerin. Common wrong queue.
One should trample you.
At some point, somehow
I pay every penny for  ck.
- What you pay for  ck?
- I was in the shop.
Mrs. Flaunce says you made me think.
They even called me a whore.
That was not my intention.
I'm sorry.
- Better to leave the city.
- Do not meddle in my life!
Who gives you the right to
playing with people's lives like that?
Drag the people themselves
and sto s  them out.
- Gef ה it llt you, len people ה qu?
- Not at all.
But you qu ה len us!
Rune just like me.
- Life is political once r ה.
- Maybe it already has.
Then it is true
what one ה erz hlt.
- From the woman who killed herself.
- Yes, that's true.
I was married to this woman.
And the man was my brother.
I have no right to forget.
M צ you'd like me more erz hlen ה?
This is a tincture from plants צ l.
I have you f  r produced.
It will heal Their H ה nde
gardens and at the same time surveilance ה.
I'm at the end! I'm ready!
I can not stand it any longer.
But what we have found
but must come from somewhere!
Somewhere, yes! This is probably
of the Flood  brig remained.
(Rumble, squeak)
What is it?
The whole earth is moving!
Caution, the tree!
(Elizabeth) Rune!
- Rune!
- Here I am.
- This is gold!
- What is it?
Gold.
The roots of the tree
have held it.
Where are you?
The freeze is in Tr  mmer gone.
What are you doing in that hole?
Look.
A miracle.
Here, here. In the tree.
- A miracle!
- (Elizabeth) Let me now through.
We are  ckspilze Eq.
(they talk and laugh excitedly)
(Frenchy) A miracle!
Come on everyone!
A miracle! A miracle!
(M ה male call and sing)
The lady and I have so much gold
that we do not know where to put it.
We have the art, and gr sch צ צ  te mine
has it ever been in the area.
Now fits on me,
I'll show you something.
Da, da, da!
Their gets all.
GOLDK צ rner so  large as peas.
Tomorrow I'll show you mine.
But today we celebrate!
This is the gr צ  th Celebration
ever in Montana.
- (Cheers)
- Peace, my friends! Quiet!
We have tons  ber tons.
It st צ mt from our ears and nose.
Lady! They will bring me  Gl ck.
Rub my arm with it.
Thanks sch צ n
No, no, lass.
I want to take home with them.
All right, partner.
- This is my little advance.
- Do what you want.
All those with me today, the city
make sure to follow me!
Come on, guys! Come on!
Now is celebrated.
Frenchy buys the store.
Free admission
f r is  Montana tonight.
Eq ה We do not need water,
The bottles here!
The bottles!
(general laughter and jeers)
Wei  t you remember last Sunday?
Because you wanted to know anything about me.
What makes it a bit of gold, eh?
- Take it's better to Flaunce.
- No, I need it here.
- This will be a night!
- You are n. wundersch צ
K צ, you can now understand
why people daf  r t צ even ten?
Yes.
- Now you'll never be poor.
- No, never.
I w  nschte, the doctor w ה here re.
Go and make yourself quickly finished.
We want to celebrate.
(M male yell and gr ה צ len)
Burn the dirty clothes.
Burn them! Burn them!
We nd z  at a bonfire
to celebrate the day!
Frenchy, the fire m  sstest see you.
(laughs)
Dr. Frail is here too?
A mine is eingest  rzt,
He has been there yesterday.
Preset  rzt?
(mumbles) What do we do now,
is a spa  f  r him.
Upstairs in his house.
Out comes between צ l!
Come between צ l!
L צ between!
(Rune) Doctor, are you there?
Do you already know the big  e news?
What do you want?
- The doctor is not there.
- You k צ nntest a sip you can g צ.
Thanks, but I do not drink.
I am invited to a celebration.
- What is happening?
- The celebration has already begun, boy.
I bring you some flowers.
F r  me flowers?
- You do not want to infect well?
- No.
W rden  now please go Frenchy?
Why?
I'm almost finished, then
we go together with Rune into the village.
Why is the village?
You and I are partners.
K צ we can celebrate as well.
Right here ...
But first we drink.
Come to Frenchy.
Or do you want
Frenchy that comes to you?
Frenchy is ready for anything.
(The mob cheered and gr צ lt)
The House of the cow doctor!
Infects his house!
- Where are Elizabeth and rune?
- At the top.
Crubb goads on the people
infect your house.
Frenchy has waited long enough.
(laughs צ b s)
(she screams)
M צ rder! Schl ה chter!
Lynch him!
H ה ngt him to the gallows tree!
(Crubb) Lynch him!
Rune!
(the crowd rages loudly)
We feel this is the most humane way
you Ten. to t צ
We take away the car
and you're dead
Tell your saying, Crubb.
Who man's blood Vergie  t
whose blood is also
be shed by man.
1. Book of Moses, 9 Chapter 6 Vers
Will not occur to me!
Their k צ nnt have our gold.
Their k צ nnt have everything
what we possess.
Rune is my partner.
He agrees.
Please take it.
We are the bottom of Flaunces shop.
There is so much.
Please take it.
Them.
Their k צ nnt even our mine have.
Here it is.
Their know what's worth it.
Please take them.
(sobs) Rune.
I tell you what:
She wants to buy their guy.
I should be glad.
Frenchy said
the mine is worth millions.
(Crubb) Help! To me!
Elizabeth.
(Music:''The Hanging Tree''
by Marty Robbins)
Warner Bros. Entertainment GmbH
Copyright © 2006 COVER, Berlin