(male narrator)
THE LEGEND
OF THE BAUDINE BROTHERS
HAS ETCHED ITSELF
INTO FRONTIER HISTORY
IN THE LAST QUARTER
OF THE 19TH CENTURY.
MORGAN "TWO PERSONS" BAUDINE,
CAPTURED BY THE CHEYENNE
AND FREED 8 YEARS LATER
BY THE ARMY.
QUENTIN BAUDINE,
A YOUNG DOCTOR,
FROM SAN FRANCISCO.
ACROSS THOUSANDS OF MILES
FROM THE MISSOURI BREAKS
TO THE CANADIAN RIVER,
FROM THE ROCKIES
TO THE HIGH PLAINS,
BOTH JOIN TOGETHER
IN A SEARCH
FOR THEIR SISTER, PATRICIA,
STILL A CAPTIVE
OF THE CHEYENNE.
THE LEGEND
OF THE BAUDINE BROTHERS.
THIS IS THEIR STORY.
THIS IS THE QUEST.
[horse neighing]
[neighing]
(Hatcher)
WHAT'S THE MATTER, SANTOS?
NEVER SEEN A LITTLE MARE
GIVE YOU THAT MUCH FUSS!
[horse continues neighing]
[Hatcher whistles]
[both laughing]
(Morgan)
QUENTIN.
WHAT IS IT?
I KNOW THAT BRAND.
THE LAZY H.
A MAN I USED TO KNOW
LIVES HERE.
WHO IS IT?
A RANCHMAN NAMED HATCHER.
MORGAN, I WANTED
TO GET INTO RED BLUFFS
BY THIS EVENING.
(Morgan)
WE CAN STILL MAKE IT.
COME ON.
[birds chirping]
[cattle lowing]
(Quentin)
HOW DO YOU KNOW
THIS MAN HATCHER?
(Morgan)
WELL, IT IS A LONG STORY,
BUT I WILL NEVER FORGET
THAT BRAND.
[horse nickers]
[sheep bleating]
[chickens clucking]
[horse nickers]
6 HORSES, $5 A HEAD.
$30.
I DON'T WANT NO $5 A HEAD
FROM YOU, MR. HATCHER.
THAT'S WHAT I CHARGE
THE OTHER RANCHERS.
YOU TAKE IT.
YOU FIXIN' TO BE
SO INDEPENDENT AND ALL.
DON'T DO ME NO FAVORS.
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU CHANGED
YOUR MIND ABOUT QUITTING.
I AIN'T CHANGED MY MIND.
THEN THE DEVIL TAKE YA!
WHAT DO YOU YOUNG MEN TODAY
KNOW ABOUT LOYALTY?
SPEND YEARS WITH A MAN
AND THEN SPIT IT
OUT THE WINDOW
LIKE A WAD OF TOBACCO.
ALL YOU GOT RIGHT NOW
IS 2 WRANGLERS AND ME,
MR. HATCHER.
AND I FIGURE MAYBE IF I GO,
IT'LL STOP YOU
FROM KILLIN' YOURSELF!
RUNNIN' OUT ON ME
FOR MY OWN GOOD, HUH?
IS THAT IT?
YOU AND THAT CRAZY ROUTE.
NO ONE TAKES A HERD
THROUGH THE BADLANDS.
AND YOU'VE HAD TOO MANY
BAD YEARS TO PULL IT OFF.
YOU'RE JINXED.
YOU AIN'T THE END
OF THE WORLD HERE!
I'LL GET ME ANOTHER RAMROD
AND OTHER MEN!
(Santos)
WITH WHAT?
YOU CAN'T AFFORD TO PAY
LIKE THE OTHER RANCHES
ANYMORE.
AND IT IS TOO LATE
IN THE SEASON TO MOVE CATTLE!
LOOK, WHY DON'T YOU SELL OUT
AND SIT DOWN A FEW YEARS?
YOU COULD USE A REST.
I'LL REST
WHEN I'M IN MY GRAVE.
MR. HATCHER,
I HOPE IT IS LATER,
RATHER THAN SOONER.
[cattle lowing]
(Morgan)
MATTHEW HATCHER?
HUH?
TWO PERSONS.
TWO PERSONS?
FROM CHIEF HO NEHE'S BAND.
HA.
NOT THAT SKINNY
LITTLE TOWHEADED KID
WITH THE FRECKLES
AND AN ADAM'S APPLE
THAT LOOKED LIKE
HE WAS EATIN' SOMETHIN'?
[laughs]
I NEVER THOUGHT OF MYSELF
IN THOSE WAYS, BUT, YES.
I'LL BE.
YOU SURE CHANGED SOME
SINCE I LAST SEEN YA.
TELL ME,
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN?
I WAS 10 YEARS OLD THEN.
HOW'S HO NEHE?
YOU KNOW I WAS THINKIN' ON HIM
JUST 2, 3 DAYS AGO.
HE IS DEAD, MR. HATCHER.
HORSE SOLDIERS.
UH-HUH.
SEEMED TO BE REACHING THE AGE
WHEN NEWS OF OLD FRIENDS DYIN'
COMES TOO OFTEN.
[horse nickers]
MR. HATCHER,
THIS IS MY BROTHER,
QUENTIN BAUDINE.
SEEMED TO RECALL
MENTION OF HIM.
BUT EVERYONE THOUGHT
YOU WAS DEAD.
[chuckling]
WELL, IT TOOK A FEW YEARS,
BUT I FINALLY
CAUGHT UP WITH HIM,
AND PROVED OTHERWISE.
WELL, I'M SURE GLAD YOU DID.
GLAD TO MEET YOU, QUENTIN.
HEY, WASN'T THERE A SISTER,
TWO PERSONS?
SHE IS STILL
WITH THE CHEYENNE.
IRON HAWK'S BAND.
IRON HAWK?
TOUGH AS HIS NAME.
ARE YOU TWO PLANNING
ON BRINGING HER BACK?
BECAUSE IF YOU ARE,
HE'LL PUT UP
A HELL OF A FIGHT.
WE'LL FIGHT
IF WE HAVE TO.
UH, WE THINK WE KNOW
WHERE THEY'VE MADE CAMP.
WE'RE HEADED THAT WAY NOW.
WELL, UH, LOOK, LOOK,
HOLD ON A MOMENT.
I GOT A HERD GOING OUT
IN A FEW DAYS UP TO PUEBLO.
COLORADO.
I COULD USE
SOME GOOD MEN.
MOST OTHERS HAVE SIGNED ON
WITH OTHER OUTFITS
AND GONE NORTH.
LOOK, I CAN PAY $20
AND THE SHARE.
THAT COULD WORK OUT
PRETTY GOOD AT THE OTHER END.
ANY OTHER TIME,
MR. HATCHER, THANK YOU.
WELL, UH,
I SURE COULD USE YOU.
WE--WE PLAN
TO SPEND THE NIGHT
IN RED BLUFFS
AND THEN LEAVE FIRST THING
IN THE MORNING.
IT IS IMPORTANT.
WE JUST STOPPED TO SAY HELLO.
AH. AH.
YOU'RE SURE?
YES, THANK YOU.
BUT IF YOU SHOULD HAPPEN
TO BE IN TOWN TONIGHT,
WE COULD HAVE FOOD TOGETHER.
AH.
UH, THANKS JUST THE SAME.
(Tucker)
HEY, MISTER,
I CURRIED
AND FED THEM HORSES
AND GAVE 'EM
BRAND NEW SHOES.
YOU OWE ME 50 CENTS
APIECE MORE.
HERE'S 2 BITS.
GO BUY YOURSELF 5 BEERS.
MISTER.
I'M A PEACEABLE MAN,
BUT YOU AIN'T MAKIN' IT EASY.
[groans]
[coins clinking]
THANK YOU.
I DO NOT BELIEVE
WHAT I JUST SAW.
WOULD YOU MIND
DOIN' THAT AGAIN?
FOR A PRICE,
I MIGHT DO ANYTHING.
HOW MUCH TO BOARD 'EM
OVERNIGHT?
2 BITS IN ADVANCE.
SO I DON'T HAVE
TO DO TO YOU
WHAT I DID TO THEM.
AND THAT'S EACH.
THAT'S A LITTLE BIT HIGH,
ISN'T IT?
THEY'LL GET GROOMING
AND A MEASURE OF GRAIN.
I'D SAY THEY NEED IT.
NO MORE THAN I DO, FRIEND.
OH, HE THREW
HIS RIGHT FRONT SHOE.
COME ON.
[clicking tongue]
YOU KNOW, I'M SO HUNGRY
I DON'T KNOW
WHETHER TO EAT FIRST
AND THEN TAKE A BATH
OR VICE VERSA.
HERE IT IS.
THIS IS THE ONE
I DID TODAY.
OH, TOM.
TOM, IT-IT'S SO LIFELIKE,
THERE'S A WHOLE STORY HERE.
AND THAT MAN,
YOU CAN JUST FEEL HIM HURTING,
WANTING TO BE FREE.
DO YOU REALLY SEE
ALL THAT IN THERE?
UH-HUH.
OH, BESS.
BESS, YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL.
HOLD IT.
I WOULDN'T GO NO FURTHER
IF I WAS YOU, WAKELY.
I'VE HEARD
THAT SPEECH BEFORE,
AND I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE LEADIN' UP TO.
NOW BESS MIGHT THINK IT FINE
TO MARRY YOU,
BUT I SEE IT DIFFERENT.
PAPA.
QUIET!
PRETTY PICTURES NEVER PUT
NO FOOD ON THE TABLE.
HE CAN'T EVEN TAKE CARE
OF HIMSELF,
MUCH LESS A WIFE OR A BABY.
[sighs]
OH, WAIT A MINUTE, BESS.
WAKELY.
YOU TAKE YOUR PAPER
AND YOUR PENCILS
AND YOU FIND YOURSELF A JOB.
[gasps]
(Cooler)
OH, YOU GUYS STILL HERE?
YA KNOW,
THERE AIN'T NO DOCTOR
IN THIS TOWN
IN CASE YOU CATCH PNEUMONY.
WELL, I HAPPEN
TO BE A DOCTOR
AND YOU DON'T KETCH PNEUMONY
FROM TAKIN' A BATH.
(Cooler)
MY ARMS ACHE SO BAD
[water splashing]
FROM FETCHIN' AND HAULIN'.
IT AIN'T NO SUNDAY PICNIC
HAULIN' THIS BOILIN' WATER.
[pouring water]
HEY, NOW, LOOK SON.
THERE IS NO NEED FOR YOU
TO DO THAT--
[gun firing]
[sighs]
OOH.
WELL, YOU SURE MADE
A MESS, DIDN'T YOU?
SUPPOSE I HAVE TO CLEAN UP
AFTER YOUR LITTLE
TARGET PRACTICE.
WELL, NOTHING LIKE A MAN
WHO'S GRATEFUL.
¶[music playing]
[men laughing]
(Drifter)
I HEARD TELL ANY BUSTER
WORTH HIS SALT
CAN BREAK A GREEN HORSE
WHILE CALMLY ROLLIN'
A CIGARETTE.
OH.
WELL, THAT'S RIGHT,
MY FRIEND.
BUT WHEN HE'S FINISHED,
HE LIGHTS UP
AND HAS A SMOKE.
[all laughing]
(Hatcher)
CAN AN IRISHMAN GET
A DRINK AROUND HERE?
COME ON, DON,
GIVE ME A WHISKEY.
[women giggling]
FOR THOSE OF YOU
WHO DON'T KNOW ME,
THE NAME'S HATCHER.
I GOT 1500 HEAD NEEDIN'
TO MOVE UP TO PUEBLO.
I CAN PAY $20 AND A SHARE.
THAT'S SHORT UP FRONT,
LONG IN THE END.
ANY TAKERS?
AMOS.
BUEL.
HOW DO LIKE WORKIN'
FOR THAT FOUR-FLUSHER AAMES?
I'M SORRY,
MR. HATCHER,
BUT WE'RE OFFERED A BETTER JOB
WORKIN' FOR HIM.
I ALWAYS GIVE YOU
FAIR TREATMENT.
WE KNOW THAT.
MR. AAMES OFFERED
MORE PAY.
WELL, YOU TELL MR. AAMES
NEXT TIME YOU SEE HIM
TO KEEP OUT OF MY WAY,
YOU SEE.
(Hatcher)
I SUPPOSE YOU'RE GOIN' OVER
TO AAMES, TOO, HUH?
YES.
BECAUSE YOU PUSH EVERYONE
TOO HARD.
I DON'T PUSH ANYONE ANY HARDER
THAN I PUSH MYSELF.
AND THAT IS TOO HARD.
NO ONE WILL WORK
FOR YOU ANYMORE, OLD MAN.
ANYBODY ELSE
TALKS TO ME THAT WAY,
I'D KILL 'EM.
(Morgan)
I THINK THE BATH FIRST
WAS A GOOD IDEA.
I'M NOT SO SURE.
LET'S EAT.
[people chattering]
(Morgan)
MR. HATCHER.
TWO PERSONS.
QUENTIN.
AH, YOU CAME
AFTER ALL.
WELL, I'M NOT WHAT YOU CALL
FIT COMPANY TONIGHT,
TWO PERSONS.
BUT, UH, YOU'RE WELCOME
IF YOU WANT TO SIT DOWN.
WOULD YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO EAT WITH US?
I'VE HAD SOMETHING.
THANKS, DOUG.
WHAT WILL YOU HAVE?
UH, I'LL HAVE A BEER,
AND SUPPER FOR BOTH OF US.
EATS ARE OVER THERE.
AND I'LL FETCH YOU THE BEERS.
I'LL GET IT.
UH, I JUST LOST MY RAMROD
TO ANOTHER RANCHER.
(man)
OH, MR. AAMES.
I FIGURED YOU WOULD SHOW UP
SOONER OR LATER.
YOU DRUNK OR JUST LOOKIN'
FOR TROUBLE, LIKE ALWAYS?
I'VE DRUNK ENOUGH
TO STAND FOR ALL OF MY MEN
BEIN' HIRED AWAY
BY YOU.
(Aames)
YOU'RE DEAD, HATCHER,
ONLY YOU DON'T KNOW IT YET.
WHY DON'T YOU GO
AND FIND YOURSELF A HOLE
AND LAY IN IT.
[women screams]
MR. HATCHER.
[Aames cursing]
(man)
OH, NO.
(Quentin)
Morgan!
(Morgan)
GET OUT OF HERE.
I WAS ONLY PROTECTING MYSELF.
EVERYBODY HERE
WILL TESTIFY TO THAT.
LOOKS LIKE
HE'S FINISHED.
NO, HE'S NOT.
I'M A DOCTOR,
GET EVERYBODY OUTTA HERE.
GET BACK.
(barkeeper)
UH, CLEAR THE BAR.  VAMOS.
GIVE ME MY GUN!
I'LL GIVE THIS
TO THE SHERIFF.
NOW GET OUTTA HERE.
(barkeeper)
COME ON, COME ON, COME ON.
GIVE ME A COUPLE OF TABLES
UNDER THAT LIGHT.
THAT'S DEEP ENOUGH.
GIVE ME SOME PRESSURE HERE.
IT'S BLEEDING TOO MUCH.
EASY, EASY.
NOW GIVE ME THE BISTOURY.
THE BISTOURY.
WHICH ONE IS IT?
I'M SORRY,
IT'S THE FLAT ONE.
THE THIN FLAT ONE.
HERE.
[footsteps approaching]
HOW DID IT HAPPEN?
HE AND AAMES
GOT INTO IT.
I'LL KILL AAMES FOR THIS.
THE SHERIFF
IS TAKING CARE OF IT.
(Morgan)
YOU KNOW MR. HATCHER?
FOR MANY YEARS.
WELL, YOU CAN STAY AROUND.
IF YOU'RE GONNA BE USEFUL,
HOLD HIM DOWN.
I CAN'T RISK HIM WAKIN' UP
AND MOVIN'.
GIVE ME THE PROBE.
WILL HE LIVE?
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
THE BULLET
ENTERED HIS LEFT SIDE,
AND IT'S RIGHT NEXT
TO HIS SPINE.
NOW IF I CAN GET IT OUT,
IF I DON'T PARALYZE HIM
DOIN' IT.
(Santos)
YOU GOTTA--
DON'T TALK TO ME RIGHT NOW.
YEAH.
YES.
I DON'T THINK I WOULD LIKE
TO BE A DOCTOR.
[sighs]
YOU SHOULD LIVE WITH ONE.
BARTENDER, GIVE ME
A TABLECLOTH THAT'S CLEAN,
SOMETHING WE CAN USE FOR RAGS.
UH, MAKE SURE IT'S CLEAN.
TEAR IT INTO STRIPS,
2 INCHES WIDE.
[cloth ripping]
(Quentin)
WELL, YOUR TICKER
SOUNDS ALL RIGHT.
I THINK YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT.
THOUGHT YOU TWO BOYS
WAS ALL FIRED
SET TO GETTING NORTH.
WE WERE,
UNTIL YOU GOT YOURSELF
INTO TROUBLE.
HMM.
GUESS I WAS OUT OF ORDER.
ONE OF THESE DAYS
MY TEMPER'S GONNA
GET ME BURIED.
SORRY SIGHT I MUST SEEM
TO YOU THIS WAY, TWO PERSONS.
NOT LIKE THE MAN
YOU MET WHEN,
WHEN YOU WAS 10.
NO.
THE MAN I MET WHEN I WAS 10
[clears throat]
WOULD NEVER HAVE
FELT SORRY FOR HIMSELF.
BUT WHO'S GOT A BETTER RIGHT?
WHAT YOU SEEN TODAY
IS ALL THAT'S LEFT OF ME
AND MY LIFE.
[breathing heavily]
A SHOT-UP, BATTERED,
RUIN OF A MAN.
AND THE RANCH AIN'T NO BETTER.
THE LAUDANUM'S TAKING EFFECT,
JUST LET YOURSELF GO TO SLEEP.
10 YEARS,
15 YEARS AGO, WE WAS
THE BEST IN THE TERRITORY.
HAD ME MY MISSUS THEN,
AND MY BOY,
AND THE WHOLE WORLD
OUTSIDE MY DOORSTOOP.
WHERE ARE THEY NOW,
MR. HATCHER?
BURIED
OUTSIDE MY DOORSTOOP.
LOST ETHEL
THE WINTER OF '68,
NOVEMBER THE 11TH, 6:40 P.M.
SON CARL WAS NEXT.
WAS TEACHIN' HIM
TO BRAND A STEER.
GOT HIS HEAD STOMPED IN
BY A NO-GOOD-FOR-NOTHIN'.
HE WAS ONLY 9.
SHOT THAT STEER 6 TIMES,
CRYIN' ALL THE TIME.
HOW DID THINGS GET SO BAD,
MR. HATCHER?
AFTER MY FAMILY DIED,
I JUST SORT OF WENT TO SEED.
BY THE TIME I COME OUT OF IT,
I WAS TOO FAR GONE.
DROVE TOO HARD,
WAS TOO SCARED.
NO WAY TO MAKE UP FOR IT.
THE BANK'S GONE WITH ME
AS FAR AS IT'LL GO.
IF I DON'T MAKE THIS DRIVE,
AND I LOSE EVERYTHING,
THE RANCH,
THAT'S THE END OF ME.
YOU CAN BURY ME OUT THERE
WITH MY WIFE AND SON.
MY LIFE WOULD HAVE GONE
FOR NOTHIN'.
MR. HATCHER,
I DO NOT KNOW MUCH
ABOUT CATTLE,
BUT MAYBE WE COULD
FIND OTHERS WHO DO.
AND WE COULD HELP YOU
ON THIS DRIVE.
ONLY THING IS
YOU KNOW HOW FAR I GOT
BY TRYIN' TO HIRE MEN.
WELL, THERE MUST BE MEN
WHO NEED WORK.
I WILL FIND THEM.
COULD I TALK TO YOU
FOR A SECOND?
OUTSIDE?
[sighs]
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKIN' ABOUT?
THAT'S 2 MONTHS' WORK
AT LEAST.
QUENTIN, WHEN I WAS 10
WE HAD A VERY BAD WINTER.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
YOUR PAST HISTORY.
THERE WAS NO GAME FINALLY,
EVEN FOR THE WOLVES.
I'M NOT GONNA LIKE THIS.
EVERYONE WENT TO SLEEP
HUNGRY AND COLD.
AND SOME OF THE OLD PEOPLE
AND CHILDREN BEGAN TO DIE OFF,
I THINK I BEGAN
TO DIE WITH THEM.
AND ONE DAY THIS MAN
CAME IN ON A HORSE,
AND 12 STEERS,
AND HE--HE WARMED HIS HANDS
BY OUR FIRE
AND THEN HE RODE AWAY.
HE NEVER EVEN ASKED
FOR A PAYMENT, OR THANKS.
ALL HE SAID WAS,
"I NEAR FROZE TO THE SADDLE
GETTIN' 'EM UP HERE.
DO NOT AIM
TO TAKE 'EM BACK DOWN."
YOU DON'T FIGURE
I EVENED THAT SCORE
BY PATCHIN' HIM UP?
I WILL ONLY OFFER MYSELF.
QUENTIN, I HAVE TO DO
WHAT I CAN TO HELP HIM.
WOULD YOU EVEN LIKE ME
IF I DID OTHERWISE?
NO.
WE'LL TRY.
MR. HATCHER,
YOU CANNOT THINK OF ANYONE
THAT WILL WORK FOR YOU?
(Hatcher)
NOT SINCE SANTOS LEFT ME.
UNLESS WE'RE FORCED TO
SCRAPE THE BOTTOM
OF THE BARREL.
I THINK WE ARE.
WELL, THERE'S--THERE'S PLENTY
AT THE STABLES. TUCKER.
HE'S OLDER NOW, BUT MAYBE...
HE HAD IT ONCE, ANYWAY.
I HEAR WALTER LUCAS
IS BACK IN TOWN.
AND THERE'S THE JANITOR
OF THE BATHHOUSE,
COOLER.
UH...
I DON'T WANT TO THINK ANYMORE,
I'M GETTIN' DEPRESSED.
(Quentin)
I CAN SEE THAT YOU KNOW
AND CARE ABOUT HORSES.
BUT DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT CATTLE?
CATTLE?
I'M PROBABLY
THE BEST BLACK COWBOY
THAT EVER RUBBED
HIS LEGS RAW ON A DRIVE.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
IT'S ALL UP TO YOU.
(Quentin)
WHERE DID YOU DO
ALL THIS 'COWBOYIN'?
RANCH IN TEXAS.
YEAH.
I WAS BORN THERE.
AFTER THAT
GREAT WONDERFUL WAR
THAT THEY TALKED ABOUT,
I TOOK MY FREEDOM AND WENT
WHERE I WASN'T A BLACK MAN.
THAT WAS ON A TRAIL DRIVE.
AND I WORKED HARD.
BUT I BECOME
THE BEST THERE IS.
NOW I DON'T
PAY MUCH ATTENTION
TO THIS BLACK
AND WHITE BUSINESS,
BUT IT'S ALWAYS NICE
TO HAVE THE BEST.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO COME ALONG?
NOW, THE PAY'S
NOT MUCH UP FRONT,
IT'S ONLY $20.
BUT WITH A SHARE,
BY THE END OF THE DRIVE
YOU COULD DO REAL GOOD
FOR YOURSELF.
MAYBE $50.
$50?
ARE YOU RUNNIN' STOLEN CATTLE
OR WHAT?
NO, NO.
IT'S HATCHER'S DRIVE.
YOU MEAN OLD MAN HATCHER?
YEAH, THEY SAY--SAY
HE'S JINXED OR SOMETHING.
NOW IF THAT WORRIES YA...
JINXED?
ALL YOU GOTTA DO
IS STEP OUT ON THE TRAIL.
LUCK AND GOD
KISS YOU GOODBYE.
A MAN CAN GET STAMPEDED,
DROWNED, DRAGGED,
GOUGED, STOMPED,
FROZEN AND FRIED
ALL IN ONE DAY.
JINX. EVERY DAY'S A JINX.
HEY, HE'S HAVIN' TROUBLE
FINDIN' MEN, AIN'T HE?
W-WHAT MAKES YOU THINK THAT?
YOU'RE ASKIN' ME, AIN'T YA?
YOU FIGURIN' I'M TOO OLD?
I'M ASKIN' YOU, AIN'T I?
I'LL GO.
I'LL SHOW THESE PEOPLE
AROUND HERE
I AIN'T NO STABLE BOY.
(Morgan)
MR. LUCAS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
CAN WE TALK?
I GOT MORE IMPORTANT THINGS
TO DO, BOY.
THIS IS IMPORTANT.
I USUALLY ONLY SAY THINGS
ONE TIME.
IT IS ABOUT MATTHEW HATCHER.
[sighs]
HE GONNA LIVE?
I THINK MAYBE SO, YES.
COME ON UP, BOY.
I WASN'T PLANNIN'
ON NO SPECTATORS.
YEAH, I DON'T PAY YOU
TO TALK, FRAN.
GET UP THERE.
OH, WANT A DRINK, BOY?
I AIN'T REFUSIN'.
MR. HATCHER SAYS THAT
12 YEARS AGO,
YOU WERE THE BEST WRANGLER
ON HIS RANCH.
[clears throat]
HMM.
I WAS.
THEN I LEFT HATCHER AND I,
I SIGNED ON WITH ONE
OF THEM OUTFITS
IN A RANGE WAR.
KILLED A COUPLE PEOPLE
IN THE LINE OF DUTY
I GUESS YOU WOULD SAY.
NOW IT NEVER SEEMS TO STOP.
THE LAST KID TRYIN'
TO PROVE HIMSELF
WAS 17, 18 YEARS OLD,
I GUESS.
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING MORE,
RIGHT.
I GOT ME
A CLOSE PERSONAL RELATIONSHIP
NEEDS DEVELOPIN'.
MR. HATCHER NEEDS HELP.
BOY, I CAN'T EVEN
HELP MYSELF.
HE'S TAKING 1500 STEERS
ON A DRIVE.
AND NO ONE WILL HELP HIM.
YEAH, WELL.
I HEARD HE'S HAD
A BAD RUN OF LUCK.
A LONG RUN.
MR. LUCAS,
HE NEEDS YOU BAD.
SAY, UH, DID MATTHEW
EVER TELL YOU
HOW HE HELPED ME?
HE WOULDN'T.
HE'S NOT THE TYPE.
HE'S THE ONE MAN IN THE WORLD
I OWE SOMETHIN' TO.
WHERE'S THIS DRIVE END UP,
ANYWAY?
PUEBLO.
PUEBLO, THAT'S ON THE WAY
TO CHICAGO.
MMM-HMM.
LET'S GO.
OH, UH...
SORRY, FRAN,
GUESS I'M OUTTA THE MOOD.
(Fran)
WELL, I AIN'T.
HERE YOU GO, GIRL.
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF.
[explosion]
[horse whinnying]
[crackers continue bursting]
[chuckles]
WELL, UH,
I GUESS IT'S TIME
I QUIT PLAYIN' THE BAD GUY
AND WENT ON BACK
TO SEE MY FAMILY, HUH?
MR. HATCHER SAID
THAT YOU USED TO RIDE
CHUCK WAGON.
I USE TO DO A LOT OF THINGS.
WOULD YOU BE INTERESTED
IN GOING ON ANOTHER
CATTLE DRIVE?
I'VE RODE WITH SOME
OF THE BEST OUTFITS OF MY TIME
AND I WAS PAID
REAL PROPER, TOO.
OF COURSE,
I HAD A LOT OF DIGNITY
BACK THEN.
BEFORE THE BOTTLE GOT TO ME,
AND OLD AGE.
BUT DRUNK OR SOBER,
I COULD FEED A MAN
AND KEEP HIM HAPPY.
WE NEED A COOK,
BUT HE'D HAVE
TO STAY SOBER.
I'LL GIVE IT A TRY.
[crickets chirping]
HI, SWEETHEART.
ARE YOU READY?
YEAH.
HURRY UP.
BUT I,
I'VE NEVER ELOPED BEFORE.
WELL, NEITHER HAVE I.
NEITHER HAVE I.
I GOT JUST A FEW THINGS.
OH, BESS,
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR ALL OF THIS STUFF.
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
YOU'RE TAKING EVERYTHING
YOU OWN?
YOU DON'T EXPECT ME TO ELOPE
WITH WHAT I HAVE ON, DO YOU?
[knocking on door]
YES, I DO.
(Pratt)
OPEN UP.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
(Bess)
NOTHING, FATHER.
IS THIS WHAT
I THINK IT IS?
NO.
WAKELY? IS THAT YOU OUT THERE,
YOU NO-GOOD-FOR-NOTHIN'
SQUIRREL!
WHERE'S MY GUN?
FATHER, DON'T SHOOT HIM!
I LOVE HIM!
OH, FATHER, DON'T!
[chicken clucking]
[cow mooing]
MR. HATCHER.
I HAVE YOUR DRONES.
BRING 'EM OVER.
[horse neighing]
COME ON IN, FELLOWS.
HERE THEY ARE.
(Hatcher)
HELLO THERE, TUCKER.
(Tucker)
MR. HATCHER.
COOLER.
LUCAS, IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME.
YEAH, LONGER,
LONGER FOR ME THAN YOU,
I RECKON.
THIS IS ALL
YOU GOT?
WELL, THERE ARE 2 MORE,
BUT THEY WILL JOIN US
ON THE TRAIL.
AH.
SO, YOU'RE ALL GONNA
DO ME A BIG FAVOR
BY GOING ON THE DRIVE,
ARE YA?
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
YOU AIN'T DOIN' ME NO FAVOR,
I SURE AIN'T DOIN' YOU ONE.
ALL OF YOU BEEN
ON DRIVES BEFORE,
BUT YOU'VE MOST LIKELY FORGET
WHAT THEY WAS LIKE.
A THOUSAND MILES OF NOTHIN',
EXCEPT DIRT AND GRIT
AND HEAT
AND SORE BOTTOMS
AND ACHES IN PLACES
YOU WISHED YOU DIDN'T HAVE.
I SAID WE WASN'T GONNA
DO ONE ANOTHER NO FAVORS.
WELL,
MAYBE I WAS WRONG ABOUT THAT.
BECAUSE YESTERDAY AT THIS TIME
I WOULDN'T HAVE GIVEN MYSELF
A CHANCE IN HELL OF EVER
GETTIN' THIS DRIVE GOIN'.
BUT NOW,
LOOKIN' AT YOU,
I FIGURE WE'RE ALL GONNA
MAKE IT.
BECAUSE WE'VE GOTTA MAKE IT.
BECAUSE WE GOT NOTHIN'
TO LOOK FORWARD TO
EXCEPT THE END OF THE DRIVE.
PUEBLO.
'CAUSE THERE AIN'T
NOTHIN' HERE FOR ANY OF US.
NOTHIN'.
SIGN 'EM UP!
WHOA. WHOA.
UH, MR. HATCHER.
HUH.
I'M WAKELY.
REMEMBER ME?
I WAS SKETCHING
OVER AT THE CORRAL
THE OTHER DAY.
YEAH, I REMEMBER YOU.
THOMAS R. WAKELY, JR.
I'D SURE APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU'D TAKE ME ALONG
WITH YOU ON YOUR DRIVE.
UH, THE SOONER THE BETTER.
[chuckling]
WELL,
MR. THOMAS R. WAKELY, JR.,
JUDGIN' BY YOUR DRESS,
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
THE HIND END OF A COW
FROM THE DROTHER.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU'RE A COWBOY?
WELL, I'M--I'M
A REAL HARD WORKER.
THERE'S NO REASON
WHY I CAN'T DRESS DIFFERENTLY.
I LEARN REAL FAST.
AFTER ALL,
I-I'M A YALE MAN.
(Hatcher)
WELL, MR. YALE MAN,
WHATEVER THAT IS,
PUT YOUR SIGNATURE ON THE BOOK
AND LET'S SEE IF IT'S LEGIBLE.
YES, SIR.
[horse neighing]
(Quentin)
WHAT'S THAT, COOLER?
WHAT HAVE YOU GO HERE?
I THOUGHT WE HAD A DEAL.
YOU SAW ME DRIVING.
I'M DOING MY JOB.
YOU BROKE YOUR PROMISE.
I HAVEN'T BEEN SOBER
IN 20 YEARS.
OR CLEAN EITHER.
HEY, NOW WAIT A MINUTE!
NOW WAIT.
WAIT A MINUTE!
I'LL TAKE CARE OF THIS MYSELF.
I'LL GO TO THE BATHHOUSE.
[all chattering]
WAIT A MINUTE! WAIT A MINUTE!
MY BOOTS!
I'LL GET YOUR BOOTS.
YOU TAKE CARE
OF THAT HAT NOW.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
WAIT A MINUTE! WAIT A MINUTE!
OH, WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR THIS.
[yelling]
IT'S WORSE
THAN I REMEMBERED.
[bell clanging]
YOU'RE GETTING BETTER.
[horse nickers]
A SADDLE
ON TWO PERSONS' PONY.
[laughing]
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D SEE THE DAY.
THIS WORLD WILL TAKE
SOME GETTING USED TO,
THIS COWBOY.
NICE PAIR OF CHAPS,
QUENTIN.
YEAH.
[laughing]
WHO'S IN CHARGE HERE?
[horse whinnying]
(Morgan)
WE ARE.
WE HEARD IN TOWN
THAT YOU'RE TAKIN' OUT A DRIVE
AND CAN USE HANDS.
(Quentin)
YOU HEARD
WHAT THE PAY IS?
YEAH, WE HEARD.
HAVE YOU HAD
ANY EXPERIENCE?
AS MUCH AS ANYONE
AROUND HERE HAS.
YOU WANTED FOR ANYTHING?
WELL, UH,
IN THESE PARTS,
IT'S USUAL NOT TO ASK
QUESTIONS LIKE THAT,
BUT I'LL ANSWER YOU.
WE AIN'T WANTED,
AND WE'RE NOT RUNNIN',
AND WE'LL CAUSE YOU
NO TROUBLE.
WHAT WE WANT
IS WORK.
JESS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE NEED THE PAY.
YOU SIGN UP
WITH MR. HATCHER.
HE'S IN THE HOUSE.
COME ON. WHOA.
I KNOW.
BUT WE DO NEED THEM.
[cattle lowing]
[mooing]
[grunts]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
[laughing]
FANCY PANTS
DON'T MAKE A COWBOY, ARBUCKLE.
I'D RATHER BRAND BILLY DON'S
HIND END THAN THE STEER'S.
YOU WANNA TRY AGAIN?
I'M GONNA HAVE
SOME WORDS WITH HIM.
HE HAD NO CAUSE TO DO THAT.
I THINK WAKELY
CAN TAKE CARE OF IT HIMSELF.
HE JUST DOES NOT
KNOW THAT YET.
WELL, NOW MAYBE YOU DON'T
WANNA TRY AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, McKINNON,
LET'S GET THIS STRAIGHT
RIGHT NOW.
(Billy Don)
YOU WANT ME TO TAKE YOU APART
IN FRONT OF ALL THESE MEN?
OK, NOW, YOU-YOU'RE NEW
AT THIS, ARBUCKLE.
BUT I WANNA TELL YOU,
IT HURTS WHEN BILLY DON HITS.
I THINK
YOU'RE ALL MOUTH, McKINNON.
NOW YOU STAY OUT OF THIS.
THIS IS BETWEEN HIM AND ME.
YEAH, HE'S RIGHT.
HE'S RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
HE AIN'T NOTHING
BUT A CITY SLICKER.
COME ON, LET IT GO NOW.
COME ON, BILLY DON.
(Tucker)
THAT'S IT, WAKELY.
COME ON, WAKELY.
COME ON, BILLY DON,
DON'T JUST LOOK AT HIM.
HIT HIM.
(Morgan)
JUST DO IT.
(Tucker)
COME ON, COME ON!
[grunts]
[all shouting]
[groans]
GO GET HIM, BOY.
NEVER SEEN ANYBODY FIGHT
LIKE THAT?
(Cooler)
THAT'S WHAT YOU CALL BOXING.
(Lucas)
GET HIM OFF!
(Quentin)
COME ON, DO IT.
GET HIM ON HIS FEET, WAKELY.
[grunts]
THAT'S IT. COME ON!
(Quentin)
COME ON, WAKELY.
[grunts]
COME ON.
(Quentin)
COME ON, WAKELY, COME ON.
KEEP HIM ON HIS FEET.
USE YOUR LEFT.
(Quentin)
COME ON, JAB HIM, WAKELY.
COME ON, BILLY DON,
HIT HIM!
(Quentin)
WAKELY, USE YOUR LEFT.
[all continue clamoring]
COME ON. THAT'S IT.
[grunts]
[exclaims]
[both panting]
(Cooler)
THAT'S IT.
GET UP, BILLY DON.
DON'T JUST LAY THERE.
(Lucas)
GET UP. GET UP.
[both panting]
(Morgan)
IS THAT ENOUGH?
IS THE FIGHTING OVER NOW?
[cattle lowing]
GOOD. WE HAVE WORK
TO GET BACK TO.
[both continue panting]
(Billy Don)
OW! IT HURTS.
HEY, McKINNON.
YEAH.
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT'S THAT?
ARBUCKLE.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
[laughs]
IT'S WHAT I AIN'T GONNA
CALL YOU NO MORE.
[laughing]
ALL RIGHT, COME ON,
GIVE IT TO ME.
PUT THESE BACK HERE NOW.
WILL YOU WAIT A MINUTE?
I'VE ONLY GOT 2 HANDS.
HATCHER WANTS TO HAVE 'EM
TO BRAND ANY MAVERICKS
ON OUR TRAIL.
[grunts]
COME ON DOWN, COOLER. I'LL...
LOOK AT IT THIS WAY.
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN BITTEN
BY THAT SNAKE MY BROTHER SHOT.
[grunts]
EITHER WAY
THE SNAKE WOULD'VE DIED.
[can clanking]
[horse nickering]
[cow mooing]
[birds chirping]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
I'VE GOT A RASH.
OH, IT'LL TAKE A FEW DAYS
TO GET OVER THAT.
MEANWHILE, QUENTIN
HAS SOME SALVE.
[chuckling]
OH, SOUNDS WONDERFUL.
(Quentin)
HOW YOU FEELING?
(Hatcher)
LET'S GET ONE THING STRAIGHT.
I DON'T WANT YOU AROUND
NURSEMAIDIN'.
YOU'RE HERE TO PUSH COWS
AND NOT TO PUSH ME.
JUST DO WHAT I TELL YOU
TO DO, I WON'T PUSH IT.
I GOT YOU AN EXTRA SUPPLY
OF LAUDANUM
AND SOME BULLETS FOR YOU
TO BITE ON.
I DON'T NEED NO BULLETS
AS LONG AS I GOT THIS.
WE'RE GONNA HEAD NORTHEAST
AND JOIN
THE GOODNIGHT-LOVIN' TRAIL
UNTIL THE COLORADO BADLAND.
THEN STRAIGHT UP TO PUEBLO.
DO WE HAVE TO CROSS 'EM?
YEAH, I'VE BEEN UP
TO THEM BADLANDS.
I SWORE I'D NEVER GO BACK.
I'VE HEARD THEY CAN KILL YA.
(Hatcher)
THEY CAN,
BUT WE ARE NOT GONNA LET 'EM.
THERE'VE BEEN
INDIAN UPRISINGS.
BUT WE GO AROUND
THE EXTRA 300 MILES,
WE'LL MISS THE MARKET.
THEN NONE OF US
WILL GET ANY SHARES.
I AIN'T A QUITTER.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
NO TALK OF QUITTIN'
FROM YOU NEITHER.
[cattle continue mooing]
YOU'LL LEARN FAST OUT THERE.
YOU'LL PROVE UP.
YOU'LL SHOW 'EM!
WELL, WHAT'RE YA WAITIN' FOR?
GET THESE THINGS MOVING!
(Morgan)
HEE-HA.
[all chattering]
[men whistling]
[all shouting]
[cattle mooing]
[all continue shouting]
[whistling]
(Santos)
MR. HATCHER. MR. HATCHER.
MR. HATCHER.
HOLD UP, COOLER.
STOP, GO, STOP, GO!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHAT'RE YOU DOIN' HERE?
I HAVE AN AMULET.
WHAT'S THAT?
THE JINX CANNOT HARM ME.
[laughing]
AN AMULET.
I SUPPOSE YOU GOT DRUNK
AND SPENT ALL OF THAT
30 BURSTIN' DOLLARS
ON SOME STOVE-UP WOMAN.
YOU COMIN'?
SOMEONE HAS TO BE THERE
TO BURY YOU.
WELL, WE'LL SEE
WHO BURIES WHO.
WHAT'RE YOU DOIN'
STANDIN' THERE?
GET TO WORK.
[chuckling]
AMULET.
(Billy Don)
HOO. HOO, CATTLE.
OH, LET'S GO.
[whistling]
HO, CATTLE. HO, CATTLE.
[men shooing]
(Billy Don)
GO. GO UP THERE.
[continue shooing]
(Morgan)
HEY, MR. COOLER,
IT SMELLS REAL GOOD.
WILL YOU OPEN SOME OF THOSE
AIR-TIGHT CANS.
GET CORN AND TOMATOES.
JUST GIVE ME
A LITTLE MORE--
IT WILL BE HERE
WHEN YOU COME BACK.
WILL YOU DO WHAT I TELL YOU?
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, COME ON,
COME ON, COME ON.
WHO'S HERE?
POINTED OUT TO YOU EXACTLY.
WILL YOU GET YOUR THUMB
OUT OF YOUR FOOD?
SAY, TUCKER,
[Cooler shouting]
EVER BEEN ON A DRIVE BEFORE?
YEAH. HOW MANY DRIVES
HAVE YOU BEEN ON?
2 OR 3.
THAT WAS BEFORE.
BEFORE?
YEAH, BEFORE I STARTED
USIN' MY GUN.
[snickers]
I HAD MY WIFE THEN.
AND I DRAGGED HER AND THE KID
FROM PLACE TO PLACE,
NO ROOTS NOWHERE.
MY WIFE WAS GETTIN'
NEAR THE END OF THE LINE
WHEN I GOT SLAPPED IN JAIL
FOR 2 YEARS.
GOT OUT,
I HEARD
THAT SHE'D BEEN WORKIN'.
BEIN' FRIENDLY TO MEN.
SUPPORTIN' THE KID, YOU KNOW.
WAS HATCHER
HAD FOUND OUT
AND HE--HE PAID THEIR FARES
BACK TO CHICAGO.
AND I--
I NEVER BEEN ABLE
TO CATCH UP SINCE.
IS THAT WHY YOU TOOK THIS JOB?
YEAH.
YOU MIGHT SAY
IT'S A NEW START.
SAY, YOU KNOW, TUCKER,
I BEEN THINKIN',
THIS HERE DRIVE
ENDS UP IN PUEBLO,
THERE AIN'T NO REASON
WHY I CAN'T MAKE A GO OF IT
IN CHICAGO.
I'D GET TO MY WIFE
AND DAUGHTER BACK.
AND I'D NEVER LEAVE AGAIN.
I'LL TELL YOU THAT.
I'D NEVER LEAVE AGAIN.
SHE WOULDN'T BE LONESOME
LIKE SHE WAS BEFORE.
I'D GET ME A HOUSE,
BE WITH CIVILIZED FOLKS
AND HAVE FRIENDS OVER.
DON'T YOU THINK
THAT'D MAKE HER HAPPY?
I DON'T SEE HOW IT WOULDN'T
MAKE ANYONE HAPPY.
YEAH, NOTHIN' FANCY,
MIND YA.
BUT JUST A NICE HOUSE
IN TOWN.
NOW ME, I GOT MY EYES
ON A PIECE OF LAND
IN NEW MEXICO.
I CAN GET IT REAL CHEAP.
WORST PIECE OF LAND
IN THE COUNTRY.
NOBODY WANTS IT.
THAT WAY EVERYBODY WILL LEAVE
THIS OLD BOY ALL ALONE.
[chuckles]
AMEN, BROTHER. AMEN.
[cattle mooing]
(Jess)
LAY IT DOWN.
TIME IT JUST RIGHT,
LITTLE BROTHER.
[Jess grunts]
[cow groaning]
(Jess)
WHEN THE HAIR GROWS BACK,
WE CAN PUT ON OUR OWN BRAND.
[mooing]
(Billy Don)
WE DONE ABOUT A DOZEN, JESS.
NOW, AIN'T THAT ENOUGH?
QUIT LOOKIN' SO SCARED.
I KNOW LOTS OF BIG RANCHERS
STARTED OUT THIS WAY.
YEAH, PAPPY GOT HIMSELF KILLED
STARTIN' OUT THIS WAY.
MEN LIKE HATCHER
STEAL A FEW COWS
FROM EACH OTHER
AND IT'S OK.
THEY CALL IT ENTERPRISING,
'CAUSE IT'S AMONGST FRIENDS.
PAPPY WASN'T THEIR FRIEND,
SO THEY HUNG HIM,
WITHOUT A TRIAL OR NOTHIN'.
WE GONNA COLD-BRAND
A COUPLE DOZEN MORE,
PULL OUT QUIET ONE NIGHT,
PUT OUR OWN BRAND
ON THEM BEEVES,
AND THEY AIN'T NEVER
GONNA PROVE RUSTLIN' ON US.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
WE JUST GOT
TO BE A LITTLE SMARTER'
THAN EVERYBODY ELSE,
BILLY DON. THAT'S ALL.
[men whistling]
[man grunting]
[men hooting]
[cattle mooing]
[man whistling]
[cows mooing]
HEY, BUNCH-QUITTER,
I'LL GET YOU BACK.
(Lucas)
MOVING FORWARD.
[hooting]
[mooing]
[whistles]
[neighing]
[groaning]
RIDER DOWN!
[horse neighing]
[horses neighing]
[snorting]
[gun firing]
[horse snorting]
(Quentin)
HE'S DEAD.
HIS NECK'S BROKEN!
BURY HIM!
[sighing]
I DON'T BELIEVE IN JINXES,
BUT THIS IS AN AWFUL WAY
TO START OFF.
[panting]
THIS IS JUST THE BEGINNING,
QUENTIN.
[cows mooing]
WHEN WE GET TO PUEBLO,
I'LL SEND LUCAS' WIFE
AND DAUGHTER HIS SHARE.
NOT MUCH CONSOLATION,
THOUGH, IS IT?
[snorts]
IT'S STRANGE TO THINK
THAT HE'LL NEVER ENJOY
ANYTHING AGAIN.
A CUP OF HOT COFFEE,
A WOMAN,
THE SUNRISE.
I HAVE THE FEELING
THAT LUCAS WOULD RATHER
HAVE HAD IT LIKE THIS
THAN TO BE SHOT DOWN
IN AN ALLEY SOMEWHERE.
YEAH.
[men hooting]
[grunts]
[man whistling]
[men grunting]
HEY, TWO PERSONS.
GOT ANOTHER DOUBLE 'A'.
PUT IT IN WITH THE OTHERS.
I'LL TELL HATCHER.
ALL RIGHT.
[crickets chirping]
YOU DIDN'T HAVE
NOTHIN' TO EAT, EH?
GOT ANY COMPLAINTS?
I ALWAYS GOT COMPLAINTS.
JESS, MY BROTHER'S
STILL ON WATCH OUT THERE?
HE'S OUT ON IT NOW.
YOU FIGURE ON GOING BACK
OUT YOURSELF?
I'M THINKIN' ABOUT IT.
[sighs]
MR. HATCHER,
WE BROUGHT IN
ANOTHER DOUBLE 'A' STRAY
TODAY.
REMEMBER DALTON AAMES,
THE MAN WHO SHOT ME
AND HIRED ALL MY HANDS AWAY?
MMM-HMM.
THAT'S HIS OUTFIT, DOUBLE 'A'.
HIS BOYS
BROUGHT A HERD THROUGH HERE
ABOUT 2 MONTHS AGO,
EARLY IN THE SEASON.
KEEP 'EM WITH OURS.
I'LL SELL 'EM IN PUEBLO.
[laughs]
WANT TO SEE HIS FACE
WHEN I GIVE HIM THE MONEY.
SETTLE FOR MY COMMISSION
AND AGGRAVATION.
AFTER WHAT HE DID TO YOU,
YOU WILL DO HIM THIS FAVOR.
TWO PERSONS,
JUST 'CAUSE I HATE HIS GUTS
DON'T MEAN
I DON'T HAVE NO HONOR.
(Quentin)
WHERE WERE YOU, McKINNON?
IT'S YOUR WATCH.
MAKING SURE YOU HAVE
A GOOD TIME.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU GO
AND JOIN THE FUN?
SAVED SOME PIE FOR YA.
[sighs]
HEY, LOOK AT THIS.
(Quentin)
YOU KNOW, WAKELY,
IF I HAD YOUR TALENT,
I SURE WOULDN'T BE OUT HERE
NURSEMAIDIN' CATTLE.
YOU SAY THAT.
I TELL YOU, THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS KIND OF LIFE
WHICH I'VE NEVER EXPERIENCED
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
WHAT I HOPE TO DO
WITH THESE DRAWINGS
IS SHOW THE CITY PEOPLE
WHAT IT'S REALLY LIKE
OUT HERE.
I MEAN, IT'S--IT'S HARD.
THE GRIMNESS OF DEATH.
BUT ALSO,
ALL THIS OPEN SPACE.
FEELING OF FREEDOM.
[chuckles]
ANYWAY,
THAT'S WHAT I'M TRYING TO GET
IN THESE PICTURES.
I DON'T KNOW.
I'VE SEEN A LOT OF PHOTOGRAPHS
OF DEAD MEN BEFORE.
BUT THEY ALL LOOK
LIKE THEY WERE ASLEEP.
BUT THAT PICTURE
SHOWS YOU DEATH.
YOU CAN FEEL IT.
THANKS, TUCKER.
YOU KNOW, SON, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THERE AIN'T A COWBOY
WORTH HIS SPURS
THAT WOULD WANT TO END UP
IN A BOOT HILL OR A CEMETERY.
HE'D WANT THE OPEN SPACES.
THE SKY FOR A BLANKET.
OLD MAN HATCHER'S
TAKIN' IT PRETTY HARD.
HE ALWAYS HAS.
I WAS WITH HATCHER
ON HIS LAST DRIVE.
AT THE FORDING PLACE
ON THE SALADO,
WE LOST MOST OF THE HERD.
THE WATER WAS BAD.
THE CATTLE DRANK AND DIED.
AND ON THE WAY HOME,
2 MEN WERE STRUCK
BY LIGHTNING.
YOU WERE STILL RIDING
WITH HIM?
[sighs]
YES, WHY DO YOU SUPPOSE
THAT IS?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
I HAVE MY REASONS.
I OWE HIM A LOT.
SO DO I.
I PROMISED MYSELF
I'D NEVER RIDE
WITH HATCHER AGAIN,
BUT HERE I AM.
HE PUSHES TOO HARD,
HE YELLS AT YOU,
HE TELLS YOU,
YOU AREN'T WORTH ANYTHING,
AND YOU CAN HATE HIM
BUT YOU GO ALONG.
MAYBE IT'S BECAUSE
HE WANTS SO BADLY TO MAKE IT,
OR MAYBE IT'S BECAUSE
HE NEEDS YOU
BUT DOESN'T KNOW
HOW TO SAY IT.
[snorts]
[cattle mooing]
[men grunting]
(Jess)
FASTER, FASTER. COME ON!
(Quentin)
COME ON!
(Tucker)
ALL RIGHT NOW.
COME ON.
COME ON HERE!
[mooing]
DIDN'T I TEEL YOU.
I KNOW.
THEY'VE BEEN FOLLOWING US
FOR DAYS.
WELL, WHY AIN'T YOU
UP THERE TALKIN' TO 'EM?
BECAUSE IT IS NOT YET TIME
FOR TALK.
I KNOW THEM.
AND FOR NOW, WE WAIT.
JUST LET THE HERD
MOVE ON AHEAD.
I AIN'T JUST GONNA SIT
AND LET 'EM PICK US OFF.
HEY, WE CAN TAKE 'EM EASY.
I SAY WE WIPE 'EM OUT!
MAKE ONE MOVE FOR THAT RIFLE
AND I WILL SHOOT YOU MYSELF.
LOOK.
[grunting]
ARAPAHOE.
[Indians shouting]
KEEP STILL.
THIS IS THEIR WAY OF TESTING.
A DISPLAY OF STRENGTH.
YOU'RE SURE THEY'RE NOT TRYING
TO SPOOK THE CATTLE.
NO.
IT'S US
THEY'RE TRYING TO SCARE.
I THINK IT'S WORKING.
[Indians hollering]
[hollering continues]
LOOK, McKINNON,
MY BROTHER WARNED YOU NOW.
HEY, NOW PUT IT AWAY!
IF HE SAYS WAIT. WE WAIT.
HUT!
"TO ALL OUTFITS,
"THIS MAN IS A GOOD INDIAN.
"TREAT HIM RIGHT
AND YOU WILL HAVE NO TROUBLE
DRIVING THROUGH HIS LAND.'
DALTON AAMES!
TWO PERSONS, CUT OUT THEM COWS
WITH A DOUBLE 'A' BRAND.
[laughs]
HEY, COOLER,
IMAGINE AAMES' FACE
WHEN HE FINDS OUT
HE'S FEEDIN' THE WHOLE TRIBE
OF ARAPAHOE THIS WINTER. HUH?
[both laughing]
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU WAITIN'
TO RUN FOR, COOLER?
GET MOVIN'!
[grunts]
[cattle mooing]
[men grunting]
[men whistling]
[shouts]
[horses neighing]
(Cooler)
GIDDY UP! GIDDY UP!
WHAT'S HAPPENING, COOLER?
STOP!
[grunts]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
I'M DOIN' THE BEST I CAN!
HEY, UP FROM HERE!
[Cooler grunts]
LOOK WHAT'S BEHIND US!
[horses neighing]
[Cooler grunting]
WAGON IN TROUBLE!
TUCKER, COME HERE!
[grunting]
TUCKER, THE HORSES!
HUT!
PUSH IT, TUCKER!
[Hatcher shouting]
(Hatcher)
TUCKER!
[grunting]
[Tucker grunts]
(Hatcher)
HURRY UP, TO THE WAGON!
HURRY UP!
[gasping]
[Cooler grunts]
KEEP IT STEADY, COOLER.
(Quentin)
TIE IT OFF NOW, MORGAN.
THAT'S IT.
NOW, COME ON, COOLER.
KEEP IT STEADY.
(Quentin)
READY YET!
WE'RE GOOD! PULL THEM!
[grunting]
[horses neighing]
COME ON, PULL NOW!
HURRY. TUCKER!
HEY! HEY! HEY!
[horse neighs]
[all chattering]
PULL!
[Quentin whistling]
[grunting]
[groans]
[Cooler grunts]
(Quentin)
TUCKER!
[Tucker gasping]
YOU ALL RIGHT, TUCKER?
NO, STAY DOWN.
STAY DOWN.
[gasping]
GET HIM SOME WATER.
IT'S HIS BACK.
TUCKER, YOUR BACK IS HURT
NOW LAY DOWN.
[gasping]
[panting]
[sighs]
LET ME REST
[gasping]
AWHILE.
I'LL BE ALL--ALL RIGHT.
[sighs]
[insects chirping]
[clears throat]
I'M ALL RIGHT.
IS THAT TOO HOT?
NO, IT FEELS FINE.
WHAT DOES IT DO?
HE NEVER KNOWS,
BUT IT ALWAYS WORKS.
MIGHT EVEN GROW SOME HAIR
ON YOUR HEAD.
WHEN WE STARTED OUT
I DIDN'T GIVE
A HOOT AN A HOLLER
ABOUT ANY OF YOU.
BUT YOU'VE PROVED UP.
YOU'RE ALL GOOD MEN
AND I THINK YOU'RE BEGINNIN'
TO KNOW IT NOW.
YOU HELP ME
GET MY HERD THROUGH,
YOUR SHARES ARE DOUBLED.
[all whooping]
THANK YOU, SIR.
WELL, THANKS, MR. HATCHER.
MR. TUCKER.
YEAH.
I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR WHAT YOU DONE FOR ME
TODAY.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
MR. COOLER,
WHERE'S MY COFFEE, HUH?
ARE WE WAITIN'
FOR THE SNOW TO FLY?
[horse whinnying]
[sighs]
GIVE ME THE COFFEE.
COULD USE SOME DOCTORIN'.
STAY AND HAVE A DOLLOP
YOURSELF.
HOW MANY YEARS
WE KNOWN EACH OTHER?
[sighs]
TOO MANY.
JUST A MINUTE,
I AIN'T THROUGH
WITH YOU YET.
I REMEMBER
THE FIRST TIME I SEEN YOU.
YOU WAS HANGIN' ON
TO YOUR MAMA'S SKIRTS,
AND BAWLIN' YOUR EYES OUT
LIKE I WAS GONNA EAT YOU
ALIVE.
[chuckles]
IF I'D BEEN SMART,
I WOULD HAVE RUN AWAY THEN.
ABOUT 5 OR 6 YEARS
OR WHATEVER,
ALL KIDS LOOK THE SAME TO ME.
IS THIS GOIN' SOMEWHERE
OR CAN I GET BACK TO WORK?
YOUR MAMA WORKED FOR ME
15, 20 YEARS.
I BROUGHT YOU UP
WITH MY BOY.
I ALWAYS TREATED YOU
LIKE A SON, DIDN'T I?
YES. YOU TREATED US BOTH
THE SAME.
BUT I FORGAVE YOU.
DAMN IT!
WHY ARE YOU SO SMART-ALECKY?
IT'S ONLY
OUT OF SELF DEFENSE.
OH.
WELL, WHAT I AM TRYING
TO GET AT
IS MY RANCH IS THE ONLY HOME
YOU'VE EVER KNOWN.
AND WHAT I AM ALSO TRYING
TO GET AT,
IS I AIN'T GONNA LIVE FOREVER.
WHAT I'M SAYIN' IS,
WHEN THIS DRIVE IS OVER,
WILL YOU COME BACK WITH ME
AND BE PART OF MY HOUSE?
I DIDN'T HEAR THAT.
WHEN I'M DEAD
THE RANCH WILL BE YOURS!
[laughs]
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
I'VE EVER SEEN YOU
WITH YOUR MOUTH SHUT. HUH?
WELL?
I WOULD LIKE THAT.
I DIDN'T HEAR YOU.
I SAID YES.
[laughing]
NOW GO ON
AND GET OUTTA HERE.
NOW DON'T GO
TELLING EVERYBODY
WHAT WE TALKIN' ABOUT.
I WOULDN'T WANT TO KNOW
I HAD A HALF-BREED FOR A SON.
[man whistling]
[men grunting]
WE GOTTA PULL OUT
SOON, JESS.
DON'T WORRY
OR YOU'LL GET OLD
BEFORE YOUR TIME.
[Jess grunts]
[cattle mooing]
[Jess whistling]
COME ON, GIDDYUP.
[whistling]
[horse neighing]
THERE IS A WATERHOLE AHEAD.
AND 3 MEN CAMPED BY IT.
UH, SQUATTERS.
HAPPENS EVERY DRIVE I TAKE.
SOME NO-GOOD WORTHLESS SCUM
STAKES OUT A WATERHOLE
AND TRIES TO CHARGE YOU
FOR IT.
I AIN'T NEVER PAID 'EM
AND I AIN'T GOING TO NOW.
WHAT DO YOU WANNA DO
ABOUT IT?
YOU BETTER GO BACK TO THE HERD
AND HOLD 'EM THERE.
THEY MUSTN'T GET
A SMELL OF THAT WATER
OR THEY'LL TRAMPLE THEMSELVES
TRYING TO GET TO IT.
BRING 'EM UP
100 AT A TIME.
COOLER AND I WILL GO AHEAD
AND TAKE CARE
OF THE SQUATTERS.
I'LL SEND QUENTIN
TO HELP YOU.
I'LL RIDE AHEAD
OF THE FIRST 100
TO MAKE SURE
THERE'S NO TROUBLE.
LEAVE ME ALONE, COOLER.
ALL RIGHT.
[scoffs]
THEY'RE ONLY KIDS.
DON'T LET THAT FOOL YOU.
WE CAN SHOOT BETTER
THAN MOST GROWED MEN.
THIS IS FREE LAND.
NOT NO MORE IT AIN'T.
COST YOU $20 TO WATER HERE.
$20!
WELL, IF THAT AIN'T
THE BULL'S BEHIND!
I DON'T WANNA TALK
TO YOU NO MORE.
GET ME YOUR FATHER?
WE AIN'T GOT NONE.
AND IF YOU DON'T TALK TO ME,
YOU DON'T TALK TO NO ONE.
I OUGHTA BLOW
ALL OF YOU YOUNG ONES
CLEAN APART.
YOU WON'T.
MAN LIKE YOU
AIN'T GOT THE HEART
TO SHOOT CHILDREN.
[rifles cock]
WE MIGHT SHOOT YOU.
YOU'RE BLUFFIN'.
YOU'RE SQUATTIN'
ON THIS LAND.
SHOW 'EM WE MEAN BUSINESS.
NOW THOSE MEN THERE,
MIGHT NOT SHOOT YOU,
LITTLE MAN.
BUT I WILL.
[gun thuds]
GO ON, DROP 'EM.
[cattle mooing]
(Willie)
YOU WAS RIGHT.
WE WAS JUST COMIN' ALONG
AND FOUND THIS HERE
OLD WATERHOLE.
WE NEEDED MONEY
SO WE SQUATTED.
YOU GOT NO FAMILY.
YOU'VE NO PLACE TO GO?
WE HAD OUR PA
TILL A MONTH AGO.
HE WENT TO BRING SUPPLIES
AND NEVER COME BACK.
EITHER HE RAN OFF ON US
OR GOT HIMSELF KILLED.
THAT DON'T MAKE NO NEVER MIND.
WE CAN ALWAYS GET BY.
THAT'S WHAT WORRIES ME.
YOU CAN'T LOCK US UP IN JAIL,
WE'RE TOO YOUNG.
YOU'RE RIGHT ABOUT THAT.
I SURE HATE TO TURN YOU LOOSE
ON THE WORLD.
DON'T SEE THAT
YOU HAVE MUCH CHOICE, DO YOU?
SINCE BEING
WE AIN'T GOT NO CHOICE,
YOU'LL TAKE MY ADVICE,
YOU'LL STICK TO THE LEGALITIES
FROM NOW ON.
NOW, I THANK YOU
FOR YOUR ADVICE, SIR.
YOU KNOW, IT SEEMS TO ME
LIKE Y-YOU MIGHT GIVE US
SOME MONEY FOR OUR TRAVELLIN',
SEEIN' AS
HOW WE ARE POOR ORPHANS.
THEY'RE JUST
WOLF PUPS NOW,
I CAN IMAGINE THEM
IN 5 OR 10 YEARS.
[cattle mooing]
(Billy Don)
WE SHOULDN'T HAVE
LEFT THE HERD, JESS.
THEY'RE GONNA MISS US.
WILL YOU SHUT UP
WITH YOUR BELLYACHIN'?
NOW THAT HERD'S AWFUL JUMPY.
[sighs]
WHAT WITH THEM WOLVES.
BY THE TIME ANYONE COMES
TO TAKE OVER WATCH,
WE'LL BE LONG GONE.
HATCHER'S SHORTHANDED
AS IT IS.
HE WON'T TRAIL OUT AFTER US
FOR THE SAKE OF A FEW HEAD.
I JUST DON'T LIKE
WHAT WE'RE DOIN'.
I MEAN, HATCHER AND THEM,
THEY'VE ALL BEEN
REAL GOOD TO US.
PUT THAT IRON DOWN,
McKINNON.
NOW, QUENTIN.
YEAH.
UH, QUENTIN--
YOU HEARD HIM, JESS.
PUT IT DOWN.
NOW, TWO PERSONS, LOOK.
NOW, LOOK,
I AIN'T GONNA MAKE NO EXCUSES
FOR WHAT WE DONE HERE.
JUST LET US GO.
NO. I CANNOT DO THAT.
. YOU SIGNED ON WITH HATCHER.
YOU'RE GONNA TALK TO HATCHER.
I DON'T AIM
TO BE THE GUEST OF HONOR
AT NO HANGIN'.
JESS, WAIT. JESS, NO!
DON'T FIRE THAT GUN!
[grunts]
[cattle mooing]
HERE THEY GO.
STAMPEDE!
JESS!
[neighing]
(Billy Don)
JESS!
THEY'VE SHOTGUNNED
6 WAYS TO SUNDAY.
IT'S GONNA TAKE US
AT LEAST A DAY
TO ROUND THEM UP
[sighs]
I KNOW.
THERE ARE AT LEAST 100
SCATTERED TO THE EAST.
LET'S KEEP MOVING.
GIDDYUP.
THERE'S ANOTHER ONE,
MR. HATCHER.
[wagon rattling]
[shuddering]
OH, JESS.
[cattle mooing]
I--I--I FOUND MY BROTHER.
THERE WASN'T MUCH--MUCH LEFT
TO--TO BURY.
LET'S TAKE THESE IN.
FEELIN' BETTER?
IT'S GETTIN' BETTER.
THAT AXLE GREASE
SEEMS TO WORK.
LOOKS LIKE
WE GOT 2 DOCTORS
IN THE FAMILY.
SURE DO.
[grunts]
HEY, SANTOS.
HOW IS IT?
8 HORSES STILL MISSING.
AND MINE'S WORN OUT.
NEVER SEEN THE LIKE.
GOIN' FROM BAD TO WORSE,
RIGHT ON DOWN THE LINE.
AIN'T YOU GOT ONE OF THEM
PATRON SAINTS
THAT TAKE CARE OF THINGS
AT TIMES LIKE THIS?
I BEEN THINKIN'.
MAYBE WE'RE ALL BEING TESTED,
YOU KNOW?
THE SAINTS,
THEY DON'T LIKE TO INTERFERE
IN THESE THINGS.
WELL, EITHER
I'M A GREAT DOCTOR
OR YOU'RE
A PIECE OF LEATHER.
(Morgan)
MR. HATCHER?
YEAH.
JESS McKINNON IS DEAD.
HOW?
STAMPEDE.
[horse snorting]
THE FACT IS, MR. HATCHER,
QUENTIN AND TWO PERSONS
CAUGHT ME AND JESS
COLD BRANDIN'.
JESS WOULDN'T HAVE IT
ANY OTHER WAY
BUT TO SHOOT IT OUT.
THAT'S WHAT
STARTED THE STAMPEDE.
I'D DO ANYTHING I CAN
TO PAY YOU BACK.
I'LL--I'LL FINISH THE DRIVE
WITH NO PAY.
[mumbling]
NO, NO.
NEVER IN MY LIFE
WORKED A MAN
WITHOUT PAYIN' HIM.
SORRY ABOUT YOUR BROTHER.
BUT IT WASN'T YOU MR. HATCHER.
THE RUSTLIN'.
HE JUST HAD ALL--
ALL THIS HATE EATIN' IN HIM
EVER SINCE THEY HUNG PAPPY.
GO GET YOURSELF SOME FOOD
OR COOLER WILL GET INSULTED.
YES, SIR.
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
[sighs]
WAKELY?
WELL, HE'S STILL RIDING HERD.
HADN'T SEEN HIM AROUND,
AFRAID WE'D LOST HIM, TOO,
AND NOBODY KNEW IT YET.
[cows mooing]
(Wakely)
IT'S NOT TIME YET.
MMM-HMM.
GO ON IN.
THE FOOD IS STILL WARM.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
NOT FROM WHERE I SIT.
YOU DIDN'T SLEEP.
YES, I DID. A FEW MINUTES.
GO ON IN.
(Hatcher)
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKIN',
YOU CAN'T GO
ANOTHER STEP TODAY.
AND MAYBE YOU'RE WONDERIN'
ABOUT TOMORROW AS WELL.
WELL, I'M SAYIN'
YOU CAN GO ANOTHER STEP
AND ANOTHER
AND ANOTHER AFTER THAT.
YOU CAN GO AS FAR
AS YOU HAVE TO
BECAUSE I'M SAYIN' IT.
AND IT'S GOSPEL.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
NO BELLYACHIN'.
I JUST WANT TO HEAR GRUNTS
FROM YOU TRYIN'.
IS THAT CLEAR?
YEAH.
WE'VE GONE MORE THAN HALFWAY.
SO IT DON'T MAKE NO SENSE
TO TRY AND TURN AROUND
AND GO BACK.
THERE'S ONE THING
I WILL DO FOR YOU.
I'LL STICK
TO THE REGULAR TRAIL.
DOESN'T THAT PUT
AN EXTRA MONTH ON IT?
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
IT WOULD MAKE US LATE
FOR THE MARKET.
WELL, MAYBE THAT WAS
A LITTLE BIT OF GREED TALKIN'.
WAIT A MINUTE, WAIT A MINUTE.
AND WHAT HAPPENS
IF WE JUST FOLLOW YOUR ROUTE
RIGHT THROUGH THE BADLANDS?
WELL, WE GOTTA PUSH,
AND PUSH AND PUSH
UNTIL WE GET TO
THE OTHER SIDE AND WATER.
FOR 40 HOURS OF HARD DRIVIN'.
WE ALL GOT A STAKE IN THIS.
THE QUICKER
WE GET THAT THE HERD
TO PUEBLO,
BETTER WE GET PAID.
RIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW,
MY GRANDDADDY USED TO SAY,
"TRUST IN THE LORD."
BUT I DON'T TRUST IN NOBODY
BUT US.
ALL RIGHT, SOMEBODY COME ON
AND HELP ME UP ON THAT HORSE.
ALL RIGHT,
THEN LET'S GIT, HUH?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
MR. HATCHER,
YOU, UH, YOU JUST MIGHT
HAVE A CHANCE.
OF WHAT?
OF OUTLASTING YOUR JINX.
WE'RE NEAR OUTTA WATER.
WE BETTER KEEP MOVIN'.
YOU KNOW, CATTLE IS UNRULY
WHEN THEY'RE THIRSTY.
SOMETIMES THEY GO BLIND.
[man whistling]
[hollering]
[whistles]
[insects chirping]
(Cooler)
NO MORE WATER TO COOK WITH,
NO ONE HUNGRY,
[horse whinnying]
COULDN'T EVEN WORK UP
ENOUGH SPIT
TO CHEW A BISCUIT.
WELL, THIS IS THE END OF IT.
YOU KNOW,
I KNEW A HORSE ONCE,
OLD JAKE.
TEXAS PONY.
THAT SMARTEST HORSE
I'D EVER SEEN.
HE WOULDN'T WORK A WATCH
MORE THAN 2 HOURS.
YOU HAD TO STAY OUT
A LITTLE LONGER,
YOU HAD TO RIDE BACK TO CAMP,
DISMOUNT,
FOOL AROUND A COUPLE MINUTES,
MOUNT UP AGAIN.
SEE, THAT WAY OLD JAKE
FIGURED HE WAS TAKIN' ON
A NEW TURN.
WASN'T WORKIN' OVERTIME
ON THE OLD ONE.
[laughs]
DARNEDEST THING I EVER SEEN.
[cattle mooing]
WAKELY.
[exclaims]
[sighs]
CAN'T KEEP MY EYES OPEN.
WELL, HERE.
TRY RUBBIN' 'EM WITH SOME, UH,
TOBACCO JUICE.
IT'S GONNA BURN LIKE HELLFIRE,
BUT YOU'LL STAY AWAKE.
OW!
UGH.
[snorts]
[sighs]
IT SHOULD BE HERE.
QUENTIN, WE COULD BE LOST
OR MAYBE
THE LANDMARKS HAVE CHANGED.
[sighs]
WIND, RAIN.
I HAVE KNOWN JUST ONE STORM
TO CHANGE THE LOOK
OF HUNDREDS OF MILES.
AH, WE WILL LET THE MEN
REST SOON,
AND THEN I WILL LOOK
FOR THE WATER AGAIN.
[snorting]
(Morgan)
COME ON, GET.
COME ON, MOVE ON.
GO NOW.
[horses neighing]
[Quentin hollering]
GO, GET UP THERE.
DON'T QUIT KNOW.
GO, CATTLE.
[Billy Don whistling]
(Santos)
WHO SAYS IT WOULD BE BAD
TO DIE?
RIGHT NOW
IT WOULD FEEL NICE
AND COOL.
(Wakely)
FOOTBALL.
[panting]
YEAH.
GOD, I LOVED FOOTBALL.
I WENT TO YALE
TO STUDY ART.
I HATED THE CLASSES.
[sighs]
[chuckles]
ONLY THING I WAS GOOD AT
WAS FOOTBALL.
PLAYED HALFBACK.
THE LAST GAME I PLAYED,
IT WAS AGAINST PRINCETON.
6 INCHES OF MUD.
A SCORELESS TIE.
OH, GOD.
YOU SHOULD'VE BEEN THERE.
YOU COULD PLAY THAT GAME,
YOU KNOW.
YEAH.
SOMEDAY I WILL.
(Hatcher)
COOLER. COOLER.
[panting]
DO YOU HEAR IT?
[sighs]
[cattle mooing]
[Hatcher sighing]
[panting]
THIS WAY.
THE HERD.
MILLING.
THEY SMELL WATER.
WATER?
YEAH. UH-HUH. UH-HUH.
(Morgan)
WATER?
YES.
GOT TO MOVE THE CATTLE,
THERE'S WATER.
THEY'LL DROWN THEMSELVES
GOING FOR THE WATER.
[cattle mooing]
[men whooping]
[man hooting]
[men laughing]
[shouting]
[all cheering]
[horse neighing]
I FOUND THAT WATER.
(Wakely)
YOU FOUND THAT WATER.
(Santos)
THE ANIMALS FOUND THE WATER.
YOU LIKE IT, BOYS.
IT'S GREAT.
WELL, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
MR. HATCHER, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF.
ACCORDING TO EVERY
MEDICAL BOOK I'VE READ,
YOU SHOULD BE
BURIED OUT THERE
SOMEWHERE.
I THINK WE SHOULD
HOLE UP HERE FOR A FEW DAYS.
LET YOU ALL GET A REST,
LET THE COWS GET
SOME MEAT ON THEIR BONES.
AND COOLER, HERE.
COOLER.
YES.
WHY DON'T YOU--
I AIN'T GOIN' IN!
[men laughing]
(Billy Don)
NEXT STOP, PUEBLO.
[cattle mooing]
(Quentin)
PUSH 'EM TO THE LEFT.
(Wakely)
HO, CATTLE, HO, HO!
HOLD 'EM UP THERE. HO.
COME ON, NOW, HO.
[guns firing]
[horse neighing]
[people chattering]
(man #1)
I JUST DON'T DRINK.
(Hatcher)
I CAN'T WAIT TO GET BACK
TO TELL THE FOLKS AT HOME
I GOT ME A SON NOW.
YOU WEREN'T SO HAPPY
ABOUT HAVING IT KNOWN
WHEN WE WERE ON THE TRAIL.
A COUPLE OF THESE IN ME
MAKES ME LIBERAL.
HEY, MAYBE WITH
A COUPLE OF DRINKS IN ME,
I WOULD RATHER
NOT HAVE IT KNOWN
THAT I HAVE YOU
FOR A FATHER.
[people chattering]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
ON BEHALF OF
THE CATTLEMEN'S ASSOCIATION
OF PUEBLO,
I'D LIKE TO WELCOME YOU.
WE FIGURED WE'D SEEN
THE LAST OF THESE DRIVES
2 MONTHS AGO.
SO IN APPRECIATION,
AS SOON AS YOU'VE DRUNK
ALL THAT YOU CAN,
WE'RE TURNIN' THE WHOLE HOTEL
OVER TO YOU.
[all cheering]
[people chattering]
(Tucker)
WAKELY, THERE'S A TELEGRAPH
COME FOR YOU.
(Wakely)
THANK YOU, TUCKER.
HEY, TUCKER.
YOU'RE STILL
THE PRINCE OF WALES.
YOU'RE GONNA STAY ON
IN TOWN FOR THE WINTER?
NAH, I KNOW SOME OUTFITS
THAT NEED HANDS.
YOU KNOW, WINTER
WORK'S A WHOLE LOT DIFFERENT
THAN TRAIL DRIVE.
YOU KNEW
HOW TO PLAY THIS GAME.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO PLAY THIS GAME?
I'M GONNA READ MY TELEGRAM.
YOU WANNA RIDE UP WITH ME?
YEAH.
DON'T MAKE NO SENSE
FOR ME TO BE SITTIN'
AROUND TOWN
WHEN I COULD BE MAKIN' ME
SOME DOLLARS.
(Hatcher)
HOLD UP THERE, TUCKER.
YOU'RE GETTIN' TOO OLD
TO BE WORKIN' SO HARD.
I WANT YOU TO COME BACK
TO MY RANCH WITH ME.
AS WHAT? STABLE BOY?
I DESERVE MORE THAN THAT.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS SAYIN'.
I ACCEPT.
[laughs]
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE EVERYBODY.
I GOT MYSELF ANOTHER JOB.
(woman)
OH, VERY GOOD.
YEAH, THAT'S GREAT.
THERE THIS A MAGAZINE
IN THE EAST CALLED
HARPER'S WEEKLY.
I SENT THEM A WHOLE SLEW
OF MY PICTURES
A LONG TIME AGO.
AND NOW BESS WRITES ME
AND TELLS ME
THAT THEY BOUGHT ONE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
YOU DID
SOME REALLY GOOD WORK
ON THE DRIVE,
YOU COULD SELL
SOME OF THOSE.
WELL, THAT'S JUST IT,
THEY WANT TO SEE
MORE OF MY WORK.
IT'S JUST LIKE I TOLD YOU.
ALL THE PEOPLE IN THE EAST
ARE STARTING TO BE CURIOUS
ABOUT WHAT IT'S LIKE OUT WEST.
THEY SHOULD SEE IT
THE WAY WE'VE SEEN IT.
ANYWAY I WAS TALKIN' TO
SOME OF THESE ARMY BOYS
IN HERE,
AND THEY SAID
THAT THEY'RE SENDING OUT
A DETACHMENT NEXT WEEK,
AND I THOUGHT MAYBE
I COULD GO ALONG WITH THEM
AND MAKE SOME ARMY PAINTINGS.
YOU KNOW,
HAVE--HAVE ANOTHER SET READY.
WAIT A MINUTE,
THE WHOLE DRIVE
ALL I HEARD ABOUT WAS,
"BESS, BESS. I LOVE BESS."
WHAT ABOUT BESS?
(Morgan)
THAT'S RIGHT, WHAT ABOUT BESS?
I--I STILL--
I STILL LOVE BESS, OF COURSE.
BUT I THINK
HER FATHER WAS RIGHT.
I--I STILL HAVE
A LOT MORE TO LEARN
BEFORE I'M READY TO GO HOME
AND SETTLE DOWN.
I'M GONNA WRITE TO HER
AND TELL HER THAT I LOVE HER.
AH, WHO AM I KIDDING?
I'M GONNA MARRY HER
AND BRING HER ALONG WITH ME.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WHO ARE YOU KIDDING.
QUENTIN, I'M OUT.
LET ME BUY YOU
ANOTHER BEER.
I-- I NEVER REALIZED
WHAT THOSE 12 STEERS
HATCHER LEFT US IN THE VILLAGE
WOULD MEAN TO ME.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU, MORGAN,
BUT I FEEL REAL GOOD.
I DID NOT THINK
WE WILL FEEL SO GOOD
ABOUT IT TOMORROW MORNING.
(Hatcher)
COME ON, ALL OF YOU.
COME OVER HERE,
GATHER AROUND.
WELL, Y'ALL GOT YOUR $20
AND ANOTHER $30
SHARE BESIDES.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD MONEY
IN MY BOOK.
REMEMBER, BOYS,
WAY BACK IN RED BLUFFS
I SAID WE WAS GONNA MAKE IT
BECAUSE WE DIDN'T HAVE
ANYWHERE TO GO.
WELL, NOW WE GOT
EVERYWHERE TO GO.
NOW JUST DON'T
HOLD IT UP TO ME
IF YOU COME
LOOKIN' FOR A JOB AGAIN
NEXT YEAR.
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT
THE FOLKS BACK HOME TO KNOW
I GONE SOFT.
[laughing]
ANYWAY,
IT'S BEEN A PLEASURE.
AND FROM NOW
TILL YOU FALL FLAT
ON YOUR UGLY FACES,
THE DRINKS IS ON ME!
[all cheering]
[man whooping]
CC ripped by Tantico (Croatia) 2011