Capt. Benedict,
there's horses down there in the yard.
They're saddle horses.
Ain't Injun ponies, anyways.
Come over here.
Hello, my two little loves.
How are you?
Hey, Josh, Morgan?
You boys take care of this place
while I was gone?
Yes, sir, Pa.
Yesterday, Morgan shot a mountain lion
after the cows.
Did you get him?
Just hit him.
Waiting for you to get home
and I was gonna track him down.
We'll hunt him up in the morning.
Can I go, Pa, can I?
Now, look, you're rabbit size,
Morgan's cat size.
- Josh is rabbit size.
- Now, that's enough of that.
Della.
Now look at your mother.
Ever see a prettier mother anywhere?
Did you bring the things
I asked you for?
Everything you wanted.
The gold, the silver, the spices,
the silk, everything.
John Benedict, you know I mean
my new hairpins and shoes for Josh.
They might be mixed up
in the gold and the silver.
Now look, kids,
take care of the horses...
and be sure you bring
those saddlebags back...
we'll poke around,
probably find something for everyone.
Whit? I didn't expect company.
We rode out from town
this morning...
not knowing you'd gone up
to La Junta for a little horse trading.
Capt. Benedict, meet
Lt. Abel Lawson, Colorado State militia.
- Lieutenant.
- An honour, Capt. Benedict.
- I asked them to eat with us.
- Fine. Good.
- l'll call you when dinner's ready.
- All right.
Lieutenant, this is Free Hobson,
he works for me.
- Hi.
- Come on in.
Make yourselves comfortable,
l'll go and get washed up.
John, the Lieutenant and I are here
on a special sort of a visit.
Oh?
Yes, sir. l'd like to recruit
your son Morgan for West Point.
Well, that takes
a congressman's appointment.
I think the Sheriff can tell you...
that we didn't give that man in Denver
many votes last time.
But any man who holds a medal...
his son can go to West Point
without a congressman's appointment.
I don't think I want to use
the medal that way.
Capt. John Benedict,
if Morgan was my son...
l'd talk to him first
before I tried to be so danged noble.
- That's your opinion.
- You never asked me.
May I discuss it
with your son, sir?
I think if there's anything
to be discussed, l'd better do it.
Dinner will be ready soon.
Stubborn. Always was.
Stubborner than a cavalry mule.
Now, where'd you get that, Free?
I went and got it out of your trunk.
What is it, Ma?
lt's the Congressional
Medal of Honour.
The President gave it to your pa.
lt's pretty.
Why don't we keep it
on the mantle?
I think your father prefers it
tucked away in the box.
What did you do, Pa?
Why, Capt. John Benedict...
I captured the entire Confederate Army
all by myself. Now isn't that enough?
There's something very interesting
about that piece of gold.
The man who holds it,
his son can go to West Point Academy.
Providing he can measure up
to the other requirements, too.
When would the Academy
be wanting a young fellow, Lieutenant?
Next month, sir.
First he'd have to go to Kansas
for his examinations.
Then they'd put him on a steam train
to New York from there.
Have to go right away, then?
Yes, sir.
Yesterday, Morgan shot
a mountain lion...
and l'd like to have him point out
where it happened.
If you'll excuse us.
Where did you first sight him, Morgan?
Way up on that south slope, Pa.
He was stalking a calf
that wandered off from its mother.
I got downwind of him.
- Long shot?
- About 300 yards.
But I hit him.
I figure he's got off into
one of the canyons to lick his wound.
We'll find him.
- You'd like to go, wouldn't you, Son?
- Sir?
Well, you'd like to go to
West Point Academy, wouldn't you?
Yes, sir.
Man graduates from there,
he can be an architect or an engineer...
or almost anything he wants.
One of the finest schools there is.
I don't think it'd be right for me to leave
you and old Free to do all the work here.
You've been doing it all
ever since I can remember.
- Do you think we can't still do it?
- No.
You can do anything, Pa.
But I just don't think it's right.
As you say.
Lieutenant, l've had a discussion
with my son...
and I think the Academy needs
men like him. He can go.
Now, just a minute.
That is, if his mother approves.
I never thought l'd have
a son from way out here...
to go to West Point Academy.
l'm glad for you, Morgan.
l'll hunt up that cat in the morning.
You better help your mother
get yourself ready to go to Kansas.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
John.
Whit.
Stay.
Free! My God!
Indians and Comancheros.
Don't go in there, Captain,
for God's sake.
God, don't do it. Hey, Captain?
Morgan. He was shooting from the barn.
Morgan, Captain. Morgan!
Morgan?
Son?
We fought them, Captain.
Me and Morgan.
- We fought them.
- I know you did.
I can't swallow, Captain.
Had my gut shot.
Captain.
I remember something.
There was two white men with them.
What did you say, Free?
One man had a white eye.
He was the boss.
Captain?
I got to sleep.
John?
Della?
Whit, look over there.
You men stay here.
My God!
Good God almighty!
Buck Thomas' place got hit last night.
Buck's all right...
but the Indians ran off all his stock.
We caught one of them.
A white man. Comanchero.
I want to see him.
Get him down.
Take it easy...
I just don't want to look up at him.
The man that worked for me...
before he died said that
there were two of you.
The leader had one white eye.
What's his name?
Now those are your teeth.
Next your eyes.
No! Tarp!
His name's Tarp!
Tarp?
Where they going to trade the horses?
I don't know.
Mexico!
l'll need that horse he's riding.
l'm going to track that bunch.
l'll go and make a pack.
We're going to ride with you, John.
- John.
- Yeah?
Texas.
Well, the trail goes that way.
We're a long way from home
and the men are tired.
I want to thank all of you
for coming this far with me.
There's 1,000 miles out there
in any direction.
Those Comancheros
could be anywhere.
We've got nothing but time now,
and I got a feeling that...
that one-eyed Comanchero bastard
knows somebody's following him.
But you've got a ranch back in Colorado.
Whit, l'd appreciate it
if you'd board it up...
sell the cattle and the rest of the
livestock, and send me a bank order...
- at Fort Stockton.
- Anything you say.
A man can't even enjoy his lunch.
I speak good American, no?
Very good. Muy bueno.
Okay.
Tell me...
l'm looking for a place called
Pueblo Plata.
Pueblo Plata lies to the West.
It's a hiding place where outlaw
Kiowa, Comanches...
and Apache Indians
bring stolen horses...
and trade them for guns and tequila.
I won't go there alone, seòor.
Do you know any men
that would go with me?
In this place, no.
All these people are poor people
and they work in mines.
What about those prisoners
I saw in the wagon?
They're convict labourers.
They work up in the silver mines.
Where do they come from?
El Hoyo.
You would say, The Hole.
A prison 5 kilometres down to the south.
Hablas inglés, seòor?
A little, seòor.
l'd like to see your commandant.
I want to hire some men
to work in my mine.
I am the Commandant's interpreter.
My name's Benedict.
I want to see the Commandant.
You wish to buy slaves to work for you,
is correct?
No, l'd like to hire some men
to do a job.
What this job?
I have a mine. I can use six men.
But just one thing. I pick the men...
because l'm going to be working
alongside of them.
My name is
Rogelio Hernandez.
But in this Garden of Eden,
I am known as Cholo.
Well, Mr. Cholo, let's get going.
We will see the Comandante. Vamos.
The Comandante is a kind
and sympathetic person.
He shows us nothing but kindness...
and respect.
We would die for him.
Wait.
In fact, we do.
Three and four a day.
This warden is so corrupt,
that should the authorities know of him...
he would wear more chains
than all of us together.
In the name of the justice
of my country...
one day, he will stand against the wall
and be shot.
Well, I wish Godspeed to the justice
of your country.
- Tequila, seòor?
- No, gracias.
Now he will discuss the price
with you.
He's going to rob you, seòor.
I am instructed to tell you by this...
son of a drunken whore,
to tell you that it will cost you...
12 pesos a week for each labourer.
And 20 for the guards.
And in addition,
you have to pay this shit...
$100 for his cooperation.
l'll pay him if I can find the men I want.
Seòor, l'm trying to tell you
the usual price is 6 pesos per man...
and 10 for the guards,
and this drunken weasel...
will shine your boots
with his tongue for $10.
Just tell him l'll pay what he wants
if I can find what I want.
It's a deal.
Who is he?
His name is Job.
He was a slave in your country.
He escaped and he came into Mexico,
but people tried to trap him...
and return him for the reward.
He became the killer
of those who tried to trap him.
He was put in here, and here he will die.
Mark him.
But, seòor,
he's not going to work for you.
Mark him!
His name is Quiberon.
He is French.
A deserter from
the army of Maximilian and a bandido.
Every day he tries to climb the wall
of this prison.
It is impossible.
Yet he tries.
Quiberon?
Do you think
you will make it to the top?
Crap on you, Cholo!
One day l'll make it.
l'll take him.
He is kept on the chain
because his is an animal and he fights.
He fights anyone.
Yet when he works in the mines
he's peaceful...
and he works like a beast.
His name is Zweig.
He is alemán. German.
Excuse me.
Mister...
you look like a fellow countryman.
You sure do.
If you're making up a labour gang,
l'd be mighty beholden to get on it.
Why, l'd work my hard old ass
clean down to the bone...
if I could just get out
of this hole for a time.
Seòor Benedict.
You ask anybody...
old Bill Hoop is a true master
when it comes to the pick and shovel.
Hot dang, I tell you...
a gopher can't hold a candle to me
when it comes to digging.
What are you here for?
Why, they claim that I was rustling
cattle up around Paso del Norte way...
and they had to blame somebody...
and I swear,
I never even been arrested before.
I swear it.
l'm just a true-blue, honest American.
You wouldn't let
a fellow American die...
in a place like this, now, would you, sir?
Excuse me, seòor. Please.
In the two months
he has been here, we all know him.
Me? You goddamn greaser!
He is a bandido, a rapist,
a murderer, a thief!
l'm going to get you for this.
l'll unravel your guts out
like a ball of yarn.
Pueblo Plata.
- What?
- Have you been to Pueblo Plata?
Maybe.
Well, 'maybe' doesn't buy
your way out of here.
Pueblo Plata?
I think I can find it.
- l'll take this man.
- I knowed it.
l've knowed you was the kind of
American that would stand up...
for the Stars and Stripes
no matter where us Americans is.
I salute you.
l'll also take the German.
No, seòor.
You said he was strong and he worked
hard. Now, I need two more men.
What about you, Cholo?
No, I wouldn't be any good as a peón.
l'm a scholar, a philosopher...
and a man filled with integrity.
I can tell you what he's filled with,
and it ain't that!
You want to get out of here?
Well...
- I think I work for you, seòor.
- All right, one more man.
Wait.
Come on, which one is it?
Against the wall.
Against the wall?
He's called El Chamaco.
The Kid.
He's a paid assassin.
He killed his first man
when he was 14 years old.
How many since then? Quién sabe?
This hombre is getting men for his mine.
You won't have to wear
chains on your legs.
Sí, a good mine, Chamaco.
You come with us,
and I think you won't regret it.
l'll take the lead, you follow me.
- Sí, seòor.
- Everyone on the wagon.
They can't make me work
for nobody.
I told them I wouldn't work.
You better shut up or he's going to blow
your black head off!
Chamaco, you see that greased holster
that Mr. Benedict hangs that.45 in?
l'll bet you
that Mr. Benedict can sling that.45...
faster than a whore's ass on payday.
My teeth ache clean down to my ass.
I wonder when Mr. Benedict's
going to stop this wagon.
Look at him...
eating hot beans with them
damned greasers...
and me, his fellow American...
trying to get some juice
out of this dried jackrabbit.
Cholo.
Tell them to put their guns
down on the ground.
There's a length of rope here,
tie them up.
Just Cholo.
The rest of you stay where you are.
Go on, get back.
Not too tight.
So they can get loose after a while.
l'm going to Pueblo Plata
to kill a man named Tarp.
He's got a bunch of renegade Indians
and probably some Comancheros.
I'd do it myself,
but the odds are a little steep.
We can cross the Rio Grande
and be into the States by morning.
I'll buy you clothes, guns, and horses.
We'll cross back into Mexico
about 100 miles to the west.
I can't make you go with me...
- but l'll take your word that you will.
- Hey.
There is no banks to be robbed?
No gold to be stolen?
Is that all you want with us?
To help you kill a man?
Now, what the hell do you care
what he wants?
You come to the right man,
Mr. Benedict, yes, sir.
You can count on old William P. Hoop.
Yes, sir.
Then I have your word, Mr. Hoop?
I hope to shake a rag
you got my word, Mr. Benedict.
Why, I wouldn't let
no fellow American down.
l'll take your word, Mr. Hoop.
Mr. Zweig?
- Can I have your word?
- Sure.
I give you my word.
This is a joke, I think.
No joke to me, Mr. Quiberon.
Well, if you think my word
is worth something...
yes, I give you my word.
It's worth what you make it worth.
What about you, Job?
You won't take my chains off.
Won't nobody take my chains off.
What if I do?
l'll have to think about that some more.
Cholo?
You can trust me as much as
you can trust these, seòor.
Now what the hell kind of word is that?
I trust him.
Then I am your man.
Chamaco?
Why you want to kill this man?
My family was massacred by this man
and his Comanches.
You got my word.
Cholo, get this gear together.
Rest of you, get on the wagon.
- Mr. Zweig, you take the reins.
- Okay, sir.
Him, drive? Why he...
Mr. Hoop.
Yes, sir.
Leave the guns.
I don't know.
I won't say something
I might not mean...
I still got to think some more.
You do that.
Hot dang, l'll tell you,
we're in my country now, men!
Yes, sir!
Hi, fellow Americans,
how you doing?
Wait for me, ladies!
I come back in a little while.
Everybody in here.
Man, I seen purple shirts,
but never like that.
I tell you, l'm beginning to feel
like a genuine human being.
Don't make the mistake
of thinking you are one.
Get off my neck,
you high-toned greaser.
You call me greaser once more,
I kill you!
You see this? It isn't an umbrella, bub.
Don't start talking about killing unless
you want your head blown clean off.
Camp over here.
I don't think
we're going to camp here, Mr. Benedict.
You don't seem surprised, seòor.
No.
I took a long chance on all of you.
You're the galldangdest fool I ever seen.
'Give me your word,' he says.
Well, how do you like the word
we're giving you now, Mr. Benedict?
Mr. Benedict...
you have appealed
to the honour of men...
who have no honour.
Even you, Cholo?
I have no time for this thing
you want to do, seòor.
Why we talk? Let's get the money.
You get the money, Mr. Quiberon.
It's in my saddlebag.
Don't touch your gun,
mister.
If I do, l'll take you first, Chamaco.
Try it.
Hot dang, I told you about
that greased holster.
I don't think maybe you could kill
all of us, Mr. Benedict.
No, but I could drop three of you.
But then I wouldn't get
to Pueblo Plata.
So I suggest that you just take
the money and we'll part company.
Go ahead, Mr. Quiberon.
Them horses of his would bring
$100 extra or so.
Now, that's another thing, Mr. Hoop.
Without my horses,
I can't get to where l'm going...
so we'd better just shoot it out
right now.
Maybe this'll make it
a little more even for you, Mr. Benedict.
Well, now...
what the hell are you doing?
You're with us.
I ain't one of nobody but myself...
and myself says...
this man keeps his horses.
It's all right.
I ain't starting no shoot-out.
Hell, you can keep your damn horses.
Adiós, seòor Benedict.
l'll give you my word now.
But I don't know why.
l'll think about it later.
I don't owe you nothing, mister.
I could have worn them chains
all my life...
and I wouldn't have give a damn.
It was when they sold me
to the breeding farm for slaves...
that's when I said to myself
I was a man.
They used to whip me but they couldn't
make me hump none of them gals.
I sure picked the wrong time to decide
I wasn't going to be a slave no more.
You know...
two of us can't do any more good
at Pueblo Plata than one.
You can make tracks any time.
Ain't just going to be the two of us,
and you know it.
You're counting on
some of them coming back.
I admit I had some such idea,
but it looked like I gambled wrong.
I shared a lot of misery with them men
and I know them, too.
Zweig's more sad than bad.
And the Frenchman, he loves a fight.
Cholo? He's a sidewinder.
Hoop, he ain't coming back
because he ain't worth spit.
What about Chamaco?
He's liable to come back just to kill you.
In that case, Job, we stay here.
He's just dead drunk.
I know. I can smell him from here.
l'll come back.
Step down, Chamaco,
we'll have some grub in a while.
I don't want your food.
Well, your horse may.
There's some grain in the pack
over there.
Looks like you had
a good time last night.
I got no money left.
I give all my share of your money
to a beautiful lady.
I can make out.
I still had $300 in my boots.
Mr. Benedict, this is not honest.
That's an interesting way
of looking at it, Mr. Quiberon.
I hear horses.
Wake the others.
Job.
You three get behind the bank there.
- Why you pick me to come with you?
- Listen.
That direction. You stay here.
Seòor Benedict.
If you are there, hold your fire.
It is I, Cholo.
It's me, too, Mr. Benedict.
But hot damn, don't shoot now.
I dragged this cabrón along
because he might be useful.
Bullshit. I come back
on my own free will.
I can see that. Cholo, untie him.
Zweig, take the horses.
Okay, sir.
And then we'll have a council of war...
and Mr. Hoop's going to tell us
what we want to know...
about Pueblo Plata.
Pueblo Plata?
Come on now.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Pueblo... Wait a minute, fellows.
God damn it!
Come on, come over here.
Damn it, let go of me.
Now look, I ain't gonna take you
to no Pueblo Plata.
If you don't take us...
you don't go anywhere.
All right.
Now look what you went
and done. You drawn blood.
We're going to play mumbly-peg
with your head, Comanchero!
No!
All right, l'll bring you to Pueblo Plata...
but it won't do no good.
If you think you're going to fool them,
you got worms in your head.
Traders, guns and whiskey.
If the Comancheros want to look
at them empty packs...
before we get to Plata...
it's going to be a Merry Christmas
in Hell, l'll tell you.
A Merry Christmas in Hell.
Have you been down to Mexico much?
Some when I was younger.
When was that?
I was on a border survey
about 20 years ago.
You ever got to a place
called Villa Acuòa?
Might have.
You remember, wouldn't you?
lt's right on the border.
I don't remember. Why do you ask?
I used to live there once.
That's all.
How many in your family?
- Five.
- How many women?
My wife, two daughters.
You had two sons?
- That's right.
- How old your sons?
One was just a youngster,
the other was 18.
You know, l'm not much older than him.
He looked like you?
No, looked like his mother.
I look like my mother...
except she got black eyes, I got blue.
She's dead, my mother.
Well, I hope she died peacefully.
Her name was Secundina.
Now look, Mr. Benedict, we're
going to get our asses blown clean off.
I tell you,
they're watching us right now.
I hope so, Mr. Hoop.
But don't you understand?
That fellow Tarp will kill us.
All stone dead!
We have company,
Mr. Benedict.
That's right, Mr. Quiberon.
Gentlemen, raise your rifles
over your head...
and get a smile on your face.
You, too, Mr. Hoop.
Now talk to him.
He wants to know what we want here.
Tell him I got a present for him.
Easy now.
That son of a bitch's name is Katwa.
I seen him gut children just for sport.
Now he wants you to open up
them packages...
and see what's inside.
Tell him we're going to deal
with the white man.
Go on, tell him!
Tarp, there's a party coming in.
Wake up, Tarp.
Tarp!
How many? How far?
I can't tell yet!
Damn Indians!
They know better than to bring
somebody up here.
Rally must have known them
or they wouldn't be bringing them in.
Bullshit.
You go down and you talk
to those people. You stop them.
And you stall them!
All right.
Indios!
Bill, take the point!