Pull up!
Where you heading, mister?
That town called Río Arriba?
- That's right.
- That's where I'm heading.
Are you Mr Simms?
No.
The sheriff don't want any strangers in town.
Not till day after tomorrow.
- Then I'm in time.
- For what?
The hanging. Tomorrow, ain't it?
Yes. So just turn around and go back.
You're welcome to Río Arriba the day after.
I've ridden 100 miles to see this hanging.
That's for the sheriff to decide.
Unbuckle your gun belt.
Give me your rifle.
Don't take the hand off the butt.
Ride in slow. I go right behind you.
- Who is it?
- Shh. I don't know.
That's his office.
Picked him up on San Marcos Pass.
Said he came to see the hanging.
I told you not to let anybody through
except Simms. Get back and see you do it.
Yes, sir.
- Well, you got a name?
- Douglass.
Who are you looking for?
Did I say I was looking for somebody?
Río Arriba's a quiet little town.
We don't get many strangers here.
What do you want?
It's like your deputy said.
I come here to see the hanging.
- Where did you ride in from?
- Winthrop.
You rode 100 miles over the mountains
just to watch a hanging?
Uh-huh.
Know the men who are gonna die?
No.
You just like to watch hangings, is that it?
I'll keep your guns. You stay away
from this jail while you're in town.
- What time is the hanging?
- Six o'clock in the morning.
They start serving breakfast at the hotel
at 5:30. You can watch it on a full stomach.
- My name is Loomis. I own the bank.
- How do you do?
They shot my bank full of holes,
killed my teller.
But we caught 'em red-handed,
all four of 'em.
- No, sir. They didn't get a dime.
- When you hang 'em tomorrow, do it slow.
- Afraid you got me confused, young fella.
- Aren't you Mr Simms?
The hangman from Silver City?
No.
If you're not the hangman,
what are you doing here?
- Just passing through.
- Maybe he came here to help 'em break out.
Just looking to feed my horse
and find a hotel room.
Sir, I'm the hotel clerk.
I can find you a room. May I take your horse?
All right.
- You didn't answer my question, mister.
- I didn't hear you ask one.
- Wha's your business here in Río Arriba?
- Quinn! Put it down.
Ain't we got enough trouble
without you starting more?
Folks are a bit edgy today.
Might be a good idea
for you to stay in the hotel.
All right, break it up.
That's just what we're trying to avoid, a crowd.
You ought to know that. Come on, break it up.
- You going to church tonight, Tom?
- Emma?
- Yes, Father. Coming. Are you, Tom?
- Yeah, I'll be there.
Willie, take care of this horse.
Saturday, we gave 'em a fair trial.
We never had a hanging in this town. We had
to send to Silver City for a man to do the job.
We all thought you was him!
Well, it's not my line.
But if he don't show up,
I might accommodate you.
Tony.
- Take my horse and I'll meet you at the store.
- Yes, Miss Josefa.
Jim!
Josefa.
- It must be four years.
- it's closer to five.
Well, when I saw you crossing from the
courthouse, I just couldn't believe it was you.
I still can't believe it, Jim.
It's me all right.
This is an occasion. It deserves a celebration.
- Yes, it does.
- Come on. I'll buy you a beer.
- Diego, dos cervezas, por favor.
- Sí, señorita.
Le's sit here.
What brings you to Río Arriba, Jim?
Nice country.
What are you doing here?
I have some business with the sheriff's office.
Gracias, señor.
Have you been back to New Orleans?
No.
- We had fun.
- Uh-huh.
Since my father died,
I don't get to travel much.
- Where have you been?
- I got a little ranch outside Winthrop.
I never heard about it.
Small place.
Sometimes I wish mine were.
It's too much for a woman to handle.
- You never got married?
- No.
I just can't seem to find the right man.
Maybe you're too particular.
That's what my father said.
When we met in New Orleans...
I was husband-hunting.
You were?
I guess I...
I guess I did behave a little foolishly.
I don't know, maybe you were smart.
Did you ever marry?
Yes, I did.
Fine girl.
I'm sure.
I have to go.
- How long are you gonna be in town?
- Just until tomorrow.
Well...
It's good to see you again, Jim.
Amigo. Whiskey.
Sí, señor.
Willie! Take Mr Simms' horse to the stable.
I'll tell the sheriff you're here.
Mind if I join you?
Sit down.
Can I buy you a drink?
- I have mine.
- I hate to drink alone.
Oh, bartender? Whiskey.
Simms is the name, from Silver City.
I've come to perform
a little service for you folks.
Say, what does a man do
for a little recreation in this town?
At night, I mean.
I'm a stranger here, myself.
(sheriff) Mr Simms?
Oh, Sheriff. Come in and have a drink.
No, thanks. Would you care to inspect
the gallows and look at the prisoners?
There's plenty of time for that.
Had a long trip. Think I'd like to freshen up.
- Your room's ready, Mr Simms.
- Oh, thank you.
I hope I see you again, sir.
Of course, not professionally.
I'll drop over to the jail this afternoon.
Sheriff?
I wonder if I could see the prisoners.
- You said you didn't know 'em.
- I never met 'em, but I think I know 'em.
Did they do you a bad turn?
I've been following them for six months.
Tracking 'em up and down the state.
It's a relief to catch up with them and
find out the law's gonna do the job for me.
- You're sure they're the same bunch?
- Two white men, a half-breed and an Indian?
That's them. We never had anything like it in
Río Arriba before. I'll be glad when it's over.
You're wasting good lumber.
A tree would have done.
They were sentenced to be hanged,
not lynched.
- Primo?
- Yes, sir.
- They giving you any trouble?
- No.
- Feed 'em?
- They ate.
All right, come here.
On your feet! All of you!
(chuckling)
I said move! Now!
- Can you spare a smoke, stranger?
- Shut up!
What are you gonna do? Punish us if we talk?
I was hoping you'd bring us a woman, Sheriff.
Like to know their names?
No.
Much obliged.
Who's that, Sheriff?
- Don't you know him?
- I never saw him before in my life.
He came to see you hang.
- This is the last night. Watch 'em.
- Yes, sir.
And don't talk to 'em.
If they want anything, call me.
- Sheriff?
- Hm?
You think I might get off
long enough to go to church tonight?
I'll see. I'll do what I can.
- Parral, Father Bailey's here to see you.
- I told you to keep him outta here!
- Your mother's with him.
- I don't wanna see her either!
Primo.
- What time is it?
- I don't talk to you.
You're the only one
we got nothing against, Primo.
Primo takes good care of us. We all love him.
- Well, I don't love you.
- Sure you do!
First time I have a little niño,
I'm gonna name him Primo, after you.
You joke when you should be praying.
(sawing)
Get down!
What you thinking, Zach?
Wondering who that stranger is.
- The way he looked, he didn't come to help.
- I can't place him.
He seemed to know you.
He looked at you the hardest.
- Luján.
- Mm?
You ever see that man before?
No, but he's got the face of a hunter.
Zach, we don't have much time.
- Don't you think we know that?
- We can't just wait here.
Go ahead, bang your head on the bars
and yell. They'll hang you right now.
(bells ringing)
Why, you say the darndest things sometimes.
Good evening, Mr Steinmetz.
Hello, Tom.
Emma, you know where
I put my stomach powders?
- Oh, yes, Father.
- Would you get me one?
Just in case.
Tom, Emma is a fine girl.
Yes, sir. I think so too.
The worlïs big and there are many wonderful
places in it, and I'd like Emma to see them.
- Well, sir, I want...
- Let me finish, Tom.
I was a pedlar when I came here. It's taken a
quarter of a century to make what I got today.
And now I am too old to enjoy it.
I want Emma to enjoy it.
But not in this out-of-the-way small town.
I want her to marry some man
who lives in Philadelphia or Boston.
Has his business there.
Mixes with educated people.
- Am I wrong to want that for her, Tom?
- No, sir.
Right now, Emma thinks she loves you.
I guess she does.
But she's never had a chance
to meet anyone else.
I want to give her that chance.
- Now, what has he been telling you?
- About Philadelphia and Boston.
Gosh. Wouldn't you love to go there?
- Good evening, Sheriff.
- Good evening, Mr Steinmetz.
Emma. Tom.
Must be big doings in church tonight.
Looks like everyone in town is going.
That's right.
It's our annual novena to St Anthony.
- Would you like to look at the prisoners?
- I'd like to finish my cigar first.
All right, there's no hurry.
Finish your cigar.
I think I'll stretch my legs.
(knock at door)
It's open.
Jim?
Come in.
I'm on my way to church.
I thought that you might like to go.
I don't go to church any more.
Jim, I... I don't understand.
Very simple - I just don't go.
I'm sorry. Very sorry.
Josefa.
If you'll allow me, I'll walk you there.
Of course.
Stay down.
- Think the sheriff would let us go to church?
- No.
It's all right if I look at it
from the window, isn't it?
All right.
Everyone's going to church.
You think they'd pray for us, Primo?
Primo.
Will you pray for us?
You want me to?
You're a good man, Primo.
Goïll listen to you.
- What should I pray for?
- That we go to heaven.
I can't do that.
But I will pray that God will forgive you.
I'll settle for that.
Was it Tucker?
How soon, do you think,
before he'll make his try?
When everyone's in church.
No talking!
I'm praying, Primo.
Do you have any children, Jim?
- Little girl.
- How old is she?
Three.
Pretty?
She's pretty.
Like her mother was.
"Was"?
She's dead.
I'm sorry.
- Good evening, Sheriff.
- Evening, Josefa.
You must have been very much in love.
Still am.
(Simms) Beautiful evening, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Thanks, Josefa.
Guess I needed to talk to a woman.
There's a woman inside
I think you might do well to talk to.
(choir sings)
Well, should we take a look
at our bad boys now?
Fine.
- Primo?
- Yes, sir.
- Everything all right?
You go on to church now.
Mr Simms is with me.
- Thank you, Sheriff. Thank you, Mr Simms.
- And Primo...
Come back as soon as the service is over.
Mr Simms may wanna get to bed early.
Oh, That's all right, Sheriff.
- Take your time. Don't worry about me.
- Thank you, sir.
All right. On your feet, all of you.
Over here.
Can't we have
a little more light in here, Sheriff?
- Sure.
- I'd like to get a good idea of size and weight.
Hold him up while I get the key.
- There's a key dropped on the floor.
- All right, get it.
- I can't reach it.
- Reach with the dipper.
Reach!
Blanket.
Come on!
(choir singing)
(whispers)
- We take her along.
- She'll slow us down.
They won't rush us as long as we've got her.
Get the horses.
I think we're all aware of the shadow
that has fallen over Río Arriba.
The gallows cast a shadow even at night.
Tomorrow four men are to die.
That they die is the just
fulfilment of Caesar's law.
But I remind you that these four men are
also creatures of God, eligible for His mercy.
Pray for them as He would.
If you recall,
there was also scaffolding at Golgotha.
And Christ, bleeding and dying, took time in
his agony to turn and pardon a common thief.
Remember that tomorrow.
For all of you, i'll be daybreak.
But for these four men...
i'll be the midnight of their lives.
Your prayers will help them.
(choir singing)
(sheriff) Help!
Help!
Wha's the matter? Que pasa?
(gunshots)
Emma!
- Here's her purse.
- Emma!
- How's the sheriff?
- He's badly hurt.
(man) Everybody, come on, le's go!
Get your horses and guns!
- Get your gun and horse. Le's go.
- Where?
- After 'em!
- They stole five horses!
We can't find Emma. They've taken her.
Josefa! They've taken Emma.
Wha'll I do? Please help me. Please!
Mr Steinmetz, we'll all help. I'll get
my horse and go with you. Come on, Jim.
You can't overtake 'em tonight
before they get to San Marcos Pass.
- One of 'em can hold that against a hundred.
- Aren't you coming with us?
It's gonna be a long hard chase.
I could use some sleep. I'll wait till morning.
Do you mean to tell me, after wha's
happened, you can just go and sleep?
Yes.
And then what?
I'm gonna find them, if it's the last thing I do.
Good night.
- What do you think?
- With the woman, they can overtake us.
Taylor, stay here and hold them off
till sundown. We'll head for Elder Gorge.
We'll wait for you there.
- Please let me go!
- Later.
- Please. My father will give you anything.
- I've already got all he can give me.
(Primo) Everybody, le's go! Come on!
Quinn, how about those boys back there?
Come on!
Quinn! Steinmetz! Le's go.
Get your horse, go into town and get a wagon
here. Take this man down with the others.
Primo, Murphy looks bad. There's nothing
I can do. You've gotta get him out of here.
Do what you can. I've sent for a wagon.
(Primo) All we can do is wait.
Then we'll follow them over the pass.
Once they get to the desert,
we can circle 'em.
- (Tom) We can lose 'em.
- They got Emma!
- I'm not going to take that chance.
- (Douglass) Hold it! Wait.
Primo's right. You can't rush 'em.
But don't worry about losing her.
What do you know? Who are you? You're
a stranger. You say, "You can't rush them."
That's all right for you, but my daughter's
in danger. Maybe you want us to lose them.
I've been following them for six months.
I'm not gonna lose 'em now.
If I was you...
I'd pick out 12 of these men
and send the rest of 'em home.
Especially the old fella
and the lady over there.
- I can't send Mr Steinmetz home.
- He'll not do any good and get in the way.
He won't leave.
I'm sorry.
Primo just told me you don't want me along.
Well, That's right.
Emma's gonna need me
when we catch up with them.
With you along,
we might not catch up with them.
You might get hurt.
I wouldn't want to see that.
Are you worried about me?
These are mean men we're after.
They're real mean.
- For the gorge you must turn off here.
- You still like that idea?
- Yes. We told Taylor we'd wait there.
- We'd move faster on the desert.
That's where they'll be looking for us.
If we keep moving,
we can reach the border in two days.
In the desert we can only ride at night.
Two days and we'll burn up.
- She won't last a day.
- Why do we need her?
I need her. We'll head for the gorge and hole
up there till they stop searching. Lead, Luján.
- What do you think, Mr Douglass?
- Sun's going down.
That's what he waited for.
We can't track 'em by night.
- Le's move ahead as long as we can see.
- Everybody, get mounted!
Somebody build a fire. Start up some coffee.
Can't we go on? Just you and me?
- Be like looking for a needle in a haystack.
- Yeah, but I'm worried about Emma.
Suppose we were lucky enough
to stumble across 'em.
You don't think they'd give up
without a fight?
- She'd be the first they'd kill.
- Here is one of them! Here he is!
Come on, all of you!
Come here, all of you! Help!
I found one of them!
There he is. See? Must be one of them.
This is not one of them.
That must be the real Mr Simms.
- Got a timepiece?
- No, sir.
Here.
Take mine.
You go back to the rim of the gorge.
- Then fire a shot every five minutes.
- But what good will that do?
Sound carries a long way
in these canyons. They'll hear it.
Make 'em wonder. Keep 'em up all night.
Take their minds off Emma.
One of us will relieve him every hour.
Keep it up all night.
You take turns standing watch.
I'll look after the horses.
I'll take the last tour. You'll take the first.
I'll take the first watch. Can't sleep anyway.
- Taylor.
- Yeah?
When we get out of this,
you wanna stick with me or split up?
- Well, I haven't given it much thought.
- I have.
You're a good man, Taylor.
I should hate to lose you.
Well, I sort of like having
a man behind me I can count on.
That Parral's a louse.
The Injun makes me nervous.
Never know wha's going on inside his head.
- I never crossed a man that rode with me.
- Well, neither did I.
I need you with me.
That goes double.
I got one weakness
I feel you should know about.
Wha's that?
Women.
Every man's entitled
to one weakness. Mine's cards.
You think Luján
needs some help with the horses?
Well now, he just might.
Is that silk?
(gunshot)
Where'd that come from?
- Where'd that shot come from?
- It's an old trick. They wanna keep us awake.
Get back on watch.
Go to sleep. You never hear
the shot that kills you.
Well, they were here all right.
Not too long ago.
Looks like those shots of ours
changed their path.
Tracks show they went down the gorge.
Yeah.
Could be the Indian's thinking,
to throw us off.
Stop that, you idiot!
- I want Emma to know we're following.
- Now they all know!
You said we'd lose them in the gorge.
They're smarter than you thought, red man.
There's only one man
that could have followed us down here.
The one with the eyes of the hunter.
The strange one.
- That the sheriff brought to jail to look at us.
- He's right.
I saw him with the posse
up in San Marcos Pass.
Well, who is he? Wha's he dogging us for?
- Maybe she knows.
- I never saw him before he came.
- Why did he come?
- To watch you hang.
- It's the truth!
- Let her go!
- He must know one of you.
- Maybe it's you he's after.
How could he be? I never saw him before.
No. He don't look like no banker.
Or the owner of any place we ever robbed.
Le's kill him. Then the others can't follow us.
- It's a good idea. You do it.
- Can't Luján do it?
No. We need Luján to take us to the border.
You catch up with us tonight.
- Why me?
- It was your idea!
What is it, Mr Douglass?
You see movement up there in that tall grass?
(Tom) No, sir.
I think there's a man there,
waiting for us to come in range.
Why don't we make him fire first?
- Then one of us would be dead.
- We gonna wait for sundown again?
Primo.
You take the lead.
You and the others circle the hill.
Stay just outside rifle range of that tall grass.
I'll go up the other side.
- Why are you doing this for us, Mr Douglass?
- I'm not doing it for you.
Come on.
Come on. Keep moving.
- I'm waiting for you.
- I'm here.
Drop it.
You remember that woman?
No.
Now look at it.
- No.
- You're lying!
I never saw her before. I swear I didn't.
You stopped at my ranch six months ago.
I never saw your ranch.
I don't even know where it is.
- There were four of you.
- We never did.
Please. You gotta believe me.
She begged. And cried.
And pleaded too, didn't she?
"Please, leave me alone. I have a baby."
"I have a husband. Please, leave me alone."
"Take anything you want,
but please leave me alone."
Didn't she? But it didn't help much.
I never saw that face before. I was never
on your ranch. I never did anything to you.
Which one of you? Which one of you did it?
I didn't do it.
I've done some bad things. Robbed. Stole.
- I've run cattle. But I never killed no woman.
- Talk! There were four of you. Which one?
Which one?
Don't do it. Please let me live.
Please let me live. Please.
I've got a wife and baby, too. Don't do it.
Please don't do it. I'll do anything.
Then it was all four of you!
(gunshot)
Holy Mother, help...
- Morning, Father.
- Morning, Josefa.
- How's the sheriff?
- Much better.
Good.
Poor Mrs Parral. I feel so sorry for her.
Yeah.
It's hard to believe. One child can bring
so much happiness, so much grief.
Any news of Primo and the men?
No.
- Douglass has gone with them, hasn't he?
- Yes.
- He came to church with you.
Do you know him?
Years ago.
I hadn't seen him in five years.
But he's changed.
What happened to him, Father?
Quite a lot.
He was out tending his cattle.
Came home one evening to find
that his house had been ransacked
and his wife had been raped and murdered.
- How awful.
- I think That's what brought him to Río Arriba.
Jim Douglass is not the kind of man
to just watch a hanging.
Must be some connection between
those men and what happened at the ranch.
I think that Jim must believe
that those men committed the crime.
- Did they?
- Nobody knows. I doubt if Jim knows.
But his child. What happened to the child?
A ranch hand and his wife
are taking care of her.
That child could have been mine.
I was in love with Jim Douglass
and he asked me to marry him.
I didn't have the sense to say yes.
You'd have married a good man.
How do I get to his ranch?
After San Marcos Pass,
you take the Winthrop road to Canyon Diablo.
There'll be a small stone cabin.
- You think Parral got our man?
- I hope they got each other.
Look.
Yeah. There's Parral now.
He got our man. I feel better.
That's not Parral.
It's the hunter.
- How could they have caught us so soon?
- They haven't.
It's only one man.
(Taylor) Well, we can handle
one man easy enough.
He's marking a trail for the posse.
- Le's wait for him.
- And let the posse gain on us?
- Go on. I'll catch up with you.
- Why you?
I'm a better shot.
And I don't like a man dogging my trail.
What do you think, Luján?
There's sure to be someone there.
- Then we'll get something to eat.
- We need fresh horses more than food.
Then we'll get both. Come back here!
(horse whinnies)
Now, where did you think you were going?
Aw, don't cry. I'm not gonna make you walk.
I'm gonna let you ride.
Right up here, next to me.
We haven't seen Douglass
since he killed Parral.
He must have gone back.
Douglass didn't go back.
Look.
- Howdy.
Can you spare a little food?
We haven't eaten all day.
- Fooïs pretty scarce around these parts.
- (sniffs)
We're willing to pay for hospitality.
- Where you heading?
- Río Arriba.
Well, you're lost.
You're headed in the wrong direction.
Río Arriba's across the Diablo in the north.
You can spare a little grub
for the lady, can't you?
- I guess so.
- We'd be satisfied with a cup of coffee.
You know what happened to your horse?
- Just one word and you'll get the same.
- I won't talk.
Eggs!
- Where can we get a couple of horses?
- Well, the...
Douglass ranch
is about four miles west of here.
But I don't know
if they've got any horses or not.
Don't get any foolish ideas.
Wha's that?
- It's gold.
- Them's my teeth.
- Where's your gold?
- I haven't any.
- What are you mining for?
- Silver. So far I haven't found any.
Well...
- I gotta get back to work.
- Go ahead. Don't let us stop you.
What did he take?
Go and see what it was.
(screaming)
(Emma) No!
(screams)
(screaming)
- Le's go. The posse's coming!
- Go ahead. I'll be along.
I said now!
Come.
There's the miner's cabin.
Douglass' ranch should be
about four more miles west.
Who's that?
You know, that looks like Jim Douglass.
Jim!
- I'm glad I caught up with you.
- Why?
Jim, why don't you stop this mad chase
after these men and let them go?
You can't undo wha's been done.
And you have a child to think of.
How can you be so sure these are the men?
Come here.
Look at this.
That's John Butler, my neighbour.
Poor devil never harmed anybody in his life.
Now they've killed him.
Le's get him in the house.
(Josefa) Jim!
Jim, come here! Come quickly! Emma!
Come on! Hurry! Hurry!
Mr Steinmetz, hurry!
We've found Emma.
She's here, in the house.
- How is she?
- I don't know.
- (sobbing)
- (Josefa) Please don't worry, Emma.
Everything's fine now. Really it is.
Look, Tom's here and your father's here.
Jim!
I know how you feel.
Go after them, Jim, and catch them.
Get them before...
Kill them! Kill them! Kill them!
Primo.
You take your men and head for the border.
I'm going by my place
to pick up a fresh horse.
- I'll meet you at the river.
- Yes, sir.
Everybody! Get moving!
All right, le's get going.
Juanita!
Juanita. Juanita.
Juanita.
Alguien viene a caballo.
No los veo.
Parece tu padre. No los conozco.
Señor Douglass.
Hace rato vinieron dos hombres, se llevaron
dos caballos y se fueron hacia el río.
Se llevaron los mejores caballos.
¿ Qué hacemos? Lo siento mucho.
Elena y yo estábamos solas.
Pablo se fue a trabajar.
Está bien, Juanita. No te apures.
We're not far behind,
but they took the only horses that were here.
Helen, this is Josefa.
She's a good friend of mine.
A very good friend.
- I want you to stay with her until I get back.
- Yes.
I don't know when tha'll be.
I'll take care of her.
Just as if she were my own.
I guess I haven't been much of a father.
Bye.
God bless you, Jim.
It looks like it all right.
Mr Douglass, here are the tracks.
This is where they crossed the river.
Mr Douglass!
This is the international border.
We can't go further.
I can.
Señora, did you see two men
on horseback cross the river here today?
No entiendo.
¿ Vio a dos hombres a caballo
cruzar el río por aquí hoy?
Ah, sí. Mire.
Bajaron allí, luego cruzaron el río,
dieron la vuelta y se fueron a San Cristóbal.
San Cristóbal. ¿Para dónde hay que ir a eso?
Mire. San Cristóbal está...
Se va usted por aquí, da la vuelta, sube
y un poco más adelante está San Cristóbal.
¿A qué distancia queda?
- Como a 20 km.
- Muchas gracias.
- Otro copa para la señorita.
- Si, Señor.
Y...
Who are you?
What do you want with me?
- Look at it.
- I see it.
What of it? It's a watch.
Look at the picture.
What about her? Who is she?
- You remember her.
- I never saw that woman before in my life.
Now get outta here.
I'm tired of you dogging my trail.
She was my wife.
Raped and killed by you.
I tell you I never saw that woman before
in my life. Now get away from me!
(screaming)
(horses galloping)
(chickens squawking)
Pablo, qué bueno que llegaste.
Bendito sea Dios que llegaste.
Mira, Ángela. Tenemos todo el dinero
necesario para el resto de la vida. Cógelo.
- Sí, pero el niño está enfermo.
- ¿Que está enfermo? ¿Desde cuándo?
- Desde hace mucho.
- Vente.
- Tiene mucha fiebre.
- Sí, pobrecito.
Necesitamos refrescarle la frente.
Bueno, le voy a poner un poquito de agua.
A ver si se le quita la fiebre.
Pero es que no hay agua.
Voy a buscar un poquito. Vengo enseguida.
(boy) No hay agua. No hay agua.
Mientras cuidas al niño,
te voy a hacer algo de comer.
Where's the Indian
who rode up here on that horse?
Perdone, señor, no le entiendo nada.
Mi hijo está muy enfermo.
Mi esposo fue a traer agua al arroyo.
¿Quién es usted? ¿Qué va a hacer?
Ese hombre te quería matar.
Ángela.
Traele algo de comer.
Eat.
Why don't you kill me?
I came here to kill you.
I have no reason to kill you.
Why do you hunt me?
Just look at that picture.
- Your wife and baby?
- Yeah.
She's very pretty.
My wife and baby, they are pretty.
Why do you hunt me?
- You ever see that woman before?
- No.
There were four men. Two white men,
a half-breed and an Indian.
They robbed my ranch house
and killed my wife.
I have never seen your ranch.
The horse you rode up here
you stole from my ranch!
I did not know that was your ranch
and I didn't see any woman.
If you've never been to my ranch,
where'd you get this money?
That I took from a miner
I met in Canyon Diablo.
We were at his house.
We ate his eggs and meat.
Then he ran down the hill
to hide that money and Zachary killed him.
I took that money
from his hand when he was dead.
No.
Butler was the one who told me - six months
ago, the day my wife was murdered -
that the four of you, you came
straight from my ranch past his place.
It is true. We did come past his place.
But we did not come from the direction of
your ranch. We came straight from the border.
Well, uh...
How...
Where did Butler get that money?
It was stolen from my house the day...
If my wife...
Butler.
What I have told you is the truth.
Oh, God.
Dear God.
That's him.
Tom.
He's back.
Sheriff, he's back.
Glad you're back, Jim.
You've been away a long time.
Father, I need help.
- We all do.
- I killed three men.
The people of Río Arriba are thankful
that you brought justice where they failed.
You don't understand. I...
I didn't... kill them for the sake of justice.
You were a member of an armed posse
legally sent out to get them, dead or alive.
No, Father. I didn't kill them for
anything that they did here in Río Arriba.
I killed them for revenge.
Revenge for something
that they didn't even do.
I set myself up as the judge,
the... jury and the... executioner.
They swore that they were innocent.
One of them even...
He begged on his knees...
for his life.
I wouldn't listen.
I killed them for something
that they didn't do.
Well...
Jim, let me point this out to you.
By telling me what you have
and feeling as you do,
you're already a step ahead of a lot
of other men that have been in your shoes.
That doesn't mean I'm condoning
what you've done, but at least you haven't
excused your own actions by saying,
as many men would,
that these men were evil and should die,
and that you carried out a legal execution.
I know that, Father, but... it doesn't help.
I was wrong.
Wrong. Wrong.
Come on.
Some people think prayers help.
(crowd cheering)
Ladies and gentlemen,
there's no need for me to tell you,
the emergency arose...
and the man appeared.
Douglass, it's not often a man gets
to do so much for his neighbours,
and do it like you did.
We want you to know, we'll be forever grateful
and you'll be in our hearts always.
Thank you.
And in your prayers.
Please.