I surrender!
Don't kill me, Silence!
I'm not going to hunt a bandit down
again, even if bounty is high.
I swear it.
Goddammit! My hands!
You've ruined my hands!
Let's move!
Even dead those damn bounty
hunters do scare me.
You came right on time.
Take this, you deserve it.
Those sons of bitches ambush us everytime, when
we're going down to the valley to get some food.
They know, that we can't stay
long here without food.
If we defend ourselves, the bounty get
raised and we would have a massacre.
You could thank me at least.
The guy has almost shot.
Your bullet was useless, believe me.
Without his thumb this bastard couldn't touch
a gun anymore, not to mention to shoot with it.
That's why Silence didn't kill him.
And it was self-defense against the others.
He knew, they waited for him,
but he was quicker, as usual.
Why somebody else has got to
defend us? We've got weapons.
Let's go to the city and show it
to those damn bounty hunters.
We or them... This way things
will come to an end.
Listen to me, friends: a lot of
us aren't guilty of anything.
It's just unfair, to put
a prize on our heads.
The new governor promised an amnesty.
- You have to resist that long.
- I give up.
I go to the city. I'll better be caught.
I will surrender.
In jail it's warm...
Wait, I'll go with you.
I go too.
- They'll wait for their amnesty in jail!
- If they'll come so far.
Miguel!
- Where's the lawyer, Mama?
- There.
I couldn't stand anymore. But I
haven't told anything to the others.
I followed your advice.
How wise of you to trust into laws.
I'm glad, that you help me.
No... what are you doing?
Mama!
Miguel!
Miguel... my son!
You have to understand, that's
how we earn our money.
I'll bring him directly to the sheriff.
What a luck, that his face isn't
damaged. So he's still recognizable.
Come, let's go and collect
the payments, Tigrero.
The reward is all yours, colleague,
I was just nearby.
I'll catch the other two,
no one wil be disappointed.
But be careful, they killed five of us.
The amnesty was the start
for a massive manhunt.
The bountyhunting has to be
put to an end immediately.
- Certainly, governor, but...
- But?
Bounty hunters are people...
who're acting following the law.
Besides it's not that easy, to stay
in control of such a big area alone.
But for you it is, sheriff.
Are you the second best gunslinger
in the state or not?
Certainly. But only, because I
succesfully avoided the best one.
Keep on going. The electors have to
believe into law and order again.
We have to put an end to "Wild West".
Bounty hunters, bandits and sheriffs
will be united in a better world.
In a world, where...
The governor would even free the murder
of his president before the elections.
What are you saying, sheriff?
I don't understand you.
Nothing. I just think loud sometimes.
- A good soldier doesn't think.
- Certainly. No thoughts, just orders.
Forwards to Snow Hill...
Utah.
Enough! Stop!
Believe me, Tigrero, I don't know anything.
- Tell me first, where I can find him.
- I don't know him.
You know him well, he was
with you in the mountains.
I don't know, where he went.
I beg you, let me go!
I don't know him.
Stop it!
Believe me, Tigrero!
I don't know anything!
Don't lie to me. I'll find out,
whatever you say.
In the mill,
outside the city,
where his wife is living.
He's armed.
Thank you very much.
I'm ressurrection and I'm life.
Those, who believe in me,
will never die. Amen.
If you're waiting for the stagecoach,
you'll need patience.
Snow fell down in the mountains.
It will delay.
You want some warm meal,
while you're waiting?
Thank you, I'll serve it right away.
I know you, stranger.
You help the weak to their rights.
Your gun avenges the innocent.
My son was innocent too.
They killed him like many others.
I beg you to avenge him!
One of his murders has left, but
the other one is still in the city.
I can only offer you Miguel's horse
for the life of his murderer.
Kill him, avenge my son's death!
So you will save some another
unfortunates from death.
Yes, I know.
Some of them collect bounties
up to 5000 Dollar.
My friend Tigrero, for example,
puts always...
some money away. But
with all that snow...
you can easily freeze your ass off.
I eat the whole time and it's still cold.
The doctor...
told me, it could be the blood.
He wanted to analyze it,
but I don't let anybody on my blood.
You're right, Charly.
That brings bad luck.
Certainly.
Shut the door, it's cold!
Shut it, I said!
Or you'll getting cold too...
but forever. You heard me?
Shut the door or I'll kill you.
Calm down, Charly.
To threat this one is dangerous.
I don't threat, sheriff, I shoot.
Close the fucking door!
Close the...
- What now, are we going to arrest him?
- No, Charly has drawn first.
The stranger shot as an act of self-defense.
This way the law can't convict him.
Maybe. But you have to draw
quicker then the devil.
Maybe it was the devil himself.
You waste your time.
My husband isn't here.
I know, but I don't risk my
skin for 1000 Dollar.
When he'll see you, he'll
stay calm. Bring me to him.
I won't do that, leave!
Come on, move it!
If you love your wife, then come out!
Move!
I want you alive.
I'll collect the bounty anyway.
So why are you afraid?
Come out and surrender!
You rotten piece of meat.
Throw away your gun and
put the hands up!
Now go and cover your
ex-husband with snow.
So he'll stay fresh on this cold.
He can't be buried, 'till I got my money.
Don't forget it, ok?
He was worth a lot.
What times are these!
A colored is worth more then a white.
Help!
My husband was murdered, help me!
Boss, hes's brought here.
Pauline... oh my God, poor thing!
- You have to be strong.
- Don't cry!
Pollicut!
You dirty racketeer! You keep
yourself in warmth, eh?
While this hapless perished because of you!
That's you, damn rascal...
who makes benefits off bounties,
set for people's heads.
This man was a criminal. He's
got nothing, he didn't deserve.
It hasn't to take effects on Pauline.
She can have anything from me.
You pig!
She'd rather have to do with
a rabid dog then with you!
Move!
Move on!
Forwards, come on.
Goddammit.
Move on!
Stupid brute!
Go!
I am the new sheriff.
I don't have any money.
Nada dinero!
If you're going to kill me, you all be hung.
If somebody moves, I'll shoot him.
You won't get me that easy.
Your rifle is frozen, sheriff.
We are experienced enough,
to hold our weapons warm...
and know how to use them right.
One false move and I'll crush your head!
Have no fear, we don't want to kill you.
- What do you want then?
- Your horse, sheriff.
What? You are so many, of what
use one horse will be for you?
Beefsteak.
It'll fill our stomachs for one week.
- Move to my place, if you want to.
- That won't help.
I just want one thing:
to take revenge, even
if it'll cost my life.
There was a reward set for your husband
and it's because of Pollicut.
When he didn't give him any work,
he practically forced him to steal.
You might be right, but the
real murder is Tigrero.
I want his life for my husband's.
There is a man, before whom
even the bounty hunters shudder.
They call him Silence...
because Silence and
Death accompany him.
We're late.
Hey! Stop!
There's somebody.
I'm a sheriff.
I have to leave here.
Doesn't matter where you're heading to,
first you bring me to Snow Hill.
- We don't go there.
- I don't care!
Bring me to Snow Hill! Immediately!
Excuse the detour, but I
have to go to Snow Hill.
It's urgent.
I am the new sheriff.
As if it wouldn't be enough,
there's now this damn cold!
I know, what you think.
You think the administration is now
sending out their people on own feet.
But... I didn't have to walk before.
The bandits took away
my horse to eat it.
Unhitch the horses and replace them.
When the snowstorm starts, we'll be stuck.
Please, help me carrying.
I'll buy a you a drink later.
I gonna take the bigger one.
How heavy he is!
Come, pull it!
Here it goes!
Hey, you!
You can't transport the dead like that.
There are exact prescriptions for it.
I am the new sheriff of Snow Hill.
I noticed from your star. In
fact you look like a rancher.
But with the star you look like
a rancher, who plays sheriff.
Go on!
Who's the clown with a priest's
hat and women's furcoat?
That's Tigrero. You better
dispose of him quickly.
- Thanks.
- No big deal.
Wait!
I have to freshen up your memory a bit.
The dead are only allowed to be
transported in wood- or metalcoffins.
Regulation's Article 15...
- These are no ordinary corpses.
- They aren't?
What corpses are they then?
Two bandits, which I eliminated
and bringing to Snow Hill.
I want to obtain the bounty finally,
before they have rotten.
If you excuse me...
There are four on the posters.
Which ones are the two on the roof?
The second and the third.
One is already in the city. He'll be
buried, as soon as he'll be paid for.
The law wants them dead or alive.
You prefer dead, it seems.
Alive they come expensive. That's why
the law accepts alternative states.
Besides it'd be far too dangerous. These
people act against God and the whole world,
against morale, law and order. They
really belong to the graveyard.
Hold it, please!
What happened?
I have to load up another one.
- Help me, I wouldn't accomplish it alone.
- What is he doing now?
Come here!
Lift him up, come on!
I took care of this one two days ago.
The cold have got him conserved.
He's only worth 500 Dollar,
but every little helps.
What do you want, money is money. You
have to take precautions for the old age.
Who knows, if you'll live
long enough to see it.
One day you're going to meet somebody,
who draws faster then you.
That'll be a pleasureable day.
Very pleasureable.
Come, the coach has arrived!
See you next time, my friend.
I hope you'll be more talkative then.
Here is your saddle.
I pictured Snow Hill a bit bigger.
If it's going to continue snowing like it
does, it'll be even smaller by tomorrow.
The man over there, with the horse...
- I want to know where he's heading.
- Alright.
Don't let your capital lying on the street.
Bury it or take it home, got it?
If you pay me right now, they're yours.
Me? That's the last thing I needed.
You think, I'm the undertaker here?
I don't like neither your
face or your manners.
So prepare, or you might
end also like them.
Good evening, sheriff.
Welcome to Snow Hill.
I'm delighted to see, that
you can enforce respect.
And who the hell are you?
You couldn't guess?
I'm Edwin Pollicut.
That's my store.
My name was surely mentioned,
when you were sent here.
I'm sorry. Are you that important? What do
you do apart from commercial business?
I'm the magistrate here.
We will work together.
So let's finish the business?
You pay me the bounty and it's done.
It's finished for me already.
Come tomorrow to my office
and receive your payment.
Yes, that's mine. Come inside.
I pictured you different
from what you look like.
It's not, like that's important...
Please, take a seat.
I asked you here, to kill a man.
How much do you want for it?
Answer me at least.
Can't you talk?
Forgive me.
I couldn't imagine...
"1000 Dollar. Who is it?"
Tomorrow or in two days at the
latest I'll have the money.
I just need some time.
It's Tigrero, the bounty hunter.
He was with you in the coach.
He killed my husband.
Also for 1000 Dollar.
No. If I have to kill him, you
should put a reward on his head.
You should do it for free.
It's of your interest. He's
an enemy of the bounty hunters.
I know him. A dreamer, who wanna
change the world through a gun.
His methods are marvelous.
He draws second...
but shoots first. But one
day he'll bite the dust.
He wants to kill you.
Pauline ordered him here.
He'll challenge you.
He won't do me any harm.
Your thumbhunter...
won't kill me in self defense.
Maybe he's looking for you.
Get the negress to your
bed quickly, you fool.
I got her husband out of your
way, what do you want more?
If you're looking for a killer,
why not to ask your footman.
Tomorrow some colleagues
of mine will arrive.
You're going to stay here tonight.
So nobody will see you in here.
There is a bed by the staircase.
Good night.
Proof your innocence.
You can't kill them.
Do it for your son!
Gordon, come out. Sheriff speaks
here. Resistance is futile.
You better go to jail
or we'll pump you up with lead.
There is a reward set on you.
Surrender to the law.
Throw your gun away!
A good attorney might proof your innocence.
All right, sheriff, I surrender.
Mama! Mama!
The boy will betray us.
No.
He'll never speak again.
First corpses, then money,
that's the rule.
The law asks for irrefutable proof,
that's why Tigrero always present the
corpses with the particular warrant.
Absolutely like the rules require.
That might be true, but why you interfere?
As a financier you only have to
advance me the money, to pay him.
Certainly, but I claim commission of
25% interest from this money.
A little income, granted by the state.
Everything, like the law says.
As well as an immediate cash payment
without formalities, or am I wrong?
For my part, pay him off
and remove the corpses!
They stink.
That'd be...
500 two times...
and two for each 1000.
Altogether 3000.
Outside there are only three,
why do you pay him for four?
- Why four rewards?
- Because... there are four.
But here are just three.
I left the negro here, but
his wife buried him already.
- Everybody here knows that.
- Yes, that's true.
That's not right according to the
regulations. Like you said before:
first corpses, then money,
but it's not like that.
I'll take a closer look at this,
so the money is confiscated for now.
I'll interrogate the widow
and initiate an investigation.
Then I'm going to write a
report to the governor.
He'll forward it to a competent
position to be taken care of.
Isn't it what you had in mind?
"Everything, like the law says."
Pretty cold, isn't it?
If it'll continue the way it goes,
you'll certainly return back to Africa.
I'm sorry, didn't mean it.
Ehmm... Pauline.
What can I do for you?
Do you want to buy anything?
I don't really want to
buy, more like to sell.
- And what?
- My house.
It's worth minimum 5000 dollars.
I give it away for 1000.
I know, you like good deals.
Let's go over there.
- Take care of the store.
- Alright, Chef.
- May I ask you, what the money is for?
- No.
Well...
I can guess already, what the purpose is.
- Qualified killer are expensive.
- That's my business.
Are you interested in my offer?
No, Pauline.
I am not like you think. I won't
take advantage of your distress.
No... I want to help you.
Go to hell.
Not bad, my friend, but
it could be better.
What do you say now?
Oh yes, I heard about it already.
Some kinda improved gun, but
not a quite accurate tool.
Good power. Damn good.
I'm wondering, what a shooter
like you, is looking here for.
Are you one of those dirty
scumbags of bounty hunters?
Answer, when I ask you something.
I'm the sheriff here.
Who are you? Where are you from?
How long you gonna stay?
If you think you can play the
wiseguy, you're wrong.
Are you going to answer or not?
He can't answer, he's mute
Ehhh, you could have said something.
I mean...
could have explained...
Listen...
Tell me something.
I heard, that you buried your husband,
after a bounty hunter killed him.
So...
- Is it true?
- Yes.
- What was his name?
- James Middleton.
- No, the bounty hunter's name.
- Tigrero.
- I raise.
- Pass.
- Cornerstraight.
- Nice play.
Come, I want another chance!
Let's double the bets.
Of course it's cold, the fire is off.
No false hopes, you won't make
money out of me today.
Actually you've promised us
"the big money" in Snow Hill.
In real here's not a shadow of a bandit.
Come on, Schulz.
Those thugs are cornered, soon hunger
will drive them into the city.
There will be so many, that
you'll get out of ammo.
Such a cold!
- You need a match?
- Thank you.
Salute!
May I introduce my friends?
It's not really of a big value to me...
to know your friends.
Here is the money.
Really nice, that you came
all the way here to pay me.
I'm not nice, I want you to
vanish as soon as possible.
But that's against my plans.
The air is very healthy, I like the
perspective... and even the sheriff.
The perspective will change quickly.
And the air might become
unbreathable for all of you.
Whiskey.
I couldn't find the money.
Anyhow I want my revenge.
That doesn't mean...
that you should do it for free.
There is somebody, who would
pay me money immediately.
More then necessary.
However he demands...
well...
You can already imagine - this
price would be too high.
But I'm ready to pay it to you.
Now, before, afterwards...
Whenever.
I pass.
Always winning, Tigrero?
At the end your friends will sit
around only in their pyjamas.
But be careful - you could get a
pyjama yourself, but a wooden one.
In your dirty sector of business you
should be prepared for everything.
Every profession has its own
rules and its own risk.
And these rules will be
followed, understood?
Otherwise I'll stitch you
this wooden pyjamas.
You buy me a beer?
No, if I'm going to stay longer,
I'll have to puke.
- Let's go out then.
- OK.
- I start.
- I go with.
200.
- I raise to 300.
- I stay.
Good.
Me too.
I hold.
Once again.
How many cards?
Two, please.
Give me three.
Two for me.
Two cards.
One here.
200 dollars.
- I quit.
- Ditto.
300 and we'll play.
I pass.
Me too.
500 dollars.
Listen, mute, you hope, that
I draw first, am I right?
That's your method, I know that.
But not with me. You won't trick me.
If somebody is going to
draw first, it'll be you.
You can't count on me.
Far from it.
Because I don't want to take a risk...
Jack, take my belt off.
Actually I really think...
that today is a pleasure day for me.
Did I hurt you?
You're busted, Tigrero. Without
me you would have fired.
- You can't imprison me.
- Of course I can.
- And what if I pay the bailment?
- It's 100 dollars.
My money is on the poker table.
There are the 3000 Dollar from you.
It's not in your possession
anymore. It's confiscated.
Give me the money. 2000 are in for you.
Very good, an attempted bribe. That
rises the bailment to 5000 Dollar.
It bugs you, that I kill bandits.
You are doing exactly the same.
That's something different.
I do, what the law wants.
- And that means?
- That's no murder, but punishment.
The death of a bandit shouldn't be
a business, it should be a warning.
- Amen.
- Shut up!
Sheriff, here are Tigrero's things. And
this is the money, which was on the table.
Thank you. You are very mindful, Regine.
- You might... have a coffee with me?
- I'd be glad, let me pour some for you.
A man like you should always be
served by a woman like me.
You're really very kind.
It would be nice, if you could
serve me coffee sometimes.
Regine serves usually another customers.
With her curves she could please
a whole regiment of sheriffs.
Don't talk like that to a lady.
I'm so sorry!
I ask for an immediate
discharge of this man.
And why?
It's a wish from the citizens of Snow Hill.
These gentlemen are their representatives.
- And the bail money?
- I advance it.
The freedom of this man
means to you that much?
There are a lot of bandits in the mountains
waiting for a unconstitutional amnesty.
The bounty hunters defend us from them.
- That's my responsibility.
- But there's much more trouble.
Among the killed was Klaus Schulz.
His brother Bodo is the best
gunshooter in whole Nevada.
He won't find peace, until he took revenge.
In short, sheriff:
If you're not going to release
Tigrero, his friends will do,
and this all leads to...
a serious trouble.
That's what you're saying...
Listen to me everybody:
Nothing will happen.
These bandits, who you're so afraid of,
are just some hungry beggars.
Put a wagon with food outside
and they'll leave you alone.
And concerning Bodo Schulz...
If he wants to free Tigrero,
then from the jail in Tonota.
That's where I'll bring him.
Boss! The bandits are coming and
sheriff brings Tigrero away.
Our hero threatens us with the name
of Bodo Schulz. This is all idle talk.
Bodo can't even know, that
his brother was killed.
And the bandits?
They're on the way here.
That's useless tattle. Do what I tell
you and nothing bad will happen.
Put food on a wagon outside
on the city entrance.
Thus, whose stomachs are full
don't need to steal.
And you all stay in your homes, understood?
Let's go, forwards!
Unbelievable. Now we have to
appease criminals with bread.
When wuill justice and reason
return here again...
After you'll be hung.
Is this son of a bitch heavily wounded?
I think so. He must have
lost a lot of blood.
I hope he'll perish soon.
- Where is he now?
- In the negress's house.
We're coming forwards too slow.
Your silent friend can follow
us and kill me from behind.
The mute is wounded and he
wouldn't shoot in an ambush.
But I'm still worried. Let's
ride on the other bank.
Whatever. The main thing is,
that I'll deliver you in jail.
Look, sheriff.
The bandits! Take off
my handcuffs, quickly!
The cuffs stay.
These people are just hungry.
Smile, as if nothing has happened.
Goddamn murder!
Today my weapon is warm and as
much as you can see, it works well.
Listen to me, friends.
Soon the amnesty will come.
You all can go home then.
So don't make any trouble.
There is food waiting for you in the city.
Go to Snow Hill and fill your stomachs.
But spare our horses this time. They
might be very indigestible for you.
- Is the food really there?
- I give you my word.
Let's return, sheriff.
We'll wait and finish them
at the food wagon.
Apart from each other they aren't very valuable,
but taken altogether it's a good business.
Usually I don't beat up captives,
but if you keep going to talk like that,
you force me to change my mind.
This proposal came from the heart.
You saved my skin, so
I wanted to pay back.
Listen to me.
One more word, and I'll make it short!
My husband was a good man.
He was accused of theft, because
he tried to care for us.
Pollicut put the reward on his head.
He hoped, I'd become his lover.
But he was mistaken.
Pauline!
We collect food for the bandits
Everybody should contribute.
Can you spend something?
Let me see.
Good, but don't haste. And
best greets to Silence...
Just take everything...
People like you aren't needed anymore.
- Do you want to abolish bounty hunting?
- No, but the crimes.
Amerika has to be ruled by
justice, not by violence.
You know, sheriff...
What?
Your prophetic skill is
worth some applause.
As soon as you dangle on the
gallows, I am going to applaude.
- I have to take a short break.
- Whatfor?
I have to take a shit.
But the handcuffs...
Alright.
Thank you, sheriff.
Go... and hurry up.
I couldn't really hold it back anymore.
I don't want to wait long, got it?
- So, Tigrero - are you done?
- Please, excuse me.
We're very late.
I want to cross the ice before the
dark - don't like to travel at night.
I'll regain some time.
Hands up, sheriff!
Tigrero, stop the bullshit! For murder of
a sheriff you'll become a death sentence!
Only an idiot would! That's why
you'll end under this ice,
and I'm going to continue to follow
the good, old rule of the strongest.
Easy, friends. Since when
wolfes eat each other?
Hey, Tigrero! Who put you on a chain?
The most likeable sheriff of this region.
Come, release me.
Ah yes... the sheriff of Snow Hill.
A dirty braggart.
That's, what he was. Now
he isn't dirty anymore.
I made him a nice bath - he didn't
came up to the surface anymore.
He couldn't swim. May
his soul rest in peace.
Now we are the law in Snow Hill.
We can work in peace again.
I know of a roaring trade,
which is completely legal.
I encountered the bandites.
They're on their way to the city.
That'd be enough to surprise them,
and we'll become all at once.
And somebody waits for us in Snow Hill...
somebody you'd love to kill:
the mute,
who likes to shoot away thumbs.
If there's a dead sheriff behind
this game, I prefer to hold off.
Dtd you already know, that
the mute shot your brother?
Klaus?
He didn't even... had enough
time to defend himself.
Come with me.
No!
Leave me alone!
Coward!
No!
Look at this hand!
Do you remember?
It used to be a normal hand. Now
it can't use a gun anymore.
But for what I have planned,
I won't need a gun.
No! Help!
Help!
My darling!
Pauline!
Tigrero came to the city
with five other men.
They're looking for Silence.
Have you herad? You must flee!
Bring yourself to a safe place!
If they'll find you, they'll kill you.
But he's wounded. He can't move well.
- We've got to hide him.
- I beseech you, help me!
Tigrero!
The mute killed Pollicut.
He's in negress's house.
Go there and kill him.
Take revenge.
Stand still, Tigrero!
One more step and I shoot!
Throw away the gun, bitch, or I'll
send you after your sheriff.
Sleazy coward, you killed him!
Have you seen, she shot first.
Search for the mute - he can't be far.
Come on, do it! You have to find him.
Not one soul is here.
Here neither.
We searched everything - the house is empty.
We're gonna find him.
The bandits are close!
Not far away from the city.
Let's go then! We'll deal
with the mute later!
I'm going to try to warn those
people, before they'll be trapped.
You stay here hiding.
Come on, friends! The food is
there, sheriff told the truth.
Don't shoot!
If we want the mute, we'll need them alive.
Give up! You're surrounded!
Throw the weapons away,
or we'll kill you all!
Come on, move ya!
Quickly!
All men down! Back to the counter!
I want, that Silence comes...
for a payoff.
If he'll succeed to kill me...
you're all free.
My friends agreed.
My life for lifes of all others.
Tell him that! You know, where he is.
I came too late.
I tried, but... Tigrero has
already overwhelmed them.
They're still alive, but
bound like animals.
When I was returning, Tigrero caught up with me.
He said, if you won't come for a
pay off, he'll kill the hostages.
But...
you shouldn't go there.
It's surely a trap.
You're wounded and they are six men.
Alone you're powerless...
against the violence.
Let's flee, move away together.
I don't want them to kill you, I love you.
Come on, what are you waiting for?
Let's finish the things up.
Kill us all. Silence won't come anyway.
Kill us, murderer!
He is here.
No!
You coward!
No, have mercy!
We don't want to die!
We have to gain our bounty money.
We'll collect it later.
Everything like law says.