Jeremiah !
Jeremiah Pit !
Hello Sir Captain!
Do you need anything?
What do you mean "sir captain"?
What do you want to say with that?
You don't recognize me? I am..
Yes... sure...
We have met at "El Passo",
7-8 years ago if I'm not wrong.
The time is passing and there are
so many things happening.
People can not remember everything.
Do you want to drink something sir captain?
Where are you going?
To the South.
Is there any village nearby where
I can spend the night?
There is Mimbres, less than
an hour from here.
But there are no hotels
for one like you sir.
Mimbres...
I have met someone who
stayed at Mimbres.
I think his name is Brown.
Montgomery Brown.
But he is called Ringo.
Do you know him?
Montgomery Brown.
Of course I know him!
But he is not back sir captain!
He went to the war and never came back!
Who knows what happened to him?
He has not returned yet?
If I am not wrong, he was married.
Maybe the wife would love...
...to talk to someone who has
met her husband.
Who knows, maybe she will permit me to
stay over night at her house.
As long as there are no hotels
in Mimbres.
Brown's wife's name is Hally,
isn't it?
Who are they?
Why they wanted to kill me?
They are Paco Fuentes's men.
He and his brothers came to Mimbres
since they discovered gold in the lake.
They say it is Mexican land and
no one wants to contradict them.
What happened to Hally?
Peace!
I need your herbs to cure
a friend of mine.
You said you need it for a friend.
It is not allowed to enter with dogs,
Americans or beggers.
There's a man on the street.
He might need help.
He doesn't need help.
- He needs a mortician (corpse puller).
Hey, you! Where are you coming from?
- An Indian? From the mountains sir!
Are you looking for a job?
Not today, today I have eaten.
What are you, an American,
Indian or Mexican ?
How could he know?
So many people entered his house,
even his mother doesn't know what he is!
Welcome to Mimbers, my friend!
What kind of work do you want, my friend?
To have enough to live but
not to get too tired.
Then go to Fuentes.
They are in Brown's house.
Now they are the owners.
They command now.
If you know how to kill,
they will hire you at once.
But I don't know how to shoot Sheriff!
- Then learn!
You must learn to handle a gun if
you want to survive here!
Just an advise you need to remember!
But you have lived long,
even without a gun!
My case is totally different,
I am not a Mexican.
I am an American, an inferior race.
And we, the inferior races,
we can survive even if we have no gun.
What are you looking for?
Some job.
The Sherriff told me to ask
the Fuentes' brothers.
Ask for a job?
You changed your mind so fast?
No, I did not change my mind...
I just got hungry!
So you are hungry?
Eat then!
Eat, eat!
Hey Hobo! Go now!
I want to see no Hobo here!
My name is "do not forget me"
or Myossothis, for friends.
Last night I thought they will die
so I kept a watch on them all night.
Now they are ok.
Do you like flowers?
I have created this species.
Brown roses.
It's the name of the masters from Mimbres...
once upon a time.
I owe them everything,
and Mrs Hally let me take care of them.
Are you passing by here?
Yes, but will stay for a little while.
Just for a little while?
At Mimbres?
You like flowers and you walk in
Mimbers without a pistol?
I think you are crazy.
Where do you want to stay?
You can help me if I don't find
something else.
There's nothing good at Mimbres.
You could help me. There's always something to do.
You remind me of someone…
This is what happen with strangers.
They always looking like someone but
no one looks like them.
Look at these flowers! I can't leave them for
two minutes, they start to lay down.
They need company
I will tell you a story...
Good bye!
Hello sir Myosothis !
Hello, Rosita !
Look, your rose awaits you!
What a nice man!
Who are you?
I have never seen you before.
I'm Myosothis'  cousin...
I came this morning.
A distant relative...
Come visit me.
I'd like to foretell your future.
I'll tell about the beautiful present you live in and
I will tell you about your future too.
What do you want more from life?
Now I know who you remind me of!
My uncle, Alfonso.
You look familiar...
- You mean what, we're relatives?
Come on in! I'll explain to you later.
- Excuse me!
I am sorry, but I have to make
a nice funeral crown.
For the judge that they killed.
Someone has to remember him.
Good night!
Help me! I need to make a nice funeral crown
for an important man.
He was killed by people
who wanted to be important.
Ok boss!
I'll forgive your sins in the name of
Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Bravo !
But you haven't written anything on the crown.
Put it there.
May God be with you
Don't go anywhere!
That's it!
I know you have found a job.
I told you about the Fuentes brothers, but
you chose to be Myosothis' slave.
You can't tell you have a lot of imagination.
I'm new in this town and
I could make a mistake.
Nobody likes to die, Sherriff.
But one who is afraid of death
could die little by little many times.
And one who is not afraid of death,
dies only once.
I'm not armed!
You can't shoot at a man who doesen't have a gun.
How does the story begin?
Somebody found gold in the river.
Then everybody came to know.
You know how it is when it is about gold.
Men are coming from far away,
These men have come from Mexico.
Anyway it is near.
Why nobody told nothing?
Because they are scared. Don't you know what fear is?
Of course! they are scared.
That's it for now.
But before the Mexicans came,
why no one fought back?
Who knows?
All the young men were at the war.
The war is over and no one's back yet
not even the people who announced it.
They're waiting at the entry point of
the village to kill them one by one .
Only the old people were at Mimbres
and only a few of them could fight back.
The first it was the senator Brown
and the last one was the judge Barnes.
You've seen how they all ended up.
They killed senator Brown?
They said he died of heart attack.
But you are always hurt when you have
a bullet in your heart.
Poor senator...
At least his son would have come back.
Maybe it's better he had not returned.
Maybe it's better this way.
Why do you say so?
He was married, and its better for a
a husband, not to see some things.
Good night!
My dear, I told you not to get far
from the carriage.
Yes, mama.
No body offers to drink?
Don't you want to make love?
It is an offer...
If a man doesen't want to make love,
It means that either he has just
made it or he is in love.
Let's see…
Let's see, who you are in love with.
The cards never lie.
They are not like men.
Esteban, that man has insulted me.
Estaban, wait!
What do you want to do with a dead man?
If you kill him,
we cannot have fun anymore.
A man can be killed only once.
But you can have fun with him everyday.
The Sherriff helped me bring you here.
Myosothis would have got a heart attack
if he had seen you like this.
You are a strange man. Esteban almost killed you,
but you were not afraid.
You were not scared at all.
I don't like people who don't get scared.
You are not scared, you get kicked
and you wear a gun under the shirt.
I'd like to fortell your future.
Your gun is in the drawer.
You can take it if you want to.
Sleep here, take the gun in the morning.
Need not make love if you don't want to.
Finally, I see you again!
Where the hell you slept last night?
In a drain? Why?
I'll explain you later.
But that dead man?
Who is that dead man?
Don't you know? He is Montgomery Brown.
He is Ringo. The senator's son. He is back.
Ok. move it.
We have work to do.
Paco Fuentes wants many flowers
for the funeral!
Captain, Montgomery Brown
died for his country.
Montgomery Brown is dead.
It is over now with him.
He may rest in peace,
as we may live.
As the gospel said, we burn in land
and in land we return.
Thank you Myosothis!
These are wonderful flowers.
I'm glad that you like them, my dear!
I'm happy with you and Myosothis.
You've done a good job.
You and your assistance may stay
for the party at the villa tonight.
Father, I need you.
I want you to marry us this Sunday.
Poor captain Brown couldn't be
saved from death.
We have no reason to delay the wedding.
we've waited long enough.
Isn't it, my dear?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
7, 8, 9, 10 and 11.
Who are you?
And what are you doing here?
Hally!
Hally, where are you?
The guests want to see you my dear,
and I want you to stand next to me.
I can't stay away from you.
Let's go.
Paco did you send somebody to the office?
To the office? No!
Maybe he is a curious guest!
I don't like curious people!
Let's see!
If I were in your shoes,
I would not run away.
Wait, my friend!
Look what our gardener does!
You decided to get rich so fast?
Once they used to cut right hand of the thieves.
We have to respect the old traditions.
But today it's a holy day so I've
decided to forgive you.
Welcome to my house!
I want to sort flowers for the church...
...it is Sunday after 3 days.
Is he in the house?
Of course, he is in the house!
What's my daughter's name?
- Elizabeth, as your mother's name.
I had to leave her home,
I am allowed to get away with her.
You have to take her tonight, I'll wait for you
with the horses at the cemetery.
Before they realize that you are gone,
we will be already far from here.
You want to run away?
All that I've had for all these years,
was it unseless?
Useless?
Why?
You've waited for me.
We can live together again.
Everybody in the village has waited,
they all have to live again too.
They are dead already.
The fear has killed them.
That's not true. They are not dead.
They will die if you abandoned them.
Listen Hally, count the mexicans. How many are there?
How many are in the house?
What can I do about myself?
Look! What they have done to me?
You never ever asked me this whole time,
if between me and Paco… ?
What does it matter?
- It matters to me!
I want you to know...
Now you know!
You said at the cemetery?
Tonight?
Not tonight.
First I have to get myself prepared.
Myosothis will tell you when?
You came to see me,
or get your future told?
How many questions for a fortune teller…
Past or future?
- I know my past.
How ironic! How things can change
in just couple of days.
Has my future changed?
- No, you have changed!
A man who has no fear, has no hope.
One who hopes, can hope an interesting tomorrow.
Who has hope, has fear too. See?
Now you are scared.
Just a moment please!
I have not told you your future yet.
- It doesent matter, I know it already.
I've earned some money these days and
I would like to earn some more.
It didn't go so well for you, grand father.
No shit!
You've cheated!
Excuse me?
I can see very clearly.
You are a damn cheater!
Have I heard well grand father?
-You heard very well!
If this two men weren't cheaters and thieves as
you are, they would confess...
Why don't you arrest them, Sheriff?
Its not allowed to cheat in this village.
You represent the inferiors here.
But perhaps this means nothing
to a person like you.
Isn't it Carson?
I got it!
You want me to take care of this.
In the name of our Sheriff, the inferior,
I will arrest you!
See Sheriff, its not that difficult,
you only need to want this!
I can help you if you want them
to be put in jail.
Who are you?
I'll explain this later Sheriff.
Montgomery Brown...
Esteban will not come tonight.
Will you stay?
The Sheriff has arrested him.
He cheated with cards and
the Sheriff  has put him in jail.
Myosothis helped him.
When Paco will find out, he will take care of
the Sheriff and Myosothis.
He need not know that.
Tell Juan and someone from the group.
It will be enough for them to be there and
convince the Sheriff to let them go.
It won't be so hard for you to convince
Esteban to get over this.
Poor Sheriff and poor Myosothis!
I wouldn't like if anything bad
happens to them.
When Paco Fuentes finds out about it...
- he will take a revenge.
You will have to take care if
you don't want to be killed.
Do you have any idea how many
brothers Fuentes have?
I will repost ,very well!
- And you must repost as well.
Very good! Who is the 3rd one, Myosothis?
Ok, he will repost as well. So what?
This is crazy.
I know!
What are you looking for?
Dynamite!
You have it?
It belongs to judge Barnes,
isn't it?
You need to change the atmosphere
in this office, Sherriff.
Sheriff, come, come out!
What a bravery, Sheriff!
I pray that Esteban won't get
mad at you.
Let him be free now.
- I'm sorry for you.
There's nothing more to do, my friends.
Esteban will stay in the jail till
the judgement day. Is it clear?
We have to to burry them.
- Not now, Myosothis, later on.
But…
- I'll explain it to you later.
What are you doing?
What's that?
Dynamite!
Wait!
With your permission, let me give you my
regards to you for the wedding.
The church is ready, and this is
for decorating the house.
Take care of your friend,
don't steal anything.
Oh, I forgot…
Esteban and the others will stay in the village.
They will organise a party for you.
Let's hurry up!
We wil have them at the door.
Flowers at the entrance will
always make you feel good.
We will put others inside.
Im sorry sir Paco…!
It's about the whole family.
It's a delicate case.
If you want, we can cancel
the ceremony till tomorrow.
I don't cancel anything!
Don't move from here, ok?
You promise me. Please…Ok!
Hello!
Hey You! What are you doing with that cartridge box?
We are here to celebrate
Sir Francisco Fuentes's wedding.
Our noble bracing.
With Hally Fitzgerald, the widow of
captain Montgomery Brown.
Esteban !
Rosita, finally!
Get us out of here!
Francisco Fuentes, do you take Hally Fitzgerald
to be your wife?
As per the norms of Romano-Catholic church?
Yes.
Hally Fitzgerald, do you want to take
Francisco Fuentes to be your husband?
As per the norms of Romano-Catholic church?
Elizabeth is waiting for you, my dear.
I pronounce you now man and wife…
I am back, Paco Fuentes!
I am back!
The horses!
They are gone!
Hally !
Why did you do that?
You didn't have to… you promised me that… !
Let's go!
He died only because of me.
We all can be wrong. We all can be...
You don't have to be scared any more.
Now you can choose.
You can fight to live or to die.
What can we do?
Take the guns and I'll let you know.
Hello!
Hi!
Move it!
Come!
Let's go upstair!
Ok, sir!
Don't call me sir,
call me dad.
What do you mean father?
Elizabeth will let you know later on.
Ok, dad!
May I help you, dad?
Nice shot dad!
Play with this now,
and stay hiding.
Whatever happens, just don't move!
Sure dad, otherwise they will catch me
and then you can't do nothing.
Am I right?
- Subtitles by AMIRA - (just an affort)
www.myspace.com/amira76