New Mexico
And that's why I tell you
to stay out of New Mexico.
And there ain't
no law but this.
Show him in.
and his help would be
invaluable to us.
I hoped you'd
say that, Steele.
Certainly.
So they're sending
another deputy, eh.
Boys, here's
to the big herd.
Hyah, hyah, hyah, hyah
There's
a man following us.
He ain't a-followin' us now.
Hyah, ho, ho!
Sounds like cows.
Ho, ho! It's Arizona.
Hyah, hyah, hyah!
Hey, fellas.
Shh, don't let on, now.
Well, boss, I got over
200 head this time.
in that fool country.
Come on, Lem.
gonna get any practice
Oh.
He's been around here
drunk for two days.
Well, come on,
let's drink up.
Everybody okay?
Aw, get out!
Look!
Well, where'd that come from
Might have knowed
he'd show up today.
Buenos dias, amigos!
Ha, ha.
The great cattle baron.
Hey, senor.
Somebody's going
to get very rich.
Ha.
Is everybody all right?
You had a pretty hard trip,
didn't you?
Yeah.
Here comes
Mr. Crew now.
How are you?
with rustlers,
renegades and bad men.
Pleasure, Miss Malloy.
How do you do?
Lay off of that kid!
So long, pardner.
Goodbye, miss.
Get out of here.
All right, Cal,
that road straight ahead, huh?
Ow!
I like your spirit
Thanks.
Aha.
and I wouldn't be
caught nappin'.
Well, that's mig
hty fine of you, Mr. Steele.
Everything's just fine.
My, isn't this
a lovely view from here.
Pat!
If I get my hands on you...
I'll see you tonight.
Wait.
What's that?
Oh!
Brett!
It's Arizona!
Get him back
Come on.
Get some water, quick.
Get some water.
Come on, let's get
out of here.
John, look! Cattle rustlers!
Duke!
Get up.
Cattle.
Round'em up.
Stick it up, boys.
Get out of here!
Hyah!
Vamos, amigos.
Aw, don't worry.
We'll catch him.
Boy, I'm sure hungry.
Shh!
Afraid you'd be
late for breakfast.
Stand up.
Who the devil are you?
and I figured you in
on the deal.
and I'm counting
on your help.
Get back against that wall
I'm arrestin' Arizona
for the murder of Cal Brett.
Set'em up here, bartender.
Here comes the deputy now.
John Steele.
Aw, come on,
let's have another drink here.
What's that?
Hey, hey.
Hm.
Aw.
Ahhh.
Duke, Duke, the door!
What's that?
Not a soul in sight.
It just an accident.
It's 9:00.
I'll show you.
Stick'em up, Arizona.
Turn around.
All right, get going.
Get a move on.
you'll never get out of
here alive with Arizona.
Just a minute.
What?
all of you
In the name of the law
Now, get in that cell.
Let's get out of
this rat's nest here.
Come on. Let's get out of here
Keep it up, boys.
They're retreating.
Mr. Crew
ain't fooling meany.
get the boss.
Hey, come on, boy. Come on
Yee-hoo!
Give it to'em, Bossy boy.
Hurry up, boys.
I hope he ain't hurt?
Where's Arizona?
I'll be meetin' up with
him before long.
Get on that horse.
There you are.
That's fine,sir. Hmm.
Say, pardner,
I wanna talk to you.
Let me go!
Sonora!
for spoiling
the big romance.
Let's see.
Where were you
Right where I never
should have been interrupted.
Hey, John!
Pardon me.
Thank you.
I wonder if we'll
get a good price
Round up every gunman
in the valley.
Well, major, good
to hear this talk.
See you all
at the fort, I hope.
They wake me up
in the middle of the night...
I'll see he don't get away.
Once more, boys. Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Whoa. Whoa.
Vamos!
Giddyap, buddy.
Where's Ginger?
Giddyap, Mike, giddyap.
Are you all right?
Hello, darling.
Bring'em up the hill.
Get those buzzards!
They're turning the herd.
Come on.
Madre de dios.
Put them in the mill.
Turn the herd.
Hoo-ha!
They're coming around, boys.
They got them in the mill.
They saved'em.
Aww, that's too far.
Giddyap.