[Child screaming]
No, Papa! Please!
I didn't mean to!
[Boy screaming]
No, Papa!
Papa, please!
I've told you not to strip
the fruit off the trees.
You're going to kill every tree!
I won't ever do it again!
I'm sorry!
- Did I say you could go?
- No, Papa!
[Boy screaming]
Papa, I didn't mean to!
Papa, no more!
Please, Papa!
WOMAN: Harge!
Don't you think
the boy's had enough?
I just can't beat
any sense into that boy.
Kalig, run along.
I want to talk to your pa.
[Door slams]
Harge, he's only a boy.
At his age, I was working,
drawing a man's wage.
There's time enough to grow up.
You're too easy on him.
You put fancy ideas
in his head with them books.
[Cough]
Don't you want him
to be educated?
I got nothing against learning!
Long as he pulls his share
of the work.
A man needs sons
to work a farm, even stepsons.
Kalig tries to be
a good son to you.
You don't give him a chance.
You're always defending the boy.
His father died
when he was so young.
You're the only father
he's ever known.
Must you always think
of Kalig as a stepson?
Calls you papa.
You're carrying
the only son I have.
Don't start thinking that.
May be a girl.
Nope! It's a boy.
We don't have nothing
but boys in my family.
What if the baby's a girl?
It better not be.
I think it would be nice.
We could call her Ethel May,
after your mother!
Stop saying such things!
Make up your mind
it is not going to be a girl.
It's going to be a boy.
We'll name him Harge after me.
It ain't right if a man's
first child ain't a boy...
to carry on his name.
Harge...
wish you weren't so stubborn.
[Coughing]
There's plenty of time
for more children.
Don't let me catch you in
the night air with that cough.
[Coughing]
See that Kalig picks the bugs
off the potato vines...
before I get back.
[Coughing]
Kalig!
Come on in.
[Coughing]
[Woman coughing]
Kalig, are you all right?
Sure, Mama, I'm all right.
OK. You mustn't mind
your stepfather.
He just doesn't understand us.
We're different, me and you.
But we understand each other.
That's all that matters.
Yes, Mama.
Regardless of what happens,
you're my son...
and you come to me.
I love you.
I love you more than anything or
any person in this whole world.
You must never forget that.
Will you love the baby
more than me?
How could that be possible?
[Thunder]
- How about some coffee?
- Yep. Yeah, I could use a cup.
OLDER MAN:
Harge, I got bad news for you.
- Did she lose the baby?
- No, Harge.
HARGE: Sarah Ann... you said...
OLDER MAN: I know.
OLDER MAN:
There have been complications.
HARGE: I don't understand.
Sit down, Harge.
[Thunder]
I've done everything I could.
I thought I could
save them both, but I can't.
Sarah Ann or the baby.
And if I say Sarah Ann, Doc?
Well, it won't be for long,
maybe a month, even a year.
Then you'll be alone...
except for Kalig.
I'm sure not
looking forward to that.
I don't know how I'm going to
handle him with his mama gone.
There's a mean streak
in that boy.
What's it going to be, Harge?
I don't have any choice, do I?
I'll hear you say it.
[Thunder]
Save the baby.
Don't you kill my mama! No!
HARGE: Kalig!
KALIG: Don't you kill my mama!
Kalig, it ain't no use.
She don't know anybody.
You stay here with your pa.
Please don't let him
kill my mama.
You listen to me.
Your mama is a sick woman.
If we don't save the baby,
they're both going to die.
I heard you tell the doctor
to let my mama die!
It ain't that way at all.
You know the cough
your mama's got.
It's real bad. There ain't
nothing the doc or me can do.
She'd worry about you
and me and the baby.
It ain't true!
You just want the baby!
You got to believe
I'm doing the right thing.
I hate you!
Your mama wouldn't like
to hear you say that.
I hate you,
and I hate the baby, too.
I've had enough. You shut up.
Start acting like a man,
or I'll take a strap to you.
I hate you.
I hate the baby.
Yes, I hate the baby.
I hope it dies.
Yes, I hope it dies.
[Baby crying]
[Thunder]
Mama!
Oh, no!
[Bell tolling]
[Door opens]
I thought you were
plowing the field.
This is the way you repay me.
I should never
have taken you in.
I wasn't going to
take it, Papa. Honest.
[Baby crying]
I'll have to straighten
you out before it's too late,
or you'll be
a bad influence on Harge.
I only wanted to
count it, Papa. Honest.
You ain't ever going to learn.
Let's get it over with.
I'm going to give you a licking
you'll never forget.
Not again, Papa!
Put the can back.
Get up and take it like a man.
Put the money back!
[Baby crying]
WOMAN: Kalig.
WOMAN: What have we here?
Found Papa in the kitchen, dead.
Dead!
Your papa dead?
Kalig, that's not possible.
He's dead, all right,
Aunt Myrtle.
What happened?
Did he have an accident?
No, ma'am. Wasn't no accident.
What do you mean, Kalig?
Someone shot him.
Someone shot him?!
Who would want
to shoot your papa?
The poor baby!
I don't know, ma'am,
but someone sure did.
It just doesn't make any sense.
Why would anyone want
to shoot your papa?
To steal his money.
All Papa's savings were gone.
Are you sure?
Yes, ma'am.
I looked in Papa's hiding place.
There wasn't nothing in it
but an empty can.
Did you see anyone
or hear anything at your place?
I didn't stay to look.
I picked up Harge,
and I got out of there as fast
as I could get my things.
Well, you did the right thing.
I'll fix you a bite to eat.
When your uncle gets home,
we'll send for the sheriff.
Thank you, ma'am,
but I ain't hungry.
It's enough for you
to take care of Harge.
Old man Anderson
offered me a job last week.
With both my mama
and my papa dead...
I could take care of myself.
Your ma would be proud to hear
you talking like that.
Mama would understand.
If it doesn't work out
with Mr. Anderson,
you know that my sister's boy's
always welcome here.
I'll remember that.
Tell Uncle Calvin not to worry
about the funeral expenses.
I'll take care of it
out of my pay.
Take the spyglass.
You always wanted one.
Your uncle and I never use it.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Thank you very much.
You're very nice.
It will bring you luck.
MYRTLE, VOICE-OVER:
The spyglass was his companion.
He was never without it.
MAN: Kalig!
They're on their way!
Kalig! The rest of Harge's men
are coming from the north.
MYRTLE, VOICE-OVER:
The Andersons,
taken in by Kalig's deception,
treated him like a son.
And Harge?
He grew up idolizing Kalig.
They were close.
Kalig took good care of Harge.
But later, Kalig entered
upon a career of crime,
taking Harge,
still a child, with him.
Always the memory of his mother
preyed upon Kalig's mind.
As Harge grew into manhood,
he organized his own gang...
during one of the many periods
Kalig was in prison.
It is my belief that during
those intervals of imprisonment,
Kalig began to brood
and nurse his revenge...
until he became obsessed with
making Harge suffer...
and pay for
their mother's death.
Although it became
apparent to others,
Harge was unable to see
Kalig for what he was:
A demented man enjoying
cruelty and destruction.
Enough of this! Get back!
Hold it!
Open it up!
Faster! Faster!
MAN: Harge, we're leaving.
MAN: Let's go!
- Harge, let's go.
- Let's get out of here.
Let's go!
Harge, it's our only chance.
Come on! Yah!
[Gunfire]
[Thunder]
WOMAN: Harge! Harge!
Harge...
The room is empty without you.
HARGE: Soon you won't need
your husband to fill this room.
I will always need you.
When you have that
little one in your arms...
and he's squalling and kicking,
you'll soon forget about me.
- That little one takes his time.
- You're his mother.
Tell him to hurry up.
Why is Harge making
such a fuss over this baby?
Babies born out here every day.
You don't know
what's bothering him?
The baby, of course.
It's not the baby. It's Eva.
I thought everybody knew.
Harge never got over killing
his mama when he was born.
What will you do about the man?
I'll do what I have to do.
If you kill this man,
maybe I will die, too...
and maybe the child.
You're talking crazy.
It is what I think.
Please do not kill him.
Let him live.
You have no proof...
only Kalig's word that this
is the man who betrayed you...
on that bank job.
Inside of me, there is life.
For the first time, I see
that it is different with you.
I see you carry death.
It won't be for long.
You do not listen to me.
Even now.
But you listen to Kalig.
You know he's ruthless,
but, oh, no...
Kalig was good to you
as a child.
He helped raise and support you,
so he can do no wrong.
Eva...
Long before I met you...
there was something that
mattered to me very much...
even more than staying alive.
That was my brother.
He was a big part of me.
Just like you.
I can't understand why you won't
see Kalig as he is.
What kind of man...
would take his nine-year-old
brother on a robbery?
It is natural to want a
better life for those you love.
My mother used to say that.
Your mother said
lots of things.
- I got some rough news for you.
- Well?
You know Kalig rode into town
yesterday?
Yeah, I heard. Great Kalig,
the big brain.
MAN: Well, he's boiling over
with a plan he wants to pull.
It's something real big.
He just needs a troop.
Where's he gonna get a troop?
He's a Ioner.
MAN: I told you there's nothing
to worry about.
Mr. Kalig don't leave
nothing to chance.
He's got the whole thing planned
down to a gnat's eyebrow.
Yo, Mungo! Cord! Keep your
hands away from your guns.
You think I was gonna
let you ditch me for Kalig?
You tell Kalig
to go take a jump...
[Gunshot]
Kalig!
One bullet solved
the problem of Sharkey.
Anybody else got a problem?
KALIG: The long, shrill cry
of the criminal will not stop...
till all humanity realizes that
viciousness is only for animals.
How's that?
MAN: I told you
Kalig thinks of everything.
He's a pretty smart man.
Did you know he studied law?
[Train whistle blows]
All right, get started.
[Gunshots]
[Gunshot]
EVA: Don't worry, Harge.
I'm not going to die.
[Moans]
Wish I could do something
to make it easier for you.
The men tell me
Kalig has come here.
Eva, you keep getting into
my territory.
Despite what you say, l...
I distrust Kalig.
I fear him, what he may do.
MAN: How long before Harge
gets rid of the Virginian?
The Virginian's no one
to tangle with.
That's Judge Garth.
He'll be lucky to take him.
The Virginian's riding with him
like a bodyguard.
The longer we wait,
the tougher it will be.
I didn't come along
to play with a spyglass.
It keeps us from
jumping in blind.
- When do we jump?
- When I say the time is right.
If you don't like it,
shut up or get out.
[Train whistle blows]
[Laughing]
Kind of a warm feeling, huh?
I have something to tell you.
- Where's the doctor?
- Out of town. Harge...
- Till when?
- Three, four days, maybe a week.
- Eva can't wait that long.
- Kids are born every day.
- Not my kid.
- I saw someone in Isleta.
- Who?
- The man you been looking for.
So he is. Kalig was right.
- You sure?
- It was him. I'm positive.
Well, get him!
- Harge?
- You bring him here to me.
Take Doud and Bassett.
- You should be resting.
- You must eat.
- How do you feel?
- Well, mi hijo.
Eva, there's not going to be
any doctor.
I can manage.
You're a good wife, Eva.
Sit down.
- What's for supper?
- Chilis rellenos.
I saw the men ride out.
It's not your brother Kalig
again, is it?
Something for me.
To seek revenge
on the Virginian, that's why.
What I do, I do, and I told you
that when I married you.
Kalig could be wrong. What if
the Virginian didn't set you up?
- Soon, huh?
- Very soon.
- I'm sorry about the doctor.
- It is all right.
Hey, what's that?
Feels like a fist.
By golly, I think it is a fist.
Feel it. It is a fist.
I can feel it.
He punches like a boy.
You want that, don't you?
I want... whatever you have.
Yes. But you hope for a boy.
How do you know?
A wife knows.
[Muffled yelling]
Whiskey.
VIRGINIAN: Didn't I
used to know you?
MAN: That's right.
San Antonio, wasn't it?
Six, seven years ago?
- Something like that.
- Let me buy you a drink.
MAN: Thank you.
I'm gonna be out back
if you have any other questions.
Where'd you get this?
Girl I met gave it to me.
Where is she?
I'll tell you the whole story...
where she is, why,
and what you got to do.
VIRGINIAN: I'm waiting.
MAN: I should mention...
anything happens to me,
it won't be good
for your boss' girl.
Not good at all.
[Man moaning]
MAN:
You all right, little lady?
[Woman struggling]
WOMAN: Where am I?
Why am I here?
I sent you after a man.
When you go fishing, you can't
always catch what you want.
The line's out,
and the hook's ready.
You're looking at the live bait.
MAN: She's Garth's daughter.
WOMAN: What do you want?
Answer me. Who are you?
HARGE: Let her go.
Now, get in there with my wife.
If she needs anything,
you help her.
She can't do this alone,
and you're a woman.
You go and help her.
MAN: No sign of Doud.
OTHER MAN:
Bassett rode out to look.
DOCTOR: Harge,
I got bad news for you.
Sarah Ann... or the baby.
HARGE, SR: Save the baby.
KALIG: Don't you kill my ma!
Don't you kill my mama!
[Slap]
- Oh, I'm so glad to see you!
- You all right?
- Yes.
- Sure worried about you.
They won't tell me anything.
Why I'm here...
VIRGINIAN: It's because of me.
You caused her a lot of trouble.
You want to see me, just ask.
- Why do they want to see you?
- I'd like to know that.
Well, Harge?
I expect I'm entitled.
You'll get
what you're entitled to.
Inside.
HARGE: I gave you a job.
I'm staying here
till I find out what's going on.
EVA: It's between them.
Just sit down there.
What's this about, Harge?
DOUD: Don't waste time.
Let's get it over with.
HARGE: Take it easy.
You recognize any of these boys?
Keeler, Bassett, Doud...
and this is Preble.
We rode herd for a living.
Dollar a day and saddle sores.
We had a rough season that year.
Long hours, short pay.
You remember talking to me
about the bank in San Antonio?
I told you we were gonna rob it.
I even told you when.
I asked you to join us,
but you'd already signed up
for a cattle drive...
and were leaving the next day.
I remember I also tried
to talk you out of it.
I thought I had.
That's the last I saw you.
The next day we hit that bank...
round about closing time.
And they were waiting for us.
The sheriff and a dozen men.
Keeler and I got shot.
The rest got killed.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Shotguns ready, and they were
just sitting there waiting.
Somebody told them
we were coming.
That's you.
You're wrong. I never told
anyone about your plan.
MAN: He's had his hearing.
What are you waiting for?
Put him in the shed.
- Know what you're doing?
- He'll keep.
What's wrong with right now?
I got a wife and kid at stake.
I need that girl.
I need her help.
I'm making sure I get it.
You'll get it.
BASSETT: Keep him alive,
she'll take care of Eva.
He's gonna wait for the baby
and then kill him.
Just like that.
You can't let
your husband kill him.
Won't you even try to stop him?
It is not up to me.
It's my husband's business.
All right, get them started.
Kalig?
GARTH: Kalig?
I sentenced you to 10 years.
I only served three months.
Why don't you write that note?
Answer's still the same.
Just creased him.
The next one's
gonna shatter the bone.
LIZ: Does that help?
EVA: Yes.
HARGE: Wish I could
make it easier for you.
HARGE: What happened?
VIRGINIAN: I had some visitors.
Which one did it?
Not important.
What is important
is what you're going to do.
We've been over that ground
once and for all.
If it's that final,
what can I do for you?
I need someone to talk to.
Talk to your boys.
Because I'm worried
about my wife and son.
The boys... some things
they don't understand about.
Maybe you ought to be more
careful who you ride with.
We were friends.
You and me.
No matter what you believe,
I didn't tell that sheriff.
Let me finish.
Help you to pass the time.
Think back, Harge.
Think back seven years.
One of your own men tipped off
that sheriff.
Now, why would a member
of your gang do that?
The obvious answer is money.
Sheriff must have paid
for that information.
Not much, but something.
Who would chose a few safe
dollars from the sheriff...
rather than the couple thousand
he'd get for robbing the bank?
You know your men, Harge.
Think it over.
[Baby crying]
Isn't he beautiful?
EVA: Boys are not beautiful.
HARGE: This one is.
If you say so, Harge.
So, that's how it is?
If it were not for Elizabeth,
you would not be holding him.
Here. You get some sleep.
You must be tired.
You go rest.
At sunup, I'll take you back.
I won't go alone.
You know that, don't you?
You don't have a choice.
Then you'll kill him?
You think that excuses it...
waiting till I've gone?
HARGE: Thanks for what you did.
To Harge II.
To Harge III.
To both.
Well, uh...
It's none of my business.
If you're gonna do something,
you ought to do it.
You like to get on
with things, don't you?
I like to get 'em
out of the way.
What would you do if you had
more than one thing...
to take care of at a time?
- I'd take 'em one by one.
- In what order?
- First things first.
- Well...
That's what I do.
How do you do it, hmm?
How do you get drunk
so fast, huh?
I'm breaking out my last bottle.
That look like I'm holding out?
That's far enough. Let's go.
- Harge!
- Two horses missing.
He's gone.
He's got Keeler's gun.
Bassett, get the horses.
Doud, take care of them.
Yahee!
GARTH, VOICE-OVER:
Follow instructions.
Don't let the law
suspect your part.
Proof of my well-being
will be tendered before payment.
Lose no time taking my letter
of authorization to the bank.
Judge Henry Garth.
MAN: Who gave you this?
Oh, uh... I think
I better go along with you.
The judge doesn't
want it that way.
Now, the only way I'm going
to turn over $100,000 in cash...
is to make sure he gets it.
There's the receipt.
Here's your man, Harge.
[Gunfire]
We'll go around.
[Gunshot]
That's far enough, Harge.
Hold it right there.
I'm going to take you with me.
I hear you got a son now, Harge.
He won't care if I'm dead.
He'll care a whole lot
if you are.
For his sake,
will you listen to me?
HARGE: I heard you out.
You didn't prove a thing.
You have the proof, Harge.
Think back what happened
after the bank.
Nothing happened.
- We hid out for four months.
- What was left of us.
- All of you?
- That's right.
If one of mine did it,
why would he stay?
Well, they didn't
want you to suspect.
They'd have to cover
their tracks.
The sheriff's money was burning
a hole in someone's pocket.
Did anyone leave
during those months?
- We can take him, Harge.
- You just give us the word.
Did anyone leave, Harge?
- Yeah. One did.
- Which one?
- Bassett?
- I got word my sister was sick.
I had to leave. What of it?
Can you prove
you even have a sister?
He took the lousy $500
and sold us out.
VIRGINIAN: How much? How much
did you say they gave you?
[Gunfire]
For seven years,
I had that man in my sight,
even in my house.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I can't understand why
that man would come back.
VIRGINIAN: He needed you,
Harge. They all do.
But you don't need them.
You got everything you need.
There's riders coming, Harge.
We got to leave.
That ranch of yours
could be made into something.
- Nah, it's too late.
- It's never too late.
KEELER: Harge, let's go!
KALIG: I'll take that.
VIRGINIAN: I wouldn't use it
to stop you. It's empty.
Big gamble with an empty gun.
If it hadn't been empty,
I wouldn't have been gambling.
PREBLE: Harge, let's go!
Preble? Preble.
Listen. Listen.
It... it weren't the sheriff
who gave me the $500.
It was... Kali...
Kalig.
You... tell that to Harge.
That's far enough.
Don't try turning around again.
- Is this all the money?
- Where's Garth?
I'll count it.
- It's here.
- Can we get going now?
Garth isn't going back with you.
[Cocks gun]
- Judge has been kidnapped.
- The whole town knows.
- Why'd they let you ride off?
- My job is to stop the sheriff.
They've dumped Garth's life
in our laps... ours and the law's.
As long as they're not chased,
he'll stay alive.
Eddie, give me your carbine.
- What'll you do?
- What do you think?
- I'm going, too.
- Not you, Eddie.
You hightail it back to town
and tell the sheriff.
Yeah, boss, but...
If he doesn't keep out of it,
the judge will die.
Come on.
You ride like a cavalryman.
I deserted from the cavalry...
after absconding
with the colonel's wallet.
And his watch, too?
"To Henry Garth,
the man on the horse..."
"from one who envies you."
"Joseph..."
"Pulitzer." Is that it?
Pulitzer.
What did you get this
in exchange for?
A stock market tip on beef?
I asked you a question.
What did he envy you?
Your money?
He was in the cavalry, too.
Loved horses,
wanted to be a cowboy.
[Kalig laughing]
I wanted to be a marine.
So I enlisted
under an assumed name,
and I wound up in Korea
fighting in 1871.
After I busted out of
the prison you put me in...
I proved myself on the field of
honor by killing a leatherneck.
The sum depressed me...
a measly $400.
Two hours before I was due
to be executed...
...I succeeded in crushing
the skull of a sergeant.
An old-time sergeant.
Then I shipped out on a clipper.
Let's head south.
Don't you want the judge
to hear my memoirs?
MAN: I say
let's burn tracks south!
You got your cut.
Why don't you ride out alone?
I've always been interested
in the arts.
Especially the art of abduction.
And I figured one of the oldest
crimes in civilization...
could be pulled off
if I found the right man.
And I have that honor
because I sent you to prison?
Revenge? That's an inhuman word
for small minds.
Now, I figured you were
the only man...
whose signature could bring me
$100,000 in cash.
- You know why I sent that note?
- You weren't ready to die yet.
You shouldn't have any regrets.
- Just one.
- Not hanging me.
You know, the kidnapper
that collects the ransom...
then kills his victim...
is a fool.
He merely intensifies
the search.
I'm your insurance...
so long as you're geographically
safe from pursuit and ambush.
It's a pleasure
to exchange ideas.
My companions here have made
conversation a lost art.
We're asking for trouble
as long as he's alive.
As long as I'm alive,
no one will try anything.
Well, I'm not waiting
for them to try.
[Gunshot]
Get his cut.
I can't figure
what got into you.
When I ride in here,
this thing bothers me.
It's bothered me for months,
that's what got into me.
- But why now?
- It's as good a time as any.
PREBLE: I don't know how to say
this, but I don't have a choice.
It's a hell of a thing to tell
a man his brother betrayed him.
Before Bassett died,
he told me it wasn't the sheriff
who gave him the money.
It was your brother Kalig.
He has hated you
from the day you were born...
because you killed his mama.
Everybody's
always known but you.
EVA: Please do not kill him.
Let him live.
HARGE: You're talking crazy.
Let Kalig go.
HARGE: Let's get out of here.
Let's go!
Lizzie Borden took an ax
and gave her mother 40 whacks.
When she saw what she had done,
she gave her daddy 41.
You comfortable, Judge?
Hey, not too tight, boys,
not too tight.
He's spending a long night here.
Tell me, Your Honor...
what do you despise
more than anything else?
Violence.
Still your favorite subject.
I'll never forget the sermon
you gave that day,
and I quote...
"The long, shrill cry of
the criminal will not stop...
"until all humanity realizes...
"that viciousness
is only for animals."
- How's that?
- Word for word.
- But empty words.
- It made an impression.
I remember another speech
you made about, uh...
man's breaking point.
Seems a lot of things...
have lingered with you
since that day.
They sure have.
Especially the fact that you
built an empire out of violence.
Oh, boy. True blue Judge Garth.
What a joke on the ants
that admire you.
Don't they know
that you wear that halo...
because you can afford to?
I mean, if you didn't
have that ranch,
if you were a saddle tramp...
you would revert to the savage
that's buried deep inside you.
There are some forms of violence
that are forced upon us,
such as, um...
When will you try to kill me?
Killing you will have
to be legal surgery.
Surgery?
Slicing you from the body
of man... by law.
Tell me, don't you
ever feel remorse?
If you mean an apparition
of a slain party...
No.
I've tried
all kinds of criminals.
- Some of them express... regret.
- Regret?
There's no thought
in a murderer,
as the poet and the romanticist
would have you believe.
I remember my father's
bedtime story when I was a kid.
He was from Salem,
Massachusetts.
He heard Dan Webster's argument
that any unpunished murder...
took something away from the
security of every man's life.
He actually believed that.
A beautiful thought,
but basically dishonest.
I feel sorry for your father.
I'll never forget the look on
his face when I said good-bye.
He caught me taking
his life's savings.
Good night, hypocrite.
The judge... Iooks like he's up.
Good morning.
I said good morning.
[Garth gasps]
I'll never forget
the indignities...
I was subjected to in court...
that day that you called me
a sadistic mongrel.
You, masquerading
as a moral high priest...
of righteous justice...
calling me a parasite.
I believe in starting
the day off sociable.
- Quinn.
- Yes, sir?
Bring the judge some breakfast.
KALIG: You know this river?
GARTH: Intimately.
- You own it?
- Not this one.
And it's deep.
Swimming alongside the horses
won't be difficult.
You try anything in that water,
you know what'll happen.
I know what'll happen
when we reach the other side.
Wrong. You still got
a couple of days left.
- Couple of days?
- Maybe even three.
Big Hole Mountains, eh?
Some of my best friends
are buried in Idaho.
I'll let you write
your own epitaph.
- I'll leave that to you.
- We'll collaborate on it.
What are we waiting for?
Give the animals a breather
before we swim.
- I ain't asking you.
- It was a stupid question.
You want me to shoot you?
Try it. If it wasn't for me,
a hundred lawmen would be
boxing you in right now.
I always wanted to hit a judge.
All right, let's get wet.
[Gunfire]
The insurance has lapsed.
Stick with the judge.
Cord, take the right flank.
- You the only one left?
- Yeah. Me and Kalig.
- How about the men on the flank?
- They're a godsend.
- How many up there?
- I don't know.
- They're gonna hit us next.
- I don't think so.
Judge, why don't you tell them
that you're all right.
You heard Mr. Kalig.
I'm all right!
- Can you hear me?
- I hear you, Judge!
I'm still in one piece, son.
They're my hands.
They won't bother you.
I think I'll make it official.
Hey, you cowpokes,
you're using your heads.
You make sure that
nobody else bushwhacks us,
and keep your distance.
How about that, Judge? Now we
got a rear guard to protect us.
Three of us left, huh?
Cord, get their cuts.
See what would have happened...
if we didn't carry
our own insurance policy?
You're a genius, Mr. Kalig.
Who else would've thought of
keeping Garth alive this long?
Your cowhands must be living
in suspense up there.
They shoot, they risk you,
and if they wait, they lose you.
Yeah, the losing side's
always full of confusion.
It's a miserable thing
to live in suspense.
It's the life of the spider.
Ha ha ha ha!
You belly down to the one with
the brown shirt on the right.
You, the one on the left. I'll
take the one with the judge.
That's the one
that's got to count.
I know. His reflex
could trigger his gun...
and blow Garth's head off.
We've got to fire
at exactly the same time.
How are we gonna do that?
We got no timepiece.
- I'll signal.
- There's too many rocks.
- We can't see each other.
- Watch for my hat in the air.
Stick to your target,
check your guns.
You know, your daughter's
very fortunate.
Of course, she'll be
well provided for.
You know,
I wished you was my daddy.
Ha ha! That way, I could
inherit your spread, huh?
And get gold watches from
journalists... who envy me.
[Laughing]
It'll be dark soon.
Then we'll cross.
[Winding watch]
Your desperate friends
must've snuck down...
within aiming range by now.
Hey, you saddle tramps!
Why don't you come down here
and get a good look?
One shot out of you...
and the pious brains
of your anointed watchdog...
will be blown
from here to Shiloh.
This is what it all adds up to.
Sentiment, loyalty,
recognition, justice.
A watch...
with tiny little
non-meaning words on it.
Oh, precious words...
but only to you, Your Honor.
You know what I think of your
sentiment, loyalty, and justice?
Yah!
[Gunfire]
SARAH ANN:
Kalig, are you all right?
Regardless of what happens,
you're my son,
and you come to me.
I love you.
I love you more than anything or
any person in this whole world,
and you must never forget that.