SUBTITLES BY
LUIS-SUBS
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
COFFEY: It's about Maryanne.
I... I'd like...
Mr. Stewart,
I'd like to talk to you.
I've come...
I've come to Washburn Creek
to talk to you...
Oh, good Jesus.
To your home.
I've come to your home
to talk to you about Maryanne.
I'd like...
I'd like very much to ask...
Maryanne...
I'd like to talk to you
about Maryanne.
It's about...
It's about Maryanne.
Maryanne?
MARYANNE: Hold still.
CHILD: I don't want to
go to bed yet, not now.
WOMAN: Oh, stop your fussing.
Come on.
(BLOWS AIR)
The splinter already hurts
more than pulling it out.
Okay?
(WHISPERS)
Mary...
- CHILD: I'm not sleepy.
- WOMAN: We'll store you to bed.
You need to take your rest too,
Mary,
if you want to look pretty when
your Irish comes courting tomorrow.
You hush.
(WHISPERS)
Hold still.
(GUNSHOT, HORSES NEIGHING)
WOMAN: What's that?
(GUNSHOTS)
MAN: Get him over there.
WOMAN: Aster, come.
Come here.
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
- What's happening?
- They were in the Williams house.
- Indians?
- Stay with the women.
Down into the root cellar, get.
WOMAN: Let's go.
- MAN: Come on now.
- WOMAN: Come on.
Come on down.
Keep your lamp low
and this door locked.
You don't open it no matter what.
Ma! Ma!
- Ma, ma.
- MAN: Quiet.
WOMAN: Mind your brother now.
Hush.
(TWO GUNSHOTS)
Josh.
Don't cry.
Be brave for me.
(BANG)
(GUNSHOT)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(SCRAPING SOUND)
(SCRAPING)
(SCREAMING)
Josh!
(ALL SCREAMING)
WOMAN: Josh!
Josh!
(CREATURE GROWLING)
MAN: Maryanne?
Mary?
Anybody home?
Mr. Williams, sir,
the Stewarts aren't home.
Oh, God.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh!
The Stewarts are gone.
Easy. Did Mary say anything
to you about leaving?
No.
What about the williamses?
No, you gotta...
Oh, God.
Damn it.
Indians took 'em.
God help 'em.
We've got to get them back.
I hit three men up there.
Really?
Indians, anyway.
I hit them dead.
Don't feed Dobie your horseshit,
Mr. Parcher.
That ain't horseshit.
That's history.
Boy ought to learn
where he's come from.
Mind the cursing
in front of my boy.
Yes, ma'am.
Great God almighty,
is that coconut cake?
Mom got it special.
Baked it.
Coconut cake from back east.
10 years back,
not a mile from here,
I had to eat a horse to survive.
That's disgusting.
It wasn't my horse.
The point is
we're here now
eating coconut cake.
Right civilized country.
- Mm!
- There's chicken and cornbread.
I know it.
I'll attend to that cornbread directly.
There's a rider.
Listen, cowboy, how about you
take your mother in the house?
He's wearing a funny hat.
I think it's your ranch hand,
Mr. Coffey.
Anybody can wear a funny hat.
That ain't Sunday riding.
Go on, take your mother inside.
Let's go, Dobie.
Go on.
Coffey, God damn it,
I was having a picnic.
Indians...
they killed...
There.
It's from Mr. Clay.
They took Maryanne,
took the whole family.
I can read.
Oh, Jesus.
Did the Indians kill them
little Williams girls too?
No, looks like Mr. Williams did.
That's a hell of a thing to say.
PARCHER: If we're dealing
with crow or Ute,
Dobie could see things a
boy shouldn't have to.
I've made up my mind, will.
You've already lost
a man to the Indians.
I don't want to risk another.
I don't have a man in this house.
I've got a boy.
Take him to Washburn Creek
and bring him back.
Maybe then I'll have two.
- Them horses ready?
- Yes, sir.
We're all set, Mr. Parcher.
Then let's get to it.
Mr. Parcher's lived
through everything
this country could throw at him.
You stay close and mind him.
You'll be fine.
- (FLIES BUZZING)
- Oh.
She should have bled out more.
Same with the girls.
Ida and Daphne.
I think those were their names.
You want to wait outside?
No.
Good.
I wonder
what kind of weapon
makes a wound like that.
No scalping knife I know of.
Maybe some kind of chisel.
That gun only fires twice.
He would have had
to have reloaded it
if he wanted to kill everybody.
Any Christian woman would
prefer dying to capture.
Mr. Williams had time to reload
because his wife gave it to him.
If it came to that,
I hope you'd be strong enough
to take care of your mother.
I suppose a wild buffalo
could have done this.
Looks like you've found yourself
a hole in the ground there, will.
That and four corpses
and six missing,
most of those being
women and children.
I'll get the horses.
Hold up now.
It's in my command.
I gotta know who we're hunting.
How long have the
Indians had them?
Near a day now.
Mm, well,
that's more than enough time for
those women to have been...
Yes, so why aren't
we on the trail?
You want to go face an Indian
war party on your lonesome?
Those blanketheads will peel
you like an orange, boy.
Follow along.
We'll do this thing right.
Don't worry.
We'll find them.
Hey, you all right?
We should be going after them.
You knew these people?
I do.
The Stewarts anyway.
That's Maryanne.
She yours?
I was working on her.
♪ Alas!
And did my savior bleed ♪
♪ And did my sovereign die? ♪
♪ Would he devote that sacred head ♪
♪ For such a worm as I? ♪
- (MEN SPURRING HORSES)
- ♪ Thy body slain
♪ Sweet Jesus, thine
♪ And bathed in its own blood ♪
♪ While the firm mark of wrath divine ♪
♪ His soul in anguish stood. ♪
COFFEY: Christ.
Who's Henry Victor's Indian?
That's ten bear, a crow Indian.
The man's paid for his worth.
Hey, Walnut, Mr. Victor's
canteen's dry.
He called you Walnut.
Yeah, he did.
Is that your name?
The name's Callaghan.
Callaghan.
You Irish?
That man that calls me Walnut
believes he's better than me
'cause nobody ever owned him.
But I'm not enlisted.
I cook for fort Lincoln,
but I'm paid.
I can leave anytime I want.
You understand?
Sure.
I'm Fergus Coffey.
Coffey.
You black?
Damnation.
What?
We're not gonna find any kidnapped
wives at a reservation.
I know it.
We could set off on our own.
Might could, though it
would only be four of us
to we don't know how many 'skins.
We have to find the Stewarts.
If we can do that with Henry
Victor's help... fine. If not...
I guess you've had every chance
to and ain't killed us yet.
Whoa.
Whoa. Whoa.
Mr. Parcher.
Hey hey.
Sorry, Dobie.
It must have stepped
in a prairie-dog hole.
Listen, cowboy,
why don't you hump on ahead
and see how much further we're
gonna press on before camp?
Yes, sir.
Go on now.
Why do you spend so much time
rubbing that boy's belly?
He already thinks
you're Jesus Crockett.
I'm courting his mother.
That's Gertrude Spikes' boy?
Yeah.
A skinny woman.
Might as well just poke the boy.
(CHUCKLES)
That's not a very godly sentiment.
(CONVERSING INDISTINCTLY)
- Hey, son.
- Mr. Victor, sir, Mr. Parcher told me...
Take a look yonder.
Is that a horse?
Go on.
He's seen us.
(CHUCKLES)
You think I didn't know that?
Why ain't he running?
Well, why don't we ask him?
(GUNSHOT)
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(PARCHER SPEAKING SIOUX)
Parcher.
CLAY: We don't have
time for this, Will.
Every prisoner is gonna slow us.
Yeah, well, I'd rather walk
in the right direction
than ride with my head up my ass.
What's happening to these
Stewart women right now?
This isn't your outfit, Clay.
This soldiers are
under my authority...
Mine.
As long as you ride with us,
so are you.
That Injun doesn't know shit.
He wouldn't talk if he did.
Mm-hmm, yeah.
He'll talk.
- (WHIP LASHES)
- (SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
- Hey.
- Walnut. Sorry, Callaghan.
You don't want to see that.
Do you know if he's talked yet?
Naw, that ain't even the point.
They stopped asking
questions a half-hour back.
What is that?
- Hmm?
- What the hell is that?
It's a tobacco pouch.
(CHUCKLES)
It's ugly as shit.
Yeah, come off an Injun,
a big buck by the name of
Sack-o-Tabacky.
- (MEN CHUCKLING)
- PARCHER: Jesus Christ.
What is it?
MAN: Shit, son.
It's a scrotum, Dobie.
COFFEY:
I can't say I like Henry Victor.
There's a sack of horseshit.
Christ.
I came close to joining
the army after New York.
Impossible to get work here.
No one will hire the Irish
on account of us being a
bunch of thieves and beggars.
Sounds familiar.
You come to this country alone?
I had a sister, died of
consumption on the boat.
They put her in the water.
They wanted to put everything in
the water to save us the infection,
but I managed to hold on to a...
What do you call that?
...Broach.
It used to belong to mother.
I gave it to Maryanne Stewart.
He's given up for the night.
Praise God.
Shit.
Hope this gets me fired.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Come on here.
Eat, all right?
(SPEAKING SIOUX)
Go on, eat it.
Come on.
VICTOR: My daddy was one of
the men behind the rifles
that held off the Sioux
in the battle for New Ulm.
You know the story
of New Ulm, boy?
Yes, sir.
My father died there.
Well, I hope you know
your daddy died noble.
I will raise a drink to your daddy
and every man at this fire,
for we will make certain
that we never see
anything like that happen
in this country again.
I'll drink to it.
Any reason's a good one.
Who fed my Indian?
Hmm?
We don't find those settlers
until he talks.
And he don't eat
until he talks!
Now who fed my goddamned Indian?
Walnut!
You goddamn...!
Where are you?
- Somebody find that...
- I fed him.
Why, you ignorant son of a bitch.
Henry.
You raise that gun
and the four of you will be
on ropes within an hour.
Christ, Henry,
he was just gonna shoot
you a little bit.
And if Coffey fed him the
same shit your cook fed us,
he ain't no happier than
he was before he ate.
Give it a rest.
Yeah.
This is my command...
Mine.
And I will not have
my authority undermined.
Apologize to the man for
undermining his authority.
I'm sorry for undermining
your authority.
Mm-hmm.
Bugle taps.
We're bedding down.
I want three men guard until dawn.
I want guns on the night.
Anyone tries to sneak back
into this camp,
anything moves,
kill it.
(RUSTLING)
(SNORTING)
(GROWLING, RUSTLING)
(SNORING)
(GROWLING)
Who's there?
(COCKS GUN)
Hey.
Are you all right?
Come on, Samuel, get up.
Hey.
(EXCLAIMS, GROANING)
Jesus Christ, Samuel,
you drunken shit.
What have you got for me here?
Give me my...
(COCKS GUN)
Who's there?
(GROWLING)
Wake up, Samuel.
Wake up, Samuel, for God's sake.
(SCREECHING)
VICTOR: Bullshit. Bullshit.
Bullshit.
Somebody saw those yellow-belly
shitheels deserting.
VICTOR:
I will not goddamn believe
that four men left this camp
and no one even goddamn stirred.
What happened?
'Morning, sweetheart.
Henry Victor lost
some of his boys last night.
Yeah?
Where?
That's the question.
(PARCHER SPEAKING SIOUX)
(SCREAMING)
What's he got to say now?
We already know that don't work.
What was that?
He says he likes white men.
He says about another tribe...
miners.
He didn't say "miners."
Men mine.
He used the word
for an animal's dig,
"burrow" maybe.
VICTOR:
Let my buck do his job, will.
(SCREAMING)
God damn it, Henry.
Hey, don't touch my Indian.
John. John.
Don't you ever touch my Indian.
I've had enough of
that man screaming.
Eh, he's shit-all for
information anyway.
We'll get our answers
at the reservation.
This ain't the Sioux,
Henry.
He just said "burrowers."
We need to face the
enemy before us.
Do you understand?
We're going to the reservation.
DOBIE: Mr. Parcher.
Oh.
What do you think, cowboy?
I don't know.
There's another right there,
maybe a third yonder.
Shitfire.
Henry Victor would rather
pull toes off the Sioux
than follow the trail before us.
Sorry, sir?
I think we're about set to
quit our military escort.
PARCHER: I ain't rode this hard
since we gone to the town.
(LAUGHS)
Dobie.
What do you think, cowboy?
It's all right.
(CHUCKLES)
I gotta go to the Jacks.
You've been doing
real good, Dobie.
You ought to sleep.
We'll be up before dawn.
We only got a few days...
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
You ever heard of a tribe
called the burrowers?
We'll stand two-hour shifts.
Yeah.
(HORSES NEIGH)
- (COCKS GUN)
- Jesus. What?
- Don't shoot.
- (HORSES NEIGH)
Don't shoot.
It's me.
It's Callaghan, Henry Victor's cook.
Shitfire, Walnut.
Are you trying to get shot?
I can't rightly account
for the others.
I didn't even know they was
missing till just now.
CLAY: Well, if you're riding
with us, you're working for us.
It's nasty work in
an unfriendly country.
You follow along, do as
you're told, you hear?
Well, can I ask which
one of y'all is boss?
We're partners.
Listen to Parcher.
Do what Clay says.
(CHUCKLES)
I'll be dogged.
The Mick's been paying attention.
Welcome to the outfit, Walnut.
This don't make sense.
Don't touch anything.
Who takes men and horses
and leaves the valuables to rot?
This is something
we ain't seen before.
We stay on the trail, huh?
Which direction are we going?
You'll go whatever direction
we tell you to, I guess.
What about the wagon?
The man said don't touch it.
(BANGS)
Damn.
Shit.
Agh!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
What in the hell?
(EXCLAIMS)
- (WOMAN PANTING)
- PARCHER: Jesus God.
She's breathing.
She's not one of the Stewarts.
Who is she?
That's just like a Williams woman.
She should have bled out more too.
Still moist.
Any other marks on her?
You got eyes.
There's something scratching.
She's been drug a spell.
- What else?
- What else do you want, John?
Did the Indians rape her?
How the hell am I
supposed to know?
There's something
scratching inside her.
What are you talking about?
I hear it too.
It's in her shoe.
Take it off.
(EXCLAIMS)
Why would they bury her alive?
I don't know.
It's a miracle she ain't dead.
What about the
crucifix stuck on her?
What if they buried Maryanne?
We'll find her.
Here, it's yours.
What do I do with it?
Hellfire, I don't know.
Find comfort in your maker.
It's your watch.
PARCHER:
Now once you get to fort Lincoln,
you stay with her.
We'll pick you up on our way back.
I can catch up with you
guys in about a day or two.
We won't have more
than a day or two
before those missing
are corpses or worse.
Don't ride it now unless you
want to break old spear's leg.
- I know it, sir.
- You'll be fine.
I wouldn't trust any other man
in the outfit to do the job.
Enough.
Let's go.
- PARCHER: I don't like this quiet.
- Hold your peace.
Yonder.
He looks Sioux.
(BIRD CALLS)
(COCKING GUNS)
Shit, they got us flanked.
Come on.
God damn it, that was a greeting.
(GUNFIRE, SIOUX HOOTING)
(GROANS)
Whoa.
- PARCHER: We got trouble?
- I expect.
I'm shot.
Jesus Christ almighty,
Walnut's horse kicked you.
And you deserve worse.
If you so much as touch
that gun without my say-so,
I will holster it in your ass.
- You understand?
- Oh, yeah.
Let's keep at it.
(DOBIE MUTTERING)
Well, don't think of it
as being forward or nothing.
Well, that's civilized.
Well, good night.
(SCRATCHING SOUND)
(SCRATCHING STARTS AND STOPS)
(SCRATCHING)
Jesus.
You're still awake.
You're trying to...
I'm so sorry, I...
What did they do to you?
You think that Sioux back
there was burrower tribe?
There's more flavors of
Sioux than I can count.
How come we never
heard of them before?
I can't say.
I expect they'll introduce
themselves shortly.
The Mick ain't made us the most
popular white men in Dakota.
You know, I have a notion to
let him go when we get home.
Amen to that.
I'll stay out till we
find the Stewarts.
They might not be so far off.
If that Indian you shot
at wanted to talk,
he wanted to trade.
The only thing he'd have
that we might want...
white people.
They don't trade in whites.
And if this is revenge
rather than rescue...
We got no reason to
think she's dead.
We can still find her.
He's right.
We don't quit.
We don't sleep. We don't...
- (GUNSHOT)
- (HORSES NEIGHING)
(SIOUX HOOTING, GUNFIRE)
Jesus, Clay.
CALLAGHAN: Come on.
- My leg.
- Stop pulling.
Get over here.
Don't waste your bullets
unless you're close
enough to kill.
- (SCREECHING)
- (EXCLAIMING)
(CREATURES GROWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
How long are we gonna lay here?
They could be waiting in ambush.
The horse is starting to smell.
Hey, that's poison oak, ain't it?
Looks it.
I'll tell you what...
Put your gloves on
and pile up as much of
this stuff as you can
while we wait for dawn.
They used to make us burn
this shit in Georgia.
Yeah?
I knew a man that got caught
downwind of the smoke.
Venting his lungs for two days.
You boys about set?
He drowned in his own blood.
All set.
All right, get to burning.
Let's go.
It just don't seem right.
(LIGHTS A MATCH)
It gets us back on the trail.
(OWL HOOTING)
(GUNSHOT)
I thought you ain't
had any religion.
So we know where he's buried.
Leave it off.
If them Indians know a
white man's buried here,
they're liable
to dig him up and
tear out his eyes,
make him blind in
the spirit world.
This mean we're heading back?
No.
Shitfire.
John Clay'd piss on us from heaven
if we turned back now.
(SNORING)
How do you think he does that...
Sleeps on his horse?
I wish I knew so I could do it.
Haven't closed my eyes
since yesterday morning.
I wish I had my hat.
Hard to fathom
John Clay being dead.
I've known that man
since we were little boys.
You ever get anyone back...
Women
from the Indians?
Not personally.
Not alive.
I...
I met a woman who...
Who come back once,
but she weren't never the same.
But she lived.
I'll take the first watch.
No, you sleep.
I'll...
I'll keep a lookout.
(QUIET GROWLING, RUSTLING)
Callaghan.
Parcher.
(GROWLING)
(COCKS GUN)
Coffey, I can't find Parcher.
Why's the fire so high?
I woke up in the heat of it.
He was already gone.
Something's up.
He's using us.
Indians see the fire, attack us...
Parcher sees the Indians.
Son of a bitch.
This fire will die down.
Do you hear that?
It's almost like...
(PARCHER SCREAMING, GUNSHOTS)
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(CREATURE SCREECHES)
(SCREECHING)
My neck.
Do we have any bandages?
It ain't bleeding.
I can't even feel it.
Jesus.
Now I can't feel my hand.
What did that Indian do to me?
Those weren't Indians.
Here, clean it out.
What right did you have to
stake us out there like bait?
It ain't about rights.
And I'm the one who's goddamn cut.
(QUIET GROWLING)
PARCHER: I can't feel my face.
COFFEY: They're all around us.
I think they're waiting for
us to go back to sleep.
Fat goddamn chance today.
PARCHER: Coffey, would you
hand that cross over?
If I don't make it back,
you give that to miss
Gertrude Spikes for me.
Or you give it to Dobie
and tell him it's for his mother.
I'll do it if it comes to that.
I appreciate it.
We've got a fire.
PARCHER: Careful, we don't
know if these are friendlies.
CALLAGHAN: Yeah, well,
as long as they're human.
(COCKING GUNS)
(PARCHER SPEAKING SIOUX)
What did she say?
Told us to set a spell.
Her name is faith.
She's talking about the burrowers.
Said they killed her family.
- As her what a burrower is.
- And where do we find 'em?
PARCHER: They... they
use some kind of poison
and bury their victims alive.
(FLIES BUZZING)
(CAWING)
They eat soft parts.
Soft parts?
What's that mean?
I like my soft parts.
Shit.
Ute Indians know how to kill them.
Does she know how
to stop the poison?
- Ute might know.
- What about the Stewarts?
What about them?
We can't stop searching so
you can find your cure.
We find the Utes;
they lead us to
the burrower tribe;
we kill the burrowers;
You get your girl;
you build a cabin on the
prairie and you play American.
Faith coming with us?
That, or I'm killing her.
(CHUCKLING)
Coffey, see that bruise
on Parcher's neck?
His face and hands too.
The man's falling apart.
I'm starting to think
I mightn't be so eager
to risk my hide
for that crazy shitbird's
Indian cure.
I'm risking nothing for him.
You still think you're
gonna find your girl, huh,
Maryanne Stewart?
What if she looks like him?
I may need the Indian
cure just as bad.
Hey...
What's the ruckus back here?
Just talking.
I thought I might
have heard my name.
Don't tell me you boys
are tired already.
This is Ute territory.
What did she say?
Not a thing.
Let's go.
We're here.
What?
There's no here here.
We're dead center goddamn nowhere.
Utes will come.
We just gotta wait.
Get me off this horse.
My ass feels like soggy bread.
Come on.
Come on down.
Christ, come on.
(CALLAGHAN REPEATING IN SIOUX)
(CALLAGHAN SPEAKING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Are your eyes open, bud?
You hear me calling?
Oy!
I'm awake.
Good.
You stay that way.
You think that boy and his squaw
are gonna try and leave us?
Did you hear what I was saying?
I... I'd sure hate
to have to shoot somebody
who was trying to
abandon me out here.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(QUIET GROWLING)
(COCKS GUN)
(PANTING WEAKLY)
(GROWLING)
What?
(FAITH SHOUTING)
Take that one out!
(SCREAMING)
(GUN CLICKING)
- Did you see those things?
- You shot my goddamn leg!
I saved your ungrateful
ass from that...
Parcher, you stupid...!
- (QUIET GROWLING)
- PARCHER: Jesus God in heaven,
that was no Indian.
Put wood on the fire, she says.
- What's she saying?
- Nonsense. The squaw is hysterical.
- Use your hands. Sign.
- Oh, great Christ.
- She wants us to go.
- No, we're staying right here.
Don't listen to that
red-skinned bitch.
She knows more than you do.
Can you ride?
Yeah yeah,
if I can get up on my horse.
We're staying right goddamn here.
Come on...
Coffey...
Don't
(GUN CLICKS)
(PANTING)
(CLICKS)
(GROANS)
God damn you to hell, Coffey.
God damn you.
You boys better hope to God I die.
(GROANS)
Coffey,
we gotta do something
about my leg.
(CHUCKLING)
Here here here.
Come on, come on.
Agh!
(GUNSHOT)
(SPEAKING UTE)
- No English.
- Shoot 'em.
I'm empty.
Drop me and get your rifle.
(GRUNTS)
Praise God.
He sent us some Utes.
- (SPEAKS FRENCH)
- COFFEY: Yeah, um...
Je parle français,
kind of.
...burrowers.
Drop me and get your rifle.
He says he can fix you.
Something about little fish.
He keeps talking
about little fish.
Oh, Jesus Christ almighty,
he's...
He's talking about bait.
(PANTING) No.
No.
No. Jesus Christ almighty,
he's talking about bait.
- CALLAGHAN: Drop me!
- PARCHER: Oh, God.
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh, God.
Shoot him!
Pick up your goddamn rifle
and shoot this son of a bitch!
Don't let them take me!
You're killing me,
you son of a bitch!
Are they gone?
I don't know.
(FAITH SPEAKING SIOUX)
You ain't thinking of going
after them, are you?
The Ute?
Oh, God.
Coffey?
She's dead.
Let's go home.
I gotta go after Parcher.
The hell you do.
The man was dead
before them Indians ever got here.
It's not for him.
We don't know how to stop
the burrowers' poison.
We don't know how to kill them.
I want to go home.
They took Maryanne from home.
Home isn't safe.
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(IN FRENCH)
Silence.
(DISTANT MOANING)
(PARCHER SOBBING)
Oh, man.
Jesus.
Coffey.
Thank God.
(MUTTERING)
What?
They made me...
made me drink.
- Drink?
- Yeah.
What do you mean, drink?
(RUSTLING)
(SCREAMING)
(MOANS)
(STRAINING)
(RUMBLING)
(DISTANT GROWLING)
(GUNSHOT)
(PARCHER MOANING)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(WAILING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
You poisoned the little fish...
To poison them.
(GROANING)
(SCREECHES)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROWLING)
It didn't work.
(GRUNTING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(BURROWERS GROANING)
It was the sunlight.
It burned them alive.
The Utes poisoned them.
They put something in Parcher
that would make them sleep.
If that Indian dies we
won't find the poison.
Shit.
Nothing's easy.
I can make it to fort Bismarck and
back with a doctor in two days.
You think that Indian
can live that long?
I don't know.
Can you?
Get to it.
(GRUNTS)
Come on.
Get up, you lazy bastard.
(SCRATCHING)
Hey.
(DISTANT VOICES CALLING)
VICTOR: Parcher's Irish.
I'll be damned.
Parcher's Irish.
My God, man,
they told me you were here.
I'm glad you made it, son.
I'm afraid you're too late
for will Parcher, though.
I know.
Yeah. What the hell
did them Indians do?
We buried him proper, though.
The man was wiser than
I gave him credit.
It took us four days
and no small pain
to get them Sioux to tell us
what Parcher guessed right off.
Yeah, well, we got scouts
routing out the Ute in
the north as we speak...
Regular Indians.
They can whoop to beat the band,
but can't fight worth shit.
Where's Callaghan?
Who?
He was your cook.
He was part of this...
Oh, Walnut, Walnut.
God rest him.
Walnut... he...
He would have owed me his life,
had he survived.
What?
We had to amputate his leg
and he up and died on us.
The man was hysterical,
delirious before he passed.
Yeah.
Of course
we never did find them Stewarts.
Yeah, well,
I doubt we ever will.
They was probably dead
before we even started.
Yeah.
Well, I guess all we
can do is make sure
them Indians never do
something like this again.
♪ Hush-a-bye, don't you cry ♪
♪ Go to sleep, you little baby ♪
♪ When you awake we will have cake ♪
♪ And all the pretty little horses ♪
♪ Dun and bay, sorrel and gray ♪
♪ A pall with six white horses ♪
(BURROWERS GROWLING)
♪ Dun and bay, sorrel and gray ♪
♪ And all the pretty horses ♪
(BURROWERS SLURPING, GROWLING)
(EXHALES)
♪ Way down yonder, down in the meadow ♪
♪ There's a poor little lamb ♪
♪ The bees and flies and
plucking out its eyes ♪
♪ Poor little lamb
crying for its mother ♪
♪ Crying for its mother ♪
♪ Mama gone and daddy gone ♪
♪ Oh, you miss our little baby ♪
♪ So when you wake we will have cake ♪
♪ And all the pretty little horses ♪
♪ Dun and bay, sorrel and gray ♪
♪ A pall with six white horses ♪
♪ And all...
♪ Those pretty little horses ♪♪
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)