For some time there'd been reports
about a vicious gang of claim jumpers...
who'd been forcing miners to sign away their
claims through fear of torture or death.
The claims were then transferred
to one of their own men...
or were sold to innocent miners
who had just arrived in the territory...
and were looking
for new claims to work.
These claim jumpers were smart enough not
to try to grab some of the bigger mines...
where there might be
enough men working to put up a fight.
Usually, they picked on the claims
being worked by one or two men...
and the more defenceless these men were,
the better the claim jumpers liked it.
Their plan was simple
and foolproof.
No one knew
who they were.
Since their victims either
disappeared or were found dead...
there wasn't anyone who could
put their finger on thesejumpers.
Working a claim became a mighty
dangerous business for any miner...
because no one knew when
or where they'd turn up next.
Hey, Luke,
come here, quick.
Take a look at this.
- There's enough dust there to blind a man.
Looks like we staked one
with some pay dirt this time, son.
It's about time,
hard as we been working.
Now you can buy
all the silver you want.
You won't have to go around
playin' poker for it.
I like to play, Dad.
You never figure on
losing, do you, son?
Well, if you figured on losing,
you wouldn't be a poker player.
We must have better
than three ounces here.
Take it to town and get it on the scales
before the assayer closes for the day.
I betcha it's
closer to five.
That sure ain't gonna
make me mad.
He's gettin' ready
to move out.
Bill. Lenny.
Take care of'em.
I'll wait supper for you,
but don't get in no poker game...
or it'll be breakfast time
before you get back.
If I do play, I promise
to win as fast as I can.
Hi.
- Howdy.
Any luck?
- Oh, there's lots richer pickings around, I guess.
Well, then you won't mind
signing over your claim.
For how much?
- Let's say one dollar... just to make it legal.
What are you up to anyway?
Get off my land before I...
Now look, you're gonna sign.
Why don't you make it easy on yourself?
I'm not signin' anything.
Change
your mind?
I told you
I'm not signin'...
Maybe you'd
like to sign now.
Maybe we're wastin'
our time, boss.
Just what
I was thinkin'.
You know, this mine is no
good to you if you're dead.
What do we do
with him now, boss?
Get him out of here.
We'll dump him in the arroyo.
I wonder what's holding up those guys.
- Here comes Bill now.
That's not Bill! Leave him!
Leave him! Get movin'!
Then old man Tompkins struck it rich
a few miles north of Silver City...
and thejumpers moved in
and killed him.
As usual, they made
a clean getaway...
but this time they left a trail
I thought we could follow...
and as I was marshal of Silver City, I
decided to get up a posse to track them down.
Lightning.
How 'bout lettin' me hold on to the marshal
job while you're out huntin' them claim jumpers?
I don't know, Dan. I'm afraid there wouldn't
be a man left without a hole in his skin...
with a famous old gunfighter
like you on the job.
You mean to say I'm not as fast on the draw as you are?
- I mean nothing of the sort.
You should. It's the truth... even if I did
teach you everything you know about a gun...
ever since you was big enough
to pull a trigger.
But I'm older now,
a mite slower on the draw.
Only a mite, Pop.
- The way I figure...
you've already tamed most of these
itchy-fingered hotheads around here...
to where I can ride herd
on 'em 'til you get back.
All right, Pop. Go into the office
and get one of those deputy badges.
Thank you, son. I knew you'd
say that, so I already took one.
Don't you worry about
a thing while you're gone.
Lightnin;
Well, is that sack for me to bring back
the claim jumpers' scalps in?
Uh-uh. Smoked venison.
- Oh.
You might be gone for a long time.
- I might at that. Thanks, Dusty.
You take care of me better
than many a wife I know of.
Johnny Sombrero looks
mighty happy about somethin'.
Maybe it's because the
marshal's leaving Silver City.
Hey, Johnny Sombrero.
How 'bout joinin' the posse, Johnny? Give
you a chance to use that shootin' iron legal.
My gal don't want me to leave town.
- Which gal?
All of them
good-lookin' female gals.
They say, should something happen to
Johnny Sombrero, their hearts would break.
Don't you go lookin' at me
when you say that.
If anything was to happen to you,
Johnny, I'd say good riddance.
Don't go botherin' Dusty
while I'm gone, understand?
Didn't know it was marshal's job to tell a
fellow what females he can interest himself in.
In this case,
I'm making it my job.
If you hold another opinion, you're welcome
to try to do something about it... right now.
Think I'd be loony enough
to draw on you, Marshal?
No. Not while
I'm looking at you.
I'm glad Johnny ain't
goin' with you, Lightnin'.
Be easy for him to put
a bullet in your back.
It's a wonder he passed up the chance.
Maybe he's got something else in mind.
We're ready to
move out, Marshal.
Bye, Dusty.
All right, let's go.
Get goin'!
Hey! There's
a posse comin'!
How many? Clear out!
- About 20 of'em.
The posse lost
them in the chase.
They tried to pick up
the trail again but had no luck.
We were near Fort Lowell when I took
the bullet through my right shoulder.
So they dropped me off at the army hospital
there, and they went back to Silver City.
That's not very good
for a marshal, is it?
I could do better
with my left foot.
Sometimes it feels like
it doesn't even belong to me.
How much longer do I have to hang around here, Doc?
- Well, let's have a look.
Hmm. Mm-hmm.
Well, it seems to be
healing nicely.
I'll take the bandage off by the end of the week.
- Oh, good.
Ooh.
- Does it hurt?
No, not really.
It's just a little stiff.
Well, it may be for a while.
Just keep massaging it.
Sheriff's coming.
Who's that on the horn?
Looks like a goner to me.
Who you got there, Sheriff?
- Tom Peters.
Claim jumpers did it.
Left him for dead.
I hope the doc
can pull him around.
Found him lyin' at the edge
of Coyote Springs more dead than alive.
Get him inside.
Do what you can for him,
will ya, Doc?
He saw
the claim jumpers.
Told me he could recognize 'em.
Then he passed out.
Be a mighty handy man
to have alive.
He'll be the first
living witness we've ever had.
Easy. Easy with him.
Thank you, boys.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Perhaps I could be of help.
I've had some training as a nurse.
If it's one thing I need around here, it's
help. Make him as comfortable as you can.
I have to probe for the bullets.
- Sure hope we can save that poor devil, Doc.
Would you get me
some water, please?
Oh, sure.
He's dead.
I'll tell the sheriff.
I guess he was farther gone
than I thought.
I'm sorry
for what happened.
I know how much it would've meant to you
and the sheriff had he lived.
It was kind of you to
help, miss. Or is it Mrs?
Miss.
Miss Opal Lacey.
And you're the famous Marshal Tyrone
of Silver City, aren't you?
"Famous" is
a pretty big word.
I'm afraid most people call me
a lot of other things.
I heard you were wounded. I
hope it's nothing serious, Mr Tyrone.
"Mr" Tyrone.
My friends call me...
I know, "Lightning. " I've heard all about
how fast you are with a gun.
As a matter of fact,
I know quite a bit about you.
And I don't know anything about you.
Isn't that a bit one-sided, Miss Lacey?
My friends call me Opal.
Well, they can't be
very friendly then.
If I knew ya real well,
I'd call you...
I'd call you Brown Eyes.
Brown Eyes.
I like that.
When are you returning
to Silver City?
As soon as I can get
this arm out of this sling.
I hope it'll be soon. I'm on my
way there now to join my brother.
You did say your brother?
- Yes.
He's a mining engineer. He's
just opened an office in Silver City.
Oh.
- Let's get on, folks.
I hope you'll
visit me in Silver City.
Brown Eyes, you're gonna find me
a nuisance when I get back.
Why?
- Because I'm gonna be sitting on your doorstep every spare minute I get.
In that case, I'll make certain
my house has a doorstep.
Bye, Lightning.
- Bye.
Evenin'.
- Good evenin', Harvey.
Good evenin', Dave. -
Hi. Hi. - Evenin', Dan.
Evening, Tim.
How's Lightnin' gettin' along?
- Well, of course...
he can't hardly wait to get home,
but that doctor at Fort Lowell...
won't let him travel none
'til his wound's all healed.
I got a letter from him
just this noon.
Who read it to ya, Pop?
- Dusty.
Why, you spavin cayuse! Are you
trying to say that I can't read?
Oh, of course not, Pop. Well, it's just that
your eyes ain't as good as they used to be.
Well, maybe they're not so good for readin',
but they're still good enough for shootin'.
Oh, don't get mad, Pop. I know
you're still plenty quick with a gun.
Well, just so you don't
forget it. Hm.
Ahh!
Goodnight. Goodnight, boys.
- Goodnight, Dan.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
You know, that old galoot
still thinks he can draw.
The only thing he
can draw is a picture.
Shot in the back.
He drew all right,
but he never had a chance.
Well, whoever did this
sure picked a perfect night.
We'll never be able
to find his tracks in the rain.
I wonder what Lightning
will do when he hears about this.
Well, I'd sure hate to be
the guy that plugged him.
Hi, Lightning.
How ya feeling?
Fine, Ben. Just fine.
Hiya, Will.
- Glad to see you back, Lightnin'.
Hi, Dusty.
- Pa! Pa, Lightning's back.
Hello, Pete.
- Pa and me's been worried sick since we heard ya took a bullet.
All that worrying's gonna make you old
before your time, Dusty. How are ya?
How is your arm?
- Oh, good as ever.
How's Dan been
behavin' himself?
What's the matter?
Pop's all right, isn't he?
He was found dead.
Shot in the back.
Shot...
When?
- Three days ago.
I'm sorry, Lightnin'. I know how much you thought of Pop.
- Who did it?
Nobody knows. It happened out in front
of the Blue Goose at night.
Oh, that's great.
That's just great.
Pop gets shot and nobody makes a move
to find out who killed him.
The rain was pilin' down when it happened.
Washed all the signs out from around his body.
Yeah. Whoever did it must've been desperate
for money. They took the gold nugget off him.
I think I'll have a talk
with Johnny Sombrero.
Funny thing about Johnny... up and got
himself a steady job right after you left.
Nobody can prove he had anything to do with it.
- Maybe I can.
Lightnin'.
Johnny's been talkin' big since word
got around you were wounded.
He figures it's bound
to have slowed you down.
I never had much respect
for Johnny's figurin'.
I hoped I still had
the Indian sign on Johnny.
Sure, I could draw as fast as ever,
but I couldn't squeeze the trigger.
But Pop had been killed, and I had a feeling
Johnny'd done it, and I had to find out... now.
That's him now.
Who killed Dan Musick?
- Why ask me? I guess he couldn't find his gun.
He didn't have a chance. He was
shot in the back. Where were you?
I was five miles out, working as a guide
for the Acme mines. That's their office.
I'll check that,
and if you're lying to me...
You don't think I'd lie
to you, do you, Marshal?
I wouldn't advise it, unless you're
thinking that bullet slowed my draw.
Has it?
- There's a sure way to find out.
Uh-uh. I've reformed...
but my friend here hasn't.
His name's Blake, from Tombstone,
and he don't like marshals.
Maybe there's a good reason
why you don't like marshals.
None of'em live long enough
for us to get acquainted.
You've been meeting the wrong kind of marshals.
- I don't think I have.
I told you the marshal
was a mighty sudden gent.
If you're in Silver City after sundown,
rat face, I'll throw you in jail.
Gimme that gun!
- Not now!
Excuse me. Can you
tell me who the, uh...
Well, Brown Eyes.
- Welcome home, Lightning.
You working here?
- Not exactly. I'm just helping my brother.
Oh, this is your brother's place, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
He's inside. I'm glad to
see that your arm is better.
Well, thanks. I'd like
to talk to your brother.
Won't I do?
- Maybe you will at that.
I'm here to find out if a Johnny
Sombrero is working for this outfit.
He is.
- Oh, this is my brother, Rod.
This is the marshal
of Silver City.
So you're the famous Lightning.
Heard a lot about you.
Glad to know you.
- What do you wanna know about Johnny?
I wanna know how long
he's been with you.
I put him on the day after I got here.
I needed a guide; he knows the country.
Why? You got anything against him?
- Nothing I can prove.
I just have a hunch he had something to do
with the killing of Dan Musick.
Oh, he couldn't have. He was acting guide
for me at the time of the shooting.
Have you talked to the Silver Kid yet?
- Never heard of him.
Opal, you shouldn't repeat idle gossip.
- What gossip?
She heard the Silver Kid could've
done it because he rode into town...
the day before
this Dan Musick was shot.
Silver Kid, huh?
Thanks for telling me. See ya.
Lightning.
They say the Silver Kid is
awfully fast with his guns.
Thanks for the warning,
Brown Eyes.
I hope the Silver Kid is
as fast as they say he is.
We'll soon know.
- Nice-looking fella.
Yes, he's attractive.
- Interested?
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
My only interest in him is to make certain
he doesn't get in our way.
Gimme a bottle.
- When d'ya get back in Silver Creek?
Glad you dropped in, Lightnin'.
I heard you come back.
Sorry about ol' Dan.
Do you know anything about a
stranger called the Silver Kid?
Not much, except I'd hate
to tangle with him.
Though he looks like he ain't dry behind the ears yet.
- Where can I find him?
Where he usually is... over there.
Doing all right for himself too.
He didn't have
the face of a killer...
but he had the cold,
steel look of one.
I noticed his hands
were quick and sure.
Bettin' 40.
Your 40,
and 40 bucks again.
Call it.
- Three aces.
It costs money to learn to play poker, Kid.
- It sure does.
It looks like it's gonna
cost you plenty to learn...
because three aces don't beat
three treys and two deuces.
When are you gonna
start shavin', Kid?
When you buzzards learn
to play poker, maybe.
Talks like
a man, don't he?
Wears a couple
of shootin' irons too.
Well, I'll bet he's a real tough hombre...
when his ma's around to protect him.
I wouldn't crowd too far
if I was you, sheep dip.
Sheep dip?
Why, you...
Thanks for
the winnings, gents.
I'll be back later.
Better come with me.
Let's see your pouch.
What's the matter? You short of cash?
- Sit down.
I hardly expected to come across
Dan's nugget in the Kid's pouch...
but I wasn't going
to overlook anything.
The Kid could've been cocky enough to carry
it on him, if he was the one who plugged Dan.
A man I thought a heap of
was shot in the back a few days ago.
His name was Dan Musick.
There's some folks in town
think you might've done it.
What do you think?
- I'm asking you, Kid.
I don't shoot men
in the back, Marshal.
The only time I draw
is when I'm crowded.
I didn't kill
this Dan Musick.
Any more questions?
- Yeah.
What's your name? And I
don't mean "Silver Kid. "
Cromwell.
Luke Cromwell.
Where ya from?
- Santa Fe.
Santa Fe, huh?
- Is that all?
'Cause I'm losin' a lot of money
sittin' around here.
Just a minute.
I'm probably wasting my breath,
but I'm gonna give you some advice.
Get outta town pronto.
Get yourself a job and quit poker.
Poker's a man's game.
- I can take care of myself.
Oh, sure, I know you're
fast with your guns...
but sooner or later you'll meet a man
who's faster... or who doesn't fight square.
Then you move to Boot Hill. You're buckin'
a sucker's game, Kid. You can't beat it.
I guess that's good advice,
Marshal, but I ain't takin' it.
Besides, how to handle a six-gun
and poker is all I know.
There is a way to stop them
riding you when you play poker, Kid.
That I sure would
like to hear.
I wasn't interested in his poker...
but I was interested
in the way he handled a six-gun.
An idea hit me.
I needed a right hand...
and he had the
fastest one I ever saw.
You like silver,
don't you, Kid?
They won't be so quick to ride you
with that pinned to your jacket.
What's the catch?
- No catch. I got my reasons... two of'em.
One is to keep you out of trouble.
The other is, with you covering my back...
I'll have a better chance of staying right-side
up 'til I square things for Dan Musick.
Pa wanted me to ask if you'd...
- Dusty, this is the Silver Kid.
He's gonna be my new deputy.
- Kinda young to be a deputy.
He handles his guns
like an old-timer.
Any objections to me
being a deputy?
None, so long as you
ride protection on Lightnin'.
That's just what
I aim to do.
Just be careful
where you aim.
Pa said for me to ask you
to have supper with us.
Oh, thanks, Dusty.
Be glad to.
Say, a deputy gets hungry,
too, you know.
Oh, I think we can stretch
the vittles for one more.
That your girl?
- Who? Dusty?
She's like a kid sister. I've
known her since the day she was born.
She don't look at you like no kid sister.
- Oh, you're seein' things.
Come on.
Let's get washed up.
You can bunk there.
Say, are you sure a deputy's
allowed to play poker?
Nothing in the regulations that says he can't.
Thinking of riding Lady Luck after supper?
Yeah. If I'm half as lucky as
you are, I'm bound to clean up.
What do you mean
by that?
A wound like that's likely to put a man's
shootin' arm plumb out of action.
I always was
a lucky hombre.
Lightning.
Well, hello.
- Care to have supper with me?
Tonight? I wish you'd have
asked me earlier.
The Kid and I are invited
to eat at Pete Fargo's.
I must be losing my charm.
Anytime you lose your charm,
Brown Eyes, I'll be glad to look for it.
My brother's working late
at the assayer's office.
Why don't I come over after supper?
- Good.
I hated the thought
of spending the evening alone.
Bye.
- Bye.
You're gonna get a bellyache
eatin' that fast.
Oh, me? I always eat fast.
- Yeah.
Especially when there's a fancy filly sittin'
all alone waitin' for him to come over.
What filly?
- The one they call Miss Lacey but he calls Brown Eyes.
The only thing bigger than
your ears, Kid, is your mouth.
Gonna see her
after supper?
Her brother's workin' late.
She's kinda scared to be alone.
You sure that's in
the line of duty, Marshal?
Look, Kid, your job is to see I don't get
a bullet in the back. That's all, understand?
You stuck on that filly?
- Dusty...
you got no right to call
that lady a filly.
Seems to me she got no right
to call that filly a lady.
All right,
that's enough.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Oh, thanks
for the supper, Dusty.
It was
a good supper.
You know, I've seen
fancy dressers like her before.
They can do more harm to a man
sometimes than a pair of six-shooters.
Anyway, I'm glad he didn't
ask me to go with him.
Why?
- Hm. Rather stay here and talk to you.
What about?
- Nothing. Just... Just talk.
Talking's a waste of time unless you're
doin' somethin' else at the same time.
Yeah? Like what,
for instance?
Oh, like for instance,
helpin' me wipe these dishes.
Go on, put that apron around you and get busy.
- Just a minute, Dusty...
Ya ate, didn't ya?
Now wipe.
You say one word about this to anybody,
you won't be able to sit down for a week.
Ya understand that?
Remember, they'll be comin' out
soon after Lacey goes in, so be ready.
I'll be waitin' for him.
- And don't miss. He never misses.
Evidently, you don't like cake.
- Oh.
I always eat slow.
- Good. That means you'll spend more time here.
I don't need an excuse
to spend more time here.
Remember what I said at Fort Lowell?
That I'd be parkin' on your doorstep?
Well, if you insist
on the doorstep.
Oh, no. I find this
lots friendlier.
So do I.
Certainly friendlier than the way you stormed
into my brother's office this afternoon.
Brown Eyes, had I known you were there,
I'd have been on my best behaviour.
But I had a lot on my mind,
some quick decisions to make.
Obviously.
What do you mean
by that?
Well, making the Silver Kid your deputy
was not only a quick decision...
but kind of a reckless one,
too, don't you think?
Oh, there's nothing wrong with the Kid
that a little growing up won't cure.
But isn't it dangerous
to make him your deputy...
particularly when he's
suspected of the killing?
Who? The Kid? Oh, no, he couldn't
possibly have anything to do with it.
Well, if you don't suspect him,
then whom do you suspect?
Johnny Sombrero. I just
can't swallow his alibi.
But Johnny was with my brother.
They camped out all that night.
They were only five miles out. Johnny
coulda ridden into town and back again...
while your brother was sleeping...
or he coulda put Blake up to it.
Blake? - Some trigger-happy kid.
Seems to be a sidekick ofJohnny's.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to get into this kind of talk.
Don't be sorry.
I'm interested.
Interested in me
or in what I do?
Both.
Well, I guess I've taken up
enough of your time.
Do ya have to leave now?
No, I don't have to. I just
don't want to wear out my welcome.
You're welcome here anytime.
Stay until my brother gets home.
You know, I like your brother,
especially when he's out.
So do I.
Well.
Next time, I'll stay
at the office later.
Next time I'll start earlier.
- I may have something to say about that.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Lightning.
I have a hunch you two would like me
to work late more often.
Always play your hunches,
Lacey. Goodnight.
Lightning, you all right?
- Yeah.
That you doin'
the shootin', Kid?
Naw, it's some
bushwhacker back there.
I was a mite slow bendin'
my gun over his head, but here's his.
Thanks for savin' my hide, Kid.
Let's take a look at him.
Lightning! - The Kid just
got himself a two-legged coyote.
Who is he?
- His name's Blake. "Rat Face" suits him better.
Is he dead?
- Come on. Tell the lady you ain't dead, Rat Face.
Come on.
Tell her!
Get me a doctor quick.
You want me to die?
You want me to answer that?
- Why'd you wanna plug me?
Thought you were
somebody else. I made a mistake.
Same kind of mistake you made
when you killed Dan Musick.
You couldn't pin that killing
on Johnny, so now you pin it on me.
You can't do it. I didn't
hit this stinkin' town...
Before I get through with you
you'll be sorry you hit it at all.
That half-wit. He had a clean shot
at him, and he missed.
If the Kid hadn't interfered,
Blake would've gotten him.
I could swear I've
run into him before.
You think Blake will talk?
- He won't.
You better make sure. Sitting in jail for a
long time can sometimes loosen a man's tongue.
He won't be in jail
that long.
You find anything?
- No.
Well, it might help if you tell
your deputy what you're lookin' for.
When I find it, I'll tell ya.
- Easy, Doc.
There. That's
the last stitch.
If you'd hit him harder,
you'd have saved me a lotta work.
What are you doing?
Quit tearin' my shirt.
Lightning. Ya ever see
one of these before?
Yeah. The jumpers use these
to identify themselves.
I know.
- How do you know, Kid?
Some time ago, me and my dad
had a little claim up in the Tomahawks.
One day, some skunks forced my dad to sign
over the claim, and... then they shot him.
I went after them and managed to get one of
them before they shot my horse out from under me.
One of them had a doodad like this
around his dirty neck.
Why did you kill
Dan Musick? Talk fast!
I didn't do it.
- How many more jumpers are with you?
Never heard of'em.
- Maybe your branding iron on his belly might jog his memory.
There's another way to make him talk,
worse than using a branding iron.
I had a hunch
that thejumpers...
would try to break Rat Face
out ofjail or fill him full of lead...
so he couldn't tell embarrassing things,
like who their leader was.
So we sneaked him to the ranch Pop had
left me, where I picked up my foreman.
I had in mind a cave that was
just made to order for Rat Face.
There. That oughta
hold the little buzzard.
This place stinks rattlesnakes.
You ain't gonna leave me here?
Yeah. Rattlesnakes crawl in here
kinda thick during the heat of the day.
If a rattler bit you,
he'd probably die.
Ready to talk? This is
your last chance, Rat Face.
I ain't scared, and I ain't talkin'.
- Abe'll look in on ya...
to see if you're
ready to talk.
If I don't hear
from him in 48 hours...
I'm passin' the word
around town where you're hidden.
Folks in Silver City
thought a heap of Dan Musick.
They'd like nothing better than
to string up one of you claim jumpers.
You ain't gonna lynch nobody. I know too
much. Besides, lynching's against the law.
So is shooting marshals
in the back.
Turn 'im into the corral, Kid.
Pete'll unsaddle 'im.
Well. What do you think
you're doing?
Guardin' the prisoner
what ain't.
Why? Doc Hardgrove
been talking?
Talkin' to me. Everybody else still thinks
you got Rat Face back there.
Johnny Sombrero and Tinhorn
are tryin' to whip up a lynchin' mob.
I figure a couple of loads
of buckshot oughta scatter 'em.
You scatter on home, Dusty.
We'll take care of the guardin'.
Don't want a pretty gal like you
gettin' all messed up.
Know somethin', Lightnin'? That's the first
time you ever admitted I was a gal.
Know somethin'?
I must be real smart.
I figured she was a gal the first time I ever saw her.
- Maybe you're smart enough...
to figure out who'll get here first,
the lynching mob or the jumpers.
Maybe I can, but right now I'm gonna
keep Dusty a little company.
I figure there's
no objections.
Hey, Dusty!
Mind if I walk you home?
Thank you, and now you can walk yourself
right back to Lightnin'. He might need you.
Just brushin' that chip off your shoulder.
You know we're both holdin' the same cards.
Maybe if you got your mind off poker once
in a while I might be able to understand you.
Look, Dusty, Lightning's so blinded by
Brown Eyes, he can't even see your shadow.
You're so blinded by Lightning,
you can't even see mine.
So that gives us something
in common... same cards.
Maybe I oughta learn
to play poker better.
What you oughta do
is get outta this game.
If you do, we both stand
a chance of winning.
If you don't, we both
wind up holding dead hands.
I better go inside.
Hi, Carl.
- Hi.
Here. This oughta blow it
into the next county.
What about the marshal
and that kid he deputized?
Johnny Sombrero will
take care of them.
Johnny's fixing it so the marshal
will have his hands full.
Just so they're outta the way.
- You have nothing to worry about.
Just grab him and
wait for us back here.
Come on.
Come on!
I'll tell you
what'll happen to him.
He'll go to jail for a little while. Then
he'll be free to take up where he left off.
Johnny's right. Them claim jumpers
go around killin' with a free hand.
What happens to 'em
when they get caught?
Why, they stick 'em in some
nice, warm, comfortable jail.
It don't seem right to me
to let a claim jumper off that easy.
That's what I say. They're a bunch
of murdering rats, the lot of'em!
If I had my way,
they'd all hang.
Well, why don't we
string 'em up?
We been putting up with this long enough.
- Let's get 'em.
Yeah!
Lightning! Lightning!
There's a lynch mob
coming after Blake.
Remember, no shooting
unless they start it.
Lightning, don't take any chances. If you
can't talk them out of it, let them have Blake.
Don't worry about me, Brown Eyes. Get on home before they get here.
- Be careful.
You can count on me,
Lightnin'.
That's close enough.
- You're giving us Blake, or do we bust in?
How come you're in this, Johnny?
Yesterday, Blake was a friend of yours.
That was yesterday. I didn't know then he
was one of the jumpers. Now hand him over.
I'm handing nobody over. Blake's done
some talking. At his trial, he'll do more.
We'll hold trial
after we've strung him up.
I'm warning you, Lightning.
We're coming in.
I got a load of buckshot
waitin' for you, Johnny.
Opal told me you're in trouble.
- And Johnny's makin' most of it.
I don't hold with
lawlessness, Johnny.
Just wanna give this jumper a piece of his own medicine.
- That's the marshal's job.
Don't listen to him, Johnny.
- Shut up, Tinhorn.
I got respect
for what Mr Lacey says.
I'm stringing
with him.
Blake gets his neck
stretched after the trial.
Give us a hand here!
Watch the walls.
The jumpers got Blake!
We're gonna go after 'em, Lightnin'.
- Never find 'em in the dark.
Too bad they got Blake.
Outside of him, we wouldn't know
who to look for anyway.
See, Lightning? If you hadn't butted in,
Blake'd be dangling from a rope.
Now he live to put a bullet in your back.
- That's enough, Johnny.
Marshal was only doing his duty. Go home
and get some sleep before you get in trouble.
That goes for all of ya.
- Anything you say, Mr Lacey. Come on, Tinhorn.
We'll get some boys in the morning,
see if we can't follow their tracks.
Good idea.
- I appreciate the way you backed me up.
I'd have been in hot water
with Opal if I hadn't. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
One of'em will be ridin'
high and wide but not handsome.
I put a load of buckshot into his britches.
- Thanks, Dusty.
Whenever I need another deputy,
I won't have far to look.
Don't know if I oughta interest myself
in a gal that can shoot like that.
Likely spend my life
picking buckshot outta my hide.
Some folks are gonna hold you to blame
for lettin' that jumper get away.
Oh, the jumpers didn't get Blake...
- Shh. Dusty.
What's goin' on around here?
You sat out there and saw 'em do it.
That's what comes of lettin' a gal in on a secret.
- Yeah.
She held it longer
than most of'em would.
What are you two
talkin' about?
Dusty's right. The jumpers didn't rescue
Blake. The Kid and I have him at the ranch.
Well, you picked yourself
a right smart young deputy.
That's what I been tryin' to tell him.
- Well, I'll be...
Come on, Dusty.
See ya in the morning.
Goodnight. -
Goodnight. - Goodnight.
How does it feel to have yourself
a right smart young deputy?
I'll let you know
as soon as I get one.
Come on, Kid.
Let's clean this mess up.
Here comes
the boss now.
You boys all right?
- Sure. All but Slim here.
He'll be ridin'standin'up for a while.
- Where's Blake?
That's what we'd like to know.
We bust in this jail, it's empty.
Empty? But Lightning
put him in jail.
Lightning said he put him in jail.
- Well, then, where is Blake?
Hidden somewhere else.
You boys get back to the hideout.
You know something?
I have a feeling Lightning would do
most anything for me...
or my brother.
What are you getting at?
- Maybe if we use a trick of our own...
we can get him
to turn Blake over to us.
What sort of trick?
Drive me back to the house, and I'll
tell you about it... brother dear.
I figured that
sometime during the night...
thejumpers might take
a notion to sneak back...
and try to force me to tell
where Blake was hidden...
so I wasn't taking
any chances.
I was going to be ready
for them when they came.
Lightning, you've gotta help me.
Some masked men broke into the house.
They pistol-whipped Rod,
and then they kidnapped him.
They hurt you?
- Recognize any of'em, Miss Lacey?
If you were listening, you
heard her say they were masked.
They had hands, didn't they?
Rings? Fancy boots?
Maybe a black sombrero?
I'll take you home and look around, see
if the kidnappers left any trademarks.
You stay here in case
the jumpers come back.
The lamp is on the table.
I'd like to look over
Rod's room first.
It's through here.
Rod must've put up quite a fight.
- He did, but there were five of them.
Any idea why they wanted
to grab him?
He never had any trouble
that I know of.
Maybe the jumpers are gonna try
to force Rod to sign over his claim.
But Rod hasn't filed
any claims here.
He was only interested in reopening
the old silver mine at Santa Rita.
You think they might've
grabbed him for ransom?
L... I don't know why they've
taken him, Lightning...
but I'm afraid for him.
I'm afraid.
Go ahead and cry if it
makes you feel any better.
Put your hands up.
You wouldn't shoot
your own deputy, would ya?
That was a smart stunt.
I almost plugged ya.
Maybe I shoulda. Might
teach ya to do as you're told.
I figured I'd
better tag along...
just in case you might need me
sorta accidental-like.
From now on
I'll do the figuring.
As long as you're here, search these
downstairs rooms and the grounds outside...
and don't trample
on any signs.
You're the boss... boss.
We better check
your room.
What's in there?
- My dressing room.
Do you think you'll find Rod?
- I'll do everything I can, Brown Eyes.
There's one fellow I'm gonna
check on as soon as I leave here.
Who's that?
- Johnny Sombrero.
But Johnny works for my brother. Why would
he want to kidnap him? It doesn't make sense.
Sombrero does a lot of things
that don't make sense.
Try to get some sleep,
Brown Eyes.
Goodnight, Lightning.
- Goodnight. See ya in the morning.
Kid.
How dare you come into my room. You oughta be
horsewhipped. I came out and found him here.
I didn't know this filly was here. I heard
something, so I came to look around.
Get out!
I've taken all I'm
gonna take from you.
Are you sure you know what you're doing?
You're not only blind, you're a cripple.
What do you mean "cripple"?
- Meaning you.
I've noticed the way you been massaging that
right hand when you think no one's watching.
Go ahead. Let me see you
pull that trigger.
You're through.
Get out.
Go on. Get out!
Johnny Sombrero finds out about that, you won't
have the Indian sign on him any more, will ya?
He didn't take anything, did he?
- I don't know yet.
No. Here they are.
I'm sorry.
Thank you. They're fire opals.
They're my birthstone.
Please.
- Oh.
Aren't they exciting?
Like their owner.
I really haven't had much practice at this.
- I'd be very jealous if you had.
You again!
- I found this on the door as I was leavin'.
I thought you might
be interested.
Is it about Rod?
- "Marshal, if you want Rod Lacey back alive...
"you and Blake
start for hideout.
"He knows where. On the way,
you'll be met and prisoners exchanged.
Just you and Blake. No tricks,
or Lacey gets it. The Jumpers. "
That's not possible. Rod
told me they'd rescued Blake.
I've got Blake hidden away safe. I'm holding
him 'til he tells who killed Dan Musick.
But, Lightning,
they'll kill Rod.
Maybe I can get Rod
and still keep Rat Face.
Well... goodnight,
Brown Eyes.
There was one more thing I had
to do before making my plans.
I wanted to find out
ifJohnny Sombrero was in town.
Rat Face had been
his friend...
and he could be using Rod
to make me turn Rat Face free.
Hands off that gun,
Johnny.
How long you been in bed?
- Since right after you let Blake escape.
Well. Wiped nice
and clean, huh?
You take real good care of'em, don't you, Johnny?
- Always.
They cost me plenty in Santa Fe.
- Where's Rod Lacey?
In bed, I guess, where you oughta be.
- He was kidnapped an hour ago.
Mr Lacey?
- Five men broke into his house and grabbed him.
And you think I had
a hand in it? You're crazy.
I work for Mr Lacey.
He's a friend of mine.
So was Rat Face. Maybe this is
your way of getting Rat Face back.
Even swap; Rat Face for Rod.
That your idea, Johnny?
You're scratching
in the wrong place.
The only way to turn up worms
is by scratching for 'em.
If he was the one who put that note
on the door of the Lacey house...
his horse would
still feel sweated.
He was cool. I could tell
he hadn't been run for hours.
I began to think I was all wrong about
Johnny Sombrero being mixed up in this.
Made this batch
a mite stronger.
Well, the stronger,
the better.
Phew! Smells like
a skunk moved in.
Garlic water.
- Garlic water?
Yeah, a trick I learned
from Dan Musick.
Rat Face gonna ride this horse
when Lightning takes him to the jumpers.
I trade Rat Face for Lacey.
Then the posse turns some dogs loose...
and they follow the trail
to Rat Face and the jumpers.
That way he figures to
get 'em all. Kinda smart, huh?
No, I don't think it's smart.
I think it's crazy.
The posse gets the jumpers, but you and
the Silver Kid get bellies full of lead.
You can stop worrying about the Silver Kid. He's not going.
- Why not?
I told him he was through.
He kept buckin' me at every turn.
The Kid's fixin'
to leave town, Dusty.
He's gettin'
his stuff together now.
Got a message for you,
Lightnin'... from Johnny Sombrero.
He's waitin' for you
at the Blue Goose.
Johnny drunk?
He's just been listenin'. He's
heard you been ridin' bluff on him.
That jumper's bullet did
things to your shootin' hand.
Oh, you can still draw plenty fast,
but, uh, can't squeeze the trigger.
Johnny aims to find out
whether he's been hearin' right.
Tell Johnny
I'll accommodate him.
It's a pleasure.
I, uh...
I heard you was leavin'.
- Well, you heard right.
There's nothin' left around here for me anyway.
- But you can't go now.
Why not?
- 'Cause Lightning's gone out to meet the jumpers alone.
What do you want me to do?
- You've gotta try and stop him.
Look, Dusty...
there's one thing
you oughta get straight.
Lightning's not
doing this for Dan Musick.
He's not doin' it
for Rod Lacey either.
He's doin' it for Brown Eyes. If he wants
to stick his neck out for her, let him.
Me, I don't figure to stop no bullet
'cause he's stuck on that fancy filly.
Maybe what you say is right.
He is doing it for that Lacey woman.
But you can't let him go alone.
He's sure to get killed.
That's too bad.
That's too bad for you.
But I warned you
to get out of the game.
I'm not
in the game any more.
You were right.
I just hope
it isn't too late.
You just couldn't wait to get even with
me, could ya? Why, you cheap little...
In just about one second
I'm gonna forget you're crippled.
Why didn't you forget it last night instead
of blabbing it to Johnny Sombrero?
I didn't say anything to anyone about your crippled hand.
- You're a liar.
Johnny sent Tinhorn around
to say he's waitin' for me.
Don't!
Now get outta town,
and keep travelling!
You're not gonna meet Johnny, are ya?
- I got no choice.
If I back down, I might as well turn in
my badge and get out of Silver City.
But if your hand's no good,
Johnny'll kill you.
I always had the
Indian sign on Johnny.
I think maybe I still got it.
Maybe when he sees me call his bluff...
he'll figure the Kid deliberately gave him
a bum steer just to frame him.
If that happens, he'll
turn tail like he always did.
But what if he don't
turn tail?
It's a chance
I gotta take.
Here he comes.
I'm takin' over
for Lightnin'.
Now you'll live
to get back to Brown Eyes.
Who killed Dan Musick?
Opal. She... wanted it.
Talk sense, Johnny.
I haven't much time.
The... The nugget.
Take a look in her jewel box
if you don't believe me.
You liar.
You dirty liar!
Who do you think told me
you couldn't squeeze a trigger?
Opal's been my gal
right... right along.
Hurt bad, Lightnin'?
- Darndest thing I ever saw. Shot by his own deputy.
Here, lemme tie this
around it.
I'm sorry I had you wrong, Kid.
- You didn't guess right on Brown Eyes either.
Better let the doc
have a look at it.
The doc'll have to wait. I've
got somethin' to attend to first.
Darling, you've been hurt...
Lightning,
what are you doing?
How did this get in here?
It was Johnny Sombrero's.
He gave it to me as a gift.
A gift of his
love for you...
to prove he'd do anything you want,
even if it meant shooting Dan Musick.
What are you talking about?
- You can stop playing me for a fool now, Brown Eyes.
Please, Lightning, you must believe me.
I didn't know it was Musick's.
How could I? Johnny didn't say
where it came from. He only said...
Stop it. Johnny Sombrero is dead,
but he did a little talking first.
Johnny dead?
- I'm clumsy with necklaces. I can't squeeze the trigger.
You wanted him to kill me,
didn't you? Didn't you?
No, I didn't!
- Who ordered Sombrero to kill me?
Was it you
or your brother?
Rod... but he
isn't my brother.
He gave me the things I had to have,
the things I wanted... money and clothes.
When he wanted to control
a man, I managed it for him.
So that's it, huh?
You and Rod are jumpers.
That's putting it a little coarsely. Let's
just say we buy up the jumpers' claims.
But Rod's through. I don't
have to take his orders any more.
I never did like him anyway,
and you've been wanting me, darling.
The trading post
is closed, Brown Eyes.
Lightning, Dusty lit off
to deliver Rat Face.
The little fool. They'll kill her!
How long ago she leave?
About 20 minutes ago.
We'll never catch her.
I know a short cut
to the jumpers' hideout.
Where is it?
- Near Silver Creek.
But you better open that trading post,
'cause you'll never find it without me.
I bet I can get it out of her.
- Stay away from me!
Wait a minute. Take us to
that hideout, we'll let you go.
All right, it's a deal.
- Round up some men.
And remember, Brown Eyes,
this time, no tricks.
Shoulda caught up with Dusty by now.
- Unless she's already there.
It's Blake! And a
gal's brought him in.
Hey, Lacey!
Hiya, Dusty.
- Mr Lacey.
I'm so glad you're not hurt.
I brought Blake in exchange for you.
Gimme a hand.
- I appreciate that, Dusty.
I sorta like it here.
I think I'll hang around awhile.
How 'bout gettin'
these irons off of me, boss?
Boss?
That's right, Dusty.
I'm much obliged to ya
for bringing Blake back.
I'd have liked it better
if Lightning had come along though.
Posse comin'!
Get her inside.
Keep her there. Quick!
Their hideout is on the
other side of those rocks.
This is as far as I go.
- Just a minute. You're gonna take us in there.
No, I made a deal. Let her go.
- How do we know she ain't lyin'?
If she is, I'll find her and bring her back.
Get goin', Brown Eyes.
Little double-crosser.
She's bringing 'em in here.
Keep down 'til you hear me fire.
Bob, take two men up there. Jack,
three men up high. Rest of you, scatter!
Now remember,
don't shoot 'til I shoot.
Opal!
Rod! There's
a posse coming.
Yeah... and you
brought 'em.
But I came to warn you.
No, Rod, don't! I love you!
We're trapped!
Spread out!
Hey! There's
Dusty's horse!
Come on. Get on up
to that trough there!
Here they are, Marshal.
Where's the Kid and Dusty?
- In there.
Excuse me.
Come here.
I just thought...
What is your name?
I can't go through life
being called Mrs Silver Kid.
Luke Cromwell.
- Hello, Luke.
Hold on. How 'bout you? Dusty ain't no dignified name...
- It's Jane.
Hi, Jane.
You again.
We're set to pull out, Kid.
So any time you're ready.
ENGLISH