Hold it!
Jim, if you want to stay alive,
you'd better be more careful.
Chris, l've been on the trail
a long time.
l've been looking for you.
We better get you into town.
Come on.
l'm scared, Ma.
l'm really scared.
l'm not excusing it, ma'am.
He did wrong.
But the punishment
don't fit the crime.
He's only 18.
Only a boy.
What did you do?
l was just funning.
Busted into a store.
Help us, please, ma'am.
Talk to your husband.
Save your tears, señora.
The marshal has no mercy,
no sympathy, no compassion.
What did he do?
Pepe Carral?
He's knocked over most
every bank in this territory.
Big Walt over there...
he's just too strong
for his own brain power.
Chris.
Chris?
No.
But he's only a boy.
He had a man's wants
when he was robbing...
and he didn't spend the money
on grub for his family.
He spent it on
women, liquor, and cards.
And then when he's caught...
he calls himself a boy again.
lf you put him
in that Tucson hellhole...
he'll come out a wild animal.
That storekeeper
you robbed had six kids.
You ruined him.
You wiped out
ten years of hard work...
for just one night.
One good time.
l learned my lesson, honest.
Chris, please.
No.
You're supposed to be
an important man...
a friend of the governor's.
You're worse than any man
you ever sent to Tucson.
ls there any man in there
that killed as many men as you?
Not by half, there isn't.
l didn't kill for
the same reasons they did.
You're not as pure as them
that stands before you.
Name's Noah Forbes, Marshal.
l've decided to do for you...
what Ned Buntline
did for Bill Cody.
Make a damn fool of me.
Make you famous.
You're a writer?
You name a big-city newspaper
and l've worked on it.
That's means
you're pretty good...
or you can't hold a job.
All you have to do
is talk to me.
l'll do the writing,
you get a third.
l met Buntline.
Read his stuff. Mostly trash.
Things weren't anything
like that.
Listen,
what people think is true...
is a lot more important
than what really is true.
Can't get rich telling them
they're wrong.
l don't make my living that way.
Marshal, somebody's going
to write about you anyway.
Why shouldn't it be me?
All right.
But you get half...
and you don't print anything
l don't like.
lt's a deal.
Rye! Bring a bottle...
and put it
on the marshal's bill.
l'll be a little short
till l finish the book.
You better write good.
Jim, what the hell
are you doing here?
You should be flat
on your back for a week.
l ain't got a week, Chris.
l ain't got an hour to spare.
Come on.
Have a drink anyway.
Jim MacKay, Noah Forbes.
Here's a man
you could write about.
He's ridden with me
more than once.
You a lawman, Mr. MacKay?
l used to be a bounty hunter.
One of the few that tried
to bring them all in alive.
But l'm a lawman now...
and don't you laugh, Chris...
a legal and respectable
town marshal.
They've got a good man.
What town?
Magdalena, down Sonora way.
lt's a farming settlement.
Mostly Mexicans.
A few American families.
We get along just fine.
An American marshal
in a Mexican town?
They couldn't be too particular.
They needed help bad.
You see,
we border De Toro's territory.
Who's De Toro?
Bandit. Raids both sides
of the border.
The Cavalry and the Rurales
could stop it...
if they'd cooperate,
but they don't.
Neither side lets the other
cross the frontier.
Those two pistoleros...
De Toro's?
l guess they figured...
l'm coming to look for
some of the old bunch.
Jim, l've crossed that border
three times to fight bandits.
l ain't going down there again.
Chris,
he's bound to hit us anytime.
He's got 50-60 men.
l got a handful of farmers.
And l've got a good job.
And a new wife
who's still practically a bride.
l don't like
to bring this up, Chris...
but l saved your life one time.
That doesn't give you
any right to ask for it now.
Besides,
didn't l save your neck today?
Doesn't that make us even
if you're keeping score?
You told me then, Chris,
''l owe you.
''You want something,
you ask, you got it.''
l hung onto that promise
for 10 years.
l saved it like grubstake...
waiting for something
important to come along.
And l'm asking now.
No, Jim, l can't.
Remember that first time, Chris?
Seven of us got $350,
50 bucks apiece.
Those folks in Magdalena,
they trust me...
me, Chris...
with everything they got.
l got $3,000 here.
$1,000 of it's yours
for just a couple of weeks work.
Well, maybe some of the others?
Dead mostly...
or semi-retired like me.
Skinner or Elliot?
Tucson Prison.
Who brought them in, Chris?
Times change, Jim.
They couldn't accept it.
Yeah, well...
l guess l don't, neither.
Luck, Chris.
Luck.
l'm glad you didn't lock it.
l figured
you'd break it down if l did.
Chris...
He's only 18.
Hickock...
Clay Allison...
The Daltons...
How do you figure
l outlived them?
By knowing when not to take
unnecessary chances.
Now, that's hard...
but it's the only way
that works.
Works against who?
Shelly's no Mark Skinner
or Pepe Carral.
l'm not asking you
to help gunfighters.
Judge Parker said to me once...
''Men l hanged
never killed again...
''but plenty
that l didn't hang did.''
You tell me he's wrong.
He wasn't talking about a boy
who robbed a store.
l've buried
a lot of friends...
who thought fuzzy-faced kids
weren't dangerous.
lt means a lot to you, huh?
l don't owe Shelly
a damn thing...
and l do him a big favor.
l owe Jim MacKay a lot...
and l don't do anything for him.
Can't seem
to do anything right.
Sure you can.
Come on.
Chris...
how come l'm in chains
and Walt isn't?
He promised not to get away.
And you believed him?
Yeah, l believe him.
Come on.
Hold it!
Sorry, Chris,
but these irons spoil my aim.
Hello, Skinner.
l'll see you next time
l bust out.
l'll be here.
Beats me where he hid it.
He learns hard.
Forget about it.
lf you say so.
All right, bring them on.
Hold it. Wait a minute.
Leave him. Shelly...
You go on home
and stay out of trouble.
Hold it, Marshal.
l got an order to bring him in.
You had an order.
Go on, git.
Come on!
Bust him, Pepe!
Damn you, Chris!
You give everybody a break
but me!
Kill the bastard!
That lousy kid doesn't
deserve it and you know it!
l'll kill you.
l will, Chris.
Not if l get to him first.
Right, Pepe?
Thanks.
Glass of water.
l put this on your bill.
You can play me for things
that aren't important.
Just don't try it
with anything that is.
l already figured
that out for myself.
Want to get some work done?
The Battle of Adobe Walls.
What was that like?
There were 28 of us.
Bat Masterson, me...
Billy Dixon, one woman...
the rest of them
were buffalo hunters.
Quanah Parker
had 600 Comanches with him.
28 against 600?
That's great. What happened?
We had a hell of a fight.
And?
We won.
When l saw that wagon pulling
out for Tucson without me...
l never felt so good
in all my life!
My feet kept saying,
''You're free! You're free!''
To do what?
Go back to that same life...
that made you risk Tucson
in the first place?
You're no better off
than you ever were, Shelly.
You feel like
coming home for lunch?
Yes.
lf you think
you're following us, forget it.
l'll run over
to the restaurant.
You run a bill there, too,
don't you?
Shelly, no!
No!
Oh, Chris.
No! No! Chris!
Any more shooting'll hit her!
-Get up!
-No!
-Get up! Come here!
You're going to be all right?
Hell, l already wrote
your epitaph...
had the governor
come to your funeral.
Thanks.
She nursed you, Chris.
She hasn't slept in 48 hours.
Where's Arrila?
They took her.
Oh, God.
l guess he just couldn't
stand the farm.
What are you going to do?
Kill them.
Hey!
Don't die just riding along.
That'd be a real anti-climax.
On the other hand,
we could say...
you left your deathbed,
just died on the trail.
That has a real good ring to it.
How far you figure we've come?
Hundred miles?
l tell you,
it feels more like a thousand.
Damn it, my ass hurts.
How can anything stuffed
with hay be this hard?
There's something down there.
lt looks like hers.
lt's a tough climb, Chris.
l'll go.
Dead?
Don't go, Chris. Don't.
They use her?
Raped, killed,
and left for the buzzards.
Hank?
Hank, you using
all your blankets?
l'm cold.
lt's so damn cold.
Go to sleep.
Thought we was out of coffee.
We are.
-Get up.
-What?
You want it lying there
or on your feet?
Marshal, please,
you got to understand.
We've been getting up
before light...
to milk cows since we was five.
Work all day,
then go to sleep at dark...
because we couldn't
afford kerosene for a lamp.
Was we wrong wanting
to get away from that?
Wanting to get away from it
wasn't wrong.
How you did it was wrong.
Where's Shelly?
Find him yourself.
You're a lawman.
You got to take us in to trial.
He won't shoot us in cold blood.
l don't bluff.
Where's Shelly?
He cut out for Mexico.
When?
Right after we left town.
Your wife--lt was Hank.
l had nothing to do with it.
l didn't even watch.
And you didn't help her.
He's my brother.
Him for what he did...
and you for what you didn't do.
No!
You could have taken him back.
Do you have any doubt
they were guilty?
lf l waited around
for what you ask...
Shelly's trail would go cold.
lt still wasn't right.
Chris!
Chris! Up here!
l knew you wouldn't let me down.
Have you seen a young fella
riding past here...
in the last few days?
Blond? About 5'10'',
18 years old, maybe?
Yesterday. Tried to hire him,
but he was in a hurry.
-De Toro's on a rampage.
-As usual.
l got nothing behind me
but a pack of good intentions.
Farmers, shopkeepers.
Them two l hired yesterday.
Paid them one quarter
what l offered you...
and they ain't worth that.
As for the rest...
they're willing enough
to get killed...
but l need killers.
That why you thought of Chris?
Didn't mean it
the way it come out.
Before De Toro hits, Jim,
you'd better ride out of here.
Staying's suicide.
That won't do you no good.
Would you ride out?
Hell, no, but l wouldn't be
in this mess to begin with.
Lemonade. Unsweetened.
lt helps fight the thirst.
Thanks.
Thank you.
You make a hell of
a posse man, Padre.
Where's your gun?
l told him
he didn't have to wear one.
Not that l would have anyway.
l fight a different battle.
l use different weapons.
This is De Toro's kind
of a battle.
You're not impressed
with my congregation.
They've been welded together
by adversity.
ln many ways, l've already won
my biggest battle.
God works in strange ways.
l know. He's got me confused
most of the time, too.
When we first
came to Magdalena...
the only things we felt were
the differences between us.
Now He's taught us,
bound us together.
Under the circumstances...
l'm not sure
he's done you any favors.
You realize you're likely
all to be dead soon?
lf that's His Will,
we're ready to die.
l'm not too worried
about meeting him.
Somehow l'm not so sure
you won that exchange.
l'm not so sure he did, either.
lf your whole posse is made up
of tigers like him...
you're in bad trouble.
Aren't you being
a little tough on them?
No tougher
than De Toro's going to be.
Where's that leave me?
Alone.
Chris?
Good luck, Jim.
Shelly's in a mighty big hurry.
Let's go.
-De Toro?
-Yeah.
lt looks like
Shelly's joined them. Come on.
Take it easy! We're liable
to catch up with them!
That's how Shelly
bought his way into the gang.
Those hills are
where MacKay set up his ambush.
Shelly's led them
right in behind him.
-Damn it to hell!
-Come on!
You're not going down there,
are you?
Come on.
l don't see MacKay.
Maybe he took your advice
and lit out.
l didn't think he would.
l don't know
whether l'm glad or not.
Sure been a lot of killing
since l met you.
Should we bury them?
The living need us more.
There can't be anything
left in their town...
but the women...
and De Toro.
l guess they took off.
There's one by the cantina.
There's another in the door
of the mission.
They're covering us.
Ease off your saddle.
Keep your horse
between you and the mission.
Right.
Noah!
lt's safe now.
You sure?
Chris.
Thank you.
l'm Laurie Gunn.
Miss or Mrs.?
Mrs. l mean...
l'm sorry.
Let her cry.
She'll feel better. Here.
l'm Noah Forbes.
Call him Chris.
Jim MacKay talked about you.
He said you were coming to help.
Only you got here too late.
How are the other women?
Oh, God. l hope
none of us gets pregnant.
Can you tell me about it?
There are
only 17 of us women...
and De Toro
came riding in here...
with about 40...50 men.
He told us that he had found
our men in the hills...
and that
he had killed them all.
Did he say where
he was going from here?
Did he say when he'd be back?
l think
they were going to Texas.
They'll stop here
on their way home.
Probably take you back with him.
That's what he said.
Most of the others are asleep.
Oh, Madge!
When can you take us
away from here?
We'll round up horses
in the morning.
They took them all away.
We can walk.
Walk? Across the desert?
You'll all die
the first day out.
At least it's a chance.
Look...
De Toro can ride twenty miles
while you're walking one.
lf he catches you
out in the open...
he'll just butcher you.
We'll go for help.
Where? lf the Rurales
could've done anything...
they'd have done it by now.
The U.S. troops
can't cross the border.
Volunteers won't come down here
and fight De Toro.
-Chris...
-MacKay's already tried it.
What are you saying?
There must be something.
l'm open for suggestions.
lf they come back here,
l'll kill myself!
Damn you!
Think of something!
Maybe l can get a few men
tough enough to match De Toro.
Where?
Tell me everything
you know about him.
What's he like,
how he acts, everything.
Well...
The first thing
you notice about him are...
are his eyes.
They tell you that he's mad.
Crazy mad.
Come on, Chris. Let's go.
You better eat something.
You won't get a chance again
for quite a while.
This isn't like with MacKay?
We're not cutting out on them?
No...
or l'd have told them
so they could make other plans.
Suddenly it's not so bad, huh?
What?
Me being a killer.
No. lt's turned out
to be quite useful.
There's something else, too.
We don't have to go
looking for Shelly now.
He'll come riding in
with De Toro. Come on.
You will come back?
Yeah.
Suppose they come back
before you do?
Just pray they don't.
Stop worrying.
We'll be back.
l knew he wouldn't run.
Shelly.
MacKay killed him.
The women need you anyway.
You got to help them, Chris.
You promised.
He did my job.
l'll do his.
l don't think
this is quite legal.
l don't care what you think.
The governor's approved it.
He's the boss.
l won't turn these men loose.
You're not turning them loose.
You're paroling them
in my custody.
lt don't seem right...
turning them loose
to do the very things...
they were put in here
for doing in the first place!
Marshal,
l think you ought to know...
they're not quite
so tough anymore.
l had to do a bit of taming.
You didn't tame them,
you broke them.
They weren't sent here
for a vacation.
Pepe.
Chris, l've been thinking
about you.
Have you?
You better believe it.
How's it going, Walt?
Answer when you're spoke to!
-lt's all right!
-lt's not all right.
They're in my custody now.
Captain.
May l ask what you mean about us
being in your custody now?
Can you still
handle dynamite, Elliot?
Good.
Still smiling, Skinner?
Only on the outside, Chris.
Fast as ever?
l wish you'd try me.
l've got pardons here...
signed by the governor,
for each of you.
When l countersign them,
you'll be free men.
Then sign them!
You're going to earn them first.
-How?
- Join a posse l'm leading.
Go to hell.
All right,
put him back in his cell.
Hey, wait a minute!
All right, Chris.
Whatever you say.
Who are we going after?
Juan De Toro.
lnto Mexico?
Pardons, hell.
That's seven against seventy.
You're taking us in there
to get killed.
The odds are long,
pay's good...
but there is one hitch.
lf l get killed, by you,
by accident...
or by De Toro's bunch...
the governor will assume
that you did it...
and he'll track you down
and hang every one of you.
But we'll be in Mexico?
All right, who wants to go?
Walt?
Get the chains off of them.
Right face! March!
You damn fool! Can't you see
what they're thinking?
They'll let you lead them
into Mexico right enough...
then they'll blow your head off
and join De Toro.
l'm sure that's exactly
what they're thinking.
That's all we're taking?
Yeah.
Let's get more men.
Seven's always been
my lucky number.
Damn it, Marshal,
couldn't you have waited...
till you got farther away
from here?
Take them.
Here's a double for you,
Skinner.
You only need one
if you're really good.
Figured you'd like to have that.
Didn't think you'd want one.
Haven't been in a situation
like this lately.
Don't blow your foot off.
Who's the dude?
He takes notes.
He'll write all about you.
All right,
when you're ready, mount up.
Elliot,
you're driving the wagon.
Hear you had a little trouble.
Few of the boys cut me some.
They have good cause?
They thought so.
Warden made me take charge
of a work detail.
Had to build up
a new cell block.
And you built it solid.
You'll be building again.
Stone or brick?
Barbed wire this time.
Hayes!
At your trial, you promised...
you were going to blow
my brains out.
That was the mood of the moment.
l picked you because l need
a man who knows battles.
Not gunfights, battles.
Let's cut through it, Chris.
l'm out and l'm not going back.
You can depend on me.
l hope so.
Let's go.
Why don't we ride in the rear?
l don't like having my back
to this bunch.
lt don't matter.
You won't be able to stop them
once they make their move.
How long do you figure
they'll wait?
This ain't a patient bunch.
This way.
Come on.
Chris, this isn't the way
to Magdalena.
Where are we going?
De Toro's stronghold.
He's not there.
lf he was,
we wouldn't be going there.
That's got to be her.
De Toro's woman.
l hope De Toro's as
proud of her as Laurie said.
Laurie was wrong
about one thing.
He's not completely crazy mad.
Let me see her.
l'll introduce you to her
in time.
How many guards you figure?
Enough to give you your share.
There's a hacienda
just over that hill.
There's a few risks...
but there's enough loot in there
to give you all a fresh start.
You're going to help us
rob a hacienda?
You'll all be rich by morning.
-Rich?
-Wait a minute.
Why are you being so good to us?
l don't think
l'm doing any more for you...
than you'd do for me.
How the hell do you mean that?
Like he says it.
You're on his side?
Kept that prison guard
from busting me with that club.
You damn fool,
he didn't do that for you.
He knew if your ass was busted,
you couldn't ride a horse.
Was that the reason?
Not exactly.
Hold it.
Chris, do you mean that?
We go in there and
we can take anything we want?
That's exactly what l mean.
All right, what's your plan?
l figured
we'd just ride in there...
and shoot down anyone
carrying a gun.
That's sloppy.
Who's in the assault wave?
Who are the reserves?
You have to have flankers.
Suppose you get hit,
who assumes command?
Noah.
l've got better qualifications.
-Relax, Hayes.
-Captain Hayes!
-l've ambushed Apaches.
-Oh, shit.
Anything in this world
is child's play after that.
He's got a good argument there.
All right, Hayes...you.
You all heard that?
Yeah, we heard that...Captain.
All right,
l'll work out some tactics.
Hayes,
you're a pain in the ass.
But a useful one.
Come on, let's go.
Pepe!
Here.
That Gatling gun right up there.
Everybody else gets
a better deal again, Chris?
How come l get the worst job?
Because you're the best
with that.
Am l?
You cross me, Pepe...
and you'll be killing
your friends, too.
Now get going.
Ain't no friends of mine.
Around the gate.
Walt! You got the stable.
Skinner...
got a good one for you.
See those two right there?
Go get them.
Come on!
Take that one alive.
Yeah. We're just leading
damn recruits.
We better give them
a few more minutes...
to get in position.
Hey, amigo.
Pepe!
Pepe! Pepe!
l'll have to get around.
l'll draw their fire.
Pepe!
Where are you?
Aw, hell.
Up here.
Come on.
Noah...
tie her up.
Hayes...
bring me the live one.
Do you speak English?
Now, you go to De Toro...
and you tell him that
l, Chris, degrade his woman.
Skinner.
And you tell him the names...
of the rest of the men
that did this to him.
Pepe Carral...
Walt Drummond...
Andy Hayes...
Scott Elliot, Noah Forbes...
and Mark Skinner.
Now, you got that?
And you tell him that
we'll be waiting for him...
with his woman, at Magdalena.
Now get going!
Stop him!
What the hell you doing, Chris?
You bastards.
You can't go back to the States
because they'll hang you...
and you can't join De Toro...
because
he'll cut your hearts out.
Now we're ready for Magdalena.
They're back!
They've come back!
The marshal, he's come back!
l knew you'd be back.
l want her watched every minute.
She's De Toro's woman.
Martha? You watch her.
You...
come on with me.
l said, come with me.
Who are they?
Volunteers.
They came to help us.
Why?
They're humanitarians.
Get some food in your guts...
then we'll go to work.
Come on.
We'll serve everybody
over in the cantina.
Just bring whatever
you have on the stove.
We haven't got much time,
so listen to me, please.
Will all the women get over
against that wall?
The men against the bar.
Now, we've got two days,
three at the most...
before they get here...
so we'll be working
day and night.
You men will be heading
work parties.
You'll also need the women
to load guns for you...
so pick your partners.
Try to make it mutual, huh?
No.
What about them?
Keep picking till they're gone.
You women will be working,
loading for your men...
feeding them,
taking care of them.
Draw your own lines.
Now, let's unload that wagon.
Long-range target rifles.
This are single shots, Chris.
We need repeaters.
Keep digging.
Watch those sights.
Got Winchester rifles.
Caliber 30-40. Model 1885.
They're brand-new, Captain.
Get the grease out of them.
You'll be able to inspect them
with white gloves.
Ladies, l want boiling water
to get rid of that grease.
Shotgun shells,
1 2-gauge double-ought buckshot.
And official police riot guns.
You would get official
police guns, wouldn't you?
Captain,
tell Pepe what you want.
l'll need you with me.
Come on, Pepe!
Go to hell.
Move!
And take your women with you.
And don't go empty-handed!
Laurie, l need everything
in town that can hold dirt.
Pillow cases,
flour sacks, trouser legs.
Get the women to sew bags
out of anything.
All right, Chris.
All right, come on,
construction foreman.
l'll show you why l brought you.
They'll have to come in
right over there...
and we'll have
to whittle them down.
Those target rifles
have got range...
so we use those
on the first line.
How many do you think
he'll have?
Forty...fifty.
We'll dig a row of pits...
then sight in the rifles
and set out range stakes.
When they pass a stake,
we'll know exactly...
how far away they are
and save misses.
Those pits'll go right in here.
lf his horses are covering...
a hundred yards
every five or six seconds...
that means he'll be here
a minute after we open fire.
That should give us time
for about three rounds.
With seven of us shooting...
we should get about
15 to 20 of them.
Or less.
When they're
about 300 yards away...
we'll start falling back
to the second line.
They're going to be
crawling all over us.
Then we'll have to do
something to stop them...
from crawling all over us, huh?
Plant a series of charges
in these pits.
That'll take care of about
five more of them.
Chris...
when we're retreating,
you have to figure on losses.
With all that lead flying...
odds are
they'll get a couple of us.
Well...then
there'll be five or six of us...
at the second line.
Which five or six?
We'll make the Winchester line
right here.
Same thing--pits.
lf the charge is broken,
they'll take cover.
You can see where they'll go--
those little gullies.
l'll plant charges in them.
You're both as crazy as De Toro.
What makes you think
he'll do everything you want?
He'll charge the first line...
because he's got contempt
for us.
When we fall back
and he sees how few we are...
it'll hurt his pride and
make him charge the second line.
Then what?
Then he'll start being careful.
-And flank us.
-Yeah.
By then, we should have
a third to half his men...
and only lost a few of us.
Wish he'd stop saying that.
They'll be coming in
from all sides.
l'll figure out some stuff.
Wires, charges...
Strong as you can.
But what happens
when they break in here?
We'll put the biggest charge
in the altar in the mission...
and take
those bastards with us.
l wonder if we'll reach water?
Come on, time to eat.
l got to keep working,
get this done.
Put the shovel down.
You gotta have something to eat.
Got to keep up
all that strength.
ls that enough?
Almost.
Getting killed...
will at least
bring us some rest.
lf you can't handle it,
Pepe, go to sleep.
They say...
if a tree
falls in the forest...
and no one hears it...
there's a question of whether
it makes any noise.
lf none of us
lives to tell about this...
can we be covered in glory?
Sure we can.
Feels good to be building again.
We've built good.
Not good enough, maybe, but...
the best we could.
l'm satisfied.
Enough money to last me
my whole lifetime.
Clothes to turn any girl's eyes.
Women for the taking.
And l'll be dead...
before l can enjoy any of it.
Old Chris,
he really had me pegged.
Right from
the first minute we met.
Said l couldn't hold a job.
Boy, he was more right
than he knew.
He must have
seen something else...
or else he wouldn't have
wasted his time on you.
Butterball...
you are looking at
a 14-karat sharpie.
A guy who's always known
all the angles.
None of the principles.
You know a few or else you
wouldn't know the difference.
You're really determined
to make me feel good.
l hope you won't get angry...
but l think we have
enough real problems...
without you hashing over
your old ones.
That's just the point.
l have started knowing
what's real.
For the first time, l know.
This thing...
or any other story...
l can tell it...
because l've learned how
to feel it.
This trip with Chris...
has really taught me
what l've always needed to know.
Now it's too damned late.
Noah said you never had
any children.
Don't you like them?
Sure l like them.
We get along just fine.
Come on.
Down you go.
He said
your wife was very pretty.
Why was he talking
so much about me?
Because l asked him.
Night-night.
Night.
What was your husband like?
You wouldn't have noticed him.
He didn't stand out
very much in a crowd.
l don't mean like that.
He was a good man.
Not much of a farmer.
And no fighter at all.
But he was good to me.
He loved them.
l wasn't unhappy.
Why'd you marry him?
l'd rather talk about you.
You've got enough answers
and l don't have any?
He promised me a better life.
A place of our own.
He kept his promise.
l'm a lousy farmer, too.
And l don't keep promises.
Of course you do.
You promised you'd come
back here and you did.
l don't make a habit out of it.
lf we get through
this thing tomorrow...
l ain't sticking around here.
l know.
Six hundred!
Lower the range!
Let's go!
Let me see!
He'll be coming back
on our flank...
and we won't be able
to hold him.
Get the women out of here!
Go on, girls!
Go!
No!
Get ready!
Pepe, help me!
Come on!
Get up, Pepe! Come on!
They're coming back!
Let's go!
Anything?
From what l can count...
we've already
got about half of them.
They got about half of us.
The odds are the same
as when we started.
Now, everybody sit down.
Sit down on the floor.
Everything.
Come on.
Here. Come on.
No, Chris! No! Please!
Laurie, stop it!
You know
this is the last resort.
Chris! Give her back to him.
Maybe he'll go away.
l would give her back to him...
but she's not important
to him now.
He'd see her in Hell...
before he'd let us
get away with this.
Laurie...
you'll have to decide
for yourself...
and do it or not.
l can't!
All right.
De Toro will let
the children live, won't he?
l don't know what he'll do.
You told me yourself
he was crazy mad.
Laurie...
they're fine kids.
Sorry.
He was a good man.
What was his name?
l never thought to ask.
Didn't seem important.
He wasn't much for talking.
Walt.
Walt Drummond.
On the roof!
Get down!
De Toro!
Oh, Chris!
Hey, Chris...
Where's my pardon?
This town needs a sheriff,
Skinner.
lnterested?
Ain't much of a town.
Three men and
a passel of women and kids.
The women are scarce
in this part of the country.
Men'll come.
Why not?
Chris! l ever tell you
l was born in Salt Lake?
l'm a Mormon.
Noah?
Guess l won't be coming
this way again.
The sheriff here's
an old enemy of mine.
lf you behaved yourself...
you wouldn't get
into any trouble.
You put him up to that.
-l did not.
-The hell you didn't!
They've grown used to you,
that's all.
Yeah, well, kids pick up
bad habits easy.
So do adults.
l ain't making no promises.
Who asked you to?
Skinner!
You just been demoted
to deputy!
Well, that figures.
Wouldn't have had much time
for work anyway.