CIMARRON KID
Glavne uloge
Režija
WARDEN: Hate gets
under a man's skin.
Spoils his whole life.
lt's like a bad growth, Kid.
You've got to get rid of it.
Yes, sir.
l'm for you.
You know that,
or else l wouldn't
have worked so hard
to get you paroled.
l know that, sir.
l've got one last piece
of advice for you.
Stay away from
the Dalton gang.
They're my friends,
Warden.
l never rode with them,
but they're still my friends.
You've got a job waiting
for you at Major Halsell's
HX bar ranch.
Thanks.
That's your country, Doolin,
Cimarron River Country.
Right.
There's a train ticket here
for Oklahoma City.
You'll be there in
a couple of days,
then take the train
for Guthrie.
All right, sir.
The HX is only about
eight miles out of
Guthrie, isn't it?
About six.
You know,
l think l'll keep this as
a present from you to me.
All right.
lt's all yours, Warden.
Good luck to you, Kid,
and stay out of trouble.
And remember,
a parole can be
a very temporary thing.
Goodbye, Mr. Gans.
Lots of luck, Doolin.
Thank you.
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
On your feet,
everybody!
Come on, come on!
All right, folks,
start filling the sack.
l'll take that, too.
You can sit down, ma'am.
Come on, hand it over.
All right,
everything, mister!
BlTTER CREEK:
Just keep it going steady!
All right,
don't be bashful.
Hand it over.
Well, what do you know?
Hey! Ain't this
your little friend?
Shut up!
Sorry, sonny,
he's always making
some mistake.
All right, give it
two blasts now!
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWS TWlCE)
We've got you
dead to rights.
l've been watching you
and you're one of them.
(ALL SHOUTlNG)
These letters from his valise
prove that Doolin
was on that train.
Marshal, what more
evidence do you want?
You're a good detective,
Swanson,
but you can't persuade me
that finding Doolin's bag
on a train
convicts him
just like that.
l got 10 witnesses who
will swear against him!
What'll they swear?
That he was part
of the Dalton fix
on that train!
lf you remember, Doolin
was convicted before,
and sentenced.
Railroaded might be
a better word.
l don't like that,
Marshal.
But l happen
to like the Kid,
Swanson.
l've known him
a long time.
There's nothing
bad about him.
As attorney
for the railroad,
l can say, frankly,
that we want to be
fair with Doolin.
l've hesitated to
obtain a warrant
against him.
l'd rather leave it
up to you, Marshal,
to bring him here,
just for a talk.
About what, Mr. Thompson?
Just some questions
about the Daltons,
that's all.
All right.
But you've got to
promise me he gets
a square deal.
He will.
Good day, Marshal.
Good day, sir.
Bill Doolin!
Hi, Bill.
Good to see you again,
Marshal.
Same here. Do you mind
riding in to Guthrie?
What for?
A railroad detective there
wants to ask you
some questions.
Swanson?
Yeah.
Wants to talk to you
about that train robbery
a couple of days ago.
Says it was the Daltons.
Says you're part of the
outfit.
You know that isn't true.
l believe you.
Are you gonna be
at this meeting?
Well, l wish l could, Bill,
but l've gotta catch a train
for Oklahoma City
in just about an hour.
But l want you to go
in there by yourself.
Set them straight
about the holdup.
Tell them all you know.
All right.
l'll just tell them the truth.
They'll be waiting for you
in Lawyer Thompson's office.
See you soon, Bill,
and thanks.
My name's Doolin.
l think Mr. Thompson
wants to see me.
Oh, yes.
Will you go in, please?
l'm glad you came in,
Mr. Doolin.
My name's Thompson.
How do you do?
l believe you know
Mr. Swanson?
Yes.
You two gentlemen will
have to excuse me.
l have some legal
work at court.
l'll see you later.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Take off your hat.
Sit down.
Now, let's start fresh.
Let bygones be bygones.
l wasn't to blame for
what happened to you.
(GRUNTlNG)
All right, get out!
All right, Kid.
Now you and me are gonna
have a nice little family
conference.
Where are the Daltons
hiding out?
l got nothing to say
to you, mister.
You ride with them.
You're one of them.
You were with them
on that last job!
Stop trying to frame
me again, Swanson.
l served my time.
Yeah, and you'll serve
a lot more, 20 years.
Unless you can tell me
where to pick up the Daltons.
And another thing, when l do,
you'll testify against them
in court!
You hear that?
ln court!
You're no good, Swanson.
You never was any good.
What was your cut on
that last Dalton job?
l got no cut.
You'll never make
a story like that
stand up in court.
Don't tell me
what l can't do!
You know,
l'm not very smart.
There's a $10,000 reward
for the capture of Bob Dalton.
You can have
that full 10,000.
All right!
You're good for
a return journey
to that state prison,
unless you make
a deal with me,
right here and now.
l'll kick your brains
all over this room!
Hey, Dynamite!
Dynamite!
Come on up!
Then you can take your nap!
There ain't nothing around
here within 50 miles.
TULSA: Certainly wish someone
could cheer the Kid up.
Hey, Bitter Creek,
maybe you could
cheer him up.
Yep, looks like we got
a worrier on our hands.
He's been sitting
that way for an hour.
lt's just that l can't
make up my mind
what to do.
GRAT: Looks to me
like you don't have
much choice, Kid.
Don't forget
you broke your parole
and mussed up
a couple of detectives.
Want to know what
Bob Dalton thinks?
l think you ought
to throw in with us.
Bob, maybe if l saw
Marshal Sutton, maybe...
Oh, he can't square
nothing for you, Kid.
You got too many charges
stacked against you.
Looks like you're riding
the same colored horse
as us Daltons.
You ain't no free
agent no more,
and you can't move
around like one.
Why, you're caught
in a trap,
and break out
or stay in,
either way,
they got you.
And another thing,
that fellow Swanson's
an avenging fool.
Why, l was ranching
out in California and doing
good for myself, too.
Suddenly this railroad
dick rides up
and accuses me
of being leader
in a train holdup.
Why, l had to break
jail to get here.
Which goes to prove
something, Kid.
lf Red Buck there
hadn't popped his mouth
off in the train,
you wouldn't be
in this fix now.
All right, Moore,
all right.
l already said l was sorry.
What do you want me to do?
Keep on saying it?
Oh, Red's a tough hombre
in the clinches, all right,
but he ain't very clever.
(CHUCKLES)
He don't think so fast,
neither.
No, only the Daltons
are clever.
The brain kids.
Think fast all the time.
That's right, Red.
You never said nothing
truer in all your life.
Why, even our little brother,
Will, there, is smarter than
you,
and he hasn't joined up
with us yet.
(ALL CHUCKLlNG)
Outside of us
fellas here,
has anybody ever heard
of the name Red Buck?
Maybe they will
after tomorrow.
Oh, you ain't going on
the Coffeyville raid.
Since when?
Since now.
How come?
Well, it's like l said, Red,
you don't think very fast.
You're tough,
but you don't think
fast enough.
Anything else?
Yeah. You don't shoot
so good, neither.
Know somebody better?
Kid, you got a minute?
Come on.
Don't make me out
a liar, Kid.
Come on, Red.
Go ahead, Bill!
This better be good.
(GUN FlRlNG)
MAN 1 : Now that's shooting!
MAN 2: That's enough
for me, Kid.
MAN 3: Tulsa!
Hey, Dynamite!
Red'll be the boss
at lndependence.
You take your orders
from him.
Does he tell me how
to blow up a county
courthouse safe?
He'll be the leader,
that's no fooling.
All right, leader!
That's a raw deal
you handed me, Bob.
Oh, l don't think so,
Red.
You always wanted
to be a leader and
now you are.
Second division.
(ALL LAUGH)
l ain't gonna be
aced out of my share
of Coffeyville!
You'll get it! So will
Dynamite and Tulsa.
Now, you'll be leveling
at lndependence
the same time as us
at Coffeyville.
So do a neat job
and get away fast.
We're all of us heading
back here, ain't we?
Well, we're not expecting
any trouble, but if we do,
why, we figure
they'll throw out
a big net for us.
And Bob was sort
of figuring...
l kind of figured that...
Well, they'd be
expecting us to
head for here,
so why don't we
cross them up?
We'll go straight to
Pat Roberts' cow ranch.
Yeah, well, maybe
Pat Roberts don't
like us anymore.
l understand he's turned
honest in a big way.
Oh, Pat's all right.
Don't you worry about him.
lf we get in trouble,
he'll help us out.
Now, l guess you fellows
better get saddled up.
Thanks.
l don't think Red
likes you very much.
(LAUGHlNG)
Quite a hideout,
ain't it?
Ain't no peace officer
gonna trail us in here
without he gets lost
or belted around
by a lot of lead.
Hey, Stacey,
think you could
rustle us up a couple
of covered wagons?
Sure can.
Clothes for six of us,
make us look like
emigrants on the trail?
Gotcha.
All right.
Then you meet us
outside Ouachita.
You know the spot
in the Cherokee Strip.
Sure do.
And better bring along
some medicines, too,
just in case.
l always carry them,
Will, you tag along
here with Stacey.
Oh, Bob, you promised.
l know l did,
but not yet.
You're too young.
Coffeyville is too tough.
You're elected, Kid.
This job calls for
six of us.
You should've taken Red.
Oh, no.
He's too ambitious.
He wants to make
a reputation all
on his own in a hurry.
Kid, this Coffeyville deal
is really gonna
be something big.
Double bank holdup
in broad daylight!
More money than
you ever dreamed of
getting your hands on
in your whole life.
Why, they'll be
writing ballads about
us Daltons after this.
lt's bigger than anything
them James boys
ever dreamed up.
Just think of it!
Two banks at the same time.
After this one,
l'm going far away.
Argentina. No fooling.
Gonna buy me
a cattle ranch there.
MOORE: There's a new world
for a man like me.
Nobody to know
l was ever an outlaw,
and no fear of somebody
taking a potshot at me
just to get a reputation
for himself.
Yes, sir, after this one,
l'm taking myself right off
to Argentina.
Bob, l don't think the Kid's
got the real picture
of Coffeyville yet.
This is really something.
Something me and Bob
has timed and timed.
Here's the way
she's gonna go, Kid.
We'll pull
out of here tonight
as soon as it gets dark.
At 8:00 in the morning,
we'll be in the outskirts
of Coffeyville.
Bob's timed our entrance
to the very second.
Now, we split up
and enter town from
the opposite directions,
passing each other
on the main street
at exactly 8:45.
Me and Grat and Big Jim,
we're riding your horses.
We tie up across from
the Coffeyville Bank.
Now you and Emmett
and Bitter Creek,
you're riding our horses.
You tie up across
from the Union Bank.
The bank opens for business
at 9:00 sharp.
But the cashiers and
the rest of the help,
they gets there at 8:45.
All except
Mr. Vice President Jergens
of the Coffeyville Bank.
He gets there at 8:50.
8:50 exactly, just as
regular as clockwork.
Now. Just when he goes
to unlock the door...
(WHlSTLlNG)
MAN: Hey, Ed!
Hi, Joe.
Got a minute?
l'll be right with you.
Morning, fellows.
Don't get excited,
Mr. Jergens.
We're going in with you.
Get over there.
Sit down!
Let's see your hands!
All right, all of you,
come out of there.
Back in that corner!
Which one of you's
the head cashier?
CASHlER: l am, sir.
Come on.
Open it!
You've got just
about 30 seconds!
Open that door
and walk in quietly.
All right, walk over
to the corner. Move!
Open up that safe.
l'm afraid
that's impossible.
That safe works
on a time lock,
it opens at 8:55.
All right, we'll wait.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Who's that? Speak up!
Mr. Jergens.
Bank robbery!
Come on! Let's
get out of here!
Come on, you.
Move out straight
down the street and
nobody's gonna get hurt.
Come on, move!
(GUN FlRlNG)
Come on.
They're still
at the bank.
Get on back, Bob!
(GROANS)
l can't make it, kids!
Get going.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
What do you know?
lt's Bob Dalton.
(GUN FlRlNG)
(NElGHlNG)
Hi, Kid.
Hello, Stacey.
Kid!
My brothers!
All of them?
ROSE: Bitter!
What's the matter?
lt ain't much, honey.
Why didn't you
say something?
What'd you want me
to do, Bill?
Stay in Coffeyville
and get it bandaged?
Rose, you sure you
don't want me to...
No, Stacey.
Not with Bitter Creek.
Hang on, honey.
Not a sign or smell of them,
despite all these reports.
Everybody's hunting
for them here
around the Five Nations
lndian Territory,
down near lngalls.
Well, maybe the Daltons
figured it that way
and decided to cross us up
around here.
Let's see, they moved
south from Kansas
up here, and west,
that's sparsely settled
country there,
just a few ranchers.
Hey, l know one or two
cattlemen there.
One of them might be
interesting to talk to.
l'll go with you, Marshal.
At least
my lndependence deal
worked out all right.
We got the cash.
All right.
So now we're gonna go
right back to Coffeyville
and stick up them two banks.
This time, if the citizens
give us any trouble,
we're gonna shoot up
the whole town.
Red, you're crazy.
Don't you tell me.
l wouldn't go through that
Coffeyville thing again for
all the gold in Kansas.
What's the matter, Kid?
Afraid?
No.
Well, then, l think you'd
better give us a reason.
l don't believe in
unnecessary killing.
Oh! He don't believe in
unnecessary killings!
(CHUCKLlNG) Well, now,
ain't that too bad?
And there'd be plenty
of it on both sides
if we went back there.
You coming with me?
Bill's right.
lf we went back there,
they'd shoot us to pieces!
l'm agreeing
with the Kid.
So am l.
Me, too.
Well, Red, speaking as
an innocent bystander,
l'd say you've
been overruled.
All right.
All right! Maybe we should
just throw away our guns
altogether.
Maybe we should
just forget that
the law is chasing us.
Well, let me
tell you something.
From now on,
l'm making all the rules.
l got a rule of my own
it might do you good
to remember.
There'll be no killing
unless it's forced on us.
Course, this might
be one of them times,
like l said.
Well, men, it looks
like we got ourself
a new leader.
(DOGS BARKlNG)
l wonder who
that could be.
Where do we go, Pat?
The stables.
(CHUCKLlNG)
Well, John Sutton!
Glad to see you.
Same here, Pat.
lt's been a long time.
l want you to meet
a friend of mine,
Sam Swanson.
How are you?
Hello.
You remember
my daughter.
How do you do?
How do you do, ma'am?
Mr. Swanson.
Well, l'll lay a bet
there's something
mighty important
brings you
all the way out here.
lt is. The Daltons.
What about the Daltons?
You got two new
wagons there, Pat?
No, no. l was
just keeping them
for a friend.
Wait here.
Would you care to come
inside, Mr. Swanson?
No, thank you,
l'll wait here.
This probably
won't take long.
Mind if l look
in your barn?
Of course not.
The Daltons raided
Coffeyville.
You ain't heard
about it, eh?
No. lt's the first time.
l suppose they...
They got slaughtered.
All but two of them.
(HORSE NElGHS)
Hey, you you've got
a lot of stock here,
Pat.
Well, l've been
a little lucky.
What's eating you, John?
l've been on both
sides of the law,
and l'd feel complimented
if you sort of laid the cards
on the table.
All right, Pat. l said
two of them got away.
You think they
might be here?
l didn't say that, Pat.
Could be, though.
There's no sense
in us talking in
the dark like this.
One of them answers
to the name of the
Cimarron Kid.
That name doesn't spell
anything to me. l'm sorry.
Would you recognize it
if l spelled it to read
Doolin?
Bill Doolin?
That name does
sound familiar.
Though l don't know
where or what for.
Well, l'll be going.
Glad to know you're
doing pretty good in
the cattle business, Pat.
PAT: Thanks, it's building.
Maybe some day
l'll have something.
Oh, this fellow
l mentioned,
this Doolin,
if you ever see him...
When you see him,
tell him l said thanks
for giving me an edge.
Tell him also,
l'm sure sorry l have to
keep on going after him.
Although he's riding
the wrong horse now,
maybe it's because he's
had a cold deck shuffle
all the way down the line.
And maybe it ain't too late
to make a deal.
Yeah, 50 years.
Of course, l can't
guarantee anything.
Pat, you've been a good,
law-abiding citizen since
you took this place over,
but harboring outlaws
is obstructing justice,
in case you didn't know it.
So long.
Let's go.
ls the Kid in there?
l'll tell you this,
we're lucky to be
leaving this place alive.
lf you don't kill a man
that's hunting you when
you get the chance,
he's gonna kill you some day.
That's a superstition l got.
Keep it to yourself.
Boys, l'm afraid
you'll have to go.
Come daylight, there'll
be a dozen deputies
swarming around here.
They'll stake out
this place for months.
l've been straight since
l came to the territory
from Texas
and l want to
keep on that way.
All l ask...
You won't be bothered
with us anymore, Pat.
That's a promise.
As a matter of fact,
we're pulling out
right now.
Saddle up.
Yeah, let's get going, boys.
Thanks a million, Pat.
lt's been nice
seeing you again, Pat.
How does it feel
to be honest?
l'll do it.
l'll ride up on
the back with you.
Honey, you ain't going.
Don't ever say that, ever!
l go with you, always.
But this is too dangerous.
l know.
lt's a bad life
and a bad way to live.
But l go with you.
Can l talk to you?
Sure.
Straight talk?
Yeah.
l know that a man
don't like a woman
who preaches to him,
tells him what to do
and how to run
his life and all that.
But l listened to what you
said inside the house and
it made sense.
About gunplay
and all that.
Why don't you
give it up?
lt's too late
for that now.
What do you think
you're gonna get
out of all this?
Money.
To spend on yourself?
For gambling?
For a girl?
None of them things.
What, then?
Land.
Land? Where?
A place far away.
l once heard a fellow
talking about a place
called Argentina.
He said with the proper
amount of money,
you could build yourself
a big cattle ranch there.
He also said,
you might even figure to
start yourself a new life.
Listen to me.
You're crazy.
You're all crazy!
Rose and Bitter Creek.
She should leave him,
but she won't, because
she's in love,
and all the time they're
heading straight to death
on a dark road.
You, too. You're
on that same road!
Excuse me, Miss Carrie.
Well, good luck.
Thanks.
Until next time.
Next time?
There's a new cattle town
called Boonesville.
Dad and l go there whenever
he's cattle to sell.
Boonesville.
l'll remember it.
STACEY: Go well, Kid.
What's the matter, Stace?
Aren't you coming with us?
lf it's all the same to you,
l'd rather not this time.
l'd just like
to go on home.
l don't blame you.
Come on.
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
(GUNS FlRlNG)
Now, notice one thing
about the Kid's operations.
The way he moves around.
He circles wide.
Never repeats a town.
Dives east, then west.
l'm putting a detective
in every town where
the rails go through.
lt'll be a big net.
Maybe we can pull in
the fish that way.
You'll have to get
the rail companies
to stand the expense.
All right?
l think it can
be arranged.
lf it can be arranged,
and it should be,
this is exactly
what l want to do.
We'll put one man here,
one man at Pawnee
one man at Seminole...
Coffee.
Northbound train,
10:42 p.m.
Stationmaster name
of Billingsley.
About 50,
not too tough.
KlD: How big is the haul?
Payroll.
Railroad section workers
going up to Chickasaw.
$18,000.
The way she wangles
information out of people.
(BLOWS KlSS)
Rose, you're wonderful.
You know, that Swanson
fellow is really gonna
learn to hate us...
What happened to
your Guadalupe?
lt must've gotten torn off
in that last raid.
l looked all over
for it, Rose.
l keep telling her
l shouldn't wear
one of these things.
lt just doesn't seem right.
l mean, with me...
lt's right for me
to pray for you.
Rose thinks it
helps protect me.
l'm just lucky.
l don't know, Bitter.
Maybe it does help.
l used to believe that...
lt helps me, Bill.
Not him.
lt helps me to believe
that maybe l can plan on
something else someday.
Excuse me.
Hello, Bill. l came
into town with Dad.
He just sold
a herd of cattle,
so we'll be starting...
We'll be getting run over
if we don't get
out of the street.
Aren't you taking
an awful chance being
seen in a town like this?
No more than
any other town.
Besides, l wanted
to come here, Carrie.
l hoped l'd get
a chance to talk to you,
but l don't know.
Don't get panicky.
Who's panicky?
Let's look at these pretty
doodads over here.
Let's go inside.
CLERK: Howdy, folks.
What can l do for you?
KlD: We're just
looking around...
CARRlE: We're looking
for some jewelry, please.
Oh, jewelry. Yes.
Just one minute, please.
You see, our... Our
jewelry department
is way over here.
Now, what kind of jewelry?
Rings, engagement rings.
Of course.
Sure enough
must be spring.
You're the third
couple this week.
Now. Here you are.
Lover's knots, hearts
and forget-me-nots,
diamonds in every one.
Oh, this is
the one we want.
lsn't this beautiful,
darling?
Yes.
How much is that?
Sixty dollars, even.
Ain't you two
got more to do
than stand around
and stare at folks?
l've got more to do.
l'd like to know your name.
KlD: l don't think
that's anyone's business,
including yours.
MAN: l'm bound to
make it my business.
(LAUGHlNG)
Well, Johnny Adams,
are you in luck!
l just made a big,
fat, juicy deal!
And it means
a lot of money
in the bank for me.
And son,
you're gonna find me
the best father-in-law
a boy ever had!
Let me see that ring.
Well, honey,
that's beautiful!
Dad, the day's gonna come
when the Adams family
will own more cattle
than you ever
dreamed about.
That won't make me mad,
Johnny.
No, sir, you two kids
go right ahead
and be happy.
Excuse us.
They're gonna keep
a mighty sharp lookout
for anything, Kid.
l wouldn't be surprised.
So l wouldn't try anything.
lt's off, as of right now.
You're smart, Kid.
Maybe you'd better
ride with us.
lt'll look better.
Thanks. Thanks, Pat.
Wait a minute.
What about the ring?
lt's all yours.
Thank you.
He's young-enough
looking.
And too innocent.
Adams.
Johnny Adams.
Just to be on the safe side,
let's send a telegram
to the boss.
lf he wants to
alert everybody,
that's up to him.
We had Doolin in
the palm of our hands
at Boonesville,
and a couple of my stupid men
let him get away.
Well, here's the situation
as of right now.
Marshal Johnston
is around Pawnee.
McWilliams is moving in
from Seminole.
This wire from Sutton
just came in.
Says he's picked up
a warm trail
at Drumright.
He's maneuvering the Kid
so that he has to go to
Columbia.
l'd say that
looks good.
l'd like to think so.
Fact is we've worn out
a dozen posses already.
Just so we keep
the quarry in sight,
there's always a chance.
l got a feeling
this is the time.
This is the killing!
We ought to be hearing
from Rose pretty soon.
lt's getting pretty
tough on her, Bill.
Every place
we head for is
being watched.
Gotta hand it
to her, though.
Don't know what
we'd do without her.
Sure is a swell
gal to know.
Yeah, l'll bet she is.
What do you
wanna bet, Red?
Well, maybe a belly
full of bullets.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
There's about 10 of them, Kid.
They picked me off the rock.
l didn't even see them.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
(CHlLDREN GlGGLlNG)
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
All right, now. lt's
time for you children
to go to bed.
Hey, ain't you
forgetting something?
Mmm-hmm.
(KlSSES)
She's my little princess.
They're wonderful kids.
How's the farming,
Stacey?
Oh, cotton crop
failed this year.
Broom corn, sorghum crop,
they ain't doing so good
neither.
Well, there's nothing
that money won't cure.
We'll be leaving
something with you
when we go.
Look, you fellows
come by your money
the hardest way there is.
STACEY: l can't
take it from you.
lf we want to
give you money,
you'll take it, Stacey.
Not out of my share
he ain't getting any.
lt's just like he says.
We come by our money
the hard way.
lf he don't want it,
he shouldn't have to
take it.
l'm in for a
piece of that.
What'll we make it,
3,000?
Yeah, that's good.
All right by me.
Same here.
Like it or not,
you're in, Red.
STACEY: Where you
fellas heading for?
Well, it looks like
Columbia, Stacey.
First, we're waiting
to pick up a message.
l sure do like
that little town.
Drink a little,
gamble a little,
boy, that's something.
l remember riding
through it that day
after we left the hideout.
Bob,
and Emmett, Grat.
WlLL: They sure figured
they'd get back there again.
ROSE: Now, you're sure
it's safe?
Of course it's safe.
Everybody here was
friendly with Bob Dalton.
They'll like the Kid, too.
No reason why not.
l've got plenty of room
in my hotel for everybody.
How big is
the Kid's outfit?
Five. Six, including me.
(CHUCKLES)
You tell him Lola Plummer
will give him
the key to the city.
Well, he ain't
much on ceremony,
but l'll tell him.
l thought you might like
a little more tea before
you go, Miss Rose.
No, thank you,
but l'll see you later.
Bye, ma'am, Charlie.
Bye.
$10,000 reward
is a lot of money,
ain't it, Jed?
Mr. Swanson?
Mr. Swanson it is.
Boy, they sure ain't
got no brass band out
to greet us!
Jed! Give yourself up!
SUTTON: We've got
a crossfire on you,
15 against your five.
lt's John Sutton.
What'd l once tell you?
Shut up!
SUTTON: Get smart, Bill.
You're at the end
of your rope.
Why all the debate, Marshal?
l promise you
a fair trial, Kid!
l heard that once before.
Well, Bill, it looks like
we're gonna have to
come in and get you!
KlD: Don't make any mistakes!
You know, this has got
a chance of getting
a little rough.
Hold it!
Man, l hope
they want trouble.
Rose, get down
and get inside.
KlD: Thanks, John.
Now l guess you'll have
to come and get us.
Thanks.
lt wasn't me, Rose.
lt was Mrs. Plummer.
They all come here
in them wagons.
There ain't a saddle
horse among them.
Look, if you can make it
through the roundhouse,
the country opens up
behind it.
Kid, we got a chance!
Don't shoot!
(GUN FlRES)
Thanks for nothing.
You fool!
(GUNS FlRlNG)
(NElGHlNG)
Rose! Grab that switch
on the turntable!
(GUNS FlRlNG)
lf they ever get that
turntable into place,
we're licked.
l'll try to get on the
other side of the train.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
(BULLETS RlCOCHETlNG)
(WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
On back, Red!
(GUNS FlRlNG)
Why, that lucky...
You're the lucky one!
He could've shot you
right between the eyes.
This place used to be
a lot of fun.
KlD: That's right, Will.
l don't guess l ever brought
anybody any good luck.
l didn't mean that, Bill.
Oh, forget it.
Coffee?
No, thanks.
How do you
feel, Kid?
Same. lt ain't just this
anymore, Bitter.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
That's the signal!
CARRlE: Hello, Bill.
l was so frightened, Bill.
She sure did a heap
of persuading,
getting me to
bring her up here.
Course, l was gonna
drop in on you anyway.
Thanks, Stacey.
Miss Carrie?
Let me take
a look at you.
Mmm-hmm.
He's all right.
Gonna be all right,
Miss Carrie.
Somebody did a mighty
fine job of fixing.
Shucks, Stacey, l been
a good fixer ever since
l was 1 2 years old.
That's all they
ever let me do.
Yeah?
Course, l guess
some of them things
you just can't fix.
lt's such a nice day.
Why are we all in here?
Especially now that
Bill has company.
Will?
Bill,
once before l asked
to talk to you straight.
This time l want
to level even more.
All right.
Go ahead and level.
l'm not a little
farm girl, Bill.
l've grown up with
your kind of men and
l've always hated them.
Until now.
Now that l've changed
my mind about that,
l've become selfish enough
to think maybe l deserve
a better break.
We've never talked
about us before.
But we both know that
we've got a chance for
the first time in our lives
for some happiness.
For some of the things
real people live for.
What are you trying
to say, Carrie?
Get well and get
out of here, Bill.
Cross the border,
find the land you want,
and then send for me.
With what?
Dad says he'll
sell the ranch.
That's out.
Tell Pat l said thanks.
All right, Bill.
l'll tell him that.
lt's not that l don't
appreciate it,
it's just that...
lt's just that you're
too proud to be helped.
The Cimarron Kid.
The country's most
notorious robber.
So clever that you
end up here in this
cold, filthy cave
with a bullet hole
in your side.
You sure leveled.
l had to, Bill.
Maybe someday
you'll know l'm right.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
Hey, Bill! lt's Dynamite!
He breathes, he talks.
He ain't even dead!
Anyway...
Man, was l hungry!
Anyway, although the fall
knocked me out,
that cold water
was a lifesaver.
l laid low for awhile
till the posse went by.
l climbed up this hill
and saw some Mexican
cowboys
herding a bunch of cattle
all the way to Dallas.
They fixed me up and
l hid out with them.
l decided to go along.
(EXCLAlMS)
Man, that Dallas is
an exciting town!
Yeah, go ahead!
Make me jealous!
Boy, oh, boy!
What a time l had me!
Seriously, though,
who do you think
l met there?
General Grant!
Go ahead. Tell.
My brother-in-law.
Fellow named Weber.
George Weber.
Married to
my favorite sister.
You know, the last time
l saw him was in lllinois.
He was working
for the railroad.
So?
He's been stationed
in the Southwest
a couple of years.
And with plenty of larceny
in his heart.
WlLL: Still in the railroad
business, l suppose?
Express company messenger
on the run from Galveston,
Texas,
to Newton, Kansas.
And?
Twice a month,
an American mining
company in Mexico
sends three bars of
gold bullion by train.
From Galveston to
the U.S. Mint at Denver.
How much are they worth?
Each bar weighs in
the neighborhood of
90 pounds.
Total value,
about 100,000!
(WHlSTLES)
Keep talking.
Each bar is expressed in a box
and the box is nailed tight,
bound with metal strips
and sealed.
But this time when
they arrive in Denver,
there ain't gonna be
no gold in those boxes.
Lead.
You catch on fast.
When is the switch made?
ln transit,
as the saying goes.
BlTTER CREEK: By you?
By the master himself.
The old safe dynamiter
from lllinois.
Do you believe
in this scheme?
l believe in
my brother-in-law.
He says
it's bulletproof.
lt's worked out
to the last detail.
How does it go?
He said
he'll give it to us
only if you play ball.
His way.
What does he
want out of it?
One-fifth.
How many men?
Weber, four of us.
How about you, Stacey?
No thanks, Kid.
You better count me out.
Like l said before,
l'll stay around here and
take care of the horses.
Listen, you couldn't come
across anything better in
a lifetime of trying.
Maybe it's too good.
All right,
l'll answer questions.
You say you met
this Weber, this...
Brother-in-law.
ln Dallas, huh?
He's on a month's
vacation.
Can we talk to him?
Sure. l'll get
him for you.
All right. Will?
WlLL: Yeah?
How'd you like to ride
along with Dynamite?
That's for me!
Come on.
lt's the only way out
for me, Carrie.
Maybe this Weber deal
will be the last one.
Maybe.
Maybe it'll mean our land,
cattle, Argentina.
Maybe, Bill.
l'll ride on down the hill
with Will and Dynamite.
lf it works out,
l'll come for you.
Yes, Bill.
Nothing is going to happen
to you and Carrie, Bill.
Just like nothing is
going to ever happen
to Bitter Creek and me.
(GUN FlRlNG)
(COCKS GUN)
(HORSE APPROACHlNG)
Hi, Stacey.
Hi.
Down we go.
Bill, they are back!
A little uncomfortable.
l'm sorry we had to
do that, Mr. Weber.
That's all right.
l know you fellows got
to protect yourselves.
Sit down.
Thanks.
Dynamite only told us
part of the layout.
That's all he knowed
to tell you.
Are you telling us
the rest of it?
When l know
you'll go into it,
and deal on
the level with me.
How much time
do you have on
your vacation?
Two weeks.
l wonder if you'd mind
being our guest.
Not at all.
lf we can get together
on this deal,
we'll have lots
to talk about.
Yeah, l know you're
good at your business,
but this job calls
for a railroad man.
Fair enough.
Now that Mr. Weber's
gonna be our guest,
l think you boys
ought to show him
around the place.
We wouldn't want him
to fall off the mountain
in the dark, would we?
l get you.
He sounds all right,
but just the same...
Rose ought to
go to Dallas.
Right.
Make a good
check on Weber.
lt's important.
You want to
bet l won't?
(SlNGlNG) Come and sit
by my side if you love me
Do not hasten
to bid me adieu
And remember
the Red River Valley
Oh, Silk!
Oh!
Well, well!
Somebody left the
Golden Gate open and
one of the angels got out.
Who is this, Stella?
My neighbor
at the hotel.
My name is
Conchita Martinez, senor.
And this character
with all the teeth
and the pretty smile
is called Silk Conrad,
among other things.
He's a gambler by trade,
and a woman-fancier by
profession.
You talk very nicely,
Senor Silk.
Talking to you makes
nice talk easy.
This is Conchita's
first day in Dallas.
Oh, this calls for
a celebration! Eddie!
Champagne.
Champagne?
But of course!
He likes to show off,
too, darling.
Why, when we're alone,
l have to drink beer.
This Dallas of yours is
very beautiful, senor.
And so are you, angel.
My George is
the only one who ever
told me that before.
Want to go back
to beer, honey?
No, let it ride.
But l'm hurt.
l'll bet he's crazy
about you.
He tells me all the time.
And you?
l mean, about him.
The same, l think.
l wouldn't want
to make a mistake.
Perhaps l know him.
What's the rest
of his name?
Weber. You know him?
George Weber? Sure!
He works for the railroad.
That's him.
You know him well?
Why, l should.
He leaves his wages
at my poker table
every payday.
He has no money, yes?
(CONRAD LAUGHS)
He has no money, no.
Oh.
Not enough to keep you
rigged out the way
you should be.
With jewels and everything.
Why, he couldn't even
buy you a hair ribbon.
But he will get
some money someday.
Yes, he told me once
he expected to make
a killing.
l never saw a man so
desperate for a bankroll.
But now, maybe
l know the reason.
Maybe ''maybe''
might be too late.
Looks to me, Conchita,
like you picked
the wrong man.
Perhaps.
But any man who is
desperate for money
will get it for me.
We will drink.
(BELL CLANGlNG)
Excuse me, mister.
Got a light?
Yeah, sure!
Thanks very much.
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWS)
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
Hi, Kid.
Hello.
We go to work.
There's your lead.
Where are the tools?
Right here.
Make yourself
at home.
We're gonna be rich.
(WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
Now you be careful.
l never did like
this setup.
You be careful.
l should never
let you come along.
l always want
to be with you.
lt makes me happy.
So don't be selfish.
Bitter?
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWS)
1 1 :28. We'll be at the
lumber yard pretty soon.
l'm ready.
Come on, lumber yard.
This thing's getting heavy.
(GUN FlRlNG)
Hey, this'd be kind of
nice for my little girl.
Let's get him out of here.
(TELEGRAPH CLlCKlNG)
Hello, ma'am.
l'm the wife of the
chief deputy out there.
He would like that sent
right through, please.
All right.
Glad to help out
the law anytime.
Thank you.
(TELEGRAPH CLlCKlNG)
(WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
Watch your feet.
(THUDDlNG)
You know, when they open
these boxes in Denver,
they're sure to pick me up.
What can they prove?
Nothing.
That's right.
l'll deny all knowledge
of the robbery.
''Me?'' l'll say.
''Gentlemen, them boxes
wasn't opened when
l was guarding them.''
You said it, brother.
''Absolutely, mortally
impossible.''
You said it!
''They must've been
tampered with
''before they was
put on the train
in Galveston.
''Blame it on
somebody in Mexico!''
That's what l'll say.
''Not me.''
(WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
Here comes
the trestle.
WEBER: Let her go!
(THUDDlNG)
(GUNS FlRlNG)
Yeah?
MAN: George Weber?
Yeah.
Telegram for you,
Mr. Weber.
Stick it through
the door.
How much further
to the lake, George?
Oh, we got lots
of time. Relax.
Let's go over our
rendezvous again, Kid.
When the train slows down
for the water stop,
you throw the gold
and jump.
You hide the bar,
then you walk
around the lake to
Lou Carter's place.
Even if they know you,
they'll never recognize
you in that outfit.
Eh, Dynamite?
That's right.
You're gonna tell them
that your rig broke down.
You mind if l see
that telegram, George?
l can't do it, Kid,
company business.
l'd like to have
a look at it anyway.
Oh, George
it's all right.
Thought you said
this was company business.
Well, l said that because
it's all Greek to me.
l don't know anybody
by the name of C. Rose.
Sure, you do.
Cimarron Rose.
Remember?
Oh, that's who it is.
l don't know why
she'd send a wire
like that to me.
She meant it for me,
Weber.
She gambled l'd see it.
They've already
got Bitter Creek
and probably Will Dalton.
l'm next.
Then Dynamite.
ls that the way
it is, Weber?
Kid, l swear
l don't know
anything about it.
Maybe it's
some other way.
How about it,
Dynamite?
Oh, snap out of it, Kid.
What did Swanson offer
for all of us?
Ten thousand?
Twenty? Thirty? Fifty?
Come over and sit down,
Dynamite.
(TRAlN WHlSTLE BLOWlNG)
All right, boys, spread out.
Stay down.
And nobody shoot
till l do.
Saving him for
yourself, eh?
Maybe.
That looks all right.
Try that for size.
What are you trying
to prove, Kid?
You're gonna get off
and pick up that gold
just like l was gonna do.
l'm gonna be
watching you
mighty close.
Come on.
Kid.
What about me?
l'm hurt bad.
You'll figure
something, Weber.
You had this timed
pretty good.
l'll say when.
Now.
(GUNS FlRlNG)
(YELLS)
(DOG BARKlNG)
Bill.
Hello, Bill.
Hello, Rose.
Thanks for the telegram.
Pat, we need
a couple of
fresh horses.
Carrie and l are
heading for the border
first thing in the morning.
One horse, Bill.
l'll get you some food.
You must be hungry.
What do you mean,
one horse?
You're riding out
alone, son.
Bill, l can't let
Carrie go with you
until you've settled
down enough
to know how to
take care of her
right and proper.
She'll be here
waiting for you
just like she said
she would.
Come over and
sit down, Bill.
You kept your promise,
Bill.
l always knew l would
if l could.
Still an awful long way
to Argentina.
We'll get there, Bill,
l know we will.
l've been building our ranch
all the way here, Carrie.
Mile by mile
and log by log.
l've been building
corrals, fences,
stocking the range.
You're gonna have
all the things you
always wanted, Carrie.
Just like real people.
He wouldn't stand
a chance, honey.
They'd catch him
before he got halfway
to the border.
What are we
really gonna do, Dad?
l don't know.
l'll get him some clothes
and clean him up.
Kiss me, Bill.
SUTTON: Don't move, Bill.
Let's see your hands.
Well, Bill,
it's been a long chase.
Kind of hate to see it
end this way, Kid.
l mean, with you
still in one piece.
lt ain't ended yet,
Mr. Swanson.
l'll be back.
That's right, Bill,
you will be back.
Could l talk to him
a minute, Marshal?
Alone.
We got nothing to say.
l think you do, Bill.
Get his gun.
Oh, listen to me, Bill.
This isn't the end,
it's the beginning.
lt's the only possible way
we can have anything ever.
Come on, John,
let's go.
Well, Pat, guess you
saved yourself a horse
on the deal.
lt's gonna be
as tough on her
as it is on you, son.
She really loves you.
lt won't be too long.
When you come back,
this ranch will belong
to you two kids.
Now why don't you go over
and say good-bye
the way you should?
l guess Pat's right,
Carrie.
So are you.
How many mistakes
can a man make
and still hope
to get away with?
Oh, Bill.
You're lucky, Carrie.
l wish that
Bitter Creek and l had
that same chance.