HYAH !
HYAH !  HYAH !
HOLD ON, HOLD ON !
IT'S FRAPP, FOR CHRIST'S SAKE !
YOU DAMN FOOL !
YOU COULD'VE KILLED MY HORSE !
WELL, WHAT'S WRONG WITH YA ?
HUH ?  DON'T YOU WANNA
HAVE FUN NO MORE ?
TOO OLD FOR THIS, I RECKON.
DAMN YOU, HENRY !
OH, SHIT.  DAMN.
I THOUGHT YOU LOST YOUR HAIR
DOWN IN THE BAYOU SALLOT.
HELL, NO !  I AIM TO KEEP
MY SCALP A WHILE.
WHOO !  LOOKS LIKE
YOU BEEN TRAPPIN'.
WHERE YOU BEEN ?
ABSAROKA.  YELLERSTONE.
WHERE YOU UP FROM ?
BEEN BACK IN THE SETTLEMENT.
I JUST COME FROM ST. LOUIS.
SEE ANY SIGN ?
HEAP.
WHOLE WAR PARTY, BLACKFOOT,
WORKIN' RIGHT HERE ABOUTS.
NAH, THEY'RE CROW.
I SEEN THE MOCCASIN TRACKS.
THEY'VE BEEN TRYIN' TO STEAL
MY HORSES FOR A WEEK.
- THEM ARE BLACKFOOT.
- CROW, I RECKON.
BLACKFOOT !  I CAN READ SIGN !
GODDAMN IT !
WHAT'S BEAVER IN ST. LOUIS ?
FIVE DOLLARS.
FIVE DOLLARS !
BE A COLD DAY IN HELL
'FORE I SELL MY PLEWS
FOR FIVE DOLLARS.
HOW ABOUT IN TAOS ?
SAME THING.
WHERE THE HELL YOU BEEN ?
DON'T YOU GO TO RENDEZVOUS
NO MORE ?
NOT FOR A COUPLE
OF WINTERS NOW.
YOU HEADIN' THERE ?
DAMN RIGHT !
I GOTTA GET SOME WHISKEY.
IF I DON'T GET SOME WHISKEY
SOON, I'M GONNA DIE !
WELL... I'VE A MIND
TO RENDEZVOUS MYSELF.
IF YOU DON'T MIND
THE COMPANY.
GLAD TO HAVE YA.
I NEED SOMEBODY TO SHOOT CENTER
IN CASE WE GOT TO FIGHT
THEM BLACKFOOT.
- CROW !
- BLACKFOOT, GODDAMN IT !
- GOT ANY "BACKY" ?
- OH, I GUESS SO.
GIVE US A CHAW.
YEAH.
NO HARD FEELINGS, OLD COON ?
OH, SHIT !
NARY A ONE.
SON OF A BITCH !
"BUFFALER" ON THE PLATTE ?
MIGHTY THIN.
GODDAMN PAWNEES'VE BEEN SHOOTIN'
THEM AGAIN FOR THE HIDES,
LEAVIN' MEAT OUT THERE
TO ROT IN THE SUN.
WHAT IS OLD BRIDGER DOIN' ?
OH, I HEARD HE WAS
IN SANTA FE, BUSHWAYIN'
FOR A BUNCH OF GREASERS.
MR. FRAPP !  WHOA !
MY GOD, MR. FRAPP--
WHERE YOU BEEN,
ASSHOLE ?
I MADE THE ASSUMPTION
YOU HAD GONE DOWNSTREAM.
YOU "ASSUMPT" THAT ?
WELL, DON'T DO NO MORE
GODDAMN "ASSUMPTIN'."
-I THOUGHT YOU GOT LOST AGAIN.
- HAVEN'T YOU EVER BEEN LOST ?
FEARSOME CONFUSED
FOR A MONTH OR TWO, BUT
I AIN'T NEVER BEEN LOST.
THIS HERE'S BILL TYLER.
YOU, UH, YOU GONNA SHOOT ME
WITH YOUR RAMROD ?
NOW, THAT'S NAT WYETH
FROM MASSACHUSETTS.
SAYS HE'S A ICE MERCHANT.
ICE ?
GOT TO TAKE HIM
TO THE RENDEZVOUS.
I'M TRAVELING TO OREGON,
MR., UH, MR. TYLER ?
I HAVE A PLAN TO SEND
SALMON EAST IN BARRELS.
SALMON ?
WELL, LET'S GET
TO THE RENDEZVOUS.  I'VE
GOT A POWERFUL DRY ON.
HOW ARE YOU GONNA GET THEM
BARRELS OVER THE ROCKIES ?
WAGONS, MR. TYLER.
WAGONS ?  YOU CAN'T
GET WAGONS OVER THE--
I'M JOINING A TRAIN
OF IMMIGRANTS.
IMMIGRANTS ?  HAH.
IMMIGRANTS.  IMMIGRANTS.
IT'S THE PROMISED LAND,
MR. TYLER.
WHAT IN THE HELL WOULD ANYONE
WANT TO GO TO OREGON FER ?
TO TRADE, TO BUILD,
TO, TO TILL THE SOIL,
TO FARM THE LAND.
YOU CAN'T FARM IN OREGON.
WON'T NOTHIN' GROW THERE.
COULD'VE TOLD YOU THAT.
BUT HE WON'T LISTEN TO ME.
MARK MY WORD, MR. TYLER.
ONE DAY, THERE'LL BE
A WAGON ROAD...
ALL THE WAY FROM
ST. LOUIS TO OREGON.
AW, BULLSHIT !
IT'S A NEW EMPIRE,
VIRGIN AND UNTRAMMELED.
HEY, GIVE US ANOTHER CHAW.
IT'S A LAND OF LIMITLESS
OPPORTUNITY.
JESUS.
SHIT !
WHAT'S WRONG ?
YOU CAN SEE WHAT'S WRONG.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
WELL, YOU DON'T SEE IT
'CAUSE IT AIN'T THERE.
WHAT AIN'T THERE ?
THE GODDAMN RENDEZVOUS
AIN'T THERE, GODDAMN IT !
WHAT'S IT SAY ?
HOW DO I KNOW WHAT IT SAYS ?
YOU READ IT.
"COME ON TO POPO AGIE.
PLENTY WHISKEY
AND WHITE WOMEN."
POPO AGIE ?
THAT CAN'T BE.
WELL, THE HELL YOU SAY.
THEY GOT WHITE WOMEN,
AIN'T THEY ?
IT'S CLEAR THE HELL AND GONE
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE DIVIDE !
WELL, YOU DON'T EXPECT THEM
TO GO DRAGGIN' THOSE WOMEN
ACROSS THE ROCKIES, DO YA ?
TRADERS BEEN COMIN'
TO RENDEZVOUS FOR TEN YEARS.
NOW THEY GOT WHITE WOMEN,
THEY WON'T LEAVE THE PRAIRIE.
'FORE LONG, THEY'LL
HAVE US PACKIN' OUR PLEWS
CLEAN BACK TO ST. LOUIS.
LISTEN, WHAT DO YOU PLAN
TO DO ABOUT THEM BLACKFOOT...
THAT'S BEEN FOLLERIN' US
ALL DAY LONG ?
CROW.
BLACKFOOT, GODDAMN IT !
I KNOW BLACKFOOT.  I CAN
SMELL 'EM A MILE OFF !
WELL, YOU DON'T KNOW
HOG JAWS FROM HORSESHIT,
'CAUSE THEY'RE CROW.
THEY WON'T BOTHER US NONE,
IF WE KEEP AN EYE ON THE HORSES.
CROW AIN'T SO BAD.
I SPENT A COUPLE OF WINTERS
WITH THEM IN THE ABSAROKA.
YOU TRUST THEIR HONOR,
YOU'LL BE SAFE ENOUGH.
TRUST THEIR HONESTY,
YOU'RE GONNA LOSE YOUR
LONG JOHNS TOO.
HEY, HENRY, I HEAR
YOU GOT INTO THE MONEY END
OF THIS MISERABLE BUSINESS.
YEAH.  I PACKED IN SUPPLIES
FROM ST. LOUIS,
WATERED DOWN THE WHISKEY,
JACKED UP THE PRICES,
WENT TO TRADIN' FOR BEAVER.
- YEAH ?  WHAT HAPPENED ?
- LOST MY ASS.
TURNED AROUND AND SOLD
EVERYTHING TO FONTENELLE.
WELL, BEAVER'LL SHINE AGAIN.
LOOK AT THESE HERE PLEWS
OF MINE.
TOOK YOU TWO YEARS
TO GET 'EM, TOO, DIDN'T IT ?
I MIND THE TIME
YOU GET THAT MANY BEAVER
IN ONE FALL HUNT.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE
WHAT FONTENELLE'S GONNA
GIVE YOU FOR 'EM.
DAMN FONTENELLE !
I'M A FREE TRAPPER, BY GOD.
I TRADE MY PLEWS TO THE HIGHEST
BIDDER, CASH MONEY.
WELL, YOU'RE SHIT OUTTA LUCK,
'CAUSE FONTENELLE'S THE ONLY
BIDDER YOU GOT THIS YEAR.
STAND CLEAR !
- OHHH.
- WHAT WAS THAT ?
WHAT WAS WHAT ?
I HEARD SOMETHING.
YOU BEEN HEARIN' SOMETHIN'
ALL THE WAY FROM MISSOURI.
MMM.  SHHH !
YOU HEAR SOMETHIN', TYLER ?
I TOLD YOU.
SHUT UP !  HEAR THAT ?
I'M TELLING YOU, THERE
IS SOMETHING OUT THERE.
'COURSE THERE'S SOMETHIN'
OUT THERE.  THERE'S ALWAYS
SOMETHIN' OUT THERE.
THERE'S RABBITS AND COONS
AND MULE DEER,
AND SOMETIMES THERE'S
JUST YOUR OWN HORSES.
THAT'S IT AGAIN.
SET DOWN, FLATLANDER.
BLACKFOOT !
MIND YOUR SCALP !
THEY'RE CROW !
AND MIND YOUR OWN SCALP.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING, TYLER ?
IS HE JUST GONNA LIE THERE ?
WANNA GET US KILLED ?
THEM GODDAMN BLACKFOOT'S
TRYIN' TO STEAL MY MULES !
STRIKES ME
THEY'RE DOIN' YOU A FAVOR.
NOW LOOK HERE.
THEM CROW PUT THE SNEAK
ON US HALF A' HOUR AGO.
THERE'S AT LEAST 20 OF THEM.
SHIT, I MIND THE TIME
WHEN TEN-TO-ONE WAS GOOD
ODDS FOR MOUNTAIN MEN.
SEVEN-TO-ONE.
YOU DON'T COUNT.  NOW, I AIN'T
GONNA LAY HERE AND LET THEM--
YOU GO OUT THERE NOW,
YOU'LL LOSE HALF THE HORSES
AND ALL YOUR HAIR.
I AIM TO KEEP 'EM BOTH.
COME ON.
WHAT THE HELL !
ROLL OUT, ROLL OUT !
JESUS !
THERE'S YOUR CAYUSE.
SADDLE HIM, AND LET'S RIDE !
HOW'D YOU GET 'EM BACK ?
I STOLE 'EM BACK.  COME ON !
WE AIN'T GOT ALL DAY.
THAT'S CROSS OTTER.
DAMNEDEST PIRATE YOU EVER SAW.
BLACKFEET ?
NO, HE TOLD YOU THEY WAS CROW,
DIDN'T HE ?  YOU GODDAMN IDIOT.
- WHAT'S HE WANT ?
- HE WANTS THE DAMN HORSES BACK.
WHAT THE HELL
DO YOU THINK HE WANTS ?
HE SAYS, "SMOKE PIPE,
FRIENDLY, GO AWAY."
MY ASS.
COME ON IN, CROSS OTTER !
WHAT SHOULD I DO ?
JUST KEEP YOUR HAND
ON THAT SCATTER GUN...
AND DON'T TAKE YOUR EYES
OFF 'EM, THAT'S WHAT YOU DO.
JESUS.  GOD.
WELL, SPEAK YOUR PIECE,
CROSS OTTER.
TYLER...
YOUR HEART IS BLACK.
DAMN IT,
YOU STOLE THEM HORSES FIRST,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
I HAVE MANY MEN IN MY CAMP.
STRONG.  YOUNG.
MAYBE THEY KILL YOU.
KEEP A HOLD OF YOUR YOUNG MEN,
OR I'LL LIFT THEIR HAIR.
BUT YOU STOLE OUR HORSES
IN THE WINTER.
YOU STOLE THEM FROM ME LAST
FALL.  YOU'RE LUCKY I DIDN'T
TAKE YOUR WHOLE REMUDA.
YOU GIVE US PRESENTS.
WE GO IN PEACE.
YOU CAN GO
IN DOG SHIT, DINGLEBALLS.
HAD ABOUT ENOUGH OUT OF YOU.
WELL, WE TAKE--
WE TAKE HORSES !
WELL, THAT'LL BE
AFTER THE FIGHT.
YOU SPEAK WITH YOUR TONGUE
LIKE YOUNG GIRLS.
YOU EAT DUNG OF WHITE COWS !
SHIT !
I ASSUME NOW THERE'S
GOING TO BE A FIGHT.
I TOLD YOU
THERE WAS BLACKFOOT
HEREABOUTS, GODDAMN IT !
YOU MIGHT BE RIGHT.
OPEN YOUR EYES, SON.
COME ON, SON, LOAD !
LOAD, DAMN IT !
AFTER ONE TWO OF THEM
BASTARDS GETS KILLED,
THEY SURE LOSE THEIR
STOMACH FOR FIGHTIN'.
CROW DOGS !  I CRAP
ON THE GRAVES OF YOUR FATHERS !
CROW AND BLACKFEET
DON'T GET ALONG, IT SEEMS.
BLACKFOOT DON'T
GET ALONG WITH NOBODY.
I'VE SEEN 'EM TAKE OFF
A MAN'S SKIN A STRIP AT A TIME.
BLACKFOOT !
COME OUT AND FIGHT !
SEND ME YOUR MEN !
CROSS OTTER, WHY
DON'T YOU QUIT YOUR CUSSIN'
AND SEND FOR YOUR BRAVES ?
MEN WITHOUT BALLS !
WELL, THAT'S SOMETHIN'
NOW, GREENHORN.
- I JUST TOOK AN ARROW.
- I CAN SEE THAT.
HERE, HOLD STILL.
NO !  NO !
HOLD STILL, DAMN IT !
GOOD THING IT WEREN'T
IN TOO DEEP.
THANK YOU.
AH !  CROW WARRIORS !
RIGHT ON TIME, HUH, SHITHEAD ?
YEAH, CROWS SOME WARRIORS !
YOU OUGHTA STICK
TO STEALIN' HORSES.
HORSE'LL CARRYYOU,
AT LEAST.
DID YOU KILL HER ?
SHE DAMN NEAR KILLED ME.
YOU GOT YOURSELF
A HEAP OF TROUBLE
IS WHAT YOU DONE.
WELL, WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED
TO DO ?  LET CROSS OTTER
CUT HER UP FOR WOLF BAIT ?
SHE'S DEAD, MR. TYLER.
OH, SHIT.
IF YOU WANNA RUN, SHOW
SOME SENSE, FOR CHRIST'S SAKE !
RUN THE OTHER WAY !
'FORE YOU KNOW IT,
CROSS OTTER'LL BE BACK HERE WITH
A FIST FULL OF BLOODY SCALPS !
HE WON'T MAKE NO BONES
ABOUT CUTTIN' YOUR FINE,
LONG LOCKS, NEITHER.
EXCUSE ME.
OH, YEAH.
HEAP OF TROUBLE.
HOW MANY MORE WILL YOU KILL ?
WE HAVE ALWAYS
FOUGHT THE CROW.
NOT OVER SQUAW.
LET THE GIRL GO.
SHE MEANS NOTHING TO YOU.
SHE IS MY WOMAN.
YOU TREAT HER
LIKE A COYOTE BITCH.
IT IS NOT THE GIRL
FOR WHAT SHE IS.
IT IS THE LONG KNIVES,
THE HAIR FACES,
MORE AND MORE OF THEM.
IF THEY ARE NOT STOPPED,
THERE WILL BE
NO FOOD TO HUNT,
NO LANDS LEFT FOR US.
THEN WHY NOT TRY
AND MAKE PEACE WITH THEM ?
TRADE WITH THEM ?
THEY SPIT ON OUR LAND,
DESTROY OUR BUFFALO HERD,
TRAP OUR BEAVER.
HAIR FACE...
BIG ONE,
HE OPENS THE PATH
FOR OTHERS.
BUT HE WILL NOT HAVE HER...
OR ONE MORE THING
BELONGING TO MY PEOPLE.
YOU ARE A BLACKFOOT,
AIN'T YA ?
I COME FROM ANOTHER VILLAGE.
MY FATHER SOLD ME
TO HEAVY EAGLE.
ONE HORSE, ONE GUN.
SLAVE ?
WIFE.  THE SAME.
HEAVY EAGLE.
HE BEAT YOU SOME, HUH ?
WHERE'D YOU LEARN AMERICAN ?
FORT McKENZIE.
IN THE SUMMER,
WE TRADE BEAVER THERE.
- YOU LEARNED GOOD.
- I GO WITH YOU.
NO.  YOU GO YOUR OWN WAY.
I CANNOT GO BACK
TO HEAVY EAGLE.
HELL, YOU--
WELL, YOU CAN COME
TO RENDEZVOUS,
BUT, LOOK HERE, AFTER THAT
YOU GOTTA CLEAR OUT.
I PACKED A SQUAW ALONG
BEFORE.  SIX YEARS.
DAMNEDEST SLUT
AS EVER CRIED FOR FOOFARAW.
ALWAYS WANTIN' VERMILION
AND BLUE BEADS...
AND MIRRORS AND SUCH.
BEDDIN' DOWN WITH EVERY BUCK
THAT COME HER WAY.
SHE WAS PRETTY, THOUGH.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
RUNNING MOON.
YOU'LL CLEAR OUT
IF I TELL YA ?
OHHHH, WHISKEY !
OHHH, WHISKEY !
AHHHHH !
I'M A MOUNTAIN MAN, BY GOD !
I CAN WHIP ANY TEN
OF YOU NIGGERS !
OH, OH, I'M SORRY.
MI-MISTAKE.  ACCIDENT.
AHHHHH !  WHEE-HAW !
I WAS WEANED
ON RATTLESNAKE BLOOD !
MY MAMMY WAS A WOLF,
AND MY PA WAS A GORE GRIZZLY !
AHHHH !
HA-HA-HA !
- THREE DOLLARS.
- THREE DOLLARS ?
GODDAMN IT, FONTENELLE,
YOU KNOW THIS BEAVER'S WORTH
A HEAP MORE THAN THREE DOLLARS.
THIS HERE IS PRIME FUR.
THREE DOLLARS.
THIS HERE'S A FIVE-DOLLAR
PLEW IF THERE EVER WAS ONE.
THREE DOLLARS
SEEMS FAIR ENOUGH TO--
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
- THREE DOLLARS.
I DON'T GO NO HIGHER.
YOU GOT THE BUFFALO ROBES,
I GIVE YOU $20 A PIECE FOR THEM.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D
SEE THE DAY WHEN BUFFALO
BROUGHT MORE'N BEAVER.
YOU'RE ROBBIN' HIM BLIND,
FONTENELLE.
I NEVER TRADED
CUTTHROAT LIKE THAT.
TAKE IT WHILE YOU CAN, BOYS.
NEXT YEAR, YOU MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO SELL BEAVER AT ALL.
THE WAY THINGS ARE GOING, THIS
MAY BE YOUR LAST RENDEZVOUS.
- WHAT DO YA MEAN ?
- SILK.
WHAT'S THAT ?
SILK.  HATS.
THEY'RE NOT MAKING 'EM
OUT OF BEAVER NO MORE, BILL.
SILK'S THE FASHION NOW,
IN LONDON.
- HELL.
- AH, SHIT.
A HEAP OF FAT MEAT
CAN'T SHINE FOREVER.
I SEEN IT COMIN'.
BEAVER'LL SHINE
AGAIN, HENRY.
ACTUALLY, IT SEEMS REASONABLE
THAT IF THERE'S NO DEMAND--
SILK.  WHAT THE HELL
IS SILK ?
DON'T YA KNOW NOTHIN' ?
SILK IS MADE OUT OF WORMS.
OH, NO.
INJUNS COMIN' !
ASSHOLE.
BLACKFEET.
SHIT.
BLACKFEET !
THEY FOUND US.
NO, THEM ARE CROW,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.  AIN'T WE
LEARNED YOU NOTHIN' ?
THAT'S IRON BELLY'S VILLAGE.
THEY SURE DO MAKE
A SPECTACLE, DON'T THEY ?
I'LL BE DAMNED !
THAT'S MEDICINE WOLF !
HE COME WEST WITH ME IN '23.
WE RAISED HELL FROM SOUTH FORKS
TO THREE PASS, WE DID.
HEY, MEDICINE WOLF !
LET ME THROUGH THERE !
CLEAR AWAY !
COME ON, LET ME THROUGH.
THERE !
LET HIM THROUGH !
- HEY !
MEDICINE WOLF,
HOW THE HELL ARE YA ?
GODDAMN !
HERE, OLD HOSS,
HAVE A DRINK.
GODDAMN !
"OH, SHENANDOAH"
" I LONG TO HEAR YOU "
" AWAY "
" I'M BOUND AWAY "
" 'CROSS THE WIDE "
" MISSOURI "
MEAN AS IF HE HAD A RED-HOT
POKER UP HIS ASSHOLE.
WELL, LISTEN--
MAYBE IRON BELLY HELP YOU.
HE KNOWS THE BEAVER
LIKE HIS OWN CHILDREN.
CHRIST, I THOUGHT
HE WAS DEAD.
HE OUTLIVED SEVEN SQUAWS.
LAST WINTER, HE HAD A SON.
SAY, WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT STUFF ?
KINNIKINNICK.
TASTES LIKE
"BUFFALER" SHIT.
IT IS.
YOU CAN'T HURT ME !
THAT'S A GOOD ONE !
I DON'T CARE
IF IT'S TRUE OR NOT !
IRON BELLY ?
IRON BELLY,
IT'S ME, TYLER.
HOW OLD IS HE ?
A HUNDRED AND TEN.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S SPANISH ARMOR.
IRON BELLY ?
IRON BELLY, IT'S BILL TYLER.
BILL TYLER ?
YEAH... IT'S ME.
THE SAME.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE DEAD.
HE WHO RUNS WITH THE WIND,
SPEAK YOUR HEART.
BEAVER'S GETTIN'
MIGHTY SCARCE, IRON BELLY.
UH-HUH.
AND DAMN FONTENELLE'S
PAYIN' NEXT TO NOTHIN'
FOR THE PLEWS.
- WHAT ?  WHAT ?
-
OUTFIT'S ARE GOIN' SKY HIGH.
VERMILION AND BEADS
AND SCALPIN' KNIVES AND SUCH
ARE MIGHTY DEAR THESE DAYS.
SOME SAY FUR'S DOWN FOR GOOD,
BEAVER WON'T NEVER SHINE AGAIN.
I AM OLD, BILL TYLER.
BEAVER GONE.
SOON I GONE TOO.
DAMN IT, IRON BELLY,
IT CAN'T ALL BE TRAPPED OUT.
IN THE MOUNTAINS
OF THE RIVER OF WIND...
THERE IS A VALLEY.
THE WIND RIVER RANGE ?
THE LAND OF OUR ENEMIES,
THE BLACKFEET.
THEIR HEARTS ARE BAD,
THEIR EYES RED WITH BLOOD.
AND IT'S CHOCK-FULL
OF BEAVER, AIN'T IT ?
AIN'T IT ?
NO.
IT HAS TO BE.
THE BLACKFEET BEEN KEEPIN'
EVERYBODY OUT OF THERE
FOR YEARS.
MUST BE SO FULL OF BEAVER,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TRAP 'EM.
JUST CLUB 'EM IN THE BACK.
SURE.
IRON BELLY--
HIGH IN THE MOUNTAINS
THERE IS A VALLEY.
IT IS GUARDED FIERCELY
BY THE BLACKFEET...
FOR THERE ARE BEAVER THERE.
AS MANY AS THE STARS
IN THE SKY.
WELL, YOU SAID THAT ALREADY.
WIND RIVERS IS A BIG RANGE.
CAN YOU NARROW IT DOWN SOME ?
I HAVE NO MORE WORDS.  HUH ?
IRON BELLY.
AHHH.  YOU WILL KNOW
WHEN YOU FIND IT.
AHHHHH !
DAMN YOUR EYES,
RUNNING MOON.
I LEFT YOU POSSIBLES
TO GET YOU HOME, DIDN'T I ?
AHHHH !
WELL, DAMN IT !  OHHHHH !
VOILA !  YOU ARE SOBER NOW,
HUH, BILLY TYLER ?
YOU CAN TAKE HER !
BETTER WATCH OUT, BILLY !
SHE'S GONNA LICK YOUR HAIR !
WHAT'D YA DO THAT FOR ?
YOU LIED TO ME !
YOU SAID YOU'D GO
WHEN I ASKED YA !
YOU HAVE NOT SAID SO.
RUNNING MOON,
WHY DON'T YOU GO HOME ?
- I HAVE NO HOME.
- OH, FOR CHRIST'S SAKE !
IT IS THE CUSTOM OF MY
PEOPLE.  I GO WITH YOU.
TRIBAL CUSTOM ? SACREDAMN !
SHE'STRES BON,BILLY TYLER.
I NEVER HEARD
OF NO SUCH TRIBAL CUSTOM.
TYLER DOES NOT WANT YOU, SQUAW.
I'LL TAKE YOU, SQUAW.
THAT'S MY TRIBAL CUSTOM, HUH ?
WHAT YOU WANNA LATCH
ONTO ME FOR ?
I HAVE NOWHERE TO GO.
HEY, TYLER, YOU GIVE ME
THAT CROW BITCH, HUH ?
I'M NOT AFRAID OF HER.
SHE WON'T HURT ME, HUH ?
EXCUSE ME.
YOU DON'T WANNA GET HIM
RILED, FROGGY.  HE MIGHT
HAVE YOU FOR LUNCH.
THERE HE GOES.
WELL, I, UH, THANK YOU.
WHY DON'T YOU LEARN TRAPPIN' ?
TAKE UP A DECENT TRADE...
INSTEAD OF LATCHIN' ON
TO THAT DAMN WAGON STRING.
TRAIN.  WAGON TRAIN.
COME ON.  WE'RE GOIN'
CLEAR TO OREGON, MR. TYLER.
YOU WON'T GET PAST THE SNAKE.
HA-HA !
YOU CAN'T GET WAGONS
THROUGH THEM MOUNTAINS !
OH, HO-HO-HO !
DAMN PILGRIMS.
DUMB ASSHOLE.
HYAH.
RECKON YOU'RE
GONNA KEEP HER ?
RECKON I GOT
ANY CHOICE ?
I DON'T KNOW.
GOT SAND IN HER, SHE DOES.
HELL.
KICKED THE SHIT
OUTTA YOU.
CHRIST !  SAND.
YOU AIN'T GONNA CATCH NOTHIN'
UP HERE 'CEPT RHEUMATISM, TYLER.
AH, WE'D BEST MOVE ON
IN THE MORNIN'.
THIS SURE LORD
AIN'T THE PLACE.
YES, SIR, WHOLE VALLEY
SWARMIN' WITH BEAVER.
FIGHTIN' TO GET INTO YOUR TRAP.
"TAKE ME, TAKE ME," THEY SAY.
DAMN IT, HENRY !
PLACE LIKE THAT AIN'T
GONNA BE EASY TO FIND.
IT STANDS TO REASON.
SEE ANY SIGN ?
SURE AS SHIT
AIN'T NO SIGN OF BEAVER.
I DON'T MEAN
THE BEAVER SIGN.
OH, MAYBE.  I CAN SMELL
BLACKFOOT A MILE OFF.
NO OFFENSE, RUNNING MOON.
THIS CHILD
SMELLS BLACKFOOT TOO.
NOTHIN' PARTICULAR,
JUST A FEELIN'.
MY PEOPLE COME HERE
MANY TIMES.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE BEFORE ?
WHY IN THE HELL
DIDN'T YOU SAY SO ?
YOU DID NOT ASK.
YOU KNOW ABOUT THIS VALLEY
ALL FULL OF BEAVER ?
MY PEOPLE KEPT IT A SECRET
FROM THE OTHER TRIBES.
THEY SAY IT WAS RICH IN FUR,
THICK AND SLEEK.
WHERE IN THE HELL IS IT ?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T REMEMBER.
YOU DON'T REMEMBER ?
YOU WAS RAISED HERE,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKES !
HENRY, SHE SAYS
SHE DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS ONLY A LEGEND.
WHERE YOU BEEN ?
TRAPPIN'.
- ANY INDIAN SIGN ?
- OH, SOME.
RECKON THEY'LL BE BACK ?
NOT THE ONES
THAT TANGLED WITH ME.
YOU LOOK ALL TUCKERED OUT, BILL.
I THINK YOU'RE GETTIN' TOO OLD
FOR THE MOUNTAINS.
LOSIN' YOUR WIND.
COULD BE, HENRY.
AHHHH.
COULD BE.
AAAAH !
INJUNS !
INJUNS, GODDAMN IT !
DAMN BLACKFOOT
STEALIN' MY MULES !
IF I WAS YOU,
I'D LET 'EM KEEP 'EM.
ANYWAYS, YOU
WAS GUARDIN' THE STOCK.
THEY SNUCK UP ON ME,
GODDAMN IT.
THAT'S WHAT INJUNS
DO FOR A LIVIN'.
HEAVY EAGLE.
HIM ?
YOU RECKON HE SAW YOU ?
LOOKS LIKE
THEY CROSSED HERE.
MUST BE HALFWAY
TO THREE FORKS--
RUNNING MOON ?
RUNNING--
OH, I THOUGHT
YOU'D GONE UNDER.
HEAVY EAGLE WILL HUNT US.
HIS BLOOD BURNS.  HE WILL--
WHERE'S FRAPP ?
HEY, WHERE'S MY SHIRT ?
DAMN IT.  RUNNING MOON,
WHERE'S MY SHIRT ?
YOU PROMISED TO MEND IT.
DAMN THING'S
PLUMB WORE OUT, ANYWAYS.
WELL, WHAT'S--
WELL, NOW, THAT--
THAT SHINES.  THAT--
THAT TRULY SHINES.
THE WOMAN IS OF OUR NATION.
SHE'S MINE.
GO ON, GET !
I STAY WITH YOU.
YOU'LL GO UNDER IF YOU DO.
I STAY !
RUNNING MOON !
RUNNING--
WHERE IS RUNNING MOON ?
IS THE LONG KNIFE
A SWIFT RUNNER ?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, RUN ?
IT WAS NOT FOR ME TO DECIDE.
THE COUNCIL OF ELDERS
ARE LIKE SQUAWS.
THE WHITE MAN'S MEDICINE
MAKES US WEAK.
WE DIE LIKE FLIES
AT FORT McKENZIE.
YOU MEAN THE POX ?
WE TRADE AT THE FORT,
AND OUR FACES ROT AND FALL OFF.
EVEN THE WOLVES
WILL NOT TOUCH US.
THIS IS STRANGE,
EVIL MEDICINE.
AND WE CAN DO NOTHING
ABOUT IT.
BUT YOU AND I ARE THE SAME.
A FEW PASSING SUNS
WILL SEE US NO MORE.
OUR BONES WILL BLEACH IN THE SUN
WITH THE BONES OF THE BUFFALO.
BUT WE SHALL BE REMEMBERED.
TOMORROW YOU'LL SEE
YOUR LAST SUNRISE.
WHERE IS RUNNING MOON ?
SHE IS DEAD.
RUN.
HE CANNOT BE FOUND.
YOU HUNT FOR HIM STILL ?
NO MAN CAN LIVE
IN THAT WATER.
NOT THE GROS VENTRE.
HE IS DEAD.
I SURVIVED.
WHEN HIS SCALP...
HANGS FROM MY LODGE,
WHEN HIS HEAD
SITS ON MY SPEAR,
THEN HE WILL BE DEAD.
IT WILL BE WINTER SOON.
RUNNING MOON, GO.
BRING US WOOD.
WE HAVE LITTLE TO EAT.
WE MUST MOVE
THE VILLAGE.
WHEN THE SNOW FALL,
IT WILL HIDE HIS TRACKS.
WE NEED NO TRACKS.
WE WILL MOVE THE VILLAGE
BEFORE THE SNOW COME.
THEN WE WILL HUNT.
THERE IS ONLY ONE PLACE
HE CAN SURVIVE THE WINTER--
IN THE VILLAGE OF IRON BELLY,
THE CROW.
GET !
GO ON !
YOU BLACK YOUR FACE
FOR A HUNT ?
FOR THIS HUNT.
CHRIST !
I AM DYING.
THERE IS NO MORE.
I AM HUNGRY TOO.
I AM MEDICINE WOLF.
I WILL NOT DIE LIKE A SLAVE.
MEDICINE WOLF !
YOU KNOW BILL TYLER ?
HE SPOKE OF YOU.
BILL TYLER IS MY FRIEND.
WHEN DID YOU SEE HIM ?
WAS HE NOT
IN YOUR VILLAGE ?
NO.
HE ESCAPED FROM HEAVY EAGLE
BEFORE THE WINTER.
MAYBE HE GO UNDER.
NO.
I KNOW THAT HE'S ALIVE.
MAYBE HE GO NORTH.
YELLOWSTONE COUNTRY.
MANY TRAPPERS WINTER
ON THE MADISON RIVER.
I AM TYLER'S WOMAN.
I WILL BRING YOU MORE.
WHAT THE HELL TOOK YOU,
TYLER ?
HENRY ?
SIT YOUR ASS DOWN
AND HAVE A CUP OF COFFEE.
OH.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S MIGHTY GOOD.
LOOK HERE, HENRY.
IF I'D KNOWN THAT...
YOU WAS LAYING THERE SCALPED--
IF I'D KNOWED
YOU WEREN'T DEAD,
I NEVER WOULD'VE LEFT YOU,
NOT FOR NOTHING.
WELL, YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL
ME THAT, FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
I KNOW THAT.
WELL, I WAS LAYING THERE.
COME TO
ALL BY MY LONESOME.
THEM BLACKFEET WAS SO BUSY
TAKING OFF AFTER YOU,
THEY EVEN FORGOT
TO TAKE MY RIFLE.
I GOT BACK TO CAMP,
I SEEN YOU WAS GONE.
JUST WALKED
THE HELL OUT OF THERE.
TAKES A LOT MORE
THAN A SCALPIN' KNIFE
TO PUT THIS CHILD UNDER.
IT SURE MUST'VE
SMARTED SOME, THOUGH.
WELL, I GUESS.
ISN'T THAT THE SHITS ?
I'LL TELL YA,
IT FELT MIGHTY QUEERSOME.
MMM.  HEY, WHERE IN THE HELL
IS RUNNING MOON ?
SHE'S GONE UNDER, HENRY.
AND HEAVY EAGLE
STOVE HER HEAD IN.
OH, SHIT.
GODDAMN !
SHE WAS SOME PUMPKIN TOO.
WELL--
SAY, YOU EVER FIND
THAT VALLEY ?
THE ONE THAT'S ALWAYS SWARMIN'
WITH THE BEAVERS ?
WHERE THEY RUN UP ON THE BANKS
AND FIGHT ONE ANOTHER
TO GET IN YOUR TRAP ?
HOLLERIN',
"TAKE ME, BILL TYLER !
TAKE ME !"
BEAVER MANY
AS STARS IN THE SKY.
THERE'S AN OLD HORSE OUTSIDE.
WHAT ?
YOU ARE ONLY A SLAVE.
THEY WILL NOT GO AFTER YOU.
FIND TYLER.
TELL HIM I WAIT.
GO.
BEFORE I GOT THERE,
HE HAD BURNED IT OUT.
KILLED THE OLD MAN
AND THE SQUAWS
AND THE YOUNG 'UNS TOO.
LEFT ME BETWEEN
A ROCK AND A HARD PLACE.
ALL I COULD DO WAS TRY
FOR THE FLATHEAD COUNTRIES,
SEE IF THEY'D TAKE ME IN.
I WORKED ACROSS
THE YELLOWSTONE.
YEAH, YOU GOT THE HAIR
OF THE BEAR ON YOU, TYLER,
THAT'S FOR DAMN SURE.
I'VE SEEN THE BACK DOOR
TO HELL, HENRY.
YEAH, LOOK THERE.
THERE SHE IS.
YOU LITTLE RASCAL.
GO ON, GET.
I TRADED
A GOOD PINTO FOR HER.
OF COURSE, I STOLE HIM
FROM HER PAPPY FIRST.
THE OLD SON OF A BITCH
HAS GOT SO GODDAMN MANY HORSES,
HE DIDN'T RECOGNIZE HIS OWN
WHEN I BRUNG HIM BACK.
SHE DON'T KNOW A DAMN WORD
OF ENGLISH, BUT SHE CAN BE
MIGHTY COMFORTING...
ON A NIGHT LIKE THIS ONE.
I DO MISS MY MULES, THOUGH.
HEY, TYLER.
WHERE'S YOUR SQUAW ?
OH, I KNOW.
YOU GET TOO OLD, HUH ?
GROS VENTRE BITCH.
BIG MELONS.
WHAT'D YOU PAY FOR HER ?
HUH ?
I BET SHE HUMP YOU
GOOD, HUH ?
SHUT UP,
SHIT FOR BRAINS.
I LIKE RED MEAT, HUH ?
I SAID SHUT UP,
YOU GODDAMN
PORK-EATIN' FROG TURD !
I CAN'T STAND
THAT NASTY-TALKIN' BASTARD.
YOU KNOW, IT'S
GODDAMN LONESOME OUT HERE.
IT TOOK YOU
20 YEARS TO FIGURE
THAT ONE OUT, HUH ?
I'M GETTIN' LONG
IN THE TOOTH FOR THIS.
WELL, THAT AIN'T AN ELK.
I RECKON NOT.
NO PRESENTS NOW, TYLER,
YA HEAR ?
NO DAMN MEAT, EITHER.
WATCH YOURSELF, BILL,
GODDAMN IT.
HE'S LIABLE TO HAVE THE POX.
HE AIN'T GOT THE POX.
THE WHOLE TRIBE CAUGHT IT
OVER AT FORT UNION
LAST FALL, GODDAMN IT !
WHAT THE HELL--
I AM MEDICINE WOLF.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE, DAMN IT.
WHAT HAPPENED ?
MEDICINE WOLF HUNTING.
THEY TAKE PRISONER.
ALL DIE.
H-H-HUNGRY.
YEAH.
YOU'LL EAT JUST AS SOON AS
WE GET YOU BACK TO CAMP.
HOW'D YOU GET AWAY ?
RUNNING MOON.
WHAT ?
SHE HELPED MEDICINE WOLF.
GIVE HORSE.
SHE SAYS--
SHE'S ALIVE ?
SHE-- SHE W--
SHE WAITS.
WHAT'D HE SAY ?
WHAT DID HE SAY ?
HE SAYS HE'S HUNGRY.
GOD.
FOR CHRIST'S SAKES.
TELL HIM WE AIN'T GOT
NO MEAT TO SPARE.
WE CAN'T GO FEEDIN'
EVERY STARVIN'-ASS INDIAN
COME WANDERIN' INTO CA--
OH, JESUS.
I DON'T RECKON
HE'LL EAT MUCH, HENRY.
YOU FELLAS EVER FIND
THAT VALLEY
YOU WAS HUNTIN' ?
THE ONE IRON BELLY
TOLD YOU ABOUT ?
THERE AIN'T NO VALLEY,
JOE.
I HEAR IRON BELLY
TELL YOU DIFFERENT, HUH ?
IRON BELLY'S AN OLD MAN.
HE WAS JUST YARNIN' ME.
IT DIDN'T MAKE
NO NEVER MIND TO HIM.
MAYBE-- MAYBE
HE TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
WHICH WAY MIGHT YOU
BE HEADIN' COME BREAKUP ?
NORTH.
DROP ON OVER
KICKIN' HORSE PASS,
TRAP THE WOLF.
MAYBE THE PEACE RIVER.
IT'S BRITISH TERRITORY.
HUDSON'S BAY AIN'T GONNA BE
TOO HAPPY TO HEAR YOU, UH,
TRAPPIN' THEIR GROUND.
IF THE BLACKFEET
COULDN'T LIFT MY HAIR,
I RECKON I CAN STAY AHEAD
OF THE BRITISHERS.
COYOTE ?
REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
WE SAW THE TETONS ?
STANDING TALL AND WHITE
AS A WOMAN'S BREAST.
THE WHOLE COUNTRY SO NEW,
IT MADE A MAN THINK...
HE WAS THE FIRST ONE
TO SET FOOT ON IT.
YOU COULD WALK FOR A YEAR
IN ANY DIRECTION
WITH JUST YOUR RIFLE.
LIVE GOOD AND EASY.
NEVER SAY "SIR" TO NOBODY.
WHAT MADE YOU
CHANGE YOUR MIND ?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT ?
I MEAN, RUNNING MOON
AIN'T DEAD, IS SHE ?
WELL, NO MORE
THAN I AM.
SO I DON'T RECKON YOU'RE HEADIN'
FOR NO PEACE RIVER, ARE YA ?
NO, SHE AIN'T DEAD.
THAT BASTARD HEAVY EAGLE
LIED TO ME.
- THERE AIN'T NO VALLEY, HENRY.
- I WASN'T THINKIN' ABOUT THAT.
THERE AIN'T NO BEAVER UP THERE,
GODDAMN IT !
I JUST THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT NEED SOME HELP...
STEALIN' RUNNING MOON BACK,
THAT'S ALL.
I DON'T NEED NO HELP.
I DON'T RECKON
I NEED ANY HELP.
HEAVY EAGLE
MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING
TO SAY ABOUT THAT.
MAYBE.
WELL, I WAS ONLY TRYIN'
TO HELP YOU,
YOU CONTRARY OLD FART.
I KNOW IT.
MMM.
GOOD LUCK TO YA.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU TOO,
HENRY.
WELL, SOMEBODY'S
GOTTA LOOK AFTER YOU.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR SQUAW ?
AH, I TRADED HER BACK
TO HER PAPPY FOR THE PINTO.
YOU AIN'T RIDIN' HIM.
THE OLD FART
STOLE HIM BACK AGAIN.
GODDAMN THIEVIN' REDSKIN.
WHOA.
TYLER.
DIDN'T FIGURE ON
MEETIN' YOU TWO UP HERE.
WIND RIVER'S A LONG WAYS
FROM KICKIN' HORSE PASS.
I CHANGED MY MIND.
YEAH, I CAN SEE THAT.
YOU'RE FREE TRAPPERS.
YOU HUNT WHERE YOU WANT.
BUT I'M TELLING YOU,
THERE AIN'T NO VALLEY UP HERE,
AND THERE AIN'T NO BEAVER.
NO ?
SO WHY YOU HERE, THEN ?
YOU BOYS ARE ON YOUR OWN HOOK.
STAY OUT OF MY WAY.
WHY ?
YOU FORSAKE YOUR PEOPLE.
I HAVE NO PEOPLE.
IAMTHE PEOPLE.
THEY WILL NOT DIE
WHILE I LIVE.
YOU CANNOT LEAVE,
RUNNING MOON.
HE WILL COME...
AS I DID.
AND HE WILL DIE.
THAT WASN'T HERE
THIS MORNIN'.
TWO, THREE HOURS OLD.
SIX, SEVEN OF 'EM.
WAR PARTY.
DON'T TRY TO TEACH ME
MY BUSINESS, HENRY.
TRAVELIN' TOO FAST
FOR HUNTERS.
MAYBE THEY WAS IN A HURRY.
WHERE IN THE HELL
DO YOU THINK THEY'RE GOIN' ?
CHURCH SOCIAL ?
YOU BEST GET BACK ON TO CAMP,
CHECK UP ON THEM TWO
CHEE-CHOPPERS.
I'LL SCOUT AROUND SOME.
THAT CRAP WALKER
DON'T COME IN BY NOW,
HE DON'T COME IN.
QUIT WORRYING.
YOU'VE BEEN OUT LONGER YOURSELF.
I THINK YOU ONE GODDAMN INJUN.
IF I WAS AN INJUN,
YOU'D BE DEAD.
I THOUGHT YOU WAS
HUNTIN' WITH WALKER.
OUI.
YOU BURY HIM.
BULLSHIT !
YOU'LL KILL US ALL, TYLER !
AND YOU'LL TAKE
ALL THE BEAVER
FOR YOURSELF !
MAYBE YOU KILL MY FRIEND.
THEN MAYBE YOU KILL ME, HUH ?
THAT AIN'T A BAD IDEA,
FROG ASS.
I SEEN THE VILLAGE, HENRY.
I GOT CLOSE ENOUGH
TO SPIT ON IT.
IS RUNNING MOON
UP THERE ?
IT'S NEAR EMPTY.
THE BRAVES ARE OUT HUNTIN' US.
ONLY A BUNCH OF OLD MEN
AND BOYS GUARDIN' IT.
IS RUNNING MOON UP THERE ?
SURE, SHE'S THERE.
WELL ?
FIGURED HOW TO GET HER
OUT OF THERE ?
WE WALK IN AND TAKE HER.
TAKE HER ?
CHRIST'S SAKES, TYLER.
"TAKE HER."
THE VILLAGE IS DOWN
AT THE END OF THAT VALLEY.
WE RIDE INTO THE VALLEY
FROM THE EAST,
THEN WE WORK UP A SIDE CANYON.
I KNOW THEY'RE WATCHING US
ALL THE TIME, SO I'M CERTAIN
THEY'LL GO AFTER US.
GO AFTER US ?  YOU TETCHED ?
JESUS CHRIST !
ONCE WE DRAW OFF
HEAVY EAGLE AND HIS BOYS,
WE PUT THE SNEAK ON 'EM.
WE WORK PAST 'EM
IN THE THICK COUNTRY...
AND WALK INTO THAT VILLAGE
AS SLICK AS YOU PLEASE.
WHO IN THE HELL DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE MESSIN' WITH ?
THEM BOYS KILL FOR A LIVIN',
YOU KNOW.
NO.
BY THE TIME THEY GET WIND
OF WHERE WE'RE AT,
WE'LL BE LONG GONE.
HEY, WAKE UP,
YOU OLD FART.
LA BONT LIT OUT ON US,
DID HE ?
YEP.
TOOK THE PACK STOCK
WITH HIM TOO.
ASSHOLE.
WELL, YOU WAS GUARDIN'
THE HORSES.
THE HELL YOU SAY !
IT WAS YOUR TURN,
GODDAMN IT !
MY TURN ?
YOU OLD BASTARD !
WELL, IT'S NEVER YOUR TURN
TO GUARD THE GODDAMN HORSES !
EVERY GODDAMN TIME
WE LOSE THE HORSES,
OH, SHUT UP !
IT'S MY TURN TO GUARD 'EM,
AIN'T IT ?
YEAH, WELL,
WHAT ABOUT THE TIME
THE REES SNUCK OFF...
WITH OLD GABE'S MULES
DOWN ON THE BIG HORN, HUH ?
YOU WAS GUARDIN' THE STOCK.
I WAS GUARDIN' THE STOCK ?
BULLSHIT,
I WAS GUARDIN' THE STOCK !
WHAT ABOUT THAT TIME
DOWN ON SIDSKIDEE WHEN
THE SIOUX JUMPED YOUR ASS ?
YOU WAS--
WHAT THE HELL ?
OH, BALLS !
HE'S LEADIN' 'EM
RIGHT BACK TO US !
ASSHOLE !
- DAMN.  THEY NEARLY GOT ME.
- WHERE THE HELL'S MY HORSES ?
WHAT YOU THINK ?
THE GODDAMN INDIANS GET 'EM.
WELL, WHAT THE HELL
DID YOU COME BACK HERE FOR,
YOU GODDAMN, IGNORANT,
FOREIGN GODDAMN SHITHEAD FROG ?
WHOA !
WE SURE PUT
THE SNEAK ON THEM.
YES, SIR.
SURE FOOLED 'EM.
"AIN'T NOBODY GUARDIN'
THIS VILLAGE."
YES, SIREE.
ALL WE GOT TO DO IS...
GIVE 'EM THE SLIP
IN THE THICK COUNTRY...
AND THEN WHIP RIGHT UP THERE
AND RESCUE
GOOD OLD RUNNING MOON...
SLICK AS YOU PLEASE.
YOU GOT ANY IDEAS ?
WELL,
MAYBE IF WE CAN
HOLD 'EM OFF TILL DARK.
GET OUR ASSES OUT OF HERE
AND UP TO THAT VILLAGE
BEFORE SUNUP.
'CAUSE YOU KNOW HEAVY EAGLE
AIN'T GONNA TRY TO
BUTCHER US UNTIL DAYBREAK.
BY THEN, WE COULD BE
HALFWAY TO YELLOWSTONE.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
HE WON'T BUTCHER US
AT NIGHT ?
BLACKFEET DON'T FIGHT AT NIGHT.
YOU KNOW THAT.
HENRY, YOU AIN'T GOT
THE BRAINS GOD GIVE GEESE.
HEY, WHAT YOU THINK ?
MAYBE WE MAKE DEAL ?
WE GIVE THEM HORSES,
THEY LET US GO, NO ?
I'VE BEEN DOWN
THAT TRAIL BEFORE.
HE WANTS PARLEY.
WE GIVE IT TO HIM, NO ?
YOU SUIT YOURSELF.
I GOT NOTHIN' TO SAY TO HIM.
HE'S WAY OUT OF RANGE.
I KNOW IT.
I JUST DON'T LIKE HIM.
DON'T MISS.
I NEVER MISS.
SAY, HENRY,
AIN'T NO NEED
FOR YOU TO FIGHT YOUR WAY
INTO THAT VILLAGE.
WE-WE COULD JOIN UP AFTER--
I EVER TELL YOU ABOUT THE TIME
THE 'RAPAHOS...
CHASED ME UP A CANYON
OVER IN THE BIG LOST ?
NO, BUT I RECKON
YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME.
WELL, IT WAS OVER
ON THE HORSE PRAIRIE.
THIS BAND OF 'RAPAHOS
HAD BEEN CHASING ME THREE DAYS.
SO I SEEN THIS CANYON.
I FIGURED, WELL, I'LL WHIP
IN THERE, THEN I'LL SLIP OUT.
THE TROUBLE WAS THAT
THERE WAS A WAY IN BUT
THERE WASN'T NO WAY OUT AT ALL.
NOTHIN' BUT CLIFFS
HALF A MILE HIGH
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
A WHOLE DAMN TRIBE
OF BLACKFOOT DOWN THERE...
JUST MADDER THAN
TURPENTINE WILDCATS.
SO I HOLED UP
BEHIND SOME ROCKS,
BUT THAT DIDN'T DO NO GOOD...
BECAUSE THEY JUST
KEPT ON A-COMIN'.
ENTIRE SIOUX NATION.
ME OUT OF POWDER, OUT OF LEAD.
- I WAS ONE SCARED NIGGER.
- I THOUGHT YOU SAID
THEY WAS 'RAPAHO.
NO, GODDAMN IT !
THEY WAS PAWNEE.
WELL, WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOU ?
I GOT KILLED, OF COURSE.
SAY, DID YOU SEE ANYTHING
OF HEAVY EAGLE...
AFTER LA BONT GOT KILLED ?
RECKON NOT.
YOU'RE GETTIN' TOO OLD
FOR INJUN FIGHTIN', HENRY.
YOU'RE LOSIN' YOUR WIND.
YOU CALL THIS FIGHTIN' ?
JESUS.
I TOLD YOU YOU NEEDED SOMEBODY
TO LOOK AFTER YA.
YOU JUST LAY QUIET THERE
FOR A SPELL, AND
I'LL HAVE YA OUT OF HERE.
OH, BULLSHIT.
I'M GOIN' UNDER, AIN'T I ?
SON OF A BITCH !
WELL, WE TRAPPED A HEAP,
DIDN'T WE ?
THE COUNTRY WAS OURS
FOR THE TAKIN',
AND BY GOD,
WE REACHED OUT AND TOOK IT.
YEAH, THEM WAS
SHININ' TIMES.
YOU AND RUNNING MOON
GOTTA MOVE FAST.
GET THE HELL UP
IN THE HIGH COUNTRY.
INJUNS DON'T LIKE IT UP THERE.
YOU CAN HAVE MY PACK MULE.
YOU AIN'T GOT NO PACK MULE.
LOOK, DON'T TALK SO DAMN MUCH.
OH, CHRIST'S SAKES.
I'M BLEEDIN' TO DEATH.
I'M GONNA TALK ALL I DAMN WANT.
LISTEN, YOU--
YOU OLD SON OF A BITCH.
YOU TELL ME THE TRUTH.
THAT VALLEY'S UP THERE.
YOU AND RUNNING MOON FOUND IT,
DIDN'T YA ?
IT'S UP THERE, AIN'T IT ?
AIN'T IT ?
YEAH, HENRY.
YEAH, IT'S UP THERE.
A WHOLE VALLEY
FULL OF PRIME BEAVER.
A MAN COULD LIVE EASY
THE REST OF HIS DAYS.
WAS THEY LIKE STARS
IN THE SKY ?
YEAH.
DID THEY HOLLER,
"TAKE ME, TAKE ME" ?
LIKE IT WAS
IN THE ASHLEY DAYS...
WHEN WE WAS FREE TRAPPERS.
OH, GODDAMN IT !
GODDAMN YOU,
HENRY FRAPP !