The events of this film
are based on confessions
... of Irish convict Alexander
Pearce, transported for stealing shoes
... executed in Hobart
Town in 1824 for murder.
Even before he hung
Pearce to murder,
... his story was told
all the colonies.
But in the months of
death was reported in London.
What has been said and
continues on,
... this is the truth.
Alexander Pearce, an Irish convict,
... imprisoned on the Isle of Sarah,
... achieved the unthinkable,
the unforgivable,
... and ran away.
On the first occasion
made with other convicts 7.
In the second with a single partner.
There were two escapes in the cannibalism
... and both times, Pearce
was the only survivor.
He was executed for murder in Hobart,
... on July 19, 1824.
But before he died confessed.
First his captor, the
Lieutenant John Cuthbertson.
And finally my Phillip Conolly,
the priest who ...
followed until the end.
These are the events.
THE LAST OF ALEXANDER PEARCE CONFECIÓN
Hobart Town, Earth
Van Diemen 1824.
Judge Knopwood room.
They can not read, you know?
I think the pass
midnight is required here.
It is one of the rare
beauties of this island.
Clear.
You are becoming
in old Mr. Conolly.
Lately it is a parade
which goes to the barracks.
Yeah.
Is business, one of the servants
Her Majesty a cannibal.
Wild Europe.
Hung.
I was told that Alexander
Pearce asked to see it.
Hear his confession.
Now if.
Remember that your evil
form and the correct ideas,
... return to the
lord and this will have mercy.
Verse 557.
Let me know how to react Pearce
the verses of the Bible.
Please?
How do you think Conolly
Take a thing like this?
He and Pearce come from
Catholic won it.
Want to hang it.
It is normal that we are all
attracted to blood.
The two sons of hunger and misery.
¿Hunger and misery?
You see a lot of opportunity, I tell you that
... there is two different things
where the wheat wine,
... Pearce and Connolly.
My name Conolly.
The Judge said
which called for a priest.
¿Alexander Pearce is his name, no?
Pearce was hung,
repent and confessed.
As desired.
So ...?
Have you come to see the devil?
The theft, by and before anything else.
I am here so you can
Mr Pearce confess.
I know, me hung.
We deceive and the truth is not ...
Back permission, born Monahu,
... only 6 miles
where I was born.
Child beggars by fighting
in life from the beginning.
Several thefts took him to Australia.
In doing so many times, was
sent to Sarah Island.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
Governor Sorell
is not good sir.
I repent.
I suggest you turn your back on this,
... unless you hurt.
Welcome to Sarah Island.
Have been sent here
for the remainder of his sentence.
No errors in it.
If you die trying to escape.
Beyond this post
terrain is wild,
... where no man survived.
Those who tried
been bitten by hunger,
... and have fallen into the
hands of the savage.
Will be eliminated,
... until the last.
While they are here to work.
If they work hard, not
will have problems.
Better not want to anger him.
Walking.
On the island of all Sarah
were willing to betray.
They spoke of redemption,
... but all that
knew was suffering.
If trying to kill, or
died or caused a fight.
This is how it is, that was what happened.
We can go.
His boat is full of oil.
They can come with me.
- How long you plan this?
- One time.
- In fact chest.
- We need 6 for the boat.
- I'm going.
- Me too.
- It's time to go.
- We must hurry.
- Quick before sunset.
- Quick.
Christ.
- Who is the musket?
- The guard of the island.
Be here in an hour.
Do not run away at that.
- Let go.
Quick, quick.
We are going to Jericho, we have friends there.
¿Jericho, why not swim to China?
Damn, we can sail
As on earth.
Accomplished nothing.
I had been told to take a boat.
The Travers and fought all night.
What were the provisions?
- None.
- Nothing?
When the time comes
just had a panic.
Take a pan but it was bad.
I had the idea that we could
find food there.
There were no animals, nothing to eat.
It is a desert land,
and we got there.
Greenhill, the browser.
Travers, the butcher.
The French and Everbright Kennerly.
Dalton.
Bodenham.
I joined all south
... only had for 4 days.
Traveled per day, and
acampábamos at night.
First some valleys
surrounded by trees.
And trees.
We stayed hidden
so that we see.
Grenhil, guided
the sun and stars.
He said he traveled to the east.
Every day we expected
to reach Jericho.
And on the fourth day we
ran out of supplies.
On the eighth day, we arrived
to a great mountain.
We think finding
something to hunt or eat.
Across the road we saw no
animals or wild.
The place was empty.
We were dead of starvation.
All we had
was eating leather.
So I boiled some pieces.
The pain of hunger was fierce.
Edward Brown was
wrong, it was always slow,
... but in the morning
he could barely walk.
Keep the pace.
Can not.
Jesus, are very hungry.
We delayed.
Okay, I know.
It was all green.
Why did not return,
... took 9 days, and
knew they had no sense?
Travers and Greenhil wanted
walking at night.
Where are they now?
The next morning, 4
We went to the front.
- Come late.
- Yes, but there is another.
I went south with a friend.
The told me about a trip to Africa,
walked for weeks without food.
The girls were 6 and others.
What happened?
Ate to
others live.
That is murder.
Is better than all die.
But it is still murder.
- That's it.
- Do I want to stain my conscience?
They did the easy part.
What does ...
To kill the other by slow.
No, I propose to Dalton.
He offered to come
when none wanted.
I suggest that we kill for meat.
One dies so that others may live.
It was true, we dragged Dalton,
... and once Greenhill said that.
The idea we are all full.
We wanted to eat.
That is horrible Pearce.
We're both Irish.
Born hungry.
Famous Irish famine.
Throughout the country with crops lost,
... Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
But hunger has not
been reason to kill
... and eating a man.
I do not idee.
No matter what I thought ...
It is a mortal sin, I will not lie.
O Hell awaits you.
I do not ...
... I would not go as murderer.
What have you done?
Greenhill made all
take part in it.
He did so no one left out.
After that Kennerly
and Brown did,
... but did not know his plan.
It was a tough spot.
For the rest of the way these
... took the parts of Dalton.
Step when no one miles were gone.
Greenhill call
but did not respond.
We went south, they needed to return,
... perhaps feared that hung.
Greenhill said he did not
be followed,
... never.
But listen they did.
Arrived at the station
the island of Sarah,
... but died after 3 days
... due to the trip.
What they said about us?
Nothing, could not speak.
They returned quite well.
But they took their sides.
They took part of his demise.
Ate the same as us.
Jailer.
Can you read Mr Pearce?
We have eternity, you'll see tomorrow.
The circumstances
including crime,
... is considered a heinous crime.
Is associated with the prisoner cannibals,
... as the same legends
vampire of Greece.
We confess that this
when our eyes,
... were filled with fear of the
that was in front the judge,
... and believed to have
sated by human flesh ...
This is bad for the neighborhood.
I hope you will repent
before being hanged.
Your salvation depends on it.
It was very sour on the court.
Not serve well if you follow this very badly.
Looks like a monster.
Mr. Pearce continued.
Then continue down 4
days for a very bad spot.
But we reached a large river,
stopped for a day or two,
... looking for a place to cross.
It would be better if you could swim.
Everything would be easier.
If you surrender Bodenham,
lose for us?
By God.
It's normal.
We were sick.
We stayed two nights there because of that.
After that we started walking.
We clean the river, in our
way it was all hell.
We believe a village or see
something from the mountain.
Was difficult.
We spent all day climbing.
At the top we could see
was the vast land for miles.
It was sad but not
was more to follow.
Walked the entire day.
Hunger and cold we invaded.
Give me that.
If I kill you right here
lost the lighter.
Jesus.
Here, see?
Do not miss.
Continue walking for another
3 or 4 days, I do not remember.
I remember sitting at
principle of a valley,
... Mather approached me.
Come on, move.
Get up.
Here there is nothing.
Keep looking.
You sent me.
What?
- Not here.
- Do not die, not here.
- I do not want to die here.
- Do not die.
But when we return
Bodenham be dead.
- See?
- Jesus.
Better him than us.
The heart and the liver was
everything we use that night.
Now we had many provisions.
Subtitles by Kosh Inc.
After a day, divided
the body and continue walking.
We walked for 3 days ...
When we cross the first crossing
west we could see for miles.
On the other side had a
River where there were trees.
We stopped there at night and
continue down the river for 3 days.
We saw many animals, kangaroos, emus ...
We said we would die before
to kill one of us.
Were in love now.
We could not catch them, they were very fast.
And almost just supplies.
Vayámonos alone.
You know what you are capable
the bastard of Greenhill.
Kill his mother
before you get hungry.
So?
What?
Tomorrow?
I was hungry again.
And the love of brothers no longer existed.
We ate the last of Bodenham,
... was not enough to satiate.
Mather did not accompany us,
... idea was to boil some roots.
Alto, said that does not kill more.
Tell him.
Keep away from the ax.
Damn.
It was getting worse, cruelty.
It was obvious to Mather
that their time was counted.
And he clung to his life
Although we knew the lost.
Let his soul rest in peace.
If.
We stayed there for
few days and continue.
Each took a
Mather of them.
I was the next era
just a matter of time.
God!
I just slipped, I'm fine.
Are you sure?
We stayed there for a few days while
Traver's foot was wrong.
I thought it would die,
Greenhill but embraced it.
An improved time.
Travers was not yet well
but when it was enough ...
well enough to walk, we continue.
That was a week after
Mather's murder.
After crossing the slope,
reached a large river.
Travers could not swim so during
vagamos three days by the shore ...
looking for a place to cross.
Then the walk began Travers
to become black.
It hurt, so I loaded it Greenhill.
I'm just slowing down,
Bob, let me here.
- I'm just a burden.
- You will get well, you'll fine.
Things went well for two days.
Continue without me, he said.
So you can die in peace, he said.
It would be good for him and for us,
damn unhappy.
Greenhill decided to stop at a
clearly illuminated by the moon.
And Travers was worse.
Smelled of death.
Kill me, kill me at once.
You continue.
Just let me die, please.
As I was sacrificed to a
man for the good of the majority.
Tell them to repent,
But what is the point?
Hunger is a real attack
against brotherly love.
- It's a fickle feeling.
- Well, it seems to me that ...
a full stomach is a prerequisite
for good manners.
Without that, no man knows
that may require you to make hunger.
You must repent, Alexander Pearce.
Without that there will be no forgiveness.
We ate at Travers and others.
When continued our way, we get
everything we could carry.
But Travers was wrong.
There was nothing on the other side of the mountain.
Why the hell are we as
toys for a living?
You hear me?
Why I had to pass
Travors to that in the leg?
The devil.
Greenhill became a threat.
I started to watch after that.
I tried to encourage thinking that soon
come to the inhabited part of the country.
We walked a long way.
Helped me more than usual and always
carried the ax to the back while walking.
She was put under the head when
is sleeping.
Survive on the remains of Travers.
When finished, walk
with empty stomachs.
After four days,
hunger again ...
worse than before.
Clearly, one of the two die.
Greenhill tried to catch
unprepared and kill me.
Since then neither
could hardly sleep.
After killing Greenhill
wandered over three days.
Then I took my rope and tried to hang himself.
Could not, the Lord
I was watching from the other side.
Nothing should have been.
Should have been on the island ...
all we should be.
But it was not.
I found a camp of natives.
Have considered a blessing
I nailed a spear into his back.
But they were not approached.
They lurk hidden.
Never again see another.
From there the road
became more hospitals.
I walked a few more days by a swamp.
There were ducks.
I could not get to be thrown
to fly, but some small.
From the top of the hill vi
a great mountain.
Follow the river towards her.
A few days later I met
a flock of sheep.
Sheep.
This is how it came from the bay
until Jerry Town.
A journey that no man
had done before.
It took almost three months.
- Impressive.
- Really?
Reached the settlement in
very poor condition.
I was so famished that people
thought it was a ghost.
He recovered with their help and
path between pastoralists continued ...
huts and caves, as inhospitable.
When crossed with other convicts
it recognized ...
said that the Government
he had forgiven.
Over time, when recovered force
joined two other former prisoners, ...
Davis and Sheffield.
They walked from the west
for a couple of months ...
making mischief and stealing.
The three were captured
after a shooting.
Davis was shot in the leg.
Courts.
Knopwood attended the event, decided mandar
Pearce again at the Sarah Island.
Why is he there again?
Ask directly.
I did not believe it, I thought that was
covering the other convicts.
He confessed all the crimes,
murder, cannibalism.
I thought I was trying
take the hair ...
for others, and Greenhill
others continue to run.
Who would believe that a
type so little ...
would cross the island, much less
that was the only survivor ...
such a ridiculous question?
It's a thief.
It is a phoney, an Irish
recalcitrant, ...
as indomitable as any.
But even so, the citizen king.
But I could not believe
it was a savage.
Anyway, even if
Indeed, there is no body.
And for a death penalty for murder
the court requires the corpus delicti, ...
not only the word of a
known liar.
How are you responding?
- I am not your judge.
- No, but I do what I was.
And Pedder, and received a fair trial.
What happened when he was sentenced
to return there?
When he was sent to Sarah Island, ...
I dare say that I
did not agree.
Its reputation precedes it
and the rest of the prison population ...
what looked like a hero instead
than as a depraved criminal.
Auction was crazy.
He spent most of the time
tied to a pole on the island Grommit.
Pearce was very crazy.
I think what prompted Cox
to escape the second time.
¿Cox was the man he killed?
Thomas Cox.
Cox Pearce killed and eight days
flight, when they still had supplies.
Did not show any remorse
when he taught us ...
where were the remains of Cox.
The corpus delicti.
- And here we are.
- Here we are.
Fellow or not, man
is a monster.
Opened to this young man in half
and we ate.
And if all that still had
bread and cheese in their pockets.
Then changed the belief that
was a hero when Pearce took ...
back to camp with
The remains of Cox.
Cox was sacrificed because
it was more sensible for him.
I have an invitation.
Sorell ...
kindly asked to
honored him with their presence ...
for dinner tonight.
That's new, Philip.
It was the same story I had
Pearce counted.
Submerged in itself, Pearce was
sent back to Sarah Island.
Marked as a liar and a hero,
his return was a cruel twist.
Once he had escaped and now
was the "choice" of Sarah Island.
As such, it became
in lesson.
The punishment was accumulated on the punishment.
I wonder what would cause minimal
left to chance.
Determined to escape their torment,
Thomas Cox invited the young ...
Pearce to flee to him.
Pearce escaped a second time,
moved north along the coast.
Outside of himself, Pearce killed Cox
when he discovered that they could not swim.
With food still in your pocket,
Pearce butchered the boy.
He signals to the first boat that passed
and confessed his crime for the second time.
This time successfully.
The corpus delicti.
Residence of the Governor Sorell
Pearce's story, in brief:
He escaped twice from Sarah Island.
On both occasions he ate
their peers.
The reports of the newsletter have
had a record audience.
Tomorrow it will hang for murder.
I was among those who tried.
The chief judge has ruled that Pedder
Pearce's body will be stuffed ...
after they die.
What irony, I guess ...
that disequen a cannibal.
For the good of society
and science.
And a lot to preserve
this savagery.
He is Catholic, is not it, Mr. Connolly?
Yes, this is Governor Sorell.
Already acquitted of their sins?
No, it's a sad case and
I have no problems ...
the lovely table by Mrs. Brown.
- I heard his confession.
- The prisoner gave details ...
I have stopped cold.
It is an uncomfortable topic, inappropriate
to discuss at the table.
So we have to eat
soon to discuss it in the room.
No, no, no.
And why is confesarlo
with a priest?
Not to die in sin.
Swift described an island that
people kept eating.
I believe that dominated
by the British.
What savageness.
It makes no sense,
Is not it, Mr. Connolly?
I think what he meant is that
to deny the Irish people ...
rights in their own country ...
- Sure, it's a satire.
Only one would dream of Irish ...
eating another man, ...
even a savage.
Ireland has suffered a lot.
As I understand, Mr. Conolly,
you will address the convicted.
Yes, it is.
How can you give peace of mind
a monster like him?
The ignominious results ...
disobedience of the law
and humanity ...
can not be ignored.
The blood must atone for blood,
society demands it.
Pearce crimes have been
checked and systematic.
You can not be lenient with him and
really need to get revenge ...
with his death.
But this man witnessed shocking
pain and suffering.
The man that I am prepared
to the gallows, came here ...
already inclined to commit
criminal acts, but here ...
Van Diemens Land ...
shared suffering with some
the most despicable human beings in the universe.
A perverse generation addicted
adultery, blasphemy, ...
malice, laziness,
deception and drunk ...
extremely recalcitrant
reprehensible.
Sent him to Sarah Island,
place for secondary punishment.
If the whip could be amended to
a man, Pearce should be ...
because he was very competent
more lashes on the back ...
as any other man and
Even so, he ran away.
He witnessed the murder and killed
himself, escaped and killed again y. ..
have eaten human flesh,
is a beast.
The beatings became so crazy.
And die here alone in this
strange island where the boys ...
do not learn anything other than pain,
anger, blood and death.
Should a complete human being
in a place so corrupt?
But yes, I will ...
peace of mind ...
while waiting for death,
according to the will of His Majesty.
I do so for fear, Ms. Brown.
- I fear, Mr. Connolly?
- For fear ...
to what we could all become.
Here, at the end of the world.
So I propose a toast.
For ...
progress.
For progress.
Alexander Pearce, this is the last
day that you spend on earth.
When dawn comes, it will
among the dead.
Your soul will be saved or be lost ...
Christian in Paradise
or infinite torment.
Has been found guilty of murder
and there is no doubt that whoever ...
to spill human blood by
human hand will have their blood ...
because God made man
his image and likeness.
I ask solemnly, Alexander,
to pray for his soul and ask ...
salvation in his final hours as
so he asked the thief and found ...
which tied to die
crucified beside our Lord, ...
can also ask and
find you.
Condemned to die on Earth
but acceptable in the eyes of the Lord.
No other way has been opened
for life insurance before you.
This is your only salvation
is not time to delay or hesitation.
Gallows, Hobart Town, July 19, 1824
Huge crowd.
Hopefully not
way.
¡Cuélguenlo!
Die!
"It killed hundreds of souls in their wake ...
"And decided
publicly their fault ...
I think we will be here forever.
Conolly is not what one says
synthetic example.
Look who is there.
That damn tracatán Philip.
I think we all know that this man
escaped last year from Sarah Island.
Come on over!
¡Ahórquenlo!
Go to Hell, Alexander Pearce!
This the body of Christ,
who gave his life for you.
Well ...
and ended up with that.
Even before he hung
to Pearce for the crime of murder, ...
The story spread all
colonies, ...
and months after it was hung,
made headlines in London.
A few were imported, if there was
some, this was just a man ...
possibly evil, but more
likely a belligerent thief ...
entangled in a skein of
extreme circumstances.
The world is always more
easily from a distance ...
and stories of monsters and
things like that.
So remember to Alexander,
not as a man.
But they have said little truths
as big as this:
A full stomach is a prerequisite
for good manners.
Without that, no man knows
that may require you to make hunger.