Down with the gun, fool.
Where is the gold, Kingsley?
Since you never come back.
Plug it.
Where is it gold, Major?
I skin you alive if you do not talk.
Fucking asshole.
Wait.
Winnetou.
Had it in the Ozark Indians
waiting for me.
Is the letter ... he is ...
I went to my village.
Flying Arrow has all the paper
to put Winslow.
There is at
where the gold is hidden.
You have to keep secret.
I do so until they called me.
Now we have all the evidence,
is no doubt ...
Major Kingsley that the gold
the army has been stolen.
The gold transport
that he led ...
Fort Dawson has left
but it never arrived.
Can I 'word?
The defense has' t speak.
To whom are you doing here, gentlemen?
To Major Kingsley.
For the honor of a brave
and good soldier ...
that the gold from Fort Dawson
would have been stolen.
What happened? The fort
had to be evacuated ...
and it had gold in safety
be charged.
Major Kingsley left the escort
then without the "t gold leave.
That was the right decision ...
because that is underway escort
robbed and slain.
Dan 's been away gold.
He acted as officer correct:
he had the gold
Three male escort.
He wanted only three man
gold transport through a field ...
that is full of rebels,
crooks and Indians?
Yes, Mr. Prosecutor.
That he has done intentionally.
Yes, I have that impression.
And where is the gold now?
Major knew that the leather,
know that he was duty faithfully.
Where it is gold, we do not know.
I will tell you that.
In Mexico.
Like the 'good' Major.
This charge ring
I ask 's court ...
to a suspension to Kinsley's
daughter, Mabel, is present.
Miss Kingsley is underway with
The last letter from her father.
That letter calls the Major Friday
and indicate where it is gold.
I protest.
That letter is a deliberate
astray. I think ...
I withdraw
the prosecutor 's word.
The request
is granted.
The session is delayed
Miss Kingsley to present.
If the river is dry cases,
we gain an hour ...
as we go forward.
I know this region.
I come here often for business.
Here is some more to get
and business is business.
A Roman once said:
Pecunia non Olette.
That means money is trump.
Or something.
It means: Money stinM not.
Smart. Funny. Money stinM not.
Smart guys who Romans.
You want what?
How you called again?
It was not Mabel Kingsley?
Yes, but things I have
no sense.
That is something for men,
not for beautiful girls.
Wait for my sign.
Halt. Hands up.
Of that car and fast.
From the car off, I said.
Get out.
Hurry.
Enter the letter.
What letter?
The letter stating
where the gold is.
Love her.
Halt. No movement.
Weapons road and hands up.
Old Shatterhand.
Go in a row.
Help, help.
You disarms the men now.
Me? No, you know.
I am a peaceful citizen.
And a coward.
Or something.
That bastard.
That put me on the spot about.
Do not.
I got a different idea.
We get them later Friday ...
and Old Shatterhand
We help.
What are you doing?
But let 's op.
Help.
Easy, easy.
The boss.
The boss is coming.
What was wrong?
We had almost the letter ...
but threw Old Shatterhand
soot in 't eat.
Suckers. Where are the horses?
That he chased away.
Catch them. Craig and I go
back to Old Shatterhand.
I get it.
Father's last letter.
He is posted in Winslow.
I know of no Indian.
In Philadelphia
nobody could translate.
It is Apache.
I understand.
What's wrong?
What do these words?
I tell that later. Now you can
better still do not know.
First, you have witnesses
for the court.
Can I give you some good advice?
You vertroum me anyway?
If no other.
There they are.
That is the coach.
There is only one driver on.
What happened?
You are too late.
It was horrible.
We were robbed.
But I have the attack
declined.
This city and this environment
are known as very quiet.
See for yourself.
Empty cells. There are no
shootings or robberies.
Would you Miss Kingsley
protect ...
and arrange a hotel room?
Of course.
Come on.
Nobody knows
where my father is ...
and yet he may soon dishonor
have resigned. Why?
Why the hurry?
Is enough for a defamation
Public dishonor to dismiss?
Miss Kingsley ...
Let me finish you.
My father raised me
according to the principle ...
that honesty is worth more
than money or property.
He let 's escort act
as astray for the crooks.
And now he is correct
accused of theft.
He 's solid gold rescued
when his men were already dead.
Dead heroes, HC?
What you insinuating?
Their graves are known.
Is Kingsley than guilty
because his grave is not known?
If he is buried somewhere.
He may also still be alive.
But where is the letter
that your father must be free advocate?
Let me see him.
The letter is here.
Give him.
No.
Wantroum the court?
No, I distrust you.
That is unheard of.
Your Honor, I object.
If the prosecutor again
go to his place?
Miss Kingsley, I warn you
Because 't court finds that your father
bravely defends ...
explains it to you now no punishment.
But now I ask you ..
allow the court access
in this letter?
No.
See?
The postmaster said in Winslow
that an Apache brought the letter.
The area of the Apache
lies on the border with Mexico ...
where your father with "t gold.
No.
No? Let see that letter.
I know why they did not want.
This letter calls your father is not free,
but charged him.
Nonsense.
Let see that letter.
If the prosecutor
go to his place?
Silence.
Miss Kingsley, the content
of the letter to comply ...
if they denM that is detrimental
for her father. Is it so?
No, Your Honor. But the letter
calls himself my father is not free.
Therefore, I more
Evidence come ...
as it courted me 60 days
postponement would be willing to give.
Would you 't find gold itself?
I beg to those 60 days for you
adjudicates on my father's honor.
After those 60 days you are in Mexico
in the arms of your father.
No, I have the time necessary
to be here to collect evidence.
I am to inspect the letter.
The court will consider your request
grant ...
If you have a witness who has
your hopes on new evidence supports.
I am the witness.
May I ask who you are?
I become Old Shatterhand
said.
You did far too conspicuous.
They wanted that letter does not give.
Loser.
Kingsley did not gold.
He is dead and
Winnetou has buried him.
First he hid the gold
and in the letter is true.
That girl is cunning.
Where did they 60 days
necessary?
In order to steal the gold itself.
What are you doing?
Miss Kingsley has room 6.
No violence.
Not now and not here.
Relax, I only get that letter.
Tell that Davis' s time.
Murdock,
do not precipitate things.
Get out.
Ram but on those keys.
Even harder.
My mother always said:
Only hard music is good.
Otherwise you have nothing.
Who's there?
A harbinger of the court.
What is it?
I got it rechtbanmerslag.
That you must still sign.
Where is the letter?
No sound and no wrong
move or I shoot.
I assume you the letter hum.
Am I right?
I got that letter.
Then I would like to see him.
Do you recognize him?
Put him down.
You get him.
We heard gunfire.
Is anyone hurt?
I wanted to chat, but my size
wanted something else.
Would you get the sheriff?
Immediately.
Now I know why I
The letter had to give. BedanM.
Miss Kingsley, we go.
You must now tackle.
I let the sheriff
a horse for you.
When we drive, we
morning in Colorado.
What does this guy out.
Where did they let you
escape?
What an ignorance.
Are you sometimes a plant?
Yes, these are plants.
I am very grateful.
Said Mr. Shatterhand
that the trip was to Rio Pecos.
No, to Colorado.
Oh yes, the Colorado.
No soldiers escort necessary?
No, we save us.
I am botanist, honey.
I collect rare plants.
What?
Well, this is beautiful.
My name is Rose. I am also known
Prairie Flower said.
I am also rare.
Search still not longer.
Gather me anyway.
I wait here for a friend.
A certain Sam Hawkens.
I can not now.
I have to go to the Wild West.
I want 'n onontdeMe plant
found ...
that my name will get:
herba castlepoolensis gigantis.
Hey, where is the whism?
I raise my bet.
You lose that card.
Excuse me, did you perhaps
Sam Hawkens seen one?
That is there.
Again, your turn.
I go.
Milord?
You now what those differences.
If I am not mistaken.
Sam.
Milord.
Come to my chest.
There you are again, milord.
What you see out.
Again, your dress again.
That continues here.
First pay.
Where is your shirt?
Wasted. Unfortunately.
Your shirt and your jacket too?
Unfortunately.
Your hair too?
For those hairs, I would like 72 dollars.
But then I pay.
Unfortunately.
Let us agree on.
Sheriff, give me a glass of water.
I am far from the headache.
Forget it.
I do it.
BedanM. Come, then I grab your colt.
Not with those soldiers there.
Tomorrow's redemption
I bring back water.
Oh, I feel better already.
Tomorrow 's too late.
I want now.
They go to Colorado.
Now I can tell you what the
words from the letter mean.
The chief
knows the road to gold.
That chief
I met later.
Winnetou?
Yes, my blood brother.
He will show us the way.
My father had often
about him.
He wrote that he was proud
Winnetou as a friend.
When we meet him?
Quick, dive behind the horses.
Halt.
Dismount.
For me?
Yes.
You were still at the session?
Yes, we are here
on behalf of the war.
To protect?
What does that mean?
And as witnesses.
You guys are guards.
Afraid that we go to Mexico?
You did it against an officer.
We do not need babysitting.
Shatterhand and I ...
Hold on.
At night you see no trace.
How did you find us?
A soldier heard
Miss Kingsley said ...
you guys to Colorado
go.
I got a misstep.
According to the sheriff told you
that we went to Rio Pecos ...
I never with the sheriff
discussed. This is a trap.
The crooks are again
behind us.
Here you have your share, mate.
Quick, on horseback.
We need Old Shatterhand
to win.
What are you planning?
In the water they hit the track
knrijt. Hopefully they keep that up.
If they follow us, is
a strategic ambush the ...
Strategy tells me nothing.
But I do know that
Winnetou us responds.
Where is my herba
castlepoolensis gigantis?
But the crooks are now
back to Shatterhand.
You can not track search?
Well, I did.
Here they set
because they were knrijt t track.
They were returned
and it went along.
And if you're wrong?
I rarely mistaken me.
Come on.
Terrible, all these adventures.
Lieutenant, I got a strategic
task for you.
You shall ensure that
Mabel no flight to Mexico.
I go to our pursuers
Iastig make.
Wait, I want to know whether your plan
it is strategically justified.
That is nothing to you.
Do what he said
and watch me. Forward.
Miss Mabel.
Pay attention to me.
What do you want?
Militarily ...
this is a diversionary tactic,
Iuitenant.
Failure to do so, that is dangerous.
You are not afraid?
Please come down.
Hello, gentlemen.
Where are you going?
Halt.
Here I am.
This way.
Brown, you can track search.
Follow four-man Shatterhands
trace.
Do not shoot.
I want him alive.
Four men with me.
This way.
Faster, faster.
Along here.
This way, gentlemen.
Here is Shatterhand
Iangsgekomen.
The rest downwards.
These are their tracks.
We need that way.
Get out.
Bees.
Back, back.
That monster, too.
Look at that.
Here, this is the track.
Halt.
Search coverage.
This is Winnetou,
the chief of the Apache.
What do you know about my father?
He died in my arms.
There is Brown.
Where were you?
We have searched everywhere.
What you see out.
What happened?
First, what to drink.
Where is the rest?
Death.
The rest is dead.
We are surprised by Winnetou.
Put their guns against our
Just off the weapons.
I know more about where you
gold to find out.
Where to go?
In the fishing grounds of the Ozark
Indians is the solution.
I have to see themselves
report so that I might reveal.
Do you know where my father
buried?
I, the daughter of my friend
bring to his grave.
If she is in Winnetou,
I know where they go.
Only knows Winnetou
where Major Kingsley's grave is.
To prove that Kingsley
dead, they now go to his grave.
That would be best 's possible.
But en route ...
we Ozark against Indians.
Winnetou that will help.
We must strike
for they are in the Ozark.
A frontal attack
is too dangerous.
We must therefore
in a decoy.
Everybody on horseback and forward.
Forward.
Hey, who are you?
Sam. Milord.
Also bees come?
We're good. I saw them.
They run 800 meters for us.
Forward.
There they are.
We address them.
Stay in coverage and follow me.
I got a job that I go to military
measures must fulfill.
My father saw as a soldier
more human standards.
I know who their gang leader.
That man also knows where
Major Kingsley is buried ...
and he will try us
to catch up.
Does it still hurt?
Only when I laugh.
Laugh or not.
But if I see you, then ... au.
They now ride for us.
Dodge them.
That is militarily 's best.
On the prairie, they can us
not entrap.
But ...
That can only be in 't good area.
If it happens,
I know what I have to do.
Did you whism with you?
No. Tools and nails.
Search by cart.
Stop. No.
He has bad luck
if he does not drink it.
Wait.
I got an idea.
Help, help.
Someone calls for help.
Come, eropaf.
No, you stay here.
Help.
Help me anyway.
I'm dying.
What is my white brother?
That cart can never be turned over
on such flat land.
The wheels are very
and the horses are loose.
So a trap?
You bet.
But those poor deserve help.
We need him to help.
That I will do now.
Stop.
You walk into a trap.
That man needs help.
It 's ambush.
You are the nail and cowardly.
You will not go there.
Sam, you look at them.
If a hawk.
If I am not mistaken.
I do not recommend
of a citizen.
You do not wind up.
Winnetou and I
they stalk.
Help.
I can no longer listen.
He will die if we him
t help.
That wait is terrible.
Where are these two heroes?
They let him
very humane death.
I am sure what to do.
Even though the 'n trap.
Halt, halt.
No.
Touch officer who is not.
I want him alive.
Freeze or he will die.
So anyway.
Listen, we have a hostage.
So be wise.
We take him under hands
to give you the letter.
Drop by watching.
Do not come too close,
otherwise your soldier is coming.
And if they do not come?
Oh, come they did.
They are still good,
noble people.
Come up.
They're coming.
And?
They wait for us.
What do they do with him?
They will torture him.
Until we give the letter.
My god, give that letter then.
As long as they have Cummings,
they can blackmail us.
And after they kill us.
The lieutenant must come.
And I know only one way.
I get it. If the moon two
fingers over the mountains is ...
are you back from the Sioux.
Yes.
Watch out for 's Deputy
chief. He hates whites.
I know.
What is he up to?
Black Panther he ever rescued.
They are now friends. He gives
it 's set to warriors.
Then we try
to free the hostage.
I'm afraid.
For him they do nothing.
My brother will be back.
He's quick.
Hey, there is no audience?
You miss the show.
Starting something.
Check with a couple man
where they remain.
You go with me four.
I'm a little fun with your plan,
so I would only talk.
Where is the gold?
We do not know.
Do you think that I faith?
Hey boss, there is nobody
to confess.
What are you doing here, was found face?
I wish Panter Black speak.
Why?
My friends at the river
the Ticano are in distress.
They are threatened
by white bandits.
Black Panther is dead. Red
Buffalo is now 't Sioux tribal chief.
All whites are bandits.
Therefore, the Sioux
The disagreements have been excavated.
They're coming.
Did you hear that?
So we can begin.
Give the letter.
We only want t gold.
My sister white
must now be brave.
My brother is so white
with the warriors.
Give that letter here.
Well, as you want.
I take it that letter.
Only when I hear clop.
Then you can bring the letter.
Slowly and halfway.
You tie him down and walk back.
If they afrennen to the letter ...
is the only hostage.
Then they overwhelm the Sioux
and we save the lieutenant.
He was unconscious.
Get 's water.
How long have you wait?
If you do not bring that letter,
I save him dead.
Terrible. I must go now.
Let me go.
That red devil
Iaat her go.
I have a better idea.
Cut him loose.
Get four horses.
Come quickly.
Let the horses draw.
Is there something?
Here with that letter or ...
I count to three ...
One.
Two.
There they are finally.
Here is the letter.
I bring you the letter.
Why not?
Very slowly.
Not too fast.
Let him down.
Cut the cord.
Come on, do what she says.
Tahesan? What does that mean?
Takesan mi umann
That is for Apache
'the chief know. "
The chief?
That is down Winnetou.
Grab him.
lndianen. Sioux.
Back to the horses.
I do not see my white brother.
The Sioux as enemies
come.
Finally, there they are.
Gentlemen, what is this?
We are still friends?
Winnetou does not want to slaughter.
I have to give me the Sioux.
All whites will die
to the torture pole.
Also Winnetou:
the friend of the whites.
If their wounds are healed,
they die on the torture pole.
Then they
prove their manhood.
Also Winnetou. The traitor.
Who me a traitor is called a coward.
He has Winnetou not fair
fought.
He simulation of friendship
of the Sioux.
There is
no more friendship.
BedanM.
It's all my fault.
That you should not say.
But if I had listened ...
I will tell you what.
My father would be the same
have done.
BedanM.
That is quite a consolation.
Cozy, you know.
The chief of the Sioux
should listen to me.
You've Red Buffalo
nothing to say.
lntegendeel.
I know where much gold is ...
to rifles, gunpowder and lead
to buy.
Or guns.
And all the warriors that you want.
A war costs money and I know
where the cash is from Fort Dawson.
Gold, pure gold.
A whole car full of gold.
You half
and I the other.
Mermen you anything?
Yes.
What a misery.
That is it.
Here he is.
Nobody knows this plant.
Such a beauty
my name can get.
He has already 's name.
What then?
Botanical donkey.
I know what you're planning.
It is the only way.
If the time is right,
I will be ready.
This showed facial said ...
I know what he said.
I also know that Red Buffalo
weapons' t want to buy gold.
But a war is devastating
for our tribes.
Red Buffalo know that I did not even
to the torture pole will speak.
So let your maiden torture:
to let me speak.
That is a worthy warrior.
Acting as a man in a skirt.
A coward
who dares not to fight.
I ashamed for the Sioux.
Their chief dares
or a girl to torture ...
but he dares not with me
for the gold to fight.
Do not listen to him.
I take the challenge.
I will kill you in a duel.
Even my white brother
know where it is gold.
He will lead Red Buffalo
if I die.
What is Red Buffalo
there opposite?
Then I leave you free,
except Old Shatterhand.
Then you get your horses
and you disappear for good.
So they do not follow behind you?
I will keep my warriors here.
Why not throw that coward?
Red Buffalo is overcome.
But Winnetou let him live.
The fishing grounds of the Ozark
are nearby.
But the crooks follow us.
The safe way is obstructed.
We need to Slangendal it.
Snakes?
Yes.
Many have already died
by their poisonous bite.
But do not worry,
flowers friend.
This is the Slangendal.
Only if we reach
the fishing grounds of the Ozark.
We have to drive slowly.
The road is rocky and narrow.
O, a fellow botanist.
Wonde_ul, or rather, great.
In the Slangendal loert death.
If your legs and your horses
this plant salve ...
keep the odor away the snakes.
Great.
What is that plant?
Herba slangensis enorma
stinkensis, if I am not mistaken.
The crooks know who planted not.
That costs them men and horses.
That does not look nice.
Would it be a trap?
We drive around it
and cutting them off.
That does not save the horses.
You're right. Follow them.
Look good.
It is full of snakes here.
Get out.
Back.
Winnetou.
Winnetou?
And now?
Two men have no horse.
So we never get more.
We are close to the Ozark.
They have enough horses.
And three solid for us.
Come on, we drive away.
Well.
These are our fishing grounds. You
be expected in our camp.
Winnetou bedanM White Feather
for his hospitality.
We make two zonsomlopen
use of.
Our injured friend
must recuperate.
These two whites are here
searching for rare plants.
Will you protect them?
Your white friends are welcome
in the Ozark long as they want.
This is the daughter of 't injured
paleface ...
that many months ago
in the Ozark knram.
I am here to promise
being issued.
White Feather know Winnetou.
There is' n canoe ready.
Winnetou the suspected al
The gold is
in the Valley of Death.
Winnetou know the way. Therefore
he will destroy the card.
My brother did not want to know
where it was gold.
Thus, it is exactly.
Gold often pay people
in the destruction.
But go to
the honor of your brave father.
He was Winnetou's friend.
BedanM.
Lieutenant, White Feather
gives us five warriors them.
If you want to stay here ...
No, I must do my duty.
Oh, it is your duty?
I just want to say that
I like to go. Really.
Today we drive further.
Wait, I get you later.
Delicious slender creature. Wait.
Say, bunny ...
when did you once loved
Sammetje for you?
Tonight.
Oh, tonight. Or never.
An echo.
Have you cross ...
Yes, me.
BedanM.
Major Kingsley
is honorable cases.
Would you still see the gold?
No. We know where it is.
My men get it on.
I would now like to be alone.
Hey, hello.
That's Sam.
No, bandits.
Halt.
None step closer.
I have another verassinkje
for you.
Hopefully you are now slim ...
or else
I should shoot them.
Throw away your weapons.
Is there something?
Road weapons.
Kingsley's daughter is enough.
NaaMe monkeys who let us here.
As we count them later.
Row for us
and lead us to 't gold.
That is the Valley of Death.
Red Buffalo
is his promise not after.
He will chase us
with Sioux fighters.
Here are chiefs
buried in 's time ...
that no whites
in our country.
The broad here to sulfur.
And petroleum.
This outfit stinM.
Hey stop, there front.
Maybe it 's a trap
rotindiaan of that.
Come, let them 't gold
Just get.
We wait here.
We have the maiden indeed.
A very pretty girl.
Not a bad idea.
You get 't gold.
You guys are back in three hours or ...
Without expensive horses' s four hours.
Then you leave them here.
But no minute longer.
Otherwise we cut
by its beautiful rockfish.
That would be a shame.
We seek cover behind the cart
as they took the gold deposit.
They will fall into the trap.
Forward, march.
Help.
Loosen them. We take them.
They are Ozark.
Do not worry, white friends.
Good idea to give them everything
to retrieve.
The gold in return for the maiden.
Women are now expensive.
It would be even nicer to
gold and the girl to have.
If they are dead,
we just suits her.
Yes, then we share her.
And? What do you think?
You are very deep
sunk.
Natural gas?
In this valley blowing the breath
of Manitoe.
Who knraads something in the sense
he will kill.
The gas burns.
Quick, back.
Where is the gold?
Halt.
The gold.
Where is the gold?
The Sioux.
Manitoe is mad at Red Buffalo
because he chooses crooks.
But Manitoe is satisfied ...
Red Buffalo as the Ozark helps
to liberate the prisoners.
There it is gold.
Down there.
Nonsense. You lie.
You are clogged.
If we do not find
are you coming. Search.
There.
He has the gold.
The Sioux are coming.
Quick, on horseback.
Hurry.
Fast horses.
No, no.
Let me live. I'm rich.
But you mention price.
Red Buffalo has paid.
The Great Spirit will 'm record.
Sam, I got him.
Come here.
He was quite.
Come on now.
Yes, I do so.
One moment.
Excuse me. From the rear.
What is it?
Never thought
I 'm still would find.
Does that vegetable soup
still no name?
Everybody knows it
that he is unknown.
But now he gets my name:
herba castlepoolensis gigantis.
Now in this town all sinners
are punished ...
the court is very pleased
to establish ...
that Major Kingsley
acted from a sense of duty.
This was due to his brave
daughter: Mabel Kingsley.
We are also grateful
two men ...
which are working
to combat injustice ...
and the right to celebrate victory:
The chief of the Apache,
Winnetou ...
and Old Shatterhand.