[ Chattering ]
SHH !
[ Man ]  LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
OF THE PRESS,
IT IS MY PLEASURE
TO WELCOME YOU...
ON BEHALF OF INTERNATIONAL
COMPUTEL CORPORATION...
TO PROJECT TIMERIDER.
PROJECT TIMERIDER
IS THE 16th IN OUR SERIES...
OF EXPERIMENTS
IN TIME TRAVEL,
AND TODAY WILL BE
OUR FIRST EXPERIMENT
WITH A LIVE ANIMAL.
[ Reporters Murmuring ]
A LIVE FEMALE RHESUS MONKEY
NAMED ESTHER G.
[ Reporters Chuckle ]
THIS EXPERIMENT, ONCE AGAIN
UNDER THE DIRECTION OF
DR. SAMUEL STELLAR,
HOPES TO SEND ESTHER G.
BACK IN TIME TO THE YEAR 1862...
AND RETURN HER SAFELY.
[ Cameras Clicking ]
BECAUSE OF THE SENSITIVE NATURE
OF THIS EXPERIMENT,
AND BECAUSE
INTERNATIONAL COMPUTEL...
IS NOT CONNECTED
WITH THE GOVERNMENT
IN ANY WAY,
THE LOCATION
OF THE PROJECT BUNKER...
AND THE LOCATION
OF THE SENDBACK PAD SITE
IS SECRET.
I'D LIKE TO THANK ALL OF YOU
FOR COMING TODAY...
AND TO WELCOME YOU
TO THE FASCINATING
AND WONDERFUL...
NEW WORLD OF TIME TRAVEL.
THANK YOU.
[ Applause ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Motorcycle Droning ]
I CAN'T SEE !
[ Man ]
IT'S SWANN.
HOW CAN YOU TELL ?
I CAN TELL.
[ Man ]
WHOEVER HE IS,
HE CAN SURE RIDE A BIKE.
[ Bearded Man ]
WELL, THAT'S SWANN.
- WHO DO WE GOT ?
- [ Both ]
IT'S SWANN.
SWANN COMING IN ?
MM-HMM.
I DON'T FIGURE IT, JESS.
YOU GUYS COULD HAVE MADE...
A LOT OF NICE BUCKS
ALL THESE YEARS
RIDING FOR A TEAM.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
A GREAT RIDER, JESS.
HE'D WIN
IF HE COULD FINISH.
WHAT KIND OF CRACK
IS THAT ?
NO OFFENSE, JESS.
OH, JESS, YOU TURN
A GOOD WRENCH.
I JUST WISH YOU'D STOP
PLAYIN' THOSE FLASHY TOYS
AND LET US GET IN BACK OF YOU.
WHY, YOU GUYS COULD BE SMOKIN'
WITH A LITTLE FACTORY SUPPORT.
OH, WELL,
YOU KNOW SWANN.
HEY, I PICKED UP SOME TIME.
HOW'S OUR TRANSMITTER ?
IT'S PRETTY HARD TO DANCE
WITHOUT MUSIC.
[ Jesse ]
IT'S OKAY NOW.
I THINK I GOT IT FIXED.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT BIKES
DID YOU USE TO MAKE THIS ?
MADE ENTIRELY FROM
FARM ANIMALS, MR. EARL.
RUNS LIKE A ROCKET UP TO 60.
AT WHICH POINT, I PUNCH
THIS LITTLE BUTTON HERE,
THE WHOLE THING TURNS INTO
AN ADULT MOTEL.
YOU JUST GOTTA
GET SERIOUS.
WHY ?
OH.
OKAY, YOU'RE UP TWO NOW, LYLE,
AND SHE'LL CLIMB LIKE A GOAT.
SIXTY-FIVE IS TOP
WITH THOSE TEETH.
DON'T YOU SEIZE
THIS SUCKER.
I GOT TWO INCHES OF FOAM
BETWEEN THE CASING
AND THE TRANSMITTER.
THAT'LL STOP THE BREAKUP.
THIS PICKS UP
AT CHECKPOINT ONE,
PROVIDING YOU DON'T
CRASH AND BURN.
[ Man On Tape ]
AT MILE 14,
OUTSIDE CHECKPOINT ONE.
SEE YOU AT NUMBER THREE
AROUND DUSK.
[ Man On Tape ]
BEAR LEFT.
KEEP THE CACTUS ON YOUR RIGHT.
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
TAKE THE HIGH SIDE.
ONCE OVER THE TOP,
HEAD DUE SOUTH
TO CHECKPOINT TWO.
[ Motorcycle Engine Revving ]
[ Whirring ]
[ Clicks ]
DR. SAM, I HAVE AN ERROR
IN THE PATH OF ALMOST
ONE MILLIRADIAN.
PROGRAM-BASED ?
NO, IT'S TIME-BASED.
WHAT ABOUT THAT WINDSTORM ?
WHERE IS IT ?
TWO HUNDRED MILES NORTHWEST.
WE'RE STILL TRACKING IT.
COULD HIT US IN TWO HOURS,
MAYBE ONE AND A HALF.
OKAY.
ESTHER'S ON-LINE.
[ Chuckles ]
HANG ON TO YOUR HAT,
DARLIN'.
HEY, JESSE,
YOU GOT A COPY ?
SWANN.
HOW'S IT GOING ?
YES, SIR.
MAN, IT'S HOT.
OVERCOOKED THE CORNER
ABOUT 20 MILES BACK,
BUT I DIDN'T BREAK
ANY OF OUR TOYS.
EVERYTHING'S WORKING--
WHOA !
WHO THE HECK IS THAT ?
GOTTA BE SWANN.
SUCKER CAN RIDE.
STAND BY FOR AUTOMATIC.
BRING UP CAMERA FOUR
TO EXTERIOR.
[ Swann ]
HEY, JESSE,
YOU STILL GOT A COPY ?
[ Static ]
[ Man ]
ALL SECTORS CLEAR.
TIME ZONE
IS LOCKED.
- [ Woman ]
PATH IS JUSTIFIED.
- HOW'S ESTHER ?
- ASLEEP.
- PATH IS STABLE.
PRELIGHT COMPLETE.
HOLDING GREEN.
[ Computer Voice ]
PERIMETER VIOLATION.
SECTOR FOUR.
- TERRY, IS THAT FOR REAL ?
- I DON'T KNOW, I'LL CHECK.
SECTOR FOUR.
PERIMETER VIOLA--
HEY, JESSE.
JESSE, THIS IS SWANN.
DO YOU READ ME ?
JESSE !
[ Man On Tape ]
WATCH FOR TALL ROCK FORMATION
ON THE RIGHT.
DOUBLE BACK IN THREE MILES,
MARKED WITH AN OLD TIRE...
WITH RED DAY-GLO
SPRAY PAINT.
TURN LEFT, STOP TAPE NOW.
ALL GREEN.
SEQUENCING FIELD START UP NOW.
[ Woman ]
FIELD IS UP.
[ Motorcycle Idling ]
OH, CRAP.
THIS THING IS USELESS.
JESSE ?
[ Computer Voice ]
TIMERIDER, YOUR SENDBACK
IS COMMITTED.
BEGIN FINAL COUNTDOWN,
MY MARK... NOW.
29... 28... 27... 26...
25... 24... 23... 22...
19... 18... 17...
16... 15... 14...
13... 12...
- TERRY ?
- YES, SIR.
DR. SAM, IT'S REAL !
- [ Dr. Sam ]  ABORT !
- [ Computer ]
SENDBACK !
NO GOOD.
[ Beeping ]
R.
"ESTHER G., TRANSMITTED BY
A '‘‘MASER' VELOCITY ACCELERATO
NOVEMBER 4, 1982."
HMM.
GEAR UP FOR BRING BACK.
RAY, CHECK TWO.  HARRY.
WE GOT IT ON REPLAY.
GIVE ME A POSITION
ON ZOOM CONTROL.
DO YOU READ ESTHER ?
BEYOND COMMUNICATION,
DR. SAM.
- START COUNTDOWN WHEN READY.
- SIXTY SECONDS TO BRING BACK.
GET YOUR PROGRAMS IN.
[ Terry ]
IT'S A MOTORCYCLE.
A MAN ON A MOTORCYCLE.
[ Static ]
JESSE, THIS IS SWANN.
DO YOU READ ME ?
[ Static Continues ]
[ Computer Voice ]
30... 29... 28... 27... 26...
- FIFTEEN SECONDS TO BRING BACK.
- 25... 24... 23...
START YOUR COUNTDOWN
WHEN READY.
20... 19... 18...
17... 16... 15... 14...
JESSE !
13... 12... 11...
10... 9... 8... 7...
6... 5... 4...
NOW !
[ Quietly ]
COME ON, BABY, BE THERE.
OH, BROTHER.
WHOEVER IT WAS,
HE'S STILL ALIVE.
GET THE FIELD TEAM MOBILE.
DON'T DISTURB ANYTHING
IN THE PERIMETER.
I WANNA KNOW WHO HE IS,
WHAT HE'S RIDING,
THE DIRECTION IN WHICH HE LEFT.
AND ABOVE ALL, I WANT
ABSOLUTE SILENCE ON THIS MATTER
TILL I SAY DIFFERENT.
IF I'M RIGHT, SIR,
HE STEPPED OUT
ABOUT 105 YEARS BACK.
AROUND 1875.
1875.
GOD ALMIGHTY !
WELL...
WE'VE GOT OUR EXPERIMENT NOW,
DON'T WE ?
[ Revs Engine ]
[ Speaking Spanish ]
- HI.
- [ Gasping ]
HI.
- MAN, AM I GLAD TO SEE YOU.
- [ Stammering ]
- WHERE THE HELL AM I ?
ENGLISH ?
SPEAK ENGLISH ?
[ Shuddering ]
[ Muttering In Spanish ]
UH, I WAS WONDERING IF
MAYBE YOU COULD SHOW ME
ON THIS MAP HERE WHERE, UH,
WHERE I AM.
[ Whimpering ]
HEY, YOU OKAY ?
HEY, COME ON, GET UP.
COME ON.
HEY.  HEY.
HEY, WHAT--
MISTER, WHAT--
HEY, SENOR.  SENOR !
HEY.
SENOR.  SENOR !
HEY, MISTER !
OH, NO.
HEY, SWANN.
SWANN, CAN YOU READ ME ?
THIS IS JESSE HARTLINE
AT SANTA INEZ.
DOES ANYBODY KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TO NUMBER 82 ?
[ Squawking ]
[ Starts Engine ]
- ANY SIGN OF HIM ?
- I AIN'T SEEN HIM.
[ Chattering ]
SWANN.  SWANN,
DO YOU READ ME ?
[ Sighs ]
WE'VE GOT HIM.
NOVEMBER 5, 1877.
DRINK UP, JACK.
WE DON'T MIND SPLITTING
THE TAKE THREE WAYS.
[ Laughs ]
BULLSHIT !
THIS WHOLE THING
IS BULLSHIT.
THEM RAGS IS BULLSHIT
AND SO ARE YOU.
- EASY, JACK, EASY.
- WELL, I JUST HAD IT
WITH YOUR ORDERING...
AND ALL THIS MEXICO CRAP.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
TAKE IT EASY.  TAKE IT EASY.
I'M GOIN' BACK UP NORTH.
THIS IS THE DUMBEST
DAMN DEAL I EVER SEEN.
JESUS CHRIST,
YOU'RE A LITTLE CRANKY
THIS MORNING, AIN'T YA ?
PUT THE GUN DOWN.
PUT IT DOWN, HELL !
DIDN'T YOU HEAR ME ?
I'M LEAVING.
NOW, BRING ME
MY SHARE OF THEM THINGS.
I'M GONNA BE SORRY
TO SEE YOU GO, JACK.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
SOME BEAUTIFUL SILK
TO TAKE UP NORTH, HUH ?
HEY.
- SILK.
- [ Chuckles ]
HEY, HEY.
DUMB BASTARD.
DUMB DAMN DEAL, HUH ?
YOU SHOT JACK, REESE.
NO KIDDIN'.
WHAT WAS I GONNA DO ?
HE TOOK HIS GUN OUT.
NOW HOLD ON A SECOND, REESE.
HE SAID
HE WAS GONNA GO BACK.
GODDAMN MARSHALLS CATCH HIS ASS,
THEY CATCH OURS.
MAKES SENSE WHAT HE SAYS.
RAGS, HUH ?
THAT'S FINE SILK.
RAGS ASS.
SORRY, JACK.
I DON'T THINK YOU'LL BE
NEEDIN' THESE ANYMORE.
HERE'S A NICE--
OH, NO, LOOK AT THIS.
GOT ALL HOLES IN IT.
ARE YOU GONNA TAKE IT ?
NO, IT'S TRASH.
CAN I HAVE IT ?
IT'S TRASH.
I TOLD YOU IT'S TRASH.
HEY.  HEY.
HEY, CLAUDE.
YOU LIKE THAT ?
IT'S TRASH.
LOOK, IT GOES GOOD
WITH MY WATCH VEST.
IT'S TRASH.
TAKE THAT OFF NOW.
NOW LOOK AT THIS.
LOOK AT THIS HAT.
DOES THAT LOOK GOOD ?
THAT'S YOU.
I LIKE THAT.
[ Mumbles ]
HURRY UP, BOYS, LET'S GO !
SHOULDN'T WE PUT HIM
IN THE GROUND FIRST ?
LET'S GO.  LET'S GO.
SHOULDN'T WE BURY HIM ?
COME ON.
SWANN, I'M TRACING YOU
BACK THROUGH THE COURSE, PAL.
SO, IF YOU CAN COPY,
BUT CAN'T TRANSMIT,
RIG A LOCATOR
AND I'LL FIND YOU.
JESSE HARTLINE ?
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT LYLE SWANN.
[ Motorcycle Approaching ]
JESSE, THIS IS LYLE.
JESSE, DO YOU READ ME ?
GOD ALMIGHTY,
DOES ANYONE READ ME ?
IT'S ALL WEIRD OUT HERE.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
HEY, BOYS,
FILL 'EM UP HERE.
THAT THIEF IN SAN MARCOS
CHARGED US MORE FOR HIS WATER
THAN THE GOODS ARE WORTH.
HE DON'T PULL
THAT SHIT ON ME.
YOU GONNA TALK TO HIM ?
YEAH.
I'M GETTING WORRIED.
I WILL.  I TOLD YOU
I'LL TALK TO HIM.
I THINK WE SHOULD HAVE
BURIED HIM.
I KNOW.  I KNOW.
- I WILL.
- YOU GONNA TALK TO HIM ?
I'M GONNA TALK TO HIM.
I SAID I WAS GONNA TALK TO HIM.
I'LL TALK TO HIM.
NOW, JUST SHUT UP.
REESE, UH, CARL AND I
HAVE BEEN THINKING.
YEAH, WE'VE BEEN THINKING.
AND I THINK, UH,
WE THINK THAT, UH,
WE SHOULDN'T HAVE LEFT JACK
BACK THERE WITHOUT BURYING HIM.
WE SHOULDA BURIED HIM.
JACK PEOPLES WAS NOTHING
BUT TROUBLE FROM THE TIME
WE BRUNG HIM IN.
I WORKED HARD TO STEAL
THIS STUFF, AND IT'S MINE,
GODDAMN IT !
NOW, PISS ON HIM.
PISS ON YOU TOO.
THAT'S THE LAST WORD
I WANNA HEAR ON THE GODDAMN
JACKASS PEOPLES--
- HOLY COW !
- WHAT THE HELL YOU LOOKING AT ?
- OH, SHIT !
- HEY, YOU GUYS !
- [ All Yelling ]
GOD ALMIGHTY,
WHAT WAS THAT ?
WHERE'D IT GO ?
I DON'T KNOW.
OKAY.  OKAY.
SHIT.  GODDAMN.
WAIT, SHUT UP !
LISTEN.
[ Swann Trying To
Start Motorcycle ]
NO.  NOT NOW.
COME ON, BABY.
WHERE IN THE HELL ARE YOU
GOING, REESE ?  REESE !
SHH !
[ Carl ]
THAT'S JACK'S GHOST.
I SWEAR TO GOD.
- [ Engine Starts ]
- [ All Gasp ]
IT'S NOT JACK !
IT IS JACK, REESE.
I'M TELLING YOU
IT'S JACK'S GHOST.
THEY COME BACK.
WE SHOULDA BURIED HIM.
CARL !  CARL !
I KNEW WE SHOULDA BURIED HIM.
THAT AIN'T A GHOST,
THAT'S A MAN...
ON SOME KIND OF MACHINE.
SOME KIND OF WHEEL MACHINE.
THAT AIN'T A GHOST.
REESE, MAYBE THAT
AIN'T NO GHOST, BUT--
BUT IT AIN'T RIGHT.
THAT THING
JUST AIN'T RIGHT.
GOD ALMIGHTY, LOOK AT IT.
HE'S RIDING IT.
I WANT THAT MACHINE.
WE COULD USE THAT MACHINE.
HUH ?
[ Laughs ]
WHAT IN THE HELL--
REESE, YOU CRA--
GODDAMN, REESE !
[ Chattering In Spanish ]
PADRE, I HAVE NO MONEY
FOR THIS WATER.
ONLY THIS RIFLE
AND SOME BREAD.
IT IS ONLY THROUGH SACRIFICE
THAT ONE CAN RECEIVE SALVATION.
SENORITA !  SENORITA !
[ In Spanish ]
KEEP THE BREAD.
PADRE.  LISTEN,
I WAS DOWN
AT THE SPRINGS.
THERE WAS A MAN THERE,
DRESSED LIKE
I'VE NEVER SEEN.
AND HE HAD A MACHINE,
A RIDING MACHINE.
REESE AND THE DORSETTS
RODE UP WHILE I WAS THERE.
THEY WERE AFRAID.
THEY STARTED FIRING AT HIM.
SO, THEN THIS MAN,
HE GOT ON THE MACHINE,
HE RODE IT AWAY
LIKE A HORSE.
REESE AND THE BOYS
WENT AFTER HIM, BUT...
THE MACHINE
WAS MUCH FASTER.
[ In Spanish ]
PORTER REESE.
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE ?
AND THE DORSETTS.
WHAT DID THEY HAVE
WITH THEM ?
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I JUST SAID ?
THIS MAN...
HE RODE THIS MACHINE
LIKE A HORSE.
DID YOU FOLLOW HIM
ON THIS MACHINE ?
WELL, I TRIED,
BUT THE MACHINE WENT VERY FAST.
THE HORSE WAS NO MATCH FOR IT.
JACK PEOPLES.
FIGURES.
I'LL TAKE POINT.
BEN.
BEN, WE'RE OUT OF
OUR JURISDICTION.
STRANGE-LOOKING WAGON TRACKS.
KILL 'IM !
[ Engine Starts ]
- [ Shuddering ]
- KILL 'IM !
[ Coughing ]
YOU SHOULD HAVE HAD HIM DEAD !
YOU LET HIM GET AWAY.
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN MINE !
DEAD, YOU CRAPHEAD.
THAT MACHINE
WOULD HAVE BEEN MINE !
YOU YELLOW, CHICKENSHIT HEAD !
YOU YELLOW CRAPHEAD !
DAMN YOU, REESE.
DON'T YOU TALK TO ME
LIKE THAT.
HEY, CLAUDE, REESE,
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S A COMPASS.
MADE IN A GLASS.
IT SAYS "AMERICA."
HE'S RIGHT.
IT DOES SAY "AMERICA."
HEY, HE'S HEADIN' UP ROCK GORGE.
HE AIN'T GONNA GET AWAY.
[ Laughing ]
I DON'T LIKE THIS, CARL.
DON'T LIKE THIS ONE BIT.
DID YOU SEE THAT THING
SPIT AT ME LIKE THAT ?
YEAH, I SEEN IT.
BLEW ROCKS ALL OVER ME
AND EVERYTHING.
[ Turns Engine Off ]
WHO ARE THESE ASSHOLES ?
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Reese ]
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA !
CLAUDE, YOU ALL RIGHT ?
YOU ALL RIGHT, CLAUDE ?
IF GENERAL LEE HAD
HAD THAT MACHINE,
WE'D HAVE WON THE WAR.
QUINN !
[ Motorcycle In Distance ]
THE SOUND
OF THE MACHINE.
[ People Screaming ]
HEY !
[ Scoffs ]
HEY, WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH EVERYBODY ?
HEY, YOU, SENOR, WHERE AM I ?
[ Yelling In Spanish ]
JESUS CHRIST,
THIS IS CRAZY !
SENORA !
SENORITA, POR FAVOR.
[ Yelling In Spanish ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Horse Neighs ]
HYAH.  HYAH.  HYAH.
GODDAMN REESE, AIN'T RIGHT.
JUST AIN'T RIGHT !
- [ Gunshot ]
- AAH !
EASY.  WHOA.
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
YOU WERE LUCKY.
THOSE ARE VERY BAD MEN.
NO SHIT.
HEY, WHAT THE HELL'S
HAPPENING HERE, HUH ?
I MEAN, WHY ARE THOSE GUYS
SHOOTING AT ME LIKE THAT ?
HEY, LOOK, I WAS JUST
IN THE BAJA 1000.
THE RACE ?
AND, WELL, I GOT LOST.
YOU GOT A PHONE
I COULD USE ?
I'LL-I'LL REVERSE
THE CHARGES.
I JUST NEED TO CALL SOMEONE.
LET THEM KNOW WHERE I--
DO YOU HAVE A PHONE ?
- THAT'S ENOUGH !
- SHE SHOT CARL.
I'M GONNA KILL HER.
ENOUGH !
[ Gunshot ]
QUINN, I CAN'T HAVE
MY MEN BEING SHOT.
GODDAMN, REESE,
HE'S HURT REAL BAD !
OH, GOD, SHE BLEW
HIS NOSE CLEAN OFF !
OH, CARL !
GODDAMN HER !
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE, REESE ?
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THIS ?
WHAT I KNOW IS THAT
THAT RIDER IS DEAD MEAT.
AND THAT MACHINE IS MINE.
NOW WHERE IS IT ?
WELL, NOTHING ELSE
IS GONNA HAPPEN HERE NOW.
GO ON, GET OUTTA HERE.
SETTLE THIS LATER.
HE NEEDS TENDIN'.
GO ON, GET OUTTA HERE.
HEY, DAMN YOU, BROTHER.
COME ON, CARL !
THERE AIN'T NO DEALIN'
ON THIS ONE, PADRE.
THAT MACHINE IS MINE.
[ Man Speaking Spanish ]
HEY, LOOK,
IF I WAS TRESPASSING, I--
WELL...
MAYBE I COULD--
[ Cocks Gun ]
WHERE AM I ?
YOU'RE IN SAN MARCOS.
SAN MARCOS.
OH, I SEE.
WELL, I, UH,
I DIDN'T SEE IT ON THE MAP.
TAKE IT EASY.
THIS IS JUST MY MAP.
IN, UH, SAN MARCOS.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM,
MY FRIEND ?
CANOGA PARK.  L.A.
L.A. ?
LOS ANGELES.
OH, LOS ANGELES.
HEY, COULD YOU SHOW ME
WHERE SAN MARCOS IS ?
I TOLD YOU...
YOU ARE IN SAN MARCOS.
[ Chattering In Spanish ]
DON'T BE AFRAID.
NO TENGA MIEDO.
NO TENGO MIEDO,
MIS AMIGOS.
[ Chattering,
Yelling In Spanish ]
SILENCIO, MIS AMIGOS.
SILENCIO.
YOU SAID-- YOU SAID...
IF WE BOUGHT THIS WATER
FROM YOU, WE WOULD BE SAFE.
HUH ?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
BUT THE DEVIL,
HE IS HERE !
WE SAW HIS RED
AND HIS FIRE HOSE.
YOU SAID THIS WAS A HOLY PLACE,
SAFE FROM SATAN.  HOLY WATER !
THIS IS A MAN.
HE IS NOT THE DEVIL.
NO ES DIABLO.
THEN, WHO IS
THIS DEVIL MAN ?
WHERE HAS HE COME FROM ?
[ People Speaking Spanish ]
JESUS CHRIST.
TWO AMERICAN MARSHALLS
ARE HERE.
WHAT DO THEY WANT ?
MARSHALLS ?
REESE AND THE DORSETT BOYS,
THEY DON'T SAY THEY'RE
MARSHALLS, BUT THEY ARE.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL, SENOR.
WHERE DID YOU GET THIS MAP ?
GOT IT AT AN EXXON STATION.
YOU TAKE CARE
OF THE MARSHALLS.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM.
OKAY, BUT THAT MACHINE
STAYS HERE.
GOD, LOOK AT THAT.
[ Goat Bleating ]
YOU PEOPLE
SOME KIND OF CULT ?
A RELIGIOUS OUTFIT.
YOU KNOW, "HARE, HARE."
LIKE THAT.
NO.
WELL, WHY DO YOU LIVE
LIKE THIS, THEN ?
I MEAN, I'VE BEEN COMING DOWN
TO MEXICO A LONG TIME, BUT I'VE
NEVER SEEN A PLACE LIKE THIS.
NO THANKS.
UH, LISTEN, UH--
CLAIRE.
CLAIRE CYGNE.
LYLE.  LYLE SWANN.
CLAIRE,
I'M HERE BY MISTAKE.
I DON'T MEAN HARM,
AND I DON'T WANT TO
CAUSE ANY TROUBLE.
I'M NOT THE LAW.
I GOT NO BUSINESS HERE,
AND I'M SORRY FOR WHATEVER
IT WAS I DID THAT MADE
EVERYBODY SO MAD.
TAKE ME BACK TO MY MOTORCYCLE,
I'LL RIDE OUT OF THIS TOWN,
AND I'LL NEVER LOOK BACK.
I-I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS
YOU PEOPLE ARE DOING.
I DON'T WANNA KNOW,
AND I WON'T SAY A WORD.
I'LL JUST RIDE OUT,
AND AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
THIS PLACE IS HISTORY.
[ Cocks Gun ]
TAKE OFF YOUR CLOTHES.
WHAT ?
YOU HEARD ME, MR. SWANN.
I DO NOT BELIEVE THIS.
YOU CAN'T--
[ Laughs ]
I MEAN, A GIRL CAN'T--
I'M VERY SERIOUS.
YOU TAKE 'EM OFF.
[ Man ]
SECTOR 12 SEARCH IS NEGATIVE.
BEGIN SEARCH SECTOR 13
ON MY MARK... NOW.
THERE'S NO TELLING
WHERE THAT GUY IS.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM,
LYLE SWANN ?
HOW DID YOU GET HERE ?
WHY HAVE YOU COME HERE ?
[ Groaning ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT, CLAUDE.
IT'S QUINN.
HOW IS HE ?
I'M PISS POOR.
WHAT THE HELL'S
THE MATTER WITH HER ?
GODDAMN BAD FOR BUSINESS.
[ Groans ]
THE MAN AND THE MACHINE,
HE HAS A POWER.
SHE'S ACTING STRANGE.
SHE BE ACTING DEAD.
SHE DON'T SHOOT NO DORSETT.
NOBODY SHOOTS NO DORSETT.
THE MAN AND THE MACHINE,
EVERYBODY'S
ACTING STRANGE.
TWO AMERICAN MARSHALLS
ARE HERE.  THEY'RE ASKING
FOR YOU BY NAME.
ONE WAS BEN POTTER.
DAMN !
BEN POTTER.  HMM.
HMM.
[ Laughs ]
YOU'RE THE STRANGEST WOMAN
I'VE EVER MET.
BECAUSE I KNOW MY OWN MIND,
MR. SWANN ?
WHY DON'T YOU
CALL ME LYLE ?
I PREFER NOT TO.
WHO ARE YOU, HMM ?
WHERE YOU FROM ?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE ?
I TOLD YOU,
I'M CLAIRE CYGNE.
I WAS BORN IN LOUISIANA.
MY FATHER WAS A PLANTER.
I HAD TWO BROTHERS
WHO TAUGHT ME TO SHOOT AND RIDE.
I WENT TO SCHOOL THERE.
THE CIVIL WAR CAME.
MY BROTHERS AND MY FATHER
WERE KILLED,
SO I LEFT
WITH MY MOTHER.
WE WENT TO NEW ORLEANS.
SHE DIED SOON AFTER.
LEFT ME WITH TWO CHOICES--
TO USE MY BODY OR MY GUN.
I CHOSE THE GUN
TO GET MONEY TO EAT.
THERE WAS SOME TROUBLE.
I HEARD OF THIS PLACE.
[ Sighs ]
SO, I CAME HERE.
THE PADRE AND ME,
WE BUY THINGS FROM PEOPLE...
THAT ARE DIFFICULT
FOR THEM TO SELL ELSEWHERE,
THEN WE SELL THEM.
THE CIVIL WAR ?  MY GOD,
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE ?
CLAIRE, DO YOU REALIZE
HOW WEIRD EVERYTHING
YOU JUST SAID TO ME WAS ?
I MEAN, WHAT-WHAT-
WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS HAPPENING HERE ?
YOU RIDE THIS MACHINE,
MR. SWANN.
NO ONE'S EVER SEEN
THAT BEFORE.
IT'S YOU
WHO SHOULD BE EXPLAINING.
YEAH, WELL, UM--
I STARTED RIDING MOTORCROSS
RIGHT OUT OF HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU WENT TO SCHOOL ?
CAN YOU READ ?
[ Laughs ]
SURE I CAN READ.
GOT ANY BOOKS ?
DO YOU MEAN
DO I HAVE ANY WITH ME ?
YES.
NO, CLAIRE, I DON'T
CARRY BOOKS WITH ME.
I HAVE THREE BOOKS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE THEM ?
SURE.
HAVE YOU READ MARK TWAIN ?
A LITTLE, IN SCHOOL.
DID A REPORT ON TOM SAWYER ONCE.
I HAVEN'T READ THAT ONE.
YOU HAVEN'T ?
THAT'S HIS MOST FAMOUS.
I ONLY HAVE THESE.
YOU CAN READ ?
READ THIS.
[ Chuckles ]
"WHAT MIGHT IT BE
THAT YOU'VE GOT IN THE BOX ?
"THEN, SMILEY SAYS,
SORT OF INDIFFERENT,
"'‘‘LIKE IT MIGHT BE A PARROT
OR IT MIGHT BE A CANARY MAYBE.
BUT IT AIN'T.
IT'S ONLY JUST A FROG.'"
[ Chuckles ]
?? ALL I WANNA DO IS DANCE
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME ??
???? [ Ends ]
"SO, THE FELLA TOOK THE BOX
AND PUT UP HIS $40 A LOAD
WITH SMILEY...
AND SAT DOWN TO WAIT."
[ Chuckles ]
MR. SWANN.
[ Sighs ]
WHAT'S THIS ?
UH, IT WAS MY GREAT-GREAT--
I DON'T KNOW,
WAY BACK THERE SOMEPLACE,
GREAT-GRANDFATHER'S.
MY GRANDMOTHER
STOLE IT FROM HIM,
AS A REMINDER
OF ONE INCREDIBLE NIGHT
THEY HAD TOGETHER.
HE TOOK OFF,
AND SHE WENT TO L.A.
TO FIND HIM AND NEVER DID.
SHE STARTED
HER OWN BUSINESS.
NOBODY REMEMBERS WHAT.
AT LEAST THEY AIN'T SAYING.
AND BECAME THE GREAT MATRIARCH
OF THE SWANN CLAN.
SHE PASSED IT ON DOWN
TO HER GRANDDAUGHTER
AND ON LIKE THAT,
TILL MOM GAVE IT TO ME
WHEN I WAS 21.
ANYWAY, IT'S
SUPPOSED TO BRING ME LUCK.
DOES IT WORK ?
DOES IT EVER.
KISS ME AGAIN.
[ Goats Bleating ]
OH, QUINN,
WHAT DO YOU WANT ?
HE HAS TO LEAVE NOW.
THE MARSHALLS, REESE--
IT'S TOO MUCH TROUBLE.
THAT'S THE BEST THING
I'VE HEARD.
SO, THEN HE LEAVES.
I'M THROUGH WITH HIM.
MY BIKE.
WHERE'S MY BIKE ?
WHERE THE HELL'S MY BIKE ?
OH, EMIL !
BASTARDS !
[ Groaning ]
HE'S ALIVE.
- REESE.
- WHERE THE HELL
ARE THESE COPS ?
NEVER MIND.
I'LL FIND THEM MYSELF.
[ Chattering In Spanish ]
[ Groans ]
I'LL CLIMB UP TOP.
YEAH.
[ Yelling, Indistinct ]
WONDER WHO THE HELL HE IS.
I GOT A CLEAN SHOT.
WHAT'S HE CARRYING ?
CAN'T TELL.
MAYBE HE'S DANGEROUS.
- SHOULD I LET HIM COME ?
- CARRYING A SIDEARM ?
NOTHING BUT THAT THING
IN HIS HAND.
DON'T LOOK LIKE NO WEAPON.
OKAY, LET HIM COME.
YOU THE LAW ?
DAMN IT,
ARE YOU THE COP OR NOT ?
[ Gunshots ]
DON'T PRESS ME, BOY.
PADRE HERE SAYS
YOU WAS A MARSHALL.
IF YOU ARE, I NEED HELP.
IF NOT, JUST TELL ME.
BEN, I KNOW WE'RE ALONE,
EXCEPT FOR YOUR FRIEND.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE MYSELF.
I DON'T LIKE
HIS SMART MOUTH.
HEY, LOOK, I'M SORRY.
I LOST MY TEMPER.
BUT SOMEBODY
STOLE MY BIKE.
- HIS MACHINE.
- OKAY, MY MACHINE.
SOMEONE TOOK MY MACHINE.
WHY YOU TELLING THAT
TO US ?
WELL, IF YOU ARE THE MARSHALLS,
MAYBE YOU COULD DO SOMETHING,
BEFORE WHOEVER TOOK IT
GETS TOO FAR.
CAN'T YOU GET ON THE RADIO ?
WHAT ?
JESUS CHRIST,
DON'T TELL--
HEY, AM I CRAZY ?
WHO ARE YOU PEOPLE ?
I WANT SOME ANSWERS.
WHERE'S MY MACHINE ?
REESE AND DORSETT.
YOU KNOW THESE GUYS ?
WE KNOW 'EM.
WHERE ARE THEY ?
- SWALLOWS CAMP.
WHERE IS IT ?
[ Man ]
LOOK.
[ Chattering ]
WHAT DID YA BRING US,
REESE ?
- I DIDN'T BRING YOU NOTHING.
- SOME KIND OF MACHINE ?
WHAT THE HELL IS IT ?
IT'S MINE, THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
IT'S MINE.
[ Chattering ]
GET OUT THE WAY.
YOU SHOULDA KILLED HER,
CLAUDE.
BRINGING HER HERE
AIN'T NOTHING BUT TROUBLE.
HEY, CARL.
HEY, CLAUDE.
HEY, CARL,
I GOT A PRESENT FOR YOU.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chattering In Spanish ]
THEY TOOK CLAIRE.
CHRIST, I NEED
SOME HANDLEBARS.
I'M GONNA TAKE A LONG TIME
CUTTIN' YOU...
CLAIRE CYGNE.
[ Chattering,
Shouting ]
- GET OUT OF THERE.
- BACK OFF.
[ Man ]
SETTLE DOWN.
SETTLE DOWN, YOU BOYS.
WHAT DO I DO ?
WELL, UM,
FIRST HE-HE PUT HIS HANDS
ON THESE TWO BLACK THI--
WELL, AND THEN HE, UH...
HE JUMPED UP AND DOWN
ON IT.
UP AND DOWN.
YEAH, HE JUMPED
UP AND DOWN ON IT, AND...
KICKED IT...
RIGHT THERE.
[ All ]
HEY !
[ Man ]  KICK IT AGAIN, REESE.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
DO BETTER THAN THAT.
HYAH !
[ Men Laughing ]
[ Man ]
I DON'T THINK
IT LIKES YOU, REESE.
WHAT ARE YOU TELLING ME ?
YOU GOTTA KICK IT HARDER.
HE KICKED IT REAL HARD.
[ Backfires ]
THAT'S RIGHT, THAT'S RIGHT.
KICK IT AGAIN.
HARDER.
KICK IT.
[ Man ]
STAND BACK.
[ Engine Starts ]
- CUT IT OUT.
- GODDAMN !  JESUS CHRIST !
GODDAMN SHITHEADS !
GODDAMN !
WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO DO TO ME ?
EASY, REESE, EASY.
I JUST TOLD YOU
WHAT I SAW.
BESIDES,
YOU DID REAL GOOD.
YOU MADE IT WORK...
A LITTLE.
YOU SHOT IT.
WHAT A BUNCH OF DUMB
SONS OF BITCHES.
YOU SHOT IT, A MACHINE.
YOU BUTTHEADS !
HEY, REESE, YOU GOT
AN ARROW IN IT.
[ Men Chattering ]
WHAT A PIT.
HOW MANY
YOU THINK THERE ARE ?
OH, 12, MAYBE 15 MEN.
ENOUGH GUNS FOR AN ARMY.
WHERE DO YOU FIGURE
REESE IS ?
THAT FAR CABIN.
YOU THINK CLAIRE
IS IN THERE TOO ?
[ Claude ]
DO SOMETHING TO HER NOW.
I'M GONNA CUT HER.
AIN'T NO GAL GONNA GO
WITH A MAN LIKE ME...
'LESSIN' SHE LOOKS LIKE ME.
LATER.
YOU TOLD ME
YOU WANTED TO--
LATER, CARL !
LATER !
GOD DANG IT.
ALL RIGHT, CLAUDE.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ENOUGH MESSIN'
WITH THE WOMAN.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M IN.
I'M WITH YOU.
NOW LISTEN, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOUR PLAN IS, BUT...
YOU HELP ME
GET MY BIKE BACK,
AND I'LL GET US INTO
A "HIGH ZOOT BOOGIE"
LIKE YOU NEVER SAW.
WHAT'S HE
TALKING ABOUT ?
YOU HELP ME GET MY MACHINE,
AND I'LL HELP YOU KICK ASS.
WHY SHOULD
WE TRUST YOU ?
WHY NOT ?
NO NEED TO TALK NOW,
WE'LL MOVE IN AFTER DARK.
AFTER DARK.
HEY, BUT WHAT ABOUT CLAIRE ?
THEY'LL GRIND HER TO PIECES.
WELL, WHATEVER HAPPENS,
WILL REST WITH YOU.
SHE WOULDN'T BE THERE
IF YOU HADN'T COME ALONG.
[ Blowing Rhythmically ]
CLAUDE ?
STICK TO CRIME.
HEY, CARL,
YOU WANT SOME ?
THANKS, CLAUDE.
[ Unzips Loudly ]
ENERGY BAR.
WANT ONE ?
WHAT ?
ENERGY BAR.
WHAT IS IT ?
WELL, IT'S DRIED NUTS,
FRUIT, NO PRESERVATIVES.
UH-UH.
GO ON, TAKE IT.
YOU'LL LIKE IT.
GOOD, HUH ?
YEAH, THANKS.
DON'T TURN YOUR BACK
ON THOSE TWO.
HOW FAR DO YOU THINK
IT IS TO THE CABIN ?
I DON'T KNOW.
CAN'T SEE A THING.
HERE, TRY THIS ON,
AND LOOK AT THE LIGHT
ON THE ROOF OF THE CABIN.
WHAT LIGHT ?
COME ON, TRY IT ON.
HERE,
LET ME HELP YOU.
I ALREADY TOLD YOU I CAN'T SEE.
WHAT DIFFERENCE
IS A HAT GONNA MAKE ?
CAN YOU SEE ANYTHING ?
NOT NOTHIN'.
TAKE A LOOK AT IT NOW.
LORDY.
BLESSED JESUS.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU ?
TRICK, HUH ?
MY WRENCH MADE THIS
OUT OF TECHNO GOODIES
OUT OF SILICON VALLEY.
WHERE'D THAT LIGHT
COME FROM ?
CYALUME.
THIS THING STOP
A RIFLE SLUG ?
GOD, I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T THINK SO.
IT'S NOT REALLY MADE FOR THAT.
I MEAN, IT WILL HANDLE
A MAJOR GET-OFF, BUT I NEVER
GOT SHOT AT BEFORE TODAY.
THAT MACHINE, THESE CLOTHES,
THIS HERE LIGHT...
WHERE'D THESE COME FROM ?
TINKER TOYS, MOSTLY.
SEE, I HANG
WITH TECHNOID TYPES.
WE PARTY,
AND THEY COME UP
WITH ALL THIS BOOGIE.
BIKE'S A BUNCH OF JAP PARTS.
REAL ZOOT, HUH ?
CYALUME FROM K-MART.
SHUT UP.
SHUT UP, YOU IDIOT,
OR WE'RE ALL DEAD.
ONE SOUND,
I'LL BLOW YOUR BRAINS OUT.
MOVE YOUR HAND.
WHERE IS PORTER REESE ?
YOU SURE ?
THIS IS ME AND REESE.
ANYBODY ELSE MAKES A PLAY,
I'LL LOOK FOR YOU TO STOP 'EM.
OTHERWISE,
YOU STAY DOWN
AND STAY QUIET.
- IS HE CRAZY ?
- PORTER REESE KILLED...
BEN POTTER'S SON
TWO YEARS AGO
IN SAN MARCOS.
EVERYBODY KNEW
IT WAS PERSONAL BETWEEN 'EM.
- WHAT IF REESE KILLS HIM ?
- BEN AIN'T NEVER BEEN BEAT
IN A FAIR FIGHT.
THE FIRST MOTHER'S SON
THAT MOVES OTHER THAN REESE
IS A DEAD MAN.
WE'RE TO SEE TO THAT.
GET YOUR RIG.
LET'S FIND SOME COVER.
COME ON.
PORTER REESE ?
GET OUT HERE !
YOU GARBAGE !
[ Chattering ]
QUINN WAS TELLING THE TRUTH.
IT'S BEN POTTER.
I WANT YOU...
PERSONAL !
CLAUDE.
REESE ?
WHEN I GET READY,
YOU OPEN THE DOOR.
REESE ?
BEN'S CALLING YOU OUT PERSONAL.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, YOU YELLOW ?
NOT YELLOW... SMART.
REESE !
SOMEONE DRUG YOUR MACHINE OFF.
BILLERS AND PIG ARE DEAD.
PIG'S HEAD'S CLEAN OFF.
[ Breathes Deeply ]
THAT'S A YANKEE TRICK.
YOU TAKE THIS,
AND WE'RE GOING
BACK DOWN THERE, MISTER.
WAIT-WAIT A MINUTE, HOLD ON.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
IT'S BARBARIC.
YOU CAN'T JUST KILL
SOMEBODY LIKE THAT.
BARBARIC ?  WHAT'S BARBARIC ?
THIS IS SURVIVAL, MISTER.
YOU TAKE THIS.
SURVIVAL ?  YOUR FRIEND
JUST GOT BLOWN AWAY !
HE STOOD UP IN THE MIDDLE
AND WALKED RIGHT INTO--
WELL, MAYBE YOU JUST DON'T
UNDERSTAND ANYTHING ABOUT HONOR.
HONOR ?  WAIT A MINUTE.
TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF ME.
OKAY, OKAY.
LISTEN, THERE'S NO NEED FOR
ANY TROUBLE BETWEEN YOU AND ME.
I MEAN, WE STILL GOT TO
GET THE GIRL OUT.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT THAT GIRL.
OKAY, I UNDERSTAND.
I WANT THE GIRL,
YOU WANT REESE...
BUT WE GOT TO
WORK TOGETHER
ON THIS THING.
TOGETHER !
[ Chattering ]
WHAT YOU FIGURE,
THE OTHER MARSHALL
AND THE MAN IN RED ?
YEAH.  THE MACHINE
AIN'T FAR, CLAUDE.
SOMETHING'S WRONG
OUT THERE.
[ Claude ]
I TOLD YOU IT WEREN'T RIGHT,
DIDN'T I ?  I TOLD YOU.
[ Man ]
DYNAMITE !  DYNAMITE !
COME ON !
SHOOT 'EM !
GET 'EM !
[ Laughing ]
WELL, HERE IT IS.
HEROICS, MISS CLAIRE, HEROICS.
AND I'M SCARED.
AND REAL PISSED OFF.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
[ Man ]
GET 'EM !  GET 'EM !
CARL !
CARL !  GODDAMN !
HOLD YOUR FIRE !
HOLD IT, HE'S GONE !
HE TOOK OUR MACHINE.
YOU GONNA LET HIM
GET AWAY WITH THAT ?
[ Man ]
OUR MACHINE ?
NOW IT'S OUR MACHINE !
REESE !
CARL'S DEAD.
LOOK OUT !
COME ON !
GODDAMN, BOYS !
WHAT THE HELL YOU WAITING FOR ?
[ Yelling,
Indistinct ]
WE'VE GOT YOU NOW.
GO ON.
THERE'S TOO MUCH
SAND HERE.
[ Continues,
Indistinct ]
DR. SAM, WE'VE SET YOU FOR
THREE HOURS SEARCH AND RETURN.
IS THAT OKAY ?
OKAY.  BUT GENE SAYS
THIS LEVEL OF POWER
IS SMOKING THE WIRES.
THERE'S TWO TOWERS DOWN
BETWEEN HERE AND MEXICALI,
SO THREE HOURS
IS ABSOLUTELY THE LIMIT.
[ Gasps ]
BEN, IT AIN'T RIGHT.
BEN.
IT AIN'T RIGHT,
IT AIN'T...
RIGHT, BEN.
[ Coughs ]
I GOT--
I GOT 'EM.
HE'S GONE.
NO, HE'S NOT.
HE'LL BE OKAY,
HE JUST LOST A LOT OF BLOOD.
GONNA GET HIM BACK.
OH MY... GOD.
HE WAS OKAY.
HE WAS RIDING OKAY.
- [ Gasps ]
- DID I GET REESE ?
YEAH, YOU GOT HIM.
[ Chuckles ]
NOT MY JURISDICTION.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Man ]
COME ON.
[ All ]  HYAH !
[ Gunshot In Distance ]
OH, GREAT.
CAN YOU MAKE IT GO ?
NO, SHE'S WHEELS
TO THE SKY.
[ Static ]
COME ON, WE GOTTA
GET OVER THAT RIDGE.
LET'S GO.
LET REESE HAVE THE MACHINE.
GIVE THEM THE MACHINE,
THEN THEY'LL LET US GO.
[ Voice On Radio,
Indistinct ]
WHAT'S THAT ?
CAN YOU READ ME ?
- CAN THAT VOICE HELP ?
- DAMN RIGHT.  HELP.
[ Beeping ]
[ Static ]
COME ON.
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT.
[ Gunshots ]
THEY AIN'T GOING NO FURTHER.
COME ON.
[ Swann ]
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Beeping ]
COME ON, LET'S GO.
COME ON !
YEAH !
BABY, YOU'RE BEAUTIFUL !
OH, SHIT !
HEY !
GET BACK !
[ Yelling,
Indistinct ]
AS WE LAND, STAY LOW
AND MOVE QUICKLY
TO THE HELICOPTER.
[ Reese ]
GET AWAY, GET AWAY !
UH-UH,
THAT'S MINE.
THAT'S MINE !
MINE !
CLAIRE, COME ON,
GET MY HAND.
COME ON.
NOBODY ELSE COMES.
THAT'S IT.
[ Dr. Sam ]
LISTEN, SWANN, YOU DON'T REALIZE
WHAT YOU'RE FOOLING WITH !
NO, WAIT A MINUTE !
PLEASE, CLAIRE !
HURRY UP !
LET'S GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE !
NO !  WAIT ONE MINUTE !
CLAIRE !
COME ON, CLAIRE !
NO, MR. SWANN.
I'LL EXPLAIN WHEN WE
GET BACK TO OUR OWN TIME !
- BUT NOBODY ELSE COMES !
- [ Swann ]
WAIT A MINUTE !
CLAIRE, COME ON !
[ Dr. Sam ]
LET'S GO !
[ Swann ]
MY GRANDMOTHER STOLE IT
FROM HIM AS A REMINDER...
OF ONE INCREDIBLE NIGHT
THEY HAD TOGETHER.
HE TOOK OFF, AND SHE WENT
TO L.A. TO FIND HIM,
BUT NEVER DID.
SHE STARTED HER OWN BUSINESS.
NOBODY REMEMBERS WHAT,
LEAST THEY AIN'T SAYING.
SHE BECAME THE GREAT MATRIARCH
OF THE SWANN CLAN.
ANYWAY, IT'S SUPPOSED TO
BRING ME LUCK.