Passengers getting off at Kalabaka,
please get ready.
Don't say anything.
You'll leave when I give you a signal.
Everybody sit down.
Get off.
- Why?
- Get off.
Move it.
Give me your papers.
Where are you coming from?
I bet you already know that.
Where are you planning to go?
Home, if you don't have any objections.
At Kalabaka the workers were waiting
at the station to welcome you.
We were afraid they might cause trouble.
If your welcoming is over,
I should be moving on.
Listen, Odysseas Hormovas,
while you were gone, we fought hard
to make the people settle.
And they didn't?
Not much it seems.
The fire is still burning.
And you want me to put it out?
What I want is that you
stay out of trouble this time.
You are the son of a nobleman,
a squire, with plenty of wealth.
Your interest should be with the law,
not with the ragged ones who want
to take the land from you.
Thanks for the advice. Anything else?
One more thing.
Do you know a guy named Antypas?
Marinos Antypas.
Why?
Because if I find that you
hang out with him,
I will you send you back to jail.
Take your papers.
Landless all of them, poor fellows.
They harvest the plantations
for a piece of bread.
They took arms and rose
against the landlords four years ago.
They asked for a piece of the land.
Their masters showed no mercy and
bashed them, you should remember.
I do.
They are now scared
that they might rise again
and they hire workers
from distant places.
They keep the locals out of the fields.
We live in tough times, my son.
People are upset.
Perhaps you should stop to take
this pregnant woman with us.
OK
Good lady, do you want to come on board?
Thank you, my feet are still strong.
- Why don't you take me instead?
- But my girl, she is pregnant.
Who knows, maybe I am too.
Go away. Leave the people
to go to their jobs.
Come on guys, hang on.
We are almost there.
- What's the matter, folks?
- Where do you come from?
- From far away.
- How far?
- From Anapli.
- Don't lie, or you will regret it.
Your face is that of a hungry dog.
You are one of those rebels who were
banished elsewhere and now come here!
I told you, I come from Anapli.
- And where do you go?
- Wherever I want to!
Get out of my way!
You go ahead.
Back! Back, you damned lot.
Back. Stay still.
What are you doing there?
Why are you not letting the people pass?
And why should we report to you?
Have you heard of Hormovas,
the master of these plains?
We are his caretakers.
And I am his younger son, Odysseas.
Move it.
I said move it!
Let me wring it for you.
Come on, old man.
Is it true that you are
the son of Hormovas?
Why?
My father admired you.
He said that this kid has a big heart.
-Your father?
- He was killed during the uprising.
You had fought together.
I am the daughter of Captain Zisis.
Prayers in Greek.
My dear Christians, the prodigal son
had all God's blessings:
a rich and well-respected father,
a beloved brother,
a large portion of land.
He turned against
his father and brother.
He stole from his own home and left.
But after a while, his soul was yearning
for his paternal home.
He thirsted for his father's forgiveness
and that's why he went back
and embraced his father's knees.
And his father willingly forgave him.
Because my dear Christians,
the beauty of remorse
and the power of apology,
is the deepest truth of God's command.
I am back, father.
I have been longing for this moment
for years my son.
To have you next to me.
Father, does Rigas know that I'm back?
Haven't I told you? Your brother has
gone hunting in the mountains.
I thought he would be coming back today,
but don't worry.
We've started the feast now.
And another day, when he comes back,
we'll celebrate for both of you!
Aren't you drinking?
- Cheers.
- To your good health, father.
You've set up quite a feast, father.
If I knew it,
I wouldn't have gone hunting.
What's up? Is this a saint day again?
No, my son. We have other reasons
to celebrate.
Did a sterile filly gave birth?
Your brother is back, Rigas.
Don't you see him?
My father you're getting old
and you're losing your mind.
My brother died four years ago.
Did you forget?
Your brother is alive.
He's back and I forgave him.
And you ordered a feast for that.
And you brought dancers.
How many lambs did you slaughter?
- Six.
- Which calf?
The brown one, with the white dots.
- Are you touched to have your son back?
- Any father would be!
And you don't remember
what he did to you?
I forgot everything.
Then I will help you remember.
The ragged ones rose
against the landlords.
They threw the bread
that we fed them back at us
and they attacked with guns
to seize our land.
Do you remember when you
came home, pale as a ghost
and threw me a gun to save our land?
Do you remember the bullets
that they planted in my body?
Or the times we stayed awake,
dead from agony?
How many times have we come
face to face with death?
Do you remember all that, father?
How could I have forgotten, my son?
Then how could you forget what your
younger son did, that horrible year?
How could you forget that he threw away
the gun that you gave him?
That he refused to defend our land.
That in the end he extended his arm
to that swarm of bees
that fell upon us to destroy us.
And now that the one who betrayed us
is back from prison,
you forget everything!
You embrace him and bang the drum.
And slaughter the calf that I used to
feed with my own hands.
Is that right?
And if it is, then tell me
who was punished for what had happened?
He or I?
- What do you want, Rigas? Speak.
- I want him to leave.
You don't have a second son.
Neither do I have a brother.
Father, let me speak to him.
No! A thousand times no.
I am not dead yet.
There is no tombstone over my head.
I'm alive! I'm your master
and I speak now.
Take it.
I said, take it!
Are you strong enough? Then break it.
Now break both of them. Break them!
Listen, Rigas. I will soon be gone,
but the land will be still here.
And more enemies will surround you.
The days to come will be even harder.
Shake your brother's hand
and hold it tight.
You should always remember that
it is easy to break one stick alone.
Keep playing. Today we celebrate.
Play loud enough for those on the other
side of the plains to hear you.
Hormovas' other fawn is back home.
I know who you are
and where you come from.
You're from Petrohori village.
You were the first to attack
the masters who were feeding you.
That's why everyone is sending you away.
Half of you are imprisoned.
The other half are bandits
in the mountains.
And the ones that remained,
women, children and cripples,
come to me now, asking for bread.
We're not cripples or beggars.
It's harvest season. We want to work.
Then go somewhere else.
- We went but they sent us away.
- And why should I care? Move on.
And go to the mountains
to harvest rocks?
Shut up!
Listen, everyone.
If you've come to your senses and
ask for wages and nothing more,
then we may have something
to talk about.
Get me the pen.
Everyone who signs this paper
will get a job.
It says that the land belongs to me
and for as long as you live,
you won't have any claims on it.
It also says,
that you disapprove
of the workers's uprising
that tried to ravish our land.
And that those who took their rifles
against us
are common thieves and murderers.
Everyone who signs will get a job
for the whole harvest season.
Free food, a free place to sleep
and an additional wage.
Those who can't write may draw a cross.
Any interested ones may go ahead.
This paper
says that we consider our fathers
and brothers to be murderers,
who died four years ago
to get some land for themselves
and that we swear to have no claims
on the land.
Neither us nor our children.
Do you really want to sign such a paper?
What does this bastard want?
- Is this your lover?
- She's my sister.
A sweet sister you got there.
To conclude, if you agree with her,
then there are no jobs.
- Speak!
- Whatever Eirini says.
Aren't you ashamed to have a woman
as a leader?
She knows more than us.
She teaches our children.
- So you're a little teacher?
- I know how to write, that's all.
And what are you supposed to be?
A farmer?
Just a passerby.
- And what are you doing among them?
- I'm just curious. I wanted to see...
See what?
Whether they will be able to find,
among all landlords,
even just one true human being.
I know your face, Marinos Antypas,
the islander who
leads Thessaly to unrest.
The beetle who wants to
light the big fire.
I told your father at Pyrgetos
that you shouldn't dare
to set foot on our land.
- All masters send me the same message.
- And what do you do for that?
I go to the slaves...
Rigas!
- What is it, Odysseas Hormovas?
- Blood makes me sick, you know it.
Then stay in the kitchen,
in the company of women.
Someone who hits the hungry
and the weak is not a man.
This guy knows that he can beat you
without hitting you.
These people are desperate.
And desperation is like a river.
If it can't find a passage,
it rises and floods the fields.
And what do you want from me?
- Give bread to the ones that struck us?
- Yes,
for otherwise they will strike again.
Why do we want them here?
Let them leave.
We will find other workers.
Send them away.
-They will cause trouble.
- Shut up!
Listen up. I'm not a literate man and
what my educated brother just said
touched my soul.
These homeless folks ask for bread.
They can have it.
The ask for work. They can have it.
Come on you hungry, let's go together!
I don't want people to say
that I was afraid of you.
You are the son of a master,
you have your own land,
yet you extend your hand.
Are you crazy,
or are you so nice a person?
If you find the answer,
let me know as well,
because I wasn't able to find it.
Mother of God! What are you doing here?
Leave, can't you hear?
Leave, someone will see us.
Have you gone mad?
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- What do you want?
- I saw my sister and ran.
I called her to count how many of you
there are and give you food.
What would you eat, rocks?
That's some nice red wine.
Leave the wine and come over here.
Take a bag of beans and beat it.
What are you waiting for? I am not going
to eat your sister. Get lost.
Watch your tone with me.
I'm not scared of you.
Giagos, go on, beat it. Go.
He better start behaving
otherwise we'll have trouble.
Never mind him.
He's a little hot-tempered.
- Tell me, how many of you are there?
- 74. Forty of them are females.
We also have two sick people.
- What's their illness?
- Fever.
What's your name?
Eirini.
- How many of the children are yours?
- None.
So you're free.
Why didn't you say so before?
Do you want something else?
You never thanked me
for what I did for you.
Thank you.
- Just like that?
- What else?
You have a sweet mouth.
And lightning bolts for eyes.
OK, you can go now.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Yesterday, when you spoiled the feast,
my soul bled.
Why, did I say something wrong?
We are brothers, Rigas.
We used to have differences.
Now the storm is gone.
We need to forget them.
We have the same blood.
Do we?
When you spoiled the feast and
your veins were swollen from yelling,
I said that we are not.
But I still believed.
When you said to the homeless,
"Come on you homeless lot, join me",
I said to myself,
"Yes Odysseas, he is your brother,
this is your real brother".
Down there you learned
how to talk a big talk,
but don't hurry,
you are still to see
your real brother, Rigas.
I'm fed up.
I no longer want this life.
Stop it.
To meet once every six months,
on the run, scared to the bone.
What do you want me to do?
They have a price on my head.
- Surrender, Kotsos.
- They will put me in jail.
Let them put you. It will end sometime.
You will come back to us again
and live a normal life.
Forget about that. All my life, I was
digging other men's land,
I was eating at a dish
that was not my own,
I was drinking water
at the same pond as their horses,
I will not let them cage me, because
I yelled for a piece of land.
- You yelled, but also hit, Kotsos.
- I hit when they hit me,
I no longer wait to get hit.
I strike first.
Our child will be born soon, Kotsos.
What should I tell him about his father?
That he lives in the mountains
like a hunted beast?
That he sleeps next to night owls
and shivers to the wind's blow?
Tell him that he's dead.
The nightingales are singing up in the,
up in the ridges.
The nightingales are singing in the
branches that summer is here,
that summer is here.
Men are going to the fields,
to harvest the wheat,
to harvest the wheat.
To harvest the wheat
with their bare hands,
with their bare hands.
To celebrate St. John's day, to make
beautiful girls look at them
and take pride in them.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm getting some sun.
Why aren't you working?
How much do you pay?
I pay as much as I want.
It's none of your business.
That's how it is.
You tell me a number
and if I don't like it, I don't work.
The Turks are gone and you say
that we're all equal now.
Shut up.
- Where did you find this thing?
- A Turk gave it to my father.
Should I play a few notes?
I told you that you were going to have
a hard time with me.
Why?
If you won't work,
then you won't be eating.
And don't you dare step on my land,
or I'll cut your feet.
I would do you even worse,
if not for your sister's beautiful eyes.
And if I find out that
you are stealing wine from me,
I will hang you upside down.
I saw you from above and told them,
"He reminds me of an old friend".
It is Odysseas Hormovas and
we need to welcome him.
- Do you remember me?
- Aren't you Kotsos?
They put you in jail and only
half of you is left, but I got away.
I see that.
What's wrong, aren't you
happy to see me?
Not if you're carrying guns.
You came with us once.
People were asking for
their rights then.
Now you're acting as thieves.
Sooner or later, I knew that you
would abide by the law.
You are a landlord. The law is the
barbed wire that guards your land.
But we, my friend, are outside the wire.
Your law is our enemy.
That's why we had to make one
of our own.
This is our law.
It is easy to change a law.
What is difficult is to make it better.
- Where is the girl?
- What girl?
- The one that is your leader.
-She's carrying sheaves, at Pera Alonia.
- What's with her?
- She likes fooling around.
Hey, move on!
- Are you looking for someone?
- You.
- What do you want?
- To help you.
You are the son of a noble woman,
but you became a bum.
Don't come closer.
What are you afraid of? We're alone.
Don't come closer, I told you!
Odysseas, get out of my way.
Get out of my way, I said!
You're going the wrong way.
Go back, Rigas.
Once, I was fighting here
for half a day to save you.
You owe me your life.
Go before I take it from you.
Leave!
We are brothers and you know me well,
I will not leave, Rigas.
Put the knife down, do you hear?
Put the knife down.
Get out of my way.
Get out of my way, I said!
- What did he do to you?
- Nothing, he didn't have the time.
He's worse than a wolf.
You are brothers, but he treats you
like an enemy.
- He has his reasons.
- I've heard about it...
When the peasants rose,
you refused to hit them.
Someone like you
couldn't have done differently.
Pull the reins.
I actually tried back then...
You tried to do what?
To hit them,
to take my father's rifle
and defend the ranch,
our land, as Rigas would have called it.
How do you call it?
I don't know.
The sea feeds the people too,
but it belongs to everyone.
The sky brings rain, it gives the sun,
but no one thought about putting
barbed wire around them.
Everyone tells me that
I am the son of a a nobleman
and I hear a voice inside
that tells me, "Odysseas,
you are foremost a human".
Are you leaving?
Do you want something?
To thank you, for everything
that you are doing for us.
If it weren't for you, I don't know
what would have happened.
I would never let someone
disgrace you like that.
You are courageous.
I admired you from the beginning.
I grit my teeth.
These people need to live.
Children need to eat bread.
And the elders need to forget
the ones they lost.
Did you manage to forget?
My father was the most
precious thing that I had.
He was taking me by the hand,
taking me to a hill
and showed me the land.
"Someday we'll have a piece of our own",
he was telling me.
"We'll pick up stones and build a home.
My grandchildren will play
on their own land".
You better forget that,
if you give up the fight
that your father started.
Shouldn't you be harvesting?
Yes, I should...
- Why aren't you there?
- There's too much sun in the fields.
- And what are you doing here?
- It's cool in here.
I'm alone.
I don't have a home of my own.
I came to rest for noon.
- Without a dress?
-Who should I be ashamed of, the horses?
- Didn't you know that I was coming?
- No.
No, or maybe yes?
Yes.
- Say it again.
- Yes.
- Why are you here?
- I told you, I can't stand the sun.
- Just for that?
- I'm tired of the land.
The rake fills my hands with blisters.
I wasn't born to live like that.
Who is it?
The old man sent me.
He's waiting for you to have lunch.
I'm busy. Tell him to eat without me.
He won't eat alone. You know it.
OK, I'm coming. Go now.
When the sun bothers you again
and you come to the stable,
let me know.
Hello, father.
You should say,
"Hello father and brother".
Your brother is also here.
Father, I'm not hungry at all.
I'm leaving.
Come here.
There are three chairs at the table
for Hormovas and his two sons.
As long as you're both alive,
I won't eat next to an empty chair.
Sit.
Your face is swollen. What happened?
- I fell off the horse.
- Don't lie.
No horse has been born
that could drop you off its back.
You fought with a man. Who was it?
I am asking you, Odysseas. Who was it?
Me, father.
What happened?
- Nothing.
- Tell me, what happened!
He called me a coward.
I got angry and attacked him.
The blood in men's veins is boiling.
You are brothers, but also men.
You fought like men,
but now you will make up like brothers.
Always together!
Rigas! How dare you do that
in front of me?
Father, I respect you,
but I cannot drink wine
with this coward.
Rigas,
- Take that back.
- I say it again to your face.
- You are unmanly and a traitor.
- Stop it!
-Odysseas, stay calm. I said, stay calm.
-Stay calm again?
Stay calm for how long?
Ever since I got here,
I've been trying to stay calm.
To forget what happened.
I came back and he is not embracing me.
And I say to myself,
"He is your brother, Odysseas".
He insults me. He sends me away
and declares me an enemy,
And I say to myself,
"He is your brother, Odysseas".
He hits helpless people.
He lashes out at poor and weak
women and I am ashamed.
I am deeply ashamed and say to myself,
"He is your brother, Odysseas".
Say to your older son, father,
that I am the son
and brother of landlords, a squire.
But that doesn't stop me
from being human.
And also tell him not to
go over the edge.
Because someday I will say
to myself for the first time,
"This guy, Odysseas,
is not your brother".
Rigas,
you tried to break two bonded sticks,
but you couldn't do so.
It's a shame because
difficult times are ahead.
The fire is burning again.
Workers are getting ready
for a new uprising.
This happened in 1828 at Morias.
It also happened in 1864 at Eptanisa.
The state was forced to
give big estates to the landless.
And the same will happen
here in Thessaly,
as long as you believe in it.
And to that end,
you all have to fight together.
You tell us to fight, but how?
Like the last time when they bashed us?
This failure was useful.
It taught you what to avoid.
It taught you not to rise separately
and at random.
You were patient for generations.
You can be for a little longer.
But when the time comes,
the whole of Thessaly will rise.
Then you will get the land either by law
or with your own hands and blood.
Eirini, Eirini.
What happened?
The pregnant woman is
about to give birth.
May she have a healthy delivery!
How long has she been trying?
About an hour and a half. Get in there.
She's asking for you.
Listen to him.
He cries for land already.
Someone is coming.
A bandit.
He's on the ranch and coming this way.
Go that way. Back, back!
Put the rifle down.
Move it now.
- What do you want?
- My wife just gave birth.
- A boy or a girl?
- A boy.
Kotsos,
Kotsos stay with us.
He was born in the fields,
under the sun.
Let's hope that his children
will be born under a roof.
Move on, without causing trouble.
Work! Everybody back to work!
Fast!
Close the tap.
That's my boy.
Last time you forgot it open.
- Move it.
- Where are you taking me?
For a walk.
It's well suited for friends of bandits.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Move it.
Harder! Harder!
Hit him! Harder!
Shut up!
I hired you because
I didn't want people to think that
I'm scared of you.
But now you are scaring me.
I give you bread!
And you try to take mine away.
Her husband is a bandit.
And this bastard brought him
to my ranch.
- In my own home!
- He is lying.
- Shut up, you bastard!
- Shame on you, Rigas.
Shame on all of you.
You're brutalizing a new mother
and a young kid.
What kid?
He's a snitch for the bandits.
He stole from me.
Just two sips of wine,
and a piece of bread that even
your dogs wouldn't eat.
Your brother is a thief
and a ruffian on my ranch.
And whoever does the same,
or helps him over the next day,
tell him that he's digging his own grave
be it a man or a woman.
Get back to your work. I said, leave!
- What's going on, Rigas?
- I caught him stealing.
And one of the bandits that were here
is her husband.
Rigas, stay calm.
Violence is a bad seed,
for it brings violence.
Cut the ropes. What do you want, Rigas?
And you should know
that I don't have only one son.
Whatever complaints you may have,
he is my son too.
Help this woman here.
Do you know what gets me
wondering about you?
What?
How can both of you have come
out of the same belly?
Shut it.
Never say that again, you hear me?
Did you get angry at what Giagos said?
Rigas is my brother.
I'm sorry that you once fought
with him for me.
That was the right thing to do.
If needed, I would do it again.
I'm getting scared.
I'm thinking about taking Giagos
and leaving.
This might best for everyone.
The day I saved you at the river
from my brother's arms,
you told me about your father
who died fighting for you,
for your future children
and for everyone else.
Do you remember what I told you then?
Not to give up this fight.
We can't stay here, Odysseas.
Your brother has respect for nothing.
It's not just my brother here.
There's also me.
I don't want to stand in between.
You have the same strength as him.
- I'm scared more of you.
- Why?
Because...
Because I can't fight you.
What are you afraid of?
What I see in your eyes
when you're looking at me.
What I also feel inside.
We shouldn't fool ourselves,
Odysseas Hormovas.
You're a nobleman and I'm no one.
Thank you for everything
that you have done for us.
I came to tell you
that tomorrow I'm leaving.
Listen Eirini,
there's nothing keeping me here either.
But I stay because I have to.
And so do you.
All these people need you.
Can you feel it?
I do.
Give me your hand
and swear that you will not
give up on them.
Do you promise?
Yes, Odysseas.
Go now.
- What are you doing here?
- Don't get scared.
- Leave.
- I told you, don't get scared.
I won't come on to you this time.
I want to tell you some true words.
Like a man.
What do you want, Rigas?
All my life, I've been
struggling with the land.
I never read or travelled.
So I don't know how to say nice words.
You have fallen down,
but you hold your head up high.
I want you.
Ever since my mother died,
my home is empty.
- You're looking for a maid?
- I'm looking for a woman.
A mother for my future children.
Rigas Hormovas,
this is the first time that you treat me
as a man would.
I'm aware of who you are and what I am.
It is an honor for me.
But I cannot say, "I do".
- Do you love somebody else?
- There's nothing more to say.
Farewell, Rigas.
Once you called me a bum.
And today I talked to you like a man.
Just know that whatever I have wanted,
I just grabbed it with my hand.
I wish I could lose both my hands.
You did well to come here.
It's time we gathered to
make a decision together.
- We can't bear it any longer.
- What's wrong?
- That damned guy from Kefallonia.
- Antypas?
- Yes.
- Him again?
Yes, him. A few days ago he was
at my ranch.
Now he's at Hormovas' land.
Tomorrow he'll be somewhere else.
He roams with a can of oil
and he spills it all over Thessaly.
Then he will light a match
and burn all of us.
What are you suggesting?
Is there someone for the job?
Yes, he's trustworthy,
but he wants a lot.
Come on in, come on in,
just two dimes per person,
an exotic presence,
an exotic world dancer,
an exotic dancer from the Balkans...
Paris, Rome, New York
It's not a boa, nor a rattler.
It's a fox from Siberia.
... the whole of the land
and leave nothing for you,
for your sweat that waters their land.
Nobody move!
- You're here again?
- As you can see...
Beating you didn't make you any wiser?
Not in the way you mean it.
There are worse things than beating.
- Do you know what I'm talking about?
- I know.
You're threatening me with death.
I'm not threatening you.
I'm trying to bring you to your senses.
What are you doing here?
What I always do.
I talk to them about the land.
And what are you telling them?
That  sooner or later
this land will be theirs.
Maybe that will convince you
that it will never be theirs.
You've already tried to persuade me
in that way, but to no avail.
But this time I will persuade you.
Beetle, eat from this land
and see how it tastes!
Eat it and taste it to see how
it grew out of Hormovas' blood.
Move away and stop beating them.
You disgrace yourself and
become the only one to lose.
Let me talk to him.
- So, you are Antypas?
- Yes I am.
Do you know that leading people
to revolt is prohibited by law?
Speak.
Beating is also prohibited, old man.
And so is feeding one dirt,
and exploitation, and low wages,
and raping women in the fields.
Is it true that you tell the workers
that they should take the land?
- Yes?
- How then?
Greece has a constitution,
and the Greek constitution article 17
is about the land.
Do you know what is stated there?
Nobody shall be deprived
of his property.
Can you hear me? Nobody!
Old Hormovas, that is not the whole
of article 17.
Let me fill the gaps.
In case of public need,
one may be deprived of his property.
Do you understand what public need is?
That nobody shall be deprived
of his property,
unless it is needed for the common good,
unless it should benefit the people
and the nation.
God bless you, Antypas.
And redistributing Thessaly's land,
will indeed benefit the people.
Because only then,
only then, after the Turks have gone,
will Thessaly's farmers
no longer be slaves.
And since redistribution
will benefit the people,
it will also benefit the nation.
Because happy nations with hungry people
do not exist!
- Free the nations!
- Way to go, Antypas!
Shut up!
Leave.
Go your own way.
You are free.
Antypas!
Antypas,
for your own sake,
- don't go towards the well.
- Why?
I saw an armed guy roaming there.
I didn't like his face.
He looks like a murderer.
Maybe it's time.
Time for what?
Nothing.
- Which way  leads to the well?
- That way.
Farewell, my girl. Thank you.
Antypas, what are you going to do?
Sometimes one's death may offer more
than his life. Goodbye.
Did you happen to see Odysseas?
No I didn't.
I told him about the murderer
and he went straight at him.
Where are you going?
Ah, you're here.
Let's not be seen.
No one knows I'm leaving.
Hand over your bundle.
It's OK that I don't have
any new clothes?
Only the ones you got me.
In Athens you will live like a queen.
Don't you want that?
- Of course I want it.
- Come on then.
The ones that paid him gave him little,
too little for such a murder.
That man who will soon be
under the earth,
is not an ordinary man.
If he were ordinary and not rare,
if he were little and not great,
if he were a coward and not courageous,
then he would still be alive.
But he chose to die.
And all of us are here
to mourn him and honor him.
The people, but also
the honorable masters,
the respectable leaders of these lands.
That man gave his life for a dream,
to see Thessaly happy again one day ,
to see its children full,
its mothers laughing,
and its farmers working their own land.
And now that he is no longer among us,
will his dream, which is also
your dream, fade away?
Will your children forget
that they are starving?
Will your women stop
giving birth to slaves?
Or will you, the men,
stop asking for, in fear of death,
a piece of land to feed yourselves?
Our fields, or our graves!
A hut and a graveyard brothers!
A hut for our children,
a graveyard for our bones.
This is why God is with us
and He sends me to bless this fight.
Long live father Dimitris
with your workers from Kalfaki.
Fight our oppressors, brothers!
I am Thymios Bazis. You know me.
I am the shoemaker.
From you poor peasants,
I have nothing to gain.
You're always barefoot,
even in the grave.
But I'm with you, a peasant among you,
ready to live and to die.
We want justice!
No rifles, my brothers! No rifles.
Nor blood.
We should only tell him one thing,
before he's gone forever.
That his words are now
a seed on this land,
and the spring he was dreaming of
will soon be here.
The sun will not come out
this dawn.
The moon will not come out
tonight.
Now that you have fallen
to the ground, oh eagle,
oh valiant eagle,
valiant eagle
A sour river
is what life is.
It will take our pain away.
Our tears, our sorrows,
oh valiant eagle,
oh valiant eagle.
Tonight, it will come out
it will come out,
the moon will come out tonight.
The sun will flash this dawn,
oh valiant eagle,
oh valiant eagle.
Who is in command of the workers here?
- I am.
- Then I shall speak with you.
- I'm listening.
- Harvest season is over.
Tell them to pack their things
tomorrow morning.
They will be paid their share
and they will leave from my land.
- Do you agree?
- I agree.
Anything more?
That chair by the table...
I want to know what to do with it.
Should I keep it or burn it?
Burn it.
Can you at least tell me why?
I'd rather not, father.
I already said enough at the funeral.
Odysseas, only tell me...
Do you think that I am a killer?
For Antypas' death? No.
Is there another death?
- Yes, father.
- Which one?
The daily death from suffering
and misfortune of these people.
It is a crime, taking place each day
in poor men's huts.
You are a human and a Christian.
Luke 3:11 says to give
one of your two shirts.
You never happened to hear that parable?
I'm going blind, please,
I'm going blind.
Stop it and don't be afraid of the soap.
It hurts my eyes, I'm telling you.
If it didn't hurt,
then it wouldn't kill lice.
Go get dressed now, go on.
What are you waiting for?
Turn around.
Someone's becoming a young man here.
Is everyone dressed up?
Go have lunch now.
Now that you've become a man,
learn how to clean yourself.
My mom is alive and you're lying,
saying she's dead.
I will look for her and go back
to the village. You are lying to me.
I'm worried about this child.
He won't accept that his mother is dead.
He'll get older and he'll forget it.
Little kids never forget.
Do older men forget?
I brought something to eat. Come on.
Father invited me back home again.
Odysseas, I'm scared for you.
- What are you scared of?
- You're a great man. All admire you.
But now you've gone a step too far.
What do you mean?
One's roots are at home,
and a man, just like a tree,
can't live without roots.
You were born the son
and brother of a nobleman.
You need to go back.
Your father never went back.
My father had no other way.
Didn't Antypas have another way?
He had a home back there.
He could have lived
a peaceful life in his homeland.
But he came here to die for everyone.
You warned him, yet he went
where his heart told him to go.
All this means nothing to you?
Listen Eirini, that's the only way.
I will stay with you
and seek to find new roots.
You think you're capable of that?
If I'm near you, yes.
- Odysseas...
- Say no more.
We will find our own hill,
get some stones and build a house,
with our own hands.
And you will hold your own children,
not those of others.
Do you want it?
I am the first among all men.
The sun needs half a day
to cross my land.
She is a shoeless peasant
and she said, "No" to me.
-That damn brother of yours intervened.
- Shut up, beat it.
- Boss.
- Leave me alone, I said leave!
My grandpa was a farmer,
just a regular man.
He was telling me that for big animals
you have to wait near water.
- What's up?
- Hm, don't get scared.
I would have laid you down,
but a good friend stopped me.
He has a better idea about you.
You're staring at me like a stupid fish.
You almost forgot me, right?
But I'm the type that never forgets.
- Hand me the money.
- What money?
The money you'll steal from the workers'
wages tomorrow. Give it to me.
Give it to me!
- And the rest, there is more.
- I don't have any.
All of your life
you were exploiting people.
To multiply your money
and to fatten your ass.
Now I will teach you what it's like
to be a peasant.
Get off of me!
You will pay for that, I swear.
Bastard, you will pay for that one day.
It's payback time.
You wanted to hang me, huh?
Come on, come on!
Enough.
The first time I saw you
you spoke of a law of yours.
Now I'm telling you to your face,
your law is worse than the one
of my brother and father.
Because this is the old one,
which is destined to die.
While yours is the new one and
that's why it should be less vulgar.
Next time I meet you, don't hit me.
Because I will hit you back
without mercy.
Let's go.
I said, let's go.
Rigas. Rigas!
- You?
-Don't talk. Try to stand on your feet.
You did bad in coming.
I didn't ask for anyone's help.
- Leave.
- We are brothers, Rigas.
Brothers? No,
there are so many things in between us.
Help!
What is this, Odysseas Hormovas?
You think you're entering a stable?
I'm asking what's going on.
- Don't you know?
- What?
- Eirini...
- The took her.
- What did you say?
- Two men grabbed her.
- When?
-Just now, we're getting ready to leave.
- Damn you!
Now that you were about to leave?
Is this why you kicked the door?
You're the only one I could think of.
You were wrong.
If I'm wrong, then I'm glad.
I wouldn't want you to be
the one who dared that.
Wait. With one rifle
and a few shoeless guys
you will not achieve much.
I'm coming with you.
Guns and bullets for your people.
I will also give you horses.
This morning a woman was kidnapped.
Did you see anything?
Speak! Speak!
At dawn I saw two horses running.
- Did they have a woman with them?
- I couldn't say.
- Why?
- They were running too fast.
- Did you recognize anyone?
- I recognized a horse.
Pasiakos,
this is bad day for you,
do you know that?
What's wrong, what do you want from me?
- Do you know who I am?
- You're Hormovas' son.
Watch it punk.
I will ask you only once and
you will give me only one answer.
- Where is the woman?
- What?
- What woman, guys?
Where is she? Where are you hiding her?
Where? Speak, speak!
Tell me where she is, speak!
Odysseas, are you out of your mind?
You want to go to jail?
That bastard has a hut
and a sheepfold up in the mountains.
Everyone, follow me!
What's wrong?
It injured itself somehow
and it limps now.
I'm losing time.
I'll meet you at the ranch.
- What is it, Pasiakos?
- I got scared.
- Everything all right?
- Yes.
That day at the river, you tricked me,
that you might be a man after all.
But you're not a human,
but rather a loathsome animal,
-a wolf that came out of a cursed belly.
- It's your fault,
I asked to make you a noblewoman,
you would walk and everyone
would bow in front of you,
but you said no,
but do you remember what I told you?
When I want something,
I lay my hand and grab it.
If only they could cut my hand.
Leave. I love your brother
and he loves me.
- Over time he will get over it.
- Leave me alone, leave!
What will you gain in getting a woman
who doesn't want you?
Leave.
I hate you!
I want you to be my wife.
Tomorrow we will forget everything,
and everyone will accept it, everyone.
Father?
Father, no.
No, father!
- Father, have you gone mad?
- Don't call me father.
The pig I just saw lying in the dirt
is not my son.
Get lost!
Drop the rifle, old man. Are you crazy?
Drop the rifle I'm telling you, drop it.
Father...
- Father.
- Stay away from me.
I've been a land owner,
but I was always a man.
Go away, don't come near me. Go!
I said, leave.
Leave.
Take that road.
Father?
Put a saddle on the horse's back.
I'm beginning a long journey.
Father, who was it? Who was it, father?
- Did you see him?
- Yes.
- Who was it?
- Rigas.
He has Eirini with him.
He's heading towards Kolones.
- Odysseas.
- Yes, father.
You have a big heart.
- Don't let a woman...
- Father.
You are brothers.
You share the same blood.
Hold each other's hand tight,
next to each other.
- Come on, father.
- Stay there!
All that land,
wide as the open sea, it is yours.
I can hear their voices at Kalifoni.
At Farsala horses are galloping.
At Killeler there's fire!
I can see them coming for your land.
Stay together, fight with all means.
Stop th...
Take him home,
and prepare a great funeral for him.
Aren't we coming with you?
From now on,
I'll do everything on my own.
Go back, Odysseas Hormovas.
It is a sin to spill the blood
of one's brother.
What's going on there?
Rigas killed his father and took Eirini.
- What?
- And who's shooting now?
- His brother, Odysseas.
Do you know what? A good day has risen
in the fields, one to remember.
Mount your horses.
Odysseas, for the last time,
I'm telling you to leave. Leave!
- Where is he?
- Giagos, please leave.
Giagos, I'm begging you.
Stay here and keep quiet.
Leave, Giagos!
Did I hurt you much?
Our father?
Take cover, Odysseas Hormovas.
Odysseas...
Now, Rigas,
look down at the land,
and tell me,
how much of it is yours?
The land separated those two,
and now it brings them together.
The land which from now on
will belong to everyone the same.
Let their death unite us.
And may the years that are to come
find us together,
to eat some bread that is sweet
and free.
A few years later, Thessaly's land
was redistributed to the peasants.
The war for the liberation of Macedonia
was approaching
and Eleftherios Venizelos
was proclaiming:
"Slaves cannot liberate slaves"