The story of the
American frontier
is a tale of conquest
but also one of survival,
persistence and the
grit of the people.
It's 20 years after
a bloody Civil War.
Despite Abraham Lincoln's
Emancipation Proclamation,
slavery is alive and
well in the Wild West,
in the form of prostitution,
the world's oldest profession.
In Kansas and most of
the western territories,
women are bought, sold
and traded like property.
TRADED
Subrip: Pix
Come on Pa, show me how!
All right, all right,
now I'm gonna do this
one time, all right?
Now the idea is when
the tyin's bein' done,
you wanna flex your muscles.
Blow your chest
up like a rooster.
What's a rooster do?
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
That's right, now you see,
when the tyin's done,
you relax your muscles,
blow all the air
outta your chest...
And now look,
the rope gives ya
just enough room
so you can get yourself free.
Show me how Pa, show me how!
Maybe after supper.
And your studies.
The capital of
Kansas is Topeka,
and the President
of the United States
is Chester Alvin Arthur.
Chester Alan Arthur.
Can we ask him now, Ma?
Before the day's activities
sour his disposition?
What do you care about
some stupid old dance anyway?
You hush up!
Do my eyes deceive
me? Is that a...
Apple pie.
I picked, peeled and
sliced all the apples,
and then spiced
them with cinnamon.
Clay, Lily was
invited to a tie dance,
over at the Tigman Ranch.
You know apple
pie is my favorite.
Spiced with cinnamon.
The dance is the girls
wear a calico dress
and they bring a matching
tie for the boys to choose.
Now I am familiar
with the procedure
of a tie dance, young lady.
In fact, there was a time...
It wasn't so long ago,
as a matter of fact...
Flies in the buttermilk?
Yuck!
Well Pa, can I go?
I'm sorry Darlin'.
Maybe next year.
But Pa!
You know what this pie needs?
My teeth?
Some honey.
I'll fetch some.
Well last summer you let
me work at the Mercantile.
Nellie Wilcott is 16 and
she's been proposed to.
Darlin'...
Nellie Wilcott is not my
beautiful little girl.
It's just a tie dance Pa.
Besides, if I ever do find
a beau, once he meets you,
he'll be too scared to
ever call on me again.
Darlin', I'm sorry.
Now this matter is settled.
I wanna have my dinner in peace.
How long does it take that
boy to fetch some honey?
I'll get him.
They're gonna
come callin' Clay.
And we both know that extra
year is for you, not her.
Amelia you's the
one what told me
what your dancin' days led to.
I was dancin' at the
Broken Spoke Saloon,
not the Tigman's front parlor.
And I didn't have
two loving parents.
That's my little girl.
If I ain't gonna protect her,
who's gonna?
Ma! Pa!
Lily?
My god!
Jake?
Jake!
What happened?
Come here.
Watch out, watch out!
You can take
comfort, Mr. Travis,
in knowing that Jake is
in a much better place.
All due respect Reverend,
I'd rather have my boy
standing right here beside me.
I am sorry for your loss.
For the life of me,
I just can't remember
the sound of his voice.
I'd give anything to hear
his voice one more time.
He was my little boy.
He's an angel.
Blame me.
Just say it.
I'm the one who
asked for the honey.
Blame me.
-Amelia.
-Blame me!
Come on!
Blame me!
Blame me, blame me, blame me!
I need you to!
Please blame me!
Please?
We're nearly outta firewood.
I'll go chop some.
Mama.
I love you, it's gonna be okay.
Where are you off to?
Going to the lake.
I...
Need you to stay here and
help me with the canning.
But Ma, you never asked
me to help you before.
I thought you said
canning's the one job
you like to do all by yourself.
This time I want you helpin' me.
I done all my chores,
all my bookwork,
I was really lookin' forward
to going to the lake.
There's no tellin'
who's out there.
Last time I was out there,
it was just old man Hill.
That was nearly
a year ago and...
Just had to help
him bait his hook.
I also want your daddy
checkin' that boat for leaks.
But Ma, the boat is fine.
You're stayin' here and
helpin' me can these tomatoes!
Why are you bein' silly?
Don't you dare call me names.
Amelia.
Isn't that just like you?
Takin' her side.
Lily, Darlin',
I want you to stay here and
help your Mama with the canning.
Just for today, this one time.
Sweetie, I'm gonna go down
and check that boat for leaks.
Okay?
Be a good girl.
Don't be doin'
me any favors Clay.
Lily get up, you've
slept long enough!
Lily!
Lily, your Mama
is callin' you.
Probably just in the
privy or the barn.
Not possible.
I was awake before dawn.
Lily's horse is missing, I'm
going over to Jane Thompson's.
Can't find Lily nowhere.
Took her horse and left in
the middle of the night.
Jane Thompson.
You tell Mrs. Travis what
her daughter confided in you.
Or that matchin' blue bonnet
goes right back to Abilene!
Woah.
She's gone to Newton to
catch a stage to Wichita.
She read an advertisement
about becoming a Harvey girl,
waitress like Jane's sister.
Thank you.
I'd like a ticket
to Wichita please.
Just one?
Yes sir.
That'll be 50 cents.
Visitin' family, are ya?
No, my family lives
'round these parts.
Employment?
Why yes,
I'm hopin' to get a
position as a Harvey girl.
I've heard a lot of
good things about that
outstandin' company.
Coach leaves in 10 minutes.
Thank you.
Good luck with your...
Job huntin'.
How do you do ma'am?
I'm well.
Name's Rig Marlowe.
Lily Travis.
Well, Lily like a flower.
Pleased to meet you.
Has anyone told
you that you look
like sunshine in the morning?
You think you're
gonna need that?
Lily's horse, all cooled down.
Limber and well-fed.
You won't find a
finer animal in town.
Where's the owner?
You're lookin' at him.
That's my daughter's
horse, where is she?
I don't know.
Fella gave me a dollar
to ride that horse back.
Where did she go?
I don't know.
But I'm keepin' that dollar.
This girl been in here?
What's she to you?
She's our daughter.
The boy's a spittin'
image of you.
We're lookin' for the girl.
She has reddish-brown hair.
Down to here.
Reddish-brown you say?
Have you seen her?
She don't look nothin' like you.
Have you seen the girl?
Did she buy a ticket?
No.
Pretty little girl like that,
that hair?
I'd remember her.
You son of a bitch.
Clay.
Clay, let's go, come on now.
Maybe she changed her mind
and she's still in town?
Fella in there
is lyin' to you.
I think it's time you
told me everything you know.
She left a couple hours
ago on the stage to Wichita.
Honest to god,
or strike me dead.
I'm going to get her.
You head back to the ranch.
I'm not losing
another child, Clay.
Go to mercantile,
get us some supplies.
I'm gonna go in and
deal with this fella.
Be back here in five minutes.
Clay, Lily told Jane she
ran off because of our...
Because of my ill
temper and distress.
Five minutes.
Take your glasses off.
Pardon me?
You son of a bitch!
Ma'am?
That fella you were with,
he gave me a note to give ya.
He said you'd give me two bits.
Thank you ma'am.
My darlin' Amelia,
do not follow me.
I'll find our daughter and
I'll bring her home safely.
Love you always.
Your husband done this to me!
Crazy son of a bitch.
He done this to me!
Broke my damn nose!
'Scuse me ma'am,
would you happen to know where
they're hiring the Harvey girls?
Thank you, thank you very much.
Woah.
I've been waiting
in this line for more
than an hour sir, I'd like
to fill out my application.
Of course miss, fill this out.
'Scuse me ladies.
You certain
we met all our quotas?
All the
way to Colorado.
'Scuse me.
I'm lookin' for my daughter.
Her name's Lily Travis.
Have you seen her?
We'll have the remaining
ladies fill out applications
then we'll inform them
they'll get a telegraph
when employment is available.
Sir, I need a
second of your time.
You see, that's my daughter.
Have you seen her?
Now take a look at the picture.
Miss Eivers! Miss Eivers!
Sir, please, please!
Ma'am, I have come
all the way from Newton,
now I'm lookin' for my daughter.
She's got reddish-brown hair.
I'm sorry, your
daughter hasn't been here.
We haven't seen her.
Thank you.
Next?
Hi yes,
I'd like to fill out an
application for the Harvey girls.
What's your name, boy?
Jacob, Jacob Oliver.
Jacob Oliver.
Stage came in from
Newton this morning,
I'm looking for a
girl that was on it.
The driver here?
No sir.
Well who switched the team?
That'd be my Pa.
Is he here?
Asleep in the back.
Well, come on, show me.
Come on now.
Show me where your dad is.
You walk any slower,
you're goin' backwards.
Mr. Oliver, listen to me now.
This is her, you see that?
That's what she looks
like, right there.
Yeah, I saw a
young girl with...
Reddish-brown hair.
That's the girl.
Where did she go, did
you see where she went?
I did see this young fellow...
Rig Marlowe.
Rig Marlowe?
Where would I find him?
The Rusty Spur.
Yeah, come in.
Well hello Benedict.
You're gonna be
pleased with these sir.
You made 10% more
this month than you
did the last month.
I see that.
Yeah.
Must've been from those...
Cowboys came through on that
cattle drive, you figure?
Yeah, they came
through in bundles.
They were generous.
Well did you have Doc check
the girls out after they left?
I hope they weren't
too generous.
We
Checked them out sir,
and they're in good shape.
Clean?
Well, you know that...
We keep those girls extra clean.
Yeah, I bet you
do check 'em out.
Speakin' of the girls,
how 'bout those new girls,
you havin' any
trouble with them?
We're not having
any trouble except
one of them got the
shit beat outta her.
This drunk, just stomped her.
He was drunker than a monkey.
Well we can't have
that can we Benedict?
Hell no!
Well go get the bastard
and bring him in here.
I'll get that son of a bitch.
Well get your
ass up, go get him!
I'm goin', I'm goin'.
Hey you, you son of a
bitch, get over there.
Have a seat, friend.
What do you think I ought
to do with him Benedict?
Well I think you
outta cut his balls off.
Give us a minute Benedict.
Thank you.
Now son,
we don't abide ill manners
in this establishment.
It won't happen again sir.
Something else we
don't abide by...
Trash like you fuckin'
with the merchandise.
Son of a bitch wanted
to hurt my sweetie.
Somebody come in here
and clean this shit up!
Lookin' for someone mister?
Yeah.
I got somethin' that
belongs to Rig Marlowe.
Haven't seen him all day.
Any idea where
I might find him?
Anywhere he can put his
hands on a pretty girl,
or a deck of cards.
If I see him, who
should I say is callin'?
Chester Alan Arthur.
He a friend of
yours, Mr. President?
Never met the man.
Just delivering his
property, you say?
Yes sir.
Spinning Wheel
Saloon, across the way.
You ain't lookin' for
trouble now son, are ya?
You remind me of a young'in
that passed through here,
fire in his eyes like yours.
I'm gonna tell you the
same thing I told him.
There's a battle in every man.
Two wolves that exist
inside each of us.
One's evil and anger,
the other's love and hope.
You know which one wins?
The one you feed.
Which one you gonna feed, Hoss?
What can I do ya for?
I'm lookin'
for Rig Marlowe.
Gent with the red vest,
poker table with
Charlie and Silas.
You got
chips at the bar here?
I do.
Thank you.
Much obliged.
You gentlemen
lookin' for a fourth?
If you stop this man
from stealin' our money.
Just a run of luck.
Have a seat.
Name's Rig Marlowe.
This here's Charlie, Silas.
Haven't had the privilege
of their surnames yet.
Arthur Alan.
Well Arthur with
two first names,
two dollar ante.
You boys
from around here?
Ain't nobody from around here.
What you have in mind?
Well, I'm lookin' for a
little female companionship.
I'm partial to the young ones.
All the girls in here...
Little long in the tooth.
Well you haven't
even seen 'em all yet.
You just got here.
Five dollars.
How many?
I'll take one.
Two.
Two more.
Let's have a look Silas.
Two pair.
Guess you are lucky, Mister.
I mean, at least for me anyway.
The Rusty Spur has the
youngest whores in town.
And they don't put a
hole in your pocket.
Ain't that the truth?
What about you, Mr. Marlowe?
You know anywhere to
find the young ones?
Seems like you're lookin'
for a particular girl, Arthur.
Five dollars.
They're all particular.
-How many?
-Two.
Same here.
Ten.
Ten it is.
Well well, we find ourselves
in the same predicament.
Marlowe?
You never did answer
me, Mr. Marlowe.
About the young ones.
What you got?
Full house.
Queens over tens!
Silas, woah, woah.
Silas, what the
hell you doin' boy?
Funny thing is
I got queens too.
Let's not be hasty, friend.
You know this is
the second time today
that I counted five queens.
-You sure 'bout that?
-Hell yeah.
How do we know where
the fifth lady came from?
You were the dealer!
That's exactly how I know!
All right, now just
put that gun away,
sit down and we'll work
this out peaceful like.
Are you in on this with him?
You son of a bitch!
You arrived this
morning from Newton
with my daughter
Lily, Lily Travis!
Now where is she?
Where?
Shit.
Find what you were
lookin' for Hoss?
Yeah.
And now I'm lookin'
for your boss.
That'll be Ty Stover.
And where do I find him?
Top of the stairs,
first door on the right.
You Ty Stover?
Yeah, I'm Ty Stover.
I'm lookin' for my daughter.
She's 17,
got reddish brown hair.
Named Lily Travis.
She was walkin' to your saloon
this morning with Rig Marlowe.
Haven't seen her.
But I'm in and out
all day, I'm...
Wichita's Fire Chief.
Maybe you outta ask Marlowe.
I did.
Well if Marlowe
doesn't know, then...
Whoever gave you that
information must be mistaken.
It's not that he didn't know,
he couldn't tell me.
He's dead.
Mr. Travis?
Clay Travis.
Mr. Travis.
I may run a brothel...
But I run it in
accordance with the law.
Maybe you're right.
'Bout my information
bein' wrong.
I apologize for
takin' your time sir.
It's quite all right.
Close the door.
Have you seen this girl?
She's got reddish-brown hair.
17 years old.
No, I haven't seen her Sugar.
Why are you singin' that song?
I heard one of the
girls singin' it today.
Can't seem to get
it outta my head.
Was it this girl?
Look at the picture.
Was it her?
Look at the picture
Darlin', she's my daughter.
Have you seen her?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's her.
Where?
Where did you see her?
I don't know.
It's my daughter!
Hands off the girl.
We don't want no
trouble here Son.
Time for you to
go outside buddy.
Jesus.
You got two seconds to
tell me what I wanna know
before I pump you full of lead.
Where is she?
Where?
Get the hell outta here.
We don't want that
kind of trouble.
I guess we know
which wolf won.
What did you expect?
It's his daughter.
What would you do if someone
disappeared one of your kin?
I reckon I'd feed
the same hungry beast.
Son of a bitch!
Where is she?
Mr. Travis! You
have to believe me!
Where?
When I tell ya that I have
no idea where your daughter is.
I don't know what
Marlowe did with her!
Where is she?
Fuck you!
I should've killed
you in my goddamn bar!
You son of a bitch!
Where is she?
Cut me loose
and I'll tell you!
Cut me loose.
Tell me first!
I traded her!
You traded my daughter?
That's
right, I traded her.
Traded her for what?
I traded her for
that fuckin' bell!
You traded my daughter
for a goddamn bell?
Yeah. I did.
To who?
LaVoie!
Where the hell is he?
He's on a train.
Train to where?
Dodge City.
Now, set me free...
Or you'll die in this town.
You're a dead man.
You'll die right here,
you won't ever get out.
I'll set you free.
Set me free goddamn it!
Yeah,
I'll set you free!
Train to Dodge?
Train just left.
Clay Travis.
Damn, I knew it was you.
You killed five men in Abilene.
Nearly 15 years ago.
Yeah.
You killed my best
friend Willie Parker.
Just turned 17.
He drew first.
That ain't what he
told me before he died.
Some men choose
to cast themselves
in a brighter light before
they meet their maker.
And Kansas soil's full of fools
who thought they were quicker.
Ya! Come on!
Come on, come on!
Ain't no damn way he's
gonna catch that train.
Lily?
I'm sorry ma'am.
Ticket.
I didn't have a
chance to buy a ticket.
Five dollars.
Five?
How long does it
take to get to Dodge?
Day's end.
If nothin' goes wrong.
What do you got in
that coach back there?
Empty.
Like your goddamn head.
Maybe I'll take
a seat back there.
Maybe you'll sit your
ass right where you're at.
Train's movin'.
It's dangerous.
Five minutes to Dodge City.
Five minutes.
Hey! Get outta there!
Apples, fresh apples,
two cents a piece.
Three for a nickel.
Apple? Two cents a piece.
Apples, fresh apples.
Two cents a piece,
three for a nickel.
Care for an apple sir?
Two cents a piece.
Fresh apples.
Mister, are you alive?
Who are you?
Name's Girl.
Girl?
They call me Girl 'cause
I'm too ugly to have a name.
Where am I?
Shack. Dodge City.
This your sweetheart?
Give me that.
That's my daughter.
Right pretty.
You live here by yourself?
Me and my Pa.
He's not my real Pa, but...
He was married to my Ma before
she was took by the angels.
Where is he?
Workin'.
He'll be home tonight.
He always comes
home every night.
I gotta use your privy.
Out back.
Pa's got the key.
This here's silk.
It still smells like my
Mama's lavender scent.
She said she got it from France?
I don't know where that is,
but I know it ain't
anywheres near here.
Europe. France is in Europe.
Know what I made
outta this here silk?
A dress?
Why would I waste it on that?
I made this fine table covering.
For fancy company.
Well with what you got left,
you should make
yourself a dress,
I bet you'd look
real pretty in it.
You got a wife Mr. Clay?
Yes I do.
Your ranch very large?
It's big enough.
After you find your daughter,
maybe I could go back
to your ranch with you?
I'm a real hard
worker and I can cook,
and I hardly eat anything.
What about your Pa?
Ain't he gonna miss ya?
Ain't you gonna miss him?
Well...
Yeah,
skin him, cook him up for stew.
Yes Pa.
This food here,
ain't for free, stranger.
I appreciate your
daughter tendin' to me.
I give you my word
I'll repay you.
Well we can't eat
promises, now can we?
I'm presently lookin'
for my own daughter.
I believe she's been
imprisoned in town as a whore.
Tomorrow you give
me a full day's work
and then I'll decide
if it's enough.
Time is crucial to me, sir.
I'd appreciate it.
Hey!
You can't leave
me shackled here!
Girl!
Give him a pot to
relieve himself with.
And you get your ass
in the back room.
Now!
Oof! Son of a bitch!
We start work at
sun up 'round here.
I hope you like bacon, eggs
and hot biscuits Mr. Clay.
Now what's this?
I made a fine table covering
outta my mama's silk from Paris.
Paris?
This came from your
mama's shack in Abilene.
A horny merchant came by and...
He exchanged
this red silk for
some afternoon pussy.
You see, her mother was a...
Silver dollar whore.
And she deserved every
purple trophy that she got.
You're a rotten liar.
Say that again Girl!
Nothing.
I hope we didn't rile
your slumber last night.
I mean we, Girl and me,
well we rattled them
floorboards didn't we Girl?
You know she got a
face that'll kinda
break a lookin' glass.
But thank the Lord.
She got her mama's pussy.
This is a feast fit
for the mayor himself.
I may have to have you
work two days for me boy.
Damn!
You know how I like my biscuits.
Smothered with honey.
Now you go and
bring me that honey.
Unshackle me.
10 dollars I
squirreled away from Pa.
Take it Mr. Clay.
You'll be needin' it
to find your daughter.
Thank you.
Hey mister, someone's lookin'
for you in the Lady Gay.
Who's lookin' for me?
Room nine.
You sure you got
the right fella?
Hey Sugar, do you wanna poke?
I'm lookin' for
room number nine.
Long time.
Nell Craft.
Damn you Clay Travis.
I was hoping you'd
be all scarred
and wrinkled like
a dried-up prune.
Been a long time.
You work here?
Not much interest in
a 40-year-old whore.
I own the place.
Nell, you look great.
The hell I do.
I wasn't quite
sure how you'd react
if we ever saw each other again.
Likewise.
Is there somethin' I
could've done different Clay?
Anything different
to get you to stay?
Nell...
Because I believe
I did just about
everything a girl
could possibly do.
And then some.
In the end,
I guess I just ended up falling
in love with a different...
Whore?
Different woman.
How is our dear Amelia?
She's out of sorts.
For old time's sake...
Can I trust you Nell?
For old time's sake.
This is our daughter.
Pretty thing.
How old?
She's 17.
She arrived this morning,
by train in a cattle car
with a few other young girls,
under the gun of a
man named LaVoie.
LaVoie recruits new girls.
The demand exceeds
the supply in Dodge.
Where do I find LaVoie?
Even you are no
match for LaVoie.
Samuel Colt's been known
to make all men equal.
If he's got your daughter,
she'll never be the same
little girl you remember.
My advice to you?
Go home.
Be with your Amelia
and that little boy.
I can't do that.
Then stay here with me.
Let me show you what
you've been missing.
Where's LaVoie, Nell?
He took possession of a
whore house across the way.
Calls it the French Chateau.
Good seein' ya again Nell.
Likewise.
While you boys are
gallivanting around town,
I need you to gather
me up some strays.
You mean girls?
Cats, roans living here
outnumber the whores.
I found me a rat
almost the size of a
beaver this morning, Daddy.
Wasn't Uncle Barkley
supposed to be
on the train this morning?
He has some important
business to attend to, son.
Now.
My brother has had his shortcomings
in the past, it's true.
But when I left that man
at that depot in Wichita,
he was clear-eyed and sober.
Praise the lord.
Mama always said Uncle Barkley
was gonna find the Lord's hand.
I ain't never been
accused of being
a church-going man
now have I Kipp?
No sir.
But in this case,
I'm gonna have to align myself
with your Mama.
Because nothin', now
you all listen up,
nothin', and I mean
nothin' in the whole world,
is more important than family.
A family,
in harmony,
will prosper.
In everything.
That's an old Chinese proverb.
That's one we
should all live by.
Yeah Daddy.
Bless the Chinese.
Come in.
Before you start talkin',
I need one of ya to
talk for both of ya,
understand?
All us girls got some demands.
We want to be treated proper.
Enough sleep so we don't
got darkness under our eyes.
A few minutes to
ourselves between turns.
A day off.
Proper doctoring,
not just a quick sideways
glance at our snatch.
Anything else?
That's the gist of it.
Anything else
you wanna discuss?
Now when they ask you,
you tell 'em that
whore's snatch went dry,
and she left town to try
her luck in Colorado,
understand?
Anything else...
You'll end up just like her.
Now get!
Afternoon gents!
Welcome to the French Chateau.
Women to the left,
liquor to the right.
Hey.
Afternoon.
Lee Crawford.
But you can call me LaVoie.
Hey Kipp, get this gentleman
here my best glass of whiskey.
Yes Daddy.
That's my son.
Welcome.
Good boy.
What brings you out 'round
these parts here, friend?
A girl.
Girl?
Well Cowboy, you
in the right place.
Tess!
This here Tess.
She's awful purdy and young,
but I'm lookin' for
somethin' a little different.
-Different?
-Different.
Well this one ain't for sale.
But it's your lucky day, Cowboy.
We just got a shipment
of young gals,
just ripe and fine
for the plucking.
But they ain't cheap, see that?
Ten dollars.
All right.
Tess, take this fine
gentleman upstairs right now!
And I'm gonna send
a girl up there
once they have her all
polished up for you.
All right, I ain't
gonna forget you now.
Hey Kipp, what do you think?
I don't like him.
I don't
like him either.
I don't like him at all.
This way, Honey.
We'll take real
good care of you.
Don't worry, the curtains are
for the three dollar whores.
You paid for a private room.
Don't be nervous Sweetie.
We cater to all types here.
The new girl will help you out.
No!
Please.
Shut your mouth!
Get up, you son of a bitch!
Pa!
-Hey!
-Go ahead.
I'll put a bullet right
between your eyes.
Please help.
Come on Darlin',
come on.
Come on now.
Jed!
What?
Come on daughter.
Son of a bitch!
Goddamn it, go get him!
Come on, damn it!
Take her outta here!
I'm not leavin' you!
I'm so sorry!
Run!
You better run
little girl, run run run!
Can't have you runnin' off
and stealing the merchandise!
We got a surprise for you today!
What you want Mills?
Telegraph for your father.
Get the fuck on!
God, what have I done?
It's all right.
I'm so sorry.
Clay Travis.
I believe you're familiar
with a Nell Craft?
You did her quite an injustice,
years back in Abilene.
You neglected to tell me
that you had kinfolk
under my roof Mr. Travis.
I'll pay you whatever you
want to leave my daughter alone.
I bet you would!
But money ain't an issue.
See, you killed a man,
in Wichita.
He drew on me first!
And that man.
Was my brother.
You kill my family,
I will have my pound of flesh.
Now I could just put a
bullet in your fuckin' head
right now, but why do that?
Why not have some fun, why not?
Blacksmith said this was the
best he could muster up boss.
All right, that's good enough.
Tie him up, tie him good.
Hell yeah!
Good fortune done brought
you back here, friend.
But I don't reckon
you'd agree, would ya?
Sir, a lady's causin'
a ruckus downstairs
about the girl you shot.
I don't care!
These women, you
can't live with 'em,
and you can't live without 'em.
Now another thing
I took away from
my time with the Chinese...
Gatherin' info.
See, during the war,
say when you're in a position
with some information,
this here done did the trick.
Opened them Union boys right up.
See, this rodent here?
The only thing on
this rodent's mind,
is this here fire, and
how to get away from it.
I seen grown men
call out for their mamas.
Beggin' for a
bullet in the head.
And when that rat realizes
there's no way out,
he's gonna start gnawin'
away at your skin.
He's gonna gradually eat his
way through your insides.
Tears a hole from your
gut through your back.
Yeah.
Now you two, you stay here,
until our little rat friend
here has done his job.
And that's when you
can see this table
through his stomach, okay?
And no matter how much he begs,
don't put a bullet in him.
Hey! Travis.
I'll be seein' ya friend.
I can abide by
shootin' an unruly whore.
But no man should be
tortured like this.
And it's gross.
Jed.
Jed, come back.
It doesn't seem right
for her to leave town
without saying a word,
she was my friend.
Ivory said she heard
gunshots from your office.
Yeah, yeah that's right.
Gunshots?
Fellas, you and Mills
showin' off your draw.
Right Mills?
Yeah, yeah, that was me!
Dumb son of a bitch.
It's not right for her,
she would not leave town
without saying a word.
She did express a
very strong desire
to leave Dodge City.
And I obliged.
Now, I suspect your
paths will cross...
Again.
Sooner or later.
In Colorado, yes?
Now either of you got
any other complaints
about how you're being treated?
If you do, you come see me.
And I'll arrange your travel.
Just like I did for Fran.
Now get back on
that goddamn floor
and sell those asses, now!
Son of a...
What the hell?
I want him dead!
You know where to look,
go kill that son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch!
Kipp, Jed, get your
asses down here!
Now!
What you need boss?
Yes Daddy?
You killed her, you
killed that poor girl!
Son of a bitch!
You touch my daughter?
I'm gonna send you
straight to hell!
Quit hidin' you coward!
Come out here, you chicken shit!
How do you like that?
Shit.
Fuck you!
I'll be damned, Mr. President.
You caught the damned train.
I've been thinkin' about
what you said at the Spur.
Figured you could use a hand.
Obliged, friend.
I ain't for anyone
beatin' no women.
One wolf to another,
I reckon I'd done
the same thing.
And if it was my daughter,
I'd kill that son
of a bitch dead.
Now go get the son of a bitch.
Come upstairs with me?
I'm just here for whiskey,
I'm not armed, I'm not armed.
Somebody's
shootin' downstairs!
Where's he at?
Drop it, drop it!
-Easy.
-Where is she?
She ain't here.
Lips or lead boy,
you're gonna show me.
You're gonna show me!
You son of a bitch.
Behind you!
Son of a bitch!
Where's my daughter?
Kipp!
I'm not askin' again.
I ain't afraid
to meet my maker.
Family?
When one piece is missin',
whole thing's broken.
You broke mine!
You know what
this was gonna be?
This was gonna be
the best goddamn
whore house west
of the Mississippi.
And your daughter's pussy
was gonna buy me a couple farms.
Open your mouth!
Open!
Bite down on the barrel.
Now someone tell me
where my daughter is.
Ain't no trains
for a good minute.
No sir.
Long ways back
where you come from.
Yes sir.
Longer still on
your own two feet.
Reckon you could use a horse.
I reckon I got a horse.
What will you do?
Reckon I'll go
somewhere quiet,
put my feet up and
retire these here boots.
It's been a long road,
and I'm tired.
But I'll find my way home.
Take care friend.
Pa, who was that man?
He's just
an old friend.
Ma!
Ma?
Maybe she's in the barn?
Lily!
Wait!