It's almost done...
Are you with the law?
-From Denver, huh?
-Yeah. Are you a bounty hunter?
No, just in a hurry to get across
the desert, like you.
It's a pretty crowded desert, ain't it...
Do you happen to have some ammunition?
-Thanks.
-Forget it.
-You had us jumping there boy.
When you took aim at us, I thought:
"Boys, this time we had it..."
Let go with the belts.
Go get your horses.
Put one under my saddle.
-You skunk. You'd pick off a beggar!
-Why not? Sit down and cool off.
Hey. The beans...
Good.
-You're welcome.
Hey, you're planning to starve us to death?
Empty...
You'll pay for this. You're a no-good
low-down vulture and hyena!
- Trinity Is Still My Name -
Well, what's the matter?
You're a good horse.
Poor Saddler...
That must've been some punch.
Get your hands up!
-Did you say...
-I said get them up!
If you're looking for a hole in the head,
I'm happy to oblige.
-You ain't lawmen, are you?
-What was that?
You know, the law, or the rangers maybe?
You got something on your conscience, stinky?
What are you worth 500?
I've just started out. But Judge Fitzpatrick
told me that if I keep up like this -
-I'll be worth 1000. Now I'm up to 50.
-50? Have you been stealing some chickens?
No. Turkeys...
Put them down, turkey.
Relax, we're no lawmen. Sit down. By the way,
have you seen anyone around these parts?
No, they had a posse after me,
but they gave up when I across the desert.
Did you got away on that nag?
-Why, what's wrong with her?
-She's no beauty.
-It's a damned good horse.
-We'll see about that a little later...
-What's wrong with him, is he sick?
-No, he has been beaten.
-Who hit him?
-A starving buffalo.
The old man was never too bright...
I heard if a man gets hit again,
he'll come back to his senses.
-Yeah, I heard the same thing.
-My uncle...
...hit my dad right on the brain.
And hit him again to finish him off.
But pop, instead of going down, snaps back
and drops my uncle - his brother.
Why don't you give it a try.
Sorry, old buddy, but maybe stinky is right.
-Well, it does not always work.
-Yeah, I heard the same thing, exactly.
-Well, it's been nice, and thanks.
-Yeah, for your horse...
Your horse... turkey-rustler.
I ain't got no objection,
as long as he don't mind...
What do you say?
He says: "No".
-I guess now we're supposed to shoot it out?
-Yeah, that's right sonny.
-Boss, do you mind if I take care of him?
-No, he's all yours, but just hurt him...
Finish him off, will you? The beans are done.
Drop the beans... um, gun-belts.
Now sit down and cool off.
Tasty.
-You ain't gonna kill us in cold blood?
-To tell you frankly, I don't know.
I'm new at this sort of thing.
What do you usually do in a case like this?
If I were you I'd forget the whole thing.
We were just joking.
But you ain't me...
You guys fight it out, and the one who
remains on his feet will be spared...
Go on, go to it boys.
Hey, watch out!
Tell me, boy, what did you just tell me
about your brother a while ago?
If I ever again get my hands on that idiot...
If I catch him again...
Who is a pain in the neck did you say?
- Who would it be? Joe, your little darling.
What has he done now?
- Well then, listen good.
A few days ago the boy pinched
a herd of horses.
Then "tired joe" is showing up...
...and couldn't think of anything better than
to give away the horses to starvelings.
If I were you, I would have reported him
to the cops immediately.
He should have reported his
very own brother to the cops?
That was a mess.
-Come on, come on.
Where?
-Hurry up, the water is hot.
Let's see if we can't get
that dirt crust off.
Wake up from your delirium and go fetch
me some buckets of water.
Yes, yes, all right.
Will you get up, you lazy bastard?
Drinking and sleeping the whole day!
Hurry up with that rinse water!
Lousy wench throwing you on the ground
like that... Poor you.
Not even for you this fury is considerate.
-Pearl, come here!
-What the hell is it now?
-There is something going on!
-Not with you anyway...
I bathe Bambino. If he get up now,
he won't get up until the next spring.
-What's the matter now? Have another attack?
-Breathe in the breeze...
Trinity!
-So you're back!
-We thought the vultures ate you.
-Why didn't you write to mom?
-Because I can't write and you can't read.
I have a surprise for you.
Hey Bambino, tell me if this ain't the most
prettiest sight you ever seen?
Hi!
Ain't you glad to see your own brother?
Bambino is right. This blasted coyote
gave away a whole herd of horses.
Set the table and shut up.
- And you my little lamb, wash up.
-Are you leaving right away?
-If you're staying, yes.
Hey, listen, if I were you,
I'd drown him right there in that tub.
Hey, you're ain't gonna take the old geezer
up on that, are you?
-Mom...
-Allright, peace to men of good will.
So cut it out for a while, it's time to eat.
Look what a beauty!
-What is it?
-Don't know, it few around here yesterday.
-It looks like an eagle.
-It might be... First, we'll pray.
There she goes again with the religion!
Always trying to break a guy's...
Dear lady up in heaven...
You were a mother, and you
had also a son who gave you worries.
So you can understand when I ask you
to look after my sons. Amen.
-I said "amen", you womits!
-Amen.
Let's drink, boys.
-Down in the throat, and may the Lord...
-He's probably eating right now, like us.
He better protect us.
Give me back my bird!
Boys, did you ever feel like
settling down around here?
-To do what?
-Work?
No. But you can of course get married.
There are some beauties in the saloon -
-who really wants a husband.
-And they make the best wives!
You should have seen your mother the day we
got married. But you were too young to-
-remember, and you were still crawling.
But we had a wild party in that saloon!
And I can still see her now.
She had a red velvet dress -
-with her frontals sticking out.
She was just as happy as a vulture
just before a hanging.
After you stop chasing the lice around,
how about getting us another bottle?
-We got visitors.
-How many?
-Four.
-Anyone a sheriff?
-Nope.
-What do they look like?
-Can't tell, they got their faces covered.
-You take good care of them, dear?
Look who's here... !
Small world, ain't it.
Yeah, and a little overcrowded...
Drop your guns.
You too...
OK, outside.
Wait a minute, dear...
-Allright, you can go.
-Come on, move!
-He is a little...
-Yeah, he's a little back, yes.
If you open your mouth wide,
I'll fill it up with buckshot!
-Here, choke.
-Thank you, love.
Boys, old drivel over here wants to talk to
you. But don't contradict him, he's shaky.
-Did he eat too fast?
-No, it's the usual attack...
Boys, the odds are pretty good that my
generous old heart will stop ticking soon.
But before I go, I want to make sure that
there's a pretty high price on your heads.
You worry me, my son.
For years now, you've been dragging your ass...
...and you still got no trade.
You can cardshap I hear -
-but I've never seen you play.
I advise you to become a horse-rustler.
You don't become a good
horse-thief over a night, you know!
Look at Bambino here...
He's on the right track.
Even though he has a lot to learn,
he'll make a great horse-thief some day.
And boys, promise me that from now on,
you'll always work together.
What?
Look after your brother.
He is young and green still. Protect him -
-as if he was your... own brother.
-I've got to protect me from him!
Let him go away in peace.
Allright, I'll protect him.
But then he must obey me.
-And please leave your damn sledge here!
-Well, if you aren't pleased by it...
No, it does not please me!
Keep an eye on him.
He's just a baby with a foot in his mouth.
Peral, this calls for another whiskey... two!
Bring the bottle. You don't want any, right?
I do.
-Can't you sit on the saddle normally?
-I get tired that way. Where are we headed?
-North.
-Why north?
Because I say so.
I got the right to know, don't I?
-No, you don't!
-Either do what I tell you, or I'll dump you.
-Where would you dump me?
Wake up - there's a little work ahead.
-Cover up.
-Why?
Rule number 1: When you rob a wagon, you'll
cover you face. So no one recognizes you.
I can't get enough leverage...
Hurry, get in the cart!
Stay right where you are!
Nobody make a move! Get 'em up!
What the hell are you shooting at?
-I'm warning you mister.
-If he lifts his hand, he'll drop the kid.
-Hand over your gold!
-The only wealth we got is the kid.
-We came west, looking for work.
-I got a good mind to plug you for that!
Howdy.
-I said "howdy".
-Howdy. Are you an outlaw?
-Well, under the circumstances, I guess so.
-But we got nothing, we're just farmers.
Oh, oh, sorry about that.
-Hey, hurry up in there!
-Bye now, just sit tight and don't worry.
-You're coming? What did you find?
-An old lady, a few rag and some stale bread.
We've been sitting here for three days now,
and Fred here got a sour stomach.
-Yeah, I see what you mean.
-We got to get into town and see a doctor.
-Then you got money after all, you coyote!
-We'll sell the wagon, maybe...
That's ridiculous.
-Hurry up!
-Hang on, don't forget the lady inside.
That wasn't so hard, was it.
Don't forget to grease the wheel.
Give them some money...
-Much obliged. If everyone was as generous...
-...you'd let yourself be robbed forever.
Get a move on!
Strangest pair of outlaws I ever seen.
-So far so good, huh?
-Even better if you'll look there.
But a little worse if you look here...
First of all, try not to catch his eye.
Keep an eye on them. They're up to no good.
Welcome to Tascosa boys,
where the West really begins.
-It's the right place to get a job.
-Just worry about the horse.
I need to find a gunsmith.
Take a look around in the town.
So if your hand take the itching,
just scratch it...
-God bless you, brothers.
-Thanks, old-timer. See you at the saloon.
I didn't ask for a drink.
Hey, bartender, give me a drink.
-You like to play, huh?
-No, not now. I'm tired now.
-It's a pretty quiet town, isn't it?
-Say that again, and you'll break the spell.
Why?
Because Wildcard Hendricks is in town,
and it don't take much to set him off.
-Wildcard, who's he?
-He's a cardsharp, a professional.
He's shifty,
but don't tell him that, he's very touchy.
You can watch him play at the saloon,
but be careful not to stare him in the eye.
Mister, aren't you getting you gun?
Where are you going?
You know who that is?
Wildcard Hendricks - a pro.
So what, are you afraid of him, maybe?
You got a couple of bills?
Now you're talkin' brother...
I like to be able to tell people that
Wildcard Hendricks played with me.
Can we play in five?
High card deals, doesn't it?
No cut.
-I pass.
-I open for 30...
Let's see your openers, friend...
Allright, how about we cut the pack, huh?
-Opening for 10.
-Let's make it 50...
100, if you wanna stay in.
Two...
-Two for me.
-Serve yourself...
100...
If you don't mind... 200.
I say you've been cheating...
-You think so?
-I think so.
The drinks are on me, boy.
When the lead hits you, it'll hurt less
with a little whiskey in your gut.
Oh yeah, give the gentleman a double,
that way you won't feel a thing.
Get going.
You like to see that again?
It's hard to catch the first time.
Cut it out...
Did you get it?
-So you think it's going to end here, huh?
-Yeah, I think so...
I'll get back at you!
Well brother, it's a good start.
Hey, how much did we win?
You mean how much did I win - you lost.
Allright, you know my share.
-Just what this town needs.
-See you. -See you.
Mr. Parker!
Yes?
Over in the saloon are two tough guys,
you should hire them.
It's nice of you to put my attention
to it, Stevens,
but I am sufficiently supplied.
Furthermore, I expect a couple of
skilled gunmen from Denver soon.
Of course, Mr. Parker.
You are the boss.
Yes, Stevens, this time you're right.
-Goodbye, sir. Thank you.
-Bye.
Holy god!
Holy god...
Howdy!
I said "howdy".
You talking to me?
We wanted to thank you...
for having robbed us. Oh, I mean helped us!
-Well, that wasn't exactly a robbery...
-I could tell you weren't real outlaws.
-We were on a special mission.
-Oh, you are federal agents?
Yes and no.
It's not exactly federal, but...
If your pop is looking for work,
this is the place.
But it ain't no place for us farmers.
I think we'll moving on to San José.
San José is a great place!
Where the west... really nice.
If he'll get worse, then don't hesitate
to bring him to me.
Goodbye now, miss. And good luck...
No wait, I would like my folks to know
that you are no real outlaws.
-Mom, pop, this here is the fellow...
-Of course, he's the gentleman who helped us.
-We are much obliged to you, mister...
-He's a federal agent.
There's some mighty bad business going on,
and the government wants to fix it.
Don't tell the captain what I told you about us.
-Did they rat on us?
-We know how to keep a secret.
-Hm, good for you. And how's little windy?
-The doctor said it's nothing to worry about, only...
-...a little airofogy.
-Oh, it's that what they call it in these parts?
The kid is really suffering.
A couple of whiskeys will fix him up fine.
-If everyone was as generous as you...
-...the kid would be an alcoholic.
I heard it's the fanciest place
until Frisco...
-I'm sorry gentlemen, you have to be members.
-What do you think we are?
There ain't no mistaking a lawman, huh...
This way, please.
There they are now...
-Well?
-Well, what sir?
-Bring us some food.
-Perhaps the gentlemen would like to begin...
-Right, we'd like to begin.
-May I suggest...
-No, you may not! Just bring us some food.
Wine for the gentlemen...
-Sooner or later the goverment will...
-Curiosity killed a lot more than cats.
You don't go killing federal agents.
You buy them.
And I never met one that wasn't up for sale.
You'll pull that again, and you'll had it.
That was a bit exaggerating.
Even their worst enemy has to admit...
that they're good at their job.
If until now we were only suspicious
that they are secret agents...
...now they've proven us.
Chasse á la Magdalen, petite oignons,
marrons glaces, pommes de terre...
-I hope it is to your liking, gentlemen.
-So what's so funny, huh?
Voilà...
i voilà.
It looks like it's going to be even easier
than I thought, right gentlemen?!
Chateaux neuve de pape.
A very special wine.
Clara, don't do that.
You're flirting with them, stop it!
They're ruminating like cows.
Outrageous...
-Would the gentlemen top the meal with...
-Wanna top it? -Yeah. -We'll top it.
George!
-Cointreau, Curacau, Grand Marnier?
-Well, how about it?
-If it suits you...
-It suits me fine.
-I saw him firing that up!
-But that's flambé suzettes!
Voila!
I'll have a little talk with them,
first thing in the morning.
Here they are now...
-Howdy, mister...
-James Parker. Mr Lopert.
-Sir, I'd like you to meet captain...
-That's a mighty fine looking animal.
-I imagine that you're an expert.
-Huh?
I imagine, being quick as you are, you have
already guessed the reason for this meeting.
I'd like to ask of a rather simple
favor of you captain.
All you have to do is close an eye...
May I, captain?
-And while we close an eye, you...
Exactly.
Even if the captain does close an eye,
he sees with the other.
2000 dollars should close them both, huh?
And two times two makes four...
You don't wanna leave my eyes open, do you?
Allright 4000. I was dead certain that we'd
come to a friendly agreement.
The government never was very generous
with its secret agents.
-The matter ends here, of course.
-Of course.
-It's been a real pleasure gentlemen.
-I hope to see you soon again.
Murdoch, must you always make such a inferno?
You hardly need to practice.
Murdoch said he would prefered to
close your eyes a little differently.
He may be right, Mr Parker. But sometimes
it's better to figure the odds first...
-You're right lieutenant.
-Heading back to Tascosa?
-To San José.
-There's nothing there that could interest-
-the government.
-Yeah, especially when your eyes are closed.
Warn our guys down at San José.
Leave me alone, and go to hell.
Hjälp oss - vi är också amerikaner.
I don't know about that!
Vamos!
-I think that he's a harsh sheriff.
-Double it...
Senjores, welcome to San José!
I'll take your horses to the stable.
-You'll be plenty satisfied.
-If that eye is a sign of customer-
-satisfaction, you better leave them here.
-No, senjor, it's not because if the horse.
-The guns... No hardware allowed in here.
-You thinked this up by yourself?
Noj, but it's a good idea anyway.
That's the law in this town.
And don't forget it, if you don't wanna get
bounched out before you can drink.
You're always in such a good mood?
No...
Sometimes it's worse.
That's the two federals that they
warned us about...
-Quite a collection, huh?
-Anybody you know?
-The guy talkin' is Reap Smith, the rustler.
-Is he good?
-The one in the middle is Lenny Smith, robber.
-And the other one?
That's Stingaree Smith. gunslinger,
bountykiller - a rough guy.
So relax.
One of those riders who passed us coming
to town is pointing at you and laughing.
You seem to strike his funny-bone, it's
the third time he looks at you and laughs.
-I suppose you let me in on the joke?
-Well now, how are you two doing?
-Hey, he put his hand on you.
-If you do that again...
-...we'll flat the whole bunch of you.
-You don't mind showing us how you'll do it?
What a rotten bunch...
Is he coming with us?
I'll be seeing you.
I bet they all got a price on their heads.
Are you crazy or something?
I told you not to show up in town.
-Howdy sheriff.
-What can I do for you?
To begin with, you can start giving us $800
for this merchandise!
-Certainly. Where did you nail them?
-In town.
-Lock 'em, sheriff.
-Oh yeah, sure.
Lets get a move on!
You too...
Just get in there and shut up!
They don't seem to know
who they're dealing with...
Sign here.
-That's an even $500.
-Fair enough, so long sheriff.
Oh, I almost forgot...
Regards from Mr Parker.
-Hey wait, then you're the two?
-Yeah, that's us.
-Well, what do I do with them?
-They work for Parker too, don't they?
-So does everybody else in San José.
-So what's the problem?
I don't suppose there's any reason
to keep them locked up, is there?
Let them cool off for a couple of days, then
let them tie you up and hit you on the head.
And put a price of $500 on their heads,
alive if you like...
You know that Parker doesn't want anybody
hanging around the mission?
Oh, sure we do.
Would you mind telling what we're doing here
like a couple of horsethieves?
We are a couple of horsethieves.
At least I'm trying to teach you to be one...
Do we wait for horses to come to us?
Let's go down to the mission instead.
-Something tells me that...
-Hush!
There must be at least 30 of them.
Wanna make a bet I'm right?
Move!
Pig-headed mules...
-Looks like their wagon is acting up again.
-Yeah, just for a change...
-We'll give them a hand?
-No.
-We're stuck if no miracle don't happens.
-It happens pop!
-We thought you might need a hand.
-They just stopped, these critters...
Ain't nothing to it, miss.
Hang on tight on my arm.
-We're going to take off like lightning.
-It's getting late, lieutenant.
They're just as stubborn as... a mule!
Now we can go.
-What you whispered sure worked.
-Are you moving out now, right away?
We'll camp here for the night. Why don't you
join us? My daughter is a mighty good cook.
Wow, she's also a good cook?
You know, you're a very good cook,
I've never eat boiled beans so... boiled.
-The stars are sparkling just like diamonds.
-Yeah, especially the big ones.
That's right, I've never thought about that.
You federal agents don't miss anything.
And do you know that rivers always flow
in the same direction?
And did you know that you and me...
-Where are you headed?
-North.
-We're headed north.
-It's nice up there.
I'll come up and visit if you like.
Oh, no, lieutenant...
Hey, lieutenant!
-You federal agents work at night too?
-Yeah, just like horsethieves.
Well, here they come now...
-Lieutenant, you've forgot we're on duty?
-Aren't we allowed to do some exceptions?
-Is that an order?
-Yeah, it's an order.
Mam, miss, it's been a pleasure...
-Hi young fellow. Heads up now.
-He seems better now.
-He's really sick.
Buy a barrel of whiskey,
that'll cure him.
-If everyone was as generous as you...
-...you'd be millionaires.
Nice boys.
-There's one leavnig for Chihuahua tomorrow.
-No, that's filled with starving peons.
-San Antonio and Houston is better.
-Where do you plan to do the hold up, river?
We ain't back in pops days.
The best place to rob a wagon-
-is near the poststation, when the passengers
are stretchy, and the cabby is off-guard.
Well, what are you looking at?
You come for the monks?
The ones by the mission...
I came to confess, and the monk
gave me a black-eye.
Once the monks were saints,
but now they're devils.
-They drink and swear. And when we confess...
-They hit you?
-We'll see about the monks.
-Really? Muchos gracias.
This business that bad monks beats up peons
bothers you, don't it?
-No, so if you think that I...
-No, I didn't think that at all...
It's just that Parker paid us 4000 to close
our eyes and the sheriff wants us-
-to stay clear of a bunch of drunken monks...
So, something stinks here.
-May the Lord be with you...
-Why?
Welcome.
When a brother knocks at our door, we greet
him by saing: "May the Lord be with you".
And he should answer: "And with your spirit."
-Now I get you, "And with your spirit."...
-Ain't you got a spirit?
-Oh, "And with my spirit."
-See if we can get them to talk, Bambino.
-Don't worry. And don't call me Bambino.
Ugly bunch...
Who's the boss here?
Let us say that I'm the shepard here.
What can we do for you?
Let us say that this pilgrim here
wants to get himself confessed...
...and this traveller wants to rest.
The traveller shall be restored,
and the pilgrim cleansed of sin.
Come with me, brother.
Don't tell me you're just drinking water?
Sure, is there anything better?
-Whiskey, for example.
And how about a game of dice,
what do you think about that?
Dice, brother?
-Yes, you've never heard of it?
And women are also frowned upon here?
I do not understand you, my son.
Don't play innocent...
It's better if you speak to the prior.
No. The prior is very busy at the moment.
Hey, what're you doing?
-Allright, were are you going?
-In the confession.
-They should've made the darn place bigger.
-This is my place, you'll be outside.
-I got to neel down?
-You may sit, if neeling bothers you.
-It's the first time, isn't it?
-Yeah, and the last...
-Tell me, my son...
-What?
-Well, aren't you here to confess?
-Yeah, among other things.
To see if you can absolve me too.
First you must confess,
then I'll absolve you.
Hey, I'm warning you, friend!
No ratting on me, huh?
No, no. Aside from myself,
only He shall know.
No, either it's between you and me,
or nothing to it!
-Very well. Begin my son.
-Begin what?
-To confess.
-Oh...
Go on, my son.
And when I was 12, my old man took me in
with him and his gang of rustlers.
And one of the boys got killed.
We pulled off a lot of neat jobs.
-That's enough, I beg you.
-Yeah, and now what?
-You must do penance, and be sincerely sorry.
-Yeah, allright, I'm sorry.
-Now, absolve me. If you got the guts.
-I don't understand...
-Come on. Absolve me!
-Certainly, certainly. I'll absolve you
Why you, I'll teach you for going around
and absolving people!
-Take it easy! Come on, what happened?
-He started off by talking to himself-
-and then really sneaky went with the right!
-I only wanted to bless you, brother.
There's something wrong with this mission.
Why did you beat up the peons?
It's not we who do the beating up -
it is Lucifer.
-You know him?
-No, never heard of him...
-Sounds like a professional from back east.
-Well, if this Lucifer shows up-
-tell him to go to hell.
-May the Lord be with you sir...
Lord, deliver us from the hands of evil.
In nomine Padre, et...
Come on, hurry up.
Piss off and don't show up here for a while.
Bring on the reward.
-Worked out fine, eh?
You really know your stuff.
Are all of Parker's guys that dumb?
More or less.
Ok, now I have had enough
of your silly laugh.
It's 2000 dollars, right?
What's your name?
-Mitch.
Okay, here's your share, Mitch.
Plus 200 for the bump in the head.
Say "thank you".
-Thanks, buddy!
Stupid traitor!
Maddock will give you what you deserve!
You nasty bastard!
He'll send you to hell for that!
Bastard!
So, what's up on the mission?
-I've no idea.
I only take care of things here
in this town, that's it, I swear.
Will you be paid for by Parker for that?
-Yes.
What do you know about the mission?
-Nothing.
They get their money for killing people.
If they succeed, you mean?
-Yes.
Farewell and bon voyage.
-Thanks.
We still see each other?
-Sure.
Brave man.
Hey, look...
-Well now, what a nice surprise.
-We were just saying the same thing.
-I thought you were heading north?
-I was, but I got a letter to a mister...
...Stingaree Smith.
Good old Stingaree? A friend of ours.
He's out of town right now.
-We can give it to him when he come back.
-Who do we tell it its from?
Murdoch. Yes, brother Murdoch.
A monk we ran into a couple a days ago.
He also told us that Mr Stingaree should
not forget to set up his scarecrows.
Fine, we'll tell him.
By the way, how's the family?
-They're fine down at the mission.
-The mission?
Yes, those lonely monks had a nice time
feeding our little Fred.
You better get back. Their gruel may
unsettle little Fred's stomach.
-Well, goodbye then, and thanks again.
-Goodbye.
-Now we can worry about that stage.
-How about going to the mission?
No, you're riding to the postalstation at
Apache Springs.
-That's where you got to hold up that stage.
-Now? That's 20 miles from here!
Son of a buzzard.
That's for the little ones.
This potion will do him good.
It'll cure his suffering.
Brother Clementino knows all secrets
of the herbs.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry that we can't accommodate
you in our house...
but the rule of our order
strictly forbids it.
We have to live in seclusion.
We sleep in our wagon, we're used to that.
Good night, my friends.
Sleep well. Quietude.
Good night.
Good night, darling.
Jag är inte trött.
Jag kan väl få vara uppe lite till?
-Hi!
-What are you doing there?
-What am I doing here? I'm on duty.
-On the wall?
-Captain ordered me-
-to keep an eye on this wall, so...
Wait there...
I was on duty on the wall, but...
Bring your bottle to your room.
We close at midnight.
What... are you doing?
-Where's the sheriff?
-He disappeared. Over a week ago.
-Do you know were Stingaree Smith is?
-In jail.
-Who put him in?
-The sheriff, I guess.
-What time is it?
-Exactly 10 o'clock.
-They're probably still in town.
-What are you gonna do?
-Take care of them two federals!
-I wouldn't push my luck with them...
They are no more federal agents than I am,
they're a couple of fast drawing pro's.
Parker got another shipment for Gonzales!
Back, march march!
This time you've been lucky, but...
-Shut up!
-Do you love me?
-You said it...
-Are you gonna settle here?
-We're hoping to, there's good land and all.
The prior was willing to give us an old
farmhouse, but the bishop wouldn't let him.
-Maybe because we're protestants.
-What are you, lutheran or baptist?
-Is that so important?
No, I do not care which.
But my father and mother, you know...
Ok, I see, but you know...
In the secret service we're not allowed
to talk about private things.
But we...
Open up!
-We'll break the gate!
Run into the carriage. Hurry up.
It's me. Gonzales is here!
Oh, no, they're back again...
Hurry up brothers, come out!
-May the Lord be with...
-Gonzales and his men!
-It's almost full.
Vamos, let's go to work!
Hey, you can pray later, now you work!
Here... it's 50 000 dollars brother.
Be careful - or señor Parker
will give you his blessing.
Every monk who is a monk, hands up!
Every monk who is a monk,
punch a monk who isn't a monk.
Hands up!
Stay there, and don't move.
This is the last time you sneak guns
across the border, right?
And don't you forget it.
-You almost killed him.
-No, I just hurt him, so I'll find out more.
-But maybe you'll explain why they're here.
-Lieutenant, what happened?
-Lieutenant?
-Yeah, a federal lieutenant.
Heaven protect us from Parker's wrath.
Even the mexican bandits are out-
-to get us now... Parker sells arms and ammo
to bandits-
-across the border. And he's uses our mission
as a tradingpost... and as a bank too.
-I have to keep this, as evidence.
-If Murdoch doesn't find the money-
-there's no telling what he'll do.
-He won't do a thing-
-not with me and my captain around.
-But they're a gang of cutthroats!
And you think one horde is enough to scare
two federal agents?
Hey...
-Have you seen Stingaree Smiths and his boys?
-They're in jail.
The sheriff came back, slap them
into jail and rode off again.
-Well, good night senjor.
-What time is it?
It's about 10 o'clock...
Get the keys.
-So lets get moving.
You may have the upper hand now,
but when we get out of here...
Where the heck have you been?
-It took you so long time to come back?
-40 miles in two hours isn't too bad.
-How do things look?
-Mighty sad...
For the stage, not for us though.
Allright, once more now...
I don't want no slip-ups.
When the stage pulls in...
at the Apache Springs poststation...
I'm going to the stage and hold you up,
You go for your gun, I shoot wide,
I ride with you on my tail,
and we split the loot.
Well, here we go.
This is your first stage, isn't it?
Just relax and everything will go smooth.
God, you don't think there will be any
trouble, do you? I am so afraid.
-Don't worry, Agnes - I'm here.
-No one with his right mind would attack-
-a stage, when the drivers are rested.
Believe me, no one is gonna stop us now.
Hold your horses!
Everybody out, on the double!
Let's go fatso. Get a move on!
You thought I wouldn't do it, huh?
A little ventilation is good for you brain,
huh, gunslinger?
Allright, drop your belt.
And now you can hand over the money.
1000 dollars more...
Fork it over, before it's too late.
Oh, don't bother, thanks anyway.
I got to be going now. Mam...
See you around.
-Ain't he the weirdest now...
-Come on, Agnes.
We're all in one piece.
-No one would attack us right outside town?
-I'm sorry, father.
-It's nothing, it happens to the best of us.
Someone is coming!
-It could be someone who come to confess.
-I kind of doubt that.
-May the good Lord...
-Put a bullet between your eyes!
I won't kill you here on the spot, because
mom says that maybe you're my brother.
-You fork over my share, or you'll die!
-You thought I was out to rob you?
I wanted to show I learned robbing from you.
You may be heads-up, but I'm ain't sleeping.
I wanted to go to the mission and lay my
hands on that bunch of money.
-Bunch of money, huh? Where's the money?
-Right there in the mission.
Parker was forcing those poor monks there...
-What do you say to that?
-Let's see the money.
-I thank you for coming, captain.
-It's my duty, where's the money?
-Money.
-Go and fetch the root of all evil...
Hurry up, Clem.
-You know, they're farmers.
-They're nice though...
Here's the root of all evil...
-Isn't that terrible, captain?
-Yeah, it's dreadful.
Lieutenant, you go get things organized,
while I take the cargo down to headquarters.
Maybe it's better if I go, sir?
-No, I prefer that we handle it together.
-Yeah, later...
-In the meantime, get your guns.
-What guns, captain?
Ain't that something, they don't carry guns.
Father, father... they're coming!
-Keep calm, brothers!
-Get the gate closed and try to gain time.
Halt!
Now, where's that fool going?
Open up!
Open up, I said!
This is the Lords house, brothers!
Come in peace, and he shall enter.
He sure is nagging...
Allright, off with your guns.
You think you're invulnerable
behind those robes?
It seems you haven't limited yourself to
preaching, but shot my clients with buckshot?
Murdoch... Pick up the money,
and blow up this barn.
-Blow up the barn...?
-Quiet you old fool!
There isn't a nickel in this whole well,
Mr Parker.
The money. Well, you're asking for it...
- Murdoch, it's all yours!
Allright, lets move it.
I said get out of the... !
Now you move it, over there with the others.
-You again?
-Yeah, us.
Drop 'em, or she's dead!
It looks like the show is over, huh.
Allright, hold it...
Well done, Murdoch. One moment...
First a little detail worth 50 000...
Nice work, boys.
Where are you going, you fool?
Hey, boys!
-Do you have any use for this?
-I don't know, ask them.
You have any use for this?
-Hold it!
I said, hold it!
-It's empty...
-Go to it.
That money is mine!
Let us throw the moneychangers
out of the tempel!
Go on!
It's locked, my friend.
Your guardian-angel wants you
to stand over here.
Violence lacks strength when reason
can prevail.
You meddling fool!
Why all this violence?
-Just like I said, there were nothing to it.
-Yeah, but I'll take that. So long...
Stay right where you are, all of you!
Get the monks to one side.
I never thought they'd get here.
-Did you sent a monk to fetch the rangers?
-Are you out of your mind.
I did, I didn't expect you would arrive
in time.
-Did I do wrong?
-No, not at all.
Our guardian-angels here, sir.
Without them, all would have been lost.
-Captain, ain't it time we go back to HQ.
-Right you are, lieutenant.
You know, for a while I mistook you for a
horse-thief we've been hunting for a while.
It ain't the first time that happened,
huh, captain?!
Sir, here's 50 000 of Parker's bloodmoney.
Take it to the judge.
You got the most amazing likeness.
Listen, the captain got this for capturing
five of Parker's boys.
I guess they're yours, according to the law.
Amazing likeness...
-Our salary is pay enough.
-The government can be very proud of you two.
I hope you're satisfied now. All the money
lost, just because a ranger recognized you.
The fact is, you can't be trusted.
And thet's the truth.
Oh, no.
Subtitle by AntiJw