McDonald!
War party out. Ulzana's gone out.
Ulzana and some others
are out on a raid!
Ulzana...
Corporal! Get that horse.
Walk him around!
All hell's going to break loose!
Ulzana's going out.
No, I'm not at all anxious to send
a large force after Ulzana
and an unknown number of warriors.
It's embarrassing when the Indian
agent has to guess how many went out.
It can't be large party, sir.
They may just trail south to Mexico.
Come in!
Mclntosh is here, sir.
- Send him in.
Morning, Mclntosh.
- Morning, Major.
We had a break at the reservation.
- I heard Ulzana's gone.
His name was mentioned.
- How many more?
Mr. Steegmeyer was uncertain.
He thought maybe 6 or 7.
Hardly a war party.
Coffee hot?
- Help yourself.
Apache war parties come in all sizes.
There's the kind with 100 braves,
and the kind with one.
Has Major posted the homesteaders?
- As stated in garrison regulations.
How many riders?
- Two.
One riding the north loop,
the other the west.
And how many mounts?
- Captain Gates saw to the details.
How many horses
did you give them, Charlie?
One mount each, as specified...
- In garrison regulations.
I know.
Who did you send?
- Mulkearn and Horowitz.
A recruit? - He was duty gallop.
- When did they go?
Ten o'clock. They should
be back by late afternoon.
Unless they bring
some of the homesteaders with them.
Their orders didn't specify escort.
- I see.
You'd better get up to the agency.
See if you can get more information.
Alright. How many troopers
is the major planning to pull out?
That's a decision I'll make when
I know the hostile force's strength.
And their probable intention.
Their probable intention is to burn,
maim, torture, rape and murder.
Tell Agent Steegmeyer, I want
to know who the guilty parties are.
They can't slink back
and escape the consequences again.
It'll take me a couple of hours.
By the time I get back,
and we go out on this trail,
Ulzana will have had over 4 hours.
I will not put a force in the field
in ignorance, Mr. Mclntosh.
I just want to be sure
we are going after them.
"Any band of hostiles
leaving a US Indian agency
will be pursued and apprehended."
What we have to determine
is how many of them there are,
and whether they are hostile.
Well, the first is open to question.
The second you can bet money on.
He's very forthright.
He's a willful, opinionated man
with a contempt for all discipline,
either moral or military.
He's a good scout
and he knows Apaches,
which I may freely confess,
is more than I do.
Will these two
tell us anything, Ke-Ni-Tay?
These two not like you.
He not listen to the words.
Old Nachito, he not like any man.
Ask them what they think of Ulzana.
Ask them, is he a great war chief?
Is he wiser than Nana?
Braver than Chato?
Is he more cruel than Victorio?
Ask them, does he make his wives
happy in the night?
Ask them what they think.
Ask them.
You must have been disappointed,
Lieutenant,
when your orders directed you
to Fort Lowell.
Oh no, sir,
I wanted to see active service.
Your father is a man of the cloth?
- Yes, sir.
Is he not a little troubled,
that your vocation differs
so radically from his?
Well sir, my father believes
one can be a Christian and a soldier.
Perhaps.
However, I doubt the Apache Indian
would see Jesus Christ as a leader.
Well sir, my father believes
that it's a lack of Christian feeling
towards the Indian that's
the root of our problems with them.
From a pulpit in Philadelphia,
that's an easy mistake to make.
Sir, I think if they had a chance...
- Lieutenant.
You will take this patrol
in place of Captain Gates.
Sir?
You may have the chance to test
some of your father's theories.
Thank you very much, sir.
Don't thank me.
I'm not giving you a present.
You will leave as soon as
Mr. Mclntosh returns. - Yes, sir.
You know what General Sheridan said
of this country, Lieutenant?
No, sir. - He said,
if he owned Hell and Arizona,
he'd live in Hell
and rent out Arizona.
I think he said that about Texas, sir.
Maybe. But he meant Arizona.
Yes, sir.
They're finished.
Half of what they say is lies,
the other half ain't true.
Tell them
they speak like true Apaches.
And that I'm glad they didn't go out.
Tell them I'll speak
to the major about the beef.
What about it, Mclntosh?
The old man tell you anything?
Old man told me they're getting
short weight on beef, Dutch.
What Indian you know wouldn't?
Check my scales any time.
And I'm not Dutch!
Well, you look Dutch to me.
I don't give a damn for your scales.
I'm just saying the ones left behind
are wondering if they should have
gone too. - What am I meant to do?
Give them extra rations?
Just don't water the beef
before you weigh them.
You'd be surprised how many steaks
are in 2 gallons of river water.
Listen, Mclntosh.
Don't tell me how to run my business!
This is my store, not yours!
Please! Please God!
Please help!
In the name of God! Spare me, please!
Spare me!
We'll come out right behind you.
Will they send somebody to meet us?
I can't say about that, mister.
I was only told to raise the alarm.
I got 3 kids and a pregnant wife.
I need somebody to bring me in.
Don't anybody care
what happens to us?
I'm sure they do,
they just don't have enough men.
I've got to get going.
I've got another holding to raise.
Good luck to you, Mr. Ginsford.
- Good luck, trooper.
Now, now, Abbie.
Not so the girls notice.
Get yourselves ready.
We're going to the Fort to see
if any packages have come for us.
Get yourselves dressed.
Come on!
Come on girls, get yourselves ready.
We're going to the Fort now to see
if any packages have come for us.
Better get the rest
of our things together, son.
Any sign of the gallopers?
No, they're coming in
with the homesteaders, I guess.
I guess.
You will follow the hostiles until
A, they are defeated,
killed, or captured, or
B, they return to the reservation
whereupon you will arrest them, or
C, they cross the international line
into Mexico where the mission ceases.
Clear, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
- Have any questions? - No, sir.
Very well. Carry on.
Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Mclntosh rides with you
in an advisory capacity. - Yes, sir.
Concerning the trailing of hostiles
and information on the terrain,
you'd be well advised
to heed his advice.
However, in matters purely military,
never forget you command this detail.
Of course, sir. Thank you, sir.
So, Harry.
You're eager to be off, I suppose?
- Yes, sir.
I strongly advised Major Cartwright
to give you this command.
Thank you, Captain.
- No need to thank me, Harry.
Prepare to mount! Mount!
- Good luck, Lieutenant.
Turn to the left.
Forward! At a walk!
Turn right!
Steady!
It's not for me to tell you,
but it'd be better if you came back
with us. It'd give us two guns.
Yeah, yeah. And when I came back,
what would be left, huh?
I got stock and I got crops.
And I ain't leaving them
for no drunk fellow to burn down.
Then I got nothing,
like when I'm fresh landed.
Look out on that!
That be a good farm some day.
And I don't leave that
for no drunk fellow, no sir.
Billy! Get on with your mama.
Go on. Go on!
Gee, Pa, can't I stay?
Do like I tell you.
Get up! Go on, get up!
You take care of your mama, right?
I wish you luck, Mr. Rukeyser.
Thank you.
You look to yourself, Willy!
I, er...
I get to that door fixing,
so you don't curse them so much.
Hup! Hup! Get going there!
Have a good trip now.
Say hello to the fellows at the Fort.
Here, Jeff!
Come on!
That's my boy.
That's my good boy.
Wouldn't it have been simpler to pick
up the trail at the reservation?
There's all ways of
doing things, sir, I guess.
They caught trail there, sir!
Stand by to dismount!
Dismount!
- Dismount!
It's them alright.
Moving steady, but not fast.
How long ago? - Early this morning.
They're way up ahead.
The only thing that slows them down
is how much killing they do.
By their line of march,
which homesteads are likely to be hit?
If they trail south, they'll kill
whatever crosses their path.
Otherwise where they please.
Can we let them know
we're pressing them?
They know we're coming.
There's no sense to hurrying.
Mr. Mclntosh, I think hurrying
is exactly what we should do.
A horse will run so far, so fast,
for so long, and then he'll lie down.
An Apache puts a fire under his belly
and gets him back up on his feet.
When the horse dies, he gets off,
eats a bit of it and steals another.
I just don't like
to think of people unprotected.
Yes, well it's best not to.
Alright, Sergeant.
Forward at a walk!
Oh God!
Mama! Indians!
Soldier!
Don't leave me!
Thank you.
Get on!
Come on, boy, jump!
Ma! No!
Hey Jeff!
Hey boy!
I'll get you, close up!
Alright you drunk fellows,
you come after me.
I teetotal you pretty damn quick.
You hear me?
Ain't nice, cleaning up after Apaches.
- Why did they spare the boy?
Spare him what?
- Well, why didn't they kill him?
Just a whim, Lieutenant.
Apaches got lots of whims.
At least they didn't rape the woman.
She was already dead.
Ke-Ni-Tay reckons
Horowitz shot the woman
and fled with the boy.
When they got his horse,
he killed himself.
Good man, that Horowitz.
I'll have to send
a detail back with the boy.
What is Ulzana planning?
He's going on. A few men
will be safe as 20 going back.
A few men?
If we run into Ulzana, Lieutenant,
we'll need all the men we got.
Sergeant. - Sir.
- Send two men back with the wagon.
You got anybody particular in mind?
- No, you pick them.
Sir!
- Roberts,
Winfield, fall out!
Escort this wagon back to the Fort.
Move them out, Sergeant.
- Troops! Prepare to mount!
Mount!
Forward at a walk!
No.
They don't get in my house.
No drunk fellow getting me!
You won't get this farm away from me.
No you don't!
Nobody frightens Rukeyser.
Nobody!
No!
Alright, I'm ready for you!
Come on!
You hear me?
Come on, show your face!
God!
You take all the praise
and all the glory.
Halt! - Dismount them here.
- Prepare to dismount!
Dismount!
Is he in there?
No.
Mclntosh!
Oh my God!
Fire's about 2 hours,
maybe an hour and a half old.
They'd have watched him for a while.
They're close.
What's that in his mouth?
- A dog's tail.
Why?
- Apaches got a sense of humor.
Nothing you'd recognize.
They just find some things funny.
Suit me,
if I never saw another Apache again.
I was out after Nana in '81
with Lieutenant Gilpoil.
I was a corporal then.
We rode for 3 weeks. We never saw
one of those murdering bastards.
He's probably up
in them hills right now,
feeding on Rukseyer's dog
and thinking he's made a good start.
Tomorrow we're going to ride.
- Right. Good night Mclntosh.
Good night.
- Good night.
Post double pickets on the stock
and put pickets on perimeter guard.
Reveille at first light and prepare
to move out by half the hour.
Ke-Ni-Tay...
I want to ask you something.
- Alright, turn it off!
Let's get some sleep.
Why are your people like that?
Why are they so cruel?
Why?
It's how they are.
But why?
They have always been like that.
Are you like that?
Would you kill a man like that?
Yes.
Why?
To take the power.
Each man that die,
the man that kill him,
take his power.
Man give up his power
when he dies.
Like fire give heat.
Fire that burn a long time,
many can have heat.
You mean,
you torture a man for hours,
and you get power from watching
some poor creature suffering?
What kind of power is that?
Here in this land
man must have power.
You not know about power.
I want to know.
I want to understand.
Ulzana is a long time in the agency.
His power very thin.
Smells in his nose
are old smell of the agency.
Old smell.
Smell of woman,
smell of dog,
smell of children,
man with old smell in his nose,
is an old man.
Ulzana came for new smell.
Pony running,
the smell of burning,
the smell of bullet for power.
Soldier pack with a wagon, no power.
Woman, no power. No pleasure.
Why didn't they kill the boy?
Man cannot take power from boy.
Only from man.
Then Ulzana will want to kill many.
Many.
Do you hate Apaches, Mr. Mclntosh?
No.
Well, I do.
Well, it might not make
you happy, Lieutenant,
but it sure won't make you lonesome.
Most white folks here feel the same.
Why don't you feel that way?
Lt'd be like hating the desert
because there ain't no water on it.
It's enough
that I'm just plenty scared of them.
Troops, halt!
Ever eat dog, Lieutenant?
No, can't say I have.
- Tasty enough if you get it young.
Where do you think they're headed?
- Ke-Ni-Tay?
They'll go where it's hard to follow.
Where will they fight us?
- He don't mean to fight you nowhere.
He only means to kill you.
You know Ulzana?
His wife my wife's sister.
Sisters?
His wife ugly.
My wife not so ugly.
Detail, halt!
Damn him!
What's he up to, Ke-Ni-Tay?
Ulzana wants to make you run now.
He wants us to kill some horses.
You know how soldiers walk?
Apache walk better than soldiers.
Troops, at a walk!
Going to be like this
all the way, Sergeant?
Halt, troops! Halt!
How long?
- Sunrise or a little later.
Lieutenant, a horse apple dries out
at a certain rate.
This one's pretty solid.
Ke-Ni-Tay figures on four,
maybe five hours. - What do you think?
I ain't about to argue with no Apache
about horseshit. He's the expert.
Well, we're not gaining on him.
- Only way to gain is push
the horses till they get the staggers,
then catch up on foot.
Ulzana would like that just fine!
I sure don't want to be on foot
around any horse-backing Apaches!
Well, what's the point, Mr. Mclntosh,
if we can't close the gap?
Remember the rules, Lieutenant.
First one to make
a mistake gets to burying some people.
How long are you out from the East?
- East?
The academy.
- Oh, about six months.
Well, they'd sure all be proud
if they could see you now.
Alright, Sergeant. Bring them on.
- At a walk!
Halt!
What's wrong?
We got a problem, Lieutenant.
- What sort of a problem?
Well, Ke-Ni-Tay thinks
the horses are running without riders,
except for two.
A lead horse and an end horse.
You mean they're behind us?
- That's right. A way back.
Is he sure?
He's pretty sure.
Signs show ponies running light.
I suppose he'll try an ambush.
- No, I don't think so, Lieutenant.
He wants to get us into the hills.
Make us keep coming
while he circles round behind.
His ponies are going to be
a lot fresher than ours.
And if we go chasing them, there's
a good chance of becoming infantry.
But if we don't,
he gets ahead of us.
Either way, he's smiling.
Sounds like he has us.
- Well, like I said, Lieutenant,
first one to make a mistake
gets to digging in the ground.
What he's up to is pretty bright.
Just might be we can outfox him.
- How?
By getting to his horses
before he does.
That's us.
That's their horses.
Somewhere along that line,
they'll double back to pick up Ulzana.
Ulzana's here.
Question is,
did he drop off to the right,
or to the left?
The other question is,
how wide a circle are
those ponies making to the right,
or to the left,
on their way back to Ulzana.
- Can you pick up
their trail in the night?
- In broken country, no,
but with 9 ponies running straight,
it should be possible,
if the moon is up.
How shall we divide the troops?
Send me and a galloper that way and
Ke-Ti-Nay and a galloper this way.
Either one of us cut trail, we'll send
the galloper to pick you up.
Alright, you'd better get started.
Who do you want for gallopers?
No preference,
so long as they don't talk too much.
Pickets checked and at their posts.
- Good, Sergeant.
You impressed upon them
the need for constant alert?
I wouldn't figure that's necessary.
I reckon Rukeyser did that good.
That the Bible you're reading, sir?
- Yes.
A gift from my father
on my last trip home.
My father's a minister.
- So I heard tell, sir.
I wish I could ask him
about the Apache.
What, sir?
Why do they do these terrible things?
I mean,
after all, they are men
made in God's image like ourselves.
It seems to me that an eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth is the part
that matters to the Apache.
And that's the way to treat them.
- Well, Christ taught us another way.
Yes, he did, sir.
But Christ never fetched no
infant child out of a cactus tree
and then waited for two hours
until it died to bury it, did he?
No.
- I did.
Ain't nobody going to tell me to turn
the other cheek to no Apache, sir.
They crossed behind us.
You ride for the lieutenant,
bring him back to pick up the trail.
Tell him to come awful quick
and follow it all the way.
Right turn!
Morning, Lieutenant.
Glad you got here.
What happened?
- I caught up with their ponies.
How many were there?
- About 9. - Hostiles, I mean.
Two.
There's one of them, dead.
Other one's hit, though.
He laid up for a while
beyond that rise and then moved on.
Sergeant!
Check for signs behind that rise.
Hayle. Buckley. Follow me.
Troops! Prepare to dismount!
Dismount!
So they're on foot? - It's a good way
to describe men without horses.
We should pursue them immediately.
Ulzana's going to be tough to spot.
We'd better wait for Ke-Ni-Tay.
I thought you could follow
a trail as well as any Apache.
Well, you thought wrong, Lieutenant.
Mr. Mclntosh, I want to press on.
You're the one who gives the orders.
Just saying my say.
He was there, sir.
He's gone now. You hit him, alright.
Can you follow the trail, Sergeant?
I figure I could, sir,
unless he runs out of blood.
Okay, take one man and go after him.
We'll catch up with you.
Lieutenant! Ain't worth the trouble.
No chance of him getting to Ulzana.
He'll crawl away and die someplace.
He may not die.
I recall you saying that
Apache war parties come in all sizes,
some with 100 warriors, some with 1.
- So I did.
Since we have to wait for Ke-Ni-Tay,
I suggest we use the time well.
Sergeant!
Yes, sir.
Miller!
Yes, Sergeant!
- Fall out. You're with me.
Corporal! Post sentries.
- Yes, sir.
Sentries, out!
Now! Come on!
- Cut him!
Cut him!
- That's the way!
Cut it out!
Cut it clean out!
Dirty Apache dog!
What's going on?
He's got a trooper's side-gun, sir.
- It's Ulzana's son.
They cut up Horowitz pretty bad.
It spooks the Apaches
when they do this to their dead.
I want that boy buried,
you understand?
Bury him!
What's wrong, Lieutenant?
Is that Ulzana's son?
So I believe.
- So you believe.
Why wasn't I told
that Ulzana's son was one of them?
Would it have made a difference
if you'd known?
It might have made me feel
I was the officer in command.
That's fair enough, Lieutenant.
I was wrong not to mention it.
Well, killing I expect, Mr. Mclntosh,
but mutilation and torture,
I cannot accept that as readily as
you seem to be able to.
What bothers you, Lieutenant,
is you don't like to think
of white men behaving like Indians.
Kind of confuses the issue, don't it?
Rider coming in.
Ke-Ni-Tay and the galloper.
All we need is your hunting party.
We'll be on our ways.
Ke-Ni-Tay thinks Ulzana will head
for water and then try to find horses.
I might have made
those deductions myself.
We're a horse short, Lieutenant.
- Ke-Ni-Tay will give you his.
Apaches walk better
than soldiers, remember?
Corporal, take care of
Mr. Mclntosh's gear. - Yes, sir!
To the left! Forward walk!
I've got your horse.
Rider coming in, sir.
It's Sergeant Burns.
Detail halt!
Report, Sergeant.
Trooper Miller is dead from wounds,
sir.
And the hostile?
Dead,
sir.
I want a full report at next camp.
- There ain't a whole lot more, sir.
Not unless you want to know
how Miller felt about dying.
Bring them on, Corporal.
- Yes, sir.
Forward at a walk!
We had a trail, Lieutenant,
but it's gone.
Or nigh impossible
to follow on these rocks.
I want to catch up with him.
Horses are almost broken down.
They need rest and feed.
Ulzana needs horses.
There's hardly a dozen around here.
- Are you telling me we're winning?
I'm trying to tell you,
Ulzana can't lead a war party on foot.
He has to steal...
- More horses, I know.
Sergeant! Where's the next homestead?
The Riordans', sir. It's about
5 miles along those foothills.
They got good water.
Any horses?
They might have 1 or 2,
I don't know for sure.
Can this man be trusted to pick up
the trail if we leave him behind?
I trust him.
Right, we'll make for the homestead.
He can meet us there.
Sweet Jesus!
Leave that body where it is!
- It needs burying.
I want the Apache scout to do that.
- Damn it, you're not making sense!
Now look, Mr. Mclntosh. That used
to be a white man, like yourself.
A white man! I think
you're not making any sense.
Mr. Mclntosh!
Get me the blanket!
- Coming up.
Get that medical kit over here.
- Cut her loose, she's not dead.
Easy with her.
How is she?
- About the same.
Are Apaches just as cruel
to their own women?
Ain't much of a life.
You live
with an Indian woman, don't you?
That's right.
Why?
That's the goddamndest question!
I understand your sympathy for them.
- Sympathy?
Living with the woman.
You'd be well-advised
to stop hating and start thinking.
You ain't doing too well up till now.
Ke-Ni-Tay,
I want to speak with you.
What is Ulzana going to do now?
Ulzana think of his son now.
In him, there is only to kill
and the place where his son was.
It takes many dead
to fill that place.
What are his plans?
Ulzana take two horses from here.
He need more.
If he not get them,
his men go back to the agency.
Apache not soldier.
Apache not sign paper to fight.
Only fight when it's good.
Are you telling me,
that the raid's over?
Ulzana must given
good power, many horse,
or the raid is finished.
How does he plan to get
this power and these horses?
From you.
He mean to kill you
and take all your horse.
How? Attack us in force?
- What will you do about Mrs. Riordan?
She'll be escorted back to the Fort.
- How many men are you going to send?
Six, with Sergeant Burns.
You'll split your force.
- Well, I have no alternative.
You don't?
What do you mean? Mrs. Riordan...
has to go back to Fort Lowell.
Apaches normally rape
women prisoners to death.
Why did they spare Mrs. Riordan?
- Maybe they thought she was dead.
Ulzana leave woman for you to find.
He know you send her back.
He attack the soldier you send.
The problem with fighting the Apaches
is predicting what they'll do next.
When you know that, you've a chance.
We force Ulzana to attack
and then we counter-attack.
So we strengthen the detail.
- Or weaken it.
You've got to give them the odds
if you want to coax them out.
I see that.
It'll be very dangerous
for the escort and Mrs. Riordan.
And Mrs. Riordan. It's fish
or cut bait. But you'd be wise
to listen to what Ke-Ni-Tay said.
Ulzana's bucks will be tired
from roaming in them mountains,
with nothing to eat but berries.
Pretty soon they'll be thinking of
agency beef
and laying up with their wives.
Mrs. Riordan!
- I want to wash.
I have to wash it off!
Mrs. Riordan! - I want to wash.
Please, I want to wash.
I have to wash it off!
It won't come off.
God damn!
Let me be! Let me be!
Damned Indians.
Peter wanted to die.
Oh God. How he wanted to die.
I can assure you, Mrs. Riordan,
that everything will be done...
Why do they do that? - Hell, they
don't treat their women much better.
Alright, if you need anything,
just call. Somebody will hear you.
Lad, if they come back,
promise me
you won't let them take me?
I don't want you to worry.
- Promise me.
Promise me!
- I promise.
Thank you.
That poor woman's almost crazy.
Imagine watching
her husband die like that?
I hate to expose her
to further danger tomorrow.
I suppose there's no other way.
- Not if you want Ulzana.
I do, Mr. Mclntosh.
I want him!
You'll be safe with this escort,
Mrs. Riordan. It's a good road back.
I hope to meet you in Fort Lowell
under happier circumstances.
Sergeant, take them on.
You'll have to make it look good.
Ulzana will watch to make sure
you take his bait,
before he takes ours.
I understand.
Good luck.
- And to you.
Come right.
Halt!
Detail halt!
Dismount!
I thought you're going
to let them pull us out?
If we follow them all the way,
it'd be too far to help Mr. Mclntosh.
If we turn back too soon,
it'd warn them and won't attack.
The right time is crucial.
Apache's calling you up, sir.
What is it?
- Ulzana want to take you up there.
Mountain of fire. His mind is clear.
Then we must go.
- No!
Where he takes you, you can't go.
If you will go,
you not ride back to help Mclntosh.
Yes, but it's too early to ride back
and they're watching what we do.
Isn't that so? How many are watching?
One man see as many as ten.
Can we find him and kill him?
- You cannot.
But Ke-Ni-Tay can?
But will he?
Ke-Ni-Tay sign paper.
Ke-Ni-Tay soldier.
Alright, find him and kill him.
Give me your long glass.
When you see it make a light,
like this,
then you must ride back to Mclntosh.
- Alright.
Corporal, call the men out.
Yes, sir.
We're going through Dog Canyon, right?
- That's right.
You're expecting them to jump us?
- Could happen.
You're not fooling me, Mclntosh.
It's supposed to happen.
And then Lieutenant DeBuin's supposed
to just ride up and save us, right?
Something like that.
Hm. "Something like that."
You're putting a lot of trust
in a man with no idea.
How do you figure they'll hit us?
Well, it don't seem likely.
These horses they're after,
you keep them tucked away.
If the worst comes to it, shoot them.
Shoot them?
- Shoot them.
The army don't like
sergeants shooting their horses.
Maybe so, but they'd like it less
if 7 Apaches ride them off.
Right, I'll pass the word.
Not so it bothers her.
- Right.
Wagon out.
Keep your eyes open.
How long do you figure he'll take?
I don't know.
Should we trust that Apache, sir?
- I don't think we have much choice.
There! Halfway up the cliff!
See it?
- That's it. Found him!
Let's go, come on.
Let's move.
Come on.
Can we go through fast?
- Let's set a while.
Set a while? - Got to give Ke-Ni-Tay
time to flush the lookout.
Dismount!
Rest your horses!
God damn!
Get those horses!
The horses. Don't let them get away!
- Come on.
They're on both sides.
Let's get the hell out of here! - No!
Get off your horses and walk them.
Use them as a shield.
Stay behind your horses!
Don't break off!
Stay down! Stay together!
The wagon. Get the wagon.
Into the rocks! Under the damn rocks!
Help me, Sergeant! I'm hurt bad.
Help me!
- Come on, grab a hold.
Come on.
Mclntosh!
I'm coming in.
He's hit. Would you look after him?
- It ain't so bad. Don't bother her.
Somebody shoot me, please!
Somebody shoot me up.
In the name of sweet Jesus!
Somebody shoot me off!
Where the hell is that lieutenant?
What do we do now?
Forward at a gallop.
You alright? - Oh sweet mother Mary.
- What day is it?
What?
What day is it?
Wednesday.
Sure don't look like Wednesday.
Wednesday...
The wagon, sir. Somebody's moving.
- What? - By the wagon.
Prepare to dismount!
Dismount!
Frederickson, look after Mrs. Riordan.
- Jack, take care of the horses.
I'll help you ma'am.
- Smithers. Johnson. Lend a hand.
We came as fast as we could.
Ulzana ran out
as soon as he heard your music.
We wanted you to know we were coming.
- The trick was
not to let Ulzana know.
Careful with him.
Set him easy.
Alright, bring some bed tarps here
and make a shelter.
Move that wagon out.
All these men!
If only I'd...
Don't start iffing, man.
You made your pick. Live with it.
Hell, Lieutenant,
there ain't none of us right.
Wouldn't say no to a smoke though.
- I've got the makings. - Good Boy.
Corporal, get those Apaches buried.
- Buried, sir?
Bury them.
- Yes, sir?
Graves detail.
- Don't suppose making cigarettes
is one of
your accomplishments, Lieutenant?
No, sorry.
Never mind.
You'll learn.
That'll be Ke-Ni-Tay.
It's time
we were getting you on the wagon.
Only cause me a lot of suffering.
Well, you can't stay here.
It'd be two days
before we got back. You'd die.
Hell, Lieutenant,
I'm going to die anyway.
Not if we get you to the surgeon.
- You won't get me to the surgeon.
You might not get me to that wagon.
What about your...
My burial?
Being another one of those
black markers back at the Fort
don't have much appeal for me.
I'll leave a detail behind.
- The hell you will.
I ain't passing the time of day
with no bunch of gravediggers.
Now goddammit, Lieutenant, let me sit.
It's not Christian.
That's right, Lieutenant, it's not.
Rider coming in!
You're right. It's Ke-Ni-Tay.
We're about ready to move, sir.
Mr. Mclntosh will be staying behind
at his own request.
Yes, sir. What about Ulzana?
Bury him.
They'd most like to see the body,
or at least the head.
They'll see my report.
- Yes, sir. I'll see to it, sir.
No.
I see to it.
Alright, Corporal.
Mr. Mclntosh.
Mr. DeBuin.
Scout!
Mount up!
Prepare to mount!
Mount!
Ready to move out, Corporal?
- Yes, sir.
Let's move them out!
Forwards at a walk!