Ken! Mr. Ken Seagull.
What do you want, Jerry?
Why don't you quit
counting that money?
Ain't all yours, you know.
$600,000
and all in one swoop.
You know, Jerry,
it'd buy a lot of
land and horses.
When I think this
money was supposed
to buy cannon,
it gives me the creeps.
You'll get the creeps
if they get
their hands on you.
That's government money
and don't you forget it.
JERRY: Look at yonder, Ken.
KEN: Go on, go on.
Them Yankees are
thicker than lice.
(URGING HORSE)
There's no sense
in letting them
catch us both together.
We'll draw cards.
High card gets
the money and escapes,
low card gets
the Yankees on his tail.
Got the cards?
I sure have. Here you are.
Whoever gets the low card
stays on the wagon.
You ready?
Sorry, Jerry.
Well, get moving.
They'll be here any minute.
Ken, if I don't make it,
take care of
Mary and the boy.
Kiss them hello for me.
Don't you worry.
Tell your tattoo that
Uncle Ken will take
care of everything.
Good luck, Jerry.
(EXCLAIMING)
Drop your pistol, rebel.
Your name?
Houston. Jim Houston.
Where's your friend?
I got no friend. I'm alone.
Lie.
Where's the money?
It's all I got.
Can't find anything,
Sergeant.
Where did you hide the money?
Tell me.
Look, mister,
the war is over.
MAN: We'll make you talk.
Where's the money?
(GROANING)
The war is over, mister?
(HORSE NEIGHING)
So, you're not talkin'.
If you want it
like this, fine.
You'll talk in prison, rebel.
MAN: What's the matter, boy?
The sun bother you?
(MAN LAUGHING)
Well, you'll get used
to it sooner or later.
That is,
unless you want to spend
a little more time with us.
Come here.
Here's what you had
five years ago.
You better check it.
We don't want any
dissatisfied customers.
One photograph.
One gun belt.
And a deck of cards.
And that's all.
No pistols, Houston.
The government
confiscated 'em.
And about that $50 of yours,
it went to buy you
a horse and saddle.
I got you
a real good buy, though.
Why, a horse like that
would cost you
at least $80
anywhere in Texas.
Did you say 50 bucks
for this nag?
Not bad.
Boy, look
who's gettin' out.
We're gonna miss you, fellow.
And stay out of trouble.
Telegram for Mr. Milton.
It's urgent.
Give it to me.
Solamente Garcia Mendez
can speak to  Senor Milton,
understand?
Yes, sir.
Vaya!
What is it, Mendez?
MENDEZ: For you,  senor,
from Fort Wilson.
Is it anything serious?
I've got to
leave you, Mary Ann.
I'll join you later.
But, Ken...
Have one of the men
take my sister safely
back to the ranch.
Certainly,  senor.
If the  senorita would permit.
I will do it myself
if the  senorita will permit.
KEN: No, no, Mendez.
I need you.
Send somebody else.
I'm sorry,  senorita .
It would have been
a great pleasure.
Only for you, I'm afraid.
Mendez.
Brewster's free.
We must move and act quickly.
Select a couple
of your best men
and tell them
to get after him.
Send Randall.
He's the only one we got
who'll recognize him
as soon as
he sets eyes on him.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Now, what are your orders?
For me,
Brewster no longer exists.
(HOME TO MY LOVE
BY GINO PLAYING)
I know a girl
with golden hair
Waiting by the window
All alone
I know my girl
knows how I care
Won't be long, my darling
Soon be home
But there's a high wind
wailing in the plain
As if I'll never
see my girl again
On my way home to my love!
Back home to my love
Back home to my love!
Back home
to my loving girl
Say
You're waiting, darling
I know my girl
Is always there
Waiting by the window
All day long
My darling girl
with golden hair
Wait a little longer
Mary.
Won't be long
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
"The war is over.
It ended a year ago
"but we're still
waiting for you.
"I can't,
I won't believe you're dead
"as Seagull claims.
"I love you too much, Jerry.
"And down deep in my heart,
"I feel that
somewhere on this Earth
you're trying to
"get back home."
MARY: "All our money is gone
"and there's
hardly enough food
in the house
"to keep us from starving.
"If I can't make the payment
on the mortgage
"by the end of the month,
"they'll turn me
and the baby out.
"Your friend, Ken Seagull,
came back from the war
"with a lot of money.
"I don't know why,
but he now calls himself
Ken Milton.
"I asked him for a loan
for the sake of
our friendship,
"but he turned me down.
"He says every man
must look out for himself."
"Oh, Jerry.
"Oh, Jerry, darling.
"I feel terrible.
"So terrible.
"If you were only here
beside me."
Seagull.
Seagull!
(GUNS FIRING)
Come on.
(GROANS)
Come on out, Brewster.
We've got you trapped.
Hey, for you, my friend.
Only two shots
but better than nothin'.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Was it Seagull who sent you?
Was it him?
Tell me or I'll cut your...
My wife.
Where is my wife and my son?
Your wife is dead.
Four years ago.
Seagull took the boy
away.
Where's Seagull now?
Where is he?
Austin, Texas.
Calls himself Milton.
(SCREAMING)
That's enough now.
That's enough.
I said, that's enough.
He's dead.
What more
do you want from him?
Come over here.
I'll bandage your arm.
I thought it was worse.
It's just a scratch.
What's your name?
Does it matter?
I like to know who I meet.
My name is Winnie Getz.
Getz, you say.
Is helping your neighbor
your calling, maybe?
Well, let's just say
I prefer
distributive justice.
Now, what the hell
does that mean?
There were two against one
and armed to the teeth.
Didn't seem quite fair.
I see.
Nothing else?
No, not at first.
But, uh,
then I got me an idea.
Yeah? And what was that?
I heard
what that fellow said,
just before he died.
And I reckon, uh,
something good
could come out of it.
Somethin' real good maybe.
I don't, uh...
I don't get you.
Well, you want to
get your revenge, don't you?
Yeah, go on.
Well, to my mind,
it'd be best for you
if that fellow Seagull,
or whatever he calls himself,
thinks you're dead.
Well, you're--
you're forgetting about
the, uh, other guys
when nobody shows up.
Oh, somebody will show up.
Who?
Me, pardner.
I'll spell out my story.
I'll tell him
I saw the fight,
took a hand in it,
killed you, but, uh,
too late for the other two,
of course.
Just what do you expect
to get out of this?
Mmm. A reward, maybe,
or a job.
It just so happens
that I'm out of work.
No. Seagull would
never fall for it.
He'll fall for it
if I can prove to him
that you're dead.
Just a minute.
I've got something
that could convince him.
Sure.
Sure,  amigo ,
you got yourself a deal.
You'll get all the proof
you need.
You really made up your mind
to go through this, Brewster?
What's the matter?
You got a weak stomach?
When he sees this,
he'll have to believe you.
It's gonna hurt.
Is that so?
(GASPING)
All right, Getz.
You've proved to me
that you're smart
and quick on the trigger.
A lot more so
than my own men.
Ain't that right, Mendez?
One moment,
you are not going to
believe this  gringo's story?
I believe in the proof,
Mendez.
And this  gringo,
as you call him,
succeeded where your men
just plain failed.
I think
he deserves a reward.
Well, uh, it's like this,
Mr. Milton.
Money comes and goes
and always brings
a lot of trouble with it.
I can ride and I can shoot.
That tattoo mark there
proves that clear enough.
I'd rather have
a nice, permanent,
dependable job.
Well said there, Getz.
All right, you're hired.
Mendez is happy
to take you on.
Right, Mendez?
Oh, happiness
is nothing,  senor .
I, I am in paradise.
(PIANO PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Come on, boys.
Let's see some of
them dollars of yours.
I'm here
to load my pockets with 'em.
Yeah.
That's my point.
Well, I'm gonna shoot it all.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Here she is, folks.
Fresh from
her triumphant successes
in Dallas and St. Louis.
Hattie Gardner!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(PLAYING VIOLIN)
Here's a song
that's free and easy
Come on, everybody,
join and we'll sing it
Tap your feet
and clap your hands...
MAN: Come on,
roll them bones.
Final roll.
Hey, listen, pardner.
I got
a very urgent appointment
50 miles from here.
I'll be seeing you.
So long.
What a very happy
little song to be singing...
What a very happy little
gay little song...
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Seven wins.
(MUMBLING)
How do you like that?
There she is.
MAN 1:
A winner with the seven.
Come along and sing
MAN 2: You'll lose your cash
if you're not careful.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
MAN 3: Give him the dice.
Stop. Hey.
MAN 1: Seven again.
(EXCLAIMING)
Now, you listen to me,
handsome.
If you're figurin'
on ruining my actin',
I got a few things
to say to you right now.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Now get away from here,
prairie flower.
Get your hands off me.
Who do you think you are?
Go back to your singing.
This ain't no place
for women.
Hey, Sancho.
SANCHO: I'll buy you a drink.
Come over here.
There's a big wad of dollars
on the board
just burnin' to
come into my hands.
Makes me sick.
Seein' big bills
give me indigestion.
Mr. Horner, two of
Mendez's men are down
by the dice table.
What do we do?
I'll take care of it.
Here she comes.
We're gonna have
a little surprise.
Seven. I made a seven.
You are great, Lofty.
I always say so.
That's a...
What do you mean?
You insinuatin'
it ain't on the level?
No. You see, I...
Is that a seven or not
on the table?
Yes.
Seven.
That's better.
Hey, you! Outside.
What did you say?
I said outside.
And you can tell Mendez
this saloon is
out-of-bounds for his men.
Get it? Out-of-bounds.
Have it your way, Horner.
The first man that moves
will get
plugged in the gullet.
Sancho!
(SCREAMING)
(MEN MUTTERING)
You get the hell out
of here, both of you!
Get the hell out of here!
Look out!
Take out those stiffs.
Whiskey!
Congratulations.
By golly,
I don't even know your name.
Houston. Jim Houston.
Well, your very good health,
Mr. Houston.
There's always a call
for men like you here.
Those coyotes of Mendez
don't make life
any too easy for us here.
What's this Mendez
all about?
You mean,
what's this Milton after.
Well, Milton wants everything.
He owns
two-thirds of the land
around here
and he wants to get his hands
on the rest of it.
But I say no!
And the other ranchers
are with me.
And how long
are you gonna keep sayin' it?
How about that, folks?
How come nobody
gave me a hand?
Listen...
You keep your hands off me.
Milton's gettin' more power
every day.
When he can't get
what he wants with blackmail
and corruption,
he resorts to violence.
And nobody in town's
got the courage to fight back.
The sheriff was shot dead
three months ago.
And there ain't
a man in the place
with the guts
to take his job.
But I want to
make you a proposition.
Why don't you help us?
I'll have to
think about that.
Right now
what I need is a bed.
Oh, um, by the way,
where is this fellow
Milton's ranch?
Oh, that's not hard to find.
Just head north
out of Austin,
and when
you've forded the creek,
the land's all his.
Hey, why are you so curious?
You aim to pay him a visit?
Could be.
(BOY GRUNTING)
Howdy.
Say, was that you
who hit that piece of iron
in the air just now.
Sure.
I can do it any time I want.
What's your name?
Tim.
Don't you think
you're braggin'
a little bit, Tim?
That's a pretty hard thing
to do.
You got a dollar?
Yeah, I reckon so.
Then I'll make
a deal with you.
You throw it up in the air
and if I hit it
before it falls,
the dollar's mine.
Well, you drive
a hard bargain, pardner,
but it's a deal.
Okay then?
Okay.
Ready?
Who taught you
how to make that sign?
It's-- it's to bring luck.
My pa used to make it.
Your pa?
Don't you want to bet now?
Scared
you'll lose your dollar?
No, no, you won it.
I knew you could do it.
Where is your pa? In town?
He died, a long time ago.
But he was a great cowboy,
even more than you.
Sure.
And you,
you're with your ma now,
are you?
My ma is dead, too.
Tim...
Nino, run along.
Go back to the village!
(LAUGHING)
What do you want?
To meet you, stranger.
They say that you put on
one hell of a fight
in Horner's Saloon
last night.
Unfortunately,
I missed the performance.
I lost two very valuable men.
So you're Garcia Mendez.
Right,  senor.
And now you will
repeat the performance,
out here in the open.
Only the end
will be different.
Right,  senor?
Oh, no pistols, of course.
It will be over too soon.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CLANGING)
(MEN GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Go after him.
Go and get him.
Fight him like I taught you
how to fight.
Go after him.
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
Shoot.
Get it over with.
(LAUGHING)
I'm not going to
kill you, stranger.
You're a champion.
And you don't kill champions,
you raise them.
And you're coming with me
to the Mayflower Ranch,
and you're hired
for top dollar.
Bravo! Bravo!
I hope
I'm lucky at this deal.
Look, Mendez is here.
MENDEZ: Juan. Pedro.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Take care of him.
Go ahead.
Round up a dozen good men
and tell them to get ready
because tomorrow
or the day after tomorrow
they run in with the herd
at dawn.
All right, chief.
Did you hear Mendez?
Nothing is hard for him.
Sure. Twelve men
for all these horses.
As if Abilene was on
the other side of the hill.
He's crazy.
Quit complainin'.
We've been hangin' around
for a month doing nothing.
MAN 1: You talk too much.
MAN 2: You're the one
who's talking now.
Take that guy inside
and shut up.
Good mornin', ma'am.
Good morning.
Will you harness Robbie
please?
Yes.
No, not that one,
the other one.
JERRY: Mary!
Mary!
You can't leave me now!
You can't leave me!
(JERRY GROANING)
Help me.
Stay with me.
Don't go.
Who are you?
I'm Mary Ann.
I heard you
call my name and...
My brother is the owner
of this ranch.
Oh.
I see, I'm...
I'm sorry.
You're in a pretty bad way.
I'll send you some bandages
and a clean shirt.
Am I mistaken
or are you new here?
No, I...
I was just hired
by Mendez.
Strange.
You don't look at
all like the type
he usually hires around here.
(LAUGHING)
What type am I then?
Well,
I'll send you the bandages
and the rest of the stuff.
What were you doing in there?
That's no business of yours.
He's one of my men,
and your brother
has given me full authority
over them.
Do you want to
know something, Mendez?
One of these days
you'll have to
find a new job.
And you know why?
Because
I'll have you thrown out
of Mayflower.
You're going to
fall in love with me.
Jerry.
What the devil?
Never mind.
Where you been?
I've been expecting you
all day.
Now, wait a minute.
It wasn't easy, you know.
But everybody's asleep now.
Listen, Winnie.
I've been figurin'
how to help those townspeople
square accounts
with Ken Seagull.
He's robbed them blind,
took their land,
even killed off
their sheriff.
And what are you
gonna do about it?
Ride to Austin tonight.
I can disappear
and nobody should notice
I'm gone.
Will you help me?
All right.
Just sit tight for a while.
I'll keep things covered.
Don't worry.
(NEIGHING)
(TAPPING ON WINDOW)
Holy smoke.
If you're not careful,
one day somebody's
gonna put a bullet
through your guts.
Well, I didn't
want anybody to see me
so I came up
the shortest way.
They fixed you up
real pretty, didn't they?
Listen, Horner, yesterday
you made me a proposition.
Now, do you still feel
the same way about it?
Sure do.
Go on.
Tomorrow at daybreak
two-thirds of Milton's horses
will be movin'
out toward Abilene
with only a dozen
of Mendez's men
ridin' herd on them.
It's a chance
for you to get back
part of
what he robbed from you.
If you agree,
your men and me,
well, we'll fix
those buzzards.
I see.
What you're suggesting
means more bloodshed.
It won't be the last.
I stand alone now.
Ken's broken their spirits,
they're all afraid.
But there is
no other way, Horner.
Can't you understand that?
Milton won't stop at anything
until he has wiped you out.
Now, he has to be destroyed
before it's too late.
Is that the only reason?
You really hate him, right?
That's right.
Well, I can't say
that I blame you.
(CREAKING)
(SHUSHING)
(GASPING)
What are you
doing up at this hour?
You ought to be in bed.
I heard some noise
and I thought
someone was here.
Well, I guess I was wrong.
Good night.
Well, Houston,
what do you want us to do?
Simple.
Fight.
All right.
We'll play it your way.
It's our last chance
to save our necks.
I'll have to
convince the others.
(MEN URGING HORSES)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
We've been double-crossed.
Ambushed.
Men and horses, killed.
MENDEZ: Get those horses.
MENDEZ: Now!
How are your wounds today?
Much better.
MENDEZ: Pedro!
By the way, I...
I want to thank you
for yesterday.
You were very nice to me.
Maybe even too nice.
MENDEZ: You come with me!
What's the matter with him?
I don't know.
It seems like Horner
played a dirty trick
on some of his men.
Horner's a murderer.
My brother has to live
shut up in the house
like a prisoner
since Horner
started persecuting him.
What do you know about it?
I can use my head, too.
Besides,
Ken tells me everything.
How long you been
living with your brother?
Three years.
Before that
I was in Spring Inn,
with my aunt.
Why do you ask?
Nothing.
No reason, Mary.
Ann.
This time Horner's
gonna pay for it.
I won't stand for it.
He can't do this.
He can't do this to me.
Pablo. Pablo!
Pablo, get rid of this blood.
We must move into action,
immediately.
If Horner
and the sheep he leads
get ideas into their heads,
all of us and everything
we've been fightin' for
will be wiped out forever.
Forever, understand.
Senor, in this life
there are those
who talk a lot,
and those
who keep their hatred
and the desire for vengeance
hidden in their hearts.
I promise you
that Horner will regret
the day he was born.
I promise you that
he will lose five of his men
for every one of
my  hombres killed.
And I promise you
that I will
discover who betrayed us
and I will kill him
with my own hands.
(MEN URGING HORSES)
Now, we will divide
up into small groups
and ride into town
without arousing suspicion.
The signal will be
when I walk into the saloon.
Then you're on your own,
and remember,
they gunned down your friends
and your brothers
and never gave them a chance.
Ramirez,
you go along the river
and then come into the town
from the south.
Pedro, you bring your men
from the east.
Sancho,
you move into the town
from the top of the slope.
And you,  amigo,
you come with me.
How does that please you?
(EXCLAIMING)
(CLANKING)
What's the matter?
I don't know.
Something wrong with his hoof.
It's a hell of a time
to find that out.
Well, I better
have it looked at.
MENDEZ: Okay, but hurry up.
Be only a minute.
Got a bad hoof.
Yeah.
I'll look at it.
Tim. Hey, Tim.
Howdy. You want to
bet another dollar?
I'll give you two
if you take this note
to Brand Horner right away
and don't let
anybody see you.
Understand?
It's important.
Very important. Okay?
I'll go but not for the $2.
Why not?
Because you're good.
Hey, Tim.
(SHOUTING)
(LAUGHING)
He's all right.
I can't understand
what was bothering him.
Houston.
Yeah.
How long you
gonna keep me waiting?
Just a minute.
So long.
This ain't no place for kids.
What do you want?
I've got to deliver a note
to Mr. Horner.
You get out of here.
Mr. Horner's busy.
But I got to see him.
It's very important.
I said he was busy.
Now get out of here.
You said you had a message
for Mr. Horner, didn't you?
Where is it?
What is it? A love letter?
Could be. Why? You jealous?
What the hell
could I do about it?
There's too many of us.
I'll take you to Mr. Horner.
Come along.
Let's go, Houston.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GUNS FIRING)
(MEN GROANING)
(MENDEZ'S MEN WHOOPING)
(GROANING)
Houston.
It's all over with me.
I'm finished.
They'll kill me,
all because of
your crazy idea.
My note.
Didn't you get my note?
What note? I don't know
what you're talking about.
This way, quick.
I'll cover you.
Keep your head down.
(SHUDDERING)
MAN: Come on out
with your hands up.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Where's Horner?
He's not here.
Sorry about that.
Tim ain't been back
since yesterday.
But that don't
bother me none.
If he wants to come back,
he knows the way.
I fed him, I clothed him.
But you know
how these little kids are.
Ungrateful whelps.
It don't do to make
sacrifices for them.
It just ain't worth it.
(VIOLIN PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Well, I reckon this ain't
the right season for it,
Mrs. Jones.
I reckon you're right.
Well, they're all
havin' a lot of fun,
wouldn't you say?
Yeah.
Do you know where Houston is?
I haven't seen him all day.
I'll tell you what.
For you,
I'll go look for him.
(ALL CHEERING)
SANCHO: Drink! Drink!
You!
You keep your hands off her.
Why do you push me away for?
Why do you push me away?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Pedro! Pedro!
Where's Houston?
Why is he not drinking here
with us?
Ain't seen him around
since this morning,
come to think about it.
Well, quit
hanging around here.
Go find him quickly.
Go ahead.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Amigo. Hey,  amigo.
Where have you been?
Oh, just, uh,
messin' around.
I don't much like parties.
Yes, but this is
a fantastic party.
Listen.
We're celebrating
the end of Horner.
Doesn't the idea
appeal to you?
Well, I better get
cleaned up a bit.
I got half the trail's dust
on me.
Oh, no, you come with me.
A drink for my friend
and make it quickly.
Because my friend
is a very big drinker.
Drink for everyone!
Drink to our victory.
Thanks. I, uh,
I don't feel like drinking.
You will drink
because I say so.
Now, just a minute.
What does that mean?
That you do not want
to drink to our victory?
It means that
I don't want a drink.
That's all.
MENDEZ: Maybe so.
Maybe so.
But some people say
that you did not fire
a single shot
at Horner's men.
And some say more than that.
Some say that
you're in Horner's pay.
Who says?
I do. And I can prove it.
Pedro!
(TIM GRUNTING)
Who brought him here?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I did.
You didn't expect that,
did you?
Who gave you that message?
Answer me!
Hands off, Mendez.
I gave him the message.
Me.
You dirty, bloody...
Why did you do it?
Why?
Look at me, Seagull.
Take a good, long look.
Don't you recognize me?
The man
whose wife you killed.
And who spent five
long years in prison
so you could wallow
in your stinkin' money.
That's why I did it.
So one day I could
see you crawlin' on your knees
beggin' for mercy.
And then...
Then I would crush you
like a worm!
Mendez.
Call them off.
Call back your boys,
Seagull, or I'll kill you.
Tim, get the horse.
(GUNS FIRING)
(MEN CLAMORING)
Kill him, Mendez.
Kill him, kill him.
Stop your firing.
Get those horses.
(SCREAMING)
I can do it.
You stay right here.
Okay.
Tim!
Come down.
Hi,  amigo.
If you're lookin'
for Horner,
you can keep on
looking for quite a spell
because he's lit out,
bag and baggage,
together with all
the rest of
the God-fearin' citizens.
We're alone.
Alone in a cemetery
named Austin.
Well, what are you
waitin' for?
Why don't you
catch up with them?
Well, our paths
have been runnin' alongside
each other
for quite some time now.
No, Getz.
This means everything to me.
It's the reason
why I live, why I breathe.
Everything I've done,
I've done
just to get right here
to this showdown.
But for you,
it's--it's different.
You still have time
so just...
Just wipe Seagull
out of your head
and get the hell out of here.
You're talkin' too much, boy.
In a few minutes,
Mendez will be here
with all the men
he can round up.
And what do you think
we're gonna stop him with,
your gab?
Winnie Getz.
Listen, Timmy,
you have to prove to me
that you're a real man,
and a real man
must obey orders
when it's necessary.
Now, you stay here,
quiet like a mouse
and still as a cactus,
no matter what happens.
Promise.
Okay, then.
Okay.
Here, I found
a whole arsenal
down in the cellar
including some
charges of dynamite.
I've already arranged
for a reserve on the roof.
So I'll, uh, receive
Senor Mendez from up there.
You watch out
for the street level, huh?
Si.
Oh, Brewster.
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GUNS FIRING)
Juan, Pedro. Get him!
Shoot him! Dismount!
Cowards,
you want to die like dogs?
Hurry up.
Two of you after him.
(SCREAMING)
Go after him.
(MAN SCREAMING)
There he is. On the roof.
Go after him.
Get him, damn it!
There he is.
Go after him.
Estupidos!
Don't let him get away!
Come on,
he's run out of dynamite.
It's just wax candles. Look!
Look. Come on!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Where'd he go?
Right here,
you yellow-bellies.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CREAKING)
WINNIE: Except for Mendez
and the two that got away,
I think we got
everyone of 'em, Brewster.
I'll catch up with them
at Mayflower.
I'll go with you.
Private affair, Winnie.
You take care of Tim.
Go get some fresh horses,
and be quick about it.
What's going on, Mendez?
My brother
refuses to talk to me.
There is no time now,
beautiful.
We will discuss it in Mexico.
Because you're coming with me.
MARY: No! Let me go.
You're not goin' off
with her.
You're not goin'.
(GROANS)
Mendez!
(MEN GROANING)
(GROANING)
Give up, Mendez.
I... I...
I didn't know.
Pablo.
Senor?
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Seagull!
Stand up, Seagull.
Drop your gun, Brewster.
This is the second time
you've drawn the wrong card.
You figured to destroy me.
I gotta disappoint you.
Again.
Can I look you in the face,
Seagull?
Sure you can.
I want to see you
spit out your soul, Brewster.
(GUN FIRES)
(GUNS FIRING)
(COCKING)
(KEN GASPING)
You will consign the ranch
and all it contains
to the governmental
authorities, Colonel,
in compensation for the theft
suffered by
the State five years ago.
Very well, Colonel.
As far as the perpetrators
of the robbery are concerned,
Ken Seagull died
in a gun fight.
And, uh, Jerry Brewster...
Jerry Brewster died
about a month ago.
I, myself, will sign
both death certificates.
But as for Houston,
for his voluntary aid
in the cause of justice,
and availing myself
of the special powers
invested in me by the State,
I confer upon him
the Sheriff's star
of the city of Austin
with the hope that
peace and justice
may never again
abandon this town.
And that, gentlemen,
completes my assignment.
(HOME TO MY LOVE
BY GINO PLAYING)