[DRUMS AND CYMBALS]...
...[MUSICAL WHISTLING]...
...[PROPELLER HUMMING]
KEEP THE LINE.
HOLD.
[TIRE BLOWS]...
...[SHUTS OFF ENGINE]...
...[HORSES GALLOPING]
Officer: BRING OVER THE MULES.
WELCOME, SENOR.
MAY WE REMOVE THE GUN?
CERTAINLY, SERGEANT,
YOU MAY.
OK.
CAPTAIN
FRANCISCO RAMIREZ
AT YOUR ORDERS, SIR.
MY GENERAL'’’S
COMPLIMENTS, SIR.
AND MINE TO HIM, SIR.
LEE ARNOLD.
HURRY UP. WE HAVEN'’
’T GOT ALL DAY.
MY PLEASURE,
MR. ARNOLD.
YOUR HEALTH.
AND YOURS.
[FOOTSTEPS]...
...10 GUNS,
MY CAPTAIN.
Officer: PREPARE TO MOVE OUT.
20,000 PESOS
IN GOLD.
WE NEED EVERY GUN WE CAN
GET AGAINST THIS VILLA.
YOU MEAN
HE FIGHTS THAT WELL?
HE'’’S A TERRIBLE
FIGHTER.
THAT'’’S THE TROUBLE
WITH HIM.
PANCHO VILLA...
CRAWLS OUT
FROM UNDER HIS ROCK,
SHOOTS YOU IN THE BACK,
ROBS YOU,
AND THEN RUNS
AND HIDES AGAIN.
HE'’’S A MENACE TO MEXIC
O, BELIEVE ME.
CAPTAIN...
Officer: GROUP IS ALL READY, SIR.
YOU SUPPOSE I COULD BORROW
A COUPLE OF YOUR MEN
TO GET THE WHEEL
BACK ON MY PLANE?
I'’’D LIKE TO BE ABLE
TO TAKE OFF.
MY REGRETS,
MR. ARNOLD,
BUT MY GENERAL
HAS ORDERED ME
TO RETURN WITH THESE GUNS
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
FIRST VILLAGE SOUTH OF US
IS CHUPADERO.
THEY HAVE
AN EXCELLENT BLACKSMITH.
HE FORGED CAISSON
UNDERPINNINGS FOR VILLA,
SO I'’’M SURE
HE CAN HELP YOU.
[MULE FOOTSTEPS]
MY REGRETS,
MR. ARNOLD,
BUT IT'’’S THE BEST
I CAN OFFER.
I'’’LL TAKE IT.
ONE OTHER THING...
THE VILLAGERS--THEY'’’RE
WHAT WE CALL PACIÍÍFICOS.
THEY DON'’’T FIGHT FOR HIM, BUT
THEY'’’RE SYMPATHETIC TO VILLA.
IT WOULD BE WISE NOT
TO TELL '’’EM WHY YOU ARE HERE.
[SIGHS]
Officer: GROUP, FORWARD...
MARCH.
THEY WON'’’T HURT YOU,
MR. ARNOLD.
JUST DON'’’T STAY TOO LONG,
THAT'’’S ALL.
SO, FIX YOUR AIRPLANE,
COME BACK,
AND FLY FOR US.
MUCH MORE MONEY.
Capt. Ramirez: HAH.
[EXCITED YELLING]
THIS IS MR. ARNOLD.
HE'’’S A GRINGO
FROM EL PASO,
HE FLIES IN THE AIR,
AND I AM TAKING HIM
TO THE BLACKSMITH.
HE'’’S A GRINGO
FROM EL PASO.
FINA, I AM TAKING HIM
TO SEE YOUR FATHER.
[CHILDREN YELLING]...
...AND I AM TAKING HIM
TO THE BLACKSMITH.
THIS IS MR. ARNOLD.
HE'’’S A GRINGO
FROM EL PASO,
AND I AM TAKING HIM
TO THE BLACKSMITH.
HO...
I'’’M THE BLACKSMITH.
MR. ARNOLD,
THIS IS
LUIS GONZALES.
HOW DO YOU DO?
MOVE. HEY, HEY.
AHH.
HEY, GET AWAY
FROM THERE.
YOU WANT IT
TO BITE YOU?
YOU HAVE NEVER SEEN
AN AIRPLANE BEFORE?
WELL,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
OH, I AM SORRY,
SENOR ARNOLD,
BUT NOTHING MORE
CAN BE DONE TILL TOMORROW.
BUT THIS ISN'’’T
EXACTLY MY AIRPLANE.
YOU SEE, I JUST, UH,
BORROWED IT KIND OF,
AND IF I DON'’’T
GET IT BACK--
SENOR ARNOLD,
DO NOT WORRY.
YOU MAY NOT BE AT HOME,
BUT TONIGHT YOU WILL
BE IN YOUR OWN HOUSE.
COME.
BUT HE'’’LL COME
LOOKIN'’’--
COME. COME.
SOMETHING DISPLEASES
YOU, MR. ARNOLD?
OH, NO,
EVERYTHING'’’S FINE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JUST GREAT.
COFFEE, MR. ARNOLD?
PLEASE.
FINA, COFFEE.
CIGARETTE.
ALLOW ME.
OH, NO.
HO HO.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
¿¿BONITO?
Luis: IT'’’S ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW,
MR. ARNOLD,
IT'’’S TOO BAD YOU DIDN'
’’T HAVE ENGINE TROUBLE
A LITTLE EARLIER.
YOU MISSED
A GREAT MOMENT
IN THE LIFE
OF OUR VILLAGE.
PANCHO VILLA
CAME HERE TODAY.
WELL, I DON'’’T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT HIM.
YOU KNOW, FROM THE STATES,
HE'’’S JUST KNOWN AS A BANDIT.
Luis: NO, NO.
PANCHO VILLA IS
NO LONGER A BANDIT.
HE'’’S NOT?
Bonito: NO.
NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO.
HE--HE IS FIGHTING
FOR THE REVOLUTION.
THE COLORADOS,
THEY ARE TRYING TO
DESTROY THE REVOLUTION.
THEYARE TRYING
TO TAKE AWAY
OUR PRESIDENT MADERO.
THAT'’’S, UH, TYPICAL
OF THE COLORADOS.
[LAUGHING]
YOU ARE A WISE MAN,
MR. ARNOLD.
BELIEVE ME,
IF YOU EVER
SEE SOLDIERS
UNDER A RED FLAG,
RIDE THE OTHER WAY.
THE COLORADOS
ARE THE CRUELEST MEN
IN MEÉÉXICO.
Luis: IS GOOD?
IT'’’S VERY GOOD.
[LAUGHS]
BONITO, WAKE UP.
LOOK.
ISN'’’T THAT MY SHIRT
FLOATING DOWN THE RIVER?
MUST BE.
THOSE ARE MY PANTS.
WELL, DON'’’T JUST SIT
HERE. GO AND GET THEM.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT
TO WEAR TOMORROW, WEEDS?
PULL, BURRO. PULL.
HEY, HEY.
IT WORKED.
[LAUGHING]
YES, IT WORKED.
?
IT'’’S GOOD, HUH
GOOD?
THAT'’’S BETTER THAN GOOD.
IT'’’S THE BEST.
AY, COMPADRE.
[FAKES WINCE]...
...[LAUGHING]
HOW CAN I PAY YOU?
NOTHING.
YOU ARE MY FRIEND.
YOU ARE MY GUEST.
[LAUGHING]
NOW...
WHERE I COME FROM...
WHEN YOU'’’RE A GUEST...
YOU HAVE TO BRING
A HOUSE GIFT.
THAT'’’S THE WAY.
SO...
FOR THE HOUSE.
[LAUGHTER]
MR. ARNOLD, THIS IS
YOUR HOUSE ALWAYS.
I BELIEVE I'’’D LIKE THAT.
[ROOSTER CROWS]
TROOP FORWARD.
FORWARD.
[GALLOPING]
COLORADOS.
[CLOSES DOORS]
STAY UPSTAIRS.
LOCK THE DOOR
BEHIND YOU.
COLORADOS.
JUAN, NO. NO.
LISTEN,
THEY KNOW WHAT I
HAVE DONE FOR VILLA.
ONE OF US MUST DIE,
BUT NOT BOTH, NOT YET.
YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YOU PROMISE YOUR FATHER.
NOW HURRY. RUN. HURRY.
[VILLAGERS SCREAMING]...
...[GUNSHOT]...
...[SCREAMS]...
...[YELLING]...
...[GUNSHOTS]...
...[POUNDING]...
...[WOMEN SCREAMING]...
...[COLORADOS YELLING]
THEY SAY THAT YOU
EMBRACED THE BANDIT VILLA.
FOR CAPTAIN RAMIREZ...
IS THERE NO EMBRACE FOR HIM?
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
THAT'’’S NOT SO NICE.
I WARNED YOU NOT TO STAY
TOO LONG, DIDN'’’T I?
ALMOST VERY LUCKY,
BUT YOU'’’LL STILL HAVE
TO DO IT MY WAY.
TAKE HIM, TOO.
[FOOTSTEPS]
WAIT.
[POUNDING]
ALL RIGHT.
WOMEN OUT.
[GRUNTING]
NO.
[MOANING]...
...[CRIES]...
...[HEAVY BREATHING]
I DON'’’T HAVE TIME
TO FOOL WITH YOU.
[SCREAMS]
UGH.
[SCREAMS]...
...[WHIMPERING]
MAYBE I--
MAYBE I DO HAVE TIME.
[CRYING] NO.
[CRYING]...
...[YELLING]
Colorado: BRING THEM OVER HERE.
THE PRISONERS...
BRING THEM
OVER HERE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
JUST A DAMN
MINUTE, SOLDIER.
Second Colorado: COME ON.
ALL OF YOU, INTO THE SQUARE.
MOVE. MOVE.
TOO MANY GUNS.
GOTTA TELL VILLA.
[HORSE NEIGHS]...
...[WHISTLING AND SHOUTING]...
...[GASPS]
[SCREAMS]...
...[CHOKING]...
...[CRYING]
ALL RIGHT,
YOU STUPID PEOPLE.
NOW WE'’’RE GONNA
TEACH YOU A LESSON.
YOU DON'’’T LISTEN.
THAT'’’S THE TROUBLE
WITH YOU.
YOU'’’RE ALL ASLEEP.
YOUR MIND
IS SOMEWHERE ELSE.
YOU DON'’’T LISTEN.
SO YOU'’’VE GOT
TO LEARN THE HARD WAY.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
MY CHIEF,
HMM?
THE COLORADO CAPTAIN,
HE'’’S HANGING EVERYBODY.
WE DON'’’T MOVE SOON,
THERE WILL BE NO ONE LEFT.
NOT YET.
Capt. Ramirez: YOU THINK
YOUR PRESIDENT MADERO
IS SUCH A GREAT MAN.
ALL FOR THE PEONS.
HE'’’S NOT FOR YOU.
WE'’’RE FOR YOU.
[SCREAMING]...
...[CHOKING]
Capt. Ramirez: I'’’LL TELL YOU,
PRESIDENT MADERO'’’S
A COWARD,
A COWARD WHO ACCEPTS
THE SUPPORT OF A THIEF
AND A MURDERING BANDIT,
PANCHO VILLA.
HE'’’S AFRAID NOT TO.
WHY ISN'’’T YOUR HERO
HERE TO HELP YOU NOW?
Capt. Ramirez: I'’’LL TELL YOU WHY.
BECAUSE HE'’’S OFF
ROBBING OTHER PEONS.
THAT'’’S WHY.
THEY'’’RE BOTH ROBBING YOU,
YOU STUPID PEOPLE.
WHY DO YOU LIKE PEOPLE
WHO ROB YOU?.
Capt. Ramirez: THESE MEN UP HERE,
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY ARE,
DON'’’T YOU?
[HUMMING]
THEY'’’RE TRAITORS.
THEY DO FAVORS
FOR PANCHO VILLA.
[VILLAGERS HUMMING
LA CUCARACHA]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?.
[HUMMING
GETS LOUDER]
Capt. Ramirez: HUH?
[GUNSHOTS]...
...[SCREAMING]...
...[GUNSHOTS]
OUT.
AAH.
HOLD IT.
[GUNFIRE CEASES]...
...[BELL TOLLING]...
...[TOLLING STOPS]...
...[WOMAN PRAYING IN SPANISH]
LUIS GONZALES...
ON MY HORSE.
URBINA.
Urbina: MY CHIEF?
POST SENTRIES.
EXCUSE ME, MY CHIEF.
WHAT SHOULD WE DO
WITH THE OFFICERS?
THE OFFICERS?
HANG THEM.
[FINA SOBBING]
THE COLORADO
CAPTAIN RAMIREZ.
MY CHIEF SENDS ME TO SAY
YOUR HUSBAND
IS IN THE CHURCH.
MY CHIEF
SENDS ME TO SAY...
HE GRIEVES WITH YOU
FOR YOUR HUSBAND
AND THAT YOUR HUSBAND
WAS A GREAT HEART.
I SAY THIS FOR MYSELF,
TOO, SENORA GONZALES.
YOU, GRINGO.
WHO, ME?
DO YOU SEE ANY OTHER
GRINGOS AROUND HERE?
[HORSES APPROACHING]
URBINA.
MY CHIEF.
READ ME
WHAT THE GUNS SAY.
'PROPERTY OF...
MUNITIONS COMPANY OF...'
[SPITS]...
'EL PASO.'
YOU KNOW...
I THINK SOMEBODY'’’S
BEEN RUNNING GUNS
TO OUR ENEMY.
GRINGO GUNS.
I THINK SO.
HEY, GRINGO.
YOU HAVEN'’’T SEEN A...
GUNRUNNING
SON-OF-A-BITCH GRINGO
AROUND HERE, HAVE YOU?
[HORSE APPROACHING]
SAY SOMETHING, GRINGO.
WHAT CAN I SAY?
WHATEVER IS
IN YOUR HEART.
RAISE YOUR HANDS.
THIS IS YOUR HEART.
URBINA.
MY CHIEF.
PUT HIM
WITH THE COLORADOS.
PLEASE.
[PRISONERS TALKING LOW]
QUIET.
I'’’M GOING TO SHOOT YOU.
Prisoners: NO.
LET ME EXPLAIN THINGS.
YOU SEE THIS WALL?
IF YOU RUN REAL FAST
AND CLIMB OVER THIS WALL,
YOU CAN GO FREE.
[PRISONERS SHOUTING]
DON'’’T WORRY TOO MUCH,
BECAUSE I AM
A VERY BAD SHOT.
WHY ARE YOU NERVOUS?
YOU THINK I'’’M GOING
TO SHOOT YOU?
BUT YOU WOULDN'’’T
WANT THAT, CHIEF.
IF ONE COLORADO
GETS OVER THAT WALL
BECAUSE I DON'’’T HAVE
A LOADED GUN IN MY HAND,
I WILL SHOOT YOU.
YES, CHIEF.
3.
NO. NO.
NO. ¡¡POR DIOS.
5 THIS TIME.
Prisoners: NO.
NO.
NO, NO, NO.
NO, NOT ME.
NO.
[GUNSHOT]...
...5 MORE.
[GUNSHOT]
CHIEF, CHIEF.
RUN.
WALK, THEN.
Villa: WAIT, FIERRO.
YOU KNOW,
THAT AIRPLANE...
IT COULD TELL US
WHERE
THE COLORADOS ARE
BEFORE THE COLORADOS
KNOW WHERE WE ARE.
THAT'’’S RIGHT.
AND I'’’M THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN FLY THAT AIRPLANE.
IT CAN BE
VERY USEFUL TO YOU.
VERY USEFUL.
FIERRO...
YOU THINK THE GRINGO
WANTS TO FLY FOR US?
I'’’LL FLY FOR YOU.
I HOPE HE CAN FLY
BETTER THAN HE CAN WALK.
I'’’LL FLY IT FOR YOU,
BUT I WANT SOMETHING.
WHAT?
I WANT TO BLOW
HIS BRAINS OUT.
I DON'’’T THINK HE'’
’LL LET YOU DO THAT.
WELL, LET THESE MEN GO.
ALL RIGHT. HOW MANY?
HOW--
ALL OF THEM.
THEIR OFFICERS ARE DEAD.
THEY CAN'’’T HURT YOU.
THEY DON'’’T WANT TO
FIGHT ANYMORE.
NO.
JUST ONE.
ONE?
ONE.
PICK HIM.
GO ON, GRINGO.
IT'’’S YOUR CHANCE
TO SAVE ONE LIFE.
GO AHEAD.
YOU PICK HIM.
LET ONE GO.
URBINA, A HORSE
FOR THE GRINGO.
[SPEAKING
SPANISH]
Fierro: 5 MORE.
[GUNSHOTS]
YOU KNOW,
YOU AMAZE ME, GRINGO.
YOU RUN GUNS, AND YOU DON'’’T
CARE WHO GETS KILLED,
SO LONG AS YOU GET PAID
AND YOU DON'’’T
HAVE TO WATCH.
MUST BE A TERRIBLE THING
TO KILL MEN
WITHOUT HATING THEM.
[GUNSHOTS]...
...[PLAYING MARIACHI SONG]
CLEAR, CLEAR, CLEAR.
PUT IT ON THE TABLE.
URBINA.
YES, MY CHIEF?
GET ME SOME WIRE
OUT OF THAT PIANO.
YES, IMMEDIATELY,
MY CHIEF.
HEY.
[PIANO WIRES SNAPPING]
WHERE YOU GOING?
I'’’VE BEEN TOLD
THE VILLAGERS,
THEY WILL FIGHT
WITH YOU NOW.
THE WOMEN?
THE WOMEN, THEY WILL
FOLLOW THE MEN.
YOU SEE?
BRING THIS OUTSIDE.
I'’’LL GET
THE MOUNT READY.
YES, CHIEF.
WHAT DID HE MEAN,
'YOU SEE?'
WELL,
IT IS LIKE THIS.
OUR CHIEF
LET THE COLORADOS
HAVE THEIR WAY
WITH THE VILLAGERS
FOR A WHILE
BEFORE WE ATTACKED.
YOU MEAN TO SAY HE WAS
HERE IN TIME TO PREVENT IT?
WELL...IT IS LIKE THIS.
THE VILLAGERS, WELL,
THEY LOVE MY CHIEF,
AND THEY LOVE MEXICO,
BUT THEY DIDN'’’T HATE H
ER ENEMIES ENOUGH TO FIGHT.
NOW THEY DO.
PABLO, MIGUEL,
ANTONIO, OUT.
[GUITAR PLAYING SOFTLY]
AY, YI. I SWEAR,
EVER SINCE
WE'’’VE BEEN FIGHTING,
MY HORSE GETS MORE
THAN I DO.
YOUR HORSE HAS MORE
TO OFFER THAN YOU DO.
AAH. UNH.
JUST A DAMN MINUTE--
Fierro: LET HER GO.
AH, WHAT THE HELL.
[MUSIC STOPS]
YOU GO OUTSIDE
AND DIE.
WHERE ARE
YOUR MANNERS?
WHAT HAPPENED?
THAT ONE
WITH THE FOUL MOUTH
WANTED HER
FOR HIS WOMAN.
SO?
SHE DIDN'’’T WANT HI
M. I TOOK CARE OF IT.
I'’’LL TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENED.
WHILE YOU WERE TEACHING
THE VILLAGERS
TO HATE THIS AFTERNOON,
SHE WAS BEING RAPED
BY CAPTAIN RAMIREZ,
SO SHE DOESN'’’T WANT
ANY MAN TONIGHT.
IT MAY JUST BE POSSIBLE
THAT SHE FEELS
THAT NO DECENT MAN
WANTS HER.
IT WASN'’’T JUST
THAT SOLDIER, YOU KNOW.
IT WAS YOU, TOO.
YOU'’’RE RESPONSIBLE.
YOU MIGHT JUST AS WELL
HAVE RAPED HER YOURSELF.
URBINA.
Urbina: YES, MY CHIEF?
GET A PRIEST.
WHAT PRIEST?
ANY PRIEST.
JUST GET ONE.
AND SO,
MY CHILDREN...
I PRONOUNCE YOU
MAN AND WIFE.
Men: ¡¡VIVA VILLA.
URBINA, FIERRO, LET'’’S,
UH, FIX THE CANNON.
[GUITAR PLAYING,
MAN SINGING]
GOOD MORNING.
NOT GOOD.
WHAT?
I SAID, 'NOT GOOD.'
WHAT'’’S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
DON'’’T YOU UNDERSTA
ND THE LANGUAGE OF MEN?
NOT GOOD.
HAVING A LITTLE TROUBLE
WITH THE WIFE?
THIS IS MY WIFE...
AND MY MISTRESS.
DON'’’T YOU
FORGET IT, GRINGO.
PLANE READY?
PLANE'’’S READY.
IS HE ALWAYS LIKE THAT
IN THE MORNING?
MY CHIEF RECEIVED
A TELEGRAM.
HE IS NOT
TO ATTACK PARRAL.
GENERAL HUERTA IS
TO ATTACK PARRAL. [SPITS]
BUT AREN'’’T THEY BO
TH FIGHTING FOR MADERO?
VILLA FIGHTS FOR MADERO
AND MEXICO.
HUERTA, I THINK
FIGHTS FOR...HUERTA.
AH.
Villa: WAIT.
FIERRO IS
GOING WITH YOU.
WHAT? NOW,
WAIT A MINUTE, CHIEF.
NOT WITH--
CHIEF, IT'’’S TOUGH ENOU
GH UP THERE AS IT IS.
NOW, YOU GO UP THERE ALONE,
YOU COULD FLY AWAY.
YOU TRY THAT
WITH FIERRO...
FIERRO WILL SHOOT YOU.
OH? AND
WITHOUT A PILOT,
WHAT'’’S FIERRO
GONNA DO?
FIERRO WILL SHOOT YOU.
FIERRO.
FIERRO,
YOU GO WITH HIM.
NO.
FIERRO...
WHAT DO
YOU MEAN 'NO'?
I MEAN...NO.
NO.
WELL, WHY NOT?
BECAUSE...
BECAUSE I DON'’’T THINK
HE IS A GOOD PILOT.
YOU'’’RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
BUT IT DOESN'’’T MATTER.
NO?
IF HE IS NO GOOD,
YOU SHOOT HIM
AND FLY IT YOURSELF.
ME?
WHY, ANY CHILD COULD
LEARN HOW TO FLY
ONE OF THESE THINGS.
AHH, YOU THINK SO?
YES.
YOU COULD FLY THIS?
OF COURSE.
THEN FLY IT.
HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MIND?
YOU CAN'’’T FLY THIS THING.
YOU TEACH ME. NOW.
CHIEF, IT TAKES YEARS
TO LEARN HOW TO FLY
AN AIRPLANE.
YOU'’’LL PROBABLY--
YOU'’’LL CRACK UP
BEFORE YOU GET IT
OFF THE GROUND.
T.
YOU BETTER HOPE I DON'’’
THIS MACHINE IS ALL
THAT KEEPS YOU ALIVE.
TEACH GOOD.
THAT'’’S FINE.
NOW,
WE'’’RE NOT WORRIED
ABOUT THE MAGNETO
ANYMORE, CHIEF.
NOW WE'’’RE LOOKING
AT THE ALTIMETER.
THE WHAT?
ALTIMETER.
THAT'’’S RIGHT.
ALTIMETER. RIGHT. HURRY.
I'’’LL TELL YOU WHAT
, CHIEF.
LET'’’S TRY THE WHOL
E THING ONE MORE TI--
NOW, GRINGO.
RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
MAGNETO SET?
Villa: YEAH.
[STOPS ENGINE]
HA HA. ¡¡VIVA VILLA.
[ALL CHEERING]...
...¡¡VIVA VILLA.
[FIRING GUNS IN THE AIR]
DON'’’T DO THIS.
I DON'’’T LIKE IT.
I WILL SHOOT YOU.
THIS IS PARRAL,
AND...
THIS IS PARRAL.
THIS IS
WHERE WE ARE.
AND RIGHT HERE...
THERE'’’S
A TROOP TRAIN
FULL OF TROOPS
COMING TOWARD US.
MAYBE 400.
WHO COOKED THIS?
ME, CHIEF.
NO, YOU DIDN'’’T.
NO, I DIDN'’’T.
COOK IT.
YEAH, CHIEF.
THIS IS PARRAL.
THIS IS US.
AND THE TRAIN...
HEADED NORTH.
YET THE COLORADOS KNOW
THAT HUERTA IS SOUTH.
NOW, THEY HAVE TO
HOLD PARRAL
TO CONTROL
ALL THE SUPPLY LINES.
YET THEY SEND A TRAIN
FULL OF TROOPS
ON A RIDE, NOT SOUTH
TOWARD HUERTA,
BUT NORTH TOWARD US.
WORRIES ME.
THEY ARE NOT AFRAID
OF HUERTA.
WORRIES ME.
MY ORDERS SAY DON'’’T ATTACK
PARRAL, LEAVE IT TO HUERTA.
HUERTA HAS AN ARMY
IN FRONT OF PARRAL,
YET HE WON'’’T MAKE
A MOVE TO TAKE IT.
THE ORDERS DON'’’T SAY Y
OU CAN'’’T TAKE THE TRAIN.
400 COLORADOS.
YOU'’’RE RIGHT, CHIEF.
THAT'’’S TOO MANY.
TOO MANY?
NOT WITH YOUR HELP.
MY HELP?
NO, NO, CHIEF.
I'’’VE DONE MY JOB.
IT'’’S ALL UP TO YOU
FROM NOW ON.
RAWHIDE, PIECES OF IRON,
DYNAMITE--
WE LIGHT THEM,
THROW THEM AT THE ENEMY,
BAROOM.
YOU'’’RE GOING TO DROP
THEM ON THE COLORADOS.
FROM THE AIR.
NO, NO, NO, CHIEF.
NOW, LET ME EXPLAIN
SOMETHING TO YOU.
AN AIRPLANE IS NOT
USED FOR FIGHTING.
IT'’’S JUST TO DETERMINE
THE SIZE
AND THE STRENGTH
OF THE ENEMY.
WHO SAID?
WELL, UH, IT JUST
ISN'’’T DONE, CHIEF.
WHY NOT?
WELL,
IN THE FIRST PLACE,
YOU GOTTA LIGHT
THOSE THINGS
IN THE AIR
IN AN OPEN COCKPIT.
SMOKE CIGARS.
WELL, EVEN IF YOU
COULD DO THAT,
THEY'’’D EXPLODE
LONG BEFORE
THEY HIT THE GROUND.
THERE'’’S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO
ABOUT THAT, CHIEF.
YES, THERE IS.
FLY LOW.
CHIEF, I SAID I'’’D FLY,
NOT FIGHT.
WHAT'’’S THE DIFFERENCE?
ABOUT $20,000.
IN ORDER TO DO THAT,
I'’’VE GOTTA FLY
REAL LOW.
THEY COULD KNOCK ME
DOWN WITH A ROCK.
THAT'’’S A PRETTY
EXPENSIVE AIRPLANE.
Fierro: WHY DO YOU ARGUE WITH HIM?
IT'’’S ALWAYS A QUESTION
OF MONEY WITH YOU,
ISN'’’T IT, GRINGO?
WELL, JUST LIKE YOU,
CHIEF.
FIRST A BANDIT,
AND THEN LATER
WHEN I BECOME
A BIG ENOUGH BANDIT,
THEY MIGHT CALL ME
A HERO,
AN IDEALIST,
JUST LIKE YOU.
YOU'’’LL GET PAID.
HOW MUCH?
25 PESOS
FOR EVERY COLORADO YOU KILL.
P.
THAT'’’S PRETTY CHEA
LOOK, GRINGO,
THIS IS A CHEAP WAR.
NEXT YEAR,
I'’’LL HAVE MORE MONEY,
WE'’’LL HAVE A BIGGER WAR.
ALL RIGHT?
OK.
ALL CLEAR.
COME ON.
[AIRPLANE APPROACHING]...
...¡¡RAÀÀPIDO.
Riders: ¡¡VIVA MEXICO.
¡¡VIVA--
Fina: BONITO.
YOU, YOU, AND YOU,
OVER HERE.
LINE UP.
GO LIKE THIS.
GOOD, GOOD,
VERY GOOD.
IT WORKS. 3 MORE.
NOW WE CAN TAKE PARRAL.
BUT, CHIEF, WITH
YOUR PERMISSION,
DIDN'’’T
GENERAL HUERTA SAY
NOT TO ATTACK
PARRAL?
NOT TO ATTACK PARRAL.
HE DIDN'’’T SAY
I COULDN'’’T GO THERE.
SEND A MESSAGE TO
THE HEADQUARTERS IN PARRAL.
WE ARE UNDER
HEAVY ATTACK BY...
PANCHO VILLA.
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO RETURN AT ONCE.
SIGNED JOSE OCHOA,
MAJOR, COMMANDING.
YOU SAW WHAT
HIS PLANE CAN DO.
I WANT YOU
TO MAKE FRIENDS WITH HIM.
HIS MOTHER
SHOULD HAVE SAT ON HIM
WHEN HE WAS BORN.
I DON'’’T LIKE HIM.
DO I LIKE HUERTA? NO.
BUT HE'’’S HELPING ME
WIN THE WAR.
I THINK.
HEY, FIERRO, I'’’M NOT
ASKING YOU TO MARRY HIM.
JUST MAKE HIM HAPPY.
WE DON'’’T NEED HIM.
NO?
NO.
YOU COULD FLY
THE PLANE.
ME?
SURE. ANY CHILD
COULD FLY IT.
I WILL DO
AS YOU SAY.
HEH.
JORGE.
YEAH, CHIEF?
WHO COOKED THIS?
ME, CHIEF.
.
NO, YOU DIDN'’’T
NO, I DIDN'’’T.
COOK IT.
[COINS CLINK]
HELLO, GRINGO.
FOR YOU.
VILLA SAYS
YOU DID VERY WELL.
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
ISN'’’T THIS
WHAT YOU FIGHT FOR?
I DON'’’T FIGHT FOR FUN.
MAYBE YOU THINK
IT'’’S NOT REAL.
LOOK.
IT'’’S REAL.
VERY REAL, MY FRIEND.
I MAY BE
A LOT OF THINGS,
D.
BUT I DON'’’T REALLY
BELIEVE I'’’M YOUR FRIEN
I'’’M TRYING
TO LIKE YOU, GRINGO.
STOP FOR INSPECTION.
INSPECT YOUR MOTHER.
SWITCH US TO THE STATION
IMMEDIATELY, LIEUTENANT.
AH, SWITCH, NO.
MY ORDERS
ARE TO INSPECT--
DO THAT FIRST,
PANCHO VILLA WILL BE
SHOOTING FURROWS
UP AND DOWN YOUR SPINE.
PANCHO VILLA?
PANCHO VILLA.
[SHOUTING IN SPANISH]...
...¡¡VIVA VILLA.
¡¡VIVA VILLA.
VILLA HAS TAKEN PARRAL.
HE DIDN'’’T ATTACK.
HE DIDN'’’T FIRE
A SINGLE SHOT.
THE CITY
FELL INTO HIS ARMS.
HEH HEH.
LIKE A WOMAN.
WHY DO YOU LOOK
SO UNHAPPY, MAJOR?
THIS IS A GREAT VICTORY
FOR OUR COUNTRY,
FOR PRESIDENT MADERO,
FOR THE REVOLUTION.
IS IT NOT?
YES, MY GENERAL.
THEN LOOK HAPPY.
COLONEL, DETACH
YOUR TROOP TRANSPORT CARS.
I WANT TO BE IN PARRAL
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
BUT GENERAL
HUERTA--
YES?
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
ISN'’’T IT DANGEROUS
TO FACE VILLA
WITHOUT YOUR ARMY?
DO YOU THINK
IT'’’S LESS DANGEROUS
TO FACE VILLA
WITH MY ARMY?
THE ONE PREDICTABLE THING
ABOUT PANCHO VILLA...
IS THAT HE WILL OBEY
PRESIDENT MADERO.
AND I HOLD ORDERS
FROM MADERO.
YES, MY GENERAL.
GRINGO.
YOU GET
THE MONEY?
I GOT IT, YEAH.
DON'’’T GO, GRINGO.
DON'’’T GO.
STAY WITH ME.
YOU FOUGHT WELL TODAY.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME,
SENORITA?
MY NAME IS EMILITA,
MY GENERAL.
EMILITA?
MM-HMM.
EMILITA AND PANCHO.
SOUNDS BEAUTIFUL.
THINK ABOUT IT.
CHIEF.
YOU KNOW, I THINK
I'’’M IN LOVE WITH YOU.
CHIEF.
BUT I HAVE A MAN,
MY GENERAL.
YOU'’’RE MARRIED?
NO.
HEY, CHIEF.
THEN IT MUST BE
THAT HE DOESN'’’T
LOVE YOU VERY MUCH.
BUT I LOVE YOU.
AND I WILL MARRY YOU.
URBINA, GET A PRIEST.
OHH.
[TALKING AT ONCE]
SEE, GRINGO,
ALL WOMEN
WANT TO GET MARRIED,
NO MATTER WHAT
THEY SAY, RIGHT?
NOW, YOU KNOW
AND I KNOW
THAT THESE MARRIAGES
DON'’’T MEAN A THING.
I DIDN'’’T KNOW.
BUT IT
MAKES THEM HAPPY.
IT'’’S THE 11th TIME FOR ME, I THINK.
THE ONLY THING I WANT TO DO
IS MAKE THEM HAPPY.
THERE IS NO HARM IN THAT.
AND SO NOW,
MY CHILDREN,
I PRONOUNCE YOU
MAN AND WIFE.
[CHEERING]...
...¡¡VIVA VILLA.
¡¡VIVA VILLA.
YOU REALLY GOTTA HAND IT
TO THAT FELLOW, THOUGH.
YES, SIR, YOU'’’VE REALLY
GOTTA HAND IT TO HIM.
HAND HIM WHAT?
PANCHO VILLA
IS A BANDIT, A BIGAMIST,
AND A BARBARIAN.
IT TAKES
MORE THAN DUMB LUCK
TO TURN THAT
INTO A NATIONAL HERO.
THE CHILI PICKER'’’S
GOT BRAINS.
I MAY HAVE STEPPED
INTO A MANURE PILE,
BUT I JUST MIGHT COME UP
WITH THE GOLDEN HORSESHOE.
ONE OF THESE DAYS, THAT MAN'’’S
GONNA OWN THIS COUNTRY.
HE DOESN'’’T WANT
TO OWN THE COUNTRY.
HE DOESN'’’T?
NO. HE WANTS
THE PEOPLE TO OWN IT.
AFTER ALL
YOU'’’VE BEEN THROUGH,
YOU STILL BELIEVE
THAT HE'’’S FOR THE PEOPLE?
N.
HE'’’S A GOOD MA
HOW '’’BOUT ME?
AM I A GOOD MAN, TOO?
YES.
WELL, I'’’LL TELL YOU
ONE THING, HONEY.
I'’’M AS GOOD A MAN AS VILLA,
AND THAT'’’S NOT SAYING
A HELL OF A LOT
FOR EITHER ONE OF US.
I DON'’’T CARE
WHAT YOU ARE.
Gen. Huerta: THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
WHY?
TELL HIM
TO STAND UP.
STAND UP WHEN YOU
ADDRESS THE GENERAL,
DAMN YOU.
I AM GENERAL HUERTA
OF MADERO'’’S REPUBLICAN ARMY.
GET COLONEL VILLA.
WHO?
COLONEL FRANCISCO VILLA.
HE IS TO
TURN PARRAL OVER TO ME,
BY ORDER
OF PRESIDENT MADERO.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
NOW, WHERE IS VILLA?
GET HIM.
OHH.
HE'’’S NOT HERE.
I WILL FIND HIM
FOR YOU, THOUGH.
.
BUT I WARN YOU,
HE'’’S VERY HARD TO FIND
I WILL TRY.
COME ON.
YOU'’’RE TAKING ME TO MADERO.
WHAT?
HURRY UP.
GET YOUR PANTS ON.
HOW?
WELL, FIRST ONE LEG,
THEN THE OTHER.
WHERE IS MADERO?
MEXICO CITY.
MEXICO...
WHAT ABOUT
THE GASOLINE?
DON'’’T WORRY ABOUT
THE GASOLINE.
WHERE IS HE?
IN THE ANTEROOM,
MY PRESIDENT.
EXCUSE ME.
PANCHO, MY FRIEND,
CONGRATULATIONS.
WONDERFUL,
WONDERFUL.
HAVE YOU EATEN?
ARE YOU HUNGRY?
NO, THANK YOU,
MY PRESIDENT.
I'’’LL EAT LATER.
COME WITH ME.
WELL...WHAT IS IT?
T.
DON'’’T MAKE ME DO I
DO WHAT?
DON'’’T MAKE ME
GIVE PARRAL
TO GENERAL HUERTA.
PANCHO, THIS IS DANGEROUS.
WHAT IS DANGEROUS?
YOUR CONFLICT WITH HUERTA.
HOW COULD I HAVE
A CONFLICT WITH HIM?
I HAVEN'’’T EVEN
SEEN THE MAN.
NOR DID ANYONE ELSE
IN PARRAL,
UNTIL AFTER
I TOOK THE CITY.
THEN HE CAME.
CAME.
PANCHO, PLEASE DON'’’T
MISUNDERSTAND ME.
I'’’M HAPPY YOU'’’RE HERE,
VERY HAPPY, BUT...
YOU HAVE JUST CREATED
A TERRIBLE PROBLEM.
OH? YOU DON'’’T
WANT PARRAL?
OF COURSE I DO.
E,
BUT WHEN HUERTA FINDS OUT
THAT YOU'’’VE COME DIRECTLY TO M
HE WILL THINK THAT YOU AND I
ARE PLOTTING BEHIND HIS BACK...
AND THAT'’’S DANGEROUS.
WHO THE HELL
IS HUERTA, ANYWAY?
DID HE WIN PARRAL?
NO.
HE'’’S NO GOOD.
HE DRINKS.
HE'’’S NOT FOR YOU,
JUST FOR HIMSELF.
DON'’’T PUT ME
UNDER HIS COMMAND.
GENERAL HUERTA IS HEAD
OF THE REPUBLICAN ARMY.
WHAT ELSE COULD I DO?
I GAVE HIM MY WORD.
WHAT ABOUT
YOUR WORD TO ME?
DON'’’T YOU
OWE ME SOMETHING?
I TOOK PARRAL
FOR YOU, NOT HUERTA.
NO NATION
CAN HAVE 2 ARMIES.
UNDER HUERTA, ONE ARMY
IS ONE TOO MANY.
WHAT IS IT THAT YOU HAVE
AGAINST HUERTA?
I DON'’’T THINK
HE'’’S LOYAL TO YOU.
YOU PERSONALLY KNOW
THAT GENERAL HUERTA
PLANS TO OVERTHROW
THE REVOLUTION?
NO, MY PRESIDENT.
HAS ANYONE INDICATED TO YOU,
EVEN BY RUMOR,
THAT HE HAS SUCH PLANS?
NO, MY PRESIDENT.
THEN WHAT?
COME ON, COME ON, COME ON.
SPEAK UP.
GET OUT OF HERE.
GET BACK TO YOUR PEOPLE.
FACTS.
I WANT FACTS.
GET OUT
OF THIS FANCY PALACE.
GIVE ME PROOF.
I CANNOT GIVE
YOU PROOF, BUT I KNOW.
I CAN SMELL IT. I KNOW.
PANCHO, DO YOU THINK THAT...
THAT I AM BETRAYING
THE REVOLUTION?
NO, BUT...
HOW CAN YOU TRUST HUERTA
AND NOT ME?
YOU'’’RE MY PRESIDENT.
I ASK YOU
ONLY ONE THING:
DON'’’T TRUST HIM.
EVERYONE IS
NOT LIKE YOU.
MY FRIEND, IT'’’S VERY MUCH
BETTER THAT I DIE A FOOL,
TRUSTING TOO MUCH,
THAN LIVE A TYRANT,
TRUSTING NO ONE AT ALL.
MEXICO'’’S HAD
ENOUGH OF THOSE.
OH, PANCHO, THIS IS
JUST LIKE THE OLD DAYS.
ONCE AGAIN,
I'’’M ASKING FOR YOUR HELP.
IT'’’S ESSENTIAL TO ME
TO HAVE YOUR PROMISE
THAT YOU'’’LL OBEY
GENERAL HUERTA
AS YOU OBEY ME.
YOU'’’RE TOO GOOD.
THAT'’’S NEITHER
HERE NOR THERE.
HAVE I YOUR PROMISE?
YES, MY PRESIDENT.
I PROMISE.
AND SO, GENTLEMEN,
TOMORROW AT FIRST LIGHT,
WE WILL INITIATE
OUR ATTACK ON CONEJOS.
YOU, COLONEL VILLA,
WILL HAVE THE HONOR
OF LEADING YOUR FORCES
ON THE PRIMARY ASSAULT.
MAJOR EBANIAS WILL HOLD
THE RIGHT WING,
MAJOR ESCOBAR, THE LEFT.
AH, THIS IS THE LAST
COLORADO STRONGHOLD
IN THE NORTH,
AND I WANT YOU
TO UNDERSTAND
I WILL NOT TOLERATE
ONE STEP BACKWARD.
HAS ANYONE EVER KNOWN ME
TO TAKE A STEP BACKWARD?
COLONEL VILLA, THERE ARE
OTHER OFFICERS IN THIS ROOM
BESIDES YOURSELF.
OR DON'’’T YOU THINK SO?
NOW, SINCE YOU'’’RE
LEADING THE ATTACK,
DON'’’T YOU
THINK IT ADVISABLE
TO GET UNDER WAY IMMEDIATELY,
COLONEL VILLA?
NO.
NO?
NO. IF I RIDE
IN DAYLIGHT,
THE DUST
WILL GIVE ME AWAY,
THE ENEMY WILL KNOW
I'’’M COMING.
I SHOULD RIDE
AT NIGHT.
MY DEAR COLONEL, YOU, UH...
YOU ARE LAYING SIEGE
TO THE TOWN...
NOT ROBBING IT.
YOU WILL LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
GENTLEMEN,
I FULLY EXPECT
COLONEL VILLA'’’S FORCES
TO DO THEIR DUTY...
TO THE LAST MAN.
DO I MAKE MYSELF CLEAR?
FIRE.
CENTER, HO.
COME ON.
UHH.
AAH.
[MEN SHOUTING]...
...[HORSE WHINNIES]
BARBED WIRE.
LET'’’S GO.
GO? WHERE?
CAN'’’T YOU SEE?
VILLA'’’S GOING
TO BE OVERRUN.
OF COURSE HE IS.
THERE'’’S NOTHING
WE CAN DO ABOUT IT.
LOOK AT THAT CITY.
IT'’’S SUICIDE
FLYING OVER THOSE GUNS.
YOU CAN SHOOT ME
IF YOU WANT TO.
I'’’M NOT GOING ANYPLACE.
NOT TILL WE GET SOME SUPPORT
FROM OUR OWN GUNS.
YOU WAIT HERE,
GRINGO, FOR ME.
[DISTANT GUNFIRE]
RETREAT. RETREAT.
COLORADOS ARE LINING UP
TO CHARGE.
WHY AREN'’’T YOU
FLYING WITH THE GRINGO?
HE TELLS ME IT'’’S SUICIDE,
UNLESS WE GET
ARTILLERY SUPPORT.
I THINK SO, TOO.
WHAT ARE THEY
WAITING FOR?
WHY DON'’’T THEY GIVE ME
ARTILLERY SUPPORT?
THAT STUPID
ARTILLERY OFFICER
SAYS THAT HE'’’S
GOT ORDERS
TO WAIT FOR YOU
TO COUNTERATTACK.
HUERTA.
HUERTA IS WAITING FOR ME
TO BE OVERRUN.
URBINA.
SPREAD YOUR MEN.
PREPARE FOR A CAVALRY CHARGE.
HYAH.
WELL...
HE COULDN'’’T HA
VE HELPED ANYWAY.
CHARGE.
[ALL CHEER]
CONTINUE THE ATTACK.
URBINA...
THE COUNTERATTACK.
HA HA. EEH.
[ALL SHOUTING]
COME BACK HERE.
REFORM RANKS.
¡¡VIVA VILLA.
[GUNFIRE]...
...[ENGINE SPUTTERS]...
...[ENGINE DIES]
VIVA VILLA.
[MEN SHOUTING]
RETREAT.
[GUNFIRE]
STILL ALIVE, EH, GRINGO?
MY GENERAL, VILLA'’’S FORCES
HAVE SECURED
THE OUTER PERIMETER.
OUR MEN ARE REGROUPING
ALONG SECONDARY LINES
OF DEFENSE.
VILLA IN THE TRENCHES?
WELL...
FOR ONCE, IT LOOKS LIKE
WE FORCED THAT BANDIT
INTO OUR KIND OF WAR.
¡¡VIVA VILLA.
THROUGH THE WALL.
[BOOM]
WHERE IS THAT
COMING FROM?
I DON'’’T KNOW,
MY GENERAL.
[GUNFIRE]
UHH.
[GUNFIRE IN DISTANCE]...
...[SPLASH]
AAH.
Crowd, chanting: ¡¡VIVA VILLA.
¡¡VIVA VILLA.
¡¡VIVA VILLA...
I'’’M SORRY, MY GENERAL.
WE DID EVERYTHING
BUT SHOOT HIM OURSELVES.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
COME IN.
Villa: SOMETHING WRONG,
COLONEL FUENTES?
SPEAK UP.
GENERAL HUERTA WANTS
TO SEE YOU AT HIS QUARTERS
IMMEDIATELY, COLONEL VILLA.
ALL RIGHT.
AS SOON AS I'’’VE FINISH
ED MY SWEAT BATH.
THAT'’’S NOT SOON ENOUGH.
YOU MUST BE CRAZY.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
'THAT'’’S NOT SOON ENOUGH'?
YOU'’’RE UNDER ARREST,
COLONEL VILLA.
WE WANT TO SEND
A MESSAGE.
NO, NO.
GENERAL--
TO PRESIDENT
FRANCISCO MADERO...
DEAR MR. PRESIDENT,
THE WORST SON OF A BITCH
IN YOUR ARMY
HAS JUST ARRESTED
PANCHO VILLA.
HE SAYS HE IS GOING
TO SHOOT HIM IN THE MORNING.
IF YOU DON'’’T DO SOMETHING
ABOUT CHANGING HUERTA'’’S MIND,
I WILL.
RESPECTFULLY...
MAJOR RODOLFO FIERRO.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WRITING DOWN
THE MESSAGE, SIR.
YOU DON'’’T WASTE TI
ME WRITING.
JUST SEND IT
THE WAY I TOLD YOU.
YES, SIR.
YOU MAKE SURE
HE KEEPS SENDING.
YOU TELL VILLA
I SENT A MESSAGE TO MADERO,
BUT NOT TO COUNT ON MADERO,
ONLY ON US.
YOU TELL HIM
IF HE GIVES THE WORD,
WE WILL GET HIM OUT.
THE GIRL AND YOUR MONEY
WILL BE IN CHUPADERO.
WE WILL ALL MEET THERE.
I WANT TO SEE
THE GENERAL.
GENERAL, WHA--
UH... PARDON ME.
LOOK, GENERAL,
I LOSTMYAIRPLANE
INYOURWAR, AND ONE
OF YOUR OFFICERS
PROMISED TO PAY
FOR IT.
CLOSE THE DOOR.
WHICH OFFICER?
YOU KNOW VERY WELL
WHICHOFFICER--
COLONEL VILLA.
NOW, IF YOU DON'’’T MIND
, I'’’D LIKE TO SEE HIM
AND GET THIS MATTER
TAKEN CARE OF.
AH, YES.
AH, YES. YES.
AH, VERY WELL,
MR. ARNOLD.
BUT YOU NEGLECT
TO MENTION ONE THING.
IT SEEMS THE AIRPLANE
WASN'’’T YOURS TO BEGIN WITH.
COGNAC, MR. ARNOLD?
I BELIEVE I WILL, YES.
ORDERLY, A COGNAC
FOR MR. ARNOLD.
NOW, TOMORROW MORNING
YOU'’’LL BE PROVIDED
WITH A MILITARY ESCORT
TO THE AMERICAN CONSULATE
IN LAREDO.
FROM THERE, THEY WILL
CONDUCT YOU BACK TO EL PASO,
WHERE YOU WILL ANSWER TO CHARGES
OF GRAND THEFT, AMONG OTHERS.
TO YOUR HEALTH,
MR. ARNOLD.
I, UH--I DON'’’T SUPPOSE
THERE'’’S ANYTHING I CAN
SAY THAT MIGHT, UH...
I'’’M AFRAID NOT.
I'’’M DOUBLY SORRY,
MR. ARNOLD. I ASSURE YOU,
WE APPRECIATE ALL YOU
HAVE DONE FOR THE REVOLUTION,
BUT YOU MUST ALSO APPRECIATE
HOW IMPORTANT IT IS
THAT I, UH...
OR MY GOVERNMENT, THAT IS,
MAINTAIN GOOD RELATIONS
WITH THE UNITED STATES.
YOU CAN SEE THAT,
CAN'’’T YOU?
OH, YES, I CAN SEE THAT.
GOOD.
YOU'’’RE UNDER ARREST.
HEY, GRINGO...
THAT'’’S ME.
LEARNING PRETTY FAST...
PRETTY FAST.
YEAH,
YOU'’’RE ALL RIGHT.
YOU'’’LL BE ABLE
TO WRITE YOUR WILL
BEFORE THEY
SHOOT YOUR TAIL
ALL OVER
THAT PARADE GROUND.
YOU'’’VE GOT TO KNOW
SOMETHING I DON'’’T.
ANSWER ME.
YOU MADE A DEAL
WITH HUERTA, HUH?
HE WON'’’T LET IT HAPPEN.
OH, HE WON'’’T?
HOW?
HE WON'’’T.
[SIGHS] CHIEF...
MADERO IS A LONG WAY
FROM HERE.
Y.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
HE'’’S IN MEXICO CIT
NOW, I KNOW THAT YOU
AND MR. MADERO
ARE THE BEST
OF FRIENDS,
NOBODY HAS ANY MORE
RESPECT FOR THE MAN
THAN I DO, BUT,
UH, IT WOULDN'’’T
BE THE FIRST TIME
IN THIS REVOLUTION
THAT SOMEBODY FORGOT
TO PROTECT A FRIEND,
NOW, WOULD IT?
GRINGO, YOU'’’RE DUMB.
ALL RIGHT.
I MAY BE.
BUT YOU THINK ABOUT
WHAT I JUST SAID, HUH?
[SIGHS]
MADERO WON'’’T PROTECT ME
JUST BECAUSE HE'’’S A FRIEND.
NO?
OF COURSE NOT.
NOW, TO BE SHOT,
I HAVE TO BE SENTENCED.
TO BE SENTENCED,
I HAVE TO BE TRIED.
TO BE TRIED,
I HAVE TO BE ACCUSED
OF HAVING DONE
SOMETHING WRONG.
NOW, ALL THIS
TAKES A LONG TIME.
BESIDES, I HAVEN'’’T
DONE ANYTHING WRONG.
BUT EVEN IF I HAD,
MADERO WOULD PROTECT ME,
BECAUSE HE WOULDN'’’T WANT A MAN
TO BE DEPRIVED OF HIS RIGHTS.
HE WON'’’T STAND FOR INJUSTICE,
SO HUERTA CANNOT
SHOOT ME TOMORROW.
NOW DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH, I UNDERSTAND.
D.
I UNDERSTAND
YOU'’’RE OUT OF YOUR MIN
CHIEF...
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS TO GET THE WORD
TO YOUR MEN,
AND THEY'’’LL HAVE Y
OU OUTTA HERE.
IT'’’S THAT SIMPLE.
IT'’’S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
WELL, YOU CAN'’’T FIGHT
FOR THE REVOLUTION
IF YOU'’’RE DEAD.
I'’’M FIGHTING FOR IT
RIGHT NOW, HERE.
THIS IS UNJUST,
TO DEPRIVE ME OF MY LIBERTY.
YOUR LIBERTY?
WHAT'’’S THAT?
'LIBERTY IS THE RESPECT
FOR THE RIGHTS OF OTHERS.'
THAT IS WHAT
BENITO JUAREZ SAID.
THAT IS WHAT MADERO
BELIEVES IN.
THAT'’’S WHAT WE'’’VE
BEEN FIGHTING FOR.
NOW, IF I WALK OUT OF HERE
WITHOUT A TRIAL,
I DENY THAT
AND BEHAVE LIKE A BANDIT.
WELL, JUST WHEN HAVE YOU
STOPPED BEING A BANDIT?
WHAT ABOUT
THAT LITTLE CAPER
UP IN CONEJOS
THE OTHER DAY?
THOSE MEN WERE TRAITORS,
AND HUERTA KNOWS IT VERY WELL--
THERE'’’S NO POINT
IN TALKING ABOUT IT.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT ME,
CHIEF?
HOW '’’BOUT ME?
I'’’M ONE OF YOUR MEN,
TOO, RIGHT?
SOMETHING
HAPPENS TO YOU,
THEY MAY
AS WELL SHOOT ME.
I'’’M DEPRIVED OF 20 YEA
RS OF MY LIBERTY.
I'’’VE GOT NOTHING.
I'’’VE GOT NO--NO PLANE,
NO MONEY.
I WIND UP WITH NOTHING.
GRINGO...
YOU NEVER
DID HAVE ANYTHING.
YOU HAVE LIVED
JUST FOR YOURSELF,
NOT FOR A CAUSE,
NOT EVEN FOR A WOMAN.
WHY, YOU HYPOCRITICAL,
FATHEADED GREASEBALL,
DON'’’T YOU
TELL ME WHO I AM.
UNH.
WHAT IS IT, COLONEL?
THE GRINGO.
THE GRINGO IS MAD.
Man: MARCH.
STAND HERE,
COLONEL VILLA.
.
Man:
LET'’’S GO...HUP
FORWARD...MARCH.
Second man: FORWARD. MARCH.
LEFT, RIGHT.
DETAIL...
HALT.
LEFT...TURN.
STANDARD...EAST.
IMPORTANT.
DETAIL, A-TEN...HUT.
[DRUMROLL]
READY...
HUT.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
TAKE AIM...
HUT.
I SAID HOLD IT.
ORDER...
ARMS.
AT EASE.
WHAT IS IT,
COLONEL VILLA?
IF I AM GOING TO BE SHOT,
I WANT IT DONE
BY MY OWN MEN.
MY COLONEL, YOUR MEN,
THEY'’’VE BEEN SENT
TO OTHER UNITS,
AND SOME
OF YOUR OFFICERS,
THEY ARE UNDER
TEMPORARY ARREST.
MAJOR FIERRO
IS WANTED FOR MURDER.
BELIEVE ME...
IT WASN'’’T MY IDEA,
MY CHIEF.
Gen. Huerta: COLONEL FUENTES?
YES, MY GENERAL?
COLONEL VILLA
COMMANDS NOTHING NOW,
CERTAINLY
NOT YOUR FIRING SQUAD.
CARRY OUT MY ORDERS.
BUT WHY?
YOU HAVE TO
TELL ME WHY.
DETAIL...
A-TEN...HUT.
I AM FRANCISCO VILLA.
I CANNOT BE KILLED
FOR NOTHING.
Col. Fuentes: READY...
HUT.
IF YOU ARE
GOING TO SHOOT ME,
YOU ARE GOING TO
SENTENCE ME FIRST...
EVEN IF I HAVE TO
CHOKE IT OUT OF YOU.
STOP HIM,
OR YOU'’’LL ALL BE SHOT.
THIS IS WRONG.
YOU KNOW THIS IS WRONG.
MADERO SENT WORD.
WHO SAID?
I DO.
COLONEL VILLA,
ARE YOU GOING TO STAND
AND TAKE YOUR EXECUTION
LIKE A MEXICAN,
OR SHALL I HAVE YOU SHOT
ON THE GROUND?
HEY, BOY.
Villa: COME HERE.
KEEP THIS.
FORGIVE ME, MY GENERAL.
FOR WHAT?
BE A GOOD BOY.
SHOOT STRAIGHT.
GO ON.
DETAIL...
A-TEN...
HUT.
Col. Fuentes: READY...
STOP.
'THE PRISONER IS TO PROCEED
UNDER HEAVY ESCORT...
'DIRECTLY TO MEXICO CITY,
'WHERE HE WILL FACE
A FULL INQUIRY...
'REGARDING
THE CONEJOS HANGING...
'AND WHATEVER SUBSEQUENT
COURT-MARTIAL PROCEEDINGS
DEEMED NECESSARY.'
'FRANCISCO MADERO...
'PRESIDENTE.'
THE PRISONER
IS TO TALK TO NO ONE.
HE IS TO BE DENIED BED
AND FOOD AND BARBER.
AND IF HE ESCAPES,
THE RESPONSIBLE OFFICERS
AND MEN WILL BE SHOT.
THE PRISONER...
LEFT TURN...
HUT.
HEY, BOY...
SAY, HOW WOULD
YOU FELLAS
LIKE TO MAKE
SOME MONEY?
NO, REALLY.
I'’’M RICH, YOU KNOW
, VERY RICH.
IF YOU ARE SO RICH, HOW COME
YOU ARE GOING TO JAIL?
RICH GRINGOS
DON'’’T GO TO JAIL.
SOMETIMES, THEY DIE,
BUT THEY
DON'’’T GO TO JAIL.
I'’’M NOT RICH.
I JUST FLAT LIED
TO YOU.
I JUST WANT
TO SEE MY GIRL.
THAT'’’S ALL.
SHE LIVES RIGHT UP HERE
IN CHUPADERO.
I'’’LL PROBABLY
NEVER SEE HER AGAIN.
GO TO CHUPADERO.
FINA?
FINA.
WHERE ARE FIERRO
AND URBINA?
THE HILLS.
HUERTA'’’S MEN
ARE EVERYWHERE.
WHERE'’’S THE MONEY?
HERE.
I DON'’’T SUPPOSE
YOU, UH, GENTLEMEN
COULD GIVE US
A MOMENT ALONE,
COULD YOU?
FOR JUST A MINUTE,
GRINGO.
WE'’’LL BE RIGHT OUTSIDE.
JUST IN CASE
YOU NEED US.
OK, WHERE IS IT?
HONEY, LOOK, VILLA'’’S
IN JAIL IN MEXICO CITY.
I'’’M TRYING TO STAY
OUT OF JAIL IN EL PASO.
ALL I WANT'’’S
WHAT THEY OWE ME.
NOW, COME ON.
LET'’’S HURRY.
THEY TOLD ME THAT SOME
OF THAT WAS TO BE USED
FOR THE REVOLUTION
AND MADERO.
I'’’M TAKING IT ALL.
WELL, I CAN'’’T JUST STAND HERE
AND COUNT IT, CAN I?
SAY I LEAVE IT. YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY USE IT FOR?
TO SHOOT UP A LOT OF PEONS
WHO COULDN'’’T CARE LESS
WHICH DOG'’’S ON TOP ANYWAY.
YOU DON'’’T WANT THAT,
DO YOU?
SAY GOOD-BYE NOW, GRINGO.
LOOK, I, UH...
I'’’LL TRY TO COME BACK
AS SOON AS I GET THIS
STRAIGHTENED OUT.
WHAT FOR?
YOU HAVE WHAT YOU WANT.
GO. FIND SOMEONE ELSE.
I WILL.
COME ON, GRINGO. LET'’’S GO.
HOWDY, LEE.
HEY, DAVE,
WHAT'’’S DOIN'’’?
NOTHIN'’’ MUCH.
GET THIS FUZZ OFF ME,
WILL YA, PARTNER?
OH, HEY, DID YOU HEAR
WHAT JUST HAPPENED
DOWN IN MEXICO?
WHAT'’’S THAT?
PRESIDENT MADERO...
THEY SHOT HIM UP.
KILL HIM?
THEY SURE DID.
ONE OF HIS OWN
GENERALS, TOO.
GENERAL, UH...
HUERTA.
AND YOU KNOW WHO'’’S
THE NEW PRESIDENT OF MEXICO?
THE SAME GENERAL HUERTA.
PRETTY FUNNY GAMES
THEY PLAY DOWN THERE, HUH?
WHAT ABOUT VILLA?
YOU HEAR ANYTHING
ABOUT HIM--PANCHO VILLA?
YEAH, YEAH. HE, UH...
HE ESCAPED FROM JAIL
IN MEXICO CITY.
HUERTA HAS PRACTICALLY
HIS ENTIRE ARMY
LOOKING FOR HIM.
MUST WANT HIM
PRETTY BAD, HUH?
YEAH, I GUESS HE DOES.
HEY, LEE.
LEE, IS THIS VILLA
A FRIEND OF YOURS?
YEAH, I KNOW HIM.
WELL, AND THEN I HAD TO
FIND SOMETHING TO WEAR
WITH THE NEW JEWELED
COLLAR DADDY BOUGHT ME.
AND I WAS SO WORRIED
ABOUT FINDING EXACTLY
THE RIGHT THING,
WELL, IN EL PASO,
ESPECIALLY,
BUT THEN
I SAW THIS GOWN.
IT WAS IN A LITTLE SHOP
RIGHT CATTY-CORNER
FROM THE HOTEL,
OF ALL PLACES.
OH, IT'’’S MARVELOUS.
T,
IT'’’S PITCH-BLACK VELVE
YARDS AND YARDS OF IT,
AND THE BODICE IS ALL
STUDDED WITH GARNETS,
AND, OH, I JUST LOVE IT.
IT FEELS SO...
SO SENSUOUS.
DON'’’T YOU
JUST LOVE VELVET?
VERY MUCH.
OF COURSE,
IT WAS OUTRAGEOUSLY
EXPENSIVE,
BUT I JUST
HAD TO BUY IT. ANYWAY,
DADDY SAYS THERE'’’S GON
NA BE A WAR IN EUROPE SOON,
AND THE PRICE OF BEEF
WILL GO UP,
AND SO WE'’’LL
BE VERY RICH.
HEY, DARLIN'’’...
THOSE MEN,
THEY'’’RE ANNOYING ME.
HMM?
OVER THERE.
LEE, DARLIN'’’,
TURN AROUND.
YOU DON'’’T MEAN TO SAY
YOU KNOW THOSE PEOPLE?
DO YOU KNOW
MR. ARNOLD?
OH, UH,
VERY WELL.
UH, ONE MOMENT,
PLEASE.
I'’’M TERRIBLY SORRY
TO BOTHER YOU, MR. ARNOLD,
BUT THOSE MEN--
IT'’’S ALL RIGHT
, EUGENE.
YES, SIR.
YOU'’’RE NOT GONNA INVIT
E THEM TOTHISTABLE.
HELLO, CHIEF.
Urbina: HELLO, GRINGO.
HOW ARE YA?
GOOD.
WE'’’VE MISSED YOU.
YOU IN TOWN
FOR LONG?
I DON'’’T THINK SO.
WE'’’RE GETTING READY
TO GO HOME NOW.
WE'’’D LIKE YOU
TO COME WITH US.
AND DO WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
'DO WHAT'?
TAKE IT.
GET RID OF HUERTA.
YOU SEE, WE THOUGHT...
WITH OUR MONEY THAT YOU'’’VE
BEEN KEEPING FOR US,
WE WILL BUY GUNS.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE,
CHIEF.
WAIT A MINUTE.
IT'’’S ALL OVER.
CAN'’’T YOU SEE THAT?
THE REVOLUTION
IS FINISHED.
YOU GAVE IT
YOUR BEST SHOT, CHIEF,
BUT AFTER ALL, HUERTA'’’
S SITTING IN THAT PALACE,
AND MADERO IS DEAD,
AND THERE'’’S NO WAY
IN THE WORLD
YOU THREE ARE GONNA
CHANGE THAT. NO WAY.
WE WOULD LIKE OUR MONEY,
GRINGO.
[SHOUTING] I WOULDN'’’T
GIVE YOU A D--
I WOULDN'’’T GIVE YOU
A DIME.
WHAT FOR?
TO GO DOWN THERE AND SHOOT
UP A LOT OF YOUR OWN PEOPLE
JUST SO SOME OTHER DICTATOR
CAN CALL HIMSELF PRESIDENT?
MADERO WAS NO DICTATOR.
PANCHO...
DON'’’T ARGUE
WITH HIM.
SHOOT HIM,
AND LET'’’S GO.
NO.
NO. WE DON'’’T
DO THAT ANYMORE.
WELL...
GOOD-BYE, GRINGO.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE,
CHIEF.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
FIRST...
TAKE MEXICO CITY,
THEN FIND
ANOTHER MADERO.
WELL,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT I HAVE NEVER
BEEN SO HUMILIATED
IN ALL MY LIFE.
TO LEAVE ME HERE,
SITTING ALONE,
AND IN FRONT
OF ALL EL PASO.
MARSHA, DO ME A FAVOR,
WILL YA?
JUST SHUT UP.
[GASPS]
MAY I HAVE THE CHECK,
PLEASE?
I'’’D LIKE TO WRITE YOU
A RECEIPT, UH...
MR. ELLMORE.
HOW MUCH
FOR THE HORSES?
UH...YOU GO AHEAD
AND BE MY GUESTS.
GET ON THOSE HORSES AND GO.
NO. WE PAY.
WHEN I GET
TO MEXICO CITY,
I'’’LL SEND YOU
THE MONEY.
HOW MUCH?
WELL, IF THAT'’’S THE WAY
YOU FEEL ABOUT IT,
HOW ABOUT $35 FOR ALL
OF '’’EM, EVERYTHING,
THE WHOLE KIT AND CABOODLE?
NOT ENOUGH.
35 EACH.
YOU'’’LL BE HEARING
FROM ME.
PANCHO VILLA.
[WHISTLING A TUNE]...
...[AIRPLANE APPROACHES]
HA HA.
YEE HA.