The pudd ng's not to their taste.
A lot of things are not to their taste.
You don't understand me, l think.
l want them to like everything
we do for them.
They're waitng.
You shou dn't sing songs ke that.
What songs?
Black songs.
Whity!
We should have him put to sleep.
There are so many ways today.
lnjectons. . .
Just a pr ck of the needle. . .
He wouldn't feel a th ng. . .
and he'd fal asleep. . .
forever.
Look.
He's fond of you, Kate.
Dead, . . .
you'd be a sweet memory.
Alive, . . .
you're just a nu sance, a useless creature.
He's a N cholson.
Yes, you're rght.
Forgive me.
You'll learn to get along wth us.
l. . .
l beg your pardon, Massa.
l. . . thank you, Massa.
What's that nigger doing here?
Who is he?
He's the Nicholson's butler.
What does that mean?
He's the wealth est
rancher round here.
That's enough.
Come on, boys.
Or are you ye ow?
Play!
Throw him out!
Do not kiss me Senora
Someone might come.
Then Garcia won't be happy anymore.
No one can disturb us.
you foolish Mexican.
Only Davie. . .
and not even someone l ke you
need be afra d of him.
Now tell me. . .
What does my husband have?
ls t ser ous?
Soon he' die.
Everyth ng eaten up.
All rotten, Senora.
l love you.
Oh, ove you!
Beat me, beat me!
Crazy!
Ben!
Whi. . .ty.
Yes?
You'd. . . ike to be rich?
That wouldn't bef t me.
Kill my father, hmm?
Oh, yes.
Yes, sir.
The doctor says you're dy ng.
Don't ook at me like that, Ben.
ls t my fault. . .
you're sick?
We'l make the time
you've got left. . .
just great, won't we Ben?
You must think
of my future. Ben, hmm?
One can get used
to so many things.
Have you been working, Frank?
l was riding out
over my father's and.
Whity's made a number
of suggest ons. Katherine.
The blacks should be g ven
more rights.
Then they wouldn't get up to. . .
so much m sch ef.
l. . . .
- Yes?
l think so, too.
We need the blacks to do the work.
And if there were trouble. . .
t wouldn't be good. . .
for the work, l mean, would it?
l've acqua nted myse f. . .
with deas like that, too.
lt mght be. . .
useful later, Pa.
- Close the door.
l shall implement
some of these ideas.
Of course, Pa.
Come here.
To hell with you, baby!
Who was that?
A customer. dar ing.
Anything wrong?
No. . .Why?
Just a feeling l had.
Let's go East. . .
the two of us.
Why not?
l'm content here.
Davie spied on us last night.
Ben couldn't get it up.
That's why he's so mad.
Whip me instead of him, Massa.
OK. Strip off!
Ye l, Whity! Yell!
lt's better you do what l want.
He's taking a beatng for Dave.
Crazy!
That was pretty good, Whity.
Yes, that's it.
Here you are.
Bye.
Has my telegram arrived?
Would you mind?
-Are you n a hurry?
Yes.
You're n luck. lt's arr ved.
Here.
She believe it mmed ate y.
Her eyes ight up.
Then she pull me onto bed
and scream should beat her.
Now l get the money.
l play your doctor well?
Oh yes.
And then?
Then he boasted that he had. . .
raped my wife.
ls this your husband?
Assass n!
Mr. N cholson's tell ng the truth.
l. . . heard it a l.
lt' l soon hea .
Ben Nichoson's a very sick man.
He hasn't much onger to live.
Then there'll be no one in charge
of the Nicholson estate.
Or do you th nk Frank,
or even Davie wou d be capable?
l reckon. . .
the two of us. . .
wou d be able to. . .
We're tough.
You must get rid of Frank.
Nigger's whore!
My mother is a whore.
lt's crazy!
He's go ng to her now.
l knew you'd come.
You called. madam?
Br ng me a g ass of water.
With ice.
Yes, madam.
You called?
Give me a candy, Whity.
And quick about t.
Thank you. Whity.
l don't want one after all.
Very we , madam.
You called?
l'd l ke a candy too, Whity.
Thanks, Whity.
l love you. l love you.
Oh, 'm sorry.
l knocked the bell over.
l don't understand you.
You don't want to be free.
You like t when they beat you.
You swine.
Servile ...
and dependent.
You don't deserve any better.
Come and ie down with me.
l can pay if you like.
Get dressed and get out.
Whity,
do l appeal to you?
Come here, my boy.
Comb my ha r.
But you mustn't hurt me.
Don't l have soft hands?
Why haven't you ki ed my father?
Stay where you are,
you damned nigger!
Stop that.
You must be crazy.
Letting a N choson pee potatoes.
He likes doing it.
Don't forget ...
you're a Nichoson. too.
l'm a n gger.
You called?
Frank was just here.
You insulted him.
Since when may a black ...
nsult a white man?
You're the curse of this family.
You know you have to be punished.
Yes, deserve t.
My God. he's crying.
He's really crying.
A human emotion.
And always thought
you backs weren't human beings.
You're right.
We're not human be ngs.
Why haven't you ki ed Frank?
l implored you to.
Didn't mpore you?
We wanted to share the property.
Just think it over.
Who else wou d g ve
the likes of you ...
a chance like that?
l can't do it, m ady.
She'll be down at once. m ster.
Hello, Ben.
- Hello. Dave.
Can l bring you a sherry?
That'd be n ce.
Take a seat!
- Thanks.
How are things
with your young wife?
Everyth ng sti OK?
l... l'm getting a divorce soon.
No...
l knew it.
That woman's a she-devil.
You can go now.
Tell me all about it.
Katherine ...
believes l'm about to die.
She's just waitng
to inherit the estate.
We'l keep her n suspense
a bit longer.
Then wham.
She'll be out on her ear.
No one cheats a N choson
and gets away with it.
You want to keep her n suspense?
No. That's marveous.
lt's fantast c.
Mr. N cholson wishes
to address us n the ha l.
Please come down, milady.
Thank you. Whity.
Mr. N cholson wishes
to address us n the ha l.
Please come down.
Do you know ...
what it's all about?
No, sir.
Thanks, Whity.
ls t something important?
Please wa t ...
till everyone's here.
Well, then...
My physicans have informed me ...
that l don't have long to ive.
The entire Nicholson estate
will pass,
on my decease,
n equal parts ...
to Katherine Nicholson,
née Stanwyck,
and Frank Nicholson.
Whereby it shou d be noted that ...
a part of Katherine's rights,
yet to be determined.
sha l pass to Frank Nicholson ...
as soon as he ...
enters into wedlock.
ln the event of Katherine remarry ng,
she shall forfe t her entire share
of the Nicholson estate,
which sha l pass to Frank Nicholson.
ln return for which,
she wi receive
a cash payment of $50.000.
The va id ty of th s ast will and
testament shall be dependent...
on the following provisions:
David Nicholson shall,
unt the end of his days,
be fed and cared for in th s house.
Furthermore,
Samuel King.
known as Whity,
and his mother, Marpessa,
sha l receive n this house ...
sustenance,
employment ...
and good treatment ...
for the rest of their lives.
This will was drawn up
on April 29, 1878.
Signed: Ben... Nathaniel...
R chard... Nichoson.
l'm eaving for Chicago tomorrow.
l've got a job as a singer.
The pay's good.
lt'd be enough for the two of us ...
at least at the beginn ng.
l'm staying with my family.
l'm fond of them.
All of them.
You've no idea
what that family's real y l ke!
You realize why your father
killed that Mexican?
Because he pestered Katherine.
Oh no.
He had to pretend to be a doctor ...
and k d Kather ne
that Ben was about to d e.
Once h s job was done,
Ben shot him down ...
ke a rabd dog.
You and your fam ly!
He gave me money.
A handsome sum.
Here.
To hell with it.
Kill them! Do them all n!
Free yourself of them.
You're a human being, too.
l must go down now.
A bott e of wh skey.
Can l jo n you in a game?
lf you've got the money.
- Sure.
Two for me.
- One.
My God. how funny you are!
Why are you aughing?
She laughed at me, Pa.
You're the only one of my sons ...
who has someth ng from me.
Frank's sick.
David's sick.
Katherine's a hyena.
l command you to kll them a .
You wil inherit the estate.
Oh, no!
Please don't shoot!
You can have the whoe estate.
Just let me...
Let me live!... l beg you.
You realize we' die of th rst now?