Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
In the winter of 1797, illness forced a band of
Cheyenne to migrate south, leaving behind those
who were too weak or sick to travel.
I will search for elk, my father
Why are there tears?
Gratitude for a son
Take care of your grandfather,
my children. He is sich
He needs comfort
Don't worry
My eyes are dim, but I still see
I am a burden...
to my family
Grandfather...
we will take care of you.
Are you  afraid to die?
No, it is time for this old body to
nourish the earth
But I was not always old
You were once a boy?
Old men do not grow from young girls
He was a great warrior
I need a wife to give me children
They are swift and strong
You have one wife already
I have counted many coups
Ah-foolish boy
Get Away!
I said - Get Away!
I will come back later
Eight skins
More than she is worth
Old friend, these horses are for you
I would share my life with your daughter
forever…
You have shamed this warrior
I am no longer welcome
among the Cheyenne
I am leaving
Keep your woman...
We are enemies until one of us dies
Our father is one of these sons?
Ehere is our father's brother?
Did you hear me? Get the wood
Get some help!
Cheyenne! Cheyenne!
Cheyenne!
Do not be afraid, little one
Do not be afraid
I am your father
You are my son
You are Cheyenne
Come quick!
Good journey, my father
The great white horse of the Cheyenne
A great warrior rides this horse
Nice little woman, that one
I will take her into my lodge with me
She will kill you-fool
More pleasant to die under a Cheyenne
woman's blanket
Than under the hooves of a war horse
We must have a horse
This warrior and his horse,
they are like one
The one will take us to the other
He cannot be caught
let us circle until the sun sleeps...
then come again to this place
I'm hungry
We are all hungry!
She cannot help her pain
Oh Great One...
I have not heard with my ears
But now I understand with my heart
He came back
Do not fear. This old man is no spirit
I was called back!
He grows weaker. He must eat
I have brought food
The Crows fell upon us. They are
still in the hills...
The Great One has sent you back to us!
Enought of this
He has counted coup and shamed us
He is grat warrior
we kill him but he disappears
And his great horse
maybe the medicine of his ghost horse
is too strong for us
I fear no enemy's medicine
I will find him
On my belt I will hang his scalp
It will not be long now
I will havethis... "ghost horse"
We have take two horses...
That is honorable
I will have the white stallion…
And the heart of this enemy
And I will have his little woman
This Cheyenne is no common warrior
He will kill you all
Youu speak like a woman!
Pride blinds you eye
This Cheyenne bleeds like every man
and he will die like every man
You have no courage
Does it take courage...
...to fight womenand children for
this horse?
We shall find and take all their horses
And my woman - by sunset
This is honorable. Then we will go
Grandfather, where did you get this
big bear skin?
From a big bear
That's here
How did you come to be alive?
Was it not good to die?
Ah, so many questions. But that is good
It's a very long story
I have many questions mysealf
I have yet to fully understand
why this old man was brought back
from the land of the
sky people
Grandfather?
Will the Crows come again?
Yes, they will come again
It is shameful
to follow this wounded warrior and
his women
If you fear his strange medicine…
then do not ride with us
Go on...
You are all fools!
I do not want to be part of it
Then leave us!
It is too soon for you to be warriors
You hearts are brave, but they are small
Today our hearts are full of one another
We must fight...
We must fight!
May all that pass come in peace
He must die for Smiling Wolf!
No - bind him
he shall not die
They are close
They warn us! Who is afraid?
Oh Great One
give us strenght
Do not fear death
As spring begins with winter
so death begins with birth
It is only a step
in the great circle of life
Fight without fear
You are Cheyenne!
I am not Crow
I am Cheyenne!
The lost one!
I have found my son
For this you have kept me so long
now I understand...
my son is returned to me!
This enemy insults me!
an old man comes to fight his battles
This is a joke!
Where is the great warrior?
No, evil eye, many seasons ago you
stole my son
Have not these years caused enough
heartache?
now let there be peace between us
Now I know the truth
I am not Crow
Let us part in life, not in death
My medicine is strong. This is my emblem
You raised me
but I am no longer your son
My heart is now with my true family
You should die...
but I let you go
In peace
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org