Man: I am Washakie,
of the great Shoshone Nation.
I wish to share with you
the story of Nick Wilson,
or Yagaichi, as he is best
remembered
among the Shoshone people.
The legend
of the white Indian boy
took place within our familiar
valleys and mountains,
known as "Wind River."
Yah!
Damn.
Shoshone.
Aah!
Yagaichi!
He's a comin'.
Take him.
- Pretty good time.
- I’ve e been riding like hell.
What happened to you?
Shoshones.
Pocatello's band again.
- Did you get 'em?
- I didn't have to.
You didn't have to?
Man: Kid, you ain't too smart
taking them Injuns lightly.
Ain't gonna be
safe around here
until they're all
dead and buried.
Yeah, well, as I recall,
they were here first.
Say, that's a nasty one,
we'd better take care of it.
There's a message
from your ma'.
There's some old woman
staying at your house
with a funny name.
Anaba?
Anuba.
- Apparently...
- Don't take that! I got
to go to Grantsville!
Man: Nick. Nick.
N iii-iiick!
Nick! Nick!
- Whoa!
- Hey! It's my turn!
Whoa, aah!
(both laughing)
Nick: Someday I'd like to ride
a real fast horse.
You have trouble
to ride the sheep.
Someday I'll be
a great rider.
(laughing)
Maybe you could learn
on your muuda.
My what?
Muuda.
I taught you.
Donkey.
I'd rather ride
a Bu... bungo,
and be a great
Da... dagwahni.
You learn fast.
But white cannot be great
warriors. Only Indians.
Like my brothers
to the north.
I'll be
a great explorer then,
like Louis and Clark.
Anything
but a sheep-herder.
The great Shoshones
of the Wind River.
My father ride with them.
He tell me
they scalp Crow and Sioux
while they ride
on their horses.
Golly.
Pantsuk,
maybe we could
leave this place.
We could run away.
We could live
with your brothers in the north.
What about our families?
What about the sheep?
We can let Sylvester
take care of everything,
since he knows
so much.
Come on,
let's make a pact.
What is pact?
A promise...
or an agreement.
Blood brothers.
Pact.
Lots of hunts,
and fishing.
We'll need horses and packs
for the trip.
And much jerky.
That's for sure.
Pantsuk, you're
my best tsaa hainj.
You are
my best friend, too.
Aah! What'd you
do that for?
I should do worse.
And you...
Why aren't you helping
your father?
- Get goin'.
- Leave him alone.
This is your job...
to make sure the coyotes
don't kill the sheep.
When grown, that lamb
could have kept us for a month.
If I ever catch you
slacking off again,
I'll kick your scrawny hide
to Salt Lake and back,
- you hear me?
- I can't do it all by myself.
I hate this place.
(sobbing)
Washakie: Before the dreams,
My mother Anuba,
a shaman and healer
among our people,
could not speak
for a very long time.
A mighty avalanche had taken
her two sons, my brothers.
When mother started
having the visions,
the power was understood.
She knew the boy
in her dreams
was good medicine
for our nation.
And we must find him.
I sent my finest warrior,
Morogonai.
(calling)
- What are you looking at?
- Don't do that.
You wanna wake the dead?
Then hush.
- What are you looking at?
- Shh!
It's Louis and Clark
if you must know.
What's it about?
It's about
Louis and Clark.
- Who are they?
- Surveyors.
- What's surveyors?
- Explorers.
they mapped out all the western
territory with Sacajawea.
She was a Shoshone.
Shoshones can scalp a person
with one hand
- while riding a horse.
- they ride a horse
- with one hand?
- No,
- they scalp with one hand.
- How do you know?
I just do. Listen,
why are you so nosy, anyway?
You writing a book?
Shh, shh.
Why don't you just go to sleep
before you make me catch hell?
Don't cuss, Nick.
N ever you mind.
Just go back to sleep.
- Goodnight.
- Sleep tight.
- Okay.
Don't let
those bed bugs bite.
I'm gonna bite you.
- Prissy.
- 'Night, Nick.
(signaling)
Nicholas.
(Nick, in haste)
Our Father, bless this food
so it may nourish
and strengthen our bodies
and do us the good we need.
We say these things in the name
- of Jesus Christ, Amen.
- Amen.
I think you s et
a re cord.
Woman: Nicholas.
Criminy, Ma.
I think you boys
are turning into heathens.
It's hotter
than hell out there.
Sylvester, I don't want
any cussing in this house.
If your father were here...
Who do you think
I learned it from?
I never saw ground
so full of rocks.
Yeah, they must be
growing more every y ear.
Ma: Sylvester, your boots
are caked with mud.
Take them outside.
Chicken coop
needs mending.
Chickens got out
last night.
Why you looking at me?
What about Jake?
Just shut up
and mend the fence.
Can't. Got to
watch the sheep.
You'll watch the sheep
after you mend the fence.
Why can't you do it?
- I got to plow.
- Nick: I'll plow.
- You ain't man enough.
- Yes, I am.
You don't even know how,
you dumb jackass.
- That's enough of that.
- Just fix the fence!
If I don't get them crops in,
you don't eat.
Nick: I wouldn't be
missing much.
- You ain't starving, are you?
- I might as well be!
Stop it, you two!
I'll mend the fence.
You got too much work.
Nick'll do it.
He does little else around here.
He'll do it after you eat.
- No!
- I said do it!
You can't tell me what to do,
you're not my father!
I hate it here,
and I hate you!
Eliza Nicholas!
When's father coming home?
Ma: Only
the Good Lord knows.
(chickens clucking)
Nicholas!
Nicholas, no!
Yah!
Nick: Whoa! Ahh!
Benjamin, stop!
Wait, Benjamin!
Nick: Benjamin, stop!
Stop!
Sylvester: Nick, no!
Nick: Help!
Benjamin stop, please stop!
Stop!
Nick!
(thud)
Man: Our Father
who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on earth,
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses,
as we forgive those
who trespass against us,
and lead us not
into temptation,
but deliver us from evil,
for Thine is the power,
and the kingdom,
and the glory,
forever. Amen.
We dedicate
this final resting place
as a place of peace
and tranquility,
until the morning
of the first resurrection,
in Jesus' holy name,
Amen.
(man singing in
Native American language)
(crying)
Stay back,
I'm warning you!
I'm not a yagaichi!
What you say?
I said I'm not a crier.
You know Shoshone?
No, just some Gosiute.
How you learn?
My friend.
Pantsuk.
What are you
gonna do to me?
- Nick: You gonna scalp me?
- Scalp?
Don't you scalp
white people sometimes?
We scalp you?
Aaah! Ahh!
No! No y ell.
No y ell.
I no scalp you.
Be still.
You be still.
Look.
You see him?
He stand tall.
He strong.
You like him?
If you come with us,
you keep him.
- You mean, just leave?
- He is fast.
Fast like the wind.
Are you gonna kidnap me?
- Kidnap?
- Force me to go with you?
Force?
No, no, no.
No, no,
we no force you.
We couldn't just go.
My mother would miss me.
I couldn't hurt her
like that.
We will not take you.
Not take you.
But, maybe...
maybe...
the wind calls you,
and you come.
If you feel
the wind,
you be here
when the sun goes up.
If you no here,
we go.
You are chosen.
Chosen.
You come with us,
you ride this horse.
You learn hunt good.
You live life
like a great man.
Great man.
Morogonai:
The wind calls you.
Pantsuk:
The great Shoshones
of the Wind River.
My father ride with them.
Ma: Nicholas!
Morogonai:
The wind calls you.
Female voice:
(music) close your eyes (music)
(music) And see (music)
(music) A world awaits you (music)
(music) A road sets you free (music)
(music) A journey will take you (music)
(music) To places unknown (music)
(music) When dreamers dream (music)
(music) The legend goes (music)
(music) It's then you'll know (music)
(music) The wind calls (music)
(music) Your name... (music)
(horse whinnying)
Can I call him Spirit?
Spirit?
Mmm, Spirit.
(music) The journey will take you (music)
(music) To places unknown (music)
(music) When dreamers dream (music)
(music) The legend goes (music)
(music) It's then you'll know (music)
(music) The wind calls (music)
(music) Your name (music)
(music) Take the time, (music)
(music) Just be (music)
(music) Beneath the stars, (music)
(music) Your night's canopy (music)
(music) A vision of future (music)
(music) The truth to behold (music)
(music) When dreamers dream, (music)
(music) The legend goes (music)
(music) It's then you'll know, (music)
(music) The wind calls (music)
- (music) Your name. (music)
- Whoa! Hey!
Hey, stop! Stop!
Stop!
Aaah!
This...
no good way
to ride horse.
I know that, I told you,
I can't ride without a saddle.
You must learn.
I want to go back.
No.
You are scared...
to fall.
I will make it...
I will fix it.
U p.
Come on, up.
Here, here.
Now, your feet
no dance.
You no scared,
you no fall.
We must ride.
We rest
when the sun goes down.
Come.
(signaling)
Man: All right, men.
You know why we're here.
We're looking for the boy.
All right?
Sylvester,
why don't you take
those first three men,
and head out on top
of the ridge?
You two men take the bottom,
and the rest of you
follow me through the canyon
and we'll fan out.
Let's go get him.
Move out.
Stop, please stop.
(crying)
Ohh.
- Why you not talking?
- I did!
You didn't hear.
Come down.
How you say?
Take off this,
take off this.
Aaah!
It's stuck.
- Sit down.
- What did he say?
He say you...
very brave.
We must cut off
your legs.
- Don't cut my legs off!
- No, no, we must cut off...
not your legs,
your pants.
Morogonai: Okay.
Be still.
Aaah!
Be strong. Strong.
(fabric ripping)
And your leg?
It hurts.
We need sleep.
We must ride
when the sun goes up.
I don't want to go.
Then you keep.
What's it for?
Mountain lion.
And coyotes.
Many.
Also, many Crow Indians.
This Indian fast
and strong.
You need to keep
hiding in trees.
Crow Indian sees you,
- kill you.
- Can't you take me back?
No.
Many white people
looking for us.
I am feel bad
your leg.
When the sun
rises up,
we go.
Who was that?
Pocatello.
He is Shoshone also.
But he goes away from us.
He is a leader
among the people who...
hate the white man.
What did he say?
He want me
to make a trade...
you for two horses.
What did you say?
Not enough.
Looks like
someone's clothes.
Man: What is it?
It's Nick's trousers.
There's blood on them.
Sylvester: Let's go.
Yah!
Well, brother, we'd better
go after him. Come on.
- Yah!
(yelling signal)
This great man.
Washakie.
He speak
for these people.
You live with him.
This boy
- Yagaichi?
- Yagaichi.
We have been waiting,
Yagaichi.
This woman
Anuba.
She's to be
your mother.
Come.
I have business
to attend to.
This place is nice
and flat.
We'll camp here.
It's not even sun down.
We got a good hour yet.
We've been going
since sun up.
We'll camp here.
Maybe if you aren't
so mad at it, it'll cooperate.
Sylvester,
we're heading back
tomorrow.
We've been at it 10 days,
and we ain't found
nothing
but those britches.
Here could be anywhere
in these mountains,
and he could be nowhere.
We have families
we have to tend to,
and so do you.
Your mother
needs you at home.
We go back tomorrow.
Yagaichi.
Oh, Yagaichi.
(all laughing)
Ahwo.
- Ahwo.
- Ahwo? Ahwo.
Bowl.
- Bowl.
- Bowl. Bowl.
Ehhe.
Ehhe?
Ehhe. Ehhe.
Blanket.
- Blanket.
- Blan-ket.
Yeah, you'll be speaking
English in no time.
(wolf howling)
What's the matter?
It's just an old wolf,
- esa.
- Ha ah.
I think my mother
would like you.
You're tough,
but you care.
My mother cares a lot.
She's never really
that tough, though.
It's hard on her.
Anuba.
Yagaichi.
Nick. Nick.
Anuba, Nick.
Yagaichi.
- Nick!
- Yagaichi.
- Yagaichi!
Nick!
Yagaichi.
(grunting)
Ho.
This...
ang...
- an... ange... ang...
- Anger?
Anger. No.
Feet.
Feet. Feet.
Feet, feet, head.
Woooo, feet.
Do it.
Do it. Feet.
Feet, feet.
Head, feet, feet.
Woooo, feet.
Wooo.
Woooo.
Anger will not
help you.
Get it.
Hah!
No good.
Good.
Thank you.
- A... an...
- Anger.
- No.
- Okay.
Feet.
(cloth ripping)
Are you all right?
I gave you a pretty good whack.
Sorry.
My name's Ya...
Nick.
What's your name?
Oh, damn it,
how do you say it?
Nick.
- Toma.
Toma, that's nice.
(baby crying)
- Sir?
- Mmm.
How come the women do
so much work around the camp?
- It is what they wish.
- Why?
The women cut
and haul the wood,
pack the meat,
take care of the children,
tan the hides,
make the clothes,
and they do
all the cooking.
Some of what you say
is true.
(speaking
in Native American)
Our mother says the women
want it done correctly.
- Boo!
- Prissy,
what the devil
are you doing out here?
I could've caught you
with the axe.
No, you can't see me
'cause I'm a ghost.
And ghosts are spirits
without bodies.
- How do you know that?
- Sunday school.
Hey, don't get too close.
Nah, you can't hurt ghosts.
An arrowhead!
Sylvester, look!
Maybe the Indians
took Nick,
and they dropped it here.
Nah, I think
he just ran away.
Do you think
he'll ever come home?
- He might be dead.
- Shut up, Jake, just shut up!
And what are you doing out here?
You should be helping Ma.
I turned into a ghost,
and floated out.
Sylvester, look.
Sylvester:
First of the season.
Prissy: Yup.
Winter's just around
the corner.
Yup. Just around
Priscilla?
Don't let her see me.
I thought no one
could see you.
Mothers can see
everything.
- Prissy, I can see you there.
- I told you.
Come in this instant.
Or you'll wish you had.
Sure wish Nick was here.
(wagon approaching)
- Man: Where would you look?
- Everywhere.
That's a lot
of territory to cover.
Martha, your bread
is delicious.
Let me pour you
some more Brigham tea.
Man: How do you know
who took him?
I think it was the Bannocks.
they're the only ones
- who come down this far.
- Why the Bannocks? Why not
the Gosiutes or the Utes
or the Crow or the Shoshone?
they were the first ones
I thought of.
- I have to start somewhere.
- And how do you know
they're not going
to take you?
Or worse, kill you?
Will that help your mother?
Good heavens, boy,
you're a farmer.
You'd be eaten alive
up there.
If not by savages, then
by the bear or mountain lion,
- or by the elements.
- I gotta try.
Don't you understand?
I gotta try.
Can't you wait until
your father comes back?
It'll be too late then.
You think Nick's dead.
That's not what I'm saying.
Martha?
He's gotta try.
I suppose if Brother Miller
takes your south field,
and Brother Cannon and I
take your north,
I suppose we could manage.
You leave Benjamin,
and take my horse Buck.
- Yes, sir.
- On one condition.
- You come back to your ma.
- Yes, sir.
Oooh!
You have ears.
U s e.
Nick: So what are you doing?
- Walking.
- That's what I was doing.
I’ve e been practicing
with that bow you gave me.
- Good.
- I think I'm getting better.
- Feet.
- I remember.
Morogonai, why'd you tell
everyone my name was Yagaichi?
That's causing me
some awful trouble.
Good name, Yagaichi.
To be a white man
family Washakie,
you need to be strong.
This name, Yagaichi,
is hard name.
Teach you be strong.
What are you
looking at?
Bad days.
What do you see?
We hunt them.
Making war.
You can see
all that in the sky?
Sometimes the sky...
is open.
When does the sky say
this will happen?
hunt always this...
- what is word? Seas... s eas...
- Season?
Morogonai: Season.
hunt always this season.
But is hard,
this time.
- No many buffalo.
- Why?
these Indian people
living over there.
No keep their land.
No keep their home.
Come here now.
they're hungry.
Need to eat.
Is it 'cause of the whites?
Many white people.
Morogonai,
do you hate the whites?
No. Morogonai no hate.
Hate make man...
I hated
my brother Sylvester.
Is no good, Yagaichi.
Keep...
keep this,
Yagaichi,
keep this.
This life no is long.
No hate.
- Morogonai?
- Mmm, Yagaichi.
How do I find
my vision?
Be still.
Quiet.
No words.
Listen.
Your heart...
vision...
comes.
He tried to do
the right things,
but his help was not
always wanted, or understood.
(speaking Native American)
Morogonai gave the boy
love, friendship,
and taught him
the way of the Shoshone.
And the way
from boy to man.
In battle,
you are no longer.
- Do again.
- I'm trying!
If you'd stop
throwing those rocks...
Aaah! Ah!
Female voice:
(music) Far away (music)
(music) You've learned (music)
(music) About the world (music)
(music) And that we are all one (music)
(music) Look to your spirit (music)
(music) To show you the way (music)
(music) When dreamers dream (music)
(music) The legend goes (music)
(music) It's then you'll know (music)
(music) The wind calls (music)
(music) Your name (music)
(music) You will always
find a friend (music)
(music) Just open up
your heart (music)
(music) If you believe (music)
(music) Then love will
raise you to new heights (music)
(music) See how your love
runs deep (music)
(music) Like the Rivers
of the wind (music)
(music) Let it soar on wings (music)
(music) And bring you home again. (music)
- (signaling)
- (speaking in Native American)
Morogonai!
Look, it's
the Indian from the road.
Pocatello.
- Haata.
- Haata? Poisoned?
- What did he say?
- He want you.
White men trade maybe four,
five horses for you.
Good price.
Sylvester: " Dearest Mother,
once again, I'm afraid there is
no good news to tell you.
I have followed many leads,
but still have no sign of Nick.
It is September now.
I will soon
have to make a choice,
to come home,
or endure another winter.
I wish you could advise me
what to do.
I will write again
as soon as I can.
Send everybody my love,
and tell them
not to worry about me.
I'm doing fine.
Your loving son,
Sylvester."
(yelling signal)
- H uh?
- (chuckling)
White men.
(Morogonai chuckling)
Ya ha.
Man: The Mormons
and the Indians
have one spirit Father.
And He is sad
that we fight.
We do not kill
white people.
No, but some
of your brothers do.
Some of yours do also.
Yes.
And our Father in heaven
is full of sorrow.
The white man comes
in peace.
Of course, there are
bad white men,
just as there are
bad Indians.
But for the most part,
these are poor,
honest folk,
searching for a home.
Your friend Brigham
is concerned for you.
He believes
it will not be many snows
before the game
in your country is gone
and there will be no food
for your families.
Would you change
the color of our skin?
Man: No, but we do not desire
for your people to starve.
We will bring
seed and tools,
and teach you
what you must learn.
Send my thanks
to my new friend Big Ham,
and tell him
we will council on his words.
(footsteps)
From brother Brigham.
Brother Brigham wanted
to know your words
about this gift.
This is good.
He wanted to know
how you felt about the gift.
Whites have
words for everything.
But they are just words
from here.
But this...
cannot speak.
Nick: Sir, am I ever going
to find out why I'm here?
Washakie:
Soon, you will know.
But I don't understand.
You don't teach me anything
like medicine,
or war, or the like.
N ever mind.
Soon I will know.
Washakie: For strength.
You should see
my real mother.
She's quite pretty.
Anyway, I think she is.
Nick: She's probably calling
everybody in from the field,
and hollering at Jake,
"Get Blackie outta the house."
Jake has this ugly
old dog and he...
What am I doing?
You don't understand
a word I say.
Yagaichi.
Washakie: When the summer
moved into fall,
we would go to our winter home
to escape the heavy snows.
Yagaichi traveled with us
at a difficult time.
As the snow
came early that y ear,
the hunting grounds
were scarce.
We were forced
even further south,
to find the abundance
needed for our survival.
What is it?
Is what the sky
has told me.
(signaling)
So?
Crows come.
Fight.
Isn't that good?
I do not like fight.
No good comes.
But Crows
will take our horses,
our women. We do not keep
our horses, women,
we will die.
We must go,
make battle.
Nick: Morogonai,
I want you to have this,
for strength.
(horse whinnying)
(war cries)
(gunshot)
(horse whinnying)
Morogonai!
Morogonai.
Morogonai?
(groaning)
I go now.
- No, I don't want you to go.
- I need go.
I need my father.
Stay here, I'm gonna
go get some help.
No, Yagaichi, no.
Yagaichi,
make a goodbye me now.
I am your friend,
always.
Morogonai.
Identify yourself.
Sylvester Wilson,
from Grantsville,
- Utah territory.
- You wouldn't be kin
- to Elijah Wilson?
- Yes, sir. He's my father.
All I ask is
to share your fire.
please, come.
You're more than welcome.
Man: May we offer you
some fish?
they're small,
but they're tasty.
Thank you, I'm fine.
It'd be a shame
to waste them.
We've already eaten, we'll
leave them for the varmints.
Well, if they'd
just go to waste.
Go ahead, do yourself up.
Thank you.
Thank you. To be honest,
I am still hungry.
So...
tell us, brother Wilson,
you look like...
you've been away from home
for quite a while.
N ear on to 18 months.
I'm searching for my brother.
Your brother?
We think the Indians took him
about two years ago.
Here,
wash it down with this.
Man #2: Which ones?
Don't know.
Can't find a trace of him.
Man #2:
Why would you continue?
Be cause...
I know he's out here.
I can feel it.
So what does this brother
of yours look like?
He'd be about 15 now.
Maybe near my height,
light colored hair,
blue eyes.
Man #2: Last fall we were up
in Wind River country,
up at Washakie's camp.
We saw a young boy
that appeared to be white.
He had light hair.
Didn't get a look at his eyes.
We weren't convinced
he was white.
He was wearing
tribal clothes.
Didn't look like he was
any kind of a prisoner.
Did you find out
his name?
No, didn't have
a chance to ask.
Why didn't you?
I'm sorry.
It's just that l...
It's been so long.
Where is
the Wind River country?
Pocatello!
This was it,
wasn't it?
You have good aim,
my brother.
I was aiming for his head.
Heard it in the wind,
Washakie.
Morogonai could read
the sky.
He knew what would happen to him
if he had to fight the Crows.
Morogonai is miss ed.
He would be
proud of you today.
You are a warrior now,
my brother.
I had council
with the elders today.
I know.
We are worried
about the posse.
I understand.
I know that I'm done here.
I must go back to my family.
I want to go back.
Do you understand?
The head understands,
the heart...
cannot speak.
Follow the River, it will
lead you back to your people.
I promise to return again
to see my Shoshone mother.
You will return.
Yagaichi.
(music) Many moons (music)
(music) have pass ed (music)
(music) Turn the page (music)
(music) As you look out and see (music)
(music) A world of adventure (music)
(music) That you've yet to live (music)
(music) When dreamers dream (music)
(music) The legend goes (music)
(music) The wind calls (music)
(music) Your name. (music)
What is it, Spirit?
Let's go!
(gunshot)
(war cry)
- Sylvester: I got you covered.
- Nick: And I have you covered.
You speak English?
Who are you?
I asked you first.
No, you didn't.
Nick?
Sylvester?
Yeah.
What the devil
are you doing up here?
Looking for you.
- You were looking for me?
- For two years.
Can you forgive me?
It's me that needs
to be forgiven.
I guess we're even then.
You know,
if we start riding now,
we could get a couple hours
closer to home before suns et.
Why you in such a hurry?
You're just going to have
to herd sheep and fix fences.
I think
I can handle that.
We're going home.
(children laughing)
Welcome home,
my young brother.
This is where our mother
wanted to be.
I promised I'd come back.
I'm just sorry...
I'm just sorry it wasn't...
while you were still alive.
(Nick sobbing)
You are still Yagaichi.
Washakie: In 1857,
Yagaichi returned home.
He mended fences,
and plowed fields.
In 1861,
Nick Wilson went on to be come
one of the founders
and original riders
of the Pony Express.
(music) Embrace the same earth (music)
(music) And their spirits (music)
(music) Will never die (music)
(music) Cherish (music)
(music) The moment (music)
(music) And stay
in present time (music)
(music) All of (music)
(music) The ancients (music)
(music) To the mountain
we must climb (music)
(music) Breathe the same air (music)
(music) Walk in
the same sunshine (music)
(music) Touch the same sky (music)
(music) Embrace the same earth (music)
(music) And the River (music)
(music) Will never dry (music)
(music) Listen (music)
(music) To the wind (music)
(music) See it in the sky (music)
(music) Feel it (music)
(music) From the ground (music)
(music) There are answers (music)
(music) All around (music)
(music) Enter (music)
(music) The circle (music)
(music) You will see (music)
(music) Through our father's eyes (music)
(music) Walking (music)
(music) Their footsteps (music)
(music) they are many,
old and wise (music)
(music) Breathe the same air (music)
(music) Wade through
the same River (music)
(music) See the same sky (music)
(music) Embrace the same earth (music)
(music) And their spirits (music)
(music) Will never die (music)
5@y3