Winnetou, the noble Apache Chief,
rides relentlessly on his sworn mission...
to keep peace between his people
and the white settlers.
The advance of the white man into the
Indian hunting grounds created tension
on both sides. Winnetou rides to persuade
the chiefs of the North-Western tribes,
to prevent occasional uprisings against
the white man from developing into a war.
A war that could mean
the destruction of all the Indian nation.
Mini ta schiha nintropan.
Ana hokesche muni.
Neha teka nintropan.
Kekaha tschekak ometan.
Unami sche loka.
Sehina mota.
Teleschoma tahini?
The Apache makes poor speech
with the Assiniboins.
Have you ever learned how to speak the
English language, heard in these parts?
We are fighting with the pale settlers.
Some of us know their language, though.
Tell me what you're called.
- Ribanna.
I am Winnetou.
- Winnetou?
Ribanna is hurt. She will ride my horse.
- Ribanna does not feel pain.
The Assiniboins are clearly courageous
if their warriors are like their women.
Ribanna can walk! Put me down!
- No.
Heta kahii!
These are my tribe's men.
Ascha kahe!
Hetet scha akulenkha Ribanna.
- Winnetou schoma mota.
Kale mina thin Ribanna.
- Ahe!
Ahi akita Apacheschana Assiniboins?
The Apache cannot speak our tongue.
But we share the speech of the white man.
Then I command him to say why an Apache is
in the hunting grounds of the Assiniboins.
To speak peace with your Chief,
Tah-Sha-Tunga.
Kitepa. Kitepa!
Enk aton!
Enem scha petra.
- Kih lo ka tahe, Ribanna?
The noble Apache Chief
saved my life today.
I was attacked by a bear
who wounded me.
Tah-Sha-Tunga's thanks.
You look to my daughter's safety.
If Winnetou should ever ask me
for anything, it is his.
Don't let them burn at the stake.
Let those men go. -I kamo nek sin!
Why should these men be your friends?
- They are not.
I beg this only to aid the cause of peace.
- Winnetou, will you follow?
Did you hear that? Winnetou might help us.
There may be a chance.
White settlers invade my hunting grounds.
I can't tolerate their ruthless invasions.
I and my tribe have sworn
to burn at the stake every white man...
who falls into our hands.
Winnetou talks of peace.
In the name of our people I ask:
Is it we who have broken it?
I can consider only one thing:
all those who will die.
Our death is far less shaming
than to allow this to happen.
We can fight. But who looks after
your families if your warriors die?
What happens if we don't win?
No. To be alive, not merely to die,
and to stay at peace,
that is what Manitou decrees.
Winnetou's words scorch me as fire does.
Give us your idea.
I come to see you up here
because I feel the tribes here
in the Northern area
should work together with us in the South.
Winnetou will meet with Old Shatterhand,
a white man. Pay him respect.
He and Winnetou and Tah-Sha-Tunga
will ride to Fort Niobara.
The head of each tribe will join us there
in talks with the white man,
and see what can be done
about ending our hostilities.
Winnetou has not satisfied all the doubts
that lie in Tah-Sha-Tunga's breast.
Ribanna owes her life to your courage.
- When peace is in question,
one woman's life must not matter.
My father will freely decide:
war or peace.
It takes them so long. What's going on?
- Nothing for us to do. They're coming!
Do you realise just what awaits you?
- Yes.
Who are you?
- Lieutenant Merril, from Fort Niobara.
Isn't that the name of the man
who represents your government here?
That is a fact.
Colonel Frederik Merril, my father.
You are free! Please deliver a message
to your father: At the next full moon,
all our chiefs will meet at Fort Niobara
to plan how we may preserve our peace.
Thanks.
Now, Winnetou must grant a request
Tah-Sha-Tunga makes him.
That he stay here as our guest.
And when that day arrives,
we shall ride to Fort Niobara together.
Bob! Ronny!
- Yes?
What's that up there?
- I don't know.
It's unusual, because I know we're in
the vicinity of a tribe named the Poncas.
Shimu nahii?
We come in peace! We're friends!
- Tell us what you want with the Poncas!
Where's Blue Water Lake?
We lost our way.
Do not come any closer!
- You could put us on the right trail.
Don't come any closer!
- But if you put us on the right trail,
you'll be a barrel full of whisky richer.
You mad men!
You'll pay for this! Take my word!
Are you crazy?
Slaughtering Indians for no reason at all!
The only good ones are dead ones.
- I've dealt with cut-throats before,
who go around murdering people.
- Get moving. Get going!
We'll see you on the gallows.
- You give my regards to the Colonel.
If you get there.
- Okay.
Bill! Joe! Matt! Avery!
If grass don't grow and the goose
don't cry, why it ain't July!
If I blast a rat and he don't die,
it's a filthy lie!
I'll be alright.
- The cavalry unarmed in this region?
Since we were captured by Indians.
- Poncas?
No, Assiniboins.
The Chief of the Apaches... - Winnetou?
You'll be alright. Go and bandage it.
Yes. If it hadn't been for Winnetou,
we would have lost a lot more
than just our guns. - You're right.
Do you know who attacked you?
- I've no idea. They were part of
a gang of men that destroyed
a Ponca settlement. - Why?
I don't know. I shall deliver a message
with a peace proposal to Colonel Merril.
With those criminals, we might as well forget about peace.
There wasn't much the3 of us could do against that gang. - Leave it to me.
You're unarmed. My friend's a good shot. He'll get you to the Fort.
We're off to the Fort. I'm ready to go it. Fastest gun here
and raring to show it! Right here's the best and the only prairie poet.
I'm very glad to meet you. Would you mind, Sir, telling me your name?
They call me Old Shatterhand.
There! Ribanna is on the target! Why isn't Winnetou pleased?
Winnetou prefers that Ribanna not play with dangerous weapons.
Ribanna has shot arrows since she was a child.
She tries to take the place of the son, her father never had.
Ribanna!
Winnetou asks for pardon. - Ribanna must see her father now.
Won't she stay?
Why didn't Ribanna mention to me she was the only child of the Chief?
Assiniboins say, if a girl talks too much, she will always live alone.
No man shall want her.
You shall not live alone, I know.
Ischoma. - Schoma anahii.
When we are threatened with danger, this cave is our refuge.
It is known only by Assiniboins. Winnetou is the only stranger
who knows it. - Is Winnetou a stranger?
Ribanna will answer Winnetou's question, if he waits right here.
Ribanna was speaking with her mouth, but not with her heart!
Winnetou is not a stranger.
And what would Ribanna say if she did speak with her heart?
What does Winnetou's heart say?
- Ribanna.
Winnetou.
Hands up!
Fine thing. Look at that hat, now.
Castlepool! - Old Shatterhand!
Well, what are you doing out here? - School's out, so here I am.
Collecting butterflies again this summer? - Oh, last year's hobby!
With the Papilio Polymnestor Parinda I completed my collection.
Something new has captured my interest. - What are you collecting this time?
Adventure, Sir. To a professor, adventure is glamour.
You sure did pick something different. I wish you lots of luck.
I am prepared to join forces with you. Adventure follows you. May I come?
It's ok. I'm after 2 dangerous criminals. They went off in that direction.
No, that's not where they rode off. They obliterated their tracks
to throw you off the trail. I myself watched them.
Come, Beauty! Come, come!
We'll seek that pair of criminals. - Alright. I'll take you with me.
But I warn you. The 2 men I'm looking for belong to a dangerous gang of criminals.
That's sensational! Let's hop to and begin!
Boss! Boss, listen. We... -1 know. Lucas told me about it.
Did you get those soldiers? - No. We was ambushed.
What? You let them get away free? Do you realise the implications?
Must have been 20 or 30 gunmen. We're lucky to be here.
Take 10 men to Decama. There are soldiers around there.
Find out what's happening at Fort Niobara. I want every information you can get.
I want you to find out about everything! Anyone follow you? - No.
No one at all. We laid a false trail.
- We'll see.
I wonder what's up.
Well? What are you standing around for?
Go on! Get to work!
Do you want us to all go up in flames? How many times have I told you: no smoking?
Hey! What do you two want here, huh? Where are you from?
From the East. - Heading West, huh?
Obviously. - Don't use them words to me!
Take it easy, Carter.
Seems we've got ourselves a couple of visitors.
Are you the boss around here? - Yes, I am. And I don't like
strangers on my oil fields. What do you want? - Oil, please.
You want oil! Perhaps you're not aware of the fact that all the oil here
belongs to me. - Congratulations, Sir. It's for my lamp.
It makes reading a pleasure. - Is he trying to be funny?
No. We've come a long way. We'd like to buy supplies from your store.
Well, you can't buy anything. I'll make you a trade, though.
I like that horse. - So do I.
Here's my offer: You give me your horse,
and in exchange you'll get merchandise from my store worth 100 dollars.
No, thank you, Mr Forrester, because... - Ok, 200 dollars. But that includes
the saddle and the 2 rifles. -1 won't part with my horse.
300 dollars for your two horses. Saddle, harness and weapons.
Now, look, Mister. You go too far. - Take it, or leave it.
You'd better take it. Bud Forrester always gets what he wants.
That's unfair! 100 of you against 2 of us. - Be quiet, Castlepool.
Go ahead.
Take him.
Stand back! And don't shoot!
I suni, Hatatitla. I suni.
Did you hear that? Hatatitla! That's Old Shatterhand's horse.
So sorry. My horse doesn't like you.
Take the weapons to the barracks. See that the horses are locked up.
Then give me the key.
Come on! - Something smells around here.
I don't notice it. -1 didn't notice it before you came.
Get that smile off your face!
Stop that!
Stop it, you hear? - We'd better get rid of them.
No. We have to find a reason first. After all, they're white men, not Indians.
But that's easy. They won't get out of here. We'll put them to work tomorrow.
Old Shatterhand.
Go in to the store. I must talk to you right away.
We were hired in Decama. Forrester supplies the oil there.
He promises commission and good lodgings, and broke his word. - He is a cad.
Folk say he has the oil concession for the whole valley.
Forrester has a claim on Indian territory? - Yeah.
The Poncas were supposed to go to Dakota. But not one of them has moved out of here.
And Forrester and his gang raise the Ponca village to the ground.
Now I understand everything. - Forrester's a murderer.
How many are you? - Over 60. And we're anxious to fight.
Forrester took our guns. They're locked out there with 2 day and 2 night guards.
Can you trust the driver of the oil wagon?
- This is him.
Good. We'll try to get the weapons as soon as it gets dark. With any luck,
we'll strike tonight. - Tonight? Something special is indicated.
I'll take these 2. It's a charge!
We made it, lads. As you can see, back at the fort, one, two, three!
The sun is sinking, out of sight. I'll do the same, and bid you goodnight!
It's Merril, Bob and Ronny.
Hey, Bruce! - Sure is good to see you three.
We were certain the Indians got you. - They almost did. It was very close.
Your father was worried about you.
Let's go!
Is the Colonel in his office? - Yes, Sir.
Lieutenant Merril, reporting in with his patrol. All present and accounted for.
Good, Lieutenant Merril. I'll expect a report in the morning. Good to see you!
Dad!
Thank the Lord you're back. We were all so worried.
Susan! - You're back!
Robert!
You're really here! - Like the bad penny, Susan.
You're brother's come back to you. Now, will you please dry your tears?
The Assiniboins tied us to stakes. They were preparing to burn us alive.
Thank heaven for Winnetou. - The Chief of the Apaches?
He saved us. I promised to bring along this message.
Winnetou convinced all the tribal elders to meet with you about a peace treaty.
So the reprisal I ordered did some good.
- You're mistaken.
You don't understand how much bitterness that caused among the Indians.
If you treated them just as you should, they'd do whatever you say.
You still take the part of the Indians. They resist the march of progress for...
You always put the blame on the Indians. Yet, I owe my life to an Indian.
But only a few hours later, I have to watch white men destroy an Indian village.
Who did it? -1 don't know. There is someone who does.
My gun. - Right!
Give a hand.
We've got them all. Get plenty of ammunition.
I hope nobody saw us. I have a feeling it went too smoothly.
These guns will have to be distributed among us. But no one must see us. Clark!
When the weapons are handed out, you will go and ring the alarm. - Right.
And, then what? - You take...
Alright! Hands up! - Weren't you taught to knock
before you enter a room? - You, too!
Higher!
Old Shatterhand. The great big hero.
The protector of the Indians. - And you slaughtered the Poncas!
I hid oil here, and they interfered with my operation.
You're a swindler, Forrester. A swindler and a murderer!
I make my own laws. One of them is that, whoever preaches rebellion to my men,
will be hanged. And this man did worse. Right?
Come on! Get up!
On your horses!
In to the store! Get your rifles, you hear?
Stop him!
Alright! Get that dynamite out! - Here goes!
Get back! It's coming towards us!
Now they've got what they deserve!
Everything's going to the devil. - It was the only way. I had no choice.
We'll build New Venango again.
Castlepool!
Winnetou.
Where has my brother gone? - The smoke still covers the valley.
I observed more than 50 men. - What are they doing?
They extinguished the fire.
One of them wore a black leather jacket. - That was Forrester.
We mustn't lose him. I'll stay here, and you go and get some help.
No. Peace must come first. After that, we'll find Forrester and punish him.
I would like first that you ride to Fort Niobara. - When?
We leave at once. We go to the Assiniboins.
I promised the chief
we would ride together with him. - What do we do about Castlepool?
He bids you goodbye. A thousand thanks for the collector's item.
I had the best time. - Where are you aiming to head for now?
For the next adventure, I should see Mr Forrester, and solve that problem.
I appreciate your wanting to. But it might be your last adventure.
Thanks! I think it will be Laramie, then. There's a lot of bad doings there!
If you'd listen to me, the one place you'd stay away from is New Venango.
Old Castlepool has got the hang of this part of the world. He knows the answers!
Yeah!
Welcome to New Venango! - What are you doing, playing with toys?
If you don't stop, I'll call the Sheriff! And I mean it! - Quiet!
What's all the noise about? Who's that?
Bring him here!
What were you looking for up there? - Raspberries, Sir. Wild raspberries.
Seems to me, I remember you. Of course! You came here with Old Shatterhand,
and began all that excitement. The fire didn't kill you? - No, sorry.
Thank goodness, that is. - Tell me, where's your friend now?
I don't know, Sir. - You really don't know?
Definitely not! - Too bad. You'll have to stay here
until you can remember. Tie him to that pole,
so the sun can warm his brain a little.
Come on!
That's her, there.
Ashameha mehe! Kitepa!
This is Ribanna.
In a few days, I'm going to marry her.
I wanted Old Shatterhand to know. You're our friend, part of the family.
Colonel? I beg to state my opinion, Sir.
It's too soon to be disturbed too much. - What do you mean? It's written here:
"The President is gravely concerned over the possibility of any new situation causing
an Indian war. We must prevent war, no matter what the cost."
Prevent! But how? Nobody can tell us how to do that.
There's no one who can make the Indians forget the Ponca village incident.
Perhaps, my dear Sir, you can advise us.
I say the problem is: How can we convince the people
we lied to for so long, that this time we mean it?
I must say, you're brutally frank. - But, it's true.
We moved into the Indian's territory.
It wasn't ours.
But that's ancient history. Those stories are over.
They don't agree with the facts. - But they still hold true, Sir.
The Indians began to offend themselves when you drove them out of their land.
Thanks very much for your advice.
But if you'd seen the mutilated victims of the Cheyennes,
you wouldn't feel so sorry for those poor redskins.
I was under the impression that we were trying to find a peaceful solution.
Of course. As a soldier, I carry out the orders issued to me.
They're coming!
For a long time only our weapons spoke. But now, we heed the call of peace.
We have sent messengers to the East, to report out desire for friendship.
Our great leader in Washington speaks to you through my mouth.
We received Winnetou's message and we felt great joy
that so many powerful and famous chiefs have gathered here. And I know,
today is a great chance for all Americans to secure the lasting peace we need.
In this momentous, historic hour, I salute you all.
I salute the brave warriors of the Assiniboins, of the Mandan,
Pawnee and Chippewa,
the Osages, Sioux and Navajos.
Of the Schoschones, Crow and Dakota.
That is the greeting I am delegated to bring from the President in Washington.
Pashi Ponca!
There's the last one. That man's a Ponca. - Now, things will be different.
We salute the government in Washington, and those of you here.
We must bury our differences. Our country is big enough for all of us,
if we respect each other and live together in peace.
There have been wrongs on both sides. - When there is property damage,
we do make it up. - How do white men value...
lives of 2 times 100 warriors, women and children of my village?
They were brutally slain by pale faces.
No more than I put on our white settlers, whom the Cheyennes destroyed at Newcomb.
War!
Kill!
Death! -War!
Outrages committed by criminals are not our responsibility!
Dako!
Where's the man to guarantee us that it will not happen again?
I, Old Shatterhand! Here's my word. Once the peace treaty has been signed,
Winnetou and I will track down these men,
and see they're brought to justice. -1 believe you.
Still you cannot do it single-handed. The soldiers must keep the law.
Peace will always be broken, because white men despise us.
Death.
Yes, kill! -War!
War!
Then still the weapons do the talking!
- No.
Aren't you tired of war and death? - We do not fear death.
No more peace! We must war!
- Kill!
Kill!
You cannot make a decision in rage. We come asking for peace.
You know the Indian. He's known to keep his oath.
Can that be said of the white men?
Who of you will guarantee peace? -1! I'll guarantee it.
Because I believe that the white man and the Indians must live together in peace.
You must realise, there are men like us, sympathetic to your people.
But as in all races, there are honourable men and men who do evil.
In other words: All men are equal.
Lieutenant Merril! I command you, be silent!
No, Father! You're wrong in the things you say of us. That we hate you.
That we are not your friends. I shall soon prove that we are friends.
Here's how it can happen. Allow a wedding that will unite all our people.
Join Ribanna, daughter of the Chief of the Assiniboins, and me!
It's up to you. I beg to marry your daughter!
You must be aware that, by doing this, you'll be through in the army.
If I can manage to bring us peace here, that's all that matters.
When Ribanna shall move into house of white man, peace shall be sealed.
Winnetou!
What is it? -1 didn't think my heart could break.
The Gods are cruel to us. The unfairest thing is, that I must bring you this news.
Shoma kateh!
Was ha manoka! Nuhu shunishie!
I can't!
Let's run away. To me, you're all that matters. I'll never marry that man!
No, Ribanna. - I'll get my horse!
Nu scha mahini Ribanna waha!
Have the noble Apache and Ribanna yet spoken? - We did.
She understands.
She knows that our fate and the path our people choose,
depend on this marriage. The choices between war and peace,
life and destruction. You must obey.
Ribanna and Winnetou respect peace.
Somehow,
I'm not sure if such an uncertain truce can be worth what we're doing.
Winnetou must try to forget. You'll help me.
We've got an awful lot to do. - We'll start on Forrester!
What did you say? Peace! - Everybody's talking about it.
Colonel Merril negotiated with the chiefs. The worst news is that his son,
Lieutenant Merril, is going to marry a chief's daughter.
Jenson! Carter! I want you over here right away! And all the other men!
Right away, Boss. - This way! Come on!
They're going to have a peace treaty with the redskins at Fort Niobara.
You know what that means? - We sure do, Boss!
By the time we wait for those dirty Indians to leave their land,
the Blue Coats will be after us. We must do something about it!
We'll spoil the plans of the peacemakers. I know exactly how to get the land.
I shall read from Ephesians:
You have taken my heart with your eyes, give me a place in your heart.
He that loves his wife, loves himself. For no man ever yet hated his own flesh.
But nourishes and cherishes it, even as the law of the church.
For we are members of his body, of his flesh and of his bones. Amen.
So come unto the Lord. And be prepared.
Robert Merril, will you take this woman, Ribanna, as your wedded wife?
Yes, I will. - And you, Ribanna?
Will you take this man, Robert Merril, for your wedded husband?
Yes, I will.
By virtue of the authority vested in me, I pronounce you man and wife.
Your union will be a shining example, and will help bring us a life of peace.
The man tied to the pole is Castlepool. He said he was going to Laramie.
The fool! He didn't listen. - If my brother will watch out for me,
Winnetou will release him. - There is only one guard,
and very few horses. - Forrester's not here, I'm certain.
What's he up to now? - Castlepool will know where he went.
It fits!
Hey! If you want my hat, the price has gone up. It's 6 dollars!
But you ain't going nowhere. - It would fit you fine if it were square,
like your fat head. - I'll shut your trap, quick!
Oh, Suzanna, don't you cry for me!
Well, how's our fine gentleman? Isn't it time you went to sleep?
Sweet dreams, your Highness. - Goodnight, my Lord.
6 dollars!
Who's that? Hey! What's going on? - Something's going on outside!
There they are!
Forrester went to Grey Stone Canyon with his men to hold up a wagon train,
and then blame the Indians. - We must get to the wagons immediately.
It's a full days ride to Grey Stone Canyon, but we have to warn them. Come on!
Halt! - Halt!
It's alright, folks! - They aren't Indians!
Follow me!
You'll never get out of here alive! So why don't you give up?
We'll come out! And you'll pay for murdering those innocent people.
You're wrong. One of my men is at Fort Niobara right now.
He's reporting as the only "survivor" of an Indian attack on a wagon train.
There'll be 3 more victims!
You!
He's the lone survivor of a wagon train. All the others were killed.
They were Assiniboins. Assiniboins!
What do you mean, Assiniboins?
They murdered Mama. They showed no mercy at all.
My mother, my children, everybody!
You've got to have courage, or try to. The thing you've been through is terrible.
Please go and make him comfortable. What is your name?
Lucas, Sir. David Lucas.
I want you to see that this man is offered every consideration.
We will serve to help him forget. Put him over in my orderly's tent.
See that he gets some rest. - Yes, Sir.
Alright, now.
Captain Bruce! - Yes, Sir?
Ride to Grey Stone Canyon with 10 men. Report to me, immediately upon return.
I want to know if what this man tells about is fact.
And, shoot to kill every last Assiniboin you can locate and destroy.
Sir, we number only 24 soldiers.
It is better to wait until Lt. Jackson returns from the field with his men.
Very well. Wait until tonight.
Not to be trusted a minute, those Indians. And I've always known it.
They talk of peace, law and justice! But as soon as our backs are turned,
they start to betray us! Now it's my turn! I order my soldiers not to show any mercy.
I am a soldier. And I must follow the orders I'm given.
I shouldn't reveal this to you. But, you're my friend, and I had to.
I thought you could to do something. - Where is this so-called "survivor"?
In the orderly's tent. Be careful. - Don't worry. And, thanks, Tom.
You've been a mighty good friend.
- Good luck.
Ribanna! -1 must clear the Assiniboins.
They didn't do it! - Where are you going?
To see my father.
We go together. I know it wasn't your father who broke the peace.
We must get at the truth together! - What can we do?
Double the guards! If there's anything suspicious, sound the alarm!
Pack everything up, including ammunition and rifles.
Put all of it on the horses. Oh, yes... Some strong rope and a tent.
If anybody asks, let them believe that we're on an overnight hunting trip.
First that "survivor" has to be contacted.
Here they come.
They adopted that from the Middle Ages! - One shot alone, won't help. But...
Those cowards! - Don't you think we'd be better give up?
We've lost 16 men. - They know we raided the wagon train.
We can't let them get away. - They're safe in that position.
Say they hold out until the soldiers come? - Your warnings will drive me crazy.
I'm going to try some other plan.
Let's go!
Forrester knows what he's in for. He won't dare quit.
We have to try to distract him, so we can get to the lake.
That body has a lasso. I could make good use out of it.
They've got 3 colts and 3 rifles, too. - My friend reads my thoughts.
Go in there and rest.
Not a sound. You make one move, you're going to be dead.
Turn over and put your hands behind you!
Go on!
Beats me where you get these ideas, Boss!
Go get the powder! - Some gadget!
Take cover!
Alright! Now!
Take this.
Here's the powder, here.
Ready!
There!
Hit it!
What is it? - Look at that! That's our men!
Why are you standing around? What's wrong? - They've gone. They're not here!
Are you crazy? They were shooting at us from there.
They took our dead men, and fastened ropes to the triggers of their rifles and colts.
Let's see. - Hey, Red!
There's more of that rope around the lake! - They fooled us for sure, damn it!
While we were busy making that catapult, they got away and pulled these strings.
Let's search the lake.
Hurry!
They're not here! The shore is there, so we couldn't have missed them!
They couldn't go far. Take half the men. You start searching along the canyon.
I'll search this direction! - Right! Come on, boys! Follow me!
Schane makela nem sche ika.
Kesche namoschi loka schi tuma. - Schuma mota!
My warriors say, a quick death would be too easy.
But my son speaks against this. - You will be given a fair trial.
We'll use him as a hostage.
Like ste squaw mine kaschu.
Та schi ma ahtili noha. - Mohana!
When the tents have been packed,
we will go.
Have courage. I know you would join me to hunt these murderers.
Remember this: remain alive and together.
If not, there's war.
Only peace can bring the Indian his freedom. Schetaha loka.
Schetaha mahini.
Halt!
Hey! It's Old Shatterhand!
We just came back from Grey Stone Canyon. - The place we were going to investigate
the wagon train the Assiniboins got. - It was Forrester and his bandits.
It was Forrester! -1 can put you on their tracks.
Winnetou won't let them out of his sight.
We didn't know about Forrester.
Any luck? - No, Boss. We rode for 3 hours...
and looked everywhere. They disappeared!
- Those dirty dogs.
What's next?
We've got to get supplies and ammunition.
- And the wounded?
They stay right here. They're useless. What are you standing around there for?
Go on! Get on your horses! - Our horses are tired. We've got to...
We're going to Vernango! The soldiers could be here any minute. If we're not...
in Blackwood before dawn, we haven't got a chance!
Kehii taschu! - Kishi ma tera!
Lorom shalera! Kose nikatuma Forrester! - Nomesha tschhi Venango makela Forrester!
My scout reports that Forrester is not in Vernango. Where is he?
No answer? Then we shall go to the fox's lair and wait.
And if he does not return by break of day, you shall die! Tse kischi pteh schoma!
Kahii ta Venango!
Come out, holding your hands high. Or we'll set you on fire!
That's enough! We're going! Come on!
Hey! Get up, you! - Look over there! Someone's coming!
Why, it's Lucas! - Lucas!
It didn't work! The Assiniboins are laying in wait at Vernango.
If we don't go to Vernango, and they search for you, they'll find our tracks.
Then, we'll have them both on our necks. - What about going to Mexico?
We'd never get there. It's 14 days hard riding!
And we've got a 4 hour lead at the most. - That's enough to get to the Assiniboins.
What's that? Why should we head up there?
- Two hostages.
One, Robert Merril. And Ribanna, daughter of the chief of the Assiniboins!
Say that again. -1 was blindfolded.
The sun was low and in the west. My right ear is sunburnt,
so we were heading south, I'm sure. From the village,
I counted 820steps. Must have a hideout, I think. Let's look for a cave.
They're coming back! - Nomi Ta-Sha-Tunga!
They look like Forrester's men. I'm sure they haven't seen us yet.
Go on! Hurry! - Nomi Ta-Sha-Tunga!
806...
807...
808...
Look over there! We've found the cave!
They've discovered the cave! They may becoming in here to hide.
We'll have to go further. - Tehine шока tinungi! Kitepa!
You're trapped, Merril! - Come on out! And the woman, too!
And come on out, or you're finished!
Is there any other way out of here? - The cliff entrance, but it's slippery.
Nobody could ever reach it. It's too smooth.
Come on!
Tell them to be quiet when the men pass. If they make a single sound...
Leschana hoka nischuni!
Hey, Boss, look! - They must be here. Come on!
There they are! Shoot!
Come on!
Robert!
It's the army.
Take cover!
Carter! See if you can find another exit. Come on! Keep going!
Forrester's men, I'm sure. -1 know what we're going to do about it.
Asihescha ti kumana!
Give up, now, Forrester!
We've got the cave surrounded, and you're in trouble!
We guarantee you a fair trial. We demand that you come out right now!
Alright! We're coming!
Merril and his wife! - Look! I'm the man who makes demands!
I demand freedom for myself and my men as far as the Mexican border!
You'll return the horses to us. Give us plenty of ammunition!
I want a 2 week supply of provisions, placed on that rock over there.
All of you stay out of range.
If you meet my demands, we'll set the hostages free at the border.
But if you don't, we'll shoot them! - We'll stall for time.
It's the only thing we can do.
Hear me. Everything's on your side. We have to go along with you.
But our pack-horses were left down below. We need an hour time to get them up here
and hand them over to you. - An hour, then. But not a minute longer!
And if any of your men start shooting, they'll be the ones to suffer!
Guard the entrance with 10 men! - Right! Come on! Step to it!
You listen to me, now! Nobody is going to be shooting, unless I order them.
Take them further in and tie them up.
- Boss! Boss!
Down this passage is a small opening. But you need a rope to get out.
J want to see it.
Hand me that rope!
You two come with us!
Here!
Up there!
It's at least 40feet. You're right. No chance without a rope.
I wonder if you can get in from the outside.
You stay here. If you hear anything, sound the alarm. - Yeah, Boss.
After we cross the border, what do we do with the hostages? - Kill them.
Somebody will help us. Try to hold on. - Ribanna has great trust.
She knows Old Shatterhand. 3 times she heard the mountain dog call.
Ribanna knows Winnetou is very near.
I don't see nothing down there.
Is it an hour yet?
27 minutes to go.
Boss! It's Tah-Sha-Tunga!
Over there.
From the very start, I wasn't satisfied with this.
Now I'm satisfied, do you hear? - How much time now?
None.
Alright, over there! Time's up!
The chief says they're having trouble getting up with the pack-horses.
One's lame. Give us 10 more minutes!
You can't make a fool of me!
If the horses aren't up in 2 minutes, I'll have the woman's tongues cut out!
He's not human. He's the devil. - Tell your soldiers to get ready.
If worst comes to worst, we'll have to attack.
41... 42... 43...
44... 45... 46...
47... 48... 49...
50... 51... 52...
53... 54... 55...
56... 57... 58...
59... . 60! Your time's up!
I'll have them bring the prisoners here, so you can see what we do to them! Go.
Ribanna! Ribanna!
He's here at last! Ribanna was sure of it. - Whose voice is that?
Winnetou!
Aya!
Chase them!
Into the cave!
Take cover!
Castlepool, hold your gun down!
- Up!
Thank you. Let's find Forrester, now.
- We can't!
Forrester must be left to the Assinaboions.
Tihe kusan oloka? - Lo!
There!
I'm thankful to you. I spent a good summer out here.
And, now what do you plan to do?
- Oh...
I'll be teaching at my university. And then, I'll begin a new collection.