Ole, guapa.
Bueno.
Ole.
Ole. Viva Espana.
Forgive me, Senorita
may l tell you how divine you are?
You are most kind.
Would you have
a glass of wine with me?
-ls this man annoying you?
-No.
He has merely
invited me for a drink.
Senorita Fuentes is occupied tonight.
Who is this man?
What is he to you?
Nothing.
lf the Senorita joins my party,
it's no concern of yours.
-You'd be wise to keep out of this.
-l do not want a scandal.
But the lady does not
want your company.
And l do not want yours!
-Shall l stop the fight?
-Not yet. This may be interesting!
-The stranger is an expert swordsman.
-This is an affair of honor!
Let them go.
You've killed him!
Take this man to the cuartel.
Lock him up!
At once.
A regrettable incident. Rest assured,
his aggressor shall not go unpunished!
You call yourself soldiers?
You cannot handle one man?
Throw him in a cell!
He is like a tiger!
Why did you not stop the fight sooner?
l've a plan, Garcia.
This hot-blooded stranger
gave me an idea.
-He's going to help me eliminate Zorro!
-Oh.
Steady, Tornado, steady.
Easy, boy.
Easy, hold it.
Good boy, Tornado.
Now we can get on with the training.
Everything clear?
Take cover!
No, Tornado. No fair, peeking.
Get back.
Good boy, Tornado. You found me!
You're getting to be
a pretty smart horse.
No one lives around here.
By the saints!
l may have discovered Zorro's hideout.
Hold it, Tornado. Easy, boy.
Steady, Tornado, steady.
Easy, boy, easy.
Soldiers? Did they see you?
Cover for me.
l will get Tornado out of here.
What are you doing out here?
Oh, never mind. He is deaf and dumb,
and l know l heard someone whistle.
Search everywhere.
He must be here somewhere.
Look behind that big rock.
GARCIA: Look over there!
Keep searching.
Do not overlook anything.
Oh, never mind. lt is him.
lt is him whistling.
Stop searching.
Oh. You can save us a trip.
l have a letter here
for Don Alejandro.
Let me... Oh, yes.
See that he gets it.
Oh, thank you!
Come on, muchachos.
We have more letters to deliver.
This is the height of irony.
After everything the Comandante
has done, he is trying to make amends.
''We request the pleasure
of your company
''at the dinner for the
leading citizens of our community.
''8:00 tonight at the
posada of Los Angeles.''
Well, l certainly am not going!
lf the leading citizens are going,
you should go.
l refuse to honor him
with my presence.
Not to honor him, so much,
but at the same time, not to offend him.
l will write a polite note
declining his most kind invitation.
Oh, uh, have Bernardo wait for it.
You heard the invitation?
A dinner for leading citizens.
l wonder what new deviltry
is the Comandante up to?
When you deliver my father's answer,
see what you can find out.
Open the cell door.
The Comandante wishes to see you.
How much longer
must l endure this humiliation?
That is what the Comandante
wishes to discuss with you now.
Come in!
-Let no one disturb us, Sergeant.
-Si, Comandante.
Last night you promised me freedom
in exchange for a favor.
-What is the favor?
-You are a daring, impetuous man.
Quick with a blade,
too quick for your own good.
-l had to defend my honor.
-Naturally.
And the lady in question
is most attractive, though fickle.
Come to the point, Capitan.
What am l supposed to do?
You have heard
of the mysterious outlaw, Zorro?
The champion of the people.
His fame has spread to Monterey.
He is a blackguard and a bandit!
Then put him in your
filthy cell instead of me.
-Or can't you catch him?
-l haven't been able to.
The people are protecting him.
They regard this scoundrel
as their friend.
When, in reality,
it is you who are their friend?
Exactly!
Tonight l am giving
a dinner at the tavern.
lt's only for the large landowners
and a few rancheros as well.
You will appear,
without invitation, of course,
as the masked bandit, Zorro.
Does this appeal to you?
Anything appeals to me
that gets me out of here.
Excellent! Come into
my quarters, please.
l have a copy of
the disguise Zorro wears.
l should like you to put it on.
The cloak.
-Now the hat.
-ls it becoming?
Quite dashing.
-Hmm.
-And now the mask.
Hardly the material
l would choose for myself.
-lt is better than prison garb.
-How do l look?
The resemblance is extraordinary!
-Yes, you will do very well.
-Just what will l do?
You will rob my guests,
even the poor ones.
Make it a point to
mistreat the servants.
A blow with the flat
of my sword, perhaps?
-Or shall l cut off an ear?
-Anything that pleases you.
We must discredit Zorro with all classes
so they will not protect him.
l will easily capture him.
After l have thoroughly proved
what a monster Zorro is,
-l am allowed to escape?
-You will vanish in the night.
-lt sounds simple.
-lt is simple.
My guests will be unarmed.
Garcia will be stationed at the front door
to see you are not interrupted.
Suppose a guest objects
to being robbed?
Then you will, of course,
defend your honor.
l bow to a true friend of the people.
Well, we meet again, eh?
Ah, the Comandante is over at the
posada getting everything ready.
The com...
Come with me.
This may require an answer.
-lnnkeeper!
-Yes, Senor Comandante?
-You have a tablecloth, l hope?
-Tablecloth?
You idiot! Do you expect
my guests to eat from bare boards?
-Do you have a large tablecloth?
-The finest, Comandante!
That is more like it.
Esperanza, take the sheets
off the bed in number three.
Oh, si, Senor, si.
Comandante, this is the servant
of the de la Vega hacienda.
He brought this letter for you.
Don Alejandro de la Vega regrets
that he cannot accept my invitation.
He shall come
whether he wishes to or not!
Have him wait for a reply.
lnnkeeper! Bring me
a pen and ink, quickly!
At once, Senor Comandante.
-l've made arrangements for the trap.
-Shh.
Oh, don't worry about him.
Remember, he is deaf and dumb.
Watch.
See? Deaf as a post!
Give me that doubloon.
lt is mine.
lt's a payment on what you owe me.
But it is all l have.
Now l cannot buy a single drink!
You never worried about that before!
Please, Capitan, could l have
a little advance on my pay?
l will give you an extra month's pay
if we are successful
in destroying Zorro tonight!
Apparently, this is a reply
from the Comandante.
''l cannot accept your refusal
to attend my dinner.
''lt is imperative that a representative
of every family be present.
''Do not fail to attend.''
This is not an invitation!
lt is an order!
So like the Comandante,
so lacking in tact.
l still refuse to go!
Senor Alcalde, those books l promised
to lend you, l shall get them for you.
Should l humble myself in order
to avoid Monastario's displeasure?
No. l wonder what
the purpose of this dinner is.
Whatever the purpose,
it cannot be for our welfare!
No, no, no. Not so fast. Now,
begin at the beginning.
You... You met Sergeant Garcia?
He took you to the tavern?
Don't tell me he bought you a drink!
Capitan Monastario was there.
He read my father's letter
and became angry. l can imagine!
He said something about Zorro? What?
Going to slit his throat?
Going to shoot him?
Oh! They're going to hang him!
Poison him?
Well, shoot him or hang him or...
lt seems they intend to destroy him.
All right, Mr. Oh-So-Clever-One.
Now l know the reason for that dinner.
They're setting a trap. And for some
reason they expect Zorro to be there.
Very good, Bernardo.
Let us not disappoint them.
Here they are. l'd mislaid them.
Thank you, but l...
About the Comandante's dinner.
You do not have to go.
The invitation says a representative
of each family. l'll go in your place.
l'm sorry, the tavern
is closed for the evening.
The Comandante
is giving a private party.
Honorable Alcalde of the pueblo
de Los Angeles, caballeros,
it is indeed gratifying
that not one person
failed to accept
my humble invitation.
All of our leading families
are represented here.
Don Alejandro de le Vega was
unable to attend because of illness.
But he sent his son in his place.
You have perhaps wondered
why l invited you here tonight.
The purpose is to promote
the feeling of harmony
and mutual respect in our community.
During the year
l have been Comandante,
several regrettable
misunderstandings have taken place.
Some of you may feel
that l have been overzealous
in the administration of my office.
Caballeros, let me assure you,
with my hand on my heart,
that l have only done my duty
for the glory of Spain
and devoted service
to our noble monarch.
Caballeros, l propose a toast.
To His Majesty, the king!
ALL: To the king!
And now that we have
sealed our friendship,
drink and be merry.
On with the entertainment!
Everyone line up over there!
Move! Quickly!
You too!
lnnkeeper, over here!
Pick it up, you clumsy lout!
-Oh.
-Collect their valuables.
Yes.
Never mind the musicians.
They never have money.
l'm sorry, Don Diego.
No violence, please, Senor Zorro!
You're making a mistake.
l'm a poor man!
Without your life's blood,
you would be much poorer!
Get me my clothes.
A man in there is impersonating Zorro,
robbing the people.
Please do not take my jewelry.
lt was my mother's.
Would you rather have
your pretty throat cut?
Canalla.
l thought you were already inside!
Hurry up. l'll hold the ladder for you.
l'll be in front when you escape!
Put it in my sash.
Stand back. He's mine!
You fool! What did you come back for?
Fight me and make it look good!
You're overdoing it.
Zorro!
-What's going on here?
-Look!
-Two Zorros! Which one is ours?
-l know the real one!
Don't interfere. He is mine!
Adios, Senor lmpostor!
This is not Zorro. This is the stranger
that killed Romero in the duel!
-He took our money.
-Yes, and here it is!
How did he get out of jail?
Well...
Sergeant Garcia, explain yourself!
-Capitan, you know very well that...
-Silence! Not a word!
Take this man to his cell.
See that he does not escape this time!
Si, Comandante.
Up, prisoner! March!
Oh, Senor Alcalde.
Here is your watch.
-Muchas gracias!
-Your jewelry, Senorita.
-Gracias.
-This...
This ring belongs to Don Diego.
Don Diego? Don Diego, where are you?
Here l am!
l saw no reason in allowing that bandit
to get away with everything!
-Here is your ring and your purse.
-Thank you.
l think l'd better be leaving.
Oh, Comandante, thank you
for a delightful evening.
lf you'll excuse me
for leaving so early...
Well, l just haven't
been myself all evening.