Thanks for helping me record, Finn.
No problem, Marceline.
Now, I'm gonna sing something really
personal, so don't laugh at me.
I would never dream of it...
m'lady. (Laughs)
Now, start a slow beat, and keep it
steady, or it'll mess up
everything.
You got it!
Daddy, why did you eat my fries?
I bought them, and they were mine.
But you ate them, yeah, you ate my fries...
And I cried, but you didn't see me cry.
Daddy, Do you even love me?
Well, I wish you'd show it,
'Cause I wouldn't know it.
What kind of dad eats his daughter's fries,
And doesn't look her in the eyes?
Daddy, there were tears there.
If you saw them would you even care?
Huh? Finn, you messed the beat up!
Marceline, if you're
thinkin' about your dad
so much, then... why
don't you go see 'im?
He's not worth the effort.
Not worth what effort?
Well... first, I'd
have to draw a circle
with a happy face
in the center..
And then... uh... douse it with bug milk.
Oh, yeah?!
And then you're supposed to chant something
like, "Maloso
vobiscum et cum spiritum."
But... I-I don't really wanna see him.
I'm still mad about the
thing with the fries. Huh?!
Wwwwhhhat?! Whoa... whoa!! Aaagh!!
Marceline!
Finn... what the heck did you do?!
I... reunited you with your family?
Is this kid your evil servant?
I'm not evil, Marceline's dad. I'm super good!
"Super good?"
What're you doing?!
Stealing your soul.
Dad! Ugh! You always do stuff like this!
Haha! Oh, Marceline!
I never know what's gonna set you off!
Whoa! Is this the family axe?
Wha—? HEY!!!
Did you turn it into some kind of lute?
Give it back, and get out!!!
Okay, I'll go.
I've got business to attend to, anyway-
—sucking up all the souls in Oooooo...
WHA—Gh—NO!!
See you kids later!
My bass!
I've unleashed evil onto Ooo!
We've gotta stop 'im, Marceline!
Fine... but I'm only coming with you to get my bass back.
Hey! How do I kill this guy, anyway?
Finn! You can't kill my dad!
Oh! I'm sorry! I didn't mean—
No! You literally can't kill my dad! He's deathless!
Oh...
Huh? Who the fluff are you?
Um... Well, I'm sure not the guy who's gonna suck out your soul.
Good 'cause that's, like, my number one fear.
Really!? Well... I know a little exercise for that! Wanna try?
Wow...
First... close your eyes.
Okay!
AAH! You coulda killed me!
Ah, but I didn't! And now, aren't you thrilled just to be alive?
Yeah, I guess... So what?
So... This next part will be all the more... horrifying.
There!! Below us! A gathering of Fluffy People!
May-haps they've seen your father!
Marceline... release the Finn-bomb!
They're all freaked out!
It's because they're scared of him.
Hm. My dad's been here. Come on. Let's go.
No! We gotta help this guy.
I've got some soul food that Jake packed for me.
You like, uh, collard greens or country-fried steak?
Look. You wanna help him? Help me get my bass back.
How will that help hi—?
MY DAD STOLE MY BASS GUITAR, FINN!! And when I get it back...
I'm gonna break it over his neck and slam my dad back into the Nightosphere!
Oh, clam! But first you
gotta return the souls
your dad sucked back to
these sad, little husks.
Right, Marceline?
Uh, sure, yeah, yeah, we'll do that.
So I popped his head like a cork!
And I says, "That's what I think of expanding Earth theory!"
Alright.
Huh?!
I've got a joke, too.
What wears a dark suit, is completely evil, and is about to suck out all your souls?
Yo mama!
That's right! I'm your mama!
Red Rock Pass. If my dad wants to get through the mountains,
he'll have to come through here.
We can work together! And smash 'im with this rock!
And once he's smooshed,
all the souls will go back to their rightful bods.
Huh?
So, finally taking a run at your old man, huh?
Daddy...
Karate kick!!
Marceline!! Keep 'im right there!! HrrrrRAAAAGH!!!
Karate chop!!
You can't destroy me!
No... D-dad... I-I don't wanna destroy you...
Look, just... stay out of my life!!
You're not even alive!
You blew it, dude. We're supposed to be a team—
a team whose sport is stop-your-dad-from-suckin'-souls... ball.
I just want my dad to care about me.
Of all history's greatest monsters,
you are by far the most evil thing I've encountered.
Offer your soul to me, dark one.
Wenk wenk.
NO! You can't have my soul! I don't even...!
Look, just get in here.
Wenk wenk.
Keep your crummy soul!
Gunter! Who told you you could fly?!
Wenk.
Huh? No one sucks the life from my penguins except me!
...And maybe polar bears, because that's just nature, Gunter.
You darest encroach upon my domain?!
You've raised my frosty dander! And for that, I shall—
AAAAAOOOOOHHH!! I've soiled my tunic... completely by choice!
YES!!
Aw, man! He's growing huge!
I'm gonna take 'im down!
Finn, you're like an ant to him.
Oh, yeah? Well, this ant's about to get in his pants!
What?
Wha?
Because I'm going to make him uncomfortable
while I release those souls!
RAAAAAAAAGH!!!
Give up those souls, Marceline's dad!
In the name of justice!!
Huh?
Oh, Marceline. Still following me?
I'll stop following you if you give me back my guitar!
No, Marceline.
NO ONE FLICKS ME IN THE BUTT WITHOUT MY CONSENT!!!
Whoa, WHOA!
Whoooaa!!
The souls...
Lumpy Space Princess! He got your soul, too?!
What? Nah.
I totally saw Hot Dog Princess get sucked in here,
and I wasn't invited?!
I was all, "What the lump?" so I'm crashin' this party!
Well, I'll save you... I'LL SAVE ALL OF YOU!!
IN YOUR FACE, DAD!
Give back that ax, Marceline!
You don't respect it enough!
Well... you don't respect anything!
Dad!! DAD!! I'm outta here!
BUT—!!
Fine!! Go!! I'm too busy sucking to deal with you!
NO, WAIT! Marceline!! Keep talking to 'im!
When he's talking, he can't steal souls!!
I said I'm outta here!
Diversion... need... diversion.
Daddy, why did you eat my fries?
I bought them, and they were mine.
But you ate them, yeah, you ate my fries...
And I cried, but you didn't see me cry.
Daddy,
Do you even love me?
Well, I wish you'd show it,
Oh, my Glob, you guys! Drama bomb!
Marceline, do you really feel this way?
Dad, I...
Marceline... of course I love you.
Dad...
I'm sorry I ate your fries. I didn't mean to hurt you.
It's okay, Dad. It's... it's really okay.
No, it's not okay. They weren't even very good. They were really cold.
I love you, Marceline. Don't you ever doubt that.
I love you, too, Dad.
Oh, Marceline, I am so—
YALALALALALALALALALALALALA!!!!!
MALOSO VOBISCUM ET CUM SPIRITUM!!
I'll see you in the Nightosphere, ya sick freak.
YES!!!!
Finn!! How could you do that?!
How could I... save the day?
How could you embarrass me like that and then stab my dad?!
How could I embarrass-save you??
WHOA! Marceline!
I'm glad he's back in the Nightosphere.
That was emotionally exhausting.
I'm also exhausted emotionally. Or... wait.
I mean, I mean physically.
I've been meaning to ask you... What's with that pocket on your shirt?
Oh, Jake's in here. 'Sup, Jake?
*Farts*