Oh, thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Well, congratulate me.
I just managed to finagle reservations
for two at Emilio's.
- How does that sound, honey?
- Sounds good to me, sweetie.
That is wonderful, Willie.
What, is she coming too?
I thought this was gonna be our night.
Oh, for heaven's sake, ALF,
it's Valentine's Day.
Kate and I are looking forward
to spending an evening alone together.
It's what keeps us from becoming bitter.
I'll just spend Valentine's Day alone...
...without romance, without love...
...without two bodies
beyond rational thought.
[SIGHS]
[GROANS]
Oh, sorry. I'm back.
Anyone call while I was gone?
Oh, please, Willie? Stay home.
We'll order out. It'll be my treat.
By the way, can I borrow
a couple of hundred till payday?
I seem to have misplaced
your credit card.
For the last time, no, ALF.
[SIGHS]
[GROANS]
ALF, would you stop that?
Now, I understand
that this is not an easy time for you.
And, so?
Actually, that was all.
Oh. Somebody needs a fresh diaper.
Willie.
Oh. Oh, oh, oh!
- What is it?
- Oh, my hands.
Look at them.
They're shaking like a schoolboy's.
One of my favorite movie stars
just moved into this neighborhood.
"Louise Beaumont."
Why does that name sound so familiar?
Oh, she was the aging vamp
in Footlight Fancies...
...and she was the tap-dancing bag lady
in Broadway and 74th...
...and she played the Swedish bombshell
in Stage Door Yohnny.
"I love you, Yohnny, you big yerk."
Oh, I remember Louise Beaumont.
She was a minor movie star in her day.
Willie, Louise is a queen...
...and her castle's just a few blocks
from here.
"Sunset Villa"? ALF, it's not a castle.
It's a retirement home.
It's not unlike the place
I'll be staying in long before my time.
Let's do something mad, Willie.
Grab your Polaroid.
We'll swing by the home.
- You're right, that is mad.
- No, no, no. You see...
...I'll hide while you ask her to sing
the theme from Naughty Señoritas.
[HUMMING]
Please, please, ALF. Please.
Wouldn't be so bad
if you could only carry a tune.
There. That ought to hold you
till we get to the sitter's.
- We ready to go?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna hold my breath
until you take me to see Louise.
Night, ALF.
I'm gonna do it again.
Good night, ALF. We'll bring you
what's left off of our plates.
Oh, boy, oh, boy.
I'm "yumping" for "yoy."
Willie doesn't understand.
He has his woman.
Poor schlub.
But, oh, Louise.
That's it. I deserve one night in the sun.
Oh. But I'll need a clever disguise.
Maybe Kate's wedding dress.
Haven't worn that in a while.
No. White always makes me look
too busty.
Oh, wow.
This could be Louise's window.
That could be her nightstand.
Those could be her teeth.
Just my luck. She's not in them.
MAN 1:
I think it went that way. Did you see it?
Where? Where?
Oops.
MAN 2:
It was the ugliest thing I ever saw.
Did you catch the nose on that thing?
Hey!
Oh. Gotta learn to stop doing that.
REBECCA:
Oh, look.
Uh, look, I know it's a long shot,
but is this the Vatican Embassy?
What is it? What is it?
My guess, it's a giant talking rat.
Hey, hey, hey. Can a rat do this?
Jack, really.
Don't you know what that is?
It's a talking dog.
I'm sorry for my friends.
Oh, fine. You want a talking dog,
I'm a talking dog.
The square of the hypotenuse
of a right triangle...
...is equal to the sum of the squares
of the other two sides.
Well, whatever you are...
...we aren't allowed pets
or visitors after 8:00, so shoo, shoo.
- Wait, Bernie.
- What?
Don't antagonize him.
He might be one of those aliens.
No kidding.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Bernie, I'm talking about an alien
from outer space.
Don't hurt us. Please don't hurt us.
Oh, look. You seem like very nice people
with very little upper-body strength.
I'm gonna level with you.
And this doesn't leave the room.
The guy with the pants
pulled up to his neck is right.
I'm an alien.
Now, I'm sorry if I scared you.
People were chasing me.
For those of you
who remember back that far.
Do you eat and drink
like normal humans?
Depends on who you ask.
So you're an alien, eh?
Oh, son of a gun.
I always knew
you guys were up there somewhere.
An alien, eh?
Do you know what I think?
I think he's here to make us young.
Just like in Cocoon.
Oh. I never saw that movie.
- Yes, you did.
- No, I didn't.
We rented it last week. It's the one
that Opie directed, remember?
Oh, yes.
It's an amazing achievement
for an 8-year-old.
Let it go, Jack. Let it go.
I just came to get a peek
at Louise Beaumont.
Just point me to her room.
Can you do that?
She's just down the hall.
But you can't see her
unless you're a family member.
There's such a thing as rules,
you know.
Well, I'm her ex-husband, okay?
I just wanna get a quick snapshot
for old times' sake.
Excuse me.
REBECCA:
Miss High-and-Mighty...
...there's a talking dog out here
who wants to meet you.
ALF: No, no, no.
I don't want her to see me.
I just wanna take her picture.
JACK:
Go on, go on.
Uh....
Hi, Miss Beaumont.
I hope my presence doesn't scare you.
Look, I don't know what you are...
...or who put you up to this,
but I'm not interested.
So don't let the door hit your furry butt
on the way out.
Who does she think she is?
Roseanne Barr?
Gee, she seemed so much friendlier
in Cellblock Serenade.
- She treat all her fans this way?
- Forget about her. Let's talk about you.
You've been all over the universe.
What an incredible amount of knowledge
you must have.
Tell us, what's it like in outer space?
Well, it's empty.
It's big. It's cold.
It's like Star Trek V without the toupees.
Well, ciao.
Oh, where are you going?
Where's he going?
Sorry. My mission's accomplished here
on Earth.
Nanu Nanu.
MAN 1:
Let's try to take him alive.
I know he's here. I can smell his breath.
MAN 2:
Can we mess with him first?
Uh....
Maybe I'll stay until I get a ride home.
Mind if I use the phone?
He wants to phone home.
Just like in that movie Splash.
I swear, if my bones weren't
as brittle as saltines...
- ...I'd be out of here so fast--
- BEN: Hey, what's going on in there?
Uh-oh. Uh....
Listen. Uh, I'll be in there. Okay?
Uh, remember, you never saw me.
I don't exist, okay? Bye.
He's cute.
Okay, what are you guys up to?
Well, we don't have a talking dog
in the other room...
...if that's what you're getting at.
WOMAN: Hurry up, Ben.
The champagne's getting flat.
BEN:
Uh....
Right.
She's helping me...
...study.
Um....
If I had the operation...
...they say there's an 80-percent chance
that I could study again.
A hundred and fourteen
point eight. Perfect.
This thermometer tastes funny.
My son.
I sacrificed myself for 30 years
to make him a successful stockbroker...
...and he put me in here.
They should only make
that embezzlement rap stick.
I get the idea. The boy's a lox.
Why do I have 16 cards?
[GROANS]
Do you realize that all you've done
since I got here is complain?
Now, there's got to be more.
Well, you're the one
who broke up the gin game.
What's your problem, anyway?
Pick, pick, pick.
I just think you're wasting some
wonderful, valuable, precious time.
Let's have some fun.
How about I take you on the roof
and show you where I'm from?
Would you like that?
This isn't just a trick to use us
as sex drones to repopulate your planet?
Again with that fantasy.
Up on the roof?
Well, we could get into trouble.
I know, I know. It's against the rules.
Who cares? This isn't a prison.
You have choices.
Take a chance for once.
Besides, who's gonna tell?
Okay, let's do it.
We're breaking the rules.
How does it feel, Bernie?
Well, I wish I hadn't taken
that water pill.
Well, as long as it's not windy up there,
we're okay.
Come on, let's go.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Oh, it's you again. Get out.
Do you want me to call
the night supervisor?
Oh, come on, Lou.
I'm taking the over-the-hill gang
to the roof to show them where I'm from.
I may even do my lounge act.
I've been described as
a short Wayne Newton.
I'm sorry. I'm too busy.
Doing what?
Staring out the window?
Every once in a while,
a man walks by with a tire iron.
Something's going down, I know it.
Look, why don't you just come
and join the party?
Look, I just don't want to, okay?
Isn't there another aging actress
you can bother?
Try Milton Berle.
Fine.
Just that I took a lot of chances
coming here...
...to catch a glimpse of the person...
...that Eleanor Roosevelt once called
the sexiest woman alive.
Stop it.
Leave me alone.
I don't need you to remind me
that I was once important, okay?
You don't know what it's like...
...to suddenly end up
in a home somewhere...
...with a bunch of people
you don't know...
...and have nothing left
to look forward to.
Ha. Have I got a story.
Well, save it.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Let's go, ALF. Ben's studying again.
We heard him through the vents.
Okay, okay. I'll be right out.
Jack, check your fly.
Louise, please. Change your mind.
These people aren't so bad.
Sure, you don't wanna listen to them
suck on a hard candy...
...but they grow on you.
Oh, go on. Join the others.
Ha, ha. I've spent most of my life alone.
Another couple of years won't kill me.
Okay.
Do you think I could take your picture?
[CAMERA CLICKS]
For what it's worth...
...this is still one of the nicest moments
of my life.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Ha, ha. Yeah! We made it!
Hey, high fives and low fours all around.
Come on.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Oh, isn't this beautiful? Ha, ha.
Oh, look. Look.
There's your mothership.
Wave.
Yoo-hoo, yoo-hoo, down here.
Get ready to be transported.
- Rebecca, that's the Goodyear blimp.
- Sure.
That's what they'd like you to think.
Rebecca, open your eyes.
We're not going anywhere.
ALF, you said you'd show us
where you're from.
Yes, ALF.
Let us in on that wondrous secret
that few humans will ever know.
I'll do my best.
Let's see.
I think you can see it right over there.
Yep, right there. See?
It's that cheap, white tract home
three houses in from the corner.
Kind of makes you feel insignificant,
doesn't it?
No, no, no. That's the house
I'm staying in while I'm on Earth.
See, my planet exploded.
My lawyers recommend
I make no further comment at this time.
Hey, look.
Ben's got quite a setup over here.
He's always up here studying.
That settles it.
I'm going for that operation.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
Oh, isn't it romantic, though?
All the lights and the music and....
Oh, ALF. Thank you.
I'm going to send you
a big soup bone later.
Hey, all right.
Well, ahem, who wants to dance?
Hey. See? What'd I tell you?
I knew he had the hots for her.
Hey. I'm glad you changed your mind.
We were just getting down
with our bad selves.
I just came up for some fresh air.
And...
...well, maybe I am a little curious
about where you're from.
Okay.
Well...
...see that cheap, white tract home
three houses in from the corner?
Yes.
Well, if you look straight up...
...it's the big star directly above it.
Oh, my gosh.
That's so amazing.
Just think. A whole other world.
Do you miss it?
Every day.
How do you keep your spirits up
so far from home?
Well, I found making other people's lives
miserable helps.
But you've gotta find your own way.
Louise, why don't you go over there
and see if they wanna--?
Maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
Maybe I better go back downstairs.
No, no, no. You just got here.
Besides, what good is sitting alone
in your room?
Come. Hear the music play.
[SINGING]
Life is a cabaret, old chum
Okay, okay.
Wouldn't be so bad
if you could carry a tune.
You know, Bernie,
it would be a nice gesture...
...if you went over
and asked Louise to dance.
What?
Dance with her!
She's already dancing.
She didn't want me, the witch.
No, no, Louise.
Look, just dance with her, will you?
Do it for me.
Do it as a favor, huh?
Uh-oh.
Would you like to dance?
I hope she asked me to dance.
Well, Tonto,
I think our work here is done.
Jack, watch the hands.
I run a clean dance hall here.
Man.
[CHUCKLES]
And then when I was at MGM,
I went out with Clark Gable.
Wow.
Hey, is it true what they say
about men with big ears?
[LAUGHING]
ALF.
Willie, I see you got my message.
Come on over.
Oh, look. We have a visitor.
Who died?
What were you thinking? I can't believe
you'd expose yourself like this.
- What? I'm wearing a sweatshirt.
- You know what I mean.
Hey, lighten up. I'll fill you in later.
Now, I want you to meet my friends.
- Bernie, Rebecca, Jack...
- Hello there.
...and, of course, Louise Beaumont.
- How do you do?
- This is my best friend, Willie.
Hello. It's nice to meet you.
I'll pay for the damages.
- Come on. We should be going.
- Just a second.
I have to say goodbye now.
I'll always remember you guys.
I only wish you could say
the same about me.
Goodbye, ALF.
I want you to have this.
It's the scarf I wore in
Stage Door Yohnny.
Oh, thank you.
Wow. I wish I had something
to return the favor.
You already have, dear.
Happy Valentine's Day, ALF.
[GROANS]
- Bye, guys.
JACK: Bye.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
I don't know why,
but I think I may be proud of you.
Yeah? Save it till we get past
the guy with the tire iron.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]