Previously on Eureka.
Loose smart dust could
potentially disrupt
every band on the
electromagnetic spectrum.
Phones, computers...
Neural impulses in our brains.
Where's the control unit?
We have a G.D. employee
in custody
under suspicion
of espionage.
Justice will be taking over
that investigation immediately.
You have one message
in your inbox.
Holly was printing
a body blank
in the
neural networking lab.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Carter.
Sorry, Jo.
Can't help you right now.
Got some things
to take care of.
- Those are Z-waves.
- But then Holly's pattern
wasn't the only one
stuck in there.
Or maybe something else
is trying to get out.
Something else from the
matrix? That ain't good.
Zane Donovan,
you're under arrest
for obstruction of justice
and destroying evidence.
Fargo, I think I found your
missing smart dust controller.
Hi.
We got a...
Now, we're even.
Jack,
where have you been?
I... I've been trying
to reach you for hours.
Well, sorry.
I guess the smart dust
is still... yeah, messing
with the cell reception.
But we found the control unit,
which is good.
Fargo says he'll
have it fixed soon.
No, not that.
Zane and I found something.
We don't even know
what we found
and then Shaw
arrested him.
Yeah, we heard.
And then you decided
to have coffee?
Don't you fret,
Dr. Blake.
Ms. Lupo is handling
the situation as we speak.
Well, handling it how?
In her usual way, with
intimidation and brute force.
Jack,
this isn't funny.
Shaw thinks that Zane
destroyed classified files.
And something else
disturbing is going on.
Jo, Henry, Holly.
People are not
acting like themselves.
I'm sure it's
just the smart dust.
The electromagnetic chaff
could be affecting
people's brain functions.
No, I don't think
that that's it...
But the E.M. levels
are on the decline.
See, we have a plan.
Dr. Tuchman, one Peruvian
macchiato to go. Enjoy.
Thanks, Vince.
Well, I think we should
probably get back to work.
Catch up with you later,
babe. Promise.
Bye.
Where are you going?
Protect and serve.
You have a visitor.
Could we,
have a moment?
Make it fast,
you don't have much time.
Grace, good to see you.
So, Henry, have you, uh,
thought about what I said?
Of course.
Could you remind me?
Don't play.
You are not responsible
for me being locked up,
which is why I'm
not giving you a choice.
If you say that you helped me
leak classified information,
I'll deny it. They have
no evidence to hold you.
They have no evidence
to hold you.
Shaw's just
making an example.
Henry, I know what I did and
I can accept the consequences.
I can't.
I won't.
And that's why
I'm getting you out of here.
Henry, what are you...
Grace, trust me.
This is the only way.
You're my wife.
And I will never
let you go.
Morning.
Dr. Tuchman, right?
Yes. I...
I do something wrong, sheriff?
Well, the smart asphalt
sensor said you were weaving.
Well, I don't think so.
It's probably
just a glitch.
Say, weren't you
on the Astraeus crew?
Yeah, unfortunately
as it turned out.
Yeah.
You're going
to have to come with us.
To where?
Back where you belong.
I don't understand.
You will.
Get out of the car,
please.
This way.
This way,
right here.
Right this way.
I've got you.
You're just making this
harder on yourself, Donovan.
I know you destroyed the files
implicating Dr. Monroe.
What files
do you speak of?
You're trying
my patience, kid.
And you're
wasting my time, pops.
You've got nothing
tying me to this
or you would have
arrested me by now.
He's right.
He's guilty
and we both know it.
Probably, but you don't
have enough to charge him.
You want me to release
your boyfriend?
Shocking.
He won't go anywhere
we can't find him.
Major Shaw, sir.
"Probably"?
Whose side are you on, Jo?
Do you want to be
in his custody or mine?
Grace Monroe just
escaped from detention.
What, wh...
How?
I don't know, but it looks
like someone else helped her.
While I was in here.
Apology accepted.
You can cut him loose,
but he's your responsibility.
Gather your team,
I want Monroe found.
Yes, sir.
Promise me
you won't wander off.
There is something
very, very wrong.
People are doing things
that don't make any sense,
like they've
been brainwashed.
Yeah, well, with smart dust
jamming up the works,
they could be.
But Jack said you found
the control unit
and you were
fixing it.
That's the first
I've heard of it
and I haven't
seen Carter in hours.
See?
Brainwashed.
What, him or me?
Jury's still out.
Where's the
bio-printer?
Henry said that he
had it moved to maintenance.
I never
authorized that.
I'm guessing
that you didn't give Holly
permission to start
printing body blanks, either.
What?
Do you know how many millions
of dollars those things cost?
Man, girlfriends are expensive.
What was she thinking?
I don't think
she was.
Zane found other
Z-wave signatures
in the mainframe where
Holly was being stored.
What if that's why she started
bio-printing more bodies?
But why would she create
new bodies for them?
Maybe because
the program told her to.
There was a deliberate
energy pulse in the lab.
What if it was a command
that her neural processor
was responding to?
So you really think
others are controlling Holly?
Zane and I saw something.
Hands, like someone
was trying to get out.
What if they did?
Power supply
is holding steady.
Smart dust control unit
is working perfectly.
Virtual Eureka
is back online.
This time,
they won't get out.
I'm going to miss
this one.
We can always
make you a new one.
And when we get
the rest of them,
I think I'm going
to like it out here.
Well, it looks like
these DNA profiles
were bio-printed
onto the bodies.
My God.
It's Jo...
And Henry and at least
a dozen others.
If they took
the bio-printer,
they could have
copied anyone by now.
Fargo, people aren't
being brainwashed.
They're being replaced.
What are you guys looking at?
What?
I was released, okay?
I didn't bust out
like someone else I know.
It's Jack.
He's one of them.
Who's "them"?
Dr. Yoo, just the woman
I'm looking for.
What can I do
for you, sheriff?
Well, I need you
to come with me.
Police business.
I need your expertise.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Love the jacket,
by the way.
You're telling me
Carter, Henry, and Jo
are all evil clones
made by Holly?
Well, technically
VR-programmed intelligences
in bio-printed bodies,
but yeah, evil clones.
I knew Jo was off,
but not that off.
I can't believe
this is happening.
Tell me about it.
My resurrected girlfriend
is the
Manchurian Candidate.
Well, we have to find them.
We need outside help.
Well, half the time
we can't call out,
reception is so spotty.
I have an idea.
I have access to a
priority-5 gets hard-line
that goes directly
to NORAD HQ.
It's dead.
They've cut us off.
We're on our own now.
What about Shaw?
They don't have
his DNA on file,
so they
can't copy him.
Plus, he has rocket launchers.
I'm on it.
I have to
find my kids.
All right, I'm going
to get us some weapons.
Nonlethal.
If we can't tell the good guys
from the bad,
we can't just kill them.
Well, we better hope
the evil clones
play by
the same rules then.
Director, I know people
have infiltrated G.D.
That's why I'm here.
I'm not talking spies.
More, doubles.
Double agents?
No,
haven't you noticed?
People have been acting
not themselves lately.
One person
comes to mind.
Well, not me. I mean...
Jo, hey.
Am I interrupting?
No, we're just...
Military man talk.
Really, you served?
Which division?
Long division.
The director seems very
distressed about...
Grace's escape.
It's terrible, really.
Do you have
any new leads?
Actually, uh, yes.
Comm's still patchy,
but we have a
security scan hit.
Grace Monroe's credit card
was used an hour ago
at a a service station
in grants pass.
Now, let's get
a team moving.
Wait, wait, wait.
That's weird, isn't it?
I mean, Grace wouldn't
be so careless.
She's on the run,
people panic.
Sir. Every second
we waste, her trail gets colder.
Agreed. Keep us
on high-alert until I return.
Fargo, I was wondering
if we could review
the latest security
lockdown procedures.
They're in my office.
No, it's okay. I mean,
the regularly scheduled
security briefing
will be fine.
You expect me
to believe that people
are being
body-snatched?
I know how it sounds.
It sounds like you're
stupid or stoned or both.
My vote's for both.
Just think for a minute.
Has anyone you know
been acting strangely?
Not themselves?
Tuchman didn't show up
for work today,
but he's always had
a lazy work ethic.
Lazy work ethic,
Okay, how is this
even possible?
My God.
Zane, stay back.
That is not me.
What? You're not me.
I'm me.
What the hell,
Zane?
Come on, man.
I'm me.
Prove it.
Okay, uh, during
estrange training, uh,
you came into Cafe Diem
and I tried to give you
one of my lima coins.
And then you didn't
want to take it,
so we thought that
it would be funny if
we covered them in tabasco
and gave them to Fargo.
Zane, come on.
Just shoot this idiot.
You know he's not me.
I trust you.
If you say so.
Zane, don't!
How did you know
that it wasn't me?
The real you
wouldn't trust me.
You dematerialized me.
Yeah, what happened
to non-lethal weapons?
Well, that one's
a work in progress.
Yeah, you don't say.
Betrayed by my own DNA.
Gross.
So what else
can we use
that won't splatter
innocent people?
Well, I guess we could
develop something
that would specifically
target them.
But if they're like Holly,
they're basically human.
Yeah, their bodies.
But not the Z-waves underpinning
their consciousness.
What if we make
a sort of E.M.P.
That'll fry only
that brainwave frequency.
That would knock
them all out.
If it worked.
Trust me,
it's not my first rodeo.
I taste like chicken.
Doug.
- Holly.
- I'm so glad to see you.
Okay,
why exactly?
Something really weird
is happening.
It's like... it's like
I'm not myself anymore.
I mean, not at this
exact moment.
Right now, I am me.
I just don't know
for how long.
They're making
me do things.
Who?
The NPCs,
from matrix Eureka.
It's like they made me
walk in my sleep, but instead
of raiding the fridge,
I'm spitting out bodies.
Like the queen alien
on Lv-426.
Okay, well that would
explain why Allison and I
found DNA patterns in
your bio-printer files.
- They made me do it, Doug.
- It's okay.
I know you wouldn't go
all pod-person on purpose.
But why would they print
replicants of us?
What do they want?
They're everywhere.
Come on, I know a place
where we can talk safely.
S.A.R.A.H., where's...
Kevin.
I need you to pack
an overnight bag,
we're going
on vacation.
Sweet, where to?
To your Nanna's.
Okay,
that's not vacation.
All right, that's me staying
upwind of grandpa all day.
I mean, he needs to lay off
the chili, I'm sorry.
Honey, just pack, quickly.
Please. Now.
Dr. Blake, your
blood pressure is elevated.
Is everything
all right?
S.A.R.A.H., I'm fine.
Honey, I will explain
to you on the way,
we need to pick up
Jenna from the day care.
No need.
I've got her
right here.
Hi, mommy.
Babe.
Where you
running off to?
Kevin,
bring Jenna upstairs.
Now.
Mom, why are
you tripping?
Yeah.
Jack isn't himself.
He's sick. I need to
bring him to G.D.
Actually,
I've never felt better.
Dr. Blake, a
full-body CT scan shows
that sheriff Carter
is perfectly healthy.
And looking forward
to some quality time together.
Not with them.
We could go somewhere.
Alone.
Subtle, mom.
Dang, get a room.
It's not what
she means.
But I got a room.
Here.
S.A.R.A.H.,
why don't you make
a snack for the kids?
Happy to.
But there's just one thing.
S.A.R.A.H., what...
What are you doing?
Kevin, it's fine.
This isn't Jack.
What?
It's a long story.
S.A.R.A.H.,
how did you know?
My CT scan also
included a DNA analysis.
Although it matched
sheriff Carter perfectly,
his cells are
only one day old.
You mean he's a clone?
Sweet.
Can we keep him please?
This is Jack's evil twin,
not a puppy.
Zane? Can you hear me?
Tell me that you
found something.
How about a Z-wave bomb
that'll fit in your pocket,
but should knock out
all the NPCs on one go?
Okay, wait a minute.
"Should" knock them out?
Yeah, we just need
an NPC test subject
that we can calibrate
the Z-wave frequency.
We, uh, kind of
microwaved our last one.
Okay, well, I think
I can help you with that.
But we need to find
a safe place
where they won't
be looking for us.
I'll meet you
at the cabin.
Kevin, honey, I need you
to help me move him
and then I need you to lock
the door and keep Jenna inside.
Don't let anyone in
until I get back.
Don't worry,
I'll keep them safe.
Mom,
you're scaring me.
Honey, everything
is going to be okay.
All right, I just need
you to trust me.
Come on,
let's move him.
It was so terrifying.
It was like that dream
where you're trying to scream,
but all you
can speak is orcish
and you know what
you're doing is wrong,
but there's no way
to stop yourself.
Yeah, I don't think
I've ever had that dream.
Me neither, but that's
exactly what it was like.
So
where are we going?
Just
a little bit further.
Brain-jacking really,
really sucks.
You're my hero.
Are you looking
for this?
I really wanted
to trust you.
You can't win,
Doug.
I'm so sorry,
Holly.
Well, that was
uncalled for.
Where's Jack?
Let's call it
"napping."
So he's alive?
Of course he's a valuable
intellectual resource.
You all are,
we don't want to hurt you.
Yeah, I wasn't born
yesterday, unlike you.
Clever.
It's for
the greater good, Allie.
Just think about it.
When you're back inside,
you'll be able to create
all sorts of amazing things
without potentially
destroying the world.
Back in wh...
Beverly's matrix program.
You're still acting on
your last directive
to keep us inside.
Call me stubborn.
So you want to put
the entire Astraeus crew
back in matrix Eureka?
Well, we're protecting
you from yourselves.
So that you can work
in safety and peace.
And the more brainpower,
the better.
My work is here. My family
is here. Jack is here.
Yes, I am.
And when I'm done,
no one
will even miss you.
A flux compression
generator bomb, nice.
Yeah, when it's time,
we flip that switch
and sayonara,
doppelgangers.
You know, Donovan,
I have always maintained
that under
proper supervision
you are not
completely incompetent.
Well, damn, Parrish.
That's probably the nicest
thing that you've
ever said to...
Probably anyone,
actually.
All right,
let's meet Allison
and take down
these meat puppets.
Okay
may I have
your attention...
By order of director Fargo,
G.D. is now under lockdown.
No entering or exiting
without authorization.
Have a nice day.
Yeah.
Are we there yet?
Shut up.
Would you
look at that.
Damn it.
There's nowhere
to run, Allie.
You're only making it
worse for yourself.
Well, she's got spunk.
I'll give her that.
GD is now on lockdown,
status Bravo.
Crap.
Why would Fargo
lock us down?
I'm betting he didn't.
You think
Larry's been replaced?
Well, maybe
all of them have.
Either way,
we're trapped.
The NPCs think that
I've been replaced, right?
So as NPC Parrish,
I put you in handcuffs,
and I walk you
right out the front door
as my prisoner.
I don't know, man.
Come on, Zane.
Dude, it will be just like
in Star Wars when
Han Solo put Chewie in handcuffs
to fool the imperial guards.
In this scenario,
you're Han Solo?
Yeah.
Trust me, Zane.
I was born to do this.
I can't believe
it didn't work.
Seriously, dude,
you're an asshat.
Come on, Han, time to
encase you in carbonite.
He's only kidding,
actually we're going
to insert a bio-absorbable
stent made of polylatic acid
into your bloodstream
and then hook you up
to a giant hive-mind.
Forever.
That is so not better.
I am really
done with her.
We'll find her.
Hear that,
Allison?
Come out, come out
wherever you are.
Where do you think
you're going?
To find my husband.
Baby, I'm hurt.
He's right here.
You got her, boss?
The hell he is.
Stop.
Carter, hurry!
She's on the road.
Stop.
Allison,
what are you...
Go, go, go.
Go!
Now what?
Now we do this
the hard way.
What happened to her?
You were right, the NPCs
have been controlling her,
making her bio-print
bodies to download into.
That's because they're
putting people
back inside the matrix program.
And they're not just stopping
at the crew... they're trying
to replace us all.
Not without a fight.
I'm telling you, Vincent.
People are being taken.
By whom?
By the sheriff
and deputy Andy.
And Jo and her guards.
We need
to warn everyone.
My God.
They're here.
Okay.
Everyone
in the freezer.
Jo.
Andy.
Vincent.
Where is everybody?
In the freezer.
Carter put in
satellite TV.
How very old school.
Fargo, focus.
Something is wrong.
Zane and Parrish should
have been here by now.
Unless they
were taken.
We need the bomb
to nullify the NPCs'
Z-wave signature.
We're going to have
to do this ourselves.
Yeah, but we have
to connect it to the
smart dust control unit
to amplify the pulse.
I bet the clone army
is using it
to power the new
matrix computer.
Yeah, except we don't
have the Z-bomb.
That does pose
an issue.
Wait a minute, Zane said
the Z-bomb fit into his pocket.
So if he and Parrish
were taken, maybe
he could still
have it.
So we just
need to find out
where they're being held
and activate it.
Except we have no clue
where that is.
Someone does.
We just need
to follow her.
Nice work, Mata Hari.
And Allison is where,
exactly?
Well played.
We need to widen
and regroup.
The program isn't complete
without the final two.
Mata Hari was probably
innocent, you know.
A better spy analogy
would have been Emily Geiger
from the
American revolution.
Or Belle Boyd during
the Civil War.
Or Violette Szabo
from World War II.
She was awesome.
Do you have
an off switch?
Okay, you find Zane,
see if he has the Z-bomb.
I'll sync my PDA to
the smart dust control unit
and amplify the pulse.
Okay, well be careful.
Don't get caught,
we may be
the only ones left.
That's reassuring.
I'll go this way.
The crew.
My God.
Jack.
Honey, you got to wake up.
You got to wake up.
Come on.
Any time now.
Silent mode,
silent mode.
Frak me.
You,
you're with me.
They're outside.
All hands on deck.
I'll be back.
Hi, Doug.
Okay.
You slippery
little fish.
Let's go, Fargo.
Get back.
Easy, easy, easy.
We don't want
to hurt you.
Speak for yourself,
he made me run.
You know
what they say, Doug.
Resistance is futile.
That's what you think.
He's controlling
the smart dust.
Well, that's annoying.
I can't see anything.
I knew night vision
mode would come in handy.
He won't get far.
- Can anyone see him?
- Think he's gone this way.
Why is Doug
even bothering?
Do not let him
get away.
Good question.
Zane, thank God.
Please be the bomb.
Thank you.
Mommy?
What are you doing?
Please don't hurt me,
mommy.
- Please.
- Jenna.
Jenna?
No, you're not real.
You're not real.
Yes, I am.
And I'm scared.
I don't understand
what's happening.
Will you stay with me?
Mommy's tricky,
isn't she?
Good job,
sweetheart.
Now you go play,
okay?
No.
I want to watch.
Always the curious one,
yeah?
No, no.
That's quite enough,
Dr. Fargo.
How did you...
I have
infra-red vision, too.
Man.
So I suppose we can't
talk this out,
man to replicant.
We're done talking.
Relax, mommy.
Time to go to sleep.
Please, I can't
leave my kids.
Jo and I will
take care of them.
Over my dead body.
We don't
want that.
Bye, mommy.
Relax,
I'll be right here.
So will I.
- Daddy.
- Jack.
Did he hurt you?
No, I'm fine.
I am so happy to see you,
the real you.
Go. Go.
It came
from in here.
Daddy.
They're gone.
Daddy's very angry.
Please tell me
that thing can help us.
It can.
Do I sense a, "but,"
or an, "if"?
If we can amplify it.
Fargo was trying to link it to
the smart dust controller,
but I think they got him.
They
we can't go back.
Not without
broadcasting the location.
Wait a minute.
Broadcasting,
that could work.
Well, I don't think
that will help us.
No, no,
but the cabin.
We could use the satellite dish
to amplify the Z-wave signal.
We just have to get
the NPCs to follow us.
I don't think that's going
to be a problem, run.
Don't let them
get away.
Can't have gone too far.
Come on, let's go.
Try the back door.
Jack.
Okay, where's
the satellite dish?
- It's in the loft.
- Okay.
Game over.
I just hate myself
sometimes.
You okay?
I got to
kick my ass.
I know
all your moves.
This one's new.
They're coming.
Jack!
Come on, let's go.
Come on, Jack.
Get up.
My God.
Allie.
Up there!
Lights...
Out.
Okay, I got it.
Holly.
You okay?
Yeah,
are you all right?
Well, there's only
one of me, so yeah.
Well, one of you
is all I need.
I love you
so much.
I'm not sure if I'm
comfortable with this.
The NPCs have human
brainwave patterns
that were downloaded into
bio-printed bodies.
There are ethical considerations
to how we deal with them.
I think you're just
keeping a spare around
in case I don't
work out.
No comment.
Well,
what else we got?
Shaw still camped out
in Fargo's office?
Yes, but I don't think
that Fargo has noticed.
He hasn't left
Holly's side since we
set off the Z-wave bomb.
It's been, like,
two weeks.
- And she's still comatose.
- Yeah.
911.
Holly.
Is the neural lattice
collapsing?
No, synaptic firing rate
is rising, and still stable.
Wait, is...
Is that good?
Come on, Holly.
You can do this.
Looks like she's
trying to wake up.
Holly?
That's my girl.
Okay, now just
need to...
Hi.
Welcome back.
You must be
director Fargo.
I'm Dr. Holly Marten.
I'm here to see your
F.T.L. drive.
Senator Wen sent me.
You look just like
your dossier photo.
Most people don't.
I think it's the glasses.
They're very distinctive.
Why doesn't
she remember him?
Knocking out
the Z-waves
must have compromised
her solid-state drive.
Yeah, her brain stores
memories like a computer,
once that data's lost...
It's gone forever.
Wait.
What happened?
Was I in an accident?
Something like that.
Here you go, and sorry about
that whole freezer thing.
That's okay.
So San Francisco
could be nice.
Or Seattle.
It rains
too much there.
Unlike here.
Jack, do you really
want to leave Eureka?
Well, I think at a certain
point, we need to ask
ourselves if the universe is
trying to tell us something.
D.O.D. is asking themselves
that same question.
Major Shaw, didn't
see you eavesdropping there.
I'm looking for
director Fargo.
Is there a problem?
Isn't there always?
What were you saying
about the D.O.D.?
I should talk
to the director.
Major,
what is going on?
Believe me,
the department appreciates
the remarkable work that's
been done here in Eureka.
Been done?
Given the latest incident
and breach in national security,
the department's terminating
its funding of Global Dynamics.
For how long?
Permanently.
We're shutting
Eureka down.
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com