Here's to the one year anniversary
of you ** wedding.
At least we're finally using
the free honeymoon.
Yeah, not exactly what I thought
we'll be using it.
Happy anniversary.
Happy anniversary!
I'm glad you all could be here
to commemorate the worst day of my life.
No. I thought the worst day
was **.
***
what about the day when
** upside down?
♪♪ right now.
Remember that time
when I got my **?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Why am I participating in this?
- Who wants an oyster?
- Me. - Me. - Me.
No. None for me. I'm extremely
allergic to selfish.
Ah, yes. She gets all puking
and I gotta take her ** very rewarding.
Wait, wait, wait, keep them away from
Dave also because he's super allergic.
Yeah. Super allergic.
Why **?
This is too much work.
Penny, you're sweet
but so so dumb.
You want to eat your oysters
as soon as they've been **.
Now, when ** an oyster you really
wanna make sure that you get in there.
*** ahh!
You stabbed me, dude!
I stabbed you, dude!
- Oh my God.
- Guys!
What do I do?
I got it.
G-get my epipen. It's in my purse.
On the chair. Okay.
Somebody get this knife out of me!
Oh, God. Ohh.
I got it! I got it!
I got it. What do I do?
Dave. Dave, Dave, Dave! You
can't touch shellfish either.
Oh, right.
What do I do? I only have one shot!
Throat's closing up.
Oh, my God!
Aah! What do I do?!
Oh, all right! Okay!
I'm not allergic to shellfish.
What?
D-- Oh, God.
Here comes the puke.
Well, why did you lie?
When you do it, it makes me...
I know. I know. I know.
I-I can't hear the sound.
Okay, everybody chill!
Aah!
Ohh. Ohh.
Oh!
Oh. Ohh.
Should we order a movie?
"Lincoln Lawyer."
I love these opening credits.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Ladies and gays,
welcome to my new home!
Excuse me, but Max is
the only gay aqui.
I don't know. A lot of people
think you're on the low.
This is surprisingly nice.
Hmm?
Agreed.
Yeah.
Yeah. Wow.
It's two bedrooms,
2 1/2 baths,
Italian marble countertops.
In a word, amah-zing.
- Oh, just gonna ride that
into the ground, huh? - Again?
- No, please stop.
- No.
Guys, it's always been
my dream to be a homeowner,
and I decided, why do I have
to wait to get married
to buy my first place?
We are so proud of you.
This is gonna be
the year of Penny.
Who wants to twirl with me?
Whoo! Whoo!
Whoo!
Hooray!
What?
Oh, now a brother can't twirl?
Dude, you psyched
for movie night?
I got all the best
black-and-white classics.
I got "Lethal Weapon,"
"Trading Places,"
"Beverly Hills Cop."
No, "Beverly Hills Cop"
is black and white and white.
What about "men in black"?
No, that's black and white
in black.
What about "Erin Brockovich"?
That's just white as hell.
"Royal Tenenbaums"?
Come on, bro.
That's white, white,
white, white,
white, white, white,
black...
Brown...
Then wack.
- Damn, trick.
- Listen, man,
I'm not gonna be able
to make it to movie night.
Just gotta work late.
What? This is, like,
the third time
you bailed on me in two weeks.
We never get to hang out
anymore.
Dude, it's just getting crazy
over there, you know?
Is this 'cause I stabbed you?
I said I was sorry.
You did not say you were sorry.
I did say-- I said I was s--
No, you said,
"comme ci comme ca.
"That was pretty cool
how it went in your leg.
I thought there would be
more blood."
That's my version of an apology,
and it's pretty heartfelt.
Come on. Let's hang out.
Come on. I don't do well
when I'm alone.
So...
How's Penny's new place?
Oh, it's awesome, but you're
probably allergic to it.
Listen, Al, I only lied to you
because I didn't have
the heart to tell you
that your jambalaya
is the most disgusting thing
I've ever tasted.
- No offense.
- Offense.
Guys, every couple has little
lies they tell each other.
I mean, not Brad and me.
We're perfect, but my point is--
Last year Brad bought
a motorcycle, crashed it,
and then sold the parts
to his cousin Randall.
Pfft. (Laughs) I knew that.
I mean, he is a... wild hog.
Anyway, you two have a chance
to start over as friends,
- so why don't you just clean the slate...
- Uh...
- And just be honest with each other
from now on? - I guess we could try.
Trust me, you will feel better.
Okay. Um...
Yeah.
I never really liked
your goatee.
Oh. Didn't-- Was not
really aware of that.
Um... okay. Uh, I don't really
love your favorite perfume.
I hate your mom.
Oh, ho ho ho!
Uh...
Okay. (Chuckles) Well...
Okay, I think that's a...
- No. No, no, no.
- Good start for today.
She wants to play.
I can play.
All right.
I'm not really afraid of dogs.
I was just afraid of what
would happen to a dog
if you owned one.
Okay.
You know those stupid webbed
barefoot running socks?
They weren't bad
for your calves.
They were bad for my ability
to want to have sex with you.
Ohh!
That's funny.
Okay. Richard Gere is not
a hurricane Katrina denier.
- What?
- Yeah.
I just said that to you
so we didn't have to watch
"pretty woman"
for the 74th time.
Well, you know
your friend Glazer?
He didn't actually steal my bra
and sell it on craigslist.
I just couldn't spend
another Sunday
- watching you two play frolf.
- Frolf?
Frisbee golf.
Okay, you know that thing
under your mantel
that I told you was
a tiny brick closet?
It's actually
a working fireplace.
I was afraid you were gonna
burn the building down.
Okay, well, I hated
that song you wrote for me.
"Love to the power of love"?
You said it made you cry.
It was 12 minutes long,
oh, and terrible.
- Oh, you want to know terrible?
- Yeah.
That stupid hula-hoop dance
that you do.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah, this one here,
where I take the hula-hoop,
and I put it on, and I do this,
and I shake it,
- shake it, shake it?
- Still terrible.
Bring it up. On the neck.
Look, I take it to the neck.
- Hey, let's-- Let's...
- And you don't like this?!
- Hoop it on down.
- You don't like this?!
Hoop it on down.
Wow! That was healthy.
God, now that
you guys aren't together,
you are able to sing your songs
and hoop around
and watch your Gere movies
and play your frolf.
I mean, whew.
You feel great?
Yeah.
I feel great.
I might get bangs.
Mm.
No, I'm not.
I'm not gonna do that.
I'm not.
Jane, you crazy.
You know, I'm gonna go
back to work.
Go to work!
Thanks for helping me
pick out this lamp, Jeremy.
Thanks for your number.
Thanks for asking for it.
I'd say this afternoon
has been il...
Luminating.
Okay, we're gonna quit
while you're behind.
'Cause it's a lamp.
- Yeah.
- See?
Year of Penny is firing
on all cylinders.
I buy a condo to prove
I don't need a guy
to get on with my life--
Boom!
I meet a guy I wouldn't have met
if I hadn't bought a condo
to prove I don't need
to get on with my life.
We get it.
You have a condo.
Well, it's a pretty big deal.
What the hell?
What?
Brad said he was gonna be
working late.
So?
So if that's work,
then I should be considered one
of "Chicago business" weekly's
top 30 under 30.
He's just hanging
with some guys.
Don't make a big deal
out of this.
Are you gonna make
a big deal out of it?
Well, I don't think
that's a very bright...
Idea.
I gotta go buy a bulb and take
this lamp bit to the next level.
I am on fire!
Year of Penny. Suck it.
Get outta here with that, man.
Crazy, man.
Thanks for that beer.
That's what's up, man.
Hey, keep it cool, brother.
All right.
That's what's up.
Whoa.
I'm sorry. I'm s--
L'Bradford! I do declare.
You must be
coming from your office.
This is a really nice office.
Is this your fax machine
right here?
You mind if I have a sip
of your fax machine?
Okay.
What a delicious fax machine!
Just calm down.
You lied to me, man, and now
I find you at a sports bar
with a bunch
of very attractive black men,
one who looks like Dwyane Wade.
Why can't I hang out with you?
'Cause I'm white?
No, Max.
This is a networking thing.
I didn't not invite you
because you're white.
It's because
you're not professional.
Well, I could be professional.
Yeah.
You have a better chance
of being black
than professional.
That's not a challenge.
- That is not a challenge.
- I feel you.
- What was that?
- Shy city.
- Just don't do that.
- Ah, ha ha.
The rock is definitely
in the building.
- Unnecessary.
- Watch the throne, son.
- Watch the throne, you know what
I'm sayin'?- Watch your step.
- I don't know this man!
- It's in my blood!
Africa! Africa!
Welcome. You are
my first gentleman caller.
That made me sound like
a prostitute.
I'm not a prostitute.
Wow.
This place is amazing.
Thanks.
Do you have any roommates?
Nope.
It is just me and you.
Really? Wow.
I live with five guys.
Ooh. I love guys.
Again, not a prostitute.
Is this Italian marble?
S-sure.
Yeah. I guess.
How many square feet
is this place?
Oh, I don't know.
You really have your life
together.
Is that a bad thing?
No. I just need to... go...
Work on my resume, and...
Oh, no, no, no, Jeremy.
I'll...
Jeremy, wait.
I know it seems like
I have my life together,
but I am a mess, okay?
Psycho.
I will, like, friend your mom on Facebook
and start showing up at events
I was not invited to, okay?
Look, you know what?
These cabinets
are not even that nice.
I mean, look at this.
Ooh!
Is that a wine fridge?
Jer? Jer Bear?
Hon, Jeremy was clearly
a loser.
Yeah, most guys would kill
to date a girl
- with a place like this.
- Mm-hmm.
Last girl I dated
lived on a boat...
That's romantic.
Docked in the parking lot of
the pet store where she worked.
Okay, I-I don't know
where you find people.
You know what?
You guys are right.
I don't even know
what I was thinking.
I mean, this place is great.
I'm great.
Year of Penny back on track!
- Mm. Yes.
- Year of Penny!
I am gonna take these
into the bedroom.
What's happening?
These are the running socks that
Alex didn't want me to wear.
Can you believe that she hated these?
Hate? No.
Those are, uh... great.
- Right?
- Uh, yeah.
So... I got you a pair...
- Ohh.
- Just to say thank you
for freeing us from our lies.
Wow.
Let's go for a run.
Oh! Good. Yeah.
What's this--
What's this color?
Like, an aquaflage?
Yeah.
I hope you like the color.
Oh, yeah. No, Jane loves
a good aquaf--
I'm gonna go try--
I'm gonna give 'em--
I'm gonna try 'em on.
Hi. I'm Mrs. Sarner from 3G.
Welcome to the building.
It's nice to see a couple
buying this place.
- Oh, it's, uh, it's--
- Oh, no. We're not--
- No.
- We're not...
'Cause the last two ladies who
owned this condo were so sad.
They both died alone.
That is something
that was not disclosed to me.
Some people in the building
even think this unit is cursed.
Isn't that crazy?
As if a condominium could turn
a gal into a sad spinster.
These cookies are cran-apple.
Thanks.
Enjoy.
Thank you.
See you at the mixer.
Penny, relax.
This place is not cursed.
Penny.
You didn't
tell me you got a cat.
He is so cute.
Aw. You are cute.
Wait. I didn't get a cat,
because...
Cats are for spinsters.
Is it cold in here?
I need a housecoat
and a hot tea with lemon.
Should I get
an AOL e-mail address?
What's happening to me?!
So this isn't your cat?
No!
Ugh.
Max, why do we keep watching
- the same "Lethal Weapon" scene over and over again?
- 'Cause I lost my murtaugh.
I don't understand
most of what my friends say.
Brad doesn't want me
joining his stupid
professional networking group.
Oh, fuzzy face. Come on.
You said you'd watch all these
Richard Gere movies with me.
I heard "Primal Fear" has
a very cool surprise ending.
Gere finds out
that Norton was lying
about his split personality
and that he murdered
the archbishop.
Come on. Okay, uh,
what about "Unfaithful"?
Gere bashes
the French guy's head in
with a snow globe.
You're killing me.
Just like tumors killed
Winona Ryder
in "Autumn In New York."
Why are you doing this?
Hello, Alex!
Oh, nice socks.
You look like a gay ninja.
I am gonna go for a run
with Jane.
Oh! And I called glaze
earlier.
Good convo. Tough, yes.
There were tears
because of your lies,
but, uh, I'm gonna go play
some frolf with him,
make him feel better.
Well, I wish I could watch
you nerds,
but I've gotta make more
jambalaya.
People are going crazy for it
at the store.
Really? Women are just going
crazy for trying on clothes
and eating hot seafood soup?
They can't get enough
of that hot seafood soup?
Yeah.
I've had the worst day ever.
Ew.
Morning started with frolf...
Dave, glaze, myself.
- Ohh!
- Ow!
And since I told Alex
she'd be a great dog owner,
we went to the shelter,
but turns out
she's only qualified
to take care of a snake.
I'm naming him Tyler.
Then I stupidly encouraged Dave
to record his song.
♪ Love times love ♪
♪ divided by love ♪
♪ equals love ♪
♪ to the power of love ♪
Then it was back to Alex's,
where she wanted to prove
she could make a fire.
I'm not... sure
you should be feeding peeps
to the snake.
He seems a little bit off.
No, he loves them.
What about the flue, al?
Snakes don't get the flu.
Did you even open it?
What?
Did you use charcoal
to make a fire?!
Oh, Jane.
Kind of ironic, isn't it?
You see, you pushed
Dave and Alex to stop lying,
but now all you can do
is lie to them.
You're doing exactly what
you don't want them to do.
Look at you, all dirty,
- just covered in lies.
- Yeah, I see. That's funny.
You want to tell me about that
motorcycle you bought last year?
Hmm? What?
Run you a bubble bath?
Okay.
- Mm. Mm-hmm.
- All right.
A bag of pennies in her face.
Maxwell Blum, JD, DDS, esquire.
How's it going?
"JD, DDS"?
You're a lawyer and a dentist?
I like cleaning teeth.
Sue me.
Hey, Max, can I talk to you
for a second?
Talk is cheap. Am I right?
Let's get down
to some brass tacks.
What's going on
with this debt ceiling?
Does China own us?
I want to join
your professional group.
You guys network so well.
Professionals' group?
I haven't had a job
in, what, like, five years?
Unless you count sleeping
till 1:00
and trying to bring back
the phrase "bust a move"
as a job.
Oh, my God.
You're, like, black Max.
You're-- You...
You're blax!
Hold up.
Is this white Daryl?
I am not white Daryl,
and you lied to me again.
Look, sometimes
I just wanna hang out
with the brothas.
Why are you talking like that?
'Cause I was hangin' out
with the brothas,
and it takes a little while for
it to go away. See? It's gone.
Sometimes I just need a break
from talking about npr
and recycling or...
That awesome chest pass
- Steve Nash made.
- Oh, really, fam?
- Yeah. - Now you're gonna
pull out that Steve Nash card
- on a brotha. - Wait. Why are
you talking like that?
Because we're all, you know,
everybody's with the brothers,
and we're all hanging out
and talking like that.
Look, I didn't tell you
because you get all crazy
any time you feel excluded
from something.
That's...
Hey, Brad.
If I hook you up
with a partially used
borders gift card,
you think you would give me
a ride to small claims court?
Crap. Damn it.
I am white Daryl.
I'm totally fine, Jane.
I took the cat to a shelter,
and I know
my apartment's not cursed.
Oh, and I decided
to have a housewarming party,
roaring '20s theme,
so it looks like
the year of Penny
is back in full...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What the hell
is with all the cats?
No. Come on.
Just get to steppin'.
Get on now.
Move it along. Come on.
Get out! Get out!
Shoo! Shoo!
Okay, Penny.
Calm down.
Get some wine. Take a breath.
Just watch some tv.
Aah! Aah!
Why is the DVR filled
with "the good wife"
and "the view"?
I didn't record these.
These are for lonely women
who talk to themselves.
Oh, my God! I'm talking to myself.
"Single meals for one"?
"Personal pizzas"?
"Personal pizzas."
Jane, you're not wearing
your running socks.
Oh, yeah.
I am bummed, too, glaze,
but Penny wanted it
to be historically correct
with the 1920s theme, so...
Grr...
Ooh, well,
then I'll just go Polish
the China
in the servants' quarters.
You don't Polish China.
'Sup?
'Sup... with you?
Shouldn't you be getting ready
for your big party?
It's already happening.
Pen. Pen. You okay?
Like anybody cares.
Give me the ice cream.
Okay. Got another one.
Okay, how did you--
Ah.
All right, g-give me
the couch ice cream...
Ohh.
And let's get you dressed.
Just leave me alone, Jane.
Give me the ground ice cream...
Mnh.
And let's get you dressed.
- Go. Go.
- Come on. Let's go.
Hey, Brad.
How's it goin'?
Oh. Where are my manners?
These are my gay friends.
You know, sometimes you just
wanna hang out with your peeps.
Right.
Anyway, this is Connor.
He's enormous.
This is Joel. He's silent.
And this is Steve.
We call him gay Brad.
No, we don't,
and my name's Ken.
- And he's Asian.
- He's Asian? Pfft.
I don't see skin color
or eye shape.
Anyway, let's get out
of here, guys.
These straight folks
are bringing me down.
- Let's go talk about gay stuff.
- Ooh!
- Gay stuff?
- That's right, Brad.
Gay stuff. Come on.
Don't you wish they made
trading cards of designers?
Ah.
Ohh. Really, Alex?
You're gonna serve
that disgusting jambalaya?
This is a housewarming party,
not a house-clearing party.
Boom! Poetry slam.
Oh, uh, heard you went
down to the shelter,
and they wouldn't let you
have a dog,
so you had to get a snake
instead.
Had to? No, no, no, no.
I chose Tyler, okay?
Dogs are played out
with their whole "soft,
cuddly best friend" thing.
Honestly, on a scale of
fur to scales, I prefer scales.
Well, things have been going
pretty awesome with me, too.
Been frolfing and jamming,
and, uh, my song turned out
so great that
glaze put it on his web site--
defglazerecords.com.
Dot org was taken.
Been getting tons of hits.
Don't make a big deal
about it, baby.
That's awesome.
Maybe you should play it here
for everyone.
- Yeah!
- No.
- Here.
- Bro.
- No.
- Yeah.
- Bro.
I didn't bring my guitar.
I-I can't--
That's all right. He's got one.
Why don't you ask him?
Uh, yeah, um...
Do you really think
I can pull off
that slim-fit James Perse
crew neck t-shirt?
As long as I can be there
when you pull it off.
What's happening here?
I was just talkin' tees
with my B's,
who are "G,"
'cause they like "D."
- Oh, yeah.
- Pound it.
No! Gay Brad,
you do not pound Brad Brad.
Gays, inside. Go!
You guys can pound me.
Why can't I pound
your friends, man?
Because they're not my friends!
They're just some guys
I met at the gym
who are way too
into the roaring '20s.
What is going on with you, man?
- I'm freaking out!
- About what?!
We used to hang out
all the time, right?
And then you got married
to Jane,
and you got
this big, fancy job.
I-I barely ever see you
anymore,
and the free time
you do have--
You spend it with other people.
Dude...
We're always gonna have stuff
going on in our lives, man.
- Well, me, you know, my life.
- Your life's pretty much--
- Of course.
- Yeah, yeah.
But you're my riggs, trick.
I am, ho?
Come on, fella.
You know murtaugh would
never bail on riggs,
even when real-life riggs
gets super racist
and verbally abusive
towards his boo.
I love you the most, man.
Bring it in.
You sure you're not on the low?
That's my cell phone, man.
♪ Love times ♪
♪ love ♪
♪ divided by love ♪
Look, everyone's having a great time.
♪ equals love ♪
What is wrong with people?
♪ To the power of love ♪
this song is so sad.
The square root of love
is love.
♪ Buddha's Christian ♪
♪ and Jews are black ♪
here. Try this.
I put peanut butter in this batch.
♪ ketchup's mustard ♪
♪ and aspirin's crack... ♪
ohh.
There's a little bit
of horseradish in there.
Ohh.
Why?
- What?
- Why?
O-okay, enough.
Uh, Dave, stop, okay?
♪ Chairs are s... ♪
I love you,
but that song is really bad.
Those running socks are hideous,
and frolf is not a sport.
- Hey, we have a newsletter.
- Shut up, glaze.
Dave, all those things
Alex said-- They're true.
Thank you, Jane.
You see, Dave? What did I--
Uh, calm down, Al.
Everything you've done
in the past few days
has been pretty stupid.
You almost burned down
your apartment.
And, Penny, oh, my God.
Is your breakdown sponsored
by Dreyer's?
Look, you're not gonna turn
into an old spinster
just because you bought
a condo,
which, by the way,
is not cursed.
Okay, yeah, Jane?
Then you want to explain
about all the cats?
Wait. You found my cats?
I live next door.
I've trained them to crawl
into vents and open windows.
Fair enough. Okay.
Then what about all the episodes
of "the view" on my tv?
Uh, you didn't erase those,
did you?
'Cause I can't DVR "the view"
at home anymore,
'cause my DVR is filled
with episodes of "the view,"
so I have to DVR it here.
Okay, then does someone
want to explain to me
this coupon
for personal pizzas,
which is really just
a really... great deal.
Ah. I'm...
I'm sorry.
You guys, thank you for coming.
I hope-- I hope everybody has
a great time.
Yeah, Penny!
One, two, three--
Actually, guys, I'm sorry.
I don't know any other songs.
You know, your jambalaya
wasn't all that bad.
There were a couple
of good batches
back in '07, I think.
Yeah, and your song--
I mean, the lyrics are
actually really touching.
♪
We're lying, right?
Yeah, works for us.
Stop having a moment, you two.
Toast.
♪
Thank you.
To my friends.
I know I'll never be sad
and alone,
because I'll always have you.
Pen, you know you're not
gonna be alone.
Aw. Thanks, Al.
No, literally, 'cause I need
to move in for a while.
Jane wasn't kidding.
I smoked out my apartment,
and there's a snake loose
that's mad at me,
'cause I probably gave him
diabetes.
Roomies?
If you'll have me?
- Yes! Yes!
- Yes?
Aw.
- Bring it in.
- Okay.
Cheers.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com