Harley Wilkes was your father.
He left you his practice.
You're the mayor?
Lavon Hayes, the linebacker?
You share a generator
with Wade Kinsella.
I don't want you
getting any ideas.
Notice how whenever I come
around, there's always sparks?
How dare you see my patients?
Well, technically, Harley left
his half of the practice to me.
I'm not gonna share this office,
not for one minute.
If one partner doesn't bring
in 30% of the revenue,
every billing quarter, the other
partner can buy him or her out.
I'm good at what I do,
and as soon as the town
figures that out,
it'll be just fine.
So Mom, you'll have
a car meeting me
at the airport tonight?
Fantastic!
Four whole days in New York!
I am telling you,
I have earned it.
Yeah. I finally got my 30%
of patients at the practice.
Now I can relax,
and have Thanksgiving
the way it was intended.
Jean Georges is catering, right?
Thank God.
I am craving elegance
and refinement.
The BlueBellians
are probably re-enacting
the Pilgrims and Indian
corn trading, and...
giving... thanks...
Or not.
Mom, see you tonight.
Bye.
I just saw the weirdest thing.
Shiver me timbers.
Oh, hi. Hardtack?
I knew this day would come.
You softened me up with
heat waves and blue people,
but I'm not falling for this.
Oh, this is no joke.
This is one of this town's
- most revered traditions.
- The early selelers
of BlueBell were doing
Thanksgiving things,
shelling peas,
brining turkey...
Watching football.
Oh, no. Getting ready to
give thanks and chow down.
When... whoosh!
Big-ass hurricane...
- Washes everything away.
- Gone.
Crops, houses, stores,
all out to sea.
But it washes some pirates in.
- Pirates?
- Yes, pirates.
But instead of pillaging,
these pirates saw the
struggling people of BlueBell
and gave them food and supplies
to get back on their feet.
That's why, 200 years later,
instead of folks having
turkeys at home, we honor
those pirates by dressing up
and having a big fish fry
in the town square.
Which we call...
- Planksgiving.
- Bam.
That is the single stupidest
thing I've heard
since I moved here.
And I hear Wade
talking to his dates
every night on his front porch.
- Hey!
- Fine, I'm sure that your
little fish fry is filled with
as much adorableness
as it is cholesterol.
But now I am doubly happy
to be flying to New York
to eat turkey with my mom.
Wade, enjoy your holiday.
Lavon, see you later.
Please change before you
take me to the airport.
You didn't tell me Zoe was
going away for the holidays.
- I thought I did.
- Yeah. Well, you didn't.
Means I can try my new amp out.
She's always complaining about
how I'm blowing out
the power, and all that.
Speaking of which,
I-I need a favor.
Bought a new fuse box.
Need you to help me to
install it while Zoe's away.
I'm sick and tired
of hearing y'all squabble
over electricity all the time.
Hey. That' a great idea.
We need it!
But, uh... you're gonna
have to find somebody else
to install it.
What are you talking about?
Oh, I don't do electrical.
You know, car engines,
carpentry, absolutely.
But, uh, electrical
just ain't my thing.
I'm sorry, but,
uh... another time.
All right.
All right, you take
it easy, Lavon.
- Oh, my God.
- Avast, fair maiden!
Come with me and we
will sail the seven seas!
Honestly, George,
I don't have time
to play pirate,
your parents are coming!
Oh. But it's, uh,
it's Planksgiving.
And I plan on plundering
me some pirate booty.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, well...
I would gladly let you pillage
me all day, Pirate Tucker.
But I have to clean
and go to the store
because for some reason,
your parents decided to
- crash our holiday.
- Okay.
Well... I mean...
Y-you don't gotta
dust the outlets.
Is that hat on too tight?
Your mother hates me.
And the last time I saw her,
I had a breakdown at Fancie's.
Look...
if it makes you feel any better,
my mama also hates Oprah,
and Reese Witherspoon,
and springtime,
and the U.S. Women's
Soccer Team.
Hey, so, you admit it,
she hates me.
Baby, all that matters
is that I think you are perfect
just the way you...
aregh!
- Yep. Eleven.
- Well, now, count 'em again.
Brick, I already
counted three times.
Face it, Zoe got her 30% of
patients for this quarter.
That is impossible,
'cause on Monday
she was three patients shy.
True, but then all four
MacKenzie brothers
got into a bar fight,
and Zoe stitched 'em up.
Then afterwards, they called
and asked for Zoe to
do their follow-up.
You know the rules:
they request Zoe,
she's counted as their doctor.
Now wait a minute,
you're telling me that
the MacKenzie brothers--
my patients--
specifically requested
Zoe Hart to treat them?
Now why in the hell
would they do that?
♪ ♪
That explains it.
I am getting a cup of coffee.
I take it he knows
about my 30%?
Have to say, didn't
think you could do it.
You've come a long way, missy.
Well, the quarter's over,
and my father's
legacy is intact.
Now I'm going to New York City,
where Zoe Hart can be a fish
in her own polluted water.
Hey, Addy.
Is Brick in?
Oh, he just stepped out, but
I have his partner, Dr. Hart.
Guess you'll have to do.
Well, isn't that sweet?
And what brings you in today?
Caleb has been complaining of
itchiness for the last two days.
Me name be Small Cal No Beard!
Of course it is.
Right this way.
Six more hours, six more hours,
six more hours...
Hey, Lemon Meringue Pie!
Oh, hi, Daddy.
Hey. Can your old dad
buy you a cup of coffee?
Oh, I'm...
I'm sorry.
I'm running late. I gotta
buy those little onions
the Tuckers like
in their martinis.
'Cause Lord knows if they don't
have their teeny-tiny onions,
then the whole earth is just
gonna spin off its axis.
Ah, the Tuckers. Well, you know
your sister's so scared of them,
she hightailed it to the
Richmans' for the weekend.
- Oh. - Yeah. Well, at least we
only have to put up with them
- a couple times a year.
- Yeah.
Unlike a certain New York City
doctor who is a thorn
in my backside on a daily basis.
I thought you two were
getting along better.
That girl still does not
get what it is to be a GP.
I mean, you know, what it's like
to spend 30 years with a family,
watching them change and grow.
No, she swishes her little hips,
and steals my patients.
Oh, Daddy, I just...
Oh. I wish
there was a spell
that we could use
to just blow Zoe Hart
- right on out of this town.
- Yeah.
Maybe she'd take the
Tuckers along with her.
Oh, Olive! A word, please.
Uh, you know, sweetheart...
sometimes I think we gotta
make our own spells.
Um... I'll talk to you later.
Uh, Olive? I just want to
tell you something...
Seems to be mostly in his legs.
Okay...
Have you changed
laundry detergent?
- Bought new sheets?
- No.
What've you been up to, lately?
Pillaging.
Sailing the seven seas,
looking for treasure.
He really loves Planksgiving.
Well, he's a kid.
He probably just rolled
around in some plant life.
Hornswaggle!
There be no plants
at sea, wench!
Huh! That's Doctor Wench
to you, kid.
He doesn't have a rash,
and his vitals are normal.
I don't see any other symptoms.
He's probably just having a mild
allergic reaction to something.
Some antihistamines
should take care of it.
Thanks so much.
We appreciate it.
One more patient
to add to my pile.
Addy, can you, uh, see if I
can get on an earlier flight?
I don't see any reason
why I couldn't make it.
Okay, Tommy,
all medical records
transferred back
to Dr. Breeland.
Yes, your brothers
already called.
All MacKenzies back
to Dr. Breeland.
- Bye now.
- MacKenzies? My MacKenzies?
Oh, no, they're my MacKenzies.
See, I just happened
to bump into
Tommy MacKenzie's wife, Olive.
Now the funny thing is,
Olive had never heard that
her husband switched over
to the pretty lady doctor
in the short shorts.
Brick, you've got
to be kidding me.
I knew you wouldn't
be happy that I got my 30%,
but I didn't think
you'd poach my patients.
You did it first.
- Oh, I most certainly did not.
- Oh, yes, you did.
Oh, no, I did not.
I treated them because
they asked to see me.
I'll tell you what.
You can have them if you can
name all four brothers.
Fine.
MacKenzie comma Tommy.
Mackenzie comma...
Logan.
MacKenzie...
The other two didn't
speak that much.
Well, you go on up to
New York, have a good time,
and I'll just stay here
and buy you out.
Oh. Enjoy your... Thanksgiving.
sync by Elderfel, corrected by susanaLC
www.Addic7ed.com
Okay, how many more patients
do I need to make 30%?
Well, you got Cap'n No Beard
this morning,
so that puts you three shy.
Well, I still have a couple
hours before my flight.
You really think you can get
three patients by midnight?
Not playing by the book, no.
I was awfully surprised
to see y'all
come down here
for Planksgiving.
Well, thought
we'd mix thinin up.
In fact, we've learned to
embrace a new tradition
in Montgomery.
It's called Thanksgiving.
We brought a turkey
with all the trimmings.
Lemon, you and I can wake up
early and get started.
I can see how your
cooking's coming along!
Yay!
I've always wanted to
make a real Thanksgiving dinner.
From scratch.
For hours and hours...
Look, Mom, thank you so much,
it's very nice of you,
but our tradition
is Planksgiving.
George, you can have your
little fish fry next year.
But this dinner is
our chance to celebrate.
Celebrate what?
Your brother, Harry...
is going to run for
the state legislature!
- Well, that's, I mean that's,
that's great! - How exciting!
- That's...
- A politician in the family.
Yeah, that's great.
Of course, that means that
Harry's gonna have to
resign from the law firm.
Leaving his position open.
Look, Dad, we've
talked about this. Okay?
I already left once
to do corporate law.
It wasn't my thing
for many, many reasons.
I'm not leaving BlueBell again,
period.
But that's the best part.
Your father convinced
his partners
to let you work from BlueBell!
You'd only be in Montgomery
three days a week.
The firm has housing
you can use.
And, well, Lemon, that means
that you'll have to join him
on those days.
Oh. Three days a week?
With you?
That's just swell!
Okay, $100 for the first person
to make a doctor's
appointment with me right now!
Come on!
Zoe, I'm sorry,
but um... Brick is our doctor.
And we are a loyal bunch.
Shelley!
Shell! Shellster,
Shellerino?
I'm sorry, Zoe.
I really am.
I think you're great.
I really do.
It's just that I saw
Brick for a checkup right
before you got here,
and I feel great.
But you had a headache
the other day.
It went away with two aspirin.
You know, there was
this case
of this guy with a headache.
Turns out he had a whole set
of teeth
growing behind his eyeballs.
All right, meet you at your
office in a couple minutes.
Hey, Tom...
Tommy!
Oh, no, no, no.
My mom will kill me
if I see a doctor
other than Dr. Breeland.
He delivered me!
Come on, Tom.
I need new patients today.
If you be my girlfriend
for a month.
Okay.
- Yeah?
- No.
Oh... An ounce of
realism, please, Tom?
Show me your boobs.
One boob?
How about you come
with me right now,
and I won't tell your mother
what you just asked me to do?
Deal.
Okay.
I cannot believe
that we agreed to do
Thanksgiving dinner tomorrow.
I mean, shoot, even if
it does get done by 7:00,
we're gonna miss the
plank-walking contest!
Plank-walking?
Really, George?
That was your big takeaway
from lunch?
Why, Lemon Breeland,
don't you know me at all?
I'm not taking that job.
My dad doesn't even
respect me as a lawyer.
The only reason he wants
me is 'cause Harry left
and he wants to retain voting
majority with his partners.
No, I have absolutely
no intention whatsoever
of giving up my practice.
Oh! Oh, my God, George,
I love you so much right now!
I was freaking out!
I know.
Oh! Okay,
so you know what?
We will just pretend
like we thought about it,
and after their Thanksgiving,
we will just tell them no.
Exactly. And then we can
celebrate this day
like it's meant to be.
With a fish fry, ruffled shirts
and eye patches!
Arrgh!
There you two are!
Oh, I was just on my way to buy
a few things for tomorrow.
Lemon, would you like to come?
Of course!
Shopping with you, Clora?
Is there anything better?
Hey-o!
Whatcha working on, hoss?
This was my grandmama's.
Just trying to fix it
so I can give it back to her
for her birthday.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look, you got your
capacitors all wrong here.
Check me out.
Okay, no polarity.
Mm-hmm.
Yes polarity.
So you put that in wrong,
when you plug it in,
it will explode.
No more grandmama's radio,
no more fingers.
Gotcha!
What?
This radio was a Wade trap.
And you stuck
your big paw in it.
Now you're mine.
I don't know what you're
talking about.
You lied to me
this morning.
You can do electrical work.
So? Maybe I didn't feel like
installing
your new fuse box. So what?
Exactly.
The question is why?
After all, every time it blows,
Zoe comes stomping over
and yells at you.
But you know what Lavon Hayes
figured out?
That only crackpots talk in
the third person?
Ah, Lavon Hayes figured out that
you like Zoe coming over,
which means you like Zoe.
Look, if by "like" you mean
I'd do her?
Sure, you got me.
I'd do her.
But I'm not that picky.
Mmm-mm, mmm-mm.
By "like," I mean
you love... her.
Hey.
You are in big trouble.
- What? - You know what
I just realized? A month ago
you made a doctor's appointment
and then you canceled it.
At least this guy had the good
sense to need stitches.
I had a sore throat,
and it went away.
What's the big deal?
Canceled patients don't count!
Brick is about to take over the
practice, and I need patients.
Zoe, I'd like to help you
out, but the thing is
there nothing's bothering me.
I-I don't want to be unethical
I'm the mayor of this town.
Ow! Oh, ow! Ow!
Now something's bothering you.
Come on. Just stop in, and
then we'll go to the airport.
Oh, yeah, Lavon.
Mmm! She is a real catch.
That's three patients,
which brings me to 30%,
which also means.
"Ha-ha-ha, Brick Breeland."
If anyone needs me,
I'll be at Barney's.
- Lavon, let's go.
- Not so fast.
They just came in,
and they specifically asked
for someone who was not you.
So I wouldn't head
to that airport quite yet.
You're still one shy.
Caleb, are you okay?
Me pirate fingers be aching.
Dr. Hart, your services are
not needed here.
Let me help.
Caleb is my patient.
- Yeah, he was your patient.
- Exactly.
Allergic reaction, my foot.
He wasn't in pain this morning.
That's new.
Let me examine him.
Look, Dr. Hart,
maybe you should
see me about having that wax
cleaned out of your ears.
He is not your patient anymore.
Now go.
Please go!
What are his other symptoms?
Joint pain and itchiness
are all we got.
Blood panel including CBC,
chem 7 and tox screen?
- Brick has no idea what Caleb has.
- Nope.
So if I diagnose him first,
then maybe his mother
will rename me as his doctor.
You'd also have the satisfaction
of treating a sick kid.
That, too.
Shady, I gotta tell ya
I am a little surprised that
you want to sell the store.
I mean, Nate's Hardware has
been in your family for,
forever. And this price?
I mean, I gotta say, no offense,
but it's a little low,
don't you think?
Yeah, but, uh, you know,
it's, it's about
a life change, George.
I mean, I've been tied to my
great-grandpa's store
for way too long now.
And my family and I, we're just
ready to move on.
Wait. Are you leaving BlueBell?
Let's face it, George.
There's bigger and better out
there in this world.
And I intend to find it.
Wow.
Well, okay. I will draw up
the paperwork for you.
And I'll see you, say,
this afternoon?
All right.
Thank you much, George.
You're welcome.
- How ya doing?
- Afternoon.
Real estate deals?
A paralegal could handle that.
Hell, a secretary could.
Yeah. I don't mind it.
Well, it's a waste of time
that could be used doing things
of value.
That's the beauty of working
with a large firm-- resources.
My secretary's at
the beauty salon.
- Uh-huh.
- It's a standing appointment.
George Tucker.
Okay, itching and joint pain
could indicate
a hundred different things.
Did Caleb give any other clues?
Only about marauding
and swashbuckling.
Well, the kid's clearly weird.
Maybe there's a clue in that.
He's not weird. He's ten, Zoe.
And this is how
ten-year-old boys behave.
Yeah, and ten-year-olds
are weird.
This how I nearly failed
my peds rotation.
I need more information.
I need eyes and ears
in that room.
Hey, this is
a great magazine.
Who knew electrophysiologists shop
for bulk toilet paper
just like us?
- Oh, we need to get to the airport.
- Lavon...
How much do you love me?
Why?
Oh, hey, this isn't
the bathroom.
What's up, Captain No Beard?
There's something
very soothing about
shelling peas, isn't there?
Reminds me of a simpler time,
a time when family
meant everything.
You know, you and I are going
to be family very soon,
so I think it's time
we had a frank conversation.
Whatever about, Clora?
Lemon, you don't have
to pretend.
We both know that things
aren't right between us.
We've gotten off
on the wrong foot,
and I'm big enough to admit
that's all my fault.
I had a practice
in BlueBell, too, son.
I, I know that small town law
can get a little, uh, small.
Yeah, I mean,
Lovey Swann over at the
library is actually having me
sue Parker Mason over
an overdue library book.
But, Dad, come on,
you, you know
I love helping
out my community.
You could still help them.
With a big firm behind you,
you could make
some real changes around here.
Class actions, defense teams.
Lemon, I get it.
Why in the world would you
let George take this job?
You don't want him around us
because you don't want
to be around us.
I mean, you have been a,
a tad bit critical of me.
I've been a judgmental hag.
I know what kind
of lawyer you are.
More importantly, I know
what kind of man you are.
The crazy part is,
I always wanted a girl,
but instead, just boys.
And here you are,
the daughter I always wanted,
and instead of embracing you,
I turn my back.
Truth is...
your brother doesn't have
half your smarts
or half your heart.
I need you at my firm, son.
George, I need you.
Lemon,
I know you've missed having
a mother in your life.
And I want to be that for you.
Well?
I heard coughing and
Caleb said he was dizzy.
Anything else?
Anything at all?
Uh... He was scratching
behind his ear a lot.
Huh.
Maybe he finally does
have a rash.
Could you go look at it?
Are you crazy?
The mayor of BlueBell can't be
creeping around exam rooms.
And how many times can I lose
my way to the bathroom?
Oh, for Pete's sake!
Hey, babe.
- Hi.
- I was just going to call you.
Listen, I've been thinking--
I know it isn't
what we discussed,
but maybe we should consider
your father's offer.
That's funny, 'cause Lemon,
I was thinking
the exact same thing, I mean...
it turns out my dad really does
want me there, and...
And it's a great
career opportunity.
Plus, your mother and I
have had a breakthrough.
Really? Wow.
So we're really doing this?
I think we are--
Senior Associate Tucker.
So, did you see the rash?
No rash. It was
just salt residue.
We're back to square one.
Why would Caleb have
salt behind his ear?
Like salt water? Residue you get
from swimming in the ocean.
Okay, so Caleb has been
swimming in the bay.
Maybe there's something
in that.
Itching, joint pain,
ocean...
- Zoe, you okay? - Addie, I know what's
wrong with Caleb. Call an ambulance.
- You've been scuba diving, haven't you?
- Are you out of your mind?
Caleb is only ten years old.
He doesn't even know
how to scuba dive.
This morning he said he was sailing
the seven seas looking for treasure.
He also told me he made his
principal walk the plank.
Maybe we should dredge
the bay for Mr. Babcock.
- Caleb...
- Me name be Captain Cal No Beard.
Fine. Captain No Beard, you have
to tell the truth right now.
If you've been diving, you're only
going to get sicker and sicker.
How dare you scare him.
He's just a boy.
Look, you are out of this room,
you are out of this practice.
Me hast been diving.
What do you mean?
You don't know how
to scuba dive.
Me brother Nate taught me.
Me robbed him of his suit.
And took to the bay.
Nate has scuba gear
because he's 17
and taken lessons.
Caleb, what were you thinking?
Becky, Caleb has
decompression sickness.
It's what divers
call the bends.
We have an ambulance coming, and he needs to
get into a hyperbaric chamber right away.
I know it sounds scary,
but as long as we
take care of it quickly he'll be fine.
And when he comes back,
he'll come in for
a follow-up with me.
See, Crickett, it was all
just a big misunderstanding
like she was a mama lion
protecting her cub.
Montgomery?
I still can't believe
you're going to be bi-citial.
Crickett, that's
not even a word, sweetie.
But BlueBell
will always be my home.
But what about
your civic duties?
How are we gonna
get on without you?
Oh, well, you'll
just have to forge on.
Oh, if you'll excuse me,
I have to go help my future
in-laws shop for Thanksgiving.
I can't believe George
caved so quickly.
- Nice work today.
- Well, I knew Lemon was key
- to getting him on board.
- Mm-hmm.
Of course, I practically
had to promise to breastfeed her
to get her over on our side.
You know, Shady,
you coming in earlier,
you, uh, you sort of inspired
me to make a change, too.
Oh, yeah? How's that?
Well, I... I'm going
to close up shop here,
and I'm going to go
join a larger firm.
Congratulations, George.
That's-- that's great.
Is everything okay, Shady?
Hold on a sec.
Of course.
Hello?
I'll be right there.
Wait, Shady, what...? Shady?
Come... oh!
Turn around.
Come on.
Thought you were taking
Zoe to the airport.
She had a last-minute
medical emergency,
- so, she got a later flight.
- Oh.
Said she'll call
when she's ready.
You know, I've been thinking,
if you did like Zoe...
I don't, all right?
Uh-huh. So, my idea--
you take her to the airport.
Tell her how you feel right
before she gets on the plane.
Now, if she feels the same,
you have yourself a nice,
romantic, airport good-bye kiss.
If she doesn't,
she gets on the plane,
and no one has to talk about it.
I don't like her, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Now, if you please.
Flight leaves at 8:00.
Hmm.
There you two are!
I made a reservation
for us at Fancie's
in a half an hour.
Harold, a martini?
Sounds good to me.
Great. Oh, and I got that gouda
you like, Mama.
It is okay
if I call you Mama, right?
- Shady!
- Caleb, are you okay?
I'm sorry.
Why were
you scuba diving?
I wanted
to find the pirate treasure.
What-What pirate treasure?
From the ship
in the Planksgiving story.
I thought if I could find it,
you wouldn't have
to sell the store,
and we wouldn't have to
move in with Aunt Glenese,
and you wouldn't have to go away
to look for work.
We could stay a family.
Look, I... I didn't want anyone
to know.
All right? Everyone's
been buying their supplies
off the Internet lately.
Son, I appreciate
what you tried to do, but...
there isn't any pirate treasure.
It's just some story
somebody made up
a long time ago.
We should go.
Wait!
I don't want it anymore.
If there's no treasure,
I can't help them.
I just wanted my family
to stay together.
Hey.
So, we going to the
airport or what?
A ten-year-old
with the bends.
I mean, I can't believe it.
No, you can't blame
yourself about that.
Me, on the other hand--
I mean, Shady Hilson wanting
to sell his hardware store--
I should have known better.
George, you never
could have known.
Neither of us could have, but...
- We're gonna have to figure out a way
to help them. - I completely agree.
What happened to Lavon?
Uh, yeah, well, I, uh...
I happened to be going
to the airport anyway,
so...
I do that sometimes
to visit my buddy
the, uh... bag guy.
So, it's not a special
trip or anything.
You know, kids--
they get so caught up
in stories and fantasies.
You feel like a jerk when
their little hearts get broken.
Really don't know what
you're talking about.
So, the airport?
Hey, y'all, can you give us a
ride back to the Breeland house?
We got a lot of work to do, and
every minute's gonna count.
- Uh, actually....
- Yeah, sure, hop in.
Thanks.
Is it this?
- But...
- No...
- Ow. Ow.
- Wade...
- Watch the...
- Ooh, sorry.
All right.
Thank you.
Ah.
Welcome aboard.
You know, Mama,
Dad, I've been thinking.
You know, George and I don't
need our own place
in Montgomery
for only three days a week.
We can just stay with you.
Won't that be
- so cozy?
- Of course, dear.
Oh, we can play charades
every night.
I just love charades.
Don't you?
Wait. Guess this one.
Sure hope we're not
late to the airport.
Somebody's got a
plane to catch.
You know
what we should do?
- We should call the town council.
- Yeah.
They got to have some jobs
for, uh... for Nate's.
You guys are gonna help Caleb
and his family?
You're more
than welcome to join us
if you want to change
your travel plans.
No, my mom's expecting me.
I already saved the kid's life,
got him to the hospital.
What more could I do?
Well, you know, my
business card says doctor,
and George's says lawyer,
but those titles
don't begin to explain
what people like us mean
to the community.
I mean, BlueBell counts on us.
What are you gonna do?
Find the Hilsons some
Planksgiving buried treasure?
You don't get it.
You know, years ago,
when BlueBell was leveled
by that hurricane,
and people lost everything,
most of all, they lost hope.
They were talking
about moving out,
deserting the town
and-and starting over,
but the town's founder,
Cyrus Lavinius Jeremiah Jones,
you know, he got together
with some of the town leaders.
They spent
the whole night fishing,
and the next morning,
there was food for everyone.
Yeah. Then, when people asked,
"Where did it all come from?"
that's when Cyrus made up that
story about friendly pirates.
I knew there weren't pirates.
Yeah, no pirates.
Just neighbor helping neighbor.
That's what got
BlueBell back upon
its feet then, after Katrina,
after whatever came to
try and knock her down.
You know what?
Like, the costumes,
the pirate stuff--
that's all just meant
to be fun.
This holiday is really
about community.
Yeah.
- Dad?
- Mm?
Do you play tennis?
- Why do you ask?
- I was thinking
we should join a doubles
tennis league in Montgomery.
I don't know how to play,
but I was hoping that
you could teach me.
Wouldn't that be a kick?
- Hey.
- Oh, there you two are.
We have reservations
for a celebration dinner
- at Fancie's in ten minutes. - I know,
and I'm sorry to have to do this,
but... y'all are gonna
have to go without us.
I've got a client
who needs help.
What client?
You're working for me now.
I'm sorry. Did you not hear
someone needs his help?
Look, Dad, this is
really important, okay?
So y'all are gonna have
to go without us tonight,
and we'll see you back
here in the morning?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay. You okay, babe?
Mm-hmm!
Oh, that is just perfect.
More time together!
You'd better get used to me,
because you and I
are gonna be inseparable.
♪ ♪
So...
Finally.
Here we are.
You and me.
On our way to the airport...
Yes, sir.
Mom, call me when
you get this message.
There's been a change of plans.
Bye.
Will you take me
to the plantation?
But the airport.
I need to talk to Lavon.
George and Brick are helping
the family business.
I need to help Caleb.
Hey, it's okay.
You'll just have to go
to the airport without me.
♪ ♪
Whew, last one.
Whoo.
No sleep, but I think
it was worth it.
Yeah, and nice touch
with that signet ring.
Well...
Good morning, Clora,
Harold, come on in.
Ah.
Correct me
if I'm wrong,
but didn't we agree
to have Thanksgiving today?
I've prepared a meal.
I know,
I-I'm really sorry,
but something important
came up.
It turns out
that Shady Hilson was--
he was going to close
his hardware shop,
so Brick and I--
well, we spent the whole
night calling all over town
and looking for
help, and, well,
you see these?
All pledges to buy exclusively
from Nate's Hardware.
Yeah, it should be
enough to keep him
up and running for
a good long time.
Lawyers don't beg for money,
especially on behalf
of a man too stupid
- to manage his own finances.
- Whoa.
I'm not sure you heard,
Harold, but there are a lot
of good folks
that are struggling these days.
And since when did helping
your neighbor turn
into a character flaw?
Well, I'm just saying,
in order to be a good
lawyer, you have to learn
how to separate the personal
from the professional,
and, and my son is
occasionally too soft-hearted
for his own good.
Then what exactly are you
proud of me for, Dad, huh?
Oh, George, calm down.
You know, it's very hard
to take you seriously
when you're
in that ridiculous getup.
Hmm.
Oh, there you are, Mama.
I have an extra costume
picked out just for you.
We can be
mother-daughter pirates.
I am not wearing
a pirate costume,
and we are eating
Thanksgiving dinner.
Oh,
didn't George tell you?
Plans have changed,
and you would look
so cute in an eye patch, Mama.
For the love of God,
stop calling me that!
How my George came from your
loins, I have no earthly idea.
How dare you?
How dare I?
My mother may not be
around anymore,
but I am not desperate enough
to replace her
with a conniving witch like you.
Using a person's
vulnerabilities
to manipulate them is just--
it's downright un-Christian.
Watch your mouth, young lady.
And you!
If you can't be proud of George,
who is the most decent
and honorable man
that I have ever met,
well, then both of you
can go
to H-E-double-hockey-sticks.
I should have known that this
was about what
the two of you wanted
'cause it always is.
Dad, I officially decline
your offer.
Oh, uh, Happy Planksgiving.
♪ Yeah-eah-eah ♪
♪ Ye-Yeah-eah-eah ♪
♪ I like to hold
your hand up high ♪
♪ On the Ferris wheel ♪
♪ And how front porch swingin' ♪
♪ With you makes me feel ♪
♪ Yeah, but when you... ♪
Come on, honey, you
need to eat something.
I'm not hungry.
Hey, the peg-legged race
is coming up.
Maybe we should enter.
Can I just go home now?
Sure, buddy,
let's go.
♪ Crankin' up
Waylon, Willie, and Merle... ♪
Avast ye, mateys.
Methinks the Hilsons
are trying to make
a fast getaway.
Oh, I think you're right
there, Captain.
I'm, uh, I'm sorry, folks, but
Caleb's wanting to go home.
Well, I think we'd
like you to stay.
As a matter of fact...
we'd like you to stay
permanently.
This is a contract for the
new gym at the high school.
For the Town Hall renovation.
Yeah, now,
there's more than enough there
to, to make things right.
BlueBell is
behind you, Shady,
100%.
Ahoy!
Uh, uh, actually, it's "avast."
I am a Jewish pirate.
Ach-hoy!
I am looking
for a pirate named
Captain No Beard.
- Hi, Dr. Hart.
- Oh, hello there.
I found this hidden
near my carriage house.
Thought you could decipher it.
Treasure map?
♪ Yeah, but when you pull up
in your big old truck ♪
♪ I can't climb up in it
fast enough ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm your shotgun girl ♪
♪ Along for the ride... ♪
Caleb, I guess you were right.
There is treasure
right here in BlueBell.
Me name be Small Cal No Beard.
Oh.
But my friends
just call me Cap'n.
Come here, Cap'n.
I have never been more proud
of you, George.
You sure you don't regret
saying no to your dad?
Corporate lawyers
are a dime a dozen,
but I couldn't help
thinking about BlueBell.
What would happen if
I closed up shop here?
I mean, these people are more
than my neighbors, you know,
they're my friends.
And I could not leave
them if I wanted to.
Where'd you go last night?
Where else?
The airport.
I'm still stuffed
from all those cinnamon rolls.
No.
Thought you were leaving.
I just want you
to know, George,
that I was trying to help you.
Towns like BlueBell
are dying off.
Pretty soon you won't have
any more little guys to help.
Yeah, well, you know what?
I think we'll be just fine.
I wouldn't be so sure.
My firm represents a certain
big chain megastore.
They're securing land
outside of town.
I was hoping a man
inside BlueBell
might help facilitate dealings
with the townspeople.
You were going to use me?
Face it, George,
the world is changing,
you got to change with it.
Did you really think
that your, your
little hardware store
was going to be able to
compete with a mega-chain?
♪ ♪
Dr. Hart.
Brick.
You did real good today.
Thank you, it feels good.
Well, enjoy that feeling
'cause the new quarter
starts today.
♪ ♪
sync by Elderfel, corrected by susanaLC
www.Addic7ed.com