(Engine chugs and dies)
(Gasping)
Excuse me.
Thank you!
(Crackling)
(Groaning)
Oh, thank you.
(Crackling)
(Engine chugging)
(Engine starts)
(Engine chugs, siren fades and dies)
(Brakes squeal)
Postman! Postman!
Excuse me...
There was a stamp on this letter!
(Bean) Hello...
Er...excuse me.
Help! Hello...
(Gasping and choking)
(Coughing)
(Thud)
(Splash)
Oh, no!
Hello. So I was posting a letter
and I crouched and I lost my keys...
(Train whistle)
(Suppressed snorting)
(Laughs)
(Guffawing)
(Laughter continues)
(Stops laughing)
Tickets, please.
Ticket, please, sir.
Ticket, sir!
Can I see your ticket, sir?
Oh!
Would you like to try this?
(Miming)
(Chuckling)
Are you feeling any better?
No?
Excuse me.
Oh!
Could you keep an eye on him, please?
He's feeling rather poorly.
Prrrp!
Help! Help! Help! Help! Help!
(Tweets)
Is this yours?
(Tuts)
Oh!
(Violent vomiting)
(Pop)
(Rumbling)