Oh, Cece. Are you two kids
back together?
- She wishes.
- No, plumbing's out-- severe clogging.
- I'm sorry I asked.
- This is what happens.
Four models with
protein deficiencies,
sharing a shower.
(Laughs)
They shed like a... like
a four-dollar Christmas sweater.
Guys, guess what?
I just made a breakthrough
with a student.
Yeah, it's true.
(Humming)
- Don't, please.
- Uh, Jess?
You know we love you,
we all support you...
♪ I'm breaking through
with students. ♪
...but when you do things
like this, I'm sorry... bowl.
Okay.
It's just not satisfying.
- I think it is.
- Okay.
You said you had
a breakthrough.
It's just a whole new world
teaching adults.
This week, I gave
them an assignment.
I said write whatever you want
just load it up
with descriptive imagery.
MAN:
My fluffy pillow,
my yellowy fluffy pillow,
next to my dog, my hairy dog,
my beloved hairy dog,
while I diddle myself.
- Excellent.
He was a merman.
He was the last of his kind,
and he needed a mother
for his mer-child.
He was not a mer-gentleman.
Can't wait to hear more.
I just can't connect with them
and I don't know why.
Look, Jess, you can't teach
people how to write.
- Not true.
- I say that as a writer.
- Also not true.
- A writing class is for
somebody who doesn't think
lyrically in terms of,
like, poetic words
that just... are strung...
You said you had
a breakthrough.
So I have this student
whose name
is Edgar
and he was not getting it.
And then today he turned
in this amazing story.
Nick, actually,
you should read this.
Writers don't read--
we write.
Jessica Day calls it
"A must read."
Look at that font.
What is this amateur hour?
At least use Palatino.
WINSTON:
Good evening, everyone.
Or should I say morning?
Hey, Winston.
Do you guys have any agave?
We might have some
pressed lentil syrup
in the mixin's cabinet.
Thank you.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Okay, uh...
- Okay, you know what?
- Hey, look...
I just felt the side, the side
- anyway, so it's...
- I didn't mean to...
CECE:
It's fine, it's...
Other way, now.
- I will fight you, Jack.
- No, not again.
Not... no!
- No!
- Jump out the way, Jessica?
What the hell is wrong
with you just waving
that thing around
like an idiot?
♪ Who's that girl?
♪ Who's that girl? ♪
♪ It's Jess.
Sync & corrections by Alice
www.addic7ed.com.
Resync for WEB-DL by Norther
Guys, listen to this.
"By day, I'm a plumber.
By night, I'm a stalker."
You read it.
"I sit in the bushes
wearing a gimp costume,
stalking my prey."
He's the first person I got
to use first person narrative.
♪ I'm an amazing teacher.
- Very engaging, keep going.
- I'm hooked.
Okay, "My prey is a deer.
"Her eyes are big, too big.
"Before she can blink
those big eyes,
"I'm stabbing her.
"I stab and stab.
I love stabbing."
Sounds like he likes stabbing.
"After all the stabbing..."
It's repetitive, but...
"...I wash my hands
in her dark red blood"?!
Listen to that detail.
This man is psychotic.
It's fiction.
There's no such thing
as a gimp costume.
- No, gimp costume's a real thing.
- That's a real thing.
You've seen me in one before.
I just don't think
you should be in a room
with this creep, twice a week.
It is not safe.
Are you worried about me,
Miller?
Yeah, I'm a little worried
about you.
And if you won't do anything about it,
then I'm taking into my own hands.
I'm doing a little
investigation.
Investigating? Please.
You're just gonna
Google his name.
I am way beyond that.
You're typing his
name into Google.
We can all see the screen.
See the screen, dude.
This is a private investigation!
Are you... I wanted
to talk to you about the...
regrettable contact
between Cece's...
her-her down there
and my, uh...
my parts.
You practically
shish-kebabbed her.
Is this something
I should apologize for?
Just let it go, man.
You pogo'd her.
I'm sorry,
what did you say, "pogo"?
- I didn't, um...
- I heard
"Pogo" -- what is that?
(Sighs)
Look, Winston, fine.
It's what we call what you
did this morning, okay?
It's a short...
it's a shorthand.
Why do you have
a shorthand, Schmidt,
because it happens so often?
You pogo'd me once.
- You pogo'd Jess twice.
- Hey, it's not sexual.
Nick's never been
pogo'd directly.
You did get his pizza one
time... which, by the way,
is a whole nother debate--
how did you not feel that?
Let me get this straight--
you guys sit around
and talk about this?
Your penis actually
changed the channel,
uh, when we were watching
the Bears game once.
You don't think me, Nick and Jess
talk about you behind your back?
Because we do.
You have more pogos than anyone.
You are completely
misusing the word pogo.
You are the pogo king.
Pogo king. (Laughs)
Pogo king?
So I wanted to talk about your
creative imagery assignments.
Wow, guys.
I really felt like I was buried
under a giant, gleaming, powdery
avalanche of adjectives.
Don't mean to interrupt,
I just hear you're the best
- teacher of adults?
- Oh, no.
- I wonder if there's
room for one more? - No!
How you guys doing?
I'm Julius Pepperwood.
- Not now, okay?
- I'm an ex-cop, ex-Marine.
I'm here to learn how
to write short fiction.
Oh, okay, Julius, just...
take a seat and, um,
keep small.
I'm from Chicago.
Thin-crust pizza?
No, thank you.
I'm from Chicago.
So, for a fun follow-up...
- Sorry, I'm late.
- No, problem, Edgar.
(Mouthing)
We're just going over our
- descriptive imagery.
- I'm sorry, dear,
I can't hear you.
Mr. Pepperwood?
I'm gonna move closer,
if you don't mind.
No, you don't have to go...
stay over there.
How you doing, pal?
- I'm Julius Pepperwood.
- Edgar.
What are you doing?
If you don't mind me asking,
why are you late today, Edgar?
Uh, traffic, it
really killed me.
- It killed you?
- Mr. Pepperwood.
Would you say that
it stabbed you?
- Say that again?
- How about glasses on or off?
Teach, if I keep them on,
am I a bad boy?
Hey.
All right, honey,
I'll take them off.
Whoa, that's a whole different
lens to see that blue dress.
No.
Okay, let's refocus.
Um, let's talk about the, um,
four classifications
of conflict.
We talked about it last week.
It's in the workbook, um...
Anybody want to help me?
Four classifications
of conflict?
Anybody?
Anybody...
So, no one has signed up for
office hours and I just want
you to know that you can talk
to me about anything.
- Adios.
- Anything at all.
What are you doing?
Nothing, man, you look
good in your Dockers.
What? Nothing happened.
I'm Julius Pepperwood.
Let it go.
Whoops.
- Why did you do that?
- The wind.
(Quietly): No, no,
no, no, no, no.
Is everything all right?
- Yeah, everything's good.
- Oh, everything's fine, bro.
- What's happening right now?
- Sorry, Edgar, um, I really
loved your story.
Um, I wanted to give you
some notes-- is there any time
you could come in...
to office hours?
Yeah, that be really cool.
I'm really excited.
Um, I'm available anytime, so...
- I'll check my calendar.
- Yup.
Can't get service around here.
Wednesday I got to go
to the bird store.
Uh, what about
Wednesday afternoon?
He's my uncle.
Hey, Winston,
I'm glad you're home.
I know what my pogo is.
It's that I dance kind
of like a sea snake.
(Hissing quietly)
Yeah, not even close, Schmidt.
What are you talk...
I know this it, man.
Is it that I barge
into people's showers?
It's my caterpillar
eyebrows-- well, look.
(Whooshes)
(Screams)
They're gone.
Nick, you've gone way too far!
Way too far.
Well, if you're here for Edgar's
notebook, you're too late.
Where's the notebook?
Nick!
What's my one rule?
It's to not steal your yarn.
Don't steal my yarn, man.
It's my one thing.
But look at what was
inside of his notebook.
Okay, he was doodling
in class, Nick.
Weapons, dripping with blood?
That is not a doodle.
What are you, the doodle police?
(Snickers)
- There's no doodle police, are there?
- Really?
I can't believe you
still don't believe me.
Jessica...
Exhibit D.
He did this.
I'm going to Edgar's house,
I'm looking for more proof.
No, Nick, you're not spying
on the one student
that I have a connection with.
- I have the address right here.
- No.
- Give me the...
- No!
- I have the address memorized.
- Fine, then I'm coming, too.
To bail you out of jail when you
get arrested for trespassing.
- Fine, then you'll see
that I was right. - Fine!
And you'll also see
who gets there first.
Maybe we should take one car.
Just, like, for the environment.
Yeah, that makes sense--
we can drive together.
- Fine!
It's my mole, isn't it?
Well, consider it gone.
Game, set, pogo.
Chill out, man,
it's not your mole.
Just tell me,
this is the worst.
This is not the worst,
Schmidt-- the worst
is actually knowing.
Knowing that your friends
sit around every single night
talking about your pogo.
What's a pogo?
Those brows don't freak you out?
Nah, I've seen worse.
A pogo is what your friends talk
about when you leave the room.
Oh, like your barnacle toenails?
Uh... sh...
You guys talk about my toenails?
(Laughs) Never...
talk about
your toenails, Sch... Schmidt.
I know my toenails
are a little rugged.
Woodsy.
I mean, I have never wondered
if you could shimmy up
a palm tree.
But it's because I have a
keratin surplus, I mean...
They're not that bad,
look at these things.
- Aah! Schmidt!
- Ew!
It looks like an open
Swiss Army knife.
Most of them are hard, but one
of them is really, really soft.
I know, I know, I know-- we'll
just talk about what my pogo is.
What's my pogo?
Is it the way I say "pan"?
Pan, pan, pan.
Look, Cece, this is more
of just a loft thing.
Just thank your lucky stars
that you don't have
calcified mongrel toes!
(Toenails clicking on floor)
Things sound like
a dang ol' crab.
NICK:
There it is.
If anything's gonna go down,
we need a safe word.
Nothing's gonna go down
unless we make it go down.
- If Pepperwood taught me anything--
- There's no Pepperwood.
Never get caught
without a safe word.
We're gonna go with "apricot."
That's way too normal.
We need to, like,
go with something weird,
like "dragon slippers."
- What?
- I use "apricot" too much in my normal life.
Why do you use
"apricot" so much?
What am I supposed to call
them-- "sweet tangy balls"?
Don't call them "sweet
tangy balls," Jessica.
Well, that's why
we can't use...
Nick... Nick...
Nick, oh!
(Whispering):
Shh! Come on...
- Nick..
- Call me Julius Pepperwood, please.
You look ridiculous.
If we're hiding from people,
- why does it matter what I call you?
- I got my eyes
- and you get my six.
- No, no, what does this mean?
- I'm pretty sure this...
- This means "right turn bicycle."
- No, I'm pretty sure this means "stop...
- " It means "right turn."
Nick, seriously--
use your words.
- Don't use freaking SWAT sign language.
- Okay, these are my words.
(Door opens)
NICK: Oh!
Apricot, apricot, apricot.
Close your mouth,
close your eyes.
- Edgar lives with his mother.
- So?
- Of course he does. - A lot of normal
people live with their mothers.
Like my Uncle Randy.
- He can't go near parks.
- He was cleared.
You've got to...
(Vehicle approaches)
(Shrieks) Apricot! Apricot!
Get over here now!
- Oh, my God.
What's in that duffel bag?
He's the plumber
from the story.
- How did I not see this before?
- What was I saying?
- Oh, my God, you were right.
- Yes, say that again,
- say that again. You were right, you
were right, you were right about everything.
- Don't ever forget you're saying it!
- Oh, my God,
- I can't believe you were right.
- I was a right about everything!
What the hell is in
that duffel bag?
- I don't know.
- No, Nick.
- Nick, you're gonna get us killed.
- Let's get down.
Nick... Nick...
Shh.
(Ringtone):
♪ I'm so excited...
Oh, my... Jessica,
turn it off.
- Turn it off! Oh, my God, it's Edgar.
- What do I do?
You turn it... Here.
- Turn it off. I don't know
how to do this. - Okay.
(Ringtone stops, door opens)
Oh, my God. Get the
hell out of here.
Jess, what are you doing?
That is ridiculous.
There was plenty of room.
It seemed like a good idea.
Why would you go under a van?
Let's leave.
WINSTON:- Keep still...
- You will not believe what just happened.
- Nick was right.
- I was right.
Oh, my God, what happened
to your eyebrows?
You look like Audrey Hepburn.
Don't we own an
industrial-size paper cutter?
- Ugh! (Gasps)
- Oh, whatever.
- What the hell is that?
- So close to the eating area!
Winston told me that you guys
make fun of my gremlin toenails.
That you call them "clickety-
clacks" or "centaur boots."
What is wrong
with you, Winston?
What is wrong with me?
Besides my pogo.
I told him.
It just kind of popped out.
You understand what
that's like, right, Winston?
Okay, you know what?
Don't act like
we don't talk about you two
behind your backs.
Because we do. You both have
pogos, my friends.
Okay, let's take a deep breath
and ask ourselves
if this conversation is worth
ruining our friendships over.
Tell me my pogo.
I need to know my pogo.
You guys need to tell me.
I can take it. Lay it on me!
You know, it's kind of a loft thing.
Is it my pies?
Are they too tart?
Pies can't be a pogo, okay?
My koala claws,
now that's a pogo!
At least you can hide
your pogo in a shoe.
They make shoes for your penis--
they're called pants!
- Tell me my pogo.
- Jessica, no.
- Tell me my pogo!
- You're a know-it-all!
- Huge know-it-all.
- The worst.
Oh, I'm the worst
know-it-all in the world?
Please. Hate hyperbolic
speak. Please.
Now you know your pogo,
you truly know it all.
There I go
being a smart-ass again.
I mean, that, that
could be my pogo.
And then there was one.
Oh, no, no, no, I'm sure
that you guys have stuff
you laugh at me behind my back.
We don't laugh about
your pogo, Nick.
Yeah. We're worried about you.
You're worried about me?
We're worried that you're
not gonna make it.
- Make it to what?
- Just in general.
'Cause you don't take
care of yourself.
Sometimes I'll crumple up vitamins
and I'll put them in your food.
We all take turns sneaking
money into your pants pockets
before we put them
in the dryer.
Yeah? Well,
I hope you're happy.
The pogos are out.
The loft dynamic is ruined.
(High voice): But what
if I talk like a baby?
You're still hot. That's all
we're gonna talk about.
A tiny little baby!
Cut into these, please.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh...! A ladder...
That'll do.
(Grunting)
Okay, okay.
Oh, this is bad.
Oh, this is... this is very bad.
Oh, no, oh, no-- no, no-
no-no-no-no-- oh, God, oh, God.
♪ I'm so excited...
Hello.
- Jess, he wants to kill you!
- What...?
- I am in his shed right now
- What?
And there are drawings
on the wall of you,
and bloody weapons
and googly eyes.
Googly eyes are actually kind of
sexy, but that's beside...
Jess, I will not let you be in
a room alone with this guy.
You're the deer in his story.
He wants to kill you.
You're the deer, you're
the deer, you're the deer.
I'm at school and I'm doing
office hours...
Get out now! Okay, I'll just,
I'll just keep you on the line,
and then I'll say
the safe word, okay?
I'll just say it like...
Apricots! Apricots!
Good. Yeah, yeah, that's what
you say if you see Edgar.
Apricots! Really, apricots!
Oh, no. Okay, okay, stop it.
He's there. Okay.
I thought it was gonna be
"dragon slippers."
Is this a bad time or...?
No, no, no, no.
I just have a deaf grocer.
Apricots! Apricots!
And butter.
I'm coming.
Oh! Ho-ho!
Welcome to office hours.
Um...
- I found my ending.
- Yeah?
It's pretty risky. I'm not sure
I'm gonna be able
to get away with it.
(Chuckles)
(Grunts)
Oh!
Remember when you told me
to base my characters
on people from my own life?
Well, I based one on you.
- So flattered.
- And then I realized
that there was only one way
for the story to end.
You need to die.
(Softly):
Apricot, apricot.
No! ♪ Hey...!
♪ Uh, uh-uh-uh...!
♪ Look at that notebook.
(Groaning)
You said, "Great literature
is surprising."
What's more surprising than
killing your main character?
What about this--
go with me-- what if, um,
what if my character lives
and the book just goes on?
Imagine coming to the end
of the book,
and then just finding
a lot more book.
Surprise.
- ♪ I'm so excited
- Um, oh.
- ♪ And I just can't hide it...
- I heard that song yesterday.
This song is everywhere
these days.
Were you at my house?
- Okay, thank you. Good-bye.
- No.
- No! No!
- I have to go... right now.
Apricot's leaving!
Oh, good.
I'm so happy you're alive.
Okay, stay inside
and lock the door.
I am coming. I am going
to protect you... (Groans)
Nick?! Pepperwood! Nick!?
Burglar?! He's not a burglar.
He's Julius Pepperwood
from Chicago.
Let's get him in the house.
The D.A.'s gonna have my badge
for this.
No! Get off of him!
You kill him, you kill me, too!
Get away from my Edgar!
(Both screaming)
My eyes! Oh!
My giant eyes!
(Screams)
You thought I was a murderer?
You thought I was a
murderer of people?
You said you were gonna
kill me, so I don't know.
Your character...
in my graphic novel.
- He's an excellent artist.
- Okay, but your drawings,
they don't have any eyes.
- Hate drawing eyes. It's weird.
- He can't draw eyes.
There's a reason for everything.
What about the duffel bag?
BOTH:
Don't ask about the duffel bag!
Bitch.
- Whoa, whoa!
- Whoa! Hey, man.
Hey, take this
as a compliment, pal.
Your stories are so real.
Well, it's because
what you taught me.
You listened?
Well, of course I listened.
You were a good teacher.
Until you thought I was a murderer
and you broke into my shed.
Aw! You were my favorite
student until
I thought you were a murderer.
- Ah...
- Your son's a really great writer.
- He's not my son.
- Oh! Are you kidding?!
Really?!
EDGAR:
Real nice, you two.
Come here, baby.
Mm! God, you smell
like waffles.
I love it. Did you just
make some waffles?
- Want to eat me up?
- Yes, I do.
I'll meet you inside.
I'm gonna get the duffel bag.
- Yes, do.
- Okay.
- Hey, Nick.
- Hey.
What are you doing up?
Just taking care of myself.
Are you putting butter on bacon?
I don't want it
to stick to the pan.
Okay, did you...?
Great.
It's just what bacon needs,
more fat.
And salt.
- What's this?
- Don't read that. I'm not finished...
"Julius Pepperwood:
Zombie Detective"?
All his murder victims
are already dead,
so they obviously don't need
a detective. I'm working on it.
- "The night was inky hot."
- Don't do this.
"She strode into his office with
a sense of purpose, place,
another word here,
question mark."
I'm looking for another
"P" word there.
"She had zombie legs
that went on for miles.
"They were the kind of legs
you could sink your teeth into.
"Pepperwood had two friends--
one, if you count his hat.
The other was his gal Friday,
Jessica Night."
It's not you, Jess.
"She was small in stature,
but not in spunk.
And a super annoying
know-it-all."
Good evening.
Hello.
Oh, bacon.
Where the hell
did you come from?
I came from my room.
No, I didn't hear the pitter-
patter of your disgusting feet.
I cut my toenails.
Yeah, the soaking really worked.
Look at that.
They're gorgeous now.
- Went down a full shoe size.
- Guys! Fire!
- Whoa, whoa!
- Oh, my God!
Everybody relax!
Call a fireman!
- You call the fireman!
- I'm the fireman.
You can't put out a grease fire
with water!
You have to smother it!
Why didn't you say
that before?!
I don't want
to be a know-it-all!
- You're so stupid!
- Shut up!
- Whoo! Oh!
- Nice!
Yes!
Amazing, my man! Whoa.
Whoa.
Honestly, I didn't know you were
gonna put your arm around me.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, you put up your pup tent
in front of the fire.
WINSTON:
It's involuntary.
It is a combination
of adrenaline
and great circulation.
And I'd appreciate it if you
don't just hug me randomly!
That's weird and...!
(Schmidt laughs)
You ever notice...
when Winston runs,
- that he kinda farts while
he's running? - Yes!
(laughs)
- Sounds like a jalopy.
- New pogo.
Oh, we got a great new pogo!
He farts when he runs!
(Jess makes farting sounds)
Sync & corrections by Alice
www.addic7ed.com
Resync for WEB-DL by Norther