Andy got back from
London two days ago,
and he still has jet lag.
It's really annoying.
We're on totally
different schedules.
Last night he mowed the lawn
at 2:00 in the morning.
Andy! Andy!
Get me a beer?
All right.
As soon as I wake up
he goes down, hard.
This has to stop.
(SNORING)
Babe, wake up.
That's my spaghetti,
Chewbacca.
Babe!
(CLANGING)
You hungry, Champion?
(GASPS)
Oh, my God,
are you kidding me?
(GROANS)
Oh, man,
I fell asleep again?
Andy, you have got to stay up
and get on a regular schedule!
Were you about to spray me
with the hose
inside the house?
Yeah.
I kind of want you
to do it now.
Okay.
(SCREAMING)
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, just a reminder, guys,
today is Leslie's last
day as a city councilor,
so everyone be
extra supportive.
Already done.
When she walked
past me this morning,
I gave her a kind nod.
Heartwarming.
Also, I want to
get her a present
to cheer her up
on her last day.
Any ideas?
A " Sorry You Lost
Your Dream Job" gift?
Um, that's a tough one.
Stay away from wine.
Wine is crying juice.
Well, I mean, you know her
better than anybody.
What does she really want
more than anything
in the world?
A nice candle!
I'm screwed.
Andy, no!
(GASPS) No!
Oh, my God.
Andy!
I'll be right out.
(SIGHING)
Well, this is the Pawnee
City Council Chambers.
Your new home
away from home.
Well, technically,
my home away
from home is in Zurich.
Frank Gehry designed it.
But this is nice too.
Today is my last day
as City... Excuse me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Let me try this again.
(HOARSE VOICE)
Today is my last day as...
Today is my last...
Today is my last day...
You know what,
you get the idea.
My old friend
Ingrid De Forest
won the recall vote,
and she's taking my place
on Monday morning.
But you know, Iuckily for me,
I've processed all my feelings
and I've gone through
the five stages of grief,
denial, anger,
Internet commenting,
cat adoption, African dance,
cat-returning-to-
the-adoption-place,
watching all the episodes
of Murphy Brown and
not giving a flying fart.
How many
stages is that?
I don't know.
The point is
I'm fine now.
This must be hard for you.
It's like what
Sir Ian McKellen
said to me
the day I sold my boat
to Karl Lagerfeld,
"Parting is such
sweet sorrow."
Oh, my God.
What is your life?
(LAUGHS)
If it makes any difference,
your work here was
a real inspiration to me,
and I am going
to do my best
to continue your legacy.
Well, I appreciate
the sentiment.
(EXHALES)
Leslie?
(GASPS) I'm sorry.
Was I singing
Goodbye Yellow Brick Road
out loud?
No. But,
would you like to?
I studied opera
at the Sorbonne.
I'd be happy to harmonize.
(SINGING) Goodbye...
Goodbye...
Nah.
No.
And finally,
here is a check
for the entirety
of the purchase
of Rent A Swag.
And here is a personal note
from my client,
Dr. Saperstein.
"Dear Tom, I win.
You suck.
Turn note over.
"You still suck.
Turn note over."
Okay, Saperstein couldn't
even face me himself?
He had to send in
his lackey.
My client isn't
at this meeting because
he doesn't have to be.
Successful people,
Mr. Haverford,
use their money
to get others
to work for them.
Mmm, that's
an interesting idea,
lawyer dude.
What if I give you five bucks
to put a bag of poop
in Saperstein's car?
No.
Ballpark me,
how much would it cost?
$10,000.
Counter-offer,
why don't you just
do it for the story?
Goodbye, Mr. Haverford.
DR. SAPERSTEIN: Is it done?
Well, how many times
did he turn the paper over?
Oh, that is disappointing.
So, look at this baby.
That is the most
symmetrical fetus
I've ever seen.
This could be a superhero.
Dr. Saperstein.
Yes.
I know that
we should hate you
because you destroyed
our friend's business,
but we love you so much.
We love you.
I'm lovable.
So, do you want
to know the sex?
Oh, my God...
Should we?
No, right?
Or maybe yes?
Is there an option
other than yes or no?
I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna write it down.
Then I'm going to
put it in an envelope,
seal it,
and when
you're ready, voilà.
That'll be fun.
It's like the Oscars.
(LAUGHING)
Let's get some food.
I'm starving.
Wait, no,
I have to pee.
I have to barf!
Actually, all three.
Being pregnant is great.
And finally,
Larry's share
of the profit.
Whoa! Good to be Larry.
No, it's not,
you boring grandpa.
Meanwhile,
Tommy's riding high,
$32,000.
I'm basically a millionaire.
What are you going to do
with the money, Tom?
Glad you asked.
A horrible man recently
gave me some great advice.
For years,
I've been coming up
with my own ideas
like some sort
of non-rich idiot.
Now I'm going to
let people come to me
and invest my scrilla
in the best idea I hear.
That sounds like
an efficient use
of the free market.
I would wish you
the best of luck,
but I believe
luck is a concept
invented by the weak to
explain their failures.
Come hear the ideas
with me, Ron.
I could use your wise,
grandfatherly advice.
Do you think everyone here
is a grandfather?
Basically,
if you're older than me,
you're a grandpa.
And if you are a grandpa,
you're dead.
That sounds right.
Uh, oops! This check is
made out to "Lenny,"
which I think is
a typo for "Larry,"
which isn't even
actually my name.
(LAUGHS) Well,
tell it to the bank,
Lenny.
Am I... Am I Lenny now?
I'd like to order
a singing telegram.
Well, my wife lost her job,
so maybe something sad
and slow?
Do you know anything
from the Requiem for
a Dream soundtrack?
This is a bad idea.
I'm hanging up now, bye.
LESLIE: Well, Ingrid is
settled into my office,
and this box contains
the last of my stuff.
Although I might have
left some salt packets
in my desk.
Maybe I should
go back for those?
Honey, it's okay.
There'll be
other salt packets.
But not the kind that
snaps in half maybe.
Okay, I know
I'm a broken record,
but getting away
from the City Council
is absolutely the best thing
for you. Trust me.
This is Perd Hapley,
talking to you now about
what's going on, today.
We're live at City Hall,
where City Councilman Dexhart
is addressing
his latest sex scandal.
Recently, certain allegations
have come to light
about my inappropriate
conduct.
I am here to set
the record straight.
I totally
did all of it.
Another sex scandal?
This guy is unbelievable.
How does
he find the time?
I also engaged in
inappropriate texting,
"sexting,"
and "Tex-Mexting,"
which is where you send
photos of your junk
from the restroom
of a Chili's To Go.
Hmm.
Ew.
Does this
make me a "bad boy"?
You tell me.
No, really, tell me.
It gets me off when
women tell me that.
He's reading this.
He wrote this down.
I sent these texts
to roughly 100 women,
under the
following pseudonyms,
(CLEARS THROAT)
"Enrique Shockwave,"
"Willie Dynamite,"
"Lee Harvey Teabag."
Well, at least
you won't have to deal
with that guy anymore.
You're right.
Not after someone beats him
in the next election.
Someone who is
smart and hard-working
and who knows the job
because she's
done it already
and is also blonde
and named Leslie
and loves you!
Is it you?
Yes, it is.
I'm going to run again.
I'm going to beat Dexhart!
...and "Anthony Weiner."
Another City Council campaign?
Leslie, think about
what you're saying.
I did. I challenge you to
find one flaw in my plan.
Well, for one,
we don't even live
in Dexhart's district.
Not yet,
but we can go and
rent a second apartment,
and we can spend 51%
of our time there,
and then I'll file
the campaign form
from that address.
I don't want to
spend 51% of our time
in his district,
it's basically
a dumping ground
for old shipping containers.
Oh.
It's like a raccoon
shanty town.
Oh, it's not that bad.
And also,
Dexhart fights dirty.
He's never lost an election
because he runs brutal,
scorched earth campaigns.
So what?
I've got plenty of dirt
on that scumbag,
I say bring it on.
So, I'm going to
start my negative PR blitz
against Dexhart and...
Look, I just think
we need to take
a deep breath,
think about if
this is really worth it.
Anything is worth
me getting back
on City Council.
Okay, let's see which one
of these lucky visionaries
is gonna make me rich.
Greg Phillips?
Hi, guys. Thanks
for meeting with me.
Enough chit-chat.
What's your pitch, kid?
Come on, time is money,
money is power,
power is pizza,
pizza is knowledge,
let's go.
Okay, so, my idea
is for an abacus,
but on your phone.
I call it
a"phone-bacus."
Son, you just
described a calculator.
But you're talking
about it, right?
Three words,
Automated Word Counter.
Get out.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Two words.
No.
One word.
As you may know,
I do like to tinker
with things in my garage.
I'm gonna hit the can
while he's up.
So, I think I have
discovered a way
to generate clean,
renewable energy.
(WHIRRING)
I think it's going to...
(SNEEZING)
Ugh! Gross!
God, Larry,
you sneezed all over us!
I'm not going to
buy that thing.
It's covered in
a gallon of your boogers!
LARRY:
I totally understand.
(SNEEZING)
Ah, jeez!
I would be thrilled
if we have a girl.
Aw, tiny dresses, braids,
glitter on everything?
Forget it.
And also girls' names
are so cute.
Daisy, Annabelle, Lilly...
Olive, Rosemary, Chicken.
Fifty burritos.
Oh, my God, I'm starving.
Miss, hi, I'm pregnant,
and I'm a little bit crazy,
so if you don't
bring our appetizers out
in the next 30 seconds,
I'm going to
plunge your face
into the deep fryer.
And also two waters,
please, but no hurry.
Thank you.
Leslie,
I don't know if there's
a story in these emails.
They're iffy,
but Dexhart has been
elected eight times.
I don't think
the voters care.
His poll numbers
are actually up
since the scandal broke.
Well, that's just
because people
found out he was
Miley Cyrus' cousin.
He is?
Morning, Leslie.
Sweet Jugs.
What? He's kinda cute.
Oh, God, Shauna, no.
I just feel like
I could fix him,
you know?
(EXHALES)
This sucks!
We heard 100 pitches
and they're all terrible.
Change of plans.
You guys are
my idea factory.
April, go!
Okay, I got one.
"Macaroni and Poison,"
it's like mac and cheese,
but with a special ingredient.
Ron?
Every socket set
I've ever bought
only goes up to half inch.
I'd love
a couple larger sizes,
take it all the way
up to five-eighths.
Andy?
Bears bouncing on
trampoline roads.
There's a chance
that I might
have dreamed that.
Okay, time to head
back to the office.
I've missed
an entire day of work,
so at least some good
came from this.
BEN: What are you doing?
Well, they couldn't
make a banner in time
for my press conference,
so I am cobbling
together a banner
from all the other
discarded banners.
"Second chunce four Lesle
"Perv Dexxxhrt
equals birthday mouse?"
Rat.
Well, that's
the closest thing
I could get to a rat.
(SIGHS) Leslie,
listen to yourself,
loopholes,
scorched earth policies...
This isn't you.
I cannot believe you aren't
supporting me on this.
Dexhart has a sex scandal
the same day
I'm leaving office?
That is not a coincidence,
this was meant to be.
You know what?
Why don't we gather
everyone in here,
you explain to them
what you're thinking,
and we get some feedback.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
Now you're talking!
I would be thrilled
if we had a boy.
I have perfected the art
of shaving the human face,
and I would love to be
able to pass that on.
Toy trucks,
superhero costumes,
tiny little acorn penis...
Forget it.
A weird image,
but one that does not
diminish my enthusiasm.
Well, Ann Perkins,
are you ready to find out
the sex of our baby?
I'm ready.
We are having a...
"Distributions."
That's what it looks like,
Let me see that.
It says "Congratulations."
I think.
Then it says,
"I leg Smurf."
Are we having a Smurf?
We are having
an "eleven-jewel toilet."
I can't tell what's words
and what's punctuation.
The suspense is killing me!
I'm calling Dr. Saperstein!
I'm calling Domino's.
Do you think Domino's delivers
to this restaurant? I hope so.
Oh, no. He's out for
the rest of the day.
I have literally never
been more stressed out.
Good, you guys are here.
Okay, everybody,
gather around.
I have a big announcement.
I am officially
seeking re-election
to the Pawnee City Council.
I am going to be
running for Dexhart's seat,
and the campaign starts now!
Oh, I love
the sound of silence
before a big cheer.
That's what's happening,
right?
Leslie, no offense,
I've heard a lot of
bad ideas today,
this is the worst.
April?
I would love it
if you ran an insane campaign
and basically turned
into the Joker.
But that means
you probably
shouldn't do it.
Andy?
I don't know, Leslie.
It seems risky,
and I'd hate to
see you go through
another tough fight.
But I could be wrong,
I haven't pooped
in three days.
Okay. Ron, you have always
given me sage counsel,
and your words
carry great influence.
So, what do you
think I should do?
I do not think
you should run again.
What the hell
do you know, dum-dum?
All of you, look,
this is my only option.
I am running again
with or without you.
Leslie, you're running
for office again?
What a great idea!
How can I help?
(SIGHS)
Well, no one else brought me
any good business ideas,
so I decided to
take care of it myself.
Talking Tissue!
Every time you pull one out,
you get a little message
to hype you up.
TOM:
Blow that nose, playa!
No.
(SIGHS) This stinks!
I'm just gonna have to
go back to my same job
that I've had forever.
Yeah, I get
why you're bummed out.
I mean, look at me,
I'm younger than you,
and I already have
my own department.
Plus I'm married,
and I make more
money than you.
Whatever.
You just merged your
department with Parks
and then made up
your own title.
Yeah. It's awesome.
I'm empty, yo!
Fill me up!
Do that again.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What could you possibly need
at 6:00 in the morning?
We couldn't read your writing,
and we need to know
the sex of our baby.
I'm watching cartoons
with my son.
Daddy, an Elmer Fudd
one is on.
Stop it.
What's up, beautiful?
Jean-Ralphio.
I live in the guesthouse.
What do you say
you and I get together
in a special way?
I'm pregnant.
The more the merrier.
With my baby.
You can come too, beautiful.
Look at that,
I guess sometimes
I call men "beautiful" too.
I guess I'm...
(SINGING)
...open-minded as hell!
I think you're
pretty good-looking
Thank you.
Can you just read that
and tell us what
the sex is, please?
Wow.
It looks like
the chicken that wrote this
had a stroke on the paper.
Listen, I kind of remember,
but I don't want to say
anything that's wrong.
Give me 15 minutes.
I will get dressed,
we'll go down to my office.
Okay.
Have a good day at
work today, Daddy.
Also, if you
don't know already,
there's a malfunction
with the TV
where it keeps
ordering porno...
Like a ton of porno,
like how can someone watch
that much porno
in one sitting,
only when you're
out of the house,
so if you see it
on the bill
that's why. Okay?
"And therefore,
with your help,
we can make our future bright.
"I believe I still have
a lot to offer this city."
BEN: I'd swap
those two lines.
Always helps to end
on the call to action.
I'm sorry if it felt
like everyone piled on.
We were just being honest,
but if you really
want to do this,
of course we'll support you.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I stormed out.
You know, I've been thinking
for weeks
of what to get you
as a " last day
in City Council" present.
I finally figured it out.
You remember Jen Barkley,
political consultant
and power broker.
Hey, Jen.
What brings you
back to Pawnee?
Ben bought one hour
of my time.
I heard you need
some consulting.
Well, uh, I guess.
I mean, how are you?
How's your family?
Okay, I get paid
$1,200 an hour.
Do you really want to
spend any of that time
talking about my mother
and her 19-year-old
Korean husband?
Well, that does
sound fascinating,
but you're right. Let's talk.
Okay, getting a chair.
Ron!
That's how I enter rooms now.
It's more dramatic.
Why did you enter at all?
Because I have
some huge news.
You're looking at Pawnee's
new Business Liaison.
I don't like French words.
I do like the word
"business."
You may continue.
April created a new
position for herself,
and I want to do the same.
The town could use
more private sector money
after the merger,
so as Business Liaison,
I would find companies
looking to move or expand,
and convince them
to do it in Pawnee.
Now this is a good idea.
You've come
a long way, son.
And while
I've got you here...
Talking Tissue.
Go for it.
Yo, dawg,
life is what
you make of it!
Leave while I'm ahead?
You got it!
Clear them sinuses,
playboy.
Someone's got the "sniffies."
Tell your mama you love her.
Step up your
vitamin C game, bro.
So they recall me after
all I've done for them!
Ridiculous.
But Dexhart now has
another sex scandal.
Of course he does.
And the plan is
I'm going to run
for his seat
because how do I lose
to a guy like that?
That's a great idea,
right?
It's a terrible idea.
I knew it. Wait, what?
First of all, you could
lose to a guy like that.
Terrible people
defeat great people
all of the time.
I should know,
those terrible people have
paid me so much money,
I have a condo on
every Virgin Island.
Now, you might win.
You're smart, Ben is smart,
you might win.
But why would you want to?
Because it's my dream job.
Then dream bigger.
Look, you love this town,
it's being run by
monsters and morons?
Get a better job,
rise above their heads,
affect change at
a higher level.
Don't be the kid that
graduates high school,
hangs out in
the school parking lot.
Be the woman who moves away,
climbs the ladder,
and then
confidently comes back
and has sex with
her hot old English teacher
just for kicks.
Is that what you did?
Yeah, Mr. Baker.
Sex was pretty good,
thanks to me.
Look, Pawnee has
done you a favor.
You've outgrown them.
You've got talent,
you've got name recognition,
which means that
you have a bright,
wide-open future
with a thousand options.
State Senate,
federal jobs,
even Congress,
all of these are
doable for you.
And you can trust me.
Because I don't care enough
about you to lie.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
Uh-oh, time's up...
Okay, if you want to
keep talking,
you're going to have to
pay me 1,200 more dollars.
(STAMMERS) I just need...
I swear to God,
if you say one more word,
you will legally
owe me $1,200,
and I will sue you.
Let's not end it like that.
Okay, great
to see you, Leslie.
Those five words
are on me.
Should I move this back?
Don't answer that.
I don't know what
you're thinking,
but you have
a press conference
in 10 minutes.
Well, this is it...
The final moment.
What are you hoping for?
I will honestly be
happy either way.
Me, too. Boy or girl,
it doesn't matter.
Because it will literally
be the greatest child
who has ever lived.
You swear
you have no preference?
You?
Not at all.
Who's ready,
raise your hand?
It's a boy!
Yes!
I thought you didn't
have a preference!
I didn't. I just really
wanted it to be a boy.
Me, too. I don't know why.
You guys are
just so neat.
Would you be interested
in adopting my children?
They're in their late 20s...
They're terrible.
No? No go?
Huh. I ask all my patients.
I have gathered
you all here today
because I have
an announcement,
a very big announcement
about my future.
I will be heading
to lunch today,
with my husband,
at JJ's Diner.
We will eat waffles
and then we will go home
and make out on our couch.
That is my future,
for now.
It's been an honor
to serve this town,
and I will cherish
the memories forever.
Thank you.
There you have it,
a shockingly un-shocking
press conference,
in which
a recently-unemployed woman
said nothing of importance.
I'm Perd Hapley
and I just realized
I'm not holding my microphone.
Jen Barkley telling me
I had a future
was the best present
I could've gotten.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
But I did get you
one other present
to take your mind off
of all this.
Aw, you are the sweetest
man in the world.
Where is it?
Well, it's not here.
We have to go get it.
(FRENCH SONG PLAYING)
LESLIE: In times of stress,
or moments of transition,
sometimes it can feel
like the whole world
is closing in on you.
When that happens,
you should close your eyes,
take a deep breath,
listen to
the people who love you
when they give you advice,
and remember
what really matters.
And if you have
the ability to go to Paris,
by all means, go to Paris.
I found one.
Oh, great.
Right here.
Yeah?
Mmm-hmm.