Digga-digga-dog
- Digga-digga-dog, digga-digga-dog
- Bow-wow-wow
Digga-digga-dog
Digga-digga-dog, dog, dog
- You dog, you!
- Bow-wow-wow
Digga-digga-dog
- Digga-digga-dog, digga-digga-dog
- Bow-wow-wow
- Digga-digga-dog
Digga-digga-dog, dog, dog
- You dog, you!
Bow-wow-wow
Yippee-yo, yippee-yay
Ain't that
the man in the moon
Dancin' over our heads
Atomic dog
Yeah, while all good dogs
are asleep in their beds
-Atomic dog
- Ohh-oh-oh
Smiling in their dreams
At the crazy things
people do
Yeah
And when you think
you've fooled them
Who'll make a fool
out of who
Whoa-ohh-ohh
You dog, you!
Don't be believin'
Bow-wow-wow
Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
- Bow-wow-wow
Don't be believin'
Bow-wow-wow
Looks are deceivin'
You dog, you!
Bow-wow-wow
Yippee-yo, yippee-yay
You think
you're on top of the game
You got a lot to learn
-Atomic dog
- Yeah, you do
When life hangs tough
Take a dog-legged turn
-Atomic dog
- Yeah, uh-huh-huh
People, they think
they're so cool
If they throw you a bone
Hey
Wait till they discover
You've got some tricks
of your own
Ah, hey, hey-ey-ey
You dog, you!
Don't be believin'
Bow-wow-wow
Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
- Bow-wow-wow
Don't be believin'
Bow-wow-wow
Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
- Bow-wow-wow
Bow-wow-wow
-A-bow-wow-wow
-Spotted dog, spotted dog
Where have you been
I've been to London
to look at the queen
Can you tell
a spotted story
Yes, I can
I saw a dog
who was walkin' a man
Oww!
- You dog, you!
- Bow-wow-wow
Don't be believin'
- Oh-ohh-ohh
- Bow-wow-wow
Looks are deceivin'
- Hey, you dog, you
- Bow-wow-wow
Digga-digga-dog, digga-digga-dog
- Don't give me no more rules
- Digga-digga-dog, digga-digga-dog
Digga-digga-dog, digga-digga-dog
Dog, dog
You dog, you!
My client is not
a laboratory animal, Dr. Pavlov.
Your client
wants out of prison, Mr. Torte...
and with my behavior
control therapy...
freedom is...
I have patented
a humane cocktail...
of electric shock treatment...
aversion therapy, hypnosis...
drugs...
and plenty
of green vegetables.
But, of course,
the real challenge remains.
I mean, this is a prison,
not a pet shop.
And I don't
represent animals in court.
- Dr. Pavlov, my client...
- Is cured.
Brush up your Swedish,
Dr. Pavlov.
This could be
your Nobel prize!
- Cruella De Vil.
- Do call me Ella.
Cruella sounds so cruel.
Ms. De Vil, I am releasing you into
the custody of the probation office.
You will perform 500 hours
of community service.
Mr. Torte, your client is,
I believe, a wealthy woman.
After my exorbitant fees,
milord...
her assets stand
at a mere £8 million.
Then you will be bound over to keep
the peace to the sum of £8 million.
If forfeited,
the money will be donated...
to the dogs' homes
of the borough of Westminster.
Which means,
if you repeat the offense...
your entire fortune
will go to the dogs.
Alonso.
My ever-loyal valet.
My only visitor...
stuttering sweetly on the far, far side
of the bulletproof glass.
Oh, Miss De Vil,
I've waited for this day.
I hope it's not too presumptuous,
but I've brought you a g-g-gift.
Oh, Alonso, how considerate.
Oh!
I think I'll call him Fluffy.
Oh, he's smiling at me.
Oh, what a sweet voice.
Wrong side, Alonso.
Come, Fluffy.
Mummy will drive.
I told you
you wouldn't believe the truth.
The dog ate your pay stubs.
Ewan, can't you do
a little better than that?
I was abducted by aliens.
Put me out at Piccadilly,
they did. It was a...
How can you work here? I can't
even keep me own story straight.
Listen.
I won't say it again.
No pay stub, no probation.
Dog shelter suits me.
- l-I think I found me self.
- Mm-hmm.
Here's a snap of me
with the dogs.
Uh, that's the boss.
He's a top bloke.
You'd love him.
Ah. Told ya.
Drooler got a hold of it.
Ewan, this is an IOU.
- Yeah, well, we're a bit tight
on funds at the moment.
- Chloe, this is...
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Ewan was just off.
All right. Thanks, miss.
Uh, next week, then?
Yes. With pay stubs.
Am I being clear?
Uh, supremely.
Um, keep the photo.
You do put the fear of God
into them, Chloe.
Which is why
I've chosen you to...
- Is it...
- Line three!
- Hello?
- Is it?
Yes! Stay there!
Keep breathing,
and I'll be there in a second.
Goodness.
Hurry!
- See you soon!
- Chloe! Chloe!
You forgot this.
What... Ah.
Oh, for Pete's sake.
Are you two at it again?
Kevin, how many times
have I had to tell you...
it's pointless for you humans
to play tug-of-war against us dogs.
Come on, Drooler!
Hit him with both barrels!
Yes! You got it!
He's ours! He's down!
He's... He's getting up!
I always say,
if you can't stand the heat, cheat!
Hurry, boys! Get in there!
We dogs need to stick together.
All right, Chomp, sock it to him!
Can you dig it, Digger?
Let's get ready to tumble!
Hey! Hey! That's not fair!
Yes, it is!
All's fair in tug-of-war!
I took you misfits in out
of the goodness of my heart,
and this is how you repay me?
That's pathetic, Kev. How many times
you gonna fall for that one?
I managed to get another week out
of my probation officer, boss.
Think she quite fancies me.
Come on, boys. It's grub time.
Where'd you get that dog food?
Didn't pinch it, did you?
No. I'm done with all that.
There you go.
- Fill your belly.
- Come on.
Good girl.
Okay, who's next?
Hey.
Fill 'er up, Kev.
I'm a very hungry dog.
Oh, thank you.
- Hey! Hey, wait!
Come back with my grub!
- Come on, Waddles worth. Come on.
Today's the day, Waddles worth.
Fly up to your house, and then I'll
feed you. Come on, Waddles worth!
Come on! Fly! You can do it.
No, I've told you once, I've told you
a hundred times: we dogs can't fly!
See? Now stand aside, birdbrain.
Save some for tomorrow. I don't know
where our next meal's coming from.
Me mum always said, "When the heart
hopes, hope comes knocking."
"'Eart 'opes"?
Hope comes knocking.
What? Evicted? But you said...
You shouldn't believe
what people say. I don't.
You can't turn
all these dogs loose in the city.
- Give us another chance.
- I'm not the one
running a charity here.
Maybe you can
get away with this...
You and your mangy pack
are out of here tomorrow!
You'd better not leave
any of this junk about!
Next time I'll bite your bum,
you smelly little git.
Don't worry.
Everything'll be all right.
Oh, Dottie,
they're absolutely beautiful.
Aren't they, Dipstick?
You must be very proud.
You are an odd one,
aren't you?
There you go.
Now you should get some rest.
Come on, Dipstick.
It's smaller than I remember.
I k-kept everything
just as you l-left it.
Oh, come, Fluffy.
We'll share a bath.
An interminable soak...
scented with lavender...
and a drop of Sumatran...
Never mind. I think I'll enjoy
doing a little dusting.
Oh, Fluffy, a bath...
followed by a nap...
submerged
in feather pillows and satin...
Alonso! Fur! It's everywhere!
Lock them away!
Bury them beyond sight and memory!
- Even the Mongolian
pony skin trousers and the...
- Now!
And this!
Is it safe?
Yes, it's s-safe.
I do not believe it.
How could they release
that... that...
You know, I pity the poor
probation officer that has to look af...
Oh, no.
No, it's not possible.
Oh!
Well, I refuse.
I'm not doing it.
What?
You remember her,
don't you?
You remember
what she almost did to you.
Dipstick.
Okay.
I'll do it for you.
And for the family.
- Miss De Vil.
- Yes?
You're five minutes late.
It's a good start.
Well,
perhaps your clock's fast.
I'm your probation officer,
Chloe Simon.
Yes, of course you are.
And we're going to be
such friends.
Mmm. Friends.
You are going to help me be a useful
member of society, aren't you?
Find me
a little niche somewhere?
Could you manage something
with puppy dogs?
I see you more as a coal miner...
or something
in the sewers, perhaps.
Ah, I see.
Oh! You have doggies?
Yes, and I don't want you
looking at them.
I'm sorry. l...
Listen, can we just be
sensible about this?
Yes! Let's.
Well, must dash.
Bye.
This is your last chance,
Mr. Button.
When the press sees what
you're doing to these poor dogs...
you'll be the most hated man
in London.
I don't see any press...
but I can guarantee
the bailiff is on his way.
Right!
That's it, Mr. Buttocks!
That one's vicious,
he is!
They're here!
Everyone on your best behavior.
Pick up your signs.
Come on.
- Here!
- Here we are outside
the Second Chance...
- You're just in time.
- Excuse me. I'm just trying to...
No, no, no, the dog shelter's over here.
These rescued dogs are being evicted...
Just one moment!
This man has no right...
- Here she comes!
- Who she comes?
- Cruella De Vil?
- Cruella! Cruella! Cruella!
- Cruella!
Please. Call me Ella.
Ella! Ella!
Well.
This place and I
were made for each other.
- Is it yours?
- No, it's mine.
- And he...
- Alonso.
Buy the dump.
And give him a little extra
for a tie.
So, could you tell us how
Cruella De Vil became plain Ella?
Well, I certainly can. It was all
thanks to Dr. Pavlov and his therapy.
And do you really think that you,
a convicted dognap per...
are the right person
to run this establishment?
Second Chance Dog Shelter
says it all.
And I think I deserve
a second chance too. Don't you?
No, I do not.
She tricked me!
It's the Red Baron,
king of the sky!
Stop playing
and give me a hand here.
Hey, look. Another volunteer.
See, Ewan? There are
good-hearted people everywhere.
Beautiful good-hearted people.
That's my probation officer!
What, that's
your probation officer?
- Are you Kevin Sheperd?
- Yes. Yes, I'm Kevin...
And you call yourself
a dog lover?
- Well, yes, I do. I am.
- He does. He is.
I'll get to you, Ewan.
I'm Chloe Simon.
Cruella De Vil's
probation officer.
Oh! She's in the back.
Is there some problem?
I mean, uh...
Ooh. Excuse us, Chomp.
I mean, Miss De Vil,
she seems devoted to...
Nice bird!
- You are a nice bird.
- I'm not a bird.
He means you.
Where are your manners?
- Buried in the yard with my bone.
- This is...
- Um...
- Chloe. Chloe Simon.
Chloe, meet Waddles worth.
- He's a rottweiler.
- Hello.
That's funny, because
he looks like a macaw.
Trust me. He's a rottweiler.
You know, I don't think I trust anyone
who knowingly puts Cruella De Vil
anywhere near dogs.
Well, yes, but she's changed.
- People like Cruella don't change.
- Of course they do.
That's why I started Second Chance.
I knew what it was like to need one.
And the same goes for dogs. Eh?
Take Chomp here, for example.
He chewed through three postmen
before I rescued him.
Now he wouldn't hurt a flea.
And Digger, he was banned from every
park in London as a menace to roses.
And Drooler...
Well, Drooler hasn't
really changed much.
- Those are dogs.
- Oh, but dogs are people too.
- But Cruella is...
- Changed.
Who's washing who, Alonso?
Now, hair
must be a statement...
a reflection
of our inner life.
Color is important,
of course...
but texture is vital.
Voila!
Oh, darling, darling.
It's you.
- Do you like it?
- I'll be keeping my eye on her.
I hope so.
Cruella De Vil
- Three!
- Cruella De Vil
Cruella De Vil
Just hearing her name
used to make you feel ill
Now suddenly she's
drippin' with good will
Can this be Cruella De Vil
A heartwarmin' laugh
Instead of a scream
She's practically human
Or so it would seem
As playful as a puppy in the snow
That's not the Cruella we know
Oh, remember when she lived
Just to be rotten
How she loved to frighten
the little tots
Who thought she could be kind
Respectful and refined
Has the lady
really changed her spots
Oh, Lord
Oooh-ooh, oooh-ooh
Oooh-ooh, oooh-ooh, ooh
Cruella De Vil
Now check this out
You know what
She gave up her bark
but will she still bite
What's wrong with this picture
It doesn't look right
Unfortunately
only time will tell
If Cruella, I mean, Ella
Is from heaven or hell
Ooh, yeah
And now BBC 2
is proud to present...
the third part in our series,
What Makes Big Ben Tick?
Turn down the television, quick!
What a unique sound pattern.
Very loud.
That would be Ben on the telly.
Yes.
It must have jolted
their brain waves back into...
This mustn't get out.
Do you hear me?
It never happened.
What are you doing?
You're... Yes.
And this is Domino.
Little Dipper's easy because his
tail is exactly like his daddy's.
- And I know Oddball
because she doesn't have any...
- Shh, shh!
I don't want her to be sensitive
about her lack of, um...
S-P-O-T-S.
Oh. Is that normal at her age?
Well, like everything else
about her...
it is a bit...
odd.
Hello? Hello?
Is that you, Nigel?
I know you're there.
I can hear you breathing.
Oh, dear. Will you take them
up to your office for a while?
'Cause I just keep
staring at them...
and I'm falling dreadfully behind
with my paperwork, as you can see.
Yes, I can see.
It's probably just as well
with Miss De Vil coming in.
- Cruella?
- Y-Yes. She asked to change her
apppointment. I thought you knew.
Come on, Oddball,
Little Dipper, Dipstick.
Quick, quick, quick, quick!
Cruella De Vil, that wretched...
- Philanthropist?
- Cruella, I didn't realize...
Oh, please, please call me Ella.
Now, Chloe, you can't stop me.
It's my duty to demonstrate
against a fur fashion show.
And it's my duty to inform you
that if you go anywhere near fur,
I'll put you straight back in prison.
Won't you even let me heckle
that monstrous Le Pelt?
- No.
-Just a teensy-weensy heckle?
You know... murderer!
Round two!
Knockout!
Body blow! Body blow!
Bonus fall.
Round three!
I have so much to atone for.
I'm seeing spots.
Dr. Pavlov!
Oddball!
- Grab my legs! Grab my legs!
- What...
Oddball!
How did you get out?
Are these your lovely dogs?
Yes. Are you all right?
Dipstick, shh, please!
I remember you as a puppy.
Why don't I come back later.
I'm feeling a little...
chilly.
Um, wouldn't you be
more c-comfortable in the c-car?
Ella?
Not Ella. Ella's gone.
And Cruella's back!
Pull! Pull!
Stand aside, worm.
Oh, mummy's home,
and I'll never leave you again!
Oh, yes! Oh, hello!
Oh, yes!
Oh! Why do I feel incomplete?
What could be missing
from my life?
Cruella De Vil, who has it all!
The softest, the rarest,
the whitest, the blackest...
the scrappiest,
the sportiest, the...
- Hmm?
- Of course.
Where is it? Where?
Where is it? Oh, there it is.
My dalmatian puppy coat.
The coat of dreams.
The ultimate fur coat...
that was denied me
by that canine cabal...
for which I have lost
three years of my life!
Alonso!
- We are going to make them pay.
- Oh, yes! How much?
Dipstick, she called him.
Ah, what fiendish justice.
He escaped me, but I shall wreak
my vengeance on the next generation.
S-Sounds w-wonderful.
Alonso, I need you.
I'm yours.
Furnish yourself with a torch.
a large sack and rubber-soled shoes.
Meanwhile, I need a furrier.
And I know just where to find him.
Freak out
Le freak, c'est chic
Aww, freak out
Freak out
Le freak, c'est chic
-Aww, freak out
- Look at me in this big spotlight
I'll make this one magical night
I am fierce
And we are fabulous
Freak out, so fabulous
So fierce
- Freak out
-So beautiful
-So freaky
- Freak out
-So fabulous
-So hip
- Freak out
-So beautiful
-So freaky
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Some kind of love
Ah, freak out
Murderer! Murderer!
Killers!
- Come on, you.
- You're nicked!
No! No!
- Monsieur Le Pelt! Monsieur Le Pelt!
- Get out!
Animals! They are all animals!
- They have no class!
- Ooh! But, monsieur...
- Leave me alone!
- No... No...
Not here!
Forgive me.
My idiots didn't recognize you.
Only two minions to abuse?
Oh, Jean-Pierre,
the world is so unfair.
Get out! You are unfit
to look upon this goddess of fashion!
Out! Out!
Cruella De Vil...
my idol, my inspiration,
at my show.
I am so sorry
for the demonstrators.
Demonstrators?
I thought they were critics.
Go away!
Jean-Pierre...
you've come such a long way
from poaching weasels.
And you, out of prison at last.
Yes. Terrible experience, prison.
Who are you, little man?
And what are you doing in my trailer?
- You shouldn't have brought them
in here, you idiot!
- But l...
He's with you!
- What is this?
- Your salvation, Jean-Pierre.
Monsieur Le Pelt
has clearly run out of ideas.
I propose...
- an alliance...
- Mmm?
between Monsieur Le Pelt
and the house of De Vil.
- You have an idea in the bag?
- Oh, Jean-Pierre.
Together,
you and I will make a coat...
so soft, so luxurious,
so practical in any weather...
so bad that we'll rip the veils
off the eyes of fashion...
and write our names
in the pantheon of stars.
Of course. From "poopies."
Ah, not just any "poopies."
" Poopies" with...
Spots.
Hey, wait for me!
Enjoy the show.
One adult, three dogs
and one bird, please.
Oy, I'm a dog, mate.
Four dogs.
- Four dogs.
- Well, look who's here.
Blimey! I'm seein' spots!
Hello, Kevin.
- Chloe! Are you, uh...
- Yeah, I'm going.
- And are these your dalmatians?
- Yeah.
This is Digger, Chomp and Drooler.
You call that a bark?
This is a bark.
That's right.
Go hide behind Mummy.
And... Oddball.
He's not gonna hurt you.
- Your change, sir.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Don't you count your change?
- Well, why should I?
- Now it all makes sense.
- What?
How you could actually believe
that Cruella De Vil had changed.
She has changed.
Shh! The show's gonna start.
Let's just enjoy the show.
Let's.
- Hello, everybody!
- Hello, Mr. Punch!
Hello, everybody!
Hello, Judy!
- Give us a kiss.
- Everybody would laugh at us!
- Wouldn't you, everyone?
- No!
All right, one kiss. Ready?
Oh, you are awful!
There's a dog around here today.
- If you see a dog, will you
call out and tell us, please?
- Yes!
- I won't be long then. Bye-bye!
- Bye!
I don't see any dog. Where is it?
Oh, dear.
What is it?
Oddball's obsessed with...
S-P-O-T-S.
- Spots?
- Shh!
What? What'd I do?
I just said "spots."
Help! Help!
Help! Help! Oh!
Oh, no!
Help, help! Help! Help!
Oddball, no!
Follow that dog!
What's that?
Oy! They've got balloons!
- Oddball! Stop!
- Get 'em back here!
Where is that dog?
Hold on! We're coming!
- Waddles worth.
- Oddball!
Now's your chance. You fly up there
and just cut a few strings.
- Not all of them!
- Right, just a few!
Come on, Waddles worth!
- You can do it! Fly!
- No!
Let go of my paw, you twit!
I told you I couldn't fly!
- Honestly!
- Don't worry. I'll go.
Hey, hey, what you doing?
Hey, get off...
Got her.
Oddball.
Oh.
- Oh, Kevin,
I don't know how to thank you.
- Oops.
Uh, how about dinner?
Sorry?
I was inviting you to dinner.
Dinner would be nice.
A coat
to make the world "shuvver."
"Shudder." "Shutter"?
- Shudder?
- Sh...
- Shiver?
- Exactement.
Genius!
Yes, but...
I need...
a special something...
for three special puppies.
Too dressy? Too dressy.
Too stuffy.
Too small. Too blue.
Dottie, I've got nothing to wear.
Please help me.
What's that?
Dottie, are you sure?
It's completely see-through. Look.
Oddball.
Yeah, that's a sweater.
But...
What a fantastic idea!
Thank you!
Thanks, Oddball.
My brilliance astounds me.
No. No.
- We should add
the "poopies" to the hem.
- Oh, you wouldn't dare.
But this is
last year's length!
If Cruella De Vil draws it,
it defies length.
No. No!
No...
What?
Forty dalmatian puppies...
sh-shipped off to Paris...
to h-his shop.
- Not enough.
- We need 102.
This time I want
a hooded spotted puppy coat.
- Hooded spotted p-puppy coat?
- " Hooded spotted poopie coat?"
But 99 puppies
would make a lovely coat.
- It's not all that easy to steal...
- Steal? Who said anything about steal?
What did you think, Le Pelt,
that we'd have time to breed them?
Skinning is one thing...
but stealing...
Oh, stop whining.
I have a perfectly good idiot
to take the fall.
Not you, Alonso. Another idiot.
On, Dasher, on, Dancer,
on, Digger, on, Drooler!
Look at me! I'm Rudolph,
the red-nosed rein-dog
with a present for Miss Oddball.
Hello?
I'll be right out, Kevin.
Take your time.
Oh, right.
Chomp's brought his favorite video.
Is that all right?
- Is it suitable for the children?
- Yes, it's absolutely fine.
Is everything all right?
Yes. Beautiful.
Um, Waddles worth,
he's brought a present for Oddball.
Yeah, about time. This thing
was gettin' heavy. Hang on, pup.
Keep your spots on...
Sorry. You don't have any.
Here you go. There.
Come on, show us.
Mr. Puppeteer and I
came to an agreement.
Oh, Kevin, thank you.
It's brilliant.
Come here, you.
- Well, I think it's a success.
- Looking good, girl!
Looking... Oh, no!
Oddball's got no underwear!
Look away, children!
Turn a blind eye!
Excuse me, young lady.
Is this spot taken?
I can see we're not needed.
As soon as the video's over,
straight to bed for the children.
No more telly.
- Bye.
- Be good.
Anybody wanna order takeout?
So, where was I? Oh, yes.
I started the shelter,
and we were going down for the
third time when Cruella stepped in.
- Her again.
- Yes.
But did you know that
if she ever goes back to dog napping...
that all her millions will go
straight into the dogs' homes
of the borough of Westminster?
Yes, I did. It's in her file.
- Thank you.
- But how did you know that?
- She told me.
And did you know...
that Second Chance is the only
dog shelter in the borough?
You're joking.
Can you imagine what Drooler
would do with £8 million?
Now, tell-a me,
what's-a you pleasure?
A la carte? Dinner?
Aha. Okay. Hey, Joe!
Butch, he says he wants
two spaghetti speciale...
heavy on the meats-a-ball.
Tony, dogs-a don't-a talk!
- He's-a talk-a to me!
- Okay, he's-a talk-a to you.
You the boss.
Mama mia.
Now here you are.
The best-a spaghetti in-a town.
Oh, this is the night
It's a beautiful night
And we call it bella notte
Look at the skies
They have stars in their eyes
On this lovely bella notte
Side by side
With your loved one
You'll find enchantment here
The night will weave
its magic spell
When the one you love is near
For this is the night
And the heavens are right
On this lovely
Bella notte
Shh, shh, shh!
Get in the sack!
Come on. Go. Get in.
Oh, Lassie... Oh.
Oh! It was a dream.
Darn it.
l, uh, had a great time.
So... So did I.
Oh, kiss her, for heaven's sake,
while we're still young.
Look, l, uh...
know you don't believe
in second chances...
but, uh...
do you believe in second dates?
I do, a-actually.
Good.
Great.
Good night.
Well, at least
he's good-looking.
Dogs.
This is the night
- It's a beautiful night
- Bye.
And they call it
Bella notte
Look at the skies
They have stars in their eyes
You know, Dipstick,
he's a lot like you.
Sweet and solid...
funny without meaning to be.
- Hello?
- There are "poopies."
- " Poopies"?
- At Second Chance "poop" shelter.
- What?
- Poor little dalmatian "poopies."
- Dalmatians?
- Oui. Second Chance "poopie" shelter.
Hello? Who is this? Hello?
Hello? Hello?
- " Poopies"?
- Oui! " Poopies"!
- Oh, puppies.
- Oui. Voila.
You will find them by the river
at the foot of the bridge.
We'll pick them up right away,
monsieur. Bye.
Box of abandoned puppies
just around the corner.
Abandoned no more.
Oh, blimey! The coppers!
Forensics is on its way. Over.
Don't panic, Kevin.
Let me handle this.
- Kevin Shepherd?
- Yes, hello, guv.
- I'm Kevin Shepherd.
- Waddles worth!
- Sorry.
- How can I help you, Officer?
A warrant
to search the premises.
You have expensive taste,
sir.
- Don't admit to anything.
- What's all this about?
Sixteen dalmatian puppies
were reported stolen last night.
Sir.
You'll never guess.
Oh, no!
Busted!
Oh, Miss De Vil!
Oh, I suppose I must.
Disgusting creature.
Chloe, that helmet!
I'd rather have my skull crushed.
Cruella De Vil,
you're under arrest.
Kevin Sheperd,
- Kevin!
- Chloe.
Hello, Miss Simon.
Is he one of your charges?
No, he's not the one. She is.
- Why suspect Kevin?
- Caught him red-handed.
And he's got a record
for dog napping.
- Well, I can explain...
- You can explain where
you were last night.
He was home kissing her.
- I was out.
- Out?
- Out.
- I think we've established he was out.
- Right. Let's discuss this
at the station.
- He was out with me.
Found this, sir.
List of addresses.
All the houses
that have had dalmatians stolen.
Chloe, you can't possibly believe...
- Oh, this is crazy! I'm being set up!
- Here's the box of puppies
you asked us to...
- Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
- No.
I sent you in
to pick up those.
- Th-There was a phone call, and, uh...
- Oops.
This is crazy!
Why would I steal dalmatians?
Hmm? What possible motive
could I have to want to put...
The judge's order.
- What?
- Oh, Kevin! How could you?
- All this for money?
- What?
Just like you said
at the restaurant.
Will somebody kindly acquaint me
with the facts?
If I'm caught stealing puppies,
my entire fortune goes to him.
Would that be a motive?
I'm innocent, I tell you!
Innocent!
- Couldn't tear them apart, sir.
- No. Never mind.
Just goes to show
a dog will love anyone.
Inspector Armstrong!
Oh, Inspector, thank you.
You and your men do such a wonderful job
protecting the weak and the innocent.
Oh, thank you very much.
And I must say, Miss De Vil...
you are the most remarkable case
of rehabilitation...
I've known
in all my years on the force.
Thank you so much. Bye-bye.
Good-bye.
Don't be hard on yourself, dear.
We were both fooled.
I'm sorry, Miss De Vil.
I had no idea that Kevin was a...
that-that I let myself trust him.
Oh, this is all so dreadful.
You need distraction, darling.
I'm having a few friends 'round
for dinner tonight with their dogs.
Why don't you and yours join us?
Adults only, of course.
Oh, do come!
Remember, darling:
We have the doggies to live for.
Smashing!
A party!
I was hoping
we would dine alone tonight.
- I can't be seen dining
with a furrier, you fool!
- You fool!
In fact,
you shouldn't even be here at all.
Why do you keep that " job odd" man
about the place?
- Are you jealous, Jean-Pierre?
-Jealous? Of him?
- What can he do for you?
- Steal puppies.
- Like taking the baby from the candy.
- Oh, just like.
Well, now's your chance to impress me.
I've saved the last three for you.
- Me?
- Three very special puppies.
- The owner will be out.
- But, cherie...
Faint heart
never won fair lady, Jean-Pierre.
The keys, my little c-c-cabbage.
Dipstick.
Chloe, darling.
Dipstick,
how kind of you to come.
Oh, not still holding a grudge,
are we?
Dipstick, be polite.
I'm so pleased you're here,
darling.
Come with me.
Now, tell me.
Your little spotted puppy
is all snug and safe at home?
- Yes. They're with Dottie.
- Oh, with Mummy!
- Yes.
- How dear.
It's such a relief
to have the bad man in jail.
If puppies can't be safe
in this world, who can?
Dinner is served. Alonso?
Take our guests of honor
to their places.
I've a special surprise
planned for you, my dear.
Tonight,
our dogs join us at table...
so we can show our appreciation
to a magnificent species.
My past has been riddled
with mistakes.
I pray someday to be forgiven.
- Shh.
- But tonight, I will begin
to set things right.
From tonight,
we'll be closer than ever.
- To the dogs!
" Bone" appetit!
Please eat. Eat.
Dipstick, do you want mine?
For heaven's sake...
Whee! Whee!
- Oh, my... Whoo.
- No!
Everyone eat!
Where's Dipstick?
Dipstick! Dipstick!
Oh. Oh.
Ah-ha.
Bonsoir, my little ones.
I am the great Le Pelt,
and you are...
how do you say... dog meat.
Oh, no. Ooh. Nice, nice doggy.
Dog nice! Nice!
Oh, quiet!
Shh. Nice. Be quiet.
Yes. Be quiet.
Be nice.
"Three puppies," she said. Hmm?
Surprise!
Earlier than I'd planned,
but c'est la vie.
- I hereby revoke your probation.
- And I hereby lock you up.
With St. Kevin of Assisi
in the clink...
it just wouldn't do if three
more puppies were reported missing.
- Three more?
- Good-bye, my dear.
- No!
- I'll think of you every time
I wear your sweet little doggies.
No!
Stop!
Ooh, not bad.
The English
can do the knitwear, huh?
Shh. Be quiet.
Ooh. Ooh. Hey.
What's that? Listen. Hey.
- Listen up. You hear that?
- What? What is it?
Uh, best I can make out,
th-they're all yapping about "tubble."
"Tubble"? Oh, "trouble"!
- Must be puppies talking.
- Listen. Hey, wait. There's more.
Uh, "widdle ones"?
" Bad man gwab widdle ones.
Twee potted doggies."
" Potted"?
"Twee widdle potted..."
" Bad man grabs
three little spotted doggies."
Oh, my gosh. Chloe's dogs.
The puppies!
Thank you, Fluffy!
Go to sleep
Go to sleep, little guardie
Dog, James Dog.
Go back to sleep
Go back to sleep, stupid guardie
Taxi!
- St. John's Mews, please.
- You know I could do five to ten
for this?
That's 35 to 70 in dog years. Ow!
They've gone.
- Where are they?
- Calm down. Calm down.
Oh!
I'm so sorry.
l-l-I should've trusted you.
No. I should never have trusted Cruella.
And with my police record, how could...
- It doesn't matter.
- Yes, it does matter.
Look...
I broke into the lab
and freed those dogs.
They were being used
for experiments.
That was
your dog napping conviction?
Yes.
- That's all?
- Yes.
What's this?
"The Orient Express. "
Paris.
They're going to Paris!
Come on!
Oh, Jean-Pierre,
you've outdone yourself.
I am the Napoleon of the fur,
and you are my...
- Waterloo?
- My Josephine. Together, we...
The rat!
I need spotted puppies,
you idiot!
But it is not a rat.
I know rats. It's a "poopie."
- Alonso!
- Yes?
Find the rat. Kill it. Le Pelt and I
will be on the Orient Express.
- K-K-Kill?
- The last time I underestimated
a puppy, I wound up in the pokey.
- Go!
- Why not him?
Yes, yes. Thank you.
Excuse me. The Orient Express?
Platform nine.
Paris! City of I'amour!
Of la mode! Of Le Pelt!
Le Pelt, with his slippery,
Frenchman ways.
She'll see.
She'll see that I'm the loyal one.
- Alonso.
- Oh, joy. Le petit homme.
You took care of the rat?
You will never see it again.
- This isn't the Orient Express.
- We're on the wrong platform!
There she is!
Come on.
Oddball!
Oh, no! I can't look!
She'll be killed!
Somebody do something! Oh, what
am I doing? Help! Ah! Help! Ha!
- Your wings! Flap your wings!
- Flap wings?
Oh, where did these come from?
Blimey, they work! I can fly!
Dogs can fly!
Whee-yah! I just realized
I'm not a rottweiler at all.
I'm a retriever.
- Where are we going?
- Paris.
- We've missed the train!
- Then we'll catch the next one!
Do you think he saw us?
W-W-We'd better hide. But where?
What? " Bad wady's cow"?
Oh! Good idea, spotty.
Paris!
Careful.
Mustn't harm the "poopies."
The p... The p-poopie man
gets to ride in the c-car.
- Is Alonso keeping up?
- The little man is too slow.
This traffic is too slow.
The French are useless behind the wheel.
- You're going the wrong way!
- They're going the wrong way!
We're going to die! Whoo!
Shut up, Jean-Pierre!
Jean-Pierre, our next challenge:
reinventing the poodle skirt.
- Nothing. Nobody saw anything.
- Oh.
I didn't know you spoke French.
Come on! Come on!
Taxi! Stop!
So, what did they say?
Follow les chiens!
It's spooky, all right, but you'd
have to be a sniveling, whimpering...
cowardly little chihuahua
not to barge right in there...
and take charge of the situation
with no hesitation at all.
After you, then.
Oh, I'm gonna regret this.
What do you look at?
Work! Work!
- Illegal immigrants?
- Of course.
Hmm.
How much?
- Fifty francs a week.
- Ooh. That's not much.
It's all they can afford.
I sure hope you know
where you're going, pup.
Bingo.
Right. Don't worry, Oddball.
I'll have 'em out in a jiffy.
Hmm. Tastes like chicken.
Ooh.
It's no good
looking at me like that.
It won't do any good, you know.
Sorry.
Okay.
We'll wait.
- Did you hear something?
- It's just your little man outside.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Hey, I thought I told you
to wait outside? Hey.
I know, but they were worried.
- Oh.
- You okay?
Hello!
- Hi!
- You all right?
Okay. Let's get them out of here.
Come on.
Well, Miss Houdini.
Aren't you in a tight spot?
Ooh, what fun,
to get away with murder. Ta-ta!
I'm really beginning
to dislike that woman.
There's got to be a way
out of here.
- Hello, nice bird.
- Shh.
- Waddles worth! Is Oddball with you?
You bet she's here.
She's commando leader.
- Now, pass up the pups, quick.
- Okay.
One. Have a seat.
Two. Good, good.
Join the other one.
- Come on. Hurry up! Hurry up!
- Yes.
One hundred.
In a bunch. Come on. In a bunch.
One hundred and... Are you one hundred
or one hundred and one? Oh, great.
- Now we have to start all over again.
- That's it.
Bring me the puppies!
Come on!
- This is my favorite part.
- The skinning? Not the strangling?
Ah, I like the strangling also.
The mark of a great furrier, Alonso,
is that he does his own strangling.
- Remember that.
- Thank you.
Shh.
It's the little rat!
- You lied to me.
- M-M-Me? Why should l...
Does she look dead to you?
Does she?
You worm!
I'll kill her myself.
You are a wormy little man.
Oh!
Whoa!
You're both idiots!
Excuse me!
Work!
Now I crush you, little man.
Who's the little man now?
I'll wear you on my sleeve.
Here, puppy, puppy, puppy.
Sweet puppy.
- Quickly. To the bakery.
- But can we trust him?
Now is not the time to
count your change, Kevin. Come on.
She's after the puppies!
I've got you now, you little rat!
Ohh.
Without spots,
you're just not worth the trouble.
Chop, chop!
And now to my coat!
Domino! Little Dipper!
- Oddball!
- Oddball?
Where are you?
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
And now for the topper:
You may now kick the bride.
I'm ruined!
This is the fall of Maison Le Pelt.
How do we get out from this mess?
- Piece of cake.
- That is the lady.
Look out, everybody!
It's the bad lady's cow.
Oh, no.
Hello, all. I've come
from Miss De Vil's solicitor...
Mr. Torte.
I asked if I might have the pleasure
of delivering this.
- Eight million pounds?
- Yes!
- It's the judge's orders.
- Eight million... Eight million quid?
- Eight million pounds!
- Eight million quid.
- It's for the dogs, of course.
- That's eight million.
- Of course.
- That's eight million!
- And for the best, unless...
unless she's rehabilitated.
No, Alonso.
Cruella will always be Cruella.
Well, hope springs eternal.
What's that puppy doing up there?
- No! Oddball!
- Oddball!
- Oh, Oddball!
- What have you been up to now? Oh.
- What have you been doing?
- Come here. Come here.
Hey. Hey.
Ohh. Look.
Kevin, look.
These won't come off.
She's got her spots.
Oddball's got her spots! Look!
S-P-O-T-S!
Digga-digga-dog
- Digga-digga-dog, Digga-digga-dog
- Bow-wow-wow
- Digga-digga-dog
Digga-digga-dog, dog, dog
- You dog, you!
Bow-wow-wow
yippee-yo, yippee-yay
Can you keep that excitation
down to a roar
Atomic dog
When fate comes a-knockin'
Better open the door
Atomic dog
Rise to the occasion
Yeah, answer the call
Hey
If they're pitchin'
second chances
Don't you fumble the ball
- No, no, no
- You dog, you!
- Digga-digga-dog, Digga-digga-dog
- Don't be believin'
- Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
- Don't be believin'
- Digga-digga-dog
- Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
Bow-wow-wow
Yippee-yo, yippee-yay
Sometimes you gotta dream
with eyes wide open
- Atomic dog
- Yeah, you do
You can't earn your spots
just wishin' and hopin'
- Atomic dog
- No, you can't
Goin' out on a limb
for a cause
The heart must be brave
Yeah
And a miracle's a gift
Of keeping the faith
- Gotta keep the faith
- You dog, you!
- Don't be believin'
- Digga-digga-bow-wow-wow
- Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
- Don't be believin'
- Digga-digga-bow-wow-wow
- Looks are deceivin'
- You dog, you!
Bow-wow-wow
Bow, bow
Spotted dog, spotted dog
Where have you been
I've been to London
to look at the queen
Can you tell a spotted story
Yes, I can
I saw a dog
who was walkin' a man
Oww, you dog, you!
What you gonna do
And I think I deserve
a second chance too.
- Don't you?
- What you gonna do
You let me think
that I knew you
I was right
I only saw
what you wanted me to
You caught me
in your web of lies
Now you tell me
that it's gonna be different
And just how much
you've changed
What you gonna do
with your second chance
What I wouldn't give
to read your mind
What you gonna do
with your second chance
Will you throw it away
Or get it right this time
I'm warnin' you
I'm watchin' you
What you gonna do, What you gonna do
I'm warnin' you, I'm watchin you
What you gonna do
- It's so easy to say it
- Say it
For a while
you can put on a show
If what you're saying
is more than words
Time will tell me so
Now I'm willing
to let you show me
You've turned it all around
What you gonna do
with your second chance
What I wouldn't give
to read your mind
What you gonna do
with your second chance
Will you throw it away
Or get it right this time
I'm warnin' you, I'm watchin you
What you gonna do
- l, l, I want to believe
- I want to believe
You're shooting straight
with me
- Tell me what's it gonna be
Baby, baby, yeah
Oh, no
And I think
I deserve a second chance too.
Don't you?
Okay.
Here's your second chance.
What you gonna do
with your second chance
What I wouldn't give
to read your mind
What you gonna do
with your second chance
Will you throw it away
or get it right
What you gonna do
with your second chance
What I wouldn't give
to read your mind
What you gonna do
with your second chance
Will you throw it away
Or get it right this time