- Hi.
How many?
Two.
Listen, I wanted to get a safe deposit box.
Can you do that for me?
Okay.
Your box will be available
any time from an
hour after opening
to 30 minutes before close.
This is your key.
Thank you.
Oh, um, also, if you open
a checking account,
we'll give you 5% off the box along
with free overdraft protection.
Oh, here I was hopin'
for a free toaster.
Why would a bank
give out free toasters?
Hello, Ma.
I'm ordering you
the French toast.
Our very patient waitress,
Maggie,
well, at least it says
Maggie on her name tag,
has asked me to order four times.
If I don't order at this point,
it's just rude.
I can come back.
No, it's okay.
You know what? I'm making
an executive decision.
No pancakes. I don't like pancakes.
No pancakes.
I'm thinkin' hash, but only if it's
like chunky style, okay?
Listen, if you order me eggs and pancakes,
I'm gonna kick your behind.
But you gotta eat breakfast.
It's the most important meal of the day.
Uh, ma'am, ignore everything
he said, okay?
Don't bring me any
eggs and pancakes.
Just bring me some coffee
and bring him a couple eggs.
I don't want eggs.
I want hash.
You know what,
put a couple eggs on it.
Give him some rye toast, too.
No rye toast for me.
I don't like rye toast.
Maybe a little silver-dollar one.
You got the little baby ones?
No pancakes, no silver dollars,
no rye toast. I like pumpernickel.
I do have pumpernickel.
Pumpernickel toast.
Hey, Maggie, wait. One more thing.
Yeah.
That's for you. You take that with you
till we see each other again
in case you miss me
too much, okay?
Why you gotta do that?
What?
Wink at the waitresses like that?
Waitresses like me.
Nobody likes you.
So?
So.
What do ya got?
So, it is a sleepy bank.
Doable?
That's correct.
I told you.
That is a lot of doughnuts.
Maggie, your hot homemade doughnuts,
they any good?
Best in three counties.
I'll tell you what you do.
You bring us three
of those bad boys.
Put 'em in a to-go box
for us, all right?
All right.
Thank you.
All right, time to make the move.
All right, there's gonna be
some sirens in this bitch.
I'm gonna go
shake the weasel.
Shake the weasel.
Gonna go shake the weasel.
Hey. Good morning, sir.
How are you? Morning.
Hey, Maggie.
I'm very sorry
about my friend.
He was kicked in
the head as a child.
He's really not that bad.
No, he is.
What's goin' on?
Okay, I'm just gonna have you all
exit the building.
It might be a false alarm,
but just do it safely.
Thank you.
Is everybody out?
I'm gonna need you to step outside.
All right, Maggie,
I'm just gonna grab my friend.
Okay.
We gotta pay our bill.
We should go.
Is that all you're
gonna leave for a tip?
It's 15%.
You leave 15%.
No, you gotta
leave at least 30.
No, you don't.
15% is standard.
My Maggie's about to be out
of a job, man. Don't be cheap.
Okay, there's five.
That's seven.
There you go.
Come on.
All right.
What?
No, you didn't.
Yes, I did.
Oh, my God.
How'd you say it?
Never rob a bank
across from the diner
with the best doughnuts
in three counties?
That's correct.
Bobby. Papi's down
in the stables.
Why don't you get
somethin' to eat?
I'm not hungry.
Sure you are.
I wanna come with you.
Hey, listen. We're here to do business.
Diplomatically.
Well, I can be diplomatic.
You can be hungry,
too, right?
Bobby.
Wait here.
Okay.
Somebody sittin' here?
Toro.
Oh, well, you move your feet,
you lose your seat, right?
Lose your head, too.
That's correct.
So, where is Little Toro?
Allí, where you put him.
Aqui?
Allí.
Let's play some dominoes.
Papi's ready.
Yeah.
Papi Greco!
"I-know-a-guy" Bobby.
Quick, an ostrich, a tank of ether,
a '63 Impala convertible.
Make it a '64.
My side of the border.
I know a guy.
What did I tell you?
He never says no, never says maybe,
never says, "I'll see
what I can do. "
Nice bull.
I hope he's a good breeder.
That's a shame
about Little Toro.
Julio caught him skimming.
Oh.
That don't sound like Little Toro.
Is that for me?
That's correct.
Everybody skims a little cream.
It's human nature.
Just 'cause it's human
don't mean you let it go.
Hmm.
Nice lines. Good color.
That's right.
He knows a guy.
What you got for me?
Cash.
Cash?
Supposed to be givin' me
100,000 to deal.
Why didn't you give me $100,000
worth of cocaine?
Where's the cocaine?
My buyer wants cocaine.
So let him buy cocaine.
That's what he's tryin' to do.
He's trying to buy cocaine.
I told him I knew a guy,
therefore I come to you.
You the guy I know.
That's why I told him.
So take back the passports.
After Little Toro, we're not takin' on
any new customers.
Well, no disrespect,
but I ain't no new customer.
You been dealin' with me
for a long time.
You keep the passports.
Keep the money, too.
When you're ready to give me the product,
give me the product.
Till then...
You owe me.
It's not very sporting, man.
At least give the chickens
a chance to shoot back.
Hey, man, I'm just sayin'.
If I'm gonna kill a defenseless animal,
I'm gonna honor its sacrifice by
grilling it into some tasty barbecue.
What I'm not gonna do
is torture it
just to prove I can't hit anything
further away than my own pecker.
Your cuate's a real junkyard dog.
Mmm.
Hey, cowboy.
You, the pretty one.
You ever hear the expression,
"You got a face only a mother can love"?
That don't apply to you. You are
uglier than the devil's asshole itself.
Stig!
What are you doin'?
They're torturing chickens, man.
What are you eatin'?
A chicken.
Come here. It's not
the same thing, okay?
See that bag over
there by the table?
Buffet table next
to the potato salad.
Yeah, the bowling bag.
What about it?
Little Toro's head
is in that bag.
Bullshit.
Yeah.
You know what?
That's fucked up, man.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let's go. Okay? Come on, let's go.
Say it in English, you goat fuck.
That's funny comin'
from you, fat boy.
You ain't seen your pecker
since you were a baby.
and brown shit comes out don't mean
it's your asshole.
What did you say?
Don't worry about it, man.
Now dig 'em up and make some
damn barbecue.
Bye, chica.
Did you just wink at him?
- I did wink at him, 'cause he's
my bitch now. - Uh-oh!
That's good shootin'.
Gracias.
You know, Little Toro never did
nothin' to nobody, man.
We should rip off Papi's stash at
the Tres Cruces Savings and Loan.
You know, Papi's guy
delivers a briefcase
full of money to Tres Cruces
every two weeks.
That's gotta add up to, what,
like three million at least.
If Papi knew we were even talkin'
about rippin' off Tres Cruces,
it would be our heads in that bag
next to the potato salad.
No way. Our two heads would
never fit in a bag that small.
Come on, man,
let's hit the bank.
Little Toro was your friend.
He was my friend.
So?
What do you mean "so"?
What if it was me? What if it was my head
Papi ran through the saw mill?
You wouldn't come after him?
Nope.
Shit, man, he did that to you, I'd kill him.
You know why I'd kill him?
Because you're my people
and there's a code.
There is no code, first of all.
You do whatever you gotta do,
whatever it takes.
And second?
Right, we're not people
'cause you don't have people.
That's correct.
Purpose for your
visit to Mexico?
My aunt in Tuba City had a heart
attack so we cut our trip short.
Tuba City?
It's near Odessa.
Nice place?
Hellhole,
but she's my favorite aunt.
Don't move. Let me see your hands.
Oh, shit.
Tell us about your trip.
Lawyer.
What's the big deal?
You were down in Sonora,
weren't you?
You don't think Agent Jessup and the DEA
know about you and Papi Greco?
Lawyer. Lawyer.
They know you were
at his ranch.
I know I need a lawyer.
Tell Agent Rees
about Papi Greco.
Who?
Papi Greco.
Well, who's that? Some Mexican Santa
Claus or something?
Come on, Mr. Stigman.
I think it's in your best interest
to cooperate.
You need to stop playin'
the stupid card, all right?
Well, ma'am, it's my intent to cooperate
with whatever you need.
I mean, as an American,
I know you're just doin' your job,
and sometimes innocent folks like me
get caught up in the system.
It's like the airlines. They don't
lose your luggage on purpose, right?
But everybody takes it
so damn personal.
Come on, Mr. Stigman.
So you wanna play games?
Well, what'd you
have in mind?
Do you wanna help yourself?
Yes.
Do I have to do it
in front of him?
All right, we're done here.
Thank you, Mr. Stigman.
You gonna leave?
Oh, yes.
Wow.
Oh, my God.
How do you concentrate
workin' with her, man?
Five border agents are rippin' apart
your car as we speak.
They ain't gonna
find anything.
Where'd you hide
the cocaine?
Can they hear us?
No.
Can they see us?
Okay.
There was no cocaine.
You had a deal in place.
Right.
Five hundred passports
in return for cocaine.
Right.
Hey, Bobby.
Good. Man, your boy Stig's
a piece of work.
He winked at you,
didn't he?
How'd you know?
Bobby didn't
get the cocaine.
What?
What happened?
Papi offered me cash.
I told him no.
I told him
to keep the passports,
so, eventually, he's gotta come up
with the cocaine.
What about this guy you said
you could flip? Little Toro?
I got him.
It's real close.
I don't know
who you are anymore.
It's like...
It's like you're
out on this limb.
And you've been out
there way too long.
And you're sayin'
that to say what?
I don't like goin' to the funerals
of my own men.
Well, then don't come,
boss. Don't come.
Okay?
I spent the last
three years of my life
tryin' to work my way
up the line to get next to Papi Greco.
You can't take me
off this now.
Jessup, he's close.
You can't take me off this now.
I know.
Not now.
Two weeks.
You don't flip Little Toro by then,
I'm pullin' ya out.
We're done.
Think Jessup
knows about us?
What "us"?
You don't do "us," remember?
Oh, I remember.
Besides, I'm dating.
Oh, right, right.
You're dating...
Mmm-hmm.
...your imaginary
boyfriend, Harvey.
Uh, he's not my boyfriend,
and his name's not Harvey.
I like Harvey.
It has a nice ring to it. Harvey.
You don't get to be jealous
anymore, Bobby.
Harvey.
You pushed me away.
So you could
be with Harvey.
Fuck you.
You told Jessup you were close
to flipping him.
I was.
But when I got
down to the ranch,
Papi's boys was throwin' his head
around in a bag.
Well, that's game, then.
With Little Toro off the board,
Jessup's pulling you out.
Not if you
don't tell him.
I'm your control, Bobby.
That's correct.
I have to tell him.
That's why I need you
to let me rob
Tres Cruces Savings and Loan.
No, Stig wants to rob
the bank. It's his idea.
So there's no entrapment.
What I want
is access to that money
that Papi's got
in the safe deposit box.
You know no judge
is gonna give you
a blanket warrant
for the boxes.
We don't need a warrant.
Not if the money's evidence in a crime.
We just trace it
back to ownership,
we got Papi on tax evasion,
possible RICO.
Yeah?
Yeah.
And what about Stig?
What about him?
He's a side dish.
he does a smooth 20 years
in the penitentiary, you get a medal.
The bank gets us Papi.
And that's all
that matters, right?
It takes whatever
it takes, baby.
Did you ever
really love me?
Hmm?
I really meant
to love you.
Shit.
You don't have to knock.
It's always open.
Yeah, good.
Let's hit the bank.
The Tres Cruces?
That's correct.
Oh, shit.
Here I am still spinnin' about how we
got yanked outta line at the border.
So you in or you out?
I'm in, yeah.
It's just...
Have you ever had anything like that
happen to you before?
I mean, they were 100% convinced
we were holding.
And we would've if Papi hadn't
welched on that coke.
So you're sayin'
that to say what?
I'm sayin' it's only 'cause
you're hearin' it.
No, you sayin' somethin'.
And if you sayin' it,
I'm hearin' it 'cause you're sayin' it.
What are you sayin'?
Let it be said.
I think you're
fuckin' playin' me.
You wanna be played?
I've been at your
hip for 10 months,
but after this,
I think maybe you're playin' me.
I got you.
No, you didn't.
Oh, I did. The corner
of your eye was twitchin'.
The corner?
That wasn't a twitch.
That was a wink.
That's my move.
Yup, that's Papi's chubby
little kid right there.
Feed that motherfucker
quesadillas...
Oh, my God.
She's chubby, too.
How does an old, fat, ugly
fuck get a girl like that?
Money.
All right,
here we go.
Same thing
every two weeks.
Papi flies over the border
with a briefcase full of cash.
He spends a week
with the mistress.
Ferret Nose Julio
drives it out
to the Tres Cruces
Savings and Loan.
Think they got three
million in the bank, huh?
Easy.
Bingo.
Money, money,
money, money.
Oh, yeah.
Why don't you hit the diner
and check out the doughnuts?
I'm kinda more in a corned beef
hash mood, to tell you the truth.
You never heard
the saying,
"Never rob a bank
across from a diner
"that has the best
doughnuts in three counties"?
That's not a saying.
Yes, it is.
I get what you're sayin', but it's
not a saying. You never heard it?
It is a saying.
It's a saying now.
Okay. Let you tell it.
Make the move.
Bad DEA agent.
Am I bad?
Yes, you are.
I'm a bad girl?
Stig decided to hit
the bank tomorrow, 3:00.
Stig decided?
Well, with or without me, he's goin' in.
Well, I still haven't
talked to Jessup.
Stig doesn't know that.
3:00 tomorrow he's goin' in.
If we want Papi,
I gotta go in with him.
You're not even gonna
give me a choice, are you?
I'm givin' you no other
options as a way to protect you.
Just have the troops meet me outside
the bank, 3:05 when we come out.
3:05.
Okay. And don't shoot me.
Even if you want to.
We'll see.
License and registration, cowboy.
Cute.
What's up, Teemo?
What's up, brother?
How are you, brother? I miss
you, man. I miss you, man.
Got you a turkey burger.
Special sauce.
Commander wants
to see you.
Yes, sir.
So, half a mile from home.
I got Bobby all wound
up and ready to go, sir.
Ordnance you requested.
Do you know, the Admiral's
proud of what you've done.
You've gone way
out on a limb.
If the bank falls
right tomorrow,
he says you can come in from
the cold, rejoin your brothers.
Great. Be good just to put
the uniform back on, sir.
I didn't join the Navy to commit
felonies and hang with drug dealers.
Even if you're
damn good at it?
I do what I do
for the Navy, sir.
It's all part of
the Admiral's plan.
we run cross-border ops on
Papi and all the other cartels.
So tomorrow,
clean and precise.
Tick all the boxes, nothing
left undone. You got it?
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Hey, nice jacket.
Hey, tell your mother
she's gotta move out
of my house
at some point, man.
All right, what do you
want, clown or Frankie?
Frankie.
So, what'd you do
with the. 22?
Traded to my cousin
for an espresso machine.
You're gonna need special
beans for that, right?
You can reach for your
firearm, but do it real slow.
Any other people
in the buildin'?
What the hell is this?
It's a bank robbery.
Only instead
of robbin' the bank
and lettin' you
chase after us,
we decided to come
after you first.
Let's go.
All right, everybody sit down.
Everybody sit down on the floor.
Ladies behind the counter, keep your
hands visible, not on the alarms.
It's all right, girls. Just
give 'em the drawer cash.
Did we ask
for the drawer cash?
Come on, come on, come on.
Sit right here. Sit, sit.
Let's go, on the floor.
Hey, guard!
Hey! Hey.
Look, I'm tryin' to
be polite, all right?
Just sit tight and
this'll be over soon.
Open the gate.
I don't have a key.
What'd you say?
You lie to me again, it's gonna
be more than a fuckin' problem.
Get out there, now.
Get on the floor.
You good? I'm goin' in.
Shh.
It's all right.
Oh, Timothy.
Hey, it's okay.
It's okay. Yeah?
Okay. Here you go.
Showtime!
Fire in the hole!
Holy shit!
Hey, Frankie,
somethin's not right.
They're all
stuffed with money.
I thought you said there
would only be one or two.
Every single one of them.
I'm at 32 boxes
and counting.
Look, there's way
more than 3 million.
And there's still
a lot more here.
All right, well, take 'em
all. We'll figure it out later.
You go ahead,
I'll get the rest.
All right.
Listen.
May be gunfire outside,
okay? So if it hits,
you get everybody
behind the counters.
This is for the jail
across the street.
You let the cops out.
Let 'em out.
Come on.
That is a hell of a lot
more than $3 million.
We couldn't be the luckiest chumps
on the face of the earth, could we?
You feel lucky?
No, I don't.
I mean, this can't
be Papi's money.
People are gonna chase us off the
end of the earth for money like this.
Well, I hate to tell you this,
Stig, but I got more bad news...
You take that hand away
nice and slow, Bobby.
Okay.
Put the gun down, Stig.
You know I really
like you, right?
I like you, too.
No, you don't.
Yes, I do.
Nobody likes me, okay?
And I'm okay with it.
I do. I like you
more than most.
You're not just sayin' it 'cause
I got a gun pointed to you?
Why don't you just
put the gun down?
Shit.
Oh.
Hot-doggin'!
I'm sorry, man.
What'd you
do that for?
Shit, man, I had to!
No, you didn't.
It's just a little flesh
wound. You'll be all right.
Drink the water,
and then you'll be able...
What is that?
In your hand. Is that
a badge in your hand?
Tell me you're not a no-good,
two-timin' son of a bitch.
Two-timin'?
Tell me.
You shot me.
DEA.
Hey, wait a minute. Wait
a minute, man. Hang on.
No, you wait a minute.
Stig.
Hey.
The United States is the
greatest country in the world
because we accept
a man is, at his core,
greedy,
selfish
and covetous.
I had no choice.
They took my key.
I would never willingly
open the vault.
Keep your hands
on the desk, please.
In America,
we line everybody up.
Say, "You're on your own.
"Grab all you can grab. "
I'm innocent.
Nobody's innocent, friend.
There's just the guilty,
the ignorant
and the unlucky.
Did you take our money?
You fellas look like
you're waitin' for a bus.
You guys let us know
when you're done.
Oh, I'm done, and thank
you for the courtesy.
Who is that guy?
You heard of
the hidden hand of God?
Well, that's God's
son of a bitch.
Call the DDO and get a list of everyone
who knew we had money in this bank.
You two realize those sunglasses
make you look like assholes.
Excuse me,
when'd that diner burn?
Yesterday.
I want interviews
with the wait staff
and every customer
in the place.
It was just
a grease fire.
Did I ask your
opinion, Gomer?
You ever hear
the saying,
"Never rob a bank
across from a diner
"with the best doughnuts
in three counties"?
If that diner fire's
a coincidence,
it's only 'cause we
ain't looking hard enough.
That is an impressive
amount of greenbacks.
43,125,000 of 'em, sir.
Recount it. Pack it up.
We'll stow it back in Corpus.
It was my impression we were
supposed to come out of that bank
with 3 million
at most, sir.
Mmm-hmm.
Whose money was it?
Bad men unworthy of it.
Did you know
Bobby Beans was DEA?
No offense, sir, but you really
need to work on your surprised face.
Well, if he was DEA,
he helped you rob a bank.
Which means he's dirty, and
for that, I have no mercy.
Where'd you leave him?
In the desert.
Is he dead?
More than likely.
"More than likely. "
You wanna tell me
what that means?
The whole point of you
working with Bobby Beans
was to kill him off
and create a cut-out
so the op couldn't
get traced back to us.
My cover's solid. There's
no way it'll trace back.
My cover is solid. There's
no way it'll trace back, sir.
That's a call made
above your pay grade.
Yes, sir.
Assign two of the boys to stow
the money back at the naval base.
The rest'll come with us to
check on the body of Mr. Beans.
Stigman,
wanna come with me?
Hey there, buddy.
Hey.
You habla?
Yeah, yeah.
I hablo.
Good, that's good.
Don't trust in him
till you see his paper.
If he's got papers, I'll see his
papers. You got papers, right?
No. No,
I got no papers.
Well, that's gonna
be a problem.
See, Slim Jay and me,
we done assigned ourselves
protection this here
stretch of the border.
Officially unofficially.
So we really gonna
have to see your papers.
Make sure you ain't
no Muslim or nothin'.
Oh, yeah.
No, I do have it.
And let me
have your gun.
Give it to me.
Gracias.
You know how to pray?
Teemo.
How we doin', boys?
Any sign of Bobby Beans?
Checked all the washes
to the southeast.
No sign of a body.
All right.
Well, Stig, you put
us in quite a hole.
I don't see it that way, sir, but
you're the man with the oak leaves.
All that pride
I had in you.
That loyalty?
You just tossed it
to the wind.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
God damn it.
He's in the wash!
Go, go, go!
Come on,
let's flush him out!
Where you going,
Stigman?
It doesn't matter
if you run.
Your jacket's wired, so you're
six-months AWOL after stabbing an MP.
You talk to anyone,
they're just gonna
hand you right
back over to me.
You all right?
Yeah.
Then get your ass up!
Toss the gun.
Fuck!
Move!
Come on, come on!
Damn it!
Jesus! What am I
supposed to do with this?
Aw, man. Aw!
Come on.
I'm a vet,
not a trauma surgeon.
I can't help you with
this, man. You gotta go.
Go where?
You gotta leave.
I can't do anything.
Kenny, you remember
a couple of months ago
you offered to sell me
500 hits of ketamine?
Yeah, you said you
weren't interested.
Right.
'Cause I'm a DEA agent.
And if you don't
fix me up,
I'm gonna go to the D.A.,
I'm gonna tell them that you
like cruising Tori Amos concerts,
selling Special K to
little weepy college girls.
There's no way
you're a cop.
No?
No.
You sure?
I'm positive.
You have the right
to remain silent.
You have the right to have a
lawyer present during questioning.
Do I need to keep going?
No, I'm good.
You're a cop.
Okay.
Nice shirt.
Thanks. It's JCPenney's.
Yeah?
Yeah.
All right,
hold on one second.
Welcome to the Camino Real.
Thank you.
Hey.
You were late.
Jesus Christ.
What the hell happened?
Excuse us.
Excuse me.
I robbed a bank.
What happened to you?
I was there with
six agents at 3:05.
No, you weren't.
Yes, I was.
You were late.
You went early.
pulled your badge at
any time and stopped it.
I did. Stig shot me.
What?
He shot me
in the shoulder.
And interrupt your rendezvous
with Harvey? I don't think so.
This is what
we need to do,
we need to find Stig,
we need to find the money.
All right. Listen.
Let me go upstairs,
make my excuses,
and then we'll find
Stig together, okay?
Okay, let's do this.
Let's do this.
Why don't you recheck
Stig's background?
Maybe there was something
that we missed. All right?
I'm going to Stig's apartment
and see what I can find out.
All right?
Okay.
Tell Harvey I said hi.
Who'd you patch up?
What are you
talking about?
What am I
talkin' about?
Well, there's a dune
buggy parked out back
that was stolen by a man
with a bullet hole in him.
Now, before he had
a bullet hole in him,
he burned down a diner
and robbed a bank.
I don't know anything
about that, so...
Okay.
Okay?
Fair enough.
Say, let me
ask you somethin'.
You ever play
Russian roulette?
'Course not.
What am I thinkin'?
The thing is,
most people,
they put the gun
to the temple.
And that's, well,
that's just stupid.
What if...
The bullet's in
the first chamber?
You blow a man's head off
'fore he's had a chance
to tell you
what you want to know.
No. No, no.
Come on, man.
Case in point.
Stig!
Stig.
Pick up, Bobby.
What the fuck are you
doing here, Bobby?
What're you
duckin' for, man?
You know
I set you up, right?
They told me
all about you.
Tough cat. Knows everybody.
Doesn't have people.
That guy? Well, shit, that
guy's a perfect cut-out.
I mean, he takes a bullet,
who's gonna care, right?
Pick up the phone.
Pick up the damn
phone, Bobby.
You got anything to say?
First question,
if you're DEA and you're
clean, why are you here alone?
Where's your backup, Bobby?
Come on, it's this
kind of attitude
makes me think you're
not one of the good guys.
before you walked into
that building, Bobby.
That's a beautiful
rifle, Stig.
Is that Army issue?
You like that? No, it's
Kmart. Blue Light Special.
Now answer my question.
Where's your backup?
No, no,
that's a military rifle.
What's the military dog
robbing banks, Stig?
Can we just have a straight-up
conversation, Bobby?
I got you dead to rights.
Yeah? So shoot me.
Again.
No?
I'll shoot myself.
Huh. Not bad.
I'm glad you're impressed.
Were you testing me to
see if I would shoot first?
If I thought you were clean, I might
tell you, but I don't, so I can't.
You're lying. You don't have
it, do you? Where's the money?
Oh, shit.
What?
You're not the only
one I was expecting.
Three very nasty men
just showed up.
If they find you in my
place, they will get ugly.
Who are they?
Yesterday I'd have said
they were my family.
Today they kinda
wanna kill me.
I understand the feeling.
You know, fuck you.
What do you know about family?
You don't even have people.
No, Bobby,
that's a stupid idea.
They're already
comin' up the stairs.
Bobby!
hang up the speaker and
answer your cell phone, okay?
If you want me
to help you out...
Yeah.
I'm gonna guide
you out from there.
Wait.
He's comin' up your rear. You
better dart across the hall.
Go over to the bedroom
and hide behind the lockers.
Go.
All right, Bobby, you're gonna
wanna scoot across the hall. Go.
Bobby, Bob...
Shit.
Teemo!
Rooftop!
Target's on the move!
Sorry, Teemo.
Where's our money?
I have no idea what
you're talkin' about.
You think DEA can just
waltz into our bank,
steal our money,
and we're not gonna kick?
Your man Bobby Trench stole
43 million of our dollars.
We'd like it back.
Because it's our money.
Because it's a blatant
act of disrespect.
And because
it's our money.
Please tell me
it's you, Bobby.
Anything new on Stig?
He's comin' up clean on every
database I'm cleared for.
No military connection?
No record of service?
To go deeper, I'd need to
get clearance from Jessup.
Well, try your old
contacts in the military.
I'm gonna tell Jessup
everything I know.
Someone has to know whose
money was in the bank.
Yeah. Stig.
Stig didn't even
know I was DEA.
Besides, somebody
tried to kill him, too.
Bobby, let me help you.
What do you need?
Take it easy. Bye.
Bobby.
Fuck!
That's how you take down
a man. Now shut the door.
Just let it come.
Agent Robert
Lynn Trench.
A.k. a. Bobby T, a. k. a.
Bobby B, a. k. a. Bobby Beans.
Let's have a chat.
You stole $43.125 million
that did not belong to you.
Now, man-to-man,
who at DEA authorized
you to rob our bank?
You a banker?
You ever play
Russian roulette?
Thing is,
most people put the gun
to the temple.
Well, that's just stupid.
You blow a man's head off
'fore he's had a chance
to tell you
what you wanna know.
Mess up your suit, too.
Who told you it was all
right to take our money?
"Our money. Our bank. "
Who are ya?
If you don't
know who I am,
how did you know to
steal our 43 million?
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
You don't?
No.
Well...
Where's the money?
Oh, boy.
Well, uh...
It ain't down there,
I can guarantee you that.
Whoo-hoo.
A.k. a. Bobby Balls.
Clean and shaven.
You know what you are?
You
are a dirty DEA agent.
That's right.
You're a dirty DEA agent
who robbed a bank.
And shot your boss.
You walk into
any federal office,
and that's the story
they're gonna have.
Unless you bring me
$43.125 million,
and you walk away.
Clean.
Have I properly
incentivized you?
More than you know.
Unless you wanna rot in
jail, you best get after it.
Go on, now. Go on.
All right.
You're thinkin'
he deserved better?
You're right.
Hey, Rudy.
Hola, Javier.
Morning, Papi.
Don't move.
Go inside, quick.
Mommy!
Whose money
did we steal?
You really wanna know?
I really wanna know.
Easy, old man, get in
there. Get in there.
Payback's a bitch!
Uh, uh, uh.
Whoa, Bobby.
Drop the gun. Give me the keys.
Give me the keys.
Nice and easy.
I can't do that.
Why not? Well, I got
him first. I got dibs.
I got a. 44. I'm taking
Papi. Give me the keys.
You want 'em?
Come get 'em.
You're thinkin' a little
blindfold, maybe use your teeth.
That's not what I'm thinkin'.
You know what I'm thinkin'?
Oh, shit, man.
How's that?
That was uncalled for.
Shit. I liked you better when
you were "I-know-a-guy" Bobby.
That Bobby was a good guy.
Well, I liked you better when
you were winkin' at waitresses
and shootin' the heads off of chickens.
Give me the keys.
Shit!
What's going on?
You saw that move comin'?
That's correct. Give me the keys.
Damn, you're good.
Now, one of us is gonna
have to pick up those keys.
Guess. All right. I'll
get 'em, all right?
Get 'em, get 'em. Put
that musket away, man.
Hey, pull over!
Pull over?
Hey, Papi,
you like my drivin'?
Oh, shit!
Come on, Bobby,
I ain't got all damn day!
What do you wanna do?
Ow!
All right. All right, all
right. All right, let me go.
You let me go first.
No, you let me go.
On three.
One. Two. Three.
See? Now you're making me
not be able to trust you.
On the count of three,
we'll let each other go.
All right?
All right. That's fair.
One. Two.
Three.
I knew it.
Let me go.
No! I'm gonna let you
go. I'm gonna let you go.
All right.
One...
Ow!
Come on, man. You gotta admit,
that was kind of fun, no?
You didn't like that?
Who are you?
Shit.
U.S. Navy Intel.
Yeah?
Or I was.
My commander
FUBARed my jacket.
And now I'm AWOL
after stabbing an MP.
You're lucky. They got me
framed for killing my boss.
Did your boss order your four
closest friends to kill you?
No, you got me there.
DEA Officer Bobby Trench, but
I guess you know that already.
Pleasure.
So, what, you just happened to pick me,
or you got orders to
set me up on purpose?
I had orders, man. I
didn't know you were DEA.
My people did.
But they're Intel.
There's not much
they don't know.
Your people?
so I can take it over my
commander's head to the Admiral.
That's why they wanna kill me
and why I wanted to talk to Papi.
Right.
Well...
I guess we can both talk
to him at the same time.
What, like we're
workin' together?
No, not like we're
working together.
No, like we're workin'
in the same vicinity.
Together.
In the same area code.
The same county.
And don't get all We Are
The World on me either.
When this is over, I'm still gonna
shoot you. But we're partners.
Come on, man,
Ebony and Ivory.
Shit, I think he puked.
He's puked or he's dead.
Oh, yeah, he puked.
Hey.
I'm gonna
fuckin' kill you both.
This might take a while.
I got all day, partner.
Let me put that in there
with ya. Put that on ya.
So, partner,
how you wanna do this?
I like that, it's got a nice
roll off your tongue there.
We're not that close. Don't
kumbaya with me. Don't kumbaya.
I'm gonna get my bucket and
towel and waterboard his ass.
No, we gotta give him a chance
to talk. You got anything to say?
I hope you guys like
the taste of balls,
because I'm gonna chop yours
off, stuff 'em in your mouths.
See?
Or maybe I'll put yours
in his and his in yours.
Want me to get
the bucket?
Kumbaya.
So why were you puttin' so
much money in Tres Cruces?
It's Tres Cruces.
We thought you just
stashed a little cash there
until we robbed the place,
found 40 million. Why is that?
You robbed Tres Cruces?
That's correct.
Why is that?
That's funny, huh?
You're dead.
Yeah, that is funny,
isn't it? You're both dead.
And I didn't even
have to kill you.
I thought you were sharp.
"I-know-a-guy" Bobby.
But you...
You just
ripped off the CIA.
The CIA?
The CIA.
He's full of crap. Why would he have
money in the same bank as the CIA?
Why would you have money
in the same bank as the CIA?
I don't have shit
in that bank.
The only money I deliver to Tres Cruces
is a payment.
To the CIA?
The CIA. They take 7% of my revenue.
In return, they let me use their planes
so I can get my shit
across the border.
I could do it a lot cheaper, but
there was really no negotiations.
You know...
They take it from
all the cartels.
Bullshit.
Okay.
They're still
gonna kill you.
Bobby?
You said stop by anytime.
You kidnapped a drug
kingpin! That's correct.
Papi Greco! And you
tied him up in my garage!
Sorry. What do you...
Yeah, sure. Please. Help yourself
to anything. Take whatever you want.
It's just a yogurt.
But it's her yogurt.
Just put it back.
Please.
Are you two like
ex-boyfriend and girlfriend?
Actually, you know what?
We never put a name on it.
So, what, you broke his
heart or he broke yours?
Wow, this guy will really ask
anyone anything at anytime.
Why don't you go and
check on Papi, huh?
What do you see
in this guy?
I could go on for hours,
but I don't know you,
and I don't think
this is the right time
for us to have this
conversation, okay?
So daddy issues, huh?
Daddy!
Garage. Papi. Go.
I get it now.
Go. Go to the garage.
Can I have the yogurt? You
can have the yogurt. Here.
I don't like her, man.
You don't get a vote.
I'm gonna watch her.
Bobby.
What are you doing?
Are you 100% sure
you can trust this guy?
No. But he's all
the help I got.
Jessup's dead.
The money we stole was CIA
money. They came lookin' for it.
I'm sorry, Deb, I didn't mean
to get you involved in all this.
You okay?
What are you
smirking at?
You know, I've been
racking my brain
trying to figure out
who you look like.
And it
finally dawned on me.
You look like a Mexican Albert Einstein.
Minus the genius factor,
obviously.
You want some yogurt?
Payback's a bitch.
That's for Little Toro.
Stig.
Pack it up!
Move it, move it!
Stig.
The one and only.
That your people?
Do you have to
say it like that?
Like what? They're your people, right?
Technically, yes, but I
thought you were my people now.
All right, two taps, we'll
hit the garage. On go.
Okay. On your go.
Go!
Fuck.
What was that about?
That was messed up.
What the hell
is going on?
I don't know.
Give me your phone, now.
I'll take the car, too.
Get out. Get out!
Oh, my God.
Está en ungray Charger.
How did Stig's people know
to come to your house?
I don't know.
They must have followed you.
I don't think so.
We would have seen 'em.
We should have seen 'em.
How'd they know to
come to your house?
Hmm?
Why were they
at your house, Debbie?
No. You serious?
Bobby...
Out of the car,
gabacho.
Hurry up.
You fucked up now, ese.
On your knees.
I know some guys,
too, Bobby.
Bag 'em up.
Let's take 'em home.
Do you wanna talk about it? No.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I told you I didn't
like her, man.
Shut up.
What are you
gettin' mad at me for?
Because you
talk too much.
What'd I ever
do to you?
Besides shoot me?
You know what you are?
You're a misanthorpe.
It's misanthrope.
I'm a misanthrope.
Did you know what
I meant to say?
No. What did you
mean to say?
That you don't like people. Shut up.
Time for my massage.
Yeah. I'll have housekeeping
clean up your bed.
Oh, shit.
My grandfather cut cane for 30 years
every day and never got a blister.
Says it smells like hell,
toughens the hands.
You know what
I like about this?
Not only do I get to take
my time with you guys,
but this time, I don't have to
worry about leaving any marks.
Don't put your
hands on me, man.
Shit.
What did you say?
Just don't put those
pissy hands on me, man.
You ain't
got a home, Bobby.
DEA doesn't
want you around.
Not with your sins.
Payback's a bitch.
You smell like
warm Corona, man.
You remember
my prize breeding bull.
With cojones
the size of coconuts.
You wanna see him?
No, it's okay.
We can see good from here.
Adiós, Bobby.
No, no.
Shit!
$43 million!
It's everything
we stole from the CIA.
You let us go,
we'll bring it to you.
I got the money.
What are you talking about? I got it.
You don't have it! I know I don't
have it. He doesn't know that.
But you don't
have the money.
I know you don't have it,
'cause I have it.
You have it?
Well, where is it?
Corpus Christi Naval Air
Station. Don't tell me. Tell him.
Oh, shit!
Where is it?
Commander Quince's safe! Corpus
Christi Naval Air Station!
The guy's pissing on us, and you're
askin' if we should fuckin' tell him.
If that's the truth, I might
as well just kill you now.
I had a run-in with a couple
boys out of your organization.
Hello, Earl.
Mr. Bobby Beans
and Mr. Michael Stigman.
Well, they're not
from my organization.
They're freelancers.
And Bobby Beans
is undercover DEA.
And Mr. Stigman's
AWOL U.S. Navy.
They stole 43.125 million
from the Tres Cruces.
We want it back.
Is there a finder's fee?
Fee is we let you
continue to do business.
Fee is we don't raise
our cut from 7% to 20.
The fee is we don't come down here
with a squad of Apache A-6 helicopters
and wipe you off
the face of the earth.
You like my country weak
and corrupt, don't you?
So you can buy your
cheap crap at the mall.
Well, Earl,
I'm not cheap.
Is this about
pride, Manny?
About machismo?
Prove you got
a big Mexican cock?
Well, your cock is huge.
It's massive.
And I,
I'm in awe of your cock.
So what? You're still a drug dealer.
And I'm still the government
of the United States.
It's a free market,
Manny.
Not a free world.
I'll take a look.
Hard!
You'll look hard.
Under every rock in Mexico.
Let's get out
of this shithole.
I've decided to let you
bring me the 43 million.
The truck'll take you
north to the border.
From there, you'll cross
on foot with the coyotes.
If it's all the same,
we'd rather drive.
With everybody
lookin' for you,
they'd pull you out
of line in two seconds.
No, you go the way
you force my people.
If we can't
risk crossing,
I'll meet you north
of the border in 24 hours.
Now, I'm trusting you to
fulfill your part of the bargain.
Hey, Bobby.
You got 24 hours
to bring me the money.
Or I'm gonna shoot her
right in the head.
Then I'm gonna find you,
and I'm gonna
gut you like a pig!
Stig!
When this is over,
I'm still gonna shoot you.
Whatever it takes, Bobby.
Pick one.
I can get in anything.
No, I don't do German, okay?
Locks are tricky, too many alarms.
Okay. Suburban?
It's gonna get like two miles a
gallon. I ain't payin' for all that gas.
For a car thief, you
are mighty particular.
I'll break
into the Honda.
I look like I'm gonna ride
in that Honda to you?
You could.
And you could pick somethin'
with a little more class.
I hate to remind you,
but we're breakin'
onto a high-security
Navy base.
It ain't no Les
Misérables for you tonight.
Oh, man,
whatever the fuck, man.
Look, it's not my fault Quince
took the money back to the base.
I thought you said you took
the money back to the base.
No, I never said that.
So the money
could be anywhere.
It could be in East Jabip,
the Cayman Islands...
No, the money
is on the base, okay?
I gave it to Commander
Quince at the Camino Real,
Right before he took you
out and tried to kill you.
That doesn't mean
he's lyin' about the base.
Not everybody's as paranoid
as you, Bobby. Jeez.
What about the Prius?
You like the Prius?
Camino Real.
Yeah, it's a hotel.
I met Debbie
at the Camino Real.
No shit?
She said she was there to
meet her boyfriend, Harvey.
Wait. Your girlfriend
has a boyfriend?
She's not my girlfriend.
Holy shit.
Yeah, just pick a car.
Right here.
You picked that one?
Yeah.
Fuck you want,
a fuckin' Bentley?
I got it.
Hi.
Hey.
Crazy question,
you wouldn't have anybody
knows how to fix a snowmobile?
Would you check for me? I
really need it fixed by tonight.
Why, a big storm coming?
You never can be too sure.
I'll be right back.
Up with that?
What?
She smiled at you,
you didn't wink at her?
I don't wink
at every woman I see.
Snowmobile in Texas, huh? You must
be in some serious shit, sailor.
You got yourself
a new claw, huh?
Gimme claw. Give it
a pound. It's a beaut.
You still got
my rainy-day stash?
Yeah.
See ya later, Stig.
All right.
You know what they say, talk softly
and carry an M-4 with a grenade launcher.
Wow.
Which one you want?
This one.
What's your plan
for gettin' on the base?
I'm workin' on it.
Remember, once we get
to the command building,
If he's not in the field, that's
where he lives 18 hours a day.
Right, right. But you
still haven't told me
what the plan is to
get through the gate.
I got a plan. I mean, I'm
capable of comin' up with a plan.
I'm just sayin' you
haven't told me. What is it?
I'm workin' on it.
Better work faster.
Much faster.
Move it up.
Quickly.
Fuck it.
Halt!
He's going through!
That fast enough for ya?
Shit!
Let's go! Let's go!
On the radio now!
Return to post!
That was your plan?
That's not a plan. Nobody in their
right mind breaks into a naval base.
That's why it's a brilliant
plan. No one expected it.
You shoulda seen your face.
Damn, they were surprised.
Your stop comin' up.
I'll play decoy,
lead 'em away, try to
get to the Admiral, okay?
All right. Things go wrong, I'll
see you back at the boat yard.
I'm gettin' a medal. I get to the
Admiral, I'm gettin' a medal. Watch.
You're gonna wish
me luck, aren't ya?
Come on, man, let's hear it! Good luck.
Quince's office
at the end of the hall.
Remember, first floor,
end of the hall!
Halt!
Stop where you are!
We have a breach
at Status Hall!
Up the stairs!
Sir, Petty Officer Michael
Stigman, ID number 540333.
Wait a minute,
what's the problem?
Shit, I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to do that to you, man.
Sir.
I've never stepped foot in an officers'
mess, much less crashed it.
Please, sir,
it's an emergency.
Stand outside, please.
Leave us alone.
Thank you, sir.
I didn't mean to hit you like that.
I apologize.
I'm listening,
sailor. Sit.
Thank you, sir.
Try the Admiral again for me.
Yes, sir.
And you believed
this stolen money
would all be used
to fight drug cartels?
Yes, sir. I thought the orders came down
the valid chain of command.
Blind loyalty
is not loyalty.
I know that, sir,
and that's why I'm here.
Well, you've shown
a lot of tenacity
and a lot of guts
bringing this to me.
Thank you, sir. That means
the world comin' from you.
Unfortunately, there's
nothing I can do for you.
Of course, sir. I mean, you
can just lock down the base.
You can arrest
Commander Quince.
The United States Navy
does not rob banks.
Its personnel
did not rob a bank.
I'm not gonna tarnish the integrity
of the Navy over one crooked sailor.
If there was money
taken from the bank
that was part of
an illegal CIA slush fund,
the Navy had no knowledge
the fund existed.
Your jacket has you
six months AWOL?
Yes, sir.
It's gonna stay that way.
Commander Quince's jacket will
likewise be amended so he's also AWOL,
making none of this
the Navy's problem.
Sir, this isn't right.
Well, I'd offer more,
but when the hand
has gangrene,
you chop it off
to save the body.
You don't keep the pinkie around
just because it meant well.
Have Petty Officer Stigman
dropped outside the main gate.
He sets foot on a military
base anywhere in the world,
I want him shot.
You know, men like me fight and
die on the orders of men like you!
Without us, those stars on your
shoulder are a fucking costume!
Open the safe.
Does your boss know
you're doin' this?
Or did the CIA kill her
like they did Jessup?
What's it to you?
I don't like loose ends.
Neither do I...
Harvey.
Huh?
Well, my mother
named me Harold.
I like Harvey. Harvey
has a nice ring to it.
Don't you like Harvey?
I don't know what you're
talkin' about. Yes, you do.
Been to the Camino
Real Hotel lately?
Open the safe.
Staging area cleared up!
Bring it through!
Where's the money?
You tell me where Deb is.
She's gettin' her nails
done. Where is the money?
I don't know.
All right,
tell me what you do know.
Well, your girl
found out where the CIA
was stashing the money
right about when I did.
that she and I could get away with the
money by setting you and Stigman up,
she didn't even blink.
Don't lie to me.
Was she that
unhappy, Bobby?
Where is the money?
Don't lie to me.
You think I'd keep it here with
you and Stigman still alive?
Come on, Bobby.
You gave it to her,
didn't you?
Didn't you?
Commander.
Back up.
Go, go, go, go!
On your six!
Move, move, move!
All personnel
evacuate the building.
Take the back,
in that alley!
Go to the front!
Let's go!
Hey!
This way! Move!
Come on,
come on! Find him!
Clear!
You okay?
Come on, let's go.
You okay, sir?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Work off the standpipe!
This is really
good barbecue.
You don't want to
regret not tryin' it.
Why don't you stop wasting
my time and just kill me?
Even if Bobby was
coming with the money,
you'd still kill us both.
But he's not coming.
He'll be here.
No.
He won't.
You think he's just
gonna let you die?
You think it was a coincidence the
Navy came looking for Bobby at my house?
If I couldn't have Bobby, at
least I'd have half of 43 million.
You set up Bobby Beans.
I wouldn't be
coming for you either.
Where's the money?
Come on. I don't know.
Gone, outta the country.
It's certainly not
on a Navy base, Papi.
Where does that leave you?
Exactly where
I deserve to be.
Yeah.
Bobby.
You're late.
I got the money.
I don't believe you.
Believe me, I got.
I'll bring it to y.
Where are you?
Hi, Bobby.
Debbie?
Can he hear us?
Just hang up
the phone and run.
Okay, listen to me.
Tell him I got the money.
Hang up the phone.
It's not your faul.
Just...
Debbie.
Tell him I have
the money. Okay?
And I know you know
where the money is.
Just tell him I have it.
Debbie, listen to me.
I'm sorry.
I really meant
to love you.
Debbie.
Where are you?
Debbie, where are yo?
Where are you? Debbie?
Hello?
Debbie? Uh...
Wait a minute,
I got the money.
What'd they say?
What'd the Admiral say?
What'd the Admiral say? Admiral
washed his hands of the whole thing.
Navy turned their back.
Where's the money?
There was no money, Stig.
What?
There was no money.
'Course there is.
I gave Quince the money.
Right, and Quince gave it
to Deb, and Deb is dead.
Papi killed her.
Fuck him.
We'll lure 'em all down, then take
every one of 'em out. Kill 'em all.
And then what?
Well, at least Quince
and Papi'd be dead.
And then what?
Oh, you just wanna
let 'em skate?
You don't get it,
do ya, Stig?
I mean, God bless you, you still
think there's some kinda code.
You followed every order the Navy
gave you, they kicked you in the teeth.
No one fights for the Navy,
okay? It's not about the Navy.
You fight for the guy
that's fighting next to you.
That doesn't mean
anything to you?
I'm goin' to Mexico.
And just so you know,
my code saved your life.
There's three inches between
your heart and your shoulder.
My bullet goes three
inches left, you'd be dead.
'Cause Quince only decided to
kill me because I let you live.
What, you think
I missed, huh?
Is that what you think?
You think I missed?
When have you
ever seen me miss?
You stay here.
I'm goin' to Mexico.
Our deal still stand?
I give you the money,
I walk away clean?
Hola. Looks like you
had a banner morning.
You better have my money.
Right here.
Every penny.
Where's Bobby?
We had a philosophical
fallin' out.
I just want your word that you and your
boys, Ferret Nose Julio, all of 'em,
you'll help me
kill Commander Quince.
Who's Commander Quince?
That's him.
Mr. Stigman, you promised me $43 million
for killin' everyone
on this ranch.
Got the money
right here, sir.
Thing is, I promised Papi
the $43 million, too,
so I'm afraid you two are
gonna have to duke it out.
Maybe he and I'll just kill
you instead and split the money.
What do you say, Papi?
50% of 40 million?
Better than 100% dead,
right?
He'll double-cross you. Minute your
back is turned, bullet in the head.
50-50.
The guy up on the roof
says 60-40.
He ain't got a trustworthy
bone in his body.
I came back,
didn't I?
Fuckin' CIA.
Red rover, red rover.
Whoever's got my 43.125 million
better come the fuck on out.
You offer him
the money, too?
I didn't call him.
It's in the trunk!
Why the fuck did
you tell him that?
Thank you, Commander.
Mr. Stigman, come on
out and open the trunk.
Nice and slow, now.
Well, what do
we got here?
Sounds like
a Mexican wedding.
Is that my '64 Impala?
That's correct.
I told you.
I know a guy.
Now,
who wants to see
$43 million?
For a minute there, I thought
you had me chasing my tail.
You want to count it?
If you're shortin' me,
I know where to find you.
So we're good?
Did I not give
you my word?
That's right.
Then don't treat me
like an asshole.
I'll try my best.
You and Mr. Stigman
are free to go.
Yes, sir.
I trust you can
find your own way home?
That's right.
What're you doing, Bobby?
Let's go.
I'm not gonna let him
get away with the money.
Let's go.
I hate these daggone teeth.
They're not just
gonna let us go.
I got a plan.
Hey, I got my M-16.
I got my grenade launcher, I
got my M-4. Let's do this shit.
I got a plan. I'm capable
of coming up with a plan.
Well, it better be
a goddamn good one.
It's a good plan.
Make it rain.
That was your plan?
To blow up $43 million?
Yeah, that's why it's a brilliant
plan. Nobody expected it.
Go.
Come on, move it!
Dumb assholes!
Move it!
You comin'?
Go ahead, I'll be right behind you.
Don't miss.
I never miss!
Told ya.
Stig! Stig!
Don't do it.
Playtime's over.
No more fucking around.
Now,
drop your weapon.
Tell Mr. Stigman
to do the same.
You tell him.
It's real simple.
We can all make a deal
or we can all die.
I'm not making
any deals.
Talk to your man, Bobby.
Be the smart one.
You think Tres Cruces
is the only stash we got?
We got 20 more.
We got money everywhere.
You're not gonna
change a damn thing.
Stig?
Yeah?
You're my people, right?
That's correct.
You good?
Never better.
We're not people,
though.
This makes us family.
All right, brother.
you're looking kind of
fucked up sittin' there, man.
You all right?
Mow my lawn.
Well, you know
what was so cool?
You rolling in
on that '64 Impala.
I mean, you looked
badass, man.
Yeah, that's right.
Listen, one more thing,
one more thing.
What?
Give me your gun.
You're not serious.
Yes, I am.
You're really gonna do this after
everything we've been through?
Arm or leg?
I'm thinking leg. Because leg, there's
more flesh, there's not as much bone.
The arm will...
You know what you are?
You are a petty...
Fucking son of a bitch!
Hurts, doesn't it? You
know you coulda killed me?
Is that right? Three
more inches to the left.
I'd still wink, I just wouldn't
be able to do anything about it.
You know me,
I don't miss.
I never miss. When's the
last time you saw me miss?
You gonna carry my ass
all the way the fuck home.
Oh, shit, man.
This burns.
That's correct.
You know, I shot you when
I didn't know who you were.
Before we were family.
But we're family now. I shot you because
I know who you are.
That ain't right.
They definitely
got the look.
Assholes and windshield
sunglasses, practically CIA uniform.
Can I get you boys
anything else?
Are your doughnuts
any good?
Tell you the truth,
they're pretty lousy.
Can't tell you how happy
we are to hear that.
You take care.
I saw that.
Saw what?
You winked.
That's a twitch.
Yeah, right.
You know, for a guy who
just blew up $43 million,
all of a sudden, you are
a very generous tipper.
Who said I blew up
$43 million?
What are you sayin'?
I'm hearin' somethin'.
You're sayin' somethin'.
Well, if you're hearin' it, it's
only because you're hearin' it,
not 'cause I'm sayin' it.
How much did you keep?
Two million?
That's like one each.
So now you get half?
Well, I shot half the guys. So?
Two million?