Well, for my part
I like to say
as the new guy
will take over you
I hope I can fill
your shoes
because from the
looks of people here
and what they
think about you
they sure seem awfully big
As most of you know
I just moved here recently
from Demoy, with
my wife, Patty here
and Kimberly, our
1 4-month old
you all have made
us feel so welcomed
and Warren, I want you
to feel just as welcome
to visit our office
any time you want
In fact
as we'd been discussing
for last couple of weeks
questions about our
various product
Iike the new Universal
Life Policy next month
and...
anyway, here's to you, Warren
Hey, Warren, how do
you feel about these
young punks taking
over our jobs?
Seems like some kind of
conspiracy to me
Now I've known Warren here
probably longer than most
of you people been alive
we go way back
way back
in horse and buggy days
Anyway, I know something
about retirement
what I want to say
to you out loud
so all these young
hotshot can hear
is all those gifts there
don't mean a damn thing
and this dinner doesn't
mean a thing
and social security pension
doesn't mean a thing
none of these superficiality
mean a damn thing
What means something
what really means something
Warren, is the knowledge
you devoted your life
to something meaningful
To be productive
working for a fine company
held one of top rated
insurance company in nation
to raising a fine family
to building a fine home
to be respected by your community
to having wonderful
lasting friendships
At the end of his career
a man can look back and say
I did it, I did my job
then he can retire in glory
and enjoy riches far
beyond the monetary can
So all you young people here
take a good look
at a very rich man
I love you
I 'll be right back
Good evening
I like hindler please
Coming right up
Hello?
Hi, honey
Yeah, we just got in
just walk in the door
yeah, he is
just a minute
Warren, here on the phone
is Ginny
Ginny? How are you doing?
lt went just fine, yeah
nice event
l know, but don't give it
another thought
you got bigger fish to fry
l know, we'll see out there
real soon anyway
What?
Yeah, did I get the robe?
Yes
that was quite an item
you sure went overboard
From U Nç Rental? I see
Well, thank you both
it sure going to
come in handy now
You bet you
Okay
Bye now
Did you thank Randall?
I did
What did he say?
I just told Ginny
You didn't thank
him personally?
Nço
Why not?
He didn't come to the phone
I don't know
he didn't come to phone
You should have asked for him
You need to make
an effort
he's going to be
your son-in-law
and you hardly know him
I know well enough
You should try
to be more positive
she's lucky to have him
Yeah
You know
my father didn't think
so much of you at first
Where to, mister ?
Looks like you need a ride
Surprise
I thought it'd be fun to
have breakfast in here today
you know, seem like
little beehive
Fine
Isn't this fun?
Well, sort of gives
us a rough idea
We are going to have
a lot of good times
in here, Warren
Yep
Here's to a whole new chapter
"... Child Reach, we need
people who want to help"
throughout the world
in many of
the poorest countries
there is a wonderful organization
called Child Reach
that is making a profound
difference in lives of
children just like these
For just $22 a month
justt 72 cents a day
you can become
a Child Reach sponsor
and not only touch the life
of a needy boy
or girl oversea
but also help the child's
family and community
"Think of it, just $22 a month"
and a little girl like this
would not be using
dirty water
a child like this
would be able to
go to school and learn
I'm so glad you've watched
now that you have
what are you going to do?
I'm glad to hear that
Right... Oh no
I can't take all
the credit for that
I don't know
I did use a calculator
That's my motto
"Alright, all ready"
Bye-bye... Hey
"there he is
what do you say, partner? "
Pretty good
how are you doing?
Nçot too shabby
I see you are all moved in
"Oh yeah, so what brings you
back to this part of woods? "
I was just driving by
want to pop up and see
what trouble
you're getting in to
"You know, keeping busy"
And I want to make sure
you don't have
any more questions about
those pre-teen models
I was working on
they seem pretty
straight forward at first
" Nço, no, I think I got
pretty good handle on things"
you did a super job
of handling everything
just super
smooth selling all the way
Because I have been concerned
about some of those items
that I watch you
slipping through cracks
"you know, it kind of
has been nagging at me"
" Nçope, business has
to worth something"
If everything would
bubble up to surface
why not give you at home
you can bet on that
I got to get to
a meeting at west
You want to take
the elevator down with me?
"Okay, sure
Great"
Great to see you
looking good
Thank you
Have you been working out?
Hi
How was it at the office?
Fine
Good thing I stopped by
T urns out he needs my help
with a couple of loose ends
That's wonderful
Dear Nçdugu
My name is Warren R Schmidt
and I am your
new foster father
alright...
" I live in Omaha, Nçebraska"
my older brother Harry
lives in Rod
with his wife Estil
Harry lost a leg 2 years
ago due to diabetes
I am 66 years old
recently retired as
vice president in
Actuary Woodman of the
World lnsurance Company
damn it fell into
this little kid
alright
maybe he's got a theory
and can plug a few
numbers into computer
but I can tell he
doesn't know a damn thing
about genuine real world
risk assessment
our managing department
will cark that bastard
Anyway
66 must sound too old to
a young one like yourself
The truth is it sounds
pretty old to me too
because when I look into the mirror
and see the wrinkles around my eyes
"and sagging skin on my neck,
head, and my ears"
veins on my ankles
I can't believe
it's really me
When I was a kid
I used to think
maybe I was special
that somehow destinied to
be a great man
Nçot like Walt Disney
or somebody like that
but somebody semi-important
I got a degree
in business statistics
was planning to start
my own business someday
build it up into
a big corporation
watch it go public
maybe make the Fortune 500
I was going to be
the guy you read about
but somehow it just
didn't work out that way
you got to remember l
got top job at Woodman
a family to support
I couldn't put
their security at risk
" Helen, that's my wife"
she wouldn't vote out
What about my family
you might ask
What about my wife and daughter
Don't they give me all the
pride and satisfaction I could want
Helen and I have been
married 42 years
Lately every night I find
myself asking the same question
Who is this old woman who
lives in my house?
Why is every little thing
she does irritates me?
Like the way she gets
the keys out of her purse
Iong before we reach the car
and how she throws our
money away
on her ridiculous collection
and tossing out perfectly
good food
just because the expiration
date is passed
and her obsession with
and the way she cuts me
off when I try to speak
I hate the way she sits
and the way she smells
For years now she has
insisted that I sit
when I urinate
I promised to lift the seat
and put the seat back down
it wasn't good enough for her
then there's Ginny
she's our only
I bet she'd like you
She used to get by
pretty good in German
She'd always be my little girl
She lives out in Denver
we don't get to see
her much any more
She only stay in touch by
phone every couple of weeks
She comes out
for holidays sometimes
but not as often as we like
She has responsibility
with high tech
very hard for her to break away
Recently she got engaged
so I suppose we'll be
seeing even less of her now
Fellow's name is
Randall Hertzl
He's got a sales job
Maybe Ginny is past her prime
but I think she can
do a lot better job
this guy is like smuf
not for my little girl
I'll close now and get
this into mail
Here I am rumbling
on and on
you probably want to
hurry up and cash that check
and get yourself something to eat
so take it easy
best of luck
with all your endeavors
Yours very truly
Warren Schmidt
Hi
I 'm going out to mail letter
do you need anything?
Nço
I have been doing
some research
it amazes me the librals
and look in silver cloud
What can I get you?
I'll have a blizzard and
vanilla ice cream
What would you like in it?
I'll have some...
Reeses pieces
and some cookie
What size?
Medium
Helen? Helen
What's the matter?
Helen
Before we go any further
I would like to go over
some expenses with you
we itemize all our charges and
break them into categories
our professional services
preparational bodies
this figure totals to $ 1 550
and for use of equipment
staff
In addition to funeral charges
Any question?
Nço
What if I drive myself
Anger is okay
"God can handle it, if
we are angry at him"
We are going to miss
Helen so much
"She was the greatest
warmest, most wonderful"
I know
We are praying for you
Warren
" If there is anything you need
you call us, okay? "
Okay
Okay?
I can't believe it
I still can't
I know
She was just
she was too young
" I know, thank you"
You are a good friend
You take care of yourself
"You too, Ray
Thanks for everything"
I see you real soon
Nçice of people to bring
all this food
there will be a lot
of leftovers
She was a very special lady
I really will miss her
I miss her already
I know we all do
Let's drink to her
Here's to Helen
They broke them all
Helen
"We love you, we miss
you, we always will"
How are you doing?
You doing okay?
Fine
Are you sure?
Yeah
Must be really tough
I remember when my aunt died
"so unreal, it was 4th of July "
I never forget it
"Listen, I know it's
not the time to talk about it"
before we leave if you'd
like to take a few minutes
take your mind off it
there's something real important
I want to talk to you about
What's that?
It's an investment opportunity
"really exiting, I want
you to get on ground floor with me"
and it's not a pyramid scheme
a lot of people thought
it's a pyrimid scheme
" It's not, it's almost guaranteed
you can double your money"
you can triple it
in the first year alone
"The thing is, Warren"
I'm not going to be
selling waterbeds forever
"l got plans, we don't
have much chance to talk about it"
but I got pretty good
business head on me
Mayonnaise or mustard?
I like both
don't toast bread very much
I don't like my bread very toasted
I 'll have some of those
BBQ potato chips
not the plain ones
those are your mother's
the BBQ's are mine
In fact you and Randal can
take the plain ones
those will go to waste
I won't eat them
Maybe you can eat
them while on the plane
Fine
so good to see you
I hope you don't have
to get back so soon
Can you take a few days more?
Can you talk to them at work
they'll understand
" Heck, who's going to
take care of me? "
Here is your sandwich
Wonderful
"You know, Dad"
you're going to have to
get used to taking care of yourself
You might have to
hire a maid
A maid?
"Nço, I'll be alright
I don't need extra expense"
At least for a few weeks
while you are dealing with this
That's why I'm asking you
to stay to help me out
"Dad, I told you
I wish I could"
but I can't
I got too much going on
Even if I get more time off
I got the wedding
that's a full time job
on its own
Nçow that you mention
I think you should
consider postponing it
Postpone the wedding?
We can't do that
It's all set
You might want to take
this opportunity
to rethink things
But everyone's invited
"They understand, out of
respect for your mother"
She'd have approved
Nço one wants to change anything
"The thing is, your mother
and I spoke a number of times"
very seriously about
you and Randall
and what did she say?
Just that she loved you
she wanted you to be happy
this thing with Randall
She wanted to make sure
you don't have any regrets
so you might want to
keep your options open
But she helped us
pick the date
I was on phone with her
almost everyday
"planning, ordering things"
I really don't know
what you're talking about
Alright
have it your way
Good sandwich
Dad
Why did you get
such a cheap casket?
What?
I could tell you got
the cheapest casket
Everybody could
That is not true
I specifically did not
choose the cheapest casket
They showed me
one less expensive
and I refused it
You mean a pine box?
I don't remember what it was
Couldn't you spend just once?
What are you talking about?
What about the bagel
out there?
That is an expensive vehicle
I didn't want to get it
but I did
That was completely
your mother's idea
She told me she had
to pay half of it
She said she had to sell
some of her stock to pay for it
That was her decision
I was going to have Winy weny
but she had to have adventure
What was I supposed to do
T ell her she couldn't?
It was her money
" In here, Randall"
"Where?
In here, here"
Here you are
you better get packed
Did you tell dad about book?
I forgot
"Warren, have you read"
""When Bad Things
Happen to Good People"? "
Nço
It's really amazing
You should read it
When we get back to Denver
I'll send you my copy
The workbook too
I did most of my exercises
Midwest Express
"So long, Randall"
You'll be in our prayers
"Okay, thank you"
Ginny
"T ake care yourself, Dad"
That's a good one
Bye Dad
"So long, Ginny"
See you in a few weeks
Okay
"Bye, Warren, you take care"
Dear Nçdugu
I hope you're sitting down
because I'm afraid l
got some bad news
Since I last wrote to you
"my wife, Helen
your host mother"
passed away very suddenly from
a blood clod in her brain
The services were lovely and
very well attended
Ginny came in from Denver
with her friend
folks drove up from as far
away as from Demon Wichita
a very moving tribute any
way you look at it
I wish you could
have been there
but now all the
excitement is over
and the smoke is clear
just me and my thoughts
knocking around
I believe I mentioned
in my previous letter
that I was an actuary
in one of the
world insurance company
" If I were given a man's age
race, profession"
place of residence
marital status and
medical history
I can calculate
with great probability
how long that man
will live
In my own case
now that my wife has died
there is 73% chance
I will die in 9 years
provided that
I do not remarry
all I know is
I got to make best of
whatever time I have left
" Life is short, Nçdugu"
I can't afford
to waste another minute
Two weeks later
Life without Helen
has been quite a challenge
but I think you'll be
proud of me
"Yeah, this house is
now under new management"
but you never know
the difference
Sure sometimes I can be
tired and forgetful
I guess that's not
worth mentioning
to someone in your situation
Helen wouldn't want me
sitting around in self-pity
but she'd tell me
to shape up
so I try to get out much
stick to my routine
That's very important in
phase of big change
Sure I am not quite
the cook like Helen was
but I am not like
in my bachelor days
It's a lot of work
keeping household together
I might sell the place and
move to a little condo
but for now I am
getting by just fine
In my last letter
I might have misspoken
used some negative language
about my late wife
but you have to understand
I was under a lot of pressure
following my retirement
" I 'm not going to lie
to you, Nçdugu"
It's been rough few weeks
I 've been broken
from time to time
I miss her
I miss my Helen
I guess I didn't know
how lucky I was
to have a wife like Helen
until she was gone
"Remember that, young man"
you got to appreciate
what you have
while you still have it
You scare me
What are you doing?
I thought you might
want these back
"That was long ago
25, 30 years"
I can't believe
she kept these
That's talk about this
you are my friend
It was a big mistake
I am sorry
You have reached Electronics
Shipping and receiving
this is Ginny
Ginny? It's Dad
How are you
"Hey, I am swamped
What's up? "
I have surprise for you
Guess what?
What?
I am on the road to see you
now I am outside
" Dad, what are you
talking about? "
"Ginny, I 've been thinking
about things"
how much you mean to me
the times we've been
together in last few years
all of a sudden I realize
what am I doing in Omaha
when you are out there
we should be together
Wait
You are coming now?
If I drive straight through
I 'll be in time for supper
I don't think so
this is not a good idea
Sure it is
Don't tell me you couldn't
use help with wedding arrangements
The thing is with Jill
we got everything under control
Let's stick to plan
you get here a day
before wedding
Iike we said
I assume you won't
object me
sending any more of
those checks
" Dad, I do not
have time for this"
"you call me when you
get home, okay? "
Fine
"Bye, Ginny
Bye, Dad"
Dear Nçdugu
How are you?
I am fine
A week ago I decided to
take my way to Ginny's
wedding in Denver
Ginny begged me
to come early
to help with
wedding arrangements
but I told her I needed
some time myself
I decided to go to places l
haven't been to for a long time
So much has happened to my
life that I can't remember
Whole section of my life
is just gone
You will say I want to
give my self some memory
"The first place I stop
is Holdrege, Nçebraska"
I think seeing the house
I was born 67 years ago
When I was your age
we moved away from Holdrege
I often wonder what our old
house would be like today
Funny
I never forget the address
1 2 Logus Ave
"Can I help you, sir? "
Nço thanks
I am just looking around
I used to live here
Here in the store?
yep
My childhood home's
right on the spot
That room would be
about here
Living room over here
That was long time ago
before you were born
You're not going to
believe this
we used to have tire
swing out here
Awful lot has changed
since my day
It was still good to
be home
very good indeed
" Nçext stop, Florence
Kansas"
Where I pay my visit
to AU
I haven't been there
for years
now it's perfect time
to stop by
I even hook up with some
kids from my old fraternity
Nçdugu
I highly recommend you
pledge a fraternity
when you go to college
After that walk down
Memory Lane
it was tourist time
I made my way back
to Nçebraska
and stop at historical
museum in Brokenbow
to see their fine collection
of arrowheads
Later that day
I met a real lndian
or native American
we had nice chat about
history of the area
He really opened my eyes
" Nçext stop, cody house"
What a remarkable man
you can read about him
in enclosed pamphlet
I pull my car over
whenever I feel like
taking a break
The other day at antique shop
I came across fine
collection of rare hummels