[ Snorting ]
[ Narrator ] This is a tale about
an unprejudiced heart...
and how it changed our valley
forever.
There was a time
not so long ago...
when pigs were afforded no respect
except by other pigs.
They lived their whole lives
in a cruel and sunless world.
ln those days, pigs believed that
the sooner they grew large and fat,
the sooner they'd be taken
into pig paradise.
- Haa! Haa! Get up!
- A place so wonderful...
- that no pig had ever
thought to come back.
- Yo! Yeah!
Good-bye, Mom.
So when the day came for their
parents to go to that other
world of endless pleasures,
it was not a time
for young pigs to be sad.
Just another step towards the day when
they, too, would make the journey.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Perhaps it was because he was alone.
Perhaps his sadness
made him easier to catch.
Whatever the reason, of the thousands
of animals in the piggery that day...
only one was chosen.
- How's this one, Harry?
- Just right for the purpose.
- How much do l owe you?
- lt's a runt, Harry.
A worthless, little runt.
- [ Chuckling ]
- [ Pig Squealing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Auctioneer Chattering ]
[ Chuckling ]
You're too modest, Esme Hoggett.
Nine out of ten first prizes
for jams and jellies...
is more than
a matter of luck.
Luck still plays its part. Our berries
were wickedly good this year.
And our water
is very tasty too.
Of course, we don't use
the town water.
[ Pig Squealing ]
Arthur Hoggett!
How's it going, Arthur?
How are those sheep of yours?
Come on, try your luck.
How about taking a guess, Arthur?
All for a good cause.
- Don't keep pigs.
- Christmas day. Think of it.
What a feast!
That'll do, Pig.
[ Narrator ] The pig and the farmer
regarded each other.
And for a fleeting moment,
something passed between them.
- A faint sense of some common destiny.
- [ Man ] Hah. Strange.
First time the little thing
hasn't screamed its head off.
Now you'll have
to have a guess.
- Sixteen pounds, five--
- [ Pig Urinating ]
Eew.
Two ounces.
[ Mrs. Hoggett ]
Hooey! Hoggett!
Thanks, Arthur. We'll be weighing
the little pig tomorrow.
We'll phone you
if you win.
When you win, Arthur.
When you win! [ Laughing ]
Care to guess
the pig's weight, sir?
Support the Lion's Club.
[ Clock Ticking ]
[ Huffs ]
Ooh!
[ Chuckles ]
What could we do
with a pig, eh, Duchess?
Just think. Two nice hams.
Two sides of bacon.
Oh, and pork chops, kidney, liver,
chitlins, pickle his feet.
- [ Phone Rings ]
- Save his blood for black
puddin'. There's the telephone.
Hoggett!
[ Man ] Good news, Arthur.
You've won the pig.
Oh.
[ Mouse ] Pigs are definitely stupid.
[ Giggling ]
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
- [ Puppy ] What is it, Mom?
- That's a pig.
- They'll eat him when he's big.
- Will they eat us?
Good heavens, no! The bosses
only eat stupid animals...
like sheep and ducks
and chickens.
[ Puppies Barking ]
Yea!
lt does look stupid,
Mom.
Not as stupid as sheep, mind you.
But pigs are definitely stupid.
Excuse me.
No, we're not.
- Good heavens! Who are you?
- l'm a Large White.
- Yes, that's your breed, dear.
What's your name?
- l don't know.
What did your mother call you
to tell you apart from
your brothers and sisters?
Our mom called us
all the same.
And what was that,
dear?
She called us all Babe.
Perhaps we shouldn't talk
too much about, uh, family.
[ Crying ]
l want my mom.
[ Whimpering ]
There, there. You've got
to be a brave boy now.
l left my mother when l was your age,
and my pups will have to leave me soon.
But l'll keep an eye on you, if you
like, just 'til you find your feet.
The little pig's a bit low.
He's going to sleep with us...
- just 'til he finds his feet.
- [ Snarls ]
Until he finds his feet.
But, Mom,
he'll wet the bed!
Nonsense!
lf you do want to do anything,
you'll go outside, won't you?
- [ Sniffling ]
- Good boy.
[ Puppies Together ]
Yea!
Yeah! Yeah!
Stomp on him!
What's your name, Pig?
- What does he taste like?
- Where did he come from?
[ Clucking ]
Comin' through!
Hey, get lost!
- [ Clucking ]
- [ Duck Crowing ]
[ Crowing Continues ]
We've got to do something
about that duck.
Ooh! Ooh!
Doodle-loo-dee-doo.
- What's that noise?
- lt's only Ferdinand.
- What's Ferdinand?
- He's a duck.
- He wants to be a rooster.
- He hates being a duck.
- We'll catch him one day
and eat him. Won't we, Mom?
- Yes, dear.
Yech!
Who'd want to eat a duck?
[ Whistles ]
[ Yipping ]
Babe, you wait here.
- Aren't pigs allowed?
- Not live ones.
- Sorry, dear. Only dogs
and cats inside the house.
- Why?
That's just the way
things are.
[ Purring ]
- [ Screeching ]
- [ Barking ]
Whoa!
[ Babe Groaning ]
- Ow!
- [ Mrs. Hoggett ] Pig-pig-piggy!
Ooh, what a spectacular feast
l've got for you.
Oh, yes! What a lucky
little pork chop you are.
Delicious! Oh, yes!
Yum, yum, yum.
Who's gonna grow up
to be a big, fat pig?
You are! You are!
Yum, yum, yum.
- [ Puppy ] Where are we going?
- To work with the sheep.
- What's sheep?
- Sheep is animals
with thick, woolly coats.
And thick woolly heads. And men
can't look after them without us.
- Why do they need us?
- [ Together ]
'Cause we're sheepdogs! Yea!
- Not you, dear.
- Why not?
We have to do dogs' work.
You're a pig. Your job
is to stay here and eat your food.
We'll be back
at the end of the day.
[ Female Voice ] They don't think
l'll remember. Well, l don't forget.
Seems like a sheep's
just born to suffer.
Hello?
Excuse me.
[ Coughing ]
Darn wolf!
- l'm not a wolf. l'm a pig.
What are you?
- Ewe.
Pig. What are you?
l'm a ewe.
A ewe!
- You're a sheep!
- l'll not be called
a common sheep, thank you kindly.
l'm a Border Leicester ewe.
The name's Maa.
- [ Coughing ]
- Oh.
- What's wrong with you, Maa?
- Foot rot. And l got me a nasty cough.
And l'm not as young
as l used to be. [ Coughing ]
[ Coughing,
Bleating ]
Hmph.
- Seem like a nice young pig.
What be your name?
- Babe.
Not like them wolves.
Treat you like dirt, they do!
- Bite you as soon as
look at you, those savages!
- Bite you?
And worse.
Some wolves be so bad,
they run a sheep down
and tear it to pieces.
- [ Coughing ]
- Fly would never do that!
Fly, is it? A right vicious creature
she be, l'll tell you.
- Not Fly.
- All them wolves is cruel
to sheep. Always have been.
Brutal savages!
That's what they be.
l wouldn't want to see a gentle soul
like you mixin' with the likes of them.
[ Coughing ]
[ Narrator ]
That afternoon when he saw Fly,
the pig's mind
was a tangle of questions.
Cruel, vicious, brutal?
What was it that dogs did
in the fields all day?
- Hello, Babe? Had a good day?
- Yes, thank you.
[ Giggling ]
[ Narrator ] The old sheep
had to be wrong about Fly.
And the pig promised himself
that he would never think badly
of any creature ever again.
Crime and Punishment!
[ Laughing ]
The morning of
the terrible crime...
started like any other
on Hoggett Farm.
Comin' through!
Comin' through! [ Clucking ]
Take off!
- [ Chuckles ] Now!
- Up, up, up.
- [ Clucking ]
- Nee-nee-nee-nee.
- [ Crowing ]
- [ Alarm Ringing ]
- Hmm?
l was worried it might have
a harsh tone, but that's
quite a nice musical ring.
l walked into O'Halloran's Hardware,
and there it was waiting for me.
What a splendid way
to wake up each morning!
Hoggett, dear.
Church.
[ Narrator ] When embarking
on an audacious crime,
a duck needs
a willing accomplice.
A creature who is reliable,
beyond suspicion,
and above all,
extremely gullible.
Hey! Psst!
Wha-- What?
You look like an intelligent,
sophisticated, discerning young fella.
- Who, me?
- Yeah. Follow me. Oh, boy!
Are you in for some fun!
What are we doin'?
Where are we goin'?
[ Narrator ] Now the duck knew
exactly what he had to do.
- The alarm clock had to go.
His very life depended on it.
- [ Duck ] Do you see it?
- Yes.
- Good.
[ Babe ] So l go through the kitchen,
across the living room...
- Good, good.
- into the bedroom.
Get the mechanical rooster
and bring it out to you.
- What about that cat?
- But quietly bring it out to you.
- Excellent.
- l don't think l can do it.
lt's against the rules. Only dogs
and cats allowed in the house.
lt's a good rule, but this is bigger
than rules. This is life and death.
- lt is?
- Mm-hmm. Follow me.
[ Duck ] Hello! Look,
there's something you should know.
- Humans eat ducks!
- [ Gasps ] l beg your pardon?
Most ducks prefer to forget it,
but the fact is that humans
like to eat plump ducks.
l don't think so.
Not the boss. Not the boss's wife.
Come on.
Humans don't eat cats. Why?
- Well, they're--
- They're indispensable.
They catch mice.
Humans don't eat roosters. Why?
They make eggs with the hens and
wake up everyone in the morning.
l tried it with the hens.
lt didn't work.
So l turned to crowing, and lo!
l discover my gift.
But no sooner do l become
indispensable than they bring in
a machine to do the job!
[ Moaning ]
Ah, the treachery of it!
- A mechanical rooster!
- Oh, dear me.
Oh, dear you?
[ Sighing ]
l suppose the life
of an anorexic duck...
doesn't amount to much
in the broad scheme of things.
But, Pig,
l'm all l've got.
Why do you need me
to do it?
- [ Groans ] l'm allergic to cats.
- Oh.
They make me sneeze.
Ahh.
Don't worry.
l won't wake the cat.
My life is in your hands.
Oh, dear.
[ Grunting ]
Oh, no!
[ Door Squeaking ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Purring ]
Ah, boy.
[ Grunting ]
[ Spoon Clatters ]
[ Quietly Growls ]
[ Muffled Quacking ]
No, no, no!
[ Tapping At Window ]
Your foot, your foot!
Take the string off your foot.
Wait, wait. Let me put it this way.
Stop. Turn around--
Shh.
No, no!
The other way! Turn--
No, stop! Oh!
[ Quacking ]
Stop!
Stop, stop, stop!
Don't, don't, stupid.
Go outside... now.
- But you said you can't do without me.
- l can. Trust me, l can.
- Are you sure? You're positive?
- Yes!
- Go outside and stand guard.
- Okay. Good idea.
[ Groaning ]
Oh, boy. Want something done,
you gotta do it yourself.
[ Ticking ]
- Hmm.
- Guard against what?
Ahh! Ahh!
Don't worry.
Stick with me and please,
l beg you, not one more word.
All right.
[ Ticking ]
[ Gulps ]
Aah--
[ Gasping ]
Don't sneeze, Ferdie.
- Just hold your breath.
- Ahhh--
[ Alarm Ringing ]
[ Screeching, Clanging ]
[ Ferdinand Quacking ]
Ah-choo!
[ Meows ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Rex ] lt was my mistake. l was
trying to loosen things up a little.
But, no. Today proves
that it doesn't work.
From now on,
we'll all respect the rules.
To each creature
its own destiny.
Every animal
in its proper place.
And a pig's proper place is under
the old cart, not in the barn.
And absolutely never
in the house.
- ls that understood?
- Yes, sir.
Now, Pig, regarding the company
you keep. Being young,
it's hard to discriminate,
so l'll make it easy for you.
l forbid you to talk to
or consort with...
that duck... ever.
- Have l made myself clear?
- Uh... what's ''consort''?
lt means, young man,
that you must not go
anywhere near that duck.
As for the fugitive duck, when
he shows himself, let him know this:
Being a duck he must behave like a duck.
No more of this crowing and nonsense.
He should accept what he is
and be thankful for it.
- That goes for all of us.
- Here, here!
[ Narrator ]
Rex continued long into the night.
Elsewhere,
there was more talk.
The subject
was Christmas dinner...
and whether that year the main course
would be roast pork...
or Duck a l'Orange.
And pork is
a nice, sweet meat.
Then there's the crackling.
That always adds interest and texture.
[ Puppies Cheering ]
Get him!
Get the pig! Get the pig!
Get the pig!
Get him! Get him!
[ Whimpering ]
- Psst!
- [ Gasps ] Ferdinand!
- Everyone's been looking for you.
- Shh. Shh.
- What is this place?
- What's happenin' out there?
Rex isn't very happy.
Boy, all these new rules!
l'm not allowed to--
Oops.
- Not allowed to what?
- [ Mumbling ]
- Huh?
- [ Continues Mumbling ]
- [ Mrs. Hoggett ] Piggy!
- What? [ Stammering ]
You didn't see me, all right?
And l didn't see you.
All right? Oops.
[ Narrator ]
The time comes for all creatures...
when childhood ends...
and the doorway opens
to life as an adult.
And so it was
with Fly's pups.
Though that time
was all too soon for Fly.
Puppy, puppy, puppy.
Come on.
[ Giggling ]
ln my pocket.
[ Mr. Hoggett Whistles ]
Fly?
May l call you Mom?
[ Narrator ]
And so it was that the pig...
found his place
in the world of the farm.
And he was happy,
even in his dreams.
[ Car Horn Honks ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
- Hello!
- Folks, how are you? Merry Christmas!
[ Screams ]
[ Mrs. Hoggett ]
How's my favorite girl?
Nanny's got
a jellybean.
Give us a kiss.
Guess what we're having
for Christmas dinner.
- Roast pork.
- [ Child ] l hate pork.
Darn silly carry-on,
if you ask me.
The cats says
they call it Christmas.
Christmas!
Christmas dinner, yeah.
Dinner means death.
Death means carnage!
Christmas means carnage!
[ Quacking ]
Oooh.
[ Giggling ]
- [ Giggling Continues ]
- Yes!
Wait.
Eatin' pigs!
Blaah! Barbarians!
You're goin' back
to the fields, Maa.
Oh, young'un, tragic there
ain't more of your kind.
- l'll be thinkin' of ya always.
- l could come visit you.
l'd like that, but--
[ Clears Throat ]
Well, we shouldn't hope
for too much. Ooh!
[ Bleats ]
[ Narrator ]
And so, it was Christmas Eve.
And time had run out
for the pig.
- Are you doing him tonight then?
- Mmm.
Good.
The blood'll drain by morning.
- Pity.
- What's that?
Nothin'.
What on earth
are you babbling on about?
Shame to miss out on the best ham prize
at next year's fair, is all.
Nice plump haunches
he's gettin'.
Beautiful.
Still...
silly to wait,
l suppose.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
- [ Quacking ]
- [ Knife Thumping ]
[ Mrs. Hoggett ]
Here it is!
- The bird.
- Yuck. Chicken?
No,
it's Duck a l'Orange.
And, Mother, it looks
absolutely superb.
- [ Girl ] l'm not going
to eat any of it!
- This is fabulous.
Ferdinand!
lf you're out here,
who's that in there?
Her name's Rosanna.
[ Ferdinand ]
Why Rosanna?
- She had such a beautiful nature.
- Oh, Ferdinand.
- l can't take it anymore.
- Really!
The fear's too much for a duck.
lt eats away at the soul.
There must be kinder dispositions
in far-off gentler lands.
The only way you'll find
happiness is to accept...
that the way things are
is the way things are.
The way things are stinks!
l'm not gonna be a goner. l'm gone.
l wish all of you
the best of luck.
- [ Panting ] Where will you go?
- No idea.
But l'm a clever duck.
l could do with an adventure.
- l'll miss you, Ferdie.
- Ferdie? No one's ever
called me that before.
Hey, good luck, Pig.
Huh?
- l am outta here.
- Bye, bye.
[ Groaning ] Ow!
Would you do me a favor, old thing?
- Anything.
- Open the gate, huh?
Ah! Ah! Ahh!
Ha-ha-ha! Whoa!
[ Sheep Bleating Excitedly ]
[ Narrator ] The pig knew it was
against the rules to leave the farm.
But something
was definitely wrong.
How lovely, darling.
What is it?
lt's a fax machine.
You can send us letters by phone.
- Hmm.
- Oh.
[ Narrator ] At any other time,
the pig would've been tickled pink...
by his first visit
to the sheep fields.
But now
there was fear in the air.
Maa and her kind
were under threat.
[ Barking ]
Hey, Frank, feel like pork
for dinner tonight?
- Young'un, you're alive!
- Maa!
What's happening?
Who are these men?
l'll get him out. Come around, Sniff!
[ Whistles ]
Where's our boss?
lt doesn't seem right.
[ Crying ]
- What's wrong, dear?
- lt's the wrong one!
l want the house l saw
on the television!
Oh, there, there.
[ Squealing ]
[ Barking ]
- Get! Quick! Get the dog in.
- [ Whistles ]
Out of the sheep!
Come on!
Let's go!
[ Barking ]
Good dog.
Good pig.
Oooh.
- [ Fireworks Exploding ]
- [ Together ] Oooh!
- Hey, hey. Dad says
his little porker's a watch pig.
- Dearie me!
lf it's not a duck
that thinks it's a rooster,
- it's a pig that thinks it's a dog!
- [ Laughing ]
A pig that thinks
it's a dog!
[ Mice ] A pig that thinks it's a dog!
[ Laughing ]
[ Mrs. Hoggett ] A washing machine,
a radio, a new alarm clock.
l think it's a lovely fax machine,
darling, but can't you use it?
We already have one, Mom.
That's the whole idea.
We can send faxes
to each other.
Don't be afraid of it
just because it's new.
These accounts are
a real worry, Arthur.
Every month your expenditure
is greater than your income.
lt's eating up your reserves.
You need to modernize, get
some sort of cash flow going.
You're still using
a horse and cart, for God's sakes.
- Dad?
- Funny, that.
- What?
- Those chickens, that pig.
What's the pig
got to do with anything?
Nothing.
Just look at them.
The browns and the whites.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Chuckles ]
Come, Rex.
Come, Fly.
Come, Pig.
Come, Pig!
[ Fly ] Perhaps he's pleased
with you for what you did yesterday.
- [ Babe ] l didn't do much.
- lf it wasn't for you, dear,
they could've stolen
the whole flock.
- ls Rex unhappy with me?
- Oh, he'll be all right.
Just stay out
of his way today.
Way to be, Fly.
Rex, come by.
[ Whistles ]
That'll do.
You're so quick.
l'd never be able to fly like you can.
Pigs aren't built
to fly, dear.
But speed isn't the thing.
lt's attitude.
They just have to know
who's boss.
Out you go.
[ Crunching ]
Mmm!
[ Whimpering ]
Get 'em up, Pig.
- He wants you to drive them
out of the yard.
- Away to me, Pig.
Remember, you have
to dominate them.
Do that and they'll do
anything you want. Go.
Woof!
- Woof, woof, woof!
- [ Laughing ]
Woof! Woof!
Woof, woof, woof, woof!
[ Sheep Laughing ]
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- Woof, woof, woof!
This is ridiculous,
Mom.
Nonsense.
lt's only your first try.
But you're treating them like equals.
They're sheep. They're inferior.
- Ah, no they're not.
- Of course they are!
We are their masters.
Let them doubt it for a second
and they'll walk all over you.
-Fly, get that pig out of there.
-Make them feel inferior.
Abuse them. lnsult them.
- But they'll laugh at me.
- Then bite them.
Be ruthless. Whatever it takes.
Bend them to your will.
- Enough!
- Go on! Go!
Move along there,
you--
You, uh,
big butt heads!
[ Laughing ]
[ Growling ]
- Ow!
- Young'un, stop this nonsense.
What's got into you? l just finished
tellin' what a nice young pig you be.
Maa, l was just trying
to be a sheepdog.
Hah! Enough wolves
in the world already...
without a nice lad like you
turnin' nasty.
You haven't got it in ya,
young'un.
You and l are descended
from the great sheepdogs.
We carry the bloodline
of the Ancient Bahou.
We stand for something.
And today l watched in shame
as all that was betrayed.
- Rex, he's just a little pig.
- All the greater the insult.
l'm sorry l bit you.
Are you all right?
l wouldn't call that a bite,
myself. You got teeth in
that floppy mouth or just gums?
[ Laughing ]
You see, ladies,
a heart of gold.
[ Sheep Together ]
Ahh. Heart of gold.
No need for all this
wolf nonsense, young'un.
All a nice little pig like you
need do is ask.
[ Barking ]
Thanks very much.
lt was very kind of you.
- A pleasure.
- What a nice little pig!
All right,
how did you do it?
l asked them, and they did it.
l asked them nicely.
We don't ask sheep, dear.
We tell them what to do.
l did, Mom.
They were really friendly.
Maybe Rex might be a little more
friendly if l had a talk with him.
No, no, no.
You better leave that to me.
Rex?
l know it was hard
for you today...
watching all that happening.
But surely it's not worth
all this misery.
Please, dear,
not on such a beautiful night.
You put these ideas
into his head!
Two-faced traitorous wret--
[ Growling, Snarling ]
Get down!
Down, Rex.
Fly!
[ Snarling ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Narrator ] A dark cloud
had descended on the valley.
And the pig felt that
the troubles were all his fault.
But he was certain that he knew
how to put things right again.
Oh, uh,
e-excuse me, sir.
But l-l-l think
all this trouble--
- [ Snarling, Growling ]
- [ Squealing ]
[ Man ] Well, it's not distemper.
Can't be rabies.
Must be the hormones.
- What about Hoggett's notion,
the dog jealous of the wee pig?
- l don't see that myself.
[ Mrs. Hoggett ]
No. So what should we do?
You can keep him locked up
or... snip, snip. l can do it Tuesday.
No.
Or Wednesday.
Hoggett doesn't want the dog
operated on. He's a breeding dog.
l can sedate him,
of course,
but he'll be useless
as a working dog.
- [ Groans ]
- [ Vet ] l'll give you pills
to put in his food.
Good dog.
[ Together ]
The Sheep Pig.
[ Bleating ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Oinks ]
[ Narrator ]
A pig doing the work of a sheepdog?
With Rex out of action
and Fly injured from the fight,
Farmer Hoggett had no choice.
Maa! Maa! The boss has
to give you some medicine.
Oh, dear, l thought so!
lt's horrible stuff, that.
- l know, but it's for the best.
- Young'un, if you say so.
Shoo! Shoo!
[ Narrator ]
When the thought first came to him,
Farmer Hoggett dismissed it
as mere whimsy.
But, like most of his harebrained
ideas, it wouldn't go away.
- [ Babe ] What are they doing?
- [ Fly ] lt's a sheepdog trial.
[ Babe ] So it's like
a competition for sheepdogs?
[ Fly ] And their bosses.
lt's like an obstacle course.
How do they decide
who wins?
lt's time and mistakes.
You get points for how quick you are.
And they take points off
for every mistake.
Every time a sheep goes the wrong way,
that's a mistake and you lose points.
- Looks like fun!
- For a sheepdog,
there's no prouder moment.
- Rex and l used to--
- Hmm?
Never mind.
Oh.
[ Babe ]
Was Rex a champion?
[ Fly ] He had the makings
of the greatest champion there
ever was, but it wasn't to be.
- [ Babe ] What happened?
- [ Fly ] A while back
when Rex was in his prime,
the winter rains brought
a great flood to the valley.
Rex and the boss got most of
the flock onto the high ground.
Then Rex went back
to look for the strays.
He found them. They'd been
stranded by the rising water.
He tried to herd them across
to safety, but they wouldn't budge.
Too afraid and too stupid
to save their own skins.
lt was freezing cold
and the water kept rising.
Rex stayed with them
right through the night.
By morning,
the sheep were drowned.
- And when they found Rex,
he was barely alive.
- [ Babe ] Oh, Mom!
[ Fly ] Two weeks rest in front of
the fire saw him back on his feet.
But his hearing
was never the same again.
He'd never want anyone to know,
but he's almost totally deaf.
- ls that why he's so, you know, angry?
- That's not the half of it.
[ Fly ] All this was barely a month
before the Grand National Challenge.
He tried his best, but he couldn't hear
the boss's calls, and it slowed him up.
The cold truth is that,
but for the stupidity of sheep,
Rex would've been
the champion of champions.
Good dog.
[ Hammering ]
That's it, all right.
Good.
[ Hoggett ]
Here we go. All right.
Now, through here like this.
And then, big hook to the left.
Big hook.
Through this gate here.
[ Narrator ] lt was at that
time that Mrs. Hoggett began
to worry about her husband.
But Farmer Hoggett knew
that little ideas...
that tickled and nagged
and refused to go away...
should never be ignored...
for in them lie
the seeds of destiny.
Close the gate like that,
and you're done.
A Tragic Day.
Mom. Mom!
Can we start work early today?
Oh, dear,
it's not even dawn yet.
You can go to work when the rooster
crows. Oh, go back to sleep.
[ Sighs ]
Ahem.
Um, excuse me.
Hello, sir. Excuse me,
but it's nearly dawn, and--
- [ Mumbling ] What?
- Sorry to disturb you.
lt's nearly dawn, and l wondered
if you'd mind crowing just a
few minutes early this morning.
- Get out of here!
- But, well, see l--
- Get lost!
- Oh, okay.
Whoa!
[ Groans ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Bleating, Barking ]
[ Narrator ] Now the pig understood
why the sheep called all dogs wolves.
And he was filled with
a deep and terrible rage.
- [ Whimpering ]
- [ Barking ]
[ Maa Groaning ]
[ Groaning ]
Maa! Maa!
- Are you all right?
- Hello, young'un.
Oh, Maa,
can you get up?
l don't reckon.
lt's over, Maa.
The wolves have gone far away.
l'll get the boss up here
to look after you.
- You'll be all right.
You'll be all right!
- [ Groaning ]
Oh, Maa! Maa!
[ Crying ]
Maa! Maa!
Maa!
- [ Sheep Bleating ]
- Maa!
[ Sighs ]
Home, Pig.
[ Narrator ] Fly knew that there
was only one fate for any creature...
that took the life of a sheep
on Hoggett Farm.
But Fly could never believe
that Babe was a sheep killer,
so she remained in the field
to do something she'd never
done before: talk to the sheep.
Tell me.
Who killed the old one?
- Wolf!
- Wolf. ls that the only words
you half-wits know?
- Wolf!
- Are you saying it was a dog?
- Where's Babe?
- Was it wolf or Babe?
[ Shouting ]
Wolf! Babe!
[ Narrator ] Farmer Hoggett
was carrying something
in the crook of one arm.
A kind of black, shiny tube.
Come, Pig.
[ Narrator ] The pig had a vague
memory that shiny tubes produced food,
and guessed that some
quite unexpected surprise...
would come out
of two small round mouths.
[ Shouting ]
Babe! Wolf!
Quiet!
[ Narrator ]
Fly decided to speak very slowly,
for it was a cold fact of nature
that sheep were stupid...
and no one would ever
persuade her otherwise.
Please, please
would you be...
so kind as to tell me
what happened?
Quiet!
Please, tell me
what happened this morning.
[ Narrator ]
The sheep spoke very slowly...
for it was a cold fact of nature
that wolves were ignorant...
and nothing would
convince them otherwise.
Babe came!
He saved us!
- The wolves killed Maa.
- But Babe drove the wolves away!
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you all very much!
Pleasure talkin'
to ya.
[ Barking ]
Hooey! Hoggett!
Hooey! Arthur!
[ Barking ]
Oh, there you are!
Well, what do you think?
That was the police on the telephone.
Said there are wild dogs about.
Apparently the Mitchells
lost six lambs this morning.
What are you doing
with that gun?
Oh, l--
Nothing.
[ Sighs ]
[ Mice ]
Pig of Destiny!
lt's all very simple.
Half an hour at 350 degrees.
l've given you
rabbit casserole for Friday.
Now, for Duchess, it's liver
in the morning, heart for the evening.
Except Fridays, when it's steak in
the morning, and cooked liver at night.
Warm it up a bit but test it,
because she bites into
it before she knows what's what.
That'll be the bus.
- Oh, bye, bye.
- Have a good time. Bye.
Hello, everyone!
Oh, dearie me, Valda.
l know l have to be
at the National Conference.
l am the Assistant General Secretary
of the Northeast Region after all,
but l do worry about
leaving that man alone.
- Still acting a bit strange?
- Just silly things.
Odd little things
only a wife would notice.
- Still, he can't get up
to too much mischief in three days.
- Of course not.
[ Whistles ]
Go on.
Go on!
[ Meows ]
- Oh! Good evening.
Shame about the weather.
- [ Hisses ]
Nasty cough!
[ Narrator ] lt had been
a long time since Arthur Hoggett...
had had an animal in whose abilities
he had so much faith.
And with the National Grand Challenge
Sheepdog Trials only two days away,
he wasn't going to let the fact
that his animal was a pig deter him.
He had been worried,
for he was a truthful man,
that the heading might say
''Name of dog.''
And then whatever he put
would be a lie.
But as it happened, luck,
for the moment, was running with him.
lt's all right, really!
- l'm just, well-- Bless you.
- [ Hisses ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Meowing ]
Whoa, whoa!
Uh, easy, whoa! Ah.
Oh, no.
- So, ah... what's happening?
- [ Cow ] Oh, no.
Shh. Easy, easy.
- Good pig. Good pig.
- Huh? Huh?
Hold still.
Huh?
[ Laughing ]
[ Narrator ] There are many
perfectly nice cats in the world.
But every barrel
has its bad apples.
And it is well to heed
the old adage,
''Beware the bad cat
bearing a grudge.''
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Loud Thunderclap ]
- How are you feeling?
- A bit tired.
You'll need a good sleep to put you
in top condition tomorrow.
Don't stay up too late.
Good night.
[ Yawns ]
Good night, Mom.
Oh, do forgive me
for scratching you, dear.
l got a bit carried away.
lt's a cat thing.
Oh. Well-- [ Chuckles ]
But oh--
Feeling good about tomorrow,
are you?
Mm-hmm. lt should be all right,
l think.
l probably shouldn't say this,
but l'm not sure if you realize...
how much the other animals are laughing
at you for this sheepdog business.
Why would they do that?
Well, they say that you've forgotten
that you're a pig. lsn't that silly?
They even say that you
don't know what pigs are for.
What do you mean?
- You know... why pigs are here.
- Why are any of us here?
Well, the cow's here
to be milked.
The dogs are here to help
the boss's husband with the sheep.
And l'm here to be beautiful
and affectionate to the boss.
- Yes?
- [ Sighs ]
The fact is that pigs
don't have a purpose.
Just like ducks
- l don't--
- All right, for you own sake,
l'll be blunt.
Why do the bosses keep ducks?
To eat them.
So why do the bosses
keep a pig?
The fact is that animals that
don't seem to have a purpose
really do have a purpose.
The bosses have to eat. lt's probably
the most noble purpose of all...
when you come
to think about it.
They eat pigs?
Pork, they call it.
Or bacon.
They only call them pigs
when they're alive.
But, uh, l'm a sheep pig!
[ Chuckles ]
The boss's husband's just
playing a little game with you.
Believe me, sooner or later,
every pig gets eaten.
That's the way
the world works.
Oh! l haven't upset you,
have l? [ Chuckles ]
[ Whimpers ]
- Mom?
- Mm-hmm.
- Mom!
- Good heavens!
What on earth are you doing
out in the rain?
You should be looking after yourself
with such a big day ahead of you.
- Are pigs for eatin'?
- [ Gasps ] Who told you that?
The cat told me. Pigs don't have
a purpose except to be eaten.
ls it true?
lt's true.
For many pigs, it's true.
So my mother, my father,
my brothers and my sisters,
- all--
- Probably, dear.
- Do you want to talk about it?
- No, it's all right.
l understand.
l'll be all right.
Even... the boss?
Yes, dear.
[ Sighs ]
[ Ferdinand lmitating Alarm Clock ]
Ooh! Ooo!
[ Quacking ]
Babe?
Babe!
[ Fly ]
Babe's run away.
Rex?
Please?
Call the boss.
[ Barking ]
- [ Barks ]
- [ Barking ]
[ Quivering, Sniffing ]
He's over here.
Hold on, Pig.
You'll be home soon.
[ Quivering ]
He's got a cold, but that doesn't
explain a pig not eating.
He's got me stonkered, Arthur.
But l can tell you this.
lf you don't get fluids into him soon,
you're gonna lose him.
C'mon, son.
Pull yourself together.
The boss needs you.
[ Door Closes ]
Here we go.
Come on, Pig.
Ah, come on.
There's my boy.
Come on, then.
Come on.
[ Shouts ]
- [ Moos ]
- [ Quacking ]
[ Clanking Noise ]
[ Munching Sounds ]
[ Man ] Listen, Arthur,
l'll tell you what we can do.
You're listed third, but we can
put you last in the program.
However, you must be here by 3:30;
otherwise you'll be disqualified.
All right.
And welcome back to the National Grand
Challenge Sheepdog Trials...
coming today from the Kingsmith Show
Ground in the heart of sheep country.
The weather's been patchy,
but we've already seen some wonderful
work by these talented dogs.
Stay there.
Excuse me, sheep.
Hello! Hello!
Good morning to you all!
[ Bleats ]
l've never met a sheep
with such a strong, dark face.
- Are they feeding you well?
- [ Bleats ]
Babe, l'll try.
All right, blockheads!
Pay attention over here!
Now, you pay attention
to what this pig has to say...
or l'll come in there
and rip you to shreds!
Hadn't thought of this. Keep talking
to them. l'll see what l can do.
- Doesn't it look a picture?
Our show ground on the telly!
- Apart from the weather.
- Look! There's your Bert!
- [ TV Commentator ] Bert Ford
and Sweep doing very well.
- Sweep's having a little trouble
with this gate, Clive.
- A lot of trouble actually.
- That's going to set Bert back.
- Don't worry, Valda.
Just a little slipup.
Look, he's doing
much better now.
[ Commentator ] Too many loose sheep.
And Sweep's usually such a reliable dog.
Hey, whoa.
Stop!
lf those sheep won't talk to Babe,
the boss is going to look like an idiot.
- l don't know what to do.
- There is one thing.
l gotta go!
l'll try to be back in time.
Ahem. lt must've been
terrible weather for you,
- out in the field with
all this rain we've been having.
- [ Bleats ]
Hey, that dog's
in a hurry.
Come on, Nick,
l got a beer and a TV waiting.
[ P.A. Announcer ] The last entry
is Pig. Owner, A. Hoggett.
- Was that ''Hoggett''?
- l think it was!
- Huh?
- He said Hoggett.
lt was clear as a bell.
Must be another Hoggett. We only have
the two dogs, and they certainly...
aren't--
[ Sighs ]
Wolf! Wolf!
[ Sheep ]
Shut up, you morons!
The little pig's in trouble.
What trouble has come
to our Babe, wolf?
The sheep at the trials
won't talk to the little fellow.
They won't listen.
He doesn't know what to do.
Don't know what
we could do to help.
- lt's not right to give help to a wolf.
- You wait here, wolf.
You'll have to speak up.
l'm a... little hard of hearing.
l asked you
to wait here, wolf.
Do what you're told
by an old sheep for a change.
We'll see
what we can do for you.
Work completed.
Restore power.
[ Commentator ] Very frustrating
to be sitting up here...
wondering
what's causing the delay.
We have someone on their way
to the judges' rooms now.
We'll tell you what's causing
the problem as soon as we find out.
- Perhaps it's a drug test?
- Yeah, it could be.
- [ Moos ]
- l've never heard of a drug test
at a sheepdog contest before.
We've got somethin' here
that might be of use to our pig.
[ Sheep ]
Password! Password!
Before we gives you anythin',
- you'll be makin' us a solemn promise.
- [ Rex ] Yes?
- Treat us civil!
- Yes! You gotta treat us nice-like.
l'll try.
- No bitin'!
- That's right.
Wolf must avoid bitin' us sheep...
- at all costs!
- All right! l'll try that too.
lt's preposterous!
We'd be the laughingstock of
every sheepdog organization...
- in every civilized country
in the world!
- There's no rule--
We'll see about that when
the adjudication committee
have finished their meeting.
What will we have next year,
a laughing hyena doing show jumping?
But the most important of all,
you must promise...
never ever to let this password
we be about to give...
to be used against
any sheep anywhere.
l promise you that.
l'll make sure the pig knows it too.
- We have the promise!
- 'Tis for Babe.
Maa would have wanted it.
Baa, ram, ewe.
[ Sheep ]
To your breed, your fleece,
your clan be true.
Sheep be true.
Baa, ram, ewe.
ls that it?
ls that the password?
[ Clapping ln Unison ]
Mr. Hoggett, the judges
would like me to convey to you...
their disappointment
that a man such as yourself,
with a long and honorable
association with the work of
National Sheepdog Association,
should see fit to flout...
the historic conventions
which have long ruled our sport.
However we find there
is no rule, as such,
which would prevent your...
animal... being entered.
The committee has ruled
that if you wish to proceed,
there is nothing we can do
to stop you.
What do you wish
to do?
[ Clapping Continues ]
[ Commentator ] There appears
to be some movement down there now.
l expect if there are
no further problems,
we shall see Hoggett
and his dog Pig.
- Unusual name. Strange name, isn't it?
- Pig.
Anyone for a game
of cards?
- [ Commentator ]
Oh, good grief! Look!
- [ Gasps ]
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughter Continues ]
[ Man ]
He's a fool!
[ P.A. Announcer ] Entry number 23,
Mr. A. Hoggett with Pig.
[ Crowd Laughing ]
[ Commentator ]
This is just too crazy to believe.
And if that isn't enough.
We have a stray dog on the field.
They trying to round him up?
The dog's gonna give a few tips
on how to be a sheep pig.
[ Laughing ]
[ Panting ]
Well,
it's up to him now.
Away to me, Pig.
[ Crowd Laughing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Get off!
Baa, ram, ewe.
Baa, ram, ewe!
To your breed, your fleece,
your clan be true.
Sheep be true.
Baa, ram, ewe.
What...
what did you say?
[ Man ]
Get yourself a dog, Hoggett.
[ Sobbing ]
There, there, Esme.
lt's not the end of the world.
[ Commentator ] ls he just going to
stand there until his time runs out?
Or could this be
some sort of protest?
Maybe we should line up an
interview with the sheep pig?
Or the sheep pig's trainer.
He's a lively sort of fellow
by the looks of things.
[ Commentator ]
Good heavens!
[ Laughter Ceases ]
- Hey!
- Shh.
[ Horse ]
lt's Babe!
l-l--
- lt, uh--
- Hmm.
Oh, beautifully done! l can't
tell you how grateful l am to y'all.
Now, for one last favor.
lf the three ladies with collars
would kindly walk out of the ring,
l'd be very much obliged.
[ Cheering ]
[ Narrator ] And so it was that
in all the celebration,
in all the hubbub
of noise and excitement,
there were two figures
who stood silent and still...
side by side.
[ Crowing ]
[ Ferdinand Laughing ]
The pig did it! The perfect score!
Yippee! Yippee!
[ Narrator ] And though
every single human in the stands
or in the commentary boxes...
was at a complete loss
for words,
the man, who in his life had uttered
fewer words than any of them...
knew exactly what to say.
That'll do, Pig.
That'll do.
[ Sighs ]
[ Mouse ] And a-one and a-two
and a-three. Hit it.
[ Mice Giggling ]