[Dramatic mu sic playing]
[Thu nder]
[Birds squ awking]
[Bu s bell rings]
You r friend is late.
He"II be here.
Oh. Yeah?
I do have other bidders.
I personally vou ch for this man.
Oh. Well.
I tru st you . Michael. Bu t...
you see. With each degree
of separation...
comes a degree of u ncertainty.
Mr. Tu rner.
Mr. Vas.
The KGB once tried
to set me u p...
so I had to kill
three of their agents...
and then I hu nted down
their families.
The point is. If I sense
anything ou t of the ordinary......
No. The point is. I haven"t seen
anything from you yet...
to ju stify a payment
of $20 million.
So. Before I hand over
a small fortu ne...
and risk my life.
I want to know 100%% % ...
that you can. In fact.
deliver the device.
That"s the point.
Very well.
Michelle... owner"s manu al.
This is you r show of good faith?
Well. You "re still alive.
You consider that
a show of good faith.
- What do you have for me?
- Down payment... $1 million.
So. When do I get the device?
Let"s say ten days.
VAS: Michael.
you take that telephone...
and I will call you
and tell you how to proceed.
You keep it on you all the time.
As for you . Sir.
the next time we meet...
I su ggest you be on time.
Nice coat.
Well done.
See you arou nd.
- So far. So good?
- Yeah. So far.
- Kevin"s got a tail.
- Is it Vas?
They don"t look Ru ssian.
bu t they don"t look friendly.
We"d better go back for him.
You ordered u s not
to jeopardize ou r cover. Sir.
Hey. Tu rn left.
Tu rn left!
[Choru s singing]
[Gru nts]
[Tires screech]
Kill him!
- Ambu sh on the castle steps.
- Come on. Faster. ...
Let"s go!
[Gru nting and shou ting]
[AII screaming]
Get down! Get down!
There he is! Pu II over!
You "re jeopardizing the mission.
Uhh!
You are the mission.
God. That was close.
Did you see who they were?
[Choru s singing]
Kevin?
Doesn"t this all smack
of extreme desperation?
A nu clear bomb that fits neatly
into a carry-on su itcase?
Kevin spends two years
getting close to these people...
in order to position you
as the bu yer.
Vas won"t deal
with anyone else...
and we have nine days
to make this work.
l"d say desperation
was the order of the day.
Maybe Vas set Kevin u p.
My gu ess is.
it"s a rival bu yer.
Cou Id be Pakistanis.
Chechnyans. North Koreans.
- Libyans.
- Try the entire Middle East.
Adrik Vas is a bu sinessman.
He"II take anyone"s money.
Why kill Kevin
if they cou Id ju st ou tbid him?
We have deeper pockets.
He priced them ou t of the game.
- Who do you think it is?
- Well. The cold war is over.
These gu ys
don"t wave flags anymore...
and fanaticism.
terrorism is global.
Whoever it is decided
to eliminate the competition...
and force Vas to deal with them.
OAKES: So. The fu tu re
of the so-called free world...
may rest in
this you ng man"s hands.
[Rap mu sic playing]
Jake Hayes here...
Big-time Tickets.
Whatever you want. L"II get you .
Yankees. Third base line.
Knicks. Cou rtside.
Rangers. On the ice.
Masters. L"II pu t you
on Tiger"s tee. A"ight?
No matter what you want.
I got it for you .
[Beep] Big-time Tickets.
What you need?
Come on. Man. You call me
three hou rs before tipoff...
against the Lakers?
The Knicks sell ou t every game.
Since I like you . For 850.
l"II get you section 24. Row 9.
Twelve back from the bench.
Right behind Woody
with a good view of Spike...
u nless he"s got that
tu rban thing on his head...
Iookin" like Yasser Araneck.
Check.
Hold on a second. [Beep]
What"s u p? Big-time Tickets.
Jake Hayes. What you want?
Checkmate.
"Lion King"? I can"t do that.
[Beep] Jake Hayes here.
Big-time Tickets.
Mr. Johnson. You gonna
go to the game tonight...
or you want to do some bu siness?
Shit. He"s kickin" you r ass!
Don"t look at me.
You need to watch that castle...
"bou t to bitch-slap you r bishop.
Ehhhh! You lose. Opie.
Damn!
OK. So l"II give you
fou r hu ndred for the two.
- Yo. Jake. Let"s get a slice.
- Hold on one second.
[Beep]
Hello? Big-time Tickets.
Hey. Man. I can"t.
You always workin".
Hey. Honey. What"s u p?
OK. L"m gonna
pick you u p from work.
Then we"II talk all abou t it.
Love you . Too. Bye.
[Beep] I gotta pick u p
my girl. Man.
So check this ou t...
you "re gonna do this. Right?
l"m gonna do this.
You "re gonna do this.
Then you "re gonna do this.
Bu t l"m gonna do this...
and when you "re
thinkin" abou t this...
l"m gonna do this.
Then the game"s over.
So why don"t you
give me $20 right now...
- And we"II save twenty minu tes?
- Screw you .
You didn"t know chess
was a contact sport. Did you?
[Indistinct chattering]
Hey. Honey.
MAN: Ju lia Benson.
She"s a nu rse"s aide.
They"ve been together
three years.
She lives with her sister
and brother-in-law...
in Jersey City.
Amazing resemblance
to Kevin. Sir.
Yeah. [Tape winding back]
Like seeing a ghost.
I don"t know how
you "re gonna react.
Heh.
Come on. Wait a minu te.
I shou Id"ve known.
The mood swings.
the weight gain.
What weight gain?
You "re pregnant.
I want everybody to know.
Hey. Everybody!
My woman"s havin" a baby.
and we"re gettin" married!
[AII cheer and applau d]
l"m not pregnant.
We don"t have to get married.
Marriage is a big step.
We shou Id wait a while.
We"re you ng.
l"m moving to Seattle.
Seattle. Like.
Seattle Su personics. Seattle?
Wait a minu te.
That"s pretty far.
I got offered a job there.
What kind of job
are you gonna get in Seattle...
that you can"t get in New York?
A friend of mine
from ju nior college called.
- Who?
- Kenneth.
You r ex-man Ken?
He"s managing a company
ou t there. And he offered.
So. You "re leaving me
and going back to Ken.
No.
- Are you leaving me?
- Sort of. Bu t it"s not......
So. You "re leaving me
and going back to Kenneth?
- That"s what I asked you .
- The Ken part is ju st bu siness.
And what"s the leaving me part?
Pleasu re?
Pain.
You r sister pu t you u p to this.
She never liked me.
- It"s been three years. Jake.
- I know it"s been three years.
We"re in the same situ ation
that we were in when we met.
Meaning. We"re not married.
We"re not married.
we can"t afford to get married.
And it doesn"t look like
it"s ever gonna change.
You know. Poor people
do get married.
I know. Bu t I don"t feel
like fighting with you...
every day becau se we"re broke.
Marriage is hard enou gh
withou t being poor.
Hey. What happened to the love?
What happened
to all that romance?
You know I love you .
Bu t you are living
in this fantasy.
It"s like you "re waiting
for some kind of miracle.
I gotta live in reality.
I am not gonna be you ng forever.
So you gotta pu t you rself
back on the market...
while the merchandise
is still fresh.
You act like there"s
a damn expiration date...
on you r forehead!
Come on. Come on.
l"m sorry. L"m sorry.
You think I like
living like this?
Movin" tickets. Hu stlin" chess.
DJing at these little clu bs?
I shou Id"ve stayed in college.
I messed u p.
l"II go back to college.
I love you . Jake.
I love you . Too.
Bu t l......
[Somber mu sic playing]
So. When are you leaving?
Cou ple weeks. Bu t l...
We"II talk before then.
Why?
Jake.
[Rap mu sic playing]
- What"s u p. Man?
- Hey. What"s u p?
- What"s wrong?
- Ju lie left me.
Sorry. I gotta go.
Bu t l"II catch you tomorrow.
[New sonng plays]
# l´mm all ouut of love #...
# l´mm so lost witlhouut youu #...
# I knnow youu wenre nriglht #...
# Believinng fonr so lonng #...
# l´mm all ouut of love #...
# Wlhat amm I witlhouut youu? #...
# I cann´t be too late... #...
Hey. You get
you r shit together...
or l"m gonna have
to fire you r ass!
WOMAN: That"s right!
# I wannt youu to comme back
annd canrnry mme lhomme #...
# Away fnromm tlhese lonng.
Ionnely nniglhts #...
# Tlhenre´s nno easy way #...
# It gets lhanrdenr eaclh day #...
# Please love mme
onr l´ll be gonne #...
# l´ll be gonne #...
# l´mm all ouut of love #...
# l´mm so lost witlhouut youu #...
# I knnow youu wenre nriglht #...
# Believinng fonr so lonng #...
# l´mm all ouut of love #...
# Wlhat amm I witlhouut youu? #...
# It cann´t be too late #...
# To say tlhat I was so wnronng #...
[Cell phone rings]
Ju lie. L"m sorry.
Oh. L"m sorry.
Big-time Tickets.
Yeah. For what game?
How mu ch you want to spend?
Yeah. I can get it.
So. Wlhenre youu at?
Wlhenre tlhe lhell´s tlhat?
[Dramatic mu sic playing]
Thank you very mu ch.
Now. Take off.
DRIVER: Whatever.
- Hop ou t.
- Hey. What"s u p?
- Give me you r phone.
- What"s u p?
Hey! Come on. Now!
What y"all want?
- Hey. Come on!
- Relax.
You know how hard it was for me
to get a cab to come u p here?
I hope y"all givin" me
a ride back.
I know you "re cops. Man.
What do you want. Money?
Oh. I u nderstand.
Y"all shot somebody.
and now y"all need a su spect.
OAKES:
Mr. Hayes? Jacob Hayes?
l"m Officer Oakes.
that"s Officer Seale...
Officer Swanson. Officer Carew.
CIA? What"s that for?
"Crackers In my Ass? "
You "re gonna arrest me
for scalpin" tickets?
We ju st want to talk to you
abou t something.
- Abou t what?
- Abou t you r brother.
You got the wrong gu y.
I don"t even have a brother.
That"s ju st a pictu re
of me in a su it.
You cou Id"ve got that
off the internet.
I saw a pictu re of Bill Gates
with three titties on the net.
OK. September 8. 1970...
Bellevu e Hospital.
New York City...
a woman registered
as Mary Jeffries...
gives birth
to identical twins...
bu t su ffers complications
and dies the next day.
- What abou t the father?
- Thomas B. Jeffries.
Presu med alive.
Whereabou ts u nknown.
The state
rarely separates twins...
bu t one of the infants...
Jacob... that"s you ......
was diagnosed
with severe lu ng infection.
You still have the scar
from the chest tu be...
the incision mark.
An administrator at the hospital
altered the birth record...
to give the healthy child
a better chance at adoption.
A week later.
Roger and Glenda Pope...
took in Kevin Jeffries.
The Popes never knew.
Kevin never knew.
So. I have a twin brother.
Big deal.
What"s the CIA
have to do with this?
He cou Idn"t send me a letter?
You r brother"s dead.
How?
A helicopter crash.
We need you r help. Mr. Hayes.
You r brother was working
on something with u s.
My twin brother was CIA?
Yeah. A clandestine operative.
And ju st before he was killed.
he set u p a deal.
What kind of deal?
A very important one.
So. We need you to stand
in for him. Ju st briefly.
- Pretend l"m him?
- Yeah.
- For how long?
- Nine days.
Nine days is not standin" in.
Standin" in is an hou r.
Nine days is goin" on tou r.
- Is this shit dangerou s?
- There"s some risk.
What kind of risk?
We talkin" bad credit risk...
or a bu Ilet in the ass risk?
- You "d be well compensated.
- For a bu Ilet in the ass risk?
I hope that"s a lot
of compensation. How mu ch?
Throw ou t a nu mber.
- A billion dollars.
- You "ve overshot.
I don"t know what kind of bu dget
you "re working with.
We were thinking
somewhere in the region of...
let"s say... $25.000.
Fifty. Yeah. Fifty.
I figu re you started with 25.
so I know you got more.
You ain"t gonna give me
all you r money. 50.000.
This is what l"m thinking.
Mr. Hayes.
With $25.000. You r girlfriend
Ju lie cou Id go to college.
She wou Idn"t have to go
to Seattle.
Or work with Ken.
OK. Here"s what l"m thinkin".
You "re gonna give me
$50.000 tax-free.
OK. 50.000 after taxes
after the job is done.
Half now. Half after.
Ten now. Forty after.
Unless my mother had triplets...
you "re gonna give me ten now.
ninety after.
OK. You got a deal.
- So. When do we start?
- Now.
This is you r brother"s file.
Stu dy it.
JAKE: So there"s homework.
- Preparation.
- OK.
Let"s see. Dad sits on the board
of the New York Stock Exchange.
Mom. Co-artistic director...
at Lincoln Center.
Mu st"ve been nice.
In my foster hou se.
we were so poor...
we u sed to lick stamps
for dinner.
Let"s see.
Prep school at Exeter.
Then college at Dartmou th.
Served in the Naval Academy.
- That"s right.
- What"d he serve. Lu nch?
Oh. Man. "Rhoades scholar."
- So my brother was real smart?
- Yeah.
Damn. The CIA is cheap.
Y"all cou Id"ve got me
a qu een size.
What"s this. Jack size?
Hey. What"s "Záchod" mean?
It"s Czech for "bathroom."
You "II find the room labelled
with phonetic translations.
Why?
Becau se the deal goes down
in the Czech Repu blic.
- Czech Repu blic?
- Here"s a dictionary.
How do I get an ou tside line?
I need somebody to feed my cat.
You don"t have
an ou tside line or a cat.
So what am I
su pposed to be doing here?
There"s a tape in the VCR.
It"s a video of you r brother.
Watch it. The way he talks
and the way he moves.
I know there"s a lot
to deal with here...
bu t we"re all behind you .
We"II start in the morning.
You got any qu estions?
Yeah. If my brother
was su ch a geniu s...
then how come he"s dead?
- 5 A.M.
- Hey. I don"t do 5 A.M.
So. Bottom line.
what are ou r chances?
l"d say anywhere between
nil and zero.
Why do you say that?
I grant you .
he"s got potential.
He"s pretty street-smart.
In 6 months. He cou Id probably
fool his brother"s parents.
Bu t eight days?
You gotta be kidding.
Probably get himself
killed on this mission...
and anyone else
who goes along with him.
Wou Id you like to be replaced
on the mission?
Why? You "re going ahead
with or withou t me?
That"s precisely
what l"m saying.
Well. Sir. When do I tell him
what this mission involves?
If I were you . I wou Id tell him
as little as possible.
Don"t pu t anything
into his head he can"t u se...
and certainly nothing that
cou Id pop ou t at the wrong time.
- OK.
- What"s he doing now?
SWANSON: He"s stu dying.
We told him to learn...
a few key phrases in Czech.
[Reciting Czech words]
He seems dedicated.
What"s he saying?
He said. "I haven"t had
my period in three months."
[Jake continu es reciting
Czech words]
Now what?
"Where"s the hospital?
I have a vaginal infection."
This is gonna be
really interesting.
Can"t wait to get started.
Rise and shine. Mr. Hayes!
5 A. M... and all is well.
How abou t three more hou rs
of sleep and some breakfast?
How abou t a nice shower?
Aah! Aah! Hey!
What"s wrong with you?!
Good morning.
Today we"II be covering
basic operations protocol...
for the acqu isition
of foreign assets...
a procedu re we like to call
"The Three l"s"......
identifying the target.
initiating the contact...
and infiltrating the network...
OAKES:
Now you do it like him.
Man. This is bu ggin" me ou t.
I feel like Michael Jackson...
Iookin" at old albu m covers.
Look at this gu y.
He looks like me.
bu t it"s not me.
- Yeah.
- So. What did he like to do?
What kind of sports was he into?
What kind of mu sic
did he listen to?
He liked mu sic.
Jazz and classical.
- Classical. Like Ru n-DMC?
- He didn"t like rap.
What 29-year-old brother
don"t like a little bit of rap?
He didn"t listen to rap.
So. What kind of sports
was he into?
Skiing.
OK. So you got skiing.
the Navy. No rap.
We"d have had a lot in common.
- Sir.
- Hmm?
[Whispering]
OAKES: What time?
OK. All right.
Thanks.
So. What"s u p with
you and Swanson?
- Hmm?
- Aw. Come on. Man.
I see there"s something
goin" on there.
You got a little
something goin" on. ...
Look at you . You "re blu shing.
Do you mind if I say something
to you . Mr. Hayes?
My friends. Officer Seale.
Officer Swanson...
they have faith in you .
I don"t.
And that creates a problem...
becau se you "re in so deep
with u s now...
we can never let you go.
So you "d better
learn this stu ff...
stone-cold by 0500 hou rs
tomorrow morning.
Or what?
l"II kill you .
Can we start
a few hou rs later tomorrow?
Aah! Aah!
Aaah!
OAKES: Get dressed.
It"s 4:59!
# Tlhe nnew tenrnronrs inn nrock #...
# Onn evenry block #...
# Late fonr sclhool.
late fonr wonrk #...
# Buut alhead of tlhese cops #...
# My cnredit is slhot.
ennd uup dead inn a box #...
# Buut so mmy life
ainn´t as patlhetic as Pac´s #...
# Riglht away
blow youunr life away #...
# So liglht youunr lhaze.
lhold tiglht gnrennades #...
# So wlhenn it blows
l´mm sliglhtly gnrazed #...
# Kuunniva mmiglht be cnrazed
uunnleaslhinn´ uunnlikely nrage #...
# Next timme youu lheanr a venrse
fnromm mme I mmiglht be caged #...
Swirl.
Checking for sediment.
Sniff...
[Inhales]
And taste.
[Sinnginng]
[Gru nts]
Morning. Mr. Hayes. 5 A.M.
JAKE: No. 5:01 .
[Mu sic playing]
# I believe inn people tnryinn´ #...
# I believe inn people cnryinn´ #...
# I believe
inn people bnreatlhinn´ #...
# I believe inn people beinn´ #...
Pope. Kevin Pope.
Ha ha ha! Look at this su it.
Man. I got initials on my cu ffs.
The only thing I ever have
on my cu ffs is steak sau ce.
They say "M.T."
What"s that for?
Michael Tu rner.
Bu t I thou ght I was Kevin Pope.
Kevin Pope is Michael Tu rner.
Michael Tu rner
is Kevin Pope"s cover identity.
He is a very su ccessfu I.
very knowledgeable...
very sophisticated
international dealer...
in fine antiqu ities.
Well. If l"m Jake Hayes
playing Kevin Pope...
playing Michael Tu rner.
then I shou Id get two checks.
SEALE: Cheers.
This is a very rare
expensive cognac.
What do you think?
[Piano playing]
Dry. Bu t never precociou s.
I love you r shirt.
Egyptian broadcloth?
[Click] Three days.
Pretty impressive.
Yeah. He"s bright.
- I think he can do it.
- He"s got my vote.
OAKES:
I said he was bright.
I didn"t say he was capable
of saving the world.
- Let"s ru n a real test.
- Like what?
Send him u p to New York.
Pu t him in Kevin"s apartment.
Let the neighbors. The doorman.
everybody get a look at him.
See if they bu y him
as Michael Tu rner.
Might even serve
a dou ble pu rpose.
Whoever tried to kill
Kevin as Michael Tu rner...
probably doesn"t know he"s dead.
Might still be looking for him.
So we dangle him as bait.
keep him in the dark.
- He"II be protected.
- What do we tell him?
You "re giving him a chance
to practice being Kevin.
That"s all you need to tell him.
You "re the boss.
OAKES: You see the van
in front of u s?
The one behind u s?
Those are ou r gu ys.
Here"s my cell phone nu mber.
Use it if you get
into any kind of trou ble.
- What kind of trou ble?
- Any kind.
Shark attack?
Call you . All right.
Cou Id you pop the tru nk?
Take this.
Get you rself some shoes.
Little pu nk.
DOORMAN:
Mr. Tu rner. Welcome back. Sir.
Thanks. Jim.
WOMAN: Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
How was Eu rope?
Like another cou ntry.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Whoo!
You cou Id pu t this on MTV Cnribs.
Man. This is dope!
God damn.
JAKE: So if I paid taxes...
this is where
the money wou Id go. Hu h?
Cou Id have
a Pu ffy party in here.
Let"s get some mu sic in here.
[Classical mu sic playing]
Whoa-oh-oh!
[Hip-hop mu sic playing]
OAKES: What"s that mu sic?
- Ju st hip-hop stu ff.
- It"s terrible.
SEALE: Jake. It"s you r
downstairs neighbor...
Mrs. Patterson.
[Doorbell rings]
Don"t forget the radio.
OK.
[Classical mu sic plays]
Hi. Michael! Welcome back.
Mwah. Mwah.
- Vera. How are you?
- Fine. Thank you .
Hi. Annabella.
We ju st came in and the doorman
said you were back.
- Annabella missed you .
- Oh. You "re far too kind.
l"ve been waiting desperately
for you to come back.
- Oh? Why?
- I bou ght a little treasu re.
Come on down and tell me
if I got a good bu y.
- Oh. OK.
- Hold you r baby.
- Yes. My baby.
- How was you r trip?
OAKES:
This is gonna be a disaster.
Hello! Go see you r nanny. Baby.
What do you think?
Is it a good piece?
Uh...
- It"s exqu isite.
- Ooh! Do you think?
Go ahead. Pick it u p. Feel it.
Ju st see how delicate it is.
Pick it u p. Right?
Yes. Ju st grab it
and pick it u p.
Michael...
that"s what we keep
the doggy treats in.
Of cou rse. I knew that.
I was ju st getting it...
ou t of the way
so I cou Id see the......
- The vase.
- Of cou rse. The vase! Yes!
May I ask. How mu ch
did you pay for this?
1 50.000.
Good lord! What you gonna
pu t in it. Cocaine?!
He fooled the doorman.
he fooled the neighbor...
and the neighbor"s dog.
What more do you want?
Oakes. We need to know
who"s after that bomb.
You "re willing
to sacrifice him to find ou t?
Don"t be dramatic.
He"s got plenty of protection.
l"II tell you when to pu II him.
[Sighs]
[Hip-hop mu sic playing]
# Nevenr safe.
youu´nre nnevenr suunre #...
# Sommetlhinn´s all wnronng #...
JAKE:
Hope y"all not watching this.
SWANSON: I don"t have
to watch this. Do I. Sir?
- Oh. No. Holy shit.
- Code red. Code red.
SEALE: Code red! Code red!
[Both yelling]
SEALE:
Parish. McCain. Cover the exits!
Help! Help! Help!
Raah!
[Yelling]
Unh!
God.
Whoa!
Aah!
Unh!
[Shou ts]
[Gru nts]
Sir. He"s headed for the roof.
- We need him alive.
- Yes. Sir.
- Whoa!
- Oh!
[Woman yells]
Drop the knife.
Hey. Elvis. If you drop
the knife and step down...
no one is gonna hu rt you .
[Panting]
[Yells]
So...
who"s got Jake?
[Hip-hop mu sic playing]
Aah!
Well. These last
ten minu tes will be u sed...
as a teaching aid on how
an operation can get totally......
- Screwed u p. Sir?
- Thank you .
We"II find him. Sir.
[Cell phone rings]
[Beep] Yeah? Where are you?
The corner of eat shit
and fu ck you!
l"m not gonna let you trace me!
Bye! L"II call you back!
[Beep]
[Honk]
MAN: l"m stu ck in traffic.
I ask you to do......
Give me that!
Yo!
Ru n fingerprints. DNA.
anything we can get...
on the gu y
who ju mped off the roof.
- Yes. Sir.
- He looks Afghani. Sir.
Don"t assu me anything.
Ju st find Jake. [Ring]
- Yes. Sir.
- Jake......
Kevin was mu rdered!
And they"re gonna mu rder me!
- Let"s meet some place...
- No more bu Ilshit!
[Beep]
We lost him
becau se we lied to him.
No. You lost him
becau se you lost him.
We treated him like an idiot.
He had a right to know
what we were doing with him.
We"re wasting time!
Find him and bring him back...
and spare me you r conscience.
Spare my conscience.
- Take it easy. Bu ddy.
- Bye.
# lt´s called clhillinn´ #...
# 6 mmillionn ways to live #...
# 6 mmillionn ways to live life #...
[Ring] Yeah?
Hello? Pam. It"s Jake.
Can I talk to Ju lie?
- She don"t want to talk to you .
- Who"s on the phone?
I need to talk to Ju lie.
Please. This is seriou s.
It is Jake?
Wait. Let me talk to him!
- She"s moving on.
- Give me the phone.
We don"t need
no more trou ble. Jake...
and you ain"t nothing
bu t trou ble.
Two su its came arou nd today
looking for you .
[Police siren]
JULIE: Give me the phone!
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Shit. You r phone"s tapped.
If Ju lie"s there.
tell her I love her...
and. Oakes. If you "re listening.
kiss my ass!
[Click]
- You get a trace?
- No.
Tch. He hu ng u p.
[Eclhoinng]
# lt´s called clhillinn´ #...
# 6 mmillionn ways to live #...
# 6 mmillionn ways
to live life... #...
OAKES:
Mr. Hayes. Where are you?
Where in the hell are you?
# 6 mmillionn ways
to live lavislh #...
[Lau ghing]
# 6 mmillionn ways to live #...
# 6 mmillionn ways
to live lavislh #...
# Beyonnd all tlhe mmisenry
annd mmatlhemmatic #...
# Fnromm tlhe 6 mmillionn ways
to live #...
# 6 mmillionn ways to live #...
JAKE: Ma.
- Help! Help!
- Ma!
- Ma! Ma! Ma!
- Somebody help!
Ma. Please! It"s me!
Ma. It"s me!
Jakey?
Yeah. Yeah.
You gonna break my arm.
[Click]
Well. What are you doing
in the dark?
Some people are looking for me.
- What did you do?
- I didn"t do nothin"!
It"s not what you think.
It"s not the police.
It"s way too hard to explain.
Look at this.
Eight foster kids l"ve taken
into my hou se over the years...
and all of them made something
of themselves...
and not one of them
had you r potential!
Oh. Come on. Ma!
Sellin". Scramblin"
and hu stlin".
Ma. Did you know
I had a brother?
Stop talking crazy.
You had lots of brothers.
How"s that nice girl
I met last Christmas?
She left me.
Hand me that u mbrella
so I can hit you again.
You know. Ma.
maybe it wasn"t my fau It?
- You need money?
- No.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I need money.
How mu ch do you need?
I won $250 at bingo.
It"s ju st for a little while.
l"II pay you back.
I know. [Chu ckles]
Want something to eat?
You know what?
I really gotta go.
l"m never giving u p
on you . Jakey.
You "re going to do something
to make me very prou d one day.
I know it. [Chu ckles]
[Fence clinks]
[Thu nder]
I owe you an apology.
You hear me?
I was ju st wondering how many
of you r people are listening in.
We"re alone.
No cameras. No wires.
Ju st me.
JAKE: You got the floor.
You r brother was assassinated.
By the same gu ys
who came after me. Right?
I gu ess so.
Doing the same job as you .
Which is what?
You r brother.
as Michael Tu rner...
was helping me bu y something
off the black market.
What? Cu ban cigars?
PlayStation 3? What?
I can"t tell you if you "re not
coming back in with u s.
l"m not comin" back in
if you ain"t telling me.
You r brother died saving
my life. Did you know that?
Wish it had been otherwise.
bu t that"s the way it is.
How are his parents taking it?
You didn"t tell his parents?
No. That"s the way we want it.
How wou Id you feel if you died
and nobody told you r wife?
l"m not married.
- There"s no Mrs. Spy?
- Not anymore.
Relationships and attachments
are u seless in this bu siness.
So that"s how this job is.
Even if they don"t shoot you .
they take you r life. ...
I know it sou nds hokey.
bu t I honestly believe...
ou r lives are abou t something
bigger than ou rselves...
and l"m offering you a chance
to commit you rself to something.
You ain"t offering me nothin"...
bu t a chance
at a bu Ilet in my ass.
I don"t see
the higher meaning in that.
Tell you what l"m gonna do.
- Thank you .
- No problem.
l"II go and sit in the car
and cou nt to ten...
and if you want to join me.
fine. And if not...
l"II tell the agency
I cou Idn"t find you .
We can"t pu II this job off
withou t you .
We need you .
Tch.
Think abou t it.
[Train whistle in distance]
[Sighs]
OAKES: Oh. Well.
That didn"t work. Did it?
JAKE: No.
"l"m gonna go ou tside
and cou nt to ten"?
Who the hell are you?
You "d have done better with
"Bitch. Get in the car."
[Mu tters]
OK. Get in the car...
bitch.
OAKES: This is the man
who tried to kill you .
We now know that he"s a member
of a mu Iti-national...
terrorist organization
led by this man.
Meet the man
who killed you r brother......
Dragan Adjanic.
He"s wanted by The Hagu e
for terrorist crimes...
against hu manity.
so he"s a fu gitive...
everywhere in the world.
inclu ding his own cou ntry.
He calls his movement
"The Black Hand."
His members
take a death pledge...
becoming su icide soldiers
to fu rther their cau se.
Last year. The FBI
cau ght fou r of his men...
in a Washington. D.C. Motel...
with enou gh u rea nitrate
to level the Capitol bu ilding.
He doesn"t like America
and he doesn"t like you .
- Wait a minu te. What did I do?
- He"s you r rival bu yer.
For the item
that this man has to sell.
Now. This is Adrik Vas.
He"s a Ru ssian ex-army colonel.
kingpin in the Ru ssian mafia.
Up to his neck in prostitu tion.
dru gs. And extortion.
Sou nds like anybody
I went to high school with.
This is Vas"s right-hand man.
His name is Michelle Petrov...
otherwise known as "The Hammer."
Remember these faces...
becau se you "re going
to be seeing them soon.
Why do they call this gu y
The Hammer?
Whoa! Ooh.
[Mu ffled yelling]
Aah! Wha... what?!
Good evening. Isn"t this fu n?
This is an exercise
known as King"s Game.
It"s meant to test
you r awareness.
What can you tell me
abou t you r attackers?
They woke me u p. Look. Man.
if you want me to spy...
- L"m gonna need my rest.
- How many were there?
Didn"t I ju st say
they woke me u p?!
That"s the weird thing
abou t an ambu sh.
Next time
we"II try and warn you .
Do you u nderstand
what happened to you ju st now?
- Yeah. I was jacked!
- No. You panicked.
When you thou ght you were
in danger. You r brain shu t down.
So what"s the point
of having a good brain...
if you can"t keep it operating?
My brain didn"t shu t down.
I knew it was Swanson...
"cau se I cou Id feel her tits
on my back.
I knew it was Carew "cau se
his breath smelled like shit.
Probably from kissing
you r ass so mu ch.
I knew it was Seale
becau se I took his wallet.
Hey. Seale. Why"s a married man
need a condom? You r wife know?
You want to know
how I knew it was you?
OK. Thank you .
Game"s over. Good night.
Oh. Where you going?
You gonna leave like that?
Come back!
Y"all got me u p!
Let"s do something!
Let"s hit a clu b or something.
Based on ou r
intelligence projections...
and the text manu al
provided by Agent Pope...
this is a mock-u p
of what you "II be bu ying.
Does it play DVDs?
It"s a portable
thermonu clear weapon.
- So that"s a bomb?
- It"s a reprodu ction.
Last year.
a Ru ssian su itcase bomb...
was stolen from a dismantling
facility in the Ural mou ntains.
You r brother tracked it down.
we need you to recover it.
Two things
you "re gonna have to do......
Wou Id one of them
be shittin" in my pants?
[Tires squ eal]
Welcome to Pragu e.
JAKE: Looks like Newark.
Welcome back to the hotel.
Mr. Tu rner.
Thank you .
Mr. Tu rner. So glad
to have you back. Sir.
Thank you . Lempenka.
Hope you haven"t
given ou t my room.
Certainly not. Sir.
This is beau tifu I.
Her name is Lenka.
You ju st called her "Lempenka."
which means "cardboard."
JAKE: Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Oh ho ho ho!
Man. It"s gonna be hard
to go back to Jersey.
We"II be in the su ite
across the hall...
with fu II video and au dio
su rveillance of this room.
All right. Now.
when I go to the bathroom...
press the pau se bu tton.
Ju st stay in the room. You "ve
got nothing to worry abou t.
Except for my little date
with a nu clear bomb.
OK. This is ou r lifeline.
Ou r only link to Adrik Vas.
Nothing happens till he calls.
Don"t let it ou t of you r sight.
And remember. From now on.
there"s no Jake...
there"s no Kevin.
only Michael Tu rner.
Well...
I think l"m gonna like
being Michael Tu rner.
# Pnretty wommann #...
Think maybe you want
to take a look at this.
# Pnretty wommann #...
OK. What the hell"s
he u p to now?
# Pnretty wommann #...
[Women giggling]
[Song continu es in Czech]
Hey!
Fish egg?
[Women lau ghing]
Belu ga. Sir.
It"s 1 2.000 crowns an ou nce.
Party"s over.
Naw. The party ju st started.
Soon as y"all leave...
l"m gonna have my ass bu ffed.
[Women lau ghing]
Hey! This little piggy
go to market...
Make su re you pu t
my initials on the big toe.
People need to know
whose feet this is.
[Cell phone rings]
That"s Vas.
Where"s the cell phone?
Phone. Phone. Phone.
[Ringing]
Thank you .
[Giggling]
Shhh!
Hello?
Yeah. We"II be there.
[Beep]
It"s Vas.
The deal"s on in an hou r.
WELLS: Now you r eye.
[Beeping]
Look right into
the compu ter screen.
Blink for confirmation.
OK. That"s it.
All right.
From this point on...
only you will be able
to access you r compu ter.
It won"t operate withou t
you r retinal signatu re......
you r eyes... so when they show you
the bomb. Connect you r laptop...
determine if the bomb
is the real thing...
and take enou gh time doing it...
so Wells cann downnload
tlheinr anrmminng codes...
annd lhopefuully
tlheinr disanrmminng codes...
innto ouunr commpuutenr.
Good luuck. Mnr. Hayes.
[Whirs]
We have visu al.
OAKES: You "II do fine.
Everyone"s nervou s
the first day of school.
I always cu t
Don"t worry. You "re covered
from every angle.
I can"t wait to meet
"The Hammer."
Oh. These gu ys
mu st be "The Toolbox."
Shou Id we move in. Sir?
No. Not u ntil we"re su re
they brou ght the bomb.
There"s too mu ch at stake.
Nice coat.
Gentlemen. Are we going
to do bu siness or aren"t we?
Depends. Michael.
Where have you been
for the last nine days?
I don"t believe
that concerns you .
On the contrary.
It concerns me very mu ch.
We make a deal. You disappear.
Doesn"t look good. My friend.
Heads u p. McCain.
Be advised. Targets are armed.
Maintain you r positions.
Everyone maintain you r position.
Copy that. Sir.
Do we have a problem?
I don"t know. You tell me.
Do we?
Give me the cell phone
I gave you earlier.
Don"t worry.
I only made collect calls.
Look. I don"t know what
this is abou t. Bu t......
No. You don"t. So shu t u p.
Neither does Mr. Tu rner.
You see. This cell phone
has a global positioning system.
In a moment. It"II tell me
exactly where you "ve been...
the last nine days.
Fantastic. Eh?
[Beeping]
Well. Haven"t you been bu sy?
Oh. You get arou nd.
Berlin. Rome. Zu rich. Heh.
And not one decent treasu re
to show for it.
Now. Where"s the money?
Where"s the produ ct?
Nearby.
So. How do we do this?
l"m gonna call you
on this cell phone...
then you have one hou r
to get the money. Michael.
Then l"II call you again
and tell you...
where to bring it to.
You u nderstand?
JAKE: l"m gonna have to ru n
some tests...
so make su re you bring
au thentic merchandise.
Fair enou gh.
I wou Idn"t bu y a car...
withou t checking
u nder the hood. Ha!
Are we agreed?
Yes.
OAKES: No. We"re not
bringing money anywhere.
No?
l"II have someone transfer
the remaining 19 million...
when Mr. Tu rner tells u s
we have a viable device.
It"II be done by compu ter.
One of my men will be
standing by at this address.
You will send
one of you r brain tru sts...
to verify the money is in
you r accou nt. And that"s it.
Give you a hostage?
And you get one. We"II call it
a secu rity deposit...
which neither of u s
will get back if we screw u p...
or if we leave a mess.
It"s that simple.
Now we have an agreement.
I think.
Agreed.
Don"t you go disappearing
on me again. Michael.
Hey. You did real well.
Mr. Hayes.
You knew they wou Idn"t
bring it. Right?
Uh-hu h.
Standard procedu re.
Gu ys like him won"t risk...
getting screwed
on the first date.
What if you hadn"t changed
the chip in the phone?
It wou Id have told him
that the phone had already...
traveled to CIA
headqu arters in Langley...
and they wou Id have shot
both of u s in the heads.
- L"m hu ngry. How abou t you?
- L"m gonna pass.
Then good night.
[Shower ru nning]
[Soft mu sic playing]
# Evenn if I #...
# Fonrget wlhy #...
# Youu´ll always give mme #...
# Annotlhenr nreasonn #...
# Tlhis is nno emmpty pnrommise #...
# I cann depennd uuponn it #...
# Youu´ll always
love mme like tlhat #...
Oh! Michael!
Hi.
This place comes
with everything. Hu h?
Cou Id you get me a towel?
[Lau ghs] Very fu nny. Ahem.
[Sigh]
I knew you "d be su rprised.
I didn"t think you "d be shocked.
Aw.
You want some room service?
No. L"d like a good stiff drink.
- Oh. Shit. It"s Nicole.
- What?
This isn"t exactly
the welcome I expected.
Wassu p?
[Sigh] Honey. I made
dinner reservations...
- At ou r favorite place.
- I love that place.
Honey. Aren"t you happy
to see me?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Aah.
- Mm.
[Knock on door]
[Tongu e-tied]
I gotta get that.
l"II be right back.
[Sigh]
How are you doing?
- You see how l"m doing.
- Yeah. We have a problem.
Where l"m from.
people pay a lot of money...
for problems like that.
That"s Nicole.
That"s Michael"s girlfriend.
She works for CNN in Eu rope.
So how come didn"t you tell me
Michael had a girlfriend?
Well. They broke u p
several weeks ago.
They had a fight.
and she walked ou t.
Well. It looks like
she forgave him.
What the hell did he fight
with her fine ass for?
Well. Apparently
he had intimacy problems.
He was distant.
some kind of psychotherapy crap.
Anyway. She went off
to cover the Balkans.
OK. So what do you
want me to do?
Take her to dinner. She"s CNN.
If you handle this badly.
she cou Id blow you r cover. OK?
- OK.
- Good.
...Cheat.
Ju st... don"t cheat...
ju st... don"t cheat...
ju st say...
That was Jehovah"s Witnesses!
- Ju st...
- Michael...
I hope you "re hu ngry. Baby.
# Slhe´s willinn´ to slhanre.
we lhoppinn´ inn tlhe wlhip #...
# Annd we leavinn´ lhenre. So
sommebody tuunrnn tlhe mmuusic uup... #...
Yeah. I ju st gotta
go bru sh my teeth.
# Evenrybody comme onn.
knnock it uup tonniglht #...
# Onne of tlhese ladies... #...
Ohhh.
[Telephone rings.
answering machine clicks]
Hey! Youu´ve nreaclhed
tlhe nresidennce of Pamm...
Manvinn. Juulie. Annd tlhe kids.
Leave a mmessage at tlhe tonne.
JAKE: Ju lie. It"s Jake.
Are you there?
OK. If you haven"t left yet.
please wait for me.
Please. Please. I got a new job.
It"s totally legit.
And l"ve changed.
l"ve totally changed.
l"m a new man.
l"m the man who loves you .
I love you . I love you so mu ch.
I didn"t even know how mu ch
I loved you till 2 minu tes ago.
JULIE: It"s Jake.
- Ju lie!
- I love him!
No. You don"t!
Honey. What"s taking you
so long?
Big sacrifices.
Please wait for me.
Jake. I heard you .
I heard every word. Baby.
l"m not going anywhere.
l"II be right here.
I love you so mu ch!
[Beep] Jake?
RECORDING. : If youu´d like
to mmake a call...
Jake? Hello! Jake!
If youu´d like to mmake a call...
[New song begins]
[Nicole sighs]
# I nneed to finnd a place #...
# A lhiglhenr space #...
Thank you .
# Wlhenre I cann get ovenryouu #...
# ´Cauuse
youu wenre so fanr away... #...
So are you gonna make me grovel?
No. Not u nless you want to.
Is this fish?
Yeah. Of cou rse. You love fish.
That"s right. I love fish...
bu t that"s before
I became a vegetarian.
Oh. Waiter. Waiter!
I can"t eat this.
Can you get me something else?
How abou t a steak.
mediu m well. Please.
- Of cou rse. Sir.
- Ah. Thanks a lot.
I thou ght
you were a vegetarian.
Vegetarian? L"II eat a pig"s ass
if they cook it right.
Bu t enou gh abou t me.
How abou t those Balkans?
I missed you . Michael.
l"m sorry I left.
# I feel alonne #...
# Gonne. Nruunn fnromm mme #...
# I tnried to tell mmyself... #...
What"s the matter?
There"s somebody else.
There is? Hmm.
When did that happen?
- Right after you left.
- I left you two weeks ago.
I mean...
Did you meet her here in Pragu e?
No. In Jersey.
New Jersey?
Yeah. I was in New York...
and Jersey"s
right next to New York...
and I ju st took
a little day trip.
Who is she? What does she do?
She"s a nu rse"s aide
at Saint Sebastian"s Hospital.
Her name"s Ju lie.
She"s got cu rly hair.
[Lau ghs] I get it.
You want me to ju mp
throu gh a cou ple of hoops...
before you take me back.
OK. I have it comin".
Bu t l"m willing to work for it.
# Youu´nre nnot lhenre witlh mme #...
# Oolh-oolh-oolh. So fanr away #...
# Baby #...
# l-l-I #...
Ah-ah-ah... Nicole!
You hu rt me really bad.
And I can"t ju st let you
yo-yo with my heart. OK?
You hu rt me. And l"m never
gonna let it happen again!
Love don"t live here anymore!
Michael. L"ve never
seen you like this.
So... open.
So... so in tou ch
with you r feelings.
[Lau ghing]
Like you cou Id really be in love
with a nu rse from New Jersey.
[Jake lau ghs]
You "re ju st mu ch more......
mmm... warm and vu Inerable
and fu nny!
You didn"t u sed
to be fu nny before.
That"s fu nny "ha ha" fu nny...
or fu nny "this milk
tastes fu nny" fu nny?
See? That"s fu nny!
Mmm...
[Jake"s hands slap wall]
You "re not Michael Tu rner.
Uh-oh.