♪ HUH
MAN, WHAT IS THIS HAVIN'-A-PICNIC
SHIT IN MY CAR?
PLEASE, MAN, I'M NOT
GETTIN' MY SEX AT HOME.
DON'T DENY ME THIS.
YOU SLEEP WITH A BEAUTIFUL
WOMAN EVERY NIGHT.
I'M MARRIED.
THAT'S WHAT MARRIED MEANS.
IT MEANS YOU SLEEP TOGETHER,
BUT YOU CAN'T GET NONE.
WHY DON'T YOU WATCH IT
WITH ALL THAT SHIT, ALL RIGHT?
HEY, LOOK. WH-WH-WHERE'S
YOUR CUP HOLDERS?
I DON'T HAVE ONE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN YOU DON'T HAVE ONE?
$80,000 FOR THIS CAR AND YOU
AIN'T GOT NO DAMN CUP HOLDER?
IT'S $105,000
AND THIS HAPPENS TO BE...
ONE OF THE FASTEST PRODUCTION
CARS ON THE PLANET.
ZERO TO SIXTY IN FOUR SECONDS, SWEETIE.
THIS IS A LIMITED EDITION.
YOU DAMN RIGHT IT'S LIMITED.
NO CUP HOLDER, NO BACKSEAT.
IT'S A SHINY DICK
WITH TWO CHAIRS IN IT.
I GUESS WE THE BALLS,
JUST DRAGGIN' THE FUCK ALONG.
OH, DAMN.
SORRY.
[ ENGINE REVVING,
TIRES SQUEALING ]
- GET IT.
- YOU SEE I CAN'T GET DOWN THERE.
YOU GOT AN ENGINE FLOOR UP HERE.
MY SHIT AIN'T GOIN' DOWN UP IN THERE.
GO. TITTY-TITTY,
STRUTTY-STRUTTY.
[ MAN ] GO ON.
MAKE 'EM WANT IT.
[ PORSCHE DRIVER] I AIN'T YOUR WIFE TO
BE CLEANIN' UP AFTER YOUR FILTHY ASS.
WATCH MY HAND. MY SHIT
CAN'T GET DOWN THERE.
IT GET STUCK.
WHAT DO YOU COME UP WITH?
YOU GOT THIS SHIT.
YOU GONNA GET THAT FRY.
THIS AIN'T NO GODDAMN
DENNY'S, EATIN' IN MY CAR.
I WOULDN'T BE BUYIN' SHIT FROM DENNY'S.
I DON'T LIKE THE WAY WE BEEN TREATED.
THEY BIT, JACK. LET'S
SKANK THESE FOOLS.
YEAH, YEAH.
YOU AIN'T INTERESTED IN THE FRY.
YOU ALL UP IN THAT.
GET OUT OF THE CAR.
- SHIT.
- WHAT THE FUCK?
ME AND MY TEAM, WE'VE
HAD A BIG WEEK, SO JUST GET
THE FUCK OUT OF THE CAR.
DAMN. WHAT ARE YOU
WEIGHIN', 350?
I BET YOU A BIG
POPEYE CHICKEN-EATIN'
MOTHERFUCKER, AIN'T YOU?
- GET THE FUCK OUT.
- WHY I ALWAYS GOT TO GET
THE BIG, THICK MOTHERFUCKERS?
- GET OUT OF THE CAR, NOW!
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT! OKAY?
HOLD ON.
THIS IS SOME
FUNNY SHIT.
LET ME TELL YOU
HOW BAD A DAY YOU'RE HAVIN'.
YOU'RE JACKIN' A COUPLE OF COPS.
OH, YEAH? WELL, I'M
A STAND-UP COMEDIAN,
AND I SUCK!
- THAT'S WHY I NEED YOUR CAR.
- I AIN'T NO WESLEY SNIPES.
I JUST HANG OUT WITH STUPID-ASS
FRIENDS THAT DRIVE STUPID-ASS CARS...
THAT ATTRACT A LOT
OF MOTHERFUCKIN' ATTENTION.
I NEED TO JUMP OVER
THIS CAR AND SMACK YOU
IN YOUR PEEZI-ASS HEAD.
YOU'RE ARGUIN' OVER
A MOTHERFUCKIN' FRENCH FRY.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE FRENCH FRY!
IT'S ABOUT YOUR LACK OF RESPECT
FOR OTHER PEOPLE'S PROPERTY!
- HEY, HEY, HEY!
- SHUT THE FUCK UP!
- THIS SHIT IS STUPID.
HOLD THE FUCK ON! ALL RIGHT,
YOU WANT SOME BAD ENOUGH?
COME GET SOME!
- [ GRUNTING ]
- [ GROANING ]
YOU LIKE THAT SHIT?
WESLEY SNIPES, PASSENGER 57.
NOW GIVE ME
A MOTHERFUCKIN' HANDIWIPE.
NOW LET'S HEAR
ONE OF THOSE JOKES, BITCH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, GUYS?
LOOKS LIKE THE REAL THING.
- YOU REMEMBER YOUR ASSIGNMENT?
- YEAH. I'M THE DECOY.
YES, YOU ARE.
[ SCREAMING ]
WHAT THE FUCK
YOU DOIN'?
HELLO, POLICE?
I JUST SAW SOMETHING TERRIBLE:
A POLICEMAN SHOT
ON SOUTH MIAMI AND FIRST STREET.
- HELP, PLEASE.
- [ DISPATCHER ] ALL UNITS, OFFICER DOWN.
OFFICER DOWN.
RESPOND CODE THREE.
[ DISPATCHER CONTINUES ] ALL UNITS IN
THE VICINITY, RESPOND AND IDENTIFY.
[ PILOT ] THIS IS AIR UNIT TWO.
WE'VE GOT A-- [ INDISTINCT ]
[ POLICE OFFICER ] OFFICER DOWN.
WE NEED ADDITIONAL GROUND UNITS.
[ DISPATCHER ] AIR THREE, ROGER.
SUSPECT OR SUSPECTS UNKNOWN.
[ MAN ] GENTLEMEN, IT'S CLEAR.
WE'RE INSIDE.
WE'RE IN.
YOU GOT 20 MINUTES.
[ SNIFFS, COUGHS ]
[ FEMALE DISPATCHER SPEAKS
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO ]
[ BELCHES, SIGHS ]
GODDAMN TACO'S GONNA KILL ME.
[ RADIO ] GUYS, WE GOT
12 MINUTES. LET'S GO.
[ BEEPING ]
[ STATIC BUZZES, STOPS ]
[ BEEPS ]
CLEAR. WE'RE IN.
- [ RADIO ] MOVE YOUR ASS.
WE GOT SIX MINUTES.
- READY.
- [ BEEP ]
- [ ENGINE FIRING ]
READY TO FIRE. GO!
[ RADIO ]
FIRE.
OKAY, GO.
GO!
COME ON, COME ON!
LET'S GO! GET OUT OF HERE!
- HEY--
- GO! GO!
- [ MEN LAUGHING ]
♪ [ RAP ]
♪ [ RAP CONTINUES ]
OHH.
[ TOY SQUEAKING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
OOH.
DAMN. MMM.
DID YOU HAVE SWEET DREAMS?
YOU'RE SO NASTY.
MM-HMM.
YOU'RE ALWAYS SAYIN'
YOU WANT QUALITY TIME.
WELL, RIGHT NOW,
I GOT THE TIME, AND YOU
DAMN SURE GOT THE QUALITY.
MMM. COME ON NOW.
MM-MMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS?
I CAN'T REMEMBER THE LAST TIME
THAT WE FELL ASLEEP TOGETHER.
OHO. BABY--
BABY, IT'S MY JOB.
IT'S WHAT IT REQUIRES.
YOU KNOW I'M A BETTER COP
WHEN I GET SOME IN THE MORNIN'.
I FEEL LIGHTER ON MY FEET.
YOU GONNA HAVE TO
KEEP IT IN YOUR PANTS.
I HEAR THREE LITTLE BURNETTS
COMIN' DOWN THE HALL.
OH, YOU'RE COLD!
YOU GONNA LEAVE ME HERE
LIKE A HUMPIN' DOG.
[ KIDS SHOUTING ]
[ WOMAN ] HI, BABY BOY.
OOH, HI.
MOMMY! DADDY! DADDY!
HEY, BOY! WHAT'S UP?
DAD, AT SCHOOL,
PEOPLE SAY I LOOK WEIRD.
THEY SAY MY EARS
LOOK FUNNY.
BOY, YOUR DADDY HAS
THAT SAME PROBLEM.
I GOT THE EARS.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
THEY JUST OUT THERE FOR YOU
TO LISTEN TO PEOPLE'S PROBLEMS.
YOU'RE AN ANGEL.
THESE ARE YOUR WINGS.
FLAP, FLAP. THAT'S ALL.
[ MOTHER ]
JAMES, STOP WITH--
TAKE 'EM OFF--
YOUR EARS ARE BETTER FOR YOU
TO LISTEN WITH. DON'T LET ME
HAVE TO COME DOWN TO SCHOOL.
- I'LL ARREST THE PRINCIPAL.
- [ GIRL ] MOM! MOM!
- [ MOTHER ] WHAT?
- [ GIRL ] JAMES KEEPS
PUSHIN' ME. QUIT IT!
- TALKIN' 'BOUT MY BOY'S EARS.
UNCLE MIKE'S
IN THE HOUSE.
- [ BOYS ]
WHAT'S UP, UNCLE MIKE?
- [ MIKE ] PARTNER, PARTNER.
- WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
- QUINCY, CHECK IT OUT.
- [ QUINCY ] WHAT?
WHAT YOU TAKE MY FOOD FOR?
- [ MIKE ] HEY, GIRL.
DON'T KISS ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE
YOUR LIPS WERE LAST NIGHT.
[ LAUGHING ]
DID YOU HAVE
A DATE LAST NIGHT?
WHOO, DID I!
- LET ME TELL YOU, BOY.
THIS GIRL WAS--
- HEY!
DON'T GO TELLIN' MY SON
YOUR SLEAZY SEX STORIES.
- I ONLY TELL YOUR HUSBAND
MY SLEAZY SEX STORIES.
- HEY.
- I DON'T WANT HIM KNOWIN' ABOUT
'EM EITHER; GIVES HIM IDEAS.
- WHY YOU PUTTIN' ME IN THIS?
[ PHONE RINGING ]
I'M WITH MY BABIES.
- OKAY? THANK YOU.
- HELLO?
- EAT. GO ON, GIRL.
- NO PROBLEM.
- MAN, SHE WAS A BLU-BLA-BLAM.
OH.
-YOU ON THE MIKE WITH MIKE.
-WANT DADDY TO WIPE YOUR MOUTH?
I THINK YOU MEAN TO SAY,
"GET OUR ASSES DOWN THERE,
PLEASE," CAPTAIN.
[ CAPTAIN ]
ALL RIGHT.
PLEASE. NOW!
[ DIAL TONE ]
MAYBE NOT.
[ CHATTERING ]
WHAT'S UP, BOY?
HEY, BABY!
HEY, FRANCINE.
WHERE'S HOWARD?
UM, HE'S DOWN THERE.
HE'S LOOKIN' FOR YOU.
HE'S BEEN IN BETTER MOODS.
AHH, DAMN.
GET IT DONE,
GODDAMN IT.
WELCOME TO
OUR NIGHTMARE, BOYS.
SEE THIS? WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THIS PICTURE, HUH?
REMEMBER THIS ROOM?
THESE SLATS, SEE?
THEY LOOK FAMILIAR,
DON'T THEY?
THERE WERE THESE,
UH, SILVER PACKETS?
THEY LOOKED LIKE BRICKS?
LITTLE RED TAGS ON 'EM?
'BOUT SO HIGH?
- ALL THAT HEROIN. GONE.
- THIS WAS OUR CAREER BUST--
A HUNDRED MILLION DOLLARS?
- [ MIKE ] THIS IS BAD.
- LET ME CALL IT WHAT IT IS.
THIS IS FUCKED UP.
- YOU GOT THAT RIGHT, DETECTIVE.
- HELLO, ALISON.
[ CAPTAIN HOWARD ]
YOU GUYS KNOW CAPTAIN SINCLAIR,
INTERNAL AFFAIRS' TOP WATCHDOG.
I'D ACTUALLY TAKE THAT
AS A COMPLIMENT IF I
DIDN'T KNOW YOU SO WELL.
UH, EXCUSE ME, BUT IF
YOU TWO WANNA GET PERSONAL,
I COULD STEP OUT--
THERE'S NOTHIN'
PERSONAL GOIN' ON HERE.
I'M JUST DOING MY JOB.
I LOVE KNOWING THAT ONE LEAK,
ONE HEADLINE, COULD TURN THIS
NIGHTMARE INTO A MEDIA FRENZY.
THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
WE'RE GONNA GET THE DOPE BACK
BEFORE THAT EVER HAPPENS.
WHY DON'T YOU START BY
LOOKIN' RIGHT HERE?
BECAUSE THIS HAD TO HAVE BEEN
AN INSIDE JOB, AND I'M GONNA
FIND OUT ABOUT IT.
SANCHEZ, RUIZ,
YOU GUYS ARE LATE.
SOMEBODY PUT THIS IN
FOR TOXIC DRUG FUMES.
YEAH, THIS WAS A BRILLIANT
DESIGN. THIS WAS REALLY
INTELLIGENT. I LIKE THIS.
I DIDN'T ASK HOW HE FEELS.
I SAID, "WHAT DID HE SEE?"
[ CAPT. HOWARD ]
WHAT DOES HE KNOW?
UH-HUH.
WHERE WERE Y'ALL
LAST NIGHT, MAN?
WHY DON'T Y'ALL HAVE YOUR
COUSINS BRING THE SHIT BACK
AND WE CAN ALL GET SOME SLEEP.
WE WERE GONNA DO THAT, BUT WE
CAME UP WITH A PROBLEM. YOUR
MAMA SNORTED UP ALL THE DOPE.
- OHH.
- ALL RIGHT, YOU TWO,
GET OVER THERE.
O'FEE'S GONNA BE ALL RIGHT,
BUT HE'S GOT NOTHIN' TO TELL US.
SO THEY KILL A DECOY,
EMPTIES THE STATION.
VERY SMART.
THEY DON'T KILL A REAL COP
'CAUSE THEY'D HAVE
THE WHOLE FORCE ON THEIR ASS.
THIS WAS YOUR CASE.
YOU'RE BACK ON IT.
SANCHEZ, RUIZ, YOU BACK THEM UP
WITH WHATEVER THEY NEED.
[ COMPLAINING ]
- SHUT YOUR MOUTHS.
- ALL RIGHT, BUT WAIT A SECOND.
IT WAS CARRERA'S DRUGS
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
BUT IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN HIM;
HE WAS KILLED IN PRISON.
WHAT ABOUT HIS CREW?
THE REST OF THOSE IDIOTS DON'T
HAVE THE PRECISION TO DO THIS,
BUT...
IN CASE I'M WRONG,
CHECK THEM OUT.
THEY'D HAVE BEEN UP HERE
WITH UZIS, SPLASHIN' O'FEE
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
- TAKES A LOT OF BRAINS TO PULL
SOMETHIN' LIKE THIS OFF.
- BIG COJONES TOO.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
TALKIN' ABOUT, COJONES?
- IT WOULD TAKE ME A MONTH
TO EXPLAIN TO YOU--
- [ ALL ARGUING ]
ENGLISH.
GUYS, HO! HO! HEY!
WE GOT NOTHIN'.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WE'VE GOT NOTHIN'!
THE GUY WHO PULLED THIS OFF
KNEW WHAT HE WAS DOIN',
AND HE LEFT US NOTHIN'
BUT A BIG "FUCK YOU."
RUIZ, SANCHEZ,
FIND OUT WHO INSTALLED
THE VENTILATING SYSTEM.
DO THAT NOW.
HO. HO-HO.
OH, THAT'S COLD.
-YEAH, SO'S YOUR MAMA'S BED.
-THIS COULD DEFINITELY BE AN
INSIDE JOB. DON'T RULE IT OUT.
THE WAY I SEE IT,
WE GOT 72 HOURS BEFORE
THE F.B.I. AND THE D.E.A....
WALK IN HERE AND SHUT US DOWN,
AND WE'RE GONNA BE THE BAD GUYS.
THE POLITICS DEMAND THAT
SOMEBODY TAKE THE RAP FOR THIS,
AND IT'S GONNA BE US.
JUST DO WHAT YOU DO,
ONLY FASTER.
JOJO.
WHAT'S UP?
YOU STILL A CHEMIST, RIGHT?
CUTTIN' DRUGS AND
SHIT LIKE THAT?
OH, I DON'T KNOW NOTHIN'
ABOUT THAT, MAN. I'M OUT
OF THAT DRUG BUSINESS.
YOU KNOW SOMETHIN'.
YOU DON'T KNOW NOTHIN'?
- NO, I JUST SAID NO TO DRUGS.
THAT'S IT.
- YOU SAID NO TO DRUGS.
WHAT YOU INTO, JO?
I'M INTO RUBBER.
RUBBER, RUBBER, RUBBER.
YOU SELLIN' TIRES,
HUH, JO?
YEAH.
- SO YOU DON'T KNOW NOTHIN'.
JOJO DON'T KNOW NOTHIN'.
- I KNOW TIRES.
YOU TELLIN' ME
THE TRUTH, RIGHT?
WOULD I LIE TO YOU?
WOULD YOU
LIE TO ME?
HEY, I'M DRIVIN'.
♪
[ MEN GRUNTING ]
YO, MAN, THIS IS
A WASTE OF TIME.
COME ON, MAN.
I KEEP TELLIN' YOU
IN MAX'S LINE OF WORK, SHE
DEFINITELY GETS THE 411.
MAXI! HOW'D I KNOW
I WAS GONNA FIND YOU
UP IN HERE?
[ GROANS ]
LISTEN, MAX, WE GOTTA TALK.
IS THERE SOMEPLACE WE CAN GO?
YEAH. EQUIPMENT ROOM?
BEHAVE YOURSELF.
OH, I'M COOL.
- LISTEN, UH, I NEED
SOME HELP... AGAIN.
- SO WHAT ELSE IS NEW?
[ BARBELL CRASHES ]
[ GROANS ]
OH, SH--
[ WEIGHT CLATTERING ]
OH, SHIT.
MAJOR, MAJOR ILL SHIT
HAPPENED DOWN AT THE P.D.
THERE'S A LOT OF HEROIN
INVOLVED; THERE'S GONNA BE
A LOT OF CASH INVOLVED.
AND THERE'S GONNA BE
SOME JOLLY YOUNG MEN
WHO WANNA PARTY.
- WHAT DO YOU NEED?
- THERE'S A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO'LL TALK TO YOU...
THAT WON'T TALK TO ME.
YOU MEAN CUSTOMERS?
I'M NOT ASKIN' YOU TO GET
INTO ANY WILD SHIT. JUST
CALL ME IF YOU HEAR SOMETHIN'.
I THINK I WILL CALL YOU.
[ GRUNTS ]
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOIN'?
TRYIN' TO KEEP
MY SHIT QUICK.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT. YOU AIN'T
GETTIN' NONE AT HOME.
YOU GOT EXTRA ENERGY.
GO AHEAD.
BURN IT OFF, BABY.
HEY, WE GOT ANYTHING,
FRANCINE?
SANCHEZ SAYS THAT THE
AIR-CONDITIONING CONTRACT...
WENT TO MANUEL ARRONA
OF KEY BISCAYNE.
PARTNER.
HE'S WORKIN' OUT OF
HIS HOUSE THIS WEEK.
THAT'S THE NUMBER.
♪
[ DOORBELL RINGING ]
[ MIKE ]
HE'S NOT ANSWERIN'.
I GUESS WE
SHOULD JUST LEAVE.
WHAT, MAKE A TRIP
ALL THE WAY DOWN HERE
TO HIGH SOCIETY FOR NOTHIN'?
NO, MAN. THAT'S WHAT THEY GOT
WINDOWS FOR. WE CAN PEEK IN.
YEAH, THAT SHOULD DO IT.
OH, LOOK. OH!
LOOK. I TRIPPED.
THE HANDLE JUST
OPENED FOR YOU?
RIGHT AFTER I TRIPPED.
I GUESS THEY WANT US
TO COME IN, TAKE A PEEK.
HELLO!
WE'RE YOUR
NEW NEIGHBORS.
DON'T BE ALARMED.
WE'RE NEGROES.
NAH, MAN. THERE'S TOO MUCH
BASS IN YOUR VOICE.
THAT SCARE WHITE FOLKS.
YOU GOT TO SOUND LIKE THEM.
WE WERE WONDERIN'
IF WE CAN BORROW
SOME BROWN SUGAR?
- WHEW.
- [ SNIFFING ] YOU FART?
NO, MAN.
DEAD GUY.
[ GUN COCKING ]
WELL. LOOKS LIKE
SOMEBODY'S HOME.
OH. AH.
WHEW.
OKAY, LET ME TAKE A STAB
AT THIS ONE.
HE SELLS THE VENTILATION PLANS
TO THE BAD GUYS. HE GETS RICH,
BUT HE GETS DEAD.
YOU'RE RIGHT ON THAT ONE.
UH, I'M GONNA GO CALL
HOMICIDE.
WHOA. WHY DO YOU
ACT LIKE THIS EVERY TIME
WE'RE AROUND A DEAD BODY?
IT'S COOL. I JUST--
[ GAGGING ]
PLEASE? LOOK AROUND?
THE SMELL AND THE FUMES.
IT'S JUST UNEXPECTED,
THAT'S ALL.
LOOKS LIKE OUR BUDDY ARRONA
WAS A BIT OF A GAMBLER.
GOT DOG TRACK, JAI ALAI.
[ GRUNTING ]
PROBABLY NEEDED MONEY
TO PAY OFF HIS DEBTS.
BOOKIE.
[ MIKE ] WHOOPS.
DAMN, MAN. WATCH WHERE
YOU SWINGIN' A DEAD LEG.
- MY BAD, MY BAD.
- DAMN THIS.
I'M CALLIN' HOMICIDE.
I'M A NARCOTICS COP.
[ GROANING ]
OH, DEAD BODIES.
UGH. DEAD ENDS.
[ ARM BANGS AGAINST TABLE ]
MAGGOTS.
MAN, UH--
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU, MAN?
- A LITTLE NAUSEOU--
I'M A--
[ GAGGING ]
I'M GONNA--
WHAT DO YOU SAY WE GRAB
A COUPLE OF BURRITOS?
YOU KNOW, YOU DRIVE
ALMOST SLOW ENOUGH
TO DRIVE MISS DAISY.
HA-HA-HA.
HEY, MAN,
THE TRANSACTION
IS DONE, ALL RIGHT?
WE AIN'T GOT SHIT,
SO IT'S OVER.
RELAX, MAN.
WE GOT IT BEFORE;
WE'LL GET IT AGAIN.
YEAH, YEAH, YOU GOT IT ALL
FIGURED OUT, DON'T YOU?
YOU GOT TO HAVE FAITH.
BY THE TIME
WE FIGURED OUT HOW,
WE'D BE OUT OF A JOB.
NO, SCRATCH THAT.
EVERYBODY IN THE DAMN UNIT
WILL BE OUT OF A JOB.
OH, BUT DON'T WORRY. THEY
TEND TO THINK MIKE LOWREY
GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
ESPECIALLY SINCE THEY THINK
YOU SOME RICH KID PLAYIN' COP.
LOOK, MAN, I AIN'T GOT
NO TRUST FUND.
OKAY? SEE, FOR ME,
NO JOB, NO CHECK.
THAT'S LIKE ALL THE OTHER GUYS
IN THE UNIT. LEAST, MOST OF US.
SO I'M PLAYIN' COP NOW.
[ CHUCKLING ]
THIS IS A GAME.
I'M JUST JOKIN' AROUND, RIGHT?
YOU ALWAYS WANTED TO BE
STARSKY OR HUTCH.
[ CHUCKLING ]
YOU KNOW WHAT, MAN?
I'M SO SICK OF THIS BULLSHIT.
WHAT, I'M SUPPOSED TO APOLOGIZE
FOR MY FAMILY LEAVIN' ME MONEY?
ALL I EVER WANTED TO BE
WAS A COP. I GET UP EARLY AND
TAKE IT TO THE MAX EVERY DAY.
I'M THE FIRST GUY THROUGH
THE DOOR AND THE LAST GUY
TO LEAVE THE CRIME SCENE,
SO FUCK YOU AND FUCK THEM
AND FUCK EVERYBODY WHO GOT
A PROBLEM WITH MIKE LOWREY.
I LOVE YOU, MAN.
FUCK YOU, MARCUS.
I DO.
YOU'RE COOL, MAN.
YOU'RE MY PARTNER.
SHUT UP.
SHUT UP, MAN.
SLOW-ASS DRIVER.
DRIVIN' LIKE A BITCH, HUH?
WHY I GOT TO BE ALL THAT?
I'LL TAKE YOU AND ME...
SLOW-ASS MISS DAISY.
OFF THIS FUCKIN' CLIFF,
YOU KEEP FUCKIN' WITH ME.
THEN IT'LL BE WHAT?
TWO BITCHES IN THE SEA.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANT?
SHUT UP, MARCUS.
MY WIFE KNOW I AIN'T NO BITCH.
YEAH,
I'M A BAD BOY.
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
♪ WHAT YOU GONNA DO
WHEN THEY COME FOR YOU ♪
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS--
[ WOMAN ]
SHELLY, ONLY MODELS.
MAX JUST DROPPED BY.
I GOTTA GO. BYE.
[ EXASPERATED SIGH ]
WHAT'S THIS?
YOU WANT ME TO CALL AROUND
LOOKING FOR THE NEWLY RICH?
ARE THERE ANY NEW GUYS
PARTYING A LOT, SPENDING
A LOT OF MONEY?
ACTUALLY, THIS GUY CALLED ME
THIS MORNING, DESPERATE--
EVERY TWO HOURS--
LOOKING FOR
NEW GIRLS IN TOWN.
- ARE YOU AVAILABLE THIS
AFTERNOON? IT'LL BE $2,000--
- I'VE GOT PLANS WITH JULIE.
SHE'S YOUR ROOMMATE, RIGHT?
YEAH.
SO BRING HER.
SHE'S CUTE; SHE'S SEXY.
GO ON.
-SHE'S NOT A WORKING GIRL, LOIS.
-DOESN'T MATTER. THIS GUY'S
ON SPEEDBALLS.
-HE'S PROBABLY SO MESSED UP
HE CAN'T EVEN GET IT UP.
-WELL, MAYBE WE'LL CHECK IT OUT.
COULD BE THE PARTY
I'M LOOKING FOR.
PARTY AT THE BILTMORE?
YEAH, THAT'LL REALLY ROCK.
[ MAX ] OKAY, JULIE,
I OWE YOU ONE.
FORGET ABOUT IT. I'LL JUST
DEDUCT IT FROM THE HUNDREDS
OF FAVORS I OWE YOU.
AM I TURNING INTO THE
GUEST THAT WON'T LEAVE?
NO, I LIKE
HAVING YOU
LIVE WITH ME.
AN OUT-OF-WORK PHOTOGRAPHER
WHO DOESN'T KNOW
HOW TO COOK.
NOT A BIG UP SIDE
FOR YOU THERE.
OH, COME ON.
SO WHAT INCREDIBLY HIP
INDIVIDUAL INSPIRED THIS
VISIT TO THE BILTMORE?
IT'S A FAVOR FOR MIKE LOWREY.
OH, RIGHT, THE COP...
WHO I THINK YOU MAY BE
A LITTLE BIT IN LOVE WITH.
WELL, MAYBE I AM,
BUT WE'RE JUST FRIENDS.
AND IF I WERE EVER IN TROUBLE,
HE'S THE ONLY PERSON I WOULD CALL.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I THINK I'VE
HEARD THIS BEFORE.
[ SNIFFING ]
HELLO.
HI. YOU MUST BE MAX. WELCOME.
I'M EDDIE.
TO THE AL CAPONE SUITE.
SO I, UH, GUESS
WE'RE A LITTLE EARLY.
OH, THIS IS
MY FRIEND JULIE.
JULIE.
[ SNIFFING ]
HI. YOU LIKE AL
CAPONE, DON'T YOU?
I HADN'T REALLY
THOUGHT ABOUT IT MUCH.
I'M NOT KIDDING ABOUT THIS BEING CAPONE'S.
HE HAD THE PLACE...
RIGGED WITH
SECRET PASSAGEWAYS.
TEN MINUTES, WE'RE OUTTA HERE.
FIVE.
JULIE, ONE DRINK. ONE SIP.
HEY, WHAT'S THE WHISPERING ABOUT?
IT'S EDDIE HERE.
[ LAUGHING POLITELY ]
JUST GIRL CHAT.
WHERE'S THE BATHROOM?
UPSTAIRS
ON YOUR RIGHT.
WATCH YOUR STEP.
[ LAUGHING ]
COME. SIT.
OKAY.
ENJOY YOURSELF.
RELAX.
EDDIE'S GOT
SOME FAVORS TO PLAY WITH.
-[ MAX ] UH, YEAH, EDDIE DOES.
-I SHOULD HAVE TOLD YOU SOONER
ABOUT EDDIE'S PRIVATE PARTY.
WELL, NOW IT'S
A SURPRISE PARTY.
OKAY, MAX, WE'VE BEEN HERE
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES TOO LONG.
I SEE YOU TREAT YOURSELF
WELL, EDDIE.
YEAH.
I NEEDED TO BLOW OFF A LITTLE STEAM
AFTER THE, UH, THE MOVE, YOU KNOW?
SO I-- A LITTLE PARTY WITH A COUPLE OF FRIENDS.
YOU KNOW HOW IT IS.
I WAS GONNA
INVITE YOU GUYS.
INVITE? LOOKS LIKE
I'M CATERING THIS.
I WAS LOOKING FOR MY TWO KEYS OF
DOPE, AND NOW I KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
YOURS? MAN,
IT'S OUR SCORE.
AND THE GIRL?
[ EDDIE ] NOBODY.
JUST ENTERTAINMENT.
HI. I'M MAX.
NICE TO MEET YOU, MAX.
I LIKE A WOMAN
WHO TAKES PRIDE
IN HER APPEARANCE.
DON'T YOU?
YEAH, I HATE
WHEN A BITCH
LETS HERSELF SLIDE.
YOU LOOK LIKE A MODEL
IN THAT DRESS.
WILL YOU MODEL
FOR ME, MAX?
OH, GREAT.
IT'S THE GOON SQUAD.
[ GUNSHOTS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
YOU WERE A COP FOR SO LONG.
YOU SHOULD KNOW HOOKERS TALK.
YOU COULDN'T WAIT
FOUR MORE DAYS UNTIL
I MADE THE DEAL?
I CAN'T WORK WITH
THAT KIND OF STUPIDITY!
STUPIDITY?
I GOT YOU CONNECTED INSIDE!
I BROUGHT YOU MY FAMILY.
EDDIE...
IT'S MY FAMILY NOW.
FOUCHET,
WE'RE STILL FRIENDS.
WHAT ARE
YOU GUYS DOIN'?
YOU PISSED HIM OFF.
-[ SIDEKICK ] USE A SMALLER GUN.
YOU GOT BLOOD ON ME AGAIN.
-HEY. SOMEBODY'S UPSTAIRS.
- [ GUNSHOTS ]
- [ JULIE SHRIEKS ]
- [ SIDEKICK ] GET HER!
MOVE, FERGIE!
- [ PANTING ]
[ SIDEKICK ]
GET THE LADY.
- SHIT.
- GO! GO! GET HER!
GODDAMN IT!
MOVE YOUR WIDE ASS!
GET HER!
WHAT THE FUCK "GET ME"?
FUCKIN' SHOES SUCK.
GET HER!
- OH, GOD!
- [ SIDEKICK ] MOVE IT!
GO! GO!
SHOOT HER!
[ GASPING ]
I GOT HER.
BULLSHIT. I GOT HER.
NO, I GOT HER. WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT SHOOTIN'?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
SHE MADE IT!
JESUS!
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
SHE JUMPED.
FUCK.
FIND OUT WHO SHE WORKED FOR
AND FIND OUT WHERE SHE LIVES.
[ SIRENS WAILING,
INDISTINCT RADIO
TRANSMISSION ]
[ HORN HONKING ]
- [ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING ]
- [ CAPT. HOWARD ] IT'S ABOUT
FUCKIN' TIME. LOWREY!
BURNETT!
COME HERE. COME HERE!
LOOK AT THIS.
YOU SEE THIS GUY?
HE'S DEAD, RIGHT?
YEAH.
EDDIE DOMINGUEZ.
HE LOOK FAMILIAR?
THE EX-COP.
TWO POINTS FOR YOU.
AND THERE'S SOME OF OUR
HIGH-GRADE HEROIN OVER THERE.
OH, THERE'S A HEADLINE
SINCLAIR'S GONNA LOVE.
LOOK, THERE'S NO SIGNS
OF FORCED ENTRY.
WHAT THE FUCK IS ALL THIS?
LOOK LIKE BEIRUT.
AH, AL CAPONE SUITE.
WHAT CAN I SAY?
SHIT HAPPENS.
THIS IS A SHITTY DAY.
REAL SHITTY DAY.
LOOKS LIKE WE GOT TWO SHADES OF
LIPSTICK OVER HERE, GENTLEMEN.
SOMEBODY'S MISSIN'
FROM THE PARTY.
LISTEN TO ME. YOUR ONLY FUNCTION IN
LIFE RIGHT NOW IS TO FIND THAT PERSON.
YOU FIND HER!
IT'S THE ONLY GOOD LEAD
WE GOT ALL DAY.
LOOK, MAN, I'M GONNA CHECK
ALL CALLS TO THE ROOM.
[ CHATTERING ]
[ MIKE ]
HEY, WHAT YOU GOT
OVER THERE, PARTNER?
COVER HER.
[ CAPT. HOWARD ]
HE KNEW THE GIRL, HUH?
LOOK, MAN. WE'LL GET THE
WITNESS, AND WE DAMN SURE GONNA
GET THE FOOLS WHO DID THIS.
YEAH. LISTEN, WHY DON'T YOU
SEE IF YOU CAN CATCH A RIDE
WITH HOWARD?
- WHERE YOU GOIN'?
- EIGHT CALLS WERE MADE
TO LOIS FIELDS.
THAT'S WHO MAX USED TO WORK FOR.
I'M GONNA CHECK IT OUT.
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
WHY DON'T WE CATCH UP LATER?
- YOU OKAY?
- I'M COOL.
HELLO. HELLO?
HELLO?
SHIT.
YEAH, BABY. LOOK, BABY,
I KNOW QUALITY TIME
WAS MY IDEA.
[ THERESA ] DON'T TALK ABOUT QUALITY TIME.
HOLD ON, BABY.
LOOK HERE.
I NEED A FULL FILE
ON EDDIE DOMINGUEZ.
THAT'LL TAKE
A MINUTE.
HOLD ON.
MARCUS? I GOT
THE RED ONE ON.
YOU HAVE ON THE RED ONE?
THE ONE WITH THE SNAPS?
WHY COULDN'T YOU WAIT 'TIL--
YOU'RE NEVER HOME.
THERES-- HOLD ON.
ALL HIS FILES
ARE BLOCKED.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT HIS PERSONAL FILES.
THE MAN'S DEAD. UN-BLOCK IT.
SCREW YOU. THAT'S ILLEGAL.
NO, SCREW YOU!
FUCKIN'--
MARCUS, ARE YOU
TALKIN' TO ME?
NAH, I'M NOT TALKIN' TO NO--
IT'S A TERM YOU USE, BABY.
"SCREW YOU" IS A COP TERM.
YOU AIN'T SCREWIN'
NOTHIN'!
THERESA!
[ DIAL TONE ]
GODDAMN IT!
♪ [ WHISTLING ]
WHERE'S LOWREY?
[ SIGHS ]
I JUST PAGED HIM.
HE'S FOLLOWIN' UP
THIS LOIS FIELDS LEAD.
THE MADAM?
21-2, REQUEST BACKUP.
614 REACH ROAD.
[ DISPATCHER ]
21-2, BACKUP.
REACH ROAD.
[ DISTANT SIREN WAILING ]
[ YELLING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
THAT MIGHT BE HIM.
YEAH. LOWREY'S DESK.
I NEED TO TALK TO
DETECTIVE MIKE LOWREY.
[ OVER PHONE ]
THIS IS CAPTAIN HOWARD.
CAN I HELP YOU?
- YOU CAN GET ME LOWREY.
- THIS IS NOT ANOTHER
PATERNITY CASE, IS IT?
NO, IT'S ANOTHER
MURDER CASE, YOU TWERP.
YOU'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT
THE MURDER CASE AT THE
BILTMORE HOTEL, ARE YOU?
LISTEN, I'VE JUST SEEN MY
BEST FRIEND GET MURDERED,
AND I'LL ONLY TALK
TO MIKE LOWREY.
- WHY ONLY MIKE LOWREY?
I HAVE A DETECTIVE HERE--
- NONE OF YOUR FUCKING BUSINESS.
- EITHER I TALK TO LOWREY
OR I'M GONNA BLOW TOWN.
- MIKE! MIKE, PHONE!
TELEPHONE, MIKE!
HE'S COMING.
HE'S COMING RIGHT NOW.
HOLD ON, PLEASE.
TALK TO HER.
I AIN'T GOT TIME
FOR THESE GAMES.
THIS IS THE WITNESS.
THE GIRL AT THE HOTEL.
YEAH, HE JUST GOT OUT
OF THE JOHN. HOLD ON.
YOU DON'T TALK TO HER,
SHE'S GONNA WALK.
I CAN'T BE NO MIKE!
TALK TO HER! SHE'S GONNA WALK
OUT! THIS IS OUR WITNESS!
CALM DOWN!
[ SMOOTH VOICE ]
HELLO. THIS IS
MIKE LOWREY.
HE DOESN'T TALK THAT WAY.
TALK LIKE HIM-- LIKE HIM!
TRY TO TALK SEXY.
YOU DON'T SOUND
SEXY ENOUGH.
CAPTAIN!
I'VE BEEN THERE.
[ CRYING SOFTLY ]
YOU DON'T KNOW ME.
MY NAME'S JULIE MOTT,
AND I WAS MAX LOGAN'S
BEST FRIEND.
OKAY, WHOA, WHOA.
CALM DOWN, CALM DOWN.
TALK TO ME NOW.
[ WHISPERING ]
[ SNARLING ]
YEAH.
AND SHE SAID IF SHE
EVER NEEDED ANYTHING--
I NEED YOUR HELP.
GIVE ME THE ADDRESS.
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
IT'S GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
HEY, MIKE'S TO THE RESCUE.
I'M ON MY WAY.
I'M GONNA SEE
IF I CAN FIND LOWREY.
- HEY, I CAN'T GO. GET MIKE
DOWN HERE. HANDLE THIS.
- YOU GOTTA GO!
GET TO THIS ADDRESS NOW.
I'LL WAIT 'TIL MIKE--
YOU WON'T SEE YOUR WIFE FOR A
MONTH! GET OUT OF THE CHAIR!
GODDAMN, MAN!
[ RAP ]
♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOOM SAID
THE WELCOME TO THE CITY ♪
♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOOM
- ♪ EVERYBODY
- ♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOOM SAID
THE WELCOME TO THE CITY ♪
♪ BOOM, BOOM, BOOM
FUCKIN' DOOR FIXED.
♪ [ MUSIC CONTINUES,
INDISTINCT ]
[ GRAVELLY VOICE ]
MIKE LOWREY.
NO. EASY.
[ SMOOTHLY ]
MIKE LOWREY.
[ KNOCKING ]
[ DOGS YAP ]
SHIT.
- WHO'S THERE?
- UH, MIKE LOWREY.
HOW DO I KNOW
IT'S MIKE LOWREY?
'CAUSE... I'M MIKE LOWREY.
OKAY, NOW WE AIN'T GOT MUCH TIME.
HOLD YOUR BADGE UP TO THE PEEPHOLE.
I'M NOT LETTIN' YOU IN
UNTIL YOU DO!
NO WAY.
- WHAT THE FUCK WAS THAT FOR?
- YOU'RE NOT MIKE LOWREY!
WHAT YOU MEAN?
YOU NEVER EVEN MET HIM-- ME.
- THE WAY MAX DESCRIBED YOU
WAS DIFFERENT.
- I'M UNDERCOVER!
- I-I--
- PROVE IT!
OKAY, LOOK. I KNEW MAX
FROM WAY BACK. I HELPED
HER BROTHER GET OUT OF JAIL.
YEAH? SO?
SO, YOU KNOW,
FROM TIME TO TIME,
WE'D GET TOGETHER,
A LITTLE BUMP AND GRIND.
- WRONG.
- GIVE ME THAT!
GIVE ME THE BAT!
YOU WANT TO GO OUT? FINE!
YOU DON'T WANT TO BELIEVE ME,
YOU GO AT THIS SHIT ALONE.
OH! I FORGOT!
THE BAD GUYS PROBABLY
KNOW WHERE YOU LIVE.
WHICH MEANS THEY'RE
COMIN' FOR YOUR ASS.
GOOD LUCK.
I SAW THE WHOLE THING.
I WATCHED THEM SHOOT HER
LIKE SHE WAS NOTHING.
PLEASE SHUT THE DOOR.
LOOK, LADY.
YOU AIN'T GOT NO MORE BATS,
GOLF CLUBS OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT
YOU COULD SWING AT ME, DO YOU?
I KNEW MAX, OKAY?
I CARE
ABOUT MAX ALSO.
I-I'M JUST HERE TO HELP YOU.
YOU'RE NOT
WHAT I EXPECTED.
[ LAUGHS ] YEAH, WELL,
I AIN'T EXPECT TO WALK
INTO YANKEE STADIUM EITHER.
- [ LAUGHS ]
- OKAY, NOW--
WE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE,
OKAY? LET'S GO.
I GOTTA GET MY DOGS.
COME HERE, DUKIE.
COME HERE, COME HERE.
DUKIE, DUKIE, WHATEVER.
UH, LOOK, YOU GOT A BACK DOOR?
WHERE WE GOING?
COME HERE, DUKIE.
- UH, PROTECTIVE CUSTODY.
- WELL, FUCK THAT.
I'M ONLY DEALING WITH YOU.
THAT WAS A COP THAT
THREW THAT LITTLE PARTY
BACK AT THE BILTMORE.
FORMER COP, OKAY?
WE GOT RID OF HIM
A LONG TIME AGO.
- LUKE. COME ON, LUKE.
- LISTEN, LADY, IF YOU WANNA
LIVE, YOU AIN'T GOT NO CHOICE.
YOU GOT TO TRUST ME.
OH, GOD! MY GOD!
GO! GO! GO!
MOVE! GO!
- [ MARCUS ] RUN FAST! MOVE!
- [ GUNSHOTS CONTINUES ]
[ GROANING ]
[ GUNSHOTS ]
GET THE DOG!
GET MY DOG!
HERE, DOGGIE!
JESUS CHRIST!
WHO THE HELL WAS THAT?
- [ MARCUS ] GO!
- THERE IS TOO MUCH KILLIN'
GOIN' ON, FERGIE.
GO AFTER 'EM!
I'LL GO AROUND FRONT.
I GOT 'EM.
COME ON!
MOVE YOUR ASS!
LET'S GO. LET'S GO!
- FUCK.
- MOVE! LET'S GO!
- [ GUNSHOTS ]
- [ CUSTOMERS SCREAMING ]
[ GUNSHOTS ]
GET IN THE CAR!
[ CLICK ]
DAMN IT!
[ JULIE ]
GODDAMN IT!
FUCKIN' DOOR!
GO, GODDAMN IT! GO!
OKAY, OKAY.
HOW DID YOU MISS 'EM?
HEY, YOU FAT FUCK!
- WATCH YOUR FUCKIN' MOUTH.
- IF YOU'D LOSE SOME WEIGHT,
YOU WOULD'VE CAUGHT 'EM!
I'D LIKE TO SQUEEZE YOUR LITTLE
FUCKIN' HEAD, YOU BASTARD.
NOW YOU'RE
IN FUCKIN' TROUBLE!
YOU GET THE LICENSE PLATE?
YEAH, I GOT
THE FUCKIN' PLATES.
- YOU COCKEYED FUCK.
- [ SIRENS WAILING ]
THIS IS YOUR GODDAMN GETAWAY
CAR? WE'RE NOT GONNA GET AWAY
FROM ANYTHING IN THIS.
WHAT IS THIS, A GODDAMN FAMILY
STATION WAGON? OH, MY GOD,
YOU GOT A BABY SEAT IN THE BACK.
IT'S A UNDERCOVER CAR, OKAY?
UNDERCOVER.
SHIT! I KNOW THEY GOT A LOOK
AT MY LICENSE PLATE. WERE THOSE
THE GUYS WHO SHOT MAX?
WHAT GUYS? ALL I SAW
WERE BULLETS. YOU TELL ME
WHAT THEY LOOK LIKE.
I DON'T KNOW.
I WAS TOO BUSY TRYIN' TO
KEEP A BULLET OUT YOUR ASS.
I'M GONNA NEED YOU TO LOOK
THROUGH SOME MUG SHOTS UNTIL
YOU CAN IDENTIFY MAX'S SHOOTER.
- WHERE ARE WE GONNA DO THAT?
- PROTECTIVE CUSTODY.
NO WAY! I TOLD YOU I AM NOT
GOING INTO PROTECTIVE CUSTODY.
LOOK, LADY,
I'M NOT PLAYIN', OKAY?
YOU REALLY PISSIN' ME OFF.
- I'LL BOOK YOUR NARROW ASS.
- OH, YEAH? AND I'LL
DEVELOP AMNESIA.
I SUDDENLY FEEL A LITTLE CASE
OF IT COMIN' ON RIGHT NOW.
FINE, LADY.
WHERE WOULD YOU FEEL SAFE?
YOU WANT TO DO PROTECTIVE
CUSTODY? WE'LL DO IN-HOME
PROTECTIVE CUSTODY.
AT YOUR HOME, ALL RIGHT?
I CAN HANDLE GOIN'
TO YOUR PLACE.
YEAH, MY-MY-MY PLACE.
MY PLACE IS-- NO WAY.
[ BARKS ]
RIGHT, RIGHT.
MY PLA--
YEAH! NO! MY PLACE--
YEAH, MY PLACE IS SHIT.
MI-MIKE LOWREY PLACE.
YOU RIGHT. WHEW.
THAT'S THE BEST IDEA
YOU CAME UP WITH TONIGHT.
YEAH, MY PLACE.
WAIT HERE.
DETECTIVE BURNETT.
HOW ARE YA?
LONG TIME NO SEE.
I'M COOL.
MR. LOWREY'S NOT HERE. HE'S OUT.
HE SAID I COULD USE HIS PLACE TONIGHT.
HE DIDN'T MENTION IT TO ME.
WHO'S THE CHICK?
HOW'S YOUR WIFE?
[ CHUCKLING ]
FINE. SHE'S FINE.
AND YOUR KIDS? THEY'RE GOOD?
FAMILY'S THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING, YOU KNOW. IS IT?
MR. LOWREY TOLD ME YOU GOT
A BABY FACTORY GOIN' ON
AT YOUR HOUSE. IS THAT TRUE?
HERE YOU GO.
[ JOINTS CRACKING ]
AHH!
IF THAT AIN'T ENOUGH,
I'M GONNA RUN YOU IN
FOR EXTORTION.
YOU KNOW, I'M SO
STUPID SOMETIMES.
ARE YOU?
NOW THAT YOU MENTION IT,
MR. LOWREY DID MENTION
YOU COMING BY TONIGHT.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
DID HE SAY HE HAD A KEY?
MM-HMM. HANG OUT.
HERE YOU GO.
HANG OUT?
THIS IT?
YEAH. YOU'RE HURTING ME.
THANK YOU.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
HAVE FUN.
IT'S NOT LIKE THAT.
SURE, SURE.
[ DOOR OPENS,
JULIE CLEARS THROAT ]
[ MARCUS ] AHEM. YEAH,
COME ON. WATCH YOUR STEP
WALKIN' THROUGH HERE.
DAMN. I MUST HAVE LEFT
SOME INCENSE BURNIN'.
WELCOME TO
CASA DE LOWREY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THIS IS KIND OF--
I'M ALWAYS MOVIN' MY SWITCHES.
SEE, I'M ALWAYS DECORATIN',
SO SOMETIMES I JUST DON'T KNOW
WHERE SHIT IS.
[ THUD ]
DAMN!
SHIT!
WHY AM I TRIPPIN' ON SHIT
I KNOW IS THERE?
[ SIGHS ]
OHH. SEE YOU FOUND
A LIGHT SWITCH.
I SHOULD'VE KNOWN IT WAS THERE
SINCE I DECORATED THE PLACE.
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- YEAH.
- [ ANSWERING MACHINE ]
HI, MIKE. THIS IS YVETTE.
IGNORE THIS.
THIS IS ONE OF
MY FREAKS, YVETTE.
SHE'S ALWAYS CALLIN'.
GOT TO HAVE IT. DON'T
CALL HERE NO MORE NOW.
-JUST ONE OF MY FREAKS.
-ALL OF THIS ON A COP'S SALARY?
[ YVETTE CONTINUES
ON ANSWERING MACHINE ]
UH, WELL-- [ LAUGHS ]
IT'S HONEST MONEY.
I'M A SECOND GENERATION
RICH KID.
SO IF YOU'RE NOT IN IT FOR
THE PAYCHECK, WHAT ARE YOU,
SOME KIND OF ACTION JUNKIE?
YEAH. [ LAUGHS ]
THAT WHAT YOU WANNA CALL IT.
I DON'T MIND BATS
SWUNG AT MY HEAD, BULLETS
DAMN NEAR GRAZIN' MY ASS.
GIVES ME A RUSH.
UH, LOOK,
LET ME GIVE YOU
A BROAD STROKE OF THE PLACE.
UH, GOT SOME T-BONES IN
THE FRIDGE FOR LUKE AND DUKIE.
SORRY. YOUR FRIDGE
IS THIS WAY.
I CONFUSE MY OWN SHIT. UH--
WAIT A MINUTE, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT, ARE YOU GONNA LEAVE ME
HERE ALONE?
YEAH, I GOTTA GET BACK
TO THE P.D. THESE ARE
MIAMI'S PEAK CRIME HOURS.
YOU KNOW.
APPARENTLY.
YOU KNOW, THEY SAID THAT
THIS DEAL WAS GOING DOWN
IN FOUR DAYS,
AND I, YOU KNOW,
OBVIOUSLY SEEM TO BE
KIND OF A MAJOR GLITCH--
HEY, Y-YOU AIN'T WITH
THE BAD GUYS NOW.
YOU WITH THE COPS.
WITH MIKE LOWREY.
YOU WITH THE COPS, OKAY?
EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
TRUST ME. HEY--
[ IMITATING ARNOLD
SCHWARZENEGGER ]
I'LL BE BACK.
I KNOW THAT
IT'S NO TIME TO JOKE,
BUT REMEMBER IN THE MOVIE--
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING, MIKE.
[ LAUGHS ]
I'M GONNA GO.
AHEM.
[ BELL DINGS ]
WHEW.
CHET.
-THAT WAS QUICK. YOU ONE
OF THOSE GUYS? IN AND OUT.
-IT'S NOT LIKE THAT. THE GIRL--
- SHE'S A WITNESS. I NEED
YOU TO KEEP AN EYE OUT.
- NO PROBLEM.
NOW LISTEN TO ME. HEAR ME.
- ME? OKAY.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
- THE MOMENT LOWREY GETS IN,
YOU HAVE HIM CALL ME AT HOME.
- OKAY, CALL YOU AT HOME.
- USE THIS PHONE.
DO NOT LET HIM GO UPSTAIRS.
- DON'T LET HIM UPSTAIRS?
HE LIVES HERE. I-I DON'T WANT
TO ARGUE WITH MR. LOWREY.
I COULD LOSE MY JOB.
CHET, TRUST ME
ON THIS, OKAY?
CALL YOU FROM HERE.
DON'T LET HIM UP.
- NO PROBLEM. OKAY.
- IMPORTANT WITNESS.
THANK YOU.
I GOT A BETTER IDEA. I'M GETTING
OFF IN TWO HOURS. I COULD GO
UPSTAIRS AND WATCH THE DOOR.
YOU KNOW, LIKE THE
COPS DO IN THE MOVIES?
THEY SIT ON A STOOL?
CHET--
I GOT A MAGAZINE
AND EVERYTHING.
- AND I DON'T LET
ANYBODY IN OR OUT?
- CHET!
SERIOUSLY, YOU KNOW,
ALL KIDDING ASIDE,
I WANNA HELP.
- YOU'RE HELPIN'.
CAN YOU DO IT FROM HERE?
- YEAH, I CAN DO IT FROM HERE.
FINE. THAT HELPS.
FROM HERE, OKAY?
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
IT'S FUNNY THAT YOU ASK ME,
BECAUSE YOU KNOW,
I WAS GONNA BE A COP.
I TOOK THE TEST AND EVERYTHING.
YOU KNOW, JUST DIDN'T WORK OUT.
POLITICS.
- YEAH. I KNOW.
- YEAH?
YOU'RE MY DEPUTY.
FROM HERE.
I'M YOUR DEPUTY. GREAT.
- WATCH OUT FOR EVERYTHING.
- YOU GOT IT.
TAKE CARE, CHIEF.
I'M A DEPUTY.
DON'T "HONEY BABY" ME.
YOU SMELL LIKE PERFUME.
[ STAMMERING ]
I-IT WAS JUST--
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
AND YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE
YOUR WEDDING RING ON!
DAMN. UM--
NAH, I WENT UNDERCOVER.
AND SO IT REQUIRED
THE TAKING OFF OF THE RING,
THAT'S ALL, FOR A SECOND.
BUT I GOT THE RING. LOOK, I
JUST PUT MY HAND IN MY POCKET
'CAUSE THAT'S WHERE IT WAS,
AND IT'S RIGHT BACK ON, BABY.
DAMN.
[ SIGHS ]
CAN I GET A PILLOW?
WELL, IF IT ISN'T
THE GUY WHO DOESN'T
RETURN PHONE CALLS.
YOU MIND TELLIN' ME
WHERE THE HELL YOU BEEN
THE LAST 12 HOURS?
I BEEN PAGIN' YOU ALL NIGHT.
WE GOT A SITUATION HERE THAT
I THINK YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT.
LOOK, MARCUS, I GOT A DEAD
MADAM, I GOT A CONCUSSION
AND I GOT A REAL BAD HEADACHE.
YOU GOT A HEADACHE.
LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT I DID LAST NIGHT.
I HAD TO SLEEP ON MY COUCH.
I WAKE UP THIS MORNIN', I GOT
A POWER RANGER STUCK UP MY ASS.
AND WHILE WE'RE DISCUSSIN'
MY ASS? I DAMN NEAR
GOT IT BLOWN OFF.
BUT GUESS WHAT
THE GOOD NEWS IS.
I GOT A WITNESS.
- MARCUS, MARCUS, MARCUS. SHH!
- LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT
THIS WITNESS--
YOU SOUND LIKE
A NAGGING WIFE.
I'M NAGGING. I'M NAGGING.
YOU SEE WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU GO OFF WITHOUT ME?
YOU GET INTO SHIT.
OH, PLEASE, LIKE
SHIT DON'T HAPPEN
WHEN YOU'RE THERE.
THAT AIN'T THE POINT, OKAY?
THE POINT IS, IF YOUR
PARTNER PAGES YOU,
YOU MIGHT WANNA
GET BACK TO YOUR PARTNER.
[ MARCUS ]
I WANNA MEET THE MAN
WHO WHUPPED YOUR ASS.
I WANNA MEET
WHO WHUPPED SHAFT'S ASS,
THAT'S WHAT I WANNA DO.
LOOK AT ME, MAN.
LAST NIGHT-- YOU DON'T
KNOW WHAT I BEEN THROUGH.
MY WIFE DONE KICKED ME
OUT THE HOUSE. KICKED ME
OUT OF HAPPY HOME.
BUT NO, YOU GOT TO
GO OFF BY YOURSELF.
"I GOT THIS, PARTNER.
I GOT THIS."
BULLSHIT.
I AM FEELING MUCH BETTER,
THOUGH, THANK YOU.
YEAH, YEAH. UH-HUH.
AND I'M GONNA
GET HIS ASS.
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER ]
[ MARCUS ]
WATCH YOURSELF.
HO! WHAT DID I SAY?
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I SAID?
I HEARD WHAT I SAID 'CAUSE I WAS
STANDIN' THERE WHEN I SAID IT.
I TOLD YOU
TO SECURE A WITNESS.
NOT TO SHOOT UP A NEIGHBORHOOD!
NOT TO DO ANOTHER DEAD BODY!
JUST GET THE DOPE BACK
AND DO IT QUIETLY.
LOOK, CAP'N.
THIS WHOLE SITUATION
IS GETTIN' OUT OF CONTROL.
YOU'RE GODDAMN RIGHT
IT'S GETTIN' OUT OF CONTROL!
LOOK, MAN,
I DAMN NEAR HAD TO
PASS A POP QUIZ BEFORE
SHE BELIEVED I WAS HIM.
GOIN', GOIN'-- SHIT.
A LITTLE OFF.
I HAVEN'T KILLED ANYBODY
YET TODAY, CAPTAIN.
HEY, DO YOU WANT ME
TO YELL AT YOU?
'CAUSE I CAN DO THAT.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
THIS WITNESS? IT'S THE ONLY
GOOD NEWS I GOT.
YOU GUYS ARE BAD NEWS.
SO WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
IF YOU HAVE TO BE MIKE LOWREY,
SANTA CLAUS, F.D. HUTTON,
I DON'T GIVE A SHIT.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE GONNA BE!
- WHOA, WHOA, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT THE HELL IS GOIN' ON?
I WAS GETTIN' 'EM ALL IN
BEFORE YOU SHOWED UP.
CAN SOMEBODY TALK TO ME,
PLEASE? CAN I KNOW
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
CAPTAIN, THESE FOOLS
COULD HAVE GOTTEN A LOOK
AT MY LICENSE PLATE LAST NIGHT.
SO WHERE'S THE GIRL NOW?
[ DRIBBLING BALL ]
- HIS PLACE.
- WHAT?
YOU LEFT HER BY HERSELF?
OUR ONLY FUCKIN' WITNESS?
YOU LEFT A STRANGE HOOKER
ALONE IN MY APARTMENT?
THE GIRL IS NOT A HOOKER,
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
I HAD TO STASH HER SOMEWHERE--
HER AND HER DOGS,
LUKE AND DUKIE.
SO YOU LEFT DOGS IN MY HOUSE?
SO THERE'S DOGS AND A HOOKER
IN MY HOUSE.
-HOW ABOUT YOU ADD SOME CHIMPS?
WE CAN HAVE A CARNIVAL.
-SHE WASN'T NO HOOKER.
HEY! SHUT UP!
FOR YEARS, SINCLAIR
HAS BEEN UP MY ASS, TRYIN'
TO PIN SOMETHIN' ON ME.
I'M ALWAYS TAKIN' IT
FOR YOU, RIGHT?
DO IT FOR ME.
NOW IF WE GET THIS WITNESS
TO I.D. THE SHOOTERS,
MAYBE WE CATCH OUR BAD GUYS.
BUT UNTIL THEN--
UNTIL THEN, YOU ARE MIKE LOWREY.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU ARE. YOU'RE
HIM. I DON'T WANNA HEAR IT.
- MAN, I--
AND YOU, YOU'RE YOU.
YOU BE YOU, BUT NOT
IN FRONT OF HER.
YOU'RE HIM.
YOU'RE YOU.
AH.
UH, CAN WE GET A TIME-OUT
HERE, CAPTAIN? WHAT AM I,
LIKE THE DESIGNATED HOMELESS?
HEY, DOES IT LOOK LIKE I CARE?
WHATEVER IT TAKES, ALL RIGHT?
WHAT DID SHE SAY TO YOU?
THE SHOOTERS ARE GONNA MAKE
THEIR DROP IN FOUR DAYS?
- SO WE GOT FOUR DAYS.
- CAPTAIN, WHAT KIND
OF PLAN IS THAT, MAN?
I CAN'T BE SHACKED UP
WITH THAT WOMAN!
I HAVE A FAMILY TO LOOK AFTER.
MY WIFE WILL KILL MY ASS!
YOU DON'T LIKE
YOUR JOB?
QUIT.
DAMN!
LOOK, I'LL STAY AT THE HOUSE
WITH THERESA AND THE KIDS.
THANK YOU, BUT NO THANKS.
YOU WOULDN'T LAST FIVE MINUTES
WITH MY FAMILY.
PLEASE, MAN, MARRIED LIFE
IS EASY. YOU ONLY GOT
ONE WOMAN TO SATISFY.
YO, MAN.
WE AIN'T THE COSBYS.
LET'S GO.
I GOT THIS.
GO.
EVERYBODY WANTS
TO BE LIKE MIKE.
YEAH, AND YOU'RE GONNA BE
RETIRED LIKE HIM TOO.
I'D HAVE DUNKED IT
ON YOUR ASS.
CLEVELAND? I HAVE NEVER--
OOH!
HEY, LOOK, WOMAN.
I DONE TOLD YOU, OKAY?
IT'S A FEDERAL SUBPOENA.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO,
TELL THEM NO?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE GONNA
TELL 'EM. WHY CAN'T HE GO?
WHY CAN'T YOU GO?
OH, YOU KNOW, I WANTED TO.
CAPTAIN HOWARD SAID,
YOU KNOW, I'M IRRESPONSIBLE.
- NO, HE SAID "LOOSE CANNON,"
'CAUSE I'M SHOOTIN' IN PUBLIC.
- MIKE!
- BANG, BANG, JUST
OUT OF NOWHERE SOMETIMES.
- MIKE! NO, MAN.
PLEASE.
LOOK, BABY, OKAY?
MM-MMM.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD HAS HAD
A LOT OF BREAK-INS.
I CAN HANDLE IT.
-I DON'T NEED MIKE TO HANDLE IT.
-I KNOW YOU CAN HANDLE IT,
BUT I'M WORRYIN' ABOUT ME.
MIKE'S GONNA STAY HERE WITH
YOU AND THE KIDS, TAKE CARE OF
Y'ALL, JUST 'TIL I COME BACK.
[ THERESA ] WHO'S GONNA PICK
THE KIDS UP FROM DAY CARE?
MIKE CAN'T DO IT.
ARE YOU LISTENIN'
TO ME, BABY? I SAID MI--
I READ A BOOK...
THAT COULD PROBABLY
HELP Y'ALL.
- IT WAS--
- MIKE, PLEASE.
CAN YOU GO DOWN, HAVE
A COKE AND A SMILE, PLEASE?
ALL RIGHT.
Y'ALL WANT SOMETHIN'?
BRING ME A COKE, MIKE.
BABY, YOU WANT A COKE?
- I'M FINE, THANK YOU.
- MIKE!
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
SO EXPLAIN IT TO ME, ELLIOT.
WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM
WITH OUR CHEMISTRY SET?
- IT'S NOT A CHEMISTRY SET.
- HE KNOWS IT AIN'T
A CHEMISTRY SET, ASSHOLE.
SO, WHAT IS IT?
THE CUTTING AGENT IS
A HIGHLY VOLATILE SUBSTANCE.
I DON'T CARE.
I DON'T CARE!
THE ETHER THAT--
I'M NOT A FUCKING
CHEMISTRY TEACHER, ELLIOT.
SO WHAT IS THE PROBLEM?
- THE PROBLEM IS THAT THERE'S
TOO MUCH MOISTURE DOWN HERE.
- YEAH. IT'S TOTALLY FUCKED.
- YOU SHUT UP!
- OKAY.
SO WHAT ELSE?
IT'S TAKING LONGER TO COOK
THAN WE ORIGINALLY PLANNED,
AND IF WE RUSH IT,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE A LOT
OF DRUGS THAT WE CAN'T SELL.
YOU'RE FUCKING WITH
MY TIMETABLE HERE.
I GAVE YOU A DEADLINE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I UNDERSTAND.
JULIE?
YEAH.
OH, YOU, UM,
DRESSED?
HI.
YEAH, YEAH. I AM.
OKAY, UM, LOOK.
WE GOTTA GO THROUGH
SOME MUG SHOTS.
SO I'M GONNA HOOK
INTO THE COMPUTER.
WE CAN DO THIS.
HEY, MIKE, WHO'S THE GUY
IN ALL THE PHOTOGRAPHS?
OH. I-- YOU KNOW,
SOMETIMES I DON'T EVEN
LOOK AT MY SHELVES,
AND I FORGOT
ALL THE PICTURES
WAS HERE.
THAT'S MY PARTNER.
YEAH, THAT'S MY PARTNER,
MARCUS BURNETT.
OH. I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE.
WELL, I CAN SEE HOW IT MAY
THROW YOU A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S A COP THING. YEAH,
THESE PICTURES ARE UP HERE
FOR EVERY TIME HE SAVE MY LIFE.
IT'S THE SAME THING WITH HIM.
YOU GO TO HIS PLACE, AIN'T
NOTHIN' BUT PICTURES OF ME.
- 'CAUSE IT'S LIKE A SHRINE.
JUST A REMINDER.
- OH.
'CAUSE, I MEAN, WHEN I SAW IT,
YOU KNOW, IT WAS LIKE
THE WHOLE WALL,
I THOUGHT MAYBE
THEY WERE, YOU KNOW,
PICTURES OF YOUR LOVER.
- OF WHO?
- I THOUGHT THAT-- YOU KNOW,
I THOUGHT MAYBE YOU WERE GAY.
[ AWKWARD LAUGH ]
THAT I WAS GAY.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, BABY.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO OFFEND YOU.
IT'S LIKE OKAY TO BE
A HOMOSEXUAL, MIKE.
NO, Y-Y-Y-YOU NOT LISTENIN'.
IT'S NOT REGISTERIN', OKAY?
BELIEVE ME. DID YOU--
DID YOU SLEEP IN THE BED?
YOU DIDN'T FEEL THE DENTS?
YEAH, THE DENTS COME
FROM ALL THAT. THAT'S
HOW I GETS DOWN, OKAY?
OH, THAT'S... SWEET.
GAY. [ SCOFFS ] IF I WAS,
I'D CHANGE THE DRAPES
IN THIS MOTHERFUCKER.
- [ BEEPING ]
- [ JULIE ] NO.
WANT SOME?
NO, THANKS.
I DON'T EAT FLESH.
DO WHAT?
THAT'S FLESH...
THAT YOU'RE SHOVELING
INTO YOUR MOUTH.
THAT WAS
LIKE A LIVING,
BREATHING CREATURE.
IT PROBABLY
HAD A NAME.
IT'S JUST BALONEY.
MY BALONEY HAS A FIRST NAME.
ACTUALLY, YOUR BALONEY
HAS ABOUT 30 NAMES,
'CAUSE THEY TAKE
LIKE ODD PARTS FROM
ALL DIFFERENT ONES.
LIKE THE LEFTOVERS--
THE HOOVES, YOU KNOW,
STOMACH LINING,
EARS,
STUFF LIKE THAT--
AND THEY PUT IT
INTO THIS MACHINE
AND GRIND IT ALL UP.
AND THEN PFFT!
OUT COMES THIS SHEET.
THAT'S LIKE WHAT
YOU'RE EATING NOW.
WHEW. OKAY. AHEM.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T EAT BALONEY NO MORE.
HOW 'BOUT A PICKLE?
- CAN I EAT THE PICKLE?
- THERE'S A LOT OF SALT IN IT,
BUT YEAH, IT'S FINE.
IT IS A VEGETABLE.
LOT OF SALT IN PICKLE?
OKAY, LET ME RINSE IT--
LET ME RINSE IT OFF.
THERE WE GO.
- HMM? HOW'S THAT?
- JUST... JUST KEEP GOIN'.
I DON'T EVEN TASTE
THE SALT NOW.
[ TAPPING KEYBOARD ]
GO BACK. GO BACK.
THAT'S THE GUY.
HE WAS THERE, IN THE ROOM.
WE GOT A TIP THEY WAS RUNNIN'
SOME MAJOR DRUGGAGE UP THERE,
SOMETHIN' LIKE 50 KEYS.
SO WE STEPS TO THE DOOR.
BOOM! FREEZE!
MIAMI P.D.! GET DOWN!
OUT OF NOWHERE, THIS LITTLE
CRAZY PIMP NAMED CHINO...
PUNCHED ME IN THE HEAD
WITH SOME BRASS KNUCKLES.
CHINO BE RUNNIN' HO'S.
YOUR DAD WILL EXPLAIN
THAT TO YOU.
LOOK AT IT.
YOUR DOGS.
THEY'RE SHITTIN'
ALL OVER MY PLACE.
LIQUID SHIT.
IT DOESN'T HELP,
YOU GOING AROUND SHELLACKING
IT IN WITH FURNITURE POLISH.
THERE'S A PIECE RIGHT THERE.
PLEASE, GET THAT.
FINE.
IT LOOK LIKE
A CHIP OF SHIT.
FRANCINE, CAN I PLEASE
HAVE THE PAROLE JACKET
ON NOAH TRAFFICANTE?
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT, MAN?
I'M GETTIN' TIRED
OF THIS WITNESS, MAN.
I WANNA GET BACK TO MY LIFE
THE WAY IT WAS. I'M TIRED.
I GOT MARRIED
SO I COULD STOP LYIN'.
I CANNOT BELIEVE
YOU COMPLAININ'.
YOU GOT IT EASY COMPARED
TO ME, LIVIN' IN THAT ZOO
YOU CALL HOME.
HEY, MAN. WHY YOU GOT
TO CALL MY PLACE A ZOO?
I'M TIRED OF YOU TALKIN'
THAT STUFF.
YOU WANNA FIGHT ME.
NO, BUT DON'T CALL MY PLACE NO ZOO.
LISTEN, LISTEN. FRANCINE, PLEASE.
LIS--
YO, THAT'S
MY SILK SHIRT, MAN!
OH.
YEAH, IT IS KINDA NICE.
I FIGURE SINCE I'M GONNA
BE LIKE MIKE, I MIGHT AS WELL
DRESS LIKE MIKE.
I MEAN--
♪ I WANNA BE
I WANNA BE LIKE MIKE ♪
- POW! HUH?
- YOU'RE SICK.
SEE, SOMETHING IS WRONG
WITH YOU.
YEAH.
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM AND YOU
SHOULD HAVE YOURSELF CHECKED.
YEAH. PROBABLY.
[ LAUGHING ]
HERE'S THE FILE.
HE WORKS
AT CLUB HELL.
THANK YOU.
[ BEEPER BEEPING ]
CAN YOU TAKE CARE
OF THIS, PLEASE?
I GOTTA CALL THE WIFE.
WHOSE WIFE?
CAN YOU PLEASE
DO SOME WORK?
ONE TIME TODAY.
JUST DO SOMETHING.
NO, I'M GONNA TELL YOU--
DO SOMETHING
THAT HELPS THIS CASE.
BOY--
YOU LOOK
REAL HANDSOME
TODAY, MARCUS.
NO, SEE, IT'S NOT
THAT KINDA DAY, OKAY?
LEAVE ME
THE FUCK ALONE.
SERIOUSLY.
ALL RIGHT?
WHAT'S UP?
P.M.S.?
NO, DAMN THE JOKES.
DAMN 'EM.
RING IT, OKAY?
I AIN'T IN THE MOOD.
HEY. YEAH, YEAH.
THAT'S COOL. HOLD ON.
[ WOMAN ON PHONE ]
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, GO AHEAD.
[ WOMAN ON PHONE,
INDISTINCT ]
ALL RIGHT. HOW THINGS
GOIN' WITH THE KIDS?
THEY'RE FINE.
THEY'RE OKAY.
HOW'S THAT POTTY TRAININ'
THING GOIN'? [ LAUGHS ]
-YOU ARE SO SILLY.
-ARE YOU GONNA BE LATE TONIGHT?
NAH, IT'LL BE 10:30,
11:00 BEFORE I GET IN.
OKAY, I'LL WAIT.
NAH, DON'T WAIT UP.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[ DIAL TONE ]
WHY DON'T YOU RENT
A MOVIE OR SOMETHING?
SOMETHING WE CAN KICK BACK TO.
[ LAUGHING ]
- SO WHAT YOU WEARING?
- GIMME THE PHONE!
GIMME THE PHONE! BABY!
SHE HUNG UP A LONG TIME AGO.
I WAS PLAYIN'.
BABY!
MAN, I'M--
HEY, NO.
I WAS PLAYIN'.
[ LAUGHING ]
HELLO?
HEY, MAN. DON'T PLAY
LIKE THAT, OKAY?
- THAT'S MY FAMILY.
DON'T BREAK UP A HAPPY HOME.
- STOP WEARIN' MY CLOTHES THEN.
[ LAUGHING ]
BOY, EVERYBODY'S 'BOUT
THE MOTHERFUCKIN' JOKES
TODAY, AIN'T THEY? HELLO?
[ MIKE SIGHS ]
I CANNOT BELIEVE THIS.
COME ON, FRANCINE.
THIS EDDIE DOMINGUEZ FILE
CANNOT BE THAT HARD TO GET INTO.
I'VE TRIED THREE TIMES.
I JUST CAN'T GET IN.
BESIDES, YOU KNOW,
THIS IS ILLEGAL.
[ MIKE ]
WELL, YEAH, THAT NEVER
STOPPED YOU BEFORE.
JUST LET ME KNOW
IF YOU GET ANYTHING,
ALL RIGHT?
ANYTHING FOR YOU,
BUT I CAN'T GET IN.
I TRIED.
♪ IT'S JUST ME
AGAINST THE WORLD ♪
♪ OOH OOH OOH OOH
♪ IT'S ME AGAINST
THE WORLD, BABY ♪
♪ OH OH
WHAT'S UP, CHET?
HEY, MR. LOWREY.
CHET.
OKAY.
THE LOWREY BROTHERS.
[ MIKE ]
LET'S JUST GET DOWN TO
CLUB HELL AND PICK UP NOAH.
JULIE, IT'S ME.
WHAT'S UP? YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE GETTIN' US INTO
THIS EDDIE DOMINGUEZ FILE.
IT'S GONNA BE
A DAY OR TWO BEFORE
I CAN GET FLETCH OUT.
WE DON'T HAVE NO DAY OR TWO.
I'M NOT THE COMPUTER WHIZ.
-IT'S GONNA TAKE AWHILE BEFORE
WE CAN HACK THE COMPUTER.
-YOU'RE NOT TAKING CARE OF SHIT.
[ JULIE ]
MIKE, I WAS THINKING
ABOUT SOMETHING. HI.
YOU MUST ME... MARCUS. MARCUS.
MARCUS. I'M MARCUS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MARCUS.
M-MARCUS, RIGHT.
I'M... JULIE.
JULIE.
ALL RIGHT.
JULIE, YEAH. HI.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
YOU TOO.
I RECOGNIZE YOU FROM
EVERY ONE OF THE PHOTOGRAPHS.
OH, YEAH, WELL,
YOU KNOW, HE'S MY MAN.
[ ALL CHUCKLE NERVOUSLY ]
ON THE WALL.
THOSE ON THE WALL.
YEAH.
WELL, YOU MUST BE VERY GOOD.
- I'M SORRY.
- A-AS A PARTNER.
GIVEN WHAT--
YOUR JOB. WHAT YOU DO.
UM, WHAT TIME ARE WE, UH,
DOING THIS THING TONIGHT?
EXCUSE ME?
MIKE SAID THAT
WE'RE GOING TO A CLUB.
[ LAUGHS ]
YEAH, WELL, WE,
AS IN ME AND MY PARTNER.
YOU WANTED HOME PROTECTIVE
CUSTODY. YOU AT MY HOUSE.
OH, THAT'S JUST GREAT.
SO I'LL JUST STAY HERE AGAIN
WITH CHET THE MINI-MORON DOORMAN
TO PROTECT ME?
- CHET IS VERY GOOD.
- OH! I'M SOR--
THAT... LOOKS LIKE A STAIN
ON YOUR RUG. DAMN.
YEAH, THAT'S MY BABY,
LUKE.
HE GETS KINDA NERVOUS
IN NEW SURROUNDINGS AND--
HE JUST SHITS, HUH?
YEAH, IT'S SORT OF--
IT'S LIKE MARKING HIS TERRITORY.
SORT OF
A MALE THING.
I OFFERED TO PAY MIKE
FOR THE CLEANING.
HE WOULDN'T HEAR OF IT.
- I'M GONNA GET RID OF IT.
- YEAH, YOU DON'T NEED THAT.
I WAS GONNA THROW THAT OUT.
I JUST WANT A NEW LOOK.
MIKE, HE'S A SPECIAL GUY.
BOY, THAT MIKE IS SPECIAL.
THAT'S WHAT I CALL HIM,
"SPECIAL MIKE."
[ LAUGHING ]
IT'S FUNNY HOW YOU COULD
JUST LAUGH AT THAT.
THAT'S WHY I LOVE HIM.
NOW, ME?
WHOO! I'D BE PISSED!
- [ CLEARS THROAT ]
- AND LOOK AT THIS CUTE
LITTLE DOG ON THE COUCH.
THAT'S LUKE.
LOOK HOW HE CRAWLS AROUND
ON THE LEATHER.
YOU WANNA MEET DUKE?
HE'S-- HE'S IN THE BED.
HE'S BEEN FEELING UPSET
AND HAVING DIARRHEA
AND THROWING UP ALL MORNING.
[ JULIE ]
OH, BABY.
OH, LET'S GO SEE IF LITTLE DUKE
IS GONNA BE OKAY, SHALL WE?
[ GROWLING, YAPPING ]
ME AND YOU.
♪ OH, MIKE.
- HEY, LADY, WHO ARE YOU?
- WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
- LOOK, YOU GOTTA GET OUT.
- GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
- LADY, DON'T PUSH ME!
- HEY, I'M YVETTE!
YOU'RE NOT ANY YVETTE
I KNOW.
GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
HEY, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
GET-- OH, LOOK.
GET OUTTA HERE, ALL RIGHT?
IF YOU DON'T STOP STALKIN' ME,
I'M GONNA ARREST YOUR ASS.
[ MARCUS ]
AND I'M TELLIN' YOU,
YOU OLD PSYCHO!
[ YVETTE POUNDS ON DOOR ]
YOU ASSHOLE!
WOMAN'S INTO SOME WEIRD SHIT.
WHAT IS GOIN' ON
OUT HERE?
EXCUSE ME.
THAT WAS CRAZY YVETTE.
STALKIN' ME.
[ LAUGHING ]
YVETTE? I FORGOT
SHE WAS COMIN'!
YOU THREW YVETTE OUT?
[ SIGHS ]
YVETTE IS A MASSEUSE.
HUH?
SHE MASSAGES SHIT.
SHE TOLD ME.
HEY, LISTEN,
ARE THERE ANY OTHER
TOTALLY HYSTERICAL...
HALF-NAKED WOMEN
POPPING BY TONIGHT
THAT I SHOULD KNOW ABOUT?
- SHE WAS NAKED?
- TITTIES WERE OUT A LITTLE BIT.
YOU THREW YVETTE OUT NAKED?
OKAY. YOU--
YOU'RE SOMETHIN'--
SEE, MY WIFE WOULD HATE--
SHE HATES WOMANIZERS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU.
SOMETHIN' WRONG WITH YOU.
THERE IS?
YOU DON'T RESPECT OTHER PEOPLE'S
SHIT, THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
- I BEEN TELLIN' YOU THAT SINCE
WE STARTED. YOU ALWAYS HAVE--
- [ JULIE TALKING, INDISTINCT ]
ENOUGH! PLEASE!
ME AND MY PARTNER,
WE'RE GONNA GO
TO CLUB HELL...
SO WE CAN BUST
THIS FOOL NOAH.
- DOES ANYBODY HAVE
A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
- FINE!
DON'T BLOW THE CASE.
♪ [ ROCK ]
OKAY, FRANK,
HERE'S THE DEAL.
YOU STAY PUT. ANYBODY
TELLS YOU TO MOVE, DON'T.
I DON'T CARE WHAT THEY SAY.
TELL 'EM YOU'RE MAKING
A DELIVERY FOR MR. FOUCHET.
YOU GOT IT? FRANK?
FRANK. OH, GEEZ.
IT'S ETHER!
IT'LL EXPLODE, YOU DOPE!
DON'T EVEN BREATHE,
YOU KNUCKLEHEAD!
[ BEEPING ]
NOAH.
I REMEMBER YOU.
[ SCREAMING ]
CHECK IT, LOWREY.
WE GOT TWO DAYS LEFT.
LET'S TRY TO DO THIS RIGHT.
NO GUNSHOTS,
NO DEAD BODIES.
I'M NOT TRYIN' TO LOSE
MY JOB ON THIS ONE.
IF I RECALL CORRECTLY,
THE LAST COUPLE DEAD BAD GUYS
BELONGED TO YOU.
AND NEXT TIME
YOU HAVE TO KILL 'EM,
WHY DON'T YOU DO IT AFTER WE GET
THE INFORMATION WE NEED?
- THAT'S JUST A SUGGESTION.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- PLEASE.
YOU AIN'T EVEN TRYING
TO COMPARE BODY COUNTS.
ONE, HUH, HUH, HUH, HUH, HUH?
SHOULD I KEEP GOIN'?
- OH, DAMN, I'M OUT.
- ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
THIS GUY NOAH'S PAROLE JACKET
SAYS HE WORKS IN THERE.
WE'RE STANDING OUT FRONT
ARGUING LIKE A COUPLE
OF SCHOOLGIRLS.
- WHAT DO YOU SAY WE PUT AN END
TO ALL THIS BICKERING, HUH?
- RIGHT.
'CAUSE YOU'RE STARTIN' TO GET
ON MY GODDAMN NERVES!
♪ [ ROCK ]
THE GUY. THE GUY.
HE GOT NO PACKAGE.
THAT AIN'T NO GUY.
♪ DIVINE
♪ SISTER SALVATION
♪ JUKE-JOINT JEZEBEL'S COMING
FOR MY CREMATION ♪
- [ GASPING ]
- ♪ DIVINE
LOOK AT YA. LOOK AT YA.
CAN YOU STAY FOCUSED?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I'M FOCUSED!
YEAH, FOCUSED ON ALL THIS
SCATTERED ASS AROUND HERE.
LET'S DO WHAT WE CAME TO DO
AND GET THE FUCK OUTTA HERE.
SIMPLE.
FINE. SPLIT UP,
CHECK AROUND. MEET YOU
AT THE BAR IN TEN MINUTES.
FINE.
♪ [ ROCK CONTINUES ]
[ MAN ]
HOLY SHIT! WHAT THE HELL
IS HE DOIN'? OH, MAN!
THAT'S THE COP!
THERE HE IS! SEE HIM?
[ SECOND MAN ]
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH!
THAT'S HIM! I'M GOIN'!
♪ [ HUMMING ]
WHAT'S UP?
[ MARCUS ]
WHOO! BUDWEISER.
FEEL LIKE I HAD
A MILLION OF 'EM.
[ SWITCHBLADE CLICKING ]
[ GROANS ]
WHAT'S UP, MOTHERFUCKER?
TELL ME WHERE TO THROW
THIS JACK-OFF!
- [ GASPING ]
- [ SCREAMING ]
ALL RIGHT.
[ GRUNTING, SHOUTING ]
OH, FUCK!
[ CLICKING ]
[ MARCUS SHOUTS ]
NEXT TIME, LEARN HOW TO WORK
THE SAFETY WITH YOUR PUNK ASS!
I'LL BE BACK.
- WHO DONE TORE OFF
AND WHUPPED YOUR ASS NOW?
- THIS AIN'T THE TIME!
THIS REALLY AIN'T
THE FUCKIN' TIME!
THEY KNOW.
LET'S GET NOAH
AND GET OUTTA HERE.
♪ [ ROCK ]
HEY, THE CHICK.
LOOK. NO, NO, NO.
THE CHICK!
THE GIRL, RIGHT!
THE BITCH FROM THE ROOFTOP!
♪ I DON'T WANT IT
I DON'T NEED IT ♪
- JULIE!
- [ GUNSHOT ]
[ PATRONS SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
- [ MARCUS ] LET'S GO!
- [ JULIE ] THAT WAS
THE GUY WHO SHOT MAX!
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
THE TRUCK! COME ON!
LET'S TAKE THE TRUCK!
- THERE! RIGHT THERE!
- MOVE, MOVE, MOVE, MOVE!
WE'RE REALLY IN A HURRY.
GO! LET'S GO!
[ JULIE ] YOU'RE COPS!
WHY ARE WE RUNNING AWAY?
HE'S IN THERE!
[ MIKE ]
HERE! GO!
OH, THIS IS GOOD.
NOAH'S CHASIN' US!
WHAT WAS THAT, HUH?
WHAT THE-- WHAT WAS THAT?
THAT WAS I...
DON'T KNOW.
BUT I HAD A PERFECTLY GOOD SHOT
AT HIM. IF YOUR FRIEND
ACTION JACKSON OVER HERE--
- OH, HO, HO!
- NO, NO, NO!
THIS IS OFFICIAL POLICE
BUSINESS! YOU HAD
NO BUSINESS IN THERE!
AND CAN YOU PLEASE
DRIVE THIS THING?
PLEASE DRIVE!
DON'T BRING IT HERE!
DON'T BRING IT HERE,
ALL RIGHT!
YOU THE ONE WHO PICKED
A SLOW-ASS ICE-CREAM TRUCK!
WHAT AM I SMELLIN'?
JUST DRIVE!
- WHAT AM I SMELLIN'?
- [ JULIE ] ETHER!
EXTREMELY FLAMMABLE
ETHER.
- OH, SHIT!
- GODDAMN!
OH, YOU, YOU, YOU THE MAN!
YOU THE FUCKING MAN TONIGHT!
YOU GO AND PICK
AN ICE-CREAM TRUCK
THAT'S A DAMN BOMB!
AH, SHIT!
- THIS IS PROTECTIVE CUSTODY?
- YES!
[ GUNSHOT BLAST ]
[ SHOUTING ]
- [ HORN HONKING ]
- OH, SHIT!
YOU BETTER DO SOMETHIN', BOY,
'CAUSE WE RUNNIN' OUTTA ROAD!
WHO PICKED THIS DUMB-ASS ROAD?
ALL THE GODDAMN ROAD IN MIAMI
AND YOU RUNNIN' OUT OF IT!
YOU BETTER COME UP
WITH AN IDEA FAST!
WHY I GOTTA COME UP
WITH ALL THE IDEAS?
- TAKE THIS SHIT!
- YO, WE COMIN' TO A DEAD END!
THERE'S NO MORE ROAD!
WE OUTTA FUCKIN' ROAD!
- MOTHERFUCKER'S GONNA BLOW!
- GET THE FUCK OUT!
[ MARCUS GROANS, SIGHS ]
WELL. SHOULD I ADD THIS
TO YOUR BODY COUNT?
[ MARCUS ]
THERE GOES OUR ONLY LEAD
TO THE DOPE.
AIN'T THIS A BITCH?
THE DOPE?
THE DO--
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
HOW 'BOUT THERE GOES
OUR ONLY LEAD
TO MAX'S KILLER?
I MEAN, HE'S STILL
OUT THERE. OH.
BUT THAT'S NOT IMPORTANT
'CAUSE IT'S NOT LIKE IT'S
YOUR JOB TO PROTECT PEOPLE.
SEE WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
SHE'S CRAZY!
I'M CRAZY?
[ ARGUING ]
MARCUS!
YOU'RE GONE!
I'M OUTTA HERE!
SHE DONE FUCKIN' ZOOMED!
SHE DONE ZOOMED!
THIS IS THE WITNESS!
THAT'S IT.
YOU DEAL WITH HER.
JULIE!
LISTEN.
NO WAY! I--
[ MARCUS ] BULLSHIT!
YES, OKAY.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THIS WHOLE THING STARTED
BECAUSE OF MISSING DRUGS.
BUT LET ME
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THERE'S NOTHING,
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING
MORE IMPORTANT TO MIKE...
THAN DOIN' THIS GUY
THAT KILLED MAX.
[ SIGHS ]
[ GROWLS ]
I KNOW. I KNOW.
SOMETIMES HE HAS
A HARD TIME EXPRESSING
HIS REAL FEELINGS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SO COME ON.
IT'S GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT, OKAY?
WE NEED YOU.
PART OF THE TEAM.
I THOUGHT HE WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE
THE SMOOTH ONE.
[ MIKE ]
THIS HAS NOT BEEN
A GOOD DAY.
[ MARCUS ]
DAMN RIGHT.
THIS IS BULLSHIT.
WE GOT TWO DAYS
TO FIND THESE FOOLS
AND WE GOT NO LEADS...
'CAUSE YOU COOKED
NOAH'S ASS BACK ON
THE FREEWAY.
♪ [ SINGING IN
MIDDLE EASTERN DIALECT ]
- SHAMPOO?
- HELLO!
THERE.
[ MIKE ] THEN LET'S
JUST DO THAT.
[ MIKE ]
HEY, WHAT'S UP?
HEY.
[ MARCUS ]
JULIE, YOU DON'T TAKE THAT LONG
TO GET SHAMPOO. LET'S GO.
LOOK AT THIS.
"ANIMAL TESTED.
ANIMAL TESTED."
DO YOU KNOW
HOW MANY CHEMICALS
ARE IN THIS STUFF?
I DON'T CARE
IF YOU GO BALD.
GET IT AND LET'S GO.
- JOJO.
- HE IS A CHEMIST.
THERE'S ENTIRELY TOO MUCH
HEROIN AND TOO MUCH ETHER
FOR NOBODY TO KNOW NOTHIN'.
WHAT IS HE
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU KNOW THE BARRELS
OF ETHER THAT BLEW UP
ON THE ICE-CREAM TRUCK?
THEY WERE GONNA USE THAT
TO PROCESS THE HEROIN.
YEAH, THEY DO THAT TO CUT IT.
IT LIKE QUADRUPLES THE VALUE.
[ MARCUS ]
YEAH, YOU CAN'T JUST
STICK IT IN THE MICROWAVE.
MAYBE YOU'RE ON
TO SOMETHING.
LET'S PAY FOR THIS.
HEY, HOW MUCH
IS THAT?
- FOURTEEN TWENTY-FIVE.
- DAMN. I MUST HAVE LEFT
MY WALLET SOMEWHERE.
FREEZE, MOTHER BITCHES!
- DON'T YOU MOVE!
- I'M NOT UNDERSTANDIN'.
I REALLY DON'T.
- SHUT UP!
- DO YOU JUST ATTRACT
VIOLENT PEOPLE?
- SHUT THE FUCK UP!
- TAKE IT EASY, ALL RIGHT?
WE ARE POLICE OFFICERS.
YOU ARE NOT POLICE OFFICERS.
I'M NOT STUPID.
I KNOW. I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN POLICE.
W-W-WHAT ARE YOU?
- I'M GONNA REACH FOR MY BADGE.
- BADGES? YOU WANT BADGES,
MOTHER BITCH?
I GIVE YOU BADGES!
HERE, 99 CENTS EACH!
I SELL YOU SOME.
YOU GOT EIGHT FUCKIN' BADGES.
I TOLD YOU THIS COP THING
DON'T WORK.
I BLOW YOU!
THEN I BLOW YOU!
BLOW ME? WHAT THE FUCK?
NO. HUMP ME. THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I AM FROM THE MIDDLE EAST!
I KILL BEFORE.
I KILL AGAIN!
- FUCK ME, PLEASE! HOLD ON!
- I'M GONNA BLOW YOU!
NO, YOU HOLD ON!
DO YOU SEE THE FUCKIN' EMOTION
I'M GOIN' THROUGH RIGHT NOW?
THAT MEANS THIS SHIT IS SERIOUS.
THAT MEANS ME
AND THIS MOTHERFUCKER'S
NOT VIBIN' RIGHT NOW.
- THAT'S WHAT THAT SHIT MEANS.
- YOU GOT SOMETHIN'
ON YOUR CHEST?
THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYIN'!
DO YOU WANT SOME--
HELLO?
THE GUY'S GOT A CANNON!
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- DO YOU WANT SOME?
- I WANT SOME!
- YOU WANT SOME BAD ENOUGH,
THEN COME AND GET SOME!
- I'M GONE.
- HEY, FREEZE, BITCH!
- YOU FREEZE, BITCH!
OH, SHIT!
I'M FUCKED.
NOW BACK UP,
PUT THE GUN DOWN...
AND GIMME A PACK
OF TROPICAL FRUIT
BUBBLICIOUS.
AND SOME SKITTLES.
HELL OF A NIGHT.
I'M GOIN' TO BED.
SO... MAKE YOURSELF AT HOME.
IT'S YOUR BED.
I'LL SIT DOWN FOR,
YOU KNOW, FOR A MINUTE.
YOU KNOW, 'CAUSE
I'M GUARDIN' SHIT.
I'M WATCHIN' OUT
FOR THE BAD BOYS.
SO, YOU KNOW,
I CAN SEE THINGS.
YOU KNOW, REAL WELL
FROM MY "PERIPHEALS."
YOU KNOW, FOR SUCH A STUD,
MIKE LOWREY,
YOU SURE SEEM A LITTLE RIGID
ABOUT HAVING A GIRL IN YOUR BED.
[ SCOFFS ]
WHO? ME?
MIKE LOWREY?
I'M NOT RIGID.
I'M [ MUMBLING ]
COMFORTABLE.
THIS--
THIS IS MY BED.
[ NERVOUS CHUCKLE ]
WHY WOULD I BE
UNCOMFORTABLE?
MM, I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK IT'S MORE
THAN JUST WIRED.
I MEAN, MAYBE IT WAS ALL
THE GUNS AND STUFF.
I'VE NEVER REALLY SHOT
A GUN BEFORE, AND THAT'S
SORT OF ALL THAT,
I DON'T KNOW, STEEL,
AND I'M FEELING--
DON'T YOU FEEL
A LITTLE... FUNNY?
-WELL, I'M NOT A COMEDIAN, BUT--
-I DON'T MEAN LIKE THAT KIND OF FUNNY.
I MEAN LIKE... FUNNY.
UH, HUH. AH--
NO, NOW, UH--
YOU-YOU-YOU DON'T WANT THAT.
YOU-YOU DON'T WANT THAT,
'CAUSE WHEN I COME,
I COME WITH
THE THUNDER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
MIKE, YOU SOUND LIKE YOU'RE
SAVING YOURSELF FOR MARRIAGE.
UH-- NO. TH-TH-THAT
AIN'T ME THERE.
THAT'S MARCUS.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
HE'S THE MARRIED ONE.
[ LAUGHING ]
I GOT SOME OTHER--
OH, NO.
OH. OH, I DONE
SEEN IT NOW.
TURN THE PAGE.
NO.
TURN THE PAGE, GIRL.
I DONE ALREADY SEEN IT.
HA HA HA-HA HA!
DON'T LAUGH!
NO. I CANNOT BELIEVE
HE WORE HIS AFRO THAT BIG.
I FORGOT ALL ABOUT THAT.
HE LOOKED CUTE
LIKE THAT, I THINK.
WHAT'S MARCUS'S WIFE LIKE?
[ SCOFFS ]
SHE'S LIKE A WIFE.
WELL, I MEAN, SHE MUST BE
PRETTY AMAZING...
TO KEEP A GUY LIKE MARCUS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
K-K-K-KEEP A GUY
LIKE WHAT?
WELL, YOU KNOW,
LIKE WATCHING HIM TONIGHT.
I MEAN, HE'S VERY...
SORT OF TAKE-CHARGE.
YOU KNOW, THE WAY HE WAS
SORT OF THROWING GUYS
THIS WAY AND THAT.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT HIM.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
YOU KNOW, HE'S SO SMOOTH,
YOU KNOW? BOY.
I BET HIS WIFE'S
ENJOYING THE SMOOTHNESS
RIGHT THIS MINUTE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YEAH, HE GOT A QUALITY
THAT WOMEN RESPOND TO.
SURE.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
THE KIND OF WOMAN...
THAT WOULDN'T FIND
MARCUS... ATTRACTIVE.
PROBABLY COULDN'T BE
AROUND HIM...
AND, UH, JUST, UH,
WELL, YOU KNOW,
LIKE OUR SITUATION.
IF TWO PEOPLE WERE ALONE-- NO,
NOT WITH A GUY LIKE THAT.
EXCUSE ME.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH HIM?
THIS ONE GOES ON
THE BULLETIN BOARD AT WORK.
UH-UH.
DON'T DO THAT.
[ RINGING ]
NO, COME ON, MIKE.
PUT IT BACK IN. I CANNOT
BELIEVE YOU TOOK IT OUT.
COME ON. MARCUS WILL KILL US
IF HE FINDS OUT. GIVE IT TO ME.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I LET YOU SEE IT.
UH! MOTHERFUCKER!
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
[ GEARSHIFT GRINDING ]
OH, GODDAMN IT!
GOT SOME JEWELRY FOR YOU.
AH!
I'M SORRY, BUT DAMN THAT.
WHOA. I THINK WE NEED
TO ADDRESS THE SERIOUS LACK
OF TRUST IN THIS RELATIONSHIP.
- PLEASE.
- IS THIS EVEN LEGAL?
I DON'T THINK THIS IS LEGAL.
I WON'T BE LONG.
OH, IT'S LEGAL.
OUTTA SIGHT.
YEAH, SANCHEZ. LOWREY.
YEAH, YOUR MOTHER. LISTEN.
I THINK THESE GUYS
ARE ABOUT TO MAKE A MOVE.
BLUE CONVERTIBLE,
TWO VISIBLE OCCUPANTS.
CHECK IT OUT, ALL RIGHT?
[ PHONE BEEPS ]
HEY, HEY.
HERE WE GO.
IS THAT OUR GUY?
WHERE'S THE GIRL?
THAT'S HIM.
I DON'T SEE ANY GIRL.
THERE'S NO GIRL.
[ TOYS CLATTERING ]
[ DOG BARKING ]
FUCK OFF, BARKIN'-ASS DOG!
SHUT UP!
[ BARKING ]
SNEAK UP ON MY OWN
MOTHERFUCKIN' HOUSE!
WHAT IN THE WORLD?
VERY STRANGE.
HIS ASS UPSTAIRS.
SUPPOSED TO BE MY BOY.
YOU MOTHERFUCKER!
DUCKIN' AND WEAVIN'
UP AND DOWN.
LOOK AT THIS SHIT.
IS THIS WHAT YOU WANT?
GOT ME CLIMBIN'
LIKE A FUCKIN' CHIMP!
NO, BUT I AIN'T GOIN' OUT
LIKE THAT. DON'T TAKE NOBODY
THAT LONG TO GET IN BED.
GOT MY BABIES
IN THE HOUSE.
YOUR MAN CAN'T GET
NO QUALITY TIME,
BUT, OH, YEAH, MY PARTNER
CAN GET SOME QUALITY TIMES.
I DON'T PLAY THAT SHIT.
AHHH!
[ AWNING CREAKING ]
- THERE'S SOMEBODY OUT THERE!
- QUICK. GET THE KIDS.
GET THE KIDS!
I KNEW IT!
I DIDN'T EVEN HAVE TO CALL
THE FUCKIN' PSYCHIC LINE!
- I KNEW IT!
- FREEZE!
[ SHOUTING, GRUNTING ]
MOVE AND YOU'RE A DEAD MAN!
MOTHERFU--
GUN RIGHT UP TO HIS HEAD.
THEY'RE GONNA SHOOT EACH OTHER.
THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE.
MIAMI POLICE! FREEZE!
I AM THE POLICE!
MARCUS, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
YOU'RE DOIN' THERESA!
NO, I'M NOT!
NOBODY DOES MY BABY!
AHHH!
MARCUS--
WE COULD SNEAK UP
AND SNUFF 'EM BOTH
RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO GET
THE GIRL. FORGET THEM.
NEVER FUCK WITH
A COP'S FAMILY, ASSHOLE.
DOESN'T THAT PISS YOU OFF?
[ RUIZ ] THAT PISSES
THE FUCK OUT OF ME.
DON'T GET ME STARTED.
GET OUTTA THE CAR.
MOTHERFUCKER!
SOME SHIT IS MAKING YOU CRAZY!
YOU KNOW THERE AIN'T NOTHIN'
GOIN' ON BETWEEN ME AND THERESA.
[ DOG BARKING ]
[ GASPING ]
MAN, I BEEN YOUR PARTNER
FOR SIX YEARS,
AND I BEEN YOUR BOY
ALL MY LIFE.
FOR YOU TO EVEN LET
SOME DUMB SHIT LIKE THAT
CREEP UP IN YOUR MIND--
THIS IS ME, MAN!
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
MAN, IT WAS JUST--
IT WAS FUCKIN'--
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST-- I JUST--
I JUST--
[ THERESA ] MIKE?
MIKE!
UH, THE-- UH, THE--
YEAH, I'M-- I'M FINE.
GET THE FUCK OUTTA HERE, MAN.
WHERE'S JULIE?
SHE'S IN THE CAR.
I HANDCUFFED HER
TO THE STEERING WHEEL.
ARE YOU TRYING TO BLOW
THIS WHOLE CASE?
MY BAD, MAN. I AIN'T
HAD NO QUALITY TIME.
YOU KNOW HOW THAT SHIT IS.
SOMETIMES YOU DO DUMB SHIT.
THAT'S ALL THAT IS.
[ PANTING ]
YO, MY BAD, HUH?
MY BAD.
IT'S COOL, MAN.
GO, GO, GO.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
I'LL DO IT. YEAH.
I'M WITH YA.
THESE PHONE CALLS
WERE MADE TO CLUB HELL
FROM THIS PRECINCT. EXPLAIN.
I'M GONNA ASK YOU
ONE MORE TIME.
GIMME A NAME.
GIMME A GODDAMN NAME!
OKAY. OKAY.
[ PANTING ]
ALL I KNOW IS HIS NAME.
GIMME HIS NAME.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT
A LOT OF TIME,
YOU KNOW THAT?
FOUCHET.
FOUCHET, I THINK.
THAT'S HIS WHOLE NAME?
FOUCHET?
FOUCHET.
I-I-I'M JUST
AN ERRAND BOY.
-STOP. YOU'RE GONNA MAKE ME CRY.
-BIG, DUMB FUCKIN' ERRAND BOY,
THAT'S WHAT YOU ARE.
WATCHING THE HOUSE
WAS MY FIRST GIG.
OH, HOW SWEET.
DOES THAT
MAKE YOU UNION?
IF YOU WERE A REAL COP,
IN THE FIELD,
WORKING EVERY DAY,
YOU'D REALIZE
THAT SOMETIMES
SHIT HAPPENS, OKAY?
DON'T GIVE ME THAT CRAP.
YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY
TO BEING REASSIGNED!
SHUT DOWN, SOON.
WHO'S GONNA
REASSIGN ME? YOU?
YOU DON'T HAVE THE AUTHORITY
TO REASSIGN ME.
SO UNTIL YOU DO,
STAY THE HELL OUTTA HERE!
THEY SHOULD JUST BONE
AND GET THAT SHIT OVER WITH.
I'M GETTING
REALLY TIRED OF THIS.
YOU'RE TIRED?
[ MAN ] THESE GUARD DOGS
AIN'T CUTTIN' IT NO MORE.
THEY'RE OVERFED, THEY'RE LAZY.
WE NEED VIDEO SURVEILLANCE.
THESE GUARD DOGS
ARE NOTHIN'--
JOJO!
OH, DON'T MAKE
THIS HARD, JO!
NICE RUNNIN'
INTO YOU, JOJO.
ALWAYS MAKIN' IT HARD
ON YOURSELF, JOJO.
GEE, JULIE.
WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN UP TO
THE LAST COUPLE DAYS?
OH, NOTHING. JUST HANGING OUT,
HANDCUFFED TO STEERING WHEELS.
WE'RE LOOKIN'
FOR SOMEONE WHO CAN STEP
ON A SHITLOAD OF HEROIN.
DO IT REAL FAST, REAL WELL.
WE'RE LOOKIN' FOR
A REAL PRO, JOJO.
I TOLD YOU ALREADY,
I'M IN THE RUBBER
BUSINESS NOW, MAN.
JOJO, WE'RE NOT PLAYIN', MAN.
HUH?
I'M TELLIN' YOU, MAN.
I'M STRAIGHT, MAN.
I'M STRAIGHT LIKE A BOARD.
LIKE AN ARROW. I'M SO STRAIGHT
RIGHT NOW IT'S SICK.
JOJO, THIS IS A LOT OF DOPE.
WHO COULD CUT IT REAL QUICK?
"CUT IT"?
YOU CUT IT UP?
I DON'T KNOW
NOTHIN' ABOUT IT.
I'M SICK OF THIS BULLSHIT!
- WHAT'S UP, YO?
- YOU PULLIN' A GUN ON ME?
YOU'RE COPS. I CAN'T
BELIEVE THIS. I SHOULD
TURN YOU IN TO HARD COPY.
- PUT YOUR ASS ON TV!
- WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
- I GOT THIS!
JOJO... [ COCKS GUN ]
I GOT 15 BULLETS
IN THIS GUN.
- MIKE!
- IF YOU DON'T START
TALKIN' TO ME,
I'M GONNA FILL
YOUR LYIN' ASS
FULL OF HOT SHIT.
- NOW WHAT'S UP?
- HE'S A FORMER GANJA SMOKIN'
MOTHERFUCKER.
HE AIN'T WORTH IT!
DO YOU WANT SOME?
I'LL BUST YOUR ASS TOO!
SO SAD.
YOU ON YOUR OWN, JOJO.
WHAT'S UP, JO?
I'M GONNA TELL YOU LIKE THIS.
YOU SPLATTER HIS ASS,
HE'S NO GOOD TO US!
FUCK THAT. FUCK THAT! I'M NOT
GOIN' DOWN OVER THIS SHIT!
I'M NOT GOIN' DOWN FOR YOU
KILLIN' JOJO, THE TIRE MAN!
- OKAY! OKAY!
- I DON'T WANT
BRAIN FRAGMENTS ON ME!
THAT SHIT GETS IN YOUR CLOTHES
AND IT STINKS!
- OKAY.
- FUCK THAT, JOJO!
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT I KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING.
- I KNOW A LITTLE BIT.
- TELL HIM SOMETHING, JO!
- IT'S THREE GUYS, ALL RIGHT?
THEY GOT A LABORATORY--
- [ COCKS GUN ]
NO, NO. NO.
NO, IT'S TWO GUYS.
ONE GUY DIED IN A PLANE CRASH
LAST YEAR. IT WAS FUCKED UP.
N-NO--
- NO! THERE SHOULD BE MORE!
OH, FUCK, MAN!
- UH-- NO, NO, NO, NO.
IT'S ONE GUY, REALLY.
IT'S ONLY ONE GUY.
DON'T FUCK WITH ME.
ONE MAIN GUY.
THIS GUY'S AN EINSTEIN,
MOTHERFUCKIN' GENIUS,
COLLEGE BOY.
FUCKIN' EGGHEAD MOTHERFUCKER.
HE GOT FOUR EYES AND GLASSES.
HE GOT A RICH MAMA AND DADDY
WHO LIVE OUT IN COCONUT GROVE.
- WHERE? TELL HIM AGAIN!
I DON'T WANT YOU TO GET HURT!
- I'LL TELL YOU WHERE HE'S AT.
YOU WOULD DO THAT
FOR US, JOJO?
YEAH, I WANNA HELP YOU GUYS.
YOU STICK THAT GUN DOWN.
I GOT THE ADDRESS
IN THE-- IN THE OFFICE.
WELL, THANKS A LOT, JOJO.
WHY DON'T YOU GO GRAB THAT?
COOL.
YOU CAN GO AHEAD.
YEAH, NOW IS GOOD.
NOW?
NOW IS REAL GOOD, JOJO. YEAH.
THIS IS ON ME TOO.
WHY DON'T YOU GUYS PICK OUT
SOME WHITEWALLS FOR YOURSELVES?
A LITTLE GIFT FROM ME TO YOU.
[ GUFFAWS ]
YOU MADE ME THINK YOU WERE
GONNA SHOOT ME FOR A MINUTE.
I WAS.
[ MARCUS ]
WHEN IS THIS PUNK-ASS CHEMIST
COMING HOME?
SO... THIS IS A STAKEOUT.
NOT WHAT I IMAGINED.
THOUGHT THERE'D BE
MORE... CONVERSATION.
SORRY IT'S NOT UP TO
YOUR... USUAL HIGH STANDARDS.
IS HE ALWAYS LIKE THIS
ON A STAKEOUT?
WHAT IS IT?
TOO MUCH CAFFEINE?
NOT ENOUGH SEX?
HEY.
OOH, I CAN'T BELIEVE
SHE WENT THERE ON YOU.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHO YOU TALKIN' TO?
THAT'S MIKE LOWREY
OVER THERE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
KING DING-A-LING.
WHY DON'T YOU WHIP IT OUT
FOR HER, BIG BOY?
- UH-HUH. RIGHT ON
YOUR FOREHEAD. YEAH.
- OH, SHUT UP.
[ ENGINE REVVING,
TIRES SQUEALING ]
- THERE HE IS! YO, LET'S GO!
LET'S GO! LET'S GO!
- I'M ON HIM.
WHAT ARE
OUR CHANCES?
REMEMBER CLUB HELL?
WORSE.
WELL, THAT'S IT.
I'M CALLIN' MAJOR BACKUP.
I WANT MOTHERFUCKIN'
SWIMMIN' DUCKS IN HERE.
WHOA, WHOA.
HOLD IT. YOU KNOW
SINCLAIR GOT EVERY PHONE
IN THE DAMN STATION TAPPED.
WE GOTTA DO THAT IN PERSON.
SHIT!
[ MARCUS ]
BY THE TIME WE DEAL
WITH THAT BULLSHIT,
EVERY JUNKIE IN AMERICA
WILL BE HIGH OFF OUR BUST.
CAN WE HELP YOU?
I STAKED OUT ALL NIGHT
IN THE BACK OF THAT JALOPY TOO.
I THINK I EARNED A PEEK.
HEY, THIS IS REAL COP STUFF.
THIS IS NOT CHARLIE'S ANGELS.
- ALL RIGHT. IT CAN'T HURT
FOR HER TO TAKE A PEEK.
- OH, IT CAN'T HURT TO LOOK?
THEY FIRE A GODDAMN BULLET
OVER HERE, IT'D HURT, WON'T IT?
WE HAVE GUESTS.
HAVE THEM FOLLOWED.
DON'T DO ANYTHING.
JUST CALL ME
WITH THEIR LOCATION.
THIS HIGH-SPEED CHASE ENDING ON
A TRESTLE NEAR THE RIVER DRIVE
AND 34TH STREETS INTERSECTION...
WAS CAPTURED TWO NIGHTS AGO
BY OUR SIX ACTION NEWS TEAM.
MOM!
...BOTH POLICE OFFICERS
INVOLVED IN THE INCIDENT...
SEEMED TO ESCAPE INJURY.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
DADDY WAS IN CLEVELAND.
CAN'T BE
IN CLEVELAND.
[ REPORTER ] APPARENTLY
THE OFFICERS DIDN'T LIKE
THE PRESENCE OF OUR CAMERAS.
NO, BABY, YOUR DADDY JUST WISHES
HE WAS IN CLEVELAND.
I'M TELLIN' YOU, MAN,
THIS FOUCHET,
HE'S A SLICK ONE.
F.B.I., D.E.A.,
THEY GOT NOTHIN' ON HIM.
BUT HE GOT TO DEAL
WITH US TODAY.
WHAT'S THAT?
THAT'S THE LAST TIME
THEY EVER HANDCUFF ME AGAIN,
THAT'S WHAT THAT IS.
GOOD BOY.
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
MA'AM.
ALL VISITORS
MUST BE ANNOUNCED!
PISSES ME OFF!
LADY. LADY!
I GUESS WHEN YOU GUYS
GET BACK,
THIS WILL
ALL BE OVER, RIGHT?
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
DON'T WORRY, THOUGH.
YOU'LL BE SET FREE.
CUT LOOSE.
YOU'LL BE BACK
TO YOUR OWN LIFE.
OOPS.
NO MORE HANDCUFFS.
[ LAUGHING ]
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
GET UP
OUTTA HERE.
THAT SHOULD BE CHET
WITH MY VEGGIE BURGER.
MOVE YOUR ASS!
YOU GOT IT, BABE.
HI. CAN I HELP YOU?
YES, I'M HERE TO KILL
MY HUSBAND. MARCUS BURNETT?
AND THAT WOULD BE THE TALL
ONE OR THE SHORT ONE?
- THE SHORT ONE.
- THOUGHT SO.
IS CHET RINGIN' THE--
OH! BABY--
UM-- THERESA.
UH, LET ME GET
YOUR HUSBAND.
MARCUS. GET OVER HERE.
[ SHOES SKIDDING ]
OKAY. I'M A--
BECAUSE I KNOW WHAT IT LOOKS
LIKE. DID YOU GET MY MESSAGE?
HUH?
UM--
CAN YOU,
UM, UM, UM,
LEAVE ME AND MRS. BURNETT
ALONE FOR--
RIGHT.
Y'ALL MET? UM--
BABY--
I-I KNOW. SO LET ME--
M-MARCUS. MARCUS. MARCUS.
AS FAR AS I AM CONCERNED,
YOU CAN KEEP THE WEDDING RING
IN YOUR POCKET.
- BECAUSE YOU, YOUR NEW
LITTLE GIRLFRIEND...
- OOH, SHIT!
AND MIKE WILL ALL BE
VERY HAPPY LIVIN' HERE.
TRUST ME. SWEETIE, HONEY.
SHH, SHH.
[ WHISPERING ] WE CAN--
IT'S NOT EVEN--
NO, NO, NO, NO.
I SAW IT ON THE NEWS.
COME ON. THAT SHIT
BE HAVIN' A SLANT.
IT'S A--
[ LUKE GROWLING ]
BABY, IT'S NOT--
YOU'RE NO LONGER WELCOME
TO MY HOUSE.
HE DIDN'T TELL YOU I WAS COMIN'
IN THE AIRPORT EARLY?
REMEMBER I SAID CALL HER?
THAT YOU WAS GONNA BRING ME
TO YOUR PLACE?
[ BELL DINGS ]
TELL HER ABOUT
WHEN I TOLD YOU.
YOU WERE GONNA BRING ME
TO YOUR PLACE--
JU-- JULIE!
- JULIE!
- ALL RIGHT.
I AIN'T EVEN GONNA,
YOU KNOW-- NAH.
WE NOT ARGUIN'
ABOUT THIS.
OKAY. I'M RAISIN' MY--
ALL RIGHT, HERE-- BABY--
BELIEVE ME,
WE WANTED TO TELL YOU.
IT REALLY DOESN'T
MATTER ANYMORE.
'CAUSE, MIKE, KOJAK--
WHATEVER YOUR NAME IS--
ASIDE FROM THAT FACT,
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING ELSE.
IF HIS WIFE COULD FIND US,
I'M A LOT BETTER OFF ON MY OWN.
THIS-- I COULD SEE HOW
IT WOULD LOOK A TRIP.
- UH-HUH.
- YOU-YOU-YOU SEE ME.
I RUNNIN' OUT. I GOT A SHIRT OPEN. YOU SEE MIKE.
HE HALF-BUTT-NAKED.
THEN YOU-- THEN YOU SEE
THE WHITE GIRL.
SO, THIS LOOKS LIKE WE HAVIN'
ONE BIG MOTHERFUCKIN' ORGY UP IN
HERE, AND AIN'T NOBODY HUMPIN'.
I'M TELLIN' YOU.
AIN'T NOBODY DOIN' NONE OF THAT.
IT'S NOT WHAT IT
LOOKS LIKE, OKAY?
HEAR WHAT I'M SAYIN'.
BABY, SHE'S
A MATERIAL WITNESS.
THAT--
THAT'S REAL!
NO.
THER-- BABY,
THERESA, LISTEN.
THAT AIN'T--
IT WAS ORDERS, BABY.
LISTEN. IT WAS ORDERS.
[ BELL DINGS ]
CAN I TALK TO YOU?
CAN YOU STOP SO I CAN
TALK TO YOU , PLEASE?
ENOUGH WITH THE SMOOTH SHIT.
IT'S NOT GONNA WORK ANYMORE.
[ SIGHING ]
I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU SAY.
- DUCK! DUCK!
- JULIE, GET DOWN! GET DOWN!
- [ SCREAMING ]
- GET OUT!
MIKE!
HELP!
OUT!
- [ TIRES SQUEALING ]
- 9-1-1!
YEAH, 911?
YEAH, CHET HERE.
GO UPSTAIRS AND TAKE THIS.
TAKE IT!
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL KEEP EVERYBODY CALM
UNTIL MY BACKUP ARRIVES.
I LOVE YOU, MARCUS.
SHIT! I FORGOT
TO GIVE 'EM THE ADDRESS!
- [ JULIE CRYING ]
- [ FOUCHET ] MOVE!
GO, GO, GO, GO!
WATCH IT! WATCH IT!
KEEP GOIN'!
MOVE HER! GET HER IN!
I'LL KILL YOU
IF YOU STOP RUNNING!
RUN!
[ FOUCHET ]
MOVE! MOVE!
MOVE!
[ MUTTERING ]
[ JULIE, WOMEN SCREAMING ]
[ GUNSHOTS,
GLASS BREAKING ]
IT'S OKAY.
I'M WITH THE POLICE.
IT'S COOL.
YOU LOOK GREAT!
- [ GUNSHOT ]
- [ PEOPLE SCREAMING ]
- DRIVE! DRIVE!
- I'M DRIVING!
[ JULIE ]
STOP IT!
[ DRIVER ]
THERE HE GOES!
[ TIRES SQUEALING ]
[ ENGINE REVVING ]
DON'T EVER SAY I WASN'T THERE FOR YOU.
[ PANTING ]
[ CAPT. HOWARD ] WHAT IS IT
WITH YOU GUYS? HOW COME IT'S
ALWAYS GOOD NEWS, BAD NEWS?
YOU KNOW EXACTLY WHERE
THE DOPE IS, BUT YOU
LOSE OUR ONLY WITNESS.
I DON'T GET IT.
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- [ RUIZ ] HEY, LOWREY,
PICK UP YOUR PHONE.
- [ RINGING ]
LOWREY.
HI, MR. LOWREY.
I'M KEEPING YOUR SWEET LITTLE
FRIEND FOR FOUR HOURS
UNTIL I MAKE MY DEAL.
AND I WILL
MAKE MY DEAL.
I JUST PUT A BULLET
IN THE CHEMIST WHO FUCKED
WITH MY TIMETABLE.
THE OTHER ONE
IS FOR THE GIRL, OKAY?
SON OF A BITCH!
TWISTED MOTHERFUCKER JUST SHOT
ONE OF HIS EMPLOYEES.
SAID IF WE DON'T BACK OFF,
HE'S GONNA KILL JULIE.
ALL RIGHT--
NOT NOW.
I TOLD YOU TO PLAY
BY THE RULES.
I AM ON THE VERGE
OF SOLVING THIS CASE.
YOU TURNED SOUTH BEACH
INTO A WAR ZONE. I FINALLY GOT
THE AUTHORITY TO SHUT YOU DOWN.
AS OF TODAY,
YOU'RE ALL REASSIGNED.
[ MARCUS MUTTERING,
SWEARING ]
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
ALL RIGHT, THIS GUY IS
PAINTIN' ME INTO A CORNER.
HE'LL KILL THE GIRL ANYWAY.
WE'RE NOT GONNA LET HER DIE.
AND WE'RE NOT WALKIN' AWAY
FROM THIS BUST. I DON'T
GIVE A SHIT WHAT SHE SAYS.
THE DEAL GOES DOWN
IN FOUR HOURS.
YOU GUYS GOT TWO HOURS
TO FIND THEM.
IT'S TIME
TO GET LUCKY.
GO DO WHAT YOU
GOTTA DO.
[ MIKE ] FLETCHER, MAN, YOU
KINDA TOLD US THAT THIS WOULD
MOVE A LITTLE QUICKER THAN THIS.
[ FLETCHER ]
IT'S NOT THAT EASY, OKAY?
IF IT WAS, YOU'D BE DOIN' IT.
WORK YOUR MAGIC. YOU SAY,
YOU'RE A COMPUTER WHIZ, MAN.
HEY, MAN, BACK UP
OFF ME, OKAY? I'M DOIN'
AN ILLEGAL FAVOR FOR YOU.
THIS IS WHAT
I GOT PUT IN JAIL FOR.
- SO YOU BACK UP OFF ME.
- MAN, YOU DON'T SIT YOUR
LANKY ASS DOWN, BOTTOM LINE?
I WILL KNOCK YOU
THE FUCK OUT!
- WHAT THE FUCK
IS WRONG WITH YOU?
- FLETCHER, HAVE A SEAT.
YOU SAID YOU'D
GET ME OUT OF JAIL.
I WASN'T LYIN'.
[ TYPING,
COMPUTER BEEPING ]
[ SIGHS ]
COPS ARE SO DUMB.
LOOK, IT'S COMING UP.
REMEMBER, YOU PROMISED TO GET ME OUT.
[ MIKE ] FLETCHER.
RIGHT THERE.
EDDIE DOMINGUEZ.
THERE IT IS.
VOILA.
[ MIKE ]
GIRLFRIEND?
IT WAS NEW YEAR'S EVE,
AND MY EX-BOYFRIEND, EDDIE,
AND THIS FRENCH GUY, THEY TOOK SOME
REALLY HORRIBLE PICTURES OF ME.
THEY SAID THAT THEY WOULD PUT THEM UP ON
THE BULLETIN BOARD OF MY KID'S SCHOOL...
UNLESS I GAVE THEM A LOT
OF NARCOTICS INFORMATION.
BUT I NEVER GAVE THEM YOU
OR THE GIRL!
LOOK, THEY GOT THE GIRL.
WE NEED TO GET THEM NOW.
BECAUSE IF WE DON'T,
THEY'RE GONNA KILL HER.
HOW DO YOU MAKE CONTACT?
I HAVE THEIR MOBILE
PHONE NUMBER.
[ SOFTLY ] GOD-- I KNOW.
I'M SORRY.
LISTEN, LISTEN. MIKE,
I'LL MAKE IT UP TO YOU.
I'LL DO ANYTHING
YOU WANT.
WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF TIME.
LET'S GO.
YOU HAVE SEXY EARS,
YOU KNOW THAT?
I WANNA LICK 'EM.
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- YEAH.
- YEAH, CAN I SPEAK TO ROMEO?
THERE AIN'T NO ROMEO HERE, ASSHOLE.
WHAT ARE YOU LAUGHIN' AT?
THIS CELL PHONE WILL KEEP TRIANGULATING
HIM NO MATTER WHERE HE GOES.
WE'LL WATCH THIS ON THIS
MAP UNTIL HE STOPS.
[ COMPUTER VOICE ] SECTOR 2-3-4.
SIGNAL'S STILL STRONG.
WE STILL HAVE A LOCK.
COME ON, BABY.
THANK YOU.
LUCY WAS THE QUEEN, BABY.
THINK ABOUT IT.
LUCILLE BALL WAS A BIMBO.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
DESI WAS THE BRAINS
BEHIND THE WHOLE THING.
HOW COULD YOU SAY THAT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
TAKE THOSE BONGOS AWAY FROM
THAT GUY, HE'S NOTHIN'.
IT'S CONGA. DON'T BE SO STUPID.
BECAUSE IT'S DESI--
YO, FELLAS,
WHAT'S UP?
[ RUIZ ] OH, THE
FUCKIN' PENCIL SQUAD!
- YOU GET US ASSIGNED TO TRAFFIC DUTY?
- NO, THIS IS REAL.
WE GOT SOMETHIN' FOR YOU.
SHIT COULD GET YOU KILLED.
LET'S GO.
HERE WE GO.
IT'S CONRAD.
I'M CALLIN' IN A FAVOR.
[ POLICE TECHNICIAN ] EASTBOUND
TOWARDS NORTHWEST 135TH STREET.
NORTHEAST.
KEEP GOIN' NORTHEAST.
IF I'M WRONG ABOUT THIS,
YOU CAN FIRE MY ASS.
NOW THIS IS WHAT I NEED.
I NEED A SWAT TEAM,
HELICOPTERS--
WE'RE CALLIN' ALL CARS.
ONLY I DON'T KNOW WHERE I NEED 'EM.
- VERY NICE CAR YOU GOT THERE.
- OH, YEAH.
THAT'S MY TOY. I'M TAKING IT
WITH ME, FOR MY COLLECTION.
AND HOW ABOUT
THE WIRE TRANSFERS?
TWO WIRE TRANSFERS TO YOUR BANKS.
MM-HMM.
TOTALING $180 MILLION.
AND 20 IN CASH.
DAMN!
THIS HAS BEEN A SHITTY WEEK.
[ POLICE DISPATCHER ] GETTING FULL
INTEGRATION ON THAT SIGNAL.
YEAH. WE'RE ON
THE AIRFIELD NOW.
I BET YOU IT'S UP IN
THE OLD HANGAR SECTION.
[ BEEPING ]
LET'S BRING IT UP!
BRING IT UP!
DEPOSIT CONFIRMATION
REQUESTED.
90 MILLION,
GELDERSBANK OF ZURICH.
- NO EASY APPROACH.
- [ MARCUS ] NO TIME. FUCK THE BACKUP.
[ MARCUS ]
WE GOTTA GO NOW.
NOT A PROBLEM.
WHAT, YOU GOT AN ITCH?
I'D LOVE TO SCRATCH IT.
SCRATCH THIS, OKAY?
I'LL SCRATCH WHATEVER YOU WANT
ME TO, YOU BLUE-EYED BITCH!
DID YOU GO TO COLLEGE?
[ BANK OPERATOR SPEAKING, INDISTINCT ]
THANK YOU.
YOU GUYS SURE YOU WANNA DO THIS?
LET'S GO!
TUCK IN YOUR SKIRT,
BABY. COME ON!
MY SHIT ALWAYS WORKS
SOMETIMES!
THIS IS THE BEST YOU CAN BUY.
IT'S BEEN VERY NICE DOING
BUSINESS WITH YOU.
- [ MARCUS ] DAMN IT!
- OH, SHIT!
- FOUCHET, IT'S A SETUP!
- I HIJO DE PUTA!
IF I GET KILLED,
I'M FUCKIN' YOU UP!
GO, GODDAMN IT!
GO, GO, GO!
- I MIRA, EL CARRO!
- OKAY, OKAY!
- OH, MY GOD!
- [ GUNFIRE ]
- [ SCREAMING, GRUNTING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ HOLLERING ]
JULIE!
- [ GUNSHOT ]
- AH, MOTHERF-- AH!
[ GUNFIRE ]
GET DOWN!
SHIT!
-YOU FORGOT YOUR BOARDIN' PASS!
-[ GROWLING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ MEN SHOUTING ]
[ SHOUTING ]
YOU MOTHERFUCKERS!
WHAT'S UP?
OH, SHIT!
- [ SCREAMING ]
- [ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ ENGINE STARTING ]
[ TIRES SQUEALING ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ GASPING ]
- [ SHOUTING ]
- [ GUNFIRE ]
MIKE, LET'S GO!
GET IN THE CAR!
GET IN, MIKE! COME ON!
- LET'S GO! GET IN!
- [ JULIE ] GET IN THE CAR!
THIS SHIT'S GONNA BLOW!
GET UP!
OH, SHIT! PLEASE, CATCH THAT
MOTHERFUCKER WHO SHOT ME!
- SHOT YOU? HE SHOT ME!
- YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE. I HAD A RUN-IN WITH JIM
BROWN OVER HERE, BUT I'M FINE.
HE STEALS OUR SHIT, KIDNAPS
JULIE, SHOOTS AT MY WIFE.
OH, WE BEATIN' HIM DOWN.
WE BEATIN' HIM DOWN!
MARCUS, I JUST GOT
ONE QUESTION FOR YOU, BRO.
HOW THE HELL YOU GONNA LEAVE MY ASS
AT A GUNFIGHT TO GO GET THE CAR?
SHUT UP
AND LET HIM DRIVE, OKAY?
SEEM LIKE THAT GUNSHOT WOUND HAS
IMPROVED YOUR DRIVIN' SKILLS.
YOU GOT THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT.
ANYTHING YOU SAY CAN AND WILL BE
USED AGAINST YOU IN A COURT OF LAW.
- WHAT THE FUCK ARE YOU DOIN'?
- GETTIN' IT OUTTA THE WAY.
JUST PUNCH IT, MAN! GO!
THIS CAR'S FASTER!
THIS IS A FASTER FUCKIN' CAR!
IT'S GONNA BE ONE OR THE OTHER!
IT'S GONNA BE HIM OR US!
YOU BETTER FUCKIN' WIN,
THAT'S ALL I KNOW!
YOU BETTER WIN!
[ SCREAMING ]
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
NOW THAT'S HOW YOU
S'POSED TO DRIVE!
FROM NOW ON,
THAT'S HOW YOU DRIVE!
[ GROANING ]
[ GLASS BREAKING ]
- [ COCKS GUN ]
- FREEZE!
HE AIN'T EVEN
WORTH KILLIN', MAN.
- [ MIKE ] FREEZE!
- [ GUNSHOT ]
[ SIRENS BLARING ]
[ MARCUS ] FOUCHET. BET WHEN YOUR
PUNK ASS WOKE UP THIS MORNIN',
YOU DIDN'T THINK ABOUT 5:00 YOU'D
HAVE A HOLE IN YOUR LEG, DID YA?
[ PANTING ]
YOU COULDN'T KILL ME,
YOU CHICKENSHIT, COULD YOU?
OH, NO, I COULD. YOU
TALKIN' LIKE IT'S OVER.
I WAS JUST PAUSIN'.
I'M GETTING THE HANG OF
THIS WHOLE MARKSMAN SHIT,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THAT SHOOTIN' 'EM FROM 30 YARDS
WHILE THEY RUNNIN' AWAY,
NAH, THAT'S NOT IT.
HERE'S WHERE IT IS, RIGHT HERE.
POINT-BLANK, UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL.
- MIKE!
- THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
- WOULD YOU DO IT?
- [ MARCUS ] MIKE, STEP OFF!
[ PANTING ]
DO IT. DO IT!
DO IT!
YO, IT'S OVER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HE'S A JOKE.
HE'S A MOTHERFUCKIN' JOKE.
[ LAUGHING ]
A JOKE.
[ GUNSHOTS ]
[ GROANING ]
[ MARCUS ]
I EVER TELL YOU
I LOVE YOU, MAN.
YEAH, YOU KNOW YOU ALWAYS
BE GETTING EMOTIONAL
AFTER GUNFIGHTS.
IT'S 'CAUSE
I'M GLAD WE SURVIVED.
[ CHUCKLES ] SHIT!
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
WHAT YOU
TALKIN' ABOUT?
[ LAUGHING ]
I LOVE YOU TOO, MAN.
DON'T BE LOOKIN' AT ME.
I SAID, YEAH, "I LOVE YOU."
I SAID THAT SHIT.
- YOU MY BOY, MAN!
- NO, NO, YOU LIKE
MY BROTHER, MAN.
- [ JULIE ] SO WHAT AM I?
- ♪ BAD BOYS, WHAT YOU WANT
OH, MAN--
JULIE,
SWEETIE, YOU--
YOU-- YOU-- YOU
A LITTLE DANGEROUS.
YEAH, SEE, YOU LIKE A MAGNET
FOR RANDOM GUNFIRE.
BUT YOU ALL RIGHT.
YOU COOL.
YOU DOWN. YOU DOWN.
[ SIGHS ]
SO... WHAT'S NEXT?
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
NAH.
NO. [ CHUCKLES ]
SEE, THERE AIN'T GONNA BE NO NEXT.
- [ CHUCKLES ]
- WHOA, MARCUS.
COME ON, MAN.
YOU WANTED MIKE LOWREY?
YOU GOT HIM.
RIGHT HERE.
THAT'S MIKE.
OLD MIKE LOWREY.
I'M GOIN' HOME TO MY WIFE
TO GET MY QUALITY TIME.
MARCUS, WHY DON'T YOU
STOP PLAYIN', MAN?
I BEEN BEAT THREE TIMES
SINCE WE BEEN OUT HERE.
I'M COOL, MAN.
DON'T NEED NO HELP.
PLEASE, BACK UP.
BACK UP.
DON'T NEED NO HELP.
WHY YOU GOING HOME
TO YOUR WIFE?
- YOU GOT SHOT IN YOUR LEG.
YOUR DICK PROBABLY DON'T WORK.
- [ JULIE ] MARCUS!
CAN WE HAVE THE KEYS?
MIKE WANTED ME TO GO TO THIS GUNFIGHT.
THEN THERE WAS
THIS WITNESS.
♪ WHAT YOU GONNA DO
WHEN THEY COME FOR YOU ♪
MY MAN.
OH, I'M SORRY.
HEY!
MY MAN, CAN YOU LET ME OUTTA HERE?
I DON'T GOT THE KEYS.
YOU DON'T HAVE NO KEYS?
WHY WOULDN'T YOU HAVE KEYS?
WOULD YOU--
OUCH!
MARCUS, I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU LOVED ME. SHOW ME LOVE!
♪ YOU'RE TOO BAD
♪ YOU'RE TOO RUDE
♪ YOU'RE TOO RUDE, YEAH
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
♪ WHAT YOU GONNA DO
WHEN THEY COME FOR YOU ♪
♪
HUH! HUH!
♪ [ "FIVE O, FIVE O"
BY 89 BOYZ ]
♪
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ IT'S TIME TO GO
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ FIVE O, FIVE O
THERE THEY GO, THERE THEY GO ♪
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ IT'S TIME TO GO
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ BAD BOYS RUNNIN' SLOW
GOTTA GO, GOTTA GO ♪
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS,
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
♪ YOU GOTTA CATCH ME,
I'M A CREW, BUT ♪
♪ IF YOU WANNA SEE ME
IN THE BACKSEAT, HUH ♪
♪ YOU GOTTA WIN
THIS TRACK MEET, UH ♪
♪ NOW TO WIN FIRST PLACE
BE IN GOOD SHAPE ♪
♪ AND PREPARE FOR A GOOD CHASE
'CAUSE I'M JUMPIN' OVER GATES ♪
♪ AND ON TOP O' CORVETTES
LIKE TONY DORSETT ♪
♪ NOW BET, BET YOU CAN'T
CATCH ME, THOUGH ♪
♪ 'CAUSE DOUGHNUTS MAKE YOU
RUN SLOW, YA KNOW ♪
♪ BUT YOU HAVE A GOOD CHANCE
IF YOU TAKE OFF THE TIGHT BLUE PANTS ♪
♪ AND CALL ALL YOUR BOYS
ON THE C.B., UH ♪
♪ AND TELL 'EM
IF THEY SEE ME ♪
♪ TO ROLL ME DOWN NOW
HOLD ME DOWN ♪
♪ BUT FIRST YOU GOTTA SLOW ME
DOWN 'CAUSE HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ IT'S TIME TO GO
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ FIVE O, FIVE O
THERE THEY GO, THERE THEY GO ♪
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ IT'S TIME TO GO
♪ HERE THEY COME HERE THEY COME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO DO IT
♪ BAD BOYS
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE ♪
♪ ELEVEN-TEN-SEVENTY
THAT WAS MY INTRO ♪
♪ BUT NOW I'M MAKIN' DOUGH
I'M ROLLIN' A SIX-FOUR ♪
♪ BUT THINGS GET SHADY
WHERE THE GRASS IS GREEN ♪
♪ BROTHERS DON'T WANNA UPSET
SOME HOODS LIKE THEY NEVER SEEN HER ♪
♪ YOUNG MAC DADDY DO HIS THING
'CAUSE I PACK RIGHT ♪
♪ I GOT 44 WAYS
TO MAKE YOU ACT RIGHT ♪
♪ AND IT'S A SHAME
HOW THE GAME MUST BE PLAYED ♪
♪ IT WAS TOLD, NIP A FOE
BY THE BROTHERS YOU CAN'T FAY ♪
♪ SO RAISE UP
OFF THIS YOUNG HO ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I HEARD YOU PUNKIN' SOME
BUT YOU CAN'T PUNK ME, DO ♪
♪ I GOT MY OWN THING
'CAUSE I LET MY BOOT SWING ♪
♪ IF YOU WANNA BRING IT
BRING IT ON NO PAIN, NO GAIN ♪
♪ SO AS I KICK, CAN YOU PEEK
WHAT I SPEAK ♪
♪ TECHNIQUE'S UNIQUE, SO WHAT
YOU'RE SINGIN' IS OBSOLETE ♪
♪ SO THERE IT IS
AS I GO ABOUT MY BIZ ♪
♪ I CAN ONLY BRING IT TO YOU
LIKE THIS IN SO MANY WAYS ♪
♪ SO HOMIES ARE REMINDED DO NOT
TAKE THEM FROM YOUR FRIEND ♪
♪ AND SHOW THAT YOU'RE LEGAL ♪
♪ IN SO MANY WAYS
♪ SHOW THAT YOU'RE LEGAL
♪ 'CAUSE I BORROWED
AND YOU'LL BORROW ♪
♪ BUT I LEND THEM
IF I LEND ♪
♪ AND SHOW THAT YOU'RE LEGAL ♪
♪ IN SO MANY WAYS
♪ SHOW THAT YOU'RE LEGAL
♪
♪ NOBODY NAH GIVE YA
NO BREAK ♪
♪ POLICE NAH
GIVE YA NO BREAK ♪
♪ THE OLD SOLDIER MAN
NAH GIVE YA NO BREAK ♪
♪ NOT EVEN YOUR IJIN NAH GIVE YA
NO BREAKS, HEY YEAH ♪
♪ WATCH OUT
♪ SAY HEY, THEY COME, COME
♪ I FIGURE THEY JUST THE BAD BOYS
PLAYIN' IN THE DIGGY DUM-DUM ♪
♪ DUMB, DUMB
♪ HEY, WHAT DO YOU WANT WITH MY LIFE ♪
♪ YOU SEEN ME ON THE BLOCK
TRYIN' TO SELL MY ROCK ♪
♪ BUT HOW DO YOU MAKE A DEAL
WITH A NICKEL-PLATED TO YOUR HEAD ♪
♪ TOCKTICK TELL THEM
HOW THE HEAD GO ♪
♪ I THINK IT'S TIME FOR ME TO QUIT ♪
♪ WHY
♪ 'CAUSE I'M TIRED
OF ALL THE BULLSHIT ♪
♪ [ CONTINUES, INDISTINCT ]
♪
♪ SO BONGO-LONGO GET YOUR GAS
DON'T FORGET YOUR CROW ♪
♪ TELL ME WHAT YOU'RE GONNA DO
'CAUSE THE DEVIL IS COMIN' FOR YOU ♪
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
♪ WHAT YOU GONNA DO
WHEN THEY COME FOR YOU ♪
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
♪ WHAT YOU GONNA DO
WHEN THEY COME FOR YOU ♪
♪ BAD BOYS, BAD BOYS
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ♪
♪ WHAT YOU GONNA DO
WHEN THEY COME FOR YOU ♪