Your boy is very impatient!
Have you thought of any name?
Shahid.
Why are you laughing?
If its a girl?
Girl!
What is your name dear?
Shahida.
Such a lovely name.
Where do you live?
So you'll only talk to your mom?
Nothing like that..
She doesn't talk to her mom either.
Why?
Shahida!
It's getting dark..
You go home..
I'll get your sheep home.
Rauf!
Where is Shahida?
Isn't she home yet?
She hasn't.
Stay here.
I have been telling you for days to
take her to Delhi.
Even mute people
can get cured there.
I was speechless at 5 years old.
I was taken there.
Did you get cured?
Do you wanna hear me talk?
But it's in India.
So what..
Its not in the US.
It is easier to go to the US..
Yes we were one nation
long time ago..
..did you forget that i
was in army for 5 years.
Indians will not give me visa.
I'll take her..
..so that she can talk again..
go to school again
I'll do anything for her.
I've decided.
I'll take Shahida to Delhi
no one returned empty
handed from the God's beloved .
She will talk again,
by the time you reach Pakistan.
Why has the train stopped?
-Slight delay due to construction madam.
It will be fixed soon.
Don't you worry.
I'll go to sleep then..
Shahida.
What happened?
-I can't find my daughter!
Indians are saying they
couldn't find your daughter
They'll search in the morning.
Sir..
Please listen to me.
Let me go and find
her myself.
But its across the border,
..in a foreign land
So what.
I've to bring back my daughter.
But to go there
you'll need a visa.
Be patient, you'll get your daughter.
-How is that possible?
Don't you understand..
My daughter is mute..
She is alone in a foreign land.
You people are hopeless..
I'll find Shahida by myself.
Trust in the Lord.
Stop crying my child..
Hope she'll be found
by a good person.
..Someone who will take
good care of her.
What is selfie?
Its that thing..we take ourselves..
photo..that's called selfie.
You danced like hero.!N-Yes I go crazy for Bajrangbali.
One paratha for this little girl please..
-OK sir.
But she is asking for 2..
You must have some name.
Sita, Gita, Payal, Puja...
Seems that she's deaf.
She heard my order
for paratha.
You are right..
Let me try.
Name?
She's illiterate..
-Try writing in French.
She's 5 years old
Eat well.
Why are you following me?
Take this.
Did you get lost in a carnival?
Say something..?
What will I do?
Bajarangbali will protect.
This temple can work wonders.
Your parents might be
still looking for you..
They'll come here,
You just sit there..
See you..
If your parents take too long..
you..
..eat that apple..
don't stay hungry.
Stop the bus!
You can't leave her here.
Why not?
Her parents will come
here to report..
What if they don't come.
-Then..
How come?
Why not?
Look at her.
Yes but you can't
leave her here.
Why?
Look at her.
Now have a look at them.
Its filled with thief,
drunkards, con-men..
By the way this is police station,
not an orphanage.
Write down your name, address,
phone no.
I'll call you when I have any information.
Until then?
Until then... God be with you.
Do you live here?
Where then?
Should be somewhere..
Lets do this..
I'll call out city names..
If its you city..
..raise you hand and
nod your head.
How?
Delhi..
Meerut..
Faridabad..
Gwalior..
Jhansi, Patiala, Amritsar, Jodhpur
Jaipur, Srinagar, Simla, Ambala?
Baroda?
Rampur?
Is it Dehradun?
Kasoli?
Pratapgarh?..
Are you from Pratapgarh.
-Yes..
Me too.
Really?..
-Bajarangbali is my witness.
Lived near the station.
My in-laws live there.
Now you've become
my relative.
I now live in Delhi..
-Why Delhi?
For girl or job.
its long story..
Tell us..we are not
waiting for any bus anyway.
Tell us bro..
You don't speak..
will you listen my story?
I'm Pawan..
Pawan Kumar Chatravedi
alias Bajarangi.
You call me brother...
How old are you?
six..
When you start talking..
..you call me uncle..
My father was a postmaster
in Pratapgarh
He was a master in Holy books.
I was just the opposite.
4 x 8?
no 25.. no 26
no 27..28...30
30?
For him health was as
important as education.
Good.. lets start.
I even failed in wrestling.
No laughing..
he won't reform
Nothing can be done..
wrestling tickles me..
Wrestling always tickled me..
I was helpless.
The honor he had was not enough for him
he also became a leader..
Studies, wrestling, leadership...
I wasn't interested in any of it
He gave me a special nickname..
What?
Zero.
-I failed.
I took 20 years to complete schooling.
..from school to graduation,
I failed 10 times.
My father had given up on me.
What?
-I failed.
My friends advised me to cheat in exams.
But I am Bajarangbali's disciple..
I said I will fail but never cheat.
So I approached him the 11th time.
Please come.
You must have broken
your own record in failing.
when you completed your schooling...
Why did you have to honor
me anymore by failing 11 times.
I've accepted that
you're foolish.
you're zero..
-But listen to me..
What should I listen? Tell me..
you've failed 10 times.
..and failed me 20 times..
But listen to me..
What is left there to
listen, you tell me...
If you want to do
something for me..
Go away from here..
Delhi.
I heard that there is scarcity of fools.
I've an old friend there
"Dayanand"
He'll get you a job..
I passed the exams.
What did your father tell you?
He might have got shocked.
I knew he'll be in shock,
but didn't know its intensity.
What happened?
Father I'm going to Delhi.
I went to Delhi to fulfill his last wish.
to Dayanad sir.
I don't have change.
Give 5/- from it, to that madam.
Madam he will pay you your 5/-
Greetings.
do you have 5/-,
so that I can give you 10/-
I don't.
Now what?
-Its alright, you keep the money
How can I do that?
5/- belongs to you.
Then give it to me.
-How can I?
5/- is also mine.
Look sir, you can keep the money.
how can i keep it..
5/- is also yours.
Then give it to me.
It also belongs to me!
Sister.
what?
Your money.
I don't want money.
Please take it..
So give me..
You took everything!
Half belongs to me.
Ok..You see that vendor?
Go and get change from him.
Do you have change for 10?
-Yes
You?..
You..
followed me home?
no sister.. i...
Don't you understand..
You know him?
was in the bus..
This stalker followed me home..
No I'm not.
I didn't follow you..
I am from Pratapgarh to meet Dayanand sir.
Who are you..
-I'm Pawan  son Chataravedi.
Chatravedi's son?
Yes Bajarangi.
Get him down..
Have some more.
-No thanks..
Its nice and hot.. specialty of this area.
when we boil the potato.
we puts salt also.
That's why it tastes so good.
.you enjoy your food..
Is someone cooking meat?
Neighbour next door.
They are Mohamaddan
starts early in the morning..
But in my house..
I have strictly decided..
not having tenants of other religions.
What do you do for living?
I'm here to find job.
can't you employ him at your school..
You too..
What?
Are you also still studying in school?
I don't study.
I teach.
Go tomorrow with Rasika..
You'll get some job.
Hail Bajaranbali.
Lots of monkeys here..
will you be bowing all day.
Take this..
Place it under your bed
before sleep.
just like monkeys
we have lots of mosquitoes.
One sec.
Give me your hand..
-Excuse me!
trust me.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
My name is not sister,
but Rasika.
Then?
Then one day Trivedi
and his son came.
Please come..
Be seated.
How are you  Proshotum?
-I am well.
Pawan...Bring Rasika with you.
Rasika.
They are here.
If Bajarangbali appears unto you..
What will you ask him?
Do you know
what I will ask?
Give me your hand.
Don't you trust me?
Where's Rasika?
She'll come.
I think she is too shy to come..
You always used to say..
..that you see your dad in your bridegroom.
i can't see it in anyone else but Pawan.
Rasika!
Forgive me..
We can't be relatives..
Its my daughter's decision.
You should have told us before..
..instead of insulting us.
Let's go.
Who wants to stay here!
Sir..
You can't be engaged with Rasika.
until you become
capable, for her.
To be capable, my
first condition is house.
which you'll buy
with your earned money
you got only 6 months,
or I'll find someone..
..who is able.
I have not asked you this yet..
What's your age?
Wow Bajarangi bro.
.wow!
Congratulations...
In 2 or 3 months
I'll get new house..
Absolutely..
Bombay......Agra?
How do you know
she's a Brahmin..
..when she can't speak?
she's fair..
..must be Brahmin.
When will she leave?
When we find her parents.
When will that be?
when Bajrangbali wills..
Have you ever
traveled by air?
I did once.
Do you know what
they say in plane?
First wear your oxygen mask,
and then help others.
When will you stop
your social work?
Think about your life also.
Work hard..
Build a house..
If you can't..
..admit it now.
So that you don't waste your time..
..neither Rasika's.
This will fit a 6 year old?
We couldn't find Munni's parents?
Will she live with us
after our marriage?
Why wouldn't we
find the parents?
What if not?
Who doesn't have parents?
Orphans.
Who is your favorite player?
Dhoni?
Virat Koli?
Yuvi?
Shekar Dhavan?
Sewag?
Told you all the names!
You know nothing about cricket!
Munni's not an orphan.
Bajarangbali would
have told me if she was.
Pawan..
Did Bajarangbali tell you
that she has parents?
Munni!
What happened to Munni?
Where is she?
I can't find her in the house.
Can't find her?
We were eating together..
did not see her after that.
I don't understand!
Munni is not at here either.
-O God!
Munni!  Munni!
Pawan!
Chicken barra, chicken mughlai,
chicken makhani, chicken hariyali..
chicken lollipop, chicken kadai,
chicken tawa..
chicken tandoori, chicken masala,
chicken kolhapuri..
chicken afghani, chicken kashmiri,
chicken hydrabadi..
chicken fried rice, chicken noodles,
chicken manchurian..
chicken 69, chicken kofta,
chicken korma..
chicken achari, chicken choudhary,
chicken biryani..
-Sir!
chicken dry, chicken fry..
..Yes sir.
Give that child
your best dish.
OK sir.
She is white like milk,
iI thought she's Brahman.
She may be Kshatriya,
..they eat meat
and are fair..
Yes!
She's Kshatriya
like Lord Rama!
Why's Munni crying?
Try these colorful bangles.
It's very nice.
Take it.
My bangles?
Excuse me sir..
Please pay for
my bangles.
Please pay.
Munni!
Nn sir, we don't need it..
Forgive the child..
-Its alright.
Stealing is bad..
Let's ask forgiveness from
Bajarangbali.
Bajarangbali..
You know that..
You know that we went to
a non veg hotel..
.because of Munni.
But i swear i didn't eat anything.
Munni ate..
Munni!
..pray.
Munni ate..
Please forgive us..
You know that..
..I'm helpless for Munni.
What to do?
Bajarangbali..
..you gave me one hint..
..that she's a Kshatriya.
Isn't it?
Munni!
Munni!..hey Munni!
Oh no..
no..no.. Munni!
Please forgive Munni..
She's just a child..
..she doesn't know
the difference..
Get in bro..
Munni!
Are you crazy?
What happened?
Munni....She..
Where's Munni?..
She..
Who?
She is that...
-She's what?
Munni is Mohammedan.
Munni?
Did you notice the way she
ate chicken last night?
..and here inside ..she..
..scarf around her..
..and was reciting.
Where is she now?
What will your
dad say?
Where is Munni?
She betrayed us.
She betrayed?!
She's only 6 years old.
..Away from home
away from parents..
..poor girl can't
even speak..
What about your dad?
She's Muslim.
Don't be stupid.
Do you know why i love you,
Because you have a
good heart.
all these caste, religion
are nonsense.
Don't waste your time
in trivial matters.
I can't say this to father.
..but you can.
Lets go..
She's alone inside..
Where is she?
He caught the ball!
C'mon India.
..Munni clap your hands..
Awesome boys..
..awesome!
Your father will kick
..Munni and me out of this house.
Only if he finds out..
What?
Who will tell him?
I will.
Are you nuts?
Oh no.. Afridi has come.
Shit man!
Have your read
Mahabharata?
..you've watched it on TV..
What does Lord Krishna
tell Arjun?
What?
Your motive should be good.
You have that..
Your aim is to take
Munni to her home..
Tell father everything after that..
Stop clapping for
the wrong team.
Everybody shut up!
I am very tensed..
What are you doinig?
This is enemy's team!
What happened to her?
I don't understand!
What is Munni doing?
Why is she dancing?
What happened you?
What is she doing?
Pakistan?
You brought her saying
that she is Brahman..
You think you are the only..
one to take care of other people..
Why didn't others take
her from Kurukshetra..
I didn't do anything..
she followed me..
You will hand her over to
Pakistani embassy tomorrow.
Father..
Her country people have killed
our countrymen without mercy..
She's not responsible for that.
I know.
..but doesn't she belong there?
I am not hard hearted..
..but I cannot keep her..
..in this house anymore.
Make necessary
arrangements to send her.
Soon.
Next..
Visa application.
Passport.
I'm not going to
your country.
I came to leave her.
She's Pakistani.
send her home.
What is your name?
She can't speak..
Where is her passport?
How'd I know.
The how do you know
she's Pakistani,
When Pakistan won
the game yesterday..
..she started dancing.
She also kissed your
flag on TV.
She became Pakistani
when she kissed the flag?
How do you know her?
Found her at Kurukshetra.
What she was doing there?
How'd I know?
Sorry can't help
without passport.
Why not?
I'm telling you she's Pakistani
send her home..
Are you crazy?
Do you have
any commonsense?!
Now leave..
I'm leaving her here.
I'm warning you..
leave now or
I'll call security..
And I'll call my people and..
..kick you out of India.
I'm an Indian,
just working for embassy.
Security!
Take em out.
14 people were injured
High Commissioner
Abdul Basheer.
..said in his official statement..
..that for security reasons..
..all visa services will be
suspended for..
one month.
Bravo Bajrangi
I just asked you to send girl home..
..you shut down the embassy.
So Munni will be with us for a month?
It will not happen.
Govind has told me
about a travel agent..
They'll take care of it.
No sir..
We don't make Pakistani passport.
Why?
Why!
Nobody ever needed.
People come for
American Passport.
Canada's..
..England,Germany
..Japan too
But when she's
from Pakistan..
..what will she
do in Germany?
You're right..
Sorry we cannot make
Pakistani passport.
Weird!
Let's go.
Sir..
There's a way without passport.
What?
I know some people..
who can help
cross border.
Really!
Yes.
I can request them..
Please ask them..
I'm in big trouble.
OK.
I'll talk to them by evening..
will need 1.5 lakhs.
1.5 lakhs!
4....4...4.....4
5...5...5...5...5....
25,000...25,000
26...
27...28...
What is this?
Withdrew from bank..
What have you done!
this money..
-I know
This money was for
our house deposit.
But right it is more
important to.
..send Munni home.
No Rasika..
You'll end up marrying someone else.
O simpleton..
..don't you get it?
No one can stop us from getting married.
Its my word.
How will you find her parents?
Those agents have
many contacts.
Don't you worry.
I'll ask them to call you later.
This is our phone no.
When you find her parents..
Please ask them to call us.
Sure.
We need to leave..
Let's go.
Why are you crying?
He'll take you to Pakistan.
He'll take you to your mom.
Let's go.
You can't stay here.
..neither can I go there.
Let's go dear.
I've been having problems
since I met you.
You finally got a
chance to go home..
Please leave us.
I beg you..
..leave us..
Go back home..
..I beg of you..
How much?
25/-  Sir.
Hey hero..
Have you seen a little girl
..her name is Munni.
She just came here.
-Yes..here.
I can be your...
No Sister!
Sister!
How did I become your sister?!
Munni!
Are you crazy?
Hey!  Not now..
..close the door.
Where are you going?
Somebody stop him.
Who's he?
Get that girl!
Let's talk in peace.
What now?
I'll take Munni to her home.
Stop talking crazy..
No Passport
nor Visa..
You are a stranger there..
We'll find a way.
I don't have a passport..
..nor visa..
..a stranger.
but just like Bajarangbali..
Lord Rama dwells
in my heart.
..and if Rama dwells
in your heart.
..everything becomes possible.
Stop right there.
Who are you?
-Who are you?
This is my area.
I never said it
was mine.
Are you gonna
cross the border.
I charge 25,000..
You have..
you come..
You don't..
Get lost.
Let's go.
Hey..
Those fences are electrocuted.
440 Volts!
You touch..
..it will suck your blood dry.
Listen..
Have a good look..
Muhammad Ali Jinnah..
Seen it before?
Its Pakistani money..
Your money won't work.
Let's go..
Listen..
Don't you
understand..
If you go this route..
BSF will spot you within 2 km.
Hey..
They will shoot first..
and then ask your dead self..
.if are Indian or Pakistani.
Hey listen.
Crossing border is not like
a walk in the park.
I can make it easy..
Come with us..
Its for her good.
It will only cost you
50,000/-
Wasn't it
25,000/-?
That's for one person.
Why should she pay?
She is going home.
Going home?
..and then I decided that
I'll take Munni to Pakistan
Amazing bro..
I knew that you are..
..a very good man.
Listen
..every 10 min, you will find..
..Pakistani army across that fence..
there are 4 tunnels
going under the fence.
..you have 10 min.
..to get across it.
..we have to get
behind..
..that sand dune.
that's it.
you are in Pakistan.
Come..
I need permission.
What?
What was that?
I'll take the soldiers'
permission and proceed.
Now is not the
time for any pranks..
Lets go.
I'm a disciple of
Bajarangbali.
I'm an honest man.
Are you nuts..
..they will shoot at us.
I beg you to leave.
Munni.. permission..
We need permission.
I knew you were crazy!
you make
him understand.
O jackass, the camels are near.
Hurry..
You will get killed.
Munni we will get permission.
Who's that?
Hello!
Are you an Indian?
-Yes.
..but Munni is Pakistani
She got lost..
I'm here to take
her home.
Sir..
Never heard this
excuse before.
Why didn't you leave?
I'm a disciple of
Bajrangbali..
I'm an honest man.
I waited for your permission.
This is Pakistani border..
If you needed permission..
why didn't you
get it from embassy.
I went there..
..at Delhi..
right Munni!
..but they kicked me out.
How did you get here?
Bu Ali brought us here.
Bu Ali!
He's an agent.
He says he has contacts
on both sides.
What nonsense!
How did you
cross the fence?
Through tunnel.
By crawling.
Its a straight tunnel.
Tunnel!
Where is it?
You are standing on it.
There!
Sir!
He's a spy.
Shall I arrest him?
No.
Listen.
..send them back
through the tunnel.
..fill it with sand.
Go away from here..
..or you will be shot.
Hello!
Hit him harder!
Munni!
..don't worry.
we are just having fun..
Having fun?
No fun..
I said it for her.
Enough.
How did you get
here again?
There's a tunnel there.
Who told you about
this tunnel?
Bu Ali.
Bu Ali!
i promised Bajarangbali..
..that I will take no rest
until I find her parents.
I'll give you rest.
Rafique!
Stand back.
Listen..
..even if you had
a passport or visa..
..I still wouldn't not
let you to go.
Go back,
right now.
It's for your own good.
Sir..
I promise you that..
as soon as I find her parents..
I'll return home.
Listen..
We will be here again..
..in exactly 10 min.
..and within 10 min..
you go this way..
or that way..
..we won't know.
Sir but..
But..
..but if you are seen again..
..you will be shot.
Lets go.
And find out who Bhu Ali is!
Hello!
Sir..
he is definitely crazy.
You don't care for yourself.
but at least think of her..
Sir..
I could have gone before you were back.
..but I'm Bajarangbali's disciple...
We know...
we know..
..that you are honest..
..and you've promised.
..but you are stuck here.
I also make you a promise.
I'll return home...
..when I find Munni's parents.
But sir..
Please give me
permission.
I told you to go..
why didn't you?
That was no permission Sir.
Its more like sneaking..
Sir he is nuts.
OK..
Go..
Sir!
Shaii I?
You can.
Let's go.
If you are Bajrangbali's disciple...
..you should definitely go back.
Its my word.
You're right..
..he's crazy.
Sir..
Yes bro...
Do you have Vegetarian?
What?
Vegetables.
There are vegetables..
there's capsicum, radish..
...tomatoes, peas, even spinach..
..filled with vegetables.
Not that...
Only vegetables.
What happened?
Is she alright?
What happened dear?
She's fine.
Then are you sick?
Not at all.
Then why just vegetables?
OK then..
let her eat...
take mine away..
I'll have tea and paratha.
Hey Bilal..
.. parathas were cold yesterday...
..better don't do it again.
Understood?
Make it quick Munni..
we need to hurry...
Are you full?
We'll find your parents very soon.
Stop right there!
Stop.
Why did the fatso follow us?
My handcuffs?
Handcuffs!
What handcuffs?
You stole it from me
Who'll steal handcuffs?
Search his bag.
Here..
Have a good look..
Did you find any?
Sir he doesn't have it.
Check her bag.
Why would she need it?
Show them.
Give it dear..
Here, have a good look.
Do a thorough search.
What is your name?
Pawan.
Pawan!
Pawan what?
Pawan Kumar Chatravedi.
People call be Bajarangi.
I won't call you that.
Are you an Indian?
Yes.
Your passport?
I don't have passport.
Are you a spy?
No I'm not.
.. and Munni is a Pakistani
Pakistani..
Is it?
She's Pakistani..
What is that?
So she's Pakistani!
..And I'm Sachin Tendulkar.
Arrest him.
Take this scoundrel.
Ahmad, you're wasting
you time..
An Indian spy was caught.
Indian spy?
Where?
At the Bilal's hotel.
He's taken to
police station.
Let's go..
Pawan sudah menghubungimu?
- Belum.
Dia pasti telpon.
Pasti dia sedang naik kereta.
Kau tak menyuruhnya telpon setelah sampai Wagah?
Aku sudah menyuruhnya.
Pasti dia lupa.
Kalau begitu kau saja yang telpon.
I've reached to police station,
you come here soon.
Tell us about your mission.
Mission?
Yes I got the
permission.
Tell us from the beginning.
How did you enter Pakistan?
From under the fence.
You are paid how much
for this dangerous mission?
Paid?
Paid for what?
It was my choice.
So you are a Patriot.
What?
Are you a Patriot?
Without a doubt.
What is the little girl's role
in this mission?
She's the reason.
That's enough..
..now leave..
Come in the front.
Hurry up.
As you've seen in our exclusive footage..
..an Indian spy and his partner in crime,
a 6 year old girl.
They've just been arrested at Chawla.
The girl's training..
has kept her from saying anything.
..sighing off with cameraman Kamil Yousef,
Chand Nawab Chawada..
Once more..
No, it was OK.
Turn it off.
Indian SIM card.
What happened?
Phone's switched off.
Sir I've taken a jaw dropping interview.
About an Indian spy.
This news can make your channel
No. 1
Sir its Chand Nawab.
says he has interviewed
an Indian spy.
What nonsense..
Tell him I'm not here.
Samsher sir is not here.
-Oh no!
Its a problem.
Ok then can you please
ask him to call me urgently.
I'll have the finished
report by then.
Hello!
What is your mission?
I've told you many times..
I'm here to take Munni
to her parents.
Tell us the truth..
i don't lie.
Where are you going?
What happened Munni?\
You know that place?
You live there.
This is her place..
What's going on?
We found it..
Munni's home.
What is this drama?
What is your name?
She can't speak.
Can't speak?
Why?
Did she loose her tongue?
Let me see.
Show me.
Open your mouth.
According to our sources..
..the Indian spy is under strict security.
..its been said that he'll be
shifted to Islamabad.
Why are you shifting?
Look behind you.
Hurry up.
Camera's with me..
..how will you shoot?
He's taking the bus..
Move faster..
I'll spy on this spy.
My bike is faster..
Ticket?
That was a narrow escape.
Hello.
This is Chand Nawab
from Chawla.
That Indian spy
is in the bus.
Which bus?
In this bus..
..he's right in front of me
Hurry up sir.
What bus is it idiot?
Its on Alipur road.
Ticket?
Do you know this place?
Is that a joke?
Where do you
want to go?
She's from Pakistan.
Don't know how
she reached India.
..all alone..
..her parents might
have lost her.
She can't speak.
..but recognizes this place.
I believe she is from
somewhere here.
Are you from India?
Yes.
How?
You know that border..
..that fence.. crawled under it.
..but with permission.
You came a long way from India..
..just to look for her parents?!
Yes.. Why?
That's amazing..
If only we had more like you in
both our countries..
..would have been great.
Show me the picture.
Sir that..
Stop stammering..
They ran away..
What!
Anybody recognize this place?
Have a good look..
Brother..
No.
There!
That should be it.. Hurry.
Over there..
What is it sir?
A man..
..they boarded this
bus with a little girl.
No sir..
there was none like that.
Has anyone of you..
seen a man
and a little girl.
No sir, we haven't seen them.
Sir that Chand Nawab told
me that its this bus.
Sir..
.she was doing this gesture..
showing that her home..
was in one of those pictures.
Where's that photo?
Its with them.
Check all the buses on highway.
Quick!
Either you are
very brave..
..or a big fool.
You entered Pakistan just like that..
no fear?
I was left with no choice.
Ok.. but how will you
find her parents?
Bajarangbali will help..
In Pakistan?
Tonight you'll be safer here.
..but..
..leave early in the morning.
What is this place?
Mosque.
Forgive me Bajarangbali.
What happened fellow?
Are you alright?
You look troubled.
What happened to me.
I'm perfectly alright.
Why stand here?
lets get inside.
Hey..listen..
Why were you absent?
Sorry sir..
Go.. I'll be there soon.
I can't go inside.
Why?
I'm not Mohammedan.
So what brother...
This place is open
for everyone.
..this is why we never
lock our mosque..
Come on..
So that's your problem.
I've never been to these places..
..but yes..
..we have some students who..
.may be from there.
Let me ask them.
Dear students..
Yes sir..
Have a good look
at this picture.
..and tell me where it is.
..and correct answer..
..will win you a price.
..a big one.
Stop!  Stop!
Take it back..
take it back.
He was with Chand Nawab.
You come here.
Sir this is Switzerland.
If you don't know then let others answer.
I'm telling you the truth.
This is Switzerland.
Here its written in English.
Switzerland.
Munni?!
Are you from Switzerland.?
Stop!
You can find such
locations in Kashmir.
Kashmir?
Go back to India?
No Sir..
..we also have a small part.
What?
Kashmir.
Stop there sir.
Please put your guns away.
Have you seen any strangers
Maulana Sahab?
There are no strangers
in God's house.
This stranger is dangerous...
An Indian spy.
Did you think that
he'll come here..
..to steal some
atom bomb formula?
Kindly inform us if you
see any strangers around.
-OK.
Its difficult to escape.
Is there a way?
There's a way.
What else will you make
me do Bajarangbali?
slept in Mosque, wore burqa..
and before
my circumcision..
..I beg you to find
her parents.
What!
He's in Pakistan!
You said..
..he'll leave her at Atari..
How can he go to Pakistan?
Who gave him passport, visa?
He went without that.
He went there without
Passport and Visa?!
You'll ruin your health...
..calm down.
You have no idea what
they will do to him.
One is hard enough..
..but Maulana Sahab has
two of them.
There will be police on road...
..you go through
those fields..
..you'll reach Khanewal.
Thank you.
You doing a
noble task.
I'll pray to Allah that
you find her parents.
How is it that you say?
Jai Sri Ram?
Jai Sri Ram.
-Yes Jai Sri Ram.
Let's keep moving.
You are responsible for this.
..neither you had to send
Munni away..
nor Pawan had
to go.
..you are the reason
he's in trouble.
Do something.
What can I do?
If you don't do
anything..
..i'll also go to Pakistan.
What!
O Lord!
Without any visa.
Can't do this anymore.
I can't breath nor walk.
One of us have to
dress like a wife.
Police are looking for
two men and a child.
You do it.
Really.
If someone asks your name..
you'll say..
"My name's Pawan Chatravedi.."
"..I'm from Delhi,
I worship Bajarangbali.."
"..I got permission to crawl
under the border fences."
Am I right Munni?
There are people..
..put down your veil.
..walk like a woman.
Munni..
Do me a favor..
She'll get caught!
This is wrong.
Dishonesty is never rewarded.
Mark my words.
You spoke again woman!
Now shut it.
O this vehicle..
Sir, can I give you a hand?
Sure.
Kindly be seated..
Start it when I tell you.
-OK.
Did you find the fault?
It takes time to
find the illness.
Are you a mechanic
or a doctor?
Try it now.
What did you do?
Try it again.
That's what I did.
Wow you fixed it in a minute.
Its my duty to help travelers.
Thanks a lot.
Shall I drop you someplace?
What's your name dear?
She has been speechless
since birth.
Wonder how her mother feels!
What do doctors say
madam?
She is also speechless.
..same condition.
..its hereditary.
Its all fate.
True.
Are you going to Khanewal?
No.
But don't you worry..
..I'll leave you home..
You don't really have to
do that sir..
Just drop us at highway.
I will ask one of my..
..officers to drive you..
..to your home.
Officers!
what do you mean?
I'm the Superintend
of that area.
I was on leave today..
..going back to work because
of an emergency.
Emergency?
There's an Indian spy
around here..
He won't escape.
Where is Chand Nawab?
I don't know.
You don't!
-Please don't beat anymore
..I swear that I saw him last time..
..entering into bus.
I tried ... calling him.
..phone's switched off.
Now..
..try calling him before me.
..hurry up!
Switched off.
Come with me..
..this is my stop.
..my men will leave you home.
Please come.
Hey Hassan.
-Yes sir.
Come here..
..they are my special guest.
..an amazing mechanic too.
Leave them at their doorstep
at Khanewal.
-Yes sir
Please come.
Thank you sir.
Thank you..
..you did me a big favor.
You may have breakfast here.
No thank you..
..we'll leave.
Let's go.
Please sit.
Careful.
See you.
Call him every hour.
He'll answer sometime.
Where's your house?
A little further.
Are you lost?
I haven't been here for
a long time..
..I eloped with her,
so her father is angry.
This is it.
Here?
-Yes.
Thank God we found your house.
You almost forgot your home..
It happens sometimes.
That's alright.
Get me Waqar.
Yes sir.
Any info about that spy?
His name is Pawan
alias Bajarangi.
He's with a local journalist..
Chand Nawab.
Let me leave you inside.
-Won't be necessary sir.
..thanks a lot for leaving us here.
Bye
-Take care.
Father-in-law..
How are you?
Who are you?
Forgive us..
..there's you daughter
and grand child.
Come here dear.
Who is she?
What's she doing?
I don't have any daughter.
What's the use of getting
angry here..
..lets go inside.
Getting me involved
without any reason.
I know you are angry with me..
But!
-Hit me.
But I...
Sir.. Sir..
Let him go sir..
Sir...sir.
Let's go inside.
Take it easy..
Good bye sir.
-Good bye.
..They also have
a little girl.
Girl?
How old?
Around 5 or 6 years old.
5 to 6 years old?
And she can't speak.
Speechless?
Yes sir.
Then why are you still
standing there?!
..Radio the message to Hassan
immediately.
Sir.
Who is that?
Open the door.
Are you gonna
break my door?
Huh!
You!
Where are they?
Who?
Your daughter and
son-in-law.
I've said this many times..
.have no daughter
or son-in-law.
Then where are they who claimed
to be your daughter and son-in-law?
How will I know?
They vanished as soon
as you left.
I was thinking of surrendering
to police.
..then the police will ..
..somehow find..
Munni's parents.
Don't even think about it.
You'll rot in jail and nobody
will know your whereabouts.
And do you think the police
will have your kind of passion?
..They might try for 2 or 3 days
..and then..
..Munni will be sent
to orphanage.
I will never allow this..
I've promised Bajarangbali..
..that I'll find her home.
..I am determined.
There might be a way..
Television.
TV?
Story has no punch.
It has sir..
An Indian..
..the way he helps a speechless
Pakistani child..
..its an awesome story sir.
Your spy's story...
had more punch..
..what happened to that..
..but he's not a spy.
..then there's nothing left.
Bye.
Hello!
Sir but...
What good is that
story to us?
Sir..
..a child will get her parents..
Get her parents!
Bro..
We sell news..alright..
..We are not
Hazrat Amin Shah Dargah.
..who unites separated people.
Bye.
Hate is easy to sell.
..but love..
What is
Hazrat Amin Shah Dargah.?
Its a famous shrine.
It is said that
wishes can come true.
Why didn't we go there yet?
Really..
..you get sick of
mosques and shrines..
Remember that mosque..
..you were running away
as if seen a ghost..
I can go to any shrine
for Munni's sake.
Lets travel tonight.
Its ringing!
Kamil!
I was worried.. thank God..
Where are you?
Is someone near you?
Nobody is around me.
Are you with the spy?
He's not a spy.
He's a noble man.
What do you mean?
He's here to unite the lost girl.
Where are you now?
We are leaving for
Hazrat Amin Shah Dargah.
Its said that it unites
separated people.
Take care of yourself.
I'll see you later..
Where are you going?
I'm Chand Nawab..
Today I am going to tell you about
a man who came here without any visa..
..but entered our land at night by crawling
under the border fences.
..His name is Bajarangi.
Just like the police, I too believed..
that he's a spy..
..but now I know..
..that he's no spy..
..then what is he?
Why is he in our land?
What does he want?
He's a common man just
like you and me..
And he's here because of love.
Compassion for a 6 year old speechless girl.
..who lost her parents in India.
When all the door
were closed...
..he had to take this route
to find her parents.
All the TV channels refused
to air this story..
..calling is bogus and
waste of time.
..and that nobody
will be interested.
So I plead you to help Bajarangi
..find her parents..
..and also for his
safe journey back home.
Ring him.
He's here with the police...
They are near.
He's not answering.
Answer the phone.
What!
-Why?
There's a plan.
Hello brother
Chand Nawab!
Is everything alright?
Everything is fine.
Did you go to the shrine?
Yes we went there last night.
Where are you now?
Now?
We are going to Gojra.
You are going to Gojra.
OK..
OK I'll call you later.
Take care.
Wow bro..
You finally lied..
When did I lie?
You made me lie!
So what..
Haven't you watched Mahabharata on TV?
Is it a movie?
Action movie?
If you recognize this
child or know anything..
..then kindly enter your phone no.
in this website..
..we'll contact you.
I've added your clips
in this video.
Internet is very powerful.
Any numbers yet?
Only fewer views yet..
will increase over time.
Do you wanna watch?
Come.
I'll rewind it.
What is it Munni?
What did you see?
Rewind it.
What is it Munni?
Pause.
Do you know her?
Your mom?
Rewind it.
She got down from that bus.
What would be the time?
Around 8:30.
Find out where this
8:30 bus comes from.
Its here.
Sir..
Where's this bus coming from?
Where do you wanna go?
I wanna know where's its from.
You're strange.
Just tell us where its c
oming from.
From Jahanabad..
Is that your village Munni?
Usain comes before that.
Usain?
Karimabad comes before that.
Karimabad?
..and then?
Sultanpur.
Sultanpur?
Munni!
..so you are from Sultanpur.
Sir!
Check out this video.
Chand Nawab uploaded
this yesterday.
Its outside the shrine.
They were never at Gojra.
..we've searched everywhere.
..no sign of them.
Listen..
Send pictures to all
the police stations...
..and check every trucks, buses and
other vehicles immediately.
Did you see your village?
Bro!
Listen to me
very carefully.
Come forward.
Show me your face.
Take it off.
He's the one..
I'm Chand Nawab..
Today I am going to tell you about
a man who came here without any visa..
..but entered our land at night by crawling
under the border fences.
..His name is Bajarangi.
Just like the police, I too believed..
that he's a spy..
..but now I know..
..that he's no spy..
..then what is he?
Why is he in our land?
What does he want?
He's a common man just
like you and me..
And he's here because of love.
Compassion for a 6 year old speechless girl.
..who lost her parents in India.
When all the door
were closed...
..he had to take this route
to find her parents.
All the TV channels refused
to air this story..
..calling is bogus and
waste of time.
..and that nobody
will be interested.
So I plead you to help Bajarangi
..find her parents..
..and also for his
safe journey back home.
If you recognize this
child or know anything..
..then kindly enter your phone no.
in this website..
..we'll contact you.
With cameraman Shah Nawab
this is Chand Nawab.
Kashmir.
I don't care what the media thinks..
For us, he is an
Indian spy.
But sir..
..we've confirmed from her parents..
..that she was lost in India.
Pakistani people has
sympathy for him.
Then..
..tell the media..
..the he has confessed ..
..he's a spy.
..then there won't be..
..any sympathy.
Ask your men to get
information from India.
Yes she couldn't speak.
I remember it well.
He brought her here.
..said she was lost.
Stop it!
Hello.
Sir we have verified
his story from..
..Kurukshetra police station
and Delhi High Commission.
He has taken
that child there..
He is no spy.
Mr. Hamid Khan..
You cannot decide
who's what...
..that's my job.
..your job is to make
him confess..
..that he's a spy.
But sir..
And yes..
..if you can't follow orders..
..then I can send someone
more able..
..and then you'll be
on long leave.
He wants his confession
at any cost.
I've worked all my life
protecting and honoring this country
..but..
..if..
..this man..
..spends all his life behind
bars in Pakistan..
..it will be against our
country's honor.
I'll not let that happen.
Hello.
Who is this?
Hamid sir!
Yes sir?
Yes
Thank you.
That's good sir.
Thanks a lot.
Get the camera..
Sir there's a new video
on the Bajarangi story.
It will go in the bulletin.
Rasika sister!
Look Bajrangi is on TV.
Tody Pakistani reporter
Chand Nawab has..
..posted a new video today
..on Bajarangi Bhaijan.
..who is locked
in Pakistani jail.
Pawan Chatravedi.
aka Bajrangi Bhaijan..
is an Indian who risked his life to
find a Pakistani girl's parents.
Run this story
immediately.
..why did he do this?
...for money?
for fame?
..for riches?
..No.
He did this out of good heart.
..he did this for a Pakistani girl
in the name of love.
..unfortunately..
..he got trapped because of
countries hatred towards each other.
..this hatred has caused Bajangi
to hide in Pakistan.
..Please end this hatred.
..and we have to do this..
..the millions of both the nations.
..who wants to raise their
children in love and not hate.
So lets us all end this
hatred together.
Let us all go to
Narowar check post..
What nonsense!
Seal Narowar check post.
Let billions of people from
both countries make sure..
..nobody stops our Bajarangi Bhaijan from
crossing the border..
..or going back home.
..with cameraman Kamil Yousif
this is Chand Nawab.
Brother Chand.
Munni?
I have fulfilled my promise.
Munni is..
Shahida..
Shahida is with her parents.
Shahida!
Yes.
Hurry up Pawan.
Come back soon.
..not under the fence..
..but with a visa.
I promise.
Please stop.
Open the gate.
Sir we are given
orders to arrest you.
If this man risks his life..
..to find your lost daughter..
..would you still not open the gate?
You know that..
I can't open this gate..
Can you hear them!
..voice of the common people
of Pakistan.
If they can tell the difference
between right and wrong...
..then why can't you?
You're a soldier!
You should know better.
Just following orders
sir.
..to stop him from
crossing our borders.
..but..
..we are few in number..
...and thousands of people present.
Did you get it?
Shahida!
Pawan!
Brother Pawan!
Uncle!
Jai Sri Ram Uncle!