Reggie ! Reggie ! Reggie !
Reggie Jackson
having an incredible night.
Two for two, with a walk,
four runs batted in.
- And he's already hit
two home runs tonight.
- Reggie ! Reggie !
- And just listen to that crowd.
Reggie !
Reggie ! Reggie !
Come on, Reggie ! Hit another one !
Hit another home run !
Coop, he's
already hit two.
It's a fly ball
to right, and deep !
That's going to be
way back !
- And that's going to be gone !
- Yea !
- Reggie Jackson hits
his third home run of the game !
- Yes ! Whoo !
All right !
- Good catch, Coop.
- I can't believe it.
I totally had it,
but my glasses slipped.
Remer, someday I'm gonna become
a big sports star, too.
Whatever you say,
Coop.
You just watch me, dude.
You just watch me.
There was a time in America...
when contests
of athletic prowess...
were a metaphor
for the nobility of man.
Historic moments, forged
by the love of the game,
celebrated the human potential
to achieve excellence.
But as time passed and
the country neared the millennium,
something went awry.
Manning rolls right.
He's got Plough at the ten.
The five--
Touchdown, Dallas !
The ideal of sportsmanship...
began to take a back seat
to excessive celebration.
The athletes caring less
about executing the play...
than planning
the vulgar grandstanding...
that inevitably followed even
the most pedestrian of accomplishments.
The games themselves
became subordinate...
to the quest for money.
Stadiums and arenas...
became nothing more
than giant billboards...
to promote
commercial products.
- Players sold their services
to the highest bidder,
-
much like the hired guns
of the Old West.
Thank you. And after playing
for New England,
San Diego, Houston, St. Louis,
a year for the Toronto Argonauts,
plus one season as a greeter
at the Desert lnn,
- I'm happy to finally play here
in the fine city of Miami.
-
-Minnesota.
- Whatever. Shit.
-
Soon it was commonplace
for entire teams to change cities...
in search
of greater profits.
The Minneapolis Lakers moved to
Los Angeles where there are no lakes.
The Oilers moved to Tennessee
where there is no oil.
The Jazz moved to Salt Lake City
where they don't allow music.
The Oakland Raiders moved to L.A.
and then back to Oakland.
No one in Los Angeles
seemed to notice.
The search for greener pastures
went on unabated.
Continued expansion
diluted the talent pool,
forcing owners
to recruit heavily...
- from prisons,
mental institutions and Texas.
-
Fistfighting and brawling
permeated every sport,
overshadowing
any athletic competition.
Oh !
As the problems mounted,
the fans became
less and less interested.
To reverse the trend, major sports
started interleague play.
When that novelty wore off,
they tried intersports play.
But no matter
how far major sports went,
it wasn't enough
to bring the fans back.
The spirit of athletic
competition, however,
indeed was not dead.
Its seed merely lay dormant
in the dreams of the young.
You know, Remer, someday
I'm gonna be a big sports star.
I'm gonna own a big sports bar.
Hurry it up, Coop.
Hold on. I just
gotta water the plants.
I don't wanna go to a party with
a bunch of losers from high school.
But this is Britney Kiser's house,
and I really want to fuck her.
- Dr. Kiser.
Coop and Remer.
We graduated
with Britney.
- You graduated ?
- Of course we graduated, cock-- Beer ?
Man, this place looks like
a Dockers commercial.
- Oh, hey, Stef !
- Coop ! Remer !
- You want a beer ?
- Oh, my God !
You guys haven't changed
since high school.
- Oh, cool.
- No, it isn't.
Cock.
- Hey, Skid Mark Steve ! Oh, cool.
- Hey, dude !
You still just hanging out
playing Nintendo ?
Well, if you must know, I'm in
my second year of med school...
and I'm training
for the Summer Games.
- What are you two up two ?
- Just hanging out.
Playing Nintendo.
Cock.
- Hmm.
-  You looking forward
to getting out of here ?
-Yeah, I'm all packed. It should be fun.
-Hi, Britney.
Coop ! Remer !
I didn't think
you guys would show up.
Well, we wouldn't
miss your party.
No, I mean, I don't remember
putting you on the guest list.
Huh. Well, Ted
told us about it.
Excuse me.
Ted, why would you tell
those losers about my party ?
-  l-l-l-l--
- This party sucks. Let's bail.
No, dude. Let's go up
to Britney's room.
-Remer !
Come in here.
Check it out.
Britney's underwear, dude.
Aw, dude.
Dude ! Dude ! Dude !
-I am so jealous of you.
Oh, God !
- Excuse me.
- Britney.
What are you guys doing
in my mom's room ?
Oh ! Oh ! Oh ! Oh !
- Get out of here !
- Uh
-Oh, Jesus !
- Ah ! Ah !
Dude, we're never gonna get a chick
like Britney Kiser, are we ?
Or any other chick.
But it's only 'cause
we have no jobs.
Our rent check's
three months overdue,
and our gas
is about to get shut off.
What do girls
want anyway ?
Well, apparently,
not total losers.
Well, we're pretty good
at basketball.
As long as we don't have to run or
jump or dribble. You know what I mean ?
- That shit's overrated anyway.
-  Hey !
- You guys up for a little game ?
- Sure.
Well, let's
make it interesting.
Say 20 bucks ?
How about 50 ?
- You're on.
- Let's go. Here we go.
- We don't have 50 bucks.
- We don't have 20.
Look, it doesn't matter.
How good can they be ?
To the lane, baby !
That's pretty !
- Oh !
- Oh, shit !
Alley-oop !
Alley-oop ! Yeah !
Come on, ladies.
We playing or not ?
Yeah, but not that pussy ass
two-on-two you guys play in the suburbs.
What, you guys
got something better ?
Yeah, but it's this new game
we-we picked up in the hood.
- So, what is it ?
- Okay. Okay.
I shoot from wherever
I want, right ?
And then you have to make that
same shot or else you get a letter.
You mean like horse ?
- No, it's not like horse ! -
Duh. It's, uh
It's baseball rules.
Yeah.
A single's
from the free throw line.
Right. And a double's
from the top of the key.
You can't shoot
from the same place twice.
A triple's from back here, and
a home run's from behind the meatballs.
- You miss, you get an out. Ready ?
- Break !
- What ?
- We can explain it more slowly.
You're not
big sports guys ?
- No, no.
- No, no, no. We get it. We get it, man.
Losers up first.
So, let me get this straight.
This is a single, right ?
Yeah, and a home run's
behind the meatballs.
Take your shot, guy.
- You can't spit beer at me
when I'm shooting.
- That's one out.
That's the way we play.
I can do whatever I want
to make you miss your shot.
- He's right. That's one out.
- One out ?
Give me the damn ball !
- I fucked your sister.
- Huh ?
- Coop lines up for a double.
- Okay, guys, second and third.
Coop's got a runner on third.
This could bring him home.
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo,
hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo.
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo.
Hoo-hoo
- Yes! Two outs !
- God, this is-- Come on !
- Oh !
-Ted Nugent.
Oh !
Oh ! Tip-in. Double play.
That's three outs.
- What ?
- We're up.
- That's a double play.
- That's nice. Real nice.
- Bottom of the eighth.
This could almost seal it.
Oh, he made that
look easy.
Aah ! Damn it !
Come on, man ! What
Oh, one of Britney's mom's
pubic hairs.
-Oh, God !
- Oh !
- Come on, man !
- Dude, we win the game !
- Dude, that was a sweet psych-out.
- Dude, here's another one.
- Oh, come here.
- What the hell's up with that ?
We win, and they get the chicks.
That sucks, dude.
It's jobs.
We gotta get jobs.
Then we get the khakis.
Then we get the chicks.
Starting tomorrow,
we gotta stop playing games.
Miss it.
Steve Perry.
- Ah !
- Yes ! Three outs. I'm up.
- It's the bottom of the fifth.
- Joseph R. Cooper ?
That's a single.
Man on first.
- Are you Joe Cooper ?
- Cut the crap, Squeak.
You know who I am.
Gentlemen, this form authorizes me
to enter onto your property...
and terminate services
forthwith until all delinquent
payments have been generated.
- What ?
- Dude, he's here to shut off the gas.
Squeak, you work
for the gas company now ?
- Gentlemen--
- Double ! Guy on second and third.
Is your canine locked up and/or
safely secured within your domicile ?
Uh, yeah. He's at the vet
getting his claws removed.
Then if you'll excuse me.
Dude, does it just suck
being you ?
I'll show those guys
what sucks.
Steve Perry. Steve Perry.
I shoulda been gone
-Oh, yeah, he misses.
- Aw, damn it.
-  You said
no more Journey psych-outs.
Dude, I'm running out of ideas.
-That's why we have
this little short shot.
- Short shot. Kind of like a bunt.
- Exactly.
- Oh, yeah.
- It doesn't put any runners on base.
- That's a sweet idea.
- You lied to me ! Again !
Oh, right. The dog's
vet appointment's tomorrow.
We put the cat in today.
Honest mistake, Squeak. Sorry.
My name's not Squeak !
All right ? It's Kenny !
All right, you little bitch.
Here. Take a shot.
I don't wanna take a shot.
I wanna turn off your gas.
And don't call me bitch.
Okay. Squeak.
Let's just shoot for it.
Shoot for it ?
What, are you insane ?
This is my job,
you assholes.
Look, all you got to do is make
a single from right here...
and you can shut off our gas,
and we'll never call you Squeak again.
- Or bitch.
-  Or bitch.
- From right here ?
-  Mm-hmm.
All right.
Check this shit out.
- Steve Perry.
- Huh ?
- Oh !
-
-Tough break, Squeak.
- Now you gotta fetch the ball, bitch.
-
-All right ! Come on, Squeak !
We can win the game
with this one, baby. Bring me home.
- Yes ! That's it ! We win the game !
-
Dude, we got five runs
that inning.
- This game's pretty badass.
-  Another game ?
You're up.
Top of the first.
Yo, Tyler.
- I hear your sister's
going out with Squeak.
- What ? Oh !
- Another psych-out.
- I'm not going out with his sister.
Dude, that's the defense.
You gotta psych 'em out.
We gotta say totally fucked-up shit
to make sure the other guy misses.
Oh, right. Okay.
Hey, wait a minute !
Why is me going out with his sister
totally fucked up ?
Yo, Pierce. I hear your mom's
going out with Squeak.
- Whoa !
- Oh, yes ! Two outs.
So, you're gonna own 1/12 of the rent,
1/12 of the water bill,
1/12 of the power bill,
1/12 of the cable bill
- Dude, check it out.
- What's that ?
It's a BASEketball.
Whoa, dude. You made a ball ?
Out of what ?
Dude, I can't believe
those ass-wipes fired you...
for not shutting off
our gas for six weeks.
It was losing the truck
that pissed them off the most.
Well, you can camp out
here for a while.
Well, this is
pretty sweet.
- Does this couch fold out to a bed ?
- Yeah, a totally great bed.
But that's Jenkins' bed.
Your bed's over here.
Dude, that is
so fucking weak.
How am I supposed
to get a chick in that ?
You couldn't get a chick if you had
a $100 bill hanging out of your zipper.
- Yeah, I could.
- No, dude, you're a little bitch.
I am not ! I don't even know why
I hang out with you guys.
- 'Cause you're a piece of shit.
- I am not a piece of shit.
- But you're a little bitch.
- Sure are.
- Goddamn it, man !
- But you're a little bitch.
- Sure are.
- Goddamn it, man !
I swear, you guys rip on me
13 or 14 more times, I'm outta here.
Well, whatever. Dude, I gotta
show you the scoreboard I made.
Your place is
a shit-hole anyway.
Well, at least
I'm on the team.
Yeah, they want me
Joe Bryant, WIGM,
at the scene where
an unusual new driveway game...
has captured the imagination
of at least one neighborhood.
An entire league
has sprung up around this quirky
...round-robins,
starting with 12 teams in June,
now down to just two, including,
we're told, the inventors of the game,
childhood friends
It's off the rim.
Could be a double play.
Maxwell tips.
Newman's try.
No !
Shirts have a shot
at the conversion.
Remer !
Keeps it alive.
Last chance.
Coop. Up !
- Good ! They make the conversion !
-
- And the home run counts !
- Yeah ! Yeah ! Yeah !
Yeah !
What a game !
The Shirts win
the World Championship of BASEketball !
Yeah !
Gentlemen.
Gentlemen,
I'm Ted Denslow.
- Ted Denslow, the billionaire ?
- Yes.
Anyway, I like your little game here.
How'd you like to go pro ?
BASEketball ?
I got three words for you:
National BASEketball League.
- We're not interested.
- Now, wait a minute. Hear me out.
Now, you kids with your loud music
and your Dan Fogelberg,
your Zima, hula hoops,
and Pac-Man video games,
don't you see ?
People today have
attention spans...
that can only be measured
in nanoseconds.
I hear you.
- Just look at these people.
-  Whoa !
- Way to go, Coop.
- They feel a certain connection
with you as players.
With BASEketball,
we can start fresh,
not allow teams
to change cities...
or players
to be traded.
And everybody
will get paid the same,
just like when I was a kid,
and players were treated like
- Indentured servants ?
- Yes !
And the real beauty
of this game...
is anyone can play.
Any normal joe
can be a sports hero.
Haven't you ever wanted
to be a sports hero ?
Sure. Once. But that--
That was a long time ago.
Well, if I know anything
about this country,
- America will go nuts for BASEketball.
-
America will go crazy
for BASEketball.
-Listen to that crowd.
- Listen to that crowd.
-  Call an ambulance !
Ooh, ooh, ooh
- Ooh, ooh, ooh
- I say she never cared
And that she never will
To do it all again
I guess I'll have
to wait until then
lf I get drunk
Well, the better
I'll understand my baby
You won't bother me
no more
And if you're drinkin'
well, you know that you're
my friend, and I'll say
I think I'll
have myself a beer
Ninth inning.
The Beers still behind by three runs...
and now down
to their last out.
And the pressure on these players
has got to be enormous.
All right, you guys.
We've got one out left.
We're not beat yet.
We can still win this thing.
- Can we do it ?
-  Yeah !
Yeah ! Go, Coop !
What a game
these fans are seeing.
That gentleman, of course,
Beers owner Ted Denslow,
the father
of professional BASEketball,
along with his lovely
new wife, Yvette.
Now shooting,
number 44, Coop "Airman" Cooper !
Coop ! Coop ! Coop !
Coop is heading
for the triple square.
Bob Costas, this has to be one of
the most exciting BASEketball games...
in recent memory.
Just five years ago,
this game was played only on driveways.
And it's hard
to believe just five years ago,
those girls were only
in grade school.
Coop ! Coop ! Coop !
So, Coop at the triple line.
Jansen sets up
for the psych-out.
- Hey, Coop.
- Be right with you, Dirk.
-  It's good !
-  Nothing but net.
Coop triples again.
- He's hit for the cycle
seven times tonight.
- He tricked me.
Yeah !
- Go, Coop !
- Yeah !
And listen to those foam heads
doing the Beers chug.
Chug ! Chug !
Coop's on third,
with two down.
And that brings up
Squeak Scolari.
- I knew it was gonna come down to me.
- Relax, dude.
It's not just you.
We're a team.
And it all comes down
to just one man.
- Oh, God !
- Listen to me, dude.
If I could have
one guy out there, it'd be you.
Unfortunately, that one man
is Squeak Scolari.
- Ah, shit !
- Pretend this is just another game.
The Denslow Cup is, of course,
the biggest game of the season.
- Ah, Christ !
- Will you turn that shit off ?
- I'm so scared.
- Listen to me !
You make that shot, or I'm gonna shove
your head so far up your fucking ass...
you'll have to
wear yourself as a hat !
And in the dugout, Doug Remer giving his
teammate some last-minute encouragement.
Now, go out there
and make that shot !
Fuck !
The talented Felon Girls...
appearing in their
third Denslow Cup game.
Now shooting, number 23,
Squeak
"Little Bitch" Scolari !
Let's go
So Squeak Scolari walks
out to take the last remaining single.
Come on, bitch !
Nice one, bitch !
Hey, Squeak.
Miss it. Miss it.
- It's good.
And the Beers
stay alive in the ninth.
Dallas Felons owner,
Baxter Cain,
hoping for another
Denslow Cup victory.
Now shooting, number 17,
Doug "Sir Swish" Remer !
Two on, two out.
Remer heads for the double line.
Remer, you better make sure
your toe's not over the line.
Hey, Jansen, nice psych-out,
dingleberry. Yes !
It's in.
It's now a two-run game.
Dirk Jansen apparently missing
another psych-out.
And everyone here at Beers Garden
is on their feet.
Coop ! Coop ! Coop !
And, Al,
at a time like this,
you can't help thinking
about guys like John Elway,
guys who kept coming close
and then finally got there.
- Ow !
- If Coop can make this one,
- the Beers' long wait will be over.
-
Hey, Coop, it looks like your boy
Denslow's about to buy the farm.
- Aah !
- Ah !
- Oh !
-  He missed.
- He missed. I don't believe it.
- The Felons win their second
consecutive Denslow Cup...
- No, no.
- on the strength
of a Dirk Jansen psych-out.
- Aw !
-I got you, dude. I got you.
- You--
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Relax. Relax.
- Do the Happy Dance.
- We just lost the game.
Do the Happy Dance.
- Where's the singing ?
- Aw, I don't wanna sing.
Do the singing.
Come on. Sing.
Happy Dance
Doin' the Happy Dance
Shit ! Denslow !
And these Beers fans
have to be disappointed.
What an unfortunate thing
to happen on Dozen Egg Night.
Oh ! Oh ! Oh !
Oh !
It's my husband.
Somebody help him. Oh, God !
- If there's anything you need--
- Oh, Teddy.
I can't believe it.
He just fell over.
- Oh !
- Mrs. Denslow ? Mrs. Denslow !
-Oh !
I wish there was
something I could do.
- Uhh !
- They stopped serving them
after the seventh inning.
Somebody get this man
a hot dog !
You're absolutely right, Jim.
Ted Denslow was a hero because
his vision brought BASEketball...
from neighborhood driveways
into big arenas,
but more importantly,
into the hearts and TVs of America.
- It's a very sad day.
- Yee-ha !
His untimely death casts an unbearable
pall over an otherwise sweet victory.
- Hey, yeah !
- And all of our hearts...
- are with you and your family on this--
- Go, Dallas !
Dirk Jansen, winner of the
Winter's Warm Douche M.V.P. trophy.
What's your take
on this stunning upset ?
The whole key to this game
was when I psyched out Coop.
No doubt about it.
And all you people watching-
I can't believe this guy.
He didn't psych me out.
If anyone should get the psych-out,
it should be Denslow.
- Dude, weak.
- Coop, I know this is
a dark time for you,
but I'd like to get your thoughts
on what happened today.
Well, Tim, today I lost
the big game and a dear friend.
Um, I'm feeling
pretty vulnerable right now.
I don't think I should be alone.
I really need people to talk--
It certainly does seem to be
raining shit on Joe Cooper right now.
On paper, the Beers
had the far superior team.
With the outside shooting of Coop
and the deadly accuracy of Doug Remer,
what happened out there ?
Well, you know,
it was a team effort,
and I guess it took every player
working together to lose this one.
Thanks, Doug. And so
- Hey ! You wanna do
an interview with me ?
- No.
So another BASEketball championship
is in the books.
Yet another opportunity lost
for the Beers.
-Man, I gotta go.
Hey, Coop.
Coop ! What's going on ?
Coop ! Coop ! Hey, Coop !
This is Tim McCarver
from Beers Garden...
-where the Dallas Felons have
defeated the Milwaukee Beers...
- in Denslow Cup IV
by a score of 13 to 11.
-
-  Everybody in.
One at a time.
-Aw, please. Can we ?
There he is !
- Where ?
- Oh, man !
- Cool !
- Can we talk to him ?
-
- Can we stay ?
- Please, Miss Reed.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Hi.
Would you mind signing a couple
of autographs for the kids ?
I think you're looking for the
Dallas locker room. It's over there.
I know,
but it was so crowded.
I mean, um, they would really
rather have your autograph.
- Really ?
- Anyway, would you mind signing these ?
Uh, sure.
Oh.
Uh, it's nice
to meet you, Miss...
- Reed. Jenna Reed.
- Joe Cooper. Coop.
- I know.
- Are all these kids with you ?
Oh, yeah. I've been the director
of the Dream Come True Foundation...
since October.
Oh, the ones that grant wishes
to sick and dying kids, right ?
Well, we prefer to think
of them as health-challenged...
and survival-impaired.
- You're a big fan of BASEketball ?
- No, not really.
I mean, the kids
are big fans.
I try and keep them interested in things
that are a little more permanent.
Permanent ?
You know how
professional athletes come and go.
Not in BASEketball.
There's rules against it.
Well, hello.
Miss Reed,
this is Remer.
Would you like
a fresh pretzel ?
I baked it myself.
Oh. Thank you.
- It goes great with mustard.
- Okay.
Miss Reed.
Dude, you didn't make
that pretzel, did you ?
- Of course not, but chicks
like guys who can cook.
- What ?
See, it works.
She was checking out my ass.
- She wasn't checking out your ass.
- All set then ?
I better get these kids back.
Little Travis is getting impatient.
Hey, I love kids.
Which one's Travis ?
- Here. Heads up, big guy.
- Uhh !
- Are you all right, Travis ?
- I think he's sleeping.
He needs a little work
on the hands.
- He's blind, Doug.
- Ah !
Felons Fans rejoiced in their team's
Denslow Cup victory...
with a huge celebration
in downtown Dallas.
Final tally:
14 injured, three dead.
And on a sad note, the sports world
was devastated tonight...
by the passing
of Ted Denslow.
By all accounts, the late Beers owner
seemed to be the only one...
surprised by his death.
And it appears time
just finally ran out...
for the old cocksucker.
Theodore Denslow,
dead at 85.
His hairpiece was 24.
These chaps I wore in
Rootin' Tootin' Rhythm...
I bequeath
to my nephew Herman.
Hope he looks
as snappy in them as I did.
And this poncho that kept me dry
during the filming of-
Mrs. Denslow.
Baxter Cain.
- May I sit down ?
- Of course.
-My deepest sympathy on your great loss.
-Thank you, Mr. Cain.
My valuable hand-painted plate
commemorating the pope's visit...
to Dodger Stadium,
I leave to my niece Susan.
-  Aw !
- Limited edition, signed in the mold,
- with a photocopied certificate
of authenticity.
- Jenna.
- This six-shooter I wore--
- What are you doing here ?
Well, I'm not sure.
I-- I got this letter.
Yeah, yeah, me, too.
And the toothbrush
used to clean the oats...
- Oh !
-
-  Clumsy idiot !
- Where's the body ?
They buried him two days ago.
This is the will reading.
Oh. Well, in that case--
These are for you, Jenna.
Now as a special
fluke of charity,
I bequeath these season tickets
to the Dream Come True Foundation.
-Thank you.
I had nothing but respect
for your late husband.
Unfortunately, he was
the one person who stood in the way...
of making any kind
of changes in BASEketball...
that might increase
the owners' profits.
I can't imagine what he had
against making money.
-I trust that quality
isn't sexually transmitted.
- That's pretty sweet, huh ?
- Yeah.
The kids will be
very excited.
- Especially little Joey.
- Joey ?
Well, he's such
a big fan of yours.
He's going
into the hospital next week,
and he begged me to ask you
if you'd come by for a visit.
But it's not a good idea.
- I'd love to come by.
- Hey, I'll come by. I like hospitals.
No, you don't.
You like Taco Bell.
I went to this hospital in France
and got together with this chick.
- Dude, that was a hostel.
- Oh, yeah.
And finally, of course,
my beloved Beers,
I bequeath
controlling interest to...
Joseph R. Cooper.
Yes !
We own the team !
I gave him the best three months
of my life.
- Sweet !
-
- Way to go, dude !
- And, Coop ?
Yes, Mr. Denslow ?
I know you have it in you to lead
the Beers to victory this season...
because if you don't,
the team reverts to Yvette.
-  What ?
- Don't feel badly
about losing the team.
I believe this is merely
a temporary situation.
Thank you, Mr. Cain.
It's nice to have a strong,
handsome man like you on my side.
Well, yes. I'd love
to discuss this further with you.
Why don't you
visit sometime ?
Maybe we could, uh...
Iay some carpet,
if you know what I mean.
At this time, I'd like
to ask everyone to leave the room...
so I can have
a private moment with Coop.
Now that we're alone, Coop,
there's something I wanna tell you.
Remember when you had
the crabs...
-and the only thing that made you
feel better was this lotion ?
Well, I found
another use for it.
It feels so good,
it makes me wanna sing.
Just like that night we spent in the
tattoo parlor in Chicago. Come on, baby.
I'm too sexy
for my shirt
-Too sexy for my shirt
So sexy it hurts
And I'm too sexy
for my car
Too sexy for my car
Too sexy by far
You gettin' this ?
That's two rooms done.
Boy, those corners
are tricky.
You've done a fine job,
Yvette.
Now, as I was saying, I think
I've come up with a plan...
to make sure that Coop
never wins that Denslow Cup.
Oh. So then
the team will be mine ?
- Yes.
- That's wonderful, Baxter.
Do you want me to move on
to the conference room ?
No. Not yet.
But you know, I think my lobby
could use a good buffing,
if you know what I mean.
Mmm. I know exactly
what you mean.
Oh !
Oh, God ! Oh !
Oh, I can't do this shit !
And the Beers coming up to bat...
for the first time
in this season opener against Miami,
a game they have dedicated
to Ted Denslow,
a team wearing black
in memory of the late Beers owner.
The Beers cheerleaders
also mourning the loss.
Glamour is a rocky road
Mmm !
Mmm ! Mmm !
Skin flicks, lipstick
Baby scribbles in the mirror
Drama overdosage
Dude, it's a whole different ball game
now that you own the team.
Yeah. I was just thinking.
Denslow was right.
This season could be different.
We just gotta kick some ass.
We're playing to keep this team.
You up for it ?
Dude, I'm in,
all or nothin'.
- Glamour is a rocky road
Glamour is a rocky road
Joining us in the booth this evening,
big fan of BASEketball, Tony Nochelino,
who plays, as you know,
latino cutup Scooter...
on the new hit comedy series
What's the Difference ?
Airing between Recycled Junk,
starring Lisa Campbell,
and Same Old Crap,
featuring teen heartthrob Mark Swenson.
All part
of the great fall lineup...
on our network's
"Who Gives a Rat's Ass" Thursdays.
- And, Tony, it is great
to have you with us.
- So Miami takes the field.
- And we're underway here tonight.
-
- Coop steps into the single square.
-  "Coop ! Coop ! Coop !"
- Bonehead !  ldiota !
It's good. And the Beers are off
to a promising start tonight.
-And this game is made
all the more special...
- by the fact
it's Free Range Chicken Night.
-
The Beers up by two, but the Dealers
are threatening here with one out.
And that brings up
Enrique Hernandez.
Psych-out ! Psych-out !
-Hernandez, look.
It's fat liposuctioned
out of Marlon Brando's ass.
Uh, aw, no.
What am I doing here ?
Ah-- Aw, it's all
salty and warm.
Oh, why would
I do this ?
This guy ate
a lot of pork. Aw !
- Muy bueno.
-
- Damn it !
- Dude, I thought
it was a killer psych-out.
- Really ? So sick.
- Shake it off. Shake it off.
I got this guy.
- Yo, Gomez.
-  Psych-out !
- Got milk ?
-
Oh, yeah, you like that,
don't you ?
Coop tips, and it's good !
Double play. Beers win.
And Remer still
nailing down that psych-out.
Dude, we totally
kicked ass.
Yeah, and this
is just a start.
- Doug, could you sign my chicken ?
- Joe Cooper. Baxter Cain.
Oh, Cain. Yeah,
Denslow told me about you.
I want to welcome you
to our community of owners.
If there's anything that you need,
don't hesitate to ask.
Thanks, dude. Later.
We're going to be
voting next week...
on making some changes
in BASEketball's rules.
- I want to tell the others
that you're with us.
- Why ? BASEketball's fine.
Of course,
in some respects.
But until we allow teams to move
cities and players to change teams...
and take advantage
of lucrative corporate tie-ins,
you and your colleagues are going to
have to continue working for-
- Chicken poo ?
- Ugh !
Feed. Chicken feed.
Coop, the ball
is in your court.
In order for those rules to change,
every owner has to vote yes.
Denslow was already filthy rich.
He didn't need the changes.
- But you do.
-
Look, I appreciate
what you're saying,
but you're asking me to go against
every reason we created this game.
Well, before you make
any hasty decisions, discuss
it with your teammate.
I don't have to.
We're best friends. We think alike.
Look, I'm sorry, but if
you want unanimous consent,
you're gonna have to get it
from one of the other owners.
- Are we gonna kick their ass ?
- Whoo ! Whoo ! Whoo !
- Yeah !
- We're gonna take
these mooks out or what ?
- Yeah ! Let me handle this one !
- In the river, baby ! Come on !
- No doubt about it !
- Yo, Coop !
Your mother's a terrible cook !
-
- Oh, yeah !
- Damn !
-I'm gonna kick your ass, Mary.
Easy.
- Can't gross me out, Remer.
- Oh, yeah ? Well, check out Coop.
- Aw !
-
Hey, Zane,
I wanna feel you...
deep inside me.
- Oh !
- Yes !
-You can't do that !
That's not fair, man !
Oh, come on, Zane. That was-- That
was fair. Come on. Let's play ball.
Hey, Watson, have you seen
those beer commercials ?
How to speak San Franciscan.
- Hey !
- "Vajoina" !
-Not fair ! That's bullshit, man !
That wasn't a gay joke.
That was an Australian joke. Aw !
-Shoot 'em up shoot 'em up, boys
Bang, bang
whoo, whoo
Yeah, ride 'em, ride 'em
ride 'em, ride 'em
- Come on, let's do it !
- What do we always say ?
One, two, three !
Fuck the Mexicans !
Duh, guess I'll
take my shot now.
Sure hope I make it so I can get home
quick and smack my wife in the eye.
- Shut up, Remer.
- Shut your mouth, bitch. I'll-
Yeah ! Yes !
All right !
- Take that, Remer !
- Aw, shit !
Du-du-du-du
- Du-du-du-du
-
Oh, my eye ! My eye !
You're sick, Cooper !
- Yeah !
- Whoo-hoo !
If a woman wants a mate
ho is responsive,
she will reveal to him
the secret of a woman's duality.
She will tell him
about the interior woman,
that one who added
to herself makes two.
-  Paging Dr. White.
- I didn't expect you'd come.
I thought I'd say hi
to our little friend Joey.
Oh. Well, he's sleeping,
and I really wanted to finish this book.
- Well, maybe it'll
make him feel better. Joey ?
- Uh, well-
Joey ?
Look who's here.
My biological father ?
No, dude, it's me,
Joe Cooper.
- Coop ? Coop, is it really you ?
- Yeah, it's me.
Wow. I watched all your road games.
Your psych-outs were the best.
- Thanks, dude. Right on.
- Coop, what's a "vajoina" ?
Uh, so, uh, what seems
to be the problem with you, guy ?
I'm-- I'm going to die.
- Well, we're all gonna die.
- Yeah, but not this week.
Joey, what did I tell you
about staying positive ?
Besides, your donor liver's
due to arrive today.
Oh, hey, look
what I brought you.
- Wow ! A La-Z-Boy !
- Yeah, I made it myself, you know.
If I had a nickel for every time
this ball pulled me out of a tight spot,
I'd have a shitload
of nickels.
Gee, Coop, I wanna be
just like you when I grow up.
Here's your
decaf mocha, Jenna.
Just like you take it:
Nonfat milk, low fat whipped cream...
- and a little sprinkle of cinnamon.
- Thank you, Doug.
And I baked you fresh
poppyseed muffins, too.
Oh.
Give me a break.
Poppyseed muffins.
I thought you had your
electrolysis appointment this morning.
I did. Here.
Look. Check it out.
Hey, listen, partner,
I talked to the people
at the Dream Come True Foundation,
and they want
to make your last wish-
Your-- Well, they want
to make your dream come true,
as long as it doesn't involve, like,
a miracle cure or something like that.
Well, hell, the guys on death row
only get a meal, right ?
Uh, so--
so, what's your dream ?
Well, I've always dreamed
of big game hunting.
How about killing an endangered species,
like a bald eagle or a giant panda ?
Joey, I don't think that's in
the true spirit of the foundation.
Well, how about
poisoning the reservoir ?
I know. How about throwing flesh-eating
fish into a public swimming pool ?
I don't think you're quite
getting the point, dude.
Come on, Joey.
Search your heart.
What's the one thing that you want
more than anything else in the world ?
Chelsea Clinton.
That's a pretty tall order,
dude.
You'd have a better shot
at Bill.
You have any backup dreams ?
Well, there is
one other thing.
Could I just once--
Could I hang out with the team ?
Just spend a day
with the Beers. Could l, Coop ?
Oh, l-l don't know.
And Miss Reed, too.
Why can't we be friends
I seen ya, I seen ya, I seen ya 'round
for a long, long time
I really, I really, I really remember
when you drank my wine
Why can't we be friends
I seen ya, I seen ya, I seen ya
walkin' down in Chinatown
I called ya, I called ya, I called ya,
but you did not look around, yeah
I pay my, I pay my
I pay my money to the welfare line
I seen ya, I seen ya, I seen ya
standin' in it every time
Why can't we be friends
-Why can't we be friends
Don't be jealous when you see me
in those fancy clothes
Down the hatch. Bartender.
This has been so fun. I feel like
I'm gonna puke all over the bar.
Oh, look, Jerry Springer.
- Here she is, your daughter-in-law--
-  She's my son's wife.
- Get that.
-
Nicole.
Let's say hi to Nicole.
-We'll drink every time
a fight breaks out.
- All right. Jerry ! Jerry !
- Jerry ! Jerry !
- What's up ?
- Hey, you bitch !
Oh, fight, fight, fight.
- Back off, bitch !
- Oh, you want some of this ? Come on !
- You fat-
Fight !
-Ah ! Ah !
I'm gon' kill you !
You see, Joey,
dreams really do come true.
- You're the best, Coop.
- Yeah.
Oh, man, it's late.
We've got a game tonight.
And you've got
that big liver operation.
- Yeah, but--
- What, dude ? You're gonna be fine.
I just know
I could pull through if-
- If what, dude ?
- Joey, just say it and Coop will do it.
Could you, Coop ? Do you think
you could hit a home run for me...
in tonight's game ?
- Well, dude--
- It's not like he's asking you
to hit two home runs.
Two ? Can you hit
two home runs ?
Of course he could. This is
Coop Cooper you're talking about.
Hell, he could hit three home runs
if he wanted to, huh, Coop ?
Three ? All right.
Remer, can I talk to you
over there real quick ?
Thanks.
Hey, you know, Joey, I've hit
my fair share of home runs, too.
That's nice, but Coop's gonna
hit three home runs for me.
- That's great, Joey.
-
I think Coop's the greatest guy
in the whole wide world.
Yeah, he's a major
dude, all right.
- There, I feel much better now.
- Aah !
- Mr. Squeak ?
- What ?
What grade are you in ?
Hey, anybody call
a taxi ?
- I called a taxi.
- We gotta get going if
I'm gonna hit those home runs.
Don't you worry.
From now on, everything's gonna be A-OK.
Gee, Coop, this is
the best day of my entire life.
- Oh !
-
Oh, my, what a story
this is.
Little Joey Thomas undergoing
a lifesaving operation tonight.
-The fans here, of course,
all wearing yellow ribbons...
in support
of this brave little boy.
And his hero, Joe Cooper,
promising to hit three home runs,
a promise that could mean
the difference between life and death...
- for this brave little boy.
-
Hey, Pete, what's the matter
with Coop tonight ?
I don't know, but he's one for 11
and he smells like Christian Slater.
Coop in the home run circle,
getting ready to take his shot.
It's up. It's good !
-Coop sinks his second
home run of the game.
His blood sugar's way up
since yesterday.
Has there been any change
in his fluid intake ?
Sweet Jesus ! His sodium's level
through the roof !
It's the strangest thing.
He's eight years old,
and he smells like
Robert Downey, Jr.
Ninth inning.
Everyone's stomach in knots here,
as Coop steps up
for his last at bat.
-  Coop ! Coop !
- One more chance
for that third home run.
Hey, she's here, man,
that girl from the bar.
- That's a guy.
- What ?
- A guy ?
- Yeah, that's a dude.
You're just saying that 'cause
you want her for yourself.
I'm saying that
because she's a guy.
It's impossible.
Just look at her.
She's got the cutest
little upturned nose,
the softest lips,
the sweetest Adam's apple.
Yeah. I think I can smell
her perfume from here.
Coop ! Coop ! Coop ! Coop !
Shh.
Coop calls for quiet.
One more chance
for that third home run.
He's in deep focus
out there, Bob.
This obviously means
a lot to him.
-  He shoots !
-  It's going, going-
Looks like Coop
has made a dream come true...
- for a very brave little--
-
Wow. The Lord must really
have it in for that little boy.
Oh, why ? Why ? Why ?
Come on, Coop.
It's over.
- Poor Joey. Why ?
- I'm sorry, dude.
If you're looking
for Joey Thomas,
he's been moved
next door.
- Oh.
- Hey !
Oh, my God !
Oh, why ? Why ? Why ?
Gentlemen,
he's in this room.
Joey ! Joey !
I'm here for you, dude.
The operation
went fine.
Just after your game,
we thought he was suffocating.
He kept screaming, "Choke ! Choke !"
and lost consciousness.
He'll be fine
in the morning.
But don't stay too long.
He needs his sleep.
Joey, I'm sorry
I missed that third home run.
-But remember how I said that
dreams really do come true ?
- Well, they don't.
- Mm !
Coop, he's awake !
He's trying to tell you something.
-Wha-what is it, Joey ? What ?
- Hey, he's turning blue.
- Oh, my God ! This poor kid's freezing.
He needs a blanket.
Where's a blanket ?
- Sir, sir, Can I borrow your blanket ?
- I'm here for you, Joey.
- Let me borrow your blanket !
- Aaaah !
Here you go, little buddy.
This should keep you warm.
-He's flatlining ! You killed him.
- Oh, my God !
- I didn't kill him.
Dude, you missed the third home run
and you killed him.
-No ! No, I'm not gonna
give up on this kid !
-  Coop, calm down, man.
- Come on, Joey. Come back to me.
- Coop, get a hold of yourself.
- Leave me alone !
- Live, damn it ! Live !
- What the hell are you doing ?
Where are those heart paddle things
that George Clooney uses ?
- Not those.
- Dude, let's just bail.
- Give me these things.
- You're gonna kill him !
- Clear !
-
- No pulse, Coop.
- Crank up the voltage.
- Ten thousand volts.
- Clear !
-
- Up it to 15,000 !
- Fifteen thousand volts.
- No ! No !
- Clear !
- Coop, do you know what you're doing ?
- What's it look like ?
- An execution ?
- I'm tryin' to save a life !
I'm givin' it
all I've got, Captain.
I love ya, always have.
Clear !
-This isn't working.
We gotta try open heart massage.
I need a rib separator and a scalpel.
- Where do I cut ?
- Start in the middle
and work your way around.
Code blue, Nurse ! Seventy cc's
of sodium pentothal, stat !
-I didn't kill him.
Get away from him.
Get out of here.
- Cardiac syringe comin' through !
-
-Oh ! Oh !
- Help me !
-
- Hard left ! Hard left !
- What the-
Reggie Jackson
having an incredible night.
-  Reggie ! Reggie !
- Two for two, with a walk,
four runs batted in.
And he's already hit
two home runs tonight.
And you have to wonder just what
Charlie Hough must be thinking,
as Reggie steps into the box
here in the eighth.
-  Reggie ! Reggie !
- There's a fly ball-
- ... nature's fury
when man and beast collide...
on the back roads
and byways of America.
Aw !
- Aw ! Aw !
-
I can't believe
those assholes taped over the game.
-Aw !
- Aw !
-
- Jenna.
- Hi.
Oh, I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
No, no, I was just
fixing clam chowder.
Uh, come in.
Well, when you weren't
at the hospital, I came right over.
Apparently, there was some sort
of terrorist attack on the post-op ward.
- Terrorist ?
- Yeah.
Evidently, they were disguised
as BASEketball players.
They went on some sort of rampage,
and I was so worried about...
Joey.
Was he, uh--
Is he-
Oh, he's fine. He came through
the operation with flying colors.
With that new liver, he should be
peeing like a champ in no time.
- That's kidneys, Coop.
- Oh.
Well, uh, have a seat.
I just wanted to stop by and thank you
for all you've done for Joey.
Oh, it's nothing.
I'm sure he's going to remember
this day for the rest of his life.
Yeah, I don't doubt that.
Oh ! What a great picture.
Look at you guys.
You seem so happy.
Yeah, l-l guess we were.
We were just best friends
playing ball in the driveway.
Next thing I know,
I'm on ESPN and Wheaties boxes.
And I guess
it's all pretty sweet.
But nowadays,
since Denslow's been gone,
I'm in charge of the team,
and the whole league now.
-Sometimes I forget why I play the game.
-Why do you play it, Coop ?
- Mr. October.
- The guy in the Chippendales calendar ?
No, that was
Dwayne Zackemore.
I mean...
whoever it was that month.
I'm talking
about Reggie Jackson.
I saw him play
in a World Series once.
He hit three home runs in one game.
I caught the third one in the stands.
I remember growing up,
it meant so much to me.
All I ever dreamed of was to be
that guy, have that one shining moment.
- Be a hero.
- You already are a hero, Coop.
You've won
these kids' hearts, but-
- What ?
- Well, I'm just worried
about getting attached-
I mean, the kids
getting attached.
I don't want them
to be hurt.
Jenna, I would never do
anything to hurt these kids.
But what Joey
really needs to know...
is where are you
going to be next year.
Right here.
And the next year,
and the year after that.
Right up
until Joey grows up...
and gets
a driver's license...
and... starts going out
with girls...
and meets
the right one...
and forgets about
BASEketball altogether.
Goes home,
does some push-ups,
fucks the sleeve
of his favorite jacket.
- What ?
- Huh ?
I'm-l'm just saying
we'll be here for Joey. I promise.
Oh, Coop, I want to believe you. I want
to believe you more than anything-
Coop, check out all this cool shit
we got at the hospital !
- Ooh, hey, Jenna.
- Hey, Doug.
Wow. You're looking a little flushed.
Do you have a temperature ?
- No. I'm-l'm fine.
- Open your blouse and say "Ahh."
- Remer !
- Doug, l-- I gotta go.
- No, Jenna--
- Yeah, I'm sorry. I gotta go.
Jenna-- Aw !
Aw ! Thanks a lot, Dr. Dickhead.
You totally fucked me there.
Dude, relax.
It was just a joke.
- Dude, give it up.
She doesn't even like you.
- Oh, she has the hots for you ?
- Squeak has a better chance
with her than you do.
- Hey, you think ?
- That's low, you son of a bitch.
- Why is that low ?
I know you're
jealous right now,
but you can't blame me
because I have a sweet ass.
I can't help it.
I'm doin' the Happy Dance.
Doin' the Happy Dance.
- Does this thing work ?
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- Can you hear me in this ?
- Yeah, yeah. Check it out.
- Asshole !
-
- You wanna get a sandwich ?
- Yeah, let's get a sandwich.
- Goddamn. Oh.
Mr. Cain,
Doug Remer is here to see you.
Remer ? I thought
I asked him to come tomorrow.
Well, yes, sir, but he's
here now in the trophy room.
- The trophy room ?
- Mr. Cain-
Mr. Cain. Mr. Cain ?
Sweet.
-Mr. Remer.
Oh, hey.
Mr. Cain.
I see you've been
admiring my museum.
- Is that really--
- Yes.
When I see something I want,
I get it.
Remind me the next time you're here
to show you the prize in the collection.
My autographed
Ty Cobb bat.
I'm planning to expand
the museum out here next year.
Killer setup,
Mr. Cain.
- What do you pay in rent here ?
- Nothing. I own it.
Oh, that reminds me.
Can you break a 20 ?
- What, dollars ?
- I didn't think so.
Let me get straight
to the point, Don.
- May I call you Don ?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Don, when I see one of
BASEketball's hottest stars...
with less than $20 in his pocket,
driving an American car,
sharing a small house
with two other guys,
you know what
that says to me ?
- Homos ?
- No, no, no.
It says you're underappreciated.
- And underpaid !
- Oh, yeah, I mean,
I guess we are underpaid.
I want to change all that.
Players of your caliber
should be making the big bucks.
Don't you agree ?
Remer ! Remer !
-Try to stay with me on this, all right?
-All right.
Now, last week, I tried to get Coop
to agree to certain rule changes...
that would
make you millions.
- Me ? Millions ?
- Now listen carefully.
Do you think Shaq got rich
playing in Orlando ?
Hardly. He made his fortune
moving to L.A.
You know how much
he makes now ?
As much as he made
playing in college ?
What ? No !
Lots more-- big money.
- And you can too !
- Would I have to quit BASEketball ?
What ? No ! I need you
to get Coop to go along !
He'd have
to quit BASEketball too ?
- Did I just fart ?
- Uhh !
Top of the seventh,
and those cheers you're hearing...
are from the nearly 15,000 on
hand here for Anal Probe Night.
So, two outs, and Doug Remer
heading for the triple square.
He's 0 for 12 so far tonight.
In fact, with the exception of Coop,
the Beers are ice-cold.
Oh, man, that
doesn't even qualify as an air ball !
And the Beers are gone
in the seventh.
The Aliens now coming up
with the top of their order.
Which, if you're
scoring at home,
is the same three guys
who came up last inning.
All right, what the hell's going on ?
You guys are lying down out there !
Oh, I get it.
You guys are pissed off.
Uh, why ?
Dude, you turned down Cain's offer
without talkin' to us.
- Mm-hmm !
- Yeah.
All right,
what do you want, dude ?
Dude, what do you think ?
We invented this game together,
but you get to
control everything.
- Listen, Cain has some
pretty good ideas--
- Dude, Denslow gave me the team.
- I already told Cain no.
- Dude, I'm sure Denslow is happy
in his little worm farm but-
- Dude, I'm not gonna do it.
- All right, dude,
listen to me carefully.
Do you think Shaq got rich
playing in Orlando ?
No, he got rich playing in college.
Everybody knows that.
Dude, it's not about the money.
It's about tradition.
Look, think about the greats
who have played this game.
It's because of them.
It's because of us that I can't
bow down to a guy like Cain.
That's easy for you to say, 'cause you
got the team ! We got jack shit !
- Even Squeak is pissed off !
- Hell, I never really minded.
Shut up, bitch ! Dude, quit thinkin'
about yourself for a change !
Dude, I'm not gonna cave in.
End of story, dude.
- Dude.
- Dude !
Dude !
Dude.
Well, I guess you've got
a point there.
All right, maybe I was wrong.
From now on, we're full partners.
- Really ?
- And you guys-- you all
own part of the team too.
Really ? You'd be willing
to do that for us ?
Yeah, and that's not all. I'm talkin'
prime equity stock options,
comprehensive health care,
full dental, traveling H.M.O.,
and the first 20 weeks
of psychiatric care free of charge-
- the way it should be !
-  Yeah !
You've been psyched
You're goin' down
I'm a trash-talkin'
talented, no-class clown
I wanna abuse you
until you lose
- You can go on home and pout
You've been psyched out
- Yes !
Go, Beers !
Hey, Smitz, you wanna see
a scary face ?
Yeah !
- What ?
- Dude !
You ain't cut
from the right cloth
You don't got what it takes
Now you blew it, oh
Another stupid mistake
Another bad, bad break
You been psyched out
and you're goin' down
I'm a trash-talkin'
talented, no-class clown
I will abuse you
until you lose
- You can go on home and pout
You've been psyched out
- He can't do that !
- You've been psyched
but you can't know me
-
- 'Cause I'm a dirty bastard
- He's a dirty bastard
Oh... Oh...
Oh, shit !
You can't handle
the pressure
Keep your head in the game
You can't do it
and it's a cryin' shame
- But you're not to blame
- Aaah !
- Oooh, ugh !
- Wait a minute !
Aaah !
Y-Y-Y-Yeow !
Sticks and stones
will break your bones
But words will
drive you insane
There were four
of them in the corral:
The once-proud beast,
the broken girl,
her mother, and finally,
the man they called The Whisperer.
The woman
stared hopefully...
into the ancient cowboy's
weathered face.
"Can you help her ?"
"Lady, I repair cows, not people."
- His disjointed voice seemed
to be coming from afar.
-
The Beers win their tenth
consecutive game. I don't know-
Who's this bimbo
Coop's got the hots for ?
Oh, that's Jenna Reed. She's
the director of some kids' charity, um-
Dream Come True
Foundation.
Ah. I know six men
on their board of directors.
Baxter Cain is not going quietly
into the good night.
Hey, Baxter ?
Who's Ty Cobb ?
- Oh, my God !
- Did I just fart ?
Ohh !
Ninth inning. Beers just
one out away from making the play-offs.
They'll have to get by Big Ed Tuttle
and the L.A. Riots to ice this one.
That's him, Squeak.
That's Tuttle.
He's been talkin' some serious shit
about you all night.
Yeah, he told everyone
that he caught you...
jacking off in the bathroom
before the game.
He saw that ?
You oughta get this guy,
Squeak.
Look at him, man.
He's huge !
You want me
to psych him out ?
- Dude, he'll never expect it
coming from you.
- Here, say this.
I'm not gonna
remember all that !
-All right, here then.
-C'mon, this is for the play-offs, dude.
If you get this guy,
we're in !
Don't worry,
we've got your back !
- Hey, Tuttle !
- Yeah ?
- Your mother's deaf.
- My mother's dead, you little twerp.
I guess that's why
she didn't move around a lot.
Unbelievable. The Beers win !
- Yes ! Sweet !
- The Beers have done it !
- Dude ! Sweet ! Yes !
- Ohh !
Talkin' away, I don't know
what's left to say
I'll say it anyway
The Beers win
a spot in the play-offs...
by beating Los Angeles on
an unlikely psych-out by Squeak Scolari.
Take on me
- Take me on
- Dude, he is pissed !
- I didn't go over
the line on that, did I ?
- No, not at all.
Don't worry about it,
dude.
Jenna ! Jenna !
Hey, you missed it.
We won !
We kicked ass ! Let 'em flow, baby.
We're in the play-offs !
Yeah, let the tears come.
You're gonna make me start crying now.
- No.
- I guess this really is emotional.
- Should we just cry ?
- I think we should. No one's watching.
- We won the game, we've got
friends, we've got everything !
- Will you stop that ?
I'm not crying
because I'm happy.
I just got the news
our funding's been cut.
They're gonna close
the foundation !
-Can they do that ?
Oh, no. Those poor kids.
We can't let this happen.
We gotta do
something !
I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to come here and ruin your big night.
I'm sorry !
No, Jenna.
Jenna, wait.
- Gentlemen !
- Mr. Cain !
I couldn't help but overhear
your conversation with Miss Reed.
- Dude, what are you doing here ?
- I jet here, I jet there.
Anyway, I just wanted
to assure you there's no reason...
for your girlfriend's foundation
to go into Chapter 11-
or for that matter,
12, 13 or 14.
Uh, but I think I may have
a solution to her problem.
There.
It's a time-tested moneymaker.
Every athlete does it.
- You want me to have bigger titties ?
- What ?
No, no.
It's a clothing line--
a Beers clothing line.
No, dude, that's against
the BASEketball bylaws.
Not if the proceeds
go to charity.
Think about it. Miss Reed's
foundation will never have
to worry about funding again.
Awesome, Dude !
I think we should definitely do it !
'Scuse us.
-Will you let me do the talking here ?
There's no way I'm doing any kind
of deal with this piece of shit.
Wait, I thought it was we. Remember,
it's not just up to you anymore.
All right, we can come up with
a better way to get money for Jenna.
Like, how ?
- See ? Thought so. Mr. Cain ?
- Hmm ?
As part owner of the Beers,
I'd just like to say, where do I sign ?
Congratulations, Don.
This is gonna change your life.
I look out
for my "wimmins" !
Before we discuss
fabric or color,
-  Freedom ! Freedom !
- we gotta decide where we
can make this stuff cheap.
We'll do a big media blitz. And don't
worry about Coop. He'll come around.
I'm a scat man
- Hi there, I'm Dan Patrick.
- And I'm Kenny Mayne.
With the first seven months of the
BASEketball post-season out of the way,
the play-off picture is now
starting to emerge.
So with last night's victory
over Boston, next week the Beers
must beat lndianapolis...
to advance to Charlotte--
that's in an effort to reduce
their magic number to three.
Right, and the Beers can advance
to the National Eastern Division
North to play Tampa.
So, if the Beers beat Detroit
and Denver beats Atlanta...
in the American Southwestern
Division East Northern,
then Milwaukee goes
to the Denslow Cup,
unless Baltimore upsets Buffalo
and Charlotte ties Toronto.
Then Oakland would play
L.A. and Pittsburgh
in a blind choice round-robin.
If no clear winner emerges
from all this, the two-man
sack race will be held...
- on consecutive Sundays
till a champion is crowned.
- Right.
Dude ! Dude ! Dude !
After the grueling,
regular BASEketball season,
we're now in month nine
of the play-offs.
No, Daddy,
don't touch me there !
The Beers,
vying with San Francisco...
for a slot in
the Denslow Cup game.
Ninth inning, Ferries up by one,
Coop steps in.
It's back,
way back-
Good ! Home run !
Coop ties it up !
- That could mean extra innings.
- Ugh !
Everybody's downtown
Come on, let's go
Let's hear it
Everybody's downtown
- Come on, let's go, let's hear it
-
Foxy, foxy teaser
Little kid's
got a mondo fever
-What's this guy ?
He's my entertainment lawyer.
He's helping me with my movie contract.
Oh, now you're such a big shot, you're
gonna act in a Hollywood movie ?
- Fuckin' sellout.
- Now shooting, number 17:
Doug "Sir Swish" Remer !
Superstar
Can't run, can't shoot
Bring on the beat
Funky girls really
turn up the heat
Can't run, can't shoot
Repeat
Beers win ! Beers win !
And the Beers have done it !
They're on their way
to the Denslow Cup !
Everybody's downtown
- Dude, who is that ?
- Who's it look like ?
Victoria Silvstedt,
Playmate of the Year.
Hello ! Victoria Silvstedt,
Playmate of the Year !
- What's that ?
- It's a commitment ring.
- What, for Jenna ?
- Yeah, I'm letting her know
that I'm ready to consider...
thinking about dating her
exclusively.
Well, I'm giving Jenna a pre-commitment
ring. It's a promise to pledge...
that we'll think about getting
engaged just as soon as we're
ready to make a commitment.
What the hell are you talking about ?
You don't care about Jenna !
You were just in a hot tub naked
with Victoria Silvstedt,
Playmate of the Year !
You know what ? That hurts, man.
That really hurts.
My clothing line is single-handedly
saving Jenna's foundation.
Oh, sorry, I forgot about
how much Doug Remer cares about kids.
- Gentlemen !
- Mr. Cain !
Hate to interrupt your celebration,
but I have something...
you might be
interested in.
Go ahead, don't be shy.
It concerns you.
Open it !
I think you'll find it interesting.
- What's that old saying, uh--
- "A penny saved is a penny earned" ?
- "Don't eat cheese before noon--"
- Shut up !
How about "One picture
is worth a thousand words."
- Oh, that's a good one !
-  God, these are awful !
- What kind of lowlife scum
would use children this way ?
- You would.
Me ? Never !
Gentlemen, those are pictures
of the Beers clothing line...
being made in Calcutta.
- Oh, just great !
- Of course, if they ever get out,
the Beers, and your girlfriend's
little foundation, would be ruined.
- Yipes !
- But, rest assured, there's
no reason to be panicked.
Those pictures never have to
see the light of day, if-
If what ?
If you two miss
the next Beers game.
Dude, the next game
is the Denslow Cup !
I can see you've been
reading the papers.
Listen, boys, do as I say.
You play ball, and you'll be just fine.
I thought you said
you didn't want us to play ball.
I want you to play ball...
with me.
You want us
to play for Dallas ?
Uh, uh, uh !
Oh, I get it. You don't want us
to show up at the game at all !
Of course, you numbskulls !
It's called blackmail !
Good evening !
Goddamn it, Remer, I told you
this was gonna happen, didn't I ?
If you would have agreed
to Cain's changes it never
would have gotten this far !
- Dude, because of you, Jenna's
foundation is totally screwed !
- Me ?
- Oh, there you are !
- Jenna !
I saw the pictures !
This is awful !
It's gonna mean the end of
the foundation. It's not endowed like-
Well, like-
Jenna,
I can explain.
- Yes, it was his fault.
- Me ?
This is your mess, Remer.
I shoulda kept the team to myself !
Dude, I don't know you
anymore !
Enough !
Look at yourselves.
You're just typical men,
with humongous... egos !
You're like every other
pro athlete. I should have
kept those kids away from you.
Their lives are ruined
and all you can do is argue
about who is the bigger penis ?
I mean, child.
Long wanger. Oh !
Throbbing cock. Aaah !
Oh, God, I don't even know
what I mean anymore !
- Jenna, wait !
- You've gotta believe us, Jenna !
It was all
Coop's fault !
- Dude, could I talk to you over here ?
- Mm-hmm.
You know something, Pig Fucker ?
Can I call you Pig Fucker ?
No, only my friends
can call me Pig Fucker.
- Aaaah !
-
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow !
You know what, Coop ?
You're not my best friend anymore.
- How do you like that ?
- I love it !
Good, I'm glad !
I'm sick of playing
second fiddle to you, and you
gettin' all the recognition.
I'm gettin' myself
a new best friend.
- Wake up, bitch.
You're my new best friend.
- Really ? What ?
Are we going
to the zoo ?
Fine ! I don't need you.
I'll get myself a new best friend too !
So go ahead. Go back to your fancy cars,
and your big bank accounts,
and your celebrity friends,
and your beautiful women,
and Victoria Silvstedt,
Playmate of the Year.
Fuck !
Your life is spinnin'
out of control
Seems the whole world
is out to get you
Everything is wrong
Nothin' seems right
There's a sinking feeling
inside
Even your best friend
has turned his back
But you can't let it
bring you down
No, you've got to fight
'Cause you try
but you can't let go
It's when you're down
that you gotta get up
Don't let 'em walk
all over your face
Stand up for yourself
And make everything
right again
Even if some guy's tryin'
to blackmail you
And your girlfriend
thinks you suck
It's up to you
to let them know
That it was all part of
some rich guy's evil plan
Look out ahead
There's a truck changin' lanes
-You got some yellow crumbs
on your upper lip
And those warts on your dick
aren't gonna go away
'Less you start using
topical cream everyday
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to
Calcutta lnternational Airport,
where it is currently 95 degrees
with a light drizzle.
We hope you enjoy your stay here
in lovely Calcutta.
Taxi !
- Amoka, come on !
- Aw, c'mon ! Driver, I'm in a hurry !
- Look, just take me to 7-1-1-- Aw !
-
Here you are,
Beerswear Factory.
- Hey, you, is this--
- I'm sorry, no entrance-
- Who the hell are you ?
- I factory manager. Who you ?
I Joe Cooper--
I mean, I'm Joe Cooper.
Wait, Mr. Cooper,
you must put on hard hat !
Aw, this is awful.
Aw, this isn't good !
Do any authorities know
about this ?
- Aw ! Aw !
- Wait, wait, please, Mr. Cooper !
Put that down !
A young man. His whole life
in front of him disappears.
A familiar story, yes.
But this is no ordinary Joe.
Joseph R. Cooper, perhaps the most loved
sports figure in the country-- vanished.
According to Mrs. Elsie Melcher, a
neighbor who asked not to be identified,
Joe Cooper left his house
two weeks ago.
According to Angelique Bones,
a nosy bitch who lives up the street,
he took with him only
a toothbrush, a wallet,
a steamer trunk
and a plane ticket to Calcutta.
Police theorize several possible
scenarios of what happened...
to the man affectionately
known to the world as "Coop."
I don't know where
the hell he is.
For all I care, he could be hanging
by his neck in his fuckin' closet.
Scenario Number One: He's hanging
by his neck in his fucking closet.
The night before his disappearance,
Coop's girlfriend had paid him a visit.
According to friends,
they had quarreled.
If you're looking for Joe Cooper,
I suggest you look wherever you find...
the most heinous, blatant and vile
exploitation of children on the planet.
Scenario Number Two:
Coop went to Disney World.
Here's a photograph of Joe Cooper taken
just days before his disappearance.
Here's a computer-enhanced simulation
of what he might look like today.
From Milwaukee, Wisconsin,
on the shores of Lake Michigan,
it's the Denslow Cup, where
the defending champion Dallas Felons...
meet their perennial challengers
the Milwaukee Beers.
Hello, I'm AI Michaels
along with Bob Costas inviting you...
to join us here at Beers Garden
for Denslow Cup V.
And we're in for
a classic battle tonight.
You're absolutely right
about that, Al.
We have over a hundred million
people throughout the world
tuned in to see this game.
Many of them, of course, with no
understanding of the sport itself,
but nonetheless fascinated
by the flickering images
and the bright, pretty colors.
High up in the stands, pyrotechnic
expert Sergio "Lucky" Ferouch...
is readying another spectacular,
halftime fireworks display.
All right, you guys.
You ready to kick some ass ?
What's wrong, you guys ?
Why the long faces ?
We miss Coop.
Can't win without him.
We don't need Coop.
I'll lead you to victory !
We're supposed to be a team.
Without Coop it's not the same.
Look, even if Coop
was to walk in here right now,
it wouldn't change
the outcome of this game one iota.
- We can win this thing !
Are you with me ?
- Yeah, yeah !
- That's the spirit. Are you with me ?
- Yeah ! Yeah !
All right, Coop's here !
We're underway here for Denslow Cup V.
A stunned crowd of
over 18,000 witnessing the Beers...
being thoroughly dominated by
the Felons. Come on, Beers ! Go, Coop !
Hey, guys, thought I told you
we weren't gonna watch this game.
-Oh, come on, Miss Reed.
It's the Denslow Cup !
These are not the kind of people
to be looked up to or emulated.
The severed and
mutilated head was postmarked Denver.
The owner still has not
stepped forward.
Update: The disappearance of
the Milwaukee Beers BASEketball star.
When Joe Cooper discovered that
the workers in the Beerswear
Factory were youngsters,
not even old enough for prostitution,
he personally flew to Calcutta.
His new, all-adult workforce
now makes a decent wage,
enjoys full medical benefits
and in-house child care.
All of us here are glad
that such a terrific human being
like Joe Cooper has returned.
If I were a woman,
I'd sure like to be his girlfriend.
Walking in the park, hand in hand,
wrapping my legs around him,
cuddling in the spoon position,
our hearts beating in unison,
staring into his eyes
over our morning coffee-
Uh, yes, yes, thank you.
- When we come back,
our next unsolved mystery--
- Come on, kids.
- We're going to the game !
-  Yea !
Ladies and gentlemen,
for your seventh-inning stretch
entertainment,
-the National BASEketball League
is proud to present...
a salute to our South Sea
neighbors: Viva Calypso !
We're up 16-nothing
at the break.
Have the trucks pull up
to the locker room.
We'll sort out the stuff
when we get to Jacksonville. Okay.
Hey, Baxter. I finally got
all the chrome off this for you.
- Nice. Very nice.
- You want me to start on this one ?
Ladies and gentlemen, please
direct your attention now...
to the Malaka-Laka
Balance Board of Trust,
symbol of brotherhood
in many Polynesian countries.
Assuming the roles of the
downtrodden but happy natives,
with their good-luck pineapple,
your Milwaukee Beers !
Thanks for flying back, Coop. You really
made a big difference in the score.
If I wouldn't have been cleaning
up your mess, I wouldn't be
jet-lagged and shitting curry !
Hey, guys, knock it off,
all right ?
Representing
their white colonial oppressors,
the Dallas Felons !
And now, let's all join
our Caribbean brothers...
in the ceremonial South Sea handshake
above the Lagoon of Peace.
-  All right, let go !
-  You let go !
Stop it. Stop it !
- Guys, come on, man !
- Money-grubber !
- Powermonger !
- Cock !
Guys, stop it !
Whoa !
-Hey !
- You son of a bitch !
- You asshole !
- Die !
- Eat shit !
Hey ! Would you just stop it ?
Would you hold on a minute ?
Look at you guys, fighting
on the Malaka-Laka board !
You should be ashamed
of yourselves !
Back in the driveway,
we were nothing !
Now we've risen
to the highest level,
but you're
throwin' it all away !
If you've forgotten
what BASEketball means to America,
you have only to look at this board--
the Malaka-Laka Balance Board of Trust.
Don't you see what
we have here ?
A game where guys
with bad backs and bad knees...
can get together and compete
on the same field...
as guys that are all
goosed up on steroids.
But more than anything,
isn't this game about gettin'
together with your friends
and havin' a good time ?
I remember-
I remember a long time ago,
I didn't have anybody.
You guys took me in.
I guess that's why it kills me
to see you like this.
If we can't be friends, then the heart
and soul are out of this game.
Certainly out of me !
I know I'll never get that back again.
We have sullied the waters
of the Lagoon of Peace !
I'm begging you, for the love
of our Caribbean brothers,
dudes, stop this madness !
- Hang on !
- Oh, my God !
Remember to hold your breath
just before we hit !
Never let go !
Bob, this has to be the most spectacular
extravaganza I have ever seen !
You can cram three seats into the space
it takes for one wheelchair,
not to mention the wasted space
it takes for the oxygen bottle.
- Hell, those little shits
never pay full price anyway !
- Baxter !
I just realized
I can't stand you !
You can kiss
these puppies good-bye !
Oh.
Shit, Coop.
I'm sorry.
I guess the money
did go to my head.
No, l--
I'm sorry, Remer.
I think I've got a lot
to learn about sharing.
Look at me. I've become
everything I used to hate.
Maybe we--
we just grew up too fast.
My worst enemy
turned out to be me.
- Dude.
Hey, Puck,
I've got two over-
- All right, let's go win
ourselves a championship !
- Yeah !
She was
a little green
He was just
a little mean
They were
together all the time
So now no one can forget this thing
that happens all the time
She would do anything
- Yo, Darcy.
- Yeah ?
- Hey, that's my wife !
- Yeah, and this is me !
They live together
all the time
So now no one can forget
this little thing
That's on her mind
It's a waste to wonder
what's a heart these days
It takes a lot to get up
and just leave those who--
- Hey, Dirk !
- What is it ?
- I hear your sister's
goin' out with Squeak !
- Aaah !
And Squeak Scolari
crosses the plate again...
as the Beers have come
roaring back since the break.
Bob, this is more like
the Beers team we've seen all season.
Ninth inning, two outs.
Beers still down
by two runs.
Felons on first and third.
The Beers have to stop Dallas here
if they want to stay in this game.
And the always dangerous
Grumsky coming up.
Get this guy, Coop.
He hasn't missed a shot all night.
I know, but I don't know what to say.
Nothing works on him.
- Hey ! Tell him he's fat !
- Dude, that's not cool.
- Yeah, it is.
- That's not cool.
- No, no, no. Just do it really subtle.
- Subtle.
Hey, Grumsky,
you losin' weight ?
Oh, big ass !
You're fuckin' fat.
You're goddamn fuckin' fat.
How'd you get so goddamn fuckin' fat ?
The Beers hold them
in the ninth on a clutch psych-out...
by "Coop" Cooper.
Coop ! Coop !
Coop ! Coop ! Coop ! Coop !
Bottom of the ninth.
Dallas, 16. Milwaukee, 14.
Remer on second,
Scolari on third.
Coop's coming up.
And so, it all comes down
to this one shot.
Coop makes it, the Beers win the cup,
and get to keep the team.
Or, he misses.
Coop ! Coop ! Coop !
Oh, my God.
La-Z-Boy has popped !
The ball Coop has used
every day of his career is gone,
and a time-out has been called
as the Beers star tries to regroup.
Excuse me, driver,
do you think you could go any faster ?
Could I go
any faster ?
- Yea !
- Hang on !
Yea !
Whoa !
No doubt about it, Al.
The loss of this ball is going to
affect the outcome of this game.
Ow ! Hey !
Come on, kids !
Thomas, where are you going ?
It's just one shot. You can do it !
We can win this thing !
- Come on, Coop ! You can do it.
- Coop !
Stop ! Don't shoot !
- Wait !
- Joey !
Here.
I brought this for you.
I made it myself.
Just like you.
Dude, you made this ?
Well, Miss Reed helped me
for most of it.
- But I finished it myself.
- Joey, this is great.
Coop, you know what
Miss Reed told me tonight ?
She said she wants me
to be a big sports star.
Just like Joe Cooper.
-Thanks, Dude.
Go get 'em, Coop !
Hey, Coop !
When's the last time you made
a home run without La-Z-Boy ?
Al, we have seen some classic
Denslow Cup battles in the past,
but I can't remember one
that ever rivaled...
the drama and excitement
of this one.
It's off the rim !
Could be a double play.
Darcy tips.
Jantzen's try--
No.
Beers have a shot at the conversion.
Remer keeps it alive !
Last chance.
Coop up.
It's...
good !
Bob, in all my years
of calling games,
I don't think I've ever
been this excited !
You're excited ?
Feel these nipples !
Update: We still have no fucking clue
where this guy is.
I can wear anything
and I can be anything
Tonight I don't wanna
feel wonderful
feel bad
'Cause tonight will be
the night of my dreams
Tonight I don't wanna
feel anything
And then things moved in
took no time at all
Tonight I don't wanna
feel wonderful
-Hey, ho !
Hey ! Ho !
All right.
Coop, what ?
- What is it ?
- It's Reggie.
Reggie Jackson.
Well, go.
Go ahead.
- Reggie.
- Coop. Nice goin' out there.
Thanks, man.
But you know, I gotta tell you.
- It's 'cause of you that I'm here.
- That's nice to know.
I brought this for you. I saw some kid
try to leave the ballpark with it.
You gotta hang on to that.
I got the two home run balls
I hit in the World Series.
Some wretched little shit
got the third one.
That sucks, dude.
I gotta get my trophy.
Maybe we can have a hot dog sometime ?
All right, sounds good.
Hey, Coop !
I don't have
your fuckin' ball !
Good luck next year.
Oh. Thanks.
Hey, Baxter !
Got milk ?
- Oh, I'm sorry !
-
And so, on behalf of
the National BASEketball League,
we'd like to present to the Beers
this year's Denslow Cup.
Congratulations !
Go ahead,
take your victory lap.
As they skate off,
all you can think about is
a team that conquered adversity,
a team that overcame the odds,
a team that defied
the critics,
a team that blah, blah, blah,
blah, a team that, uh-
And so,
the ideal of sports once again
blossomed from a tiny seed,
nurtured, as always,
by the dreams of the young.
Yeah !
I'm the King of the World ! Yeah !
You've been psyched out
and you're goin' down
I'm the trash-talkin'
talented, no-class clown
I will abuse you
until you lose
You can go on home and pout
You've been psyched out
You talked to 20 men
Your shoe's untied
And your mama
never loved you
Mama never loved you
She said she did
but she's ugly and she lies
She's never thinkin' of you
Mama doesn't love you
You ain't cut
from the right cloth
You don't got
what it takes
Now you blew it
Oh, another stupid mistake
Another bad, bad break
You been psyched out
and you're goin' down
I'm a trash-talkin'
talented, no-class clown
I will abuse you
until you lose
You can go on home and pout
You've been psyched out
Oh, yeah
Subtitles by Captions
SOFTFAKER WAS HERE
Doorways
open up and close
More ways
to a punch line
They're all laughin'
at your clothes
Standin' in
the lunch line
You're the talk
of the town
First you're up
then you're down
It's a cycle I've found
It always comes around
But I will
still be laughin'
Yes, I will
Air raids in the afternoon
The children are playin'
Switchblades
Colored red balloons
No one hears you prayin'
And it comes back to you
all the things that you do
They'll come lookin' for you
But I will
still be laughin'
Yes, I will
Doorways lead
to other rooms
Always leave you lyin'
Face down
in a stranger's tomb
Didn't know
you were dyin'
And you rise
and you fall
And you wait
for the call
You're watchin' the walls
But I will
still be laughin'
I will
Yes, I will
still be laughin'
I will
Yes, I will
still be laughin'
I will
Laughin'
laughin', laughin'
I will
still be laughin'
Yes, I will
Laughin', laughin'
laughin', laughin'
Laughin'
Dude.