As you all know,
by the next timewe meet...
this angel is going
to be my wife.
But don't let this distract you.
Our work is not done.
Where arewe today?
Kids are killing each other
inschool playgrounds.
Half nudewomen are on every
billboard and magazine cover.
Songs have more dirty words
than clean.
Andyet I'm the one
they call crazy.
They don't know anything.
Do you know what Isay?
Drop the pills andsmokes
and come up for air.
We haven't exceeded our
humanity, we've destroyed it.
Let me remindyou, children,
that God burned Sodom.
He burned Gomorra.
If theworld doesn't want to
listen towhat I have tosay...
thenwe're headedstraight back
into the fire, all of us.
So long as you all follow me,
not us.
There are few places left where
you canstillsee thestars.
Is thiswhat you
wanted toshow me?
.Would that be enough?
.Yes, of course.
Sorry, Maxwell. You're trying to
teach me and I'm missing it.
That's not it.
That's it.
An engagement present
from me to you.
Are youserious?
That's incredible! I've always
wanted to take a cruise.
Iwanted tosurprise you.
I've made a decision, Trace.
It's timewe all got to know
the power of our crusade.
Oh, God!
It's no coincidence.
What's the matter?
You'reshaking.
You're insane.
You are insane!
You misunderstood me.
Always playing games.
Where are you?
No one runs out on me.
You know that.
I'll findyou.
Where couldyou possibly go?
Come on!
Nobody betrays me.
Remember, you're llstenlngto
Hot V egas 102.
Hlghtomorrow, 107,
2degrees hotter thantoday.
How couldyou possibly
get arrested, it's legal here.
Goodwin, freeze to that chair.
Do youwant to tell me
what the hell these are?
Looks like astack
of case reports.
They 're yours, wise ass, late
and filled out incorrectly.
They 're allsolved, aren't they?
God damn you!
This city isn't your playground.
I'm not your nursemaid to
watch after you...
so youwill fill out
these reports correctly.
Youwill get back
on thestreet...
and remember you're a cop,
not a one man disaster area.
Get ahair cut.
Morning, chief.
Where's the fun in this?
.Morning, chief.
.Morning.
.Willyou marry me?
.Very funny, uncle Roger.
Come here. Sit down.
Tell mewhere your dad is.
Let me guess, he'ssick so he
sent you here to be my partner?
.He called my mum again.
.I thought hesaid hewouldn't.
Why?
Due to the restraining order?
You know Dad can't get enough
of abad thing.
Hewanted to get back together.
Shewanted him to go to hell.
I'msorry.
.I know he's out drinking.
.Everythingwill be okay.
.I promise.
.Yeah, you and everyone else.
Hi, could ljust get awater?
Thanks.
I'm at the Sands of Time hotel.
Youwon't believewhat's here.
I II keepaneye on her
untllyou get here.
.Can I get you anything?
.No, thanks.
Oh, Christ.
.You can't do this, Kenny.
.I know.
Our shift started2 hours ago,
so you're on my time.
I've got the bad attitude and
you're thestable one, remember?
It's just one drink, Iswear.
I lost track of time.
.I called Donna again.
.Your daughter told me.
She came to thestation
looking for you.
She's a tough kid,
but she needs a f ather.
And I need apartner
so the deal is this...
Either youstop this or lose
two more people fromyour life.
I'm gonna. Iswear.
.Let's go.
.Hang on.
.Areweworking or not?
.We'reworking right now.
L.V. Police department.
Canwe have awordwith you?
.Come here.
.Stop.
It's okay, I'm apolice officer.
Are you okay?
.What's going on?
.A typical night in Vegas.
.What's your name?
.Tracy.
Call911, tell themwherewe
are and that shotswere fired.
Have themsend an ambulance.
Can't wait until the chief
hears about this.
My God!
.Let's go.
.Get out of theway.
Get out of here.
Somebody help me!
Are you crazy?
You're crazy!
This is Det.
Roger Goodwin.
Currently travelling northbound
pursuing hotelshootingsuspect.
Thissuspect is now driving
an L. V. P. D. Cruiser.
What's going on?
Chief, what asurprise.
I toldyou to
stay out of trouble.
Troubleseems to find me
wherever I go.
Hold on.
Don't cut me off.
Nice parking.
I'll tell Hacket you did it.
Get everyone ready.
He'd better not be
wasting my time.
Still no answer.
.Thank you.
Welcome to the Sands of Time
Hotel. How may I help you?
I'm looking for a guest here.
Her name is Tracy Cantra.
With pleasure.
.No one here by that name.
.Are yousure?
Yes, Sir. I am.
Well, well...
My angel appears
to have lost her wings.
.You've got a visitor.
.Here?
Says you havesomething of his.
Wouldn't take no for an answer.
Excuse me.
I expected this to be
much bigger.
We never formally met.
Det. Goodwin, Metro division.
.I'msurprised tosee you again.
.I've got more lives than a cat.
But not the guy wewere chasing.
What you reap, what yousow.
I guess you do.
This must bewhat
you came for.
Thanks, for everything.
Youwere great there.
No big deal.
I don't want to be rude but
I have to finish getting ready.
Sure.
.Good luck, detective.
.You too. Break aleg.
Can I have your phone number?
I might need astatement.
Iwouldn't have much tosay.
I only saw the floor...
and I heardsomeshots
and I dialed911, like yousaid.
.I may need to get hold of you.
.I'msorry.
I don't give out my home number.
You can reach me here.
If you don't mind,
I have to finish getting ready.
See you around.
Iwasn't drinking. Iwas taking
care of some business.
Remember what I toldyou
about lying.
Aren't Isupposed to be telling
you about that stuff?
Alongwith 1OO other
things I'm learning on my own.
I'll be home tomorrow andwe'll
spendsome time together.
.Drink, Sir?
.No thanks.
.What was that, Dad?
.Here's Roger, I've got to go.
-Let me talkto hlm.
.I love you, I gotta go.
.Dad?
.Everything all right?
.How's theshow girl?
.Weird.
Weird likesexualweird?
Weird as inwe need to hang out
here alittle longer.
Come on.
Hello.
Can I help you?
.Where am I calling?
-The Sandsof Tlme Hotel.
.Thanks.
-You're welcome.
You know what I think?
That Roger's got a crush
on theshow girl.
Maybe.
I'm tellingyou:
she's hidingsomething.
She had alook on her f ace like
awall going up.
Sheseemed toshut downwhen
I mentioned theshooter.
Cocktail, sir?
.I'm gonnahit the bathroom.
.Don't even think about it.
Now.
Everybody out.
Get down. Come on.
Everybody out!
Get out of here.
Come on, move.
Move it. Let's go.
Move out.
Now.
Run.
It's chaos out here.
Requesting multiple back up.
Multiple back up.
We need everythingyou've got.
.Rise andshine.
.Is that you, Rog?
Come on, man.
I've got you.
Let's get out of here.
Run.
Chief's right.
You're awalking disaster.
Listen up.
Iwant to know who these
people are andwho they 'rewith.
And how they got into
that building. Lets move!
Who'sshe?
She'swith the hotelshow.
Shesays one of the guy 's got away.
Tracy, her cop friend
and his partner.
What cop friend?
Good looking guy. Hesaid
his namewas Roger something.
You gottabe kidding.
Get her out of here.
Chief.
Chief Hacket, L. V. P. D.
Who am Ispeaking to?
Allyou need to know
is I'm in control.
The hotel is completely sealed.
There's noway in or out.
I have hostages lwon't
hesitate to kill.
To assume my powers are limited
is to make abig mistake.
Okay, I've got the message.
What exactly do youwant?
Time and breathing room.
When I'm done I'll leave
this town f ar behind.
Andwhat if Isay no?
I'llshow youwhich part
of no you don't understand.
Take cover.
.Any sign of her yet?
.Nothingyet.
I'mshutting the place down.
They 'vesealed the entrance.
We can't get in or out.
The front entrance's blown out.
Everybody out.
Move, move.
She's not to leave
this building, understand?
Anyone trying to help her escape
lwant dead.
It's thisway.
Hello.
Nosignal.
.What is it?
.C4.
Letsseewhat's behind door 2.
What's going on around here?
Everyone's been through
and there'sstill nosign of her.
She'sstill in the building.
Gamer, what do you have?
A bunch of empty rooms but that
only covers3O% of the hotel.
The other 7O% is about
3 millionsquare feet.
If she's out there, it could
take days to find her.
We don't have days.
What was that?
Some of the bombs
wereset on timers.
You told us to.
Weweresupposed to be
out of here by now.
Of coursewewere.
It was asimple operation.
I put my trust in you people
andyou f ailed.
Are you incapable of carrying
out my vision?
No, Maxwell.
.We'll find her.
.That's right, wewill.
Over my dead body andyours,
I'm not leavingwithout her.
Find her.
Ricky, we've had
a change of plans.
What'syour status?
Almost done.
It's gonnabe beautiful.
Good, someone I can count
on in this organization.
Listen carefully.
I needyou to do one more thing.
Allunits,
thls Isthe chlef speaklng.
We have a fullscale alert
at the Sandsof Tlme hotel.
Repeat, a fullscale alert.
I mon route, E. T.A. 10 mlns.
Have allemergency units
onstand by to recelve.
We've got a full
scale tactlcal alert.
Swat team, flreflghters,
all avallable pollce crulsers...
to the Sandsof Tlme hotel.
The structure Is burnlng.
Hostages have beentaken.
The structure Is burnlng
andthere are people Inslde.
Damn, Kenny.
.That was good bourbon.
.Good time tostop drinking.
.I'd like to diewith asmile.
.We're not dying down here.
Kenny 's right. It's over.
There's noway out.
You too...
Fine.
Then if we're all about to die,
why don't you tell uswhy?
How would I know
any more than you?
Youwere running from the first
shot so drop the act.
Who are these cowboys?
They 're not cowboys
and they 're not robbers.
Not even terrorists.
They 're his personal army
sworn to his holy war...
convinced that they 're
saviors of the modernworld.
They 'll do anything hesays.
They 'll die for him.
.The guy on the dance floor.
.Yes, Maxwell.
How do you know all this?
Because I used
to be one of them.
Great!This is getting
better and better.
Allemergency pollce andflre
units are respondlng.
The structure Is burnlng
and hostages have beentaken.
I repeat.
Hostages have beentaken.
This isn't the first time.
Two years ago he blew up
aship in San Pedro.
I remember, they never found
out whowas responsible.
Did it ever occur to you to
tellsomebody? Like the cops.
.Sowewouldn't end up here.
.Iwas running for my life.
The cops couldn't catch him
or protect me, I had no choice.
Ishould have known he'd come
back for me. Wewere engaged.
Well, that just takes the cake.
Nowonder I couldn't get
your phone number.
Your ex.boyfriend's
the Messiah.
It wasJo Lewlswho sald"you
can run but you can't hlde".
Hewas talking about
another fighter.
It took12 rounds, but he beat
the other fighter to apulp.
His opponent didn't have the
opportunity I'm givingyou.
I mthe only
way out of here.
Andyour last chance
to turnyour llfe around.
Look at the people next to you.
They 're agents of the devil.
The lies they tellyou
will damn them forever.
This is no freedom trail,
just aslow way to killyourself.
Which if you ask me is truly
the greatest sin of all.
There'sstill time.
Theworld I promised
youstill exists.
You just have to let
me take youthere.
I love you, Tracy.
I'llsee you realsoon.
Alf ateam, Icansee the hotel.
Set upa perlmeter on
the SouthWest quadrant.
Copy that.
Bravo team, I have touchdown.
Commence sweep.
I need two guys round the back
and four guys round the front.
Keep it hot.
Who does he think he is?
Moses?
And Jesus, and Manson,
and Hitler all rolled into one.
If he thinkswe're gonnawait
for him to exterminate us...
he's not the prophet
he thinks he is.
All hewants is me.
I can end this right now.
Oh no, you don't.
You're under arrest.
For accessory to that and
whatever else he does tonight.
We're takingyou out of here.
Thenwe're taking him down.
Let's go.
We've covered the basement.
There's noway out down here.
.Thenwe'll move upstairs.
.Cameras, he'dspot us.
Not if he can't see.
Like it or not,
you'restuck with me.
Thls Is Bravo dlvlslon
repeatlng alert.
Squad leader, thls Isthe chlef.
S. W.entrance Issecured.
N. W.entrance Isstlllon hold.
Leader hasenteredthe bulldlng.
Tangos have beenspotted.
Ten, four.
Tell me this isn't happening.
Gamer, lwant you
to tell me this isn't happening.
I'msorry, thewhole
building is down.
.Well, bring it up.
.It's gone off in the basement.
Not gone off.
Cut off.
Everyone to the basement
and don't let her get away.
Looking for me?
Come on.
We're playing by the rules.
Just how much time do you need?
Sorry to disappoint you.
Why are you always in the
middle of this crap?
What'dyou do to this guy?
I've got something hewants.
Have youspoken to Maxwell?
.Is that the psycho's name?
.More on that later.
Takewhat hesays to be true.
Thiswhole place iswired.
We've dodged his bombs. I hope
you've got away out of here.
We've almost cleared aservice
exit on the S. E. corner.
Iwas gonnasend the SWATteam,
but If you can make it...
I'll pump the placewith gas
and choke them.
.Fine. Wait for us.
-Don't take too long.
.We'llsee you on the outside.
.Roger that.
By the time Maxwell realizes
we're gone...
.he'll besucking teargas fumes.
.What about her?
Jenna.
Oh, my God.
What'sshe doing here?
Shewas at home.
Isaid I'd call her tomorrow.
.Not soon enough.
.Do you know this girl?
.She's my daughter.
.This is Roger.
Icansee you.
Just stay where you are.
Honey, everything's okay.
Just sit tight.
Gamer, what is going
on up there?
We need Maxwell here.
Thenwe get her and go.
Mr. Gamer can't come to phone
now, leave amessage.
Well, what do you know.
You must be the Prince Charming.
I'm just doing my job. You're the
one living in a f antasy world.
But when I've erased all the
ignorant sinners like you...
my worldwill be the only one
standing.
Assoon as you realize,
you'll do yourself a f avor.
Hand the girl over.
You bring upsome interesting
points but I'm gonnakeep her.
Jenna,
stay right there.
What do you know about these?
Everything.
Don't.
It was one of ours.
And that?
.One of theirs.
.Come on.
There.
Honey.
.Don't you hang up on me again.
.I can explain everything.
Youseem like asmart guy.
But you're outnumbered and
running out of real estate.
Guys, canwe do this later?
Dad!
.Come on.
Go, go.
Come here.
Iwas never really
good at Math. Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Take this for me.
Thanks.
.Where are you?
.I ran into aroadblock.
Several, actually.
Kenny 's daughter'swith us.
-What?
.It's alongstory.
.We're not gonnamake it to you.
.I knew you'dsay that.
Team's on theway. We'll pick
you up at the front entrance.
There's a ventilationshaft
to the roof in the ballroom.
It's probably not booby trapped.
Chopper us out from there.
Isaid meet upwith
S. W. A. T. team.
-lcan get usout of here.
.God damn it, that's an order.
And lexpect youto follow it.
Now move out.
Quit whining.
.Isn't sorry enough?
.Talk is cheap, Dad.
.Hey!
.Sorry.
Thisway. Come on.
Let's go.
How many llvesdo you
have to ruln, Tracy?
Youwalk out with me
and everyone llves.
No disrespect, but isshe
worth all this?
Loosing f aith in my direction?
.No ljust mean...
.Maybewe don't need her.
Maybewe don't needyou.
Mention her again and Iswear...
Come on.
Tracy, listen to me carefully.
Iwant you here now.
.Were you really engaged to him?
.Iwas young and he talkswell.
Wewere gonna
change theworld.
.How didyou end up in Vegas?
.It's the last place he'd look.
I could alwayssing.
Learn a few dance moves.
Show girlTracy.
You could have picked Paris.
Meet any threat with
extreme prejudlce.
-Rendezvous level1.
-Afflrmatlve.
.What's going on up there?
.We're taking fire.
Get up!
Let's go out of here.
It appearssomeone didn't pay
attention to my instructions.
Bravo, thls Isteam leader.
Do you read me?
Bravo squad,
do you read me?
Talkto me.
What's golngonthere?
Talk to me.
.Ricky, thesecond project.
.Everything's ready to go.
Welldone.
Your men are dead.
Dldyouthlnkyou'd get away
with astunt llke that?
I gave you my word...
but people don't trust
each other nowadays.
Didyou think I'dsit on my ass
and do nothing?
You're apolice officer.
In this twistedsociety...
you get aspecial achievement
award for perverting justice...
andstanding in theway
of decent human evolution.
In case youshowedyour true
colors I arranged abackup plan.
.What are you talking about?
.Youwon't get away with this.
To assume my powers are limited
would be making abig mistake.
I'm gonna teach everybody
in this town another lesson.
The Buddhistssay we don't die.
We just cycle around.
Each life leading into the next.
Gathering knowledge.
So for allthose
about to passon...
weshouldn't think
of it as an ending.
It's like I'm giving them
aseminar on life.
Thls Is Alrborn 1, suspect has
just blownupthe overpass.
RepeatlSuspect has blownup
the entlre overpass.
What's going on out there?
He blew up the overpass.
It's aslaughter house.
.He blew the overpass!
.I'm giving himwhat hewants.
You don't understand.
This is all because of me.
Iwon't let anyone get hurt.
If we give in now,
he'll never stop.
Trust me on this.
Let's take one more chance.
.Can you get ahelicopter?
.I'm calling theshots not you.
I can get us out of here.
Don't give up on us.
Okay.
Be there and I'll pick you up.
.Are yousure this is theway?
.Positive, right through here.
Everybody be careful.
Eyes open.
Damn, that was close.
.I could use a drink.
.Dad!
He's just kidding.
I think.
Let's get moving!
Back up!
Let's clear theway.
Bring the ambulance in.
Herewe go.
We need help on thisside.
.Where is everybody?
.Coming up right now.
Stop.
Thisway.
.Chief!
.Over thisway.
Get down.
That's the part of"no"
you didn't understand.
Stay here.
She can't killyou.
Shewon't shoot.
It looks like you're running
out of believers.
Why don't you pack up
the arc and float away?
The flood is coming.
Right now.
Iwon't let you leave, Tracy.
You better believe that.
I'm gettingsick of this guy.
Run, Maxwell.
Come on, Jenna.
Is he alright?
Is he alright, Roger?
Out.
In all his life time, Van Gogh
only sold one painting.
Galileowas jailed...
for saying that the earth
revolved around thesun.
I don't have to tellyouwhat
they did to Christ.
Why Issoclety
so afrald of greatness?
Why does it turn its back
on the ones it needsthe most?
Inthe endthese great men
are alwayssanctlfled.
But they always
have to dle flrst.
I'veset every bomb
to go off in ten minutes.
That'senoughto brlngthls
place down before you get out.
It'senoughtlme for youto
declde If I get to be ahero...
or dowe all go out
as martyrs.
Go!
.We canstill get out.
.We'll never make it.
.Kenny, you can disarm it.
.Not in 1O mins.
Let's just wait
for him to kill us.
There is oneway.
Turningyourself over
is not the answer.
What if he just thinks I am?
What? Like a trap?
Like one last roll of the dice.
We are in Vegas.
Fine.
Let's go for it.
Okay, how dowe do this?
Tracy?
It's me.
Are youwilling to take me back
as if my thoughtswere your own?
Yes, Maxwell.
.Then come back to me.
.Meet me in the Kings chambers.
.Yousure youwant to do this?
.Moresure than I've ever been.
Keep his attention.
All I need is one goodshot.
Listen to me.
Youstay right here.
Promise me.
Promise me you'llstay here.
You two continue
to be a thorn in my side.
.What dowe have here?
.I'm Jenna.
Jenna's apretty name.
It's good to have an extra ace.
Tracy, you dlsappolnted me.
What are they dolngto you?
Daddy...
-Daddyl
.How did he find her?
.He's gonna get you.
.Be a good girl and come along.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
The King's chamber, Tracy.
You bastard!
Isn't it beautiful
when you cansee the light?
Let her go.
I'm comingwith you.
The Building issurrounded.
The police arewaiting for you.
.Andwait they will.
.Are you okay?
We're gonnaslip out
right under their noses.
The basement.
I missedyou.
Come on.
Let's go.
Are you alright?
Are you okay?
Let's go.
Maxwell, yousick freak!
Let's go! Let's go!
Time to go.
.Damn it!Where isshe?
.King's chambers.
Oh, honey.
.Did he hurt you?
.I'm okay, but he took Tracy.
.Where did they go?
.They 're headed to the basement.
Hesaid the hotel is
going to blow.
Not with us in it.
Let's play find the cult leader.
Come on.
Through here.
.What?
.A bomb!
.Leave it for the bombsquad.
.It's motion activated.
Can you do this?
Dad!
Let him go.
We're running out of time.
.Let's go.
.Come on, let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Listen up, everybody.
Today we lost one of the best
cops this city has ever known.
So this city isshut down until
we find the guy who did it.
Nothing moves in the air or on
the ground until Maxwell's ours.
Let's do this, people.
.You okay?
.I'm okay.
This is it, I've done enough
damage for one life time.
I'm glad to hear you
say that.
Thls Is aspeclal
news announcement.
Emergency crews are cleanlngup
the Sandsof Tlme hotel.
Pollce are stlll looklng
for the malnsuspect...
aradlcalcult leader
knownonly as Maxwell.
He Is bellevedto be
Inthe area.
He's armed and may stlll have
one of the hostages.
Where arewe going?
You'llsee.
Thls Is Alrborn 2.
we're tracklng asuspect.
Drlver and passenger
matchthe report.
Headlngwest on 75.
.Shit.
.The Hoover dam.
.I'm going after this guy.
.Your not doing this alone.
Stay here andstart
the evacuation.
Get me the governor's office.
Thlsthe L. V.P.D.requestlng
acode red.
Evacuatlonof the dam.
Repeat, thls Is acode red.
Thls Is not adrlll.
Command acknowledgescode
red, fullevacuatlon Isunderway.
The perlmeter Issealed off.
All roads are closed.
Upwe come.
It's like being
on top of theworld.
Please, I'll do
whatever youwant.
Thisway.
Get me asclose
to the dam asyou can.
2cllcksover thls rldge.
Right thisway.
Let's go.
There's nothing to bescared of.
Isavedyou once fromyourself
and I can do it again.
Assoon aswe blow the dam.
Yousaid allyouwanted
was for me to comewith you.
Purified.
I'm purifying the future.
What'syour status?
The tourlsts are belngevacuated
but no slgnof Maxwell.
.Finish up this barricade.
.Let's get this rigged up.
Let's go.
.Oh, man.
.Look what he's doing.
.You don't know when to give up.
.I'm no good at taking orders.
A Greek warrior oncesaid...
Sometimes from the
worst fortune...
you can create astroke of luck.
That'swhere you come in.
You make the prize
moreworth it.
Are you okay?
Oh my God!
Look.
He's dead.
It's all over.
Come on.
Feel me, Tracy.
.Run.
.Oh, my God!
168 people have perlshed
Inthe flood.
But due to the f ast actlon
of Det.McDanlels...
Way to go, hero.
.I can't wait for career day.
.Why is that?
So I canshow my dad off
to thewholeschool.
What's next?
Record aNo. 1hit in L. A?
The only number I'm gonna
record is yours.
Sorry,
I can't give out my home number.
.Really?
.Really.
Give me your hand.
Not here.