Slow down, slow down.
Move it back up.
- Here we go.
- They're drivin' me crazy!
- Don't go too fast.
- Come on!
- What's the matter?
- You threw the cage on my foot!
- I didn't do that.
- Yes, you did.
I need puppies.
- Okay. All right. Come on.
- Puppies.
Hi there.
Isn't that the sweetest?
- He's cool. Yeah.
- He likes us.
What a cute guy.
Isn't he cute?
Hi, puppy.
No, absolutely not.
Well, how big's
he gonna be?
- St. Bernards get to be 150 pounds.
- I got a junkyard.
I need a big, mean
junkyard dog.
Let me see him.
Come here, puppy.
He looks good and mean.
I don't know. He's pretty sweet.
You can make
any dog mean.
Hey!
Damn little beast!
God!
You got any pit bulls?
Come on. It's a pushover.
I cased the place.
What about the cops?
Video surveillance?
You're crazy if you're gonna
just walk up like this.
What about the alarm?
All you gotta do
is step over.
- I got you.
- Okay, okay.
There, you see?
In and out, quiet as a mouse.
Get some dogs.
Come on, puppy.
We're just goin' for a little car ride.
Look at the wee, little ones.
Come here, little puppies.
Here we go.
Come on, puppy.
Here puppy, nice puppy.
I've stepped in the beam.
Here, puppy, nice puppy.
See, didn't I tell ya?
Doesn't this beat takin'
strays off the street?
- You are a genius!
- Get off!
Sorry! I'm sorry.
I'm just a little bit excited.
That's my very first felony.
I've committed a lot of misdemeanors,
but that was my first felony.
Why are they barking?
They're dogs.
I know they're dogs!
Go in the back and check.
Okay, doggies,
what's the racket back...
Hey!
Okay, doggies,
back in your house.
Back in your house.
Here, doggie, nice doggie.
No, doggie.
Don't jump.
Bad dog!
Good puppy!
Bad puppy, don't jump!
Good puppy, don't jump!
Come back!
Stop the van!
Harv, what is it?
Why did you want me to stop?
Hurry, they're gettin' away.
Hey, you, come back here!
Come here!
I'll give you a bone!
Come back here,
you little runt!
Come here, you!
7:00 a.m.
Up and at 'em!
Ted, I'm sorry.
Mmm. What's wrong?
Did you have another nightmare?
Yeah.
Mom, it's Saturday and it's 7:02.
Do we really have to get up?
Yep, you heard
your father.
I know, Daddy's rules.
That's it! I'm not
gonna take it anymore.
Mom, I have a news flash.
It's Saturday!
- Yeah, I know, honey.
- This sucks!
Why do we have to get up
so early on a Saturday?
Ask your father.
Don't say "sucks."
The bathroom's mine!
- Nanny, nanny!
- Shut up! Let me in.
Open up, you little wimp!
Let me in!
- Mom! Let me in!
- You have no bladder control.
Wait 'til I get my hands on you.
Let me in!
A puppy!
Hi!
Guys, do you have to...
I dreamt I had a puppy,
and it came true!
Honey.
I take back everything I said
about you being cold and insensitive.
Dad...
I take back anything
I said too.
Dad, I have everything
I ever wanted.
- I owe you big time.
- Why?
Daddy, can we
call him Fred?
- Let me have him. It's my turn.
- No, it's my turn!
- I saw him first!
- I'm gonna have him for 5 more minutes.
We can't have a dog.
We can't have a dog!
You can't show a child a puppy,
then take it away two minutes later.
I didn't show a child a puppy.
It's obviously lost.
- Occupy the kids. I'll run to the pound.
- No, no way!
- It'll be destroyed.
- If we keep it, the house will be!
- Millions of people have dogs.
- Not people like me.
Dogs sniff.
They lick, chew.
They drool, scratch...
- Alice, they have parasites.
- Oh, God, yeah.
The kids'll lose interest.
It'll grow to be enormous.
It'll take over the yard.
When the dog finally
settles down, it'll die.
Everybody will be upset. We'll have
to get another puppy and start all over.
- Do you understand?
- No. Could you be more specific?
- Alice, I need a little support.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
All right.
How shall we handle this?
Go tell the kids.
- Come on.
- Come over here.
He loves me the most.
- Hi, kids.
- Hi, Dad.
- Can he sleep in my room?
- No, in my room.
- He's sleeping in my room.
- He's not sleeping in anyone's room.
Listen to me a minute.
We are people people here.
We are goldfish people.
We're ant farm people.
We're not dog people.
Dad, why can't you
just give us a chance?
You're always saying
we have to have responsibility.
That's true.
It's my decision.
I mean, I've decided.
I knew it!
Think of something
to name him.
When he destroys my house,
I wanna know what to call him!
- Thank you.
- This is temporary.
This is temporary
until we find the owner.
Okay, the dog's name
will be...
What is it?
- What's his name gonna be?
- You can't change it. That's the rules.
Okay. Emily?
Did you do your name
in a crayon?
Well, I don't think words
for parts of the body make good names.
But he's got one of those.
I looked.
I'm sure he does,
but I don't think Daddy...
wants to stand on the front porch
at night yelling that out.
But that's what
you call Uncle Richard.
Okay, the dog's
name will be...
You asked for my input.
- What?
- Nothing. Let's just call him Rover.
- Mom, please, M.C. Hammer.
- Ultimate Warrior.
M.C. Hammer?
No, no, Rover.
He doesn't like
any of those names.
- Right! Like you can read his mind!
- Ryce!
Emily, what does the dog
want his name to be?
This is ridiculous! It's a dog.
He doesn't have preferences!
- Call him Ding Dong. He wouldn't know.
- Yes, he would!
He'll tell us what
he wants to be called.
Beethoven.
Roll over.
Come on, boy. Roll over.
You!
No, no, no!
If this business is gonna
grow, we need more money.
They're talking about twenty-five.
That's not gonna do me any good.
They said, "No?"
I said, "No."
If this is gonna take off,
I need some capital, not a Band-Aid.
"What kind of figures
are we talking about?"
I said, "A hundred and fifty sounds
like a good neighborhood to me."
- Did you really say that?
- Yeah. This is a business.
Advertising, signs, ;
but I'm optimistic.
- Ted, get down here.
- Where's my shoes?
- I don't know, honey, just backtrack.
- Mom, please?
Look behind
the bathroom door.
- Daddy?
- What?
He wants you to
scratch his head.
Uh, you know...
I don't wanna scratch his head.
Back off, back off!
But he wants you to.
Sometimes we don't get what we want.
That's not the way the world works.
If I don't get this deal,
I'll kill myself!
Honey, don't talk like that
in front of the kids.
If I can just get them to smell
the stuff. Air fresheners are visceral...
- Dad, I got a great idea.
- What?
Can I have karate lessons?
I didn't get any bacon.
What do you want karate lessons for?
Brenda's littler than me,
and she's got a green belt.
Why don't we skip the lessons
and get you the belt?
No! Come on!
He slimed me!
He slobbed! Look at this!
Don't worry about it.
I've got dog drool
on my pants!
I can't meet with Vanguard Capital
with dog drool on my pants!
- Just change your pants.
- I'm gonna change my pants.
I had a schedule and now it's gone.
I'll never have that again!
- Just change, George.
- I'm gonna change my pants.
If I change my pants,
I gotta change my jacket.
If I change my jacket,
I change my shirt.
If I change my shirt,
I change my tie.
I have to change
my belt, shoes, socks.
Just change your pants, George.
I don't need you to
drool all over me, for God sakes!
You're so smart!
What am I telling you about?
Listen to me!
Bye, honey.
Sorry.
Good luck.
A little Kleenex
or something.
Hi, puppy.
Thirsty, huh?
Easy, buddy.
Save some for the fishes.
Look at Tom.
He's wide open. Shoot it!
Put it up.
Put it up!
- This guy's all over me.
- Shoot it.
Yeah!
All right, that's it. Hit the showers.
Give me ten.
Let's go, hustle.
Hi, Mark.
- You're sweaty.
- You like it?
Air fresheners are the fastest-growing
area in household hygiene.
Fascinating!
All of these use a two-dip process
that guarantees a longer smell life.
Smell this.
That smell nice?
If we get the right amount of capital,
we can take this place to the top.
I don't just mean successful,
I mean, dominant.
Here's a favorite.
Look at this.
- New leather.
- Oh, that's cute.
- I could use that in my Beemer.
- I could use it in my Beemer!
A lot of people
could use 'em.
I wouldn't want to hang it from
my rearview mirror... Tacky!
No, there's velcro
on the back.
People hide them.
A lot put it under their dashboard.
Ingenious!
Bravo, Newton. Kudos.
Thank you.
- Let's get Ted.
- Hey!
Hey, Teddy boy.
That's a nice lunch you got there.
- A veritable nutrition lesson.
- Oh, yeah.
Don't forget to wash it down
with a big glass of milk.
Oh, man!
See ya on the bus.
Hi! Miss Simpkins
made me stay after.
Want a Twinkie?
Hold on a minute.
Good boy.
See over there?
That's Donna Ditsworth.
She's the most popular girl
in the whole school.
Her hair is perfect.
Her teeth are perfect.
Even Mark thinks she's perfect.
Beethoven!
Hey, check out Fido.
- What a cool-lookin'dog.
- I bet you wanna play fetch.
You gotta give me the stick,
if you want me to throw it.
Hey, where we going?
- Cool dog.
Is he yours?
- What's his name?
- Beethoven.
- Wow. Hi, Beethoven.
- Hey, Beethoven.
Cool dog. Good boy.
Well, see you later, Ryce.
Yes! He knows my name!
He knows my name.
No question about it. You've built
yourself something impressive.
Thank you very much.
- That mean you're interested?
- Absolutely.
We've smelled
a lot of stuff.
I speak for myself as well as
the "Brie Meister" when I say...
yours smells the best.
That's great.
Thanks a lot.
We're gonna crunch
some numbers.
- Maybe we can get together later.
- That would be great.
- We're looking forward to it.
- I'll get it.
- Thank you.
- Ciao.
- Ciao, George.
- Ciao bello.
- Ciao!
Ciao.
How ya doin', Theodore?
- Nice backpack, Teddy!
- Can I see it?
Oh... woops!
Sorry!
Why do you guys
always pick on me?
'Cause you're a
little four-eyed dork.
Give them back!
They're mine.
Where you going, Teddy?
Wait up, Theodore.
We wanna walk you home.
What are you?
A chicken?
- Come on.
- Scaredy-cat!
Scared?
Come on, fight me.
- Now he can't even see.
- Blind as a bat!
What's going on here?
He looks mean!
Yeah.
- Give him the glasses.
- Sorry.
And don't come back!
I know it doesn't mean
that he likes me.
But he's gotta like me
better than before he said my name.
You think he could
like me, Beethoven?
I know you like me.
Good night, sweetheart.
You, out!
Good night, Beethoven.
- Good night, honey.
- Good night, Dad.
Mark.
All right!
You, in here!
You sleep in here.
I sleep there. You...
See, that's very nice.
That's progress. I appreciate that.
Good night.
Ever since you started
looking for investors you seem...
- You wanted us to expand.
- I want you to be happy.
You even said you'd
come back to work.
I said I'd give you
one wish for your birthday.
Well, I wish you'd
come back to work.
There's other things
that are important.
I like being home
when the kids get home.
I don't want them to
come home to some stranger.
We'll get a great sitter, somebody
reliable that the kids'll just love.
In the 3rd occurrence this month.
We've seen a 500% increase in
the reported incidence of stolen pets.
Police believe an animal
kidnapping ring is at work.
That's "News Break."
Back to "The Wolfman."
- Did you hear something?
- No.
I heard something downstairs.
You were right.
The TVwas on.
I don't know.
I hope I'm doing the right thing.
It feels like a good idea
to expand...
but I don't want to do it
at everybody's expense.
We have to get somebody wonderful
to take care of the kids.
There's no question
about that.
It's hard to know
what the right thing is.
No matter how many
showers I take...
I still smell Beethoven
all over me.
Are you okay?
You're so quiet.
You're not mad at me,
are you?
Oh, baby!
Oh, baby, it's not even
Saturday night.
Oh, Alice, you
drive me crazy.
Oh, has Daddy's little girl
been naughty tonight?
George?
Who you talking to?
How dare you!
Are you crazy?
Did you think you were
gonna get away with it?
Ohh... that's
how you do it!
I'll put a stop to that.
You've ruined my life,
my furniture, my clothes!
My family likes you
more than they like me.
Why? All you do
is drool and shed.
You're never getting out
of there again. Never!
Do we understand each other?
Do we...
Hey, little buddy.
How ya doin'?
Thank you.
Good work.
- Vernon!
- Come on, Harvey.
- Can I tell you something?
- What?
I don't like it
when you tease the dogs.
Are you some kind
of animal lover?
We've developed
a new type of ammunition.
It explodes on contact.
We'd like you to use this
revolver for the tests.
We want to know the extent
of the damage at close range.
You wanna know
how messy it is.
I presume you can get dogs
with big skulls for the tests.
Newfoundlands,
Great Danes, St. Bernards.
Large dogs are
difficult to come by...
harder to manage.
I'm sure we'll
be able to handle it.
- Mr. Newton?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Varnick.
This must be Beethoven.
He's a magnificent animal.
Magnificent!
Magnificent, ahh!
- In for his shots?
- That's right.
He'll be a little groggy
this evening.
That'll be nice.
You should leave him
overnight for observation.
- I'd be happy to.
- Dad!
It's just a shot.
He'll be okay.
Let's take him home.
He's scared and wants to go home.
Mr. Newton, I wonder if I might
have a word with you privately.
Sure.
Good dog.
Take good care of
these nice people.
They aren't gonna
hurt Beethoven, are they?
Nothing could hurt Beethoven.
Please, sit down.
Mr. Newton, have you...
Have you noticed anything strange
about your dog lately?
You know, I mean, he's...
He's destroyed my life.
I wish I was kidding.
That's very funny. St. Bernards
have been heavily over-bred.
There's been quite a bit written
about behavioral problems.
- What kind of problems?
- Well...
I've had to put down several
over the past months.
They have a tendency
to turn on people...
attack without
provocation.
I only mention this
because you have children.
Good boy!
George, come on.
Beethoven isn't even remotely dangerous.
He'd never hurt the kids.
He might take a bite
out of you, though.
First snarl, first any kind
of weirdness, and he's gone.
Weirdness? What should I watch for,
his wearing my clothes?
Good boy!
You guys are
gonna love Devonia.
I don't need a baby-sitter.
How come you gotta go back to work?
There's no point of us
going into this with a bad attitude.
Hi there,
you little cutie!
Don't you worry
about a thing.
We're gonna get along great.
Right, kids?
I'll be back before dinner,
so it's not that long.
We're gonna do neat stuff.
I was hopin' we could
sing a tune together. You like music?
What kind of music?
How about Herb Alpert
and the Tijuana Brass? Oh, sorry.
I am a nut for
the disco beat!
Okay, kids, be good.
- You've had some time to think and...
- And we made our decision.
We wanna get in bed with
Newton Auto Air Fresheners.
Excellent!
That's just great!
- Thank you very much.
- As quickly as possible.
We meet our lawyers today
and have the papers drawn up.
That's excellent!
Let us take you
out to dinner.
Are there any good restaurants
in this burgh?
Ah... restaurants.
Uh, what?
- Why don't you come to our house?
- We'll barbecue.
Barbecue!
Let's live dangerously!
Well, our food may not be great,
but it's not dangerous.
I hope it's better
than this espresso.
Lady Marmalade
down in old New Orleans
Struttin'her stuff
on the street
She said, Hello, BigJoe
You want to give it a go
Gitchy, gitchy
Ya-ya, da-da
Soul sister
Go, sister
Hey, sister, go, sister
Soul sister, go, sister
Make Marmalade
down in old New Orleans
Help!
Help, somebody!
I love you too.
Thanks, Beethoven.
You saved my life.
But you better go home now.
Mom said to stay in the backyard.
You kids might be interested
to know that I am a performer...
Saturday nights
at the Padded Zebra.
Oh, my gosh!
Emily's in the pool!
The pool?
- Emily!
- What are you doing in the pool?
Get out this instant.
You want to get me into trouble?
- Emily, are you all right?
- I fell in.
Oh, Emily,
you must've been so scared!
I thought
I was gonna die.
Oh, you poor little thing.
Now, you were never
in any real danger, were you?
We don't want you to get into trouble,
so we'll let this be our little secret.
I'd like to call
my mother, please.
- Your mother?
- Immediately.
She must've snuck out while
I was watching Ted and Ryce.
It was hot out, so I guess
she wanted to take a little swim.
And where were you while
all this was happening?
Where I was supposed to be,
inside watching the other two.
If Emily had stayed where I put her,
none of this would've happened.
If you ask me, what these children need
is a little discipline.
What these children need
is their mother.
You're fired.
- Honey, it was an accident.
- So what?
We can't throw out having a baby-sitter
because we had a bad one.
We'll find somebody responsible
to look after the kids.
- Over my dead body.
- Oh, come on.
We're fine on our own.
You don't have to entertain us.
Do you have any kids?
We have a career.
Big one.
Excuse us.
- Brats.
- Monsters.
If we pull this off...
in six months we will own
Newton Auto Air Fresheners.
Touch it.
Sorry for the delay.
- We, we, we...
- No problem.
- Vegetables. Here you go.
- Look at that.
- Here's the paperwork, Giorgio.
- I've got my own chair, honey.
- Look at that.
- You gonna do that now, honey?
Alicia.
- Alice.
I'm sorry. Alice.
Could I have a refill, please?
Sure.
Thank you.
Just right down
at the bottom, George.
This is everything we've discussed?
Oh, yes, exactly.
Right at the bottom you can sign.
Hon, don't sign that now. Why don't
we have a little something to eat?
- You can read it over...
- Alice, tell me about your dog.
Well, he's a dog.
He sure is!
Hello, cutesy-ootsy.
- He's a St. Bernard.
- He's a purebred St. Bernard, isn't he?
Hello. Oh, look at that big old tongue!
Yes!
Look at that.
Come here. Oh, yeah.
You wanna come
with Mommy and Daddy? Yes, you do.
Oh, come on.
We'll come to Mommy and Daddy.
Come on. Come on!
I just love these
big, dumb animals.
I bet you do.
Dogs obey so much better
than children, don't they?
Come here.
Oh, look, cutesy-ootsy-oogy.
Oh, Mama just loves
this great big doggie-woggie.
The places for you to sign...
are marked by that
blue clip right there.
These are all
standard stuff?
You sure you wanna
"signee-wignee" right now?
Oh!
Alice, I'm sorry.
I've got that. I don't
want you to break a nail.
Right down there where
the blue arrow is.
Right there, George.
Honey, you sit.
I've got this.
You guys don't seem
to have made a good impression.
I'm crushed.
- Me too.
- I'll cry all night.
I don't like 'em either. But these
people are important to Dad's business.
I hope Beethoven slimes
that lady's dress.
If you don't want our capital...
we could find another
investment somewhere else.
- Sure!
- No, no, no, no.
- Beethoven, down, down.
- Is there some problem?
- No, no.
- Did I miss anything?
No. Giorgio has gone over
all the papers...
and he's about to sign.
Just standard stuff,
really.
Will you get outta here,
you mutt?
I pitched in college.
Beethoven, stop!
Bad dog!
Sit! Stop! Stay!
No!
Beethoven!
I really don't like our dog.
I really don't like those people.
I don't trust them.
I don't want their money.
I know my opinion
doesn't matter, but...
I'm not interested
in expanding.
If I had been home instead of
helping you impress those morons...
Emily wouldn't have
fallen in the pool.
And I'm not reentering
the workforce, George.
You're gonna have
to do this on your own.
And you will.
Somehow you'll make
your fortune.
And tucked away behind you deep
in the shadows will be me and the kids.
That's how you see me.
Suddenly I'm a lousy
husband and father.
Everything was fine
until Beethoven came into our lives.
I've tried to be patient,
but I've had it.
The dog has to go.
I'm proud of Beethoven.
Those two idiots insulted your kids,
treated me like dirt.
He was the only one who had the nerve
to give them the ride they deserved.
I'm going to bed.
My dream's going down the drain,
and you're worried about a dog.
Your family's going down the drain,
and you're worried about a dream.
Oh, hush.
Why do we gotta be so quiet?
You're a big boy!
- Sit down.
- We made you breakfast, Dad.
- Scrambled eggs the way you like them.
- I fed Beethoven.
We washed him too.
You should smell him.
I'm gonna walk Beethoven
every day.
We divided up the dog chores. You won't
have to do anything for Beethoven.
I see.
Is there anything else you need?
Anything else at all?
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
I dropped part of
an eggshell in there.
Chew carefully, Dad.
Okay, fine. Great, Ryce.
I'm gonna get that thing.
- That leaf's mine.
- I get the next one!
Okay, fine.
Get that question box.
Give me five.
Shake.
Mrs. Newton.
- Yes.
- I'm Dr. Varnick, the veterinarian.
I'm sorry to trouble you...
but I wonder
if I might come in?
Well, sure.
Come on in.
With animals
as large as yours...
I like to do a follow-up on rabies shots
just to see how he's doing.
- It's nice of you to come down here.
- No trouble at all.
- Here you go.
- Thank you. I'll only be a moment.
Would you like a lemonade?
- Oh, no, I'll be fine. Thank you.
- All right.
Well, Beethoven,
how are you doing? Huh?
Lookin'good.
Beethoven, this
is gonna hurt you...
a lot more than
it hurts me.
But it's a great
benefit to mankind.
Put some of this here.
- I'm gonna get those bones.
- No, I get some!
You get the next.
Okay, that'll do ya.
All right now.
- No!
- Emily, what's the matter?
Come on,
you big stupid mutt!
Help! Help!
George!
Oh, my God!
Help, somebody!
Help!
Good boy. Good boy!
Beethoven! Beethoven!
- No!
- Get off him.
Beethoven!
Beethoven.
Oh, my gosh, Beethoven!
- Why'd he do that?
- My gosh, look what he did!
- Are you all right?
- Well, I don't know.
- What happened?
- He just lunged at me!
That's not true.
I saw you hit Beethoven.
- Emily, please.
- Why would I? I patted him on the head.
It's possible that
from a distance the child...
Liar!
- Emily!
- I'm sorry. Everything's all right.
It's very natural the child
would want to defend her dog.
- Let's call an ambulance.
- No, no. I'll take care of it.
I'll take care
of this myself.
I'm terribly sorry.
He's never done anything
like this before.
Once an animal crosses the line
and attacks a human being...
you can rest assured
he'll do it again.
Of course, next time
it could be one of your children.
I'm very, very sorry.
Let me help.
Mr. Newton, we have
a real problem here.
The law is very clear when
it comes to dealing with this.
Unless you bring the animal
to my office immediately...
I'm afraid I'll be forced
to press charges.
I'm, I'm so sorry.
I don't want anything
to happen to Beethoven.
Dad won't believe us
'cause he hates Beethoven.
He's always
hated Beethoven.
Dad has Beethoven!
Wait, wait!
Stop!
Stop! Daddy!
Wait! Wait!
My dad had to take our dog
to the vet to be put down.
I hated him for it.
Now I'm doing it myself.
I know you won't believe me,
but I don't wanna do this.
You understand.
It's not your fault.
- Mr. Newton.
- Dr. Varnick.
I know that you're doing
the right thing.
I hope so.
Follow me.
Come on. Come on.
How is your arm?
Oh, it's fine, fine.
- 37 stitches.
- I'm so sorry.
Do you want the collar
and tags?
- Some people like to keep them.
- Yeah.
Do you mind?
I have the bad wing.
Come here.
I'm sorry.
You were my dog too.
Sad state of affairs.
Come on, boy. Come on.
Come on, boy.
In you go.
There you go.
All right.
Magnificent.
George Newton.
We're gonna have to charge you
for a day's boarding...
becauseJimmy, who handles the
lethal injections and disposals...
he doesn't work today so we're gonna
have to hold the dog overnight.
Should we bill you?
Dog killer!
- Nice dog, huh, Doc?
- He's perfect for the animal experiment.
Get everything ready.
I'll be by in the morning.
We'll do the test
on him first thing.
All right.
Nice doggie, good doggie.
Okay, close the door.
I've got him.
Come on!
Good doggie. Come here, doggie.
- Okay, I got him.
- Good, good.
- I got him. Come on, doggie.
- Not you! The dog!
Put him in.
Okay, you got him?
In the cage. Get in.
Shut up!
There.
Doc will work on him
first thing in the morning...
and then he's
one dead puppy.
Can we eat?
- Yeah. You hungry?
- Yeah. I'm hungry.
- What do you feel like?
- A chef's salad.
Did I do the wrong thing?
I don't know, honey.
Beethoven made
this house real.
He put the dents in it.
I know he slobbered,
and he smelled bad, but he loved us.
Even you.
I just hope your motives
were pure...
and you did this for
the safety of the kids.
Because I really hate to think
we sold Beethoven down the river...
for a piece of carpet
or a chance to sell more air freshener.
It had nothing to do with carpet
or air freshener. You saw what he did.
I know. But we don't
know why he did it.
Maybe the vet didn't hit him, but maybe
he handled him too rough or something.
Emily's really
sticking to this.
Have we ever known her to attack
an adult and accuse them of lying?
No, but why would
a vet say that?
Instead of listening to some guy
we've met only twice...
maybe we should try
listening to our own child.
Honey, something doesn't make sense.
Can't we talk to him?
Oh, what do you
want me to do?
Dr. Varnick, are you sure
you didn't hit our dog?
Yes, Mr. Newton,
I just remembered I did hit your dog.
- Come on!
- It'd make me feel better. Let's go.
- I'm coming with you.
- So am I.
We're all going
with you.
I'm terribly sorry.
- We want our dog back!
- Where's Beethoven?
- Kids, let Daddy handle this.
- What can I do for you?
- We want our dog back!
- I'm terribly sorry.
It's too late.
The dog's been destroyed.
- Dad?
- Now, wait a minute.
I was told this
wouldn't happen until tomorrow.
- I don't believe you!
- Hey, hey, hey!
Take your hands off her!
What are you...
I told you
he was lying.
What the hell
are you trying to pull?
You can't come in here.
This is private property.
Beethoven?
- He's not here.
- Hold it right there.
You have no right to be in here.
Out, all of you.
Where's my dog?
I don't have to answer
your questions.
You ordered that dog destroyed,
and it was done. Now get out.
You hit me, I'll have you put
in jail for assault and battery.
- Whoa!
- Dad!
- Honey!
- That was amazing.
Dad, you were awesome.
- You were really cool.
- I never found you more attractive.
I may need an X ray.
- He said our dog bit him.
- But he didn't really. Tell him.
There were no bite marks
on his arm!
"So what?"
What do you mean?
I'd like to file
a report on you!
What? They're not
going to help us?
- Not this year.
- Dad?
- Look.
- Dr. Varnick.
Let's follow him.
Maybe he'll lead us
to Beethoven.
Hold your door.
Shut it.
Dad, haven't you ever followed anyone?
Turn off your lights.
- I think that's the last of it.
- Start getting the dogs.
The dogs?
Yeah! He said we gotta
destroy all the evidence.
I'm gonna check this out.
It's 9:30.
If I'm not back
in 15 minutes...
call the police.
Don't come in after me.
Before you
destroy the dogs...
bring me the St. Bernard
for the ammo test.
Okay.
And bring me a little one
for this chemical test.
Sure.
I know just the one.
Hurry up.
Latch.
Congratulations.
You're gonna be a pioneer.
- Like Davy Crockett, right?
- Right.
Good doggie!
Oh, no! No, no!
I'm saving you.
I'm saving you!
He pushed me on the ground,
and I couldn't get up.
Emily, come on.
Here, Ryce, take her.
Lock the doors.
If I'm not back in 15...
- I'll be back.
- Lock the doors. Lock that one.
Nice doggie.
We're gonna have a field test
with this new ammo.
So long.
You're a very foolish man,
Mr. Newton.
You should've left
well enough alone.
- That was a gun!
- Daddy!
- Mom, get over here!
- There's no time!
I don't know where.
It's a big thing, a warehouse!
- Buckle up.
- You can't drive.
You don't have a license!
- We're going in!
- What are you doing?
I don't know.
It's a...
Ted! Ted!
Ya-hoo!
- Cool.
- Dad!
Dad!
Oh, my babies!
Are you all right?
- Beethoven!
- I love this dog. What a good doggie!
- George!
George!
Oh, my God!
Be careful!
- Is everyone alive?
- Oh, yeah. Where were you?
I was shopping, George!
I called the police.
- I jumped. I fell on the guys.
- You're kidding?
- You let Ted drive through the door!
- I didn't let him drive!
- Don't yell at me!
- I'm not yelling.
Oh, I love you too.
- You're free!
- You can go home!
You're free! You're free!
Go, go!
Sic 'em, boys!
Help!
Get outta my way!
Oh, my God!
Out of my way!
Come on, Harvey.
Over the fence.
You thought you could get me,
you feebleminded mongrels!
- Stupid, stupid doggies!
- Never! You'll never get me!
- Never!
- Stupid, stupid doggies.
Stupid, stupid doggies!
Stupid, stupid...
You little mangy thing!
And you and you,
you little one!
Never! Never!
You little mangy...
What?
The final chapter of a horror
story for animal lovers...
concluded at
County Courthouse today.
- Ruth Walters has the details.
- Animal lovers everywhere...
Hey, it's us!
...when Dr. Varnick and two associates
were indicted on animal abuse.
Boo! Hiss!
These were scientific
investigations!
And leading the cheers were
the ring's unlikely captors...
the Newton family
of Valley Vista.
I had no choice.
Beethoven is not just some dog
that wandered in off the street.
He's a member of our family,
and we love him very much.
Have you always been a dog lover?
Maybe not as much as now.
Thank you.
This is Ruth Walters reporting
from County Courthouse.
Okay, guys.
Let's go to bed.
- Oh, do we have to?
- It's been a long day.
- You look beautiful.
- Daddy, you're the best.
- Good night, Dad. I love you.
- Good night, sweetheart.
Say good night to Daddy.
Can I stay up?
You are up!
Go to sleep.
Hello? Yeah.
Hold on one second.
Ryce?
Who's calling?
Ryce!
- Don't stay on too long.
- Okay.
Dad, who is it?
Somebody who saw you on TV.
Mark something.
Mark.
Hello?
Yeah.
No.
Really? Friday?
Good night, honey.
Good night.
Sleep tight.
Good night, Beethoven.
Good night, Sparky.
- Good night, Mitch.
- Good night, Murphy.
Good night, Sally.
Good night, Lacey.
Good night, Fred.
Good night, Eliot.