Raphael, stop running, you are gonna fall !
The car is far , we will be in trouble
It's pretty, isn't it?
I don't know...
All of this seems complicated ....
No...; You'll see , it will change our life
Right...
aaaa... we will be so happy in Cassi
Because we are not happy here ?
yes, we are !
At least , here we have the sea
Also... Ho!
Don't take the call , we'll have an accident!
i take the free hand kit
Here we are !
hello? Yes !
Ah , Jean ! It's funny that you are calling, because we are talking about Cassi !
And we....
I have a bad news about your transfer....
I call you later...
What's going on?
You don't need to quit your job
What?
i did'nt obtain my transfer...
Damn it...
You don't have to be upset ...
I am not upset !
Am i upset right now?
No no....
So, don't tell me that I am upset , damn !
Are you okay?
I understand,  Yes , what you can do ...
I call you later...
Thanks a lot Jean !
Why do you thanks him?
its was useless that he pulls trings for you !
It's not his fault...
it's a handicap person who got the job !
A handicap person is priority
We have to be a handicap person in order to live in the south of France?
of course not...
i was glad to move...
But before, you didn't want to !
i didn't want to because i know that we will move
Now that we don't move anymore , we miss something important !
if you want, this summer ...
No !
I don't care about the holydays
You told me that we will live on the seaside
You have worked so hard for this transfer that we did'nt see each other
i want to live there all year long ! You hear Philip Abrahams?
yes, honey
Are you upset right now?
Yes I am , so what?
Don't be upset, it's useless
Why do you always do everything to annoy me?
Hello - Hello
Are you mad , What a re you doing here?
Did someone follow you?
We saw you coming into my office, right?
Did you talk to someoe about that?
Oh jean.. we are working at the Post Office
I risk a lot !
What?
Speak less loud , i risk a lot !
You don't risk anything
i didn't get the job
i am a middle manager !
i have been working for eleven years
if you speak as loud as that , i am screwed !
i diserved this transfer !
More than any handicaps persons
Philip , i will give your money back
You gotta find me something else
It's the war with Julie
A Saranis sur mer , the director is geting retired, he will leave soon
Saranis is perfect!
I need this job !
yes , but speak less loud , damn
here it is !
Here it is , what?
shht !
Mister Sobrier
yes, it's me , i'm listening
Are you busy?
no, i'm not
the director wants to see you
Ah, for what?
He just wants to see you
I'm coming right now
Well,
You don't leave as the same time than me
Let's ask for the job at Saranis as an handicap person
Are you mad?
Why not?
If there is a mistake on the folders..; what do i risk?
A lot , a lot...
I don't want you to do that
Because , if someone find out this, you are in trouble, and i am dead !
I'm..I'm coming
Thank you doctor for being there
Doctor?
No no, i won't stop my job, it's was not a big deal
Thank you doctor , bye
Hello
hello
Don't be so happy , i'm still working here for two days !
Excuse me , sir, an inspector wants to see you
what kind of inspector?
A factory inspector , about your transfer
Where is he?
In your office
Make him wait for five mintutes
Five minutes
Right
Hello
Hello...
I'm Philip Abrahams , you wanted to see me
Mister Lebuick
i wanted to clarify few details about your transfer
Of course
little brats !
The kids of the neighbourhood who bursted my wheel...
They should  work at school !
I'd be happy not to see them
You want me to help you?
No! I have to do it alone
Sit down , please, it's already done for me
How may i help you?
How long have you been handicaped , mister abrahams?
It's rather hard for me to tell you
I was a little kid
Fuzzy...
Thinking about this horrible traumatism
Sorry, muscular spasm..
It's ok , cool...
Mister Abrahams, two transfers has been asked by yourself, one very recently
For the job at Sanarri , being fit...
And this one for Cassi, six months ago
Are you these two same persons, mister abrahams?
I....
I've done these two requests..
I did !
The first one...
being valid...
Because i want my file being conseidered as a fit person
As everybody
It's important for us... Handicaped persons !
To see in fit persons's sight , as you mister lebuick
Pity...
As you want mister abrahamas
If there is a problem for my file...
No no, not at all
It's just a necesarry check
You know, sometimes I have fake files
To get good job
In the south of France....
Oh no !
What a shame !
Oh  right ,mister abrahams
You will enjoy Sanarri sur mer
Well... I won't disturbe you anymore
You don't disturb me
Bye Mister Lebuick...
What a shame !
Insane !
You are totally insane !
You are my friend , Jean
You will fix that, right?
I won't fix anything !
I don't want us to be friends ! Especially here
I'm not a friend of a mad man who fakes and pretend that he is a handicp person
I did that for Julie
I should'nt have done that
I swear, I regret
Well..
I have a bad and a good news
I am suspended, right?
Worse...
Fired??
Even Worse
Worse than fired , what is it?
you are transfered in the north of France
The North?
Lyon?
No.. Not Lyon, the north...north
Not Paris! Don't tell me , they send me in Paris?
Not Paris !
Norther than Paris
Belgium?
No ...No, before Belgium , there is???
Calais , you are transfered in Calais
Next to Lille
Lille? The island of what?
To Lille, the city !
The city of Lille?
It's horrible
And you start Next morning
Monday which is coming?
I can't.... I don't have warm clothes...
I even don't know where to live
Look ! you have an administrativ accomodation for the director
Damn, where am i going?
To Bergues....
Bourges?
Bergues....
I don"t want this transfer
You can't , you have no choice
Hum... What is the good news?
This one ..
So what's the bad one?
You will stay for Two years there
Two years?
At least..
Two years in the Nord pas de calais... No! no !
You have no choice , you have to accept to work in the north or to quit your job !
How will i tell that to Julie?
i haven't told her for Sanarris...
You can leave when the corridor is clear
Now ! Come on , go go
Good evening, honey
Hi...
Hey, i'm looking at Sanarris sur mer, and there are such wonderfuls flats !
We should be hurry in order to visit
Don't worry , we don't go anymore
What?
a controrder..
Don't tell me that a handicaped person had a job?
Kinda, yes...
It can't be true..
Wait ! We propose me something more interesting !
Oh, I was frighten...
Where?
To Bergues !
What?
Bergues, the beautiful city of bergues !
Bergues?
Bergues , in the nord pas de calais !
It's wonderful, isn't it?
Philip, what have you done?
me? nothing
i'm not stupid...
The ones who works well stay in the south of France
In the North, means that you did something serious
Not at all...
The direction proposes me to spend two years in the north
I get points !
I'm the first to get any jobs !
Especially in the south of France!
Because, if i spend two years in the Nord pas de calais, Im considered as a handicaped person !
i don't want to !
i won't freeze to death
Who will freeze to death?
Julie, we won't live outside there !
Dad, i don't want to loose my toes !
Why would you loose you toes?
i don't want to live in the North Pole...
We are not going in the North Pole , but in the North of france !
Philip , tell me the truth..
What did you do?
I have such a great promotion, i don't understand your reaction !
Well, i call Jean
In order to have the job in Sannari, i pretend to be a handicaped person..
pretend to be a handicaped person..
i'm sorry
You will go alone in the North Pole !
hello..
(strong north french accent )
What is it?
Who is it?
You know who I am? I am philip, your nephew's husband
Oh yes.. She told me that you will annoy me !
What do you want?
i have to leave in the Nord pas de calais....
A transfer !
Julie told me that you knew a little the coutnry around Lille
yes, in 1934,
My mother has slept with a " ch'timi "
What a re you sayin'?
In 1934, my mother has slept with a "ch'timi "
A " ch'ti me "?
Not a " ch'ti me " a "ch'ti mi " , everybody is called like that in the north, children, wowen, men..
Des " ch'ti mis " ?
Even the animals are " ch'ti mis"...
cats too... cats....
Cows... Chickens.........
Veals...; all " ch'ti mis "
The language too is "ch'ti mi "
"o" instead of "a"
"che" instead of "que"
et "ce" instead of "ce"
It's diferent..
And when you thin you have understood , you think that a word is in reality an other one...
How is the life there?
Quiet no?
No...
tough , tough.....
There is only the ones who work in the coalmine who live well
The others are just...
Depressed...
And they die very young, very very young there
Fortunately , my mother moved in the south of France
i was ten
I could not bear the cool
Is it very cold?
In summer , it's ok, it's 0° or 1 °
But in winter, it's going down , down....
-10° , -20° , -30°
And also -40°
-40°?
IT'S THE NORTH !
You asked me kid, right? IT'S THE NORTH !
Did i answer?
Get out !
You see ! Freezing fog ...
What is a freezing fog?
It's horrible
No , you see? 6° in the morning and 11° the afternon, that's not so bad..
You think that these are the real temparatures?
Of course ! No?
Open your eyes, Philip
In the North, they fake the temperatures
Otherwise, nobody will come
You think?
Freezing fog....
It does not exist..
Itinerary calculated..
It exists !
Please follow..
Shut up , bitch !
Sorry not to come with you but I can't...
You are better here with the sun, with the kid
Why do you put off your down jacket?
I'll be hot , and when i'll be in then orth , i'll be cold
It's better if you wear that all time long
Raphael..
Take care of your mom
Can i count on you?
Yes you can !
It's my fault, all is my fault !
No... Julie, it's not yours, it's the destiny
I'll call you when I am ......
... in the Nord pas de calais..
hello , Mister Mayeul?
Yes, i'm listening
i'm Philip Abrahams from " Salons de provence " your new director...
I'm leaving , right now, I'm coming in the begining of the night
Let's meet in front of the city hall
I can't hear you perfectly , the line is bad...
See you tonight !
Avec la mer du Nord
Pour dernier terrain vague..;
Et des vagues de dune...
Pour arrêter les vagues...
Et de vagues rochers....
..que les marées dépassent...;
Et qui ont a jamais..
Le coeur a marée basse.
Oh damn....
Damn ,damn,damn....
(Strong south french accent )
Nationl police force...
Papers , please...
Excuse me, i was driving too fast...
I wasn't paying attention
I know I am wrong
You were driving at 50 km/h...
150?
2x25
50? Is that possible?
It's too dangerous to drive slowly on the motor way, mister....Abrahams.
I'm going to have to charge you !
I am transfered in the Nord pas de Calais, i just did'nt want to arrive too early...
In the Nord pas de calais?
Yes , in the Nord pas de calais..
Go ahead...
Thank you..
Hey ,string up like a mushroom !
Good luck...
Damn........
Nord pas de calais...
Welcome to the Nord Pas de Calais
You are arrived to your destination
It can't be true...
Oh my God !
Are you okay?
Are you dead?
( French north accent, almost impossible to undertand)
Welcome mister the director..
Mister mayeul?
Don't move, it's better if I call an ambulance
no no it's okay
oh.. I could have killed you
No problem , I'm Okay
Yes , i saw your number plate which is 13, and here it is 52
But it's okay , I'm fine
Are you hurt?
What?
Are you hurt when you are talking?
WHat?
is your jaw ok?
No its okay ( impossible to understand...)
Le " chu" , it's not understanding..
You shoudl see your jaw to a doctor !
No , i'm okay " vindiouce "
You  are talking with particular voice...
Because I talk "chti"?
Sorry?
i speak "ch'ti mi""...
Oh damn, is that the " famous " ch'ti mi?
Your flat is upstairs..
Above the Post office
here it is !
Wonderful !
Here it is !
Thank you
good night , sir !
see you tomorrow !
yes, well, see you tomorrow !
Mayeul, wait !
there are not furnitures !
Where are the furnitures?
In this scene, the "ch'ti " says " dog" instead of "his" in French, impossilbe to translate in english !
it's not furnished !
The last director took them with him
Why did he leave with the furnitures?
Because it belongs to the "dogs"
What "dogs?
The furnitures !
I don't understand !
The furnitures belongs to the "dogs "
the furnitures belong to the "dogs", what does the dogs do with the furnitures?
Why did he give furnitures to the dogs?
No ! Not the dogs , animal, but his "dogs" !
Why are you saying that he gave them?
I've never said that !
You said " dogs " !
You sais , his furnitures belong to the "dogs"..
Oh right !
i said the furnitures belong to the "dogs " !
It's what i'm telling you !
" dogs " to him !
aaaaa belong to HIM !
Him not " dogs "
Cats, dogs, damn, everybody is talking as you here?
Yes we are all "ch'ti mi ", everybody speak this language !
I will have so much fun !
What you wanna do?
Go to the hotel the nearest !
An hotel ? At Bergues? at this time....
This is a chHouse
Chhouse? It's even not french...
What?
Nothing...
It's not very big in my house but a least i have furnitures !
It's very nice to you to let me sleep in your house, really !
It's a pleasure for me ! Would you like to drink or eat something?
m.mm... No thanks, I'd like to sleep, i'm exhausted...
You better going to sleep ! it's upstairs
Are you married , right?
Married? me? you know, the wifes and I....
You wanna say, you live alone or...
With my mom....
Are you living at your mom's house?
Yep , it's her bedroom, she may sleep at this time
In the back, there is the bathroom, and everything you need
Here is the bedroom..
Ah...
We must be quiet !
Are you okay? you are pale ....
No i'm not..
You need me to borrow you a pyjamas?
No thanks, i have everything i need
Oh...
Don't move..
Oh right....
You may like the lavender as you come from the South
Clean sheets, my mother cleans them with lavender.
It's smell so good !
Let's do the bed together !
I'll do it myself thanks !
Good night !
good night...
Sleep !
Well....
You.... too
What the...?
Mister Abrahams.. It's time...
Sir, you need to wake up !
You Scared me !
YOU scared me !
What do you want?
No, what do YOU want?
What do I want??
For...the breakfast !
What time is it?
It's 7:15 am, it's almost time to go to the post Office...
Ah... We are still in the Nord pas de calais?
Yea ! it's a house, not a barge !
Well, One tea please
There is no tea, only coffee
What else?
Nothing... Only coffee
Well, coffee...
( strong north french accent )
Why is he sleeping in the guest bedroom?
This bedroom...You don't need to borrow a bedroom !
Are you sure we don"t have tea?
I hate tea !
You hear what I'm saying?
mommy... I didn't want him to sleep in the living room....
It's my new boss ....
That's not the point !
Hello madam !
Hello...
Sit down
Did you move something in the guestroom?
No madam, I didn't !
Have you made the med?
Not yet...
Stop mom...
She is kidding !
I'm not kidding at all...
He is the boss right, but he has to do the corves !
Right boy?
Yes madam...
Is that caramel?
No it is some chicory, we always put chicory in the coffee ...
Some what?
Chicory !
Taste it !
Is it bad, right?
No it's not !
What have you put on your toast?
That?
It is "maroille" (very strong cheese ! )
" maroill " ? What is it?
It's a cheese which smells a bit strong..
Like an old cheese...
You want to taste?
no !
you are wrong !
It's less strong by tasting that smelling...
It's good , right?
Oh ! It is also strong inside !
That's why we dip it in the coffee !
That is sweeten....
come on, dip !
No , I won't !
Come on !
good !
Young man !
It is a cake with brown sugar...
You have not eaten....
Thank you...
Well, and not before time either !
my " ch'ti"....
Don't come back too late
i won't !
Bye !
Promise?
Yes !
Very Special mom !
Not for me ! I've always known her this way !
Is that some "maroille" in the brown sugar cake?
No because you have still the smell of the cheese in your nose !
o... Everything stinks !
Breathe with the mouth , it will ventilate...
That the " maroille "...
Weird... it's not that cold !
For April, it's pretty hot...
Yes , right...
It's because of  the global warning !
It was colder before , was not it?
Yes , at this time years ago, we were  skating on ice, building a snowman..
Sure...
The part of the cool that i regret most, is that I was delivering the mail with a sleigh !
With a sleigh, are you kidding me?
A little bit , sir...
It's not funny !
not at all !
Why have you chosen the North if you are afraid to freeze to death?
Hi Antoine !
Hi " tizzot "
How are you?
This is Mister Abrahamas, th new director of the post Office !
Hi mister " tizzote"
Hello mister " tizzote " !( actually tizzote is a nickname .)
That's a good one !
Are you laughing at me?
No we are not !
You think you are smart with your accent?
Your cheeses whick stinks and you houses with the red bricks!
Excuse us , but...
Where are you going?
To the Post office !
I will let you laugh with your friend !
Mister Abrahams...
Let me introduce you...Fabrice Canoli
The older post office employee...
Sir, Welcome to Bergues !
yes, we have already told me...
And Yann Vandernoout who occupied the part of the banking...
So you come from the " Chouth"?
No , not the " Chouth ", the  South....
S.O.U.T.H, the "Chouth" I don't know where it is...
What the hell is that?
See you tonight !
Have a nice day !
Bye !
Hi everyone !
Antoine, close you mouth, a fly will get in there !
You may be Mister Abrahmas?
Annabelle Deconninck , i'm behind the position window and I'm busy with the accounting...
hello ... Well , can you show me my office?
Yep ! I'll show you !
I have mails to deliver....
jerk....
If only I could hit him...
be nice... He looks to have a sweet look..
I 'm telling you it's a funny one !
I feel it...
Do you know this  biker who drop Annabelle?
No no....
Oh no...
Where is your mind?
You have forgotten your lunch...
But mom, I'll lunch with the colleagues...
You don't need to spend your money for.... nothing !
it's not for nothing, It's for eat !
Take your lunch, don't be stupid !
Mom ! I'm 35 years old !
Roger !
Your bike will hurt you whereas your arms are new!
Hello madam  Bailleul
What's wrong with her?
Mom !
How does the director think about his office?
Damn...
It will pass fast...
It will pass fast....
Only two years, it will be fast !
Hello everyone !
hello... hello !
hello Mister Vasseur !
How are you this morning?
like and old man....
Is that true that the new director arrived?
Ye, this morning !
Can i see him??
Sure, it's possible
What is it?
Sir, a customer wants to see you !
For what?
... He  wants to see you !
Hello Sir, How may i help you?
( Too hard to understand, very very strong accent....)
I didn't get it !
You need what?
...........................................;
It does not work....
...............;;
Two seconds sir !
Right..
What do you want?
........................................;
I think it was betther on the other side...
Yes?
.................;..........;;Next................................;;retired.............
Next, retired....
Yes?
Yes or no??
Don"t move !
What's your name already?
Annabelle sir
Can you look after mister please?
Because... Right
Fine...
I'm listening to you Mister Vasseur...
We are going to lunch, are you coming with us?
Where are you going?
To the " French fries House"
"French fries House"....
What a pretty name !
Hello !
Hello..hello...
How are you? Fine...
Where is your restaurant?
What?
What restaurant?
Your restaurant...
"French Fries House "
aa.. It's not a restaurant !
a " French Fries House " is a French Fries House !
Right there !
Take away or here?
It's a caravan...
It used to be a caravan ! Now its a French Fries House...
They don't sleep here anymore.. They're making french fries....
Next please !
Hi there !
What do you want?
Hi momo...
As usually...
Yes !
Two French Fries with one american....
Allright !
"Fricadelle " and one american...
What do you want?
I don't know... Like you..
Add a " fricadelle " momo!
Which condiment?
Picadilly !
Allright, picadilly !
And one Picadilly !
aaaa that's  gipsy food !
What?
No...no, it's our speciality !
That's good !
What's in there?
" Fricadelle " We can tell you what there is inside of it !
In the North, everybody knows what there is inside of it !
But nobody says it !
It's like americans with the " coco "
The what?
The " coco -colo "
aaa the coca - cola !
It's what he has just said !
The "coco -  colo " !
That a nice little place !
it's not the little place but the big one !
This church is lovely !
It's not a church !
There is nothing religious with it...
it's our belfry !
During the Middle age, it helps the army to prevent the ennemies to come in !
Let them come !
We see all the country here, it's beautiful !
But you need to ask Antoine to show you, he is the bellringer !
The what?
The bell ringer?
Right there, there are about 50 bells called peal of bells...
And Antoine is the only guy who know how to play !
In his family, everybody used to be a bell ringer !
When he plays, it's beautiful!
We hear him very far away...
it's true....
Momo, a beer please !
Oh Antoine, we were talking about you?
Really?
You were not talking about your biker? the show off man?
Why is not here, He does not like french fries the " boubours " ?!
It's not funny, stop !
me too I can show off with my bike !
Come to sit Antoine !
I know you !
It it the South guy !
Are you okay?
Are you allright Bailleul?
You know what he did that night?
I invited to my house
He saw the pictures of us on the wall and he freaked out. He closed his door
You were afraid that I fell in love with you?
Don't be out of respect !
it will be sad if I give you a warning the first day...
Oh ! I'm frighten !
Well....
No, we'll pay !
So? You didn't learn to say " thank you " in your country?
Antoine stop !
Enough !
you must be ashamed....
He has just arrived !
Imagine that you are in the South and that we speak to you this way !
We have been knowing for a long time with Antoine...
He is not a bad guy, you know !
It's not a reason to insult me...
And it is forbiddent to drink during hi work...
Especially his mother who makes his life more difficult...
It's not a reason !
You won't give him his warning?
Have you forgotten something?
How are you , Sir?
What do you wanr bailleul?
We agree with the colleagues...
We have all gave you something to furnish upstairs !
Look at that !
A chair..;
Look !
The footstool !
It's better than before, right?
it's look like a flat of Lille !
It's vey nice, it's wonderful, you didn't have to !
I'm a bit disapointed...
Why?
Beyond tonight, we don't sleep together...
How will I thank you... Except...
for the French Fries House..
Oh ! We can eat together In Lille !
Oh no.. my back hurts me so bad...
It's okay, you don't eat with your back !
You know Lille, Mister Abrahams?
Is it a cheese which smells bad again?
Sure, but it's a nice city too !
What do you want to eat?
I invite you !
There are a lot of specialities here !
The best one " le Chichon au gratin "
The " Chicon au gratin "?
No ! The " chichon au gratin " it's like big  endives with some béchamel sauce!
And the " Maroille Pie"
And the Maroille , I know what it is !
He has to taste the "carbonate "!
He must not leave before tasting the "carbonate "!
The what?
The carbonate !
It's like a  boiled beef with vegetables
We won't order everything...
We just have to take a little of each food ! and  we pick at one's food !
Right?
Yes !
It's not complicated to speak " ch'timi"...
For example...
We don't say : " Sorry sir, I beg you pardon , i didn't understand what you have just said"
We say : " WHAT?"
What?
No that's not a real " what" !
It has to get out from here !
What?
At the beginnig, when you start speaking " ch'ti "
or the " picard " we are similar...
You have to add a " what " at the end of the sentence !
Come on try !
I get it , what?
Great !
Ok , what?
Here, you speak " ch'timi" !
Damn !
no ! We don't say " damn", we say " vindedious " !
" vindedious ", what ?
Good job "biloute" !
Good job , who?
"biloute" !
Evrybody is called like that, it's a whole nickname !
What the meaning of " biloute " ?
" biloute "?
It means.....
that means nothing !
It means , little penis....
Little penis?
Yes, no... It's nothing about penis...
It's just affectionate !
ok ok !
Teach me insults ! it's important to learn insults when you star a new language !
We don't say " shit " we say " dubrin " !
We don' t say " jerk", we say " boubours " !
" boubours " !
In the South , we say " couillostis " !
That's pretty !
We don't say " hell !" but " miard " !
" dubrin " , " miard " , what? !!
I noticed too that..
We don't say " me " but "ti ".. No !
No ! We don't say " me " but " mi" and not " you " but "ti" !
Right !
It's like " che " become " ce " and " ce " become "che " !
Like " chores " became " cores " !
Right !
You have to order something !
No; no ,no...
yes ! it will be a training !
Yes, that's a good idea ! " Chek le dedans "
"check the..." what?
" Check le dedans "...
Which means?
Means, " let's do it Sir, don't be afraid !
Well...
Waiter !
Louder !
WAITER!!!!!
Great !
Good evening !
Good evening " biloute" what?
"mi" with the Post team ....
We'd like ...
We'd loke ..loke !
We'd loke ..
We'd loke...
A ......
Please, what?
Excuse me, I am not ch'timi, I'm coming for Paris and I didn't understand...
See you tomorrow !
Bye !!
See you !
Bye !
Hello?
Phillip??
Omg ! Are you okay?
Julie, what is going on?
i leave you a lot of messages ! You had to call me when you were there !
Damn ....
I thought something happened to you....
no no..; excuse me , it's just...
It was very....
Complicated...
More that i was expected...
What did they do to you?
Nothing ! i didn't want to worry you !
Now , all is allright !
Stop, honey.. You can tell me everything....
"tell me everything" , tell you what?
It's horrible, right?
Not that much ...
Ok !
it's the North...
It's not thath cold and moreover they are very... euh... very...
welcoming !
Please , Philip , stop it !
Stop what?
Don't do it again, stop lie to me !
Tell me the truth, what's going on ? I know it's awful...
I know that you suffer, I'm your wife, tell me evrything !
It's the truth!
Philipp !
It's true, it's awful....
I can't bear it.... It's horrible...
You see! I know you...
Yes !
poor dear...
Come back home and i will take care of you !
I really want to be fiftten days later, because it will be  a nightmare...
Philipp...
i'm proud of what you are doing for your family !
i love you...
So do I !
It's very nice !
he invited us !
really?
Thanks a lot !
Are you okay?
Hello !
Hello Sir !
Hello Antoine , how are you?
Fine and you?
You slept well?
Hello Yann , what about you?
Hello Sir!
Have a nice day !
Main road !
Main road..
How are you?
HAve a nice day !
Fine... and you?
Thank you
Good evening !
It's open !
The fifteen days passed so fast !
Be careful , Sir !
You'll have a long road...
Be careful on the road !
You phone when you arrive and you let the phone ringing twice, we'll know that it was you.
Stop it, you are not his mom...
See you monday !
Have a nice week end !
Thank you...
Where is Antoine?
He is doing the bellringer !
Don"t you hear?
Is he playing right now?
yes !
He is gifted !
He is the best !
Bye !
Dad !
You are not putting to bed yet?
Mom said i could wait for you, I could'nt sleep...
Show me your toes !
Don't worry.. I have all of them...
How are you honey?
you had a good trip?
You have circles under one's eyes but you look fit !
I'm okay ! I'll put Raphael to bed...
Dad , show me your toes !
But...
Show me your toes !
1 , 2 , 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10
it's okay mom, everything 's ok !
good for him !
Good night !
Good night dad !
Sleep well !
Little man!
Take some bouillabaisse ( provençal fish soup)
It's good, I made it yesterday , it's better the next day .
Take some vegetable soup with pistou !
No? You want a " tapenade " toast (  condiment with olives )
No thank you honey...
usually , you love that !
I know but I'm not hungry..
Come on cry !
if you want to cry, go ahead ! It does not embarassed me ...
Thank you...
I can't...
Honey.. What did they do to you?
I can't talk about that...
Are they awful with you?
They are...they are....
First, they drink !
All of them...
A lot...
It is the only thing they have...;
To the Post Office , it's like the Middle age, I can't understand what they say , like
Sure, alcoholics....
They are not really alcoholic...But...
They drink to warm up...
It's is always cold right there, it amounts to the same thing...
What a nightmare...
my love...
Thanks to that food, you can eat for fifteen days !
It passed so fast !
I wanted to stay one day more....
be strong....
Here, your present !
Lined with fleecy !
Thank you !
wear it !
No... you know, it's not that cold...
Phlip..Please , don't be over protection....
Wear it!
Damn...
160 km/h !
You look better !
Yes thanks !
Are you going to the Nord pas de calais?
Yes , i am , actually I like this country...
It's great !
Really?
Well...Good for you !
It will cost you 4 points on you driving  license , and 150  !
Oh "dubrin"....
Sorry?
Nothing !
Get off your vehicule...
Hello...
Hello " tizzot " !
What's up "tizzot"?
It's cloudy today...
Yes, it's going to " dracher " (rain)
Antoine , bring that to the mail room, I need it as fast as possible...
I'll do it...
When you are there, Phone to me in order to tell me if he had it...
i heard , i bring it and i tell you what...
That he has the file !
yes, I know... I bring that to him and I tell you what.
What? I juste tell you " what "!
Ye, i got it !
So you call me !
Yes , right....
When I give that to him...;
I call you and I tell you what...
I don't know....
For example...
" Hello , it's Antoine, I gave the file to the responsable of the mail room " !
Right?
Yes.. I'm not " boubours "
I'll call you ...
Right... You call me...
And i tell you what....
Look at me Antoine...
you are drunk !
No, i'm not...
Sir, actually , " I tell you what " means in " ch'ti ", it's ok , I'll tell you if i did the job !
aaa , right....
Forgive me Bailleul....
It was not a big deal....
You call me, and you tell me what...
That I delivered the file !
Paris est magic !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
Here...
Antoine has forgotten his lunch again...
Antoine is easily influenced....
You can't ask him so many things...
He can't go to the French Fries House everyday !
Can i count on you?
yes, madam...
Yes?
YES madam...
Well.....That's a bit tacky...
I won't tell anything... But I have some doubts...
Really !
Here madam ! I'm sorry , it took  a long time, sorry....
Bye !
Next please !
Hello madam, how may I help you?
I'd like to weigh that letter and stamped it .
Nice stamps please
my little kid collects them !
That's cute...
You like this one? there is a hedgehog on it !
Yes, perfect...
envelope...
" vindedious " , 20 pounds !
20 pounds, it's impossible...
it might be grams...
yes , right ! I was wondering what there was in it...
17  !
17  for 20 grams?
It's impossible.. how much are the stamps?
Is there a problem If i add stamps with  a goat?
Are you mad? You may be wrong !
What a mess........ No place for the hedgehogs...
I have to put the other stamps on the other side...
17  for 20 grams.....
It's impossible ! you are wrong !
I have swallowed some stamps, but you don't pay for them, don't worry...
Stop it !
Give me that Antoine...
leave !
I take care of it madam.. You won't pay anything !
Don't worry, I'm on it !
I'm coming !
That rings you a bell?
Leave me alone... Go home !
Have a nap !
Annabelle i don't know what i'll do without you....
You won't drink, trust me , it will be good for you...
Come on...
So?
That was awesome !
Great !
What?
Oh " dubrin " !
Great , right?
How are you Antoine?
Fine, fine , I won't " braire" ( cry)
" braire "?
It means "cry"...
How do you say " laugh "?
" laugh" we say " laugh" !
That's the same !
We must at least speak a bit french , right?
About the work, everything ok?
no problem...
I'd like to tell you something....
We are all happy that you are our new director...
Thank you Antoine...
You live in a country very welcoming , really..
We maybe a country welcoming but if we have nobody to welcome , we thanks you...
You are welcome...
There is a huge ch'timi proverb which says...
" When a strranger comes in the north , he " braire " twice...
Once he arrives, and when he leaves "....
That's true i felt bad when i arrived there...
You'll see when you will leave...
no !
We are gonna see this....
The south is my home...
We are gonna see...
here , 10 , 20 , 30 
Thank you!
Bye madam !
So, what are we going to do tonight? We haven't planned anything !
Sir , we are friday !
Don't you come back home?
In the " South " !
Already friday?
Yes !
" vindedious "...
Julie?
Surprise !
I have invited our friends to cheer you up !
Dad !
Hey little man !
Julie told us that you are through a living hell...
When i opened the Post office, it's still the night!
It's sunny at about 11:30 am !
And at 5 pm , suddenly , night !
They are all... depressed, whites , miserables...
Yes, they have not enough light...
And moreover the hygiene... Last week, a begining of a desease !
The... The cholera !
Cholera !
Cholera!?
yes...
Have you done your vaccines?
I have to !
We have to check !
The North is worst than the hell !
Weird... i used to work in the north...
I had such a great memory !
For the Easter week end, we may go to Belgium!
Why not?
i have to work..
What's wrong?
It embarassed you by seeing us?
no, not at all !
So what?
Kiss me !
Listen , it's ridiculous...
See you tonight !
Kiss me !
You hurt me!
Is there a problem , annabelle?
No , I'm okay !
What's wrong with the postman?
A problem?
You've got mails for me?
Stop.. Tony !
Shut up...
No I haven't...
But I have a text message...
As you don't know to read, I'll tell you...
Antoine stop it !
" it's forbidden to park in front of the Post Office , cheers the postman "
hey , is your mom here?
is she cleaning your room?
No no no stop ...
What's wrong bellringer, you wanna fight?
No, I'm against the violence between humans...
But about the objects....
Damn !
Are you insane?
Stop !
Antoine !
Stop that, Help me guys !
Stop Bailleul!
Stop !
Sir...?
Sir?
He does not look fine...
No , it's ok...
Look he is not aware...
It's OK !
Come on Sir...
He can't say no !
You know , you understand...
You know, people are happy when the post man arrives...
" Would you like to take a drink Antoine? "
Then....
Then... He fights in front of the post office ! that's serious !
He might say no , but i can say stop !
A reprimand? Maybe too much , Sir
You won't take his defense, right?
no i'm not !
I just want him to be good...
it won't fix everything if you give him a reprimand...
You know what is the real problem of Antoine Bailleul?
he is in love with you !
Actually....
We used to be together for a year...
Why did you dump him?
He dumbed me...
i don't get it..
I was very happy with him...
one day , I had an argue with his mother who is a bit...instrusive...
I was very upset...
i told Antoine to choose....
He chose...
What i have to do?  I'm the director of the post office.. not  a social worker...
It's beautiful Antoine....
Go ahead !
You are gonna give me a musical diploma or a reprimand?
Why don't you talk to your mother?
My mother?
i talked with Annabelle...
It's the relation with your mother which cause all your problems...
no...
Antoine...
My mother... i have to help her, she had a difficult life...
It's not helping her, if you don't tell her what you really think about her....
If you want to be relieved, we are all like you...
My wife.. I love her !
But i spend all my week end liying to her....
What?
Too long to explain...
i didn't know that you were married....
Thank you!
If you are married , why does your wife not come here to live with you?
My wife is...
Rather depressed.... Even depressive...
That's why if she came in the North it could be worse....
Why?
Hum... It could be worse for her... to leave her town.
in all places...
ok..
look Antoine...
I ask you to be careful during the work times...
it won't help you for your problems if you drink... it's even worse...
i behave like a "babache"...
We all do mistakes....
By the way, when you realised them, you must fix them....
If you can fix them...
It's always retrievable...
Except... his motor bike !
you wanna try?
What?
Playing the peals of bells...
No...
Why?
You might know a song, it's like a piano !
If I play, everybody will listen to it !
then , we must take the headphones !
Go ahead " biloute "
Not this one !
oh my god...
Not easy...
More pitched...
yes...
Antoine , wait, I come with you !
i know the road...
i'm coming with you...
it's time to say " no" !
You are the boss !
Hey " biloute " !
hello mister Magnieux...
Hello " tissote " !
i'm the director of the Post Office of Bergues...
it's really nice to say hello !
Come on in !
No thank you sir, it's really nice, but we have to go !
it's a bit early for the aperitif...
You even don't want to talk a little coffee?
A coffee? That's different ! Ok !
Let's go !
A little drink of alcohol in it?
No thanks, not for me !
Come on, it will warm you up , cause you are coming from the South !
Right Antoine....
i can't drink that !
the " geniève " is th typical drink of the North !
Taste it !
Worse it can happened, it will heal you !
Cheers !
Take a  sugar lamp dipped in alcohol....
That?
No no no , please....
Come on !
Thanks a lot for the coffees Jules !
You are welcome !
you can come when you want !
Well... See you tomorrow !
Have a nice day !
You see Antoine...
We can be sympatic with the customer... only by drinking a coffee !
Yes, I see perfectly what you mean !
But now, stop ! over !
No " geneviève" anymore ! ( french name)
" geniève ".... ( name of the drink)
Why are you ringing? If you do that, they will offer us something to drink !
It is for a registered...
Ok ok , it's different.. but we don't come in, we don't drink !
Come on in !
No , we can't, we stay outside !
It's too dangerous !
Oh it's you ! i know you , i've already heard that voice !
Mister Vasseur, what a good surprise !
It's for a registered, mister Vasseur, you have to sign there !
hey , mister vasseur, I know how to speak ch'timi right now ...
i understand all what you say !
Ch"timi second language !
Let's celebrate that !
Come on in , I give you something to drink...
Let's go...
Is " geneviève" here?
" geniève "...
No sorry, i don't have " geniève " i don"t drink alcohol...
Maybe i have some yellow drink as you say in your country, maybe already opened...
yellow drink , pastis ..
Oo.. Pastis like in my country !
i don't wanna drink...
Pastis won't hurt you...
Actually we should not...
Don't worry i won't say anything...
i don't want...
Bailleul ! It's an order ! From the Headquarters !
ok but with a lot of water then...
As you want...
Here it is , youngs guys...
not higher than the glass !
be careful , Avoid your mom !
Thank you...
beautiful...
Hi " biloutes " ! Here are the postmans !
We don't have to say hello to everyone..
I'm thirsty !
Hello madam !
Hello
You see how I say know to the fifth beer , antoine?
see?
Polite !
you were wrong ....
It's a soft beer, I'm not drunk !
Now me must stop drinking buddy, we shoud drink less !
You know what we say Antoine?
No thank you?
No !
No Thank you !
Here it is..
I love your country Antoine...
I love your country...
I love the north !!
I love you too !
Wait Antoine , let's be on familiar term with you...
Yes...
Antoine?
" vindedious " !
" dubrin" !
I'm gonna throw up...
If your ass does not hurt , you can still sit on it !
Hello Antoine
Hello Sir !
It's ok, he opened the door, stop ringing !
Hi mister Leborgne
We don't have mails for you...
But we'd like something to drink !
To celebrate our friendship !
Well, come on in !
Let's do the race ,Antoine
No no, not a race !
Come on ! The last who arrived , is considered as a " boubours " !
Watch out the " stop " !
Philip ! the " stop " !
"vindedious " !
Come on Antoine !
We are gonna shake them off !
Stop !
haha " vindedious " !
Are you okay?
Who are you?
Police !
So we are both employees !
Follow us to the  police station !
Stop that " biloute " !
Between ch'ti !
We are all ch'tis , right "biloute" ?
I became a ch'ti !
Don't do your " boubours " !
Calm down !
It's not possible, you are not ch'timi !
You, you are not !
You are not !!
Wait ! We are all going to the French Fries house !
momo ! 4 french fries !
Wait , we have not eaten yet !
no , wait !
Hello?
My love?
I won't be here tonight honey, i'll be here tomorrow morning !
I'm to the Police station...
Oh my god Phlip, you have been attacked , right?
No.. it's just that, I've drunk a little....
And i get arrested...
By car?
No, by bike...
By bike?
What were you doing drunked on a bike?
i learnt how to say "no" to alcohol !
My love, what's going on?
You don't need to drink in order ton avoid your problems !
I know it's hard
but you need to resist !
Ok...
Yes?
I need to hang up, they will sober me up !
I love you !
i love you !
So?
So what?
Show me your hands...
you are not shaking, you have not been drinking for two days, do you want some alcohol?
No I'm okay...
No...
What's wrong?
you drank my parfum?
It's happened when you are alcoholic.
I swear , i'm okay...
I prefer that i give you a glass of alcohol instead of drinking my "givenchy".
Yes...
What are you doing?
Julie...
I was silly, I was weak, forgive me....
What are all of these?
My suitcases !
I'm leaving with you!
What about Raphael?
My parents take him tonight, and there, we'll find a school !
What about the shop, your work....
I'm on vacation...
i want to live with you in the North !
No no Julie no!
I'm a bit afraid, but happy to come with you....
We will always be together now...
You'll see, together, we'll be stronger !
Have you put your belt?
yes, of course !
is he insane?
Well..
What was your speed?
Good one !
We will take you to the hospital !
My husband did not drink !
He has parfumed his mouth , maybe , that's it !
Don't worry my love, go with the  breakdown van !
No, i stay with you !
No , go home, check the car, the house, I'll take the train !
better...
Ok honey...
Be careful !
I join you as fast as possible !
Great !
Come into my office !
i need to talk to you all !
That serious....
What's going on?
my wife is coming tomorrow !
that's a good news !
no , not really !
You two are in good terms?
Yes , we are !
Since 1000 kilometers are between us, everything is perfect !
My wife is depressive ...
that helps so much that I live in the North...
that focus her mind in something concret....
tell me...
I'm afraid not to understand....
Yes, i lied to you... She thinks that I'm living in hell...
that i'm depressed...
The more she looks after me, the more she gets better...
Weird story...
Maybe, but it works...
We have never been so happy since I lived in the Nord pas de Calais...
What did you say to her about us?
Few " clichés "...
I have not invented...
I said that you were....
basics
a bit..
Simple...
a bit rude...
Sometimes vulgar...
Jerks....
Late....
And few things...
hello honey !
It's really pretty here !
My love, I have to tell you something..
Welcome to the " ch'nord"....
Welcome !
Welcome to the "ch'nord"...
Come !
Julie, Julie, Julie !
Need to drink !
Pretty wife !
Yep
Fuck off !
Go home !
Look at that mess !
Where are we?
To bergues, honey...
We are arrived...
Ladies and gentlemen..
Who are all these guys?
Ther miners of the mine...
I thought the mines were stopped?
Not all, not this one..
Even if it's closed, we still live in there...
Where do you want us to go ?
"vindedious " what the hell...?
There, the town hall...
Right there, the Post Office, and in front of that, the party rooms, but there are not parties anymore..
It is worst than you told me...
it's what i try to tell you at the station... I didn't want you to see this...
are you living there?
Yes...
But it's rather shiny!
i forgot to say... We eat at 9 am , you must not be late...
We don't eat together?
No... It's the welcoming meal, if we don't go there, i'll be in troubles...
Talk to them, they'll be happy...
It's great to eat outside...
We don't have to stay too late, because of the tigers....
What are we eating?
Meat...
What kind of meat?
it depends of what we find...
You'll see !
Damn!
miss !
it's ok , we have enough meat, come on eat !
I'm coming !
Dinner is ready !
Thank you .
I can't...
I can"t...
Give me some bread...
Tomorrow...
We'll go to the mine and play hide and seek.
Great !
You think they go to sleep in their mines?
i don't think so, it's only 1 am...
We hear the neighbors...
What are they saying?
An argue...
like every single nights...
This is it , problem is finished...
oh my god, someone is dead !
no , don"t worry he shoots in the ceiling to afraid his wife ...
What a nightmare...
How can you live this way for two years?
First, how did you do to live until now?
I'll take something...
You should go home, it's too hard for you..
I'll bring you to the station tomorrow...
ok...
in order to take the rest of my clothes.
What?
Raphael can't join us...
He will live two years to my parents's house..
I'll move here, with you...
It's not possible....
i don't want it !
I love you...
your life is mine....
so?
i can't hear anything.. maybe they're sleeping...
Maybe we can start a fire !
Are you mad?
Are you "babache"?
Anyway , all the thing I propose, you don't care...
no...
The shotgun was a good idea.
Ok I do it again !
No !
Yann, enough !
Let's go home.
Don't you come Antoine?
No , i stay here, Somebody has to stay here..
ye, it's true...
Annabelle wait !
Is it better if you stay here?
Antoine...
Please...
No , because tomorrow, i'll be alone, it won't be work...
She will have doubts !
right now.. i'm the one who has doubts...
... The only moment where we are both In bergues, without my mother..
Good night.
So, are you okay?
no!
Neither do i...
Julie wants to stay here...
Here , in the North?
no , there , there ....
What?
You realize... We have done everything to disgust her...
And she agree to stay here...
But why?
Because she loves me.
"dubrin"...
I have fought for many years in order to live in the South and fix our couple problems..
And everything is getting better, here, in the North
Good for you , if everything is getting better.
What I am supposed to do?
She does not want to leave this hole !
Why don't you tell her the truth?
No...
I realized that my wife loved me, I don't want to make her upset...
Coward !
no i'm not !
yes , you are !
Your wife loves you, you too, so be true and tell her what you really have to say !
Antoine !
i don't have to take lessons of a 35 years old " boubours " who can"t leaves her mother !
What?
i say that you are not brave !
i can talk to my mother when i want !
Go ahead !
Go talk to your wife instead of telling me what i have to do !
OK i am busy with my wife, you with your mother !
Please?
Julie?
Julie !
Madam Abrahams?
How may i help you madam?
I'm a bit lost, where is the Post office of Bergues?
Bergues?
It's not here...
We are in Bergues , aren't we?
No we're not...
It is the old miner city here....
Bergues is right there, far away...
Really?
Thank you.
Get in !
I'll bring you .
Get it, don't be afraid, i won't eat you .
My wife has disapeared...
no no, she is waiting for you, she is upstairs...
I had to tell her everything...
It's not " Versailles " but i live correctly...
It's the ch'tis who borrowed me some furnitures, they are very nice with me...
it has been months that you are telling me craps...
Many times I tried to tell you the truth, but i couldn"t.
I told you what you wanna hear..
You did all that stuff because you didn't want me here.
The less we see each other, everything gets better.
We separated in order to be a better couple.
Right?
I have to go back to the South
So, mister " biloute"
You've got some mails for your mother?
No, I need to talk with you mom.
What's going on?
Are you sick?
You have catched a disease?
No no mom...
I want you to listen what i have to tell you
Don't reply, i want you to listen...
And if you have something to say, it won't change things...
Because what i have to tell you is like that et you can't talk !
Ok?
I didn't say anything !
Yea
So...
I'll leave the house..
I'll buy a flat...
And i will move with Annabelle
Even if you don't like her...
I love her
And she is the one that i have chosen.
Here
What do you have to say?
Well ... Finally you did it !
I was wondering when you were able to ask me that !
Aren't you upset?
Why , i have to be?
I have all a mother dreams...
That her son finds his own happiness.
I didn't raise you for myself
And if you can do a little " biloute "
Or a little girl " biloute "
I'll be so glad , you know.
Ok?
Ok...
Is it the only thing you gotta ask me , because I have to finish my potatoes.
Thank you !
Think about it...
You must know that I'm here...
I'm coming , i'm here right now .
Kiss Raphael.
Hello Annabelle !
Hello Madam Bailleul !
What would you like?
I'm here to congratulate.
Good job !
You won my boy !
I leave him alone.
It's over !
I won't watch him anymore.
Beyond this day..
I watch you two !
You have to be happy ! Otherwise You 'll be in troubles !
You got it?
Congratulations!
Thank you!
We know each other with Annabelle on this song !
The singer comes from here !
" Ch'tivie Wonder"
I'm sorry, I'm not in a mood to laugh....
By the way, I didn't ask you what happened with you?
perfect...
I dare to speak with my mother.
i told her I will marry Annabelle !
How did she react?
She wants us to make kids !
Great !
Now, I just have to warn Annabelle...
You didn't talk to her?
I can't, i'm afraid that she says no ...
Is she still with her biker?
Dunno.
Hope not.
Mister Abrahams? What's going on?
I need you Annabelle, really !
At this time? Can we wait for tomorrow morning?
it's an order ! Please come with me ! Go down !
You stay here, don't move !
It's ok, she is downstairs...
Are you ready?
I'm nervous...
Go on ! " check la dedans " !
" Annabelle , I love you, Marry me Biloute "
Before you give your answer, you just know that I leave my mother;
I know.
She told me.
That's really nice what you've done !
You liked it ?
You are stupid !
Julie?
When me met each other, we were living nowhere, we didn't care !
We were happy, because we were together.
how could we have forgotten that?
post man.
It's for you Philip.
Damn.
Human resources manager.
3 years that you are here, sure it will arrive.
So?
Porcorole.
That's wonderful !
Yes.
See you tonight !
HAve a nice trip.
Always the same thing with the directors.
You come from nowhere.
and you leave
And when everything is perfect, you escape such as thieves...
Stop it.
YEs , but.
A beer for you !
thank you !
Thank you !
We'll see you during the holydays .
Right Annabelle?
You know, the South is pretty good !
Thanks for everythings " biloute" .
You don't have to thank me .
Ye you have
You see I was right.
What?
A stranger who comes in North , cry twice
When he arrives and when he leaves.
i'm not crying.
Yes ,you are !
No i'm not !
YEs , you are !
No , i'm not
No , you're not.
Bye !
Thank you , subs by Théo. Hope the film by Will Smith will be as good as this one :)
I love you !
i love you, and I want you to live with me in the Nord Pas de Calais.
i want us to be together.
For ever.
Dad , mom... Why are you kissing in front of everybody?
Come on , we are going to loose our toes !