Hi. Welcome to the future.
San Dimas, California, 2688.
And I'm telling you, it's great here.
The air is clean. The water's clean.
Even the dirt is clean.
Bowling averages are way up.
Mini-golf scores are way down.
And we have more excellent waterslides...
...than any other planet
we communicate with.
I'm telling you, this place is great...
...but it almost wasn't.
You see, 700 years ago,
the two great ones...
...ran into a few problems.
So now I have to travel back in time
to help them out.
If I fail to keep these two
on the correct path...
... the basis of our society will be in danger.
Don't worry, it'll all make sense.
I'm a professional.
I'm Bill S. Preston, Esquire!
And I'm Ted... Hold on.
Bill, here, you take it.
Okay.
- And I'm Ted "Theodore" Logan.
- Yeah!
And we're Wyld Stallyns!
- Smell it, dude.
- Let's bail.
We blew it.
Guess we used too much power.
I liked it.
While I agree that, in time,
our band will be most triumphant...
...the truth is,
Wyld Stallyns will never be a super band...
...until we have Eddie Van Halen on guitar.
Yes, but I do not believe
we will get Eddie Van Halen...
...until we have a triumphant video.
It's pointless to have a triumphant video...
...before we even have decent instruments.
How could we have decent instruments
if we don't know how to play?
That is why we need Eddie Van Halen!
And that is why we need
a triumphant video.
Excellent!
- We're late!
- For what?
- For school, dude!
- Yeah.
Bill, I'm waiting.
He's dead?
What you're telling me, essentially,
is that Napoleon...
...was a short dead dude.
Yeah.
You totally blew it, dude.
- Ted, stand up.
- Stand up?
Yes, son. Stand up.
Now...
Who was Joan of Arc?
Noah's wife.
Listen, guys, don't forget:
Tomorrow, final report...
...1:30 to 3:30, okay?
Guys.
Mr. Ryan...
Before you say anything,
my distinguished colleague, Ted, and I...
...wish to express to you our thanks...
...for all the things
we have learned in your class.
And what have you learned?
We've learned
that the world has a great history.
Yes. And that thanks
to great leaders such as...
...Genghis Khan, Joan of Arc...
...and Socratic Method...
...the world is full of history.
It seems to me the only thing
you've learned is that Caesar...
...is a "salad-dressing dude. "
Bill, Ted, this is really quite simple.
You have flunked
every section of this class.
Now, unless you get an A plus
on your final oral report tomorrow...
...guys, I have no choice
but to flunk the both of you.
You know your topics.
So I would suggest
you at least cover those areas...
...if you want to pass the course.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Okay.
Your report
had better be something very special.
Man.
What are we supposed to know
for our report?
I'm not sure.
One thing I know is that
Joan of Arc is not Noah's wife.
- Then who is Noah's wife?
- I don't know, Ted.
But I do know we're in serious trouble.
Listen to this:
"Express to the class
how an important historical figure...
"... from each of your time periods...
"... would view the world
of San Dimas, 1988."
We're in danger of flunking
most heinously tomorrow.
- Hi, Bill. Want a ride?
- Sure, Missy.
I mean, Mom.
- Your stepmom is cute.
- Shut up.
Remember when she was a senior
and we were freshmen?
I'll be right back as soon as I get my books.
- What are you doing home, Dad?
- I'm looking for my keys.
You haven't done anything with them?
No, sir.
I spoke to your principal today.
- He said you're failing history.
- Me and Bill...
He also said that if you fail history,
you flunk out of school.
You know what that would mean,
don't you?
That I would have to go
to Oates Military Academy, sir.
I spoke to Col. Oates this morning.
He's anxious to meet you.
Dude, we gotta pass,
otherwise there's no more band.
- Why?
- My dad's sending me to military school.
Where?
Alaska.
It is time. Their separation is imminent.
Be excellent to each other.
Party on, dude.
Okay, Ted, George Washington.
- One: The father of our country.
- Two: Born on Presidents' Day.
Three: The dollar-bill guy.
You ever made
a mushroom out of his head?
Alaska.
Okay.
Had wooden teeth, chased Moby Dick.
That's Capt. Ahab, dude.
Wait. Remember Disney World?
- Hall of Presidents?
- Yeah, good. What did he say?
"Welcome to the Hall of Presidents. "
Hi. I brought you guys some food.
It's your mom, dude.
How's it going?
Bad.
We're destined to flunk
most egregiously tomorrow.
And I am destined to end up
at Oates Military Academy.
And then we will never start our band.
Good.
- What are you guys studying, anyway?
- History.
Mr. Ryan?
Tell him hi.
Why don't you guys take a dinner break?
Thanks, Dad.
Now your dad is going for it
in your own room.
Shut up.
- Your stepmom is cute, though.
- Shut up.
- Remember when I asked her to the prom?
- Shut up!
1275.
Okay, the lady in that car over there...
...said that Marco Polo was
in the year 1275.
It's not just a water sport. I knew it.
Excuse me.
When did the Mongols rule China?
I don't know. I just work here.
- You want to try the Thrifty Mart?
- Sure.
Not bad.
Greetings, my excellent friends.
Do you know
when the Mongols ruled China?
Perhaps we can ask them.
Bill S. Preston, Esquire.
And Ted "Theodore" Logan.
Gentlemen...
I'm here to help you
with your history report.
- What?
- How?
I hate that part.
- Bill.
- What?
Strange things are afoot at the Circle K.
Dudes, you guys are going to
go back in time!
You are going to have the most excellent
adventure through history.
- Who are you guys?
- We're you, dude!
No way.
- No way.
- Yes way!
We know how you feel.
We didn't believe it either
when we were you...
...and we-us said
what we-us are saying right now.
Okay, wait.
If you guys are really us...
...what number are we thinking of?
Sixty-nine, dudes!
- Look, dudes, we gotta go.
- Yeah, we gotta get back to the report.
Rufus!
Listen to this dude Rufus.
He knows what he's talking about.
Right. And, Ted,
give my love to the princesses.
- Who?
- You'll see.
Gentlemen, is everything all right?
Yeah, except how come
the number we dialed...
Don't forget to wind your watch!
Thanks, Rufus.
Catch you later, Bill and Ted!
Dude, are you sure
we should be doing this?
Ted, you and I have witnessed
many things...
...but nothing as bodacious
as what just happened.
Besides, we told ourselves
to listen to this guy.
What if we were lying?
Why would we lie to ourselves?
How are you going to help us?
Yeah, are you going to call someone
and get the answers?
Gentlemen, we're going to do
a lot more than that.
Excellent.
Brace yourselves, amigos.
Gentlemen...
We're history.
Rufus, where are we, dude?
These are the circuits of history,
gentlemen.
They'll take us
to any point in time we wish.
How?
Modern technology, William.
- That was most unprecedented, Rufus.
- Yeah.
But where are we, Rufus?
Austria, 1805.
The French have just invaded.
Bill, check it out!
We're in the middle of a war, dude!
Amigos, time to depart.
How's it going, dude?
Now where are we, dude?
It's my house.
Rufus, can we go
anywhere we want at any time?
You can do anything you want...
...as long as you remember this:
No matter what happens...
...you must get to that report. Got it?
All right, amigos...
...that book will give you the number
of anyplace you want to go.
Now, most important,
no matter what you do...
...no matter where you go,
that clock, the clock in San Dimas...
...is always running.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
All right, time for me to go.
- What do you mean, Rufus?
- Yeah, aren't you coming with us?
Gentlemen, you're on your own.
- Ted?
- What?
This has been a most unusual day.
- It's Napoleon.
- Who?
The short dead dude
from our history review.
I have a most excellent idea.
Grab his legs. We gotta get him inside.
I think I figured out
a way to pass our report.
How?
We got one historical figure here,
maybe we can go back and get more.
Yeah.
Deacon, you have to watch this guy.
His name is Napoleon.
He is a very famous French dude.
We've decided to collect
other important figures from history...
...for an oral report we are doing.
While we are gone,
you are not to let him out of your sight.
Here is some money.
Take him to the movies or something.
Napoleon?
I am Bill.
We'll take you back to France after
you tell us what you think of San Dimas.
- This is Ted's little brother, Deacon.
- Hi.
He'll take care of you.
- Ready, Ted?
- Ready, Bill.
Let's go back into history.
This should be most triumphant.
I want to speak with you, son.
Alone, please, Bill.
All right, sit down.
What am I going to do with you?
Great.
You lose my keys, you fail history.
You spend all your time
with your loser friend...
...planning a band that will never happen.
You're not to leave this house
until tomorrow morning.
Yes?
Capt. Logan, this is Dep. Van Halen
down at the station.
Dep. Van Halen?
I'm new, dude... sir.
Look, we found your keys...
... and if you want them,
you better come and get them.
When I get back from the station,
I want you packed and ready to go. Got it?
We are in serious trouble.
My dad already signed me up.
My plane leaves tomorrow night.
That's only if we fail, dude.
No way!
Okay, we got Sigmund Frood,
Beeth Oven...
Is there one for the Western Movement
in America in the 19th century?
Yeah.
Well, then...
Let's reach out and touch someone.
How's it going, Old West dude?
This is just like Frontierland.
Yeah, but you can get shot here.
- So just try to act natural.
- Okay.
- Howdy, partner.
- Howdy.
- Watch out for the horse crap.
- Thanks, dude.
- I'm totally thirsty.
- Me, too.
Two beers, please.
- He didn't even card us, dude.
- Yeah, we'll have to remember this place.
Who should we take with us?
- Who's he?
- He's Billy the Kid.
He's famous, dude. Let's bag him.
I need two men.
Who's with me?
We're with you, Billy the Kid.
Here's the deal. What I win, I keep.
What you win, I keep.
Sounds good, Mr. The Kid.
Dude, you've got to have
a poker face like me.
Three aces!
What the hell's going on here, Billy?
Are you a-cheatin' us, Kid?
Cheating? Me?
Excellent!
Look, we're totally weak.
We can't possibly fight you.
However, how would you gentlemen like...
...free passes to Waterloo,
home of excellent waterslides?
Nice try, dude.
Come on.
- Look.
- It's the Goodyear blimp.
I can't believe they fell for that.
- Let's get 'em!
- Let's kill them!
Come on!
- You guys saved my life.
- Nothing doing, Billy the Kid.
- Where are we going?
- The golden age of civilization.
- Where?
- Ancient Greece, dude.
Don't worry, we'll bring you back
as soon as you talk at our report.
What?
Socrates?
- We know that name.
- Yeah. Look him up.
It's under "So-crates. "
Yeah.
"So-crates:
"'The only true wisdom...
"'... consists in knowing
that you know nothing. "'
That's us, dude!
Yeah!
- Let's bag him.
- Yeah.
How's it going?
I'm Bill. This is Ted.
We're from the future.
Socrates.
Now what?
I don't know.
Philosophize with him.
"All we are is dust in the wind," dude.
Dust.
Wind.
Dude.
Let's get out of here, dude.
All right!
Not bad, eh, So-crates?
- Where are we, dude?
- England, 15th century.
We are in most excellent shape
for our report.
Yeah, all we need is one
more speaker from Medieval.
Excellent.
Billy, you are dealing with
the oddity of time travel...
...with the greatest of ease.
Excuse me.
Do you know where
there are any personages...
...of historical significance around here?
Check it out!
Must be the castle of King Henry.
Let's go, dude!
Billy, guard the booth.
And watch So-crates.
Who should we get for Medieval?
How about that gnarly old goat dude?
I'm in love, dude.
Those must be the princesses
you told yourself about at the Circle K.
We gotta go.
It's a history report, not a babe report.
But, Bill...
Those are historical babes.
Okay.
You're the ladies' man.
How are we gonna meet them?
Excellent!
- Bill.
- What?
- These are heavy.
- Yeah.
Heavy metal.
- We better go find the princesses.
- Yeah.
Watch it!
Who turned out all the lights?
- What?
- I'm Darth Ted.
I'm Luke Bill.
And you're not my father! No!
Come on!
Beat you, I will, yes!
- I totally conquered you, dude!
- No way!
Come on!
I'll never rule the universe with you!
- Bill!
- What?
- We totally know how to sword fight!
- Yeah!
Search the castle! There might be more!
Get out of here!
Bogus.
Heinous.
Most non-triumphant.
Don't be dead, dude.
You killed Ted, you medieval dickweed!
Ted! You're alive!
Yeah! I fell out of my suit
when I hit the floor.
Fag!
Dude, you totally boned that dude
in the head!
He's a total bonehead!
He's a fat old man. There must be a way
to escape before the night falls.
But how?
What's that?
Those boys. I can't believe they're here.
How's it going, ladies?
You're the ones
we saw in front of the castle.
I am Ted of San Dimas.
And I bring to you a message of love.
From who?
From myself.
And what is this message you speak of?
Lyrics, dude. Recite them some lyrics.
O you beautiful babes from England...
...for whom we have
traveled through time...
...will you go to the prom with us
in San Dimas?
We will have a most triumphant time.
Way to go, dude.
It's Father!
What does your father want?
We're to be married to
two horrible old men today.
No way!
Will you help us escape?
Of course, babes.
How's it going, royal ugly dudes?
I'm the Earl of Preston.
And I am the Duke of Ted.
Put them in the iron maiden.
Iron maiden? Excellent!
Execute them.
Bogus.
We'll save you, babes!
Witches! Heretics! I saw them!
They fell from the sky!
Heretics!
They fell out of the sky!
They had fire in their eyes
and they had horns!
Off with their heads!
- Bill?
- What?
I believe our adventure through time
has taken a most serious turn.
- Billy!
- So-crates!
Let's go!
Guards! After them!
- So-crates!
- Bye, babes!
Catch you later, evil dudes.
Kill them! Guards!
Hurry up!
Out of the way!
Dial fast, dude!
The number you have
dialed is not in service at this time.
Please check your directory and dial again.
Party on, dude.
Okay, I got one! Let's go!
You guys stay here.
Where are we, dude?
I don't know.
- Sure do play excellent music.
- Most outstanding.
- It's you.
- Yeah. It's us.
Who are we?
I think they want us to say something.
What should I say?
Make something up.
Be excellent to each other.
Party on, dudes.
Good one, dude.
Got to get back to our report.
Yeah. We'd take you with us,
but it's a history report...
...not a future report.
Later.
- Let's get back and do our report.
- Good idea.
- Dude! Where are we going?
- I don't know! I think the booth's broke!
We've got to keep dialing San Dimas
until we get back and get Napoleon.
Behold.
The Zyggie Pig.
The single greatest ice-cream spectacle
known to man.
"Eat the Pig, eat the Pig,
zyggie, zyggie, zyggie, zyg!"
Embêtants!
It's ice cream.
You eat it.
It's good.
La glace.
Whatever. Just eat it.
All behold!
- He ate the Pig, thus proving that he's...
- A...
"Zyggie piggy!"
What's that?
I don't know.
Shit!
Where did we land now?
Dude, it's Sigmund Frood.
How much time we got left?
Tons. Why?
Extra credit, dude.
How's it going, Frood dude?
What is this? Let go of me.
What are you doing?
Was? Was ist los?
Come on, So-crates.
Welcome aboard, Miss Joan of Arc.
My name is Ted and this is Bill.
Want a Twinkie, Genghis Khan?
Say please.
Come on, guys. Jump him!
Candygram!
Yes, what can I...
We've got plenty of time,
but we don't have any more room left.
- Ted, we're out of control.
- What?
Next place we stop...
...we gotta try and figure out
what's wrong with the booth.
Bill, I think I got an idea what's wrong.
What?
The antenna's broken.
Yeah. All right.
Attends.
Crétin.
Come on, let's ditch him.
Attends!
- Excusez-moi, monsieur.
- Hold on there. Not so fast, buddy.
- "Buddy"?
- You ain't paid yet.
- Pay?
- Pay.
I don't want to see
you around here anymore! Beat it!
- Vous me connaissez, monsieur?
- Beat it, buddy!
Idiot!
Deacon!
Here is a treat to make
our minor prehistoric pit stop...
...a bit more enjoyable.
Why, thank you.
Thanks, guys.
I sure hope this works.
I think it's working, dude.
Just a little farther, I hope.
That's us. We're back in San Dimas!
Yeah. Only now it's not now,
it's last night.
Dude.
- What?
- Let's go talk to ourselves.
Excellent.
- What did we say, anyways?
- I don't know. Let's go find out.
Sixty-nine, dudes!
Look, dudes, we gotta go.
Listen to this dude Rufus.
He knows what he's talking about.
Right. And, Ted,
give my love to the princesses.
- Who?
- You'll see.
Gentlemen, is everything all right?
Yeah, except how come
the number we dialed for San Dimas...
...brought us here
instead of to tomorrow, Rufus?
Because in San Dimas
it is tomorrow, William.
You have to dial one number higher.
Yeah. Thanks, Rufus.
And hurry,
because you don't have much time.
What do you mean, Rufus?
We got 10 hours left.
You got two hours.
Ted, you forgot to wind your watch again.
And after you reminded yourself not to.
I better remind myself again.
Don't forget to wind your watch!
Thanks, Rufus.
Catch you later, Bill and Ted.
That conversation
made more sense this time.
- Watch the gonads, dude.
- Abe, you're too tall, man.
That's just the way I'm built.
Great, we made it!
Who's the señorita? She's cute.
It's his mom, dude.
Hi, guys.
Hi, Missy, I mean, Mom.
Miss Preston,
we'd like you to meet some of our friends.
Yeah, this is Dave Beeth Oven.
Sie sind so schön, Madame.
And Maxine of Arc, Missy.
Herman the Kid.
Bob Genghis Khan.
So-crates Johnson.
Dennis Frood.
And...
Abraham Lincoln.
It's nice to meet you all.
There are sodas in the fridge.
Can you give us a ride someplace?
Bill, I'm not taking you anywhere
until you do your chores.
Done!
This is the San Dimas Mall...
...and this is where
people of today's world hang out.
All right, everybody,
watch your step getting off.
Beeth Oven,
make sure you don't get sucked under.
Everybody get together.
Remember who your buddy is.
So-crates, watch out for your robe, dude.
Okay.
Follow me.
You got your Broadway down here,
you got your Sears over here.
The stratification of our society
is much like Marie-Antoinette's.
The few possess much...
... while the masses possess little
but their television sets.
This dichotomy led to a revolution...
... in which Antoinette
and her husband were beheaded.
Today, leaders are impeached
rather than beheaded.
Still, while in her day, Marie-Antoinette
said, "Let them eat cake... "
... perhaps today she'd say,
"Let them eat fast food. "
- Enjoy!
- Okay, look around. See what you think.
We'll be back as soon as
we find Napoleon, okay?
Come on, dude. We don't got much time.
Yes, but what do we eat?
You ditched Napoleon?
Do you realize you've stranded one of
Europe's greatest leaders in San Dimas?
He was a dick!
How are we going to find him?
Okay, wait.
If we were one of
the greatest generals in history...
...and we were stranded
in San Dimas for one day...
...where would we go?
Waterloo!
Eleven children, please. Are you okay?
We're going.
Come on.
Mon Dieu.
Qu'est-ce que c'est ça?
Buddy, you're holding up the line!
- Sacrebleu.
- Come on, buddy.
Fantastique!
Come on, Napoleon.
Everybody's waiting for us at the mall.
Why be soft and flabby
when you can be firm and trim?
When you can have a body that cries:
"Look at me! Admire me!"
With our specialized weight-training
and aerobics program...
... we can help you attain the kind of body
you've only dreamed of having.
All right, let's go, ladies!
You guys are looking great! Okay!
Jumping jacks! Up!
You a musician?
Here. Try this.
What is this?
- Oh, my God.
- What are they doing?
Yeah, don't you think? Look at his sandals.
I don't believe his clothes.
- Weird.
- They're coming over to sit down.
Hi.
I'm Billy.
This here is So-crates.
- Socrates.
- We're from history.
Hello. I'm Dr. Freud,
but you may call me Siggy.
Oh, my God.
You both seem to be suffering
from a mild form of hysteria.
- God!
- You are such a geek.
Way to go, egghead.
- Geek.
- What is a geek?
I need help. I got a live one here.
Okay, I need the Lincoln hat
and the stupid beard back.
You don't understand.
I'm Abraham Lincoln.
Yeah, right. Come on, mister!
- It's my hat and my beard!
- Come on!
Keep it up! You're looking great!
- Take it easy there!
- Stop! Hold it right there!
Cut that guy off!
Stop him!
- No, Sig! Over here!
- Excuse me, miss.
- Move.
- Pardon me.
- I demand einen lawyer.
- Don't get smart, buddy. Let's go.
There they are!
All right, come on, grandpa.
Bogus!
That's enough.
Mom, can't you go any faster?
I want to know
why you claim to be Sigmund Freud.
Why do you claim I'm not Sigmund Freud?
Why do you
keep asking me these questions?
Tell me about your mother.
God.
- Would you like a couch to lie on?
- No, I don't want a couch to lie on.
- All right. What's your name?
- Abraham Lincoln.
That's L-I-N-C-O-L-N.
I know how to spell "Lincoln. "
What's your birthday, Mr. Lincoln?
February 12, 1809.
Everything is different, but the same.
Things are more moderner than before.
Bigger...
... and yet smaller.
There's computers.
Take your time.
San Dimas high-school football rules!
I can't believe my dad arrested them all.
What are we going to do?
You go in and talk to your dad.
I'm gonna scope the place out.
Missy, I mean, Mom,
please keep an eye on Napoleon.
Stay.
- Lock him up with the rest of the wackos.
- I am a lawyer, you know.
- Dad!
- You pack your bags.
- What?
- You're going to military school.
- But, Dad...
- I don't wanna hear it!
You go home and you pack your bags now!
- How'd it go?
- Bad.
Our historical figures are all locked up
and my dad won't let them out.
Can we get your dad's keys?
We could steal them,
but he lost them two days ago.
If only we could go back in time
to when he had them and steal 'em then.
- Why can't we?
- 'Cause we don't got time.
We could do it after the report.
Good thinking, dude!
After the report,
we'll time travel back to two days ago...
...steal the keys and leave them here!
- Where?
- Don't know. How about behind that sign?
That way, when we get here now,
they'll be waiting for us.
- See?
- Yeah!
So, after the report, we can't forget
to do this, otherwise it won't happen.
But it did happen!
It was me who stole my dad's keys!
That's exactly it. Come on.
- Mom?
- Yes?
- Can you please bring the car around back?
- Sure.
Come on. We've got some
historical figures to rescue.
Over and out.
How are we going to get past my dad?
- You got a tape recorder at home?
- Yeah.
- Remember to get the tape recorder.
Set a timer on it for...
2:13.
- Got it?
- Got it.
- What am I going to say on it?
- Dad!
Hey, Dad!
It's you, dude.
- Ted?
- I'm over here.
Yeah, this way!
Look! Check it out.
"Dear Bill and Ted.
"Good luck on the report.
"Sincerely, Bill S. Preston, Esquire
and Ted 'Theodore' Logan. "
That was nice of us.
"P.S.
"Duck!"
Excellent work, dude.
- Way to go!
- Come on.
- Merci.
- People, time is of the essence.
I ask that you all work together
so that we can get down to the car.
Very quiet. Quiet!
Against the wall, everybody, please.
Single file.
- Hurry up, Billy.
- How do we get out of here?
Over here, Dad!
Down here!
Way to go, dude. You stalled him.
What else do I say?
And now, opening for Iron Maiden,
Wyld Stallyns!
Come on, put your back into it.
What in the hell do you think you're doing?
- Trashcan. Remember a trashcan.
- Trashcan? What are you talking about?
Get this thing off me!
Sorry, Dad,
but we got to go pass our history report.
By the way, I found your keys.
Where are you? Get this off me!
In conclusion, I think Abraham Lincoln
would be most impressed...
... with the world of San Dimas.
I know I am.
Down the hall, to the left. Quiet.
And I'm sure I speak
for Mr. Ward and Mrs. Rowe...
...when I say that your reports
were very entertaining...
...and very informative for all of us.
It seems we may be
one report short today...
...so we'll leave just a bit early.
But once again, I want to thank you all
for your very hard work.
Who turned out the lights?
Hello, San Dimas.
Please welcome,
for the final report of the afternoon...
... from all throughout history...
... some of the greatest people
who have ever lived...
... in their 1988 world tour!
How's it going?
I'm Billy the Kid.
I'd like you all to put your hands together.
Now, my good friends...
...Bill S. Preston, Esquire...
...and Ted "Theodore" Logan.
Thank you.
Hello, San Dimas High.
Mr. Ryan,
fellow distinguished classmates...
...teachers, babes.
- Our first speaker was born in 470 B.C.
- Hi! Long time no see.
A time when much of the world...
...looked like the cover of
the Led Zeppelin album Houses of the Holy.
We were there. There were many steps
and columns. It was most tranquil.
He is sometimes known
as the father of modern thought.
He was the teacher of Plato,
who was in turn the teacher of Aristotle.
And like Ozzy Osbourne, was repeatedly
accused of corruption of the young.
And since he doesn't speak English...
...my friend Ted, here,
is gonna interpret for him.
So please welcome,
to tell us what he thinks of San Dimas...
...the most bodacious
philosophizer in ancient Greece...
...Socrates!
...totally out of control.
I've got a good idea where he gets it.
If you and your wife used a little discipline,
your son wouldn't be such a bad influence.
Is discipline your key to success with Ted?
Yes, it is! He's going to
an Alaskan military school.
...loves you best...
...in all the world.
What are they doing up there?
He also loves baseball.
Therefore, Ted's father's
own fear of failure...
...has caused him
to make his son the embodiment...
...of all of his own deepest anxieties
about himself.
And hence,
his aggression transference onto Ted.
Okay?
Yes.
Thank you very much, Sigmund Freud.
No, just got a minor Oedipal complex.
It is indeed a pleasure
to introduce to you...
...a gentleman we picked up
in medieval Mongolia...
...in the year 1269.
Please welcome,
the very excellent barbarian...
...Mr. Genghis Khan!
This is a dude who, 700 years ago...
...totally ravaged China,
and who, we are told, two hours ago...
...totally ravaged
Oshman's Sporting Goods.
A most bodacious soldier and general...
...Miss Of Arc totally rousted
the English from France.
And then she turned this dude,
Dauphin, into a king.
And all this by the time she was 17.
Je vais remporter un triomphe terrible...
... en Russie...
... avec mes waterslides.
The music of Ludwig von Beethoven.
As you can see,
Genghis very much enjoys Twinkies...
...because of the excellent sugar rush.
He also loves billiards.
Beethoven's favorite works include
Mozart's Requiem...
... Handel's Messiah,
and Bon Jovi's Slippery When Wet.
To improve on the condition of her armies,
Joan of Arc plans on instituting...
...a full-scale aerobics program
on her return to France.
I don't think it's going to work.
Triomphe, Napoléon!
He loves...
He loves San Dimas.
And now, for our last speaker.
One of the greatest presidents
in American history...
...Mr. Abraham Lincoln.
Fourscore and...
...seven minutes ago...
...we, your forefathers...
...were brought forth upon
a most excellent adventure...
...conceived by our new friends...
...Bill...
...and Ted.
These two great gentlemen...
...are dedicated to a proposition...
...which was true in my time...
...just as it's true today.
Be excellent to each other.
And...
...party on, dudes!
No way!
Thank you, San Dimas High.
We want more!
Intro.
I'm Bill S. Preston, Esquire.
What's up, Ted?
We traveled through time.
I mean, we met lots of great leaders
and we got an A plus on our history report.
And look at us. Nothing's different.
Maybe it's time we get Eddie Van Halen.
Maybe we should start
learning how to play.
Maybe you're right.
Hello again, my excellent friends.
Congratulations on
passing your history report.
Rufus, the babes.
We looked all over England for you.
Where'd you get those savory clothes?
Rufus introduced us to
a place called the mall.
And something called credit cards.
I got them out of England just before
they had to marry those royal ugly dudes.
Way to go, Rufus.
How can we ever thank you, Rufus?
You can start by signing this for my kids.
- Why?
- They're big fans of yours.
- What?
- Everyone is.
Wyld Stallyns' music has become
the foundation of our whole society.
No way!
Yes way!
In fact, I believe you were there.
That futuristic place with the domes?
And the totally excellent music.
They totally worshipped us there.
I know.
That's why I was sent to make sure
you passed your history report.
If you guys were separated, it would have
been disastrous for life as we know it.
You see, eventually, your music
will help to end war and poverty.
It will align the planets
and bring them into universal harmony...
...allowing meaningful contact
with all forms of life...
...from extraterrestrial beings
to common household pets.
And...
...it's excellent for dancing.
Why don't you have the ladies sign as well,
would you please?
- After all, they are in the band.
- They are?
Excellent!
Where are you going, Rufus?
I got a surprise for you.
Here.
That's to help you
as you start your new band.
Thanks, Rufus.
I just have one further humble request:
If I might be so honored to jam with you?
- Do you know how to play, Rufus?
- I play a little.
- Most outstanding.
- Let's jam.
- Bill, my friend?
- Yes, Ted, my friend?
This has been a most excellent adventure.
- One.
- Two.
One, two, three, four!
They do get better.