Synchronized to this version by M.D.
[Don't know who the author is]
Silverlake
Animal Rescue
That one!
Here, boy.
You're heavy!
and slobbery!
There.
You're a good boy.
You're my good boy!
5 years later...
Hello!
Honey, I don't have much time!
Daddy?!
Are you okay?
Some thing's come up at work,
honey...
Daddy is not going to be
home for a while.
I don't understand.
You can't go back to the house Penny,
Okay?
What's happening?
It's alright.
You won't be alone.
You have Bolt.
I've altered him.
He can protect you now!
BOLT
Everything is positioning nicely.
There he is, Dr. Calico!
Any luck getting our guest
to spill his guts?
Oh, his guts will spill!
One way or another.
Never! I'll never talk.
Daddy!
You're beginning to irk me, professor.
I am irked and that will not do!
Has the package arrived?
I think it might make our dear friend, a bit more communicative.
I'm sending an agent to pick it up.
Gorgeous, have him bring it to me on the first flight?
Bolt, let's go!
We only need the girl!
- What?
- Where is Calico?
I'm not talking to you!
Bolivia, Bolivia,
Calico is in Bolivia.
Near Lake Rocriagudo!
Lake Rocriagudo,
I should have known!
Come on, Bolt,
Let's go.
Bolivia,
there's a flight leaving in 10 minutes.
Bolt, zoom zoom!
Bolt, fetch.
Puppy!
Good boy!
Airport!
Bolt, speak!
Okay, okay...
Good job, buddy.
Mission accomplished!
That's a keeper!
It's alright, tough guy.
You got them all.
Don't worry, Bolt.
You've saved the day again.
Good boy!
Airport!
Bolt, speak!
- Boom mike!
- It's a boom mike.
That's sloppy!
The dog could have seen it.
He could have seen that.
Uh, who cares
if the dog sees a boom mike?
Forgive me for answering a question with a question!
But, who are you?
Mindy Parker,
from the network.
Of course... Let me ask you,
Mindy from the network.
What do you see here?
- The dog?
- The dog, she says.
O, Mindy... poor, poor Mindy!
Am I... missing something?
You're missing everything, Mindy.
You see a dog...
I see an animal,
who believes with every fiber of his being...
every fiber...
That the girl he loves
is in mortal danger.
I see a depth of emotion on the face of that canine,
the likes of which has never been captured on screen before.
Never, Mindy from the network.
We jump through hoops to make sure that Bolt believes everything is real.
It's why we don't miss marks.
It's why we don't reshoot.
And it's we why most certainly,
do not let the dog see boom mikes.
Because, Mindy from the network...
if the dog believes it
the audience believes it.
Wow, okay, you want reality?
Here you go chief.
The show's too predictable
The girl's in danger, the dog saves her from the creepy English guy.
We get it, there's always a happy ending.
And, our focus groups tell us,
that 18 to 35 year-olds are unhappy.
They're not happy with happy.
So, maybe you should, I don't know,
spend a little less time worrying about the dog's method acting,
and more time into
figuring out how to stop
20 year-olds in Topeka
from changing the channel.
Because if you lose so much as
half a ratings point, so help me,
I will fire everyone in this room,
starting with you.
How's that for real?
There... perfect.
You saved me again, Bolt.
It's okay,
it's nothing.
No more bad guys.
Ah? Are you hungry?
You got it, Bolt.
No one's going to hurt me.
Bolt look at me!
I'm fine, see?
Come here buddy! Come here!
Go get it Bolt!
Go get it!
Yeah, that one's no fun either.
Huh, well what do we have here?
Mr. Carrot.
Oh, Bolt!
You know I have to go.
Yeah, you're my good boy.
And there she is, my little superstar.
Let's get to that Teen Vogue cover shoot.
Mom, I want to take Bolt home this weekend.
- Well, I, um...
- Ah, that would be nice, that would be great...
A little girl and her dog.
Nothing better than that.
So I can bring Bolt?
As your friend, I say, Yes, absolutely,
but as your agent...
I have to remind you,
this is Bolt's world.
He has to stay right here, okay.
- Let's go!
- But, he never gets to be a real dog
and it would only be for the weekend,
and I just want...
But, you know what, it's a fair question,
Let's do this, let's put a pin in it?
Boop, pin in. There you go.
Now... Let's let that hang there for a bit
and then we'll address that when we've thought things through.
Okay, Good enough for everybody?
Smiles all around? Let's get out of here, come on.
But I don't need to think it through.
I want to take Bolt home.
Look at this face...
I have a little girl at home,
love of my life.
I will do anything for her.
And I would trade her for you in a heartbeat.
...True story.
That reminds me, we need to be getting over to wardrobe,
quick, quick, let's go.
And so, the dog thinks this is all real??
Oh yeah, you're new. Guy never leaves the set.
It's unbelievable. Whenever I get a chance,
it's the perfect way to unwind.
I like to start with an evil laugh.
Hello, hairballs!
You may have won today Bolt,
But, in the end...
We will get your little Penny.
Not likely, cat.
For you have chosen to follow the path of evil,
and ultimately, it will destroy you
along with your fiendish puppet master.
- Wow.
- I know, right. Watch this.
She's a goner, dog.
The green-eyed man has a plan,
and soon, he will execute it.
- Yeah. And then he will execute her.
- Nice.
I would super-bark you both back into the hole that you crawled out of,
but I need you alive,
because I've got a little message
for you to take back to your green-eyed man.
You tell him,
that his old friend, Bolt...
Is it long?
Is what long?
- The message!
Is it a long message?
Because I have a horrible memory.
I'll make it brief, all right?
You tell him, that I said that I'm gonna...
You know what? Why don't we do this?
You remember the first half of the message,
and then I remember the second,
then we can pass it on to the green-eyed man together.
I don't care how the message is translated.
Allright? Just do it! Okay?
Tell the green-eyed man
that I will not sleep, I will not rest,
until my Penny is safe
from his evil clutches.
You tell the green-eyed man...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
way too many words,
I was like "What?"
and then I was like "Huh?"
and then I got a little bored.
Something about clutches.
Anyway, I'll do my best.
Ciao!
By the way, huge fan,
love it, love you, gotta go, thank you.
Get back here, you sick, revolting...
Dogs!
Cats!
I'll never let them get you, Penny.
You ready, Bolt?
Let's lighten out camera three,
ready four.
Go four.
And, driver!
Thanks, Larry.
Alright, Scooter. Light the grate.
Ready on the rubber bars.
And track with them!
The Calico supercomputer.
If we can access it
we can finally learn where they are keeping my father.
The weapon's hot!
Heat vision time.
Bolt, stare!
Now!
Nice move.
Come on, come on.
Such devotion, it brings tears to my eyes.
Calico!
Your father's discoveries could be of great use to our
organization.
I'm sure, he'll be more accommodating,
now that I've got
his lucky Penny.
Bolt!
World domination is within my grasp.
How did your focus groups feel about cliff-hangers?
You asked for unhappy 18 to 35 year-olds.
I give you,
unhappy 18 to 35 years-olds.
Bolt, it's okay.
I'm fine!
Whoa, whoa, guards stop her!
- Hey, Hey!
- Hold on!
- Listen to him. He needs to know that I'm okay.
- Nope, you're not okay.
You've been kidnapped by the fiendish
Dr. Calico.
At least, that's what the dog needs to think.
Just imagine, close your eyes and
just imagine how excited he will be
when he saves you tomorrow, okay.
But, he will be freaking out all night,
just let me...
Whoa, wait a second,
what's that behind your ear?
Is that a... Yes, it is,
it's a pin.
Let's do this. Let's take the pin
and put it in this conversation.
Boop!
And we will not take it down, no ma'am,
until this matter is resolved.
But I just...
- You know what that reminds me of...
the "DVD" release junket.
Let's get going, it's a big push.
Alright people, let's give her some air.
Let's not crowd the talent.
I've been working on my evil laugh.
It really is an evil laugh.
Here's the thing, you're not ready
for the evil laugh
you could do a chuckle,
like a mildly upset chuckle,
after my evil laugh. Never mind...
Hey, Bolt!
Bolt, come back!
I'm too late.
Bolt, help!
- I am coming, Penny.
Hold on, Penny.
Hold on.
Bolt, help!
Penny!
Bolt! here Bolt!
...
Okay Bolty. Okay, stay cool.
You're cool, Bolty.
The green-eyed man!
Penny... Penny?
Penny!
Target acquired!
It ends here!
Penny!
Penny! ...
They moved her!
There's no time for formalities, brothers.
My person is in danger.
And I, I...
What are you doing?
- I'm sorry.
Do you want to sniff mine first?
- What?
Not from around here, are you?
- Hey, stop it!
This is serious!
Hey there, are you lost, sweetie?
Wait.
Why can't I bend these stupid bars?
Yo, Buddy!
You got your head stuck
pretty good, huh, guy?
Hey, guys. Come here.
Check this out. He's got his melon stuck.
Yeah, that is one stuck melon.
Hey, hey, buddy.
Take it easy, slow down!
I will not take it easy, pheasant.
I am missing my person.
Hey, buddy. Relax. Like this:
Turn and pull. Turn and pull.
Forget about it, you'll be out in no time.
What are these things?
They've weakened me.
Whoa. Well, they're Styrofoam packing peanuts.
- Styrofoam!
This has the green-eyed man written all over it!
Have you seen the man with the green eye?
You know, I gotta say something,
if I could say something here
You look familiar.
Joey, look at this guy's mug.
Yeah. You know? I could have sworn that
I've seen this guy before.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
I gotta tell ya!
I never forget a face!
He never does.
Yeah, yeah. He's real good with the faces and such.
Listen, listen, the man with the green eye,
tell me what you know, birds.
- I know this dog!
- Yeah, yeah. Me, too!
I've got to remember.
It's gonna kill me! Hold on...
No, I don't know. I, I, I thought I know.
Hey, did you ever hang out down on
14th street with a stray named Kelvin?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Kelvin, the Labrador.
- What?
You gotta give me something here,
cause this is redonkulous.
absolutely redonkulous!
- Capisch redonkulous.
Do you know what that means?
Ah, you pigeons are useless.
I need someone on the inside,
someone close to the green-eyed man.
A cat!
- Who, a cat?
Yeah, a cat, and when I find him...,
when I find him, I will make that cat wish
that he'd never been born.
He-he, I think we know just the cat.
Right on time, Saul. Come on in.
Okay, Saul, nice work.
Let's see if we can find some mustard next time,
okay, babe?
- Yes, Mittens. Thank you, Mittens.
Oh-Ho. Is that an everything bagel, Ted?
Attaboy!
- Good day, Mittens.
Louie!
What is this?
You hear this, Louie?
I'm starving here!
And when the old stomach starts talking,
it ain't talking to me,
it's talking to the... claw.
- Not the claws. please.
I'm holding these boys back the best that I can,
The thing is, it's not up to me
the stomach's got a direct line to these babies
and I'm picking up a lot of chatter.
So I'll talk to the claws,
but in exchange, next week...
all your food comes to me.
- But, that's not our deal!
I give you half,
you give me protection.
That's our deal!
- Yeah, well the deal just expired!
Now, get lost.
- Mark my words, Mittens,
one day, someone's gonna stand up to you,
someone's gonna teach you a lesson.
Yeah, I'm really scared now...
You should be!
Aaah... Okay... You!
Where is she?
Aaah,... who?
- You know why I'm here.
Aahh...
- Where is she?!
Okay, okay, look buddy,
I - I don't know what you're getting at, but...
Come on, Mittens. Tell the guy where she is.
Tell the dog, make him happy.
- Yeah, yeah, come on, Mittens. Tell him.
Joey, Vinnie, Bobby, my boys!
Will you tell this crazy canine
that he's got the wrong cat?
You got her, pal.
- That's her.
She's the one.
- That is definitely the right cat!
Looks like we're going to do this the hard way.
Whoa, aaah, you're crazy man?
Hey, Joey, did we go too far on this?
Are you kidding?
This is the best day of my life.
You work for the man in black,
who works for the man with the green eye.
They've taken, Penny.
Where is she?!
I don't know what you are talking about!
- This is becoming tiresome, cat!
In fact, I feel a yawn coming on!
Okay, okay. I'll talk.
I know where Penny is!
They have her. Yes,  the man in black
and the guy with the blue eyes!
Blue eyes?!
Ah... Oh, green, yes.
The one green eye.
You just can't stop lying.
Can you cat? It's in the genes.
It's gross!
I know, it's disgusting.
I disgust myself.
Huh, Hollywood!
But, if you put me down
I'll show you where she is.
Waffle World
You know, I hope you appreciate the risk I'm taking here.
Every bone in my evil cat body is
telling me not to betray the trust
of the green-eyed man.
Okay, this is a top,
top secret map,
of the entire earth.
Now, we're over here, by the green lady with big torch,
and my boss has Penny locked up...
uh,... right, right over... here,
here, by the waffle with the sunglasses.
Now, all you need to do is get from here to there.
Well, I told you where to find her, so,
if you untie me, I'll just be on my way.
I'll release you, cat,
when we find Penny.
Excuse me?! That wasn't the deal! We had a deal.
Your deal just expired!
She said that to me 10 minutes ago.
The Irony!
OOo, perfect!
Hum, padlocked.
Listen, "Cujo",
I've got some pretty wicked claws under these mitts.
Do not...
I repeat, do not, make me bring out these bad boys.
It gets ugly.
What are you doing?
- Stay back!
If I stare at the lock really hard,
it will burst into flames and melt.
Now, I'm concerned on a number of levels.
Easy, watch it. Watch it though.
- Intruders!
Hey, slow down, you're scraping the fur off my...
Oh, boy, this thing is heavy.
- Put it down.
I forgot the keys.
I'll be right back.
Hey, lucky penny.
Thanks, now move your butt.
Okay! Up on your end
- You got yours...Yeah.
It's on the tip of my tongue.
I know that dog!
I'm telling you, Joey, Bobby, you guys
are looking at me like, you don't know...
I'm telling you, I know this dog!
I seen him somewheres.
You'll remember it tonight when you're dreaming
-That's, that's what will happen.
I've got some... good news!
- Really?
Yes, I do, I've just booked you
on the Tonight Show, lead guest.
That's right, I...which means, absolutely nothing,
if Bolt is still missing.
It's not even good news, like whatever so what,
it's the Tonight Show, like who even cares. I don't care.
It's okay, baby.
He must be so scared.
- Scared? This is Bolt we're talking about!
He's not scared of anything.
I bet Bolt would want you to do the Tonight Show!
It's a... Maybe not.
Bolt loves you very much, sweetie,
and you're here.
He couldn't have gone far.
WELCOME TO OHIO
So, uh, if you got superpowers, I guess that would make you what,
like some kind of super dog?!
That information's classified.
Ah, come on! Like, like,
what's your best power-your go-to move?
How about flying...?
Can you fly?
Don't be silly. I can't fly.
Okay, fine. If you don't have any powers,
you don't have any powers... what's it to me?
- I have super-bark.
- A super-bark, wow, you're kidding me?
Uh, what exactly does one do with a super-bark?
I really can't talk about it.
It's classified.
I suggest you pipe down
and take me to Penny.
You're awfully attached to this Penny character?
She's my person.
- Please, she's a person.
And if you ask me
the only good person, is a...
Styrofoam!
Tuck and roll.
Tuck and...what?
Oo, what, what is this
red liquid coming from my paw?
It's called blood, hero!
Do I need it?
- Yes!
So if you want to keep it inside your body where it belongs,
You should stop jumping out of trucks doing 80 on the interstate.
Yeah, well normally, I am a tad more indestructible.
It must have been the...
Styrofoam,
That stuff. It weakens me.
What are you doing? Put that down!
- That's it. I've had it with you. Untie me, pooch!
Or I'm gonna...Uh, uh, I'm going to seriously wound you,
I'm going to seriously wound you with this Styrofoam.
Are you mad? You don't know the power of Styrofoam
- Oh, you bet I'm mad, baby,
and I'm about to unleash it,
the power... of the Styrofoam.
Alright cat, you win.
I'll untie you.
That's a weird place to put a piano?!
Are we going to have anymore problems, cat?
- No, no, no more problems.
I'll take you to Penny.
What is that?
What?
- That!
Okay, you have 2 seconds to tell me what you've implanted in me, cat.
Poison, parasite?! Poison?
What, I just said that, didn't I?
See, I'm all discombobulated.
I can't think straight.
I don't believe this.
You're hungry!
Where is the antidote?
- Okay, okay, alright!
There's your antidote.
Food!
Go on, use the "dog face".
It's gonna be beautiful..
You know, beg.
Do the "dog face".
What, "the dog face", what does that mean?
Figures, I'm tied to the one dog on earth
who doesn't know how to beg, huh.
Okay, if you want the foo... ah, the antidote,
you're gonna have to do exactly what I say.
Nah, not likely.
You're a degenerate creature of darkness.
Yeah, yeah, granted, but that said, all I'm asking you to do is
tilt your head a little. You can do that, can't ya? Come on.
More, more, ...
- This is stupid!
No, no, come on, work with me a little on this.
You're almost there.
Oh, boy!
Okay, try it the other way.
There you go, Tilt up. Down. Now a little smile.
Nah, lose the smile. Drop your left ear.
Your other left.
Okay, the other way was better, drop them both.
Hold it right there.
And ever so slightly look up.
Soup is on, baby!
Ah, here you go.
Yes!
Ah, look at the little guy!
Get out of here, stupid cat!
Well, hello puppy! Did you come for
some of Grandma's butter bean dumplings?
You wait right there.
Look at you, you're quite the little actor.
I haven't eaten like this in ages.
Hey, look my stomach's distended! How great is that!
Yeah, well, don't get used to it, we gotta to keep moving.
But, this, this place is a goldmine,
What's wrong with you?
Every week, new RVs bring us new suckers,
who bring us new food.
Look around... it's perfect!
Do my eyes deceive me?
Is this some apparition that I see before me?
Or could it be...
My hero!
Oh my gosh, oh my gosh, oh my gosh.
You're Bolt, the super dog. Really very awesome!
Wait a minute,
you know this dog?
Oh, I do. He is very awesome.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, we've established that.
Who are you ?
- I'm Rhino.
Rhino, the hamster.
Well, my ancestry isn't all hamster,
I'm 1/16 wolf...
you know, with a little wolverine in there...
but, but, but, that's beside the point.
We have before us a legend.
Bolt... the super dog.
He can outrun speeding missiles, and...
burn through solid metal with his heat vision
OOo, ooh, and best of all,
he can obliterate large structures with his super-bark...
Wait a minute!
You've seen the super-bark?!
Have you been observing me?
- Oh, yeah, I watch you all the time!
That's incredible!
- Ah, it's nothing, really.
But, I'm always so vigilant...
No one could invade my detection.
You're a phantom.
- Uh, if you say so. Oh, hey, check it out.
Take a gander at this Bolt action.
Scary, huh?
It's like we're twins.
- Yeah... scary.
So, where's Penny?
- She was kidnapped by the green-eyed man.
Kidnapped? This is terrible,
She could be in grave...
Grave danger. I know,
but I've captured this cat.
An agent of the green-eyed man, I presume.
Oh ho, you presume correctly.
She's taking me to Penny.
You, you are vile vermin.
How do you sleep at night?
Penny's the most wonderful person ever, and she's all soft.
And he's awesome, and you're a monster!
How dare you disrupt their relationship with your evil...
Die, die...
- Whoa, whoa!
I can take her, Bolty.
- Easy, easy, Rhino.
You're right.
We need her alive!
Eh, we?!
- Yes. Bolt, I can be a valuable addition to your team.
I'm listening.
- I'm lightning quick.
I have razor-sharp reflexes and I'm a master of stealth.
Plus, I'll keep the cat in check.
The road will be rough!
- I have a ball.
There's no turning back.
- I guess I'll have to roll with the punches.
Easy won't be part of the equation.
- Promise.
Gotta warn you. We're going into the belly of the beast,
danger at every turn.
I eat danger for breakfast.
- Are you hungry?
Starving!
- Welcome, aboard!
Hey, can we talk for a second?
I don't know what's going on here, but
I'm just a little bit concerned
about the number of lunatics on this trip.
My limit is one.
- He's coming with us!
But I...  - Move it prisoner,
we're losing daylight.
I agree.
Now, we need to find a fast set of wheels.
Oh, I've got a better idea.
Follow me.
Okay, so what we do here is give the target
a quick fly over, we adjust the trajectory
and land dead center.
Am I missing anything, Rhino?
Just the knowledge, that every minute spent in your
company becomes the new greatest minute of my life.
No, uh-uh, forget it!
How do you say, "No way, I'm not doing this!" in crazy?
Calm down, cat. You're with me.
- That's the problem!
Oh, would you relax! Every time he did this
on the magic box, it was awesome!
Magic what?
You know, the magic box people stare at.
OOo, wait does this magic box have moving pictures on it?
- Yeah, and Bolt's pictures are the best!
Bolt's pictures. Of course, he's a...
Oh no, oh no. Stop, wait!
- Let it begin! Let it begin! Let it begin...
- Wait, you are not a super...
What are you doing?
Mittens!
Mittens, take my paw.
I need you alive.
You're crazy.
Stay away from me.
Take my paw, I'll save you.
- No, you won't.
You're not really a...
Bolt!
Saboteur!
Ouch! You're moron! stop it! I'm trying to help him.
Help him? Yeah, right!
Don't' worry Bolt,
I'll stop her!
I can't hold him.
Let go, you monster!
- Bolt!
The real world hurts, doesn't it?
But, you wouldn't know about that, would you?
Get down here, cat!
We don't have time for this.
I'll get a ladder.
Look genius, you're part of a TV show.
Do ya know what that is, TV?
I mean, do you really that you were born
with a birthmark, and the exact
shape of a lightning, Bolt?
It's my mark of power, cat.
It's a mark of a makeup artist, dog.
You're ridiculous. Now, get down here!
No! - Mittens, so help me, I will super-bark you out of that tree.
Yeah, Go nuts. Let's see how that works out for you.
- You leave me no choice.
Oh, the super-bark.
Scary, scary!
Yeah, that's really, really super.
It's not true. This is not true.
Wow, that one felt really super.
Wait!
No, it didn't.
Okay, okay. Uh huh, I get the idea.
You can stop now.
That's enough! Seriously, dog, stop.
I'm not kidding.
Would you stop?!
Uh...
Okay fine, you're a super dog.
Bolt, Be quiet please.
Bolt, we've got to run.
Bolt!
- Come here!
Lost Dog BOLT
Look who we found, young lady!
It's Bolt.
They found him.
- Bolt! - That's right, the little puppy dog.
That is not Bolt.
Well, that depends on how you look at it.
You know, when I was little,
I wanted a bicycle for my birthday,
but my parents, got me a baseball glove...
So, you know what I did? I pretended that the
baseball glove was a bicycle.
And I rode it to school everyday.
True story.
It's not him.
- I think it's him, I do.
Thank you.
Look, kid. It's time we were honest with you.
If we don't get back into production,
people will lose their jobs.
Good people, with families.
- But. Bolt's still out there.
We feel for you,
and the last thing that we want to do
is ask a little girl to make a
grown-up decision but it's come to that.
We need you to move on.
We need you to let Bolt go.
It...must...be made of Styrofoam.
No, no, no. It can't end like this.
Stop worrying, cat. I will get us out of here.
You can't, Bolt!
You've got nothing.
No super strength,
No super-bark!
and no heat vision.
Listen, okay. We are being taken to a
place where people go animal shopping.
And this is what humans do.
They always pick the cute ones.
The ones that look like you, Bolt!
But the rest of us,
never come back out.
I said I will get us out of here, alright?!
My hero!
Ring, ring! Who is it?
Destiny!
I've been expecting your call!
Oh, would you give it up already?
You're liquefying, whatever brains you have left.
I cannot be contained,
in any container.
You quitter, watch this!
I did it, I'm back!
That Styrofoam is wicked stuff.
Totally awesome! There's no truck I know of
that can keep in Bolt and Rhino.
Rhino, what are you doing here?
Oh, nothing. I enjoying an evening
stroll and thought that I would just
pop the latch on that containment unit.
You opened the door?!
- Yes, I did. Yoink.
That, that's great, Rhino. That's really good.
Alright, let's go get the prisoner back.
I can't do it.
What did you say?
I can't.
- What, who are you?
I am not... You just, just...
You are Bolt! - But I am Not.
Who single-handedly destroyed the
green-eyed man's under sea's labs? - Me
And who foiled his plan to infiltrate
the Olympics with gymnastic cyborgs?
Who, Bolt, who?
- Me. But, none of that...
You! You can Bolt!
Because all over this planet,
there are animals who feel like they can't.
Like a little hamster,
who once spent his days in an RV park,
dreaming of the day, when he too,
would save a little girl from danger
and be told...
"You did it. You did it, Rhino. You saved the day!"
They need a hero, Bolt!
Someone, who no matter what the odds,
will do what's right.
They need a hero,
to tell them sometimes...
the impossible can become possible.
If you're awesome!
Well, you're right about one thing, Rhino.
Mittens does need a hero.
I guess, I'll have to do.
Such modesty!
Now, who's going to save that cat?
Me!
- Who, tell me, who?
I'll get my ball.
Elmwood County Animal Shelter
Over there!
There it is!
This will be just like the time
you infiltrated Calico's arctic hover base.
It's not going to be exactly like that, Rhino.
We're going to have to do things a little differently.
Oh, stealth mode!
Goodnight, Esther!
- Night, Lloyd!
Lloyd!
Lloyd Spoon, you jump out and scare me
and I'm gonna pepper spray ya again.
I swear, it's like I work with toddlers.
The rat nullified.
I feel alive!
- Shhh!
There's a guard!
I'll snap his neck!
We need to get him away from that door.
Ball! - Ball! - Ball!
- Ball! - Ball!
Oh, just..., Can't you just..., I'm reading..., Ah...
Mittens?!
Bolt!?
Wh,,,wha,what are you doing here?
- I'm busting you out!
You - you came all the way back here, for me?
- Yeah.
But how'd you, I mean you don't have any superpowers!
I know.
- Really?!
Yeah.
- Wow!
Crazy day for ya, huh?
- It's been a lot, yes. It has.
Are you ready for this?
- No.
Me neither.
Hey, hey, hey, what is twisting your giblets?
What? Where did you get that hamster?
Give it, give it.
Wait!
- Initiating escape.
Hey, Lloyd, lock the door!
Lock the door!
Superbark!
Sweet Sister Frances!
What did you do to my new truck?
Sally Esther!
Both you boys need serious help.
- Spicy eyes!
We need a ride.
- Oo, I've got a big one!
You're welcome!
I can't believe it, my whole life
I've wanted to see a real live superbark.
You are legendary.
Mittens, if..., if I don't chase bad guys,
then what am I?
I mean, what...
Aah, don't worry about it! Being a regular dog
is like the greatest gig in the world, okay?
Look, I'm gonna let you in on a little secret.
A little secret. A little known cat secret.
You know why we hate dogs?
Because we want to be dogs.
We have dog complexes.
But, what do dogs do?
Slobber, sleep, chase tails, chew shoes.
You don't exactly need a master's degree.
You know, most dogs live in a place like this.
- And I don't know, they do things like...
- Out of this? But, but...
And this is your dog bowl.
- What is?
This! The entire floor.
If it hits the ground, it goes to the hound.
How cool is that?
And on cold nights, this and a ball of yarn.
Boy.
It doesn't get better than that.
You... seem to know a lot about these places.
Yeah, I did my time in one of these,
but I'm more of an alley cat at heart, you know?
sprung out first chance I got, never looked back.
Rhino is awesome!
He's so awesome!
He's beyond awesome,
he's... be-awesome.
He's a...
I am... be-awesome.
I think it's about time I introduce
you to the regular dog
piece d'resistance.
Go ahead, stick your head out.
- Why?
Just do it.
This is awesome!
And stick your tongue out!
This is totally awesome!
You should try it.
Ah, no thanks.
It's really a dog thing.
I have got so much to give,
I swear I do.
I may not have nine lives,
this one feels brand new.
Yes I've lived a good one.
I have tried to be true.
There are some things I never realized,
till I met you.
How the wind feels on
my cheeks,
when I'm barking at the moon.
There is no home like the one you've got,
cuz that home belongs to you.
Woo-Hoo! Here I come.
Woo-Hoo! Back to you.
There is no home like the one you've got,
cuz that home belongs to you.
Well I was in trouble, bad.
I was so confused.
I may not see in color babe,
but I sure can feel blue.
I have been a lot of things,
they may not all be true.
My experience was so mysterious,
till I met you.
Now the sun will rise
in the east,
but I'm barking at...
the moon.
There is no home like the one you've got,
cuz that home belongs to you.
Woo-Hoo! Here I come.
Woo-Hoo! Back to you.
There is no home like the one you've got,
cuz that home belongs to you.
Hey! Hey, Bolt... wake up!
Come on. I've got a surprise for ya.
Okay, no peeking.
Alright now, open them.
Bask in the glow, baby.
Just let me give you the grand tour.
This one is mine,
and this one is all yours
Mittens, I...
- Oo, I found this really soft pillow thing for you.
and get this, I found some Styrofoam and stuffed it inside,
which I thought it was kind of creative and ironic
you know what I mean?
Mittens, I don't think...
- Oo, check this out! Total privacy.
and completely soundproof.
Yeah, well, I don't think that...
- Okay, I lied, it's not completely soundproof, but you...
Mittens, I can't stay here!
What?
- We're one waffle away from Penny.
You're still going back to her?
Mittens, she's my person.
Look at me, Bolt! I'm real.
Now, how about this?
Is that real?
Does this look real to you,
or that? Is that real?
Or that, how about that Bolt?
She's an actress!
She's jsut pretending.
- Not, Penny!
There is no Penny!
She's fake.
No, you're wrong. She loves me!
No, Bolt, that's what they do, okay?
they act like they love you,
they act like they will be there forever
then one day they pack up all their stuff and move away,
and take their love with them,
and leave their declawed cat behind to fend for herself!
They leave her...
Wondering what she did wrong?
That... I'm sorry, Mittens, but...
Penny is different.
Then go!
Mittens, I...
- Get out of here, Bolt!
I never should have taken pity on you.
Aw, Mittens...
- Get out of here, Bolt!
You take care, Mittens.
That meat lover's pizza is not loving me back at all.
Hey, there, Rhino.
- Morning, cat.
Where's Bolt?
- He's a...
He's gone.
- Bolt... left?
Yea... But he a... he instructed me to tell you...that, em
He had to face the green-eyed man alone.
Whoa, where are you going?
- To Bolt!
But he doesn't need us anymore.
Trust me, I've seen it a million times before.
In the cold dark night, before the battle,
when the steely fangs of evil are sharpened,
and posed to strike
the hero must go and face his greatest challenge...
alone!
But, if Bolt's taught me anything,
it's that you never abandon a friend in times of need!
When your teammate's in trouble, you go.
Whether they ask or not, you go!
not knowing if you are coming back dead or alive...
He went the other way!
... you go! Knowing how deep the shrapnel
pierces your hide, you go!
Holywood
Penny!
No way, wow, Bolt!
I'm a really big fan of yours, brother.
I'm... Wait, this is my partner, Tom.
Tom say, What's up!
What's up?
- Wow!
Oh! And, this is our personal assistant, Billy,
who was supposed to wait up on the wire.
Bolt, I've admired you for such a long time and
there's always something that I wanted to tell you
if I ever get a chance to meet you, and now.
Billy, that was horrifying, What you just did.
Why don't you make yourself useful and get me some bread crumbs? Go!
Whole wheat is not the same as whole grain, Billy!
Not the same, Billy!
- Do not come back here with whole wheat! - Or pumpernickel, Billy
Okay guys, I really got to get going.
- Yeah, I know that your a busy dog.
But, if you have a second,
we would love to pitch you an idea for your show.
Tom's better pitching. I will let him take it from here.
Tommy's got the spotlight
Wait for it!
Aliens!
- O, snap!
Aliens?
- Audiences love aliens!
It willl be huge man, huge!
- Trust us!
I love it, tell you what,
if you guys can help me find Penny,
that girl from the television show,
I'd love to hear more about this aliens idea,
but on the way.
We got a nibble!
- Don't freak out, this is how you blew it with "Nemo".
And as the alien tractor beam is pulling Penny
toward the mothership, we fade to black.
And we have a great pop song for the end credits.
- Talk to your people.
We are ready to move on this.
He's so on board!
There it is!
The most terrifying place on earth.
BOLT
THURSDAYS 8pm
At long last, we have arrived at the belly of the beast.
The lair of the green-eyed man!
Wait up!
Hold up!
What's the problem?
I'm pumped!
Listen,... this may be really hard for you to really understand,
but, you see? Sometimes, things aren't what they seem to be...
and sometimes you think some things are really real,
and it's not, and sometimes...
All of my training has prepared me for this moment.
Die! Diiie!
Prepare yourself, foul man-beast,
for I will eat your pancreas with your spleen,
and then I will rip your liver out of your...
Oh, you're so cute with your little whiskers.
I had a hamster like you when I was a little kid
Bolt
Bolt!
You're okay!
You came back!
Oh, Bolt, I thought I lost you.
You're my good boy.
Good boy!
Okay, people, let's move it to
stage 7 and do it for real.
I miss him!
- I know honey.
I do, too!
First positions, please!
Okay, hold still for me sweetie.
15-take 1, mark.
And action!
Ah, professor!
I'd like to thank you for granting
us access to that
limbrithium mind of yours.
You know, I'd never do such a thing!
Unless, it was the only way to save your little girl's life.
Penny!
- Daddy!
Bolt!
Here, Bolt!
Your dog is nowhere near...
Get that dog!
Go! Go! It's okay, boy.
Come here!
Fire! Fire!
It's fire!
Hey, legs!
Mittens, what are you doing here?
Long story, short. I was tied to a delusional dog,
and dragged across the country.
But that is not important now!
The real question is:
What are you doing here, and why aren't you in there?
You were right about her, Mittens!
She a... well... it wasn't real.
No. Bolt, it is real!
I was in there just now...
I saw her face after you left.
She's broken-hearted.
She doesn't want just any dog.
She loves you!
She's your person, Bolt,
And you are her dog.
Bolt, you're just going to have to trust me on this
- Mittens, be quiet!
No, you need to hear this!
- No seriously, be quiet!!
What is it?
Penny!
Help!
Please... Help!
My gosh, the stage!
Yeah, you better run.
I'm on your six.
- What do we do?
Just make sure I get inside that building!
Bolt!
Is anyone still in there?!
- I don't know.
Coming through!
It's a good day to die!
- Not on my watch, rodent.
Bolt!
I knew you'd come back!
Bolt, zoom zoom!
Bolt, just go on out.
Go!
It'll be okay.
You're my good boy.
I love you!
Have you seen my daughter?
Has anyone seen my baby?!
Did you hear that?!
Quiet! Everyone be quiet!
It's the super-bark.
It's coming from over there!
- Come on, Go, go!
Over here, we've found them!
They're here, we've found them!
We need oxygen!
Coming through people, make a hole!
Bolt!
- Sweetie!
You got to be okay!
You'll be just fine.
She's stable, but we're going to take her to the hospital,
just to be safe!
Oh, I'm just so sorry this happened!
I can't imagine what you must be feeling!
No mother should ever have to go through something like this...
but, I promise you,
we're going to make this work for us...
I'm talking cover stories, production deals,
I'm talking executive producer credit.
This is so great.
We quit!
No, No.. let's not make any rash decisions!
Lets, stick a pin in it!
I'm afriad that your injuries where more severe
then we previously though, my dear.
We had to completely reconstruct your face!
Have a look.
Well, at least Calico won't be able to recognize me.
Calico!
Bolt!
Aliens!
That is totally unrealistic.
Absolutely, redonkulous.
- You could say that again.
Oh yeah... right there, over...
yeah, that's the spot.
Hey, silly doggie!
That's a keeper.
You want to go play outside?
You want to go outside?
Let's go!
Does that dog look familiar?
- Nope, I've never seen him before in my life.
There is no home like the one you've got,
cuz that home belongs to you.