I've got the vibes.
This thing is evil,
Man.
I got a bad feeling.
Shut up and keep moving.
Is big mistake.
Let it go, Man.
We set it down,
And we let it go.
Aah!
It's only a bloody monkey,
For christ's sake.
Now pick it up.
Listen,
You no pick up the cage,
You no get
The big dollars.
Ooh!
Grr!
Holy shit!
Don't move!
What are these buggers
Playing at?
He says that that monkey
Must be set free.
He says we must leave
This valley
And never return,
Or the evil spirits
Will exact their revenge.
Permit.
Look and see. Permit.
Permit!
Aah!
I'm a new zealand
Zoo official,
And this monkey is going
To new town.
No.
Oh! Aah! Aah!
No!
Move it!
Aah!
Start her up! Quick!
Hey!
Wait!
Drive, You buggers!
Ow!
Man, Wait.
Step on it!
Aah!
Ow!
The little bugger bit me.
Zingaya.
Zingaya!
You've got the bite.
There's... There's some
Dettol in the jeep.
Aw, Jeez! No!
No! What are you doing?!
Aah!
Zingaya.
Oh, Jee... Oh!
Aah! Oh!
Oh! Oh! Aah!
Zingaya!
Aah!
N...
Thank you.
HI, Paquita.
Good morning, Roger.
That's the lot.
Tell your dad I'll be
Round on thursday
With the saveloys.
That's a pretty dress,
Paquita.
See you later,
Alligator.
You like that boy,
Paquita?
Shuffle the cards.
We will see
If you and roger
Are destined
To be together.
Create his image
In your mind
And cut the cards.
Paquita,
I thought we'd seen
The last of this.
Whenever he come,
You start over again.
This...
Is you.
And this...
Is the man
Of your future.
But he doesn't look
Like roger.
It is not roger.
There will be
One romance,
And it shall last
Forever.
Romance. Puh.
What about money?
This man will enter
Your life...
In the near future.
And you will become...
Romantically entangled
With him
Almost immediately.
But who is it?
You will recognize
This man...
By the symbol...
Of the star...
And of the moon.
What is this?
Oh! No, Not that one.
Paquita,
We have a customer.
It is bad, Yes?
Oh, Nothing.
Paquita!
Uh, Just dropping off
Our order.
Um...
Mum says to pack
The biscuits on top,
Because she doesn't
Want any broken.
Uh, Actually...
I'll take
One of these now.
Sorry.
Santa maria.
Ooh.
I better be off,
Then.
Oh!
Woman: Lionel!
Lionel!
Woman on radio:
Good morning, Everybody.
Morning, Everybody.
Well, Now I'd like...
There's a beetle.
Eh?
There. Under the fridge.
Horrid little creature
Scuttled right in front of me.
I thought I told you
To spray this house!
The place is infested
With vermin.
I'll get on it
Straight away, Mum.
Lionel!
You'll be pleased
To know
That your mother has been
Voted treasurer elect
Of the w.L.W. L...
The wellington ladies
Welfare league.
Ah, That's great, Mum.
And on friday,
The president
Nora matheson
Is dropping by to offer
Her congratulations.
Wow. The president.
Oh, God!
Look at the state
Of this place!
All the windows
Will have to be polished.
Woman on radio: Whiter,
Brighter, Cleaner wash.
Look at this dust!
It's an inch thick!
You'll have to do
The silver.
I polished it
Last week.
And the drapes
Need cleaning.
Woman on radio:
Once a week, Once a month...
Ohh!
I just mowed
The lawn.
Does this look like
A well-Maintained frontage?
Woman on radio: Very often
After drying the dishes...
Whoa! Aah!
Ooh. Ugh.
Get up,
You stupid dog.
Here,
I'll help you.
No. I manage.
Your brother usually does
The deliveries.
Not today.
Ohh. Is big house.
You live here always?
Yeah.
You like my dog?
Is very big, Yes?
Any bigger,
And he'd belong in a zoo.
Zoo? Pardon?
Zoo. You know.
Uh... Animals.
Cages.
Ahh!
Claro.
I like to go with zoo.
I go with the zoo?
Oh, No. No, No.
You want to go
To the zoo.
Yes, Please.
Ohh.
Oh, Ok.
Tomorrow?
I'll meet you outside
The shop.
Ok.
I have to go.
My jardiniere.
It's shattered.
Ah, Mum,
That was your favorite.
It wouldn't have happened
If you'd dusted carefully.
I can get you another one.
It's irreplaceable.
A present
From your father.
Our last
Wedding anniversary.
Before...
He was taken from us.
Ohh.
I miss him, Too.
Oh.
Look.
Cary grant.
He is such a dream.
I wish I could be
Grace kelly.
She is so pretty.
Such beautiful
Blond hair.
Lionel?
What is wrong?
Ohh.
Uh, Sorry.
Um...
When I was young,
I was at the beach,
And I...
I nearly drowned
When I fell off
This pier.
Uh, My dad dived in
To save me, But...
As he was climbing out,
This...
Freak wave just...
Washed him out to sea,
And...
He drowned.
Oh, The little monkeys!
Look, Lionel.
Oh!
There! For you!
Ohh.
Poor little bugger.
You get out of there,
You vicious little shit!
Reckon they're only found
On one island, You know?
Story goes,
These great big rats...
Come scuttling off
The slave ships...
And raped all
The little tree monkeys.
You know,
The natives use them
In black magic rituals.
Really?
Yeah.
Don't ask me how.
Probably suck the blood
Of virgins, Eh? Eh?
I want to sit down.
Wow.
Mmm.
Oh! Oh.
Aah!
Aah! Aaaaah!
Mum?
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Ew.
Ohh.
Mum!
Holy shit!
Look at this.
It bit me.
I've been savaged.
And my dress.
Here. I help you.
Oh!
Lionel...
Take me home.
Uh...
There you are, Vera.
Now you just rest up.
I'll be back
In a couple of days
To change
That dressing.
Thanks,
Nurse mctavish.
It's all right,
Lionel.
I'll see myself out.
Why have you
Deliberately
Gone out of your way
To upset me?
I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
I don't deserve
All this attention, Darling.
If you need anything
During the night,
You just call.
You're so good to me.
Good night, Mum.
Lionel!
Hello!
Shh!
Keep your voice down.
Look.
I have your jacket.
Yeah.
I'll get it tomorrow.
What?
Look.
Ooh.
Oh!
It could've waited
Till the morning.
Is that all
You have to say?
Ohh.
Look, I'm really sorry
About the zoo, Paquita.
It's just mum.
She's...
You know.
We go out again?
To a movie?
Look...
I'd like to...
But it's not...
It's just not possible.
Not possible?
But we are romantically
Entangled.
Entangled?
Oh, Look...
Look, I don't know
What you're thinking,
But, Um...
I just can't see you
Anymore.
Ohh.
Oh, Paquita.
There will be
One romance...
And it shall last
Forever.
Ohh!
Ohh, Wow.
Mum, What a beautiful day.
Ohh.
I'm gonna call
Nurse mctavish.
No. You'll do
No such thing.
I'm perfectly
All right.
But...
You look after me,
Lionel.
Nora matheson.
Ladies welfare league.
Your mother's
Expecting us.
The mathesons are here.
No, Mum.
You're not well!
Get my dress!
Oh.
Jeez.
Please go back to bed,
Mum.
I'll put them off.
It's only the mathesons.
It's the w.L.W.L.
Oh.
Sorry.
Careful.
It'll stick on crooked.
Ok.
Our...
Main objective
Next year,
Is to...
Get the younger
Generation
Involved
In the league.
That's why
I'm so pleased
That you're on
The committee.
Thank you, Nora.
It's a great... Honor.
H- Have you had
Any thoughts
On the agenda for
The annual meeting?
Annual meeting.
Ann...
What we need's
Another war!
Yes, Dear.
I hear
Sir edmund hillary's
Planning an attempt
On the south pole.
Right you go.
Have some more beans,
Mrs. Matheson.
I'll have
A few of those, Lad.
I really think
We should be going.
Thank you, Lionel.
What?
No pudding?
Only custard,
I'm afraid.
Custard!
I haven't had
A good custard in years.
She never
Makes the stuff.
Damn fine custard.
Mmm.
Rich and creamy,
Just the way I like it.
Touchy on
The old food front, Eh?
Never mind.
That was
A fine meal, Boy.
Thank you,
Mr. Matheson.
Lionel!
What's wrong?
Lionel,
You must listen to me.
Dark forces are amassing
Against you.
My grandmama has seen it.
Say, "The path ahead
Is one of fear
And great danger."
Eh?
Fernando!
Paquita, Wait!
God, Mum.
Oh, Fernando.
Your mother ate my dog!
Not all of it.
Aah!
Get nurse mctavish, Quick.
Ohh.
How long has your mother
Been like this?
Since this morning.
Oh. I'll call
An ambulance.
You pack some things
For the hospital.
I'll do it.
Nurse mctavish.
Your mother's dead,
Lionel.
I'm sorry, Lionel.
There was nothing
We could do.
She loved you very much.
Which toothbrush?
Lionel!
Your mother's
Toothbrush...
The white one
Or green one?
Green!
Man on radio: Mother.
You are looking well today.
Woman on radio:
I woke up this morning,
How about
A nice cup of tea?
I'll just put the jug on.
Sorry, Mother. That
Was your favorite teapot.
It slipped
Out of me hand.
Never mind that.
Aah!
Paquita: Jacket,
Nightgown, Slippers,
And toothbrush.
Where's your mother?
She's gone to hospital.
Oh.
I didn't hear
The ambulance.
No, No.
Um...
No, Uh...
She went
In nurse mctavish's car.
Sort of, Uh, Well,
Sort of Iying across
The back seat, Really.
Yeah. Her and nurse mctavish.
Off to hospital.
But her night bag?
I'll take that.
Man on radio:
So, It's you
Who've been poaching
My rabbits.
Lionel.
Man on radio:
I've a good mind
To let you have it
With both barrels.
Second man on radio:
It weren't me, Sir.
It were that johnny
Morris what did it.
Well, I go now.
Man on radio: You just be
On your way, Young lad.
If I see you here again,
I'll give you what for.
What do you want?
You're not
From the immigration?
I told you people
I lost
My bloody papers, Ok?
My family left latvia
During the occupation.
We were hunted
Like dogs.
I just want to buy some...
Sedatives.
What do you think I am,
A goddamn doctor?
I don't sell sedatives.
Tranquilizers,
I do have.
Do you want
A syringe,
Or are you
Going to sniff?
Aah!
Oh, Lionel,
I am happy to see you.
Tell me about these...
Dark forces.
Death surrounds him.
There will be torment
And suffering.
You are marked.
Lionel.
Lionel, If something
Is wrong, I can...
Nothing's wrong, Ok?
It contains the power
Of the white light.
It will protect you.
Keep it with you always.
How is your mother?
Oh, Fine.
They want to keep her in
Hospital for a few more days.
Bye.
Aah!
She ran
Right in front of me.
They must have
Discharged her early.
It was
A dreadful shock,
Losing vera
Like that.
Had lunch with her
Only last friday.
Picture of health.
That boy of hers,
Where is he?
Fine lad.
Lionel called half a dozen
Times in the last 2 days.
Very keen
To view the remains.
Of course,
I had to put him off.
It would have been
Far too distressing.
As it is, It's been a damn
Difficult embalming job.
Oh, My god.
Excuse me.
I can tell
You're not a cosgrove.
You're far
Too good looking.
Pardon?
Les is the name.
I'm lionel's u...
Lionel's uncle.
And who might you be?
Paquita maria sanchez.
Latin, Eh?
Excuse me, Father.
I am looking
For lionel.
I haven't seen him.
And if he's not here
In 10 minutes,
His mother will be delivered
Into the hands of the lord
In his absence.
Mortician: You idiot.
I told you to stay in there.
The embalming machine
Should be turned off.
Oh, Great!
Blowout!
Mortician:
You're a half-Wit.
This is coming
Off your wages.
I'll fix them up.
No, Leave it.
We've got to get the body
To the service.
The theme of
Today's service
Is the sanctity
Of motherhood.
Vera cosgrove
Will be surely missed
By her friends
And grieving family,
For she was indeed
A fine woman,
And everything a boy
Could wish for in a mother.
Father mcgruder: Lionel...
Though deprived of his father
At an early age,
Was blessed with an abundance
Of mother love.
Father mcgruder:
Though our dear ones depart,
They live on in our hearts
And memories
Until,
In the fullness of time,
We, Too, Depart
From this world...
Until we are reunited
Once again.
A christian spirit
Is eternal.
Yea, Whosoever believeth
In the lord jesus christ
Shall be...
Resurrected.
Poor lionel.
He was always dreadfully
Attached to his mother.
Well, I've seen some displays
Of grief in my day,
But nothing
Quite like that.
Do you need anything?
I'm fine.
I called
To see you yesterday,
But you didn't
Answer the door.
I just want to be left
Alone for a while, Ok?
At least he's
Well provided for.
Yes, Well, The cosgroves
Were hardly paupers.
He'll be the sole
Beneficiary.
Hey, Guys.
Look what I found.
What are you doing
With this thing?
Digging up a few stiffs?
L...
Shut up!
You know
What you are?
A bloody sicko.
Yeah, Mean talk.
Get his wallet.
That's my mother
You're pissing on.
It's a zombie!
Aah!
Mom, No!
What in god's name
Is going on here?
The devil is amongst us.
Stay back, Boy.
This calls
For divine intervention.
Yaaaaaah!
I kick ass for the lord!
Aah!
No!
There you are, Mum.
Void.
Use the spoon.
Ohh!
Arrrrrr!
Ohh.
Hey, Hey.
Cut that out.
Shh.
How's it going, Lionel?
Uh...
Come on, Mate.
I'm dying for a slash.
I've got a urinary infection.
Christ, What a stink.
Yeah. Dog
Must have crawled
Under the house
And died.
Huh.
Can't have been easy for you
These past few weeks, Lionel,
What, With your mother gone.
Uhh.
Who's that, Uh,
Little girl
You've been seeing?
What?
You know,
The little latin number
With the cute bum.
Lionel: Paquita.
Oh, Yeah, Paquita.
That's the one.
She's a bit of all right.
Wouldn't mind her
Doing the growl on me.
So...
All this is coming
Your way, Eh?
Of course, Uh...
Your mother
Was always intending
To leave me a bequest.
Oh.
Oh, Yes.
We talked about it
Many times.
It was a foregone
Conclusion, Really.
It's just, With her
Dying suddenly,
She didn't get the chance
To include me in her will.
Well, You'll have
To talk to the lawyers
About it, Uncle les.
Don't bring the bloody
Lawyers into it.
This is a private
Family matter.
What the hell's that?
It's the pipes.
They do that sometimes.
It's not the pipes,
Lionel.
It's somebody
Doing the business.
Please, Uncle les,
You just gotta leave.
So you found your dad's
Old stag movies, Eh?
Yeah.
Father mcgruder:
Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh!
Is that the one
With the donkey
And the chambermaid?
No, Please.
All right.
I understand,
Lionel.
Some things
A man prefers
To do on his own.
It's all part
Of the grieving process.
Be seeing you, Lionel.
Man on radio: Nijinsky
Was of what nationality?
Second man on radio:
Nijinsky is russian.
Russian is right.
That's very good.
Um, 13.
Number 13,
He's going for.
Lionel!
I dropped a shilling.
It must have, Uh...
Rolled down the drain.
I come to see you,
You shut the door
In my face.
You built a big wall.
I telephone,
And you don't answer.
Why?
Speak to me.
You don't want
To see me anymore?
It was a mistake.
Sorry.
Good-Bye.
Paquita.
Leave me alone.
I'm sorry.
Take your hands
Off her, You creep!
You know what they're saying
About you, Don't you?
You've gone funny
In the head.
A real bloody weirdo.
You touch her again,
And I'll knock you into
The middle of next week.
Come on, Paquita.
Ohh.
Hmm.
Ohh!
Ahh.
Cute.
Uhh! Aah!
Hello. Hello.
Oh, There's a cutie.
How's cute little selwyn
There?
Ow!
Ohh. Ohh.
Peekaboo.
Whee!
Aah!
So I said...
Yeah!
Hyperactive.
So, I tackled
This guy, Right?
I brought him down
This real bone cruncher.
And the ball rolls free,
So I scooped it up,
And you know what I did?
I drop-Kicked
From 50 yards out.
Ha ha! God, You
Should have seen it.
Put us 3 points ahead.
Gave us the match.
Fantastic.
Hello, Lionel.
That's quite
A collection
Of stiffs
You got down there.
And I thought you were
Such a quiet chappie.
Uncle les,
They're not what you think.
Back off, Mate!
Lay a hand on me,
I'll have you
For breakfast.
I'm sorry, Lionel.
If I don't
Report this,
I'll be an accessory
After the fact.
I hope they can keep it
Out of the papers
For your mother's sake.
She always
Hated a scandal.
This is hard
For me, Lionel,
Informing on
Me sister's boy and all.
Of course, If I was
To keep me mouth shut,
I'd be taking
A hell of a risk.
Hey, Put me through
To the police, Please.
Of course,
If I was to, Uh,
Get my fair share
Of vera's estate,
I might be
More inclined
To protect a member
Of the family.
You want the money?
Speak to sergeant bauer.
I'd like to report
A multiple murder.
Yes, I'll wait.
The money and the house.
Blood is thicker
Than water, Lionel.
Yeah, G'day.
Les about?
Hey, You bastard!
Thought
We'd pop over
And take a squish
At your new digs.
Yeah, Mate. Why not?
Rip the skins off
A few brown ones.
Yeah. We'll make
A night of it.
Where are you going?
Just for a walk.
No, Mate. These people
Want a feast.
We'll get a party going.
Let's get
Some snacks, Mate.
You got real-Live
Stiffs here?
Man: Hey, Les, Let's
Stick some real music on.
Oh, Yeah.
Comin' through, Buzzer.
Clear the dance floor.
I don't know
What sort
Of kinky shit
You're into,
But I want
Those things buried.
Come on, Babe.
Have a dance.
It's no good asking lionel.
He's nothing
Like his old man.
He was a real stick man.
Used to pull the birds
Like you wouldn't believe.
Don't talk about
My father like that.
Ho ho ho ho ho!
Ho ho!
Mmm.
Tasty.
You got anything else
That I can, Uh,
Nibble on?
So, You know,
I throw him a dummy,
Fooled him
Completely.
Now, You
Gotta imagine,
This is, Like,
10, 15 Yards out
From the sideline.
There are several
Of these big buggers
Coming towards me,
Right?
So what do I do?
L... I put
My head down,
And I shot
To get a touchdown
Right between
The posts. God.
The coach reckons
I'm a dead certain
For the next
Callback trials.
What do you think
About that, Paquita?
You could be going out
With the next bob scott.
Where were you?
A cute little
Se}orita, Eh?
Oh, God. Wait.
Oh, Come on, Now.
Don't be a party pooper.
Come and have a drink.
Oh!
Oh, I bet you go off
Like a rocket.
Oof!
Ohh!
Oh! Oh! Little bitch!
I'll get you!
Where is she?
Aw, You foreign bitch!
I'll get...
Hello?
Aah!
Paquita!
Eeeeeee! Aah!
Paquita.
"Death surrounds him."
Lionel: They're not...
Dead exactly.
They're just...
Sort of rotting.
Nurse mctavish.
Father mcgruder.
Your mother!
I don't know what to do,
You know? I...
Don't know how
To stop it.
You must destroy them.
I...
I can't.
Not mum.
That thing
Is not your mother.
Come on, Les.
Join in.
I'll do it.
Aye, What's this?
Her lap bird's
Flying the coop, Is it?
Out of the way!
You're not going
Anywhere, Mate,
Until the house
Papers come through.
Come on, Lionel.
No, You don't!
Oh!
Oooooh!
Arrrrrr!
Whoa!
Come on!
Rrrr! You foreign
Animal bitch.
Time you and I got
Better acquainted.
Help! Someone!
Please!
For god's sake, Run!
Not so loud, Mate!
Aah!
Oh! Aah! Aah!
Bitch!
Lmadre de dios!
Help us!
Bugger that!
Aah!
Run, Paquita!
Help!
Help! Help! Help!
Oh, No! Shit!
Help! Help!
Aah!
Please don't kill me.
It's ok. It's me.
That's a nasty plaque
Problem you got there, Mate.
Got a bit of a cavity
There, Mate.
Heh heh!
Mandy.
It's me, Rita.
Remember?
Oh. Oh.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Ha ha ha ha!
Oh!
Uhh!
Ya mutant
Little shit!
You'll be ok.
Let me in!
For christ's sake,
Let me in! Help me!
Help!
Paquita,
We must.
Come on! Help!
Quickly!
There's thousands of them!
What the hell's this?!
Leave her alone.
She's been bitten!
You know
What that means?!
She's gonna turn
Into one of them!
I won't. I won't.
Help me!
You stay out of it!
I know what to do.
She's history.
I've read
The comics!
Total lobotomy!
Dismemberment!
Are you crazy?!
There's no room for
Hysterical women in my unit.
Aah!
Step right up,
You creepo bastards!
Aah!
Lionel.
Paquita!
No!
Uhh!
Oh!
Aah!
Just as well someone around
Here's got balls, Eh, Girls?
Ohh!
Goddamn little rug rat!
Get out of the way!
Come on, You little maggot!
Where are you,
You little crawler?!
Aah!
No! Whoa!
Whoa!
Lionel!
Holy christ. Vera.
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Leave me.
Aah! Aah!
Party's over.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Rita?
No!
Oh!
Now, You just get
Out of here.
What?
Haven't seen mum yet.
Aah!
Come to mummy,
Lionel.
Come on!
No!
You don't
Scare me, Mum.
All my life...
You told me nothing
But lies.
That stuff about dad,
None of that was true!
You drowned them both,
Mum...
Dad and that blond woman.
You caught them together,
And you killed them,
Didn't you?
How dare you speak
To me like that.
Didn't you?!
Lionel, Help! Quick!
Slut!
Don't you touch her.
No!
No one will ever love you
Like your mother.
No! No!
No!
Such a good boy.
Heh heh heh heh.
Aah!
No.
The sign of love
Has cost its toll
The truth foretold
Is now revealed
Its mystery
Our destiny
The stars and moon
The sign of love
Has come at last
2 Lonely hearts
Are in the past
It blazes bright
Love's blinding light
Through darkest night
And floods the room
The stars and moon
The sign of love
Our time has come
The stars and moon
Stars and moon
Will shine for us
The stars and the moon
Are guiding us
We follow the sign
To perfect love
The sign of love
Our time has come
The stars and moon
Will shine for us
The stars and the moon
Are guiding us
We follow the sign
To perfect love