Good morning, Miss Swallow.
- Why, what's the matter?
- Dr. Huxley is thinking.
Alice, I think this one
must belong in the tail.
Nonsense. You tried it in the tail yesterday
and it didn't fit.
Yes, that's right. I did, didn't I?
David, it's a telegram for you from Utah.
It's from the expedition.
The expedition! Open it. I'll be right down.
David, they found it! They found it, David!
Not the intercostal clavicle?
It's on its way. It'll be here tomorrow.
Just think of it, Professor.
The very last bone we needed
to complete the brontosaurus.
The intercostal clavicle is arriving
tomorrow after four years' hard work.
- Congratulations, my boy.
- Isn't it great? I can hardly believe it!
Stop it. Really, David, there's a time
and place for everything.
What will Prof. LaTouche think?
After all, you're getting married tomorrow.
- Yes, I know we are...
- Right, we're getting married tomorrow.
Isn't that odd? Two important things
happening on the same day.
I think the occasion calls for a celebration.
Don't worry, we'll celebrate.
We're going away
directly after we're married.
Going away? What are you thinking of,
David? After receiving this telegram?
As soon as we're married,
we're coming directly back here...
- and you're going on with your work.
- Alice.
Now, once and for all, David,
nothing must interfere with your work.
Our marriage must entail
no domestic entanglements of any kind.
- You mean...
- I mean of any kind, David.
Alice, I was sort of hoping...
You mean children, all that sort of thing?
Exactly. This will be our child.
Yes, David, I see our marriage
purely as a dedication to your work.
Alice, everybody has to have
a honeymoon and...
We haven't time.
You have an appointment this afternoon.
- Have I? What for?
- To play golf with Mr. Peabody.
What Peabody?
The Alexander Peabody
who represents Mrs. Carleton Random.
Now let me think.
Who may donate $1 million
to the museum to complete all this.
Oh, sure! That Mr. Peabody.
$1 million.
That's pretty white of Mr. Peabody.
You haven't got it yet.
Let me remind you that a lot depends
on the impression you make on him.
Don't worry. After I've received this,
I feel good for anything.
I'll wow him, I'll knock him for a loop.
David, no slang.
Remember who and what you are.
- That's right.
- Go on. You mustn't keep him waiting.
- Goodbye, Alice. I mean, Professor.
- Don't forget your golf clubs.
Remember, let Mr. Peabody win.
Yes, Alice. I will.
Oh, dear. Excuse me.
I can't tell you, Mr. Peabody...
how much this endowment
would mean to the museum...
and to me personally.
If you could just give me
some assurance...
If you could give me some assurance
that you'd...
consider us first before you donate that
million to anyone else, I'd appreciate it.
Dr. Huxley, you seem to be
under some misapprehension.
I haven't got $1 million.
I represent the possible donor,
Mrs. Carleton Random...
whose legal advisor I happen to be.
Yes, of course. I forgot.
Mr. Peabody, then I wonder...
if you could use your influence
with Mrs. Random, that would be nice.
Dr. Huxley, when I play golf,
I only talk golf...
- and then only between shots.
- Yes, of course. I'm sorry.
Couldn't we continue this discussion
over a whisky and soda after our game?
Yes, we could.
Meantime, I believe you hooked your ball.
Yes, I did.
I'll be with you in a minute, Mr. Peabody.
Yes. All right.
Look! You can't...
That's my ball. Just a minute!
Here's hoping.
I say, just a minute. I beg your pardon.
Oh, dear.
- You shouldn't do that, you know.
- What shouldn't I do?
Talk while someone's shooting.
Anyway, I forgive you
because I got a good shot.
- You don't understand.
- It's right next to the pin.
That has nothing to do with it.
- You playing through?
- I've just teed off.
You must be a stranger here.
You should be over there.
This is the 18th fairway and I'm on
the green. If I sink this, I'll beat my record.
Be there in a minute!
What kind of ball are you playing?
- PGA.
- I'm playing a CrowFlight.
I like a PGA better.
I'm trying to prove
that you're playing my ball.
A PGA has two black dots,
and a CrowFlight has a circle.
I'm not superstitious.
- That has nothing to do with it.
- Stop talking and take out the pin.
Oh, my, this is so silly.
See? It's a circle.
Of course. Do you think
it would roll if it were square?
I have reference to a mark on the ball.
That proves it's a CrowFlight. That's mine.
What does it matter?
It's only a game, anyway.
Young lady, you don't seem to realize...
you've placed me
in a very embarrassing position.
Really? I'm sorry.
The most important lawyer in New York
is waiting for me on the first fairway.
Then it's silly of you
to be fooling around on the 18th green.
You don't mind if I take this with me?
Not at all.
Tell the caddy master to put it in my bag
when you're finished.
Huxley, come on!
Yes, I'll be with you in a minute,
Mr. Peabody!
Hey, mister, I think that's your car.
I'll be with you in a minute, Mr. Peabody!
What do you think you're doing?
I'm trying to un-park my car.
- Oh, hello.
- This is my car!
Good. Would you mind
moving it out of the way?
- No. This is my car.
- Yes, I understand that.
If you move it back four feet,
I'll be able to get out.
I'm afraid you've made a mistake.
Maybe this is yours. What did you say?
I said if you move it back about four feet,
I'll be able to get out.
I'm in a terrible hurry, and I can't budge.
- You want me to move your car?
- Would you mind terribly?
- Yes, I will, but...
- That would be awfully kind.
- Take it very easy.
- Yes, I'll go slowly.
What are you doing?
I have to get into position.
Please be careful.
I will. Now, you say when.
- Yes, all right.
- Am I clear?
Yes, you're clear now.
- Now look what you've done.
- That's all right. I'm insured.
I don't care whether you're insured or not!
Let me drive this car.
It's all right. It's an old wreck, anyway.
It doesn't matter.
You don't understand. This is my car!
- You mean this is your car?
- Of course.
Your golf ball, your car?
Is there anything in the world
that doesn't belong to you?
Yes, thank heaven. You!
Now, don't lose your temper.
Young lady, I'm not losing my temper.
I'm merely trying to play some golf.
You choose the funniest places.
This is a parking lot.
Will you get out of my car?
- Get off my running board.
- This is my running board!
All right, honey, stay there.
Help me!
Don't think everything
in the world is yours.
This is my car, I'll handle it.
If you want to come with me, go ahead.
I'll be with you in a minute, Mr. Peabody!
Good evening, sir.
I'm looking for Mr. Alexander Peabody.
I believe he's dining here.
Mr. Peabody has not arrived yet.
Is that so? Well, I'll just wait.
- Yes, sir.
- Good evening, Louis.
- Good evening, Mr. Brown. Right this way.
- Thank you.
May I check your hat, sir?
- Excuse me?
- Check your hat?
No, I better... Maybe you'd...
I'm sorry.
Look at that. I dropped my hat.
I'd better hang on to it.
- Now, watch very carefully.
- I'm watching.
I take an olive, I throw it in that glass,
but there it is.
- Now I throw it in that one.
- Wait. Now, without the... Go on.
Watch.
I know what happens. That's wonderful.
You take three, don't you?
Only you cheated.
You can see me take three.
You throw it in the glass.
Take another one, throw it.
- Good!
- And then you do this.
I'm so sorry. Oh, hello.
You're sitting on your hat.
- I know it.
- That's silly. Get up. I'm awfully sorry.
I couldn't be more apologetic, really.
Well, I might have known you were here.
I had a feeling just as I hit the floor.
That was your hat.
Look at it. Look.
Yes, it's too bad, isn't it?
Joe here was showing me a trick,
and the olive got away.
First you drop an olive,
then I sit on my hat. It all fits perfectly.
You can't do that trick
without dropping some of the olives.
It takes practice.
What, to sit on my hat?
No, to drop an olive.
Now, if you're going to be angry with me,
what can I do?
Go away.
No. I was here first.
- Then I'll go away.
- What, you...
Won't you just take the olive dish?
No, it's all right.
I'll sit here. You don't mind, do you?
- Not at all.
- This is rather difficult.
- I guess it is.
- Goodness.
Your face is familiar.
Haven't we met somewhere?
Not to my knowledge.
You're wrong. My name's Susan Vance.
I'm Dr. Fritz Lehman.
That's all right. You can sit down.
I don't mind at all.
- You may have heard me lecture.
- What do you lecture about?
I usually talk about nervous disorders.
I am a psychiatrist.
Oh, crazy people.
We dislike the use of that word.
All people who behave strangely
are not insane.
Is that so?
Would you mind if I asked your
professional opinion about something?
Not at all.
What would you say about a man
who follows a girl around...
and then when she talks to him,
he fights with her?
Fights with her?
Is the young man your fiancé?
No. I don't know,
I never even saw him before today.
No, he just follows me around
and fights with me.
The love impulse in man very frequently
reveals itself in terms of conflict.
The love impulse?
Without my knowing anything about it...
my rough guess would be
that he has a fixation on you. A fixation...
Wait a minute, I can't remember
more than that. A fixation?
"The love impulse in man frequently
reveals itself in terms of conflict."
- That's right.
- I'm eternally grateful to you.
You're absolutely wonderful.
Thank you very much.
Do you know why you're following me?
You're a fixation.
I'm not following you.
I haven't moved from this spot.
Please, you're following me.
Don't be absurd.
Who's always behind whom?
My dear young lady,
I haven't been behind anything...
but what they call the eight ball.
I haven't been all day.
- You're angry, aren't you?
- Yes, I am.
The love impulse in man frequently
reveals itself in terms of conflict.
- Excuse me. The what impulse?
- Love impulse.
The trouble with you is that you have a...
Look, all I'm trying to do...
is find the gentleman whom,
thanks to you...
I abandoned on the golf course today.
That's all. Now please go...
Say, this isn't...
Where do you suppose I...
- Hold this a minute. I'll be right back.
- Yes.
Missed.
- I'm sorry I was so long.
- It's quite all right.
I had a very entertaining conversation
with a young lady who does tricks...
with olives when she gets it right.
Fritz, where's my purse?
I thought you had it with you.
No, I left it right here on the table.
- My diamond pin was in it.
- Your diamond pin?
You just lost a diamond pin.
We're going to find it, all right?
- Don't worry about it.
- Excuse me.
Why, there it is. Thank you very much.
It's very kind of you.
- Thank you.
- Why, no.
This is my purse. My diamond pin is in it.
- Will you please...
- No, I'm afraid...
- Give me that.
- Will you please hand it over?
- Do something about it.
- Keep out of it, darling.
- I did the trick.
- You did? Good.
It is madness for you
to say it's not my wife's.
You've made a slight blunder.
This belongs...
There is the young lady.
Isn't this your purse?
- No, this is my purse.
- There you are. Hand it over.
Just a minute.
Didn't you give me this purse to hold?
Yes, that's right, I did.
I gave him the purse to hold.
There's been a mistake. I lost my purse.
I must've picked up your wife's purse
by mistake.
I wanted him to stay here,
so I gave him this purse...
while I went to find mine.
I was coming back.
- Now, that's all perfectly clear, isn't it?
- No, it isn't.
- She's going to give me an explanation.
- No!
My dear sir, it never will be clear
as long as she's explaining it.
- Now please let me go.
- Just a minute.
He's innocent.
Now you have your wife's purse,
I have my purse...
and Louie will explain it all to you
and everything will be all right.
Please listen.
You can't think I did that intentionally.
If I could think,
I'd have run when I saw you.
If you'd only let me explain.
I just gave you my purse to...
You've torn your coat.
Now, I didn't do it on purpose.
That's not right. It's not my fault.
I did it, but I didn't mean to do it.
I just caught hold of your coat.
Will you do something for me?
A needle?
No, it's simpler than that.
Let's play a game.
What?
Watch. I'll put my hand over my eyes,
and then you go away. See?
Then I'll count to 10,
and when I take my hand down...
you will be gone. One...
I like that. I was only trying to be nice.
Thank you.
Just a minute!
You can't talk to me that way
then crawl out of it.
- When I'm mad, I'm mad.
- Something horrible has happened.
Don't tell me about it.
Just get out of it as best you can.
Please stop following me around,
fixation or no fixation. I've had enough.
- Stop talking, so I can tell you...
- Will you stop crowding me?
- I'm just trying to tell you, you've torn...
- No, I didn't.
- Lf you'd waited for my explanation...
- Not my coat...
...your coat would still be very all right.
- What is the matter with you?
- You see, I...
Do you realize you're making
a fool out of yourself?
You can't tell me I tore your coat.
There's such a thing as being fair.
Will you please stop doing that
with your hat?
Just stand there, will you?
What in the world is going on?
- No! Please don't move!
- I've had enough of this.
Listen to me. Let's get out of here.
Just start walking.
So now you want to walk.
Well, I'm quite sure
that I don't want to walk with you.
I hope you realize that you've made
a perfect spectacle of yourself.
Have you finished?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Don't just stand there. Do something.
Oh, my goodness. Get behind me.
- I am behind you.
- Get closer.
I can't get any closer. Are you ready?
Be calm. Left foot first.
- Go straight out the door.
- I have to meet someone here. There he is.
Don't you dare leave me.
I'll be with you in a minute, sir.
It's very important that I meet this man
to explain to him what happened...
although if I saw him,
I wouldn't know what to say.
It's perfectly simple.
Tell him you met someone you knew
and were detained.
I can picture myself explaining our exit
from the Ritz Plaza to Mr. Peabody.
It's not Boopie that you're trying to see?
No. His name's Peabody.
Alexander Peabody.
But that's Boopie, and I know him well.
I was going to have supper
with him tonight. He'll do anything I ask.
- Let's go to the Ritz and catch him.
- I'd better go there alone.
If we miss him there,
we'll go out to Riverdale. There you are.
- I couldn't spend that much time.
- Riverdale's only half an hour away.
Yes, but I have to go to Carnegie Hall
to meet Miss Swallow.
- Miss Swallow?
- Yes. I'm engaged to Miss Swallow.
Engaged to be married?
- That's right.
- That's nice.
- Then she won't mind waiting, will she?
- I wouldn't like to...
If I were engaged to you,
I wouldn't mind waiting at all.
- I'd wait for ever.
- But it wouldn't be right.
- I finally got you here, didn't I?
- Yes.
Susan, do they build all the houses
in Riverdale alike?
I don't think so. Why?
Because if they don't, we've passed
this one six times in the last hour.
But it was such a lovely night
for a drive. Come on.
Oh, dear.
There aren't any lights.
Mr. Peabody must have gone to bed.
No, he couldn't have gone
to bed this soon. It's early.
If they expected you, they could,
with the covers over their heads.
If you don't stop nagging, I won't help you
arrange matters with Boopie.
I've a feeling it might be better
if you didn't.
- Why?
- I don't think we ought to do this, Susan.
If we wake him up, he'll be irritable.
I don't think it's gonna work,
but I know where Boopie sleeps.
You can't climb
in a man's bedroom window.
I know. It's on the second floor.
Please, it's too late now.
You can't wake him up.
Can't I?
What are you doing?
- Pebbles.
- What for?
If you throw pebbles against a window,
people think it's hail...
and then they come and close the window.
I know we ought to go now,
but somehow I can't move.
I guess they weren't big enough.
Why not...
What?
- Here's a pip.
- Just a minute!
Jeepers! Let's get out of here.
Don't worry,
everything's going to be all right.
Tomorrow, when Boopie's calmed down,
we'll go and see him together.
Now, just a moment. Don't think
that I don't appreciate all you've done...
It was nothing, David...
Just a moment. But there are limits
to what a man can bear.
Besides, tomorrow afternoon
I'm going to get married.
What for?
Because... Anyway, I'm going
to get married, and don't interrupt.
Now, my future wife has always
regarded me as a man of some dignity.
Privately, I'm convinced
that I have some dignity.
Now, it isn't that I don't like you, Susan...
because after all, in moments of quiet,
I'm strangely drawn towards you...
but there haven't been
any quiet moments.
Our relationship has been
a series of misadventures...
from beginning to end.
So if you don't mind,
I'll see Mr. Peabody alone and unarmed.
Without me?
Yes, without you,
and definitely without you.
Now, Susan, I'm going to say goodnight.
And I hope that I never set eyes
on you again. Goodnight.
Yes, I did see Mr. Peabody,
but I didn't see him.
That is, I didn't see him really.
Yes, I spoke to him twice,
but I didn't talk to him.
But I don't understand.
Did you see him or didn't you?
No, I don't know.
How do I know? Because...
There's someone at the door.
You see, there are some things
that are very hard to explain, Alice...
and as soon as I...
Yes, Alice.
Now, Alice,
before we're married this afternoon...
there's one thing we must have clear.
I don't want any woman interfering
with my affairs. It's fatal.
That's the stuff, buddy.
- What do you want?
- Dr. Huxley?
Sign here.
Just a minute, Alice.
I have to sign something.
Alice, it's arrived!
The intercostal clavicle.
Yes, isn't that wonderful?
Isn't that a marvelous wedding present?
Thank you.
You see, I'm going to be married
this afternoon.
Don't let it throw you, buddy.
Yes, Alice. Yes, isn't it great?
Alice, I'm so excited.
I'll tell you what you do.
You go on down to the museum...
and I'll meet you there right away.
Goodbye.
Hello. Oh, it's you.
I can't hear very well.
Come closer to the telephone.
I said, "Good morning, David."
Do you want a leopard?
Why should I want a leopard?
For that matter, why should I?
But I've got one.
- Where would you get a leopard?
- I wouldn't get a leopard.
My brother Mark got him.
He's hunting in Brazil and he caught him.
Of course. It's a stuffed leopard.
Of course. Why should my brother
be hunting stuffed leopards in Brazil...
when he can find them right here
in New York?
David, it's lucky I met you yesterday,
because you're the only zoologist I know.
Of course I know what a zoologist is.
Get out of here. No, not you, David.
Baby, get back into that bathroom.
You're making a nuisance of yourself.
No, not you, David.
No, I want you to come right over.
David, don't be irrelevant.
The point is, I have a leopard.
The question is,
what am I going to do with it?
Susan, I regret to say
the leopard is your problem.
You mean you refuse to help me?
David, you can't do that.
You can't leave me alone with a leopard.
I'll come and get you in my...
Susan! What happened?
Is it the leopard?
No. Nothing happened to me, David,
I just...
I mean, the leopard!
David, the leopard!
Can you hear me, Susan?
Susan, be brave! I'll be right there!
Hold on there, Susan!
Susan! Can you hear me?
I'll be there, Susan!
- You're all right.
- Yes, I'm all right.
- You lied to me!
- No. Just a little.
Telling me a ridiculous story
about a leopard.
- I have a leopard. Right in there.
- Where is it?
- I don't believe you.
- But you have to believe me.
I've been the victim
of your unbridled imagination once more.
Chasing all the way...
That'll teach you to go around
saying things about people.
You've got to get out of this apartment.
But I can't. I have a lease.
You've got to get that thing out of here.
Don't worry, he's all right.
What are you gonna do?
- Call the zoo.
- You can't!
That's the meanest thing I ever heard.
He's a pet, he'd be miserable in a zoo.
Listen. From my brother Mark:
"Dear Susan, I'm sending you Baby."
That's Baby.
"Guard him with your life.
"He's three years old, gentle,
and he likes dogs."
I don't know whether that means he eats
dogs or is fond of them. Mark's so vague.
"He also likes that song, I Can't Give You
Anything but Love, Baby. "
- That's absurd!
- No, it isn't, really. Listen.
This is probably the silliest thing
that ever happened to me.
It's silly but true.
He absolutely adores the tune.
What's the difference?
It's silly that he likes such an old tune.
I imagine that down in Brazil...
- Stop this, Susan.
- Let me show him to you.
Don't go near the door! Dear, dear.
Watch, David.
He'll go right toward the music.
Look at that. Isn't this remarkable?
It loves it, David.
If we put the Victrola in the bathroom,
will it go back in?
Yes, but the music sounds better out here.
Besides, he likes it.
Here it comes.
Now go away! Please go away!
I'm gonna get out of here.
Susan, I don't like leopards.
- Just think of him as a house cat.
- I don't like cats either.
- Stand still. Don't be nervous.
- Make him stand still!
Don't be silly.
You can't make a leopard stand still.
Do something. Turn off that Victrola.
I don't think it's the music. I think it's you.
I think you've found a real friend.
Isn't it affectionate, like a baby kitten?
I never saw anything take such a liking
to anyone. It'd follow you anywhere.
We'll have no trouble
taking it to Connecticut.
My farm in Westlake, Connecticut.
I'm not going to Westlake, Connecticut.
I will not be involved
in any more harebrained schemes.
Imagine Aunt Elizabeth coming here
and running smack into a leopard.
That would be an end to my $1 million.
If you had an aunt who was going to give
you $1 million and she found a leopard...
- in your apartment, what would you do?
- I don't know.
You have to help me.
There are only two things I have to do,
finish my brontosaurus and get married.
Go on, quitter.
It's no good calling me names,
because I won't argue with you anymore.
I don't want anything to do with a leopard.
Go on, Baby, down the stairs.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Professor.
- Good morning.
You'd better change your mind
about coming to Connecticut.
Susan, we settled that question
once and for all.
But what about my leopard?
That's your problem.
It's not all my problem.
Susan, will you please go away?
All right. Since he likes you so much,
I've decided to give him to you.
I won't take him.
You've got him.
Don't go away! I've got the leopard!
Oh, dear, look at that.
No, David,
all I was doing was driving along.
You were standing on the sidewalk yelling,
and looking very silly.
You know very well
you tricked me into this trip.
Look. Eating your car.
Look at the road!
I have a feeling
something horrible is going to happen.
Everything's going to be all right.
I don't care anymore.
Hello. What's the matter,
did you get lonely?
Susan, if you know any shortcuts,
please take them.
We'll be there in no time.
I just want to deliver this leopard,
take the first train back to town...
and forget
the last 24 hours ever happened.
Now, what's wrong with the last 24 hours?
I've had a wonderful time.
Susan, I don't know.
You look at everything upside down.
I've never known anyone quite like you.
You've just had a bad day, that's all.
That's a masterpiece of understatement.
Look, I can't discuss anything with you...
with Baby breathing
down the back of my neck.
Get down. Go on. Now lie down.
Susan, duck!
Never hang on to a leopard's tail!
Sing, David!
Anyway, I still insist that he was
right in the middle of the road.
I've never hit anything
that was in the right place.
That wagon was on the side of the road.
It was straight ahead of me.
That's why I hit it.
- What time is it?
- We'll be there in no time.
We just have to stop at Westlake
and get some meat for Baby.
Why, he's already had an assortment
of ducks and chickens.
Not to mention a couple of swans.
All feathers.
Yeah, very expensive feathers.
I don't see how any pair of swans
could cost $150. That was a gyp.
If you'd run, as I told you to,
we shouldn't have had to pay for them.
Susan, when a man is wrestling a leopard
in the middle of a pond...
he's in no position to run.
There it is, David. Please hurry up.
Why, of all places,
when you have a leopard in the car...
did you stop in a town
where there's a circus?
I didn't stop because there's a circus,
but Baby's going to be hungry.
Please hurry.
If Baby wakes up, we'll be in trouble.
I don't suppose it will make any difference,
but you're parked in front of a fireplug.
I know it. Don't worry.
I'll take care of everything. You go ahead.
50c, $1.00. Thank you.
Yes. What can I do for you?
I want 30 pounds of sirloin steak, please.
Did you say 30 pounds?
- Yes, that's right, 30 pounds.
- How will you have it cut?
- Just in one piece.
- You going to roast it or broil it?
- It's going to be eaten raw.
- Yeah.
Hey, lady. That's a fireplug.
I know it.
- It's against the law to park alongside one.
- I know it.
- Come here.
- Who, me? Why?
I am Constable Slocum.
Is that so?
- How do you do? I'm Susan Vance.
- How do you do?
I don't care who you are, I just want you
to know you can't park beside a fireplug.
- I was just watching the parade.
- You were?
I suppose you get free seats to the circus.
Elmer and I usually get a...
That has nothing to do with it.
I'm just going to give you a ticket.
Thank you very much.
I'd love to go to the circus...
but you better keep your tickets
because I'm busy tonight.
Yeah? Well, it ain't that kind of a ticket.
Jeepers.
Young lady, it might interest you
to know that you're under arrest.
Oh, well. I mean, why?
For parking alongside of a fireplug.
I'm not parked next to a fireplug.
Yeah? What do you call that?
You mean that you think
that this is my car?
Ain't it?
No. That's my car.
Why didn't you say so in the first place?
You didn't ask me.
Say, do you grind this up
before you eat it?
This isn't for me. It's for Baby.
For who?
Hurry up, Baby. Get in!
- But...
- Jump on!
That isn't your car!
No, but it's my leopard!
- Wait a minute! That's my car!
- What are you yelling about?
They stole my car. Last night,
she tried to steal my wife's purse.
Don't stand there.
Do something! Catch them!
Well, Elmer, bless me. Bring back that car!
- I'm glad we finally got here
- Isn't it wonderful?
We could put him in that box
Wait, don't open the door
- until you close those
- I think that is a good idea, too
I hope he won't get out
Stand by that door, and I'll open this one
He'll just walk along, I hope
Come on, Baby. Go on
In the stall, Baby
Come on, baby,
right in there, right in there
Right in there
Now everything is quite all right
No, everything is not all
Everything is not all right, Susan. Maybe
for you, but I've got to get to New York.
Now one thing's settled,
you start worrying about something else.
One of us should worry!
On top of all this, we've stolen a car!
That's all right.
I'll send it back. I don't like it, anyway.
I suppose you'd like me to leave it
with the constable on my way back.
No, you might be arrested.
Besides, it's a hot car.
You're going to file
the numbers off the engine.
No, I'll have the gardener take it back
after it's dark.
- Stop it!
- You're shedding.
Now, where's the telephone?
- Out that door.
- That's all I want to know.
What I want to suggest is...
I don't want any more suggestions
from you. My fiancée is waiting for me.
In order to get married,
I have to get to New York.
I want you to be married,
I think you should be married.
I think every man should be.
But I don't think any girl will marry you...
- Iooking the way you do.
- Where's the phone?
- In there, but look at yourself.
- What's the matter with me?
I am dirty, aren't I?
You see? What I want to suggest is...
The only way I'll follow
another of your suggestions...
is if you hold a bright object
in front of my eyes and twirl it.
I understand. I simply wanted to suggest...
I don't want any suggestions.
I just want to clean up.
Where is there a shower?
That's what I was going to suggest,
a shower.
- Hannah.
- Yes, Miss Susan?
Send these into town
and have them cleaned and pressed.
- Why? I can do them here.
- Don't argue with me, Hannah.
Into town.
Have them cleaned and pressed.
It'll take a lot longer.
There's no hurry, no hurry at all.
- Hurry up, David.
- I am hurrying.
- David.
- What?
- What's in the box?
- What did you say?
That's the intercostal clavicle
of a brontosaurus.
Really?
It's just an old bone.
Yes, it's just an old bone.
Put it down gently and go away.
All right.
Is there anything else I can do for you?
Hand me my clothes, will you?
They aren't here. They're being pressed.
- What?
- The gardener's taken them into town.
For what? Stop him. I can't wait.
I must leave immediately.
You can't leave without clothes.
I know that. Where are you going?
I'm going to take a shower.
Susan! Don't leave me here like this!
Don't be impatient, David.
We'll talk it over after I've finished.
Everything's going to be all right.
"Everything's going to be all right."
Certainly, everything's going
to be all right.
Everything's going to be...
I'm losing my mind, that's all.
Roaming around Connecticut
without any clothes on.
I don't believe it. How can all these things
happen to just one person?
Susan, where are you?
Will you come out and help me find some
clothes or must I come in and get you?
You wouldn't.
Yes, I would!
Maybe I wouldn't.
- Susan, where's the gardener's room?
- Why?
- Because he must have some clothes.
- What? I can't hear you.
- You can hear what you want to hear!
- What did you say?
I just said... Never mind.
I'll find the place myself.
The gardener must have clothes.
Clothes are clothes.
The gardener's in town.
He couldn't have taken all his clothes
with him!
Yes, he could.
Of all the conceited,
spoiled little scatterbrains.
My goodness, the man who gets...
The man who gets you
is gonna have a lifetime of misery!
"Everything's going to be all right."
What do you want?
Who are you?
- Who are you?
- What do you want?
Who are you?
I don't know. I'm not quite myself today.
You look perfectly idiotic in those clothes.
These aren't my clothes.
Where are your clothes?
I've lost my clothes.
But why are you wearing these clothes?
Because I just went gay all of a sudden!
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Now, young man. Stop this nonsense.
What are you doing?
I'm sitting in the middle of 42nd Street
waiting for a bus.
Go away!
- Who is this man?
- I don't know.
- Stop it, George! What's he doing here?
Susan, come back here. Stop it, George!
Aunt Elizabeth, it's you!
I've never been so thrilled in my life.
This is amazing to see you here,
and George dear.
- What made you come out here?
- Quiet, George!
Now, stop gushing
and tell me, who is this man?
- Where'd you get him?
- He's a friend of Mark's.
- What's he doing here?
- Susan brought me.
I don't doubt it, but why?
I got a letter from Mark.
He said David was an old friend of his.
He'd been working very hard in town...
and was on the point
of having a nervous breakdown.
I'm a nut from Brazil.
He's very excitable.
We let him do whatever he wants.
- Where are his clothes?
- Susan took them.
- What's he doing in that thing?
- Mark said he should be allowed...
to wear a negligee. No telling what'll
happen if he's not allowed to.
Does he want to wear those clothes?
No, I don't want to wear this thing.
I just want to get married!
Susan, I forbid it!
I absolutely put my foot down. The idea!
- Quiet!
- Please listen to me!
- Don't talk so much.
Perhaps you could help me.
Perhaps you could help me
find some clothes.
Why, yes.
There must be some of Mark's things
around somewhere.
- Aren't there some...
- Are there?
Well...
Yes. There are some
in Mr. Mark's room, sir.
- Yes, sir.
- Which is Mr. Mark's room?
It's the end, sir. Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Go away.
He loves me. He loves me not.
David! Where'd he go?
He went to get some clothes.
If he gets clothes, he'll go away.
He's the only man I've ever loved.
David! What will I do without David?
Stop. Get away from me.
George, please be quiet.
- David?
- What?
- Can I come in?
- I don't care what you do!
- Thanks. Where are you?
- Here I am. What do you want?
Go on and laugh.
I know it looks ridiculous,
but I'm past caring.
What are you going to do?
What I've been trying to do,
get back to New York!
You can't go dressed that way.
They're all I could find,
and clothes are clothes. I'm going.
I'm going back to New York...
if only to repair the damage
that's been done since I've known you.
The damage to Miss Swallow,
the museum, Mr. Peabody and everybody...
Mr. Peabody? But, David...
the one way to get to Mr. Peabody
is through Aunt Elizabeth.
Please listen for one second.
He'll do anything she tells him to.
He'll even like you.
He's Aunt Elizabeth's lawyer.
He's her lawyer. Mr. Peabody.
- What's your aunt's name?
- Elizabeth.
- But she has another name.
- Of course.
Never mind. Don't tell me.
Why not? It's Random.
Mrs. Carleton Random.
- Yes, I know. I knew that was coming.
- What's the matter?
Out of seven million people,
why did I have to run into you yesterday?
What have I done?
Susan, Mrs. Random is going
to give away $1 million.
I know.
I wanted it for the museum.
I'm afraid you've made a rather
unfavorable impression on Aunt Elizabeth.
I quite realize that.
- Susan, listen to me.
- What?
A lot of things have happened but
we'll forget them because this is serious.
What, David?
Can you concentrate for just a moment?
There's only one thing to be done.
And this is important to me
and to my work.
What?
You're so good-looking
without your glasses.
- Listen to me. Try and remember.
- What?
I've made a horrible mess of things.
Your aunt must never find out who I am.
You do understand, don't you?
Yes, David.
You can tell her that I'm Mark's friend
and I have bats in the belfry...
but don't ever tell her my name.
Can you remember that?
- Yes, David.
- You're sure?
Yes, David. But you are good-looking
without your glasses.
Never mind, Susan.
What did I say?
What did I do? What did I say?
- What did I do?
- I just asked you to remember...
- I swear I'll remember...
- Where is it?
- I know exactly what you told me to say.
Where's what?
- My intercostal clavicle.
- Your what?
My bone. It's rare. It's precious.
What did you do with it?
Your bone?
- You had it. Give it to me.
- I haven't got it.
- Did you carry it somewhere?
- Why would I carry a bone around?
I wouldn't dare give a reason
for anything you do.
I guess you'll have to find another one.
It took three expeditions
and five years to find that one!
Now that they know where to find one,
couldn't you send them back for another?
Susan, you had it.
You took it out of the box.
- Where did you put it?
- I put it back in the box.
- Was there somebody else in the room?
- There was nobody else, but...
- George.
- Who's George?
The dog. Don't you see? Dog, bone.
- George!
Stop it! You sound like an echo.
- Nice George.
Did you see him?
- See who?
- George.
Are those the only clothes you could find?
Come back here this minute.
What are you doing?
- Hunting for George.
- Why?
David wants him.
David thinks he's such a nice dog.
George? He's a fiend, and you know it.
- But David doesn't.
- Come here!
He's definitely not in the house.
That's settled.
Don't do that. He knows you want him.
He'll hide.
Susan, where's he apt to go?
- George is apt to go anywhere.
- No. Where does he hide things?
- How can I tell?
- You ought to know.
There he is! George!
My goodness, look at his nose.
He's been digging. He's buried it.
There are 26 acres in this garden.
That's awful.
George, where did you hide that bone?
No, David, not that way.
Now, George, we're not angry.
David and Susan need that bone.
It's a nasty old bone,
it's hundreds of years old.
That's David's bone.
Susan will get you a nice, fresh bone
if you'll show us where it is.
- Look at the nasty little cur!
- You'll ruin everything. Spell it.
George, don't be stubborn.
Susan loves you.
Where'd you put it? Don't you remember?
Where'd you dig?
He's not paying attention... George!
It's easy if you know how to handle him.
Everything's going to be all right.
This must be the spot.
He's going to start digging in a minute.
That's right, George.
- It's very simple if you keep your head.
- I do hope he doesn't hurt that bone.
Isn't he a strong little man, David?
He's got something! Come on, dig.
- Dig.
- I'm digging.
I feel something!
I hope it isn't hurt.
Look, David, a boot.
- A boot.
- Don't hit George, David.
I wasn't going to hit George.
George, that was fine,
but you've got to concentrate again.
David has to find his bone.
No. Not in there.
- Isn't this fun? Just like a game.
- Yes.
George, if you get tired of digging
you just tell David and Susan...
where you hid it, and they'll dig.
Susan, do you think
George is really trying?
Almost every place he's taken us,
we've found something.
- There's nothing here.
- Look, David, another boot.
Another boot. That makes three pairs.
Come on, George, quit stalling.
Where is it?
Don't be discouraged.
George, concentrate. Bones, not boots.
- There he goes.
- See? He's got the idea.
- I'm getting tired of all this digging.
- Yes, what we need is a plow.
- Susan?
- Jeepers, it's Aunt Elizabeth.
Follow him, David, don't let him get away!
Yes, Aunty, I'm coming.
Susan, what on earth are you doing?
What are all these?
Those? They're holes.
I can see they're holes.
How did they get here?
David and George and I were digging.
- Who is this David?
- He's a friend of Mark's.
- Is that all you know about him?
- I know I'm going to marry him.
He doesn't know it, but I am.
If you're planning to marry him
on my money, you're mistaken.
I don't want another lunatic in my family,
I've got enough.
When are you going to marry him?
What's his name?
It's Bone.
- Bones?
- One Bone.
One bone or two, it's a ridiculous name.
What does he do?
He hunts.
Hunts? Hunts what?