I believe in America.
I believe in the American dream.
In the American way of life.
That every American should have a job,
a family and home of their own.
And two cars in every garage. You betcha.
What does a $100,000 car do?
Play with your nuts while you drive?
That would beat cruise control.
Anyone with a $100,000 car
deserves to get it stolen and get beat up.
- I'm driving.
- Hell, no.
What do you mean, "No"?
You drive like the kid from Life Goes On.
You drive like a goddamn maniac.
Yell louder.
You didn't wake anybody up yet.
Wrong.
Did you see the size of his gun?
That was a big gun.
Hey, you said the guy wasn't home.
We got company.
Shit!
Don't kill me, man!
I got shit to do tomorrow!
God, no!
Watch it!
All right, people.
Shit!
We didn't hit them.
Happy? You messed with me.
Why are we in front of a police station?
Yo, officer!
Excuse me.
Did you smoke crack tonight?
It's going to be fine.
Could you help us?
We're trying to get to Disneyland.
You two are going to Disneyland?
This is my retarded friend.
He's from Arkansas somewhere.
He wants to go to Disneyland.
You want to go to Disneyland with me?
Disneyland.
See? Disneyland. Where?
I love the way he says that. Say it again.
Disneyland.
He loves Disneyland.
So that's where we are trying to go.
Go east on 10.
When you get to the 5,
go south to Anaheim.
There are signs everywhere.
The cop not only gave us directions,
my man drew us a map.
Yeah, he got me.
But you do that again, I swear to God...
Hey, baby, I got it. Let's see...
Get drinks for everybody.
Thanks, Archie.
To the Rock and Archie Show.
You know that.
There's something I don't understand.
Everything we get,
we split down the middle.
Of course, we're partners.
So why's your bankroll
always fatter than mine?
You got money problems?
No worry. It ain't no shit I can't handle.
Whatever's mine is yours. You know that.
I know that.
- I like that.
- Easy, lover-boy.
Any woman that fine
has to have a man somewhere.
So?
You fight like Peter McNeeley.
You wanna get whupped again?
That's the beauty of having you around.
You got my back.
You hope.
What?
What do you mean "What?"
You called me over here.
I didn't call you over.
My friend said you wanted me to come.
He said you wanted to make out with me.
Are you kidding?
He's the one who said it. I will if you...
What's up?
What the fuck are you doing?
Oh, shit.
I know it looks like I was hitting on
your girlfriend, but...
...actually, I was hitting on her
harder than you think...
...so step the fuck back...
...before I bitch slap your fucking heinie!
- I'm going to kill you.
- Is there a problem?
Fucking snatch face is a fucking problem.
- There's things I want to do to you...
- Chill, Archie.
I'll bite your ear off!
Come on, Archie.
I'm trying to chill,
but Daddy-dipshit won't let me!
He's got me nuts with those crazy eyes
and that armpit stench!
Apparently, you got some shit to work out.
No. We worked the shit out.
I'm glad we worked that shit out.
I'll buy you a drink.
Here it comes.
Now it's on, motherfucker!
Keats!
Man, not like that.
- What's up?
- Like this.
That's the old-school shit.
Honey? Muffin?
Honey. How's your Twinkie?
Yo, man,
what kind of nasty ass-meat is that?
It looks like shit
out of Jeffrey Dahmer's refrigerator.
Thanks.
Okay, thank you.
I do have some shit going on.
The car stealing we do is fine.
I enjoy doing that with you...
...but I have serious income
coming from this guy.
He is the biggest drug lord in the West.
The biggest.
Get out of here.
You know, Ron, of all your inventions,
this is probably...
My mother uses that stuff. It works.
And two cars in every garage.
There's the man himself.
Come to Colton Motors and fetch
your piece of that American dream.
What do you do for him?
I'm the point man.
I set up jobs, meet the shipments.
I keep Mr. Colton happy.
If he's as large as you say,
he must be happy.
I've been thinking. You need money.
You're the only guy
I've ever trusted in my life.
I could talk to Mr. Colton
about bringing you in.
Yo, I'm just a petty car thief.
You're talking industrial type shit.
I swear, it's very, very easy.
- Easy, huh?
- You in?
I trust you. Put me down.
Good decision.
You want a ride?
No, I'll walk.
- Sure?
- Lf I can avoid driving with you, I will.
Okay, keep it real, son.
Police! Freeze!
Party's over.
If you move, I'll blow your brains out.
You're breaking my arm.
- You fucking pussy!
- Relax.
Why are you
and Black in the Hat following me?
We were in the neighborhood.
Have fun at Disneyland?
Here he is, Captain.
Did you know
you look like a struck match?
What's the word, Rock?
Jack. Whatever your name is.
The word is, El Capitán...
...this last year of my life
is about to pay off.
What are you saying?
What I'm telling you is...
...Archie Moses is taking me
to meet the man.
Finally, Frank Colton is going down.
Congratulations, Jack.
Bringing down Colton
will make your career.
I don't care about that.
I care about putting that scumbag
behind bars.
There's a shipment coming into San Pedro
next week. It's supposed to be huge.
When do you meet Colton?
Moses is introducing me tomorrow.
Wear a wire.
I don't know.
It's a good idea to wear a wire.
I'll sleep on it.
"Disneyland. "
What?
Nothing. Just something Archie did.
He's crazy.
You getting sweet on this guy?
- No.
- Listen to me.
You pal around with someone
long enough...
...you forget he's the bad guy.
Tell me about yourself, Mr. Keats.
Well, there ain't much to say.
I did some time for breaking and entering.
Armed robbery.
Petty shit like that.
What about references?
You trust this man, Moses?
Mr. Colton, I trust him with my life.
That's good.
Because trust is an important commodity
in business.
True that, true that.
True that.
I'll tell you who I trust. I trust Moses here.
Thank you.
And I trust my colleague, Mr. Bledsoe.
But most importantly,
I want to tell you who I don't trust.
I don't trust you.
I don't trust you 'cause I don't know you.
Search him.
This is bullshit. I won't search him.
You search him, not because you want to,
but because you have to, understand?
Jesus.
Mo, this is like some embarrassing shit.
I know this guy like I know myself.
If he's a cop, I'll suck your dick.
I'm sorry, bro.
See, no wires.
Well, hell, search him.
Nothing.
Well, fine.
If you don't ask, you never know.
Understand?
Remember...
...nobody moves until Jack lets us know
Colton is on the premises.
- Listen, Cap.
- Yes, Jack?
Let me bring Archie in.
A lot of testosterone will be flying around.
I don't want some overzealous asshole
denting Archie.
I knew it.
You are sweet on the son of a bitch.
- I know him. He's not that bad.
- He's a lowlife scumbag.
Then he's my lowlife scumbag.
When this is over,
maybe I can help him get his life together.
You look tense. Relax. It'll be fine.
Relax. It's just a friendly doggie.
How are you, buddy?
You like that? See? He's licking me.
He loves me.
He just licked his balls
and he's getting rid of the bad taste.
Hey, Ese, don't shoot. It's me.
How you doing?
Colton didn't mention a new guy.
Rigo, meet Rock Keats, mi amigo.
Yo, what's up?
What is it about you?
Nobody likes you except me.
What you see there is 100 percent uncut...
...grade A heroin.
Where's your boy, Colton?
He'll be here to check on my shit.
Let's go. Up, up.
Good job. A little quicker.
What you keep looking around for?
Back off me, son. What's your problem?
What are you looking for?
That's my problem!
- Relax, man.
- You tell Tattoo something.
This fucking maricón makes me nervous.
He acts like a cop.
Well, he's not a cop.
He's my friend. So relax.
- I don't know that.
- You think he's a cop?
Damn it, he's not.
Take a look. Satisfied, scumbag?
You fucking piece of shit!
- Move.
- What about Colton?
The hell with Colton!
Everybody, move now!
Archie Moses, you're under arrest.
- You better be joking.
- You have the right to remain silent...
You were like my brother!
How can you do this to me?
Moses, stop!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
No one hurts him.
Come on, Moses.
If you come out now,
maybe we can make a deal.
Don't talk to me about deals,
you lying sack of shit!
Come on. Give yourself up.
You're going to get killed here.
Okay, Officer Keats, I'm coming out.
Don't shoot.
Come on, Moses.
I'll blow this dog's head off his body.
Drop your goddamn gun!
No, you won't. You love animals.
I hate dogs!
Get out of here, you stupid, ugly dog!
I'm trying to save your life.
Fuck you!
No. God, no, no.
Jack's down.
Get that son of a bitch! Get him!
Bledsoe, it got all fucked up in there.
Where were you guys?
We had a flat tire, asshole.
Damn it!
This little fuck-up of yours cost me
millions of dollars. I'm very mad.
I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
"I'll suck... " No.
"If he's a cop, I'll suck your dick. "
That was the quote.
I don't think I did say that.
Maybe Bledsoe said it.
Here's your last meal. I hope you enjoy it.
Don't do this, please.
You don't need to do this.
Get this damn mutt off me!
You slimy rat-bastard!
Let's move it.
- Blood pressure's dropping.
- He's bleeding.
To the Rock and Archie Show.
You know that.
How long?
I mean, you're the only guy
I've ever trusted in my life.
Disneyland.
Welcome back.
Take it easy for now.
Getting back on your feet won't be easy,
but...
...you're in good hands.
- This is Traci Flynn, our physical therapist.
- Hi.
Keep me posted.
Good.
Bring it down.
Come on, Jack.
I want you to make it to the end of the bar.
Pull it forward.
Put your weight on it. Now the other one.
Five, five, let's go.
You're doing real good.
Come on, Jack. You're ready for this.
I'm proud of you.
The ghost himself.
Not even a bullet in the head
could stop him.
A millimeter to the right or left,
and he'd be dead.
I wouldn't want to have to mess with him.
Sir!
Where are you headed, sir?
Mexico. I have to start my life over.
I'm going to be a bullfighter.
Have you been drinking, sir?
I had about half a beer,
but the dog had a lot.
Would you step out of the car
and walk a straight line?
Yeah, no problem.
So you got Moses.
What has it to do with me?
Moses is going to turn state's evidence.
He's rolling on Colton?
Colton wasn't happy
Moses brought a cop into his organization.
He's had a hit on him ever since.
Now that Moses is up against it...
...he's ready to give us Colton on a platter.
Jack, Steve Finch, DEA. He's in charge.
And what is he getting out of this?
Commuted sentence.
- How commuted?
- To be determined.
- Bullshit! How commuted?
- Jack, take it easy.
You want me to take it easy?
That asshole shot me in the head.
Now this bigger asshole
is letting him get away with it.
Jack, that's not how it happened.
- Moses will do the time...
- You know what?
You and the DEA figure that out.
Leave me out of it.
Hold on, Jack.
The deal with Moses:
One condition.
What condition?
I don't know why he wants you
to bring him in and I don't care!
With him, we finish what we started.
You don't have to be afraid.
We'll send in a team for backup.
You think I'm afraid of Moses?
After the way you treated him, I wouldn't
be surprised if he put another bullet...
Jack, it's okay. Take it easy.
You're right, Stench.
I am afraid of Moses.
I'm afraid if I see him again, I'll kill him.
Come on.
What do you know about it?
Let someone else bring Moses in.
As far as I'm concerned, this shit is over.
You know,
your cop buddies all say the same thing.
They say you're not the same man, Jack.
When you got shot, you lost something.
I didn't even know you then, but...
...I think they're right.
- What do you mean? I'm happy.
- Come on.
You pretend you like your job when
it makes you miserable 8 hours a day.
You pretend Moses doesn't exist...
...which makes you miserable
24 hours a day.
If you don't finish this thing with Moses...
Come here.
You're right, as usual.
You're right.
Okay, little Keats, sit.
Good doggie. Now beg for your life.
That's right, little Keats.
Come on, you can do it. Cry.
No good. Bang.
Got ya!
Poor little boy.
I'm surprised you showed up.
Why isn't this prisoner in cuffs?
There he goes, being a cop again.
- He wasn't going anywhere.
- You cuff him...
...arms, legs, feet.
I want his asshole cuffed to his nuts.
Then put him on the plane.
Before you do that. See you later, buddy.
Man's best friend, right here.
You like that? Look at that.
He's licking me 'cause he likes to.
Not 'cause he's trying to get close to me
and then fuck me over.
Do I speak with an accent?
- No.
- Then cuff the prisoner!
Don't you want to know
why I asked for you, Keats?
I know why.
You want to finish what you started.
I'm warning you, Moses...
...I'm looking for an excuse to kill you.
If you sneeze, if you fart...
...if I even smell your breath,
I will shoot you dead.
What if I chew loud?
When I eat, I chew loud.
Will you shoot me?
I won't try anything.
And you are so wrong about that day.
I don't want to hear nothing you have
to say about any subject, at any time.
And, yes, I will shoot you if you chew loud.
Man down! Sniper!
- They want to kill me!
- On the plane!
Hustle! Let's go!
What's going on up there?
- The pilot's dead.
- I have 1,000 hours.
- What?
- I got 1,000 hours flying.
- Bullshit.
- Colton's in the importIexport business.
Here, buddy. Sorry, sorry.
Come on, fly this thing.
No, not until you apologize to me.
- What?
- Apologize! You did some shitty shit.
You better hurry.
Fly this plane or you'll experience death
then déjá vu.
Fly the plane!
You are a bad person, man.
I can actually taste my nuts.
Oh, you're killing me again!
Mayday. Does anyone read?
"Mayday"? Is this a Kirk Douglas movie?
Is everything a joke?
You're wasting your time anyway.
Can we make LA?
Not without gas.
They blew our gas tanks.
Oh, shit!
We'll probably crash head first, right?
I'll be in the back, on the black box.
Here we go now! Yeah, yeah!
Oh, shit! Stop, stop!
I saved our fucking life!
I have some advice for you right now.
Don't move.
I said, "Don't move!"
I didn't, asshole!
The plane is starting to slip.
Slow.
Easy.
Don't yell.
The echo, the vibration makes it move.
You have to whisper. Whisper.
Shit! That ain't working either!
One...
...two...
...three!
That was God's way of telling you
to let me go, I think.
We must serve different gods.
Mine says to shoot you
and throw you over that cliff.
I don't like your god.
Your god scares me.
I'm your god right now.
You're a piece of shit, you know that?
Sometimes,
I wish that bullet had killed you.
Watch what you say to me.
That's pretty sick.
You pretend to be my friend for a year...
...then you bust my ass.
That takes someone really cold-blooded.
Someone not even human.
I was doing my job! Understand?
Now, bringing me in safe and sound
is your job.
And you're the kind of cop
who'll do his job. Am I right...
...Officer Keats?
You're right.
In case you're wondering
why that hurt so much...
...it's because I have a metal plate
in my head, thanks to you.
So, from now on,
you better watch what you say to me.
Seriously, Keats,
you blink and I am out of here.
Oh, really?
You'll get to LA
with only your ding-dong in your hands.
Which reminds me, I got to take a leak.
Piss in your pants. We're not stopping.
In my pants?
I haven't done that since I was 24.
Seriously, man. I got to take a leak.
I got to take a leak!
You have 15 seconds.
Fifteen seconds won't cut it.
I got to unzip, shake, that takes time.
You have 10 seconds.
Oh, God!
I know you won't believe this, but...
...that day you got shot...
...it really was an...
- Time's up.
- I'm not finished.
- You are.
Come on! I've wet pants!
Get up!
I got piss on me!
That was a big mistake,
making me piss my pants...
...'cause it's payback time.
I don't know when...
...but I think it'll be when you're sleeping...
...'cause I know you'll sleep soon enough.
And then, guess what?
I'll piss all over you.
See, that's worse.
It's my piss on me right now.
You can deal with your own piss.
But you'll have my piss on you,
and that's gross.
I'll get other people to piss on you.
I'll get animals to piss on you.
Cows, pigs.
I'll get a whole farm to piss on you.
What kind of weird place is this?
All right, they got porno.
Can I help you, gentlemen?
I need to use your phone.
Charlie, is it?
Charles.
I saw the sign.
You got a lot of porno here?
Yes. We have an excellent selection.
Great. I like porn.
Well, good.
Cap, it's me.
Someone tipped Colton off
about the pickup.
We got word. We heard about the attack.
Are you okay?
I'm okay. Who's there with you?
Finch.
We're in a motel, outside of Flagstaff.
A place called the Hunting Cap Lodge.
We'll find it.
We'll have someone there in the morning.
Let's keep this between us.
We can't trust nobody right now.
You must loose your mind
up here in the sticks, with nothing to do.
You whack off a lot?
What's "a lot"?
You got five minutes off, nothing to do.
You go into one of the rooms,
pull down your panties, whack it.
Excuse me.
We need a room.
You guys aren't... you know?
It's been a long day, just give me a room.
Okay...
...just fill this out...
...please.
Charlie, come here.
I want to talk to you.
He says he's not gay, but...
...let's see what some drinks
and a massage will do to him.
That'll gay him up, don't you think?
Look at the way he's standing.
He's not gay?
He's waiting for you.
Oh, that's...  I don't...
That your wife back there?
Yeah.
Damn, she's hot.
Thank you.
The three of us could burn it up together,
don't you think?
What do you mean?
You know damn well what I mean.
Which room?
Let's see.
The only room we have available is the...
...honeymoon suite.
We'll take it.
Charlie, come here, please.
So, what do you think?
Me, you, the old lady,
some sandwich action?
What do you mean?
You're a piece of bread,
she's a piece of bread, I'm the salami.
She can't eat sandwiches now.
She's on a diet.
All right. Well, think about it.
Let's go.
All right. Well, enjoy your night...
...and thank you for staying here.
"You
"my darling you
"Bittersweet
"memories
"That is all
"I'm taking with me
"So goodbye
"please don't cry
"We both know I'm not what
"you need
"And I
"will always love you
"I will always love you"
Will you shut up? Shut the hell up!
Keats, you'll always be my bodyguard.
You know that.
Let me guess, you dropped the soap?
Please take that out of my ass.
I want you on the bed, now.
Hey, Charlie.
What's up, Chuck?
No, we're in some ratty town
called Beaver Pelt.
How will you get out?
Turn that off.
The guy is going down on her
and she's eating an apple. It's hilarious.
I'm sorry. What did you say?
What's going on there?
It sounds like someone's having sex.
Nobody's having sex. It's just Moses.
Will you turn that shit off?
This is a '70s porno. Know how I can tell?
The guy's dick has sideburns.
So, baby, what are you wearing?
What am I wearing?
You wearing that little black lacy thing
I bought you?
Well, as a matter of fact, I am.
Why do you ask?
I don't know.
I'm just sitting here, thinking about you.
I'm really missing you.
I miss you, too.
I got to let you go.
Where did you get that?
Didn't they search you?
I had it in my ass. Want a hit?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
You just wasted good weed.
Who were you talking to, your girlfriend?
I didn't know you had a girlfriend.
I'll probably marry this one.
Marry her? I ain't ever getting married.
I wouldn't drag anybody
into my miserable life.
And two cars in every garage. You betcha.
What was wrong with you...
...getting involved
with a piece of shit like that?
I don't know.
Crime's the only thing I'm good at.
I had a normal job once. A busboy.
I got fired in three days.
I don't know how to give people butter.
I got the guy in the yellow trunks.
$20, the man in the green.
Actually, you already owe me $20.
For what?
Knicks at the Forum.
Remember, you didn't want to take
any points? Were you crazy...
...or a sucker?
Maybe I'm the sucker.
Damn handcuff shit!
Man, you really had me fooled.
I would've done anything for you.
I would've taken a bullet for you, Keats!
I bet that's not even your real name, Keats.
Holy shit.
Your name really isn't Keats, is it?
It's Carter. Jack Carter.
I told you personal shit about myself.
Shit I'd never told anyone in my life.
And you didn't even tell me
your real name?
I was working undercover,
what do you expect?
You didn't tell anybody, did you?
About what?
The shit I told you!
You probably told every cop on the force!
What, that they over-circumcised you?
That's bullshit!
I made that up to make you laugh!
Don't worry about it,
I didn't tell anyone anything.
You're a liar.
Don't give me none of your shit. I'm not
the one that made you cross that line!
I may be a criminal, but I'd never do
to anybody what you did to me.
That's messing with people's feelings.
That's why your head hurts right now.
You feel guilty.
- My head hurts because you shot me in it.
- Keats.
It's Carter, and I risked my ass
to be sure you didn't get hurt.
And I got a bullet in the head
for my troubles.
That was an accident.
- Don't tell me that shit.
- It's the truth.
Admit that what you did to me was
much worse than anything I did to you...
...or shut up!
Well, it was.
Don't say it!
An accident!
My head feels a million times better.
I'm going to sleep like a baby tonight.
How about you?
Sorry about the turds in there.
It was an accident.
"And I
"will always love you"
But, honey, you're the one always saying,
we need to try new things to keep...
...the passion and fire in our relationship.
How do you know
you wouldn't like some sandwich action?
Okay, stud, say goodbye.
I have to go, honey. Goodbye.
Where are they?
- Who?
- Understand me.
I'll ask you one more time,
then I'll blow your brains over Mr. Moose.
Bungalow 7.
Good night.
Get in! Get in!
All right, Charlie! Go!
Get down.
Those fellas
messed with the wrong hombre.
They don't get out of here alive! Let's go!
- Here they come!
- Shit.
Aren't you going a little fast, Charlie?
Don't worry. I know these woods
like the back of my hand.
Look out, look out!
That elm came down in a storm
we had a week ago.
Guess those fellas aren't from here.
That's Jimmy's Creek.
Good fishing if you're ever here again.
Are you getting a woody doing this?
I had one before we started.
Come on, Charles.
I don't like that look in his eye.
Where are we going? What are you doing?
God almighty! Charlie!
Devils Drop-Off.
235 feet straight down.
Kind of hard to make out in the dark.
I'd like to make out with you in the dark.
- Get out of here. Get away.
- Don't be shy.
All right, Charlie.
Yeah?
Mr. Colton, I've lost them
and I don't know where they are.
Hold on a second.
Fucking idiot! Prick!
Naturally, if you lost them
you don't know where they are, you idiot.
Sorry.
Where might they be?
Probably on their way to Los Angeles.
See you later.
Thanks for being a hero, Charlie.
You're putting the handcuffs back on.
Thanks.
It's Finch.
It has to be Finch.
- One thing I don't understand though.
- What's that?
He's a special DEA officer.
These guys don't usually flip out like that.
Colton can fix anyone who might be able
to help him. You fucking shit!
You ruined my life!
Sorry.
Where are you going?
- I'm calling the FBI.
- What?
Did you not listen to a word I said?
You're saying Colton has FBI agents, too?
Is it the plate in your head?
I don't remember you being that stupid.
Colton has notebooks
with people's names in them.
Cops, judges...
...FBI agents. I know
'cause I wrote some names in there myself.
You're just afraid the FBI
will make it harder for you to run.
Your problem is,
you see everything in black and white.
You don't realize
most people live in a gray area.
Spare me your ignorant philosophy.
I trust the FBI more than a guy
who shot me in my head.
Call me wacky.
The bus comes in at 7:00.
Right. Okay. 'Bye.
Hey, man, can I call my mother?
Why?
You just got me killed.
I want to talk to her one last time.
- No.
- You know I talk to her every Tuesday.
She'll get nervous if I don't call.
Do you have any change? Come on.
I always did like your mom.
How is she doing?
If she stopped drinking booze
and smoking weed she'd be all right.
The doctor says...
Don't talk about my mother.
Why are you so defensive?
It would break her heart
if she knew what you did to me.
I did my job. That's what I did to you.
My mother loved you!
She said you were my only real friend.
It's ringing.
Did you tell her what happened?
No, I wouldn't do that.
Will you please help? Thank you.
How's it going?
Mom, are you high?
Jeez, what else is new? Okay.
Rock Keats is doing just fine.
Yes, he's right here. He's with me.
You want to talk to him?
I'll put him on the phone.
You said you've nothing
to feel guilty about.
- I don't want to talk to her.
- Talk to my mommy, Carter.
Carter, Mommy, right there. It's all right.
Hi, Ma.
Yeah, I'm doing great.
No, I have a new girlfriend now.
Yeah, named Traci.
No, not Stacy. Traci.
No, she's not like the whore in Mexico, no.
Yeah, I'm taking care of your Archie.
I know.
Well, he's my best friend, too.
I look forward to seeing you. Okay.
You're going to make me
sweet-potato pie? Great.
Bye-bye.
Back at you.
- You know I'm going to kill you for that.
- Carter, stop that.
Okay, these are our guys.
- The Blues Brothers?
- Yeah.
Guess which one of them
is your real father.
The one with the hat.
Detective Carter.
Special agents Gentry and Cole.
Man, am I glad to see you guys.
Gentry and Cole?
So what?
Don't mind him. He's simple.
I guess you had a rough ride.
You can say that again.
Darryl Gentry. Darryl Gentry.
That's my name. Don't wear it out.
First name is Darryl, right?
Named after my mother's brother.
Man, talk about simple.
Uncle Darryl was a goddamn pinhead.
Now, how did I know your first name?
What?
How'd I know your first name?
I suppose I said something at the station.
That's right. Remember, Keats?
At the station he goes,
"I'm Darryl. I'm Darryl Gentry. "
'Cause it's not like I'm a psychic.
If I was psychic,
I'd have known you were a cop.
How do you shut him up?
This usually works.
Get the wheel!
Goddamn. Are you going to shoot that?
Get the hell out of my car!
You okay?
Good. You're on the road.
Oh, my God!
That guy looks like a tumbleweed!
The Rock and Archie Show.
You did good.
I told you I was telling the truth
about them FBI guys.
So you did.
Just like I did about how shooting you
was an accident.
Don't go there.
I may not know where you're really from,
or where you went to school...
...or if your dad was really a smackhead...
...but you know me, man. Say it.
Tell me I ain't a liar. Say it, Keats.
You ain't a liar.
Hallelujah.
Hey, Mo.
My father really did die
with a needle in his arm.
You're the only person I ever told that to.
I'd hug you, but I got these damn cuffs on.
Stick your finger in your ass.
The reason Colton wants me...
...and why the D.A. Cut me a deal,
is, I know how Colton's operation works.
How he imports drugs and launders money
through his car dealership...
...and it's all written in them notebooks.
The ones with the names?
You could put Colton away for 20 lifetimes.
I could help you get them...
If I let you go?
The cops don't care about me.
They want Colton.
No can do.
How can you do this to me?
You giving up Colton,
you won't do much time.
Yeah, smuggling dope, shooting a cop.
See you in 10 years.
That's if Finch doesn't get me
on the way to headquarters.
I'm not taking you there.
I'm taking you to my precinct.
I trust the people there. You'll be all right.
We were friends, Keats, friends.
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
Don't give me that shit about
just doing your job. That's crap!
I was doing my job then
and I'm doing it now.
Well, your job sucks!
Could you move your head to the left?
That plate is ruining the reception!
Jesus, you're right.
Where's the Captain?
I haven't seen him.
You look like shit. Go home.
We'll take this guy.
Do the names Sulliman and Jones
mean anything to you?
What's with you, Jack?
You don't trust us all of a sudden?
I don't trust anybody, Whoopi.
Sulliman, Jones.
Doesn't ring a bell.
Keep him away from Finch,
that bastard's on Colton's payroll.
That son of a bitch.
I knew there was a reason I didn't like him.
Can you do me a favor?
Can you check in with my mom,
once in a while...
...to make sure
she's not smoking too much weed?
I got nobody else to ask.
You got it.
I'll look after her.
- Hey, bright eyes.
- Jack, where are you?
I'm at the... Hello?
Welcome home, Jack.
You son of a bitch.
If you hurt her, I swear to God...
Yeah. Listen.
I'm a businessman, Jack, so...
...let's discuss business.
You have something I want,
and I have something you want.
What I'm talking about here
is an even swap.
I don't have Moses. I turned him in.
Well, that's not very good, is it?
You better get him back.
Bring Moses to my house
or you'll never see your girlfriend again.
Come on down here.
Watch yourself.
Don't do what I think you want to do,
'cause neither one of us will like it.
Hold up! I need him back.
What are you saying?
- I'll take him to headquarters myself.
- Why?
Never mind why. Get the fuck off me!
He's taking me back, so we're going.
Sorry about your lunch.
I knew you'd come through.
Was it that last look I gave you?
Yeah, all of that.
Where are you going?
You gotta trust me on this, Captain.
He's dirty.
What?
You heard me.
Are you crazy?
- I'll explain later.
- No, you'll explain now.
Jensen.
This guy's name is Jensen?
Why? What?
- It's not Finch! Jensen works with Colton.
- What's he saying?
Get me out of here, now!
He's saying that you're in bed with Colton.
Back up!
He's a lying son of a bitch.
He doesn't lie.
Are you going to take the word
of that little prick over mine?
Right now I have to.
You're on suspension, you son of a bitch.
Now turn that prisoner over.
Don't even think about it!
And you...
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
- Hey, man.
- How you doing?
I cannot believe it was Jensen.
He's been like a father to me.
Shit!
I'm not going to tell you,
'cause you'll get mad.
What are you talking about?
There was a chance,
I'm not 100 percent sure, but...
...maybe it was Benson, not Jensen.
You bullshitting me?
No, I'm not positive.
Actually, I am positive it was Benson.
- Jensen, they sound close.
- I could kick your ass!
Jensen, Benson: They rhyme.
Jesus, give me a break!
A break?
You should be happy your captain's clean.
I hit my superior officer on his ass
and pulled a gun on him.
I should be happy?
The good thing is, finally, you acted
like a human being instead of a cop.
You wouldn't let me rot in that jail cell
and I love you for it.
Moses.
I swear, I'll make it up to you.
I got something to tell you.
- Go ahead.
- You won't get mad?
No way. I'm falling in love with you
all over again.
Okay. Colton has Traci.
The only way to get her back
is by turning you in. There, I said it.
You can't stop fucking me over!
I'm not turning you in,
but I can't get her back without you.
You're the only one who knows that place.
I won't make it out of that place alive
if I go there.
Forget it. I ain't doing it.
Fine!
Then, I guess you lied to me, after all.
Okay. About what?
You said you'd take a bullet for me.
I would have taken a bullet for you
at one time...
...but that shit is all gone now.
Cool, then don't do it for me.
Do it for yourself...
...because as long as you're alive
Colton wants you dead.
It's only a matter of time
before he puts your lights out.
Goddamn it.
Okay, give me a gun.
Moses, you're a fugitive in my custody.
I can't give you a gun.
Even if it means I get killed?
Even if it means Traci could get killed?
Just leave that black and white shit
and come over to the gray area.
I think Mr. Colton's waiting to see us.
He certainly is.
Hand it over.
After you.
Right in the eyeball!
Bet you're glad you gave me that gun.
This door has no alarm.
- Where does it lead?
- Guest kitchen. No one is ever in there.
Shit!
Get her out of here.
I think they're eating fajitas.
Goddamn it!
Throw it back.
Now!
So no one's ever in here, huh?
Shit.
Is that all you got?
Come here.
Motherfucker!
Thank God. I was so scared.
Where's Colton?
I saw him drive off
when the shooting began.
Okay, let's go.
There may still be guys out there.
I have no gun.
I have one.
Great. Let me have it.
Put your hands up, Jack.
Now is not the time for jokes.
Put your hands up, or I will let you have it.
Move toward the door.
So, after all this time, it was you, huh?
I'm sorry.
Just shoot me in my head.
It won't hurt as much.
Give me the gun, bitch. Thank you.
- Where were you?
- Getting the notebooks. They say...
...that it's Nurse Traci's job to get close
to someone, then fuck them over.
No wonder you liked her.
Jack, please!
Move it!
Colton knew you'd be coming after me...
...so he sicked devil-eyes on you
to lead him to me.
Colton made me do it.
He would have killed me if I hadn't done it.
She's playing you, Keats.
But then I fell in love with you.
Shut the fuck up.
I swear to God I did.
She's lying out of her devil ass!
Will you shut the fuck up?
Why don't you make me?
I got to learn how to fight.
This is pathetic.
Moses, don't do it!
Your girlfriend's shooting at me.
What should I do, tell her she's pretty?
Traci!
Put the gun down.
I'm walking out of here.
Don't try to stop me.
Goddamn it, will you stop this?
Don't take it personally.
I'm just doing my job.
Oh, shit! I've heard that before.
Moses, shut up.
Traci, please.
Doesn't feel too good, does it, Keats?
I'm coming out.
I don't want anyone else to get hurt.
Keats, take the gun. She's crazy.
Put it down.
Look out!
Jack-off, you make one hell of a partner.
First you bust him, then you get him shot.
You know what? Screw him!
I built my whole business
selling to morons like him.
You come down to Colton Motors.
I'll sell you a new partner.
One without a bullet in him.
Think of the depreciation.
Step into my office, chump.
I could kill you now,
but that wouldn't be enough...
...because first, man,
I'm going to fuck you up.
Goddamn it!
Let's get our story straight.
You two broke in here to kill me.
That's what you get
for trying to make me suck your dick.
I can't believe you did that.
Did what?
You actually took a bullet for me.
That was pretty nice of me, wasn't it?
Sit down. Let me look at that.
That's just a little flesh wound.
A bullet hit my back. It hurts.
Try taking one in the head.
That probably hurt more.
Those notebooks should make
that Benson or Jensen forget you hit him.
It's Jensen.
And you better get out of here.
Thanks, man.
Take care of yourself. Try not to mess up.
I'm done with a life of crime.
I'm going to Cabo.
Drinking margaritas, banging señoritas.
Fuck that shit.
I'm going to be a bullfighter.
Those guys make a lot of money.
You should come.
Maybe.
To the Rock and Archie Show.
To the Jack and Archie Show.
I'll see you later.
See you, Moses.
The American custom
is different than here in Mexico.
When you first meet someone,
you just start kissing, kiss each other...
...get to know each other. It's a little odd,
but if you loosen up you can enjoy it.
Señor, you are so funny.
I'm funny and good looking, too.
Admit it. I'm not great looking...
...but pretty good. About a 7.
How many of you have done it
with a bullfighter?
- Anybody? Come on, a show of hands.
- We don't like bullfighters.
We hate when they kill the bull.
No, I wouldn't kill the bull. That's not nice.
I like to get to know the bull.
Teach it how to read...
...make him stop smoking.
Bulls shouldn't smoke.
How's it going?
We don't like you gringos
bothering our women!
And I wouldn't do that.
That's why I'm leaving. Nice meeting you.
Oh, God. Come on.
You got a problem with him,
you got a problem with us. Right, Keats?
You don't want to beat me up
in front of my mother, do you?
Ma!
Subtitles by SOFTITLER
Ripped by:
SkyFury