l believe in
the Church of Baseball.
l've tried all the major religions
and most of the minor ones.
l've worshipped Buddha,
Allah, Brahma, Vishnu...
Siva, trees, mushrooms
and lsadora Duncan.
l know things.
For instance, there are 108 beads
in a Catholic rosary...
and there are 108 stitches
in a baseball.
When l learned that,
l gaveJesus a chance.
But it just didn't work out
between us.
The Lord laid
too much guilt on me.
l prefer metaphysics
to theology.
You see, there's no guilt
in baseball...
and it's never boring...
which makes it like sex.
There's never been a ballplayer
who slept with me...
who didn't have
the best year of his career.
Making love
is like hitting a baseball--
you just gotta relax
and concentrate.
Besides, l'd never sleep
with a player hitting under 250...
unless he had a lot of RBl's or was
a great glove man up the middle.
You see, there's a certain amount
of life wisdom l give these boys.
l can expand their minds.
Sometimes when l've got
a ballplayer alone...
l'll just read Emily Dickinson
or Walt Whitman to him.
And the guys are so sweet,
they always stay and listen.
Of course, a guy will listen
to anything if he thinks it's foreplay.
l make them feel confident,
and they make me feel safe...
and pretty.
Of course, what l give them
lasts a lifetime.
What they give me
lasts 142 games.
Sometimes it seems
like a bad trade...
but bad trades
is a part of baseball.
Who can forget Frank Robinson
for Milt Pappas, for God's sake?
lt's a long season,
and you gotta trust it.
l've tried 'em all,
l really have.
And the only church
that truly feeds the soul--
day in, day out--
is the Church of Baseball.
Hey, Skip, that Max,
hell of a guy.
Where's Ebby?
Ain't he warming up yet?
No. His professional debut tonight,
and he forgets about it.
Better find our "bonus baby."
Have you seen Ebby?
No.
Ebby!
Jesus.
Game starts in four minutes.
Why ain't you warm?
l am warm.
Jesus, this is your
professional debut tonight.
Million guys give their left nut
to be in your shoes.
You're leaving your fastball in
the locker room for some piece of ass.
Skip, it is me.
l am not some, quote,
piece of ass, unquote.
Oh, Millie.
Jeez, sorry.
Didn't recognize you.
Don't take this personally, Millie,
but if l catch you in here again...
you're banned from the ballpark.
You can't ban me
from the ballpark...
'cause my daddy
donated that scoreboard.
And if you ban me, he just might
take that scoreboard away.
What do we need
a scoreboard for?
We ain't scored any runs
all year.
Now you get your ass out there!
Hey, boss, l got a question.
What?
You think l need a nickname?
l think l need a nickname.
We were talking about it.
All the great ones have nicknames.
Like "Oil Can," "Catfish."
What was the one you were--
"Pokey."
What do you think of"Pokey"?
You got three minutes.
Goddamn, son of a bitchin',
motherfuckin' shithead!
Time for another quickie.
Jesus, you got
a game to pitch.
We got three minutes.
Come on, folks.
Let's hear it for Max Patkin--
the clown prince of baseball.
You gonna sit there all day?
And now
"The Greatest Show on Dirt"...
your own Durham Bulls!
l'm there. l'm ready.
And now WRDU radio presents...
the voice of the Durham Bulls,
Teddy Garland.
The Bulls off to a slow start,
having dropped their first three games.
But hope to turn it around tonight
with the professional debut...
of heralded young pitcher,
Ebby Calvin LaLoosh.
Millie, you gotta stay out
of the clubhouse.
You're gonna get everybody
in trouble.
l got lured.
You did not get lured.
Women do not get lured.
They are too strong and powerful
for that. Now say it...
"l did not get lured. l accept
full responsibility for my actions."
That's better.
You got your radar ready?
- Ready.
- Go to it.
Steppin' in
for the Peninsula White Sox...
is leadoff hitter Willie Foster.
Word on LaLoosh is that
the good-looking, young pitcher...
has a major-league fastball, but
sometimes has problems with control.
Damn.
One ball, no strikes
to Willie Foster.
No problem!
Go get 'em, one, two, three, babe.
Get 'em, big guy.
Ninety-five miles an hour.
That's great.
He looks just great.
Stepping in
for the Peninsula White Sox...
second baseman Allen Powley.
What's it say?
lt says he's not bending his back
on his follow-through.
Scotty, baby, take this
to Ebby Calvin.
All right, let's get down to it.
How was Ebby Calvin LaLoosh?
Well, he fucks
like he pitches.
Sort of all over the place.
My!
He walked 18.
A new league record.
- Struck out 18.
- Another new league record.
ln addition, he hit
the sportswriter...
the public address announcer,
the Bull mascot twice.
Also, new league records.
But,Joe...
this guy's got
some serious shit.
Yeah, serious shit.
Who are you?
Who's he?
l'm "the player
to be named later."
Crash Davis?
l'm Joe Riggins.
And you, Larry Hockett,
should recognize me...
'cause five years ago
in the Texas League...
you were pitching for El Paso,
l was hitting cleanup for Shreveport.
You hung a curveball
on an 0-2 pitch in a 3-2 game...
in the bottom of the eighth,
and l tattooed it...
over the Michelin Tire sign,
beat you 4-3.
l remember. l should have
thrown a slider.
Damn, Crash, how ya doin?
l'm too old for this shit.
Why in the hell
am l back in A ball?
'Cause of Ebby Calvin LaLoosh.
Big club's got
a hundred grand in him.
He's got a million-dollar arm
with a five-cent head.
Had a gun on him tonight.
Last five pitches he threw
were faster than the first five.
He's got the best young arm
l've seen in 30 years.
You've been around.
You're smart.
You're a professional.
We want you to mature the kid.
We want you to room with him
on the road.
Stay on his case all year.
He can go all the way.
Yeah? Where can l go?
You can keep going
to the ballpark...
keep getting paid to do it.
Beats the hell out of
working at Sears.
Sears sucks. l once worked there.
Sold Lady Kenmores.
Nasty work.
Even if it is
the Carolina League...
this is a chance
to play every day.
You don't want a player.
You want a stable pony.
No.
My triple A contract
gets bought out...
so l can hold the flavor
of the month's dick.
ls that it?
Fuck this fucking game!
l fuckin' quit, all right?
Who we play tomorrow?
Winston-Salem.
Batting practice, 11:30.
How's it feel to get
your first professional win?
lt feels out there.
lt's a major rush.
lt doesn't just feel out there,
it feels out there.
Kind of radical
in a kind of tubular way.
But most of all,
it's out there.
This is hopeless.
This is utterly, fucking hopeless.
Hey, l'm Millie.
l'm Tony.
l play second base.
l know.
How do you just keep
coming back every year?
'Cause l love the game, Annie.
l love it.
- Here you go.
- We didn't order these.
- He did.
- Who?
The guy in the booth.
Who's that?
That's Crash Davis.
Hey, Crash, come here.
Get over here.
He's kinda cute.
He's played in more ballparks
than l have.
Hell of a guy.
He's really different.
l actually saw him read a book
without pictures once.
- Hi, Max.
- How you doing?
Come over and sit down.
l'm Crash.
Annie Savoy.
Wanna dance?
l don't dance.
How embarrassing.
What is that?
Who's he dancing with?
All of them, l think.
You Annie Savoy?
Thanks for your note. You're right.
l wasn't bending my back.
You have a live arm there.
Thanks.
Ebby Calvin LaLoosh.
You need a nickname, honey.
l've been telling
everybody that.
- You wanna dance?
- Yeah.
She's dancing with me.
'Fraid not, pal.
You boys gonna fight
over little ol' me?
- No.
- Let's go.
Step outside and party, man.
Don't be such guys.
Max, let's dance.
You comin' or not, homeboy?
Let's go. Come on.
We're waitin'.
- Let's go, homeboy.
- Come on, Ebby. There he is.
l don't believe in fighting.
Let's just--
That's really sweet.
Fuck you, you pussy.
All right.
Take the first shot at me.
No way.
l don't hit no man first.
All right, then.
Hit me in the chest
with that.
l'd kill you.
From what l hear,
you couldn't hit water...
if you fell out of
a fuckin' boat.
Go ahead, man.
Go ahead, come on.
Right in the chest.
- No way.
- Come on, Meat.
You're not gonna hit me 'cause
you're thinking about it already.
Starting to think
how embarrassing it would be...
to miss in front of these people,
how somebody might laugh.
Come on, Rook.
Show us that million-dollar arm...
'cause l got a good idea
about that five-cent head of yours.
Hit 'im, man!
Fuck!
Ball four.
Who the fuck are you?
Good punch.
l'm Crash Davis.
l'm your new catcher...
and you just got
lesson number one:
Don't think.
lt can only hurt the ball club.
Come inside,
l'll buy you a drink.
He's my new catcher.
We fight, she gets the clown.
How's that happen?
God, l like this song.
Did you boys stop fightin'?
Pals now?
That's good.
l love a little
macho male bonding.
l think it's sweet.
l do.
Even if it probably is latent
homosexuality being rechanneled.
l'm all for rechanneling,
so who cares, right?
Okay, shall we go to my place?
Which one of us?
Both of you, of course.
These are the ground rules.
l hook up with one guy a season.
Usually takes me a couple weeks
to pick the guy.
Kind of my own spring training.
You two are the most promising
prospects of the season so far.
l just thought we should kinda
get to know each other.
Time-out.
Why do you get to choose?
- Why?
- Why do you get to choose?
Why don't l get to choose?
Why doesn't he get to choose?
Actually, nobody on this planet
ever really chooses each other.
lt's all a question
of quantum physics...
molecular attraction
and timing.
Laws we don't understand that
bring us together and tear us apart.
lt's like pheromones.
You get three ants together,
they can't do dick.
You get 300 million of them,
they can build a cathedral.
ls somebody gonna go to bed
with somebody?
Honey, you are a regular
nuclear meltdown.
You better cool off.
Where you going?
After 12 years in the minor leagues,
l don't try out.
Besides...
l don't believe in quantum physics
when it comes to matters of the heart.
What do you believe in, then?
l believe in the soul...
the cock, the pussy...
the small of a woman's back...
the hanging curveball,
high-fiver, good scotch...
that the novels of Susan Sontag
are self-indulgent, overrated crap.
l believe Lee Harvey Oswald
acted alone.
l believe there oughta be
a constitutional amendment...
outlawing Astroturf
and the designated hitter.
l believe in the sweet spot,
soft-core pornography...
open your presents Christmas morning
rather than Christmas Eve...
and l believe in long, slow,
deep, soft, wet kisses...
that last three days.
Good night.
Oh, my.
Hey, what's all
this molecule stuff?
Crash, wait!
All's l want is a date.
l'm not gonna fall in love
with you or nothing.
l'm not interested in a woman
who's interested in that boy.
Good night.
- l'm not interested yet.
- Who you calling a boy?
See you at the yard, Meat.
Damn, nobody's ever said no
to a date with me before.
He's crazy.
l want you bad.
Honey, hold on.
Slow down.
l wanna watch.
Go ahead.
Put it back on.
Jesus, what kind
of chick are you?
When you know how to make love,
then you'll know how to pitch.
l know how to pitch.
Good.
Now take it off slowly.
That's nice.
Oh, my, what a nice back.
Honey. Sweetheart.
Try taking off
your shoes and socks first.
My socks?
lt's cold in here.
What?
You think Dwight Gooden
leaves his socks on?
Ebby, honey.
Have you ever been
tied up in bed?
Bring it on, baby!
l heard about shit like this.
You ever heard
about Walt Whitman?
Who's he play for?
He sort of pitches
for the Cosmic All-Stars.
- Never heard of him.
- Oh, good.
Listen to this.
"l sing the body electric.
The armies of those l love
engirth me and l engirth them.
They will not let me off
till l go with them...
respond to them
and discorrupt them...
and charge them full
with the charge of the soul.
But the expression of a well-made man
appears not only in his face...
it is in his limbs
and joints also."
Excuse me.
Are we gonna fuck or what?
"lt is curiously in the joints
of his hips and wrists.
Love flesh swelling
and deliciously aching.
Limitless limpid jets of love,
hot and enormous."
Listen up, guys.
Can l have your attention a minute?
l'm gonna be leading a daily chapel
service here in the locker room...
- at 3:00 in the afternoon.
- Amen, brother!
Y'all are invited to stop on by
and worship before batting practice.
Jimmy, goddamn it.
Loosen up and get laid.
l know y'all think
l'm pretty square, but...
l believe what l believe.
Jesus, Ebby, you look like
a truck ran over you.
Nuke. Call me Nuke.
Annie says
it's my new nickname.
Okay, Nuke. Go get 'em.
Annie nailed you?
Annie did?
That's great. That means
you're gonna have a great year.
ls she as good as they say?
No, man, we didn't fuck.
No, she read poetry
to me all night.
lt's more tiring than fucking.
"Limpid jets of love."
Hey, Crash. Does that mean
what l think it means?
"Limpid jets of love."
Your shower shoes
have fungus on them.
You'll never make it to the bigs
with fungus on your shower shoes.
Think classy,
you'll be classy.
lf you win 20 in the Show...
you can let the fungus
grow back on your shower shoes...
and the press will think
you're colorful.
Until you win 20
in the Show, however...
means you're a slob.
Y'all don't forget
Saturday is Bull Day...
down at the Northgate Mall.
Strike!
Whoa, too bad, Butch.
Charge!
Not getting that cheese
by me, Meat.
And now batting for the Bulls,
number eight, Crash Davis.
Foul ball!
God, stupid fuck, Crash.
What'd you swing
at a breaking ball for?
Fuck me.
You usually start me off
with a hammer.
You're thinking too much, Crash.
Get out of your fuckin'head.
Don't let him in your kitchen.
Come on, Crash.Just relax.
You got it, honey.
All right, here we go.
Stay back. Relax.
Quick bat.
Foul ball!
Throw that shit again, Meat.
Throw that weak-ass shit again.
Okay, get close.
You got it. One more, baby.
He's gonna throw the deuce now.
He's gotta waste one.
Stay back and wipe that
silly grin off his face.
Come on. Bring it.
Jesus Christ!
What the hell was that?
What goes around,
comes around.
Son of a bitch throws hard.
lt's okay, Crash.
You take it easy, honey.
All right, one and two.
You can eat this shit. Relax.
Annie.
Who's this Annie?
Jesus, get out of the box, idiot.
Where's your head?
Get the broad
outta your head!
Time-out!
Give me a rag.
Get a hit, Crash.
Shut up.
All right, you've seen
all his pitches.
You've seen them all.
Shorten up, Crash.
Bring me the gas, kid.
Quick bat.
Strike!
Scotty, baby,
take this to Crash.
Folks, we have
a little lost girl up here.
Says her name is Lana Ann Baker.
- She'll be waiting...
- lt's for Crash.
at the ticket box
for her daddy, Cedar Baker.
Cedar, come get
your little girl.
- What?
- From Annie.
Read it.
"Dear Crash, you have
a lovely swing...
but you're pulling
your hips out too early.
l'd be happy to meet you tomorrow
at the batting cage to discuss it.
Signed, Annie."
lf there's one chick who'd know
you were pulling your hips out early...
it'd be Annie.
lt's kind of a personal note, kid,
so don't read it.
There you go.
Here, Millie.
What's it say?
lt says, "l wanna make love
to you. Crash."
Oh, my.
See my hips?
Yep.
And l think Susan Sontag
is brilliant.
ls this gonna happen? Us?
l'm committed to Nuke
for the season.
Oh.
You had your chance
the other day.
What is it you see in this guy?
He's a young, wild...
dim, pretty boy.
Young men are uncomplicated.
And he's not dim.
He's just inexperienced.
lt's my job
to give him life wisdom...
and help him get on
to the major leagues.
That's funny,
that's my job too.
Damn!
You're pulling your hips.
l know,
but they're nice hips.
l looked up your records.
You what?
You hit 22 7 home runs
in the minors.
That's not bad.
Don't tell anybody.
Why not?
You hit 20 more this year...
you're gonna be the all-time
minor-league champ.
The record's 246.
Well, 24 7 home runs
in the minor leagues...
would be a kind of
dubious honor.
l think it would be great.
The Sporting News should know it.
No.Just no. Please.
Okay.
Last chance,
your place or mine?
Despite my rejection
of most Judeo-Christian ethics...
l am, within the framework
of the baseball season, monogamous.
- Gimme a break.
- lt's true.
Stop it.
Jeez, the fact is...
you're afraid of meeting a guy
like me, 'cause it might be real...
so you sabotage it with some,
what is it...
bullshit about commitment
to a young boy you can boss around.
That's a great deal.
Nice.
l know women like you.
You're a regular
patron saint.
Stray cats, lost causes...
or 6'3" homeless studs.
Oh, Crash,
you do make speeches.
Crash, that was fabulous.
Crash?
You mean Nuke.
You said Crash.
No, l said Nuke.
Oh, no.
Sweetie, you shouldn't listen
to what a woman says...
when she's in the throes
of passion.
They say the darndest things.
Yeah, you said Crash.
Honey...
would you rather l'd be making love
to him using your name...
or making love to you
using his name?
Yeah, maybe you're right.
Welcome to the Eastern Seaboard
Tobacco Growers...
City Council Little League
Cash Drop Day.
These young fellas-- young men,
l should say-- over here to my left.
Hi, 18. Hi, 12.
Hey, Dino.
Hey, Millie.
Hey. l'm Millie.
l'm married.
What is that?
Chicken bone cross.
Takes the curse off the bat
that brings me hits.
What are you,
a goddamn witch?
Yes, a switch-hitting witch.
Will that work for me?
lf you believe in voodoo.
Jose, l am zero for 16.
A big fucking
doughnut hole for 16.
l can't remember the last time
l had a base hit.
Let me have
some of that stuff.
That is not belief.
That's desperation.
Jose, come on.
Just touch my bat once.
Come on, just once. l won't
bother you the rest of the day.
l swear to God.
Just touch the bat once.
Ladies and gentlemen,
five, four...
three, two, one.
Let it go!
One thousand big ones!
That batter ain't nothin'.
Come on, Nuke.
Cut it!
Time-out.
Let's play ball!
Stay there.
Give me the ball.
Hey.
Relax, all right?
Don't try to strike
everybody out.
Strikeouts are boring.
Besides that, they're fascist.
Throw some ground balls.
More democratic.
What's this guy know, anyway?
lf he's so great, how come he's
been in the minors for ten years?
lf he's so hot, how come Annie
wants me instead of him?
And another thing, Meat,
you don't know shit.
You wanna make it to the Show,
you'll listen to me.
Annie only wants you 'cause
she can boss you around. Got it?
Relax. Let's have
some fun out here.
This game's fun.
Fun, goddamn it.
And don't hold the ball so hard.
lt's an egg.
Hold it like an egg.
What's he know about fun?
l'm young. l know about fun.
Old man, he don't know
nothin' about fun.
Nobody's goin' out there.
Why's he calling
for a curveball?
l wanna bring heat.
Shake him off.
Throw what you want.
Goddamn it. Time-out.
Hey, why you shaking me off?
l wanna bring the heater.
Announce my presence with authority.
- To announce what?
- Announce my presence with authority.
"Announce your presence
with authority"?
This guy's a fastball hitter,
looking for heat.
So what.
He ain't seen my heat.
All right, Meat.
Give him your heat.
Why does he always call me Meat?
l'm the guy driving a Porsche.
Fastball.
Come on, Nuke. Settle down.
Take your time.
Home run for Bud Shelton
of the Fayetteville Generals.
What are you doing standing here?
l gave you a gift.
You stand here showing up
my pitcher? Run, dummy!
Give me the ball.
He really hit the shit
out of that one, didn't he?
Held it like an egg.
And he scrambled the son of a bitch.
He hit the fuckin' bull.
Guy gets a free steak.
You havin' fun yet?
Oh, yeah,
l've havin' a blast.
Good.
Sucker teed off on that like he knew
l was gonna throw a fastball.
- He did know.
- How?
l told him.
One down now!
Come on, Nuke. You're the man.
No batter. Chuck hard, baby.
Don't think, just throw.
Strike!
God, that was beautiful.
What did l do?
Hang on, Millie.
Here we go again.
That's the first home run
of the year for Crash Davis.
That brings the score to
Fayetteville 14, Durham 2.
Hell of a shot.
Sorry it got wasted.
l don't know what to do
with these guys.
l beg. l plead.
l try to be a nice guy.
l'm a nice guy.
They're kids. Scare 'em.
That's what l'd do.
Yeah.
Everybody into the shower!
Anybody ain't in this shower
in ten seconds gonna get fined $100.
- Larry.
- One Mississippi...
two Mississippi,
three Mississippi...
- four Mississippi.
- Get in there! Hurry it up!
seven Mississippi,
eight Mississippi...
nine Mississippi,
ten Mississippi.
You guys, you lollygag the ball
around the infield.
You lollygag your way
down to first.
You lollygag
in and out of the dugout.
You know what that
makes you? Larry.
Lollygaggers.
- What's our record, Larry?
- Eight and sixteen.
Eight and sixteen.
How'd we ever win eight?
lt's a miracle.
This is a simple game.
You throw the ball.
You hit the ball.
You catch the ball.
You got it!
We have got a 12-day road trip...
starting tomorrow.
Bus leaves 6:00 in the morning.
Goddamn, son of a bitchin',
motherfuckin' shithead. Goddamn it!
Yeah, Skipper,
you wanted to see me?
Yeah, Bobby.
Shut the door.
This the toughest job
a manager has.
But the organization
has decided to make a change.
They're releasing you
from your contract.
Skip, l know l'm in a goddamn slump,
but l hit the ball hard today.
Couple flares drop in for me,
l'm right back in the groove.
Sorry.
Let's go. Come on.
Nuke, honey!
Let's go.
We got five hours.
Honey, l want you to wear these
when you're pitching on the road.
- What are they?
- They're garters.
They're gonna hug your waist
and snuggle...
and dangle off your thighs
and buns in such a wonderful way.
lt'll help you see things
differently.
Plus, it'll remind you of me,
which is a lot nicer...
than thinking about
all those nasty hitters.
Jesus, Annie, l don't know.
You've been pitching
on the wrong side of your brain.
This will help put things
on the right side.
Big-league pitchers
don't use these.
They did when they were
in the Carolina League.
Nuke, excuse me.
Time to go to work.
All right.
Bye, y'all.
Gimme a break.
Go get 'em, boys!
Hit 'em where they ain't.
She may get woolly
Young girls
they do get woolly
'Cause of all the stress
Yeah
When they get woolly
Try a little tenderness
Stop it.
Thank you.
What?
lt's not "woolly."
Nobody gets "woolly."
Women get "weary."
They don't get "woolly."
Nobody's got "stress,"
they're wearing a "dress."
Damn, l hate people
that get the words wrong.
How come you don't like me?
You don't respect yourself,
which is your problem.
But you don't respect the game,
and that's my problem.
- You got a gift.
- What do l got?
You got a gift. When you were
a baby, the gods reached down...
and turned your right arm
into a thunderbolt.
You got a Hall-of-Fame arm,
but you're pissing it away.
l ain't pissing nothing away.
l got a Porsche already.
l got a 9-11,
with a quadraphonic Blaupunkt.
You don't need
a quadraphonic Blaupunkt.
What you need is a curveball.
ln the Show, everybody
can hit a fastball.
How would you know?
You've been in the majors?
Yeah, l've been in the majors.
You were?
You've been in the Show?
Yeah, l was in the Show.
l was in the Show
for 21 days once.
Twenty-one greatest days
of my life.
You never handle your luggage
in the Show.
Somebody else
carries your bags.
lt's great.
You hit white balls
for batting practice.
Ballparks are like cathedrals.
The hotels
all have room service.
The women all have
long legs and brains.
They're really hot?
Yeah, and so are the pitchers.
They throw ungodly breaking stuff
in the Show.
Exploding sliders.
You could be one of those guys.
Nuke could be one of those guys,
but you don't give a fuck, Meat.
l am sick and fuckin' tired of you
calling me Meat.
You wanna step outside?
Yeah, l'll step outside.
What's the problem?
What's happening?
l was just gonna ask Crash to show me
how to throw a breaking ball.
Good idea.
Did anybody bring a ball?
Double off the wall by Higgins.
Once again, Durham pitchers are unable
to get the first out of the inning.
The Bulls will attempt to end
a six-game losing streak...
against the Greensboro Hornets
with Nuke LaLoosh on the hill.
Base hit to center field
off LaLoosh.
That closes the book
on LaLoosh today.
Five earned runs,
five hits, five strikeouts...
five walks
and five wild pitches.
lt's time to tell it
like it is, sports fans.
This is the most wretched
road trip l've seen in 20 years.
And possibly the worst Durham team
in half a century.
ls the modern-day athlete a pale
imitation of the great warriors?
Only Crash Davis
stands out this year.
Begging the question, what are
these boys thinking about?
'Cause it sure ain't baseball.
Hey, Mr. Hormone,
check out this.
lce-skaters.
God, look at 'em.
Hey, fellas,
that's what we need, man.
One night with these skaters,
we can get right back on track.
Yeah, right.
Just need a night off
to end our losing streak.
What we need is a rain-out.
l can get us a rain-out.
There ain't been a cloud
in the sky in weeks.
Hundred bucks says l can get us
a rain-out for tomorrow.
You're on.
l ain't paying for this.
Crash, pay for this.
Shut up. You're gonna
wake everybody up.
Let the bonus baby
pay for it.
Jesus, man.
Crash, what are you doing?
Oh, my goodness!
We got ourselves
a natural disaster.
Wake up.
You're awake.
You're okay.
You were dreaming.
l was playing damn near naked.
- What?
- l was naked.
Playing naked.
l know.
l know. l had that dream
all the time too.
We're almost home.
Watch your head.
Here you go.
Let me get that back there.
- l'm not your slave.
- No, that one over there.
Hi.
God, l'm tired.
What a trip.
l was lousy.
l was worse than lousy.
But every time l pitched, it was
like throwing gasoline on a fire.
l mean--
What is all this l, l, l?
What about me?
Aren't you glad to see me?
Don't l look nice?
You look great.
l'm sorry.
l'm just totally exhausted.
Good. Physical exhaustion
can be spiritually fabulous.
What you need
is a good game of catch.
Catch?
Baby, come on.
Fire one in here.
This is ridiculous.
l'm a professional.
Will you just give it a try
and lean in?
Thank you.
l want you to breathe
through your eyelids.
My eyelids?
Like the lava lizards
of the Galapagos lslands.
Some have a parietal eye behind their
heads so they can see backwards.
Haven't you ever noticed
how Fernando Valenzuela...
he just doesn't even look
when he pitches?
He's a Mayan lndian.
Or an Aztec. l forget which one.
l get 'em confused.
- So do l.
- Stand up for a second.
l want you to be aware
of the chakra connection...
between your feet
and your testicles.
- Chakra.
- Your right leg and left testicle...
and your left leg
and your right testicle.
l like that.
l bet you do.
Give me the ball.
l'm tired of hearing this.
Fire one in there.
Come on.
Okay.
You're patronizing me,
and l will not be patronized.
lf l throw too hard,
l'm gonna hurt the girl.
This girl has handled
a lot of pitchers...
whose records
are a lot better than 1-7.
1-6. Give me
the goddamn ball.
- How do you like that?
- That was much better.
You see that? Because your delivery
was fully integrated...
'cause you weren't thinking about it
'cause you were pissed off at me.
That's progress.
Get your butt up here.
Let's bend over,
and l'm gonna show you--
l give up. Let's go inside
and make love and fall asleep...
until it's time
to go to the ballpark.
Or we could just take
all that sexual energy...
and kind of hold
onto it for a few hours...
and then rechannel it
into your pitching tonight.
You're a powerful young thing,
Ebby Calvin.
You want something
for that sore shoulder?
l want that shit
that don't smell bad.
- lt's on back order.
- Give him some of that shit.
That's hot.
l mean it,
that's very hot.
Annie says it'll keep
one side of my brain...
occupied while l'm on the mound,
keeping my brain slightly off center...
which is where it should be
for artists and pitchers.
Okay.
She also said l should throw
whatever pitches you call for.
Annie's a very smart lady.
What?
The rose goes in the front,
big guy.
Now batting
for the Salem Buffs...
center fielder, Joe McCorkle.
This underwear
feels kinda sexy.
That don't make me
queer, right? Right.
Breaking ball.
Yeah!
All right!
Way to start, baby.
l ain't queer.
No, l ain't.
Fastball.
Strike!
Ninety-six miles an hour.
He looks good...
but why is he all
twisting up like that?
He's using his parietal eye,
just like Fernando.
That was a humdinger.
Yeah.
Fastball again?
Why's he want the heat?
l just threw heat.
Don't think, Meat.
Just give 'em the gas.
Strike!
Jesus, what's got into Nuke?
He's wearing garters...
and he's breathing out of his eyelids
like a lava lizard.
lt's an old Mayan deal.
- Aztec.
- Aztec deal.
Got it!
l got it!
Way to go. Hustle in!
Have my mojo working.
You know what a mojo is?
- Sure.
- No, you don't.
l was great, huh?
Your fastball was up.
Your curveball was hanging.
ln the Show,
they would have ripped you.
Can't you even let me
enjoy the moment?
The moment's over.
Come on, Crash.
This guy starts me off
with a breaking ball...
l'm taking him downtown.
l dare you
to throw me the hammer.
You ain't that stupid.
Stepping up to the plate
for Durham, our own Crash Davis.
Come on. Put your hands
together for Crash.
Let's hear it!
Let's go.
Come on, Meat.
Bring me that weak-ass shit.
Bring it.
Oh, my.
Two-nothing
Bulls in the second.
First time the Bulls have been
ahead in weeks, eh, Whitey?
Mm-hmm.
Let's see if the real
Nuke LaLoosh will show up.
There you go!
Dig in there!
Back!
Crash, you got room!
What are you doing out here?
l'm cruising.
l want you to throw
the next one at the mascot.
l'm finally throwing it
where l want to throw it.
Just throw it at the bull,
all right?
Trust me.
He's the boss.
A staggering start by LaLoosh.
He's thrown five outs
on nine pitches, all of'em strikes.
He's got pinpoint control
here tonight, Bull fans.
Here's the pitch.
This guy's crazy.
Yep. l wouldn't dig in there
if l was you.
Next one might be
at your head.
l don't know
where it's gonna go.
Swear to God.
You're the man!
Easy game!
Top of the ninth.
Two outs.
One out away from a stunning
two-hit shutout for LaLoosh.
Bring it on, Meat.
Don't let up.
You own these guys.
Dad would love a shutout.
No.
No, he's looking for heat.
Let me give him the deuce.
Play ball!
Oh, no, he's shaking off
the signs.
Big mistake.
This son of a bitch
is throwing a two-hit shutout.
He's shaking me off.
You believe that shit?
Charlie,
here comes the deuce.
And when you speak of me,
speak well.
No, serve it up.
Yeah.
Home run.
Give me the ball.
You told him l was gonna
throw a deuce, right?
Yep.
That ball got out of here
in a hurry.
Anything that travels that far
oughta have a damn stewardess on it.
Don't you think?
When Nuke started listening to Crash,
everything fell into place.
He started throwing strikes,
and we started to win.
But Nuke was still confused.
He was so encouraged
by his victory...
that he vowed not to have sex
until he lost.
Unfortunately, however,
he kept on winning...
and for one extraordinary
June and July...
the Durham Bulls
began playing baseball...
with joy and verve and poetry.
The two sides of my own brain
werejumbled up and cross-wired.
While one side
was being neglected...
the other was in paradise
watching our Bulls play...
like big leaguers.
We swept a four-game series
at Kinston...
two games at Winston-Salem...
and kicked the holy shit
out of Greensboro in a three-game set.
And Crash,
who kept hitting dingers...
was approaching
the minor-league record...
though l told nobody.
After sweeping
theJuly 4 doubleheader...
the Durham Bulls
were tied for first.
Beautiful as the winning streak was,
l was getting damn lonely.
Something had to be done.
l needed a man.
l love winning, man.
l fuckin' love winning.
You know what l'm saying?
lt's like better than losing.
Teach me something new.
l need to learn.
Teach me something.
You got something
to write with?
Good. lt's time to work on
your interviews.
My interviews?
What do l gotta do?
You have to learn
your cliches.
You're gonna have to study them,
gonna have to know them.
They're your friends.
Write this down.
"We gotta play 'em
one day at a time."
"Got to play--"
- lt's pretty boring.
- Of course it's boring.
That's the point.
Write it down.
"One day at a time."
"l'm just happy to be here.
Hope l can help the ball club."
l know.
Write it down.
"l just wanna give it
my best shot.
And the good Lord willing,
things will work out."
"Good Lord willing...
How's Annie?
She's getting
pretty steamed, actually...
'cause l'm still rechanneling
my sexual energy.
l'm figurin' l'm just gonna cave in
and sleep with her.
You know, calm her down.
Are you out of your mind?
l'm just--
Talking about one time.
lf you give in now,
you might start losing.
Never fuck
with a winning streak.
Hi, boys.
Hi, darlin'.
Get in here.
Hey,Jimmy!
Want a ride?
Have you accepted Jesus Christ
as your personal savior?
No.
Can l give you my testimony?
You can do anything you want.
Hop in.
l am so proud of you guys.
You want
some more soup, honey?
No, thanks.
That was great.
How about a little back rub?
No, l'm okay.
l think l'll just take
a little nap.
You want me to tuck you in?
Annie, you can't seduce me.
Sweetie, l'm not gonna
try to seduce you.
What's that?
That's my leg.
l know what it is.
l thought maybe we could work on
some fundamentals...
since we're not gonna make love and
improve your hand-eye coordination.
My hand-eye coordination?
Unsnap my stocking.
The other day, Crash called
a woman's pu--
pussy--
You know how the hair
is kind of in a V-shape?
Yes, l do.
He called it
the Bermuda Triangle.
He said a man could get lost in there
and never be heard from again.
What a nasty thing to say.
He didn't mean it nasty.
He said getting lost and disappearing
from the face of the earth...
was sometimes a good thing to do,
especially like that.
But, he also said
that there were times...
for discipline and self-control.
And l think this is
one of those times.
Crash is a very smart man.
Honey, let's give it a try.
Here, wait. Watch.
You try. Go ahead.
Yep.
You're playing with my mind.
l'm trying to play
with your body.
You're trying to seduce me.
Of course
l'm trying to seduce you.
l'm doing a damn poor job of it.
Aren't l pretty?
God, l think you're real cute.
Cute?
Baby ducks are cute.
l hate cute.
l wanna be exotic
and mysterious.
You're exotic
and mysterious and cute.
That's why l better leave.
Nuke, you got it all wrong.
There's no relationship
between sex and baseball.
- Ask Crash.
- l did.
What did he say?
lf l give into you,
l'll start losing again.
He did?
Yeah.
l'll be back when we lose.
Damn it!
How dare you tell Nuke
to stay out of my bed.
You are messin'
with my private life!
Knock-knock, you know?
Come in.
- You're confusing him.
- Like, thank you.
You're bending his mind
all out of shape.
- l'm what?
- You're confusing him!
l'm confusing him? You got him
breathing out of the wrong eyelid.
You got him parading around
the locker room like a fruit.
That is a religious ritual
and happens to be working.
Wait a second.
Who dresses you?
- What?
- Who dresses you?
You think this is a little excessive
for the Carolina League?
"The road of excess leads to
the palace of wisdom." William Blake.
William Blake?
- What do you mean "William Blake"?
- l mean "William Blake."
Who are you?
Do you have a job?
l teach part-time
at Alamance Junior College--
English 101
and Beginning Composition.
Having a conversation
with you is like--
is like a martian
talking to a fungo.
That's really cute.Just because
sometimes you manage to be clever...
and have a nice smile,
does not mean you are not full of shit.
l'm full of shit?
You are full of shit.
- Chastity was your idea.
- l know!
- Keep your hands out of this.
- l never told him...
- to stay out of your bed.
- You certainly did.
l never told him
to stay out of your bed.
l told him a player on a streak
has to respect the streak.
- Fine.
- You know why?
They don't happen
very often.
lf you believe you're playing well
because you're getting laid...
or you're not getting laid,
or you wear women's underwear...
then you are,
and you should know that.
Come on. Think of something
clever to say.
Something full of magic
and religion bullshit.
Come on. Dazzle me.
l want you.
What?
l said, "l want you."
Stop it.
You're scared.
Maybe l am.
But l still think
you should leave.
Okay. Well...
this is the damnedest season
l've ever seen.
The Durham Bulls can't lose,
and l can't get laid.
Come on. Show 'em what you got,
Super Nuke!
Show 'em there, Super Nuke!
LaLoosh. L.A. Loosh!
Just relax out there.
Don't aim the ball.
Nuke's overthrowing tonight.
Don't look loose.
Anything bothering him?
He says his chakras are jammed.
He's having trouble breathing
out of his left eye.
- Left eye?
- Right eyelid.
Right eyelid.
Give me the ball.
Fuck!
Time-out!
Up to the plate,
Junior Chavley.
What's wrong?
l'm a little nervous.
My old man's here.
Your dad's here?
Where's he at?
He's right behind home plate.
Don't look.
Look, he's waving,
and he's just your old man.
He's as full of shit
as anybody.
What's going on?
You breathing through
the wrong fucking eyelid again?
- Shut up.
- You hear about Jimmy and Millie?
They got engaged.
Can you believe that?
Yeah? Wait till l tell him she's gone
down on half the Carolina League.
Anybody says anything bad
about Millie, l break his neck.
Excuse me. l've got
a game to pitch here.
Hey, you guys.
Don't throw me anything.
My girlfriend put a curse
on my glove.
l'll take the hex off.
Give me the glove.
You gotta cut the head off
a live rooster.
Play ball!
What the hell's
going on out there?
Looks like a convention.
Pretty soon they're gonna call roll.
Get your ass out there
and check it out.
You bet.
Let's play some baseball!
Hurry up!
Excuse me. What the hell's
going on out here?
Well, Nuke's scared...
'cause his eyelids are jammed
and his old man's here.
We need a live--
ls it a live rooster?
We need a live rooster to take
the curse off Jose's glove...
and nobody seems to know
what to get Millie or Jimmy...
for their wedding present.
That about right?
We're dealing with a lot of shit.
Okay, well, candlesticks
always make a nice gift.
And maybe you could find out
where she's registered.
Maybe a place setting
or a silverware pattern's good.
Let's get to it.
Go get 'em.
Come on.
Get your ass in gear.
LaLoosh looks in for the sign.
Here's the pitch.
Ball hit deep in the right field,
off the wall.
You should be
at the game, Annie.
No, l'm fine.
Beautiful night for baseball
here in Durham.
And as the batter steps in--
How much time did you and Jimmy
spend together...
before he proposed?
About five hours, l guess.
We both just knew.
Once again,
he goes to the resin bag.
Annie...
do you think l deserve
to wear white?
Honey, we all deserve
to wear white.
Ball two, in the dirt.
Shit! Piss! Fuck!
Bring it!
Come on!
He's coming. Go home!
We got 'im!
- Safe!
- No, l got him!
- You missed him!
- l didn't miss him!
- Don't bump me.
- He still hasn't touched the plate!
He still ain't
touched the plate!
Fuck it!
lt's a cocksucking call!
Did you call me a cocksucker?
l said it was a cocksucking call!
You can't throw me for that.
You missed the tag!
- You just spit on me!
- l did not spit on you!
You're in the wrong business!
You're Sears & Roebuck material!
You're pushing it, buddy!
You want me to run you out?
- You want me to call you a cocksucker?
- Go ahead. Try it.
Beg me!
Pretty please, beg!
Call me a cocksucker,
and you're outta here!
You're a cocksucker.
- You're outta here!
- Shit!
- What the fuck is that?
- Holy shit!
He called me a cocksucker!
He missed the tag!
l've never seen Crash so angry.
And frankly, sports fans,
he used a certain word...
that's a no-no with umpires.
Crash must have called
the guy a cocksucker.
God, he's so romantic.
When Crash got thrown out,
the game got out of hand.
Jose made three errors
with his cursed mitt...
Nuke never quite got in the groove,
though he didn't pitch bad...
and the winning streak
came to an end with a 3-2 loss.
The good news was that a man
was about to come calling.
Bad news was
it was the wrong guy.
Annie.
l know you're in there.
l can hear that crazy Mexican singer.
We lost.
lt's okay.
Oh, Annie, l'd like you
to meet my father.
Oh, my!
Ebby's told me
a lot about you.
Ebby tells me you taught him a lot
about discipline and self-control.
We were worried that he might
get involved in the wrong crowd.
We're so pleased
he met a Christian woman.
Praise the Lord.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Dad.
What?
- We got a lot of catching up to do.
- Your father is right there.
Crash tells me l gotta quit
worrying about him...
so l think it's a good opportunity
to go for a quickie.
We gotta talk.
Hello?
Yes, he most certainly is here.
lt's for you.
Hey, Skip, it's me.
What?
My God.
Okay.
Yeah. All right.
What?
l'm going to the Show.
Dad!
They're sending me up to the majors.
l leave first thing in the morning.
Can you believe it?
Let's have a quick word
of prayer.
Oh, let's not.
l gotta find Crash.
Come on. l'll dump you off.
Wait.
Not so fast.
He'll be right with you.
Come on, sweetie. l just want to
have you alone for a second...
so we can say good-bye.
l'll be back.
When somebody leaves Durham,
they don't come back.
l mean later.
Oh.
Oh, God, Annie.
Jeez.
What do you have in there?
Nothing.
You're not going to
be needing these anymore.
- l'd better take them.
- No, you're ready.
You think l'm ready for this?
Ebby Calvin "Nuke" LaLoosh.
Don't think too much.
l won't.
You know something, Annie.
You can't breathe
through your eyelids.
Of course you can't breathe
Whoever told you
such a ridiculous thing?
Now, get. Come on.
Drive careful.
Oh, my.
Hey, there you are.
Crash.
Hey, Crash...
guess what.
l'm going to the Show.
Big club's expanding its roster
to finish out the season.
Nice shot.
And l am going to the Show.
So why don't you go then?
Let's celebrate!
Congratulations.
Hope you end up on the cover
of Sports lllustrated...
or maybe a cereal box.
What's your problem, man?
l'm trying to thank you.
Let's get out of this dump.
- l'll buy you a beer.
- Hey.
You callin' my place a dump?
No, he's not.
He's not. Are you?
- No.
- He's not.
All right?
Do you know who this is?
This is Sandy Grimes.
Sandy Grimes hit 371
in Louisville in 1967.
376.
l'm sorry.
He hit 376.
That's a career, man.
- ln any league.
- Got that right.
Did you hear what l said?
l'm going to the Show.
You know what the difference
between hitting 250 and 300 is?
lt's 25 hits.
Twenty-five hits
in 500 at-bats is 500 points.
There's six months in a season.
That's about 25 weeks.
That means if you get
one extra flare a week.
A gork. You get a ground ball.
You get a ground ball
with eyes.
You get a dying quail.
Just one more dying quail a week...
and you're in Yankee Stadium.
You still don't know
what l'm talking about.
Get the hell outta here.
All right.
Fuck.
Send you a postcard.
Send me a postcard?
Hey, l made it.
You made it.
You made shit.
Hey!
You crazy?
What the hell's
wrong with you?
- l'll be all right.
- l'm talking about my mirror.
Shit, l'm sorry. Hey!
l'm not gonna fight you.
What do you mean you're not gonna
fight me, you fuck?
Why am l a fuck?
Because you got talent.
l got brains,
but you got talent.
See this right arm?
Worth a million bucks a year.
All my limbs put together
aren't worth seven cents a pound.
What are you talking about?
You're a great catcher.
l'm a great catcher?
- Forget it.
- Hey.
- Fucking forget it.
- Hey, Meat.
Damn!
l didn't mean to hit you.
You hurt my eye!
Sorry.
Did you hit me with
your right or left?
Did you hit me with your right hand
or with your left?
My left.
That's good.
You get in a fight with a drunk,
you don't hit with your pitching hand.
l can't keep giving you
these free lessons.
Quit screwing around
and help me up.
You look great, man.
Be careful with those now.
We got a boy going to the Show.
Sorry about last night.
Forget it.
l have been known
on occasion to...
howl at the moon.
You understand?
No.
Well, you will.
Look, Nuke...
these big-league hitters are going to
light you up like a pinball machine...
for a while, all right?
Don't worry about it.
You be cocky and arrogant,
even when you're getting beat.
That's the secret.
You gotta play this game
with fear and arrogance.
Fear and ignorance.
No, fear and arrogance,
you hayseed, not ignorance.
l know.
l just like seeing you
get all worked up.
Listen.
Thanks.
Hey, Nuke.
Good luck.
You too...
Meat.
l now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Jimmy, we all pitched in,
and we got you a little gift.
Tony.
Kind of a special wedding cake
from the Durham Bulls.
Oh, my Lord!
Yeah, Skip?
You wanted to see me?
Crash, shut the door.
l wanna thank everyone!
Gimme a piece of that!
This is the toughest job
a manager has.
But...
the organization
wants to make a change.
Now that Nuke's gone, they wanna
bring up some young catcher.
Some kid hitting 300
in Bluefield.
He's probably a bust.
l put in a word for you
with the organization.
Told them l thought you might make
a fine minor-league manager someday.
There might be an opening
at Visalia next year.
You had a hell
of a year, Crash.
But...
you know how it is.
l got released.
l heard already.
Oh, my.
l think probably with my love
for four-legged creatures...
and hooves and everything,
that in another lifetime...
l was probably Catherine the Great
or Francis of Assisi.
l'm not sure which one.
What do you think, honey?
How come in former lifetimes...
everybody is somebody famous?
How come nobody ever says
they were "Joe Schmoe"?
Because it doesn't work
that way, you fool.
God, you are gorgeous.
You wanna dance?
Yes.
l guess you do.
Crash took off at dawn.
Said he heard there might be
an opening for a catcher...
in Asheville
on the South Atlantic League.
A woman should be so strong
that she's not affected by such things.
lt wasn't the first time
l went to bed with a guy...
and woke up with a note.
At least the son of a bitch
left me breakfast.
You have to respect a ballplayer
who's trying to finish the season.
At least,
that's what l told myself.
Baseball may be a religion
full of magic cosmic truth...
in the fundamental ontological
riddles of our time...
but it's also a job.
Come on, Meat.
Throw me that weak-ass shit.
You ain't gettin'
that cheese by me.
Bring it.
When Crash hit his 2 4 7th home run,
l knew the moment it happened.
But l'm sure nobody else did.
And The Sporting News
didn't say anything about it.
"Full many a flower is born
to blush unseen.
And waste its sweetness
on the desert air. "
Thomas Gray.
Or William Cullen Bryant.
l don't know.
l get 'em mixed up.
Anyway, my attempts at housekeeping
were feeble as usual.
l sometimes
get easily distracted.
Funny thing was
l stopped worrying about Nuke.
Somehow l knew
nothing would stop him.
The world is made for people
who aren't cursed with self-awareness.
Crash was right--
Nuke had a gift.
l'm just happy to be here,
and l hope l can help the ball club.
You know, l just wanna
give it my best shot...
and good Lord willing,
things will work out.
You gotta play them
one day at a time, though.
Raye Anne, right?
That's a beautiful name.
ls that Greek?
lt's a beautiful name.
There's a great song by Motley Crue.
Do you know it?
"Raye Anne, she's a stay in."
Anyway, a good friend of mine
used to say...
"This is a very simple game.
You throw the ball, you catch
the ball, you hit the ball.
Sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose.
Sometimes it rains."
Think about that for a while.
What happened?
l quit.
Hit my dinger
and l hung them up.
l'm quittin' too.
l mean boys,
not baseball.
There might be an opening for
a manager in Visalia next spring.
Think l could make it
to the Show as a manager?
You'd be great.
Because you understand about
nonlinear thinking.
Baseball seems like a linear game
with all those lines and box scores.
But the fact is, it's a spacious
non-time kind of time to it.
What?
l got a lot of time
to hear your theories.
And l wanna hear
every damn one of them, but...
now l'm tired and l don't want to
think about baseball.
And l don't wanna think
about quantum physics.
And l don't wanna
think about nothing.
l just wanna be.
l can do that too.
Walt Whitman once said,
"l see great things in baseball.
lt's our game.
The American game.
lt will repair our losses
and be a blessing to us."
You could look it up.