Ah, if I give the love
you know you won't forget
Girl, if I give the love
If I give the love
you know you won't forget
Girl, if I give the love
Come on to me, baby
And take my blues away
What I need to see now
Is brighter days
I want to take away
my dark skies
Take away my tears
Take away my sufferin'
People feel for
all these years
Ah, if I give the love
you know you won't forget
Girl, if I give the love
If I give the love
you know you won't forget
Girl, if I give the love
Let this love light shine
Let it in your soul
Steady on forever
It's time to take control
- On your mark, get set, run!
- We don't need no darkness
We don't need no fear
We don't need no sadness
All we need is care
Don't get upset
if you ain't got nobody
if you have no fun
- Don't get angry
- Don't get upset
- When you wake up in the mornin'
- Hey, Derice, where you runnin', man?
- 'Cause it's a new day
- West.
- Mornin'. How are you?
Life's just begun
Ooh, yeah
Give thanks and praises
- Hey there.
- Derice!
- Yeah, man!
- Love is coming your way
Don't get upset
if you ain't got nobody
if you have no fun
- Don't get angry
- Don't get upset
When you wake up
in the mornin'
'Cause it's a new day
Life's just begun
Ooh, yeah
Give thanks and praises
- Morning.
- Faster, Bannock, faster!
Come on, child, you have
an Olympics to get to.
Handsome as a lion, that one.
I could watch that backside
all day.
Come on!
- Go! Come on!
- Ah, if I give the love
you know you won't forget
Girl, if I give the love
Take away my sadness
Take away my tears
Hey, Sanka.
This steering wheel
is finished.
All right, team, let's get ready
for the pre-race cheer. Ready?
- Yes, sir!
- Ready?
All right,
one, two, three, toot!
Who's the captain
of our crew?
Who's a friend to me and you?
Kind of nice, good-looking too.
Sanka! Sanka! Yea, Sanka!
Get back to work!
Who's the big hot bag of air who
doesn't have to comb his hair...
who doesn't bathe
and doesn't care?
- Sanka! Sanka! Sanka!
- Yea, Sanka! Hey!
What's happenin', star?
Where you been, man?
You almost missed my all-time world
record: seventh derby in a row.
Easy, Rasta. I'm not going to forget
my best friend on this day of days.
Derice, my grandfather says
you're definitely going to
make it to the Olympics.
He says you're even faster
than your father.
-Yeah, man, do it for Jamaica!
-Hey, you know what my grandfather says?
- What?
- Get back to work!
- Booie, booie!
- What are you talkin' about?
Good luck, man. I'll see you
at the finish line, all right?
- Hi, Momma Coffie.
- Hi, Derice.
- Derice, is Sanka ready?
- Who knows?
Ready. That boy's never ready.
He's a lazy, crazy, sorry,
no-good bag of bones.
So what you laughing at?
All pushcarts
to the start position!
- Ready, little man?
- Ready, big man.
Kiss the lucky egg.
Let's go!
- On your marks...
- Feel the rhythm! Feel the rhyme!
Get on up!
It's pushcart time!
and go !
Here we go, Winston!
The Rockett has been launched!
Hey, fruitcake!
Where'd you get that cart?
Clear out!
Come on, move out! Look out!
Sanka Coffie,
pushcart champion!
- Pushcart champion!
- Get away! Get away!
Hey, grandma, out of my way!
Hey, Sunday driver, make room
for the Rasta Rockett! Make room!
- Sanka, four more carts left!
- Pee Wee, move! Move out!
I love Jamaica,
and Jamaica loves me!
Champion! Champion!
You can't mess with the best!
- Move over! Move over!
- Get away! Get off me!
- Go, Sanka!
- Get him! Get him!
One more cart left!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Yes! We win!
Jump, Winston, jump!
Sanka!
Move it, man!
Move, move, move!
Sanka, you dead?
Yeah, man.
And where do you think
you're going?
You caught me.
- You have papers to grade.
- I'm just getting in one last run.
I can't believe the tryouts
are finally here.
- You nervous?
- I'm not nervous.
I'm ready. I've been ready
for this day my whole life.
I don't care how fast they run,
I'm going to run faster.
I don't care how much
they want it, I want it more.
I'm going to the Olympics, baby.
I feel it.
I'm going to win the gold.
Derice, are you nervous?
I'm terrified.
It's my turn, Joy!
It's my turn!
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the final event...
of today's Olympic tryouts.
We have now come to the
main event of our games...
the running
of the 100-metre finals.
We've had a most
successful afternoon...
and I'd like to congratulate
all the athletes...
who have participated
in today's events.
- You sure no one can beat him?
- Oh, sure, I'm sure.
I'm just a little concerned
about that big baldy.
Let me first congratulate our athletes
on a splendid performance...
and let me remind them that
only the top four finishers...
will earn the right to represent
Jamaica in the forthcoming
summer games in Seoul, Korea.
Wait. Y-You're Derice Bannock,
right?
- That's me.
- Oh. I hope I make the team.
-It would be a real honour to
run with you. Good luck to you.
-Good luck to you.
Derice Bannock.
Hey, good luck to you too.
Runners, take your marks.
Get set!
Mr Coolidge, please,
you have to run the race over!
I'm sorry, Derice.
Nothing can be done.
But I was born to compete
in the Olympics!
Then you're going to have to work
on your boxing or your cycling.
Those are the only other two sports
in which Jamaica competes.
I am not a boxer,
I am a runner.
And it wasn't fair.
It rarely is, my boy.
It rarely is.
Well, Papa, what do I do now?
Look, Derice, let it go, eh?
Let it go.
You'll have another chance
in four years.
Yeah.
Mr Coolidge...
who is the other man in
the picture with my father?
Irving Blitzer. He's an
American who lives here.
- Unless, of course, he's
been arrested or shot.
- Excuse me?
Well, he's a bookie now.
Takes his bets in a small
pool hall just past Sandy Bay.
- Isn't that a gold medal
around his neck?
- Oh, yeah.
That lunatic was an Olympic
bobsledder who tried to get
your father to switch sports.
He had some theory about using
track sprinters to push the bobsleds.
Some ridiculous
thing like that.
Can you imagine
a Jamaican bobsledder?
And you're sure this man,
he lives on the island?
- Oh, yes.
- Mr Coolidge, thanks a lot.
- Good, Derice.
- Oh, could I borrow this picture?
- Bring it back!
- Yes, sir. Thanks a lot, Mr Coolidge.
- Oh, just one more thing.
- Mmm?
What's a bobsled?
That's a bobsled.
Oh. So a bobsled is
a pushcart with no wheels.
-That's what it looks like here.
-Let me see that.
All right. "The key elements
for a successful sled team...
are a steady driver
and three strong runners
to push off down the ice."
Ice? lce?
Well...
it's kind of a
winter sport, you know.
- You mean winter, as in ice?
- Maybe.
You mean winter, as in igloos
and Eskimos and penguins and ice?
- Possibly.
- See you.
Where you going?
I'm going to take a hot bath.
I'm getting cold just thinking
about all this ice.
- No, man! You're going to be
part of my bobsled team!
- What do you need me for?
Who is the best pushcart driver
in all o' Jamaica?
- You're looking at him?
- Then you're going to do it?
No!
Hey, man, you could be famous.
You could have your picture
on a Wheaties box.
But you said "no," and that's
all right, because I don't need you.
Everybody is going to want
to be on my bobsled team!
Look, star, let me tell you
a little something, all right?
When you need something from me, you
don't have to hand me a bunch of lines.
All you have to do is
look at me in the eye and say,
"Sanka, you are my best friend.
We been through a whole heap together
and I really, really need you."
Sanka, you're right.
And you are my best friend.
- And we've been through
a whole lot together.
- Heap. Heap.
Sorry, man.
Whole heap together.
- "And I really, really need you."
- And I really, really need you.
- Forget it.
- But you just said if I said that--
All right.
All right, all right. All right, man.
So, let's talk about
this bill-sled team.
- No, bobsled team.
- Whoever.
Now, about the Wheaties box--
I'm going to be on it by myself, right?
No, man, you're going to
be on it with me.
And down the stretch they come!
Tumbleweed is holding on...
- as Captain Video makes it
all the way on the outside.
- Yes, Tumbleweed, yes!
- Come on! That's it!
- Brewster is dropping back
as Tumbleweed holds the rail.
- Good Tumbleweed! Good Tumbleweed!
- And here comes Captain Video
on the outside!
- Tumbleweed is slowing!
- No, Tumbleweed! No! Bad
Tumbleweed! What are you doing?
- Tumbleweed can't hold it and he
gets pinned against the rail.
- What? Don't do--
- It's anyone's race
as they approach the rail!
- Don't do that! Let him out!
- Captain Video makes his move!
Tumbleweed is running gamely...
- No! I need this one!
- but Captain Video seems
just a little bit too strong!
- Please! Come on!
- Here they come!
- No!
Yes! Tumbleweed can't hold it,
as Captain Video takes charge.
And it's Brewster finishing in second,
Susan's Pride finishes third...
and Tumbleweed
is nowhere in sight!
But, my, oh, my,
the odds-on favourite...
- showed his true colours
with that late-stretch run.
- That's all right. Uh-huh.
Tumbleweed held on momentarily,
but realistically...
only a fool would put
their money on Tumbleweed.
That horse had no chance of--
That guy won two gold medals?
I think so.
That's Tumbleweed gone.
Okay, next race.
Excuse me. Are you
Mr lrving Blitzer?
Well, that depends
on who's asking.
My name is Derice Bannock.
This is my teammate Sanka Coffie.
Greetings, sled god.
We were just wondering if you'd
be interested in coaching the
first Jamaican bobsled team.
Derice, remember the radio?
Radio?
Stick. Shooting with the stick.
Let's go!
Let's go, Derice!
Come on, Coach.
Just help me get started!
- Greetings, sled god.
- Sorry to bother you...
- Get out! Get out!
- but you're the only one
that can help us!
- Go away.
- Okay.
Nice to meet you!
- Maybe today is a bad day.
- Yeah.
I'll come back tomorrow, and
the next day, and the next day,
- No. No!
- and the next day.
- Look, whatever you're name is--
- Derice.
All right, Derice, let me lay
out some difficulties for you.
Snow-- you don't have any.
It's 900 degrees out there.
Time-- you don't have any.
The Olympics
are in three months.
And me-- you don't have me.
As far as I'm concerned, the sport
of bobsledding no longer exists.
I don't want to do it,
I don't want to coach it...
and most of all--
and I mean most of all--
I don't want to be within
2,000 miles of anyone who does.
- Now, did you follow all that?
- Then how come you still have
that poster on the wall?
Is that what's bothering you?
There. Is that better?
Are you happy?
Like I said,
my name is Derice Bannock.
I'm Ben Bannock's son.
I haven't seen this picture
in twenty years.
Huh! Would you look at me then.
- Ooh. Would you look at me now?
- Please, Mr Blitzer.
Just give me a chance.
If I don't have what it takes,
we forget the whole thing.
- Believe me, kid, you do not
have what it takes.
- But you thought my father did.
Your father was one of
the toughest competitors I ever saw.
He ran the 100 metres
in ten-flat.
Well, I run it in 9.9.
Come on. Coach me.
Sorry. You're a couple
decades late.
Oh, I see. Well, it might be
easy for you...
to walk away from me,
Mr Blitzer...
but you can't walk away
from this:
20 years ago you came down here
to see if you could make...
a Jamaican sprinter
into a bobsledder...
and you never got that chance.
Look at me, Mr Blitzer.
I'm your chance.
Take it.
All right, everyone quiet down.
Nice group here.
Now, for two of you lucky people,
our trip to the Olympics...
starts right now.
And I want to introduce you...
to Mr lrving Blitzer...
who's going to be
our expert bobsled coach.
Sanka, hit it, man.
You're on the air, sled god!
- Gentlemen, a bobsled
is a simple thing.
- Yeah! So's a toilet!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Basically, what you're looking to do
is get your sorry rear ends...
from the top of an icy chute
to the bottom.
You're ziggin',
you're zaggin'.
It's the biggest, coldest roller
coaster you've ever been on.
I-lce.
Oh, yeah.
I almost forgot, uh--
One minor drawback to this
delightful winter sport...
is the high-speed crash.
That hurt. Aah.
Always remember, your bones
will not break in a bobsled.
No, no. They shatter.
So...
who wants in?
Look, Baldy's here.
- Glad you could make it, man!
- Don't touch me!
No problem. So what's your name?
Yul Brenner.
Well, it's good to have you
as a teammate, Brenner.
Let's get one thing straight,
Bannock.
We may be on the same team...
but I am no one's teammate.
- Long as you come here to bobsled.
- Hey, listen, man...
the only reason why
I come here...
is to get off of this
stinkin' island.
If I have to take one
of those bobsleds to do it...
then all right.
- No problem.
- Uh, yes.
Yes, I have a problem. There's
no such thing as a three-man sled.
- You're one Jamaican short.
- Hey.
The meeting start yet?
- Uh-oh.
- You!
- I'll kill you.
College boy, I'll kill you!
- Wait! Hold on !
- Hey, hey! Lighten up!
Whoa! Whoa! Down, boy!
- Wait a second!
- He didn't mean anything!
He didn't mean it!
- You're dead! You're dead!
Kill him,
and we don't have a team.
- I'm not riding
in the same sled as that.
- He tripped me too, you know.
But in case you haven't noticed,
there's no one else here.
You're crowding me, slinky head.
Slinky head.
That's a good one.
- What are you laughing about?
- Nothing.
If it wasn't for you, rich boy,
I'd be in the Olympics right now.
I don't know what
you all are arguing about...
- 'cause Derice was going to
beat both your butts anyway.
- What are you talking about?
How 'bout I beat your butt
right now?
How 'bout I draw a line down the middle
of your head so it looks like a butt?
Forget it, man. I'm gone.
Fine. Stay here on the island.
We're going to Canada.
All right.
I'll do it.
But you'd better tell
this mama's boy...
to stay the hell
away from me.
You understand?
No problem.
Hey, lrv...
say hello to the first
Jamaican bobsled team.
Oh, goody.
Gentlemen, this is a bobsled.
Sort of.
- All right, here's what
we're going to do. Yul--
- Don't touch me.
Of course. Sorry. You're going
to be the second middle man.
You're strong, you're fast, and
you're going to love that seat.
Junior, you're the first
middle man.
You're quick, you're sharp.
Hop in.
-Sanka--
-I know-- I'm the driver, right?
- No, you're the brake man.
- No-- No, I'm the driver.
No, you're not.
You're the brake man.
- I'm the driver.
- You're not! You're the brake man.
See, you don't understand!
I am Sanka Coffie!
I'm the best pushcart driver
in all of Jamaica!
I must drive! Do you dig
where I'm coming from?
- Yeah, I dig where you're coming from.
- Good.
Now dig where I'm coming from.
I'm coming from two gold medals.
I'm coming from nine world records
in both the two and four-man events.
I'm coming from ten years of
intense competition with the
best athletes in the world.
That's a hell of a place
to be coming from.
You see, Sanka, the driver
has to work harder than anyone.
He's the first to show up
and the last to leave.
When his teammates are all out
drinking beer, he's up in his
room studying pictures of turns.
You see, a driver must remain focused
one hundred percent at all times.
Not only is he responsible for knowing
every inch of every course he races...
he's also responsible for the lives
of the other three people in his sled.
Now, do you want
that responsibility?
I say we make Derice
the driver.
So do l, Sanka, so do l.
Oh, the back is nice.
All right, Father, listen here.
You see, I've made up my mind.
I'm going to be a bobsledder.
That's right. A bobsledder.
Oh, really?
Well, I'm sorry
you feel that way.
Fine. Cut off my allowance.
Because you see, Father...
a man has got to do
what a man has got to do.
Just who I wanted to see.
- M-M-Me?
- You know where I just came from?
- W-Where?
- I got you a job...
with Webster, Webster and Cohen,
the biggest brokerage house in Miami!
- Oh, right. Webster, Webster and Cohen.
- Yes! That's right.
And you start end of the month.
- Yes, but I thought that I would--
- Look...
we went along with this
track nonsense long enough.
And we agreed that it's time to
get on with your real future. Right?
- I know--
- Right?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
I'm going to tell your mother.
I guess we sure told him.
Winning a bobsled race
is about one thing: the push start.
Now, I know you dainty little
track stars think you're fast.
Well, heh, let's see
how fast you are...
when you push
a 600-pound sled.
Now, a respectable start time
is 5.7 seconds.
If you speed demons can't
whip off an even six-flat...
you have a better chance of
becoming a barbershop quartet.
Derice, come on! Hey!
Junior, get in! Never mind!
We'll have to move it back.
Let's go!
- Here on this mountain top Whoa-oh
- Slow down! What are you
doing to me? Slow down!
- I got some wild, wild life
- 14.3. No good.
- I've got some bills
to pay, whoa-oh
- 13.5. 11.7.
This is what it's all about!
This is where you win or lose the race!
Right here in the pushcart! This
is where you're gonna practise!
Right here! Right here in the
Volkswagen, you're gonna practise!
No, Junior, quit falling down!
Come on, hustle!
Catch up to them!
There you go!
Junior! No! Do it again!
Whoa, whoa! Stop! Stop, Derice!
Stop! Wait! Wait for me!
Wait! I'm in! Stop!
Slow down!
- Great. Very good. Try it again.
- Wild, wild life
If I've said it once,
I've said it 46 times.
Cold weather endurance is vital
to building a successful sled team.
- Cold enough?
- Wild, wild life
- You got to live your life
You got to live your life
- One, two, three!
Wild, wild life
- Wild, wild life
- Go! Go! Go!
- Here on this mountain top Whoa-oh
- Whoa! Slow down!
- Sanka, hit the brakes!
Hit the brakes, man!
- I can't! It's stuck!
Hold on!
About some wild, wild life
Sanka, you dead?
Yeah, man.
What have you done to the
police unit? I shall arrest you!
- Who owns this thing?
- We do, sir.
- And who are you?
- The Jamaican bobsled team, sir.
Don't give me that business.
I wasn't born yesterday.
5.9! 5.9!
You did it! You did it!
5.9! We did it!
We did it! 5.9!
Get out of the way. Get out
of the way. 5.9, guys. What?
- Who are you?
- I'm their coach! You guys okay?
- Yeah.
- How's the sled?
- Yeah, man, we're fine.
- Sled's okay?
Well, it's in the wrong place!
Get it back to the top of the hill!
Let's move it right now, you slackers!
Move it! Let's hustle! Come on!
Let's move it!
Come on, you guys! Move it!
I'm not asking for
a winter sports programme.
All I need is a lousy 20 grand so I can
get us to the Olympics. That's all.
How in God's name are you
going to get to the Olympics?
These boys have never even
seen a sled race before!
Mr Coolidge, I have been looking at
sledders since I was twelve years old.
If I say these kids can make it
to the Olympics, they can make
it to the Olympics.
Okay. Well, I'll tell you
what we'll do.
Practise down here with
the boys a bit more, and when
you're a little further along...
- I'll come along and see you--
- No! No! No!
Now, just a minute,
Mr Blitzer.
This country enjoys
a fine athletic tradition...
and if you think I'm going to give you
the little money we have...
so that you can parade us around in
front of the world like a freak show...
you've got another thing coming.
It's bad enough how you
embarrassed your own country.
I'm certainly not going to
allow you to embarrass ours.
No go, kid.
That's okay, Coach.
We'll get the money.
- Do the words "give up"
mean anything to you?
- Not a thing.
Some people say you know
they can't believe
Jamaica
We have a bobsled team
'Nuff people say you know
they can't believe
Jamaica
We have a bobsled team
Hi. I'm here to offer you an
opportunity of a lifetime.
We're looking for a sponsor
for the first Jamaican bobsled team.
Oh!
We have the one Derice
and the one Junior
I'll pay you a dollar
to shut up!
We got nine dollars and fifty-two cents
from Yul Brenner, thank you.
We got a hundred and eighty-four
dollars from Derice and me.
Sanka, how did your singing
on the street go?
How did it go?
It went like this:
'Nuff people say you know
they can't believe
- Sanka, we know.
- Jamaica, we have a bobsled team
- Sanka.
- We have the one Derice--
How much?
- I made a dollar and sixteen cents.
- Oh, that's great.
We're only short about
nineteen thousand bucks.
- Sorry I'm late, everybody.
- No, really, that is terrific.
Don't pack a suitcase, Junior.
We're not going.
Mmm, that's too bad.
- Whoa!
- Oh! Where'd you get it, man?
- I sold my car.
- Yes, man.
- I am going.
- No, we're not.
Look here, Junior, I appreciate
what you're trying to do here...
but we can't accept this money;
it just wouldn't be proper.
Uh, Derice, if I hadn't
tripped you fellas...
we'd already have been going
to the Olympics; I want you to have it.
You mean you want us
to have it, right?
Right. Us.
Thanks a lot, Junior.
Thanks a whole heap, man.
Remember, this doesn't mean
that I like you, you understand?
Be sure to thank your father for
us, 'cause Lord knows, he didn't
have to let you sell that car.
Well, uh, he doesn't know
I sold the car.
Um, he doesn't know
I'm on the team.
He thinks I'm off to Miami...
and I loaned the car
to a friend...
to work for Webster, Webster
and Cohen, someplace like that.
Some people say you know
them can't believe
Jamaica
We have a bobsled team
- Yes!
- We have the one Derice
- And the one Junior
Yu-- Sanka
The fastest of the fastest
of Jamaican sprinters
Go to Olympics
Fight for Jamaica
Welcome to Calgary, Alberta, Canada,
home of the 1988 Winter Olympic Games.
- This is it.
- We hope you all enjoy your stay.
Sanka, man, what you smokin'?
I'm not smokin'.
I'm breathin'.
- All right, fellas,
this is us. Let's go!
- Move! Let's go! Move!
- Aah! Me first!
- What's the matter? You guys cold?
It's not so much the heat; it's
the humidity that'll kill you.
Excuse me, do you know where
you can register for bobsled?
Do you know where you
register for bobsled?
- See you.
- I'll see you around.
- Okay, Mike, good to see you again.
- Ja?
- Take care. All the best.
- Ja? Okay, ja.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah, I'd like to
register for the tryouts.
- What country?
- Uh, Jamaica.
What country?
Jamaica.
Well, what do you know?
A Jamaican bobsled team.
Okay, here it is.
Uh, it says here your qualifying run
will be held on the evening of the 10th.
Your judges will be Shindler,
Gremmer and Kroychzech.
- I know Kroychzech. He's a good guy.
- Yeah.
In order to qualify, you must
complete the course safely in 1
minute, 2 seconds-flat or under.
- Used to be a minute, five.
- Yeah.
Times change.
- Irv, is that you?
- Roger, how you doing?
Hello, Kurt.
Been a long time.
Obviously not long enough.
- Hello, Larry.
- Jesus Christ, lrv.
What the hell did you
do to yourself?
- Don't worry about them, lrv.
- Roger, you got to do me a favour.
- What?
- Please. You know that
revolving restaurant thing?
- Yeah.
- Meet me there in half an hour.
- Half an hour?
- Yeah. Please!
- Roger, come on!
I'll try.
- Thanks, Roger.
- Yeah, well-- What's up, lrv?
- How about a drink?
- No, I'm fine.
- What's so important
that it couldn't wait?
- Want something to eat?
- No, I'm fine!
- A salad or something?
- Irv!
- I need a sled.
- You came all the way
to Calgary without a sled?
I got 4,800 dollars.
I just need something competitive.
- For five grand?
- I know you got something
lying around, Roger.
- But, lrv--
- Anything.
- You know I can't do that.
- Now, wait a minute, Roger.
Remember when you were desperate
to make that last slot on the
'68 Grenoble team...
and you pleaded with me
to talk to Kurt?
Did I say, "Sorry, Roger,
I can't do it"?
Come on, don't make me beg.
Roger, it's me.
All right, maybe I can get you
one of our practise sleds.
You're a saint, you know that?
A saint! You haven't changed
a bit! You're still a saint!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, look, don't get
all mushy on me. Just tell me one thing.
Is this whole thing a big joke,
or do you really expect these
Jamaicans to qualify?
Not only are they going to
qualify, they're going to
turn some heads doing it.
Listen, three of these guys
can run the hundred in under ten-flat.
I don't care who you are,
that's lightning.
Yeah, but can lightning
run on ice?
No problem, man.
God!
Irv, these special shoes
aren't very effective.
Grip with your toes!
All right, you sugar-coated
track stars!
Move out and let the ice rasta
show you how it's done.
- Yeah. Like that, yeah. Good.
- Hey, fellas!
- Look at my progress.
- Stop touching me!
All right, fellas, that's it!
Let's get off the ice before practise.
- What practise?
- That practise.
That's right.
Good team this year.
Ein, zwei, drei!
Oh, man, you should see this
on the hill.
- It's like a miracle.
- What's "Schweiz"?
- No, man! Swiss!
- This is the real thing, man.
Gentlemen...
I'd like to introduce you to
the newest member of our team.
Um, you won't believe what I
had to go through to get us
a sled in such good shape.
Uh--
If we're going to make it
into the Olympics...
this is the boat that's
going to take us there.
Well, I'm-- I'm told
she's actually quite fast.
I, uh, know she's not
much to look at...
- but, uh--
- Shh! She's beautiful!
All coaches must sign teams in
before approaching bob run.
Here we go.
Let's go! Let's go!
- Hold on a minute.
- All right, come on.
Here we go.