What was that?
Honey, are the kids
up? What are they doing?
I peed.
Kevin peed the bed.
Our bed? Uh-huh.
All 500 thread counts
of Egyptian cotton.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
I don't want you to
worry about it, buddy.
It'll happen again your freshman
year of college, trust me.
No more sodas before bed!
Sit down here. But I like soda.
How you doing, big guy? Good morning.
Let's have a big morning!
Let's start off with a little
breakfast, get our Froot Loops.
Here's Daddy's coffee. And I need it.
Here's your bowl of
fruit, without the loops.
Why no loop?
Daddy doesn't need loops.
I gotta eat it. If I eat a big meal now,
then I can watch what I eat later.
Otherwise, I'll get starved
and raid the refrigerator.
Okay, honey. We've got to hurry up,
'cause we got to go to hockey.
I thought you could do that
because I might try to get a
little bit of work done today.
Honey, we have to go by the
showroom and pick out the tile.
I want you to see it. We
talked about this last week
and I told you how
important today was for me.
I'm Mega Man! May the best team win!
Okay, guys, let's keep it down.
Keep the eyes on the... On the screen.
You guys doing good?
- Yes.
Honey? Yeah.
What do you think? Nickel, brushed
nickel, chrome or brushed chrome?
I like the silver ones.
They're all silver.
Well, great. Pick out whichever
knob that you like, then.
No, I'm not gonna pick
whichever knob I like
because you know what's gonna happen?
Is that I'm gonna pick one
and then you're gonna complain
once they're in and
then it'll be too late.
Hello? Dave, where
the heck have you been?
I'm picking out pulls. Why have
you been calling me nonstop?
Well, you know how my credit's
all screwed up because of my wife?
But you're divorced.
I need you to cosign for my motorcycle.
What motorcycle? I'm
buying a motorcycle.
Shane, you have no money.
Why in the world would you be buying
a motorcycle that you can't afford?
Dave, you're white. You
can't understand this.
This is something different.
Don't play the race
card with me, Froot Loop.
I'll take him in. You
stay with Kevin, okay?
Okay. All right, go ahead.
Have fun, champ. Go get 'em, buddy.
You should see this thing. It's
awesome. Even Trudy loves it.
Who's Trudy?
That's my girlfriend.
Girl from the mall?
She's 20 years old, Dave.
Let's go. Let's move
it. I got bikes to move.
Listen, Shane. You are not buying
some 20-year-old
broad a motorcycle.
I'm not buying her
anything, it's for me!
Daddy, what's taking so long?
Hey, baby, I'm on the phone,
and I would prefer it if you
didn't call me that in public.
But I call all my boyfriends Daddy!
Dave, you gotta do this for me.
Why don't you just lease it?
No, she'll know.
Who will know? She's a kid.
Buy her a Hello Kitty book.
Get her an assignment notebook
and put rainbow stickers in it.
You don't have to buy her a motorcycle.
Did you or did you not say, "Move on"?
I told you to try to work it out.
Joey's the one who told you to move on.
Can you give me a minute?
Try to make it fast, Daddy.
Dave, I'm hurting. I would
love for my wife to come back.
But we know that's not gonna happen.
It's nice to feel appreciated.
I need this for me.
Fine. Just text me the address. Okay?
Pick out a helmet, baby!
Daddy!
So, honey, this is the tile.
It's all gonna happen at once
and I really need you to dial in.
Sweetheart, I'll help you.
I want a sugar cone.
I'm gonna hit you
after this, buddy. Okay.
Honey, you work from 8:00 to 8:00.
You're not gonna be helping anyone.
Hang on, honey, okay?
It's just really busy right now
because the video game ships this month.
Now that I have you, I
just want you to dial in
and tell me what you really think.
It's fine.
Do you love it?
As much as I can love
tile, I love this tile.
Okay, good, 'cause it's $1,000.
Really? Mmm-hmm.
Is that installed?
Nope, just the tile.
Well, what is it made
out of? Whale tusks?
No, it's not made out of whale tusks.
This is so boring.
Give me just one second.
Let me just grab this.
Honey? We have to do this today. Hello?
Hello, Dave. Joey?
Yeah, hey. Look... Just
one second, that's it.
...what are you doing
about the Jason thing?
If it's Joey, can you ask him
if he's coming to the party?
Are you... Are you coming
to the party on Sunday?
Yeah, yeah, I'll be there.
Yeah, he's coming, all right?
Give me one second. Stay with Mom.
One second.
Jason's gonna be calling you, all right?
He's got another one of
his PowerPoint deals that...
Hold on one second. Hello?
Hey, Dave, it's Jason.
Listen, I'd love to put something
on the books with you and Ronnie.
Are you gonna make it to
Kevin's birthday on Sunday?
Yes, I am. Now, listen,
I was hoping that
you guys would come
down here to the firm
because Cynthia and I have
a PowerPoint presentation
that would just play gangbusters
in the conference room.
Okay, okay, hold on one
second. It's ringing.
Hello? Why'd you hang up on me?
I didn't hang up on you. You're on hold.
He's trying to get me to see
another one of his PowerPoint things.
That stuff creeps me out.
It's just how he communicates.
He's... He's, you know...
He's overly efficient.
Well, I don't like
hearing about ball cancer,
let alone looking at diagrams.
Joey, he was scared.
Tell him I'm not going.
I ain't telling him you're not going.
You know, I got him on the other line.
You can tell him yourself. Hold on.
I don't want to... I don't...
Hello, Jason?
Yeah. I got Joey on the line.
Hey, Joey, I've left you
a bunch of voice mail messages
all morning. Where are you?
Listen, I can't make it.
Well, we haven't even
set a time yet, you know.
If you'd listened to the voice mail,
you'd know that this
is just a feeler call
to check your temperature on schedule.
I'm not sitting through another
slide show about ball cancer.
Listen, pal, I'm alive today because
of early detection, all right?
Is this about ball cancer?
"Cause I..
- I'm not into that, either.
I'm gonna wrap this up right now.
and if you two refuse to check
your scrotums for hardened nodules,
I certainly can't force you, can l?
Look, I gotta go, all right? Bye+
Dave, are you still there? Hello, Dave?
Kevin! Kevin, that's not a real toilet!
Sweetheart, he's pissing in
the middle of the whole thing!
Buddy, I gotta go.
But Cynthia and I are willing to
offer you a life-changing opportunity.
Jason, you don't understand.
My son is literally peeing
right in the middle of the
store. I gotta go. Go, go, go.
Okay, but that's not
a real toilet there.
It looks like a real toilet to me.
Yeah, it looks real. Okay.
That's a whole other conversation.
You feel better? Yep.
Okay, let's button those up.
You want me to get those for you?
Yep.
There's not a lot to
say. Sorry about that.
Mom, Dad's home.
Hi, hon.
Hey, how was your day?
Usual. Yours?
Good.
Okay, love you. Bye.
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait
a second, wait a second.
You're going out? Yeah, I'm going out.
What are... What are you wearing?
Shorts. Shorts?
That's... That's a Maxi Pad.
Dad, they're designer shorts.
They're French. Goodbye.
Could you just come over
here? Sit down for a second.
I don't have time for this.
Come here. Sit down. No, I'm...
I'm late and they're waiting for me.
I know,
but you still live in my house
for another few months, okay?
Yeah, I know. Now when
you dress like that,
you send signals.
You know what kind of
guy you attract like that?
You attract the guy with the...
With his pants around
his ass at the mall.
No, I don't! Yes, you do.
Sweetheart, he is right.
Lacey, I'm saying you're beautiful.
You're smart. You're a good person.
You just got accepted into Stanford.
We're so proud of you.
I'm just saying know your value, okay?
And if a guy doesn't see
that, he doesn't deserve you.
No, and you don't want to
be with those guys, honey.
Okay, then I'll go change.
Thank you.
And could you change the
pictures on your Facebook page?
Dad.
It's just 'cause we love you.
Love me less.
I don't want any bikini
pictures on the Internet!
When you're living in my
house, you're a Taliban!
Okay? You keep your body a secret.
Except you get to, you know,
go to school and read books.
Did you send the tuition check?
You said you were going to.
Please. Don't start this again.
Yeah, I didn't start with
it. You just brought it up.
You're supposed to send the check.
You said you were gonna do it.
You never do anything
you say you're gonna do.
Eighteen years. Just try to hold it
together for another couple months.
Trust me, I'm counting the days.
Do that hurt, Daddy,
or do that feel good?
It's both. It hurt and it feel good.
Bang, bang.
Did you put in the wide beauty shots?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
Why would you ask me that?
You know I triple-check everything.
Yeah, no, I know. It's just,
you know, super-important, okay?
We only get one shot at it.
It'd just be nice if you could
show me a little bit of trust.
I do. Come on, I do, I do. I just
want this to be perfect, that's all.
It's not about trust. Come on.
I want it to be perfect, too.
Good.
How old is she?
I think she's 20. He
met her at the mall.
She was working at Foot Locker.
He was so in love with Jennifer.
I am shocked he met someone so quickly.
I know. I was hoping they
were just taking a break.
I haven't even heard from
her since they split up.
I think he got us in the
divorce. You want more wine?
Cynthia, it's time. We're
all set up in the bedroom.
Great. Ladies?
You're kidding, right? No, it's easy.
We brought our own screen.
You can't do it right now.
We're in the middle of
my son's birthday party.
It won't take long and I know
you"re gonna be really excited.
Bring your booze.
Okay, then.
We're taking the wine.
Watch this, guys. Watch.
This is a really spooky ball.
Just, could you please put
the ball cancer video on?
I'm trying, Joey.
Please. I don't want to
watch that ball cancer video.
Where's Trudy?
Oh, she's watching the magician.
Well, there it is. Okay.
This is not a video and it
is not about ball cancer.
Thank God. That,s a first.
Jason and I are seriously
considering getting a divorce.
Okay? So, it's no secret
that Cynthia and I have had our problems
trying to conceive
over the last 12 months.
That's no reason to get a divorce.
No.
We know. Of course not.
But suffice it to say, it's been
more than taxing on both of us,
and it's forced us to question
our entire relationship.
You two are perfect for each other.
We're just not so sure
about that anymore.
We're not in a good place.
Now, this is not a decision
that we're taking lightly.
Cynthia and I have been
together for eight long years.
And if it's not meant to be,
we just don't want to waste
any more of each other's time.
Yeah. Because, if we do get divorced,
it will take at least six months
to go through the five stages of grief.
For the sake of argument,
let's optimistically assume it takes
six months to find compatible mates.
Tack on another 12 months for courtship,
an additional six months
for attempting procreation...
You can see how this starts to stack up.
Sounds like you guys are really
working from the heart on this one.
Well, we're lost, Dave,
and so what we need to do is we
need to take the next two weeks
and we need to find out whether
we're gonna push forward,
or whether we're gonna fold up shop.
And that is why we are going to go here.
You're on, Cyn.
Welcome to Eden. Okay? The
ultimate playground for couples.
It's got fun, it's got sun.
It's Disneyland for adults.
Wow. That is amazing.
Yeah, you guys are gonna have a blast.
Actually, we have found
a great group rate.
Oh, there's the fine print.
No, now... Now, Joey, you know, just...
The embarrassing fact is that, you know,
Cynthia and I can't afford to
go to this place by ourselves,
but if all of us go
together, it's half-price.
It's called the Pelican Package.
Okay? It's six nights, seven
days and it's all inclusive.
And there are quite a few
activities you can choose from.
Who here likes to eat?
I know you guys do. I sure do.
Right? Boom!
Why not do it at a
four-star restaurant?
You guys, it has a
state-of-the-art spa.
Ah. Mmm-hmm.
They've got your kayaking,
they've got your windsurfing,
they've got your canoeing,
they've got your jet skiing. Wow.
It's got Couples Skill
Building and snorkeling...
Who, whoa, whoa. Back up.
What was that last thing?
Snorkeling?
No, no. Before snorkeling
and after jet skiing,
you said, "Couples Skill Building."
That sounds like therapy to me.
See, that's gonna be a problem.
We don't believe in therapy. No.
Hell to the no.
Then you don't have to do it.
That's the great thing about
the Pelican Package, you guys.
It really includes everything.
Obviously, Jason and I want to partake
in the Couples Skill Building,
but you guys can just do the fun stuff.
So what are we asking?
We're asking for you
guys to fly to paradise
and have an awesome time, okay?
I mean, this... Come
on, it would be a blast.
Jason, I got a job,
and with everything that's going on with
the house and with the kids right now,
it would be impossible
for us to leave them.
Yeah, we can't.
When was the last time you
two took a vacation? Hmm?
I mean, don't you want to go
to this island and have fun,
together, as a couple?
What kind of question is that?
That's like asking Richard Simmons,
would he rather stuff his face
or skip around to the oldies.
Of course he'd rather stuff
his face, but he can't,
'cause he's... He's got
to stay thin so he can...
So he can get up and do his
thing and... And make videos.
Maybe he needs the money. Maybe
he's got a gambling problem!
I don't know what goes
on in that dude's head!
And I'd love to go to that
island, but I can't, either.
Not 'cause I got to make videos like
Rich, but I got other obligations.
Listen, I can really appreciate
the situation that you guys are in.
Right, well, we need
to know by midnight.
We've been on the wait list forever
and these slots just opened up.
We'd need to leave next week.
Next week?
That's right.
What happened to spontaneity?
What happened to fun?
I don't know. Why don't we
have a PowerPoint presentation
on spontaneity and fun
and figure that one out?
Look, Cynthia and I
need this trip, okay?
I mean, really. You
know, the problem is,
you know, we've stopped having fun
and we're not even sure we
know how to anymore, okay?
So, what we need to find out
is can we get back to the place
where we really enjoy
each other, you know?
Can we get back to the place
of, you know, being in love?
Cynthia's IM-ing me.
Jason was IM-ing me all night.
What'd you tell him?
I logged off.
The place did look beautiful.
You know what it made me think?
It'd kind of be like we got
to take our honeymoon, finally.
God, yeah.
That'd be great.
Really?
Yeah.
Don't you think? I mean, I don't
know, maybe it's a girl thing.
When you're a little girl,
you dream about your
wedding and your honeymoon...
You know.
I was pretty lucky to
get that job right away.
Yeah, of course.
I mean, I can't even imagine...
Living in your dad's
basement any longer? No.
It's funny how time goes so fast.
That doesn't seem that long ago.
No.
Seems like we just had so much going on
and we have ever since,
but maybe the thing to do is just really
buckle down over these next six months
and then when we come up
for air, we'll go somewhere.
That sounds like a plan.
Dave? Did you hear that?
Go back to bed, honey.
What's going on?
I think there's someone outside.
Okay, I'll check it out.
Honey, be careful.
Freeze! Do not move!
Hey, don't... No, it's me, it's
me, it's me! It's me! It's Jason!
What's going on?
It's fine, honey, it's Jason.
Hello!
Why didn't you call?
Didn't want to wake you up.
Sorry, blew that. Back to bed.
Are you crazy? I could've
blown your head off!
What does that say about you, huh?
Rapists don't gently toss
pebbles at the window, Dave.
Wait, can you let me figure it out,
please? There's too much going on.
Turn it off!
It costs money every
time this thing goes off.
Hello? Yeah, everything's
fine. I'm sorry.
The password is
"ass-tastic." That's right.
"Ass-tastic." One word.
"Ass-tastic." "Ass-tastic." It's...
A-S-S-T-A-S-T-I-C.
Okay? Ass-tastic.
That's right, it's... Okay.
Yeah. No, thank you. We're fine.
l... Yes, thank you.
Didn't want to go with the pet's name?
What are you doing here, dude?
What do you think I'm doing here?
Jas, you're showing up to my
house in the middle of the night.
Dave. You're breaking and
entering. You're on tilt.
Yeah, I know, I'm losing my mind.
This... The whole fertility doctor
thing is just an absolute disaster.
We don't communicate anymore.
We're fighting all the time.
We... The only time we have sex is,
you know, when she's ovulating,
and even then, it's
cold. It's emotionless.
It's... I don't know.
Like an oil derrick.
We used to be very,
very spontaneous at that.
Now, it's... I don,t know.
Twice a week, tops.
That's a lot.
Is it? How often do you do it?
It's different now, 'cause
we got the kids, so...
So?
Well, my son falls
asleep in the bed with us.
That shouldn't stop you.
That's disgusting.
I'm not saying he
should tickle your balls.
Just move him into his
room when he falls asleep.
Jason. I can really appreciate
what you're going through,
but, man, this couldn't
come at a worse time.
There's just no way
that we can pull away
from everything and go right now.
I'm sorry, but there's just
no way we can go on the trip.
I'm just scared, you know. Just scared.
You know, my whole life,
everything I've known about it
for the last eight years might be over,
and, you know, I'm
prepared to face that,
you know, if it,s for the best.
If, you know... If it's not
there anymore, then, you know,
I'll face it. I don't
want to do that alone.
And I know that Cynthia
doesn't want to do that alone.
You know, we'd just... We'd
love to have our friends there.
You know that if you go,
everyone else will go.
And I have never asked you for anything.
But I am asking you for this, Dave.
Daddy?
Hey, guys, the alarm
was just an accident.
You can go back to bed.
It's just Uncle Jason.
Okay, guys. It's fine. Let
me take you back to bed.
We want you to go on your trip.
We heard you talking at the party
and you said you
couldn't go because of us.
We don't want you guys to get a divorce.
What?
What are you talking about,
honey? We're not getting a divorce.
But we just want you to be happy.
Guys, we are happy.
We're very happy, honey.
Were you guys listening to
Uncle Jason's slide show?
Thank you, buddy. That's great.
That was adult time.
And why do you think they
were listening, Jason?
I'm sorry about that.
We want you to go, so we called
Grandpa to come take care of us.
You called Grandpa?
You called him tonight?
It's a three-hour drive.
Grandpa's coming to babysit us.
Is Grandpa driving down here now?
Yay! Grandpa Jim Jim's here!
You know, this has
gotten way out of hand.
I'm sorry. I just... I wanted five
minutes of your time. I'm so sorry.
You got... You got kids, you got guns,
you got grandpas that, you know...
You got to explain infertility
and divorce and all that,
and so you got a lot of
parenting to do tonight.
I'm gonna go. I'm gonna
let myself out right here.
I will, however, take the fact that
Grandpa Jim Jim's at the front
door as a firm, tentative yes.
Pack lots of shorts.
It's really hot there.
You're gonna sweat your
bag off. Night-night, kids!
Hi. Welcome.
Thank you.
This place is beautiful.
Look. Hi, hello.
Holy shit, this looks like
a screen saver! Thanks.
Seems like he might be kind
of the guy. Come on, gang.
Hi, we are the Smith
party. Party of eight.
Eight for Smith.
Jason Smith?
That's me.
Welcome to Eden.
My name is Sctanley. Spelled with a "C".
I will be escorting you
to the Eden West resort.
Please, step aboard our shuttle.
No need to take your bags. They will
be waiting for you in your villas.
Excuse me. Sorry. Is this the
shuttle for the Eden resort?
Oh, yeah, yeah, that's the shuttle.
Raq, she's still a little
buzzed from the flight.
Man, totally. Me, too. I
don't even know what I'm doing.
Excuse me. What name are your
reservations booked under?
The San Diego Dance Academy.
Wow.
Ah. You ladies are actually travelling
on this shuttle, to Eden East.
Bummer. Bye.
See you. Bye.
Bye.
Would you care to join your wife?
Let's do it. Shall we?
Are they going some place else?
Eden East. It is an
entirely different resort.
It's beautiful.
And the luggage is
already in there, huh?
Yeah. This is yours.
Unbelievable.
The 101.
- Wow.
And we can jump right
out into this here?
You can do whatever you like.
Wow.
Look at the water.
Please. Thank you.
Wow. Wow.
I'm gonna check the bedroom. Okay, baby.
Look at this, baby.
Oh, my God. Look at this.
Welcome to your villa.
It keeps getting better, huh?
It's like a little love hut.
Wow.
This is insane!
Honey, they got fish that you
can see here through the floor!
Baby, they got a hole
where you can see the fish!
Yeah, they got fish in here, too, baby!
Jason, this is dreamy.
Baby, you can jump right
in the ocean on this thing,
and they got a hot tub on the deck!
They got the ocean and
they got the hot tub!
You can dive in the ocean
and you got a hot tub!
Yeah, they got a hot tub in here, too!
Oh, my God. Yo, I gotta
take a picture of this.
Did I tell you? Did
I deliver? Oh, my God.
She ain't never seen nothing like this.
I roll like this! Shit, yeah!
I'm glad you like, sir.
I be rolling like this.
So what goes on over
there? I hear there's music.
Is a party for single
woman and men, sir.
Yes. How do l get over there?
No, you cannot. You can
take the boat if you want,
but not for you. Okay,
when's the boat? Not for me.
No, because you got married here,
the west coast to Eden Resort
so that's why you must keep here.
I don't understand what you're
saying. You sound like Chewbacca.
Well, my instinct is
to stay married to her,
but what do you think I should do?
I mean, do you get a good vibe
from us or not-so-good vibe?
I don't know, sir.
What about this room, in particular?
You've checked a lot
of people into this room
and checked a lot of people out.
Do they usually leave
happier or less happy?
I really don't know, sir.
How do I get over to the party?
By boat or by taxi boat.
Okay. I'd like to arrange
a boat or a taxi boat.
No, it's not possible for you.
Must to stay here with your wife.
Okay, so how do I...
Fish!
Hello.
Where's the television? The main house.
There's no TV in the
room? No, not possible.
But it's the playoffs.
As an alternative to television,
might I recommend a stroll
to the hidden waterfall?
Might you recommend
putting honey in my ears
and having me fall asleep on an anthill?
It's the playoffs.
Honey, the waterfall sounds
amazing. A little romance.
You'll find that the Eden program
creates a palace of solitude,
if you just give yourself over to it.
How's the cell service here?
Monsieur Marcel believes that
technology is a distraction.
Well, how about tipping,
would that be a distraction?
I'm kidding you.
Tipping is not permitted,
nor is money of any kind.
Everything here in Eden is free.
Really?
We do, however, accept smiles.
Did you guys hear what
they have in the spa?
With the snow?
Did you know that they have a
steam, a rain, and a snow room here?
It's a new European spa.
What's a wahoo?
It's a fish.
I don't eat fish.
It's out of this world.
They catch it right here.
I used to work at Red Lobster,
so I know what they do with
them fish in the kitchen.
But, baby, this is not like the Red
Lobster. It's a four-star restaurant.
I don't give a shit! It's
still Mexicans cooking that shit
and I know what they do to it!
I'm one-twelfth Latina, and
even if I wasn't, I'm 100% human,
so I don't appreciate
comments like that.
I don't make fun of tu
la raza, so porfavor,
please, don't make fun of mi la raza-
Oh, I'm sorry, boo. I
didn't mean no disrespect.
Yo, I was with mad Mexicans
before Shane, anyway.
Good evening. I trust
you're all settled in.
Hey, my main man!
Are you in the mood
to accept some smiles?
"Cause this spread is phenomenal.
Why don't you join us for a
drink? You want to pull up a chair?
We'll order some shots.
You might want to go easy on
those. You have an early morning.
Quite the contrary.
I don't have an early morning,
'cause I tell you what's
gonna go down tonight.
I am going to get just
a little bit tipsy.
And then I'm gonna go ahead and
stuff my face on the Seafood Tower,
and I plan on shutting
it down in a big way.
l, if everything goes
well, will be in my room,
passed out on my face, come lunch-ski.
Well, I'm afraid that
isn't going to be possible.
I'm here to present
you with your itinerary.
Fantastic. You guys hear that?
This is a hard copy thing, too.
This is not like... This isn't like
a piece of paper with an itinerary.
No. This is like a book.
Thanks. And the journey begins.
Couples Skill Building at 6:00 a.m.?
Yeah, see, I was
planning on sleeping in,
and then maybe hitting the jet skis.
That is not part of your immediate
program here at Eden West.
But it was in the slide show. Uh-huh.
That would be more
appropriate at the Eden East.
What's Eden East?
The singles' resort.
Singles" resort?
Here at the Eden West, our
focus is on renewing bonds
and nurturing neglected partnerships.
And what's your focus over there?
Sex, mostly.
Freeing inhibitions.
I'm sure if we play our cards right'
we'll be having plenty
of sex here on our side.
Am I wrong, gang?
I spent three years of
therapy with Jennifer,
talking about our
feelings and our problems,
trying to hold onto our marriage.
The last thing I want to do is talk.
Look, I think there's been
a misunderstanding here.
See, we signed up for the fun stuff,
with the touchy-feely
shit being optional.
Thank you.
I think it's called the Pelican Package.
Yes, the Pelican Package,
which is monsieur
Marcel's signature course.
Great.
A healthy combination of
couple-friendly activities,
ample down time... That's the one.
...sprinkled in with some
Couples Skill Building courses,
designed to reignite the dimming flames
of even the most
mismanaged relationships.
Okay, see, these relationships
are not mismanaged.
Well, thank you, Dave. Yes.
Yeah. I'm just saying
we're here to have some fun,
so we are excited about
the couples' activities,
as well as some down time.
It's the flame-lighting thing
that does not have us inspired.
That's more suited for
this particular couple here.
I don't think you're
quite understanding me.
Monsieur Marcel's Pelican Package
is not a fast-food restaurant wherein
you pick what you want from a menu.
Monsieur Marcel is the
single most-recognized
couples whisperer in the entire world.
Couple whisperer?
He has studied
psychology, yoga, tai chi,
The Art of War, and combined
them to form this place, Eden.
The Mecca for couples. Mmm.
He has designed a program
specifically for you.
You either partake of the
entire meal or have none of it.
I think you're being a little
extreme here, Mr. Belvedere.
We have a very long waiting list.
If there's been some
kind of misunderstanding,
I'd be happy to refund your
money, and you can go on your way.
We will, however, not be
able to refund your airfare.
No, it's just that we were excited
about the sightseeing and the hiking
and the jet skiing and
the snorkeling. It's...
Well, there are plenty of places
that provide those activities.
Perhaps this troupe
might be more comfortable
at a Sandals or a Club Med.
This here is monsieur Marcel's Eden.
Now, if you're not at Couples
Skill Building by 6:00 a.m.,
I'll take that as you want your refund
and will not be completing the program.
Screw him! Where does he get
the ass to run down Sandals?
Sandals rocks.
It's just one little
thing we have to do.
It'll be over in a few hours and
then we have fun the rest of the day.
You know, let's just
not forget why we came.
This is not what we signed up for!
This is not what we signed up for.
I don't remember ever
seeing 'mandatory,"
but, listen, we just go with it.
Now we're on Han's Island about
to do the thing with Bruce Lee.
Guys, guys, I don't think
there's any reason to overreact
right off the bat, okay?
Obviously, the meal is included,
from what he said, so
let's just sit here,
we'll weigh the pros and cons from
a calm place, we'll make a decision.
That was amazing.
Oh, might have been the
best meal I've ever had.
Well, could be a full week of those.
What are you doing? Your last course.
Dessert.
It is so beautiful here. I can't
wait to go see that waterfall.
The weather is perfect, we got huts
on the water, and now I am eating art.
So we give up a little bit of
our day to talk about feelings.
How bad can it really be, right?
Welcome to Eden Resort.
I am Marcel.
Hi. Morning.
I know why you are all here.
You are here to seek the answer
to the most commonly
asked question by all,
how do we make it work?
How?
I have laid out a personalized program
designed to challenge you all,
both as couples and as individuals.
If you follow diligently my program,
the answer to this question
will be revealed to you,
as well as your inner animal spirit.
This I promise.
I do not, however, promise
that you and your chosen partner
will have what it takes to sustain it.
Please, line up on the beach.
Take your places.
Out here?
This way. Men on one
line, facing the ocean.
Women, back to the water.
Now remove your mask.
Undress!
Oh. All right.
It's a freeing exercise.
This is starting to
get a little creepy now.
It'd mean a lot to me if you"d just
take your pants off, all right, Dave?
Is that why you brought me here?
This is... What is this?
You must undress, my friend.
I'm afraid that's not a option
for me today, you know, man.
It's the program.
Right. I don't have any drawers, though.
Well, Sctanley said he had this
conversation with you last night.
Now, if you've chosen to stay,
you've chosen to participate.
Now, if you're not wearing any drawers,
then, hey, that was meant to be.
Let it all hang out.
Explore. Explore with your eyes.
Explore your mate.
We are all made in God's image.
That means we are all perfect.
Stand with pride. Look
closer. Own your bodies.
And now, tell your partner
a truth. A beautiful truth.
You look like the earth.
What?
Why are you listening
to what I'm saying?
Why don't you have
your own conversation?
It's hard to have my own conversation
when you're telling Cynthia
that she looks like the earth.
Did you hear what I said?
Yeah. I'm not really
sure I like that one.
Well, I just mean that, you
know, you look bountiful. Okay?
Fruitful. Fertile.
Okay. Now this is getting uncomfortable.
Please, make a palace of solitude
between you and your partner.
Why are you wearing trousers?
I explained to the guy in the dress
that I didn't have any drawers on.
Yes, but this exercise
is about owning your body.
Mmm.
What is your name, dear?
Trudy.
Trudy. What a beautiful name.
Please, tell him that you love his body.
For real? Yes.
I love your body.
Really?
Of course! So powerful, so strong.
Powerful frame with layer upon
layer of dormant, relaxed muscle,
waiting, like a panther, to
pounce on its quivering prey.
Please, take off his pants. Yes.
I'm not ready to pounce today.
Yes.
I don't have any drawers.
No. No. Right here, baby.
It's okay. It's okay. Hair!
Sorry, I'm sorry. Careful.
Here it comes. Here it comes.
Wonderful! Stare at
it! Stare at all of it.
Is his junk out?
Yep.
Is his junk literally out of his pants?
Now it's a party.
How would you describe
your relationship?
Average. Great, yeah.
Great. Average. I mean, yeah.
And, to clarify, what is an
"average, great" relationship?
Well, we... We make it through
things pretty good together.
You know, we have two great kids.
No one's called 911 in
the middle of the night.
Like there's not domestic
violence in the... The... Yeah.
Ronnie, when you say you 'make
it through things together,"
what do you mean?
Well, you know, the
usual stuff. Work, kids.
I'm much less interested
in "the usual stuff"
and much more interested
in your particular stuff.
So, what do you make it
through together, specifically?
Well, right now, specifically,
Dave is dealing with his new launch
of his video game, Guitar Hero.
He sells Guitar Hero.
And I am dealing with the renovations.
That's interesting.
What's interesting?
Why do you keep writing stuff
down on your little pad there?
Oh, I'm taking notes.
Would it make you more
comfortable if I didn't take notes?
Yeah, actually, it would
make me more comfortable.
Thank you.
That's interesting.
So we want to make the most
of our time here on the island,
so what we did was we put together
a little informational packet
to bring you up to speed
on our relationship.
Go ahead. That's for you.
It just contains pertinent medical data,
family histories, you
know, stuff like that.
Everything but a mix tape.
How would you
characterize your marriage?
Perfect.
Fantastic.
Well, let's start with
something easy, then.
What's your favorite
thing about your partner?
Uh...
She's a good mom.
He really is a great dad.
And where did you meet?
School. High school. High school. Yeah.
She was a cheerleader
- I was on the football team. Fullback.
I coach now, but I used to play.
And we had... We actually
had our daughter... We...
On prom night, we conceived Lacey
and it was a little confusing at
the time, but it's been a blessing.
It's been the best thing
that's ever happened to us.
that ever happened to us.
We did the right thing.
How often do you have sex?
She wants me to be
tougher, screw harder.
Work less, but bring home more.
I can't keep this shit straight.
All I know is, whatever I
do, it's not good enough. Mmm.
It's over.
Then why are you here?
This is not my wife. This is
Trudy. I met her a couple weeks ago.
Can we go boogie boarding now?
And once people knew what
we were going through,
I think my cortisol levels
just shot up through the roof.
Because it's difficult to go through
a very private struggle publicly.
I heard what you think,
but you know what I'm
really interested in
is hearing about how you feel.
Just tell her how you feel.
Well, I think if you
looked at everything that...
No, no, no, no. Just... Don't
explain intellectually how you feel.
You know, just tell her
how you feel. In one word.
Sure.
Angry.
Cynthia?
Judged.
Very good.
Yes? Progress.
Excited.
Relieved.
That is it. Yeah.
We're awesome at feelings!
Okay. Nice job today, guys.
That's all for today? Great
job. That's all for today.
All right, well, great. Yeah.
How did we do? Did we do good?
I mean, are we gonna make it?
Well, you know, it's just
our first session, you know.
We're not looking for an end
result here. It's not a competition.
I get all that, but have you seen
couples that are worse off than us?
Yeah. Or are we that far gone?
We're... Are you gonna put a...
Like a numerical value on it?
You know, Doc? Like a one to 10?
One being worst, 10 being best?
No, hang on one second.
Where would you put us?
Right where you are, sir.
What if someone put a gun to
your head right now and said,
"You have to answer this
second or I'll shoot.
"Are they gonna make
it?" What do you say?
What would you say?
Whoa! Okay, no one has a
gun to my head, Mr. Smith.
It's hypothetical.
It's not a place for
inappropriate behavior.
And you definitely don't pull a
hypothetical gun on your therapist.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Let's clear the karma. Okay?
I'll holster this.
See, you know, I work 10 hours a day,
so by the time I come
home, I'm exhausted.
It's not that I don't want to answer
questions about the house renovation.
I really just don't want to
answer questions about anything.
But, you know, you may just
be shutting your mind off,
but it can feel like you're
shutting your partner off as well.
Again, that's a caution area.
And just as a point of interest,
when you speak that way, David,
you're really
de-prioritizing your teammate.
Excuse me?
It's called "crossing
emotional boundaries."
Or, more commonly,
"bulldozing." And it's ugly.
Ronnie, when you spoke earlier of...
Let me just find it in my notes here.
There it is+ You said, "We make
it through things well together."
That doesn't sound very fun.
You don't want to look back and
say, "I made it through my life."
We want to enjoy our
projects, enjoy our work week.
lives, celebrate our lives.
And all this talk about my project
and his work, and my this and his that,
and mine and his, and
mine and... It,s...
Where's us in all that?
Where is our journey? I don't hear it.
And it's because it's not there.
Listen. I'm not saying that there's not
some really stressful times sometimes,
because there is, but it works for us.
Does it?
I don't know.
Oh, gosh, I don't know, you guys.
There's no "us." There's no "we."
You two could be perfect strangers.
I think the one thing that
we can agree on, today,
is that you guys should be doing
a lot better than just "works."
Pretty sure that's why you're here.
Oh. That's it. Great. Great
job, everybody. Thank you.
Lucy?
Good day, sir. I got room
service for you. I'm very sorry.
I didn't order that.
I think your wife,
she called me for you.
I'm...
This is just... Because I got a sunburn,
'cause it was... The sun
was very strong today.
Yeah. I know. This is
good for sunburns, right?
No. Okay.
It's good, yeah?
It's good for sunburn?
Okay, so I don't see anything.
See what? There's nothing to see.
Yeah, yeah, no, no, no. It works great.
Okay, I move now. No. That was.
-. That was...
There's nothing to move.
I... I was... I had a sunburn.
Good night, sir.
Now we will enjoy looking at the fish!
See and take in with your eyes
all the beauty the ocean has to offer!
As these new things come at you,
you may not have seen them before,
but be open to them and
find the beauty within.
Hey, buddy. Yep.
Thanks a lot for bringing
me to Problem Island.
What are we gonna do for an encore?
Talk about all the people that we
slept with before we were married
and really stir shit up?
What the hell are you talking about?
The therapist is trying
to create a problem
in my marriage that doesn't exist!
Maybe he's not creating them,
maybe he's just noticing them.
Okay, you know what?
Don't start with me.
I'm serious. I don't need it.
These are the best in the world
at what they do, all right?
If Jeff Gordon told you
that your oil was low,
you might want to
think about changing it.
From the bucket, feed them!
My therapist is kind of pushy.
Really? Yeah.
God, I like ours.
Yeah, he said that Dave and
I take each other for granted.
That, you know, our relationship
has become more like a job.
How do you mean?
For example, he says that
Dave is de-prioritizing me,
that he doesn't pay attention
to what I actually want.
Yeah, but, honey, that's just
Dave being Dave, you know?
Yeah.
But so then, what if Dave
being Dave is sort of like
Dave bulldozing me?
Please continue to look at the fish!
Enjoy them as they come at you!
I get it, dude, it's
advanced snorkeling.
Dave... Hey, I'm trying
to do this exercise!
Why don't we talk about
this during down time, okay?
This might be what the
therapist is referring to.
You're missing out on life.
It's happening right now, out
here, all around us, all right?
And you're too busy
complaining about your problems
to enjoy all these beautiful
little fish that are...
Marcel!
Yes?
Marcel, we have a real problem here!
It is not a problem!
It is a circle of life!
The circle of life is
circling our lives right now!
Do not move, do not panic.
Shark! What?
Shark! Jason!
Okay, it's all happening, Marcel!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God...
Don't worry! Wait!
These are only lemon sharks!
This is all part of the course.
It is like life. Like in relationships.
They will not attack
unless they feel attacked!
Marcel, I need you to take
the French out of your mouth
and tell me what to do!
Don't let them see your fear.
Okay, I think we just hold
tight, we play it cool,
we don't make a move.
What was that? What?
What was that? Jason, stop...
He said not to panic!
I'm sitting in blood!
Marcel, this isn't a drill, buddy!
You got real sharks here!
It's time to get the guns'
and it's time to shoot some fish!
Here on Eden, there are no guns!
You got an American life at stake.
One life is not more
important than another.
What do I do?
My friends and my wife left me to die.
You must get out of
the chum, but slowly.
Okay.
Swim slowly out of the chum!
Slowly. Slowly. Yes, yes.
Slowly, baby! Stop!
I don't know what to do.
I don't know if I'm standing
still or I'm swimming.
Swim now! Stop!
They're torturing me!
They're playing with me!
They're slow-playing me! Shoot them!
Swim slowly.
Swim, swim, swim.
Save yourselves! Go to
shore! It's too late!
They've got me! It's
only a matter of time!
There's no sharks around you,
honey. You're safe now, baby.
I don't know what's going through
my mind! I'd love some ice cream.
What? I'd love some ice cream,
with maybe some pecans in it!
Couples' massage is part of
your program and so important.
It gives you the chance
to bond, relax, reconnect.
We prefer to bond on our own.
Okay, would you prefer
male or female therapists?
What would you recommend more for like
a nurturing, pampering, motherly energy?
Would that be a man or
a woman, do you think?
A woman.
Well, I'm just so tight in my
shoulders. Do you have any...
Let me see.
We do have a male
masseur available, madam.
Daddy, I can't wait to
get my drink on tonight!
Damn! Is this whole thing
uphill? Where's the downhill part?
We gonna get our groove
on tonight. Right, Daddy?
Of course, baby. You know how we do it.
Well, hello.
Hi.
Lucy.
Yes.
Excellent.
Who are you?
I am Xavier and I will be
your man-seur for today.
Xavier?
Yes.
Mmm.
Twenty, 30, 40, 50...
Hi.
Joey.
Yes.
What's your name?
Gert.
What a beautiful name.
Well, thank you.
Do you mind if I heat up the lotion?
No. Heat that lotion up.
The hotter the better.
What kind of massage do
you want? You left it blank.
Korean?
Korean? I am not familiar with Korean.
Dealer's choice. Whatever
releases the most tension.
Mmm.
Oh, that feels so good.
Thank you.
I can't tell you how much I need
this. It has been a long time.
Oh, I love pleasuring people.
So do l.
I mean, it's not my job,
but it is a job that I love
doing, if you know what I mean.
I know exactly what you mean.
So, Joey, do you have any problem areas?
I hold a lot of tension
in my upper thighs.
We'll get to your upper thighs.
It's just the top of my quads.
As a matter of fact,
if you want to do, like,
the full 80 minutes on
the thighs, I'm good.
Whatever you want.
Oh, I need this. You have no idea.
Oh, you got great hands.
Okay, Joey, what I want you to
do for me is just close your eyes.
Quiet that mind, okay?
Just listen to my voice.
Feel the sound slide down my throat
and come out through my mouth.
Down my throat, come
out through my mouth.
Down my throat...
Keep... Keep going, keep going.
Sir, I'm so sorry.
No, no, no. Don't be sorry.
You shouldn't be sorry.
No, I aroused you.
You should be proud.
This hasn't happened
to me in a long time.
Are you attempting to have a
manual stimulation from me, sir?
Am I...
I am here on a couples retreat
with my wife in the other room.
My husband Scott is just like a cat.
Scott?
My husband.
I'm trying to save my marriage
here. Look what you did to me.
Well, that wasn't my intention, sir.
It wasn't mine, either,
and now I'm humiliated.
Well, I'm sorry.
You told me not to think.
Well, when I don't think,
this is what happens.
You can't leave me all
backed up like this.
What do you want me to do, sir?
I don't know. We got to
figure out a solution.
You know, let's not take
anything off the table.
Let's start brainstorming. We"re
both in a maze together, okay?
How do we get the cheese?
I'm sorry, sir, but that is
not gonna have a happy ending.
Give me the oil.
Go grab a smoke.
Daddy, this is awesome!
Yo, they should put me up
in a video on this bitch!
Don't go chasing waterfalls
Stick me in the ocean I'm
gonna make it look real good
You go, girl.
Daddy's got to ice his knee, baby, okay?
If you just let me recharge my battery,
I promise, this'll be
more for you later, okay?
Technically, I was bit by a shark.
Were you bit or were you nipped?
I mean, if you had been bit,
you probably would have lost
a great deal of blood and...
What difference does it
make to you two, anyway,
what you would call it?
It hurt. And I had shark
teeth penetrate my skin.
And besides, Jason, it's
your fault that it happened.
The only reason I got
bit in the first place
is because you did the worst thing
you could possibly do in that situation.
You panicked and you threw
a bucket of chum in my face.
I did the prudent thing and I
got the hell out of the water.
There were sharks in there,
David. What was I supposed to do?
You know what? Remember
it however you want to
and I'll remember it
how it actually happened.
Dave. I mean, really, did
they penetrate your skin?
Do you really need that bandage?
Lucy, I don't know
what to tell you, okay?
You tell me if I need the bandage.
It looks like you scraped
yourself on the ladder,
maybe, on the way out.
I'm sorry?
Did you get out of the water abruptly?
Hey, I don't know how to explain
it to you. Maybe I have tough skin.
Perhaps lemon sharks don't
leave that bad of a mark.
Maybe they're pack animals
and they're marking me
for later. I don't know.
Dave, I was in a car
accident once, okay?
And it was really scary, I
had nightmares. But when...
I've been in a car accident, too.
Have you ever been bit by a shark?
I was never bit by a shark. I'm
just saying that I understand. My...
Say it again. I was in a car accident.
No, say the last part.
I was never bit by a shark.
That's it! Then you
shouldn't talk about it.
And I'm not gonna sit here
and try to explain myself
to a bunch of black
and white suburban trash
who don't know a damn
thing about the ocean.
And you understand the ocean, honey?
I have some real field
experience, honey, yeah.
I had a shark attack.
I'm part of a very elite group.
Like people who have
been struck by lightning.
Not everyone can say
that they've had that
and maybe that's what's
going on here today.
You know what? I don't want
to get in an argument with it.
I really don't. You know what?
I'm really exhausted.
It's been a long day.
I'm gonna go back to the
room. You want to come with me?
Baby, I thought we were gonna
go to the waterfall tonight
and have a little alone time.
Sweetheart, I'm a shark attack survivor.
I'm fried.
Honey, I think the fear was a
lot worse than the actual attack,
which I can totally appreciate,
but the good news is you weren't hurt,
so let's not ruin the evening over it.
I'm sorry?
Honey, you weren't hurt.
Good night.
Dave! Where you going?
Dave. Come on, okay,
you got bit by the shark.
You got bit, I believe you!
We're here all the time, so let's
take that opportunity to go to bed.
Honey, we'll go to
the waterfall with you.
We'll grab our drinks and go.
Yeah. We could all go
together. It'll be beautiful.
Hon? I was thinking that maybe
we might go back to the room, huh?
Bolt the door, draw the shades, huh?
Just shut the whole world out
and sit Indian-style and
really explore our feelings.
Daddy! Wake up!
It's too deep!
Yo, you having a nightmare. You ain't
even in the water. It's night time.
Look, you said we was gonna have
fun, so let's get up, let's dance,
let's do a shot, let's
do something. Anything.
Baby, let's just go back
to the room, all right?
I don't want to go back to the
room. I don't want to go to sleep.
We're not going to sleep.
We're not?
Mmm-mmm.
What we gonna do in there?
For real?