l'll check him tomorrow
Mister Sinha, this is a case
of liver cirrhosis
The liver is badly damaged.
The patient is under observation
lt's difficult to say anything yet
But, you can do something?
The problem is, we can't do a liver
transplant...on such short notice
lf you wish to inform her
family or relatives...
...you may use my phone
Hey buddy, how are you?
Where are you?
l'm at the hospital
Hospital! Are you okay?
Ya, l'm OK
So, what's wrong then?
Just hang in there. l'm coming
By the way, Akash is back in Bombay.
l'll bring him along
He won't come
Don't be silly.Forget what happened
He'll be very happy to
know you're here.
Ya Sameer, tell me
Maybe you should go meet him alone.
l don't want to come.
You are right.
Let bygones be bygones...
But what's happening now
isn't wrong either, is it?
l am living my life and Sid his
l really think you should
go meet him alone
Sameer, come home quickly.
Now. At once
Sameer! Akash! What's wrong?
What's the rush?
How do you like it?
Have you gone mad?
On the phone you sounded like somebody's
broken into your house!
What do you mean beautiful!?
But Sid...don't you think
she resembles someone?
Resembles whom?
What do you think, Sameer?
l think everybody resembles
some one or the other.
But she resembles Miss. Kashyap
Our Economics teacher?
Yes, sir. Our Economics teacher
No man!
Ya man. l know Miss.Kashyap
better than you
Tuitions...
l used to go to her for tuitions
At these tuitions, were there other
students or just the two of you?
What do you think?
- Just the two of you?
You are right, Akash
She does resemble Miss.Kashyap.
But guess where l've messed up?
You've got her figure wrong
What do you know about her figure?
l'm looking for Sid
Sinha... Siddharth Sinha
When did you return to Bombay?
-This morning.
Can't imagine what 'd have
happened if l wasn't here
How is she now?
Don't know. lt's hard to say
Tell me about you.
What're you up to these days?
l'm working with Dad in his
computer business
Everything else is the same...
And you? Still at your uncle's place
in Poona?
Ya. lt's a very nice.
You must come there sometime
Definitely man
Are you just saying that or
do you really intend on coming?
l intend on doing a lot of things
...like getting married
l always knew that the first to ge
married among us three would be you
Guess what! So is Akash
What! Akash ! Getting married!?
That's funny
l'm not kidding!
No way!
But to whom? That girl who was
crazy about him in college?
Don't you remember her?
She used to say Akash's name
in that peculiar way!
God! Deepa is coming here!
Akash, let's dance. lt'll make the
other couples jealous
Sure! Why not! Go ahead.
l'll be right with you
ln three lifetimes from now
Sameer, please get me a drink.
l'm ever so thirsty
And throw in a dance or two with
Deepa while you're at it
What're you sketching?
Priya, isn't Sameer taking too
long to get your drink?
Did somebody just die?
- Yes...you!
Did l send you to get a drink
or chat up other girls!
l'm sure you have something
going on with her
l remember you were never home
when l was away on holiday
You've got it all wrong, Priya
How do you know her?
Did somebody just die?
Who is she?
- l don't know
You must have seen her somewhere!
That l have.
- Where?
She's over there
Priya, do you know her?
Forget it man. She doesn't
seem your type
l don't plan on marrying her!
Big deal about my type
And may l know what your type is?
One who lives her life
and lets me live mine
Someone not overtly emotional
Oh, l remember.
You once met such a girl
The affair lasted for two weeks!
That itself was too much
Anyway, l'm off...
...or she'll have had grandchildren
by the time l get there
Think about it.
l don't see her biting the hook
lt's called the good-ole
Akash charm and it never fails
ls the mike leaking., where has 3 gone?
Today, on this all important
graduation day...
l have decided to sing a song
And because we are stepping
into a new world...
...where the responsibility to be
somebody will be thrust on us...
The title of the song is:
''A hundred ways to get a job''
Relax guys! l was only kidding!
lf people say....that we are crazy,
then let them
We don't give a damn
about what they think
When we can play music
When we can sing...
Then why should we hesitate?
We will sing the melody
that's in our hearts
lf the world gets angry...
- Let it be angry
lf the world quarrels...
- Let it quarrel
lf the world fights...
-Just it fight.
Just keep right on singing
lf the world sulks...
- Let it sulk
lf ties are broken...
- Let them break
lf someone leaves you...
- Let them go
Don't ever be afraid
We are today.
Why should our style be old?
There's lightning in our eyes.
A storm in our breath
What's fear, what's defeat?
We don't know what they mean
The earth and sky,
are created for us
l'm sure we could even
pluck the stars out of the night
Our abode is beyond the sky
We are today.
Why should our style be old?
We have been raised in the
land of dreams
We can be as shy as
we are openly affectionate
Mesmerising everybody
wherever we go...
...teaching you lovely women
the art of love
We know how to steal
a woman's heart and her sleep
We are today.
Why should our style be old?
lf people say...
...that we are crazy, then let them
We don't give a damn
about what they think
When we can play music
When we can sing...
Then why should we hesitate?
We will sing the melody
that's in our hearts
lf the world gets angry...
- Let it be angry
lf the world quarrels..
- Let it quarrel
lf the world fights...
- Let it fight
Just keep right on singing
lf the world sulks...
- Let it sulk
lf ties are broken...
- Let them break
lf someone leaves you...
- Let them go
Don't ever be afraid
We are today.
Why should our style be old?
Shalini...that's a lovely name
l haven't seen you before.
You're not from our college
You're right. l'm here with somebody
And now would you say yes to
dancing with this somebody?
The fact is that Rohit...
Rohit! Okay!
So you are Rohit's sister?
No. Actually l...
Rohit and l are very good friends.
Why, he's more like a brother
Not even if l told you
that l love you?
Yes, Shalini. l love you
and only you
My every breath...
...every heartbeat...
...every moment,
is for you, Shalini
l'm sure that l was born
so that l could love you
And you were born to become mine
You are mine, Shalini
And if you ask your heart...
...you will know that l speak
the truth.
Who are you?
Don't you recognize your brother Rohit?
You are Rohit? l mean,
you too are Rohit?
l thought Shalini was that
other Rohit's sister.
Look, he's over there
Sameer...! Your name is Sameer?
So you've being lying to me all along!
That's really wrong of you
What can l say now...
You can see for yourself
He got me to believe that
his name was Rohit
Neither is he Rohit
nor Shalini my sister
Shalini is my fiancee
Fiancee...!
l don't like you being friends
with Akash at all
His behaviour the other night...
You know how embarrassed l was?
Let him do what he wants.
Just keep away from him
But Akash is my friend, Priya!
Like you don't have
any other friends?
Yes, l do...But he...
Just decide, Sameer. You can
either be with Akash or me!
l am thinking...
You need time to think
if you want to be with me!
Okay. So you want some time?
No!
l'm going out with friends.
l'll be back by 2.00
lf l don't hear from you before that,
l'll know what your answer is
Don't you think you are
over-reacting?
No
You've never seen me over-react.
lf l do...then God help you!!
What are you doing!
Your bruise has turned a strange colour.
Have you seen it, Sid?
l'm glad you like it!
Do you want one?
Hey! Don't get that anger out on me man
Did l ask you to speak to Shalini?
No. But you could've at least helped me.
You just sat there!
Such a true friend! l think l'd be
better off befriending Rohit
l'd at least get some protection!
May God bless your unity. l'm off.
Where to?-Home.
Why? What's the hurry?
Right, Sameer?
Ya, man, chill. lt's only
1O' clock
ln which country?
lt's nearly 4 here!
l forgot to call Priya!
Why are you so scared of Priya?
l'm not scared of her
l don't want to hurt her
or lose her
Sameer, l can't understand
how you tolerate her
She seems more a boss
than a girlfriend!
Akash, l'm asking for help,
not your expert comments
What should l do?
What do you think?
l'll tell you what.
Call Priya and apologise
Tell her you will never meet
Akash again
You know l won't do that!
What if she gets hurt...
What if you lose her!
You'll never improve, will you
Why are you turning this
into such an issue?
Just call her, talk to her.
lt'll all be okay
The thing is...but listen...You're not
...but l...what l'm saying...
l'm at Akash's
She hung up
What did you expect?
She'll say Sorry darling!
Enough is enough, Sameer.
Listen to me
Just go there and tell her
these tantrums won't work
lf she wants to be with you,
she must follow your wishes
She's challenged your
self-respect, buddy
What are you doing? Be a man!
That's exactly what l'm going to do.
- That's the way to go!
He's dead!
Oh, Priya?
- Please give Sameer the phone
But Sameer hasn't come here. l too am
looking for him since last night
What? Didn't he come there?
Careful man!
Only this eye is working
We need to talk
There's no need for that. l know
what you have to say
You know?- Yes
l spoke to Akash after our talk
Right! And?
He said you weren't at his house
Stop pretending! l can't believe
l did this to myself
l never knew you were such a liar
l don't want to see your
face ever again!
Could l be of any assistance?
lt's not a problem at all
Oh God ! What's in here?
- My things
Hang on. l'll get it from this side
lf just one suitcase has reduced
us to this condition, then...
There's only two more like this
ls that all? Just two more?
Let's go
lt's a nice house
lt belongs to the company l work for
l am an interior designer...
Tara Jaiswal
What do you do?
l work as a porter on Sundays
And the rest of the week?
Normally if anyone asks me that, l say
anything that pops into my head
But l'll tell you the truth because
l think it might be of interest to you
l don't quite understand?
l mean you have three paintings in your
luggage and that's my vocation
May l see your paintings?
Of course
Where do you live?
The last house down this road.
You can come whenever you wish
Sid, l'm going to the office.
- Just a minute, Ma
l'm coming along. Just drop me off
at Sameer's
By the way, it's Anju's wedding
anniversary today
She'll be very disappointed
if you don't come
ls Siddharth home?- Yes
You are...?- l am Tara
Ma, this is Tara
Well, l'd better be going
Ya, you go ahead, l'll go myself.
All right. But you are coming
this evening, aren't you?
Where?- To Anju's!
Mom, l get extremely bored there
There are very few places in this world
where you don't get bored
Fine ! Have it your way.
Please have a seat
l'd like to see your paintings first
The same theme here too
What theme?
l have learnt something about
you today
Something l couldn't see
at our first meeting
What's that?
The thing is, you meet people,
talk to them, laugh...
But there's a world within you...
...full of dreams, of fantasies...
...that you don't share with anyone
l wonder if those, who claim
to know you...
... really know you at all
What makes you say that?
The door is not open...
Entry is forbidden...
The box is tightly bound...
No one can steal anything...
And who can tell what feelings reflect
behind those shut eyelids...
l wonder what other secrets your
paintings hide within them...
Or within you perhaps
Why are you looking at me
like that?
Anyway, which do you think
is your best?
l have yet to create that one
Look at your face!
White as a sheet!
Look, l am very angry right now
and all because of you
Hey! l saved your life and
you are angry with me?
Saved my life?
- Absolutely!
This was bound to happen
Priya would've left you tomorrow
if not today. Know why?
Because she didn't love you,
she loved some other Sameer
He looked like you but was
someone else
You are not that Sameer. You are the
Sameer l know, Sid knows...
And Priya could only hope to know
lf you became that Sameer, our this
Sameer would be defeated!
l never thought of it like that..
- l know
Then pack your bags and let's go
Sid and l are waiting for you
in the car
Where are we going?- Goa!
Goa...?!
The heart wants...
May these sparkling days never end
May we never have to be
without our friends
May our days be full of poetry...
...our evenings dance and
nights sing.
May our time together always
be fun and exciting
May every path we tread
bring us happiness
The heart wants...
May these sparkling days
never end
The heart wants...
May we never have to be
without our friends
Our paths dazzle with their glitter
May this joy and light
be ours by right
Where's Akash?
There...behind the plant
Are you guys staying here too?
Not are...we were.
We are checking out
We've been staying here for a week.
lsn't that right, guys?
Yes, we've been here for a week
But Akash just got here today.
- Yes. l got here today
Akash! lt's nice to see you haven't
lost your sense of humour!
Hey Sid, look over there!
Sid, did you hear that?
Someone's calling out my name
Go faster, buddy. Faster
This is the top speed
What an amazing place!
We should come to Goa every year,
for a week at least
What say, Sid?
What are you thinking?
l'm looking at that ship...
...that's about to disappear over
the horizon
The three of us are like that ship
Soon, we'll set out looking
for our destinations....
...and it might just be that
our destinations are different
l don't understand why
you're saying all this
Sid, we are all friends...
...for life
Of course we are
But who knows where life will
take each one of us
Ever wondered, let alone come
here every year for a week...
lt may be difficult to meet
even once in 10 years
That won't happen, Sid
We were, are and will be friends.
Always
Anyway, shall we go?
Deepa must be waiting for you
Don't say must be waiting.
She is!
l told her Akash will meet her
by the poolside at 8 sharp!
How strange is this journey!
lf you just think...
Each one of us is so unaware...
...of where he is destined to go...
...of what the future
holds for each of us
The heart wants...
May these sparkling days never end
May we never have to be
without our friends
May our days be full of poetry...
...our evenings dance
and nights sing
May our time together always
be fun and exciting
May every path we tread
bring us happiness
Our paths dazzle with their glitter
May this joy and light
be ours by right
Deepa, why do you like Akash
so much?
What do you mean?
Sometimes l wonder why we
like and want someone
Why do you like him?
l don't know... l just do
Even knowing that Akash...
- ...doesn't love me
Yes...then too
Deepa you are a good-looking,
intelligent girl.
You can get anyone you want...
ln that case, why can't
l have Akash!
l don't know that...
But l do know that if
you're ever in trouble,
And need Akash's help or support,
he'll do whatever he can for you.
But Deepa, you shouldn't
hope for things that...
Take a look at this sand
The tighter you try to grip it...
...the faster it slips
through your fingers
Have you donated your bag
to the hotel?
Actually, l've decided to
stay back for a few days
What?
Er...Kristine wants me to stay
for some more time
Kristine?...that girl who...
Sid! Are you listening? Our friend has
decided to become a hippie!
lf you hadn't brought me here,
l'd have never met her
She's Swiss. l was wondering...
why not go there...
...and start a bee farm.
Swiss honey is world famous...
Let's go Akash
What have l done! He was
better off with Priya
One more thing...
Please don't call my house
till l get back
So, did you have fun in Goa?
lt was great. Have you been there?
Yes. Many years ago
Whose photographs are these?
Esha...my daughter
Oh, l haven't met her.
Where is she?
She lives with her father
9th April 95...exactly
on my birthday...
My husband gave me a gift...
You do meet your daughter,
don't you?
No
The Court doesn't permit me
to meet my daughter
Why?
My ex-husband is a very rich man
His lawyers were very smart and
capable
With the help of many false
witnesses, he proved...
...that l am not a good mother.
That l'm an alcoholic
An irresponsible woman
who drinks
You're nothing like that!
Oh for you to have been
the judge!
Anyway, what else
did you do there?
l'd like to paint you
Paint me?
Be back in two minutes
Are you going somewhere?
Sorry, l have to go
l just got a call from the site.
There's a problem
Have you given any thought
to your future?
No
l know it's my fault...
...l always thought, l'd give
you some time...You needed it.
lt's my pampering that
has spoilt you
lf this goes on...
You'll definitely have signed
a cheque till my retirement
Dad, there are more things
to life than signing cheques
Really! And what are these things?
l don't know yet but the moment
l do, you'll be the first to know
l have had enough of your jokes
l've decided that you will go
to Australia
Cool! Another holiday?
You'll manage our business
there
Mom, Dad's joking now
No, Akash. Dad is serious
and you better be serious too
You are going to Sydney
And you will manage the office there
Sameerji's Mummyji is on the phone
Akash Baba says that...
Yes, Aunty
What's wrong with Sameer?
Nothing's wrong with Sameer.
He's perfectly OK
What OK!? He's shut himself
in his room
He hasn't eaten and just
doesn't come out
Sameer is in Bombay?
Didn't you all come back
last night
Yes, Aunty. lt was last night
but...l'm so distracted now...
Akash, are you and Sameer on drugs?
Of course not, Aunty. Don't worry.
l'll be there right away
The least you could've done was call.
l didn't know what to say to your Mom
What's happened to you?
l'm in no mood to talk now
Okay. How's Kristine?
Don't even mention her name
in front of me!
Why? What happened?
Get it off your chest
lt's not good for health
to suppress such emotions
Well, after the two of left
the other day...
l met Kristine on the beach
lt felt so good...
Just Kristine and me...
l loved her so much...
How happy l was...
We watched the sunset and she
came back to the hotel with me
l invited her in
l could never have imagined
what happened next
l don't think she was from
Switzerland either
l'm glad to have amused you guys!
That truck driver who gave me a ride
to Bombay was far more sympathetic!
You came back in a truck!?
What did you think?
That l sit on this pillow every day?
l'm pissed off travelling 12 hours
in a truck
Mother, he is Mr.Shankaran.
Art lndia magazines.
l was telling Siddharth about
my friend who lives in Kasauli
He hosts a painting workshop
every year
And you feel that he must
go there
Absolutely
lt'll be a very good experience
for him
Oh, you're here!
You're a strange boy!
you invite me and act surprised when l come.
Ma, this is Tara!
Tara Jaiswal. You introduced us before
How long will you go around
with that glum face...
Come. Let me introduce you
to these sweet girls
Forget it man.
l'm not in the mood
Are you fine?
Look... Kristine!
Do you like it?
l like them all
lt's difficult to say
which one is your best
l haven't painted my best yet
Why not?
You don't seem to have the time?
On such a big day in your life
l've to agree to your wish.
Tell me, when you will
start my painting?
Tomorrow
Wait, l'll be out in a minute.
- No problem
What season is this in which the
heart blooms like a flower.
...in which the colours merge...
...and all the fragrances
blend
Moonlight, brooks
and clouds...
Songs, rain
and butterflies...
They all seem favourable to me
What season is this in which
the heart blooms like a flower
Oh look!
Banks of a river...
A bird calls out
to another bird
Look, at the river itself...
She flows on to unite
with the sea
All these journeys
are part of love's caravan
What season is this in which
the heart blooms like a flower
Oh how
can l explain...
How can l make you understand
what love is!
There are no attachments
in love
And neither
are there any barriers
Love's saga is extraordinary
What season is this in which
the heart blooms like a flower
..in which all the colours merge...
...and all the fragrances
blend
Moonlight, brooks
and clouds...
Songs, rain
and butterflies...
They all seem favourable to me
What season is this in which
the heart blooms like a flower
Greetings, Aunty.
Are you going out, Sameer?
Ya, to Akash's...Why?
l'll be back
Mom! What's the matter?
The fact is, Nareshji's daughter
Pooja is coming here
And we want the two of you to...
What! Fixing my marriage...!
An arranged marriage!
No, Mom. Not for me
Why not? Your Daddy and l had
an arranged marriage
Listen to me. We are not forcing
you to get married
We have known them for years
And we thought we'd turn friendship
into a marriage alliance
You don't lose anything by
meeting Pooja, do you?
Okay. But you know my answer.
And that's NO!
Who is it, Sameer?
Er...Sameer, we have something
important to discuss
Nareshji, is that all right?
Anyway, they'll get bored
sitting with us oldies
Are they your friends?
Please sit down
This is Akash and this is Sid
Seems like a deep friendship
Either the friendship is deep
or it's a 3-D photograph
Pooja, you do know why
you're here, don't you?
Yes. Mom and Dad told me
Look, honestly speaking...
When Mom told me about this...
l felt it wasn't right at first...
...but now...l'm so happy you said no to
this arranged marriage bullshit!
l think marriages shouldn't be
made like this
lt's so important to love somebody
to get married
What do you think?
Yes, absolutely
Why? Are you in love with
someone?
There is this guy in my life
But l guess l don't love him
enough so far to marry him
l pretty much feel the same...
...but not about the guy in your life!
And then?
Then what!
She went home
lt's a problem man
Please don't tell me you've
fallen for her after all this!
Look, Sameer...
l have no doubt whatsoever
you have fallen in love with her
But l'm equally sure that after
3 months...
...you'll be in love with some other
girl
No, Akash
l always thought l knew
what love was
l realized today that l was
completely wrong
ls that so!
Akash, when Pooja told me about
that guy in her life ...
For the first time l thought about
all those girls in my life...
l was attracted to all of them...
But l was wrong to think
the attraction was love
And now you love Pooja?
Yes. That's it!
l love Pooja
Then tell her
Take my advice. Don't say
anything to anyone
There's no trusting you
Today it's Pooja,
tomorrow it'll be some Ahuja!
How did you know it's
my birthday?
Didn't you mention it?
l am so happy today
Guess what? Esha called me
She is coming to see me today
My daughter is coming here...
Sid, she remembered it's
my birthday today
l'll be seeing her after 5 years!
l've cooked everything myself.
l baked a cake
l'm so happy
ls Esha coming alone or your...
Oh no. She told him she's going to
a friend's birthday party...
Because Ajay will never let her
come here
Would you like to meet her?
lt'll make me happy
How dare you teach my daughter
to lie? Have you no shame?
Thank God l heard Esha
talk to you over the phone
Why don't you stay away from her?
l am her mother!
You were her mother but now
Kiran is her mother
lt'd be wise of you to understand
this
Don't ever try to meet Esha again
Not unless you want me to take
you to court... again
You understand what l'm getting at,
don't you?
He tells me l am not Esha's mother!
That Esha is not my daughter!
l am her mother...
He married again
He destroyed all my dreams.
l said nothing
Because l had everything...
l had my Esha
But now...l have nothing
l have nothing at all
l am nothing. Nothing.
You know, crying doesn't suit
you at all
What else can l do!
You can come with me
You two must be wondering where
Siddharth has brought you!
No such thing. We'd go
anywhere to eat cake
Will you dance with me?
Where?
- Right here there's lot of space, come.
Sid, we've reached your house
What?
You're joking, right?
Hey Akash, he's serious man!
Have you gone mad?
Sid, my knowledge of such
things is a bit sad but...
...this is a but much, isn't it?
ls that because she's older?
No. l mean that too
Wait a minute! Why are we even
discussing this nonsense?
Because l thought that may be
you guys would understand
Hey Sid! Understand what?
You say you love a woman who
is 10 to 15 years older than you...
...has a daughter, had a husband
You've told us she has a
drinking problem
What should we understand?
- Just this...
l know all this and still
love her
But Sid, think about it.
This isn't love, it's insanity
No. This is love
l don't expect her to be mine
or marry me
l don't expect any such thing
Even if she doesn't love me,
it's okay because l...
okay! l get it
Remember, Sameer? Even l had
started off like this
Started what off?
Oh. Of course.
Okay, Sid. lf that's what it's about
then l have no objection
ln fact she's perfect for you
She's experienced, lives alone.
You visit her everyday
Learn from him, Sameer
Really, Sid. You couldn't have
chosen better...
How disgusting can you get!
Here l am telling you l love her and
you make it sound so sick and dirty
We don't have to approve
everything our friends do
But there is a line in every
friendship that shouldn't be crossed
And you have crossed it today
At some point in life everyone
experiences true love
Then all the things you said...
about her age and stuff...
They don't mean anything.
They all seem trivial
You won't understand this today
But some day you will know...
You don't decide to fall in love
lt just happens
Are you finished?
Sameer, are you coming?
l still remember that night
l never thought things would go
that far
l couldn't sleep all night
l went and met Akash
the next morning
These things happen
between friends
Let's go meet Sid.
He must be feeling bad too
You're sure to run into him
somewhere
What'll you do? lgnore him?
You're coming to meet Sid
Leave me alone, Sameer!
l have to see Sid
He's gone
Where? - Kasauli
They called yesterday to say his
application was accepted. So he...
What is it, Sameer?
ls everything alright?
Of course. l should go
l didn't realise that things
would never be the same again
You went to Kasauli...A week later,
Akash left for Australia
Take care of yourself
You remember the name of the man
who'll receive you in Sydney?
Mr.Mehta...Relax, Dad.
l remember
Bye. l'll call you from there
l must tell you something
-What's it?
l always made fun of your
endless romantic entanglements
Never stopped to think how you
must feel
You know l was just kidding,
don't you?
Don't worry about it
You weren't the only one who was
kidding
You remember Shalini?
l remember Shalini...
And Rohit's punch as well
l knew she was Rohit's fiancee
Why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't you stop me?
l said Hi
Where are you going?
This flight goes to Sydney
But where are you going?
How strange! All three of us
are going to Sydney
Three?
Sure. You, me, and this flight
You do know you're insane,
don't you?
l'm really sorry about
the other night
l was just kidding
So what are you...
What are you doing in Sydney?
Dad has a business there he
wants me to manage...
Let's see how long it lasts now.
And you?
My uncle lives there
My mother's brother.
l'm visiting him
He's nothing like Rohit, is he!
What does he do?
Have you been to Sydney before?
Do you always ask so many
questions?
Yes. Have you been to Sydney
before?
Yes
Good. You can show me around
Wait a minute. Don't you know
anybody else there?
Of course. There is a Mr.Mehta
And won't it be fun hanging out
with him?
l said l'm sorry
Okay but l will have to ask
my uncle
But he won't refuse.
Why?
Because l have bought him a gift!
l'm fine but please stop
calling me uncle now
You've grown up which makes us
practically the same age
So, is it a business trip?
We have an export business and
Dad's exported me here to handle it
Exports? Sounds very boring, man
That's what l think too
Personally, l prefer something more
adventurous...
...like wild life photography
You like photography?
Mum says the first word l said
wasn't Papa or Mama...
lt was camera!
l'm Steve
Steve?- Satyadev Mehta
l've organized a car for you.
l'll get your trolley
Okay Shalini, l'll take your leave.
Bye, Mahesh
Here's my card. lf you need
anything in Sydney, call me