Disaster MOVIE
Subtitles by RABBIT : minimog_diablos@yahoo.com
10,001 Before Christ
Fuck you!
Did the Wolf  Gotcha!
What?
It is an official mark,
that obtained from my record.
There are many things over which they must pass.
I had to arrangements on the Internet,
I have to do a site of stupidity,
when you register a catchy phrase.
I burst!
Then I'll get another person.
Well, get up,
man, get up!
The opponent, Will!
Yes!
And in another corner, The Wolf!
3, 2, 1 ...
He got it wrong "wolf"!
"We do not believe I was kidding!"
It was not to discourage you.
Come on, it does not help.
A fool that is my way!
Come on! You want a bit of me?
I am a son of a bitch in the ring!
Oh, yes!
They are small in any way ...
damn!
Wild.
Amy Winehouse?
Get lost!
Don 't want to mess with a Bitch,
not drunk!
Like the dinosaurs were
destroyed in the Ice Age
You also
become an extinct species.
When? How long do we have?
Damn! Calm down!
You speak too quickly,
I can not hear me, even
think. My head hurts!
Or perhaps the
I had gases.
God, which was good!
O God, I love drinking petrol!
It is excellent for voice exile.
This is my little secret.
How long do we have?
Let's see ...
Wait a minute ...
All right.
Well, let's take a look.
Now, all appear on "Facebook" ...
This typing
The end of the world
will take place on August 29.
God ...
By the bottom jaws!
Badalhoca!
Take note of my words,
man of the mountains ...
....,
Great Hunter!
You can do it with this!
Crystal Skull?
This is ... really no more time,
I do that just for fun.
Cruz credo ...
I knew I should not take all this Viagra.
Amy!
Wake up, honey, I
I had a dream eestranho!
Amy!
Flava--tasty!
I have your baby, a little of
"Flava love!
Get the fuck out, Flava!
Aiiii, Flava--tasty!
What was that?
What? I told you not
we have a serious relationship ...
I know! But ... Flava?
Will ...
I want to go to the next level.
I love you ...
I also like you.
I do not understand. I think if
approaching the end of the world.
This is very interesting for those who
says he has problems with commitments.
Although, Jojo.
Papaste the Jojo?
Goodbye, Will.
Still come to my party of 16?
You have 25 years!
I never had one!
You're invited
the super--anniversary
16 years of the Will.
Super--happy birthday 16 years!
Amy! You came!
Will! Happy birthday!
Look at me!
Hairy of the girls are wild
Hi, Will, here I am your brother,
Dr. Phil.
Hey, let me show you why my colleagues,
usually call me "Dr.acaricias well."
Hi, honey.
Unsafe!
come back here,
"Breasts--small!"
Hey, Will!
Where is that girl, your fan, Amy?
not to let him escape!
It is a flower of high quality!
a true piece, just like that.
Come back here, you bitch!
Nice.
IO is done!
....
He sleeps like a baby.
You can put your hands
him in cement.
I've done this before,
I toss the coin.
crown.
fell to the contrary.
certeiro.
Those guys are trying to steal our drinks.
What?
We will get the alcohol, the girls drunk
and finally managed to get cookies!
-- Good idea, "Coolaberry"!
-- Yes, I know.
Like "Coolaberry"!
For to say that!
"Coolaberry "!...
God, you are a fool!
Give me that!
Nobody I can myself
steal my drink!
Give them a tirooo!
Lisa, as I do that?
I have a clean shot.
Shoot a bullet in effect.
What?
You can control the bullet's path as you want.
Do not tell him what fazer.É my man!
Get lost, bitch! You're not gonna want to mess with me!
Game of the Divas (www)
Come on, bitch!
Take it, bitch!
Now is your time to get to the bottom!
It's time to teach you ...
manners ...
....
Left foot on yellow!
Calvin ... Calvin!
You gonna turn the bullet's path,
or what?
Hallo!
Yeah, right, you are right.
My work and my patients,
"Bothers me ...
Sorry, Phil.
Crap. I can do that.
Shit, Hurry up!
Just bend the bullet!
I know you got the power.
Nice shot, man of ass!
June why do not want abortion
Now is the coaliþia
Barney Frank to power?
I can take you from a shoulder
and do it myself.
As Linn Jamie Spears
create their babies,
and it seems comtigo and not
with George Clooney
I just sold the baby
who has more on Ebay.
Call up: 5 euros
Grantor: Brangelina.
You're a teenager sarcastic
that acts like ...
-- Do you know if the Amy come here, tonight?
-- No, she is your girl!
In fact, done.
She left you?
You got dumped?
-- No.
-- Apamhaste her in bed with another guy?
I saw "The memories of a
Gheiser, I know she goes with everything!
I'm involved with it.
And why, you finished?
I was not working.
Better finish now
than a pledge,
you know? you gotta stop being afraid
Commitments to
I know exactly, how this will end.
I also know that iste my fear, began when,
Dad was left when I was little ..
Look it's there.
Look at the guy who came with her!
It seems to have had trouble
find an underwear model.
Forget it kid,
you will have something to cheer ..
Why trade you a band?
What better way to commemorate their
super--teen party?
Super School's music!
Come on, guys, let's spend,
It's good to see you all.
Rich girl who likes me,
And the priest that if I throw the well.
I remember the feeling of time
when I was in college
I tried.
Amy after it broke my heart,
I found someone,
I think his name was "Caliente."
We will all be friends
forever,
At least that a Disaster,
in destroying the same day.
We will be friends forever
because that would be
a day of shit.
1, 2, 3, 4!
After he left,
My heart was broken
so I started to think with your head.
Got a blackboard.
I thought it was my
and the Jonas Brothers, and put everything in a row.
Girl, girl, this is not good,
you have to stop sleeping with everyone.
-- Hey, what?
-- Eiei au!
Two hearts that love really is
Always deserve a great prize!
We will be friends forever
At least that a Disaster,
in destroying the same day.
We will be friends forever
because that would be
a day of shit.
1, 2.3, 4.
JT is here! Justin T.!
You only through a reality ...
You do not trust me ...
All the beautiful women
I ate some beautiful girls
Britney, Cameron, Scarlett, all
They proved my taste.
.....
They had only
a chance ...
-- I Love,
-- Lance Bass.
Lance Bass? And Jessica Simpson!
I'm looking for Jesus
everything is for Jesus.
Damn!
My God, you are not people from meeting
Batista ... Yeah, but asked asked that?
I can not hear ... Let's see ... "They are a'cercar me ."...
What? "A" ...
A ", a write--in," Daah!
Here is a launch!
We will be friends forever
At least that a Disaster,
in destroying the same day.
We will be friends forever
because that would be
a day of shit.
1, 2, 3, 4, hurray!
What the hell was that?
This is an emergency.
Shut up, Listen!
Something is happening in the city.
We are receiving reports that may be a
earthquake or a shit like this.
Ooo, Fuck you!
The seismology is established in
epicentrul of a fashionable neighborhood of
whose inhabitants are young
attractive with about 20 years,
who are dancing to music of the poor anos'80s
They  shirts Abercrombie & Fitch
and like to drink beer "light.
God, we die!
Take a Xanax, Javi!
I acted just like you, a
concert of Iggy em'73.
What?
All right, Moody. Tas surprised?
I have a dim view.
For your general culture,
Battle--groin Galaxy,
Smiling Grape those are not even Cornelius
nemuritorul original Knocktimber.
Deltoidule, I never saw
so pack a bite Thursday
.....
I do not noticing anything DOQU tas saying.
Because the video speak painfully
rights for people of intelligence.
Now is the time to
feed the "bastard".
This is an emergency.
Amy!
Are you OK?
Yes
Because you another trade
guy to my apartment?
Why you care?
Because ...
I do not care.
I'm off
Later, bitch!
You know, Will?
Every time we made love,
I was thinking about another guy.
Me too!
Damn!
Will!
You gotta hear this!
The earthquake caused a leakage of
gas that destroyed the ghetto.
I can live without remorços.
we are receiving reports that
There are asteroids falling from the sky.
Ben?
End of the world.
Pinkberry tocme has just been destroyed!
Like my dream.
It is the Armageddon, the end of the World
I kill, the same me!
My God!
Hanna Montana died!
No!
Goodbye to all my fans!
The party continues!
She is a cabinet of treasures!
Also, ask your parents
for you to buy
Official lacheira "Hanna Montana"
the trap of cheese "Hanna Montana"
and toilet paper "Hanna Montana"!
And Make sure you going to
Hanna Montana concert
This Wednesday,
87 on Central.
I spent two days in a row
to get these tickets!
Damn!
You know those pictures too
sensual and provocative, to me?
Were made entirely
without my permission.
But if you look at pictures,
was wearing my new line
sexy lingerie "Hanna Montana"!
It was an opportunity that could not be missed!
God! Hanna Montana
is actually Miley Cyrus
Daah, do not tell me, Sherlock!
I changed only a little voice,
and put a wig.
Even the children
to know the difference!
So twice the gain
money and seeing twice as many products.
Only recalling, my new CD:
"The other legacy of Miley Cyrus."
Will be available in all stores,
and will contain songs of
my father, Billy Ray,
late 1995!
Help us!
There is nobody who can help us?
Fly High With Aspiration
Hancock!
We need help.
Wake up, your drunk of shit!
Move your ass bitch, flies apart
and solve this mess,!
Man of Cuuuuuuuu!
Rays, of course not!
I will rather bazaar, here.
Sorry.
Holy shit!
He comes from this side!
What do we do?
Let's get away from here!
Come here! Come on!
And now?
Wait a minute.
I will wait here until
pass the storm.
Hey!
This is our hideout.
Put yourself go!
Right, Carrie?
Hello, darling!
Unless you want to fight.
We do not want problems.
I never back ..
Get some!
As you can see,
I already did.
And then I thought:
can a girl like me in New York,
hit a pregnant teenager?
I wonder ...
Like Dolph Lundgren in Rocky IV,
I have to agree with you.
I am in time to breastfeed.
Muuu!
God!
-- These are your feet?
-- Yes
These are the feet of my son.
Smell it!
And prove it!
Suck my placenta!
Yes!
God! Carrie! Carrie,
my dear, they right?
Come on, ladies, come on
get out of here now!
What the hell is happening?
I do not know.
Wake, and feel the temperature.
I know it is an awkward truth, but
is called "global warming".
No.
It is not global warming!
Amy Winehouse she appeared in a dream
After I fought with a
American gladiator.
I think it has something to do with
the crystal skull ...
Come on! O fool, Winehouse?
Crystal Skull?
You look like a fool.
Remember, is getting late.
Let's spend the night here,
And wait until the storm passes.
Freezing!
We get the clothes.
Why?
Our bodies produce more heat if they are together.
Otherwise, did not survive tonight.
Yes ... yes.
He is right.
I think my water will burst.
Sorry.
I have something to tell you.
Actually, I am not a banker.
-- I am a "JUMP".
-- A what?
Can I travel in space and time.
I hope they stay together forever!
I love you!
Goodbye.
I am Prince Caspian,
I came to save, Narnia!
A little help please ...
Guys?
It is the kind of Star Wars!
What?
Well ... We saw your dream.
Boy got a bad relationship with Amy.
I wonder what could head say
a girl of whom like.
What is fires, sexy,
it has a good job ...
This girl is not for your nose!
Yes, yes it is!
Sure. She has to
lead with your bad breath.
Not to mention
you have an abnormal ass.
Put your shirt.
Ok. You're right, you're right,
I screwed up Amy with.
Should not screen lets go.
Jesus Christ!
This was an earthquake.
OK, there it is:
We have to get out of this damn town.
What do you say?
Why the hell, let me back?
Be calm staff.
The disaster is under control.
The city is safe.
Like I said, still
come on, everything is under control.
I will bug out of here
What was that?
Are you OK?
-- Will, I am, Amy.
-- Amy! Where are you?
I am at work. Was
was concerned about the artifacts.
You okay?
I'm afraid.
You gonna be OK, I promise. Listen ...
I have something to tell you.
You were right when it said.
I was an idiot.
I love you.
What do you think? I still love her?
A call interrupted
can f ** a conversation.
Tell a bitch of shit!
Man of ass!
Hello, Amy?
Crap!
I have to go back.
What?
Amy is in trouble problems, back then.
I let her go before,
I will not lose it again!
Boy, these crazy!
Is there any type of disaster in the city!
If not, we now bazaar,
we die!
I have to do that.
You continue.
No, You're my brother,
I will comtigo.
Yes I mean, we are already
this together, so ...
.. what's problems
I could could hold out?
I mean, most of which are swollen
Vince Vaughn in "The Break--Up" or
Vince Vaughn in Fred Claus ...
I think only Vince Vaughn in general.
Though.
Lisa, come on!
Malta ...
Although, baby!
I have a bad feeling
in relation to this.
Lisa!
Mataram, the Lisa!
Come on, come on!
Sorry,
for his girlfriend.
"The sense" to
His girl, "kimosabe.
I'm sure you are destroyed
Siegfried Roy became worse after being
attacked by the white Bengal tiger.
Lisa was a beautiful girl.
Lisa!
Where am I?
That charming place!
Everything is so clean and fresh!
Wonderful!
What kind of magical creature are you?
My dear prince,
I apeguei in you.
Honey, you landed on my lap ...
Let me guess.
An evil witch you Bani
in its history.
No, my dear adolescents.
Actually, I am just a beggar,
Nick to live in the sewer.
Nice.
How you got there?
Drugs. Many, many, many, many
charming drugs!
I do not do that.
This is getting dangerous.
Let us bias,
if you want to survive.
-- Okay.
Goodbye, wait ...
I go with you.
Yes, you!
National Museum of History
is right in the middle. Va--mos walking.
Dreams and fairy tales,
my true love.
talks to squirrels
and magic of ... and many things.
Princess, wait, where are you?
And who is this horrible warrior?
I am your new boyfriend, and you who is?
Very funny, Highness,
I am the Prince Eduadrdo.
-- Princess, it is your pimp?
-- Thank God, yes.
But no matter,
I can not have multiple boyfriends.
What to do?
can fight, one against another
who win stay with me.
Tas ready for Step--Up (street dance)?
Wait, as in the first film "Step Up"
where the boys dancing in the street, were challenged
by the academy?
No, I'm thinking "Step Up 2", where
challenged the dancers and street dancers of the academy.
Strangelove in your wave!
To start, here I come!
It was only my sleeve.
Look for this loser!
Must have been something.
Give some space! Get out!
rays, that girl dance!
Probably has a lot of practice,
he is not a common girl.
Look how it spins!
I want to dance.
I am not sure whether,
can go.
--Not sure, there can handle the pressure not!
Strangelove--ready!
I will yes, Bazaar here!
It's all yours, brother.
get away, get away!
Nobody will save us?
We need a hero!
I am the Iron Man!
Wow, that cow until it rains!
Damn, this is very crazy!
Now it makes me furious!
I came away with this!
fuck! Another cow?
What was that?
was not cool!
Look at me! Look at my hand!
It is the arm of a lobster!
What it ...
what a guy has to do to,
get out of hell?
I am not nervous.
not gonna like to see me nervous.
There are aspects of my personality,
you can not control.
He did not even hit him with a cow!
We are not going to enter the museum.
I know she is still alive!
Hello, Jojo?
Jojo? No, no, I am!
Will, Will, I'm stuck.
A statue fell on egícia
me during the earthquake. .
Keep yourself calm, Amy, stay calm ..
I am full of fear,
with great fear.
Wait, Amy, listen to me ...
Do not panic.
I go there, I promise you!
Amy? Amy!
Malta, I will return to search it!
You can save it, you'll be dead!
Come on! move comes!
Come immediately. Hold on!
Amy? No! No!
-- You can go back!
-- Amy!
I know that I'm crazy pension
But all these disasters have
something to do with the crystal skull.
It seems that it is very PMDD.
PM what?
Much information at once?
Why not just say the word,
Because when you use acronyms?
relax, not LL LL Cool J.
Stop this conversation.
Now, who is hungry?
oh, it is delicious!
That matters.
Bon appetite!
-- You want some?
-- No.
What?
I have to answer the phone.
Oh. .. crap.
Only a little.
You are cool.
I do it forever.
What is it?
Hey, guys ...
is the mother of Lisa.
I have to say le, what happened
her daughter.
Hello Mrs. Heller.
Lisa e. ..!
Lisa is dead!
Of course I am ... LOL!
I met a princess ... Caliente!
She will do whatever I want!
You have to talk to her.
Talk to her!
Hello?
Yes, he's right, I'll do anything.
Actually, if you have 5 euros
I show you.
After I went with someone from
100 years, no longer do that.
You are very cool!
Should we combine a day--to quit.
We have to go Tuesday with Amy, in
National Museum of History.
-- No. .. no ... I can not see anything!
-- Not me!
Someone is trying to excite me.
Kelvin?
Just do it.
They are so perfect.
Staying full of milk.
What the hell was that?
Wonderful.
What beautiful creatures of the forest.
I'm not happy, even ...
I mean ... I was feeling happy
I do not feel happy ....
-- Boy, I knew them they are bonss.
-- They are cool.
Yes, you are right or not,
Alvin and the Chipmunks?
I think they have rabies.
Where you going, head of Pumpkin?
Alvin (Help me)!
What ... but ... ray?
One, sausage!
I feel ignored. Nobody me
he did not bite my legs.
This is all we got,
baby's mama?
Stay out with the girls
Die!
Oh, God, that tasty!
June!
Forget it, kid, you can not do anything.
She is still alive.
They are eating me, Carter.
I am prepared with eggs Rachel Ray
40 U.S. dollars per day.
You gonna die if you go
there to help her.
Hey, "Best Friends Forever"
which is interest of 411 instead of 911?
It is really annoying.
You're completely TH, not
I am irritating,
but please KIT
before I forget 187 ...
Cover your ears.
-- In the end.
It was a wonderful lunch.
Now we will eat you.
... They are all well?
Yes
Honey, knees ...
your knees are bleeding!
Yes, but not because of squirrels.
But I still have a headache.
apply for the head.
Rub it directly on his forehead.
-- But ... I just do it!
-- I did apply, its cow!
-- rub it directly on his forehead.
-- The screw.
not put it on you, your adoscente bitch! I said
applies them directly in your maldilta forehead.
Okay, okay.
These happy?
Look, the white shit!
Rub  meantime, your daughter's p *****
p ***** on your forehead.
All right? already, I went everywhere.
Forehead, cheeks, nose, eyes, ...
This is fantastic, the headache passed.
But I still have an infection
on the lips.
Anybody want a ...?
-- God ...
-- Let's go to the museum.
Excuse me, sir ...
What's happening? Where will all?
It is a mass evacuation, everyone
should leave the city immediately.
You can not, you will also bazaar, Batman?
Hell, yes! ya, am I?
I do not want to die.
I was not in my plans for today. Not on the agenda,
had other things to do.
The plan was: wake up,
make breakfast,
work, experiences
scientific, die. I was not!
I was not, right?
Done?
Anyone who stays in the city after the
11 will be buried under the rubble ..
-- I hate garbage!
-- I have to go to the museum save my girl, Amy.
She is stuck!
Sorry to have to go back to your
girl, but you have 0 opportunities to survive.
I will toss.
Look, the bus evacuation
leaving the city the 21.
The 21? What is this? E. .. 5 to 6 ...
9 of the night, I'll save you the work
design, is the 9 o'clock in the evening.
It starts at noon and
after 9 hours ... then it is 9,
atunci trebuie sound you urci în
autobuzul sau wing and one of you om mort.
M. .. Dead?
Come on, it is 5:30.
Say again ...
5:30? Jesus Christ ...
God, I wasted the whole day I ...
was in the Amazon, ecomprando stuff.
Crap! Why? Why do I
Purchases of the Christmas today?
Why I chose this day?
rays, son of a oz.
Okay, time for plan B.
-- I'm Batman.
-- I am a sweet princess!
True story. Had
a woman for some time,
I have been in the top 4 of the
the best lovers.
This is a true story,
and ask me why.
Would you like to see me playing with ... ...
Goodbye.
Come on, come on!
National Museum of History.
Attention to death and destruction.
Hands up, boy! It's better this sairres
Mach 5, or I will put you in the eye of a balázio ass!
You know they say that the first
Homicide is always the hardest,
but I found it easy,
actually very fun.
Take this! Come on!
Here you can and no eyes!
How do you like, punk?
I'm just playing with my monkey!
Come on!
Go!
Care!
these shoes glass
I do not help to run ...
Will? Help me.
Amy!
-- You came because of me.
-- I love you, Amy.
I know. I also love you.
Take me this madilta,
pole on my shoulder?
Ok.
Okay, okay, okay.
It crossed the two sides.
It will not be so simple. Calvin,
I will need your help.
Okay.
Why the hell did you do that?
I wanted to let her incosciente,
so do not feel pain.
Well thought out.
... Love is for your own good.
boy, hit like a girl.
Yeah, let me try.
This girl is resistant.
Is not working. Let's just try
take it from here.
I will count to three.
1, 2, 3.
We gotta get out of here, the
building will fall on us.
No, not until I return
This
back to the altar.
A pipe Magic!
skull of Crystal. As in my dreams.
No, the legend says that if the skulls
Crystal lacking at the altar, is
Near the end of the world.
Earthquakes, asteroids,
Return of the Spice Girls.
Yes!
Revelation!
And you know all of these things
because work at the museum.
No, because I saw the movie,
Indiana Jones and "crystal skull."
I know what this means?
You know you have dreamed of the skull,
and you know about the skull?
It means we are destined to be together?
No. It shows that both
like skulls.
And this, too.
Will we have to get out of here.
They are almost 9 hours.
If we do not hurry--mos
we die!
Vai, Calvin, I am here with Amy.
We will return the skull to the altar.
-- Even the sight.
-- Nice to meet you.
We will seek the altar.
What's happening?
I think the exposure of
museum and resurrect!
Help!
Yay!
Let's get out of here!
-- The sanctuary of the skull of Crystal is here.
-- Okay.
I. .. am ... Beowulf!
Hi!
What?
I am Beowulf.
-- Could you put some clothes?
-- I am Beowulf.
I never went to confront someone, and so
And I will fight you.
And if I, I was naked?
-- I am Beowulf.
-- This is becoming gay, boy.
-- No, I am not gay ...
-- No, I'm sorry, but you are gay.
It is not gay, is not it!
It is what we do in 507. Pilas
-- Yes
-- Ask anyone.
Okay, I will do,
I will ask my friend Paul,
we go together, alongside the field of relaxation
I see wha he says.
-- Paul?
-- My friend Paul. It's my partner.
It is my friend, but
we are also partners.
-- Partners for life?
-- No, partners in business!
We opened a store
antiques, together.
This is gay.
Why Gay?
Why antiques is gay?,
I like things old.
I am Beowulf!
Excuse me, you're ready
to get hurt?
Oh no, Kung--Fu Panda.
Should not have done this.
Ready to feel ... the Panda?
The girl seems to me your family, boy,
Last year I paid 20
per 20 minutes,
If I understand.
It is true.
Enough!
Damn!
Yay!
Nice work!
My dear prince,
You have defended my honor!
Kiss me, baby!
You're a guy?
I am a travesti.Pensei you knew.
Shows you, Will!
I am Beowulf!
Yes, I already know.
Let go! And you can get a pin and
arrangements you some tickets for "Jersey Boys"!
I am the king of "Dance
for you, "in Latin dance!
No!
I will take you to "cruise
of Rosie O'Donnel "
Just me, you and my darling
friend, Jorge Decay.
Suck my dick!
Ow! Ow!
Hurry! We have no time ...
Altar of the Crystal Skull
Indiana Jones?
Indiana, my ass!
From here, take me.
Thank you, son.
That's right, I am your father!
You are my father?
Your mother won the round.
She was a hell of a bitch.
Okay, I understand.
I regret that you have left
and your mother,
but I had an adventurous spirit.
and that ass magic,
everywhere we did.
Look what we have
here! This is your baby?
What young beautiful!
I want a hug, your
As you are well!
Tasty, my God!
Father!
-- You are so beautiful ...
-- Dad!
That was nice ass, a
hamburgher, honey, you okay with everything!
Father!
Practice "Kamasutra"?
Just ask, just ask.
Do not do what your
old "Dad" did!
Make a pledge.
Is no cure for herpes and
rays that you do not have.
Looks easy.
It is not so easy, so for me!
Damn, my balls!
You know I have to prang.
Okay, Dad.
Why not walk, only to the altar?
It is 3 meters away.
Girl innocent!
Do not worry, I'll be fine.
Semanalike Hari, Hari Semanalike.
I am the Guru Pitko.
And today we are here together to bring ...
Amy and Will in one,
union of peace and happiness.
E. .. Amy, you're good as corn!
Amy, will accept as peanut butter and
in the jelly belly candy?
Yes
And Will ...
amy accepted as
owner of your love?
Yes
Well, in this case,
unite their fists,
closes the key,
Cut ...
Now things with something ...
-- I love you, Will.
-- I love you too, Amy.
But ... I have to tell you something.
What?
Ando with Matt Damon.
Are you seeing it with Matt Damon?
I was with Hanna Montana.
She walked with Hanna Montana.
I mean me and my fans urged me!
I mean, I see all hands up!
And I went, with Flava!
Yes, come here, a little taste of Flava!
And I was with June.
Yes, I know, but true, Flava--flavor
I am.
I'm with Calvin and with his girlfriend.
And we all tavamos with Hell Boy.
They are hell boys
and I Tou with Hulk.
Yes, yes they are angry, they are
so green, are angry.
Alas, they are burned, and
I was with the princess.
Ding--Dong!
Who touched, my campaign?
The girls of the man of iron,
NMAL of i--mi place împuþit.
It is very good,
because I am with the wolf!
Take the wolf, it takes a little bit, because I
I am with the babes of "Sex and the City".
He proved the girls of "Sex and the City".
So I asked:
Wolf would have been jealous if you think I would
was the guy with that big belt?
And everyone with Batman.
Now I'll never recover,
because I am with Amy Winehouse.
he is with Amy Winehouse.
Low him go, go, go.
I am with Jessica Simpson.
Because I made a mistake, error, error.
I'm Jessica Simpson, yes, and I think
I was with my rooster to do.
They are very cool,
and are, and Mexican
and the guy was crazy.
Let's play the currency
-- I was with JT.
I was with each model
to show how good they are.
And I like
until next Kalvin Klein.
It is true, JT, that once we see,
as I am and with prinþul Caspian.
They are beautiful and I am strong,
why am I
boys high school.
Come on, encouraging!
It's time to spend,
I hear you all!
You know what time it is?
No! What time is it?
It's time we married.
Take me!
Take us!
In our school, in showers
case
Nobody knows ...
I do not know ...
I am with Indiana Jones.
I am Indian and I am Hancock.
And am Beowulf!
And I was with Kung--Fu Panda!
And I was with Michael Jackson!
And I was with the Chipmunks.
We, Alvin and the Chipmunks.
And the Chipmunks are with you!
Subtitles by RABBIT: minimog_diablos@yahoo.com