I just read that money
as we know it is dead.
Soon the world
is only gonna buy and sell
products using Bitcoins.
It's like
a complicated math equation.
So, one day we're gonna
buy things with numbers
from a math equation?
Dope, right?
Malcolm Adekanbi is a geek.
Malcolm lives with
his single mother and has
only one memory of his father.
Malcolm lives
in Inglewood, California,
in the Darby-Dixon neighborhood
referred to as The Bottoms.
Give me your bike,
nigga!
Malcolm's friends,
Jib and Diggy, are also geeks.
Yo.
Shit.
All I want to do
is a zoom, zoom, zoom
and the boom, boom.
Word.
Malcolm, Jib and Diggy...
are all deeply obsessed
with '90s hip-hop culture,
submerging themselves
in the music,
watching old
Yo! MTV Raps episodes
for fashion tips...
and using the slang.
Huh?
Bro, that shit
was whack.
- What?
- They were biting Brand Nubian.
That's not even possible.
Jackpot, niggas.
Gushy, gushy.
Mmm!
Oh, did I mention
that Diggy was a lesbian?
Although from the way
she dresses, you might not
have noticed she's a girl.
Save her, Lord!
Yo, hallelujah!
Hallelujah!
Every Sunday,
her grandmother asks the church
to lay their hands on her...
in order to
pray away the gay.
Praise the Lord!
- So, did it work?
- You know.
I was watching Justin Bieber
the other night
and I got a little moist.
Yeah?
So maybe.
- That's just because
he's a little ho.
- That's true.
He's a very pretty nigga.
Yes, he is.
What's up, boss?
For most geeks,
a bad day might be being
the butt of jokes in class,
the occasional food prank
and the worst--
being beat up by a jock.
But when you live
in The Bottoms,
a bad day might be
accidentally
getting killed.
Like Wytony Johnson,
who got shot buying
a pastrami cheeseburger...
from Jimmy's Burger
on Centinela.
Hey! It's the Rollin' 60s,
dumb-ass niggas!
The real tragedy is...
that he was seconds away
from defeating Ganon.
He had a hell
of a comic book collection.
Jib has been trying
to talk Wytony's mom
into giving them to him...
for the past two weeks.
Malcolm, Jib and Diggy
don't play sports
and they aren't in a gang.
They're always getting
ridiculed by their peers because
they're into white shit...
like skateboards, manga comics,
Donald Glover...
and for listening
to white shit like
Trash Talk, TV on the Radio...
and for doing white shit
like getting good grades
and applying to college.
Malcolm, Jib and Diggy
used to be in
the school marching band,
but quit in protest
after refusing
to play the Harlem Shake.
They arranged to use
the music room during lunch...
for their recently formed
punk band, Awreeoh.
One, two.
One, two, three, four!
Hey-hey!
You know the program, niggas.
Shoe program.
Turn around.
Let me see what the fuck
you working with.
Oh, shit, man.
All these motherfuckers got
small feet around this bitch.
Goddamn. Nigga, I don't know
why you was looking.
Hey-hey!
My nigga, my G.
Oh, man.
Where the fuck
you goin', man?
Goddamn.
What's up with you?
Hey, them last shoes
you gave me, man,
I was feeling them.
Classics. The Force 2s?
Yeah, I was liking those.
What's these you got on?
Bro, these are straight
from the flea market.
Shut the fuck up, nigga.
These the J-3s
with the red mark on 'em.
Oh, yes.
Come up out those right now.
Right now, nigga!
You speak English?
Do I gotta beat
the shit out of you again
and take them?
Damn.
This nigga's speaking African
or some shit, like he
don't speak what we speak.
This nigga always--
Hey!
Go, Dig! Come on!
Dig! Go!
Come on, Dig!
Oh, shit!
Hey, hey. Hold up, hold up.
Get your fuckin' hands
off me, man!
Don't think I won't
beat your ass, Marquis!
I came up with your daddy.
You better ask him about Stacey.
And see what's what
around this motherfucker!
Let's go, man.
I'm gon' get the other one,
you little, bitch-ass nigga.
Go, man.
Malcolm, when I see stuff
like this personal essay,
I think you're not taking
the process seriously.
I'm-- I'm taking it
seriously, Mr. Bailey.
I promise.
I'm talking about
something that I love.
I mean,
it's well-reasoned, supported
with historical data,
it shows creativity,
critical thinking.
If Neil deGrasse Tyson
was writing about Ice Cube,
this is what it would look like.
I suggest you go
in a different direction.
Write something personal
about you.
Your family, your life.
I mean, I-- I could write
about the typical...
"I'm from a poor,
crime-filled neighborhood,
raised by a single mother,
don't know my dad"
blah-blah.
It's cliché.
This here, this--
this is--
This is creative.
This shows
that I'm different.
This is the kind of essay
that Harvard wants
from their students.
Malcolm, I'm gonna be
honest with you.
You're pretty damn arrogant.
You think you're gonna
get into Harvard?
Who do you think
you are? Hmm?
You go to high school
in Inglewood.
To the admissions committee,
your straight A's,
they don't mean shit.
If you're really serious
about this exercise and you're
not just wasting my time,
or yours,
then it's gonna be about
your personal statement,
your SAT scores,
your recommendations...
and most importantly
your alumni interview tomorrow.
- Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
You'd better be.
I just found out
you're interviewing
with Austin Jacoby.
He's from Inglewood too,
so he'll be able to relate
to your circumstances.
Jacoby Check Cashing?
Harvard? Really?
I'm sorry. They don't all
go on to be president.
On this day,
their usual route home
is blocked by a Blood gathering.
They were shooting a video
for their YouTube channel.
Well, where do you want to go?
Some nigga really needs
to invent an app like Waze
to avoid all these hood traps.
The only way to get home
is down 104th Street.
But that's where
the dope dealers are...
who, for sport, routinely
try to steal their bikes.
- Go!
- Hey, little nigga.
-  Such is the life  of a geek in The Bottoms.
- Come here.
A daily navigation between
bad and worse choices.
Come here, little nigga.
Yo, man.
I be seein' you and your
little friends with y'all
flattops and MC Hammer pants,
riding around in this shit,
looking like y'all came out
of a DeLorean or some shit.
You know, the '90s was like
the golden age of hip-hop.
Everything from
It Takes a Nation of Millions...
to The Blueprint
was killing it.
I guess me and my friends
just wish we grew up back then.
It Takes a Nation
came out in '88.
Blueprint came out 2001.
What the fuck are you
talkin' 'bout right now?
Technically, um--
But, you know,
the spirit of the music
was definitely still '90s.
I mean, It Takes a Nation,
Straight Outta Compton...
Paid in Full
was ahead of their time.
And then you got
Snoop, Biggie, Wu-Tang.
They took the game
to the next level.
Blueprint was kind of like
the punctuation mark.
Let's not forget,
the '90s also gave us...
Vanilla Ice, MC Hammer...
and we can't forget
about the Fresh Prince.
Everything in the '90s
wasn't great, but--
Oh, shit.
But you gotta admit
"Summertime" was a classic.
What's your name,
little nigga?
Uh, it's Malcolm.
Look here, Malcolm.
I want you to do a favor for me.
You see
that green apartment there
in the middle of the block?
There's a nice little piece
over there.
I want you to go up to her
and tell her that Dom
wants to talk to her.
Uh, th-that's-- that's it?
Yeah, nigga.
Can you handle that?
Uh... y-yeah.
Get to pedalin', nigga.
Drop that up here.
Yeah.
You gonna say something
or just stare at me?
Um, Dom says...
that he would like you
to come over
and talk to him.
Well, why don't you tell Dom
that if he wants to talk to me,
he can come over here
and be a fucking man...
and not send a little kid
to talk for him?
Tell him just like that.
She said that shit?
And that Dominique
was way cooler
before he became Dom.
And, um, that if you think
that she cares about your
dope money, sh-she doesn't.
Listen, tell her that
I'm throwing a birthday party
at Verse tonight...
and I would really enjoy
the pleasure of her company.
Go ahead, nigga.
You should, uh--
You should work inside out.
Do the stuff
in the brackets first
and then square the sum.
Yep.
Okay. Thanks.
Oh! Uh...
Dom says he's throwing
a birthday party
tonight at Verse.
Mm-hmm.
He said he'd really love
the, uh-- the pleasure
of your company.
That nigga did not say that.
He did. I s--
I swear. He--
Lord.
Well, I'll go if you go.
I'll save you a dance.
You are going.
We are going.
She metaphorically
showed you her pussy
and said, "Come and fuck me."
Jib, um, this is Dom
we're talking about.
We're not going to
a drug dealer's birthday party.
That's-- You're trippin'.
We're in our
senior year, bitches.
Okay?
- It is time we started
expanding our horizons.
- No.
Call your mom
and tell her you're-- you're
studying late at my place.
Come on. Dig? Huh?
Look, it's better than what
you normally do at night, so--
Mm-hmm.
Looking beautiful. Oh!
One, two and tres.
Been working on my Spa--
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- What you doing?
- You let them in without
checking the list.
- What's up?
Okay, let me educate you
real quick.
I am the gatekeeper,
I'm the grandmaster,
the authority...
in keeping
a proper nigga-to-ho ratio.
You understand
what I'm saying?
So unless you little niggas
got some pussies, I'm gon'
need y'all to get the fuck--
- I have one.
I know y'all some bitches,
but you ain't gotta say
you got pussies.
She-- She's a girl.
What?
This little nigga's a bitch!
Like-- Like Boys Don't Cry
like a motherfucker.
Remember when
we was seein' that shit?
Yeah, I remember that.
Nigga, what the fuck.
Let us in.
Oh, well, yeah, yeah.
You know, it's 21 and older.
I'm gon' need some ID,
some verification.
- Uh--
- Oh.
Wait.
Y'all don't have no IDs?
Aw! Sorry! I'm gon' need y'all
to get the fuck off.
Come on.
Get the fuck off.
There's a Baskin-Robbins
down the street.
Enjoy yourselves.
Hey, man, don't this dude
look like the dude
that danced in Santa Monica?
- Breakdance?
-          Don't he look like--         What the fuck.
You're coming in, right?
Get the fuck outta here, man!
Get the fuck outta here, man.
Old Coolio-looking motherfucker.
Hey, baby. You're looking good.
Thank you.
Digs. Digs. Digs. Jib. Jib.
Come on, come on.
Hey. Hey, w-wait-- Hey!
Yo, yo, yo. It's cool.
It's cool. Let 'em in.
Look, I ca--
I can't let you do that.
These kids are underage
and I cannot lose
my license tonight.
Not tonight.
I don't mind having
this discussion with you.
I actually enjoy
the thoughtful exchange
of ideas.
And you do bring up
a valid point.
Know what I'm sayin'?
But see, you put me
in a bit of a spot, nigga.
'Cause I can't have you
back-talkin' me
in front of my niggas...
without at least
fuckin' your ass up.
You feel me?
You don't have to do that.
I kinda do though.
I don't want to.
It's my birthday and shit.
But there's principles
to this shit,
and I'm a principled man.
- They in, Dom. It's all good.
- I know they got in.
That's my point.
But I got this nigga telling me
what he can't let me do
and shit. Like I give a fuck.
Man, if I let this shit slide,
we got what they call
a slippery slope.
You know what
a slippery slope is, nigga?
No. I don't--
I don't know
what a slippery--
Anyone?
Do it got anything
to do with skiing?
Nigga, sit your ass down, man.
I know using your brain
is a challenge and shit.
You use skis on a slope--
You might fuck around,
give yourself a concussion.
It's a small event that leads to
a chain reaction of events...
with unintended consequences...
that were unforeseen at the time
of the inciting event.
See, this is
a smart little nigga
right in here, bro.
You probably got one of them
"photogetic" brains
or some shit, huh?
You mean photographic memory?
- Nigga, what I just say?
- I mean, yeah, y-you said it.
I'm reiterating that--
I'm still a little shaky
on the concept.
Basically, if I let
this nigga slide, man,
then I'm going to have
the next nigga coming along,
thinking they can
pop off and shit,
you know what I'm sayin'?
And so on and so forth.
- Damn!
- Oh, shit.
- Hey, little nigga,
you coming in?
Yo, it's cool.
You coming in, Malcolm?
Nigga, come on.
Yeah.
Nigga, school's out.
What the fuck you doing
with a bag on?
Hey, throw this behind the bar
for my little homey.
Yo, let me
get a round of shots.
Cheers.
Hi.
So, are you gonna ask me
to dance or what?
I think you said
something about me...
being man enough
to come talk to you.
Can I have this dance, Nakia?
It's my birthday, you know.
Hey, uh--
We were dancing, man.
Kids say
the darndest things,
don't they?
See, this is what happens
when you don't
spank your children.
Anyways--
Why do you have to
talk to him like that?
- You look nice tonight.
- Dom.
Boom!
Damn, nigga, that was ill.
This nigga doesn't know
what hit him.
Check this nigga out.
He's walking
his jihad dog and shit,
scratching his nuts.
Yahtzee, nigga.
Ooh, this shit crazy.
Yo, man, straight up,
I really used to think
Obama was a bitch, man.
Drones though, nigga?
That's some gangsta shit.
I need one
of those motherfuckers.
This shit ain't funny.
It's fucked up
if you really think about it.
How, nigga?
He killing all them
Al-Qaedas and shit.
Nigga, that ain't all
that gets killed.
And that nigga's saying
he can drone-strike
Americans too.
They killed an American
working with them niggas
in Yemen.
Man, he was a terrorist, dawg.
So it's like set trippin'.
You can't decide
to be a Blood...
and then get mad
if the Crips try to
kill you and shit.
Man, all I'm saying is...
this shit started somewhere
like Pakistan or some shit.
And before you know it,
they'll start saying
that we're the terrorists.
They're gonna have planes
riding all around Inglewood,
droppin' bombs on Crenshaw
and shit, man.
Ah, slippery slope.
Exact, nigga.
Shit, I wish a nigga
would try to fly drones
in my hood.
- Fuck that.
- Hell yeah.
I wish I would see
one of them motherfuckers
in Inglewood, man.
For real.
Don't let them niggas
come to my hood.
What you got there?
- Ah!
- Whoo!
Breakfast Club, nigga.
Molly Ringwald.
So, this the latest
and greatest shit, huh?
Yes, sir.
Pure as a nun's pussy.
Know what I'm sayin'?
This ain't like that
ghetto shit y'all niggas
been fucking with either, man.
This is that A-1 shit.
A.J. say you ready
to move out the D-league
and move up to the NBA.
- Oh, shit.
-           Jesus!
Get the fuck out of here!
Let's move. Go!
Nakia! Nakia.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Malcolm!
Shit.
Come on. I drove.
Thanks for helping me.
Most of those niggas
just saw me
and stepped over me.
Luckily for you,
I'm not one of those niggas.
Oh, really?
- What are you, then?
- I don't know.
I'm just--
I'm black as fuck, right?
Uh, I guess I'm just used to
hearing that, uh,
niggas don't listen to this,
niggas don't do that,
niggas don't go to college
unless they play ball
or whatever.
It's just time to accept it.
I'm just not one
of those niggas.
Well, me neither then.
'Cause I'm going to college.
Just gotta get my GED first.
That's what
you were studying for.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
If I pass, I'll go to El Camino
or Santa Monica or something.
Transfer to Dominguez
or Northridge.
Well, you shouldn't
sell yourself short.
You could do better.
You hardly know me.
So how can you say that?
I can just tell.
You shouldn't settle
for what's expected.
Like Dom, right?
I--
I didn't say that.
Don't try and be slick.
You're trying to
block him.
So, you two--
Y-You guys--
It's complicated.
But trust me,
he's got nothing on you.
You probably got all
the girls lined up asking
you to prom and shit.
You making fun of me?
N-No.
I'm sorry.
Hey, I didn't go
to my prom.
You didn't go
to your prom?
Seriously.
I had one guy ask me--
Anthony Davis-- and he
fucking stood me up.
I didn't even care
about missing prom.
I was more mad about not going
to Six Flags the next day.
All my friends had dates.
I didn't want to go alone.
Would you want to
go to prom with me?
I mean, I--
I know that
I'm not complicated or--
But--
It's just with studying
and all,
I don't think
I'll have time.
But thank you.
What if I helped you study?
And what if you passed the GED?
Would you go with me then?
I'll think about it.
Okay.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit.
Three words.
Did you fuck?
You're a pussy,
nigga.
Come on, man.
She let me feel her titties
and finger-bang her.
Bullshit.
No, I'm dead-ass
serious.
Smell my fingers.
I don't smell shit.
Just cream.
You never smelled pussy
before.
Wait. I have.
I don't smell shit.
See, she don't
smell shit either.
'Cause you only know your pussy.
Exactly!
- Wait, wait, wait. Hold it.
- Whoa, whoa.
Wait a minute.
You two go back through,
one at a time.
One at a time.
What's getting into you?
Come on.
Hey, hey. Calm down.
Go. Everybody else wait.
Turn around, go back.
We gotta do pat-downs.
The machine is broke.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Yo, yo, yo.
Oh, shit!
What's wrong? What?
Oh, shit.
Fuck! Is that real?
Boy, how'd you get this shit?
I have no fucking clue, Jib.
No fucking clue.
What do you mean
you don't have a fucking clue?
I have no fucking clue
where that gun came from.
Or the drugs.
Drop your weapons!
Get the fuck outta here.
Let's move. Go!
Last night at--
at the fucking party.
At the party.
Dom put that shit
in my bag. Had to be.
Well, we gotta
get rid of it then.
You know? Dump it, or--
Or take it to the police.
Yeah. Let's take it
to the police.
Are you joking?
You want three niggas
to take a bag full of dope
and a gun...
to the fucking
police station?
Like, "Here you go"?
N--
And-- And you don't expect Dom
to find out who snitched?
- Well, what do you
wanna do with it?
- Yo, that's a lot of weight.
It's like 20, 30 keys.
I don't know.
- It's a lot of shit, right?
- I don't know, Dig.
I don't know anything
about this shit.
All I know is Jeezy paid LeBron
and Jay paid Dwyane Wade.
What?
He was talking about dope?
Shit.
I-I-I-I answered it.
You did what?
I don't want that shit.
Shit.
- Hello?
-      Who the fuck is this?
U-Um, who is this?
This the nigga
that's gon' fuck you up,
you keep asking questions.
Now, who the fuck is this?
I prefer not to say.
Okay, I see how
we gon' do this then.
If this ain't
a nigga named Malcolm
at Yukon and 104th Street,
then I'm gon' kill your ass.
How do you know
where I am?
Find an iPhone.
Steve Jobs
a motherfucking genius.
Oh, shit.
Now, if this
a nigga named Malcolm,
say, "Damn right."
Otherwise,
click-click-boom.
Damn right.
Damn right, my name is Malcolm.
Malcolm. Malcolm!
How you feeling, man?
Dom told me there was a mix-up.
You accidentally took my lunch.
That true?
- Took your lunch?
- Yeah, my lunch.
A nigga hungry.
Yes. Yes, I--
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Baloney sandwich. Mm-hmm.
Baloney.
It got cheese on it?
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
We talking about
the same sandwich, nigga?
'Cause I ain't ask
for no cheese.
I find that my fucking
sandwich got cheese on it,
I'm gon' kill your ass.
I don't know.
You just-- You know,
there's a bag and--
What? What?
You're the one wanted
to get all cute, talkin' 'bout
baloney sandwiches and shit.
- I just asked you
if you had my lunch.
- Yeah.
Yeah, you're right.
You're right.
Uh, your lunch. It's right here.
I'm looking at it right now.
Coolio.
Now, after school, you're gon'
see a red El Camino parked...
and this
handsome-ass nigga inside.
That ain't Lance Gross, nigga.
That's yours truly.
Just walk up, hand me
the baloney sandwich
and be on your way.
You have a nice,
happy, productive life with
a hell of a story to tell.
You got it?
Yeah. Yeah, I got it.
Red El Camino after school.
Cool.
It's almost over,
little nigga.
You did good.
What the fuck did we
get ourselves into, man?
I don't see it.
Where is it?
Yo, he's over there.
- Where?
- To the right.
Oh, I see him.
You good?
Yeah. Yeah, let's go.
All right.
Yeah.
He asked for you alone,
you know?
I got your back and all.
It's just I don't wanna mess
with his explicit instructions.
You'll be fine, bro.
Right?
You're just dropping it off.
You're good.
Uh, hey. Yeah.
I'm, uh--
I got your lunch.
I'm walking
to the red El Camino
right now.
What you say?
Who's this?
This is Dom, man.
Look, do you have
what I left in the backpack?
Yeah. Yeah.
You in the red El Camino?
What the fuck
you talking about?
Somebody called me earlier
saying I need to bring him
the sandwich.
Nigga, why the fuck
are you talking about
sandwiches right now?
The-- The backpack.
He-- The guy, he said
that I needed to bring it
to him after school.
He'd be
in a red El Camino.
Yo, McFly, I want you
to listen to what I'm about
to tell you right now.
Somebody snitched.
I'm in County right now.
I don't know
who the fuck called you.
There's two possibilities.
Either the motherfucker
in the El Camino is POPO--
As soon as you give him
the package,
he gon' arrest you.
Or that motherfucker's
the snitch.
In that case,
he'll take the package,
kill you,
then I'm headed to Chino
with a price on my head.
I'm gon' need you to trust me
right about now, you understand?
Do not take that backpack
to the nigga in the whip,
else we both fucked. Hear me?
I'm gonna text you
this address.
Go there, ask for A.J.
Tell him it's about
the Boys Club.
Give him the package.
Tell him it's from me.
You hear me?
Nigga, run. Get the fuck
out of there, nigga.
Run. Go now!
Get the fuck out of there!
Oh, shit.
Go!
Oh, shit. Oh, shit!
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit.
Go! Let's go! Come on!
Go, Jib!
- Get the fuck back over here!
- Oh, shit!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move the fucking car!
Let's go!
Come on!
Yo, man, what the hell happened?
Who the fuck was that?
Dom.
What?
Dom!
That nigga called me
and said that the nigga that
called earlier isn't with him.
Well, then who is he?
Oh, shit.
How the fuck did they find us?
Yo, let's go.
Jib! Dig! Bus!
There. Right here.
Right ahead.
It's that bus.
Right there. Right there.
They on that bus!
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Open the fucking door!
Open the fucking door,
bitch!
You see three little niggas
get on this bus
a couple stops ago?
I don't know.
Lot of young niggas
get on this bus.
Don't get smart. I'm just
asking you a motherfucking
question, all right?
I don't see shit
but the road.
- He's here.
Is it you? Huh?
Is it fuckin' you?
Congratulations.
You have found your iPhone.
Damn.
Yo, Lily, what are you doing
opening the door
butt-ass naked for?
Excuse my dumb-ass sister, man.
What up?
Are you A.J.?
No, that's my dad.
I need to speak to him.
It's about Boys Club.
Right. Right.
Well, my dad's at his office
for a couple of hours.
But y'all can hang out here
until he gets back if you want.
Um--
No.
You know--
Hey.
Yeah.
- You wanna come in?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Y'all come in.
You Piru?
Crenshaw Mafia?
Uh, I'm just Malcolm.
That's your hood, though.
Right? Right?
Yeah.
In the guest house
is where I got my studio.
That's where I lay down
my tracks.
I fuck around with it, you know.
I do my little thing.
My style is, I'm like a Dilla
meets a No ID with a little bit
of splash of Rick Rubin.
- Right.
- Know what I mean?
I actually got something
that I did the other day.
Check this out.
Yeah, what the fuck
is "bereal"?
Oh, shit. Look.
I meant "cereal."
But that's how much
I hate crab-ass niggas.
'Cause my mind, it thinks
these C-words, but my mouth
won't let me say them.
Okay, so, you replace words
that start with C's with B's?
- Like Crip dyslexia.
- Criplexia.
But only soft C's, because
you said "crab" no problem.
That's true. Why won't
your mind tell your mouth
to say "brab" instead of "crab"?
- I don't know.
It's a case-by-case thing.
- Not "base-by-base"?
See, you would think
this hard "C" would be
the issue, but no.
That's interesting.
Fuck y'all. I'm just tryin'
to rep my set. That's it.
- Ladera doesn't have a set.
- What the fuck you mean?
Huh?
- Does that make me any less   of a nigga than y'all?
-  - No.
Because my dad
was from The Bottoms.
Yeah.
My uncle, everybody on my side
reppin' the Inglewood family.
'Cause that's
where my heart is.
Yeah.
Even though my--
my body's right here.
- Mm-hmm.
-         - It's cool.
I-It's "bool."
Fuck all y'all. 'Cause I was
in a good mood and shit.
What was that?
A song that we--
You just reminded us
of something we was writing.
"Was"?
Let's-- Let's get to it.
- What you mean?
- Let's record.
- Let's record what?
- The song.
Quit fucking around.
Come on.
Randy.
Check this out.
Little niggas.
Got 'em.
I know y'all hungry.
If you want, you can just
help yourself to my fridge.
Or I could have Marta
cook us up something.
- Can she cook
chili-cheese fries?
- Chili-cheese fries. Yeah.
Marta! Yeah.
- Right?
- Where you get 'em at?
Jimmy's Burgers on Centinela
and Inglewood Avenue.
Yes, um-- Cuatro órdenes
de chili-cheese fries...
at Jimmy's Burgers
on Centinela and Inglewood.
Niggas, let's roll.
You coming, Malcolm?
No, I think
I'm gonna stay here.
So...
you're a boy
from the hood.
Good thing you found
the Boys Club and have such
an amazing mentor as my father.
I'm bored as fuck.
Will you play with me,
my little boy
from the hood?
Yeah.
Yeah, we--
I can-- Well, what do
you want to play?
How about we play
Mother May I?
You remember that game,
right?
Yeah.
S-- Yeah.
Go ahead.
Ask me a question.
Um... what's your name?
Lily.
No, you're supposed to
ask me something like,
"Mother, may I
take two steps?"
If I say yes,
you take two steps
toward me.
Or I may say,
"No, you have to
take three steps back."
Now it's my turn
to ask the questions.
Okay.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
May I take off
my clothes?
Yeah.
May I walk over
to you?
Yeah.
May I touch you?
Yes.
Are you a virgin?
No.
Don't.
Don't do that.
There are too many liars
and bullshitters
in this house, Malcolm.
I can tell
you're not like that.
Not like him.
Don't start now, okay?
Okay.
Yes, I'm a virgin.
I gotta pee.
Jaleel keeps rubbers
over there.
I want you ready
when I get back.
Go.
Can we get some
chili-cheese fries?
Burgers too.
All right,
we'll get, uh--
Yo, can I get
a grilled cheese?
What the fuck is this?
We got a problem, blood?
Listen to this motherfuckin'
Abercrombie and Fitch-ass nigga.
You little niggas
were supposed to deliver
my lunch today.
After school.
Now, I need my shit.
Right now, nigga.
Right now.
What the fuck are you even
talking about, nigga?
You hungry?
She's right there.
Order some shit.
Order some shit?
See, first of all,
you do not know me, bro.
Let me tell you
what's going down.
All right?
We're gon' order
our food.
And then you can
order your lunch
or whatever the fuck else.
A'ight?
Then we gon'
keep it pushin'.
Where is my bag?
- Yo.
- What's in the backpack?
That's for my dad, right?
Fuck.
Lily.
Lily?
What the fuck?
What are you doing?
Look--
You don't know what you--
This is your--
Oh, my God!
This can't even be happening.
Look-- Look at you.
Come on--
What is wrong with you?
Have you ever fucked on Molly?
I haven't fucked
on anything. Remember?
Okay.
Okay. All right.
What the fuck!
You-- You threw up on me!
It's everywhere!
It's all in my mouth!
Who the fuck is this?
Son of a--
Why are you
yelling at me?
I don't know you,
Mr. Bailey,
but you're being
very rude.
What the fuck!
Bye.
Yes, this is Malcolm.
Malcolm! Come here.
Yes, can I reschedule,
please?
Mr. Bailey, come on--
Fuck!
Wait. Wait.
I have to go.
Wait. We're not done yet.
Where are you going?
Stop being so mean.
I have to go.
I spaced on
my college interviews!
my college interviews.
I only have 20 minutes
to get down there
or my whole life is fucked.
I'll take you.
What?
- Whee!
- Lily! Lily, get up!
Oh, Lily! It's a stop sign!
Lily, stop. Stop!
Stop!
Oh, shit.
Lily.
Lily!
I gotta pee!
Get out of my house!
Let me use the toilet!
Lily! Get back!
- Lily!
- I gotta pee!
I gotta pee! I gotta pee!
What the fuck?
Tell you what's going down.
We gon' order our food.
And then you can
order your lunch
or whatever the fuck else.
A'ight?
Then we gon'
keep it pushin'.
Yeah?
Shut your fuckin'--
Diggy, fries, fries, fries!
I want my motherfucking dope!
I want my fucking dope!
Shit, where the fuck is Jaleel?
Fuck!
That was our ride.
What the f--
Run, run, run!
Freeze! Down on your knees!
Keep your hands up!
What the fuck?
Mr. Jacoby's just
wrapping up a staff meeting.
He'll be a few minutes.
Dom?
Is that-- Is that Dom?
Oh, shit.
Austin Jacoby.
Nice to meet you,
Malcolm.
Take a seat.
Come on, relax.
So, uh...
Malcolm Adekanbi.
Did I pronounce that
right?
Yeah? Great.
You're Nigerian.
My dad, um--
He-- He went back to Nigeria
before I was born.
Sorry to hear that.
I know what it's like
to grow up without a father.
That's why I spend
a lot of time and a lot of money
with the Boys Club.
Those, um--
Those kids--
A-Are they your kids?
Yes, they are.
Not too much older
than you.
So you know Dominique?
Excuse me?
You-- You probably
know him as Dom.
No. Sorry.
Why do you ask?
Dom gave me something...
to deliver to someone.
As crazy as it seems,
I-I think
that someone is you.
This Dom person--
what did he say
that, uh,
I should have to do
with this, uh, delivery?
I don't know.
I just know that he told me
to deliver it to A.J., so--
And why did you do it?
- I didn't have a choice.
- Oh, come on, Malcolm.
Come on.
You always have a choice.
You could have done
a lot of things
with that package.
You're a smart kid.
I'm sure you thought
about all of them.
But you chose
to make the delivery
for this Dom person...
because you thought it was,
what, in your best interest?
So, you should
take responsibility...
for the choice
that you've made.
Now, you know
I'm not the person
or persons...
for whom this delivery
was intended.
Something happened
along the way.
It's like, uh, Amazon.
If you order a Rick Ross
or Macklemore CD--
I would not order
a Macklemore CD.
That wouldn't happen.
All right. Who, then?
Casey Veggies.
Casey Veggies?
That's-- That's an artist?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay. All right.
So, you order
a Casey Veggies CD
from Amazon, right?
No, you don't order
a Casey Veggies CD.
You just go online
and you download it.
Yeah, okay. All right.
But you are aware
that Amazon does
ship discs, right?
And if you order that disc
and it does not come
in a timely fashion,
you're gonna call them
and say, "Where's my stuff?"
And Amazon has to
assume responsibility.
But it's just one CD.
But what if it's 100 orders
and 100 CDs don't show up?
Or a thousand?
Or 10,000?
It's a slippery slope.
Slippery slope.
So, Amazon has
got to assume...
the full cost
of the loss.
But most importantly,
they have to deal with the loss
of their reputation.
A reputation that has taken
a long time to build.
You understand
what I'm saying?
So let's do this.
Let's reschedule
this interview...
for a few weeks from now.
Give it a little time.
Go out there.
Make the delivery
for which you have
claimed responsibility...
to the appropriate
consumers...
so that the suppliers
of this product...
can be whole.
Metaphorically speaking,
of course.
If you're able
to do this,
it shows me more
about you...
than any interview
ever could.
And I would then
make it my business...
to make you
a man of Harvard.
I want you to get out of
The Bottoms just like I did.
I know from growing up there
it's very, very dangerous...
and that your family
or your friends could
get killed at any moment...
just by being
in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
I'd hate for that
to happen to you...
or any
of your family members.
Getting on?
Looks like you and I
had the same kind of day.
How'd the interview go?
Okay.
Well, sit down.
My shift's almost over.
I'll take you home.
Thanks, Mom.
The incident took place today
at Seven Bucks Coffee--
apparently the side effects
of the popular club drug MDMA,
or "Molly."
Tannehill James was a witness
to this bizarre scene.
So, I'm here
at the Seven Bucks, drinking
my vanilla chai latte...
and eating me
some pound cake.
'Cause you know niggas
don't eat scones, right?
When all of a sudden
this crazy little naked ho
comes up...
and she squatted down
right in front of me
and she pissed right there.
I swear to God.
Pissed right there
for a long time.
So, now, you tell me
how am I supposed to
eat my pound cake...
after witnessing
something like that?
Reporting live, Karen Myetta,
Channel 10 News.
Up next, a fight over lunch
turns deadly in Inglewood.
Did he actually say,
"I'll kill you and your friends
if you don't sell these drugs"?
Or just you? What?
Don't act like
you weren't curious too.
Not directly.
He was talking about
Amazon and Rick Ross CDs
not getting to their customers.
Niggas don't even buy
CDs anymore, dawg.
Jib, that's not
the fucking point!
Are you gonna go and sell
on the corner? 'Cause we're
a bunch of bitches, man.
Speak for yourself, Jib.
Yes.
I am a bitch-ass nigga.
I don't give a fuck.
I own that shit.
Who are you trying
to impress, Diggy?
We're talking
about Molly, Jib,
not fucking heroin.
All we gotta do
is find the white people.
- Go to Coachella, Lollapalooza.
- Yeah, yeah.
We can backpack and hitchhike
and sing Mumford and Sons songs
and all that faux fucking shit.
Fuck you. Okay?
I'm just saying it could work.
Yeah, yeah.
Why stop there, you know?
Why not hit Bonnaroo also?
Bitcoins.
That's how we do it.
Do what?
Oh, shit.
There's these sites
where you can-- you can
sell everything...
from fake credit cards
to illegal guns and drugs.
And they use Bitcoins
so they can't be traced.
We don't have to
stand on any corner.
Dark Web. Could work.
Way better than Coachella.
Guys, the FBI
can track us. The police--
No, they can't.
- Not if you use a Tor browser.
- What the fuck is that?
- Onion routing.
- Layered encryptions.
It's like a game
of Whac-A-Mole with
thousands of computers--
What the fuck
is a Whac-A-Mole?
Look, these dark Web sites
run off these secret
IP addresses.
Like LulzSec-level shady.
We need to find one somehow.
W--
William Ian Sherwood III.
Musician, scholar,
rake, entrepreneur,
conspiracy theorist.
Malcolm,
Jib and Diggy met William
at band camp three years ago.
Yo, if you niggas
need some weed, I got you.
Good shit. Fair prices.
William assured them that
he used the word "nigga"...
only as a term
of endearment...
as explained by Q-Tip
in the classic song,
"Sucka Nigga."
That's your room
right there.
After that,
they all hit it off.
Though he never used that word
in front of them again.
The mission at band camp
was to give kids
from different backgrounds...
a chance to exchange
music and experiences
unique to their cultures.
W-W-Wait. Okay, so
you're saying white girls
will suck dick...
yet still claim
they're virgins?
Yeah, man. I'm serious.
Really?
Dude, check it.
I've been getting head since
I was, like, 12, all right?
I've been
hitting hos in the ass
since I was, like, 14.
It's true, man.
These chicks will
let you fill any hole,
except the pussy,
with a dick, no problem.
So, technically,
you're still a virgin too.
- Yeah.
- Right.
But here's something
to wrap your brain around, man.
I've never had intercourse
with a pussy.
Mm-hmm?
Only asshole and oral.
Okay?
So the question isn't,
"Am I technically a virgin?"
What the question
could be is...
"Am I technically... gay?"
Oh. That's deep, nigga.
Yeah. I don't know.
William went to--
prep school,
where he smoked
a pound of weed a week,
skipped classes...
and had a 1.9 GPA,
yet got a perfect score
on his SAT.
He was accepted
to his father's alma mater
under academic probation,
which meant he had to maintain
a 3.0 grade point average.
So, William hacked into
the--  database,
erasing all grades
from the entire freshman class.
Small-batch, craft-brewed,
40-ounce malt liquor.
That same year,
he achieved his dream of
having sex with a black girl.
You ever fucked
on Molly before?
No.
Hey, nah, it's good, man.
It's like-- It's like
being fucked by God.
Everybody is going to
Black Market Reloaded
and a bunch of smaller sites.
But, dude, that shit
is getting mad sketchy now.
If you nigga--
If you guys
want drugs,
I can get you good shit
way less expensive
than online.
Nigga, we don't need
to buy anything.
We need to set up
a store to sell.
Wha-- Nah, really, dude.
What can I get you, man?
I'm dead-ass serious,
nigga.
Dead-ass serious.
Okay.
All right. Wait.
'Cause this is
ridiculous, man.
Why the fuck,
after all these years,
you can call me N-word
and I can't say it?
Yo, look, we already
went over this.
I'll have to slap
the shit out of you again.
I don't want to do that.
See, that's not even right.
I mean, like, really.
You know I'm
not the one, all right?
This is all love here.
Look, let's--
let's get back--
Hey, you asked me
to do something for you.
I'm like, "What?" I'm down.
I don't give a fuck.
Because you're my people,
all right? You're my n--
And this is where
I would insert that word.
It's nothing personal.
You're still my nigga.
But I gotta slap
the shit out of you
based on principle.
- Let's get back
to what's goin' on.
- No, no, no. Wait. Principle?
Okay, you want
to talk principle.
What about Jib here, man?
This dude isn't
African-American.
He's like fucking Latino
or Moroccan or some shit.
Where's this conversation going?
Technically, he shouldn't
be able to say the word.
- Why can he use it?
- Okay. Because I'm 14% African.
Four-- Fourteen?
That doesn't--
Shit, I'm probably 14%.
I am 14% African.
Ancestry.com.
Look, we don't
give a fuck.
- For real?
- Just say the damn word, okay?
- It doesn't matter.
It's cool, right?
- I don't give a shit.
I give a fuck.
Don't say that shit. I will
slap the shit out of you.
No, no, no. No, you won't
because you have been
outvoted by your peers.
I'm George W. Bush.
I don't give a fuck
what the vote says.
Dig.
What the fuck?
- Let him say it.
- All right, you can say it.
- Thank you.
And I appreciate that.
I really do.
Now, like a nigga was saying--
What the fuck!
What the fuck?
Yo, it was a reflex.
- Reflex? A fuckin' reflex?
- Dig!
It won't happen again.
I'm sorry.
Look. Will,
we need your help
to sell this shit.
That's why we're here.
- Whoa. How did
you guys get this?
- It's a long story, man.
We need to know
if you're gonna help us.
Why? I mean, you guys
could set that type
of shit up easily.
Nah, nigga,
not like you. Okay?
I need to go ghost.
None of this shit
can point back to me.
The type of protection
I need for this shit
requires a hacker.
Anon shit.
You broke into
the fucking USC database.
Hey, hey. No, no, no. Okay?
Samo did that.
I don't know shit, all right?
Whatever, nigga.
Look, we don't know shit
about selling dope.
Nothing.
Nothing about the units,
the terminology, the pricing.
None of that shit.
I don't even know how much
this fucking bag is worth.
You do.
Okay.
But if this is
a Samo-type job,
man, I can't just
do this as a favor.
What do you want?
A percentage
of the profits?
Fuck that.
Pay me in Molly.
Cut up the shit.
You're gonna want to
measure it out...
so you can bag it up in grams,
sell it that way.
But, you know, what a lot
of the kids are liking nowadays
is the pill form.
So, where we
setting up shop?
Here.
Here?
Yeah. Here.
Are you fuckin'
retarded?
No. It's actually
genius, bro.
We have a science lab.
We want to enter
the Google Science Fair.
All we need you to do
is open up the science labs,
and we can do
everything else.
Don't lose that shit,
okay?
We have a computer lab
which nobody ever uses.
And all the supplies
laying around the band room
would be perfect for shipping.
And the best part--
watch.
Nobody's going to
suspect a thing. We're just
geeks doing what geeks do.
Right?
That's what I'm saying, bro.
You're into it, bro.
What's up?
Yo.
Hey, congratulations
on getting the store set up.
Now, uh, we gotta get you guys
some customers, right?
- Yeah.
- Check it out.
My house
is having a party.
We could use
a cool band.
Okay. Say we're, like--
What about if you're quoting,
like, rap lyrics?
Say we're all listening
to The Chronic, Doggystyle.
We're all rapping along.
Like, what are we
supposed to say?
I'm sorry.
That's bullshit, dude.
Yes.
-What about the artist's intent?
-Dude, that is exactly what
I'm talking about, man.
Dude,
I saw your bitch, Lily,
on YouTube.
Okay. Well, Lily is not
my bitch anymore, so--
Then can I get at her, dude?
'Cause I gotta find out
what she was on.
Nigga, I don't give a fuck.
All right?
Go for it, dude.
Hey, but for real,
she was using this.
Um-- Mike check.
One, two. One, two.
Um, hi.
I'm Malcolm Ad-Rock
on guitar.
We've got diggity
Diggy Dawson
on the drums,
and we've got
steel-faced bobblehead Jibby
right here on the bass.
Play something, Fresh Prince!
All right.
We are Awreeoh.
We're about to
turn it up, okay?
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
What the fuck?
Diggy, Diggy, Diggy!
Yo, fuck Molly, dawg!
It's all about that Lily, son!
How am I supposed
to eat my p-p-p--
pound cake?
Eat my pound cake.
My pound cake!
Is this Channel 10?
You're all out here, huh?
Hey, homey,
videotape this.
I want to tweet
this later, man.
Son of a bitch.
"Lily"?
I can't believe we're
really doing this right now.
No.
This shit better work,
Will.
Oh, shit.
Lily, dude,
that was unbelievable.
Principal Harris
tells me that there are
three young men...
who actually joined
the Google Science Fair.
Please.
Proof...
that the public school system
is still a ladder...
to success.
Half an ounce
for Joe Patterson.
We have an ounce
for John Smith.
We have an eighth
for Ashley Down.
- Susan Thompson.
- Steve Burke.
Yeah, this popped up
about a few weeks ago.
Look at what they're moving.
It's major volume too.
I don't know why
they're calling it "Lily."
Maybe, uh, 2 Chainz
called it that on a mixtape.
He's a rapper.
Yeah, you know,
"The Birthday Song."
"Big booty ho."
Okay, never mind.
Forget it.
Hi.
Um, is that offer
still on the table?
Help.
If you're busy,
I can come back
tomorrow or later.
No, um, no. They're--
They're about to leave.
Yeah.
Yeah, we were stepping.
Okay, cool. Thanks.
Bye. Bye, guys.
Have fun.
Thanks
for helping me.
No problem.
You're
a fast learner.
Aw.
Thanks.
Shit's been real crazy
since Dom got locked up.
A few of his boys
got smoked on the corner
the other day.
I don't want
to go back there.
Sorry. I just don't
have people I can talk to
about this stuff...
that understand,
you know?
I know.
Thanks.
Dom called from jail
the other day.
He asked about you.
That's why you showed up
all of a sudden.
What's that
supposed to mean?
It means
that Dom sent you here
as his messenger.
All this
crying on my shoulder?
Bullshit.
You're supposed
to put your feminine
wiles on me...
and find out
about the fucking dope.
Right?
Wait. I--
And here I was,
stupid enough to think
that you were different...
than these other niggas.
Nakia, Nakia, Nakia.
Fuck you!
"Feminine wiles"?
Good morning.
Today you're going
to take the SAT.
The SAT is your chance
to show how prepared you are
for college.
You will have 25 minutes
to work on section one.
Yo, what the fuck
was that?
What do you mean,
you don't know?
Drug search, dawg.
They do it randomly,
like, every month or so.
It's all for show.
I mean, it's not like
somebody is stupid enough...
to put some shit
in their locker.
Can I go to the bathroom?
Yes, but you will not
be given more time.
Man.
Come on, man.
What in the hell
are you doing?
Um, SAT's.
SAT's?
I had to use the restroom,
and I'm kind of late
getting back.
You know?
Thank you.
Good luck,
little man.
Bring that beat back!
One, two, three, four!
Here it is!
The set ain't over!
Come on, y'all.
Let's get busy.
Come on. Say "Yeah!"
Say "Hell yeah!"
- Ain't it funky?
-  I'm not doing this shit no more.
Bro, I can
fix this shit.
I can fix
this shit.
The bag is almost done.
The shit is almost gone.
I mean, I can't sell
this shit no more. We almost
just got fucking caught.
Look, I don't want
to go to jail. I want to
go to fucking college.
I want to get a good job.
I want to help my mom!
Dig?
That's cool.
It's my fault,
my weight to carry.
Yo, that's bullshit.
We all wanted
to go to Dom's party.
Especially you, Jib.
It's our weight
to carry too.
We've got your back
to the end, right?
Right?
Fuck.
Ooh.
- There it is.
- Gracias.
All right, so, when we get
the Bitcoins, then what?
I need cash.
Well, you would have to
do a currency exchange...
to get the US dollar equivalent,
but, I mean--
that kind of
defeats the purpose of
a non-fiat currency, right?
Okay, see,
I don't give a fuck about
all that Aaron Swartz...
Occupy Wall Street shit.
Okay, well, you'd have to
link your Bitcoin account
to a bank account,
and then there's
this infinitesimally
small chance...
that it could be traced.
I mean, the Feds
would have to know exactly
what they're looking for.
It's not something
they could just
stumble upon randomly.
Basically, I would just
have to make a stupid-ass
mistake for them to trace it.
And do I look like
the type of nigga that
makes stupid-ass mistakes?
Um--
So, you want me
to set up that exchange?
I'm-- I'm good.
I'll do it.
- Um--
- Huh?
What if I want
zero chances of trace?
Well...
if you want zero trace,
you gotta go
black market, homey.
Yeah, you got to put
the Bitcoins on a drive...
and make
a hand-to-hand exchange.
You get cash
minus the transaction fee.
If you really want
to go that route--
and I really don't suggest it--
I know a dude
in the garment district.
Ask for Fidel.
If you pass his test,
he'll help you.
If you don't--
Well, just pass his test.
One of these alligator bags
was made here.
One is from the store.
Which one is which?
The right one,
I mean, 'cause it's--
Mm-hmm.
poofier.
They both
look the same.
The reality is...
I sell 90% of my stuff
to white hos.
Most are rich enough
to afford retail.
Why do you think that is?
I don't know.
They know. They know
the only difference...
between
these two bags...
is the person
rocking them.
So, when they rock 'em,
people are gonna assume
it's real.
And the flip of that is...
it doesn't matter
if you had the receipt
from Barneys sewn into the bag.
People gonna assume
it's fake.
Only you know the truth.
So, what are you, man?
Are you a real?
Are you a fake?
That's what I need
to find out.
I'm just Malcolm.
"Just Malcolm"?
Who the fuck is Malcolm?
Show me.
I want you to hit me
as hard as you can.
Hey!
Don't look at them.
This is between you and me.
I'm-a give you five seconds.
You can either man up
or run out like
the little bitch you is.
- One!
- Malcolm, let's just go.
Listen to
your friends, boy.
Two!
You can't be serious.
I'm more than serious,
motherfucker.
Three!
I need that money.
You ain't gettin' shit.
Four!
Yeah, you see
your pussy friends leaving?
They're running
like some little bitches.
Run, pussy.
Five! Five! Five!
Hit me, man!
Five, motherfuck--
Oh, man. You--
Drive.
Where?
Give me the drive!
Shit.
Come here, man.
Now I know
who you are--
A man that
does not give a fuck.
Hey, blood!
Don't you owe me
another shoe, nigga?
Shit!
Get on the ground,
bitch-ass nigga.
- Get the fuck off me!
- Malcolm!
- Get off us! Malcolm!
- Stay the fuck down, nigga.
- Malcolm!
- Bitch nigga. Yeah.
Yeah!
- Jib, get the fucking bag.
- Come on!
Oh, shit.
Hold on, hold on.
Hey, hold on.
Give me the bag.
Please,
just give me the bag.
I don't even want
that shit, blood.
Let's go, nigga.
All right. Come on.
We out, we out, we out.
It's okay.
Come on.
Let's go.
That's 10%.
Consider it a proffer.
- The rest is
in a Bitcoin account.
- Bitcoin?
It's an untraceable
Internet currency.
There are Web sites
that sell a lot of things...
that people
would get in trouble
for selling.
They use Bitcoins.
Kind of like Amazon.
So you sold on the Internet?
No.
No. You did.
Excuse me?
You set up a store
on Black Market Reloaded.
Very successful.
I mean, you moved
your entire inventory.
See, the market's
been pretty volatile,
but as of right now,
you have $97,267 and 31 cents...
in your Bitcoin
exchange account.
10,000 in cash.
Now, as long as
your Bitcoins stay
in the exchange account,
they're safe, untraceable.
Now, if you were to exchange
the Bitcoins into dollars...
and transfer that money
into your Jacoby Check Cashing
corporate account,
there would be a
really, really small chance
of it getting traced...
by the DEA or FBI.
I mean, that would
only happen if you were
idiotically sloppy...
while setting up
the Bitcoin exchange account.
So you want me
to set up that exchange?
I'm good. I'll do it.
I mean, that-- I mean,
it would almost have to be...
intentional.
And why should I believe
any of this, Malcolm?
Is your Jacoby APS
shipping account number...
FX4578?
California regional
bank number 267856783?
Federal Tax ID 95--
Hey, you really should
just upgrade your firewall,
you know?
I actually know a guy.
He's kind of familiar
with your system already.
You're all out
of toilet paper, hon.
Courtside, okay? Courtside.
Gotta have it. No, come on.
Now, what if I report
to the authorities...
that my securities
have been breached...
and my identity
has been stolen?
As I've just learned,
it doesn't matter
if this bag is real or fake.
Because of where I come from,
everybody's going to
assume it's fake.
So, since you and I come
from the same place,
what is the DEA going
to assume about you?
And because you and I
are from the same place,
Malcolm,
you should know
what a person like me
can do to a person like you.
Yeah.
But that's not what
a Harvard man would do.
Nah, see, a man of Harvard
is smart enough to see...
that would set off
a chain of events...
that would
inevitably come back
and destroy him...
and everything he's built.
That would be a shame.
So, I think you should
take this opportunity
before you very seriously.
Do everything in your power
to ensure that I become
a man of Harvard...
and make sure nothing happens
to a hair on my gorgeous head.
Can you dig it?
Malcolm,
you forgot your bag.
It's fake.
Malcolm.
You're pretty damn arrogant.
You think you're gonna
get into Harvard?
Who do you think you are?
Let me tell you
about two students.
Student "A" is
a straight-A student who lives
in the suburbs of Los Angeles.
He plays in a punk band
with his best friends.
He loves to skateboard
and ride on his BMX bike.
His favorite TV show
is Game Of Thrones and his
favorite band is The Thermals.
He's a '90s hip-hop geek.
Student "B" goes
to an underfunded school...
where teachers who would
rather not be there...
teach kids
who really don't care.
He lives with a single mother,
doesn't know his father
and has sold dope.
Now close your eyes.
Picture each of these kids
and tell me what you see.
Be honest.
No one's going to judge you.
Now open your eyes.
So, am I student "A"
or student "B"?
Am I a geek or a menace?
For most of my life,
I've been caught in between
who I really am...
and how I'm perceived,
in between categories
and definition.
I don't fit in.
And I used to think that
that was a curse, but...
now I'm slowly
starting to see...
maybe it's a blessing.
See, when you
don't fit in,
you're forced to see the world
from many different angles
and points of view.
You gain knowledge,
life lessons from disparate
people and places.
And those lessons,
for better or worse,
have shaped me.
So, who am I?
Allow me to reintroduce myself.
My name is Malcolm Adekanbi.
I'm a straight-A student
with nearly perfect SAT scores.
I taught myself
how to play guitar
and read music.
I have stellar recommendations
and diverse extracurricular
activities.
I am a Google Science Fair
participant,
and in three weeks,
I helped make over $100,000
for an online business.
So, why do I want
to attend Harvard?
If I was white,
would you even have to
ask me that question?
Nice haircut.
I like it.
I'm-- I'm sorry...
for all the stuff
that I said.
There was a lot going on
at the time.
And... that wasn't me.
Yeah, it was.
You might have all
these other folks fooled,
but not me.
You're...
complicated.
Anyway, I just came by
to say thank you.
Thank you?
You-- You passed?
Mm-hmm.
You passed.
You were supposed to
go to prom with me.
No.
I told you I wasn't mad
about missing prom.
Hey.
I was mad about
missing Six Flags.
I'll pick you up
in the morning.