MAN: The following story
is based on actual events...
(ALARM RINGS)
(CHATTERS)
What's up?
Animal Planet.
Man, I just had the craziest dream.
- About what?
- I don't remember.
Yeah. Yeah.
Morning, guys.
Morning, Gene.
(GENE URINATES)
What did we do last night?
I don't know.
Wait. Didn't the twins have a party?
Yeah, that's it. Twins had a party.
- Right.
Were we there?
I'm assuming we were.
What kind of boyfriends
would we be if we weren't?
Did I get any messages?
Nope.
See you tomorrow, Gene.
GENE:
Shibby.
How do you know Gene?
Oh, I thought he was your friend.
No, no, I don't know him.
CHESTER:
I'm starving.
- It's pudding.
- I always wondered what a fridge...
...full of pudding would look like.
Is it possible that we got
so wasted last night...
...we bought a lifetime supply
of pudding and then forgot about it?
I'd say it's entirely possible.
(PHONE RINGS)
JESSE ON MACHINE: Jesse.
CHESTER: And Chester are shibby.
JESSE:Please leave your shibby
at the beep. Shibby.
WOMAN 1: What happened last night?
You show up...
... with a bunch of people, pizzas
and a keg. Our house is trashed.
WOMAN 2: You're sucky boyfriends.
Always disappointing us.
WOMAN 1: Now you're probably
on the couch in your underwear.
WOMAN 2:
Playing thumb wars.
Wearing those Army helmets.
WOMAN 1: And if you are, you've
probably forgotten our anniversary.
BOTH:
Which is today.
WOMAN 2: You don 't get the special
treats we had for you.
Just wanted to thank you guys
for trashing our house.
BOTH:
Bye!
Twins sound pissed.
- Good thing we already got them gifts.
- Yeah.
So where are the gifts?
- They must be in your car.
- They're in the car.
So we'll just take the gifts
to the twins' house...
...get our special treats.
Hey, what do you think they mean
by special treats?
We've been going out with them
for a year now.
And we still haven't had sex.
"Special treats" is code for sex.
Of course.
- Special treats!
- Sex.
MAN:
Open up, you slackers!
Mr. Pizzacoli!
You left work last night...
...with 30 pizzas
that didn't get delivered!
I want some answers!
Open up this damn door!
It's open.
JESSE: Moron!
CHESTER: What? I'm sorry.
(KNOCKING)
Hey.
Mr. Pizzacoli.
- Hi, how you doing?
- 30 pizzas didn't get delivered!
If I found out you was taking
my pizza home to eat yourselves...
...I will crush you like a doodlebug!
- Look, it's an elephant!
- What?
(CAT SCREECHES)
- Guess it was just a mailman.
- You two are the most irresponsible...
...and disappointing employees
ever to work...
...at Mr. Pizzacoli's
Pronto Pizza Delivery!
A trained dolphin could do
a better job than you!
Well, sure, but then the pizzas
would get all wet.
Look, a unicorn!
(GLASS BREAKS)
A unicorn?
Sorry, I guess it was just
a regular horse. Weird!
You've been embezzling my pizza.
And I will catch you eventually.
And when I do, I swear to God,
you will never deliver pizzas...
...in this town again!
- Close one.
- Yeah.
We'll go to the twins' house.
We'll give them their gifts
and apologize for trashing the house.
And then we get our special treats.
Dude, where's my car?
Where's your car, dude?
JESSE:
Dude, where's my car?
CHESTER:
Where's your car, dude?
Dude, where's my car?
- Did I drive last night?
- Yeah, I think so.
- Really?
- I'm not sure.
- Dude, where's your car?
- Dude, it's not funny. It's gone.
- Yeah.
- Dude, where's my car?
Shut up, dude!
Okay. Okay, look.
You're right.
What we need to do is...
...get into the state of mind
we were in last night.
That way, we can retrace our steps.
- Yeah.
- Sense Memory Simulated Perception...
...AItered Consciousness
Memory Retrieval.
Discovery Channel.
Nice.
- Nelson's?
- Shibby.
- I'm sick of walking, dude.
- Me too.
Hey, it's Mrs. Crabbleman.
She'll give us a ride.
Hey, Mrs. Crabbleman!
Hey! Hey!
Mrs. Crabbleman.
Fucking stoners.
She must not have recognized you.
- It's the Binglemans.
- Oh, hey.
Mr. Bingleman!
Hey, Mr. Bingleman.
- Maybe we should just walk.
- Yeah.
JESSE:
Listen, Nelson, the car is gone...
...and we need to do
this sense memory thing...
...so we can get back in the state
of mind we were in last night.
Deep in your consciousness,
you must look.
Concentrate on the knowledge inside,
you must.
Aha!
Your eyes, you must close.
And you take it to the mo.
Mo...
Whoops.
(NELSON CHANTS)
Concentrating, you're not.
Sorry.
- Is your dog dead?
- He's not dead.
Come here, Jackal. Come here, boy.
- I don't think he's coming.
- Maybe he's deaf.
Deaf, he is not, dude.
Come here, Jackal.
- Come here, Jackal.
- Does he know any other tricks...
...besides not moving?
All right, you want
to see a trick, man?
Hey, Jackal.
Bite down, killer.
Here comes the fun. All right.
Good boy, Jackal.
Good boy.
Breathe deep. There you go.
- Dude, your dog's a stoner.
- Can he also bong a beer?
Nah, pretty much all he does is...
...lie around and smoke his pipe.
CHESTER:
Jackal, can I see your pipe?
Oh, no, don't!
Very protective, he is of his pipe.
When other people touch it,
he does not like.
Sorry, Jackal.
NELSON:
Yeah, see? He's sorry.
Holy crap.
- That's one psycho dog, dude.
- You know what we should do now?
- Eat?
- No. Eat.
Choice excellent, my friend.
I'll get the keys.
JESSE:
Hey, Nelson. Let me order.
WOMAN:
"Chinese Foooood." May I help you?
- I'd like to place an order.
- What you like?
Yeah, I'd like three orders
of garlic chicken.
- And then?
- And then three orders of white rice.
- And then...
- Hey, you guys want soup?
- Sure.
- Yeah. Three orders of won ton soup.
- And then?
- Oh, some fortune cookies too.
That's about it.
And then?
No, that's it.
- And then?
- No "and then."
L... That's all I want.
And then?
And then... And then nothing else,
because I'm done ordering. Okay?
And then?
See, all I want is the three orders
of the garlic chicken...
...and the white rice.
And then?
- And the soup, dude.
- Oh, and the won ton soup.
- And then?
- And the cookies, fortune.
And the fortune cookies.
So it's just the chicken, the rice...
...the soup and the fortune cookies,
and that's it.
And then?
And then you can put it
in a brown paper bag...
...and put it in my hand,
because I'm ready to eat.
And then?
I refuse to play
your Chinese food mind games.
- And then?
- No! No "and then"!
- No "and then"!
- And then?
- No! No "and then"!
- You're starting to piss me off, lady.
- And then?
- And then...
...I'm gonna come in there
and put my foot in your ass...
...if you say "and then" again!
And then and then
and then and then and then...
And then?
Come on, Nelson,
just help us find my car.
You didn't have to go all "egg roll"
on that speaker box.
I'm not the one that called
the Dalai Lama a fag.
- I was just kidding around.
- Well, Nelson didn't appreciate it.
Look, it's Christie Boner.
Wow! The hottest of the hot.
El fuego of all that is el fuego.
- Did she just wave at us?
- No way. She would never wave at us.
Then why did she just wave at us?
I don't know. Maybe she thinks
we're other people.
People she waves to.
Hi, Chester.
Hi.
Hi, Jesse. I had a really
good time with you last night.
- Me too.
- That was some crazy party.
- Hey, have you seen my car?
- Well, I saw it last night.
I mean, I saw the back seat.
- I mean the whole thing.
- Get another one with all the money...
...you were throwing around.
- Money?
Yeah. You had that really nice
suitcase full of money.
- A suitcase full of money?
- Don't you remember giving me $500...
...to show you my hoo-hoos?
- $500?
- Hoo-hoos?
You mean, you don't remember anything?
How about now?
No.
I'm a little bit fuzzy too.
Maybe if I could get
a little refresher course.
- All right.
- Go.
- Are these losers bothering you?
- No, Tommy.
Guys like you could never score
with a chick like this.
- Stick to your own kind.
- Don't be such a jerk.
Next time you guys
bother my girlfriend...
...stoner-bashing time.
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
- Okay.
- Consider this your warning.
Later, dudes!
CHESTER: Dude, you touched
Christie Boner's hoo-hoo.
Shibby!
Low-five.
CHESTER: Yeah.
JESSE: Let's get out of here.
Chester!
Dude, that Christie Boner
is super hot.
Where did we get a suitcase
full of money?
Why don't we have it now?
Maybe we deposited it
in a Swiss bank account.
Now, if we had a ridiculous
sum of money, where would we go?
Dude.
Sweet!
No way we were here last night.
We'd never fit in
at a place like this.
Look everyone!
It's Mr. Jesse and Mr. Chester!
Look at the toggles on that kitten.
Good afternoon, Jesse, Chester.
How are we feeling today?
A little fuzzy.
Hi, Chester. Hi, Jesse.
Did you guys enjoy
yourselves last night?
- Have we met?
- It's me, Tania.
Remember last night
when I gave you...
...that super-special,
slippery-wet lapdance?
Of course. How can I forget?
You want to do it again?
This time, it's on me.
If you say so.
Didn't I get a special lapdance?
Did you ever.
Sweet!
So...
...just how super-special
can a slippery lapdance be?
What the hell were you thinking,
throwing around my money like that?
- You're a...
- I'm a gender-challenged male.
What does that mean?
Oh, dude, you're a dude! That's...
You...
Last night, I had you sneak a suitcase
of stolen money out of here.
- Stolen money?
- $200,000.
$200,000!
I gave you the case and left.
We were supposed to meet.
But you never showed up!
Where's that suitcase?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- Where's that suitcase?
- It's in my car.
Then get it. Fast.
Or else you'll be singing soprano.
Dude. Dude, dude!
- We gotta go.
- Are you crazy?
I'm with breakdancing strippers.
Seriously, dude, this is an emergency.
So is this, dude.
It's a breakdancing
stripper emergency.
- Goodbye!
WOMEN: Bye, Chester!
I love you!
We were supposed to meet her with
the suitcase, but we didn't show up.
Sounds like us.
How wasted were we last night?
I touched Christie's hoo-hoo,
we're on the hook for $200,000...
...that belongs to a transsexual
stripper, and my car's gone.
- I'd say we were pretty wasted.
- We really need to find your car.
Okay, let's see. The last place
we remember being last night was...
The twins'. But we can't show up
without the anniversary gifts.
I got it! We'll get them
a little something for now.
When we find the car, we'll give them
the real gifts. That's a dollar...
...thirty-nine.
- I don't know.
- Trust me.
- It'll be totally cool. Let's go.
- Okay.
We are so dead.
I roger that.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
WANDA: We've been cleaning all day.
WILMA: What do you guys have to say?
Happy anniversary.
We ate the dark ones.
We know you guys don't like those.
Dark ones are the only ones
we do like.
Oh, yeah.
But you could use the box to keep...
You keep...
...ribbons.
- You guys forgot our anniversary.
JESSE: No, of course not.
No, we got you guys great gifts.
We just had some car trouble.
We came over here
as soon as we could...
...to help you guys clean up but...
Oh, no.
It looks like you're already done.
All we have to do is
take out the trash.
Guess they haven't been outside yet.
You know what?
We'll take out the trash.
You guys go and take a nice hot bath.
Yeah. You deserve it
after all this hard work.
Pamper yourselves.
Just don't make a mess.
Slow and steady, good buddy.
10-4.
- You're tilting.
- Sorry.
- Why are you tilting?
- You gave me the heavy end.
- Let it go, man.
- No, we can get it.
No. Let it go.
We're not leaving it behind.
Okay.
- I'll take my shoe off.
- Okay.
Watch it. Stop pushing!
Watch it! Careful. Careful.
- Are we cool? Are we cool?
- We're still cool.
Now, take your shoe off,
and you get it.
- Okay.
- Get it. That's it, that's it.
I got it!
Oh, my God!
You can't do anything right.
Why do you have to mess everything up?
- I got three words: Anger management.
- Yeah!
Dude, we really need
to find your car.
JESSE: Hey!
CHESTER: Ow!
Sorry about yanking you
off the street like that.
- We really need to talk to you.
- Who are you guys?
My name is Zarnoff. This is Zabu,
Zellner, Zilbor, Zelmina...
...and Jeff.
- Hey.
More specifically, we are
the recipients of instructions...
...from extraterrestrials regarding
the interstellar path to outer space.
JEFF:
Go ahead and laugh.
We are used to being mocked.
Okay.
We have been sent
by our wise and powerful leader...
...Zoltan...
...to find you and recover
the continuum transfunctioner.
Hey, have you guys
ever been to Uranus?
It's supposed to be
nice this time of year.
This is important. We intercepted
an interstellar message...
...that leads us to believe
that last night...
...you were in possession
of the continuum transfunctioner.
Where is it now?
- The who what?
- The continuum transfunctioner...
...is a very mysterious
and powerful device.
- And?
- And its mystery...
...is exceeded only by its power.
Sorry, we don't remember
a thing about last night.
You must be careful.
Danger follows the continuum
transfunctioner. So says...
- Zoltan.
I'll tell you what.
We'll keep our eyes out for the
continual trans-ding-a-ling thing...
...and if we see it,
we'll give you a call.
Yes. You must.
But remember,
you are in great danger.
Trust no one.
Except for us.
Thank you, Jeff. Good point.
Trust no one, except for us.
Zoltan.
Wait a second. Let's recap.
Last night, we lost my car...
...we accepted stolen money
from a transsexual stripper...
...and now some space nerds want us
to find something we can't pronounce.
Maybe we should cut back
on the shibbying.
- Thanks, dude.
MAN: Oh, good!
You're right on time.
You pick up special suits.
Mr. Lee, tailor, make special
suits for you. Come on.
- Dude, you got a tattoo!
- What?
- So did you, dude.
- Naw.
- Dude, what does my tattoo say?
- "Sweet"!
- What about mine?
- "Dude." What does mine say?
"Sweet."
- What about mine?
- "Dude."
- What does mine say?
- "Sweet"!
- What about mine?
- "Dude." And mine?
"Sweet." What about mine?
"Dude." What does mine say?
"Sweet"! What about mine?
"Dude"! What does mine say?
"Sweet"!
Idiots!
(SPEAKS IN CHINESE)
Your tattoo says "dude,"
your tattoo says "sweet."
Got it?
Sorry.
- Hey.
- Sorry.
- Shibby.
- Very sharp, very sharp.
You two number one, extra-special
good-Iooking guys.
- We got these last night?
- You were pretty...
- How much are these?
- You already pay for.
I just do some minor alterations.
Add the secret pockets you order.
Maybe we got
the continual trans-sphincter.
What's...?
Oh, dude!
Dude!
Sweet!
(BIRD SMACKS WINDOW)
Cool!
- How did we pay for these suits?
- Oh, you pay cash.
Cold hard cash,
crispy new hundred-dollar bills.
Hey, did you see
what car we were driving?
Me? No, I don't see no car.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
Dude, we bought cell phones.
That's not all we bought, dude.
(YOUNG MC'S "BUST A MOVE" PLAYS)
Shibby!
(REVS ENGINE)
Man, I cannot believe
we leased a car last night. God!
- But who's Johnny Potsmoker?
- That's my alter ego.
I thought that was my alter ego.
No, that's my alter ego.
- Your alter ego is Smokey McPot.
- Oh, yeah.
You're never gonna figure that out.
(WATCH BEEPS)
Okay, dude.
There it is. Break time's over.
Time to find my car.
This is impossible.
CHICK 1:
Are you Jesse and Chester?
Huh?
I don't know. Why?
If you are Jesse and Chester...
...perhaps we will give you
erotic pleasure.
- That's us.
- Right here.
We are looking
for the continuum transfunctioner.
- Who are you guys?
- We are not guys. We are hot chicks.
She's totally right.
CHICK 2:
The continuum transfunctioner...
...is a very mysterious
and powerful device.
- And?
- And its mystery...
...is only exceeded by its power.
That doesn't really help.
We will give you pleasure now, if you
give us the continuum transfunctioner.
Let me get your proposition straight.
First you give us...
...the pleasure, then we give
you the continuum transfunctioner?
No. First you give us
the continuum transfunctioner...
...then we give you the pleasure.
I've heard that one before.
Okay, look. How about this?
You give me pleasure...
...then we'll give you
the continuum transfunctioner.
- Lf there's time, you do him.
- Dude...
- Deal.
- Sweet!
- Wait a second.
- Thank you.
Come here. Those space nerds
told us not to trust anybody.
Yeah, but for the love of God,
they're offering us oral pleasure!
What...?
- Okay.
Hey. Where did the hot chicks go?
Where's my money, boys?
We were just going to get it.
You picked the wrong
transsexual stripper to screw with.
CHESTER:
You're pinching me.
Well, let's see what the cops
have to say about this.
- You're busted.
- Busted.
- B-U-S-T, busted.
- This one.
- These guys.
- Chester! I saw this on COPS!
- Kick hard and hit back!
- Bye-bye, boys.
CHESTER:
Put on the siren.
You're sticking to the
"I don't remember" crap.
Yeah. We don't remember.
Last night, your car
was spotted leaving...
...the scene of a major drug deal.
- You found my car.
You guys got more important things
to worry about right now.
Where were you between
midnight and 2 a.m. Last night?
I told you, okay?
We don't remember anything.
I see we're gonna have to do
this the hard way.
Where were you last night between
the hours of midnight and 2 a.m.?
We don't know.
What the...?
- Now do you remember?
- No.
- How about now?
Hey, leave him alone!
He doesn't know anything!
- Now are you ready to talk?
- Dude, we don't remember!
Okay, here are the whips
you guys wanted.
Hey, it's the donut guys.
These two were at
the Donut House last night.
We started talking and they bought
donuts for the whole precinct.
What time did all this happen?
Let's see. Must've been
between midnight and 2 a.m.
Damn!
You can't be the guys
we're looking for. Sorry.
Hang in there, bro.
- Come on, Kojak.
- All right.
I'm really sorry about all this.
Looks like it was a case
of mistaken identity.
Actually, those are
the real criminals over there.
One of our officers...
...made a wrong identification.
- Yeah, that was me.
I'm sorry about that, fellas.
Rick will tell you exactly
where your car is.
- We found the car.
We found the car!
- Yeah, we found the car.
- Found my car.
Now we get the gifts, go to the twins'
house, and get our special treats.
Sweet!
Give us the keys
and we're out of here.
You got it.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
What's the problem, Rick?
Nothing, I just... Boy.
Okay. Jeez.
Did you say you wanted your car back,
or you wanted it impounded?
We want the car back, please.
Oh, I see. That's kind of funny,
because what happened was...
...I accidentally sent your car
to the impound.
- Rick.
RICK: I know.
I can definitely tell you this.
You guys...
...can get the car back in a few days.
We don't have a few days, Rick.
We need the car back now.
Say, how about a treat?
There's Bavarian cream.
- Yeah.
- That's a good one there.
- It's good.
- It's great. I have a lot of them.
- You know what? Forget about it.
- Okay.
- Psych!
- Oh, jeez. You got me.
Hey, fellows, who's the goose? Me.
You're such a joker.
PIZZACOLl:
One.
- Damn!
CHICK 1: Where are Jesse and Chester?
- What?
- We're looking for Jesse and Chester.
I don't know where they are...
...but I bet those punks
over there do.
So then, remember?
I said, "Later, dudes."
- Why were you with those jerks anyway?
- They were just being nice...
...unlike someone I know.
Maybe it's time I find someone
with a sensitive side.
Someone who respects me as a person.
Maybe somebody like Jesse or Chester.
Okay, listen up.
We're gonna find Jesse and Chester.
And when we do, stoner-bashing time!
CHICK 1: Do you know Jesse and Chester?
- Who are you?
- We are hot chicks.
- Yes, you are.
We believe they have
the continuum transfunctioner.
However, if you recover the continuum
transfunctioner from them...
...and bring it to us,
we will give you erotic pleasure.
You've got yourselves a deal.
Okay, guys. Okay, guys, new plan.
First, we find those stoners,
get the continuum transfunctioner...
...then, it's jerk-bashing time.
- Yeah!
Oh, yeah.
I just remembered where
you might be able to find them.
TOMMY:
Send those chicks to meet the twins.
That'll put those dudes
in some hot water.
(BEEPING)
Try it again. Okay?
Just knock it out of the park.
All right, give it a shot.
Okay, you almost got it.
Now just concentrate on the beep,
swing as hard as you can...
...and keep your ear on the ball.
Okay?
All right, little buddy,
you can do it!
(PAGER BEEPS)
I did it! I did it!
I hit it! I did it!
CHICK 1: Do you know Jesse and Chester?
- Pardon me?
- We're looking for Jesse and Chester.
- Who are you?
We're extremely hot chicks
with big breasts.
Really?
Can I touch your face?
It's the only way I can see...
...who I'm talking to.
- Okay.
Wow! You are hot.
Is this normal?
Oh, yeah. This is how
blind people shake hands.
- Sammy, you're up next.
- Okay...
- Come on.
- What the...? Sis!
Excuse me, a little help.
Wanda. Wilma.
- Anthony?
- Anthony, what is going on?
Nothing. I was just reading.
Bye, ladies, I need to be alone now.
- We're looking for Jesse and Chester.
- Who are you guys?
We are not guys. We are hot chicks.
We're supposed to meet them later,
but we can't wait.
- We don't know where they are.
- And frankly, we don't care.
JESSE: Dude, let's call Nelson.
CHESTER: Yeah. See if he's home.
(PHONE RINGS)
- Hello?
- Hey, Nelson, it's Chester.
Hey, Chester! No, it's me, Tommy.
Your buddy Nelson is busy
at the moment.
This is bad karma, boys.
Hey, tell me where
that continuum transfunctioner is.
No hablo English.
Your friend's dead meat unless
I get that continuum transfunctioner.
NELSON:
Jackal! Get your pipe!
- My balls!
- What was that?
Tommy's gotten to Nelson! He knows
about the continuum transfunctioner.
Those double-crossing
sexy, sexy sluts!
I am so sick of hearing about
this continuum transfunctioner thing.
- Lf one more person asks...
- You got the continuum transfunctioner?
Who are you guys?
We are the keepers
of the continuum transfunctioner.
It is all that stands between
the universe and destruction.
It is a mysterious
and powerful device.
And its mystery
is only exceeded by its power.
- We know.
- We don't have it.
But the universe?
Screw the universe.
Screw the universe?
WOMAN: Chimpanzees often use sticks
as crude tools.
JESSE:
That is one smart primate.
(KNOCKING)
- Hey.
JESSE:
What are you doing here?
We just wanted to see
how that car trouble thing was going.
Oh, the car. It's in the shop.
WILMA:
Really?
The shop run by beautiful women
in black jumpsuits?
The ones you were
hanging with earlier?
- Well, you see, Jesse thought...
WANDA: Today's our anniversary.
- Not only do you not have gifts.
WILMA: But you guys ditch us...
...for some big-breasted bimbos...
...while we're cleaning our house...
WILMA: Which you trashed.
Twice.
- You're sucky boyfriends.
- But...
We just wanted to come
and tell you in person that it's over.
- Wilma?
- Thank you, Wanda.
- They're totally right.
- Yeah.
We are sucky boyfriends.
Do you even remember
what kind of gifts we got them?
- I bet we got them sucky gifts.
- Yeah.
We suck.
Wait, I just got a really bad feeling
in the pit of my stomach.
You should go sit on the toilet.
No, no.
You know what the feeling is?
It's love.
- Is that what that is?
- Yeah.
I'm in love with Wanda.
And you're in love with Wilma.
But see, now that we know...
...that we've been sucky boyfriends,
we can change.
- We can?
- Yeah. And you know what else?
I'll bet you that we did buy them
super-cool anniversary gifts.
You know why? Because we love them.
Are they wrapped in cool paper?
Yeah. I'll tell you what we'll do.
We'll go to the impound lot, get
the car, which has the gifts in it...
...and then go to the twins' house,
and beg for them to take us back!
Yeah! Let's do it.
No, hold on. I gotta take a crap.
- Told you.
- I know.
I know your body.
Boys, I got some good news.
We just got your car in this morning.
All right!
But the bad news is...
...not only did Officer Boyer
send your car to the impound...
...he tagged it for auction
and it was sold this afternoon.
Rick.
- Do you know who bought the car?
- I have the address right here.
All right.
But it'd be against Regulation...
...457XY2-665 to give it to you.
Come on. Just...
Reaching onto this side
of the counter isn't allowed.
The last guy who tried it ended up
with three broken fingers.
- Reach it.
- You can reach it!
No, I got...
One of these has carpal tunnel.
What if I further injure myself?
I have to do everything.
I'm a better lookout.
My vision's better. You know that.
That's it, that's it.
- Got it!
- We're good, we're good.
- What are you doing?
- Dude, I'm stuck!
- Come on. I'm stuck.
- You seriously stuck?
Don't!
Dude, here she comes! Help!
Get it!
Hold on, hold on. I gotta get...
Okay, okay.
- I got it, I got it.
- Help me!
We'll spit on it.
You know, lubrication.
- That's gross, dude!
- Okay, fine.