25 fps
Hand-titled by Andante
andante1983@yahoo.com
How do you do?
It's my very pleasant duty
to welcome you here...
...on behalf of Walt Disney, Leopold Stokowski
and all the other artists...
...and musicians whose combined talents
went into the creation of this new form of entertainment...
..."Fantasia"
What you are going to see, are the designs
and pictures and stories...
...that music inspired in the minds
and imaginations of a group of artists.
In other words they're not going to be
the interpretations of trained musicians.
Which I think is all to the good.
So now we present the "Toccata and Fugue
in D minor" by Johann Sebastian Bach...
...interpreted in pictures
by Walt Disney and his associates...
...and the music by the Philadelphia Orchestra
and its conductor Leopold Stokowski.
You know it's funny how wrong
an artist can be about his own work.
Now, the one composition of Tchaikovsky's
that he really detested was his Nutcracker suite.
Which is probably the most popular
thing he ever wrote.
Incidentally, you won't see
any nutcracker on the screen.
There is nothing like to him
but the title.
And now we are going to hear
a piece of music that tells a very definite story.
It's a very old story,
one that goes back almost 2000 years.
A legend about a sorcerer
who had an apprentice.
He was a bright young lad,
very anxious to learn the business.
As a matter of fact,
he was a little bit too bright...
...because he started practising
some of the boss's best magic tricks...
...before learning how to control them.
Mister Stokowski, Mister Stokowski...
My congratulations, sir.
- Congratulations to you, Mickey.
- Gee, thanks.
Well, so long!
I'll be seeing you.
Good-bye.