Alright girls now, not one word about your dad´s surprise party tonight, okay?!
That means you, Steph.
What makes you think I'm gonna tell him.
Because you blew dad's surprise party last year.
I was only four. Give me a break!
Steph, this is an important birthday. Your dad turns the big three- 0
How much more than five is the big three- 0?
Well, here I´ll show you.
This is you
And this is your daddy.
Wow, he´s almost the whole box.
Make way, it´s a good year birthday glimpse.
I had to take a couple balloons off or else she would have been picked up by radar.
All right, your daddy is on the way down.
Stephanie, I heard about last year. Do not spoil the surprise party.
Man, one little mistake.
Good morning everyone!
Happy birthday!
Okay, it´s been said.
Now we can just move on and forget the fact that
I´m… I´m…
Thirty!
Thank you! Okay, anyway I don´t turn … turn…
Thank you! I don´t turn, what you just said, until 8.15.
Dad, it´s 8.20.
O, my God!
This is a present from Michelle, Steph and me.
Look at this, DJ, Stephanie and Michelle´s coupon- book.
This is great! And you made it yourselves. I love this!
DJ and Stephanie will change Michelle´s diaper.
I´ll hold on to this.
Sorry Jesse they are not transferable.
And a free car wash for my car "Bullet".
Do you realize I bought that car 10 years ago on my twentieth birthday.
You know, every time I get behind the wheel I put the top down and start blasting myself
with improvement tapes, I feel like a kid again.
Boy, you were born to raise heck.
Dad, that must be another birthday surprise.
Look at them run. Did I ever run like that?
You bet, you always ran like a girl.
Come on grandpa, I help you cross the living room floor.
You know, you shouldn´t be so cocky, just because you are 24 and I´m… I´m…
Thirty!
All right, girls tell our lucky contestant what´s behind door number one. Phana! Carol Marol!
I won a man?!
Not just any man. Jimmy, tell him what he has won!
Okay Bob! Danny Tanner, you´ll be riding in style because you have won your very own chauffeur- driver limousine for a day.
Yes, it´s a stretched limousine complete with a bar, TV, telephone and a year supply of calendars. One!
You guys have gone all out. This is terrific. But I wish you hadn´t gone to such a big expense.
We didn´t. I´m gonna fumigate his house for free. I can´t say it enough, God bless silverfish.
Hey girls, do you want to ride to school in a limo?
I´d love to ride in a limo. But can it take us somewhere else besides school?
Let´s hit the mal!
All right, Steph!
You´re going to school. Let´s go! Let's go
Thanks for a terrific birthday.
Okay, I want one thing. I want you to remember I do not want a party.
This will be our little secret.
I mean it, no party.
Fine!
Back to the party.
Well, Bob I think we´ll make up the decorations in to…
No, no, no, don´t with the voice.
Okay, food arrives at five. Belly- dancer arrives at 5.30.
Belly- dancer leaves at 6.
Guests arrive at 6.30.
Limo- drive standing here at home at 7.
What about his present?
All right, the present. I´m leaving work early. I´m gonna take "Bullet". Get him fitted for seat covers. He is gonna love it. Come on!
Boy, he really loves this car.
Hey, who wouldn´t? I mean we´re talking about a car that goes from 0 to 60 in two weeks.
Now Steph, do it just the way I told you.
D.J. I´m old enough to carry a tray of apesisers… alebisers…cheese- sticks!
Excuse me, do you care about cheese?
Thank you, Stephanie!
Steph, it´s do you care FOR cheese?
She took one, didn´t she?
All right, good night! Thanks for dragging it home.
Sure pal, good luck!
Poor "Bullet".
Maybe Danny won´t notice.
Boy, am I in trouble. Joey!
Jesse, what´s wrong? I have never seen your face this shade of green before. This must be serious.
It is.
Uncle Jesse, is something wrong? I´m getting these vibes.
Yes, something is very wrong.
I knew it. This is great.
I´m sorry, but I´m developing woman´s intuition. It´s a big step in my life.
Listen, your father´s car has been in a little accident.
How little?
Big little. Follow me! You guys can take a look.
You´re dead meat!
This is going to take all the fun out of those seat covers.
What are you going to do?
I´m gonna do what I have to do. I´m gonna tell him the truth.
When we´re in trouble we give dad "we´re the cutest little girls in the world look".
That may work for you girls, but I don´t have those cute little dimples.
Maybe if you put a pretty little bow in your hair or something.
Not funny.
Danny´s coming up the steps! Come on!
What do we do?
Okay, here´s the plan: First we hide the seat covers.
All right, hide the seat covers.
Now what?
It´s tough enough for Danny turning 30. It´s his birthday and you got to promise you are not going to ruin it for him.
Okay, I promise.
Then we have to make sure he has the best time he has ever had in his entire life.
Good, we do that.
Then in the after glow, you´ll set him down and gently rip his hear out.
Can´t you come up with a happier ending.
Yeah, the car- ferry shows up and makes everything wonderful.
Sssch! Quiet everyone!
Let´s see, 15 of my friends´ cars parked right out front, I wonder…
I don't believe this!
Thank you, thank you! This is great! I love this! Everybody is here. This is so nice.
All my friends from the station are here. Are we running a test pattern tonight?
Cousin Ed! O, cousin Ed!
Caroline, why aren´t you out running your fishing- boat?
O, what?! And miss your nineteenth birthday party.
I´m so glad you are here.
Daddy, would you care for some cheese?
O, yes Stehpanie, thank you!
This is too easy, I´m ready for dip.
There you are you birthday- nuts. I thought I told you no party.
You say that every year.
This is the last surprise, isn´t it?
Danny, I just want you to know that Jesse deserves the all the credit. This whole party was his idea, because he loves you.
Always remember that.
Jesse, I know you hate when I hug you…
Hey, I have an idea: It´s your birthday, what the heck, why don´t I hug you this time,
Brother in law!
Say cheese!
Cheese!
We´ll call this the "before picture!
Now Danny, if you don´t like it there´s no way I can return it, so you better like it.
Caroline, this is great.
The last time Danny went fishing on my boat he didn´t catch a thing, so I minored his bate.
Hey, I´m just out there for the fresh air.
Daddy, I found another present.
You never saw me!