[Rain Falling]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
Don't just stand there.
Give me a hand with the canopy.
- Mary?. Merriman?. Are you ready?.
- Mary?
[Mary]
yes, Mr. Burkett.
Everything's ready, milady.
[Thunder Continues ]
[ Car Door Closes ]
- I think she's knocking.
- well, see what she wants.
I can't open
this wretched thing.
I suppose we better stop.
I can't get
this top off.
Hello.
Is everything all right?.
Are-Areyou okay?.
- Am I what?.
- we're all right, thankyou.
Is that LadyTrentham?.
LadyTrentham.
It's, uh--
I'm william McCordle's cousin, Ivor.
Ivor Novello.
yes, of course.
May I introduce
a friend ofmine from California?
- Mr. Morris weissman.
- Hello.
Hi.
Uh, we werejust wondering if
we were headed in the same direction.
I dare say we might be.
well, if-if everything
seems to be all right--
Bye.
Could we get on
before I freeze to death?.
- was that really Ivor Novello?.
- yes. Could we get on?.
[ weissman ]
Oh, hello. Nice house. I like it.
- [Man ] Hello, Ivor.
- welcome back, your Ladyship.
Constance, welcome.
Hello, dear. Ifhe has to call me
by my Christian name,
why can't he make it
""Aunt Constance"?.
- I'm not the upstairs maid.
- [ whispering, Indistinct ]
He's still got that vile
little dog, I see.
yes, the ones we hate last forever.
Did you have a horrid journey?.
yes, fairly horrid.
Take the car around the back
to unload it.
you better follow him.
Mrs. wilson will look afteryou.
your Ladyship.
- your Lordship.
- Mm-hmm.
- Louisa.
- william.
- Raymond. Lots of good shooting coming.
That's what
we're here for.
Just leave everything in one pile
around the corner there.
Make sure it's properly labeled.
It'll go up in the luggage lift.
These are the guns.
where's the gun room?
Down there on the right.
Find Mr. strutt, the keeper.
He'll show you what to do.
- I know what to do.
- [woman ] Ellen, what doyou
thinkyou're doing over there?
Take that rain offthose cases
before you take them up.
[ woman #2 ]
Those are Mr. Novello's bags.
- who are you?.
- I 'm Mr. weissman's man.
- The Countess ofTrentham.
- yes.
Make sure they're properly labeled.
Put them down there.
- where am I ?.
- you're in the stable block
with the grooms.
Her Ladyship is in the Chinese room.
Elsie!. Elsie!.
you'll be sharing
with the headhousemaid.
She'll showyou where everything is.
Elsie,
this is Miss Trentham.
- Mrs. wilson-- Excuse me, ma'am--
- Take care of her, will you?.
My name's Mary.
Mary Maceachran.
Not here it's not.
It's Trentham.
Lord stockbridge.
Guns.
- Down there on the right.
- The name's Parks. Robert Parks.
Mr. Parks?.
Mr. Parks, below stairs
you'll be known as Mr. stockbridge.
- There's three more outside.
- I knew a Mr. Parks
who was in service in Norwich.
Is he any relation
ofyours?.
No.
London born and bred.
what should I do
with Her Ladyship's jewels?.
It's this way.
George is in charge ofthe safe.
He's the first footman, and you
wanna watch where he puts his hands.
[Bell Dinging]
she's new.
[Elsie ]
Haveyou got the ones for tonight?
Oh, sorry.
Always bring a separate box
for the first night. It saves bother.
[ Closes Case ]
- [ Chattering, Indistinct ]
- Freddie, do wait.
For goodness sakes, Mabel.
what is it this time?.
- Does my hair look all right?.
- It looks fine.
where the hell were you?.
we're not late.
Freddie, do please stop going on.
Isobel?.
- Hello.
- Hello, Isobel.
Darling, I'll seeyou in there.
There's been something
I've been meaning to say toyou.
- Haveyou, uh--
Haveyou spoken toyour father?.
- No.
what doyou mean, no?.
Hey, you promised.
I never promised.
I said I'd do my best.
- you're so beautiful
when you resist me.
- stop it.
I'll ask him tonight.
- well, you bloodywell better.
- [Footsteps ]
- you shouldn't sneak up
on people like that.
- Don't worry. It's nobody.
sorry, Miss Isobel.
Doyou really thinkyou'll have
a chance to speak to him tonight?.
- would you stop going on about it?.
- Izzy, that's all verywell--
I think it's ridiculous.
I'm here to shoot.
Darling, it's a reliefto me to sit next
to someone who isn't deafin one ear.
I'm sorry?.
[ Chattering ]
Darling, what doyou mean,
""leave it"?.
well, I just meant
let it come naturally.
Don't try and steer
the conversation.
- It makes you sound so desperate.
- well, I am fucking desperate.
Hello, Raymond. This is
my brother-in-law, Lord stockbridge.
Hello.
I'm Morris weissman.
- who?.
- Morris weissman.
- weissman, yes.
- Hello.
Oh, Elsie? Elsie,
this is LordStockbridge's valet.
He's new to the house,
so show him around, will you?.
you'll be sharing with
Mr. weissman's man.
- Has His Lordship's luggage gone up?.
- supposedly.
He's in the Tapestryroom,
wherever that is.
Oh, well,
here we go again.
[ Mary ] That's just it. I've never
done a house party before, not properly.
[ Elsie ] How come you got
taken on as a countess lady's maid...
- ifyou've got no experience?
- She wants to train me.
she said she didn't care
about experience.
she didn't want
to pay for it, you mean.
It's cold in here.
you should know to packyourwoolies
when you come to this house.
Here we are.
- Is everything all right, Elsie?.
- Fine, Miss Lewis. Thanks.
That's your bed there.
- That good?. yeah, that's tasty.
- Very tasty.
I think I'll--
I shall go in the library.
Hereyou are, Pip, Pip.
I begyourpardon, sir. I thought
I'djust take the Times up with me...
- in case you'd like to read it
when you're dressing.
- Thankyou, Probert.
- Look after Pip for me. Good boy.
- Of course, sir.
I have to make a telephone call
to California in a couple ofhours.
- I can't find a telephone.
- well, there's a telephone
just here on the left.
Oh, wonderful. Thankyou. you know,
of course, I'll reverse the charges.
yes.
There's a newrestaurant in the Strand.
It's an automatic restaurant.
It's open 24 hours a day.
you can go in any time day or night.
so who's the funny
I ittle American?.
- Morris weissman.
He's a friend of Ivor.
- Oh.
He makes films in Hollywood.
Ivor asked ifhe could bring him along.
Didn't see why not.
I thought he might be interested
in guns and shooting.
Oh, well, never mind.
He adds to the glamor of the gathering.
I didn't expect anything
halfas exotic.
Oh, no, not for me.
you know that I hate drinking whisky.
Go on, drink it.
Doyou good.
- Go on.
- [ sighs ]
Oh, really, Bill.
you are such
a bad influence.
well, don't blame me
ifI start misbehaving.
[McCordle] I don't knowhowimpressed
yourhusbandis with our Hollywood folk.
well,
you know Raymond.
He only feels safe
with his own kind.
Bill!
[ Chuckles ]
I thought ladies'maids
never wore aprons.
Her Ladyship used to have a French maid
who wore a black one like this.
she thinks it's got
a bit of style.
I bet she does, and I bet
she took it out ofyour wages too.
she likes to have
everything just so.
Mmm.
Don't they all.
- That's him.
- who?.
Ivor Novello.
He passed us on the road today
on his way here, and he spoke to me.
well, he spoke to Her Ladyship,
but I answered.
I only cut it out for Garbo.
I prefer the American stars.
I think they've got
more oomph.
Go on!
- Is he really sirwilliam's cousin?.
- yep.
Imagine having a film star
in the family.
- Ladysylvia must be thrilled.
- Oh, I don't think.
whywouldn't she be?.
'Cause she's a snobbish cow.
'Cause she--
she looks down on anyone who got
to the top with brains and hard work.
just like she looks down on her husband,
except when it's time to foot the bills.
And then she's got
her hand out, all right.
- what was her family, then?
- what'd you expect, really?.
Toffee-nosed and useless.
Her father was
the Earl of Carton.
sounds good, except
he didn't have a pot to piss in.
what's she like
to work for?.
she's horrible.
But he's--
He's okay. Come on.
we better get cracking.
- Hello, I'm Ivor.
- I know who you are.
- Mabel Nesbitt.
- Hello, Mabel.
-[Mabel] Howareyou?
- Very well, thankyou.
Oh! I don't smoke.
Thankyou.
[Elsie ] Mrs. Nesbitt's
only got one dress with her.
says her husband rushed her
when she was packing.
Do you always look after visitors
if they haven't got a maid?.
sometimes Dorothy helps,
though why Mrs. wilson...
makes the still room maid
do it beats me.
I think she only does it
to annoy Mrs. Croft.
- which one does Dorothy answer to?.
- Both. That's the problem.
she's rushed offher feet as it is.
Areyou nearly done there?.
- yes.
- Here she is-- Miss Bossy.
Tell me, what was Greta Garbo
really like?.
- Didyou get to knowher?
-[Novello ] yes, I did, actually.
she's coming to stay
with me next month.
[ Gasps ]
Tell me, howmuch longer areyou
going to go on... making films?
I suppose that rather depends
on how much longer the public
want to see me in them.
yes, it must be hard
to know...
when it's time
to throw in the towel.
what a pity about
that last one ofyours.
what-what was it called?.
- The Dodger.
- The Lodger.
The Lodger.
And it must be
so disappointing...
when something just, you know,
flops like that.
yes, it is...
rather disappointing.
Look at this.
Machine-made lace.
- Hark at her.
- well, I hate cheap clothes.
They're twice the work,
and they never look as good.
I'll murder that dog one day.
Look at that. All over his waistcoat.
what doyou expect from a woman
without her own maid?.
Lady Lavinia says a woman who travels
with no maid has lost her self-respect.
- she calls it ""giving in."
- I don't have a maid.
I haven't given in.
- [Sarah] That's different.
-[Elsie ] why?
- what's your name?.
- I think here I'm called Trentham.
No, I meantyour real name.
Oh. Mary.
Mary Maceachran.
Blimey. what does
Her Ladyship call you?.
well, sheshouldcall me Maceachran,
now I'm a lady's maid.
That's what my mother says.
But Her Ladyship can't pronounce it,
so she calls me Mary.
I don't blame her.
sylvia.
I'm serious.
There mustn't be anymore nonsense.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
[ Clock Chiming]
Done much shooting
this year?.
[Stockbridge ]
Quite a lot.
- Hello.
- Does Louisa always go out with you?.
- Usually.
- It's very good ofher.
- Do you have a minute?.
- Don't do that! That's bad for him!
Put him down.
- [Pip whimpers ]
- yeah. Bores me stiff.
- All right, Pip.
- I just wondered--
[Sylvia ]
william's such a rotten shot.
I usually try and duck out ofit,
particularly in Scotland.
I 'm rather fond
of scotland.
All right,
get on with your work. yes?.
- Ah, Mr. weissman. There you are.
- I'm dealing with this.
- what is it, Mr. weissman?.
- well, to start with,
my name is Denton.
- Henry Denton.
- you're here as valet to Mr. weissman.
That means you'll be known
as Mr. weissman below stairs
for the duration ofyour stay.
we stick to the old customs here.
It saves confusion.
- It's about Mr. weissman's diet.
- yes?.
He's a vegetarian.
- A what?.
- A vegetarian.
He doesn't eat meat.
He eats fish, but not meat.
well, I never!
Doesn't eat meat?.
He's coming for a shooting party,
and he doesn't eat meat.
Mr. weissman doesn't
intend to shoot.
I think he just wants to walk
out with them, get a bit of air.
Get a bit of air?.
yes, thankyou.
we'll make the necessary arrangements.
Now I suggestyou get one of
the servants to takeyou upstairs.
Mr. weissman is in
the Green bedroom,
and you'll be sharing with
Lord stockbridge's valet--
Robert Parks.
[women Chuckling]
He's very full ofhimself, I must say.
""Doesn't eat meat."
Now, now, Mrs. Croft. we don't want
to be thought unsophisticated, do we?.
Mr. weissman's an American.
They do things differently there.
Good boy, now.
Give Louisa a kiss from me.
[Novello ]
Darling, I'm sorry about that.
- I should have made it clear
that Morrisjust doesn't shoot.
- [ Sylvia ] Don't worry.
wil I iam's just making a fuss.
He has this ridiculous idea...
that Americans all sleep
with guns under their pillows.
They do, but they're more for
each otherthan for killing birds.
[ Clears Throat] Remind me.
How areyou related towilliam exactly?.
[Novello]
Ourmothers were first cousins.
[Stockbridge ] Don't believe
I ever met william's mother.
Didn't she do something
rather original?.
well, she was a teacher.
And so was mine.
- That's marvelous, isn't it?.
- [ Constance ]Sylvia is so clever.
She always finds
such wonderful servants.
I don't know how she manages.
I 'm breaking in
a new maid.
I 'm simply worn out
with it.
Actually, there's nothing
more exhausting, is there?.
- I don't have a lady's maid.
- Oh. Hello.
I was just telling dear Mabel here
about my new maid.
Honestly, the amount I have to do
for her, she should be paying me.
she does seem
ratheryoung.
well, ofcourse, whatshe is,
my dear, is wonderfully cheap.
you've no right to pull me away
in mid-conversation.
Mabel, where are you going?.
The room's this way.
why the hell did you have to mention
you don't have a maid?.
why would you mention you didn't
have a maid, for God's sake?.
you'd find it a lot easier to clean
them ifyou put the trees in first.
I was just about
to do that.
Are these
Mr. Novello's shoes?.
yes.
- Doyou really live in Hollywood?.
- I do.
Hmm. How did you get there?.
where did you start from?.
where else doyou think?.
scotland.
wereyou always
in service?.
Did you ever think oftrying to
get into films whileyou were there?.
I wanted to be an actor once...
when I was little.
I suppose
old MotherTrentham...
will have her begging bowl out
while she's here.
she won't be bothering
your employers, that's certain.
- why not?.
- [Elsie ]
Because Lady Lavinia Meredith...
- hasn't got a penny
to bless herselfwith.
- And whose fault is that?.
There's nothing wrong
with the commander.
He's just been a bit
unfortunate.
I'll say.
I think he's pathetic.
Then why don'tyou
hand in your notice?.
well, the other two sisters
fell on their feet.
Of course, it helps
that they're both good-looking.
- [Mary] LadySylvia's lovely.
- you think so?.
- She might have done a bit
better for herself, really.
-[Elsie ] I begyourpardon.
Lord Carton was determined to have sir
william for either of the two eldest.
I was told he could have
had his pick.
- why was Lord Carton so keen?.
- why do you think?.
who do you suppose pays
for him to swan around Biarritz
for six months of the year?.
Come to that, who keeps Ma Trentham
in stockings and gin?
- Old money bags, that's who.
- I think it's disgusting
the way they all use him.
None of the rest of them
have got the brains to make
the price of a packet oftea.
- Areyou finished, Elsie?.
- yes, Mrs. wilson.
- I'vejust got this hem to do.
- what's Lord stockbridge like?.
He thinks
he's God Almighty.
They all do.
- why does this fork go on the right?.
- [ Chuckles ]
Because they eat the fish
with two ofthem.
- One in each hand.
- why is that, then?.
- search me.
- [ George ] what areyou doing here?
-J ust looking around.
- Mr.Jennings will be up in a minute.
If I were you,
I'd go and look around somewhere else.
- Is that what you'd do?.
- That's exactlywhat I would do.
Then that's what
I'll do.
- something funny about that bloke.
- His accent for a start.
- what doyou think his game is?.
- I don't know.
Areyou finished?. what about
Lord Rupert standish and Mr. Blond?.
Her Ladyship said
not to wait for them.
The stuffs all ready
ifthey turn up on time.
we can stick on
two extra places in a jiffy.
when they arrive, you'll be
dressing Mr. Blond, Arthur.
- Mr. Blond?.
- yes, Mr. Blond.
George, you'll have
Lord Rupert.
Ifthey're very late,
they can change by themselves,
and you can tidy up
when they're downstairs.
Is Mr. Nesbitt
settled?.
I'll go and finish
him off now, sir.
- And Mr. Novello?.
- Mr. weissman's man will attend to him.
Right.
Afteryou're finished,
join me in the drawing room
with the drinks.
- what's the matterwith you?.
- Nothing.
Only I thought I'd be doing
Mr. Novello, that's all.
Nowyou won't get to see him
in his underdrawers.
Never mind.
Better luck next time.
They're rather
a mixed bunch.
That Mr. weissman's
very odd.
Apparently, he produces
motion pictures.
The Charlie Chan mysteries.
Or does he direct them?.
I never know the difference.
Really?.
I enjoy those, milady.
ye-- Mary.
I suppose it's fun
having a film star staying.
There's always so little to talk about
after the first flush of recognition.
And why has Freddie Nesbitt brought
that awful, common little wife ofhis?.
I mean, Isobel onlyaskedhim
because a gun dropped out.
That's no excuse
to inflict her on us all.
Mary!.
[Sighs ]
so what's the gossip
in the servants' hall?.
- Um, nothing, milady.
- Hmm?.
Nonsense.
Come on. Out with it.
well, is it true
that sirwilliam...
could have married Ladystockbridge
ifhe'd wanted to?.
Is that what
they're saying?
Only that Lord Carton was
after sirwilliam for one ofthem,
but he didn't care which.
what would you say
if I told you...
they cut cards for him?.
william, Lewis said
you wanted me.
- who's next to me at dinner?.
- Oh, you know.
Aunt Constance
and Lavinia.
why do I have to have
that bloody old trout all the time?.
- I want Louisa.
- Do I have to explain
the table ofprecedence again?
- I don't give a shit about precedence.
- well,you always complain...
that people look down on you,
and then you behave like a peasant.
Now, tomorrow morning,
I 'll--
I 'll breakfast in bed,
and then get straight up
into the tweeds.
what shirt
have you brought?.
Um, the green
with the pink stripe.
Oh, no, dear. No.
That's quite wrong.
No, always something
veryplain for countrysports.
The one I had on today
will do.
- But it's soi led.
- yeah, well, you can wash it,
can'tyou?
God. I hate shooti ng.
why does one
have to do these things?.
[ McCordle ]
Has Constance asked for moneyyet?
- No.
- Raymond tells me...
she's been complaining that
her allowance isn't big enough.
Good mind to stop it
completely.
- I thought it was for her lifetime.
- [Laughs ]
No, no.
- will that be all, sir?.
- Mmm.
I do wish thatAnthony
wasn't here.
Make sure I'm not
left alone with him, willyou?
- [Sylvia ] why?
- I'm pulling out of his scheme.
Oh.
Have you told him?.
No, and I'm not
going to either.
Louisa said I should leave it
till next week.
Let him sob in private.
Go. say hello to your mommy.
Go on.
Far be it from me
to contradict Louisa.
[ whimpers ]
- will there be anything else?.
-Just get Pip.
He might fall down the stairs.
Hey, hey, come here.
Come here.
Thankyou, Elsie.
you keep hold ofhim.
- Is everything all right?.
- Cheap dress, wrong shoes.
I'm making bricks without straw,
Mr. Probert, really.
- you don't have any
spare hairpins, doyou?.
- yeah.
I'm trying to get back to the room
for a second, and I can't find it.
It's the staircase
at the end ofthe corridor.
- Oh, thankyou.
- Ah.
Oh, Pip.
Oh, thankyou, Elsie.
Thankyou. Oh!
you've got some hair on your dress.
- Thankyou, sir.
- yes.
[Nesbitt] Shut up, Mabel! There is
nothinggoing on between me and Isobel.
Can't you just tell me the truth?.
you're a liar, Freddie.
- There is nothing--
- you are a liar!
- Don't you call me a liar!
- [knocking On Door]
I found some pins, madam,
from LadyTrentham's maid.
Right.
we're supposed to be
downstairs already.
well, you go on.
[ sniffles ]
I'll be down
in a minute.
-[Door Opens]
- Tryandmake herlook respectable.
[Door Closes ]
Oh, thankyou.
well... there's no harm
in trying.
[ weissman ]
well, thankyou very much, Mr.Jennings.
-JustJennings, sir.
- All right.
JustJennings.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, bytheway, I've booked
a telephone call to California,
and I'd appreciate it ifyou would
get me as soon as it comes through.
- Very good, sir.
- Thankyou,Jennings.
you're not gonna provide
entertainment?.
That's howyou got
your invitation.
-  [ stops ]
- Oh, no, don't get up.
- Please, go on.
- you look lovely in that dress,
ifI may say so.
-  [Resumes ]
- what is it? I don't recognize it.
[Novello ]
A little something I'm working on.
I can't imagine how one
ever goes about inventing a tune.
where do you start?.
It's rather difficult
to say.
well, I think
you're too clever forwords.
- Good evening.
- Hello.
- Lovely dress.
- Thankyou.
Hi.
How doyou manage
to put up with these people?.
well, you forget I earn my living
by impersonating them.
Can I helpyou?.
you know, I really enjoy the way
you do things, Mr.Jennings.
I beg your pardon?.
- what is it, Henry?.
- Nothing.
I just wanted to be sure
you had everything you need, sir.
yes, I do.
Thankyou.
It's wonderful to find a servant
these days who really shows
an interest, don'tyou think?.
sir.
[ Chattering, Indistinct]
Come on, girls. sit down.
Tuck in. we've got 20 minutes.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ George ]
Shuffle along. Here he comes.
- Everything satisfactory, Mr.Jennings?.
- yes, thankyou, Dorothy.
They have their drinks.
I thinkwe can all take
our leisure for half an hour or so.
what's this?.
- I believe this is my place,
Mr.Jennings.
- Oh.
And sincewhen did a baroness
outrank a countess?.
Miss Trentham, wouldyou
take the place ofhonor, please?
- Miss Trentham?
- [ Clears Throat ]
I'm all right here,
Mr.Jennings. Thankyou.
Go on.
Don't keep him waiting.
[Jennings ]
Ah, Miss Meredith.
would you come and sit
on my left?.
Naturally, I'm nothing when
there are visitors in the house.
- Nevermind. I'm used to it.
- Good evening, Mrs. wilson.
Good evening.
[All]
For what we are about to receive,
may the Lord make us
truly grateful.
[Jennings ] Right.
Start whenyou get it.
No time for loitering.
I 'm not serving tonight,
Mr. Jennings, am I ?.
Not tonight, Elsie,
but probably tomorrow.
where is Mrs. Croft?.
Always eats
with her own staff.
Does she take her pudding to
Mrs. wilson's room?. Our cook does that.
Fat chance.
They hate each other.
- Can I ask a question?.
- Certainly, Mr. weissman.
How can we helpyou?.
I just wondered, how many people here
had parents in service?.
And was that why
they chose to go into it?.
what an interesting question,
and one to which, I'm afraid,
I cannot provide the answer.
All ofyou whose parents
were in service, raiseyour hand.
- My fatherwas.
- Both-- nanny and groom.
- Notyou, Dorothy?
- My fatherwas a farmer, Mr.Jennings.
A tenant of Lord Carton's.
- Mr. Meredith?
- Factory hands, both of them.
- And ifyou ask me,
theywere better off.
- [ Chuckles ]
what about you,
Mr. stockbridge?.
[ George ]
what's the matter? Don'tyou know?
yeah, I know
what they did.
But it didn't have any effect
on me or my choice ofwork.
- And why's that?.
- Because I grew up in an orphanage.
[Jennings ]
Thankyou, Mr. weissman,
for giving us all
a little something to think about.
Oh, Her Ladyship.
[ Sylvia ]
Oh, I'm so sorry to disturb you.
Please, do sit down
and fi nish your supper.
Mrs. wilson, a major crisis has arisen.
I havejust found out...
that Mr. weissman won't eat meat,
and I don't know what to do.
I can't tell Mrs. Croft.
I si m ply don't dare.
Everything's under control,
your Ladyship.
Mr. weissman's valet informed us
as soon as he arrived,
so we've prepared
a special version ofthe soup.
He can eat the fish
and the hors d'oeuvres,
and we'll have a welsh rarebit
for the game course.
I don't know what we're going
to do about the entree,
but we'll think of something.
Thankyou, Mrs. wilson.
Ten steps ahead as usual.
which one ofyou
is Mr. weissman's valet?.
I am, your Ladyship.
Areyou, indeed?.
yes, heavens.
Um, thankyou foryour...
efficiency.
- you're all set, then.
- [Jennings ] yes, George?.
Nothing, sir.
I shouldhope not.
I'm veryhungry.
[ Chattering ]
I was, uh,
wondering, william,
ifI could have a word
with you alone after dinner.
I can't leave my guests,
can I?.
you'll make that dog sick.
Isobel, didyou know
that william and I...
are going into business
together in the sudan?.
- No, I didn't know that.
- It's quite exciting.
what's happenedis
apparently,
there are hundreds and hundreds
ofSudanese native soldiers,
entire regiments
wandering around the desert,
wi I ly-ni I ly, without
anythi ng on thei r feet,
which causes some hardship,
I imagine.
No, I grew up
in Leicester.
- My father had a glove factory.
- Really?.
One thing I do know is
how a glove should fit.
Really, darling. you're boring
poor Mr. Novello to death.
[ Mouthing words ]
- [Novello ] No!
-[ weissman ] I think he's going
to explain everything to me...
and ki nd of show me
how it all works.
There's gonna be a pheasant hunt
in my picture.
There's a large market in modernizing
the armies in the sudan...
and providing them
with boots.
[woman]Andthen the oldbag
justservedit to all the servants.
I couldn't believe it.
Aren't you cold?.
It's better
than that kitchen.
Here. I thought
you could do with this.
- Oh, that's kind, love.
- [Vehicle Approaching]
[Man ]
Elsie, hello.
- Good evening, your Lordship.
- we've got bags and guns
and everything and no man.
If I give you the keys,
will you sort it out for me?.
- Of course, your Lordship.
- Thankyou.
- we'll getyour bags, sir.
- Thankyou. That's very kind ofyou.
Good evening.
Right.
In the boot, is it?
sorry, can I trouble you
for a light, please?.
- you got that bag?
- yeah.
Thank you.
Good evening.
[ Meredith ] you mean you think he's
losing interest in that sort ofthing?
well, not just that.
The whole Empire.
I think he said
the steam's gone out of it.
[ Chuckles ]
william?.
That's not true, is it--
thatyou think the Empire's finished?.
I've been what?.
well, the Empire was
finished after the war.
well, because ofthe war.
It changed everything.
- Empire Leicester square?.
- well, I don't care
what's changed ornot changed.
As long as oursons are spared
whatyou all went through.
Oh, not all.
you didn't fight, didyou, william ?
I did my bit.
[ Sylvia ]
well, you made a lot ofmoney,
but it's not quite the same thing as
charging into the cannon's mouth, is it?
Thank God for Raymond.
At least the family...
had one representative
in the front line.
Raymond, tell them how many times
you were mentioned in the despatches.
- I forget.
- No,you don't. Come on.
- [ Nesbitt ] Is he being modest?
- yes, he's being very modest.
what do you thi nk
you're doi ng here?.
Mrs. wilson asked me to tell you
that the others have arrived.
[Jennings ]
Good.
Lord Rupert standish
and Mr. Blond are here, milady.
No, they're too late. They can
have a tray in the billiard room.
- They can join us later.
- Very good, milady.
- Is Rupert here?.
shall I go and say hello?.
- [Sylvia ] yes.
No, I don't think so.
[Blond]
Face it. you're ayoungerson...
with the taste ofmarquess
and the income ofa vicar.
Her mother likes you.
she does too.
Now, I know she's not
exactly a show-stopper--
- Her father's not keen on the idea.
- He'll come around.
"" Have you met my daughter,
Lady Rupert standish?"
He thinks I'm in it
for the money.
Ofcourse he does.
Butyou can't let that putyou off.
He's much more ofan obstacle
thanyou think.
Thenyou must overcome that,
mustn'tyou?
Her Ladyship asked ifyou would
join her in the drawing room
when you've finished.
[ McCordle ]
All right, ladies, offyou go.
[ Chattering ]
Gentlemen.
Gents, move down.
Move down.
Louisa, look after Pip
for me, will you?.
I wonderifwe couldhave
a word or two later on, william?
Do you think so?.
Ah, good, good.
-Jennings, could I--
- Certainly, sir.
[Bertha ] There's more in here.
I'mjust getting them.
I need all the knives there.
All the knives.
Come on, Maude.
Let's go and get the fish kettle.
Fred? Albert?
Ready?
- There he is.
- who?.
Lord stockbridge's valet.
Apparently, he grew up in an orphanage.
Arthur said they made him
shout it down the table.
Makes you feel
sorry for him, really.
[Mrs. Croft] It's nothing to be
ashamed of. It's not his fault.
would you like me to ask Lord Rupert
and Mr. Blond to join you, sir?.
No, leave them be.
They can entertain the ladies.
Give Mr. Novello a rest.
Anthony, did I overhearyou
at dinner saying...
- you were going into business
with sir william?.
- I beg your pardon?.
- Is it very old?.
- Possibly, possibly.
Ifyou need an expert
in changing money,
especially Africa,
I'm your man-- expert.
yes, the expert.
No, it's not here.
And Mr.Jennings is certain
he hasn't got it?.
Oh, so he says.
But ifit's a silver carving knife,
he must have it.
It's just gone in the wrong drawer
in the silver pantry.
- Itwouldn't have been put in here.
- well, that's what I told him.
How old would you say
that Mr. stockbridge was?.
Don't know.
About 31, 32.
- why?.
- Oh, no reason.
I think I'll turn in.
we got an early start.
you can tell Mr.Jennings
we haven't got that knife.
Pleasant evening, milady?
Not really, no.
Had Lord stockbridge on one side
boring for Britain,
and Freddie Nesbitt
on the other sucking up.
Oh, I'm worn out.
Is there any more chocolate in that pot?.
I'll go down and
make some more, milady.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Door Opens, Closes ]
Lewis?.
I was looking
for my maid.
she's just gone downstairs.
Can I help?.
she's going to fetch me some chocolate,
but now I wonderwhether
I wouldn't prefer milk.
would that be hot milk
or cold?.
you decide.
I couldn't say, milady.
Hot then, with something
to make it sweet.
you haveyour hands
in your pockets.
- Otherwise, I'll never sleep.
- why?.
Doyou have trouble sleeping,
milady?.
I have a feeling
I might have trouble tonight.
I'll be wide awake at 1 :00 a.m.,
bored to sobs.
Then we must try and think
ofsomething to amuseyou.
- Barnes. It's all right.
- Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
No, I knew it. I knew william
would try something like this.
- well, ofcourse he would. Fuck him!
- [DoorSlams Shut]
- short arse.
- Andfuck this room!
I thinkyou should
come with me tomorrow.
I'll just say
I need you.
Oh, I got through
to the coast tonight.
Finally.
Is that clock right?.
we got turned down
by Una Merkel,
so... sheehan's
pushing for a rewrite.
He thinks the part's
too small.
It's a fucking Charlie Chan picture,
not a movie about a socialite.
so...
[ Clears Throat ]
will I seeyou later?.
I don't think I should risk it.
Doyou?.
Good night, sir.
- [Door Opens]
- Henry.
Don't forget those.
They'll thinkyou don't care.
Oh. I must've taken
the wrong stairs.
you better not
be seen up here.
- I'd better go down.
- why?.
There's no rush.
since you're here now,
what about a drink?.
[ Gasps ]
what are you doing?.
[ Grunting ]
No!
Get offme!
[yelling]
Get off me!
Get off--
what?.
what's this?.
what are you doing here?.
I came up the wrong staircase. I was
just waiting till the coast was clear.
well, you better go down again
before anyone catches you.
Just a minute.
- what?.
- Nothing.
- Doyou want a drink?.
- sure.
so what doyou make
ofthe place?.
Is this a well-run house,
would you say?.
Doyou think Sir william
wouldbe good to work for?
No.
How long you been
doing this?.
- what?
- Valeting?.
About seven years.
I was a footman before that.
And working for Lord stockbridge--
is that a promotion?.
No.
I used to be with
the Earl ofFlintshire.
Then why did you move?.
'Cause I felt like it.
who's that?.
- That's my mother.
- where's she live?.
she doesn't. That's why
they put me in an orphanage.
That's right. sorry.
what happened to her?.
what do you mean?.
I mean, why didshe die?
was sheyoung?
was it in childbirth?.
you're not very curious,
are you?.
yeah, she was young.
she worked in a factory.
she had me.
A little while later, she died.
End ofstory.
Then why didn'tyousay
she was a factory worker at dinner?
'Cause I didn't fancy discussing
my private life
with a table full of strangers.
I'm sorry if I spoke
out of turn, mate.
Didn't mean to offend you.
I'm not offended.
And don't call me ""mate."
well, I'llseeyou later.
I've got a date
with a hot glass ofmilk.
[Door Opens, Closes ]
[Elsie ] I shouldn't worry about it.
It goes with the territory.
Oh, look.
I t's Mr. Novel lo.
J ust thi nk of him
sleeping downstairs.
I 'm gonna have to watch you, my girl.
I can see that.
Her Ladyship says Mr. weissman's
a Hollywood producer.
He does
the Charlie Chan films.
yeah, I like those. I like
a bit ofa fright in the cinema.
you could go with his valet.
He'd giveyou a fright.
you'd better keepyour eye on him.
I think he's a queer one.
He's not from scotland,
for a start.
At least not any part ofit
that I know.
- what's Mrs. Nesbitt like?.
- she's all right.
I feel a bit sorry
for her, really.
- Of course, it neverworks.
- what neverworks?.
well, when a man like that
marries beneath him,
he hasn't got the brains
to carry it off.
I think it's romantic
to marry for love.
Love?. Not him.
He's a nasty piece
ofwork.
The Honorable
Freddie Nesbitt.
That's a laugh.
No, it was her father's money
he was after.
It was less than he thought,
and now it's all spent,
all he's got to show for it
is a wife he's ashamed of.
And he's lost his job.
wants Miss Isobel toput in a word
with Sir william.
what's the matter?.
I never washed that shirt!
Oh, she's gonna kill me.
Do you think
I could do it now?.
- Do you want me to go with you?.
- No.
I'll be all right.
what are you doing
down here?.
I'm supposed to wash
LadyTrentham's shirt for tomorrow.
There's a sink
in the ironing room.
[ water Running ]
[Shuts Offwater]
Is someone in there?.
what areyou doing here?.
I just had to rinse
this shirt out.
should've knocked,
shouldn'tyou?.
Miss Trentham?.
I was just washing a shirt
of Her Ladyship's.
I hopeyou foundeverything
you required.
Does she have to have
marmalade?.
Only Dorothy made
too little ofit lastJanuary,
and we've run out ofthe homemade.
I don't suppose she'd care
for strawberry jam instead?.
- No, I thought not.
- [Footsteps ]
Oh, I was rather hoping for
a word with Mrs. wilson.
Mrs. wilson,
will you tell Jennings...
that we'll have the soup
after the fourth drive tomorrow.
And-And tell Mrs. Croft
to make sure it's hot.
It's been cold the last few weeks.
And more pepper in it.
[Sylvia ]
Is thatyou?
were you expecting
someone else?.
-[Men Chattering]
-[Dogs Barking]
[Man ]
Seven hundred day today?
[Man #2 ]
well, lads, don't coach your guns,
even ifthey can't hit
a barn door.
- Don't tell them where
they're missing unless they ask.
- [ McCordle ] Lovely day.
-Jennings.
- I hope it holds foryou, sir.
- Enjoy the shoot.
- Can a pheasant ever be dangerous?.
- Dangerous?.
- Do I have to worry about it attacking?.
- Good morning, sir.
- Right, drawyour pegs.
- I'm gonna be cheering him on.
- Drawyour pegs.
[McCordle ]
Here we are.
- Morning,Jennings.
- Areyou shooting today, sir?.
- I never shoot.
- Oh.
yousee,
I'm-I'm starving.
where have you been?.
sorry.
Oh, they always send up
a good breakfast here.
I'll say that for sylvia.
she's not at all mean
in that way.
Oh, dear.
Bought marmalade.
Dear me,
I call that very feeble.
well, I suppose
one can't have everything.
Mary, I don't think
I'll wear that shirt after all.
The other one's warmer.
That's all I care about.
Ooh, yum my.
yum my, yum my, yum my.
what do you mean,
you're going shooting?.
Mr. weissman wants me to accompany him.
Nothing wrong in that.
But what for?. you're not loading.
He hasn't got a gun.
- He might need something.
- what could he need?.
yeah, we know the very idea ofservice
is offensive toyou, George.
But there's no need
to take it out on the rest of us.
Please forgive ourill manners,
Mr. weissman.
I think he's got
something to hide, that one.
we all have something to hide,
Mr. Meredith.
would you like to
get changed now, miss?.
- He won't do it.
- who won't do what?.
My father.
He won't give Freddie a job.
I spoke to him last night,
and he said he'd think about it.
But this morning, he says it isn't
up to him, when, of course, it is.
- why not?.
- I don't know.
something to do with
why Freddie was sacked.
But I can't get a straight answer
out of either ofthem.
well,you've doneyourbest.
Mr. Nesbitt can't ask
for more than that now, can he?
But he can, much more!
He says he's going
to tell him.
-[ Opening Drawer]
- Doyou think he will?
I don't know. He says Daddy
will give him a job to keep him quiet.
will you say something?.
To Mr. Nesbitt?.
To Daddy.
Really, miss, why do you think
I can make a difference?.
will you?.
I thinkyou should wear
yourwarm underwear today.
[ Horn sounding ]
[Gunshots ]
Nearly.
- [ Gunshots Continue ]
- That's mine.
Oh, God!
It's on its way.
- [ Barking ]
- [whistling]
Damn!
Bloody gun's no good.
[McCordle ]
I toldyou not to bring this one.
[ Gunshot ]
- [ Gunshots Continue ]
- [ McCordle ] Blast.
I think I pricked that one.
I -I 'm pretty sure I pricked it.
[ McCordle ]
Bugger!
Ohh! Oh!
Blast it!
- [ Gunshot ]
- Oh, damn!
-[Man ]Areyou all right, sir?
- No, I'm not!
God, where the bloody hell
did that come from?
- It's nicked you, sir.
- [ Groans ] It's nicked me.
- what cretin did that?
- I don't know, sir.
Find Strutt. Ask him
ifhe knows who's responsible.
And ifhe knows, tell him to send
the gun back to the bloody house.
Everybody knows the desperate situation
we're in, but nobody seems to care.
Oh, there you are.
Didyou find one?
- well?.
- Don't look at me.
If I so much as open my mouth on
the subject, it'll make things worse.
- I've already tried.
-Jennings says the car's ready.
Oh, goody. I'm starving.
I do love--
- what are you wearing?.
- why?. Don'tyou like it?.
- you bought it.
- Did I?.
Oh, how extraordinary
of me.
Come on.
Better get going.
- where's that wretched Mabel?.
- [ Constance ]
Has anyone checked her outfit?
she's probably in black velvet
with a feather in her hair.
[ Lavinia ] she's in the morning room
looking perfectly normal.
- Don't be such a snob, Aunt Constance.
- Me?.
I haven't a snobbish bone
in mybody.
Oh, Mr. Meredith.
- Is Mr. stockbridge in?.
- search me.
Oh.
Mr. stockbridge.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I was just making
my routine inspection.
so, uh, how areyou settling in
with Lord stockbridge?.
I'm sorry?.
How areyou settling in
with Lord stockbridge?.
I knowthatyou haven't
been with him forlong.
Not long, no.
I'm afraid smoking
isn't allowed up here.
I hope you're finding everything to make
His Lordship's stay more comfortable.
I hope we haven't
forgotten anything.
I can't believeyou forget much,
Mrs. wilson.
No.
Not much.
well, I'll leaveyou
toyour book.
[Door Closes ]
[ McCordle ]
you know-- Bang! whoof!.
[ stockbridge ] you should be more
selective about the peopleyou invite.
well, I've got
a good appetite.
yes.
[women Conversing]
[ weissman ] It's very muddy,
so watch whereyou step.
[ sylvia ]
Terribly muddy here. Do watch.
Do you see what I'm saying?.
I've been noticing it.
Doesn't this look lovely?.
They really have done well.
Now do go in
and have a drink.
I can tell you, Raymond, it's
a bloody awful thing to have happened.
- [McCordle ] Oh, God, Louisa.
- Oh! Oh, I say.
Two inches to my right I'd have
been dead. I've just been shot.
- what?.
- yes, that's right.
[ Constance ]
Oh,yes, please.
- what happened to your ear?.
- some idiot shot me.
- I was a terrible shot.
- Did you have fun?.
- I don't thinkyou realize
howserious this is.
- [Lavinia ] Ofcourse I do.
why can't you get
your sisters to help?.
Darling, do you think I haven't tried?.
you know what they're like.
well, I know they couldn't care less
ifwe go under.
why should they care,
as long as their dressmakers are busy
and their dinners are on time?.
- wait a minute. There's a queue here.
- shh. shh.
Ohh!
shut the door,
for heaven's sake.
Don't worry.
It's only Lewis and Dorothy.
If any ofthe men get found up here,
they get sacked on the spot.
worse luck.
so don't tell me,
you're a convent girl.
Or is that
Presbyterian modesty?.
- Is the water hot?.
- Not really.
No, it won't be
till the guns get back.
I'd better
get in yours.
Her Ladyship says that sirwilliam
loves his shooting.
yeah, he does. Can't hit a barn door,
but he does love it.
It's quite sweet,
really.
- Elsie.
- yeah?.
Last night--
what?.
No, I shouldn't say.
yes, you should.
what?.
well,
when I went down
to wash that shirt,
I think I saw him
in the ironing room.
[ whispers ] He was with
one ofthe kitchen maids.
- No, that wouldn't have been him.
- I think itwas.
He came down the passage
a minute later,
and I don't see how--
No, it wasn't him.
you weren't serious
last night, wereyou?.
I'm afraid I was,
old boy.
I was going to tell you next week,
but sinceyou mentioned it--
I don't thinkyou've grasped quite
what it'll do to the whole project,
and in particular
what it'll do to me.
- It can't be as black
as all that, can it?.
- yes, it bloodywell is.
I'm sorry to hearthat,
but business is business.
- I'm not a charity commissioner,
you know.
- william, I'm begging you.
[McCordle Gasps]
Damn it!
[ Constance ]
Oh, dear.
- [Jennings ] I'll clearthat up.
- I'm sorry.
[Jennings]
Arthur, go andget a bucket.
- Have you a cloth?.
- Under the table.
[Man ]
Seems verynervous.
[Jennings ] we'll have that
cleaned foryou at the house.
-  I do like gathering nuts in May
- Terrified the life out of me.
- I borrowed it from Lewis.
-  Ifyou've a dimple
it's very simple
-  All you need is a smile
that's sweet and shy
- shot, frightened to death.
Andsort of
a twinkle inyour eye
Here I come
gathering nuts in May
when I detect 'em
I soon collect 'em
- I think it's left me deaf.
- They stand around me
simply waiting to be picked
you know how you said si r wil I iam
could've had his pick...
between Lady sylvia
and Lady stockbridge?.
- Aye.
- well, I asked Her Ladyship about it.
she said
they cut cards for him.
- No!
- I know.
I can't believe it
either.
Do you suppose
it was a joke?.
well, I wouldn't
be too sure.
you know what I heard?.
Oh,just listen to me.
- what?
- why do we spend our lives
living through them?.
I mean,
look at poor old Lewis.
Ifher own mother
had a heart attack,
she'd think it was less important
than one of Lady sylvia's farts.
you must know.
you can't fool me.
Ifthere's one thing I don't
look for in a maid, it's discretion.
Except with my own secrets,
of course.
well, I don't knowmuch,
milady,
but apparently he was counting
on sirwilliam for an investment...
and had guaranteed his interest,
whatever that means.
Anyway, Mr. Barnes,
the commander's valet,
he said he wanted
to leave at once,
but Lady Lavinia's persuaded him
to stay until tomorrow
to make less of a thing of it.
-[Door Opens ]
-[Sylvia ] Oh, thank heavens.
Lewis told me
you were wearing white.
white?. she must be mad.
I never wear white.
I thought
it was a little odd.
By the way, for God's sake,
don't rub him up tonight.
- I don't know what you mean.
- you know exactlywhat I mean.
He's in a filthy mood
with everyone.
He's talking about
stopping your allowance.
But it's for life.
That was settled. He can't do that.
Justyou watch him.
He's absolutely spoiling for a fight.
so ifyou'll take my advice,
you won't give him one.
[Door Closes ]
Now, thatyou can be
discreet about.
Thankyou.
[Lavinia ]
Goodness, isn't it prettyhere?
The house has
such lovely position.
The best view's
from the old water tower.
you might well
walk up there tomorrow.
Do you really have to
go back to London?.
I am afraid so,
Raymond.
when you're ruined,
there's so much to do.
yes, there is,
isn't there?.
Moan, moan, moan.
[whispering]
would anybody care for
a game ofbridge after dinner?.
[Nesbitt]
Oh,yes, I wouldn't mind.
who else?.
Louisa, how about you?.
Oh, I don't think so.
I've rather gone off cards.
I've never been very lucky
with them.
Me too.
Mr. weissman, tell us about
the film you're going to make.
Oh, sure. It's called Charlie Chan
in London. It's a detective story.
- set in London?.
- well, not really.
Most of it takes place at
a shooting party in a country house,
sort of like this one,
actually.
A murder in the middle ofthe night.
A lot ofguests for the weekend.
Everyone's a suspect.
That sort of thing.
How horrid.
And who turns out
to have done it?
I couldn't tell you that.
It would spoil it foryou.
- Oh, but none of us will see it.
- [ Gasps, Chuckles ]
Are you thinking of
making it here, Mr. weissman?.
Uh, no, we're going to shoot it
in Hollywood, on the back lot.
Butsince I was in England,
I thought I would do
a little research on country living...
and Ivor was kind enough
to arrange it for me.
Mm m, no.
wil I iam arranged it for you.
- [ weissman ]
Are you interested in films, sir?
- [ scoffs ] Not likely.
why shouldn't I
be interested in films?.
you don't know
what I'm interested in.
well, I know you're interested in money
and fiddling with your guns,
but when it comes to anything else,
I'm stumped.
That is not fair.
Bill is--
[ Laughs ]
Elsie.
Elsie, what's--
It's not as if
I didn't know.
- [ Chuckling ]
- so we can all play bridge.
- All playing?.
- who's going to play bridge?.
Are they going to play?.
where's Rupert?.
- Rupert!
- [Standish ] Coming.
[whispering]
- I heard Lady Sylvia spoke out ofturn.
- you didn't actually see?.