Long ago, in the far away land
of ancient Greece...
there was a golden age
of powerful gods...
and extraordinary heroes.
And the greatest and strongest
of all these heroes...
was the mighty Hercules.
But what is the measure
of a true hero?
That is what our story is...
Will you listen to him?
He's makin' the story sound
like some Greek tragedy.
Lighten up, dude.
We'll take it
from here, darling.
You go, girl.
We are the Muses...
goddesses of the arts
and proclaimers of heroes.
Heroes like Hercules.
Honey, you mean "Hunk-ules."
I'd like to make some sweet
music with him...
Our story actually begins...
long before Hercules,
many eons ago
Back when the world was new
The planet Earth was
down on its luck
And everywhere gigantic brutes
called Titans ran amok
It was a nasty place
There was a mess
wherever you stepped
Where chaos reigned
and the earthquakes and
volcanos never slept
Say it, girlfriend!
And then along came Zeus
- He hurled his thunderbolt
- He zapped
Locked those suckers in a vault
They're trapped
And on his own,
stopped chaos in its tracks
And that's the gospel truth
The guy was too "Type A"
to just relax
And that's
the world's first dish
Yeah, baby.
Zeus tamed the globe
while still in his youth
Though, honey,
it may seem impossible
That's the gospel truth
On Mount Olympus, life was neat
And smooth as sweet vermouth
Although, honey,
it may seem impossible
That's the gospel truth
Hercules!
Behave yourself.
Oh, look at this.
Look how cute he is.
He's strong like his dad, hmm?
Excuse me!
Hot stuff coming through!
Excuse me. One side, Ares.
Why, Hermes, they're lovely.
Yeah, you know, I had Orpheus
do the arrangement.
Isn't that too nutty?
Fabulous party.
You know, I haven't seen...
this much love in a room since
Narcissus discovered himself.
Dear, keep those away
from the baby.
He won't hurt himself.
Let the kid have a little fun.
On behalf of my son,
I want to thank you all...
for your wonderful gifts!
What about our gift, dear?
Well, let's see here.
We'll take... yes.
A little cirrus...
and a touch of nimbostratus...
and a dash of cumulus.
His name is Pegasus,
and he's all yours, son.
Mind his head.
He's so tiny.
My boy.
My little Hercules.
How sentimental.
You know, I haven't
been this choked up...
since I got a hunk of moussaka
caught in my throat!
So is this an audience
or a mosaic?
Hey, how you doin'?
Lookin' good. Nice dress.
So, Hades, you finally made it.
How are things
in the underworld?
Well, they're just fine.
You know... a little dark,
a little gloomy.
And, as always,
full of dead people.
What are you gonna do?
There's the little sunspot.
Little snootchie.
And here is a sucker...
for the little sucker, eh?
Here you go. Ya just...
Powerful little tyke.
Come on, Hades.
Don't be such a stiff.
Join the celebration!
Love to, babe...
but unlike you gods
lounging about up here...
I regrettably have
a full-time gig...
that you, by the way, so
charitably bestowed on me, Zeus.
So... can't.
Love to, but can't.
You ought to slow down.
You'll work yourself to death.
Work yourself to death!
I kill myself!
If only. If only.
If there's one god...
you don't want to get
steamed up, it's Hades.
'Cause he had an evil plan.
He ran the underworld
But thought the dead were
dull and uncouth
He was as mean
as he was ruthless
And that's the gospel truth
He had a plan
to shake things up
And that's the gospel truth
Pain!
Coming, your most
lugubriousness.
Panic!
I'm sorry. I can handle it!
- Pain!
- And Panic!
Reporting for duty!
Fine, fine, fine.
Just let me know the instant
the Fates arrive.
They're here.
What? The Fates are here,
and you didn't tell me?
We are worms!
Worthless worms!
Memo to me, memo to me.
Maim you after my meeting.
Darling, hold that
mortal's thread of life...
good and tight.
Incoming!
Ladies! I am so sorry that I'm...
- Late!
- We knew you would be.
We know everything.
- Past...
- Present...
And future.
Indoor plumbing...
it's gonna be big.
Great, great.
Anyway, see, ladies...
I was at this party,
and I lost track of...
- We know!
- Yeah. I know... you know.
So here's the deal:
Zeus, Mr High And Mighty...
Mr "Hey, You, Get Off
of My Cloud," now he has...
- A bouncing baby brat.
- We know!
I know... you know.
I know. I got it.
I got the concept.
So let me just ask:
Is this kid gonna mess up
my hostile takeover bid,
or what? What do you think?
Oh, no, you don't.
We're not supposed to reveal
the future.
Wait. I'm sorry.
Time out. Can l...
Can I ask you a question,
by the way? Are you...
Did you cut your hair
or something?
You look fabulous.
I mean, you look like a Fate
worse than death.
- Oh, gross!
- It's blinkin'!
Ladies, please. My fate...
is in your lovely hands.
All right.
In 18 years precisely,
the planets will align...
- ever so nicely.
- Ay, verse. Oy.
The time to act
will be at hand.
Unleash the Titans,
your monstrous band.
Good, good.
Then the once-proud Zeus
will finally fall...
and you, Hades, will rule all!
Yes! Hades rules!
- A word of caution to this tale.
- Excuse me?
Should Hercules fight,
you will fail.
What?
OK, fine, fine.
I'm cool. I'm fine.
Pain? Panic?
Got a little riddle for ya.
How do you kill a god?
I do not know!
You can't.
They're immortal?
Bingo! They're immortal.
So, first you got to turn
the little sunspot...
mortal.
- What?
- What is it?
The baby!
No!
Now we did it! Zeus is gonna
use us for target practice!
Just hang onto the kid, Panic.
Hurry! Let's just kill the kid
and get it over with, OK?
Here you go, kid. A little
Grecian formula.
Look at that! He's... changing.
Can we do it now?
No, no, no. He has to drink
the whole potion.
Every last drop.
Who's there?
Alcmene, over here.
Oh, you poor thing.
- Oh, don't cry.
- Is anybody there?
Now?
Oh. Well, he must have
been abandoned.
Amphitryon, for so many years...
we've prayed to the gods
to bless us with a child.
Perhaps they've answered
our prayers
Perhaps they have.
"Hercules"?
Help, help, help!
Hades is gonna kill us when
he finds out what happened.
You mean, if he finds out.
Of course he's gonna f...
lf. If is good.
It was tragic.
Zeus led all the gods
on a frantic search.
But by the time
they found the baby...
it was too late.
Young Herc was mortal now
But since he did not
drink the last drop
He still retained
his godlike strength
So thank his lucky stars
Tell it, girl.
But Zeus and Hera wept
Because their son could
never come home
They'd have to watch
their precious baby
Grow up from afar
Though Hades' horrid plan
Was hatched before Herc
cut his first tooth
The boy grew stronger
every day
And that's the gospel truth
The gospel truth
Hercules, slow down!
Look out!
Sorry, guys.
- Hey, watch where you're goin'.
- Sunday driver!
Thanks, son.
When old Penelope twisted
her ankle back there...
I thought we were done for.
No problem, Pop.
Don't unload just yet.
First, I have to finagle
with Phideas.
Sorry, Penelope.
Now, Hercules, this time,
please just...
I know.
Stay by the cart.
That's my boy.
Oh, my goodness. Whoa!
Careful!
- Why, thank you.
- No problem.
Why, Hercules!
It's you!
Let me help you with that.
No, no, I got it!
I'm fine.
You just run along.
- Are you sure?
- Oh, yes.
Absolutely.
Give it here!
Hey, you need an extra guy?
Sorry, Herc.
We already got five...
and we want to keep it
an even number.
Wait a second.
Five isn't an even...
- See ya, Herc.
- What a geek!
Destructo Boy.
Maybe we should
call him "Jerkules."
Heads up!
I got it!
No! Stop!
It's OK.
- Son!
- Hang on, Pop! Be right back!
Oh, no!
Watch out!
Nice catch, Jerkules.
Son...
This is the last straw,
Amphitryon!
That boy is a menace!
He's too dangerous
to be around normal people!
He didn't mean any harm.
He's just a kid.
He just can't control
his strength.
I'm warning you.
You keep that...
freak away from here!
Freak! Yeah, go away!
Son, you shouldn't let...
those things they said back
there get to you.
But Pop, they're right.
I am a freak.
I try to fit in.
I really do.
I just can't.
Sometimes... I feel like...
like I really don't
belong here...
like I'm supposed to be...
someplace else.
Hercules, son...
I know it doesn't
make any sense.
I have often dreamed
Of a far off place
Where a great, warm welcome
will be waiting for me
Where the crowds will cheer
When they see my face
And a voice keeps sayin'
this is where I'm meant to be
I will find my way
I can go the distance
I'll be there someday
If I can be strong
I know every mile
Will be worth my while
I would go most anywhere
to feel like I
Belong
Hercules, there's something
your mother and I...
have been meaning to tell ya.
But if you found me,
then where did I come from?
Why was I left here?
This was around your neck
when we found you.
It's the symbol of the gods.
This is it!
Don't you see?
Maybe they have the answers!
I'll go to the temple
of Zeus and...
Ma, Pop, you're
the greatest parents...
anyone could have, but...
I gotta know.
I am on my way
I can go the distance
I don't care how far
Somehow, I'll be strong
I know every mile
Will be worth my while
I would go most anywhere
To find where I belong
Oh, mighty Zeus, please,
hear me and answer my prayer.
I need to know: Who am I?
Where do I belong?
My boy.
My little Hercules.
Hold on, kiddo!
What's your hurry?
After all these years...
is this the kind of hello
you give your father?
Father?
Didn't know you had
a famous father, did you?
Surprise!
Look how you've grown.
Why, you've got your mother's
beautiful eyes...
and my strong chin.
I don't understand.
If you're my father,
that would make me a...
A god.
Hey, you wanted answers,
and by thunder...
you're old enough now
to know the truth.
But why did you
leave me on earth?
Didn't you want me?
Of course we did.
Your mother and I loved you
with all our hearts.
Someone stole you from us
and turned you mortal...
and only gods can live
on Mount Olympus.
And you can't do a thing?
I can't, Hercules, but you can.
Really? What?
I'll do anything.
Hercules, if you can
prove yourself...
a true hero on earth...
your godhood will be restored!
A true hero. Great!
Exactly how do you
become a true hero?
First, you must seek out
Philoctetes...
the trainer of heroes.
Seek out Philoctetes.
Right. I'll...
Hold your horses!
Which reminds me.
You probably don't
remember Pegasus...
but you two go way back, son.
Pegasus!
He's a magnificent horse...
with the brain of a bird.
I'll find Philoctetes
and become a true hero.
That's the spirit!
I won't let you down, Father!
Good luck, son.
I will beat the odds
I can go the distance
I will face the world
Fearless, proud and strong
I will please the gods
I can go the distance
Till I find my hero's welcome
Right where I
Belong
You sure this is
the right place?
What's the matter, little guy?
You stuck?
Butt out, buddy!
Girls! Stop! Come back!
Geez!
Wait!
Oh, nymphs!
They can't keep
their hands off me.
What's the matter?
You never seen a satyr before?
Can you help us?
We're looking for someone
called Philoctetes.
Call me Phil.
Boy, am I glad to meet you!
I'm Hercules.
And this is Pegasus.
Animals! Disgusting!
I need your help.
I want to become a hero,
a true hero.
Sorry, kid. Can't help ya.
Wait!
Sorry.
- Why not?
- Two words: I am retired.
Look, I gotta do this.
Haven't you ever had a dream...
something you wanted so bad
you'd do anything?
Kid, come inside.
I want to show you something.
Watch it! That was part
of the mast of the Argo.
The Argo?
Who do you think taught Jason
how to sail? Cleopatra?
I trained all those
would-be heroes.
Odysseus, Perseus, Theseus.
A lot of "yeuseus."
And every single one
of those bums let me down...
flatter than a discus.
None of 'em could
go the distance.
And then there was Achilles.
Now, there was a guy
who had it all...
the build, the foot speed.
He could jab, he could take
a hit, he could keep on comin'.
But that furshlugginer heel
of his!
He barely gets nicked there
once and... kaboom!
He's history.
Yeah, I had a dream once.
I dreamed I was gonna train...
the greatest hero
there ever was.
So great, the gods would hang
a picture of him in the stars...
all across the sky...
and people would say,
"That's Phil's boy."
That's right.
But dreams are for rookies.
A guy can only take
so much disappointment.
But I'm different
than those other guys, Phil!
I can go the distance.
Come on. I'll show you.
Geez! You don't give up, do ya?
Watch this.
Holy Hera.
You know, maybe if l... No!
Snap out of it!
I'm too old to get mixed up
in this stuff again.
But if I don't become
a true hero...
I'll never be able to rejoin
my father, Zeus.
Hold it!
Zeus is your father, right?
Zeus. The big guy.
He's your daddy.
Mr Lightning Bolts! Read me
a book, would ya, Da-da?
"Once upon a time"!
It's the truth!
Please!
So you wanna be a hero, kid
Well, whoop-de-do
I have been
around the block before
With blockheads just like you
Each and every one
a disappointment
Pain for which
there ain't no ointment
So much for excuses
Though a kid of Zeus is
Askin' me to jump into the fray
My answer is two words
OK.
- You mean you'll do it?
- You win.
- You won't be sorry, Phil.
- Oh, gods.
So when do we start?
Can we start now?
Oy, vay.
I'd given up hope
that someone would come
Along
A fella who'd ring the bell
for once
Not the gong
The kind who wins trophies
Won't settle for low fees
At least semipro fees
But, no
I get the greenhorn
I've been out to pasture, pal
My ambition gone
Content to spend lazy days
and to graze my lawn
But you need an advisor
A satyr, but wiser
A good merchandiser and... whoa!
There goes my ulcer
I'm down to one last hope
and I hope it's you
Though, kid, you're not exactly
a dream come true
I trained enough turkeys
Who never came through
You're my one last hope
So you'll have to do
Rule #6: When rescuing
a damsel...
always handle with care.
Rule #95, kid: Concentrate!
Rule #96: Aim!
Demigods have faced the odds
And ended up a mockery
Don't believe the stories
That you read
on all the crockery
To be a true hero, kid,
is a dying art
Like paintin' a masterpiece
It's a work of heart
It takes more than sinew
Comes down to what's in you
You have to continue to grow
Now, that's more like it!
I'm down to one last shot
And my last high note
Before that blasted underworld
gets my goat
My dreams are on you, kid
Go make 'em come true
Climb that uphill slope
Keep pushin' that envelope
You're my one last hope
And, kid, it's up to you
Did you see that?
Next stop, Olympus.
All right,
just take it easy, champ.
I am ready. I want to
get off this island.
I want to see battles
and monsters.
Rescue some damsels.
You know, heroic stuff.
- Well...
- Aw, come on! Phil!
Well, OK. You want a road test?
Saddle up, kid.
We're going to Thebes!
- So what's in Thebes?
- A lot of problems.
It's a big, tough town. Good
place to start buildin' a rep.
Sounds like your basic D.I. D...
damsel in distress.
Not so fast, sweetheart.
I swear, Nessus.
Put me down or I'll...
I like 'em fiery!
Now, remember, kid.
First, analyse the situation.
Don't just barrel in there
without thinking.
He's losin' points for this!
- You don't know what you're...
- Halt!
Step aside, two legs.
Pardon me, my good sir.
I'll have to ask you...
to release that young...
- Keep movin', junior.
- Lady.
But you... aren't you
a damsel in distress?
I'm a damsel.
I'm in distress.
I can handle this.
Have a nice day.
Ma'am, I'm afraid you may be...
too close to the situation
to realize...
What are you doin'?
Get your sword!
Sword. Right.
Rule #15: A hero is only
as good as his weapon!
Hold it! Hold on!
He's gotta do it on his own.
Come on, kid! Concentrate!
Use your head!
All right! Not bad, kid!
Not exactly what I had in mind,
but not bad.
Gee, miss.
I'm really sorry.
That was dumb.
Excuse me.
Nice work! Excelente!
Is Wonderboy here for real?
What are you talkin' about?
Of course he's real.
And by the way, sweet cheeks,
I'm real too.
- How was that, Phil?
- Rein it in, rookie.
You can get away with mistakes
like those...
in the minor decathlons,
but this is the big leagues!
At least I beat him,
didn't I?
Next time, don't let
your guard down...
because of a pair
of big goo-goo eyes!
D-oh! It's like
I keep tellin' ya.
You gotta stay focused,
and... you...
Are you all right, Miss...
Megara. My friends call me Meg.
At least, they would
if I had any friends.
So did they give you a name...
along with all those
rippling pectorals?
Are you always this articulate?
Hercules. My name is Hercules.
I think I prefer Wonderboy.
So...
how'd you get mixed up
with the...
Pinhead with hooves?
Well, you know how men are.
They think that
"no" means "yes"...
and "get lost" means
"take me. I'm yours."
Don't worry. Shorty here can
explain it to ya later.
Well, thanks for everything,
Herc.
It's been a real slice.
Wait! Can we give you a ride?
I don't think your pinto
likes me very much.
Pegasus? Don't be silly.
He'd be more than happy to...
I'll be all right.
I'm a big, tough girl.
I tie my own sandals
and everything.
Bye-bye, Wonderboy.
She's something.
Isn't she, Phil?
She's really something.
A real pain in the patella!
Earth to Herc! Come in, Herc!
Come in, Herc!
We got a job to do, remember?
Thebes is still waitin'.
Yeah. I know.
How cute.
A couple of rodents
looking for a theme park.
Who you callin' a rodent,
sister?
- I'm a bunny!
- And I'm his gopher.
I thought I smelled a rat.
Speak of the devil.
Meg, my little flower,
my little bird...
my little nut, Meg.
What exactly happened here?
I thought you were gonna
persuade the river guardian...
to join my team
for the uprising...
and here I am, kind of
river guardian-less.
I gave it my best shot...
but he made me an offer
I had to refuse.
Fine. So, instead of subtracting
two years from your sentence...
hey, I'm gonna add two on, OK?
Give that your best shot.
Look, it wasn't my fault.
It was this wonderboy, Hercules.
Hercules? Why does that name
ring a bell?
I don't know.
Maybe we owe him money?
What was that name again?
He comes on with this big,
innocent farm boy routine...
but I could see through that
in a Peloponnesian minute.
Wait a minute.
Wasn't Hercules...
the name of that kid
we were supposed to...
Oh, my gods!
Run for it!
So you took care of him, huh?
"Dead as a door nail."
Weren't those your exact words?
This might be
a different Hercules.
I mean, Hercules is
a very popular name nowadays!
Remember, like,
a few years ago...
every other boy was named
Jason...
and the girls were all
named Brittany?
I'm about to rearrange
the cosmos...
and the one schlemiel
who can louse it up...
is waltzing around in the woods!
Wait, big guy.
We can still cut in
on his waltzing.
That's right! And at least
we made him mortal.
That's a good thing.
Didn't we?
Fortunately
for the three of you...
we still have time to correct
this rather egregious oversight.
And this time, no foul-ups.
Is that all one town?
One town, a million troubles.
The one and only Thebes.
The Big Olive itself.
If you can make it there,
you can make it anywhere.
Stick with me, kid.
This city is a dangerous place.
Look where you're goin',
numbskull!
Hey, I'm walkin' here!
You see what I mean?
I'm tellin' you... wackos.
Pita bread. Pita bread.
Get your pita bread here.
- Hey, Mack.
- Whoa!
You wanna buy a sundial?
He's not interested, all right?
Come on, kid.
The end is coming!
Can't you feel it?
Yes. Thank you for the info.
We'll ponder that for awhile.
Just stare at the sidewalk.
Come on. Don't make eye contact.
People here are nuts.
That's because they live
in a city of turmoil.
Trust me, kid. You're gonna be
just what the doctor ordered.
It was tragic! We lost
everything in the fire.
Everything... except
old Snowball here.
Now, were the fires before
or after the earthquake?
They were after the earthquake.
I remember.
But before the flood.
Don't even get me started
on the crime rate.
Thebes has certainly
gone downhill
- in a hurry.
- Tell me about it.
It seems like every time
I turn around...
there's some new monster
wreaking havoc and l...
All we need now is
a plague of locusts.
That's it! I'm movin' to Sparta!
Excuse me.
It...
seems to me that what
you folks need is a hero.
Yeah, and who are you?
I'm Hercules, and...
I happen to be a hero.
Is that so?
Some hero!
Have you ever saved
a town before?
No, not exactly, but l...
Have you ever reversed
a natural disaster?
Well, no.
Listen to this. He's just
another chariot chaser.
- This we need.
- That's a laugh.
Don't you pea brains get it?
This kid is the genuine article.
Isn't that the goat-man
who trained Achilles?
Watch it, pal.
Yeah, you're right.
Hey, nice job on those heels!
Ya missed a spot!
I got your heel right here!
I'll wipe that stupid grin off
your face! You...
Hey, Phil! Take it easy.
What are you, crazy?
Young man, we need
a professional hero...
not an amateur.
Well, wait. Stop!
How am I supposed
to prove myself a hero...
if nobody will give me a chance?
You'll get your chance.
You just need some kind...
of catastrophe or disaster.
Please.
Help! Please! There's been
a terrible accident!
Speakin' of disasters.
Wonderboy! Hercules!
- Thank goodness!
- What's wrong?
Outside of town,
two little boys.
They were playing in the gorge.
There was this rock slide,
a terrible rock slide.
- They're trapped!
- Kids? Trapped?
Phil, this is great!
You're really choked up
about this, aren't ya?
- Come on!
- No, l... You don't under...
I have this terrible fear
of heights!
I'm right behind ya, kid!
I'm way behind ya, kid.
I got a fur wedgie.
- Are you OK?
- I'll be fine.
Just get me down
before I ruin the upholstery.
Help! I can't breathe!
Hurry!
- Get us out!
- We're suffocating!
Somebody call IX-l-I!
Easy, fellas.
You'll be all right.
We can't last much longer!
Get us out
before we get crushed!
- How you boys doin'?
- We're OK now.
Jeepers, mister.
You're really strong.
Well, try to be a little more
careful next time, OK, kids?
We sure will.
A stirring performance, boys.
I was really moved.
"Jeepers, mister"?
I was going for innocence.
And, hey, two thumbs way, way up
for our leading lady.
What a dish. What a doll.
Get outta there, you big lug,
while you still can.
Phil, I did great.
They even applauded... sort of.
I hate to burst
your bubble, kid...
but that ain't applause.
Phil? What do you call
that thing?
Two words: Am-scray!
Let's get ready to rumble!
That's it. Dance around!
Watch the teeth.
Keep movin'. Come on.
Lead with your left!
Your other left!
All right!
You're bad! OK!
See, Phil?
That wasn't so hard.
Kid. How many horns do ya see?
Six?
Close enough.
Let's get you cleaned up.
Guys, relax.
It's only half-time.
That doesn't sound good.
Definitely not good!
Will you forget
the head-slicing thing?
Phil, I don't think we covered
this one in basic training!
My favourite part of the game:
Sudden death.
There goes another one.
Just like Achilles.
Game...
set... match.
Phil, you gotta admit.
That was pretty heroic.
Ya did it, kid!
You won by a landslide!
Hades mad.
Well, what do ya know?
From that day forward, our boy
Hercules could do no wrong.
He was so hot,
steam looked cool.
Bless my soul
Herc was on a roll
Person of the week
in every Greek opinion poll
- What a pro
- Herc could stop a show
Point him at a monster
and you're talkin' S.R.O.
- He was a no one
- A zero, zero
Now he's a honcho
He's a hero
Here was a kid
with his act down pat
Zero to hero in no time flat
Zero to hero
Just like that
When he smiled
the girls went wild
With oohs and aahs
And they slapped his face
on every vase
On every "vahse"
From appearance fees
and royalties
Our Herc had cash to burn
Now nouveau riche and famous
He could tell you what's
a Grecian urn
Say amen
There he goes again
- Sweet and undefeated
- And an awesome ten for ten
Folks lined up
just to watch him flex
And this perfect package
packed a pair of pretty pecs
Hercie, he comes, he sees,
he conquers
Honey, the crowds were
goin' bonkers
He showed the moxie
Brains and spunk
From zero to hero
A major hunk
Zero to hero
And who'd have thunk
Who put the glad in gladiator?
Hercules
Who's darin' deeds are
great theatre
Hercules
- Isn't he bold
- No one braver
- Is he sweet
- Our favourite flavour
- Hercules
- My man.
Look at my Hercules
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Bless my soul
Herc was on a roll
Undefeated
Riding high
- And the nicest guy.
- Not conceited
- He was a nothing
- Zero, zero
- Now he's a honcho
- He's our hero
He hit the heights
at breakneck speed
From zero to hero
Herc is a hero
Now he's a hero
Yes, indeed
Pull!
Nice shootin', Rex.
I can't believe this guy.
I throw everything
I've got at him...
and it doesn't even...
What are those?
I don't know.
I thought they looked
kinda dashing.
I've got 24 hours
to get rid of this bozo...
or the entire scheme
I've been setting up...
for eighteen years
goes up in smoke...
and you are wearing
his merchandise!
Thirsty?
Looks like your game's over.
Wonderboy is hitting
every curve you throw at him.
I wonder if maybe
I haven't been throwing...
the right curves at him,
Meg, my sweet.
Don't even go there.
See, he's gotta have
a weakness...
because everybody's
got a weakness.
I mean, for what? Pandora,
it was the box thing.
For the Trojans, hey.
They bet on the wrong horse, OK?
We simply need to find out
Wonderboy's.
I've done my part.
Get your little imps...
They couldn't
handle him as a baby.
I need somebody who can...
handle him as a man.
Hey, I've sworn off manhandling.
Well, you know, that's good
because that's what got you...
into this jam in the first
place, isn't it?
You sold your soul to me
to save your boyfriend's life.
And how does
this creep thank you?
By running off with some babe.
He hurt you real bad,
didn't he, Meg? Huh?
Look, I learned my lesson, OK?
Which is exactly why
I got a feelin'...
you're gonna leap
at my new offer.
You give me the key to bringing
down Wonder Breath...
and I give you the thing
that you crave most...
in the entire cosmos:
Your freedom.
You should have
been there, Father.
I mangled the Minotaur...
grappled with the Gorgon.
Just like Phil told me.
I analysed the situation...
controlled my strength,
and kicked.
The crowds went wild!
Thank you.
You're doin' great, son.
You're doing your old man proud.
I'm glad to hear you
say that, Father.
I've been waiting for this day
a long time.
What day is that, son?
The day I rejoin the gods.
You've done wonderfully.
You really have, my boy.
You're just not there yet.
You haven't proven yourself
a true hero.
But, Father, I've beaten
every single monster...
I've come up against.
I'm the most famous person...
in all of Greece.
I'm an action figure!
I'm afraid being famous
isn't the same...
as being a true hero.
What more can I do?
It's something you have to
discover for yourself.
- But how can l...
- Look inside your heart.
Father, wait!
On your left is Hercules' villa.
Our next stop is the Pecs
and Flex Gift Shop...
where you can pick up
the great hero's...
30-minute work-out scroll...
"Buns of Bronze."
At 1:00, you got a meeting
with King Augeas.
He's got a problem
with his stables.
I'd advise you not to wear
your new sandals.
I told you, don't move!
...D.G. R, the Daughters
of the Greek Revolution.
At 3:00, you gotta get a girdle
from some Amazons.
Phil, what's the point?
That's it!
Keep your toga on, pal.
What d'you mean,
"What's the point?"
You wanna go to Olympus,
don't ya?
Yeah, but this stuff doesn't
seem to be getting me anywhere.
You can't give up now.
I'm countin' on ya.
I gave this everything I had.
Listen to me, kid.
I seen 'em all.
And I am tellin' you... and this
is the honest-to-Zeus truth...
you got somethin'
I never seen before.
- Really?
- I can feel it...
right down to these
stubby bowlegs of mine.
There is nothin'
you can't do, kid.
- It's him!
- Hey, watch it!
- I touched his elbow!
- I got his sweatband!
Phil, help!
- OK. Escape plan beta.
- Gotcha.
Where is he?
There he goes! On the veranda!
Let's see. What could be
behind curtain number one?
It's all right.
The sea of raging hormones
has ebbed.
Gee, it's great to see you.
I missed you.
So this is what heroes do
on their days off.
I'm no hero.
Sure ya are.
Everybody in Greece...
thinks you're
the greatest thing...
since they put the pocket
in pita.
I know. It's crazy.
You know, I can't go anywhere
without being mobbed. I mean...
You sound like
you could use a break.
Think your nanny goat
would go...
berserk if you played hooky
this afternoon?
Oh, gee. I don't know.
Phil's got the rest
of the day pretty much booked.
Phil, schmill.
Just follow me.
Out the window,
round the dumbbells...
you lift up the back wall
and we're gone.
Wow. What a day.
First, that restaurant
by the bay...
and then that, that play,
that, that Oedipus thing.
Man! I thought I had problems.
- Stop foolin' around!
- Get the goods, sister.
I didn't know that playing hooky
could be so much fun.
Neither did I.
Thanks, Meg.
Don't thank me just yet.
Careful.
Sorry. Weak ankles.
Yeah? Well, maybe you
better sit down for a while.
So, do you have any problems...
with things like this?
Weak ankles, I mean.
No. Not really.
No weaknesses... whatsoever?
No trick knee?
Ruptured... disks?
No. I'm afraid I'm fit
as a fiddle.
Wonderboy, you are perfect.
Thanks.
It looks better that way.
No, it really does.
You know, when I was a kid...
I would have given anything...
to be exactly like
everybody else.
You wanted to be
petty and dishonest?
Everybody's not like that.
- Yes, they are.
- You're not like that.
- How do you know what I'm like?
- All I know is...
you're the most amazing person
with...
weak ankles I've ever met.
Meg, when I'm with you...
I don't feel so... alone.
Sometimes it's better
to be alone.
What do you mean?
Nobody can hurt you.
Meg? I would never,
ever hurt you.
And I don't wanna hurt you,
so
let's both do ourselves
a favour and...
stop this before... we...
All right! Break it up!
Break it up! Party's over!
I been lookin' all over
this town!
Calm down, mutton man.
It was all my fault.
You're already on my list,
sister...
so don't make it worse!
And as for you, ya bum, you're
gonna go to the stadium...
and you're gonna be put through
the work-out of your life!
Now get on the horse.
- I'm sorry.
- He'll get over it.
Move!
Hey, watch it!
Keep your goo-goo eyes on the...
That's it. Next time, I drive.
What's the matter with me?
You'd think a girl would learn.
If there's a prize
for rotten judgement
I guess I've already won that
No man is worth the aggravation
That's ancient history
Been there, done that
Who d'ya think you're kidding
He's the earth and heaven
to you
Try to keep it hidden
Honey, we can see
right through you
- Oh, no
- Girl, you can't conceal it
We know how you feel
and who you're thinkin' of
Oh-ho
No chance, no way
I won't say it, no, no
You swoon, you sigh
Why deny it, uh-oh
It's too cliche
I won't say I'm in love
Shoo-doo, shoo-doo
Oo-oo-oo
I thought my heart had
learned its lesson
It feels so good
when you start out
- Ah
- My head is screaming
Get a grip, girl
Unless you're dyin'
To cry your heart out
- Oh
- You keep on denying
Who you are
and how you're feelin'
Baby, we're not buyin'
Hon, we saw you
hit the ceilin'
Face it like a grownup
When you gonna own up that you
- Got
Got it bad
Oh, no chance, no way
I won't say it, no, no
Give up, but give in
Check the grin
You're in love
This scene won't play
I won't say I'm in love
You're doing flips
Read our lips
You're in love
- Shoo-doo, shoo-doo
- You're way off base
- I won't say I'm it
- She won't say in love
Get off my case
I won't say it
Girl, don't be proud
It's OK, you're in love
Oh
At least out loud
I won't say I'm in
- Love
- Shoo-doo, shoo-doo
Shoo-doo, shoo-doo
Sha-la-la-la-la-la-la
Hey, what's the buzz, Meg?
What is the weak link
in Wonderboy's chain?
Get yourself another girl.
I'm through.
I'm sorry. Do you mind
runnin' that by me again?
I must have had a chunk of
brimstone wedged in my ear...
- or something.
- Then read my lips! Forget it.
Meg, my sweet deluded
little minion.
Aren't we forgetting one
teensy-weensy...
but ever so crucial
little, tiny detail?
I own you!
I got another horn here.
You work for me.
That kid's gonna be doin' laps
for a month.
If I say "sing," you say,
"Hey, name that tune."
If I say, "I want Wonderboy's
head on a platter," you say...
"Medium or well-done?"
I knew that dame was trouble.
This is gonna break
the kid's heart.
I'll work on that.
I'm sorry. You hear that sound?
That's the sound
of your freedom...
fluttering out the window
forever.
I don't care. I'm not gonna
help you hurt him.
I can't believe you're
getting so worked up...
about some guy.
This one is different.
He's honest...
- and he's sweet...
- Please!
He would never do anything
to hurt me.
He's a guy!
Besides, oh, oneness,
you can't beat him.
He has no weaknesses.
He's gonna...
I think he does, Meg.
I truly think he does.
Hey, Phil! What happened to you?
Kid, we gotta talk.
Phil, I just had the
greatest day of my life!
I can't stop thinking about Meg.
She's something else.
Kid, I'm tryin' to talk to ya!
Will you come down here
and listen?
How can I come down there
when I'm feeling so up?
Gotcha!
Very nice!
What I'm tryin' to say is...
That if it wasn't for you,
I never would have met her.
I owe ya big time,
little guy, I do.
Will you just knock it off
for a couple of seconds?
Rule #38. Come on, Phil.
Keep them up there, huh?
Phil, I got two words
for ya: Duck!
- Listen to me! She's...
- A dream come true?
- Not exactly.
- More beautiful than Aphrodite?
- Aside from that!
- The most wonderful...
She's a fraud!
She's been playin' ya for a sap!
Come on.
Stop kiddin' around.
I'm not kiddin' around.
I know you're upset
about today...
- but that's no reason to...
- Kid, you're missin' the point.
The point is I love her.
- She don't love you.
- You're crazy.
She's nothin'
but a two-timin'...
- Stop it!
- No-good, lyin', schemin'...
Shut up!
Phil. L... I'm sorry.
OK, that's it. You won't
face the truth? Fine.
Phil, wait. Where you going?
I'm hoppin' the first barge out
of here. I'm goin' home.
Fine! Go!
I don't need you.
I thought you were gonna be
the all-time champ...
not the all-time chump.
Geez Louise!
What got his goat, huh?
Baboom. Name is Hades,
Lord of the Dead.
- Hi. How ya doin'?
- Not now, OK?
I only need a few seconds...
and I'm a fast talker,
all right?
See, I've got the major deal
in the works.
A real estate venture,
if you will.
And Herc, you little devil you.
May I call you Herc?
You seem to be constantly
getting in the way of it.
You've got the wrong guy.
Hear me out, ya little...
Just... hear me out, OK?
So I would be eternally grateful
if you would just...
take a day off from this
hero business of yours.
Geez, I mean, monsters,
natural disasters.
- Phew. You wait a day, OK?
- You're out of your mind.
Not so fast, because, ya see,
I do have a little leverage...
you might wanna know about.
- Meg!
- Don't listen, Herc...
- Let her go!
- Here's the trade-off.
You give up your strength
for about 24 hours, OK?
Say the next 24 hours.
And Meg here is free as a bird
and safe from harm.
We dance, we kiss,
we schmooze...
we carry on, we go home happy.
What d'ya say? Come on.
People are gonna get hurt,
aren't they?
Nah! I mean, it's, you know,
it's a possibility.
It happens 'cause, you know,
it's war.
But what can I tell ya? Anyway.
What do you owe these people?
Isn't Meg... little smoochy face...
isn't she more important
than they are?
- Stop it!
- Isn't she?
You've gotta swear she'll be
safe from any harm.
Fine, OK.
I'll give you that one.
Meg is safe, otherwise you get
your strength right back.
Yadda, yadda. Fine print.
Boilerplate. Baboom. OK?
We're done. What d'ya say
we shake on it?
Hey, I really don't have, like,
time to bat this around.
I'm kind of on a schedule here.
I got plans for August.
I need an answer, like, now.
Going once, going twice...
- All right!
- Yes, we're there! Bam!
You may feel just a little
queasy. It's kinda natural.
Maybe you should sit down!
Now you know how it feels...
to be just like everybody else.
Isn't it just peachy?
You'll love this.
One more thing.
Meg, babe, a deal's a deal.
You're off the hook.
And by the way, Herc,
is she not, like...
- a fabulous little actress?
- Stop it.
- What do you mean?
- I mean...
your little chickie-poo here...
was working for me all the time.
You're lying!
Help!
Jeepers, mister,
you're really strong.
Couldn't have done it without
you, sugar, sweetheart, babe.
No! It's not like that.
I didn't mean to...
I couldn't... l...
I'm so sorry.
Our hero's a zero!
Well, gotta blaze.
There's a whole cosmos up there
waiting for me...
with, hey, my name on it.
So much for the preliminaries,
and now on to the main event!
Brothers! Titans!
Look at you
in your squalid prison!
Who put you down there?
Zeus!
And now that I set you free...
what is the first thing
you are going to do?
- Destroy him!
- Good answer.
Crush Zeus!
Freeze him!
Melt Zeus!
Blow... him...
away!
Zeus!
Guys?
Olympus would be that way.
- Zeus!
- Freeze him!
Hold it, bright eye.
I have a special job for you,
my optic friend.
Destroy Zeus!
Oh, we're in trouble!
Oh, big trouble! I gotta...
My lord and lady,
the Titans have escaped...
and they're practically
at our gates!
Sound the alarm! Launch
an immediate counterattack!
- Go! Go!
- Gone, babe.
Charge!
On to battle!
You windbag!
Boom, badda-boom,
boom, boom!
Where are you?
What can we do?
Where is Hercules?
Yeah, Hercules'll save us.
Hercules! Come out!
Face me!
What are you doing?
Without your strength,
you'll be killed.
- There are worse things.
- Run!
Wait! Stop!
- Hey, look! It's Hercules.
- Thank the gods!
We're saved!
So, you mighty Hercules.
Easy, horsefeathers.
Stop twitching.
Listen.
Hercules is in trouble.
We've gotta find Phil.
He's the only one who can
talk some sense into him.
Get back, blast you!
- Ooh, chihuahua.
- Zeus!
Come on! Hurry up!
We're shovin' off here!
Phil, Hercules needs your help!
What does he need me for when
he's got friends like you?
He won't listen to me.
Good! He's finally
learned something.
Look, I know what I did was
wrong, but this isn't about me.
It's about him.
If you don't help him now,
Phil, he'll die.
I need more thunderbolts!
Hephaestus has been
captured, my lord.
Everyone's been captured.
I've been captured!
Watch the glasses.
Zeusy, I'm home!
Hades. You're behind this!
You are correct, sir!
Flea.
Come on, kid. Come on.
Fight back.
Come on. You can take this bum.
This guy's a pushover.
Look at him.
You were right all along, Phil.
- Dreams are for rookies.
- No, no, kid.
Givin' up is for rookies.
I came back 'cause I'm not
quittin' on ya.
I'm willing to go the distance.
How 'bout you?
Me bite off head!
Whoa, baby!
Hercules! Look out!
Meg! No!
What's happening?
Hades' deal is broken.
He promised I wouldn't get hurt.
Why did you...
You didn't have to...
People always do crazy things...
when they're in love.
Oh, Meg.
Meg, l...
Are you always this
articulate?
You haven't got much time.
You can still stop Hades.
I'll watch over her, kid.
You're gonna be all right.
I promise.
Let's go, Pegasus!
Hup, two, three, four.
Come on, everybody!
I can't hear you!
I swear to you, Hades,
when I get out of this...
I'm the one giving orders now,
bolt boy.
And I think I'm gonna
like it here.
Don't get too
comfortable, Hades!
This oughta even the odds!
Yeah, Hercules!
Thank you, man.
Get them!
No! Get him, not me! Him!
Follow the fingers! Him!
The yutz with the horse.
Thank you, my boy.
Nice horsey!
My intentions were pure!
I really was attracted to you.
Throw!
Now watch your old man work!
Guys, get your titanic rears
in gear...
and kick some Olympian butt!
Whoa, is my hair out?
Thanks a ton, Wonderboy.
But at least I've got one swell
consolation prize...
a friend of yours
who's dying to see me.
I'm sorry, kid.
There's some things
you just can't change.
Yes, I can.
We were so close!
So close. We tripped
at the finish line. Why?
Because our little nut, Meg,
has to go all noble.
- Where's Meg?
- Look who's here.
Wonderboy, you are too much.
- Let her go.
- Get a grip.
Come here, come here.
Let me show you around.
Well, well. It's a small
underworld after all.
No, no, no. Mustn't touch.
You see, Meg's running
with a new crowd these days.
And not a very lively one,
at that.
You like making deals.
Take me in Meg's place.
Oh, well.
The son of my hated rival...
trapped forever
in a river of death.
Going once.
- Is there a downside to this?
- Going twice!
OK.
You get her out.
She goes; you stay.
You know what slipped my mind?
You'll be dead
before you can get to her.
That's not a problem, is it?
What's the matter
with these scissors?
The thread won't cut.
This is impossible!
You can't be alive!
You'd have to be a...
A god?
Hercules, stop! You can't
do this to me. You can't...
Fine. OK. Listen.
Well, I deserved that. Herc.
Can we talk? Your dad,
he's a fun guy, right?
So maybe you could put in a word
with him...
and he'd kinda blow this
whole thing off, you know?
Meg, talk to him.
A little schmooze...
Get away from me!
Don't touch me!
Get your slimy souls off me!
He's not gonna be happy
when he gets outta there.
You mean,
if he gets outta there.
Lf. If is good.
I don't feel so good.
I feel a little flushed!
Wonderboy, what... why did you...
People always do crazy things...
when they're in love.
Three cheers
for the mighty Hercules!
Flowers for everybody!
Hercules, we're so proud of you.
Mother.
Fine work, my boy!
You've done it!
You're a true hero.
You were willing to give your
life to rescue this young woman.
For a true hero isn't measured
by the size of his strength...
but by the strength
of his heart.
Now, at last, my son,
you can come home.
Congratulations, Wonderboy.
You'll make one heck of a god.
Father, this is the moment
I've always dreamed of.
But...
a life without Meg,
even an immortal life...
would be empty.
L...
I wish to stay on Earth
with her.
I finally know where I belong.
Hit it, ladies!
Oh, gonna shout it
from the mountaintops
A star is born
It's the time
for pulling out the stops
A star is born
Honey, hit us with a hallelu
That kid came shining through
Girl, sing the song
Come blow your horn
A star is born
He's a hero who can please
the crowd
A star is born
Come on,
everybody shout out loud
A star is born
Just remember
in the darkest hour
Within your heart's the power
For makin' you a hero too
So don't lose hope
when you're forlorn
That's Phil's boy!
Just keep your eyes
upon the skies
Every night, a star is
Right in sight, a star is
Burning bright, a star is born
Like a beacon
in the cold dark night
A star is born
Told ya everything would
turn out right
A star is born
Just when everything was
all at sea
The boy made history
- The bottom line
- Bottom line
- He sure can shine
- He can shine
His rising sign is Capricorn
He knew how to
He had a clue
Telling you a star is born
Here's a hero
who can please a crowd
A star is born
Come on,
everybody shout out loud
A star is born
Just remember
in the darkest hour
Within your heart's the power
- For makin' you a hero too
- A hero too
So don't lose hope
- When you're forlorn
- No, no
Just keep your eyes
upon the skies
Every night, a star is
Right in sight, a star is
Burning bright, a star is born
HADES: What d'ya say?
It's happy ending time!
Everybody's got a little taste
of somethin' but me.
I got nothin'.
I'm here with nothin'.
Anybody listenin'?
It's like I'm... what am I,
an echo or something?
Hello? Hello?
Am I talking to, what?
Hyperspace? Hello, it's me.
Nobody listens.