You must remember young thespians
learning is never seasonal
Do allow the shimmering lights of summer
to refresh and illuminate
.... our fertile young minds
what's she talking about?
Which will great you with it's magic mirror
Reflecting each golden moment
each embolden choice!!
dude miss Darbus has snapped her cap!!
Dude, you’re actually listening?
Yes Jason?
oh what was your favourite song in
memory Miss Darbus
(All Start Sighing)
Some things have passed fleetingly since
i was your age but
.... I remember each with ponyant clarity
..... the unforgettable summer of dinner theatre
Summer! Summer!
.... i was the only actress to understand
all the Summer! Summer!
.... roles in the entire seasons repetoire!
Summer! Summer!
What time is it! Summertime,
It's our vacation
What time is it! Party Time,
That's right... say it out loud!
What time is it?
The times of our lives... anticipation
What time is it... Summertime, school's out...
scream and shout!
Finally summer's here
Good to be chillin' out
I'm off the clock, the pressures off
My girl is what it's all about
Ready for some sunshine
For my heart to take a chance
I'm here to stay, not movin' away
Ready for a summer romance
Everybody ready, goin' crazy, yeah we're out!
C'mon let me hear you say it now, right now
What time is it! Summertime,
It's our vacation
What time is it! Party Time,
That's right... say it out loud!
What time is it?
The times of our lives... anticipation
What time is it... Summertime,
school's out... scream and shout!
Goodbye to rules.. No Summer School
I'm free to shop till I drop
It's an education vacation,
And the party never has to stop
We've go tthings to do..we'll see ya soon
And we're really gonna miss you all,
Goodbye to you and you
Bye bye until next Fall...b-bye..
Everybody ready, goin' crazy, yeah we're out
C'mon let me hear say it now, right now
What time is it! Summertime,
It's our vacation
What time is it! Party Time,
That's right... say it out loud!
What time is it?
The times of our lives... anticipation
What time is it... Summertime,
school's out... scream and shout!
No more wakin up at 6:00 AM
Cause now our time is all our own
Enough already, we're waiting,
c'mon let's go!!!
Go outta control!
Alright
Everybody
C'mon
School pride let's show it
We're champions and we know it
Wildcats, (yeah) are the best (yeah)
Red, white and gold
When it's time to win we do it
We're number one...we proved it
So let's live it up (yeah)...party down...
What time is it...
Summertime is finally here
Let's celebrate,
Wanna hear you loud and clear
School's out,
We can sleep as late as we want to
It's our time, now we can do
whatever we wanna do
What time is it...It's summertime
We'll be lovin it
What time is it...It's party time
Let's go and have the time of our
lives...yeah
Seriously guys
this summer i gotta make bank
My parents keep talking about how
much college is going to cost
My folks are going to match what ever i make
but i have to get hired first!
Dude, I am saving up for a car
so i can take that little hottie out on a proper date
Gabriella.
I understand you have moved for the
past five summers and
i would hate to think today is goodbye
No worries my mom promised i will
be here till graduation next year
Oh! Bless moms little heart!
Sharpay, we really got off to a rough start
but you really came through
i mean you helped me with the
winter musical.
I did?
With those vocal exercises.
Cya!
Gabriella and I have had like five job interviews
but we keep getting beat out by college kids.
Yeah same here i guess i am back in
the babysitting business!
Hi Martha, Hi Taylor.
Hi Kelsi, what are you planning
to do this summer?
Woe. Write music!! Woe
Your summer activities
consultant has arrived.
Help with some of those activites
wont help me get a job.
Hey whatever happens as long as
we are together?
it is cool, right?
You promise?
Here is my promise.
just can't
T as in Troy
Well....
Yes
Hey man? how’s it going?
there you go, boss.
lets go!
yeah sure!
so your not busy or anything.
we could go to the moves
Download music
oh and i am definitely teaching you
a twisted flip on a skateboard.
Oh and i have first aid training
so i can patch myself up afterwards.
Alright!!
Going to movies, listening to music.
Golly Troy
i have first aid training!!
Oh please!
Oh come here Kelsi
i have a summer job for you.
at our summer club
our rehearsal pianist is evidentally moving.
(whispers) Or hiding!!
Pardon?
Sounds great!
Cheer up Shar, its summer
we can do whatever we want too!
Everything changes
Ryan.
Who is the most premo boy to
have at this time i would say Troy Bolton
has that category pretty much locked up
don't you think?
and East Highs premo girl?
Just answer the question!
Gosh err.... You?
Troy and Sharpay.
sharpay and Troy. Sharpay....
Shar...!
It just make sense.
evidentally not to Troy.
but its summer Ry.
Everything changes.
What time is it! Summertime,
It's our vacation
What time is it! Party Time,
That's right... say it out loud!
What time is it?
The times of our lives... anticipation
What time is it...
Summertime, school's out...
scream and shout!
WOW nice work out
(all cheer and agree)
I want to see moves i didn’t see last season
keep it coming guys
What team? WILDCATS!
So guys how is the job hunting going?
Big zero!!
Girl friend alert!
Talk to me!
This is Thomas Fulton, general manager at
Lava Springs Country Club
..... here in Albuquerque. I understand you
have been looking for summer work
Troy? Does Gabriella
still remember you name,
or did she find someone new
to Karaoke with this summer?
It sounds fantastic Mr. Fulton, but
How did you get my name?
We've always had a student summer work
Program here at Lava Springs
so are you ready?
Here is the thing....
... i know the most amazing girl
oh i mean student....
....with straight A actually several straight A
and it would be so amazingly perfect if....
Well we can certainly speak with her!
He is really working someone?
Could be Gabriella.
when ever she calls he just blushes
i never said that! YES!
Whats up dog?
Nothing, Nothing.
NOTHING!
Ok , i tell you what you guys
stick together this summer
and work on your game....
.... and we will be invincible.
Can we all redirect this energy
by carrying in the groceries?
Yes Mrs Bolton
Hey we are kicking out for another
hot summer in Albuquerque
so for those cool enough
to have a convertible.
Crank up the sound and breath
in that fresh air and say helloooo to summer!
Mrs Evans, Mr Evans
Looking very sharp this summer.
Welcome back to Lava Springs
Thank you Charles
hi Boy!
Oh and can you find
some shade for my car?
Even if we have to plant a tree!
Fulton.
and may i say....
Welcome back.
It's good to be home.
are the flyers ready?
this year we embossed...
the flyers for the show
Inspired.
Oh i plan to limit
Auditions to 30 secs each
Amateur performers are very....
Draining?
Yes!
Understood.
and should I....
(clears throat) we be fortunate as
to win the Star Dazzle award again!
but where will we put it?
We are planning on expanding....
.... the trophey case.
The plans are in my office.
Fulton, you are so efficient.
the staffing matter that we discussed....?
Done!
With discretion.
Fabulous!
(under breath) what staffing? Yes!
Ryan!
Sharpay
Girls!
Your shade in its usual spot sir?
Thank you Javier.
Emma, Jackie and Lea east of me.
and you will be a prince and move
our shade on the hour....
.... as the sun moves./N Well thanks to the....
.... kind words from your mother
last season i have been promoted.
but no worries i will make sure that
the new lifeguard is fully briefed on...
...just how you like things.
So what is the theme for this
summers talent show Sharpay?
Redemption.
I love it.
its been a very trying year, ladies.
My drama department
was invaded by outsiders.
Singers came from the
Chemistry lab and the locker room.
Shockingly.
Sis.
We have the pool, the entire club
and the whole summer to enjoy it.
and the Spa has been redone.
there is a guacamole facial,
and a seaweed body scrub on the menu
what could be more fabulous?
More ice!
right away sir.
Its out with the old and in with the new,
Goodbye clouds of Gray, hello skies of blue
A dip in the pool, a trip to the spa
Endless days in my chaise, The whole world according to moi
Excuse Me...
Thank you
Iced tea imported from England,
Lifeguards imported from Spain,
Towels imported from Turkey,
Turkey imported from Maine,
We're gonna relax and renew,
You, go, do!
I want fabulous,
That is my simple request,
All things fabulous,
Bigger and better and best,
I need something inspiring to help me get along.
I need a little fabulous is that so wrong?
Fetch me my Jimmy Choo flip flops,
Where is my pink Prada tote?
I need my tiffany hair band,
And then I can go for a float.
A summer like never before
I want more!
She wants fabulous,
That is her simple request,
All things fabulous, Bigger and better and best,
She needs something inspiring to
help her get along,
She needs a little fabulous is that so wrong?
Fabulous pool, fabulous splash,
Fabulous parties even fabulous trash,
Fabulous fashion, fabulous bling,
She's got to have fabulous everything.
Nothing to Discuss,
Everything's got to be perfect. For me
She wants fabulous, That is her simple request,
All things fabulous, Bigger and better and best,
She needs something inspiring to help her get along,
She needs a little fabulous is that so wrong?
This won't do, that's a bore,
That's insulting, I need more!
I need, I need,
I Need FABULOUS!
Fabulous Hair, fabulous style,
Fabulous eyes and that fabulous smile.
I like what I see, I like it a lot
Is this absolutely fabulous?
Absolutely
NOT!
I got you, i got you its ok
What are you doing here?
i am the new lifeguard.
Wait! are you a member here?
I told you to hire Troy Boltan
not the entire East High student body.
You told me to hire Troy Bolton
whatever it takes!
Well why didn't you warn me
that i have the rest of them?
I did discuss the matter with
the Lava Springs board, of course.
by the board, you mean our....
....MOTHER!
Gabriella Montez and the Wildcats!
Mother, how could you?
Think of your future kid,
these are your school chums....
.... not the fuddy duddy Lava Springs staff.
These are not my chums.
They will steal my talent show.
and what fresh talent you
will have for your summer show?
Mother!
Did you hear what i just said?
Ryan, Talk to Mother!
Hi Mom.
Ducky, how is my dashing boy?
Tell pumpkin if she worries to much....
...she will get frown lines.
Doh Narnaste!
I want them out!
but your mother...
Specifically said....
Don't mention that backstabbing yokley to me!
If you can fire them
make them want to quit.
I am hoping that chef Michael
is going to teach me....
.... the art of Austrian flake pastry.
and Sharpay is going to
be where i work everyday!
How much better can
summer get right? right?
Yeah sounds like a real dream come true
if you actually got to know her....
....i mean Dude!
i didn't even know Sharpays parents....
.... owns this place
Mr Fulton just said you know ....
.... there are Wild Cat fans at
Lava Springs and jobs are available.
So i said lets go for it!!
Inspiring, Mr Bolton.
Truly inspiring, but
what we are looking for from all of you,
is not inspiration.
Its perspiration.
Confirming assignments.
Bolton, Danforth will be waiters.
and when needed Caddies.
what?
Miss McKessie, i am told
that you are efficient
Prove it you will handle
member activities.
keep me advised at all times!
Kelsi ha!
Piano.
Lunch time and cocktail hour
that means mood music.....
....not new music, got it?
Martha, chopping, cutting...
preparing plates.
Do complete the summer with the equal amount of digits....
.... i assume that you currently possess
Zeke!
You will assist chef Michaels in the.....
(under breath) the promised land!
You hold on to that!
Mr Fulton, your Excellency Sir.
Would it be ok if we draw straws to see who wait on Sharpay?
Please, none of you will
be waiting on Sharpay!....
You will be serving Miss Evans.
Who is that?
Always address our members
as Mr, Mrs or Miss!!! (Laughs)
Right shall we?
(Whispers)I dont know.
Miss Evans, would you care for a lemonade?
Actually i am not miss Evans.
Im Jason.
Oh it smells so good and
i am so hungry, what’s for lunch?
Miss Montez, it would seem your lunch break
doesn't start for another 3.5 minutes.
Did you hope no members
would drown in your absence?
Henceforth do remember to clock in
and out on time because 3 infractions of any kind,
and your employment
is terminated, Got it?
Ok that man officially scares me.
Suddenly i am beginning to
miss detention with Miss Darbus.
How sick is that?
Come on we have a hoop out back,
2 to 3 meals a day and
we only have to wear these stupid outfits on duty.
All for one and one for all?,
This is our summer.
What team? WILDCATS!
Now come on.
How did we get from the top of the World
to the bottom of the heap?
I don’t recall you mentioning
the boss is such a creep
We still have the ingredients to
make this summer sweet
Well, i got rags instead of riches
And all these dirty dishes
Just wish i had three wishes
(Okay guys, break it up)
We've got to work, work, to work this out
We'll make things right,
the sun will shine
If we work, work there'll be no doubt
We can still save the summer
If we work this out!
(Dude, what have you gotten us into?)
(Come on, we can totally turn this thing around)
I'd rather face a seven footer straight up in the post
That sure beats hangin' here, And burning someone’s toast.
I needed Benjamins, but this ain't worth the stress
Maybe there's a better way to fix this greasy mess
We're a champion team,
a well-oiled machine,
and we've faced tougher
problems than this.
I know it's a grind, but
I’m sure we can find
a way to have fun while
we get this job done.
We've got to work, work
to work this out
We'll make things right
the sun will shine
If we work, work
there'll be no doubt
We can still save the summer
If we work this out!!
(Let's work it!)
Tell me what you want
Tell me what you need
A little bit of sugar
A little bit of butter
It's the perfect recipe!
Pay day!
It'll taste so sweet
Pay Day!
Good enough to eat
Gonna make some motion pictures
Hit the mall with all my sisters
Get tickets to the Knicks and Sixers
Kick it with the music mixers
Buy a ride that suits my style
Lounge around the pool and while
Make a date with my favorite girl
We've got it made!
We've got to work, work
to work this out
We'll make things right,
the sun will shine
If we work, work
there'll be no doubt
We can still save the summer
If we work this out!
Work This!
Gotta Work This!
We can work this out!
Can we work this out?
Yeah we can work it out!
Waiters all in.
Miss me?
Of course she did.
Have you ever been on the golf course?
Some employees,
Troy, not members.
and i don't play golf.
Who said anything about golf?
Are you sure its ok
for us to be out here?
Yeah unless the jack rabbits turn us in.
So how is kitchen duty?
Well you know the team that
washes dishes together, wins together.
My mom says summer jobs
are good on college applications.
All part of the frightening
concept called our future.
Are you worried?
Hey.... college costs a fortune.
My parents are saving pennies
unlike the people at this place.
your certain for a scholarship
Im only as good as what
happens next season.
I always liked the idea of
being in charge of my future.
Until it actually started happening.
So just think about right now.
I have never been in one place
for an entire summer.
It means a lot to me.
especially being here with....
an outstanding peanut butter
and jeally sandwich maker like me?
I want to remember this summer, Troy.
Here, Catch.
Awww i love this game.
Ready?
Go.
beautiful.
YES!
Your turn.
You didn't get a single one.
You....
That was so bad.
Fulton, when i was in the fourth fairway/N today it seemed bone dry.
No way!
Can you tell maintenance to gibe it an extra splash?
No way.
May i have this dance?
why of course you may!
Lets go then.
It's soooo WET!
Keep an eye on them tomorrow
and keep me posted.
Why are you smiling?
No worries, Ryan.
This is out turf. remember?
First a break time infraction
and now frolicking on the golf course.
We are not off to a very good start are
we Miss Montez?
Actually Mr Fulton this was my idea.
How Gallant, but irrelevant.
We wont allow this to
happen again will we?
Morning everybody.
That smells good!, that smells good!
Come on its ready
You are the music in me.
Sounding good Kelsi.
Thanks, actually i gotta get
ready for the ladies luncheon.
Wont exactly be rocking out but....
You know i am so excited
about the club talent show.
Employees get to do a number,
and i have ideas for everyone.
you guys can sing the lead,
Zeke and Chad can do backup.
and everyone can dance.
Big time out on that one,
my singing career began....
.... and ended with the
East High Winter Musical.
Im just here to make a cheque
and sneek into the pool after work.
Thats really it.
What was that you were playing a minute ago?
Oh its nothing.... just nothing.
Whats this?
I was thinking if you do the show.
I wanted to be ready.
i wrote this for you guys.
Come on. Go.
You are the music in me
You know the words Once Upon A Time
Make you listen. There's a reason.
When you dream there's a chance you'll find
A little laughter or a happy ever after
Your harmony to the melody
It's echoing inside my head
A single voice (Single voice)
Above the noise And like a common thread
Hmm, you're pulling me
When I hear my favorite song,
i know we belong
Oh, you are the music in me,
Yeah it's living in all of us
And it's brought us here because
you are the music in me
It's like I knew you before we met
(Before we met)
Can't explain it (Ohh ohh) There's no name
for it (No name for it)
I'm saying words I never said
And it was easy (So easy)
Because you see the real me (I see)
As I am, you understand,
and that's more than I've ever known
To hear your voice (Hear your voice) Above the noise (Ohh ohh) And no, I'm not alone
And no, I'm not alone
When I hear my favorite song
I know that we belong (Yeah ohh)
You are the music in me
It's living in all of us
And it's brought us here because
You are the music in me
Together we're gonna sing (Yeah)
We got the power to sing what we feel
(What we feel)
Connected and real
Can't keep it all inside (Ohh)
You are the music in me (In me)
When I hear my favorite song
(Favorite song) I know that we belong
(We belong)
You are the music in me
Yeah it's living in all of us
It's brought us here because (Here because)
You are the music in me
I really love that song.
Great job Kelsi.
I have got the talent show
sign up sheet right here.
Are you in?
Maybe we can work this out, but only.....
....if we are all in this together.
This is going to be fantastic.
I will coordinate the rehearsals
coincide with all our schedules
Golden Throat,
This is Jazz square.
We may have trouble.
Its an amazing song but
kelsi didnt write it for us.
Hi mom
Seaweed scrub, darling?
May be later.
Ryan, it might be wonderful.....
.... if Troy participates in our talent show.
WHAT?
If he sings with Gabriella then our
whole show will be the Troy and Gabriella show.
Im not certain Gabriella
is ideally suited to help.....
.....Troy realize his true potential
here at Lava Springs.
Mommy, what time is daddy
going to be here?
We tee off at noon.
Join us?
Love too.
How are we getting to the food today Chad?
I dont know perhaps skipping.
Well then.
Shall We?
Danforth, Bolton.
Your caddying today, 40 dollars a bag.
You have been requested.
What?
By who?
Dude! who cares for 40 bucks....
.... I would caddy for Godzilla.
Close, very close.
Thanks.
Thank you sir.
Hey Boys.
Hey.
Troy, i thought it was time for
you to meet my parents.
Ashanti
Awesome.
Hi.
Hello.
where is your dad?
Hi daddy.
Where is the first tee?
and what is the course record?
Im just kidding i built the course
myself and hold the record
Who is counting?
Princess.
Son, you have been working out.
Yoga.
Bring that around there you go,
quite a season you boys had?
Oh Troy played for the golf team to daddy.
Versatile.
How about you son?
Baseball, track or field.
Outstanding.
Might come in handy the way i play golf.
Fair Warning.
Brilliant darling, brilliant.
Chad, you will be caddying
for mother. Troy.....
....for Daddy.
Daddy.
Bravo.
Brilliant. Lets take a walk.
Is that a new outfit?
Yes i got it just this morning and yours?
Come on, Chad.
You think?
Well it is 190 to the pin,
down hill lay. Elevated green.
I would go with the full 5, Sir.
Nice call.
Princess. Grab your pitching
wedge, this ones yours.
Thanks, Daddy.
Line it up.
That’s my girl.
That girl needs to take up knitting.
Or some sport where she
can only injure herself.
I’m in the sand.
Me too.
Knees, hips, shoulders, hat.
Good, show me.
Backboard.
Thats my boy.
Where?
We have no idea.
Gabriella, dinner tonight?
Sneek a swim?
Lovely darling, nice.
daddy.
Why not let Troy try a shot?
of course, of course.
No i shouldn’t.
Come on.
Are you sure?
YES!
If its ok Mr Evans?
It sure is.
A little to the right.
Thank you.
That’s a beautiful swing.
Really is.
That is a beautiful swing!
That was a awesome.
Thanks, man.
What?
I don't know.
Off we go.
I’m saving up for a car.
Tiger Woods would have been
proud to make that putt.
Its a shame Troy is only
Busing dishes all summer.
Given that he is a potential star.
Ive seen Troy play basketball.
The Red hawks would be
very interested in him.
That’s inspired, daddy.
Troy is very concerned about college.
Really?
How is Coach Bolton these days?
Fantastic.
Outstanding.
What?
Next time i see pink cart princess.....
...... I am going to launch her and
her pink cart into the lake.
I will build the ramp, buddy
Danforth, this is a kitchen,
Not a day spa.
you and Jason,
suit up for dinner duty
in the dinning room.
Bolton, you have 5 mins to change
and come with me.
In case you’re not familiar
with this particular item,
It goes around your neck.
Like a err...... Dog Collar.
She stepped on a.....
I did not!
Yes, you did.
Hey, here is our superstar.
Troy Bolton, this is Peter.
Peter.
Good to meet you.
This is Claire.... Hello
and you know the family.
He is pretty handy on the fairways
as well as the basketball court.
I bet you worked yourself up quite an appetite
lugging those bags all over the place, huh?
Errr.... yeah just a little bit.
How about we get you some food......
..... then we can talk about your future.
My future?
Yes, sit down.
Daddy is on the board of directors
at the university of Albuquerque.
So, Troy.
I saw your championship game
and i mean WOW.
That last second shot at the buzzer,
that was outstanding.
Actually my team mates here.
Stole the ball, otherwise
i wouldn’t have had a chance.
Oh you’re much to modest, Troy.
You were voted MVP for the entire season.
This year positively screams for a winning season.
Thank you.
Let me get that for you.
They have got a heck of a basketball
program over at the university.
Its got an excellent scholarship
program as well.
Scholarship?
Yeah, you know between the two of us here
we pull quite a bit of weight over at the school.
Well time flies when
your are having fun.
But Mr Fulton will probably want
me clocking out at the minute.
Oh come on don’t be silly,
you haven’t even had any dessert.
We haven’t talked about golf yet?
Basketball and golf are just......
..... the beginning of Troy, daddy.
Have you heard him sing?
ohhh a triple threat.
Oh how wonderful, Troy can
participate in the talent show.
Come on, Troy why dont you
give them a sample. Kelsi!
Actually my voice is feeling a little
bit horse tonight. With all the talking but....
...... Thank you very much for the
food and the golf and everything,
it was amazing.
You will sing some other time wont you,
with me?... promise?
Promise.
Perfect.
Dessert?
Sorry i am late give
me 2 more minutes.
Nice tie.
Your shoes don’t match though.
Kidding.
Honey, 2 minutes is being late.
but hour? is approaching a felony.
Just because Troy is a nice guy
doesn’t mean he is immune.....
to Boy Disease.
Boy Disease?
Yeah, forgetting things he shouldnt forget.
Now you’re a boy expert?
My older sister,
Has ten rules about
boys behavior.
and 9 of them involve boys forgetting
things they should never forget.
like dinner dates.
Well it wasn’t an official date type of thing.
Rule number 3 :
ALL dates are official.
whether the boy knows it or not.
HEY..... Lifeguard!
Your crazy, Wildcat.
Im so late. but i have bought
food a couple of candles.....
.... im going to throw a pool side picnic.
what do you say?
Zeke, even made us some desserts.
But first i dare you to jump in.
You know we are not meant
to be in the pool.   ...Club rules!
Cramp!
I need a lifeguard.
Help! Rescue me!
Save me!
Here i come!
If your coming in. Follow me.
Listen?
you know.....
....here now with you....
... its finally starting
to feel like summer.
Yeah, it is.
the water bugs are back!
Look Mr Fulton this was my idea.....
.... she had nothing to do with it.
I generously over looked your....
... Previous break violation, but then came the golf course trip.
and now.... comes this, 2 strikes.
Don’t get a third!
Out of the pool.
Sharpays dad let me play a few holes,
and then invited me to dinner
with some of the university board.
Really?
They were talking about scholarships.
While Jason and Chad
were like serving me.
You’re getting paid for it.
its called a job.
You were invited,
There is nothing wrong with that.
I don’t know, it felt weird.
I love that you have got
the team working together.
But your not going to be a Wildcat forever.
The team is now.
and that is good but
everyone has there own future.
Im not sure i know what you mean.
Well, when you graduate lots
of people will be chasing....
.... the same opportunities.
There is nothing wrong with
keeping your eye on the prize.
In fact if you don’t, you will get left behind.
Yeah i know, I’m just saying....
I didn’t get my friends jobs so they
could sit and watch me eat in the dining room.
Im just saying that you should never be ashamed
of attention as long as you have earned it.
A scholarship is special.
That is why there are only a few of them around.
I get it, Dad.
So how was the food at Lava Springs?
Insanely good.
Take it out for a spin.
No way?
Well you didn’t think i was
going to drive this heap, did you?
Ok, bring those knees up as high
as you can and circle those arms
Hey Water bug.
Last night was so fun,
.... i really didn’t mean to get you in trouble.
Same here.
So maybe later we can have our....
TROY!
So what time is your lunch break?
Half past 1
Half past 1, great.
Cheeseburgers are on me.
Everyone it looks great
Awesome job.
Jumping Jacks!
What is she up too?
Who knows?
Believe me, she does.
I am sorry i am late Mr Fulton.
About the pool thing last night....
...you cant blame Gabriella.
Im promoting you.
Your what?
There is an opening as an assistant....
to golf pros
Salary job, no clocking in,
at 500 dollars a week,  plus tips.
What? per week?
Oh my.... That is off the hook.....
... I think it sounds very natural.
Shall we?
Wait so you want me to teach golf?
To kids.
Oh the joy.
Sir, i don’t think
i am qualified.
Worry not, just show the little angels
which end of the club to hold,
Tee the ball up and then duck!
In addition,
the board is extending
membership privileges to you.
You have complete use of club facilities.
But do so prudently.
Which means hello wildcats, NOT!
Congratulations.
You will find an appropriate
choice of clothing here.
Do not mix checks with plaids or
blue with browns...
...and above all wearing
white socks at all costs.
Leave you shoes outside you locker.
We will have them polished each evening.
Man.
Save it for the first tee.
To get there.
This might come in handy,
that is the key to your golf cart.
Number 14. The same number
that is on your basketball uniform.
So i am told.
Questions?
How did this happen?
It would seem that the evans family
Thinks you have...
... Untapped potential.
Young man,
the future is full of uncharted waters.
This family has real pull.
So i suggest you take the ride.
Italian.
Awesome junior golfers,
you guys look amazing!
Slow down champ, slow down.
Save some for the other kids.
There you go.
Cool shorts, buddy.
Alright.
Hey cutie. Try holding the club that way,
you will hit the ball way further.
Nice back swing, nice back swing killer.
Make the ball fear you.
You look good, great job everybody.
GREAT JOB GUYS.
Bolton, Bolton.
Your Half 11 is here
Thanks.
Good luck buddy.
Man!
Cool Balls!
Thanks.
Your welcome.
By the end of the summer,
you will have me playing like a pro.
Yeah right, if i live that long.
I am so excited about the show,
Dont worry, we will find something great to do.
Sharpay, i have already told you.
That singing isnt really my thing.
Here is the best news,
all the Redhawks will be there.
Really?
Of course.
We will lock up your
scholarship with a high C......
....right from centre stage.
We are all in this together, right?
Your parents have been really really nice, Sharpay.
Singing with you is not a part of my job.
No. just something you promised to do.
Remember?
You look fabulous in your
new clothes by the way.
Do you like the shoes?
There Italian.
Nice.
Let me show you
how this is done.
Its really easy.
Just line up your target.
Now easy back swing.
Hey Gab!
Hey.
That girl has more moves than an
octopus in a wrestling match.
Nah, he knows how to swim.
Yeah, Troy can handle himself.
I did over hear him asking for
her opinion, on his new....
.... Italian golf shoes.
He didn’t ask me.
So wake up sister. She is
basically offering him a college education.
Just so he will sing with
her in the talent show.
Troy would never do that.
You got eyes, use them.
Lets go eat.
Yeah i gotta go.
See you later?
Ok.
You take it back, then through.
Troy, Fulton wants you in the lobby.
Fantastic. Thank you. Cya.
.... And she steps on the ball.....
Troy Bolton this is.....
Ive seen them all play for the university.
Alright, come scrimmage at our gym.
It will be good for your game.
Play with you guys?
Yeah lets get down, bro.
Awesome
Alright.
Lets all get some awesome lunch.
I knew it, Coral Blue.
It is perfect for your skin tone
And mine too.
We are naturally skin tone compatible, Troy
I have no idea what that means.
You don’t need too
I am here for you.
Who’s hungry?
Lets eat!
How can you hit the ball straight
if your club doesn’t trust you?
Thats the key. So its all in the grip,
you have to hold it just right.
OOOOO That looks great!
I almost forget.
I order Swiss on my burger.
Check it out man and try it.
Alright.
There from the university.
Table 3 needs more ice tea.
No, rotate your hands over the top. Put your
thumb on that side and there you go, man
You good, I will see you on the course.
Yeah lets do it, man.
Zeke, Yo Troy. One swiss.
Coming right up.
I think you’re right, there is a guy out
there who looks just like Trou Bolton.
But i have no idea who he really is.
Kelsi has got some great new ideas
to spice up the talent show.....
Eye on the results.
That new duet that Troy and Gabriella sing.
I need it.
Actually its not available.
Repeat.
Its something i wrote for Troy
and Gabriella, just in case they decided.....
Your an employee
Not! a fairy god mother. Lets have it.
Transpose it in to my key.
Troy and I will be doing it in the talent show.
Oh and run up the tempo.
We will need to keep people awake.
What about our song, what about Humuhumuh?
Change of plans.
What am i meant to do with
my tikki warrior outfit?
Save it for Halloween,
Go to a luau, or sell it online.
Dont know. But in the meantime
keep an  eye on those Wildcats.
If there planning on
being in the show.
Which i doubt, once they
find out about Troy and me.
I don’t want any surprises.
Oh and don’t worry.
I will find a song for you somewhere
in the show, or the next show.
Really?
Dont strain yourself, Slick.
Entertainers are so temperamental.
Transpose!
Look at you!
Go team!
Its a gift from the guys.
The guys?
Oh, you know those tall people.
Look, i have got
to go in a minute.
I will be back within an hour and
i will pick you up in m y new truck.
We will go to a movie. I promise.
A promise is a really big word, Troy.
Yeah, i know.
We also have the staff Baseball game....
.... to work. Remember
that you would play?
Right, Right baseball.
I will absolutely meet you there.
You forgot didn’t you?
No, i just got the days mixed up.
Sorry i couldn’t make lunch today.
It’s just been completely wild.
You know? I can’t believe how
things are working out here.
I see. Italian golf shoes,
new clothes. Golf carts.
Its crazy stuff. Its hard to
keep track of it all i bet.
So what’s your point?  It just doesnt seem like new stuff.
Its like a new Troy.
Alright. Lets see if Tiger Woods
still has a jump shot?
Hey Bolton, come on.
Hey.
Tell them to come over here and mix it up?
We will show them some game.
You know, i don’t think that is how they roll.
How they roll?
No, No that is not what i meant.
Its a closed practice, i am sorry.
Maybe you can get us a video.
Bolton, come on.
I thought we were going to play two on two
after work before the baseball game.
I know, i know man.
I am sorry.
Come on, Zeke that was from yesterday.
When we were all on a team!
Hey, how is it going?
Its my ball.
lets go guys.
Would you guys be mad at me, if i asked him to
get me one of those cool red jackets?
Hey, come on.
Im so excited about they game.
Hey Ryan!
No rehearsals?
Nope, my sister is working
up something new.
So are you coming to the baseball game?
Im not staff.
I wasn’t invited.
Hey, everyone is invited.
Come on, hop in.
Alright.
Are you in.
Hi Martha, Hi Kelsi.
What Fulton sent you
here to spy on us?
No, my sister did. She thinks your going
to upstage her in the talent show.
No worries. We were going to do
the show but Troy bailed on us.
Whatever.
What do you mean whatever?
Its our summer, remember?
I thought we decided that
doing the show would be fun.
Well i think so.
Me too.
Who are we kidding?
I dont think so.
We dont know how to put together a show.
But he does.
If we have a real director putting it
together then it would be great.
Have the employees ever won the dazzle award?
No
I know what you can do, Ryan.
So why not do it for us?
Do you want to play ball.
Then grab a mitt.
But i don’t dance.
I think that dancing takes some game.
You got game?
A little.
Hey pitcher.
Come on, Wildcats.
Get your head in the game.
Lets play ball.
Hey, batter, batter, hey batter, batter swing.
I've go to just do my thing.
I'll show you that it's one and the same
Baseball, dancing, same game.
It's easy
Step up to the plate, start swingin.
I wanna play ball now, and that's all.
It ain't no dance that you can show me.
You'll never know it you never try.
There's just one little thing that stops me every time YEAH.
Come on!
I don't dance.
I know you can.
Not a chance.
If I could do this, well,you could do that.
But I don't dance.
Hit it out of the park!
I don't dance.
I say you can.
There's not a chance.
Slide home,you score, swingin on the dance floor.
I don't dance,no.
Hey,batter,batter, hey batter,batter swing.
I've go to just do my thing.
Two-steppin, now you're up to bat.
Bases loaded, do your dance.
It's easy
Take your best shot, just hit it.
I've got what it takes, playin my game
so you better spin that pitch you're gonna throw me, YEAH.
I'II show you how I swing.
You'll never know if you never try.
There's just one little thing that stops me everytime.
Come on!
I don't dance.
I know you can.
Not a chance.
If I could do this, well, you could do that.
But I don' dance.
Hit it out of the park!
I don't dance.
I say you can.
There's not a chance.
Slide home, you score, swingin on the dance floor.
I don't dance, no.
Lean back, tuck it in, take a chance.
Swing it out,spin around,do the dance.
I wanna play ball,not dance hal
I'm makin a triple, not a curtain call.
I can prove it to you til you know it's true,cause I can swing it, I can bring it to the diamond too.
You're talkin a laugh show me what you got STOP!
Swing!
Come on, swing it like this!
Come On
Jitterbug... just like that!
That’s what i mean,
that’s how you swing.
You make a good pitch but i dont believe.
I say you can.
I know i cant.
I Don't dance
You can do it.
Nothin'to it.Alta boy, alta boy. YEAH.
Hey,batter,batter, hey batter,bater what?
1, 2, 3, 4
everybody swing!
I Don't Dance
I know you can.
Not a chance.
If I could do this,well,you could do that.
But I don't dance.
I don't dance.
There's not a chance.
Silde home, you score, swingin on the dance floor.
I don't dance,no
I dont dance.
I know you can.
Not a chance.
If i can do this,
then you can do that.
I dont dance.
Hit it out of the park!
i say you can.
Theres not a chance,
Slide home you score, swinging on the dance floor.
I dont dance.
Its all good!
Evans!
Im not saying that i am
going to dance in the show.
But if i did.
What would you have me do?
Come on, lets go. Defense.
Hes free.
Play it, play it.
The kids good.
I like what i am seeing.
Troy gives 110%,
24 hours a day.
That you can count on.
Its there.
Good game.
Well, was i right?
Alright, great.
So you call that a little game?
Little, meek. World series.
Newport, Road Island.
Champions.
Hey guys.
Thats so awesome.
Troy, are you ready to run it back?
Right, lets go.
Come on.
Come on,  all lets run it back!
Its looking good.
Wild, Wildcats.
To much?
Only in the daylight.
East side colors
Very impressive.
Hey... be true to your school right?
Absolutely.
Everyone is excited
about doing the show.
Hey, i know everyone
thinks i am Sharpays poodle.....
If they were thinking that?
There not thinking that today.
How do you do that swing
step you did last night?
Thats easy.
I called last night.
I got caught up at the gym.
Hey my dad says your doing great
with those college guys.
Oh yeah, there awesome, playing
them is like ebing in another world.
Well you missed out on a fun night.
It was a great game.
But the dessert afterwards
had to be the best part.
Her mum makes the best brownies in the entire world....
Yeah i know, i have had them.
Ill see you guys later.
Hey labron, how did it go with the Redhawks?
You know, there very tall.
We got Vince from maintenance to play,
So it all worked out incase your wondering.
Well maybe we can play later today?.
I dont know will have to check with Vince
Mr Evans setup the workout not me.
Did you even ask to include us?
Captain?
I didn’t go looking for the Redhawks.
The Redhawks came to me.
Ok?
I didn’t signup for this golf job.
Fulton offered it and i said yes.
It was my decision but i show up
to work the same as you.
So chill.
You get a speck of dirt on your pants,
someone dry cleans them.
Don’t say you wouldn’t do the same thing.....
If i was as good as you?
No i didn’t say that.
You didn’t have too.
Neither did you.
We didn’t vote you captain,
Because of your jump shots.
We did because you’re the guy
who usually knows what’s up.
But i guess things change.
You think you got me all figured out?
Well i don’t think so.
and i don’t answer to you.
Until you start acting yourself.
We have been like brothers
since pre-school.
If i don’t know who you are
these days, then who does?
Excuse me, but your
all being paid to work.
Not play Doctor Phil.
Table settings are nice.
No, No, No, No, No.
Now that is fabulous.
Daddy will make sure the entire
Scholarship committee is right here.
Perfect view.
I have already spoken to your mother.
They are going to sitting on
a table right next to ours.
Its going to be a fabulous evening.
Come on
Great.
Rehearsal everyone places, fabulous!
Look, Sharpay. I know i promised that i would do this.
Take it easy on me, i am kind
of new at the whole performing thing.
5, 6, 7, 8...
You are the music in.
You are the music in,
are the music in.
You know the words
Once upon a time,
Make you listen, there’s a reason.
When you dream there
is a chance you will find,
A little laughter or
a happy ever after.
Yeah harmony to the melody
It's echoing inside my head
A single voice (Single voice)
Above the noise
And like a common thread
Hmm, you're pulling me
When I hear my favorite song
I know that we belong
Oh, you are the music in me
Yeah it's living in all of us
And it's brought us here because
Because you are the music in me
You are the music in me.
You are the music in,
you are the music in.
yeah harmony to the melody
It's echoing inside my head
When I hear my favorite song
I know that we belong (Yeah ohh)
You are the music in me
It's living in all of us,
And it's brought us here because
You are the music in me.
Great job, just one second.
Good rehearsal, Everybody break!
You know, Troy
I have known you were special.
And its pretty obvious
that i am special too.
I think we are meant to sing together.
Dont you?
I need some air.
Dont be long!
We are going to run it again!
Show me what you got!
Come on people.
Now in the front, here we go.
Give it your best.
If you got it flaunt it, that’s it move it.
Keep it going now.
You got it now.
Good Job.
That was great, cya!
Thank you.
You’re welcome.
I said keep an eye on them.
Not turn them into
the cast of grease.
Its pretty cool, huh?
Do you want us to lose the star dazzle award....
....to a bunch of dish washers?
Us?
I guess that is show business.
When did you become....
.... one of those?
You know i will take that as a compliment.
But you and Troy
have a good show, sis.
Oh we plan too.
Give me a beat.
The midsummer night talent show
means something to me....
....and to my family.
Those Wildcats will turn it into a farce.
Your brother is one of
those Wildcats, so i am told.
Oh don’t you mention that traitor to us.
Employee involvement
in the show is a tradition here.
Traditions change. My parents have
important guests coming.
We will need every employee
working the party.
and not on stage.
Pardon moi..... but we are not
just talking about employees....
....were talking about your class mates.
You might want to think this one out.
Alright.
Done.
Now do it!
Distribute these in the staff area
but not till the end of shift.
What? Wait Mr Fulton.
No discussion, Miss McKessie.
This is a business.
Welcome to the world of adult.
who wish to keep there jobs.
They have mortgages they wish to pay,
tuition bills, car payments etc etc etc.
So sometimes we have to perform tasks no matter how unpleasant.
That are necessary for that
all to important pay cheque.
Into our all to empty pockets.
May i get you a cup of tea, Mr Fulton?
Chamomile would be lovely.
Go Martha, Go Martha.
Could i have your attention please?
I need to make an announcement.
All junior staffers will be required
to work on show night.
What?
Yes, No staff participation in
the show will be allowed.
No exceptions.
No show?
There is a show
we are just not in it.
This is great.
Sorry you guys.
There is nothing we can do about it.
Its Mr Fultons orders
There is no way,
this is Mr Fultons idea.
Not unless Mr Fulton suddenly has
blond hair and wears designer flipflops.
Excuse me.
Forget about the rest of us.
How about the fact that your brother,
Has worked extremely hard on the show?
Oh Boo Hoo he will be in the show.
He will do his celebrity impersonations.
Don’t lecture me about Ryan.
Given the way you
have been interfering?
What?
You got him written....
... up by Fulton for sneaking on the golf course.
Swimming after hours.
I had to step in just
to save Troy’s job.
Im not interested in what you...
...think your doing for Troy.
That is between you and him.
Your messing with my friends,
on my summer.
That is not ok with me.
You just don’t like the fact that i..... won.
What is the prize?
Troy? or the Star Dazzle award?
To go through all of this
just to get either one?
No, Thanks Sharpay.
Your very good at a game that
i dont want to play.
Im done here. But you better step away from the.....
.... Mirror long enough to check the damage.
That will always be right behind you.
Girls!
Hey, what do you mean your done here?
You cant quit.
Us working together sounded good, but....
....things change and people change.
The club talent show is a big deal for Sharpay
and evidently for your future.
Its cool, just make it happen.
Where your new Italian shoes.
Im still me.
Blowing off your friends?
Missing dates.
If that is you then its good to know.
No, I am only doing that because
i am working on the scholarship thing.
You know that.
What if you along the way you act
like someone your not then pretty soon,
that is who you will become.
I meant what i said about movies,
.... and summer and just being together.
Im sure you did.
At the time.
I also meant what i said.
That i want to remember this summer.
Not like this, Troy.
I gotta say what’s on my mind
Something about us
doesn’t seem right these days
life keeps getting in the way
Whenever we try,
somehow the plan is always rearranged
Its so hard to say
But I’ve gotta do what's best for me.
You will be ok..
Ive go to move on,
and be who I am.
I just don’t belong here
I hope you understand
We might find our place in this
world someday
But at least for now,
I gotta go my own away
Don’t wanna leave it all behind
But I get my hopes up
and I watch them fall every time
Another color turns to grey
and its just too hard to watch it all
slowly fade away
I’m leaving today cause I’ve
gotta do what’s best for me
you will be ok..
I’ve got to move on
and be who I am
I just don’t belong here,
I hope you understand
We might find our place in this
world someday
But at least for now,
I gotta go my own away
What about us?
What about everything we have been through?
What about trust?
you know I never wanted to trust you
and what about me?
What am I supposed to do?
I gotta leave but I will miss you
I will miss you
so
Ive got to move on and be who I am
Why do you have to go?
I just don't belong here
I hope you understand
Im trying to understand
We might find our place in this
world someday
but at least for now
I want you to stay
I wanna go my own way
I’ve got to move on...
....and be who I am
What about us?
I just don't belong here
I hope you understand
Im trying to understand
We might find our place
...in this world someday
but at least for now
I gotta go my own away
Usually your taking
these right off the grill.
Maybe i have been eating
to much at the club.
You haven’t been out of your room for the past couple of days,
lets call the guys and get a game going.
They wouldn’t come even if i called.
I find that hard to believe.
Dad.
Do i seem different to you this summer?
You dress a lot better, that’s for sure.
Im serious.
Maybe my friends are right,
Im turning into a jerk with new shoes.
New shoes, not a new kid.
where is this coming from?
I have been so focused on my future.
Gabriella quit.
Chad won’t talk to me.
I don’t see the Wildcats running around here.
Is this about going after what you want?
Yes, Dad. The scholarship is important, i get it
Look it is only a big deal
if it makes sense to you.
I don’t even know who i am anymore.
You know what?
I have known this kid for a long long time.
I have a lot of faith in him.
He looks alot like you.
I am absolutely sure that he is going to
figure out the right thing to do.
Its ok Ryan can help.
I don’t know.
We will get it eventually.
Excuse me.
Everybody's always talking at me
Everybody's trying to get in my head
I wanna listen to my own heart talking
I need to count on myself instead
Did you ever?
Loose yourself to get what you want
Get on a ride and wanna get off
Did you ever?
Push away the ones you should've held close
Did you ever let go?
Did you ever not know?
I'm not gonna stop, that's who I am
I'll give it all I got, that is my plan
Will I find what I lost?
You know you can
Bet on it, bet on it
(Bet on me)
I wanna make it right, that is the way
To turn my life around, today is the day
Am I the type of guy who means what I say?
Bet on it, bet on it
How will I know if there's a path worth taking?
Should I question every move I make?
With all I’ve lost my heart is breaking
I don't wanna make the same mistake
Did you ever?
Doubt your dream will ever come true
Blame the world and never blame you
I will never
Try to live a lie again
I don't wanna win this game if I can't play it my way
I'm not gonna stop, that's who I am
I'll give it all I got, that is my plan
Will I find what I lost?
You know you can
Bet on it, bet on it,
Bet on it, bet on it
I wanna make it right, that is the way
To turn my life around, today is the day
Am I the type of guy who means what I say
Bet on it, bet on it
Oh, Hold up
Give me room to think
Bring it on down
Gotta work on my swing
Gotta do my own thing
Hold up
It's no good at all
To see yourself and not recognize your face
Out on my own, it's such a scary place
The answers are all inside of me
All I gotta do is believe
I'm not gonna stop
Not gonna stop 'til I get my shot
That's who I am, that is my plan
Will I end up on top?
You can bet on it, bet on it
I wanna make it right, that is the way
To turn my life around, today is the day
Am I the type of guy who means what I say
Bet on it, bet on it, You can bet on me
This way.
What do you mean your not doing the show?
Exactly that.
We are singing a duet, Troy.
A duet means two people.
Well that means mostly me...
.... in this case, but still a duet.
I am an employee.
I am not allowed in the show.
No, No your an honorary member.
Not anymore.
I asked Mr Fulton for my kitchen job back.
What?
I dont like the way you have been treating my friends.
I dont like they way i have been treating them either.
So, I am doing something about it.
An entire table of university sponsors
are coming to see you.
Thanks to me.
So i will be there waiter. They will be thrilled.
Troy, This could change your life.
I am more interested about....
.... what my friends think of me
and what i think of myself.
Oh, we could all hold hands
around the campfire some other time.
Right now we have a show to do.
No!
You have got a show to do.
I have a kitchen to clean.
It’s ok.
Kelsi, find Ryan.
This evening you will be seated at table 21.
Right this way.
Now, returning with an abridged version of.....
.... last years tap dancing epic.
Tina and here tipety tapety toes.
There you are, thank goodness
you came to your senses.
Plug in the volcano because humahuma is back on.
Enjoy your pineapple on your own sis.
Im not doing the show.
What?
Put some fresh batteries in your
tikki warrior costume and lets get going.
I took your advice, and sold it online.
You have always wanted the spotlight.
Now you have got it.
Break a leg.
The curtain is up.
Its ShowTime.
Kelsi told us about what went down
between you and Sharpay.
I am more interested in what went down
between me and you, man.
I was a jerk.
Yeah.
Brothers fight.
but there still brothers?
Guys, i messed up your show.
I am sorry.
Yeah because show business is
our entire lives, right?
I hope you havent permanently filled my
spot in the two on two game.
Ryan, i know how hard you
have worked on the show.
Making these Wildcats look good
couldn’t have been easy.
So i apologies.
The truth is we have all had a lot of fun.
At least i have.
You guys should see him play baseball.
I'm looking forward to it.
Troy, listen. All those people out there,
i dont really want to see my sister crash and burn.
At least i think i don’t.
You should sing with her.
My life is over.
I have been a good girl.
I never lied.
Except when necessary.
I have always brought my parents expensive gifts.
It was with there credit card of course, but.
I dont deserve this humiliation.
You need to get out there.
Miss Hoffenfeffer and her sock puppet are
stinking up the premises.
Now the only thing that would make this any lovelier
would be if i won that Star Dazzle award, Sharpay.
I am going to find you,
that award it tell you it is mine, mine.
Mirror, mirror on the wall, whos the....
Oh forget it.
How is the show going?
hows it going?
This show makes the captain of the Titanic
look like he won the lottery.
I will sing with you, Sharpay.
What?
I promised.
And i keep my promises.
But what was the first thing you said to me
when i first started working here?
Bring me more ice tea?
Think harder. we are....
all in this together.
Exactly.
Well, we are.
Lets get out there and knock them
dead Troy Bolton. I do the show,
If the Wildcats do the show.
I would think fast.
I just sort of wish you were doing this for me.
Your a good guy, Troy.
Actually... right now i think i like
you better than i like myself.
Did i just say that?
Girls! Places.
Ok, Everyone, Ryan the show is on.
Where is the music?
Where is Troy?
Talked to Sharpay, and everything is cool.
Speaking of my sister....
.... she wants you to learn a new song.
Everyday.
I cant learn a new song.
Kelsi will help you with it.
What?
Its Showtime!
What team?  WILCATS!
What team? WILDCATS!
Now it is time for our five time
Star Dazzle Award winner.
Sharpay Evans, singing this year
with our assistant golf pro,
Mr Troy Bolton.
Where is Troy?
Why did you switch songs?
Switch songs? What?
Ryan said....
Bolton.
But....
I didnt learn a new song.
Exactly.
Girls!
Once in a lifetime
means there's no second chance
so I believe than you and me
should grab it while we can
Make it last forever
and never give it back
It’s our turn, and I’m lovin' where we’re at
Because this moment's really all we have
Everyday of our lives,
wanna find you there, wanna hold on tight
Gonna run, While we're young
And keep the faith
Everyday
From right now
gonna use our voices and scream out loud
Take my hand
together we will celebrate,
celebrate. Oh, ev'ryday.
They say that you should follow
and chase down what you dream,
but if you get lost and lose yourself
what does is really mean?
No matter where we’re going,
it starts from where we are.
There’s more to life when we listen to our hearts
and because of you, I've got the strength to start
Yeah Yeah Yeah
Everyday of our lives,
wanna find you there, wanna hold on tight
Gonna run while we’re young
and keep the faith
Everyday
from right now
gonna use our voices and scream out loud
Take my hand
together we will celebrate,
Oh, ev'ryday
We're taking it back,
we're doing it here
together!
It's better like that,
and stronger now
than ever!
We're not gonna lose.
Cause we get to choose.
That’s how it's gonna be!
Everyday
of our lives,
wanna find you there, wanna hold on tight.
Gonna run
while we're young
And keep the faith
Keep the faith!
Everyday, of our lives,
wanna find you there, wanna hold on tight.
Gonna run while we're young
and keep the faith
Everyday, from right now,
gonna use our voices and scream out loud
Take my hand; together
we will celebrate,
Everyday
Live everyday
Love everyday
Ev'ryday! Ev'ryday! Ev'ryday!
Ev'ryday! Ev'ryday! Ev'ryday! Ev'ryday!
Fabulous Fabulous
If you will all take your seats.
There is one last task that i have to
perform this evening.
The Star Dazzle for this year
goes to of course....
our one and only....
My brother, Ryan Evans.
That’s our boy.
Nice hat.
You are the music in me
You know the words
"Once Upon A Time"
Make you listen?
There's a reason
When you dream there's a
chance you'll find
A little laughter or happy ever after
yeah harmony to the melody
It's echoing inside my head
Here is to the future!
No
This is to right now.
pulling me
When I hear my favorite song
I know that we belong
Oh, you are the music in me
Yeah it's living in all of us
And it's brought us here because
you are the music in me
You are the music in me
1, 2, 3, 4...
The summer that we wanted,
Yeah, we finally got it!
Now's the time we get to share
Each day we'll be together,
Now until forever
So everybody, everywhere
Let's take it to the beach
Take it together
Let's celebrate today 'cause
there'll never be another
We're stronger this time,
been there for each other
Everything's just right
Everybody all for one,
A real summer has just begun!
Let's rock and roll and just let go,
feel the rhythm of the drums
We're gonna have fun in the sun
Now that all the hard work, work is done!
Everybody, one for all and all for one!
Summertime together,
Now we're even closer
That's the way it's meant to be
Oh, we're just getting started
Come and join the party
You deserve it, same as me
Let's take it to the beach
Take it together
Let's celebrate today 'cause
there'll never be another
We're stronger this time,
been there for each other
Everything's just right
Everybody all for one,
A real summer has just begun!
Let's rock and roll and just let go,
feel the rhythm of the drums
We're gonna have fun in the sun
Now that all the hard work, work is done!
Everybody, one for all and all for one!
Everybody up!
Everybody rock it!
Take it from the top!
And never ever stop it!
It's not about the future
It's not about the past
It's makin' every single day
Last and last and last!
Fun and sun. What could be better?
Let's have fun Everyone together now!
Everybody, e-everybody now!
This is where our summer really begins
The very last time it's ever gonna be like this
It's the party you don't wanna miss!
Guys rise!
Show 'em we can make some moves, hey!
Girls!
Show 'em we know how to groove, oh!
Here, and now,
Let's turn the party Out!
Everybody jump in!
Everybody all for one,
A real summer has just begun!
Let's rock and roll and just let go,
feel the rhythm of the drums
We're gonna have fun in the sun
Now that all the hard work, work is done!
Everybody, one for all, everybody all for one,
A real summer has just begun!
Let's rock and roll and just let go,
feel the rhythm of the drums
We're gonna have fun in the sun
Now that all the hard work, work is done!
Come on, everyone let's dance!
We can't let this moment pass!
Let's make this party last!
All for one!
All! For! One!
Coral Blue, that so goes with your skin tone.
mine too.
(mess up rest of sentence)
Thats my daughter.
Maybe you should start answering to yourself.
By the end of summer you will
have me playing like a pro.
If we live that long.
For you.
Cut!
Put it in forward!