20 million years ago,
an apelike creature
inhabited the earth.
[Also Sprach Zarathustra
playing]
And the ape stood
and became man.
-Rrr!
-Arrgh!
-Ahh...
The greatest calamity
that could befall early man
was the loss of fire.
Fire-- the mysterious phenomenon
that cooked his food,
heated his cave,
and kept him alive.
If he could not
start a fire,
he and his would surely die.
Even in most primitive man,
the need to create
was part of his nature.
This need,this talent
clearly separated
early man from animals,
who would never know this gift.
And here, in a cave
somewhere in
the North American continent
about 2 million years ago,
the first artist was born.
And, of course,
with the birth of the artist,
came the inevitable
after birth...
The critic.
In the year 1 million BC,
it is thought the first
homo sapien marriage occurred.
It was shortly followed by
the first homosexual marriage.
One of the first weapons
man invented
was the spear.
[Pfftt!]
Aah!
Aah...Ah ah...
Ohh...Ah--
In ancient times,
man was ignorant
as to the cause
and nature of death,
so death was greeted
with a certain degree of awe.
-Aw...
Bungwa.
But because man
did not have the time
for complicated rituals,
funeral services
were often brief.
-Aah!
[Thud]
[Ptooey]
Even in early man,
the need to laugh was vital
for emotional survival.
Rrrr!
Aaaghh! Aah!
-Ha ha!
Aahhhh!
Music began
long before it was formalized
into notes and phrases.
For mankind, it began
with an accident.
Goonga heard the sound
and liked it.
Goonga begged Gowi
to repeat the beautiful scream,
but Gowi could not.
So Goonga thought and thought,
and finally he found the answer.
Ahha aha ah--
Aaahhh--
Aah ah ah ah!
Aaahh--
Aaahhh!
Aahahah!
Wooh ahhh...
And so, music was born.
Hallelujah
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Halle-lu-jah!
Owh owh owh owhh!
Moses went to the mountain,
and God spoke unto him.
Moses,this is the Lord,
thy God,
commanding you to obey my law!
Do you hear me?
Yes, I hear you,
I hear you.
A deaf man could hear you.
What?
Nothing. Forget it.
Oh, Lord,why have You
chosen me?
What would You
have me do for you?
I shall give you my laws,
and you shall take them
unto the people.
Yes, Lord!
[Thunder]
Wow!
Lord, I shall give these laws
unto Thy people.
Hear me! Oh, hear me!
All pay heed!
The Lord,the Lord Jehovah,
has given unto you these 15--
Oy!
10, 10 Commandments
for all to obey!
Rome--vortex
of modern civilization.
Rome--fountainhead
of culture.
Rome--blazing pronouncement
of mankind's
most glorious achievements.
All right, now.
Columns, columns!
Columns! Columns!
Get your columns here!
Ionic, doric, corinthian!
Put a few columns
out in front,
turn any hovel
into a show place!
Columns! Sir, don't TOUCH
the merchandise!
All right, now.
Columns, columns!
Haircut, shave,
shampoo...blood letting!
Sooths! Soothsaying!
Get your sooth said right here!
I can tell the future!
You, sir!
For a weefee of two drachmas,
I can tell you your future!
Ha! Yes,yes! I see, I see!
I see that you are going on
a lo-o-ong journey!
Yes. You, sir,
are going to Rome!
But I am in Rome!
Do I lie?
-No! No!
-Ha ha!
Ah ha! Sooth, sooth!
We give great sooth!
Ha ha ha!
Chariots! Used chariots!
Low mileage! They're great!
I'm very excited about it.
It's a new concept.
It's called a centerfold.
-Ha ha!
Plumbing!
Plumbing here! Plumbing!
Yes, citizens, plumbing!
It's the latest invention
to hit Rome!
It moves water
from one place to another!
It's astounding, it's amazing!
Get on the bandwagon!
Pipe the shit
right out of your house!
Plumbing! Plumbing here!
Plumbing! Brand-new invention!
Occupation?
Gladiator.
Did you kill last week?
No.
Did you try to kill last week?
Yeah.
This is your last week
of unemployment insurance.
Either kill somebody, or we'll
have to change your status.
Sign here.
Next!
Occupation?
Standup philosopher.
What?
I coalesce the vapor
of human experience
into a viable
and logical comprehension.
Oh! A bullshit artist!
Mmmmmm...
Did you bullshit last week?
No!
Did you try
to bullshit last week?
Yes!
Comicus!
Comicus! Comicus!
Back in the line!
He's not in line.
He's my agent, Swiftus.
Good news!
I just got you a job!
Now you won't be needing this.
Wait a minute! That's mine!
I'm on my wine break!
[Smash!]
Ooh ooh oo!
Dopus!
I almost had
the money in my hand.
I like that.
I bust my anus to get you a job,
and you're angry?
You are nuts, N-V-T-S, nuts!
OK. What's the job?
Just the best gig in Rome,
a date that every standup
philosopher, including Socrates,
would die for.
Believe it or not,you're going
to play Caesars Palace!
The Main Room?
The Main Room!
-Groovus!
Let's not be late!
The show starts in an hour!
The Main Room!
10, 10, 10.
20, 20, 20.
30,30,30.
40,40,4O.
Do I hear 50?
50!
Sold for 50 libra!
Oh, no!
Come here,you!
The slave auction is over!
Take these rejects
to the Colosseum!
Sell them for lions' bait!
-No!
Wait a minute!
What is this with lions?
I cannot go to the lions
because I happen to know
that the lions
only eat Christians!
I am a Jew,Jewish person.
I can prove it.
Watch this. Look out.
SINGS: Havah nagilah, havah
Nagilah, havah
Nagilah,vaynism' chayh
Everybody!
ALL SING: Havah nagilah, havah
Nagilah, havah
Nagilah, havah--
Now, hold it!
I'm Jewish, I'm telling you!
Call the temple,
call the rabbi,
call Sammus Davis Jr!
Call Sammus!
He'll vouch for me.
We are tight.
Jewish, huh?
He missed.
I jumped, and he missed.
It was his first day.
He was nervous.
I got an appointment
for Thursday.
He'll give me a local,
bup, I'm out!
Get him out of here!
You could make
a lot of money with me!
Wait a minute. Money? Come here.
How?
I'm very entertaining.
I got special talents.
I'll show you.
I need sand.
What?
Sand. You're standing on it.
Get the sand. What the hell's
the matter with you?
Thank you.
Yes. A little sand on the stage
for the native
shim-sham sand dance.
Look out. I'm going to start.
Bop a do ba bow
Born to do it!
-Ha ha ha!
-Ha ha!
Hey,what country you from?
Ethiopia.
What part?
125th Street.
-Ha ha!
I'll sign him.
The big turn.
And that's the Ethiopian...
shim-sham!
-Ooh!
-Ahh!
He's great!
He's good!
The kid is wonderful!
[Horse neighs]
[Thump!]
Go on, lazy brute, get up!
You're costing me good money!
-Oh!
Please! Stop it!
The poor thing's in pain!
Out of the way,
or you'll get the same!
No! You mustn't!
Aah!
Hey! Hey!
What, are you crazy?
Aaugh!
Whoa! Ohh!
Oh!
Ohh! Oww! Mmm!
Little shot. Thanks.
Oh,thank you.
He was beating
that poor, exhausted horse.
Oh, gee.
Oh, he's not exhausted.
Here's the problem. Ahh!
See?
[Horse neighs]
Come on, boy. You can get up.
Come on,fella.
Neigh!
-Yay!
Wait a minute.
I know this horse.
He used to be thefastest horse
at the chariot races.
His name is Miracle.
Neigh!
Miracle?
Oh,what a beautiful name!
What's yours?
Miracle--uh, Comicus.
I'm a standup philosopher.
Oh, I'm Miriam.
I'm a vestal virgin.
I'm really sorry to hear that.
I work at the palace.
We're going to be there!
Really? Aah!
Whack!
Aaarugh!
Wow!
Put her there, pal.
Man,you saved my life!
I'm Comicus, standup
philosopher. Who are you?
I'm Josephus. I'm the main
course at the Colosseum.
Say hello to some friends--
my agent,
Swiftus Lazarus.
Looked good, man.
This is Miriam, a vestal virgin.
Hi.
Seize him!
Oh, seize this, Honkus!
Don't say that to the cops!
Do you know the punishment
for a slave
who strikes a Roman citizen?
I do!
OK. You. You had
your hand up first.
Death by torture!
No. You?
Crucifixion!
Wrong.
They shove a living snake
up your ass.
Ah, no, but that's
very creative. Uh,you.
They send you to the lions!
-Right!
-No!
What do you mean, no?
He was right!
[Royal fanfare]
-Ahh!
-Ooh!
It's the Empress!
It's Nympho!
Move that miserable
piece of shit!
-Yay!
Halt!
Stop.
Could you please...
step on the same foot
at the same time?
My tits are falling off!
Empress Nympho!
Miriam,what are you
doing here?
Vestal virgins aren't allowed
outside the palace
without an escort.
Empress,this man
just saved our lives,
and now they want to kill him!
We need your help!
Which one? The white guy
or the colored guy?
The colored--the slave.
Please spare his life!
Perhaps you can use him at the
palace. He's truly gifted.
Gifted. Bob?
Yes,Your Highness.
Oh, Bob?
Do I have any openings
that this man might fit?
-Whoa!
Well,we could use
another wine steward.
I got a great corkscrew.
-Woo!
Hey,this is a hip crowd.
All right.
We'll schlep him along!
For the time being,we'll
use him as a litter bearer.
Oh,thank you,Your Highness!
Oh, good, oh, good!
Good work, good work!
Litter bearers,
prepare to move!
Litter bearers, march!
-Yay!
See you at the palace.
Good-bye.
Bye.
Hey,we got to go.
We'll see you later.
Bye-bye!
[Royal fanfare]
All hail Caesar,
Emperor of Rome,
monarch of the Roman Empire,
ruler of the world!
Hail, Caesar!
Hail--
[Burp!]
Ohh...Ohh...
[Bthht!]
[Fanfare]
[Pfftt!]
All hail the commander
of His Majesty's Roman legions,
the brave and noble
Marcus Vindictus,
who returns to Rome
after winning a great victory
over the Cretins at Sparta.
Make that the Spartans at Crete!
Remember,thou art mortal.
Oh, blow it out your ass.
Ohh!
Oh, Caesar--
[Burp!]
I have brought your illustrious
name before the earth.
I've subdued and conquered
the barbaric hordes
in the name of Rome.
I've penetrated
into the farthest--
What's under the sheet?
Sheet?
Sheet!
Sheet! Oh! Oh,the sheet,yes.
To begin with, number one--
a beautiful hand-carved
alabaster...
bathing vessel!
Nice.
Not thrilling...but nice.
Aha! But to fill the tub,
behind curtain number two,
treasure from the Orient!
[Music playing]
[Applause]
Treasure...
Bathtub...
Treasure bath.
I'm going to have
a treasure bath!
Treasure bath!
Treasure bath! Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Do it! Do it to me!
Oh, Nympho. I would do
anything, anything
if you would only
grant me your favors.
How can I entice you?
How can I ensnare you?
What bait must I use
to catch your love?
I am your servant.
Ah, but the servant waits
while the master bathes.
Yes--
Hee hee hee--
Ahh! Ohh!
Here. Wash this.
Uh,yes, sire.
The muse...is upon me!
Thank you, Caesar.
All be quiet!
His Divine Immortality
has consented to favor us
with a new poem.
Speak,
oh, glorious Caesar!
Speak.
You faggot!
Oh,yes, sire. Thank you.
Bring me a small lyre.
Small liar!
I didn't do it!
I wasn't even there!
The check is in the mail!
Not that kind of liar!
Tmkd hnn audht!
What?
Take him out!
Oh!
Miriam,wine!
Josephus,wine.
Say when.
8:30.
It's so lonely
at the top of Olympus!
More women! More wine!
More--
Ha ha ha!
Ok,faggot! What's next?
Comicus,the new standup
philosopher from Vesuvius.
Good!
I like a mountain comic!
Comicus...
You're on.
[Playing Hooray for Hollywood]
Good evening,
ladies and emperors.
I just got back
from Venice,
and, boy, are my arms tired.
[Rimshots]
[Pfftt!] Ha ha ha!
Venice is a very old city,
very wonderful, ancient city.
You can learn a lot.
Want to make
a Venetian blind? Like this!
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha!
Have you all heard about
this new sect,the Christians?
They are a laugh riot.
First,they are so poor...
How poor are they?
Thank you. They are so poor...
that they have only one god!
-Ha ha!
[Rimshots]
Ho ho ho!
We Romans are rich.
We got a god for everything,
only we don't have a god
for premature ejaculation...
But I hear that
that's coming quickly.
Ho ho! Ho ho! Ooh!
The little fag gets it. Ha ha!
Terrific. Terrific.
Let's face it.
What's the rage today?
Losing weight is all the rage.
Everybody in Rome
is either in a steam room
or a vomitarium.
Half of Rome is either
cooking or puking!
Cooking or puking!
Ha ha ha!
But you can't
blame these people
for wanting to be thin.
Who wants to look like
a big fat pig?
-Oh!
Did he say "Bigfat pig"?
Yes, he did, sire.
Did he mean me?
I believe so.
Get off the fat jokes!
Get off fat!
F--No fat. N--no.
Uh,there's two Jews
got off--no.
Uh, Syrian--[pfftt!]
Uh...No, uh...
Politics, politics,
politics, politics!
Politics! Yes!
The Roman Senate.
The Roman Senate
is the best legislature
that money can buy!
Corruption starts
in the streets
with the little peddlers.
They bribe an assemblyman,
he bribes a councilman,
the councilman bribes
a senator, and the senator...
It goes all the way
to the Emperor!
Shit!
Kill him!
Taxi!
Wait! No autographs,
no autographs!
Seize him!
More wine!
More wine.
[Burp]
Boy,when you die
at the palace,
you really die.
Aah! Arrgh! Aah!
Oops?
Aarrrrghhh!
K...
Kill him,too!
Please, Empress, save them!
Wait!
Ah! I've just had
a wonderful idea!
What was my idea?
Oh,yes!
Let these two fools
fight each other
to the death during dessert!
Ha ha ha!
Mmm!
We who are about to--
boo hoo hoo--die
salute you!
Salute.
All right. All right, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Thank you.
I never killed another
human being in my life,
But you got to start sometime!
Oooh!
Oooh! Maniac!
Hey! Wait! Watch it!
Wait!
Isn't that Lena Horne
over there?
[Laughter]
Ah! Oh!
Oh, Emperor,
spare this poor man.
He has fought so bravely
for your amusement.
Let him...
-Oh!
die.
Tough shit.
Oooh! Please!
Oh, please, buddy.
Ooh!
Ah ya ya ya ya!
Aah! Easy!
Oh, I can't do it!
Take the shield.
We'll fight our way out.
Guards, destroy them!
You're the first white person
I even considered liking.
Oh,the tide is turning.
Hold it right there.
In the name of Caesar--
[Whistles]
The rope!
Aah!
[Emperor]
No! Your hands are cold!
Find them! Capture them!
Kill them!
[Clucking]
Wash this!
Whoa!
Oh!
Oh, it's you.
This way, men!
All right!
Forget that shit.
I almost fell.
Virgins,fall out!
-Oh!
-Oh! Oh!
Competence--
Oh, Competence,tell me.
What will happen to those two
rogues when they are caught?
If they're captured,
they're hung.
Not necessarily. Ha ha!
My goodness!
Where are you leading me?
To the reviewing stand.
You must choose your escorts
for the midnight orgy.
Send them in.
Quickly, march!
Arms rest!
Very nice selection.
I'm going to start on this end.
Hmmm.
SINGS: Yes!
No, no, no, no, no, no
Yes! No, no, no, no, no, no
Yes, no, no,yes
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no,yes!
No, no, no, no,
no, no,yes!
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no
Wait a minute!
SINGS: Yeeeeees!
Ole!
That'll be all.
Quick time harch!
I love quick time harch.
Where are we?
Don't worry.
Who's that?
Quick. Hide behind the drape.
I liked your choices. You made
some very big decisions.
Thank you.
Stick together.
They couldn't have gotten far.
Halt!
All right,virgins,
put on your "no entry" signs.
[Giggling]
We are about to confront...guys!
How dare you?
No men may search
the Empress' quarters.
As you wish.
You're beautiful when you--
Shove it!
Speak up, Mucus!
Eunuch.
[Speaking Italian]
...caca.
What?
That slave over there.
He looks rather puny.
When eunuchs are castrated,
don't they become enormous?
It's Josephus,
your wine steward.
Please help him.
[Coughs]
You have to give him some time.
He has just been snipped.
-Ooh!
If he is truly a eunuch
like the others,
there would be no harm
to take the test.
Test?
[High voice] Test?
Hmpf!
Test.
Eunuchs! Come down here.
Let us have Caladonia do
her highly erotic temple dance
in praise of Eros.
And if all these creatures
are indeed eunuchs...
Hmm hmm hmm!
..then nothing should arise.
Get it?
[Bang]
[Whimper]
Caladonia!
Caladonia! Let's make
their big heads so hard!
He's a eunuch.
Yeah.
He is a eunuch.
He's dead.
He'll never survive!
-Ooh!
-Oh!
The jig is up!
And gone!
After him!
Go on, men, get him!
Quick. Back through
the corridor.
He's heading for the Senate.
We can meet him
near the cloakroom.
In pectorum, quid pro quo.
In pecuniam,
sic transit gloria.
I didn't know
Gloria was sick.
Where is he?
Don't worry.
He has to come this way.
He should have been here.
The Senate is in session.
All fellow members
of the Roman Senate, hear me.
Shall we continue
to build palace after palace
for the rich,
or shall we aspire
to a more noble purpose
and build housing
for the poor?
How does the Senate vote?
ALL: Fuck the poor!
Good.
Oh! Josephus.
The man was dead
when I got there, I swear!
Where you been? Who was dead?
How do we get out of here?
Put this on.
I'll find Swiftus then meet you
at the theater.
The theater just
across from the baths.
Good-bye.
Stop with the good-byes!
If we do escape,
will you come with us?
Of course.
Of course. Of course!
Good-bye.
Of course! She's coming with us!
She's coming with us.
There's some of the senators.
Right behind these guys.
Here we go.
Bullshit.
Give to Oedipus!
[Bang]
Hey,Josephus!
Hey, motherfucker.
SONG: Funky town
Won't you take me to
Funky town?
They should have been here
over 30 grains ago!
What could be keeping them?
I don't know.
There they are! Come on!
Come on.
Now, hurry. Walk this way.
Hurry. Get into
these Trojan costumes.
...punching a hole
in the left.
Keep punching a hole
in the right.
Keep punching a hole,
let's fight!
Relax. Casual. Casual.
No matter what happens,
don't panic.
Don't panic.
Keep punching a hole
in the left.
in the right.
There they are!
Panic!
-Oh!
-Aah!
Keep punching a hole
in the left.
Keep punching a hole...
Captain Mucus!
Let's get after them.
You take the left flank.
[Bang]
Don't you know your left flank
from your right flank?
I flunked flank.
Get the funk out of here.
Here. This way.
Chemist, help me. I'm looking
for a pack of Trojans.
Gee, I just ran out.
Captain Mucus.
Captain Mucus,
have you found anything?
Nothing, Commander, nothing!
Search all the market places,
the square.
Half you men search
that area over there.
And the others
will run with Mucus.
We've got to get out of Rome.
But how?
The streets are crawling
with soldiers.
Oh,we'll never get out of Rome.
Only a miracle can save us.
Neigh!
Miracle!
We gotta get to that wagon.
Wait here.
[Whinny]
Come on. Hurry!
Aha!
No,you don't!
-Ha ha!
-Ha ha ha!
Oh, my God!
I'm fighting with card board!
Good-bye, head!
Hello, balls!
Oh! Ah! Oh!
Ahh haa haa!
Come on, Comicus!
Waa!
Hurry,take off!
Let's go, Miracle!
What--Commander.
Where are they?
[High voice]
Get the horses!
Get the chariots. Get the men.
Onward!
Get me an ice pack. Hurry!
Where you going?
I don't know!
Uh-oh. Here come the bad guys.
Come on, Miracle, hurry.
They're gaining on us.
Hurry!
Come on, Miracle. Go, boy!
Come on! We're gaining on them!
They're gaining on us!
Come on, Miracle!
Go, boy, go! Stretch out
those long white legs!
We're pulling away!
We're losing them!
Ya! Ya!
Quickly! Go to the left!
Go to the right!
Stop!
I smell something familiar!
Yes! Yes! I got an idea!
Pull over!
I knew I smelled something.
Are you crazy?
They're right behind us!
The nose knows.
What the heck is he--
Why is he picking flowers?
Roman red.
Roman red?
A whole field of wacky weed.
He's picking weeds!
Papyrus. Rolling papyrus.
Paper! Paper!
What kind of paper? Like this?
That's good.
E-Z Widers. These people
don't know the value.
Josephus, hurry!
Hold this.
Yes, indeed!
They'll be here any minute!
Not to worry. We are now armed
with mighty joint.
Mighty joint?
Let's go, Miracle!
Hurry! You've got to catch them!
Quickly! After them!
We've got to--
get...moving.
It's working!
We got to stay loose,you know.
Let it cool--
Let the coolness
get into our vertebrae.
Woo! Woo!
Woo!
Yahoo! Yeeha!
You men go northward!
You go southward!
I'm going to walk here
round in a circle.
What will we do?
We're trapped.
Who's that?
Look what he's done.
Oh, my God!
Oh,what a wonderful man!
Wow.
Let's go, Miracle!
And keep 'em up.
You son of a bitch!
You bastard!
An old man,
they don't let you live.
They don't let you breathe.
[Muttering in Hebrew]
That son of a bitch!
Go this way.
Why?
It's a short cut to the port.
There's a ship
leaving for Judea.
-Judea?
-Judea!
I'm going to stay right here.
No, I'm going to move here.
Do you care if it falls?
What?
The Roman Empire.
Fuck it.
Is that our men?
Why have they stopped?
Oh, Marcus...
Why have you stopped?
Why aren't you still
chasing them?
Have you lost your senses?
Do you want to be stripped
of your rank?
Do you want to be
thrown into the dungeon?
Do you want to dance?
Lindus!
[Big band music playing]
Look,there's the ship
that will take us to Judea!
SING: We're off
on the road to Judea
We certainly do get around
Boom chicky boom chicky
boom chicky boom...
See. I told you there was work
to befound here.
You're right.
"Help wanted. Cashier,waiter,
and dishwasher."
I'm going to be...waiter.
I'll be cashier.
I'll be the hat check girl.
All right,
I'll be the dishwasher.
I'll scout the area
for a possible club date.
I'll try Galilee.
King Herod is
bringing in gambling!
[As John Wayne]
Let's go, Miracle.
Take care, Swiftus.
Bye! Bye, Miracle.
Comicus!
[Claps hands]
Sir.
Now,tonight we have
a private party.
Take their orders.
Be correct.
Be polite.
And push the mulled wine.
We're stuck with it.
Don't write it now. Go.
Yes, sir.
You can't get
any good help today.
Pfft!
Before this night is over,
one of you shall betray me
three times.
-No.
-No. No.
How can you feel that
anyone here would betray you,
you who we would follow
even unto our death?
Does everybody want soup?
Please,we must talk.
This may be our last supper.
It's my first order.
Are you all together,
or is it separate checks?
Please go away!
All right, OK.
Yea,yea, so you say,
but one who sits amongst us
has already betrayed me.
-Who?
Who can it be?
Judas! Do you want a beverage?
Try the mulled wine.
No!
Go! Go! Go!
All right. All right. Jesus.
Yes?
What?
Yes.
Jesus!
What?
W--you said "what."
Nothing.
Ah, Leonardo.
Buon giorno.
Just a second.
It's all right.
We ordered a group portrait.
Ahh.
Oh!
This is no good.
All I got is the backs.
OK. Everybody want
to be in the picture,
go to the other side
of the table.
Hold it.
[Gregorian chant]
Aah!
[Whip cracks]
[Crack!]
Aah!
The year was 1489.
The black plague
ravaged the continent.
It was the hour
of the infamous auto-da-fe,
where,for public amusement,
heretics and non believers
were tortured and burned
in a carnival-like atmosphere.
And it was guided
by the most fearful specter
to ever sit in judgment
over good and evil--
The Grand Inquisitor...
Torquemada.
All pay heed! Now enters
his holiness,Torquemada,
the Grand Inquisitor
of the Spanish Inquisition.
[Gong]
Torquemada--do not
implore himfor compassion.
Torquemada--do not beg him
for forgiveness.
Torquemada--do not
ask him for mercy.
Let's face it. You can't
talk him outta anything.
[Gong]
Let all those who wish
to confess their evil ways
and to accept and embrace
the true church
convert now
or forever burn in hell,
for now begins
the Inquisition!
SONG: The Inquisition
Let's begin
The Inquisition
Look out, sin
We have a mission
To convert the Jews
Jew Jew Jew
Jew Jew Jew Jews
We're gonna teach them
Wrong from right
We're gonna help them
See the light
And make an offer
That they can't refuse
That the Jews just can't refuse
Confess
Confess, confess
Don't be boring
Say yes
Say yes, say yes
Don't be dull
A fact
You're ignoring
It's better to lose
your skull capthan your skull
Oy gevalt!
The Inquisition
What a show
Here we go
We know you're wishin'
That we'd go away
But the Inquisition's here
And it's here to stay
The Inquisition, oh, boy
The Inquisition,what joy
The Inquisition,
Oy! Oy!
I was sitting in a temple,
minding my own business
I was listening
to a lovely Hebrew mass
Then these Papist persons
plunge in
And they throw me
in a dungeon
And they shove
a red-hot poker up my ass
Is that considerate?
ls that polite?
And not a tube
of Preparation H in sight
I'm sittin' flickin' chickens
And I'm lookin'
through the pickin's
And suddenly these goys
break down my walls
I didn't even know them
And they grabbed me
by the scrotum
And they started playing
ping-pong with my balls
Oy,the agony!
Ooh,the shame!
To make my privates
publicfor a game
The Inquisition
What a show
Here we go
We know you're wishin'
That we'd go away
But the Inquisition's here
And it's here to--
Hey,Torquemada,
what do you say?
I just got back
from the auto-da-fe
Auto-da-fe?
What's an auto-da-fe?
It's what you oughtn't to do,
but you do anyway
Skit skatvoodle de vat
and toodle de day
Will you convert?
No, no, no, no
Will you confess?
Will you revert?
No, no, no, no
Will you say yes?
Now I ask in a nice way,
I said "pretty please"
I bent their ears,
now I'll work on their knees
Aaah!
Ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Hey,Torquemada,
walk this way
We got a little game
that you might want to play
So pull that handle,
try your luck
Who knows,Torque?
you might win a buck
[Bell rings]
Put it in the car.
-In the car.
How we doing?
Any converts today?
-Not a one.
-Nay, nay, nay.
We'll flatten their fingers,
we've branded their buns.
Nothing is working.
Send in the nuns!
[Bell tolls]
Whoa!
Aaah!
Oy!
The Inquisition
What a show
Here we go
We know you're wishin'
That we'd go away
So come on,you Moslems
and you Jews
We've got big news
for all of yous
You better change
your point of views
Today
'Cause the Inquisition's here
And it's here
To
Stay
[Playing La Marseillaise]
Paris. A cityfilled
with poverty,
misery, and despair.
The time was ripe
for revolution.
Apple cores!
Freshly picked
from the garbage of the rich!
Apple cores!
Rats! Rats!
Nice dead rats for sale!
Perfect for rat stew,
rat soup, rat pie,
and the ever popular
ratatouille.
Nothing!
I got absolutely
nothing for sale!
Rats! Rats!
Sir, help me. I'm starving.
Help me.
Get away,you swine.
Please! Money,food,
anything. Help me.
Get your filthy hands
off me. Begone!
-Please!
I'm starving to death!
Look what we have come to--
beggars begging from beggars.
Bonjour, Madame de Farge.
Bonjour, scum.
All right, keep quiet.
The meeting begins.
Fellow wretches...
I don't have to tell you
that poverty stalks
the streets of Paris.
-Yes.
Families don't even
have enough money for bread.
-No.
We are down to almost nothing.
Last week, I myself
ran out of wool.
[Ding]
We have no rights.
We have no say.
-No!
We have no dignity!
We are so poor,
we do not even have a language.
Just a stupid accent.
-She's right!
We all talk like
Maurice Chevalier.
Auh hauh hauh!
-Auh hauh hauh!
What we need...
is a new language--
A song that speaks
of struggle,
that speaks of triumph.
[Pop]
[Ssss]
It is timefor action!
-Yes! Yes!
-Yes!
Everybody, stand!
Repeat after me--
[Cough cough cough spit]
No, no, no, dumb scum.
I mean, death to King Louis!
Death to King Louis!
Good! Good!
And now, let's end this meeting
on a high note.
[All sing a high note]
With this long trip and
this exhausting conversation,
I'm famished. Bearnaise...
Yes?
Do we have any of those...
delicious raisins left?
You ate yours.
These are mine.
Au contraire.
They are mine. I paid for them.
Hand them over.
"Au contraire. I paid for them.
"They are mine."
Don't be saucy
with me, Bearnaise.
-Food!
Count de Money!
De Monet! De Monet!
-Count de Money!
Aah!
Aaaaah!
We should get rid
of your tailor.
I don't like your cuffs.
I don't like your cuffs,
A man's cuffs should be even
with the tip of his pee-pee.
Yours are all the way down
to your balls.
At least I have them.
You bitch!
Lackey!
Count de Money.
De Monet.
Monet. Say it.
Mo-nay.
Perfect. Don't forget it.
Say it again.
Monet.
Where's His Majesty?
Playing chess.
Chess?
I hate chess.
Th-th-th!
It's your move,Your Majesty.
I'm quite aware of that,
you petite putz.
I see.
Knight to rook4!
Your move, Popinjay.
Yes, sire.
Oh...
Pawn threatens bishop!
What the hell did you say?
All right! I understood.
Pawn threatens bishop.
All right, Popinjay,
I'm invoking
the King's privilege.
Three moves to one.
Knight jumps Queen!
Whoops!
Bishop jumps Queen!
Ah!
Pawns jump Queen!
-Oh!
-Ah!
Gang bang!
Come on, let's all
jumpthe Queen.
Whip out those little dicks!
Here we go!
What a spectacle.
-Oh!
Isn't the Queen a good sport?
And he's such a fool.
Nevertheless,we must
do everything we can
to save the thing
that divine right and history
have placed on his head.
His wig?
No,you twit, his crown--
the symbol
of "might makes right,"
the thing our fortunes
and titles are attached to,
the monarchy.
-Ah!
-Oh!
Will you speak to His Majesty?
Perhaps later. We've had
such a bouncy journey.
Where is the garcon de piss?
There he is.
Merci, monsieur.
Piss boy!
Ah, oui, monsieur!
Oui, oui.
Yes, a lot of it.
S'il vous plait.
Keep searching.
You'll find it.
Leave me alone.
I can handle this.
[Tinkling]
Ah!
You look familiar.
Who do you look like?
Je ne sais pas.
Who is that girl?
She's gorgeous.
Pardon, pardon, pardon.
Yes?
You are pissing on my shoe.
Sorry. Mind your pail!
Sorry.
[Tinkling stops]
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh.
Wait for the shake.
[Tinkle]
There,there.
That's for you.
Piss off.
Thank you. I'll get it later.
Oh,that's better.
Let the Queen up!
She's been so good to all of us!
Ooh!
There's a naughty bit
of crumpet!
Mmm!
Oh!
Your Majesty.
How's it going, Marie?
It's good to be the King.
Ah!
Hmmm.
[Sniff]
Everything's so green.
Majesty, may I have
a word with you?
Ooh! Care for a toot?
Non. Merci.
Don't indulge? Well,
that leaves more for us.
Who are you?
Your Majesty, I am
Mademoiselle Rimbaud.
Mmm. Nice names.
Tell me, my dear,
what can I do for you?
My father, Monsieur Rimbaud,
for 10 years has languished
in the Bastille.
If I don't get him out soon,
he will surely die.
I throw myself on your mercy.
Please release him.
Why was he put
into the Bastille?
He said something
at a royal dinner party.
What did he say?
He said,
"the poor ain't so bad."
"The poor ain't so bad"!
You're lucky he's still alive.
Please,Your Majesty,
don't let him die.
I'll do anything to gain
his pardon. Anything.
Anything?
Your Majesty!
I was raised in a convent.
I don't indulge
in pleasures of the flesh.
You don't put out,
he don't get out.
But Your Majesty,
I simply don't do it.
Come on. You do it.
You know you do it.
We love to do it. You do it.
No, I don't.
You want to do it.
I do it. I love to do it.
I just did it, and I'm ready
to do it again.
Don't tell me
you don't do it.
You do it, or your father dies.
Hump or death.
Humperdinck?
Not Humperdinck.
Hump or death.
You got 10 seconds
to make up your mind.
Hump, death. Hump, death.
Hump, death.
Your time is running out!
All right, all right!
Hump! Oh!
Very good. I'm glad
you thought it over.
Be at my chambers at midnight.
A tout a I'heure.
Wait.
Don't wear anything...
complicated.
Ah.
Ohh.
It's good to be the King.
Your Majesty, I must
speak to you. Aah!
Ah,the Count de Money.
De--
Don't correct me.
What is it?
Of course,Your Majesty.
I've come on urgent business.
It is said that
the people are revolting.
Yeah. They stink on ice.
This is a serious problem.
The peasants feel
you have no regard for them.
What? I have no regard
for the peasants?
They are my people.
I am their sovereign.
I love them. Pull!
[Gunshot]
Aaaah!
Drifting to the left.
Your Majesty,
the situation is worsening.
The peasants may grow violent.
Violent?
Yes.
I hate violence.
It's the one thing
I detest. Violence.
I abhor it. Pull!
[Gunshot]
Aaah!
Fell like a stone.
ButYour Majesty,
just in case
of the remote possibility
of a temporary revolution,
wouldn't it be wise to have you
safely spirited out of Paris?
Perhaps you're right.
But who would sit
on my throne?
We'll find a double.
Ah. A double in case of trouble.
I like it.
Ha ha ha!
But where would you find
a handsome dog to replace me?
Oh,yes. Of course, of course.
That's it!
Your Majesty,
you look like the piss boy.
And you look like
a bucket of shit!
You don't understand,
Your Majesty.
It is God's will, sire.
Except for the beauty mark
and the mustache.
There's our double.
You're right.
I do look like the piss boy.
At the first sign of trouble,
he shall be King. Go.
Immediately, sire.
Garcon, I must have
a word with you.
I'm not finished.
You're finished.
Come with me.
You'refinished.
Ooh!
Lackey.
Your Majesty.
Ohh!
It's good to be the King.
Good. Now the beauty mark.
It's coming.
Na na na!
Wonderful. No one
would ever suspect
that His Royal Highness
is really the lowly piss boy.
Ha ha ha!
This is never going to work.
Please, Count de Money--
De Monet.
De Monet, Dubonnet, see Bonet.
It won't work.
I can't behave like a King!
Please. See? See? I can't
even walk like a King.
I can't walk in heels.
He's good in heels.
Why are you doing this to me?
Why are you dressing me up
like the King?
It's very simple, really.
Is my hair all right?
Dreadful.
Well,fix it.
Recently,there has been a rumor
about a revolution,
and if this revolution
should succeed,
the people will
cut off the King's head.
But if there is
a double on the throne,
the King can remain safe
while they cut off
the double's head.
I get it. Whoa! I get it!
[Knock knock knock]
They're here to kill me!
Hide. I'll see who it is.
All right,take me!
Ravage me,Your Majesty!
A bargain is a bargain!
All right.
Wait! You're not the King.
True. I am the Count de Money.
De Monet.
The King is
temporarily indisposed.
You've come to the right place.
Please.
You seem troubled, my dear.
Let me helpyou.
Whah.
I don't see how you can.
Why not?
I've decided to
trade my virginity
for my father's freedom
and submit to
the King's lustful wants.
Uh suh luh--
[Clink]
Ohh.
Chipped.
This is the saddest night
of my life.
And the happiest night of mine.
[Sobbing]
Excuse me.
Whooaa!
Whoa!
[Branches breaking]
Count?
Count de Money!
[Weakly] De Monet. De Monet.
Excuse me.
Did you see the Count?
He was here a moment ago.
Oh! All right!
Your Majesty,
please ravage me!
Gee, I just ate.
Oh,take me,
Your Majesty! Take me!
Where?
Defile me! Humiliate me!
Only do it!
Hump, hump, hump!
[Whistles]
It's good to be the King.
Look,why don't we go out
to dinner, have some wine,
see a few nude paintings--
Get in the mood,you know?
I don't understand.
You said if I let you
have your way with me,
you'd let my father
out of the dungeon.
Ah! That's what I said!
For all intents and purposes,
I'm the King, right?
There must be a pardon
in my desk.
We'll get your daddy
out of jail.
Let's look through the desk.
Must be thousands of pardons
in the King's desk.
Here we go. OK.
Execution, execution,
execution, execution.
Execution, ex--
Tough guy.
Must be a pardon somewhere.
Let's see.
Ah, one. One left.
We're lucky. Yes.
Let's see. Your father's name?
Rimbaud.
Rrrimbaud. How do you spell Rrr?
Never mind.
Rimbaud. Is that French?
Oui.
All right. Here we go.
July 14, 1789.
Signed by Louis-- let's see.
Quatorze, quinze--
sixteen, sixteen.
How do you say sixteen
in French?
Seize.
Seize you. Good.
OK. Roll this up.
Now,you give this
to the head officer at the jail,
and he will
set your father free.
Oh, Majesty.
[Tweet tweet]
Tweet tweet tweet
tweet tweet.
Hello?
No song for me
today, Pierre? Eh?
What's the matter with you?
Cat got your tongue?
Rowr!
I was right.
It got his tongue, eyes,
and beak-- the lot.
Oh, dearie me.
Not so lucky, Pierre.
Oh,you naughty pussy.
Naughty, naughty pussy.
And now to invent the catapult.
Rowr!
Yreow!
He's in there.
Father!
Aah!
Oh, my darling father,
I have good news!
You're free!
Rowr! Free!
Did you hear that,
my little winged friends?
Free,free!
And so they shall be free,too!
Too!
Fly, my pretty one! Fly!
Whee!
The sky's your playground!
Happy landings!
Mother. Mrs. Schultz.
Hurry, Father,
before the King
changes his mind.
[Explosion]
What a racket! I can't sleep.
Guns,fireworks!
Quick,your Majesty!
It's a revolution!
You've got to escape!
They're storming the palace!
So that's the noise!
The revolution!
I'm free! I'm free!
My father,the man you pardoned.
I thought I'd never live
to see the day
when I was once again--
Yes,yes.
[Snoring]
Dad!
Aaah!
Whatfool put a carpet
on the wall?
Hurry up!
You're not as tall
as you used to be.
Quick! Hurry!
What the--
Who designed this place?
[Crowd yelling]
That way! That way!
There he is!
Wait! Wait! You're making
a big mistake!
In the name of the people
of France--
Frawnce.
Frawnce. We place you,
King Louis,
under arrest.
But--dot dot dot--
you don't understand.
Take him away.
Take them all away!
No! Wait! I'm with you!
Whee!
[Yelling]
Courage, my dear.
Watch me and take heart
by my example.
I may not have been born a King
or lived like a King,
but I can die like a King.
Your Majesty,you're next.
Do you require a blindfold?
None.
Have you any last words?
Test the guillotine.
[Crowd roars]
Holy shit! Wait a minute!
Wait a minute!
Last request. Last request.
What is your last request?
Novocain.
There is no such thing
known to medical science.
I'll wait.
Seize him!
Off with his head!
Please, listen to me.
I'm not the King!
-Bullshit!
It's a very hard crowd.
Seize him!
Wait! Give me a break!
I don't want to die!
Don't hurt me!
Only a miracle can save him!
Neigh!
It's Miracle!
I don't believe it!
Josephus!
Whoa!
Hey, baby! Get down. Get down.
Jump. Get down.
Come on.
How'd you get all the way here
from the Roman Empire?
Don't be square, mon cher.
Movies is magic!
Uh-oh. We had better kiss soon!
Why?
We're coming to the end.
See?
Oh, my darling.
[Smack]
Oh, my love.
This is a big ending.
Wait! Where are you going?
[Waltz playing]
SING: Ohh ohh ohh
Ohh ohh ohh
Ohh
We're Jews out in space
We're zooming along,
protecting the Hebrew race
We're Jews out in space
If trouble appears
We'll put it
right back in its place
When Goyim attack us
We'll give 'em a smack
We'll slap 'em
right back in the face
We're Jews out in space
We're zooming along
Protecting the Hebrew race