Why not call it the Pecu?
Or the Nipia one?
I'm just saying how do we know
it's an ice age?
Because of all the ices!
Well , things just
got a little peculiar.
Help! Help!
Come on, kids, let's go.
The berg is moving.
But, dad. . .
No "but".
You can play later.
Okay.
Come on, guys.
Sally, where's Eddie?
He said something about being on a
verge of a revolutionary breakthrough.
Really?
I'm flying!
Some breakthrough.
Look out!
A mammoth is on its way.
Hey, do the world a favour!
Move your issue off the road!
If my trunk was that small ,
I wouldn't draw attention to myself, pal .
Give me a break.
We've been wandering with our babies.
Go ahead. Follow the crowd.
Be quiet when you're gone.
Come on.
I'm up, I'm up!
Rising sign, everybody.
Zeke? Mashu?
Birdie? Uncle Fungis?
Where is everybody?
Come on, guys.
We gonna miss the mi . . .
My patient.
They left without me.
They do this every year!
Why? Doesn't anyone love me?
Isn't there anyone who cares
about Sid the Sloth?
All right, I'll just go by myself.
Oh. Stinks!
Hey, wait, buddy!
Tell me next time!
I can't believe it.
Fresh and green.
Frank, you're cutest ever.
Go ahead, pick it.
A dandelion.
I thought the frost wipe them all out.
All but one.
Make me so. . .
This is definitely not been my day.
You know what I'm saying, buddy?
What a mess.
Hey, you rhino, you have really
nice race, do you know that?
It's just a fact.
You know what I'm talking about.
A dandelion.
Must be the last one of season.
Carlo.
Easy, Frankie.
He ruined our salad.
Oh, my mistake.
It's my mistake. Let me. . .
No, seriously, let me take care of this.
Oh. What is this?
My goodness, that's my favourite.
Hmm , delicious.
That's a. . .good eating.
Don't let me have it all .
Yes, you have some.
Tasty, isn't it?
Gonna have to pick tooth.
Now?
Now.
Please save me.
I wanna hit him full speed.
That's okay, Frank.
We'll have some fun with him .
Don't let them kill me, please.
I wanna live!
Get off me!
Come on, you're making a scene.
We just take off free and go.
Do your mind?
Buddy, if not them today,
it's just someone else tomorrow.
I rather not be today. Okay?
Gotta break your neck so you
don't feel the pain. How's that?
Wait a minute.
I thought rhinos are vegetarians.
An active point.
Shut up!
Who says we gonna eat him
after we kill him?
Come on, move it.
You know, I don't like
animals to kill for pleasure.
Sid, for matters that cares.
I'm the matter that cares.
Okay, look. If either of you make it
across that sink hole in front of you,
you get this one.
That's right, you losers.
You take a step and you're dead.
You're bluffing, huh?
Yeah, that was a bluff.
Go!
A dandelion?
We're steady!
What?
You have beautiful eyes.
Get off my face.
You and me, we make a great team .
What do you say
we just head South together?
Yeah, jump on my back
and relax your whole way.
Really?
No.
Wait, aren't you going to South?
The changing season,
emigrational things?
Is it ringing a bell?
I guess not, pal .
Okay, thanks for the help.
I can take it from here.
Hey, you over grown weasel .
Wait till we get down there.
The whole South thing is way out.
The heat, the crowd.
This great. You and me, two guys
knocking about in the wild.
No, you just want a bodyguard
so you don't become somebody's side dish.
You're very strut mammoth.
Can you lead the way, Mr. Big Guy?
Manfred.
How about Mandy the moody
mammoth or nanny the. . .
Stop following me.
Okay, so you got it.
You won't even know I'm here.
I'll just zip the lip when I say. . .
Look at the cute little baby, Diego.
Isn't it nice if he joining us for breakfast?
It wouldn't be breakfast without him .
His daddy wiped our hair for pack.
And rag our skin to keep warm .
And ruin our lives. Don't you think?
Let show that human what happen
when he messed with Sabers.
Alert the troops.
We attack at dawn.
And Diego, bring me that baby. Alive.
If I'm gonna enjoy my revenge,
I want it to be fresh.
I'm wiped out.
That's your shelter?
You're a big guy. You got a lot of
woods. I'm a little guy.
You only got a stick.
Yeah, but with my little stick,
and my highly evolved brain. . .
I'll start the fire.
Fascinating.
We'll see if breeze try to blow us
tonight. Now won't we?
Hey, I think I saw its flare.
Any chance I can squeeze
in there with you?
Isn't there someone else you can annoy?
Friends? Family?
Poison reptiles?
My family is bad.
They just kind of migrate without me.
You should see what they did last year.
They woke up early and
they tied my hands and feet together.
They buried the cave door,
and covered their tracks.
They made it anyway.
So what about you? You got family?
Okay, you're tired, I see.
We'll talk tomorrow morning.
Manfred? Manfred.
Could you move over?
Come on, nobody fall asleep that fast.
Mandy!
That's Diego, fall back!
Where's the baby?
I lost it over the falls.
You lost it?
I want that baby, Diego.
I'll get it.
You better. Unless you want to serve
yourself as the replacement.
We'll go up to half peak. Meet us there.
It'd better be alive.
Can we trust you with that, Diego?
Let's go!
And you pick this year off my shoulders.
If you gonna have a mating partner,
at least pick a female
with the same color palette, right?
And I thought, wow, he's gonna go
primal , you know what I'm saying?
If you find a mate in life,
you should be loyal .
In your case, it's grateful .
Get away from me.
Well , I think mate in life is stupid.
I mean everybody just sit around. . .
Mandy?
Look at that.
He's okay.
She's gone.
Hey, Mandy,
are you forgetting something?
No.
But you just saved him .
Yeah, but I'm still trying
to get rid of the last thing I saved.
You can't leave him here.
Look, there's smoke.
That's his heir right up the hill .
We should return him .
Let's get something straight.
There's no "we".
There never was a "we".
In fact, without me,
there wouldn't even be a "you"!
Just up the hill .
Listen very carefully.
I'm not g-o-i-n-g.
Fine. Be a jerk.
I'll take care of him .
Go. Yeah, that's good.
You take care of him?
You can't even take care of yourself.
This I gotta see.
I'll return him .
We don't need that Mandy.
You know we do.
You're embarrassing the nature,
do you know that?
I'm fine. I'm fine!
I'm gonna die.
That thing is mine.
No, actually that thing belongs to us.
Us?
You two are barely a couple.
There is no "us".
I see.
You can have one of your own
so you won't adopt.
Look, I'm sorry to interrupt this.
But we gotta go.
The baby, please.
I'm returning to his heir.
Oh, yeah. Nice try, bucktooth.
You're calling me a lair?
I didn't say that.
You were thinking it.
I don't like this cat.
He reads mind.
Name is Diego, friend.
Manfred. And I'm not your friend.
Fine, Manfred.
If you're looking for its heir,
you're wasting your time.
He left this morning.
Thanks for the advice. I beat this.
All right, I'll help you bring it to its heir.
But promise me
you'd leave me alone after that.
Okay, deal .
What's your problem?
You're my problem .
But I think you're stressed.
That's why you eat so much.
It's hard to get fat on a diet.
I'm not fat. It's all this fur.
It makes me look puffy.
All right, yeah. Fat hair.
But when you're ready to talk, I'm here.
Just drop it on the land.
Shouldn't we make sure they found
him? Good idea.
No, no, no!
Wait.
Don't spear me!
This is a problem .
Now what?
That's perfect.
I told you they were gone.
Look who it is.
Don't you have some flaw
defenseless animals to disembogue?
They couldn't be far.
They went this way?
Or this way?
You don't know much
about tracking, do you?
I must lost. I see trees,
either leaves, that's my tracking.
You didn't miss them by much.
It's still green.
They head north 2 hours ago.
Is it? They head north 2 hours ago.
You don't need this aggravation.
Give me the baby.
I can track human down
faster than you can.
And you're just a good citizen
helping out, right?
I just know where the human will go.
Find the pass.
Everybody knows they have
a settlement on the other side.
Unless you know how to track,
you never gonna reach them
before their pass closed up with snow.
Which should be like, tomorrow.
So you can give that baby to me
or go get lost in the blizzard.
It's your choice.
Here's your little bundle of joy.
We'll return it to the human.
Big bad Tiddy Widdy get cliff.
Poor Tiddy Widdy. . .
Sid, Tiddy Widdy is gonna lead the way.
Mandy, can I talk to you for a second?
No.
The sooner we find the human,
the sooner I get rid of Mr. Stinky-drew-face.
And the baby too.
You always have that jumbo
around to protect you.
And when that day comes,
I suggest you watch your back.
Cause I'll be tuning on it.
Human tracker,
up front so I can see you.
Help me.
You gotta make him stop.
I can't tolerate anymore!
I think this thing didn't complain this much.
Stop shouting at me.
You're holding it wrong.
Watch its head!
Just put it down.
Its nose is dry.
That means something is wrong with it.
Maybe we should lick it.
Just in case.
I'll do it.
You know, the baby stinks.
So if it poops, where does it go?
Humans are disgusting.
Okay, you.
Check for poop.
Why am I the poop checker?
Because returning it is your idea.
Because you're small and insignificant
And because I'll pound you if you don't.
What else?
Now, Sid!
I mean, my goodness.
All right, look out. Coming through.
Watch out!
Stop waving it around!
Oh, I'm gonna slip!
It's clean! Got you!
Would you cut it out!
Hey, do that again.
He likes it.
That makes me feel better too.
Turn him towards me.
Where is the baby?
There it is!
Stop it! You're scaring it!
I bet he's hungry.
How about some milk?
I'd love some.
Not you, the baby.
I ain't exactly doing it right now, pal .
You alone are the food
jamming mouth, aren't you?
Enough!
Food!
Prepare for ice age!
Protect the Dodo valley!
Survivals separate the Dodo off the peak!
Prepare for ice age!
Ice age?
I've heard of these cracks, buddy.
Intruders!
Don't fall in. if you do, you'll physically. . .
Burned and died.
Hey, can we have our melon back?
Junior is hungry and. . .
No way! This is our private
stuff for ice age.
Some of us has been looking
around for billions billions years.
So you got three melons?
If you weren't smart,
and I'll cut it into half and throw on you.
Wait for me.
No!
Retrieve the melon!
Attack!
The melon!
There goes our last female.
The last melon!
That's it.
Now we gonna find more food.
We got dinner on the shore.
Now the meal will be feeding a hungry sloth.
With who?
A vole?
Come on, you wanna fist me?
Bedtime.
The triumph has returned.
Shuffle.
How about a good night kiss for you?
Shh. It's asleep.
I was talking to you.
Fine, I'll tuck myself in.
Good night.
Would you stop that!
All right. All right.
Trying to relax.
All right.
What the. . .
Go ahead. Slice me.
It'll be the last thing you'd ever do.
I'm working here, you wasted fur.
For who, Diego?
Tracking down human
is too difficult for you?
What are you two doing here?
Soto's getting tired of waiting.
Yeah. He said,
come back with the baby,
or don't come back at all !
I have a message for Soto.
Tell him , I'm bringing the baby.
And tell him , I'm bringing a mammoth.
A mammoth.
Mammoth never travels alone.
This one does.
And I'm leading him to half peak.
Look at all that meat.
Let's get him !
Not yet!
We need the whole gang
to bring this mammoth down.
Get everyone ready.
Now!
Where is the baby?
You lost it?
Sid!
It's so ugly.
But it's adorable.
Hello, pumpkin.
Where did you find it?
The poor kid all alone in the wild.
Sabers gang nailed on it.
So I just snatch it.
So brave.
Well , he needed me and
I only wish I have with my home.
Really?
I never attracted to a male.
Who wouldn't want a family, I always say.
Well , you know.
Cute kid, huh?
So I was saying, ladies. . .
Hey! Mandy!
What's the matter with you?
Excuse me, ladies.
You just keep aggregating
and I'll be right back.
He's not much to look at
but it's so hard to find a family guy.
Tell me about it.
But the sensitive ones get eaten.
No, please.
I beg you, I need him .
Why? A good looking guy like you?
You say that but you don't mean it.
No, seriously, look at you.
Most ladies, they don't stand the chance.
We have a very cool sense of humour.
Don't let me crap this time.
Thanks, man. You're the best.
Without the baby.
Mandy, I need him .
So, ladies, where were we?
Carlo?
Easy, Frankie.
Pretty tired, huh?
Somebody moves like a cheater.
And that tiger.
Yeah, Mr. Great Tracker.
Can't even find a sloth.
What am l? Head winder?
What are you looking at?
Look at you. You gonna
grow into a big predator, huh?
I don't think so.
What do you got?
You got. . .
Iittle patched fur,
no teeth, no claws.
Your foot is skin-wrap in mulish.
What so threatening about you?
Hey, am I like pillow a to you?
Okay. All right, wise guy.
You just started time out.
You think that's funny?
How about this?
You'll lose snack in an hour.
I'm a little square to give you that.
Thank goodness.
Oh, a tiger!
Help! Help!
Where's the baby?
The rhinos are after me.
So think about it.
He got me!
Help. . .
Get away from me.
This way.
Over here.
No, Carlo!
The tiger beat us to him .
Wait a minute.
It's dead, all right.
No.
Carlo, where's your all upon?
I hate to bend like that.
But you know how it is.
All right, thanks.
You can put me down now.
Mandy!
Guys, I thought we're in a hurry.
When Diego speaks that out,
you're gonna wiped.
Boy. For a second, I actually
thought you gonna eat me.
I don't eat junk food.
I thought you're gonna. . . Were you?
Wait up. Wait up!
Can you wait a second, please?
Hey, fellows!
Thanks for waiting.
3, 2, 1 .
Sure is faithful .
Don't make me reach back there.
He started it.
I don't care who started it.
I'll finish it.
Modern architecture.
It'd never last.
Hey, Mandy.
Hey, Diego.
Hey, Sid.
You're lost, aren't you?
No, I know exactly where we are.
Ask him direction.
I don't need direction.
Fine, I'll ask him .
Hey, buddy. Have you seen
any human goes by here?
I love this thing.
Okay, three words.
First word, stamp.
Let me try.
Pack.
Good word, Mandy.
Long teeth?
Great news
I found a short cut
What do you mean short cut ?
I mean it's faster that the
Long way around
I know what a short cut is
Either we slip through there and
Beat the past
Or take the long way and miss them
What do you take me for?
This time you can be a free man
Hei guys check this out
The tiger found the short cut
No thanks I chose light
Did I suggest you take
The short cut ?
Are you threatening me?
Move sloth
Stick together it's easy to get lost in
here
Fish
I don't want to keep track
Of one baby
I got you
Tell the kid to be more careful
Tigers
It's ok
Tigers are just playing with the
antilopes
With their teeth
Come on Sede
Somebody pinched me
Look! This fat one
Just like you
Look he is playing with this kid
See that's your problem
That's what men're supposed to do
Find the shelters, have the babies . . .
Sede
What ?
Shut up
Look at this
Next stop.
Major pass
How could I ever doubted you ?
Did you hear that ?
You are almost home?
I feel a sweat
Do you have to get a new flask
Every time your body does something ?
Just ignore him
Seriously, my feet are really hot. . .
Tell me that was your stomach
I am serious about this
From under . . ,
Come on keep up with me
I wonder if you're moving
I wish I'd jump like that
Come on move faster
Mandy are you ok?
Come on say something Anything
What I can't hear you
You are standing on my trunk
You're ok
Why'd you do that ?
You'd have died trying To save me
That' what you do when I'm hurt
We guard for each other
Well . . .thanks
I don't now you guys
We're the weirdest herd I ever seen
I can't wait to get my
Claws on that mammal
No one touches until I get that baby
Knock it off I am starving
I told you to knock it off
Save your energy
Mammals don't go down easy
There is only one way to do it
First you have to force him lnto a corner
Cut off his ribs
Then go for throat
We gotta get this kid out Of the wind
How much further ? 3 miles
what're you doing ?
I'm painting sloth on a map
Why don't you make him look
Realistic and make him like down
Make him rounder
I forgot how to laugh
I am a genius
Now you have to refer me as
Sid, Lord of the flame
Lord of the flame, your tail ls on fire
Thank you
From now on I'm gonna call You Diego
You touch me and you are dead
I am just kidding you little Nuthead
Look at this
I don't believe. . .
Come here
Come to uncle Sid
No no this way
No. go to him
Ok
Good job
Practise
A little guy growing up
Come on sleep tight
You know I never had a friend
who'd Risk his life for me
Yeah he is a good guy
Yeah he is
Well , good night
What is your problem ?
Nothing it's freezing my Tail off
Hey Diego you're frozen back there
Get down What
Get down and follow me
What's going on?
There is an ambush waiting for you
What do you mean ambush
You set us up ?
It was my job, I was supposed to
Get the baby but. . .
You pull us home for dinner
That's it you're out Of the herd
I am sorry
No you are not . not yet
Listen I can help you
Stay close Sid
We can find our way out
You can't . Pax is too strong
You have to trust me
Trust you ? why in the world
Would we trust you ?
Cos I am your only chance
Hello ladies
Look who decided to show up
Diego. I was beginning to
Worry about you
No need to worry
In about 2 minutes you'll be
Satisfied your taste for revenge
I see the sloth
He got the baby
Don't give away your position
Until you see the mammal
He is the one you have to surprise
You wanna eat something don't just ache
what are you waiting for?
no I said wait for the mammal
got you
eat my powder
sorry fellas you got a little surprise
ok follow me
we take Sid up here where we can
come on Diego let's bring
this mammal down
that's right that's maybe. . .
what are you doing ?
Ieave the mammal alone
I'll take you down first
We did it
We were some team , huh?
We're still a team
I am sorry I set you up
You know me I am too lazy To hold a bunch
Knock it off
You have to be strong
You have to take care of mammal
Especially Sid
You're a tiger I can carry you
What do you think?
Come on everything's gonna Be ok
Listen. You have to leave me here
Or the humans get to the pass
You'll never catch them
You didn't have to do that
That's what you do in The herd
Forget about us , ok?
We won't forget about you
Good bye
That's right. Where is the baby ?
Come on Sid
What is that sound?
Save your breath Sid
You're alive
9 lives baby
you ok. I'll kiss ya
welcome back partner want a lift ?
no thanks I gotta save whatever
dignity I got left
With us now, buddy.
Dignity has nothing To do with it
But I'll take that lift
Climb upon
March!
Not march. , either way
Subrip by drEAmEr(C) 2002.