Adi... -  Although going to the
court is beneficial to her...
In just 4 hearings the matter
will become clear...
And she will know what she
genuinely deserves...
...and what she should expect
from this company!
Look, I don't think we should
jump to any conclusions!
We are meeting here because we are
considering Mrs. Khanna's demands.
Consider? Who gave you
the authority to...
Good morning, sir.
- Good morning, sir.
Hello, Mr. Kashyap.
Nice meeting you.
Sir. Photographs please
Congratulations!
Passengers, attention please,
this is the train...
...boarding to delhi
from Chatrapati Shivaji Terminus...
...from platform no.5 at 5:05.
Hey, hurry up.
Mister, hold this luggage!
- Let me get in!
Give it! Give it!
Give it to that gentlemen!
Ma'am, you quickly get in!
You don't worry about me!
Just load the luggage inside!
Quickly! Here!
Ma'am, I told you in the
beginning itself...
...you have luggage enough
for two coolie's!
Here... Hold the frame carefully!
Its Babajii's frame!
Is there more luggage?
Don't worry! No matter how much
more luggage there is. Let it come.
Here!
- Here! Here! Hold this!
This is really risky!
Ma'am, you please look ahead!
- Yes, I am!
You just quickly load the luggage!
Come on! Come on! - Give me
your hand! Give me your hand!
Come on!
Oh God!
This was the limit, I
crossed the line today!
Do you know what?
Till date I have not missed
a single train!
Thank you, Babajj! You saved
me from breaking my record!
I am inside now.
- Yes
... You can leave my hand now...
I am not that beautiful!
I prefer travelling in
a Non-AC compartment.
But my family... they
say 'you are a girl! '
As if I don't know that I am a girl!
Mister, is this A1?
- Yes!
Thank you!
Now what is the connection
between AC and a girl?
I don't understand that!
I am not travelling alone
for the first time!
That too in this train! This
is like my second home!
17, 18, ...here it is
Please show me your ticket.
Hello! I am talking to you!
Hey! This is my seat. 23!
Strange. Hey, mister!
This seat is mine! 23!
Nobody likes to take
the passage seat
But I always insist
on the passage seat.
The reservation uncle gets
very alarmed and worried
But my logic is that... my journey
doesn't end with this train!
I am going to Bhatinda.
My house is there.
My family is there.
Everybody has a family.
I have one too.
Everybody says that Mumbai
is a crowded city.
What do you mean by crowded?
People like us form the crowd!
They are a part of the crowd!
Still they crib!
I am leaving Mumbai! Forever!
Do you know when I came here?
When Mumbai was Bombay!
Hostel! Hostel! Hostel!
St Teresa's boarding school
hostel in Shimla!
Missionary hostel for college
girls in Bombay Central!
I swear! Henceforth I will never
live in a hostel again!
I hope the road digging
stops before the monsoon.
Otherwise do you know
what will happen?
Anyway! What happened?
What are you doing?!
...last time a kid fell and died...
It's really dangerous!
Are you dumb? You can't talk?
Or are you shy?
Or are you just insolent?
Something is surely the matter!
I have asked three times...but
still no answer!
Ticket please!
It's on the berth! I will
just give it to you!
Excuse me, mister! Ticket please!
Hello, mister! First
come inside! Come on!
Show me your ticket!
He wants to see your ticket. Ticket!
Where is your ticket?
- I don't have a ticket.
Actually you see what
happened is that...
...his plan was made at
the very last minute.
So there was no time
to buy a ticket.
By the way the train
is quite empty...
So you can give him a ticket now.
There is no problem, right?
Mister! Are you convinced
or shall I say more?
Ticket for where?
Hello!
Where is this train going?
- What?
Last stop. Delhi. Give
him a ticket to Delhi.
Look. I might as well tell you.
A tragedy has occurred with him.
He is going through bad times.
So that's why he... Delhi!
Oh Mister! What's the matter?
Are you doing drugs?
Look, if there is any problem,
then you can tell me.
I don't mind! Tell me!
All my friends tell
me their problems!
And I solve it!
Do you know? I am that
kind of a girl!
Like an agony aunt whose articles
you find in the magazines?
I'm just like that!
Tell me! What's the matter?
Tell me what is your problem?
Tell me! Don't feel shy! What
is your problem? Tell me!
You are my problem!
You are talking non-stop!
Don't you understand that I am not
interested in talking to you?
I don't want to talk to you!
I don't want to know whether you
are going to Bhatinda or Benaras!
Whether you lived in some
hostel or some brothel!
I just don't care! All right!
So just please! Please! Leave
me alone! All right!
That thing about brothel
was not right!
Yeah! I... Iook... I...
I know! You are clearly very
upset about something!
That's why you got
upset with me too!
And you started talking nonsense!
But it's okay! I don't feel bad!
Actually nowadays I don't
feel bad about anything!
Do you know why?
Because I am going to
get married! Very soon!
Listen! I am eloping!
The guy is not Sikh so
my family won't agree!
But what can anybody do
after the marriage?
We will go and fall at their feet!
They will have to forgive us!
I like mountains a lot! Really!
Since childhood I had this
craze for marriage! By God!
What is the difference between
hill and mountain?
I could never understand.
I was just waiting for my
college to get over...
And his travel agency to open up!
But you don't find good
shoes there. That's why...
Hang on!
Hey! The train is leaving!
Listen! Hero!
- What's his name?
Hey, mister!
- His name is mister!
Look here!
- Is he with you?
Oh God!
- Listen!
Listen!
Where are you going, ma'am?
The train is leaving!
- Ma'am!
Ma'am!
Hey, black pant!
- Ma'am!
Hey, Mumbai guy! Listen!
The train is leaving!
Hello!
Are you mad? The train
is leaving! Come on!
What?
Go to hell!
Ma'am, what have you done?
Where are you running away?
Who will pay the compensation?
Leave me! The train is leaving!
Stop! Somebody pull the chain!
Stop!
Such a fat woman!
Even a blind man could
see such a big basket!
And this crazy girl!
Now I don't know in which corners
my tomatoes are lying!
I will pick it up from here! You
pick it from there! - Okay!
You stupid weirdo!
Which world do you live in huh?
I have missed my train
because of you.
My entire luggage has gone!
I have lost everything!
And now I am stuck in these
clothes and slippers...
... on this God forsaken platform
called Barnagar?
What will I do now?
Did I tell you to get
down from the train?
Can't you mind your own business?
Oh! So It's my mistake! Shameless!
I was helping you! You
should be thanking me!
And instead you are
showing me attitude!
Okay! Thank you! Thank
you for helping me!
Now will you please leave me alone?
Leave you alone?
I see! It's not so easy!
I have missed my train
because of you!
So now you will take me to Bhatinda!
To my house! Along will my
entire luggage! You see?
I am not going to spare you!
Don't have any doubt! I am
a Sikh girl from Bhatinda!
Hey! He is running away!
Nab this man!
Thief! Thief! Thief!
Thief!
Hey!
- Move!
Nab that thief!
Shameless! Throw away your uniform!
Ma'am!
Hey!
- Hurry up!
Yes! Come on! Come on! Come on!
Yes! God heard your prayers!
Now come on, move!
What are you doing?
How will we catch the
train like this?
You can't catch the train anyway.
Ratlam is the next station.100
kms away.
What do you know what you are?
He is mad! He is totally mad!
Stop the car!
- What?
- What happened?
What happened?
O God! Couldn't you
hold it for sometime!
Get in! Come on!
Hey! What? What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Don't disturb! There
will be an accident!
Mark Three... this a Mark
Three Ambassador.
Mister! Please stop! Stop!
Everything is shaking!
The car is shaking!
You don't be tense! Listen to me!
This man is no ordinary man!
Look at his style...
He has lots of money!
I bought this car by
selling my land...
No good can be done by this!
Look, we all are in this situation
because of him...
If anything breaks... he
will pay for the damage!
You don't worry! I will
ensure that he pays!
Stop the car! Stop the car!
If anything happens to this car,
then everything will be ruined!
Nothing will happen!
Hey! My fare!
Where are you running away? My fare!
Give me my fare!
Hey! Where are you running away?
Hey! They are running away
without paying my fare!
'Passengers pay attention.'
The train on Platform no. 1
is 2137 Punjab Mail to Delhi.
The train will stop at
Ratlam for 10 minutes
Get in!
- What about you?
Look, don't try to help me anymore!
I am fine alone... All right!
My fare! Give me my fare!
- Stop!
You are running away!
- Hang on!
Ma'am, you were saying...
Money. I need to borrow some money!
I want to buy water!
I will return it in the train!
Do you have more? Its
full fare right?
Look, I am paying you alright.
You quietly stand here! Got it?
Water! I am breathless! By God!
Cold drinks have their own
place but finally...
...only water can
quench your thirst!
Its said... best things
in the world are free!
But now even water is no
longer free! How much?
14 rupees!
Why? Railway prices are cheaper!
Ma'am, this is the rate!
- Is that so?
Shall I ask the consumer
court what's the rate!
You are trying to fool me!
For 2 rupees you are
arguing so much!
If 2 rupees are nothing, then
why are you stealing?
Stealing?
- Then what?
And you are saying
that I am arguing!
Return my money!
Here!
Stop!
Stop! Somebody pull the chain! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Hey, look at her. -  She is alone.
Hey, let's go and ask her.
The next station is Kota. I
will call the station master.
He will keep your luggage there.
Nothing else can be done.
But how will I reach there? Shit.
Who told you to get
down from the train?
You should have been alert!
Now what will you do?
Zest of youth! You don't understand!
You don't understand!
Look... life is like
a railway track...
1 inch bend. And a distance
of many miles...
Your small mistake
can ruin your life!
Yes! I too have missed many trains...
But at that time I was a man!
I mean I am still a man...
but... you are a girl.
A girl travelling alone is
like an open treasure box!
Yes! Do you know? Do you know?
What all things could
happen with you?
I will tell you! Look...
Excuse me! I want to ask you...
What you are saying... do
you charge money for it?
Or is this free education?
No, this is for free.
Good! Because I don't
have any small change!
Look, old man! Stop this nonsense.
And do your work!
Call Kota! The rest is my problem...
I will handle it!
You... Quickly call!
Come on! Come on!
A 23 Seat Number passenger's
luggage...
Your water!
I am not a thief! It's really bad!
What happened? What happened?
This poor girl missed her train!
There is no train till morning!
- O God!
Is she alone?
- Yes!
Now what will she do?
Exactly! Do you know?
A girl travelling alone is
like an open treasure box!
Listen, don't try to act smart!
Got it? Get lost!
Am I a bomb that I will explode?
Try to understand, ma'am!
Before somebody tries to
take undue advantage...
...I thought... I will help you.
Don't let her stay here
at night alone...
You will have to take some trouble.
But... take her somewhere.
Yes. There is no other option.
Don't try to act too smart!
Got it? Get lost!
This is the limit! Nobody
appreciates decency!
Tell me! I am taking you to
the right place and you...
Shut up!
I will give you a slap
if you talk too much!
Let her slap you. At least
she will touch you.
Fine! If this is what makes
you happy, then slap me.
Fulfil your wish. Slap me.
Slap me!
Where are you going? Today I wont
leave before you slap me!
Mister!
Hey!
Oh no!
Hey! Come!
Come on! Come on!
Just one man... Full night!
My place! Come on!
I am not that!
What?
That!
Listen! If you want money,
then I will give it to you!
Why are you acting pricey?
Come on! Come!
Listen!
You drunkard! You come here
everyday! Get lost!
Come!
Why are you making me run around
at night? Listen to me!
I will pay you!
She is acting so smugly! Listen!
Thank you, Baba! Thank you!
O God! God knows what would
have happened today!
Thank you! Thank you!
You missed the train again?
And who is this joker on the bike?
Hi! I am Geet!
Aditya!
- Aditya! Pleased to meet you...
Infact... I have never felt as
pleased meeting anybody...
...as I feel after meeting you today!
Because you are the one who has
started all these problems!
Remember... I told you not
to have any doubt...
I will not let you go! You
will escort me home!
I have seen that you have
money in your wallet...
We will stay in some
hotel till morning
Then we will go to Kota. Collect
the luggage.
And then all the way
to Bhatinda! Come on!
Come! You can give me this
look while walking too!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Ratlam! Come on! It's the limit!
What does this mean? I am roaming
in the lanes of Ratlam!
From the train I would watch
these houses, these lanes!
Life is so strange! Right?
You are having a lot of fun, right?
As if we have come for a picnic.
You should be kept in a museum!
People should be charged
for seeing you!
What's the matter? And where
should you be kept?
You are in the train but you don't
know where the train is going!
You get down on some
unknown station!
Then you drive the car
like a crazy man...
...almost killing me...
you reach here.
And here... you are walking
in the dark lanes!
Alone! In the lanes of Ratlam!
What is your problem? Tell me!
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
You don't share your problems
with anybody!
Right! Are you Bachchan's
fan? Angry young man!
Today you will be very happy!
Agnipath! Agnipath!
Tell me! Who is your favourite hero?
Tell me! This is not a secret!
Where have I come? What
am I doing? Why?
Come on! Please!
Do you accept credit card?
No credit! Only cash!
- Credit card!
What's the tariff?
- What?
How much do you charge for
a room for a single day?
Do you need the room per hour?
Just answer what I
am asking you! OK?
How much for a room for a day?
Why do you need it
for the whole day?
We don't have to stay
here the whole day!
Listen, let me talk! - Yes. You
are talking a lot of sense.
As it is we have less money!
We will take the room
on a per hour basis!
Geet! You are not understanding
what he is...
Be practical! Why do
you feel ashamed?
We need it just for a few hours!
We will take the room
on per hour basis!
How many hours?
2... 2 hours will be enough?
Fine! To be on the
safe side 3 hours!
3 hours are more than enough!
3 hours!
Ok.
Where did you find her?
- In the train!
In the train? You met
her in the train?
Nice idea!
Listen, how is the girl?
Hot! Beauty!
Thanks! 3 hours!
What were you whispering to him?
You are such a cartoon!
Do you know that?
Possible! But I know karate!
- So?
I am just informing you!
I am brown belt!
I see! I see! I see!
You know karate.
Meaning if I tried to rape you...
then you will use karate on me!
Right?
Possible! I mean yes! Absolutely!
I just look like this... But
I have beaten many people!
Don't worry! I won't rape you!
You can't do it!
- I don't want to do it!
Even if you wanted to, you couldn't!
Are you trying to provoke
me to rape you?
No! I am just trying to clear it
So that you don't get
any wrong signal!
I hugged you at the station.
And I said let's go to some hotel.
I don't know what you
must be thinking.
That too a man like you!
A man like me? Meaning?
Girls must be hovering
around you in Mumbai!
Those kinds of girls!
But let me tell you that I
am not that kind of a girl
Don't even think of it!
My thinking is orthodox!
One man woman!
And I have a boyfriend! Anshuman!
One and only! Forever and ever!
You will be happy to know that
I too am a one woman man
All right?
Look at this!
Show! Show! Show! Wow! She
is really beautiful!
You are very lucky!
No! I am not lucky!
- What?
Oh! So this is the problem!
This girl has dumped you!
Life has dumped me!
- What do you mean?
O God! The famous silence!
What is this great secret of yours?
I have told you everything!
Why can't you tell me?
Anyway! Look! Look at this photo!
This girl has ditched you.
Right? Hold this!
Burn it!
Come on, Geet! You can't be serious!
I am damn serious! Burn
the photograph!
What childishness is this!
Listen to me! Do this childish
deed! Burn this!
You will feel really good! Burn her!
Here!
Burn it! Burn it! No tension!
Burn it!
Okay! Now go to the bathroom!
And flush her out of your
life forever! Go!
Do you feel better?
You know what?
Doing this foolish thing...
I am actually feeling nice!
I am actually feeling better!
You were right!
See? And shall I tell you the truth?
You are not bad looking!
You are handsome
You seem to be rich too!
You will find much better
girls than her!
She was nothing compared to you!
Thank you. That's very kind.
I am telling you! Am I not a girl?
Any girl will be smitten by you!
You are of that type!
Look, I am getting married
to Anshuman and all that
But if he had not been in my
life then you never know...
Maybe I would have been smitten
too! Just imagine!
You like yourself a lot, don't you?
A lot! I am my favourite!
What happened?
I wish I too could
have been like you.
That is very difficult.
But you will find a better
girl... that's for sure!
Why don't you only find
a good one for me?
Tell me something. Do you like me?
What?
- Look! Look at me!
What kind of question is this!
Geet, don't be stupid!
Tell me!
Quickly open the door! Run!
Wear your clothes! And quickly run!
Give me the full amount!
- Hello! What happened?
There is a raid! There is a raid!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Come on! Run!
Hey! What is going on?
We will have to run!
- Why?
Police!
- Police!
Come on!
Quickly! Hurry up!
Everybody quickly run!
I will open the back door!
Listen!
What is going on? What happened?
Come on! Come on! Hurry up!
What happened? Why are we
acting like smugglers?
Next time get some suitcase
to show to the police
That you belong to a good family
But I missed my luggage
in the train!
For the first time I am
seeing a train girl
Why don't you book a compartment
in the train?
Like those meant only
for two people...
I will tell you next time! Come on!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
What was he saying?
- Run! Run!
Please, Babajii! This is the limit!
Please don't give any more
excitement for this night!
Now please make this night boring!
The bus will leave in the
morning at 6 o'clock.
Are you feeling sleepy?
- No! What about you?
That... Why were you asking me
whether I like you or not.
Yes! Tell me! Do you like me?
- But why?
There is no answer for this why!
Do you like me? Nice, sweet, great?
Tell me quickly!
- Yes!
Yes?
If you like me, then you
will like my sister too.
Roop. My cousin. She
is just like me!
Listen to me. I am going
to elope every soon
With Anshuman! You
and Roop too elope!
Your problem too is the same.
Grandpa won't agree!
And then all four of us will live
together in the mountains.
We will have great fun!
What do you say?
Why don't we do this?
We both will elope.
We both will get married.
And live in the mountains.
Look, it's a convenient option.
If we don't go to Bhatinda now,
then we are eloping anyway.
Look... if you marry Roop then
I will be your sister-in-law.
Half wife.
What will I do with just half?
I want you completely.
You will get complete Roop.
And me partly.
Okay! Okay! Okay! It's
a bargain offer!
Yes. Half free with one!
Free! Free! Free!
That makes sense! But if I marry
you, the offer is still valid.
I am talking to you about
an alliance with my sister
And you are flirting with me!
Do you always talk nonsense?
Or today is a special occasion?
No! I always talk nonsense! You?
This is my first time! Actually
I have never met a girl like you.
Come to Bhatinda! I will
introduce you to one!
When we started walking.
The paths too started moving.
These paths seem lovelier
than the destination.
Come. Let's get lost.
Let's get lost somewhere.
Come... Let's walk for miles.
Where to go? It should be unknown.
When we started walking.
The paths too started moving.
These paths seem lovelier
than the destination.
Sitting like this, how will
we discover a new path.
You too walk. And I too will walk.
Only then will these distances
bridge someday.
Sitting like this, we
discover a new path.
Come ...We both should have
no bond with anybody.
Come... Let's walk for miles.
Where to go? It should be unknown.
When we started walking.
The paths too started moving.
These paths seem lovelier
than the destination.
I don't like it without you.
On opening the eyes, slumber says.
What fervour is this?
Here and there. God knows where.
This fervour is taking me.
Come. We will find
a way in this world.
Let's walk for miles.
Where to go? It should be unknown.
When we started walking.
The paths too started moving.
These paths seem lovelier
than the destination.
You are great...
I have never heard anybody
sing so well!
You should have been a singer!
A person doesn't always
get what he wants.
Why? I think that whatever a person
really, actually wants...
...is what he gets.
You know there was a time
when I really wanted...
There was no greater passion
in my life than music!
Your life is over now?
You are talking as though are dead!
Its not over but...
Now music... can't happen anymore.
Why? Why can't you do it?
What is your helplessness?
Tell me!
O God! Don't tell me! Fine!
But don't become an angry
young man again. Please!
Okay.
I will start the conversation
- Of course!
The water is so nice right?
- Yes!
Have you ever jumped in
such a lake before?
Geet, I think we should be leaving!
We should try it! We
will have great fun!
Hang on! Hang on! I wanted
to ask you something.
Have you ever consulted
a physiatrist?
O shut up!
- No! You need one, Geet!
Shut up! And let's jump! - Okay!
Just relax! Just listen to me!
Just think! We might not get the
chance to do such a thing again!
I don't want to do such a thing
ever! Have you gone mad?
You have tried being childish
right? You had great fun
Now try madness!
- Geet, relax! Listen to me!
It was so much fun!
You need a physiatrist!
Don't look here!
Have you heard Dharamraj
Kashyap's name?
The industrialist? Of course!
He died last year! Why?
I am his son!
You... are Aditya... Kashyap!
Yes!
Now you know me.
You are the Kashyap!
It was your mother that ran
away with another man?
Shit. Sorry.
Yes! It was my mother... who
ran away with another man.
Actually I heard it in the
news in this language...
So it came out that way. I am
really sorry. Really, really!
No, Geet! I will have to hear it!
Why you are you saying sorry?
If somebody's mother
can be so cheap...
...if she can do such a
derogatory deed then...
Mr. Kashyap! You shouldn't talk
so disrespectfully about her
Why? That woman destroyed
my entire family
Because of her I will feel ashamed...
...in front of everybody all my life!
So why shouldn't I talk
disrespectfully?
Because she was in love!
- Love? Are you serious!
Look... she is your mother.
So it's difficult to understand
this about her.
But when somebody is in love...
...then nothing is right or wrong!
Who told you all this?
In which stupid novel did
you read all these lines?
Everybody says so! All
is fair in love!
Everybody lies! It's
all hogwash! Got it?
Yes! Yes!
Listen! You are so rich!
Elope with my sister! Everybody's
life will prosper!
You... are an original piece!
Do you know that?
There is no other girl like you!
She has come!
Coming!
Hi, Amrik!
She has come! She has come!
Geet has come, aunt!
So what's the plan?
- Let's see!
You come inside with me!
No, no! No, Geet! I... I will leave.
Where will you go?
I will be okay! Don't worry!
No! You come inside with me!
I can't let you go
like this! Come on!
Geet, really I... I got to go!
Look, my family is here! Don't
create a scene in front of them!
You stay here for sometime.
I want to talk to you.
Then you can leave! Come on!
- Geet!
Hi, mother!
Geet!
- Hi, sexy aunt!
The authorities in the hostel
didn't look after my niece well!
She has become so thin!
How are you?
Come! Come! Come on!
Uncle!
Greetings, grandpa!
Who is this guy?
He is my friend, grandpa.
- What kind of friend?
Grandpa, that is not so!
- What?
I mean... he is just a friend.
- Then why did you bring him home?
Grandpa... he is the one
who has brought me home.
I missed the train at
a station in the night.
If he had not been there...
You know. A girl travelling alone
is like an open treasure box.
I didn't even know him.
We met on the train.
Still he has travelled
so far with me.
To Bhatinda! To escort
me home safely!
No other kind of friendship?
Because in my age... in a
glimpse I get to know...
...what is going on between
a boy and a girl.
Grandpa, please. You
are embarrassing me.
Embarrassing you?
If you had any shame...
Then would you have come home
wearing such clothes?
If you can come home wearing
such clothes...
then in Mumbai you must
be roaming around naked.
What's his name?
Aditya!
- Aditya what?
Aditya Kumar!
Yeah!
What work do you do?
I... am a musician.
Dear, I am indebted to you!
Now you will have to stay
here for a week. With us...
So that we can thank you properly
- Okay!
May God protect you!
People in Mumbai don't eat much!
That is true!
Enough! Enough! Enough! Please!
Please! My stomach will
blow apart! Please!
What nonsense! Have you ever heard
of somebody's stomach blowing up?
Then what? It's really strong!
No... Geet! Geet! Geet!
Please save me!
You people didn't give
him buttermilk?
He has come to Punjab and
nobody gave him buttermilk?
I will get it!
What are you doing?
I have some work with
you! Come inside!
You have saved my sister!
I can do anything for you!
I made a mistake by
saving your sister!
Henceforth I won't save
anybody's sister!
Son, you go ahead. I will
get a night dress for you.
Okay. O God Amrik! I will die!
Nothing will happen! Come on!
You don't understand!
My stomach will tear!
You go and check whether the
guest room is open or not.
What happened?
There is a problem.
- Now what happened?
I had told you that here nobody...
...knows about Anshuman...
Geet! What are you doing?
Good that you came! Aditya,
she is my sister Roop!
Roop, he is Aditya! You
have to elope with him!
Geet! Think for a second
before you start talking.
And what were you doing inside?
Possessive! Already you
are feeling jealous!
Don't worry! We were not doing that!
He is a one woman man! He
will be faithful to you!
The room is open!
- So take him!
Why are you making
him stand here? Go!
Listen. You look there!
It's a secret!
Tomorrow morning get up early!
There is an old tractor in the
field...We will meet there!
Why?
- Bye! Goodnight!
Goodnight!
Wow! Today you are looking
very stylish!
You haven't seen anything yet...
Just wait and watch...
That's great! You speak
Punjabi so fluently!
That's my style too!
From where did you learn how
to speak Punjabi so fluently!
My... my mom was a Punjabi!
Oh Yes! So why don't
you talk in Punjabi?
Just like that!
- You should do it, you know.
You woke me up at 5 in the
morning for this chit-chat?
No! There is a problem!
- What happened?
Manjeet is coming!
- Who is this Manjeet now?
Manjeet Mann! They had shifted
to Patiala a few years ago!
Grandpa and the rest have fixed
my marriage with Manjeet!
And they are coming today to see me!
Hold on! Hold on!
Your opinion won't be taken
into consideration?
They will get you married
just like that?
Actually there is a twist
in the tale. -  Go ahead.
These Mann's... they are
our old family friends.
Manjeet and I have been
together since childhood.
Everybody said that
we will get them...
...married when they will grow up!
I would feel nice to hear
that I will marry Manjeet.
While playing family, I never
let Roop be Manjeet's wife!
When we were 8 years old,
Manjeet and I would...
...stand on this tractor and
hold hands and say that
we will build our house
on those fields
Then I grew up
And I considered this Manjeet
episode as a joke!
But yesterday I came to
know that my parents...
...have not grown up.
They are serious! Everybody
is serious
And now I am in trouble!
So now what?
I am running away!
You always talk of running away!
Don't even think of that!
It's really a cheap thing to do!
There is so many risks and
other problems involved...
There is no other option!
There are countless options!
- Like?
Like... tell your parents
about Anshuman!
They won't agree!
In fact they will trap me here
by emotionally blackmailing me!
Bad option!
Look, if you can't explain
to your parents...
...then forget Anshuman!
Next option!
Don't marry anybody!
- Next!
Get Manjeet and Roop married!
In the court prove that
Manjeet is impotent!
He is not impotent! Next!
How do you know? Hang on! Hang on!
How do you know that Manjeet
is not impotent?
You can tell!
You can tell? Did you and he...
- Next!
Did he tell you that?
Did you see him with somebody?
- Next!
Mr. Dhillon! Great to see you...
All are fools!
Look, how happy they are!
What do they know that
I am going to elope!
Don't come too close to me.
They will misunderstand.
I am not going to marry here!
All these wrestlers will bash me up!
Endure it for me, beloved!
Let go of my shirt!
What are you doing?
This is a nice idea! To
stop this marriage!
This is the right option!
You stay away from me! Got it?
Hello!
- How are you?
Fine! Long time!
- 3 years almost!
After Jaspreet's marriage.
- Yes!
And... how are things in Mumbai?
You people too can talk!
There is no punishment!
She says to talk!
Aditya!
- Yes!
Listen!
Daarji's calling...
Come! Come! I will introduce him!
- Who is he.
He is Aditya! He is a musician!
You won't remember everybody's name!
So meet the main guest.
Manjeet Singh Mann!
Hi, Manjeet!
- How are you?
Sit!
- No, no!
He is a really nice singer!
- I see!
Shouldn't he be singing a song
on this happy occasion?
Yes! Why not?
No, no! She is just joking!
- No, no! I am serious!
Am I laughing? Look!
Ladies and Gentlemen!
My friend Aditya from Mumbai!
He is going to sing
a song for you all!
Uncle, no, no! Please!
Please!
So I want all of you to keep quiet!
Listen! Please!
Look... sit down everybody!
- Dear! - Yes!
Now you do sing!
Let me also see what Mumbai
people can do! - Okay!
Come! Come! Very good! Hey,
fellow! Get a chair!
Come!
Come! Sit! Sit!
Start!
Why are you all looking
at me like this?
I will get nervous!
No problem! Look here and
there! Here and there!
Don't look at him!
I am starting! You all
too please join in!
No problem!
We all too will join in!
We are Punjabis!
We need an opportunity
to start celebrating.
Okay! Silence! Silence!
Settle down! Sit comfortably!
A capricious, bubbly girl.
Her mesmerising eyes
are like daggers.
And her beauty is lethal.
When her beauty created rampage,
the discussion started.
Beat the drum. Beat the drum.
A capricious, bubbly girl.
Her mesmerising eyes
are so piercing.
And her beauty is lethal.
Her deadly beauty is the
point of discussion.
Beat the drum. Beat the drum.
Whenever that girl
comes to the window.
Some see her and die.
And some die without seeing her.
When she would pass the lanes,
there would be festivity.
Every lover used to
celebrate and dance.
And the feast would begin.
Beat the drum. Beat the drum.
My youth is yours in any case.
You need not try to steal my beauty.
Since childhood she had a beloved.
His task was to keep the
other lovers at bay.
The one whom he had to make
the queen of his heart.
She was crazy for somebody else.
One story ended and another began.
Beat the drum. Beat the drum.
A capricious, bubbly girl.
Her mesmerising eyes
are so piercing.
And her beauty is lethal.
Her deadly beauty is the
point of discussion.
Beat the drum. Beat the drum.
We mainly deal in fertilizers.
- Okay.
And now we are going to enter
pesticide market too.
Is that so?
- Uncle is planning...
Hang on!
Hit here! Come on! Hit!
Hit! Hit! Hit!
Superb!
- Go! Your papa is calling you!
O God!
- Now what are you going to do?
Is he coming?
- Who?
Manjeet!
- Yes!
Is he looking here?
- Yes! You stay away!
Did he see?
Manjeet, she is just playing
a drama! Stand straight!
O no! Manjeet!
Look, Manjeet! What you are
thinking... that's not true!
She is playing a charade!
Ask her! Tell him!
Yes, yes! He is right, Manjeet!
There is nothing between
us! I swear!
We are just by-the-way friends.
Tell him, Aditya!
Nothing had happened between
us even in Mumbai!
Nothing at all! Tell him!
Papa said he didn't call me!
- He is lying! I will come!
Listen, brother!
You are mistaken! There is nothing
between me and Geet!
We didn't even meet in Mumbai!
She was just playing a charade!
I might not be smart
like city people!
But I do have eyes! I can see!
She did all this to show you!
- Why?
Because...
- Tell me!
Why would she want to show me this?
You better ask her that!
As it is you both have known
each other since childhood...
Don't shout!
Are you mad? What
are you doing here?
Congratulations! You
ruined everything!
I had such a nice plan in place!
By now Manjeet would have
returned to Patiala!
Now he says that he will
talk to me alone!
So I am going!
- Where?
What do you mean where?
I am running away!
Geet... don't ever do that! Okay!
I am doing it! Everything
is planned!
I have come say bye to you!
You are leaving now?
As in right now?
Yes! You stay here for a few days!
After that you go back
to Mumbai! Okay!
Hang on! Hang on! You
are running away!
And I should stay here!
- So?
Tomorrow Manjeet will open his
mouth and these people...
...who already think you and
I are having an affair...
...they will tie me with
their buffaloes!
Great! Then you come with me too!
If we run away together then their
suspicion will be confirmed!
Big deal! What difference
does that make to you?
Correct! What difference
does that make to me?
Come on!
Listen! Did you tell Roop that
we are running away? - Why?
O God! Run!
Geet!
What are you doing?
I will return in two days!
I will call you tomorrow!
And please! You are under my oath!
Don't tell anybody! Okay?
Papa! Uncle!
- What's the plan?
Geet is running away!
- There are many options! - Options?
We can either go to the railway
station or the bus stand!
But how will we reach there?
Let's see! We might get an auto
rickshaw from the main road!
Unbelievable, man!
- Come on!
This is your plan?
Let's see, we might get an auto
rickshaw from the main road?
Do you have any brains?
Did I know that Roop will see us?
Now why are we standing here?
Let's go!
- Wait!
Why are you looking there? Run!
Not there! Here! Come on!
I am not going back!
You have created enough nuisance!
Now do as I say! Come on! Come on!
But why are we going back?
- Just shut up and run!
Where did they go?
- Towards the road!
You let them go? You
didn't stop them?
Satya, go and check! Hurry up!
Call the guys!
There is a staircase for
going to the terrace.
Why the terrace?
- Will you tell me?
Come on!
Hey, quickly open the garage!
Take the jeep out!
Found them?
Where will they go?
Where did you see them?
- They left from the gate!
What happened?
I knew it! In the first
glance I recognized him!
Raj, get my wallet from the room.
I found out what is going
on between them!
But you people are very
intelligent, aren't you?
You people don't heed me!
Where are you? Open the garage!
Come on!
What are we doing here?
Look, Roop saw us going
towards the front gate!
They would have easily caught
us in their jeeps and bikes!
Now they will go out! They
will call other people too!
They will search everywhere!
But they won't search the house!
So now we will wait here!
Then at the right time we will
leave from the backyard...
...and reach the taxi stand
on the other side.
Got it?
You had even planned to elope
with that photograph girl?
Come on, Hurry up.
Have faith in God!
She told us everything!
Why did she hide this?
All this is that Aditya's doing!
He only has corrupted Geet's mind!
Listen! Carefully!
- It's all his doing!
You have high BP!
He stayed with us! He
even ate with us!
Don't get so angry!
If I catch him, I won't spare him!
We will thrash him!
I will thrash him black and blue!
Where is your boyfriend meeting you?
In Manali!
He is not coming to
Bhatinda to meet you?
Actually I have not been
able to speak to him!
No man!
Please don't tell me that
the man doesn't even know...
...that you are running away for him!
What are you doing, Geet?
Why are you playing with your life?
Because it's my favourite
game! Life!
What's yours? Football? Badminton?
I know! Car racing! Right?
You know... I used to think that...
...there are many problems
in my life!
Now how to get out of this problem?
You are so selfish! You are
thinking only about yourself!
What about me?
What about you? This is your
life! It's your plan!
You are going to elope!
What am I doing here?
I mean, I am taking the risk of
running away with the girl!
People are looking to murder me!
And I don't even get
the girl! Great!
I told you to elope with Roop!
You are having fun! Right?
Uncle has gone to the
railway station!
Has asked should we
inform the police?
No! Don't inform the police!
You have to go to school!
So go to sleep!
Fine! I will check the bus stand!
Take my cell along!
Don't worry! Everything
will be fine! Just watch!
You are consoling me, Geet?
I will just take a flight
and go away from all this!
What about you?
The way you are handling your life...
...you can get into a
grave problem, Geet!
Do you realise that?
Life is not just about fun
and merriment, Geet!
You have to be serious in life too!
Aditya, you were very
serious in life!
What was the use?
You got into a grave trouble too!
What is going to happen
in the future...
...nobody can control that.
So I do what my heart tells me!
In the future I don't
want to blame anybody!
That my life got ruined
because of you!
No matter what my life becomes...
I will know it's like
this because of me!
So I will be happy!
Too much philosophy, right?
These moments... which we
are spending together...
...its really a lovely time.
Just watch! In the future we
will remember this and laugh!
I will return very soon!
Soon as I get married
and with Anshuman...
...I will fall at their feet!
They will scold me, taunt me.
Then they will give their consent.
Let's go.
Tell me the truth. What
I am doing. Is it right?
No! What you are doing is not right.
But you only had said... that
when somebody is in love...
...there is no right or wrong.
All is fair.
And if today I can understand
my mother... then don't worry.
In the future your parents
will understand you.
Come on!
There is some reason.
That I am enjoying
my life like this.
What is in the breeze?
That a slight intoxication
has entered me.
Don't ask what has happened to me.
Coming in your path.
Don't ask what I will get.
Coming in your arms.
This love gives you
a glimpse of heaven.
O God!
This love gives you
a glimpse of heaven.
I have broken all the
bondages of the world.
I won't break my promise.
You are half the part of
the tale of my heart.
I am the other half, beloved.