Kate & Leopold (2001) - 23.976 fps
Cleaned by Xylo
Time.
Time, it has been proposed
is the fourth dimension.
And yet, for mortal man,
time has no dimension at all.
We are like horses
with blinders
seeing only
what lies before us.
Forever guessing the future
and fabricating the past.
Brilliant.
Quite right, Your Grace.
How, you ask, can we lift
these shackles and live-
not in the moment
but in the glorious expanse
of time's continuum?
Listen, and I shall tell you.
The secret lies in the enduring
power of our achievements
our creations!
As the pyramids testify
to the Egyptians
so my glorious erection
shall represent
our culture in perpetuity.
Behold, rising before you
the greatest erection
on the continent.
The greatest erection
of the age!
on the planet!
Hold this.
Of course.
For the Herald, Your Grace.
I understand
you'll be making
an important announcement
tonight.
Good afternoon, ladies.
Please, excuse me, please.
Good afternoon.
And the Perrier-Jouet
should be chilled.
- You understand? Chilled.
- Yes, sir.
Leopold!
Leopold, where have you been?
Otis, I demand explication!
It's half past 5:00!
He's not even dressed!
He'll be ready, my lord.
I assure you.
I don't want him ready.
I want him resplendent!
Ah, Miss Blaine.
You dance like a...
like a herd of cattle.
You are a rare woman
who lights up a room
simply by leaving it.
Might you be rich,
Miss Blaine?
You see, whilst I
am the third Duke
the little secret of those
of us in the Royal Court-
apart from our
general uselessness-
is our massive
indebtedness.
It's always been
your misfortune, Leopold
that you so thoroughly
amuse yourself
with the sound
of your own voice.
In a life as stagnant as mine
that I can amuse myself at all
is an evolutionary marvel.
Please don't touch that.
The device you were
jabbering about.
To take priests
to the bell tower.
To take anyone, Uncle, to
the floor they so desire.
Buildings continue to climb.
Soon they will outstrip
the stamina of our legs.
You speak of progress
and invention.
Yet what I offer you downstairs
is reality.
Take a wife. Marry.
Marriage...
marriage is the promise
of eternal love.
As a man of honor, I can
not promise eternally
what I have never
felt momentarily.
Born into privilege,
yet perversely ashamed of it.
That is your tragedy.
My God! If my brother
could only see you,
he'd be heartbroken.
You are no duke!
Of course I'm not.
The monarchy is dead, Uncle.
We are relics.
That is reality.
The new Royals are men
of accomplishment.
Men like Roebling,
with his bridge
Edison, with his lamp
Diesel, Bell, Westinghouse...
Those men made themselves
from nothing!
You, on the other hand,
were born with everything
and from it,
fashioned nothing.
As of tonight,
I wash my hands of you.
Take a good look
at your dance card, Leopold.
A wealthy bride
is your only surety.
Your Grace,
may I present Miss Tree
of the Trees
of Schenectady, sir.
Miss Tree?
It's an honor to be making
your royal acquaintance,
Your Highness.
Shall we?
Many dreams, all useless.
Who are you?
No, no, no.
Okay, rela...
Please, wait, no.
I don't want to harm you.
Stop! Please!
Sir, wait!
Pardon me. Pardon me.
Go! Go!
Ya!-
Ya!
Stop, sir! Please!
Oh, my God.
No!
Oh!
Let go!
Just let go. It's okay!
You don't understand!
Let go!
Oh!
I don't want to hurt you!
Let go!
Goddamn it!
Bart!
Wait!
Shit!
Oh, my God.
We must remember, Bart
that sometimes it is okay
to color outside the lines.
Hello?
My Palm Pilot.
You still have it.
Kate, it's 1:00 in the morning.
And clearly you're awake,
so what is the infraction?
Look, Kate, I don't know
where your Palm Pilot is.
And I can't do this right now.
Not now. I'm expecting a call.
Oh, Bart.
Oh, I'm sorry, baby.
She is not a happy person.
Goddamn it!
You know what, Stuart?
You know what? I'm...
Kate...
Please. I've got
somebody here, okay?
I know. I saw her.
No, you didn't.
Yes, I did!
It's a him, if that's
any kind of consolation to you.
So, look, now that you know
I'm not getting laid,
just go to bed, okay?
Nuh-uh, don't. Do not
hang up on me, Stuart.
Don't do that.
Kate, please.
I beg of you.
Something big is happening.
Something that validates
my entire life...
What could that possibly be?
- Are you sitting down?
- Yes.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
- Ye...
Okay.
I found it.
What did you find?
The portal.
A crack in the fabric of time.
It was over
the East River, Kate
- just where I said it would be.
- You found the portal?
A portal into April 28th, 1876.
I jumped off the Brooklyn Bridge
and took a walk
in 1876 today.
I followed the Duke of Albany
around old New York.
- Are you listening?
- Avidly.
This here's the twist, Kate.
Here's the kicker.
What's the kicker?
He followed me home.
The Duke of Buffalo...
No, the Duke of Albany.
...Albany followed you home
through a crack in time.
He's a brilliant engineer.
He patented
the counterweight pulley.
He invented the elevator,
for Christ's sake.
You know what, Stuart?
You know what?
I'm not your girlfriend anymore.
I haven't been
for a whole month now.
You can tell me the truth.
I am telling you
the truth, Kate.
You can tell me you went
and picked up a transvestite
in Times Square.
I don't care.
You know what, Kate?
This is it, right here.
This is it, in a nutshell.
Our downfall.
You never- not once-
believed in me.
Oh, I did, Stuart.
I did, for four years.
And I got burnt.
Okay, you want to know
who he is?
I'll tell you who he is.
He is a hacker.
High end. English.
I know him from Columbia.
He's in town for the Mac Expo
at the Javits.
We went out, got a little sloppy
on Guinness
and he passed out on my couch.
And that's the truth?
Mm-hmm. That's the truth.
Okay? Are you happy now?
Is that plausible enough
for you and your little
focus group?
You know what, Stuart?
I blew my best years on you.
Those were your best?
Look...
I'm sorry.
I have to go.
You'll get your Pilot in the morning.
Orange alert.
Otis!-
Otis!
Bart, stop!
It's okay.
- It's okay.
- Where am I?
Well, um, there's not
an easy explanation for that.
If it's a ransom you seek,
my uncle won't pay a cent.
Except, perhaps, for my demise.
No. no. You're not
being kidnapped.
Bart, quiet!
I can scarcely see,
thanks to your spray.
My eyes feel like Steak au Poivre.
So I ask you again,
where the hell am I?
As far as I'm concerned,
you might be Jack the Ripper!
And you would have me believe
that I'm being detained
at present in the hereafter?
- The time to come?
- Yes.
Bart, quiet!
He needs a walk.
Oh, and you would have me believe
that you have found
a crack in time.
You, of all people,
should understand.
I mean, you're a scientist.
You invented the elevator.
What is an elevator?
What the hell are you talk...
Where the hell am I?
I told you-
you haven't actually gone anywhere.
You're still in New York.
That, sir, is not New York!
I'm afraid it is.
- No, Kate.
- Hello. Hello there.
What's your name?
- Leopold.
- Tell me something.
I'm having trouble
with my G-5.
How much RAM do I need
to properly run OS 9.6?
Clearly, the Mac Expo is out.
So you must be...
a man out of time?
Or Sergeant Pepper?
You know what?
Actually, we could use
a little privacy.
Stuart, I want my Palm Pilot.
- I'm not... I'm serious.
- Maybe later on, Kate.
I just want
my Palm Pilot, Stuart!
- No. No.
- Hey, give me my Palm Pilot!
Give it to me.
This is madness.
Who was that?
I-I feel as if I've seen her...
Women have changed
since your time, Leo.
They've become dangerous.
It's on the landing!
You say this is no kidnapping.
You say you mean no harm.
Then why is it, sir,
you will not unlock the door?
I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry about her. I'm...
Look, with all due respect
I can't let you just go running
around free out there, okay?
This is New York City.
It's not such a safe place
anymore.
Look at you.
You look like some sort
of psychotic escapee
from a Renaissance fair.
I understand you
have some anxiety
but you have to trust me.
I'm going to get you home, okay?
I promise.
Bart!
The portal opens up again
next week. Monday.
I know that, because it was
my back-up
in case I didn't make it last night.
It's on a cycle, you know?
Kind of like, uh...
total eclipse.
Once every 20 years.
You understand?
Generally,
I understand everything.
Since I've met you, nothing.
I can only assume
I'm in a nightmare
brought on by agita,
or else I am dead.
You're not dead.
Come here. Sit down.
Here.
Want some milk in yours?
Bart, can I just have...
Sorry. He's really
got to go out.
I'd be honored
if you took a look at those.
I'll explain everything
when I get back.
He's got to go out
or he'll drop a bomb in there.
Come on. Let's go.
Back in five.
One quick trip to Spectra, Bart
and you and I will be Nobel...
Laureates.
Come on, Bart.
Hey, let's go.
Come on. Let's go!
Oh, Jesus!
Good boy, Bart!
Stay!
Stay, Bart. Stay!
Oh, Bart, please stay!
Stuart, you forgot
the pointy thing!
Stuart...
Look, this is not complex.
He gave me the Palm Pilot
but he forgot
the pointy thing.
- I've been warned about you.
- Oh. Really?
And what, pray tell
did the great disappointment say?
That you were dangerous,
though you hardly look it.
- Oh, really?
- A lady in trousers isn't dangerous, merely plain.
- I take it you're a career woman.
- Yeah, market research.
Fine avocation
for women, research.
Perfect for the feminine mind.
You're a trip, Lionel.
I myself once courted
a librarian in Sussex.
Oh.
Good for you.
I must confess, I feel as though
we've met on a previous occasion.
Well, Lionel, seeing as I've never
met a single friend of Stuart's-
I'm not even sure
he's ever had any-
I really don't see
how that's possible.
Oh, man! Bart!
He just made Lake Erie
out there.
You just can't toss a dog
out into the hall like that.
- You can't do that.
- I assure you, I did not.
Let's go.
- I beg your pardon?
- Come on. Let's go!
Look, pal, I don't care
how many elevators you've got.
This one's in my building.
Hang on a second.
Sorry about
the elevator, Miss Kate.
I've got them
on the phone right now.
Hey, Gracy. This is Lionel,
Stuart's friend.
How do you do?
Ten minutes?
I need someone here right now.
- Watch it, man.
- I beg your pardon.
Hey, what are you doing?
You need to be going
that way.
There's an electron... Hello?
- There's an electronics store.
- I'm sorry, miss.
There's a patch of grass
across the street.
Take him there.
He'll do his business.
Can you give this to Stuart, please?
It's his cable bill.
They haul our furniture
and cradle our children
but this morning, from
the Battery to the Bronx
elevators have mysteriously...
So sorry.
- Stupid!
- I do beg your pardon.
I beg your pardon.
Are you going to remove that?
I beg your pardon?
Pick it up
and put it in the trash.
Absolutely not.
Maybe you don't understand.
It's against the law
to leave it there.
Are you suggesting, madam,
there exists a law
compelling gentlemen to lay hold
of canine bowel movements?
I'm suggesting you pick the poop up
and throw it away now.
I refuse. Respectfully.
All right.
What's your name, fancy pants?
Leopold...
Alexis Elija...
Walker Thomas Garrett
Mountbatten.
All right, Stuart.
Have a nice day.
I appreciate you putting in
a good word for me
but J.J.'s not back from London.
Right. Bye.
- What's with the elevators?
- It's happening everywhere.
Darci.
Last page.
I'm sorry.
Did everyone live
happily ever after?
He lost his leg to gangrene
waiting for her on the island.
But they're together now.
Wonderful.
- Oh, look, you got your Palm Pilot back.
- A nightmare.
Okay, so who do I owe?
Okay, Bobby at Hasbro,
Reeves at Crunch.
And the finals came in
for "Love for Sale."
The call with the studio is
at 4:00.
The margarine thing's in 15
in the conference room.
And J.J. wants to talk
to you before that.
Oh, and one more thing.
I remember that you told me
to start thinking ahead
so I know your brother's
getting back
from his retreat tomorrow
and if you want something
in the fridge...
- Darci...
- Mm-hmm?
Can you tell me
why I'm upset right now?
Because, uh...
J.J. called this morning.
That is why I have a cell phone.
- So you can call me...
- Kate, Kate, he didn't call.
He just popped his head in here
and spoke two sentences.
So he's back?
Margo says he's going to make
a big announcement
about the merger next week.
Margo? What does she know?
How does she know
anything about anything?
Oh. All right. So he
popped his head in here.
All right, so you have to tell
me exactly what he said, Darci.
You have to start
at the beginning and tell me...
He said, "Tell Kate I'm going
to sit in on Farmer's Bounty."
J.J.
Good morning, Kate.
Good morning.
I'll see you in there.
Good Lord, it still stands.
The world has changed
all around it
but Roebling's erection
still stands!
That, my friend, is a miracle.
- What?
- It's a miracle, man!
It's a bridge.
Tell me... when did they
adapt it for steam engines?
The fire brigade.
I don't know how it happened.
I found him in a shaft.
Stuart!
Leopold, what are you doing
out here?
Get back inside!
They're taking him
to Goodman Memorial.
"Fresh creamery butter."
"Is there anything
more comforting?"
"There is,
and I know you will agree"
"when you try Farmer's Bounty"
"with the essence of real butter
in every bite."
Your first choice.
However, 45% of our demo
circled "shifty"
as his key descriptor.
Not good.
"This is what I say."
"Everybody should be trying
Farmer's Bounty"
"with the real, rich, creamy
taste of real butter."
"Try it, and you will be losing
pounds. Poof! Boom! Voila!"
Your second choice.
Unfortunately, the group found
him obnoxious, abrasive
and a whopping 72%
found him just plain creepy.
The spot rolls out in four days.
We have to shoot...
The product is shipping,
what the hell am I supposed to do?
We have to do
another session, tomorrow.
I had my assistant book the
response room at National
so we can decide then and there.
Kate, are you all right?
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
Geez, Kate, I'd ask for a decaf.
Monica, I need you
to call Barney's.
I need a white blouse,
size small
in Kate's office by lunch.
Oh, dear.
"Hi, you've reached Stuart."
"Please leave a message."
Leopold? Leopold, look,
don't be frightened.
This is Stuart, okay?
I see it is Bell's talking telegraph.
I saw a prototype
at last year's fair.
I need you to pick up
the handset, Leo.
You pick up the green handset,
because I need to talk to you...
Are-are you there?
- Hello?
- Leopold, thank God.
Listen, they're taking me
to X-Rays.
Everything's going to be fine
but you have to stay in the apartment.
Do you understand me?
Oh, Stuart,
I saw Roebling's bridge today.
I saw it... complete.
Yes, yes, but listen to me.
You can't go out again.
You have to stay
in the apartment.
Stay in the apartment?
For how long?
Leo, I'll be back tonight.
I promise-
no more field trips.
Would you...
Hel... hello?
Stuart? Hello?
Blast!
Hello.
Hello. Who are you?
Hector. My mom works late
on Wednesdays
so I watch TV with Stuart.
Want some Pirate's Booty?
Hang on.
Excuse me, J.J., I wanted
to thank you for the shirt.
That was very nice.
Come in, come in.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Absolutely.
Oh, good, good.
Yeah, she's here right now.
I'll tell her.
Okay... okay.
Bye.
Sit down.
That was Barry.
He was thrilled with your work
at the screening last night.
Oh, good. Good.
You're a rarity
among women, Kate.
I'm sorry?
You don't cling to illusion.
You don't get caught up
in emotion.
You don't do pretty.
I don't?
You skew male.
You're like a man.
A man who understands women-
their desires, their needs.
You understand them
but you're not really one of them.
- You don't mind my being frank, do you?
- No. I don't. No.
Endamame?
Kate?
One day, he lowered
the Jolly Roger
- Stu?
- and set sail in search
of another kind of treasure.
Not money, not jewels,
not gold...
but a bride.
Despite his being a ruffian
of the brine
fearless in his plunder
and merciless with the sword
the Pirate King
was also lonely.
You see,
he had never met a lady.
He never met a girl?
No. Not a girl, not a lady,
not even his own mother.
- So what happened?
- As with all comedies
the most ridiculous thing
imaginable- the Pirate King
fell in love with
the major general's daughter.
I had the good fortune to see
the premiere last month
at the Fifth Avenue Theatre.
Since when is
Penzance at the Fifth?
Is it your habit, sir
to simply enter a conversation
without introduction?
Whoa, you are deep in it.
It's cool. I'm an actor, too.
I'm Charlie. I live downstairs.
Kate McKay,
senior vice president.
Darci, it hasn't happened.
All he did
was dangle a carrot.
Until he makes a decision
the pressure's doubled.
When's he going
to make a decision?
We're having dinner tomorrow
to discuss it further
at Commune.
- Kate?
- Yeah.
- I have Stuart on the line.
- No!
- He says he's in the hospital.
Leopold is just sitting alone
in my apartment right now.
God knows what could happen
to him.
Do you know he got outside today?
Of course he did-
I made him walk your dog.
What? No, Kate,
you can't do that!
He can't go outside!
Jesus Christ, Kate.
He's from 1876, Kate.
He doesn't know our customs.
If something were
to happen to him
- it could be catastrophic.
- Shh!
If he doesn't go back
to April 28, 1876,
he doesn't get married
he doesn't have children,
and you want to know what?
What happened
with the elevators today, well
that's going to seem
like a walk in the park.
Stuart! This is embarrassing.
It's embarrassing now,
all right?
Someone has to keep
an eye on him.
Stuart, he's a grown man.
He's a grown man. He's fine.
He can take care of himself.
- No. Wait. Aah!
- I'm going.
Kate, please.
Just take this to Spectra, okay?
Get it developed.
You'll see I'm telling
the truth.
Tell Manny it's important.
You want double prints?
That's not funny, Kate.
This is not a joke.
You need help, Stuart.
You need help.
Charlie?
Hey, Kate!
Can I see you downstairs
for a minute?
I invited someone to dinner.
He's up there all alone.
Stuart's in the hospital.
I didn't think you'd
have such a problem...
No, you didn't think, Charlie.
You didn't think.
You came home early,
one day early from actor camp.
Okay, it's not actor camp
and yeah, I came home
a day early, all right?
There was this tai chi
broad who kept trying
- stick her fingers...
- No, this is the point.
You immediately march upstairs
to my ex-boyfriend's apartment
and you invite
his freakish friend...
See, that's what it's about.
It's not that
I went up there.
It's that it was
your ex-boyfriend...
No, it's not about Stuart.
- Greetings, Kate, Charles.
- Hey, Leo.
Be nice.
So, when's Stuart getting back?
Couple of days, maybe a week.
He promised me that he would
return late this evening.
Well, maybe he will, Leopold.
He's so big on keeping
his promises.
May I have the next course?
There is no next course.
Where I come from, the meal...
is the result of reflection and study.
Menus are prepared in advance
timed to perfection.
It is said,
without the culinary arts
the crudeness of reality
would be unbearable.
We had a saying
in the McKay house:
"You shake and shake
the ketchup bottle.
None will come,
and then a lot'll."
What is that?
- I beg your pardon?
- Why are you standing?
I'm accustomed to stand
when a lady leaves the table.
Tell me, Charles
when Stuart and your
sister were engaged
did you happen to read
his papers on
the temporal universe?
I spent the morning perusing
them, and must confess...
Stuart and I were never engaged.
Not even close.
But I did read...
Thank you.
But I did read his papers, however,
to show support.
Is Stuart still trying
to make a time machine?
That's the beauty of it
he discovered no machine was necessary.
All one had to do was
to develop formulae to forecast portals-
natural windows
in the fabric of time.
Apparently, Stuart located one
utilizing modern...
Utilizing modern theories
of weather prediction.
What's a portal?
An opening which exists
for but a moment.
This explains why one must
jump through it from a height-
in order to achieve
the required velocity.
The speed of gravity,
to be exact.
It's quite brilliant.
You are so method.
You don't even break
for a second, do you?
It's unbelievable!
Oh, stop it, please!
No more! Stop, please?
I beg you. I'm tired.
Can you go away?
Can you just go away?
She's drunk, Leo.
Oh, shut up, Charlie!
And you, can you go upstairs?
Can you go away?
I am truly sorry if I have
offended you in any way.
Goodnight, Charles.
Goodnight, Leo.
What the hell was that?
He thinks he's from
the 19th century, Charlie.
He thinks he's a duke.
- I know. Isn't that cool?
Kate, he's in character.
He is an actor.
Oh, really? For what show?
You know that just because someone
doesn't have a paying gig
it doesn't mean they're not
working on their craft.
What's going on here?
I think there's something wrong
with his, uh...
thing.
Give me that telephone.
No.
- Give it to me.
- No, I need to...
What do you expect me to do?
You took away my cell phone.
They're not allowed
on hospital property.
I have to make a phone call!
You're not going
to make one now.
No, no, you don't understand.
This is a very important phone call.
I have to leave this hospital now.
I can't be here anymore.
Mr. Besser,
I'm tired of telling you this.
You are not going nowhere
until Dr. Feinstein signs
your release!
Did you ever take any
earth science, Esther, hmm?
You look like a smart woman.
Ever hear of the
time-space continuum?
Sounds important, doesn't it?
Well, it is.
And you want to know
something, Esther?
It's broken! Okay?
And I'm the only guy
who can fix it.
So why don't you
go down the hall there
and get on your
little telephone
and call Dr. Feinstein...
Goodnight, Mr. Besser.
You tell him that...
You tell him that I...
Point the toes,
pull your shoulders back.
Take a deep breath in
and then exhale
into downward-facing dog.
Oh, be quiet!
Be quiet... oh!
Bart, shut up!
That thing is a damned hazard!
It's just a toaster!
Well, insertion of bread
into that so-called toaster
produces no toast at all-
merely warm bread!
Inserting the bread twice
produces charcoal.
So, clearly, to make proper toast
it requires 1 1/2 insertions
which is something for which
the apparatus doesn't begin to allow!
One assumes
that when the General of Electric
built it
he might have tried using it.
One assumes the General might
take pride in his creations
instead of just foisting them
on an unsuspecting public.
You know something?
Nobody gives a rat's ass
that you have to push
the toast down twice.
You know why?
Because everybody
pushes their toast down twice!
Not where I come from.
Oh, because where you come from
toast is the result
of reflection and study.
Yes, you mock me.
But perhaps one day,
when you've awoken from a
pleasant slumber
to the scent of a warm brioche
smothered in marmalade
and fresh creamery butter
you'll understand that life
is not solely comprised
of tasks, but tastes.
Say that again.
Pardon me?
- Did they start yet?
- Yes.
Session list.
Leopold, Darci.
Darci, Leopold.
I'd like him to read.
Can you tack him on at the end?
And, Leopold, go with Darci.
She'll take you to the greenroom
and explain everything.
I need to work out.
I need a place I can work out.
If I could get Mr. Duke?
Is he ready? Where is he?
Oh, my God, look at this.
Let's skip this one.
Mr. Duke.
Right here on the floor.
Excuse me, that's your marker, right there.
Just stand on that tape line.
Look, forget this guy.
I can't waste any more time, J.J.
We need to make
a decision now.
All right, we've got
plenty of good choices.
Let's cut it off, Kate.
That would be a mistake, J.J.
Kate, the client wants
to move on.
We should see this last guy.
It'll... Two minutes!
I think he looks like
the Quaker Oats guy.
Well, Phil, it's really not
about what you think.
It's about what they think.
They've been in a coma all day
and now look at them.
To them, this guy is a dream.
He's handsome,
honest, courteous.
Stands when you
walk in a room.
Brings you brioche in bed.
If you eat his margarine
maybe your hips will shrink
and he'll come to your door.
I take it this is to be
delivered in direct address
as on Geronimo.
Geronimo?
He means Geraldo.
Exactly.
Okay, everyone- quiet please.
And action.
Start talking, bud.
Fresh creamery butter.
Is there anything
more comforting?
I say there is.
And perhaps you'll agree when you sample
fat-free Farmer's Bounty
with the genuine essence
of creamery butter
in every bite.
With every mouthful
of Farmer's Bounty
you shall receive butter's
luxurious comfort in your mouth
without adding to the luxury
of your waistline.
Not bad, Kate.
Where'd you find him?
He lives in my building.
- Where do I sign?
- Right here, and here.
Oh! Hi.
That was spectacular, Kate.
- Thanks, J.J.
- A lot to talk about tonight at dinner.
- Nice work, Mr. Margarine.
- Thank you.
Outfit was a great idea. Nice.
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
You seem pleased.
Oh, you did so great in there!
Man!
You are going to be on
a national television spot!
I take it you're dining
with that man tonight.
Huh? Oh, yeah, J.J.
He's my boss.
You require a chaperone.
His intentions are obvious.
Oh, I'm alone with you.
Do I need a chaperone?
We're not courting, Kate.
If we were, as a man of honor
I would have informed you
of my intentions in writing.
Good day.
- Hey!
- Kate, why don't we take one of these.
They're for tourists.
Sorry, she doesn't
seem interested.
Oh, hey, hello. Hello.
Hey! Hey, you...
Kate!
Hey, you asshole!
I'm gonna get you!
Asshole!
Goddamn it.
Give me your hand.
What?
Your hand, woman!
Yah! Yah!
What do you think you're doing?
Whoa, hey!
Yah!
I warn you, scoundrel
I was trained to ride
at King's Academy
and schooled in weaponry by the
palace guard. You stand no chance.
Where you run, I shall ride
and when you stop,
the steel of this strap
will be lodged in your brain.
Your boyfriend's
a very good rider.
Yeah.
Are you for real?
Pardon me?
I believe so.
You're a duke.
I was born a duke.
I've never felt like one.
Stay. Sit.
On your feet. Stay.
Stay. Good boy.
I'm off to dinner.
What are you two doing?
I don't know. Maybe we'll...
watch the rest of the game
or go out or something.
Oh, thank you.
Kate, may I repeat my offer
to serve as a chaperone?
No, thank you, Leopold.
Charles, don't you
find this inappropriate?
- As her brother, I would think...
- As her brother, I would think
that my sister would invite me
to an audition.
Could be just me, though.
Seems kind, but...
- Charlie.
- Hmm?
You're not exactly
a margarine spokesperson.
- I can't sell butter, Kate?
- I don't mean to be insulting...
It's insulting. I'm an actor.
You don't have faith in me to sell butter?
- No. No. I'm sorry.
- I can do British, Kate.
- I'm an actor. I can be anybody!
- You're a very, very good actor.
- I am a good actor.
- You are.
Okay, fine, all right.
A Victorian dude who's never
seen a Mets game watching TV.
Scene: I say, are those little people
in that box of phosphorous?
Why, crikey! I believe it is!
This game's more
beguiling than cricket!
Indian: Good golly, oh, Jesus!
It looks like Mike Piazza
just hit a game!
How about Canadian?
Oh, right on.
Right on, you like butter, huh?
Yeah, what's that about?
Good night
Good night.
...all those people
up in that stadium.
Know what they probably could go for?
Some margarine!
When your friend walked in
in that outfit
I was getting a little
nervous for you there.
"If you eat his margarine,
maybe your hips will shrink."
It's brilliant. You saved Phil
from his own ambivalence.
I knew it was the way to go-
in my gut.
I'm counting on that gut.
Can I get a bottle of your '95 Lynch-Bages
and a bottle of Evian?
I'll tell you one thing:
your friend
is going to be bigger than Mr. Whipple.
Thanks.
You're not sleeping with him,
are you?
No
No.
Leo. Leo, come on. Come here.
How's it going, man?
See the girl with
the long brown hair?
That's Patrice.
She's lovely.
She's mine.
Congratulations.
Hey, everybody, this is Leo!
Leo, this is everybody.
What's up? Dennis.
Shelby, Allison, Monica.
And this, this is
the insatiable Patrice.
- Hey, Charlie.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- How do you do?
- Patrice, let me assist you.
- Thanks.
You got it?
I was going to get it.
Let me get that for you.
There you go.
You look nice tonight. Very...
Like a Judy Blume book.
That's good, because I thought for a moment
that body of water here
was a moat.
No, that's a pond.
The gardens are devastating.
They are. They're very,
very beautiful.
You'll have to come
and see them firsthand.
Right, right.
After the merger I'm going to be stuck
over there, setting things up.
I'll be craving a little face time
from my new top honcho in New York.
- What are you saying?
- I'm saying you should come visit.
- I'll fly you over for the weekend.
- Oh, yeah, I heard that, but the...
the other part,
the part before that.
The part about the top honcho.
I didn't understand that,
that part.
How about catching an opera
Saturday?
La Boheme's at the Met.
Okay, so she comes back-
the audience is about to leave-
she comes back on stage
and she starts squirting the audience
with this turkey baster
filled with this pine mist.
And she's screaming
"Un-sex me! Un-sex me!"
But no tears.
Just raw human passion.
Isn't... Willem Dafoe
part of that group?
Yeah, and he did this monologue
about how
all the best things in life are
hidden in people's basements.
Like the Louvre.
I'm sorry.
You were saying, Charles?
- Just...
- No, what about the Louvre?
Tell us what you
were going to say.
Well, only a fraction of
the Louvre is on the walls.
- The rest is in the basement.
- You've been in the basement of the Louvre?
Oh, yes.
I was an art history major
at Vassar.
And so, what's down there?
Well, that's where
the real show begins.
Unspoiled by dilettante.
Da Vinci, Michelangelo,
David, Chardin.
"Allow me to assist you, Patrice."
"Oh, let me light that
for you, Monica."
"What, this?"
"This is my family crest."
"Been in the family for..."
"Oh, in the basement?"
"What do they have in the basement?
Why, the works of da Vinci"
"Michelangelo, Chardin, David"
"all surrounded by great coral
sponges to absorb the moisture."
Just for the record, I was working it.
I was in the zone
and I would have
gotten her number
if you hadn't turned
the evening
into a guided tour
of the Louvre.
My apologies.
Let's get
one thing straight.
Patrice, she thought
you were cute -
probably gay and cute.
And cute, Leo,
that's the kiss of death.
- Perhaps.
- Perhaps? Certainly.
I believe this is her number.
As I see it, Patrice has not
an inkling of your affections.
And it's no wonder.
You, Charles,
are a merry-andrew.
A what?
Everything plays a farce to you.
Women respond to sincerity.
This requires pulling one's
tongue from one's cheek.
No one wants to be
romanced by a buffoon.
Now, that number rings her.
- Yes?
- So ring her tomorrow.
I can't. She gave
the number to you.
Only because I told her
of your affections.
Wha-What did you say?
Merely that you admired her but
you were hesitant to make an overture
since you'd been told
she was courting another.
Shit. That's good!
Wha-What did she say?
She handed me the napkin.
Charles, it's quite late.
No, no, no,
she won't be home yet.
I get her machine,
I leave a message.
Ball's in her court.
You're ladling calculation
upon comedy.
The point is,
to keep the ball in your court.
You're right. You're right.
Okay.
Nothing need be done
till tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Then I make my move.
An overture, Charles.
Make your intentions known.
Think of pleasing her,
not vexing her.
No vexing.
You're intoxicated.
We should retire.
I'm sure Kate will be home.
I doubt it.
But it's nearly midnight.
You like her, don't you?
- Who?
- Kate.
- You do!
- Oh, Charles, stop.
You like my sister!
Well, you made your
intentions known, right?
- Right?
- You've been drinking.
Leo, Commune is right
around the corner.
We could stop in, you could
give me a couple of pointers
pull out a chair or two,
you could throw out a gesture here or there.
Yeah, see, it's one thing with Patrice.
You don't give a shit.
It's a whole other ball of wax
when it's a girl you like, huh?
Yeah, who's
the merry-andrew now?
You want to vex my sister!
I have to confess that
I'm a little bit confused...
No. Thank you.
When you asked me to dinner tonight
I was under the impression that...
- we were here to discuss...
- The merger.
Yes. Right. Yes.
And a possible promotion.
Yes.
Yes, that, too.
And, well, dinner
is winding down
and we haven't
really discussed
anything even remotely relevant to
what I thought we came here to...
I don't believe I've ever
seen you this flustered, Kate.
You haven't even kissed me yet.
Yeah.
Right. Well...
I like you, J.J., I do.
I like you quite a bit.
As a matter of fact...
I think you would agree
that a working...
a successful
working relationship
requires a great deal of...
- What exactly is our working relationship?
- Kate...
Hi, Kate!
Hi, Charlie.
Wha... what are you doing here?
- We just thought we'd come by to say hi.
- Kate?
- J.J., right?
- Right.
Might I have a word with you?
- Now?
- In private.
No! No.
Mr. Margarine.
Please... please join us.
And where did you say it is?
- In Sussex.
- Near Balmore.
- Yes.
- Built in the 18th century.
Early 18th century.
Early? Are you quite sure?
Yes.
He's got pictures, Leopold.
Perhaps you were swindled,
because I can assure you
as of the late 19th century
there's nothing
but farmland near Balmore.
- You're mistaken.
- That's not possible.
Well, it's quite possible,
Leopold, that you are mistaken.
No, it is not possible...
Balmore is the only manor house
in the county.
- I know because I grew up there.
- Leopold, it wasn't...
Leo, do you enjoy opera?
- I do. And do you?
- Oh, yes.
It keeps... keeps me alive.
Do you have a favorite?
Bohme. La Bohme.
- La Bohme?
- I've seen it 12 times.
That's... that's how
I learned to speak French.
- You speak French?
- Fluently.
Que ton visage est doux
entour par la lumire
de la lune.
What did he say?
"How sweet your face looks
gently encircled
by the soft moonlight."
Oh, I like that.
From the opening scene of Bohme.
A stunning duet.
- Andre sings it to Mimi.
- Andre...
I invited Kate to the Met next week.
She's never been.
Patrone is singing Andre,
and she turned me down.
Can you explain that, Leopold?
Well...
Bohme is one of man's great achievements
and should not be missed.
But perhaps Kate resists
on moral grounds.
- How so?
- Should we get the check?
Well, some feel that
to court a woman in one's employ
is nothing more than
a serpentine effort
to transform a lady to a whore.
J.J.
This guy's charming, Kate.
The Duke of Margarine
thinks me a serpent.
- No, he doesn't.
- No, not a serpent.
That's too grand a word.
Simply a braggart and a cad
who knows less French than I,
if that's possible.
And by the way
there's no Andre in
Bohme- it's Rudolfo.
And though it takes place
in France
it's rarely played in French,
as it is written in Italian.
Good night.
Sorry.
Kate, might I have a word?
- Morning.
- Hi.
- You want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
- You want to read your paper?
- No, thank you, Charlie.
I want to go to work
and try and clean up
this mess you made.
You sure you don't...
Kate...
Uh, Kate!
What?
I just thought maybe you'd want a...
kiwi for... the subway.
That's a papaya, Charlie.
Oh? You're right. Okay.
But while using the product 80% found
the product too soft to be...
effective.
This, of course, presents
a conundrum for us marketeers.
How do we maintain a soft feel
on the exterior
of a plastic wrap or pack
while retaining the useful
tensile strength in the sheets?
Now, I'm going to suggest
to the Summer Soft people
to scale back to a limited
release of the product...
Dearest Katherine...
I behaved as an imbecile
last night
animated in part by drink,
in part by your beauty
and in part
by my own foolish pride.
And for that
I am profoundly sorry.
Please accept
as a gesture of apology
a private dinner on the rooftop
tonight at 8 o'clock.
Okay, where are we
on Farmer's Bounty?
Kate?
Care to share with us?
Farmer's Bounty?
Where we are?
Where we are is good.
Um, as you know, we
found our spokesperson.
The response room final showed
a 96 in the top two boxes.
His key female descriptors...
were "handsome", "romantic"
with several write-ins
of...
"What a hunk."
Great.
Would you hold this?
J.J.?
J.J., hi.
Um, listen, I just want
to apologize again
for what happened last night.
There was no need
for things to get that way.
I appreciate that.
So... everything's okay?
Yes, Kate.
I didn't jump; I fell.
There's a difference-
a subtle difference,
but nonetheless a difference.
Why did you fall, then?
Because there was no elevator.
And you feel that
was your fault?
You know what, I'm sorry.
I got to concede that
you are a very busy man
and I'm sure there are
plenty of people clamoring
for your particular
brand of attention.
Unfortunately,
I am not one of them.
So if you don't mind, would you
please unlock this door?
I'm concerned you might be
a danger to yourself.
And in such cases...
- state law requires...
- Hello?
Will someone please open this...
Fuck...
Everything all right,
Dr. Geisler?
Yes, Gretchen.
Everything's fine.
So, Stuart, I'm going to prescribe
something called Prolixin.
It's a mild antipsychotic.
Nothing too strong.
"I was wondering..."
"I was wondering if you
would like to accompany me..."
"If you have a previous engagement,
I understand."
Tonight at 7:00, 7:30.
Please don't be late.
I got to talk to you
about this, okay?
'Cause there's some shit here
that just cannot be said.
Did you assemble
a bouquet for Patrice?
I'll just get one of these, but look,
you just can't tell a woman she's...
- "gracefully serene."
- No, no, this one won't do.
Wha... Why?
What is wrong with this one?
The orange lily
implies extreme hatred.
The begonia and lavender
danger and suspicion, respectively.
Every flower has
a meaning, Charles.
Might I suggest the amaryllis,
which declares the recipient
a most splendid beauty.
Or the cabbage rose.
Darci!
- What is this?
- It's a reply to Leopold's invitation.
You're going, right?
I haven't decided yet.
Oh, you haven't decided if you want to have
dinner on your rooftop with a duke?
...Who thinks he's from 1876!
- No! And I would appreciate it if...
- Kate, come on, okay?
I don't know what this guy did
to piss you off
but that is the best apology letter
in the history of mankind.
Just sign it, Kate.
It's 4:30. We'll fax it.
Kate McKay's office.
They hung up.
Hi. Is Patrice there?
Hey, Patrice?
- Hi. It's me, Charlie.
- Hey, Charlie.
I was just calling to find out
if you got my flowers-
your flowers.
I was calling to see if you got
the flowers I sent you.
Yeah, I did.
And I was just wondering
if you would like to go
to a movie tonight
and maybe afterwards perhaps
accompany me to a dinner?
I mean, I...
I understand completely
if you're otherwise engaged.
But, uh, you know,
I just wanted to say that, um...
Yeah?
I wanted to say
that you've, uh...
you've made an impression on me.
And-and it-it's not
just the way you look-
I mean, which are great.
Your looks are,
you know, top-top shelf.
But, uh...
I don't know, it's, um...
What?
You're graceful.
You know, the way you move
and speak.
I mean, some people have a way with words
and, you know, you... you do.
The bottom line is, I like you.
Patrice?
What about 7:00?
7:00?
7:00 would be heaven. Okay.
See you then.
It worked! It worked cool!
Who's going out with Patrice?
Charlie's going out with Patrice!
Over there! Charlie's going over there!
Oh, better go get ready.
Better go get changed.
Shouldn't change too much, though
'cause she likes me for who I am.
- Hey.
- Charlie, you look fantastic.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I got a date.
I got to go. Bye.
Bye.
- Kate?
- Yeah?
Um, have a good time tonight.
Bye.
My God.
This is beautiful.
The very word for which
I was searching.
May I?
She was a real romantic, my mom.
When Prince Charles and Lady Di
got married, she had a party.
She made crumpets and jam.
It was like a Super Bowl party,
but for moms.
She cried for a week.
I don't know the story
of Prince Charles and Lady Di.
Oh, you don't want to.
It's a cautionary tale. Further proof.
- Of what?
- That you can't live a fairy tale.
I'm not very good with men.
Perhaps you haven't found
the right one.
Maybe. Or...
maybe the whole love thing is
just a grown-up version of Santa Claus
just a myth we've been fed
since childhood
so we keep buying magazines
and joining clubs
and doing therapy and
watching movies with hit pop songs
played over love montages
all in this pathetic attempt
to explain why our love Santa
keeps getting caught
in the chimney.
Otis always told me
love is a leap.
Lamentably,
I was never inspired to jump.
By my 30th birthday,
I had, according to my uncle
become a blemish
on the family name.
So he brought me to this country
with the proviso
I marry an American.
A girl with a
good deal of, um...
Charm?
Money. Since my parents died
our family fortune had become,
shall we say, depleted.
I would be married now
if I hadn't followed Stuart.
I was to announce a bride
that night.
Who?
I don't know.
Someone.
One of them.
What are you doing?
I'm just cleaning up.
Would you do me
the honor of a dance?
Please?
- I am not much of a dancer.
- You're doing famously, then.
Leopold, this was lovely.
But I don't know
if I can leap
even if I am inspired.
People might think
I'm brave, but I'm not.
The brave are simply those
with the clearest vision
of what is before them.
Glory and danger alike
and notwithstanding,
go out to meet it.
Hey.
Morning, Charles.
How was your evening
with Patrice?
Good. Nice.
How was yours?
So, Leo, don't you think it's
time you tell me who you are?
- What do you mean?
- I mean...
it's a blast doing
the duke thing with you 24/7 but...
I don't want to see Kate
go through Stuart: The Sequel.
I know she seems pretty tough
but she hasn't had it that easy.
She's always getting stuck with people
who don't hold up their end.
Like me.
- I just don't...
- I understand, Charles.
- You do?
- Yes.
So...
Who are you?
I am the man
who loves your sister.
Okay, pour the soap in.
Shut the lid.
Push the drawers in.
Close the door, and
you push this button.
A word to the wise:
Don't press that
till she wakes up.
So she sees you doing it.
How clever.
The proverbial tree in the woods.
If a man washes a dish
and no one sees it...
Did it happen?
- A cup of coffee, my dear.
- Thank you.
Breakfast?
Nine-grain toast with strawberries
and mascarpone, Madame.
It's apparently low...
in polyunsaturates.
It's really good.
It's good.
What should we do today?
Oh no, no, no, no, no, no.
Thank you. No.
You know what makes me happy?
You don't look good in those.
They're so completely
inappropriate for you.
Kate.
Kate, Kate, come.
Leopold? Leopold?
- Hey, what are you doing?
- It boggles the mind that it is still here.
This is my uncle's home. Well, was.
This is where I lived.
Good Lord.
A portrait of my parents...
and me.
Leopold?
Look, I just don't think
that we should just be
barging around here like that.
Leopold?
My old quarters.
What are you doing?
The place where I put
everything I most cared for.
Things I didn't want
my uncle to touch.
My mother's ring.
Oh, it's beautiful.
You know,
I live on an island
connected to everything
by bridges
and I never cross them.
I've lived here for ten years and I've...
never been
to the other side of anything.
You've never traveled?
No.
Do you...
What?
Do you miss where you're from?
In a way, I...
I miss...
I miss its rhythm.
It was slower?
Quite a bit slower.
- Like today?
- Yes.
Do you hear that, Leopold?
Do you hear that music?
Yes.
Have you ever seen the movie
Breakfast at Tiffany's
Uh, no.
"No."
Not yet.
You see that guy down there
with the light on?
He listens to the soundtrack
of Breakfast at Tiffany's
every night
until exactly midnight.
And then he
turns his light off
goes to sleep.
* My huckleberry friend *
* Moon River *
* And me. *
Oh, that means it's Sunday.
Oh, I don't want it
to be Sunday.
I want more of this.
More 1876.
But, Kate, you don't work on
Sundays. We can have more.
Well, I don't know,
'cause Sunday is the day before
the day I work, so...
it gets poisoned.
I see.
Besides, tomorrow is the day
we shoot your commercial.
Kate.
Would you...?
Might you ever...
consider...?
Hmm?
It's time for bed.
I'm so relaxed.
That's all right.
You're tucking me in.
Yes.
You're my Otis.
Yes, Your Grace.
Oh, wait.
Hey, hey, don't...
don't go upstairs.
Stay.
I love you, Kate McKay.
Scone, Your Grace?
Ah, thank you, Millard.
And you brought
the Farmer's Bounty?
But of course.
Ah!
Fresh creamery butter.
Is there anything
more comforting?
I say there is
and perhaps you'll agree
when you sample fat-free
Farmer's Bounty
with the genuine essence
of creamery butter in every bite.
With every mouthful
of Farmer's Bounty
you shall receive butter's
luxurious comfort in your mouth
without adding to the luxury
of your waistline.
Farmer's Bounty.
Now, on this one
take a bite and smile.
And... cut!
All right, check gate.
Good enough for me.
Can we get a Dedo up here
and something...
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me. Is this an actual
sample of Farmer's Bounty?
Yeah. Why?
This tastes like saddle soap.
Well, it's not really
your concern, now, is it?
Not my concern?
This product tastes
like raw suet.
How is that not my concern?
Hey, pal, it's a paycheck!
- A Paycheck?
- Wait a minute...
This is an outrage!
Don't worry about the taste.
Come back. We need another shot.
Something that
brings the light up on this...
Leopold.
Leopold!
Leopold, what's going on?
What are you doing?
They-they need you
back in there.
Do they?
Yeah. They have to shoot the rest of
the spot. They're not finished yet.
Well, I want no part of it.
Why?
Have you tasted it?
- Farmer's Bounty?
- Yes, Farmer's Bounty.
- Yeah, I've tasted it.
- It's revolting.
I know.
You know it's revolting yet you have no
qualms enlisting me to endorse it?
It's diet;
it's supposed to be awful.
I mean, what is the problem?
The problem is that for no reason
beyond my affection for you
I find myself peddling pond scum
to an unsuspecting public.
Hey, listen, you know the stakes
are very high for me here.
- You can't just quit because...
- Yes, I can. And so can you.
When one finds oneself
participating
in an endeavor entirely
without merit, one withdraws.
No. No. Because sometimes
you have to do things
that you don't like.
Sometimes you have to suck it up
and finish what you started.
It's part of life.
You sound like my uncle.
Look, Leopold, Jansen Foods is
a very important
account for my company.
If you don't go back in there
then I get into
a lot of trouble.
Is this what you do
at work, Kate?
Research methods
to deceive people?
Refine lies until
they resemble truth?
It's no wonder
you dread your work week.
Oh! Man, I don't have time
for this.
What has happened to the world?
You have every convenience,
every comfort
- yet no time for integrity.
- No.
What I don't have time for
are pious speeches
by 200-year-old men
who've never had to work
a day in their life.
You have no idea
what I've done with my life.
And you-you have no idea
what I've done with mine!
I haven't had all that many
comforts and conveniences, Leopold,
because I've been
paying dues all of my life
and I'm tired,
and I need a rest
and if I have to peddle
a little pond scum to get one
then so be it.
Very well.
We're kidding ourselves,
Leopold.
In point of fact I don't even
really know who you are.
You still don't believe
I'm the man I say I am?
We had a great weekend;
that's that.
Now it's Sunday.
It's over.
* There's such a lot of world to see. *
I know.
I know, I know,
it sounds crazy-
talking about...
finding a crack
in time under the East River.
But in, in point,
in point fact, Gretchen
you know...
it is no more crazy than, uh,
a dog finding a rainbow.
Dogs are color-blind, Gretchen.
They don't see color.
- Really?
- Just like we can't see time.
We can feel it.
Oh... we can feel it passing but,
we can't see it;
it's just a blur.
It's like, uh...
it's like we're riding
in a, in a supersonic train
and the world is
just blowing by.
But imagine if we could stop
that train, Gretchen. Hmm?
Imagine if we could stop
that train
get out, look around
and see time
for what it really is.
A universe,
a world, a thing as unimaginable as
color to a dog.
And as real and tangible
as that chair you're sitting in.
Now, if we could see it
like that
I mean, really look at it
then...
maybe we could see
the flaws as well as the form.
And that's it.
It's that simple.
That's all I discovered.
I'm just a...
just a guy who saw a crack
in a chair
that no one else could see.
I'm that dog who saw a rainbow.
Only, uh...
none of the other dogs
believe me.
I believe you.
I can see that some things have...
happened since I went away.
But...
you have to go back.
You understand you'll be going back
to the same day you left,
- April 28th.
- Yes.
So you understand you might be
repeating a few things.
You might even see me.
Just don't follow me
this time.
Can I go in?
J.J., you asked to see me?
Come on in.
I understand you, uh,
put out a fire
at the shoot yesterday.
Guess Mr. Duke's got a bit
of an ego on him, huh?
Yeah.
I'm going to England
this week
and I made a decision.
You're going to be
the top New York honcho.
So, this is going
to be your office.
I'll be making it official
tonight.
Thank you, J.J. Thank you.
You've earned it.
I'm heading over to Jansen to sign
the buy-out papers,
FTC stuff. So I'll...
see you later
at the thing.
- What did he say?
- I got it.
Oh, my God.
It's wonderful!
Just give me one second.
I'm sorry, Darci. One second.
Hi. You've reached Stuart.
Please leave a message.
Hello?
Leopold, I-I don't know
where you are
but if you're there,
please pick up.
I got it.
I got the job.
I'm the new
senior vice president
at CRG.
Uh, please call me. I...
I'm sorry about the way
things came down yesterday.
I apologize. I...
I just really need to see you.
I'd love to see you tonight
but I have this thing at Farmer's Bounty.
But I'd love to see you later.
I miss you..
I miss you.
Hey, Stuart.
How're you feeling?
Where's Leo?
He went home.
He was for real..
He was for real!
Holy shit!
Look at this!
Oh, my God.
Chilled, do
you understand? Chilled.
And be sure to leave another
case of the Chateau Laffite.
Yes, sir.
Leopold! Where have you been?!
Otis, I demand explication!
It's half past five.
He's not even dressed!
He'll be ready, my lord,
I assure you.
I don't want him ready.
I want him resplendent!
This is the invitation. You've got...
your table number, your car number
and I've got Morty down there-
the guy you like. He's on the Madison side.
Also, your phone sheet
is in here.
And Stuart called
you a couple times. So...
Have a great time tonight.
You look beautiful.
I don't think this is right.
I'm supposed to be going to 2640 Madison.
That's where we are,
Miss McKay.
Have a nice evening.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Invitation, please.
No, no.
Look, they're still plugged.
But they're just randomly seeded
with Minoxidil.
- No cornrows.
- Excuse me.
Hey, Kate.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
To hell with the facelifts.
I'm into mini-lifts now.
Just a tiny little bit each year.
I hear they'll bring them
back to 840 next year.
So I'm just running
out my lease.
- Kate, congratulations.
- Thanks, Bob.
Hey, Kate.
J.J. Hi, Barry.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
Anyway, I'm just glad
they've got them fixed.
I was going to move my office
down to the lobby.
Excuse me.
Kate, don't powder
your nose for too long.
I'm going to give this speech
in a couple of minutes.
Okay.
All this time I thought
that I had
pretezled fate and it had to be untwisted.
But what I never considered is that
the whole thing is a pretzel.
A beautiful 4D pretzel
of kismetic inevitability.
Okay, you know what, get off Park
as soon as you can, and then go up Madison.
I was supposed to go back.
He was supposed to come forward then
he was supposed to go back again and...
so was she.
Now it is my
pleasure and honor...
to turn this over to my friend,
J.J. Camden...
...to take
priests to the bell tower.
You speak of progress
and invention.
But what I offer you
downstairs is reality.
Take a wife. Marry.
Let us not bother
with this banter, Uncle.
Tell me whom you want me
to marry.
Well, who has the most money?
Well...
that would be Miss Tree
of the Trees of Schenectady.
Good. Consider it done.
Otis, fetch the ring.
I will announce at midnight.
Invitation, please.
Uh, hello.
My name is Stuart Besser.
I'm sorry, I know
we're not on your list
- but his sister is Kate McKay...
- I'm sorry, sir, I can't just let you in.
...and I learned that there was one thing
that I could do and it didn't require money
and it didn't require
a fancy school.
I learned that I could
please people.
And there is nothing wrong
with that!
I am a people pleaser, people!
Thank you so much. I am so...
Kate!
Stuart!
Charlie! What are you doing?
- You should look at these pictures, Kate.
- No! No-no-no-no!
Now it's time to introduce
the woman who's going to be
holding down the fort
in our New York offices
our own little rising star,
Miss Kate McKay!
- Just listen to me for a second, please?
- They're introducing me downstairs right now!
I'm sorry I was a lousy boyfriend.
I'm sorry I let you down.
I know all you wanted
was someone you could trust...
Oh, Stuart, really
I can't talk about...
No, Kate, just listen
to me, okay? Please.
Maybe we weren't such
a waste of time after all.
- I mean, maybe there's a reason I was your guy.
- What are you talking about?
Maybe I was supposed to help
you find your guy... Leopold.
You got to go back, Kate.
You got to go back there.
Go back?
How?
You have to jump off the Brooklyn Bridge
within the next 23 minutes.
Kate? Katie?
Kate, just look
at the pictures, okay?
Is there a... a Kate McKay
in the house?
- Yeah. Here I am!
- Kate?
Here she is. Here she is.
Well, without further ado
the new senior vice president
of our New York offices.
Here she is, ladies and
gentlemen- Kate McKay.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Quite an entrance, huh?
Thank you, J.J.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
Wow.
Well...
This is a great night.
We here at...
CRG have always
considered ourselves to be
in the "Find what people want"
business and at Jansen,
you guys are in the
"Make what people want" business.
So, imagine
what we can do together.
We'll be able to find out
exactly what people want
and make it... for them.
So... yeah, so our customers...
will be able to get exactly...
...what they...
...they want.
And...
...it's a great thing to...
to get what you want.
Uh, it's a really good thing.
Unless what you thought
you wanted wasn't really
what you wanted
because what you really...
...wanted
you couldn't imagine, or you
didn't think it was possible.
But... but what if someone
came along who knew
exactly what you wanted
without asking?
They just knew. Like they could...
hear your heart beating
or listen to your thoughts.
And what if they were sure
of themselves
and they didn't have
to take a poll
and they loved you...
and you hesitated?
And...
I have to go.
I...
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
Kate?
Stuart,
can you tell me
in short, complete sentences
featuring no words over two syllables
why exactly
I am in these pictures?
- Probably not.
- Try.
- Because you were there.
- I wasn't.
I would remember. Believe me,
I would remember if I was there.
Because you're going to be there.
If we get there in time.
These are pictures
of the past, not the future.
Not exactly.
Theoretically speaking
if you go to the past in the future
then your future
lies in the past.
And that is a picture of you
in the future, in the past.
We'll have to make a run
for it. Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Let's go, let's go. Come on!
Whoa, where the hell do
you think you're going?
$6.80 on the meter, pal.
It's going to close, Kate!
Come on!
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention?
The Duke of Albany
will be making
a very important announcement
in 20 minutes
from this very stage.
And I believe it shall be
an announcement
that will justify
the playing of a bridal waltz.
Okay...
this is the hard part.
- What?
- The girder.
- The girder?
- You have to cross the girder, Kate.
That girder?
Stuart, I can't cross
that girder.
- You love him, right?
- What?
Leopold.
You love him, right?
Yeah.
That's all you need to know.
Now go.
- You'll be fine.
- Katie...
Charlie... Charlie, what am I...
How are you gonna...
No, go! Don't worry about me.
- Now, Kate, now.
- Now?
- The portal's going to close.
- All right.
Go.
-Oh!
- Jesus.
Oh, God.
You can do it.
Don't look down.
Charlie...
I'll love you forever.
Love you.
It's okay.
Lady... lady, what
are you doing?
Step back, lady.
- It's okay.
- Step back from there, lady.
Come back, lady.
Central, be advised,
this is Bridge Post Four.
I've got a jumper on the southwest
location of the bridge.
Have a supervisor, ESU and Harbor
respond to this location forthwith.
Ladies and gentlemen
it is with a glad heart
and a bright eye
that I proudly introduce
my beloved nephew
Leopold, Duke of Albany.
Thank you, Uncle Millard.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, madam, but
this is a private affair.
No, you don't seem
to understand.
I need to get inside.
- I need to get inside right now and...
- What seems to be the problem?
Are you Otis?
Well, let us proceed.
Please raise your glasses...
so we may toast
to my bride-to-be
the woman whose welfare and happiness
shall be my solemn duty to maintain.
The future Duchess of Albany...
Kate McKay.
Of the McKays of...?
Massapequa..
Massapequa.
- I love you.
* If I caught the world in a bottle *
* And everything was still beneath the moon *
* Without your love would it shine for me? *
* If I was smart as Aristotle *
* And understood the rings around the moon *
* What would it all matter if you love me? *
* Here in your arms, *
* Where the world is impossibly still *
* With a million dreams to fulfill *
* And a matter of moments *
* Until the dancing ends. *
* Here in your arms, *
* When everything seems to be clear *
* Not a solitary thing would I fear *
* Except when this moment comes *
* near the dancing's end. *
* If I caught the world in an hourglass, *
* Saddled up the moon so we could ride *
* Until the stars grew dim *
* Until... *
* One day you'll meet a stranger *
* And all the noise is silenced in the room *
* You'll feel that you're close to some mystery *
* In the moonlight when everything shatters, *
* You'll feel as if you've known her all your life *
* The world's oldest lesson in history *
* Here in your arms, *
* where the world is impossibly still *
* With a million dreams to fulfill *
* And a matter of moments *
* until the dancing ends. *
* Here in your arms, *
* when everything seems to be clear *
* Not a solitary thing do I fear *
* Except when this moment comes *
* near the dancing's end. *
* Oh, if I caught the world in an hourglass, *
* saddled up the moon then we would ride *
* Until the stars grew dim, *
* Until the time, that time stands still, *
* Until... *