Agatha  Weiss.
J & apos; asked a limousine.
Much.
There & apos; there were more.
Been here before?
I have to collect you & apos; first.
C & apos;'s 45 & apos; hour, minimum 2 hours.
Here, 200 dollars.
You have a map of the stars homes?
C & apos; eastern & apos; wasted money,
except to see a cheesy TV.
You just & apos; where?
Jupiter.
Florida.
You're L.A. to...?
I just see family.
You drive stars?
J & apos; got Al Gore once.
Probably the most famous.
J & apos;'ve also had Tatum O & apos;
Neal for his reality show.
Chuck Lorre.
He created a Half Men.
A lot of producers, filmmakers.
Juliette Lewis.
Scientologist.
I think convert.
C & apos;'s good for my career.
You are an actor?
Actor, writer.
I know Carrie Fisher.
Really?
- But how?
- Met on Twitter.
We are very friendly.
I & apos; help for his new novel.
It could become an HBO film.
C & apos; hell is this place?
I thought c & apos; was on the map.
There was a big house.
The house & apos; childhood Benjie Weiss.
How do you know?
J & apos; was his babysitter.
The evil babysitter, c & apos; was me.
Strange!
My agent wants me to play in Babysitter 2
This & apos; not sure yet but
Jakob Leitner, my personal trainer,
m & apos; got an audition.
It is very influential.
We were together in Beverly.
Fingers crossed.
Hi!
I don & apos; hoping more for you to come.
Why is that?
You're so caught.
Not for you.
J & apos; loved Bad Babysitter.
It was $ 780 million in the world
.
People tend to forget.
You don & apos; did not & apos; iPad?
Arnold, found him an iPad.
Mini.
We'll cram shit in 3D.
We have satin jackets.
With "J & apos; was a bad babysitter"
in gold.
How did you get AIDS?
I don & apos; not have AIDS,
c & apos; is a non-Hodgkin lymphoma.
You know what...
I'll make a movie about your life.
Ryan Gosling will play my role.
And I, yours.
We'll all  Oscar.
- Non-Hodgkins?
- Sorry.
- C & apos;'s this disease, damn!
- Something to blood, I think.
C & apos; is "no" that m & apos; bored.
You & apos; aces or you & apos; did not.
You were serious?
Could show it to Ryan.
He ​​will like.
We could show Ryan?
You come just to wipe your ass.
It would be very moving.
J & apos;'ve even Song:
A shitty life.
No empty promises & apos; air!
Dixit euthanasiste great!
Rabbi of life and death.
Greater sage.
The Great Zen archer.
J & apos;'ve found your nickname
Museum & apos; Holocaust!
Stop, Benjie.
Stop?
J & apos;'ve got a better idea.
Show me your pussy!
I know you have one.
Species & apos; Jew motherfucker!
- They offer how much?
- Five million.
Plus 10%.
That request Genie?
Eight.
20% of revenues.
You think about it what?
We have them by the balls.
Super.
C & apos;'s when, & apos; audition?
This & apos; not an audition.
C & apos;'s true.
And c & apos; When is the test & apos; urine?
They are seen Friday at 10:00.
They want s & apos; make sure you're clean.
But  & apos; agreement depends on the match?
- They protect their franchise.
- C & apos;'s me, the franchise.
You want to eat, Stafford?
J & apos; listening to a cassette of the Dalai Lama.
Forget his politics.
This guy is a pro.
Free Tibet!
But Tibet is overpriced.
J & apos;'ve even kept the receipt & apos; Amazon.
Buddhists say a prayer...
- Genie will be there?
- She does not prefer.
I want that & apos; she comes.
"Do eaters,
that & apos; they eat and eating
." Are completely without ego "
I go into my room
No, Mom...
=. = No, Mom...
Do not hurt me...
N & apos; between not in my room...
when I sleep
N & apos;. between not in my room when
I sleep
I will not let you do more
Species bitch
You're hurting me
How
I t & apos;..!.? did wrong
J & apos; was your little girl
and yet you m & apos; did wrong
Why, Mom
Your parents t & apos;.? beat
This b & apos;'s no excuse?.
Stop  forgive Havana.
I do not care that & apos; they did.
They would have killed you.
I t & apos; would have killed her...
How dare you do that to a child
?
How could you do this to me
to me, your daughter?
I want to be free, Clarice.
Clarice, mom, free me!
I want to be free.
I want to win back the stolen years.
S & apos; he pleases you...
I now rely on a special item.
Everything is stored in
thighs.
Regains years, Havana.
Stolen Regains years the little girl.
Rebecca, stop.
You're a patient here.
I want t & apos; help, not...
Do not you think that I & apos;'ve fired?
I think you do not want to.
You need & apos; help.
You do not want m & apos; help?
Not like that...
should think about that & apos;'re doing.
On any given flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
J & apos; put your name
Miss Havana?
Miss Genie is there.
How are you, darling?
It's going... J & apos;'ve had a very hard session with
Stafford.
You're so brave!
I do not feel brave.
J & apos; i need & apos; slave.
And your famous Adagio?
J & apos; had to fire her.
- But why?
- It robbed me.
My God... Incredible!
It m & apos; stole & apos; silver ring
and Vicodin.
My God!
And you & apos; got caught in the act?
- You called the police?
- I & apos;'ve threatened to do so.
And she is & apos; hosto?
With all the slaves cameos.
They have their special wing.
I'll call Carrie.
Not. Love her all you want but
& apos; not fuck with that.
It will make laugh.
I have to see her at a party.
It will give me names.
Good...
And Stolen Waters?
They are all at Sundance.
Everyone except me!
C & apos; was the best reading of my life.
I'm totally amazed!
I know.
The only thing that worries might be
to cast a star in a supporting role.
But everyone does!
C & apos; film is rather minor,
your mother turned
There 30 years.
It could be great.
C & apos;'s a reinvention.
C & apos;'s a film & apos; author.
Who do you think has had the & apos;
idea of ​​my mother watching
Stolen Waters if she lived?
C & apos;'s me!
J & apos;'ve given & apos; idea Damien
there 4 years.
I know.
I deserve the role and
& apos; be credited as a producer.
Worth & apos; Oscar for Supporting Actress,
& apos; is a second chance...
c & apos; Javitz is Damien.
It raises the actors!
And I & apos;'ve been great.
Sterl always does?
It m & apos; owes.
I & apos; was presented to Harvey, who produced.
J & apos;'ve talked to Harvey
will talk to Damien.
But you know...
Harvey Harvey will always
and Sterl can talk...
You know that & apos; everything is done for.
But ultimately, c & apos;'s a film & apos; author.
You'd be great in this role.
But in case you & apos; forgot,
your mother is dead but a cult actress.
And Damien Javitz
& apos; not PT Anderson.
- There are so many movies...
- Really?
- The blockbusters.
- Where?
Where it Genie?
L & apos; other day Jacob m & apos; said,
as I know many celebrities
I should become an agent.
You know what & apos;
we feel when we told you that?
All I'm doing
in my life and in my analysis,
& apos;'s role.
It will not?
J & apos; have cramps.
- It's all right?
- No, that's wrong.
L & apos; mother-daughter incest,
it's too 80s
I'm not Anne Sexton.
The shock will s & apos; mitigate.
Qu & apos; do that & apos; there, Havana?
You thought it would be the sixth sense?
The dead speak?
You want to know what the dead?
You know what & apos;'s & apos; Hell?
A drug-free world!
But what is happening?
The worst cliche porn Vana
this fantasy child rape!
Vis, whore!
Or die.
C & apos; not a little shabby
want to be me & apos; screen?
You hate me,
but you're ready for anything
for me!
Do you want this role, but you do
& apos; shalt not.
You don & apos; not even have the talent.
I & apos; was
and j & apos; was young and beautiful.
You? With your tits hanging
and your old worn hole?
It stinks even more than me!
Who is this?
C & apos;'s non-Hodgkins.
What are you doing here?
On my notebooks & apos; schoolboy
On my desk and trees
On the sand snow
J & apos; put your name
I'll make this movie...
You are just that?
What & apos; said Arnold?
On any given flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
J & apos; put your name
On my notebooks & apos; schoolboy
On my desk and Trees
On the sand snow
J & apos; put your name
On any given flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
J & apos; put your name
Freedom
See you at & apos;
school with Bad Babysitters.
I'm stuck?
Not at all. You're the first.
Your holidays were hectic.
Rather productive.
It & apos; was not easy
for any of us.
But he learned a lot.
Absolutely.
I myself spent
by this drug trip.
Not at your age, of course, but...
We all do stupid things, right?
It & apos; arrived very young.
Benjie has matured a lot.
A lot.
In Praise the Heavy,
I was getting 300,000 a week.
J & apos; was 9 years old.
C & apos; not hallucinating?
L & apos; crazy money.
For all.
He was worth.
You have many fans.
J & apos;'ve exceeded...
Mother Teresa péterait sinkers
before so much dough.
She has already lost it.
She is dead.
You can not fart higher!
We have a warrant.
Cristina knows.
And you too.
Must protect the franchise.
We & apos; played tight...
Arnold, your team was great.
Nothing in the tabloids.
An adult into rehab,
it can boost a career.
A kid, c & apos; different.
We understand Jeb.
Although Drew has benefited.
Friends,
we are on your side.
You have to understand.
We would not be here without
a dose of confidence.
- There are already a budget?
- 58
But C & apos; is confidential.
We lost it.
But we did not count on it.
Sign is Emma Watson for the young mother.
It s  & apos; entertain well.
One must know how Benjie s & apos; is detoxified.
Benjie went into a private home.
That of & apos; associate of my husband.
Your mother is really great.
She can hit without a trace.
Damn.
Never nobody m & apos;
yet humble way.
Never.
C & apos;'s over, baby.
They were.
Damien finds me too old?
And the cast? Sarah Horowitz?
Havana, the character is simply
younger.
C & apos;
which is Sarah Horowitz & apos m; gave my first role.
He must have seen me in this horror
on TNT.
Do not work for the & apos; silver.
We can not all be as malignant as
you.
You'll support me, Sterl?
You'll talk to Damien?
You know I do.
He thinks Azita Wachtel.
She was nominated for an Oscar
and is Canadian.
You know the reputation of this Wachtel?
It would leave producers
piss him in the ass.
C & apos;'s good to know.
You know him well, Damien...
That's three times
I & apos; calls in vain.
Your reading was great.
There you & apos; said?
He said C & apos; "very strong".
There & apos s; really said?
Yes.
I have to have this role.
It would be awesome together.
I thought that & apos; we & apos; already.
Diandra?
But it is very old!
She is 23! 16 on IMDb.
- How do you know that & apos; she is 23 years old?
- Large pierced lips.
Please take 23 years for that?
It is tattooed on his ass.
She is menopausal!
Sympas, girls, right?
- Rhett, you told him?
- You will not believe it.
C & apos;'s too weird.
I will not tell you.
It's starting to like me.
C & apos;'s a crazy...
She posted 6,000 messages on my Facebook
in 2 months.
You'll & apos; marry?
- Fuck her, Rhett.
- Licking for the rules.
- Do not be vulgar.
- He does not like that.
It can not... because t & apos;'re menopausal.
Shut up!
Calm down!
We discover that & apos; technician sold him my shit
to 3000 dollars.
You said, your shit?
You heard. My shit.
C & apos; shit is high quality.
It is rice Nobu.
Straight from your caravan?
When the guy is emptying...
Qu & apos; do that & apos; she did?
She & apos; stores... just in case.
- Where is she & apos; money?
- A brown box...
Benjie, you're disgusting!
I offer daily specials when
j & apos; have the runs...
- Liquidation of stock.
- Everything must go.
Come...
Who is it?
- Starla Gent. Country singer.
- She won The Voice?
She made second.
C & apos;'s a fucking bitch.
And a great actress!
Javitz gave him your role.
Shut up!
I wonder if Blake Shelton pissed in that ass.
And Sam, you like her?
You can kiss it, you know.
She wants to play in your film.
And she has good Vicodin.
It's been almost 90 days.
- What?
- What I'm sober, asshole.
My God, what a stench!
This bitch
TV was in the toilet.
How it s & apos; calls?
As if a corpse had farted.
This & apos; not Sterl Carruth?
Yes, Havana Segrand.
We have the same agent.
How old is she?
Totally menopause.
Beyond.
Quasi-dead.
Older than my grandmother.
No, it & apos; is a GMB
Grandmother fuckable.
- They fuck together?
- Genre fucking compassion.
As nurses who violate the old to the & apos; hospice?
His mother & apos;
not die in a fire?
As Jack Cassidy.
C & apos;'s that?
The Swinger deviation.
The father of David Cassidy.
- And c & apos;'s that?
- The brother of Shawn Cassidy.
You know that his mother was a very cool
actress.
Clarice Taggart?
A & E made a documentary about it.
It was very cool.
She was young.
C & apos; hell is that?
Hi, Damien, what's going on?
Yes, I know.
I am ready to wear two earrings
& apos; ear.
Maestro
I am with my kids
and I tell them a story.
Can I call you?
Yes, I remember you. Immediately
.
Cite my name when you speak.
You're so crazy.
Suck me and say something about you.
I & apos; loved so much.
You were a little girl so pretty...
But you were lying.
How could you become
monster who lies?
Qu & apos; do that & apos; he goes?
Tell me.
I'm sorry...
J & apos; was not & apos; ease.
I'm not terrible, as dyke.
You should take a Klonopin.
I know a man
who lives under  & apos;
sword of Damocles we call AIDS.
"When my time comes,"
m & apos;
. "I'll be ready
." Has he said,  My bags are packed, the
threshold "
J & apos; like it
J & apos;. really like.
There is a time
in our life and therapy
s when our eyes & apos;
linger on luggage near the door.
After crying.
After suffering.
After dried fountains Memory
and bloodied our hands on the remains of our parents.
I thought Garry Marshall would be there,
that & apos; was a meeting, not a hearing
.
They m & apos; gave a bad route.
J & apos; had to walk two terminals.
At & apos; arrival I stank.
And the casting director
not even calculates me.
It goes without saying to me hello.
And she told me that Garry
didn & apos; perhaps even expect it.
C & apos; Garry Marshall is not Bertolucci.
His films are even more & apos; silver.
And I know Garry well.
She told me that & apos; they will shoot me.
And I: "Sorry, but I need
makeup."
And she said:
"Well, you do it or not?"
Like this!
I & apos; take it anymore, Jacob!
I'm so tired and
c & apos;'s so pathetic...
C & apos;'s Carrie?
In addition, Jacob more.
Hi, Carrie!
How are you?
When  j & apos;
have reconnected with myself, I'll tell you.
It was crazy.
Have you finished filming?
We return to Prague tomorrow
to redo some scenes.
You go Javitz?
J & apos; hope.
Did you hear something?
Genie m & apos; said you preparing yourself.
It would be so great
you play your own mother.
Every girl should have the opportunity, right?
You know Damien?
We just had dinner together in Tangier.
If you see him, tell him to m & apos; commit.
Genie m & apos; spoke of & apos; Adagio.
- You & apos;'ve had a long time?
- Three years.
Still Looking an assistant?
Yes. You became my agency
& apos; hiring.
Do me a favor.
It will seem odd,
but & apos;
would like you to see a girl he met on the Internet.
I'm so nervous.
It's okay. Want some tea?
Thank you. Yes.
Your home is so beautiful.
The walls so thick and the wind organ
...
They come & apos;
a monastery in Dharamsala.
J & apos;'ve met the Dalai Lama,
c & apos;'s a very cool guy.
He laughs a lot.
C & apos;
is like a guy with whom you would want to hang out,
but & apos;
is impossible because it is the Dalai Lama.
Thanks for the tea.
Is Maria & apos; hospital.
My housekeeper.
One of his daughters is sick.
It should have 40 kids.
So you know why you're here.
Thanks to Carrie.
You are known on the Net?
She was looking for someone & apos; one on Twitter,
for a novel.
On a girl who had been burned.
I replied and s & apos;
is seen in a Star Wars convention.
It must have been strange for you.
She is so great and so funny.
We are pretty crazy, we finish each
phrases & apos; another.
You came to see her?
I just wanted to see Hollywood.
It m & apos; invited to the Four Seasons
for breakfast incl.
There was Zooey Deschanel.
And Sally Draper, the girl from Mad Men.
C & apos; was awesome.
You have a family?
In Florida.
C & apos;'s where I come from.
Agatha...
We can talk about burns?
I worked in a planetarium.
J & apos; was 12.
There was a short circuit
and I stayed at the & apos; inside...
like a bitch.
This & apos;'s not a very glamorous job.
I don & apos;'ve ever known glamor.
Basically, the job would
of shopping and & apos; fix the small stuff.
Miss Segrand  I'll be the most loyal, most skilled
and the best personal assistant
imaginable.
You have a car?
You know how to drive?
J & apos; have a license in Florida.
I can rent a car. Genre...
a Mustang?
Carrie is funny.
She knew that & apos; were to be seen.
You know how my mother died?
In a fire.
I think you're beautiful.
And you know who you look like?
At & apos; inside?
Segrand Havana.
- There is a race.
- Qu & apos; do c & apos; is?
A tower & apos; Hollywood. Cash call.
Holly Crest Hotel.
On my notebooks & apos;
schoolboy on my desk and trees
On the sand snow
J & apos; put your name
On any given flesh
On the front of my friends
On each hand reaching
J & apos; put your name
Freedom
You survived a fire?
I don & apos;'ve never known what m & apos; happened.
I think j & apos;
was gone and I fell asleep.
What will you do in Hollywood?
Your money will s & apos; fly,
if you ride in a limo...
Actually, I & apos; got a job.
Really? Where?
You know Segrand Havana?
By reputation, yes.
I am his personal assistant.
C & apos; Carrie Fisher is the connection?
Well yes...
Havana lent me a car.
You want that & apos; have dinner together?
Not this weekend.
I have to...
scénar my work.
J & apos; have a great idea © e movie.
Could & apos; Ã © write together.
The theme of & apos; incest. But
c & apos;'s a bit overrated.
L & apos; sexual abuse: the new religion!
In fact, my parents were Ã ©
brother and sÂur. C & apos;'s a secret.
Ã  a could be like that...
confession.
Ã  did some Blasa ©
but independent movie ©.
J & apos; would play.
With you, if you want.
It would be pretentious pre ©
if we keep the side © mythological.
Ã  listen, Agatha...
I think you're crazy.
Yes. So what?
I mean...
What I am saying, c & apos;'s...
I go out with someone DÃ © ja & apos; one.
I wish Result © ussir.
I do not want your money.
Kiss my ass.
C & apos; Ã © was like a dream, but damn
, dating and seemed so Result © el!
Continue.
A girl that
j & apos; had known at the & apos; hospital.
He was sent © iPad,
but they said that & apos; Ã © it was dead.
She came in my room,
at home.
Ã  a m & apos; screwed up a sacred © e funk.
J & apos; perhaps have dreamed ©.
Do I get mad?
Not.
The time has come to confront you at certain things.
My sÂur?
Yes.
She always wanted that & apos; they marry.
C & apos; Ã © was his game
It was the cÃ © © Result ceremony..
C & apos; Ã © is strange, right?
You think I'm crazy,
like her?
Not.
More...
be aware © Result sister.
Mom and Dad had gone to a party.
I must have been six or seven years.
That night, when everything happened,
we did the wedding ceremony.
It m & apos; gave so-called vitamins.
I woke up & apos; hosto,
j & apos; got a wash & apos; stomach.
Firefighters m & apos;
had taken and I & apos;'ve ever reviewed.
You asked your parents?
They never talk & apos; her.
This girl & apos; hospital...
Harriet, what should I do?
What should I do if it comes back?
You  m & apos; call.
J & apos;'m afraid when I see it.
She & apos; look real.
I do not want to be hospitalized.
My career is already pretty crappy.
You have experienced trials,
as a child.
j & apos;
have a split personality?
I do not see it.
Qu & apos; do that & apos; she wants me,
this bitch?
When you went out of your hiding
and you have expressed your fear,
Mom & apos; not appreciate.
But that & apos; may appoint
there is treatment.
She wants  j & apos; fails.
I will not yield.
C & apos;'s my little Vana.
Give him homage.
The "divinity of & apos; Imago"
as & apos; called Jung.
For us, it & apos;'s "& apos; magical child."
And that child n & apos; not fail.
Lie down.
J & apos;'ve hired a girl.
C & apos;'s crazy.
Why is this crazy?
She is disfigured.
Following a fire,
has severe burns on his face.
D & apos; where does it come from?
From Florida.
C & apos;'s crazy.
Fre apos; showed up at my door.
J & apos;'ve & apos; impression that & apos; in & apos; engaging,
I found.
People & apos; not come into our lives by chance
. We are convened.
Two women associated with fire.
I bet those visions
will disappear.
You really think so?
You welcome mom home.
You tell her, "Mom,
" between, you do not scare me.
"I'm invested.
" The soup is served.
"C & apos;'s my home, Mom
." I & apos;
have built on my affliction and my hopes.
"And you can not hurt me.
" I am a magic child.
So between.
"Mi casa es su casa."
Now take a deep breath.
Breathe!
If she comes here?
She will not come.
Qu & apos; do that & apos; she doing here?
From tourism, perhaps.
This & apos;'s not funny.
We have always responded differently,
you and me.
It needs to get fired.
Next?
If it works for Havana,
we know where she is.
And it saves time.
And if she saw Benjie?
C & apos; tabloids is that m & apos; worried.
J & apos; my class have to do.
On my notebooks & apos; schoolboy
On my desk and trees
On the sand snow
J & apos; put your name
On any given flesh
On the front of my friends
= = Son?
A second.
Between.
J & apos;'ve seen the light.
I can not sleep.
Me either.
You were reading?
A little, scénar.
C & apos;'s hard without a partner.
Mom gives me the Result © Plique.
But I & apos; like connaître
the Result © Replicas & apos; first.
C & apos;'s what makes you a pro.
I want to talk to you.
I take nothing.
Even no Seroquel.
J & apos;'ve got a good sponsor.
It is clean and sober for twenty years.
He had Robert Downey Jr, Demi Lovato...
No.
C & apos;'s your sÂur.
Perhaps that & apos; she has returned...
in Los Angeles.
She has called upon?
Not yet.
I thought she was in jail.
Ã  & apos; hospital...
very far & apos; here.
But it is free, white
and she is 18.
We had LIBA © rer.
I nÃ © gocie measurement & apos; Ã © remoteness...
A measure & apos; Ã © remoteness?
bad you & apos; hast not get in a
at birth.
You should have brought a judge
motherhood.
T & apos;'ve maybe tried.
We tried lots of things.
We mostly tried to do our best.
C & apos;'s in your book.
C & apos;'s your big thing.
"Do your best."
C & apos;'s supposed to be positive.
I do not know anything about this girl.
If j & apos;'ve never known who she was...
I do not know if it is unsafe.
I knew this day would come.
I thought that & apos; would it low profile.
C & apos; was silly.
But I want you to tell me
if she tries to see you.
I'll tell you, if she goes.
We like to share, remember...
some sleep, son.
And by the power  & apos;
a word I start my life
I was born to know you
To name you
Freedom
Havana, darling...
I do not know not if you & apos;'ve read,
but they announce that Damien chose Azita.
This & apos; is hardly a surprise, but...
I am furious with the method used.
It makes me lose face.
But C & apos;'s my problem, not yours.
I'm so sorry, darling.
Damien m & apos; called.
C & apos;'s hard to say this on your answering machine...
I did not want you & apos; may learn from another.
I think you don & apos; got nothing to regret.
I & apos;'ve always thought.
I know it & apos; was important to you.
But it must
that you put it behind you.
So, onward!
I & apos; sends six scenarios.
There are plenty of awesome projects to
& apos; horizon.
Remind me when thou dost.
I & apos; kisses.
L & apos; year will be tremendous!
J & apos; did a
hole that & apos; we can see everything.
All to see?
Money back.
I want to see her back zin.
Cut!
Mr zin will harvest all the laughs.
There & apos; appears in four scenes.
And he steals all!
Small shit.
Call Genie.
I want that & apos;
it turns this little shit.
Qu & apos; do you do here?
I wanted to talk to you.
It can wait.
Even the studio and paranoid drugs?
. Neither the studio nor his paranoid.
One & apos; expected, Benjie!
K you put it!
I want to eat.
My blood sugar drops when I turn with
Will zin shit.
You can put a burrito in the microwave?
Just two minutes.
It's okay?
Very well.
I thought you worked your
scenario.
J & apos; would.
J & apos;'ve got bills to pay.
How's the show biz?
It's okay.
J & apos; got a call to Blue Matrix.
You look?
I don & apos; not like soaps SF.
C & apos;'s like Battlestar Galactica
but post-September 11.
I don & apos; think not!
J & apos; spent 18,000 dollars. Let's go!
Havana, c & apos; is Jerome.
Hi.
There is a driver.
Awesome.
It comes  & apos;
audition for Battlestar Galactica.
In fact, Blue Matrix.
I am one of your fans.
Thank you.
Good luck!
My God!
Azita!
Sydney m & apos; said you were here.
J & apos; going t & apos; call. Congratulations!
Thank you. It m & apos; excites.
You'll be sublime.
And you'll love work with Damien.
It's so awesome.
I feel so good.
And your mother was exceptional.
It'll be a fun challenge for me.
This is not an imitation.
You know who will play mother?
Anne.
Hathaway.
How are you?
You love Anne.
You know her?
She's great.
Empare up the character.
For a split second...
j & apos;'ve thought © accept the role.
Crazy, right?
You should DA "...
J & apos; Ã © tais at the" tea © therapy at all costs. "
As cute!
You & apos; call...?
C & apos; Micah.
Say hello at Havana.
Micah... you're so cute.
C & apos; my timid.
He will break the cÂurs.
- Happy T & apos; seeing.
- Me too.
In 10 minutes?
Thank you, Uma.
Been output.
J & apos; love your new slave.
C & apos;'s a horrible sentence, right?
You have a lot in common.
This horrible type & apos; first.
"I'm invested, Mom.
" The soup is served.
"I am a magic child
So between.
" Mi casa es su casa. "
& apos; do you want?
This bravado...
C & apos;'s silly. Sorry.
C & apos; Only...
I feel your touch nervous.
C & apos;'s funny, but
j & apos;'ve lost & apos; used to people.
I do not want to hear it.
These "incidents" of which you speak
in talk shows,
these are false memories.
Liar!
Since the first day.
C & apos;'s your stepfather t & apos;
did these things. J & apos; should have seen.
His first wife
m & apos; said that & apos; he was like that.
You had m ​​& apos; blame
not t & apos; having protected.
Do m & apos; not approach.
You & apos; want it for that night.
"C & apos;'s my home, Mom
." I & apos;
have built on my pain and my hopes
"and you can not hurt me."
J & apos "Sorry ."; Was not & apos; ease.
"I'm not terrible, as dyke."
Are you okay?
J & apos; have the flu.
J & apos; I need cigarettes.
American Spirit.
Go get me some medicine.
Ambien, Vicodin, Xanax
... And Zoloft & apos; astragalus
and & apos; goldenseal.
And Yogi tea.
Agatha...
You know Stafford Weiss?
The therapist?
Not.
Of course not.
Why?
I repeat what I said a fucking corpse.
J & apos; do need Tampax.
And the Cozy Shack.
It is sold in trays,
as tapioca.
A rice cake.
And truffles Maison du Chocolat.
You'll find it all at Neiman.
Come into the garden.
I have to move some plants.
They are there since the earthquake.
I want to move here.
Do not care tiles,
we will redo.
They & apos; heavy air.
Do not make me go
to the wicked mother. You are strong.
You already have gloves.
Put all your weight & apos; effort.
Do it rotate like that.
Do it rotate.
The door was open.
What is going on?
- This n & apos; has not yet gone to JT?
- What?
The boy & apos;
Azita Wachtel died.
But I just see them!
He was with his father in Ojai
and s & apos; drowned.
My God! But how?
In the pool.
She & apos; was not there?
I do not know.
Nobody & apos; still has the details.
But here's what we'll do.
I know, it & apos; horrible.
You could replace it.
But how?
Is Azita & apos; hospital.
She lost her head.
Under sedatives.
- They can run without it.
- It will not resume work.
- They turned a lot?
- Just days.
The cast m & apos; called three times.
Sarah? You & apos;'ve remembered?
Yes. They make an offer.
Damien called?
No, but he must be devastated.
They will not & apos;
offers free & apos; approval of Damien.
Azita should.
It is expected to resume shooting.
Go to  & apos;
funeral and resume the movie.
I know  c & apos; limit is,
but do you want the part?
I need to talk to Damien.
Good. But that comes & apos; happen.
I don & apos; was able to reach anyone.
It must be said that
s & apos; cated they are, we will win everything.
At least that & apos; & apos they have someone, a d & apos; another.
I & apos; calls I know.
J & apos; send flowers?
You don & apos;'re not supposed to know.
Guard flowers for Damien,
when you sign.
Come on, sing!
C & apos; Micah is for breakfast!
For the miracle!
Who is Micah?
Fire and & apos; water.
There is fire and he & apos; water.
Adieu!
Farewell, Micah!
L & apos; fire and water. Say it.
Excuse me.
Looking Jerome Fontana.
There is a call for him.
C & apos; Vorbalid is?
Try to makeup.
& apos; do you do here?
Havana is in the canteen.
I was looking for.
C & apos;'s supposed to be a burn?
No, it & apos;'s a birthmark,
something.
There are 30 minutes.
Request for a makeup artist to remake you that.
There was a tarp to the pool
but the engine was being repaired.
He could not swim.
The father heard the phone
and he thought c & apos; was Azita.
He ​​left a second...
C & apos;'s always like that
it happens.
I mean,
c & apos; is that & apos; we hear.
You had Azita?
Yes, I went to her house.
I said you would play the role.
It & apos; was relieved.
Finally, apparently.
I do not feel at & apos; ease...
Going to tell him that!
But we're close.
J & apos; going t & apos; call
to speak to you of my decision to take...
Azita , but
c & apos; was such madness...
J & apos;'ve understood, Damien.
I don & apos; have no problem with that.
Me, though.
I don & apos; not like this approach.
J & apos; had loved your reading.
You know.
J & apos;
had reservations about the relationship with your mother.
But the film I turn
is so different from the original script.
In fact, it doesn & apos; looks like any more.
What the & apos; will reproach me.
The script is amazing.
Thank you.
I want you to feel strong,
despite the circumstances.
Nothing  & apos; happens by chance.
C & apos;'s what I think.
I'm glad you're here.
Victoria Rabbit. Star Channel.
Are you ready?
L & apos; interview was 16 hours.
Do you Genie & the apos; not say?
Can you give us 15 minutes?
But we have been waiting for...
Why not talk to my co-star Jim Carrey Jr?
Here!
Hey, Mr. & apos; turd will zin,
you want to be on TV?
Yeah.
Bring your ass here.
Hello. I, c & apos; is Roy.
Hey, Benjie!
Fuck! Get out!
All is well.
I have come to ask forgiveness.
How did you get in?
I work for someone & apos;
a spinning here. Havana Segrand.
You want me wrong, Agatha?
I mean you no harm.
You're my little brother.
If you try, I'll kill you.
Do you understand?
Are you hungry? A burrito?
I leave immediately.
Havana Segrand...
C & apos; not bullshit?
It's really good.
We have the same agent.
How thou art come
to work for it?
For & apos; intermediate & apos; friend.
Carrie Fisher.
For a disfigured schizo,
you're doing pretty well here.
They know you're there.
How?
Dad knows and sees everything,
if you forgot.
Watch out, & apos; elsewhere.
The old T & apos; stuck
a prescription & apos; distance.
Do not tell her you m & apos; sawest.
I'm not addicted to
"tour page"
So if you are looking for a revelation
easier your life...
It's been years since I t & apos; writing.
To explain.
Benjie, c & apos; Berg is Jeb.
I take a nap.
It is there.
I'm with my nieces
Connecticut...
We at Universal.
Just leave them in the train!
T & apos;'re so mean!
I kiss later.
You want a Cobalt?
Not. Sugar makes me mad.
Very funny!
So, Mom and Dad t & apos;
have sent in crazy?
The judges, anyway.
You & apos; look well.
J & apos; was among burn victims
and after my transplant, Florida.
The homeland of Scarface, Tony Montana.
Super.
C & apos; was you who brought it?
C & apos;'s mother & apos; Havana.
C & apos; was you who set the fire?
C & apos;'s hard.
No shit... C & apos; are you?
I did not want to hurt you.
You know, for them? Who we are? They'll
& apos; say?
Pills, vitamins?
Probably sleeping pills.
So you m & apos; gave pills
and you damn fire to the house?
J & apos;'m having a little trouble believing
that you would not hurt me.
I was seeing things.
- Like what?
- Children.
What were you doing when you saw them?
I said to them:
"With this ring, you m & apos;'re dedicated."
I remember. C & apos; was our game
It worked every time..
I said and they disappeared.
You should go now.
There ACS © nario.
You are part of & apos; very beautiful SCA © nario mythological.
Oh, my God!
My sÂur psychopath will
pitcher ACS © nario me!
Agatha, Will & apos; into.
And rebuke this DVD.
Do & apos; inquiète not
I'm not a pyromaniac.
They coupe © pilot.
Work your program, Milton.
No hassles in bed
The bed is for sleeping, do
& apos; love
but not to compete.
Thank you.
See you Tuesday.
Is that & apos; she's there?
Hi, Agatha.
My books. Thou hast read?
Yes.
Secrets kill.
A classic.
How do you m & apos;'ve found © e?
No & apos; examination, s & apos; he should flashplaygames.net you.
- Benjie...
- M & apos; said where you Ã © tais?
How would he know?
Did you go see Benjie?
What a bad idea!
C & apos; was dangerous.
But the question remains:
What are you doing in Los Angeles?
I am recovering.
I wanted to make amends.
Nobody & apos; escapes the 12 Steps...
Why & apos; not you come?
C & apos;'s a question of victim.
Like, "I t & apos;
have never promised a rose garden."
You know why.
I do not reward a murderous behavior.
J & apos;'ve changed.
I wanted to tell you how...
I'm sorry for what I & apos; did.
I wanted to tell you both.
J & apos; wrote.
Apology accepted.
You need & apos; money?
No, I & apos; have a job.
I work for  Segrand Havana. She
m & apos; told you.
Here. Here 10,000 dollars.
I want you to take a plane.
Our lives are rich.
We have built on your ashes.
Resigns from home Segrand.
Daddy.
I & apos; please.
N & apos; not even try to see
Benjie or Cristina. Do you understand?
You don & apos; did not believe that I & apos;
refoutre'd let you in my life & apos; air?
Take your skin cream,
your meds and your bags
cardboard and put them by the door.
And your program is working.
Good.
C & apos;'s over, Benjie.
At Friday.
D & apos; agreement. Thank you, Rusty.
Qu & apos; do you do here?
Qu & apos; do
you doing in my pool?
Who are you?
Micah.
C & apos; is a little drowned.
I do not want to see.
I t & apos; do anything.
His father thinks that & apos; he could keep him from drowning.
Fathers think like that.
I will do nothing.
Go play with someone & apos, a & apos; another.
I live, asshole.
I'm alive and I'm not crazy.
I know a man
who lives under  & apos;
sword of Damocles we call AIDS.
"When my time comes,"
m & apos;
. "I'll be ready
." Has he said,  My bags are packed, the
threshold "
J & apos; like it J & apos; really like
Say
Freedom: "We have to stop."
"You're a woman....
I would like t & apos; help "
" You do not think that I & apos;.
Have triggered these lights, b & apos; not it? "
Say: "No & apos; was not your intention
You need & apos; help, c & apos;'s all.".
You do not want m & apos; help?
N & apos; not remove my socks.
J & apos;
have scars on my legs, stomach and back.
On my notebooks & apos; schoolboy
On my desk and trees
On the sand snow
J & apos; put your name
On any given flesh
On the front of my friends
On any hand reaching
J & apos; put your name
Your mother, of course, was
Clarice Taggart
wonderful actress
died in a fire in the 70
Christmas .
You spoke of his addictions
and revealed, with great courage,
I must say,
that & apos; she abused you physically.
And sexually, yes.
What is rare. D & apos; usual
c & apos;'s father or stepfather.
And we'll talk about it,
but d & apos; First
j & apos; have a burning question:
Qu & apos; does it feel
turn in the remake
Stolen Waters
and play precisely the role of your mother?
Scary.
You say all that & apos; we will become his mother,
but then c & apos;'s a bit extreme.
She was even named...
For an Oscar, yes. But it n
& apos; had that & apos; Golden Globe.
I also feel good
as possible.
And we have the opportunity
& apos; having Damien Javitz.
Agatha, can you come here?
Who did rather strange films.
Really strange.
Do not be shy.
The Vicodin m & apos; totally constipated.
I want you to go get me a laxative
: Happy Moment.
They should & apos;
call Unhappy Moment.
I'm going to need you tonight.
Maria is taken.
One of his brats 1000
has nabbed cholera...
What should I do?
Tips for cooking.
Fill glasses.
Maybe use a little table.
It & apos; entertain.
A lot of interesting people.
It will serve you.
Fuck!
I will need an enema.
Wait a minute.
I wanted to ask you a question.
You see men?
Sometimes.
You see someone & apos; one right now?
I see that yes!
Just a little.
What does he do?
He is an actor.
These are the worst! Must play their
the mirror every morning.
Not mine.
There is also a screenwriter.
You look very appealing.
No false modesty.
You fuck?
Can you tell me!
Up & apos; where did you go?
Just about everything.
You have orgasms?
Go for it!
Is server?
He drives a limousine.
You & apos;'ve seen.
He's cute.
Drivers are tombeurs.
J & apos; just need yoghurt and cigarettes.
And call the plumber.
L & apos; water is cold.
Damn, it stinks here!
Hey, pilot fish.
- You go out late for a schoolboy.
- Two days off.
Take a Shirley Temple.
Are you kidding, I & apos; hope.
Do m & apos; not call Shirley.
Benjie  Weiss, Gretchen Voss.
Want  m & apos; burst.
Do you have something?
- The T & apos producers emmerdent?
- They try.
But one thing at a time.
Where is... Kayla?
We & apos; buggers.
C & apos;'s already done. After the union
sold him my shit.
- She & apos; has had his song.
- She & apos; was where?
- C & apos;'s a long story.
- Long and hard.
And Sam?
We'll soon find out,
at least I & apos; hope.
She had a crush on you and you
& apos;'ve thrown.
But no.
I know you cam.
I do not want you to lose your sobriety.
You'll turn a result of Babysitters?
Yes, they m & apos; made an offer
my mother n & apos; was denied.
It made so much money!
I & apos; saw in Thrill Kill.
Cool.
A comedy & apos; horror.
Critics have understood.
If you want, I & apos; have some GHB.
It smashes.
I & apos; love you.
Well, Sam is on the way.
Contract respected.
The Terminator.
At yours.
I & apos; bought on eBay.
It seems that & apos; he served
at Columbine massacre.
Is responsible, man.
I'll empty it.
Do not fuck.
Benjie!
He is sick.
If & apos; America knew!
Rhett, completes the joke.
On the clodhopper.
Never mind that & apos;
one hour that & apos; she started.
The clodhopper told the yuppie...
- C & apos; What is a yuppie?
- Are you serious?
I know what  c & apos; east.
But not what it means.
The clodhopper say yuppie:
"I know a place to go,
" we dance, we & apos s, y beats, we drink,
"and there fuck!"
This joke is safe sex?
It s  & apos; underway. It bareback.
Come on, give it to me.
J & apos;
asked if that joke was guaranteed safe sex.
J & apos; hope not.
Then I'll kill you.
It's starting to do well.
The yuppie said:
"Super
Do that & apos; there will & apos; other people.?"
Then the clodhopper said:
"No Who & apos; another
Just you and me.?."
Fucker!
You & apos;'ve killed!
- Damn!
- It is crazy.
- Get out!
- Dude, I'm sorry.
J & apos; had removed all the bullets.
You killed my dog.
Species con.
Motherfucker of Barje,
you killed my dog.
Bar up!
I come in?
Bad idea.
I did not stay long.
I wanted to make amends.
J & apos;
saw this house in magazines.
In Architectural Digest.
With the profile of dad.
I feel a bit exhibited,
but Stafford likes personalize everything
for that & apos;
we know how and where we live.
Do you want anything?
No, thank you.
Theoretically, j & apos;'ve stopped.
I thought you'd come earlier.
It'll be seven years.
C & apos;'s time that & apos; he m & apos;
had to do my makeup.
Agatha, I did not go to see you...
J & apos; would have done the same.
J & apos; afraid.
Ã  because of what you did.
N & apos; explain anything.
J & apos;
©'m so dreamed of & apos; old house.
C & apos;
is the first place that I & apos;'ve visited ©, at my return.
- Nobody & apos; nothing bÃ ¢ ti.
- The land belongs to us forever.
I redo the same dream for a
Ã © © eternity.
Benjie and me
we get married out there,
under a white canopy. J & apos;
when I get it & apos; knew for you and Dad.
Tu Ã © tais in Europe.
J & apos;'ve found the © © trunk key.
All photos.
We did not know that & apos; Ã © one brother and was sÂur.
We had been Ã © sÃ © © © s
Pará since childhood.
C & apos; Ã © was a monstrous thing.
It s  & apos; © s is met on campus.
We did not know.
What are you doing here?
Stafford, the n & apos; not.
I & apos; told to leave.
You did not know.
C & apos; was a monstrous thing.
J & apos;'ve found your diaries.
L & apos; love is stronger than death.
Dirty bitch!
Stop!
Daddy, no...
You're hurting him.
You gotta leave.
Do not hit!
Dad...
Leave me alone!
My ring.
She took my alliance.
My ring!
Inspection pee.
You're caught in the act!
You know you deserve a shouting match
sacred.
What does that mean?
You know what I mean...
Will zin my two!
Who is the star here?
You can tell me, Roy?
C & apos;'s you!
There & apos; not your enemy.
You...
L & apos; love is stronger than death.
You're a naughty babysitter, Benjamin.
Creve!
You're a naughty babysitter.
Fuck!
Holy shit!
There should be a little groggy.
My baby.
I'm sorry, Mom.
But why?
Benjie, why did you do that?
This & apos; was that & apos; small boy.
J & apos;'ve seen the girl...
Who, baby? Agatha?
Agatha came to see you?
The girl. It m & apos; trapped.
What little girl?
That of & apos; hospital.
The one that died
and I & apos; keep seeing.
My baby...
Must go home.
Must be that & apos; he left California.
Jonas must speak to the prosecutor.
There & apos; only 13 years old!
The violence of & apos;
aggression will play against him, Cristina.
There & apos; has robbed someone with a gun.
He hurt one boy!
Justice has become very hard
for minors.
They'll put him in jail?
They will not put him in jail.
The kid n  & apos; nothing.
Thank you God!
They stopped the series.
Will there be another casting?
But C & apos;'s a very small role.
Benjie. I speak of the role of Benjie.
It's all over.
C & apos;'re done!
Now the whole world will know.
The world will know that we have committed crimes.
You  m & apos; not want
& apos; appealing to you?
No, I & apos;'m happy.
My God. I feel bad.
I think j & apos;'ve bronchitis.
Your voice is more exciting.
Thank you.
And your story & apos; love?
It can go. It works.
C & apos;'s all you have to say?
I do not understand.
Well, that stuff burns...
This & apos; not a little unhealthy?
From the kiss?
Not. Not really.
She removes her gloves?
Your friends do not think it's a little unhealthy
?
Do your friends know her?
J & apos; started a...
a screenplay about it.
C & apos;'s research.
Everything is research,
to a certain level.
And I, you would be willing to fuck me for
"search"?
I do not know.
How would we do?
You come to see me?
Look at what I do.
How do we kiss?
For behind?
If you want.
I want it.
That last long?
Yes.
I am more beautiful that & apos; her?
And my skin?
Do that & apos; she is more beautiful?
Yes.
And my holes?
Do that & apos; are better, my holes?
You want to fuck my holes?
Yes.
Must j & apos; go.
And S & apos; you like him, do not go down.
Put yourself behind the wheel.
What & apos; happened?
J & apos; took the bus.
And the car?
It is broken.
That  t & apos; happened yesterday?
J & apos; was sick.
J & apos;'ve been sick this week.
But I get up at 5:00
and I work 14 hours a day.
You're going wrong?
I think j & apos; have the flu.
You act strangely.
And you're dirty.
Sorry.
And c & apos;
is too much to ask that & apos; send a text message?
Sorry.
Stop repeating that!
You know...
Maybe that & apos;
it's time to return to Florida.
Returns to Kansas, Dorothy!
C & apos; perfect.
But you could move your ass.
Because it gives me the creeps.
You stink. You stink. Do you understand?
Go home take a bath.
I'm sorry.
Oh, my God!
But you're bleeding!
You do not put Tampax?
You are psychotic?
I'm sorry.
I don & apos; do not believe...
My assistant bled on my couch to 12,000 dollars!
Get out of my life
dirty  degenerate!
I'll pay you.
Go to the kitchen
seek Perrier and rubs.
Go on Google for the stain.
I & apos;'ve picked up in the street.
I t & apos;'ve not paid for it.
For you to have your period
on my couch!
Do you think Carrie Fisher...
Nicole Kidman or Halle Berry
employ dirty critters?
Wacky and misshapen?
Hi, Agatha!
J & apos; ran away & apos; hosto
and told a carer
I would give him 10,000 dollars.
Con Poor fan!
How  m & apos; did you find?
You  m & apos; told work for it.
I've been here.
Where is Havana?
She went to Canyon Ranch.
Damien gave him two days of rest.
I'm lost, Agatha.
I can not go anywhere.
Benjie, I want you to m & apos; listens.
's All over, you know?
C & apos; is that of Cristina.
Go get that from Dad.
Can you?
You can pick her up?
Let's keep it a secret
much as possible.
Nothing should spoil my class.
At worst, I go to Oprah.
I confess
kind Lance Armstrong.
It could generate a lot of money.
This Monday on GMA,
We launch to try.
Cristina!
Daddy?
I n  & apos;'ve never taken so much!
C & apos; Ã © was so brave of you
back out there.
I & apos; just did
slide his finger.
As S & apos; he wanted me to take her.
We should start...
J & apos;'ve vÃ © cu thirteen Ã © been © s.
C & apos;'s not so bad.
Not bad.
With this ring...
You m & apos; devoted © es...
I am devoted to you... ©
As my Ã © lice...
Like your Ã © lice...
With this ring...
You m & apos; are devoted © e Ã ©
as my wife...
I am devoted to you © e
as your wife.
Set me as a seal on your
cÂur.
You may kiss the bride © e.
On & apos; lack no deposit © Sir
On the bare loneliness
On the death marches
J & apos; Ã © yell your name
On Santa © back
The likelihood disappeared
On & apos; hope no memory
J & apos; put your name
And by the power & apos; short...
I start my life...
I born to know you, you... To name