MONEY TRAIN
Merry Christmas.
Watch it!
Thank you very much.
We wish you a Merry Christmas ...
- Check this dude.
- He looks like the Five-0.
Are you a cop?
He's no Five-0. He's been drinking.
He's checking out the D.
We have two Hispanic males.
Let's see if they end the game.
- This looks familiar.
- He's got a slice. Stay alert.
He's got my ring.
Shit! He's wearing my watch.
Nobody go
until you see him pull his lapel.
- Shit!
- Fucking white boy!
Stay!
Get out of my way!
Move!
- Get out of the way!
- Come on, grandma.
- No laying down on the job!
- I'm glad my pain amuses you.
Come on. Move!
T.A.!
Slow down.
You've got cops down there?
All trains north and south of
Wall Street Station stop and stay.
- Doesn't he ever sleep?
- Yeah, during the day. In a coffin.
- You're stopping trains. Why?
- We've got cops in the tunnel.
- Where is the revenue train?
- At Wall Street.
- Send it through.
- We've got cops on the track.
Nothing stops the money train.
- The money train!
- I've got a new plan.
Get out of my way!
- Here's the cash.
- You sold a lot of tokens today.
Watch it!
- Freeze!
- They're not stopping.
- I don't believe this shit!
- We're cops.
- Back up, men.
- Look. it's the Transit Twins.
- Did you have to shoot him?
- He's a fucking kid.
- We're only following orders.
- Does he look like a train robber?
Don't try to hang the blame on us.
- You ran him down the track.
- What did you say?
You're not gonna hit him ...
I'm gonna hit him.
Chief, the detectives are here.
Sit down.
- Don't bleed on my chair.
- No sir. Chief Patterson.
That report says you're brothers.
You are a negro.
He is white.
Is somebody trying to jack me off?
- No. we're foster brothers.
- I ran away from this orphanage ...
Shut up!
Today, you caused my money train
to arrive 46 minutes late.
When my train is late, I take it
as a personal sign of disrespect.
The revenue collection of the entire
subway system is under my command.
My train. My people. My money.
No one dictates the movements
of that train without my permission.
- Am I making myself clear?
- As a bell. sir. Your train.
- Shut up!
- Yes. sir.
Now ... any questions?
Why did you send the train through
when you knew we were in the tunnel?
Your situation last night
didn't affect me.
Your men shot that kid to shit
over a rope chain.
Yeah, they shot him to shit ... and
you can't buy publicity like that.
That boy is a goddamn hero.
Thanks to his sacrifice
the word went forth today:
You fuck with my train
and I'll kill you!
Now I'm gonna send one more message:
I don't like you.
So don't fuck with my train again.
If you do, we will tangle ass ...
... and you will lose.
You're dismissed.
I hate bastards like that.
You can't put a price on human life.
- He's worried about his schedule.
- You know what I'd like to do?
- Shoot him?
- No. I'd like to take his train.
- Take the candy from the baby.
- You say the word.
- Word.
- I'm there.
- Let's do it.
- If I didn't have this badge ...
- We're not nuns.
- We're not taking the train.
Too late.
- I sure miss the old neighbourhood.
- You should come back more often.
- Are you coming in?
- No, I've got a date.
With a girl ...
or a deck of cards?
- Do you think I'm gambling again?
- Yeah, I can see it in your eyes.
- You've got a suspicious mind.
- I know you.
Have you got any cash?
- I'm buying your Christmas present.
- With my money?
Yeah, so don't be stingy.
- You never cease to amaze me.
- Don't count it. I trust you.
- Will you really buy me a present?
- I love you.
- Then give me my money.
- Where's your Christmas spirit?
In your pocket.
No ties or cologne, all right?
Remember where you are.
You'd better change that walk.
Are you all right, man?
- 1.000.
- I'm in.
See the grand
and kick it a grand.
- Not me.
- I'm out.
I'm gonna have to kick it to 5,000.
Too rich for me.
Charlie ...
are you gonna eat or play cards?
Sorry. I'm making a mess.
- I'll call you.
- With what? You're light.
Gentlemen, say hello to Oyster.
Mother-of-pearl.
Charlie, let me get you a parachute.
Your brother better get here soon
or he'll be an only child.
- Okay, nobody move.
- Is that you? My brother?
- Thank God you're here!
- What the hell is going on here?
- You brought the money, right?
- 300 bucks.
- He owes Mr. Brown 15.000.
- 15.000?
This is no time to be cheap.
- Drop him.
- He's kidding.
- They don't have a sense of humour.
- I'm tired of this shit.
You're the man.
Okay, let's make a deal.
Here's the 300 bucks.
- The rest, you get in a few days.
- I'll pay you, I swear to God.
Okay, reel him in.
You guys are great. I was kidding
about the sense of humour thing.
- I thought they were gonna drop me.
- You said you'd stopped this shit.
- I thought I couldn't lose.
- You say the same thing every time.
- I'm tired of saving your ass.
- I'd have got out of that shit.
If I hadn't saved you,
you'd be a chalk outline right now.
I have changed at a basic level.
I was up there. 51 stories.
Dangling. Imminent death.
Suddenly ... it was like
Buddha consciousness.
I've read about it.
God spoke to me. She said,
'You have got to stop gambling."
- I bet $10 you can't do it.
- Make it $20.
- Where's your sense of humour?
- You've been drinking dog piss.
It's good for you.
Let's see that drunk walk again.
Say hello to Grace Santiago.
She's gonna be working with us.
- Hi, guys. Nice to meet you.
- How are you doing?
Welcome aboard.
- She is smokin'.
- I think I'm in love.
All quiet by the D.
Okay, we've got a Christmas shopper.
A white male. 19.
Dressed all black.
He's interested.
His girlfriend's after him.
She's dragging him away.
- Did you do much decoy?
- Six months in the outer boroughs.
This transfer
was definitely a lucky break.
- They say you guys are the best.
- Modesty prevents me ...
No. it doesn't. We are the best.
His arm's swinging. He looks like
he forgot how to take a whiz.
He got that from me.
- Where are you from?
- The Bronx.
- Are you living by yourself?
- Yeah.
- Keep watching the D.
- We've got something going on.
What have we got here?
Look at those big hands.
- Let's take him home.
- I'm into it.
Hey, honey,
we're gonna take you home.
You want to come home?
You're a fine-looking man.
- Don't fight us.
- Look at that face.
We're gonna love you.
- We're gonna chew you up.
- Come with us.
Shouldn't we break it up?
Hey! That's my man.
Get your hands off my man.
- Do you want to get hurt?
- We didn't know he was your man.
Get out of here!
- I can't trust you for one minute.
- They were huge.
She's beautiful.
Wait right there.
What are you looking at?
Alone at last.
- May I help you?
- We can help each other.
- What do you want, sir?
- I want to ask you a question.
Do you know what it's like
to smell your own flesh burning?
Hand out the cash. bitch.
or I'll light you up.
- I gave you the money.
- I'm not in it for the money.
It's the torch! Call the EMS.
I'll take the street.
Get down!
Sick bastard!
Police!
Get off me.
It's okay.
Johnny, Merry Christmas.
What are you drinking?
The usual. Jack. Straight up.
Give me to of those
and give me to beers.
This is a little hard
so you should drink it with ...
... a beer. Obviously ...
... you've been there before.
That's with me, Johnny.
You took a pretty hard one today.
Too bad he got away.
It was his lucky day.
That won't happen twice.
The EMS people say the clerk
is going to be just fine.
That's good to hear.
This job can be hazardous to your
health if you take it too seriously.
- I don't know no other way.
- Me neither.
It takes a special kind of person
to do this job.
- Someone with dedication.
- Perseverance.
- Stamina.
- Strength.
- Courage.
- Cojones.
- Complete and utter stupidity.
- It's a curse.
- Welcome to the team.
- Thanks.
- How are my to favourite people?
- We were fine.
He's a kidder.
I looked long and hard and I found
you something for your first day.
- The alcohol preserves it.
- Thanks.
He probably stole it
from a girl scout.
Grab us a couple of cervezas.
You don't expect Grace to pay,
and I'm having a cash-flow problem.
You mean you're broke!
You ain't got a dime to your name.
I love the flower.
Great guy ... too bad he's gay.
- How are you doing?
- Good. man.
How does it feel
to be brothers with a white guy?
I told you that story.
I heard a garbage can making noises.
You found him?
Did you feed him? You can't
get rid of them when you feed them.
- Stay black.
- I ain't got no choice.
- The night is young.
- I've got to go.
- The night's a puppy.
- She's leaving.
- I'm in love.
- You ain't got a shot.
- I am deeply in love.
- She is nice.
I'd introduce her to Ma Di
if she was still alive.
You know what they say:
May the best man win.
- I intend to.
- You're dreaming.
You ain't even got a chance.
She didn't even keep the rose
you gave her.
That's fucked up!
- You can buy her a new one.
- I wouldn't do that to you.
It's typical of your insensitivity,
like pissing on that car.
You've always got to be the coolest.
You've always got to be on top.
- I'm just kidding.
- You're always that way.
- Ma Di gave you everything.
- Ma Di treated us the same.
No. She treated me great.
She took me in. she loved me.
but she loved you better.
We got the same thing, Charlie.
It's called sharing.
- I get your coat, you get my shoes.
- I'm always in your shoes.
I'm always Hook's little brother.
- Is this about shoes or Grace?
- My ceiling is always your floor.
- Then move out of the building.
- I like the building.
But you're always first
and I'm always one step behind.
- So now it's my fault?
- Yeah, partially.
- It's you who always fucks it up.
- Now you're calling me a fuckup.
- I didn't say that.
- It's the same fucking thing.
- Are you listening to me?
- I don't need this shit.
- Get your hands off me.
- Or what?
- I'm here, you're there ...
- Make a move. man.
You want to try me?
Wallets, rings and watches.
- Give up your shit.
- Are you deaf?
- I'm talking to you.
- You heard the man.
- Chill out, white boy.
- Now look at the shit we're in.
- Are you gonna blame this on me?
- Definitely.
Who was watching the street?
My back was to the street.
- I'm sick of you.
- Stop pinning everything on me.
Give it up!
- You called me a fuckup.
- I did not!
- Fuck you, man!
- Fuck me? Fuck you!
I'm robbing your ass!
Give up your shit!
I'll get you his shoes.
I'll shoot you.
This is a stick-up!
I'll shoot you full of holes.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
- You took my Ice Cream records.
- Ice Cube!
They're sick!
- Would you really shoot me?
- Hell. no.
You had that Alabama look.
You're lucky
I didn't have a fire hose.
- You think this girl could be it?
- Yeah. I do.
- Hey, go for it.
- Yeah?
- I'm out of it.
- Are you serious?
I hope she makes you happy.
- Merry Christmas, man.
- Merry Christmas to you, too.
The department says we must have
backup in the Christmas season.
Shut up and stay out of our way.
We didn't ask for this assignment.
We're not here to steal anything.
They're pissed off because we
beat up their buddies on day shift.
Everybody chill.
We're here to help you out.
There's just a Little bit too much
testosterone in here.
Back to your stations.
We've got a schedule to keep.
Dooley ...
- You gonna take in a lot tonight?
- Yeah. three or four million.
- That's money.
- Stop drooling.
Just taking a few mental notes.
Check out that grate.
Look alive.
We've got something up ahead.
Just tunnel workers.
- You're in my place.
- Stop poking me with that thing.
- Shut the fuck up!
- Stop pushing me.
You ain't gonna hit him ...
I'm gonna hit him.
Beautiful!
- Is she your wife?
- No. sir.
- Your girlfriend?
Perhaps your sister?
That would make sense.
A white brother. a black brother ...
... and a Latino sister.
- Officer Grace Santiago, sir.
- You boys are lucky.
How did you get so lucky?
Are they lucky, Officer Santiago?
- I don't know what you mean, sir.
- Having you as a partner.
- I'll try my best to do my job.
- I'm sure. You're dismissed.
This doesn't concern you,
Officer Santiago.
You boys, you don't listen.
This time you may have your nuts
in a wringer.
The first time my train
was only late, this time it's light.
- Light?
- Sit down.
It seems that in the darkness
somebody made off with $25,000.
- How could that happen?
- Why ask us?
You're a bad gambler.
You're in debt up to your eyeballs.
You're good at losing money.
- How do you think I lost mine?
- Do you think we're behind this?
Did I say that?
All I said was that bad things
seem to happen around you to.
Some money got ... lost.
I think you can help me find it.
- How so?
- You look for it.
If you dig down in that commode
that you call a soul, -
- you'll come up with something.
- I didn't ask to be disturbed.
- You might want to hear this.
Get out of here.
You're dismissed.
- Dismissed?
- Dismissed.
One second you're calling us crooks,
the next we're just dismissed.
The money has been recovered.
A collection agent confessed.
What happened to that money train
model that was on your desk?
Yeah. when I didn't see it.
I was heartbroken.
- It's just gone.
- I bet it took ages to make.
You're a wreck
looking for someplace to happen.
I'll be there ...
and I'll fuck you dead.
- Does he want to fuck us to death?
- When we're dead. he'll fuck us.
Either way, it's a pain in the ass.
Fuck him. Thinking I stole
the money. That's insulting.
- I thought you stole it, too.
- You did?
That's all right, you're family.
That son of a bitch ...
What?
- Look over there.
- It's Wollman Rink.
Last night, those repair guys
came up a ladder into the park.
I see what you're saying.
Stop the train near the rink.
Use the ladder to climb up
and take away the cash.
- We disappear into the park.
- It'll never work.
How much do you think we can get?
Three or four million. at least.
- We could be rich.
- Free. And our people deserve it.
- Say it loud.
- I'm black and I'm proud.
We're talking
"Lifestyles of the Rich and Famous".
- We could take cruise ships.
- Island to island.
We'd be like boat people, but rich.
We could just buy an island.
Now you're talking.
We could buy Mali.
- Or Bali.
- Tahiti.
We wouldn't have to put up
with any more crap from Patterson.
- We don't deserve that.
- Let the sharks eat him.
- Let's do it.
- Here's what I'm saying ...
Talk to me.
The best possible time
to pull this off is New Year's Eve.
It'll be loaded with currency.
It'll just be fat!
- Where did you learn that word?
- MTV Raps. It's my heritage.
What do you think?
Charlie. come back to earth.
- Calm down.
- What are you talking about?
- We're not going to rob the train.
- Why not?
We're cops ... "Serve, protect,
break a mother's neck."
- We can do this.
- No ...
It would be no problem.
I'm telling you. It's easy.
Put that away before somebody thinks
you got it for Christmas.
- Don't let me interrupt.
- It was too hot inside.
So you're getting down. Salsa.
I love this. I grew up with this.
I'm from the Bronx.
Let's see what you've got.
I'm very surprised.
E Street.
- See that?
- You're teaching me something now.
You've got to learn from somebody.
Watch out now.
I might throw a spin on you.
- It's rough the first time.
- We need to get some practice in.
- We were dancing.
- That was nice.
- Don't just leave me hanging.
- Slow music? No ...
- I don't dance to slow music.
- Don't you like slow music?
How would it look for me
to step up to you like that ...
... and start dancing with you close
and stuff like that?
That could work.
- I've got a confession to make?
- What's that?
This is the first time
I ever danced with a cop.
Me. too.
- I hope that's your gun.
- Yeah, it's poking me, too.
Maybe it's my gun.
- Put your stuff in the back.
I think I should go in.
- We don't want people talking.
- We wouldn't want that.
You know how the precinct is.
You go ahead.
Good night.
Grace ...
- I enjoyed dancing with you.
- I enjoyed it, too.
How goes?
A pina colada?
You've got to get up
you've got to get up in the morning .
I knew I shouldn't have told you
where I hide my keys.
Get up. Time to play.
Say no more, man.
It's hot in here.
- It's like a sauna.
- Don't touch the window.
- Fresh air.
- It's cold outside.
- You've got to get fresh air.
- You're not in the Alps.
- It's good for your lungs.
- Not in New York.
You smell like you haven't been
back to your place to wash.
- I've been out.
- Grace?
I've been out with Grace all night,
and God, I'm feeling good.
All night?
All night, and I feel all right.
Did you try some of your
cheap-ass moves?
- A gentleman never tells.
- What?
A gentleman never tells.
Then you can go ahead and tell me.
How did it go?
We ... I ain't gonna say.
Did you kiss her?
You kissed her.
- Shouldn't you be home in bed?
- Too much energy.
I thought
you worked that out last night.
I've still got
a little something left.
- You want to go at it?
- What? Boxing?
Come on, let's go a few rounds.
Don't hold back.
Are you sure you want to do this?
Sneaky!
Get out of here.
I ain't going nowhere.
Okay ... good.
- You want to talk about last night?
- You mean about you and Charlie?
About you and me,
and the reason you backed off.
Are you gonna box or talk?
- It's Charlie. isn't it?
- Yes!
- The guy's crazy about you.
- This has got to be a first.
You care more about your brother
than you do about yourself.
He is my brother.
Yes. I care about him.
I ain't no saint.
There are times
I could kill the guy.
- I heard he's kind of a fuckup.
- Fuckup?
- I'm sorry.
- I'm okay.
- I was out of line.
- No.
- I have to look after my brother.
- I understand about your brother.
I don't understand what's going on
between you and me.
You and me ...
Yeah.
You and your feelings about me.
Well, I decked you, didn't l?
- I feel the same way about you.
- This could get painful.
Hey, love hurts.
Adios.
Charlie, I want to talk to you.
Come here. man.
- I want to give you this.
- You got me a Christmas present.
- What is this? 15 grand?
- I've been saving for a rainy day.
- It's raining, Charlie.
- I can't take this.
Take it. Handle your affairs.
Go ahead and pay Mr. Brown.
- You're always there for me, Hook.
- You'd be there for me.
No. I wouldn't. You wouldn't
get yourself into a mess like this.
- I'll pay you back every dime.
- I know you will.
I love you, man.
- Handle it.
- I'll do it right now.
I'd better put this shit away.
Meet me tomorrow night.
I want to talk to you.
You got it.
You never cease to amaze me.
My best New Year's ever.
Or something.
- Are you all right?
- Yes. I'm fine.
Easy does it.
Thank you.
Police!
- Get off of me!
- Settle down.
- Does this look familiar?
- That's my wallet.
I see this all the time.
The best place to keep
your valuables is right here ...
No! Open the door!
Stop the train!
Hi.
Round to.
I know you won't believe this,
but I had Mr. Brown's money.
Some old lady dipped me.
Dip this!
God ...
Charlie, at least let me explain ...
There is nothing to explain.
I knew what was going on.
- You're lying.
- If I'm lying, I'm flying.
I'm happy for you guys.
Why wouldn't I be?
We're brothers, right?
Did you pay Mr. Brown?
Actually, I lost the money,
but what else is new, right?
Damn. Charlie!
Two tokens, please.
What are the chances of the robbers
actually hitting my booth?
The report says it's only one guy
and that he goes for female clerks.
So ... act female.
What? Powder my nose?
Paint my toenails?
Skip said you'd be a little late.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah ... I'm fine.
I was reading that book
you lent me. "The Kabbalian."
It says that the universe
is a mental creation of the All.
- You're drunk.
- No. I'm not drunk.
- Your breath's about 90-proof.
- That's from last night.
I don't want to hear it.
Go home and get some rest.
You've got a lot of nerve
coming in here like this.
- Let me explain about the money.
- What is it this time? Horses?
No. I was on the train
and this old lady dipped me.
- Don't lie to me!
- Have I ever lied to you?
- Maybe about little things.
- A lie is a lie.
- I want you to believe me.
- I don't. Don't say another word.
Are you gonna hit me?
- What the hell was that, Darryl?
- Somebody fell on the track.
Grace, hold your position.
Somebody fell on the tracks.
- Keep your eye on Grace.
- Yeah. I can handle that.
- Who's handling dispatch?
- I don't know.
What happened?
- What the fuck ...
- You remember me?
Sure you do.
That's my scent you're wearing.
- Do you want the money?
- No, I don't want the money.
10-13! Grace is in trouble!
Freeze!
Come on!
Police! Move!
Out of the way!
Move. Police. Out of the way.
No. Charlie!
Move! Get out of the way.
Move! Police!
You see what happens
when you play with fire?
You get burned.
Perfect.
You created quite a shit storm.
You could've blown people away
with your reckless shit.
Now, if you want to look
like a hero, I think I can help.
Don't worry, kid,
we'll get you out of this one.
All you've got to do ...
... is ask for my help.
It's your badge. It's your life.
It's your call.
What do you say?
No.
From there.
Why aren't you laughing?
Don't you think I'm funny any more?
- Now, say it.
- You want to hear the words?
I want to hear the words.
- Kiss my fucking ass.
- You kiss it. You're fired!
Get up, Charlie.
We can work this out.
- Not with this piece of shit.
- Your brother ain't a cop no more.
- Let me talk to him.
- What do you want to help him for?
Everybody knows
your brother is a fuckup.
- A what?
- A fuckup.
I don't have to take this shit.
I'll bust your ass!
Go ahead. take a bite of me.
You'll never get rid of the taste.
- You son of a bitch!
- That's it! You're busted!
I don't have to take this shit!
When your friend calms down,
tell him his badge belongs to me.
I'll send a uniformed officer around
to pick up my hardware.
You don't have to send nobody.
You can come and get it yourself.
This is between you and me,
not you and him.
Who does he think he is? Fuck him!
He's gonna regret this day.
No, fuck you, Charlie.
- Fuck me?
- Yeah, fuck you.
I didn't ask you to step in ...
but it'll work out, don't worry.
No, it's not gonna work out.
Not this time.
- Come back. bro.
- We're not brothers.
We have nothing in common.
I've always been carrying you
on my back.
Am I gonna give up my career
for you? No! Get out of my life!
Frank, do you happen to know
why blind people don't skydive?
No, why?
It scares their dogs.
It scares their ...
You're a tough crowd, Frank.
Another Jagermeister.
You've had enough, Charlie.
You're cut off.
What's your problem?
You're interfering with me
at the embryo stage of a bender.
Other than that
I've got nothing to worry about.
I've got no job, no brother,
no girlfriend, no future ...
I've got nothing to lose. For the
first time in my life ... I'm free.
- "God bless us all, Tiny Tim."
- You're over the top, Charlie.
Don't do anything stupid.
Where's the fun in that?
I just remembered,
I have to urinate.
I'll pick this up later.
I don't have the money.
Go ahead and kill me.
Right now it'd be a relief.
I hate to hear
that kind of fatalism, I really do.
We can't keep on doing this because
it doesn't have any effect on you.
What I do in a case like yours,
and I'm being forced here ...
... is threaten someone you love.
A wife. A child.
- A brother ...
- Son of a bitch.
Merry Christmas, Charlie.
January 1st ...
or your nigger brother's dead.
- What are you doing here, Frank?
- I want to talk about Charlie.
He's in a lot of trouble.
Gentlemen, keep the fires hot!
- Where are you going?
- To talk to Mr. Brown.
Get out of here.
You missed.
I hate that.
- You've got a disgruntled employee.
- Kick his fucking ...
You can't come in here like that.
Stop fucking around.
Bring him over here. I'll kill him.
You got big balls? I'll cut 'em off.
What the hell are you doing?
You bunch of pussies!
- We're not getting along.
- You want some of me?
What are you, stupid?
You'll get your money.
But if anything happens
to my brother ... You understand me?
Oh yeah ...
Who are you calling a nigger?
- Happy New Year.
- Hi. John.
- Johnny!
Charlie came by earlier
and left it for you.
- It took you long enough.
- I'm sorry I'm late.
What is this dress you've got on?
Turn around.
- This old rag?
- Just one you had in the closet?
- You got a permit for this dress?
- You're happy.
I did one last favour for Charlie.
so I'm feeling like a free man.
"The Islands Call."
- Charlie sent it over.
- Open it.
- Damn it. He's gonna do it.
- Do what?
Rob the money train.
- Say again?
- He's gonna rob the money train.
- He wants me in with him.
- Patterson will kill him.
- Aren't you gonna do anything?
- Why should l?
Charlie is going down ... and you
are the only family that he's got.
Open up.
Jesus Christ!
Shoot!
- The money train has been stolen!
- I've got to call Patterson.
Out of the way!
Move!
Attention, everyone!
The situation here
will be resolved immediately.
These perpetrators are fools
and their luck just ran out.
Let's get them. Remember:
The money train has not been stolen.
It is still in our tunnel.
and soon it will be in our hands.
Shit!
You scared the shit out of me. man.
- How did you find me?
- You told me the plan, remember?
- Only Plan A. Now we're on B.
- What?
- We'll figure it out.
- This is Plan B:
- We leave without the money.
- I ain't down with that.
- Then we've got a serious problem.
- Yeah, I guess we do.
If you turn me in, you get a medal.
- Get us the hell out of here.
- I thought you'd never ask.
When this is over.
I'll knock you out.
The money train is reported
going south on the A-line.
This is Donald Patterson.
Shut down the train and surrender.
Don't do that.
Donald, the robbery's going great
and you'll still get your cut.
You sons of bitches.
I don't know who you are, -
- but when I get my hands on you
I'll rip your hearts out.
I don't appreciate
that tone of voice.
Don't even look at me.
When Patterson trips the brakes,
our joyride is gonna be over.
We have to bleed the brakes.
- Great, then they can't stop us.
- Then we can't stop, either.
It's bleed the brakes or end up
the butt brothers in D-block.
Bleed the brakes.
- Get me 42nd Street.
- Stand by for Chief Patterson.
The money train is coming your way.
Shut her down.
Trip her brakes.
Reach in and tear her guts out.
Come on, baby. It's got to work.
Yes!
It didn't stop, sir.
I don't think it has any brakes.
I want the shooters
on the Grand Street platform.
- Aim at the motorman's cabin.
- Use a construction barricade.
Good point.
I want a barricade in place now!
That thing's reinforced steel.
They'll be killed.
Money train, this is Patterson.
I have an information update.
At the Grand Street Station we have
a reinforced steel barricade.
Shut it down
and turn yourself in ...
... or die!
He's bluffing, right?
You. over there.
You to. come with me.
What are we gonna do?
We can't stop this thing.
Go faster. Faster!
Come on!
Charlie ... he wasn't bluffing!
Ready. Easy, now.
Wait for my command.
Fire!
You're not gonna believe this.
The train broke the barricade.
- I'll have to start clearing track.
- Wait a minute.
- What's the nearest train?
- The 12:20. I'll sidetrack her.
What? And give them a clear track?
Raise me the motorman.
- Command to 12:20.
- 12:20 to Command.
This is Donald Patterson.
Bypass all stops.
- What's going on?
- Shut up and do your job!
Maybe we're on the wrong train.
It didn't stop.
Two trains are on the same track.
there could be a derailment.
There'll be no derailment.
They'll shut the money train down.
If the money train can't stop,
people could die.
That's what we live with.
- Charlie, what are you doing?
- I'm getting paid.
- The money stays.
- Feel that.
That's our freedom.
I'm not leaving here empty handed.
"Charlie the loser."
I've heard that my whole life.
- Thieves aren't winners.
- Save the lecture for Tahiti.
No, forget it.
Don't fuck with my fantasy!
lf you want out, get out of my face!
- I won't let you ruin your life.
- How are you gonna save me?
Get that foot off that bag!
Don't try me. Are you trying me?
- Just let it go.
- I'm taking the money, man.
Damn!
Give me your hand.
Grab onto my hand!
- I've got you, man.
- Charlie ...
Come on. John.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Are we straight?
- Yeah, we're straight.
- Let's shut this puppy down.
- That's easier said than done.
You and me. man.
What can stop us?
My God!
Patterson didn't clear the tracks.
- We're gonna derail them.
- These people are gonna die.
- Do something.
- The bitch won't move.
Maximum speed.
The other train's too fast!
We're fucking dead! You hear me?
All emergency units,
head to Fort Hamilton Station.
- Throw the damn thing in reverse.
- The train will do a somersault.
- But we live, right?
- No, they live. We die.
So be it. We hit the reverse switch
and say goodbye.
- We don't have time for this.
- Just jump, man.
I can't jump! We're in a tunnel!
This is my responsibility.
It's my fuckup!
We're in this together.
What are you doing?
Are you gonna pole vault
out of here?
Autopilot. When this hits,
it'll throw her into reverse.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I don't know.
- Where's my train?
- It's to minutes out.
Good!
When we get out of this,
remind me ...
Don't let go.
Get to the front.
- Are they dead?
- There's nobody here.
They're here.
They're here. You fuck with my train
and I'll find you.
I'll find you.
- Shit! Is that Patterson?
- Get out of my way.
- What are we gonna do?
- I'll find you.
Be cool.
- We came as fast as we could.
- What a mess.
- If we can help ...
- All you've got to do is ask.
- What are you doing here?
- We just want to help.
How's your cock working now that
you ain't got a badge any more?
This is what I think of you,
you fuckup ...
You spit in my face?
You aren't gonna hit him ...
I'm gonna hit him!
We'll both hit him.
Arrest those to for assault.
No, Patterson, I'm arresting you.
You endangered people's lives.
Did you see that?
Arrest his ass! He tried to kill us!
- Who are you?
- You don't remember me?
Officer Santiago.
- We did it!
Happy New Year.
I love you, man.
- What is that?
- I've put on some weight.
- What are you, six months pregnant?
- You're gonna overreact on this.
- I knew you'd overreact.
- Overreact?
We risked our lives. man.
It's New Year's.
- I saved your life.
- It's a miracle we're alive.