And the first prize of today's raffle
in aid of the roof appeal
Thank you Lilly
Tthe magnificent holiday
to the South of France
Kindly sponsored by
Deals Travel Limited
The winner will travel by Eurostar
train to Paris
Then catch the fast train Southbefore spending
the week on the beaches of the French Riviera
It also includes 200 Euro spending money
And Barbara this wonderful video camera
Kindly donated by
''A.K. Electrics ON THE ROAD''
The winner of this amazing prize is....
919...
Anybody have ticket 919?
Anyone?
Yes!!
Oui
No
You speak very good French
Gracias
Ou vas vous?
Choo, choo, Gare de Lion
How long are you staying in Paris?
Of course I'll be in Cannes for my Premiere
Till then I am working on an exciting new project
With the wonderful actress Cindy
- Sabine
- Right
STOOOP.......
Back.... back a bit..
Stop back back
No, no, no...
back
Gracias, Gracias
Stop
Open the door
- Open the door
- There's nothing here
Attention all aboard please
My bag
Yes
Papa
Nothing
Come on
Cut
Cut, Cut
What is he doing
Ehere did he come from?
Some of us here are trying to make a work of art
-Everyone back in position
I want some different angles
Put him in the background
...... hard
And you never stop. OK?
Remeber you are crazy for the
taste of Fruzzi yoghourt
Cut
The guy with the video camera is fired
You're fired
Come again
Action
Cut, Cut
Where's my explosion?
All I wanted is an explosion
A little tiny explosion
Is it really so hard for you guys
I mean
All you have to do is this
Dunlop
Cannes?
Gracias
No
No, No
Oui
Bean
Bean, Sabine
Bean, Sabine, Bean, Sabine
Oui, Oui
Telephone, Papa
This film is for all of us
longing for the truth
For all of us who cry out in pain
For those who souls need to sin
Merci
These pictures were released of the Englishman
Beleived to have abducted the son of Cannes Film Festival,
Jury member Emil Dechevsky
A positive Id of the boy was made
at a service station yesterday
The police now believe ότι that the man
is travelling with a female accomplice
A national manhunt has been launched
and stop and search procedures....across France
You are not Russian?
No
You are not this boy's father?
- No
- You are English?
Oui
You know the whole of France is looking for you
And now they look for me too
Who are you?
Where are you going?
To the Beach
This boy's father is
a Judge of the .... film
We take him there
And the beach?
Forget the beach
I have only one scene in this movie
And I am not going to miss this Premiere
not for you not for the Police
Now do as I say
Bonjour Madame
Gracias
Buenos Dias Senora
Come on we find Papa
Stay here
Papa
Where is his father?
A look this is my scene
He cut my scene
It's Mr Carson Clay
Where is he?
Where is the projectionist?
Stop
He stole my son
No he didn't
Where is my son?
Where is he?
Here
A strange thing happens when you
are making a work of art
Don't quite see the elements come together
and then when it all comes together
there is something magical, or something
organic, such a thing happened today
And everyone said this wouldn't work
They said it was a terrible risk but I wanna
keep on making films just like this
The video film combination it's something that's realy
been done before but not quite like this
I am glad the reception was so great
and I am just happy to be here
Vive La France
Bless you
Come and see what I made