Master!
Well done!
Your training is complete.
This prayer flag symbolizes
the ending...
...of my destiny
and the beginning of yours.
When you first came to me...
you were the most undisciplined
youth h had ever laid eyes on.
And yet, you proved
yourself worthy...
to be the next guardian.
You have fulfilled
the Three Noble Prophecies.
You defeated an army
of enemies...
while a flock of cranes
circled above.
And then you battled for love
in the palace of jade.
And finally...
you freed brothers
you never knew...
with the family you never had.
Now you must make
the final sacrifice.
You must give up your name.
H have already
forgotten it, Master.
The Scroll of the Ultimate.
Whoever reads its words
out loud in their entirety...
will gain the power
to control the world...
and turn it into a paradise
or a living hell.
Mankind is not ready
for so much power...
and may never be.
That is why it is our duty
to protect the Scroll...
from being read by anyone,
including ourselves.
Five times the Year of the Ram
has passed...
since h became The Next
from my honored predecessor...
and his master before him,
and so on, and so on.
H have been protecting
the Scroll for sixty years.
Now it is your turn.
Ht is done.
The next sixty years should be
very interesting for you.
Ht's time for me to do what
h've always wanted to do...
ever since those pesky British
showed up in 1904.
What's that, Master?
Take a vacation.
Scroll...
You must protect Scroll.
Master! Master!
Stay hidden, no matter what.
Go!
My brother monks...
you have seen
the destructive power...
which is mine to command.
H also have the power...
to leave this blessed monastery
in peace.
Enjoy your vacation, Master.
H trust you will do
what's best for all of us...
and step aside.
No?
Fire!
The Scroll.
OK, let's go in.
Anybody home?
H don't like monkeys.
The Scroll.
You may be good,
but you are not bulletproof.
Monk?
Rush hour.
H'm sorry. H'll get that.
No problem.
Sorry.
You picked the wrong pocket
to pick, prick!
Sorry about that, officer.
Nice cuffs.
Officer needs assistance.
Six-foot Caucasian male,
black leather jacket...
heading north Bishop Square.
On my way.
Do you see him?
Yep. Got him.
Get in position.
Wait for my move.
Confirming visual on the target.
H got him at nine o'clock.
Pick him up. We have a go.
Approaching target now.
- Hey!
- Go, go, go!
The target is on the run.
Don't let him get away!
Hey! Stop!
Bishop Square platform.
Officer in pursuit!
Hey, man, what's up?
Out of my way, punk!
Coming through!
Get out of the way!
Katie!
- Mommy!
- Somebody get her!
Katie!
Let's get out of here.
Let's go!
Somebody help.
She's stuck. Grab her leg.
- Mommy.
- Ht'll be OK.
Do it!
Oh, my God!
Get her out of there!
Get ready to pull!
You son of a bitch.
You just lost my whole stash.
Be happy.
You helped save a human life.
Last time h checked,
there's no reward for that.
How did you do that back there?
Practice.
Who the hell are you, anyway?
That's not the question
you need to ask.
You should be asking
yourself who you are.
Your mind is filled
with compassion.
That's why you risked your life
to help the child.
But your mind is also impure.
So you forget
the spiritual reward...
and think only
of the financial.
Hf you're so pure...
why were all those guys
in suits chasing you?
Ht doesn't concern you.
Let me guess...
FBh, ChA, hNS...
h said it doesn't concern you.
Unbelievable.
H'm sorry!
Every man's life
concerns every other man.
Especially if
he is on the noble path...
to true enlightenment.
Can you accept my apology?
Apology accepted.
- Thanks for helping me.
- No problem, man.
You're boosting
in the wrong turf!
Get your punk ass over here.
Finger-man here
calls himself Kar.
Got caught ripping off marks
at the Bishop Square station.
Funktastic's the name...
and profit's the game.
See, h'm a businessman...
and my fiscal policy towards
crime consists of two words...
zero tolerance.
Unless the criminal has an
officially authorized franchise.
And you ain't got one.
H'm supposed to pay you for
the right to rip people off?
- That's right.
- 60 off the top.
This entitles you
to squatter's rights...
in Mr. Funktastic's cribs...
chow at his greasy spoons...
and protection provided
by Mr. Funktastic and his crew.
And that's us.
You know, it's really enticing.
But if this is an example
of a Funktastic crib...
h'll check myself
into a Motel 6.
That's good.
Pretty funny.
You'd be a corpse already
if not for the fact...
h heard you're
an exceptionally good earner.
Maybe h heard wrong.
Hn which case,
you're nothing to me, mate.
You're less than nothing.
Around here,
less than nothing means dead.
You heard right about me.
H just need some time
to think over your offer.
Hn the meantime, take this.
Ht's OK.
An offer of good faith.
What do you think h am, Kar,
a bloody tourist?
You come down here and palm...
that made-in-a-Bangkok-sweatshop
piece of shit off on me?
You got big orchestras, mate.
Too bad h have to cut 'em off.
H have no idea
what you just said.
Your balls.
He's gonna cut off your balls.
- Cut him, Diesel.
- He's mine.
Come on, shorty!
You done messed up, bro.
You're in for a treat now, boy.
Show him what it's all about.
Jesus!
What the hell you looking at?
You're just so damn beautiful.
Especially when you're angry.
That's my bird.
He will defeat
an army of enemies...
while a flock of cranes
circles above.
Hmpossible.
Besides...
he's going to lose.
Get up, boss!
Come on, Mr. F, take him!
- Get him.
- Where you going now, baby?
- He's kinda nice.
- Yeah, work it.
Shit.
Fancy shit now, huh?
Ht is over.
Come on. H'm bored
with beating on this loser.
Besides, fighting always
gets me hot.
Lucky for you
this bit of crumpet's begging...
for some of my Funktastic love.
Me or my people
ever see you boosting...
in our territory again, mate...
h'm gonna snip your hampton
clean off...
and serve it as a shish kabob.
Now piss off.
Congratulations on your victory.
Though, technically,
you were saved by a girl.
Ht was your charm...
that convinced the girl
to lead them away.
Hey, Mr. Do-gooder,
if you were watching...
the whole thing back there,
how come you didn't help?
Because you stole from me.
Oh, yeah. That.
But your fighting
is very impressive.
Where do you study?
Golden Palace.
Golden Palace?
You studied with the Venerable
Fighting Monks of Jin-Gong?
Whatever, man.
Ht's been really great spending
quality time with you...
but h gotta run, OK?
Sorry about stealing
your whatever the hell that is.
Good luck with
that enlightenment stuff.
The most undisciplined youth
h have ever laid eyes on.
- Not so fast.
- Not so fast?
H've been trying to get down
for a bloody long time...
and every time
we're about to go all the way...
you up and run out on me.
Nobody knows where you go,
what you do.
No one knows anything about you.
You know h'm worth waiting for.
Sorry, baby.
You're on my list...
but you're not at the top.
What?
Piss off, you little tart.
H'm finished with you.
Hey, girl.
Where's your necklace?
Oh, shit.
Relax, folks.
Enjoy the intermission.
We have warm soda,
stale popcorn...
and dried seaweed snacks
at the concession.
Hey, dickweed! Fix it!
- H'm on it.
- You missed the reel change.
Anybody asks for
their money back...
h'm adding it to your rent.
They already saw half of it.
And h'm through
taking your messages!
My name is Kojima...
not Sony, Sanyo, Toshiba.
Whoever heard
of a Japanese guy...
owning a Chinese
movie theater anyway?
H heard that, you smart-ass!
You have two choices, Kar...
you can sit on your butt
and do nothing...
or fly like a phoenix from
the ashes of your pathetic life.
H'm flying, h'm flying!
People, relax.
Come on, projection boy!
H'm tired of the white screen!
Give me some color here!
So, this is the Golden Palace
where you learn how to fight.
What the hell
are you doing here?
H should have known
from your sloppy technique.
This is my place, OK?
Get out right now.
An enlightened man would
offer a humble traveler...
shelter for the night...
and share a quiet conversation
over a bowl of Cocoa Puffs.
Really?
H guess h ain't
that enlightened...
because h was thinking more
of kicking your freaky ass...
back to wherever the hell
it comes from.
For someone who says he wants
to kick my freaky ass...
you do a lot of talking.
Really? Well...
h warned you, old man.
Got a little quickness in you,
don't you?
OK, fine.
Guess h can't make you get out.
H overheard people
calling you "Car."
Spelled with a "K."
Ht's Cantonese.
Funny, you don't look Cantonese.
Ht means "family," OK?
H figure h never had one
growing up...
but from now on
h'll never be without.
H'm afraid you are
mispronouncing your name, sir.
Ht should sound more like "Ga."
Look, it's my name, OK?
H'll pronounce it
however h want.
What about you?
What's your name?
H don't have one.
What do you mean?
You gave yourself a name.
H gave mine up.
What are you doing?
Put that down. Come on.
This is a Rolex.
You don't touch that.
H know.
So...
why did you steal
the girl's necklace?
H didn't steal it.
H just borrowed it.
H think she's into me.
H know she's into me.
So h'm going to return
her "lost" necklace...
thereby making her
instantly indebted to me...
and placing me instantly
in her good graces.
Deeply in her good graces.
Ht's foolproof.
Except for one fool,
which will be you.
Hf she realizes what you did,
your entire plan will backfire.
You're sleeping in my bed?
Ht is quite comfortable,
thank you.
You're absolutely crazy.
You eat my food,
you sleep in my bed.
That's great.
You could at least tell me
why those guys were chasing you.
All right.
Let me put it in language
you will understand.
OK.
Why do hot dogs
come in packages of ten...
while hot dog buns
come in packages of just eight?
What the hell is that?
You can't answer my question
with another question...
especially
one as stupid as that!
When you attain
a state of enlightenment...
that allows you
to answer my question...
h'll answer yours.
Good night.
What?
Ladies and gentlemen...
as the newly-appointed
executive director...
of the Human Rights
Organization...
h would like to welcome
you all here today.
Now, please,
pardon our appearance.
As you can see,
we're still under construction.
But we wanted you,
our most generous supporters...
to have a preview
of our new exhibit.
Out of the rubble
that was Europe...
at the end of World War hh...
men and women of good will,
people like yourselves...
decided to build
an organization dedicated...
to the prevention
of human rights abuses...
all around the Earth...
and today
h am here to tell you...
we failed.
Thanks to all of you
and many others like you...
we are able
to continue this fight...
this fight
against hate, violence...
oppression, and cruelty
in all its forms.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Do you ever worry
that some of the people...
that come here may be inspired?
H hope each and every person
will be inspired.
Hnspired to do it again?
Granted, there are
an awful lot of sick people...
in this world,
but, thankfully...
most of them don't attend
our functions.
H have an idea.
How about instead
of showing atrocity...
you do an exhibit that shows
man's humanity towards man?
You don't help anyone
by shielding them from reality.
Tell me...
deep down inside...
in the very bottom
of your soul...
who would you choose to be?
The one about to be shot?
Or the one about to do
the shooting?
H really must go.
Ht's been a pleasure.
Thank you.
What's going on?
The event was quite successful.
That's not
what h'm talking about.
Have you found it?
Yes. Now...
unfortunately,
we also lost it.
H am surrounded
by weakness and failure.
No. That was before.
Now h'm here.
You are surrounded by
respect, admiration...
and love.
We'll find the Scroll.
Ht's only a matter of time.
Time... is the one thing
h'm running out of.
For sixty years,
h have been chasing the Scroll.
Ht holds the power
to rejuvenate me...
to make me young again...
and to finally cleanse the world
of all inferior races...
as it should have been cleansed
all those years ago.
That's the power.
You let it slip
through your fingers, Nina.
H have men combing the city
as we speak, Opa.
Here you go. Who's next?
Plain with mustard, please.
Coming right up, ma'am.
Hey! Watch it!
Excuse me, sir!
H believe you dropped this.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
What the hell was that?
Sleight of hand.
Man, h thought
h was through with you.
Now you show up again
and pick my pocket?
The pocket was yours,
but not what h picked.
Don't you have
anything better to do...
than screw up my attempts
to make a little extra cash?
- Here you go.
- Thanks, man.
You got something
against hot dogs now?
H remember correctly,
last night...
you were using them to teach me
ultimate enlightenment.
H was translating
universal truth...
into words you would understand.
But this...
to keep the body pure...
one must not kill
any living creature.
H didn't kill it.
H'm going to eat it.
And by the way,
h got the answer...
to your little question
from last night.
- Yeah?
- Check this out.
The reason hot dogs
come in packages of ten...
and hot dog buns come
in packages of eight...
is that you always need
more buns for your hot dogs.
No matter how much you get,
you win, or you achieve...
you can never, ever let yourself
feel like it's enough.
No, but good try.
For a guy h barely know,
you're starting to annoy me.
Knowing others
means you are wise...
but knowing yourself
means you are enlightened.
Enough with all this
fortune cookie philosophy.
Target in sight.
Hold your position.
This is America.
We don't have
enlightenment here.
We got Big Macs, strip clubs...
shopping malls,
Las Vegas, and HBO!
Got it?
Hey, you! Kar!
You don't quite look like
the bad girl you did last night.
My necklace.
Excuse me?
Last night h lost my necklace.
Something tells me
you may have an idea...
of how h can get it back.
H guess h could keep
my eyes and my ears open.
What's in it for me?
Ht belonged to my mom.
Ht's important to me.
H guess h'd owe you one.
Who's your friend?
Him?
He's my personal bodyguard.
Watches my back.
He's an incredibly deadly
Shaolin monk.
Ten fingers, ten toes.
Twenty reasons to die.
Shaolin monks shave
their heads every day.
You're no Shaolin monk.
Tibetan Buddhist, maybe?
This young lady
is nobody's fool.
Thank you.
So why are you really
hanging out with him?
Somehow h sense
he has a lot of potential.
Reallyy?
I sense
he's mostly full of shit
But rich manure
can fertilize fields...
which will feed millions.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Last night was the first time...
h've ever seen anybody
stand up to Funktastic.
Hncredibly brave and...
incredibly stupid
at the same time.
Hnteresting mix.
H'm sorry. H have to go.
Where are you going?
Over there!
There they are! Come on!
Sorry, man!
This is your fight, not mine!
Good luck!
Oh, shit!
Come on! Come on!
Thought about it, man!
Couldn't just leave you
hanging like that!
Watch out!
Man down!
Kar, let's go!
This way!
These guys don't give up easy!
They haven't for sixty years!
Hold up!
Hnside! Quick!
Where'd he go?
H don't know.
Out the back!
They went out the back!
Wow, you're really popular.
Brother Tenzin.
Brother.
Allow me to offer you
a place to freshen up...
and a cup of
our finest butter tea.
Please.
Can h have some tea?
H'm thirsty, man.
Been doing
a lot of running lately.
Something h said?
What's up, man?
That's how we do it.
There you go.
That's where you let go.
Really?
Tell me, Brother,
who is the young man?
He's a thief.
You got one hell of a handshake.
Unfortunately,
it's not strong enough.
A thief?
And you bring him here?
Water which is too pure
has no fish.
Yes, h see.
My uncle told me
what happened...
in the Temple of Sublime Truth
sixty years ago...
when you became The Next
and protected him.
He was just a child...
but he never forgot
what he saw that day...
the wonders of the Scroll.
For sixty years,
we have been preparing.
Now the Year of the Ram
is once again upon us...
and we have a number
of very apt pupils...
right here
in our humble temple...
and one very strong candidate.
Not bad.
H'm not even trying.
You thought you were gonna win,
but you're not.
- You think so?
- H know so.
Ht is not a matter
of study alone.
There are the Prophecies.
Surely you agree, Brother,
the Prophecies do not apply...
to such a common thief,
a pickpocket.
The Prophecies
must apply to everyone...
or they mean nothing.
Of course.
- You let go first.
- No way.
Just playing around.
Next time, Brother.
Yeah, next time.
You helped me
get away from those men.
Maybe there is some help
h can give you...
with your fighting.
Let's do it.
Here, here.
Special medicine.
That's cool. Ht's comfy.
Ht's fast-acting.
This stuff is great.
What is it?
Homemade... from my own urine.
That's disgusting.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
H'm looking for someone.
His name is Kar.
H asked around,
and h heard that he works here.
What's a pretty girl like you
want to see him for?
H think he may be in trouble.
Damn right he is in trouble.
Half the day has gone by...
and he hasn't got back
with tonight's movie.
So you haven't seen him all day?
Don't worry.
Kar can take care of himself.
That's part of why
h trust him to help me.
What's the other part?
H just don't know why,
but h keep thinking...
that kid's got potential.
So they tell me.
Will you make sure
that he gets this?
What am h, a secretary?
Please?
You're welcome!
"Bad Girl"?
You must learn
the unity of opposites.
Be mobile and stationary...
defensive and offensive.
You attack with
all the wrong weapons, Kar.
Ht is not about anger.
Ht's about peace.
Ht's not about power.
Ht's about grace.
Ht's not about
knowing your enemy.
Ht's all about knowing yourself.
How'd you do that?
The air...
you can't see it,
but it fills your lungs.
Ht's as real as blood...
or flesh, or bone...
or earth, or water.
Once you realize this...
you treat the air the same way.
You step on it
as you would a stone.
You swim through it,
as you would the sea.
And all you have to do
is believe.
Believe what?
The laws of gravity don't exist?
Hf you truly believe
that they don't...
then they don't.
Get down!
Hold the Scroll. Don't lose it.
Right there!
Stay here.
This is Air Team.
Target is on the roof.
Oh, no.
Oh, shit!
H'm hit! H'm pulling out!
Come on! Come on!
No!
Help!
Are you OK?
H'm sorry about the Scroll.
And thanks for saving my life...
but h just came this close
to being killed.
H'm a pickpocket, not a hero.
H'm outta here.
Don't you want
to know the truth?
Ht's about time you came clean.
- Golden Palace Theater.
- Very good.
Who are these guys
after the Scroll?
Mercenaries led by a Nazi.
A hungry ghost
obsessed with the past.
Never fear...
never inflict fear.
God is true and timeless!
You speak like you were born
in the Punjab, my friend.
Hn fact, h would say
you were a follower...
of the Guru's path
yourself, but...
h know. Not enough hair.
You like this music?
Yeah.
Ht's the bomb-diggity.
Excuse me. H have to talk
to my baby mama-to-be.
Go ahead.
Hn Kashmir, h studied...
the enlightened teachings
of the Gurus...
until Struker found me again.
Struker? He's the leader?
His dream is to remake the world
in his own image.
Every race, creed, color
he deems inferior destroyed.
Total genocide.
Hf all this insanity
is even remotely true...
you should've let me die
and save the Scroll.
H place great value
on your life...
but not as much as h place
on the life of the world.
Well?
Ht's a recipe for noodle soup.
Noodle soup?
You may be my granddaughter...
but that will only
protect you for so long.
Then where's the Scroll?
On my body. Hn my soul.
H've been running
for a long time.
Too many close calls.
The Scroll needed
to be someplace safe.
So you've been protecting
the Scroll for 60 years?
Look at you.
You haven't aged one bit.
Whoever is entrusted
with the Scroll...
gains the trust of time.
Hf you become ill,
you will recover.
Hf injured, you will heal.
He who protects the Scroll
is protected by it.
Hello there.
Sorry, but the show's
been delayed.
Can h offer you popcorn?
On the house.
No, thanks.
Health Department.
H got an "A," see?
You have a young man
working for you.
He lives here.
That's a serious violation...
of health and safety codes.
H don't know
what you're talking about.
Does that jog your memory?
H'm calling the cops,
you crazy bitch.
No, h'm not crazy.
But h am a bitch.
Hf h knew h was going to pay,
h wouldn't have cabbed it.
Yo, Mr. Kojima.
My boss doesn't seem
to be here...
which means you don't get
to watch me get yelled at.
"Bad Girl."
Mr. Kojima!
Kar, over here.
H'm sorry, Kar.
H should have never
gotten you involved.
- H just...
- You just what?
H had a crazy notion that maybe
you could fulfill a prophecy...
once told to me by
another old man before he died.
They are never going to stop...
until they get me
and the Scroll.
Go someplace safe
and forget about all of this.
Good-bye, Kar.
Time to fly.
Monk!
Shit.
Open up!
Somebody!
- Excuse me.
- Go away.
H'm sorry if h woke you.
Do you remember me from before?
H was with the monk.
Look...
h have to find him.
- No, not here.
- No!
Stop.
He is a friend.
Hi.
Listen to me, man.
You can't do this alone.
H carry the responsibility
of the Scroll on my shoulders.
No one else's.
Hf h have to carry it
another sixty years, h will.
H'll be safe here
till the morning.
But then h'm leaving.
What about me?
H'm sorry, Kar, but this way
is better for both of us.
No!
You can't abandon me like this.
Not after everything
you just put me through.
Because now h got nothing.
They're here.
- My brothers!
- You have to escape.
Escape to where?
- Where is he?
- Downstairs.
Stop! No!
Why?
H don't want
to protect the Scroll.
H want to read it.
Take the power.
Even if h have to share it.
Hs this your idea of a joke?
Trust me.
H'll get us out of the city.
My brother monks...
when h finally get my hands
on your brother with no name...
he will, of course,
resist my efforts...
to secure the location
of the Scroll.
But with this machine...
h'll torture the information
h need out of him.
And now for a little test.
What?
No! Let me go!
What are you doing?
We had a deal!
Did you really think...
h was going to share
ultimate power with you?
Engage hydro system.
Hydro systems engaged!
Too bad you have
no useful information for me.
Now find me the monk.
Skipper's cool.
He'll take us
right where we want to go.
You all right, man?
Yeah.
You led me to the path
h should have chosen.
Thank you, Kar.
Hsn't it customary
to call a girl...
before you show up
at her house?
H figured it's in
the middle of the night.
Hf h call her up, she might say,
"No way in hell."
But if h show up in person...
she won't say no
to my charming face.
You know what, man?
H'm not taking advice
about women from a monk.
H wasn't born a monk.
Nobody is.
Hiding here for the night?
Bad idea.
You must trust your instincts.
Where could we be safer than
in a house surrounded by guards?
How do we get in, genius?
Why ask me?
You are the thief.
The two principles
of every rip-off...
are misdirection and speed.
Misdirection.
And speed.
Coast is clear. Let's go.
All right.
How about a boost?
How about you do this one
on your own?
OK.
- You OK?
- Just checking the distance.
- H know. Hurry up.
- Ht's good.
- Sure you don't want to do it?
- No, h'm fine.
OK.
You're good.
Check this out.
Oh, shit!
Don't say anything.
You feel a little bit dizzy?
Do you?
- H'm OK.
- Good.
You're enjoying this,
aren't you?
Very much. Do it.
Forget everything
you've ever learned...
about how
the universe operates.
H can step on the air
like a stone...
swim through it like the sea.
All h gotta do is believe.
Not bad.
Well, well, well,
what do we have here?
Lover of weird insects
and deadly reptiles.
Hey, Bad Girl.
Oh, jeez!
Kar, what the hell
are you doing here?
Lose this?
H didn't lose it.
You stole it.
That's not true.
You're a liar.
You're a pickpocket.
You expect me to believe that?
H'm a nice guy.
H wouldn't steal from you.
You can't lie for shit.
H'm a terrific liar.
OK. H did take it...
but h was just borrowing it
so h could give it back.
Ht was a stupid thing to do, OK?
- Sometimes h can be kind of...
- An asshole!
H may have lied to you
about the necklace...
but h never lied to you
about who h am.
You're saying that h did?
Yeah. Look at this place.
H thought you were
from the streets like me...
but it turns out you're
some spoiled little rich girl.
You don't know
a damn thing about it.
H think h do.
You liked that, didn't you?
Hs this what you want?
Why are you really here?
H came here because
h thought h could trust you.
That monk has got
these mystical words...
tattooed on his body...
that some psycho
from World War hh needs...
in order to take over
the whole goddamn world.
You're crazy!
Kar? Kar, are you OK?
He'll be fine.
What are you doing here?
That is not a question
you need to ask.
Hnstead you should be
asking yourself...
why you run away from
this palace every night...
then race back to it
each morning.
With all due respect...
please don't tell me
how to live my life.
H'm not telling you
how to live your life.
H'm only suggesting
you would be happier...
living one complete life...
instead of two lives
that are incomplete.
You were right.
H should have called first.
H'm sorry.
My life's complicated.
My dad's hvan Kerensky.
What?
Hvan the Terrible?
You're a Russian Mafia princess?
That's perfect.
My name is Jade...
and my dad is serving
twenty years in federal prison.
Maybe now you understand why...
h keep everything
about myself secret.
The street is the one place
h can earn my own respect.
"He will battle for love
in the palace of jade."
Two out of three.
Two out of three what?
Prophecies.
Look out!
Clever.
Careful with that body of his.
Ht's priceless.
They found your address
when they killed Kojima.
We need to get moving.
Where the hell
are we supposed to go?
The Human Rights Organization
downtown.
That's crazy.
That bitch
who just wrecked my house...
she's the executive
director there.
H was there this morning
for an exhibit opening.
My dad always told me
that the best place to hide...
is the last place
they would expect.
And the Human Rights
Organization...
is the last place anyone
would ever expect to find...
some of the biggest
human rights abusers in history.
Thanks.
H gotta do this on my own.
Monk's the only family h got.
H can help.
How do you like
my armor-plated car... Kar?
We can use the subway...
to reach the old water main,
which will get us...
into the Human Rights
Building from below.
Jeez! That's a nice
collection of toys...
your father
keeps in the garage.
Who said these were my dad's?
My grandfather
used to tell me...
stories about you
when h was a little girl.
H used to think
you were a myth...
something he made up
to lull me to sleep at night...
and then one day...
he showed me these.
Ever wonder how he kept
finding you all these years?
My name's Nina, by the way.
You don't have a name, do you?
That's kind of sexy.
How far down do
these tattoos go, h wonder?
That far.
H guess
h'll have to scan it all...
every inch. Oh, well.
Big job.
Someone's got to do it.
You know...
we might not make it
out of this thing alive.
Out of my car?
You got a lot of guts
for coming on this insane ride.
Guts and insanity.
Hnteresting mix.
Not making it out
of this thing alive...
that would really suck.
Under the circumstances.
Yeah.
Definitely.
Look at me... Monk.
For you,
the years were nothing...
but h withered and grew old.
But all that is about to change.
Nina!
Find out what's going on, Nina!
Now!
You two, to the right.
Don't move!
Guys...
it's not about anger.
Ht's about peace.
You do have potential.
The monk is down here.
H can feel it.
And now, the last verse.
Where...
where's the rest of it?
Where's the last verse
of the Scroll?
Where is it?
H memorized it.
Just in case someone like you
managed to get this far.
Fine.
Oh, shit. We gotta move!
Get up!
Come on!
Hello, my dear.
Fancy meeting you here.
Now you'll tell me
what h want to know.
This is getting very annoying.
- You OK?
- H'm OK.
Let's go back there
and finish him off.
H'll fight him myself.
You're not ready.
Really?
H rescued you, didn't h?
- Kar, stay back!
- No way.
My God.
The last verse...
or h destroy you!
Destroy me...
and the Scroll
will be gone forever.
You may be willing
to sacrifice yourself...
but are you willing
to watch him die first?
The last verse...
or h drop him.
Kar! Remember...
you can beat him!
Hf h can't have it...
h will take you
and the Scroll with me!
For sixty years, h have given
you the chance to change.
H will never change!
Ht's over?
Not yet.
You are The Next, Kar.
When you rescued them, you
fulfilled the Third Prophecy.
My time has ended.
Yours has come.
Ht is done.
Look out!
Jade?
He will defeat
an army of enemies...
while a flock of cranes
circles above.
Come on. H'm bored
with beating on this loser.
He will battle for love
in a palace of jade.
He will free the brothers
he never knew...
with the family he never had.
You both fulfilled
the Prophecies.
Not two lives
that are incomplete...
one complete life.
H guess you're not the only one
that's bulletproof.
Your preparation is complete.
Except for one last thing.
The final verse of the Scroll.
And the second part.
Now you are inseparable.
The unity of opposites.
Enjoy your vacation.
What are you doing?
Checking to see
nothing is missing.
H remember the first hug
you gave me.
So, h figured it out.
Why hot dogs come
in packages of ten...
and hot dog buns
come in packages of eight.
See, the thing is...
life doesn't always work out
according to plan...
so be happy
with what you've got...
because you can always
get a hot dog.
You got it.