(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL CLAMOURING)
MAN: Gentlemen, we are in danger.
There is a storm coming.
My men are terrified.
We must leave.
ROBERT: That tomb is here somewhere.
I can feel it.
Please, Robert,
it's been two months!
Archie,
I'm not stopping!
CECIL: Dad!
What's going on
with this wind, Pop?
C.J, go wait in the truck.
I don't want to
just wait in the truck.
I said go! Windows up!
(SIGHS)
Robert!
MAN: Mr. Fredericks!
What?
(WIND HOWLING)
Ah!
(COUGHS)
Help!
ROBERT: C.J?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine!
I'm coming down!
Yes!
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I looked for the tomb
ofAhkmenrah for 20 years,
and what do you do?
You fall right into it!
Amir, start loading
the trucks.
Mr. Fredericks...
there is no time.
The storm is almost upon us.
Then you'd better hurry.
Come on.
Everybody works.
(AMIR SPEAKING IN ARABIC)
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(SCREAMING)
Hey! What's the matter
with you? Huh?
(SPEAKING IN ARABIC)
He said, "We must leave
this place immediately.
(MAN CONTINUES IN ARABIC)
'Wfanyone
disturbs this tomb...
(MAN CONTINUES IN ARABIC)
"the end will come."
(REPEATS IN ARABIC)
"The end will come."
We load the trucks.
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(MEN CLAMOURING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
I can't help feeling we're
making a terrible mistake!
We're not making a mistake,
we're making history!
Don't worry!
C.J! Let's go!
"The end will come."
(HAMMER POUNDING)
WOMAN: Welcome, everyone,
to the Grand Reopening...
of the newly renovated
Hayden Planetarium...
here at the Museum
of Natural History.
New York's glitterati
have all turned out...
for what has promised to be
a memorable evening...
filled with the dazzling
special effects...
and technical wizardry we've all
come to admire from this museum...
and its renowned
Night Program.
Tonight gonna be fun-fun!
Here come Dum Dum!
Hey, how we doing, Sac?
Rexy is waxed and buffed.
Teddy is grooming
his moustache.
Oh, and I reviewed fire safety
procedures with the primordial men.
By the way, have you
seen them lately?
The museum has
added a new one.
LARRY: What? No.
Oh, and make sure the
centurions stretch, all right?
They really went for it
in the dress rehearsal...
and they're just not used to
those kinds of dance moves.
Okay, everybody.
Everybody, listen up.
I don't want to make
anybody nervous...
but the mayor and the
governor are both out there.
And, uh,
I'm not 100 percent sure,
but I think
Regis Philbin, too.
(GASPS) Reeju Philbo?
Yeah, Reeju Philbo.
Okay, Rexy, do me a favor.
(GRUNTS)
Watch the tail, okay?
There's gonna be open flame.
Oh, Dexter...
how you doing, my man?
All limbered up?
Looking good.
I like the tie.
Got kind of a Chippendales
thing going on.
All chalked up, ready to go?
(CHATTERS)
Good. Okay, everybody relax
and have fun, okay?
AH KMENRAH:
Larry.
You better come see this.
(CONTINUES CHATTERING)
Have you ever seen
it like this before?
Never
AHKMENRAH: This corrosion
has never happened before.
It's always been
exactly the same.
I wonder
what's up with it.
I have no idea.
And to be honest...
my father knew the secrets of
the tablet better than I did.
Unfortunately, he swore
he'd never reveal them.
He never did.
(GASPS)
Whoa!
You Okay?
Yes.
Yes, I'm fine.
Just take it easy out
there tonight, all right?
You got 15 minutes
till showtime.
We're gonna figure
this out tomorrow.
All right.
(OCTAVIUS LAUGHING)
JEDEDIAHI Look at that!
Doggoneiﬂ
(CATS MEWING) OCTAVIUS:
Did you see that?
They're trying
to catch the light.
But you can't do it, boys!
You can't catch light!
It's as elusive
as human happiness!
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
I should like
to comment.
Summon the apparatus.
Yeah.
Summon the apparatus!
What are you gonna say?
L...
O...
L-
(KEY POUNDING)
"Laugh out loud."
Yeah, that's what I did.
Now, post these
adorable kittens
with my edict of
approval to Facebook.
Give a big Texas "hell
yeah" from old Jedediah...
because I loved it too!
Just send a smiley face.
Yeah, but with a wink!
A smiley face and a wink!
(KEYS POUNDING)
Guys, what are you doing?
We're just
watching kittens.
You're on in five minutes.
You got to focus, here.
I told you we don't
have time for this!
You gave it a Texas
"hell yeah!"
Hey, Teddy,
ready to roll?
Indeed, Lawrence.
Great.
Battle of San Juan Hill...
cool as a cucumber.
Right now, butterflies like
you wouldn't believe.
You're gonna be great.
Lawrence?
Yeah.
Have you seen
the Neanderthals lately?
No. Why does everybody
keep talking about this?
You may want to
give it a look!
(MAMMOTH BELLOWING)
(NEANDERTHALS GRUNTING)
Hey, guys,
what's going on?
(GRUNTING EXCITEDLY)
ALL: Ooh!
Okay-
All right, very funny.
That's hilarious.
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
You don't have
to come down.
It's okay, really.
Hi, how are you?
I'm Larry.
I'm Laaa--
You're "Laaa"?
Laaa.
Laaa. Okay,
nice to meet you, Laaa.
Welcome aboard, and--
Yes, we look similar.
Yeah, we look like
each other, I know.
It's a joke that
somebody played.
Dr. McPhee had you made
to look like me.
It's just a--
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(YELPS)
Stop it. Stop, okay?
Dada?
What?
Dada.
No, not your Dada.
Yeah, Dada.
No. Stop.
Dada.
Dada!
ALL:Dada!
No, I'm not his--
I'm not your Dada.
Dum Dum got a new son-son!
(GRUNTING)
No, he doesn't.
Dada!
ALL: Dada!
DR. McPHEE: A toast to
our new chairwoman.
Cheers, everyone. Cheers.
Cue the music.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
And Teddy in three,
two--
(APPLAUSE)
Since 1869, when I was
a mere boy of 11...
this museum has been a shining
beacon to our great city.
Tonight we'll expand
our horizons even further...
to the Sun...
the Moon, and the stars.
(MOUTHING)
From our very beginning...
mankind has looked
to the heavens
and given names
to what he saw.
The constellations.
I thought you might
like to meet them.
(WHISPERS)
Cue the constellations.
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
Wow.
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
Orion, the hunter!
(GASPING CONTINUES)
(CHUCKLES)
What?
(YELPS)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
All planned.
I knew that was gonna happen.
So,yeah.
Good. Going great, guys.
Going great.
Let's drop the silks.
And go with the monkey.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
What?
(CHUCKLES)
(CHATTERING)
Come on.
(GRUNTS)
(AUDIENCE GASPS AND CHEERS)
(CONTINUES CHATTERING)
That's what I do.
TEDDY: Thank you
for your patronage...
and for your unwavering support
of this fine institution.
This newly renovated planetarium
will serve as a lens...
(LAUGHING)
(JABBERING INCOHERENTLY)
"Once more unto the breach,
dear friends!"
What?
(JABBERING CONTINUES)
(SCREECHING)
Charge!
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Rough Riders!
It's okay! Just hang on!
Is this part of it?
LARRY: Sorry folks,
a little technical issue.
What are you doing?
Stick to the script. Stick
to the script! Huh?
It's me!
I don't know you.
(ATTILA SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(AUDIENCE SCREAMING)
JEDEDIAHI Pull!
I don't know what's come
over me, but I like it!
Drop 'em!
(SCREAMING)
Ha-ha!
Yeah! Yeah!
(SHOUTING ANGRILY)
What's going on?
Do something!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING EXCITEDLY)
ALL: on!
(CHATTERING)
What are you doing?
Ah!
(GROANING)
(CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
LARRY: Orion, don't!
(LAUGHS)
(ALL CLAMOURING)
(REXY ROARS)
Rexy!
(ROARS)
Guys, what was going
on out there?
(LAAA GRUNTING INCOHERENTLY)
Seriously, what were you thinking?
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
Laaa, I got this,
all right?
Just“
Go over there.
No, go over there.
Go.
Attila...
what were you doing
to that dolphin, man?
It's a dolphin!
It's one of the most peaceful
creatures on earth...
and you're hacking into it like
it was The Cove or something.
Did you see the look
on Regis Philbin's face?
Ream'?
Yeah, Reeju.
Teddy, what were you doing
pointing a gun at me?
Forgive me, Lawrence. I don't
know what came over me.
Do you even remember that?
Not at all.
(MACHINE POWERING UP)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(LAAA GRUNTING)
Laaa, shut that down!
It's a defibrillator.
Put it down.
It's dangerous!
Laaa, that's electricity.
Those aren't headphones.
Stop it!
Oh! Hey! Whoa! Dexter!
What are you doing?
(CHATTERS)
LARRY: Huh?
Honestly, if you're
gonna act like a baby,
then I'll get
you some diapers.
You want diapers again? Huh?
(CHATTERS)
JEDEDIAH: Whoa! Whoa!
Ease up on
the rems there, hose.
Can't you see?
He feels terrible!
Hell, we all do!
LARRY: I don't know what's going
on with everybody here...
but tonight was really weird.
Really weird.
OCTAVIUS:
We feel awful.
Something took hold of us
like an evil spell!
JEDEDIAH: Yeah, like we
just weren't ourselves.
(GRUNTING)
(MOBILE RINGING)
LARRY: Hello?
DR. McPHEE: Larry.
Hey, Dr. McPhee.
Yeah, hi.
How's it going?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Uh, okay.
Good,good,good,
good,good,good.
You know that sound of when
you're hiding in a trash bin...
fearing for your life because a Tyrannosaurus
rex is using it as a Hacky Sack?
No. I don't know
thatsound.
You don't know that sound?
Oh, hold on one second.
That's the sound! That's the sound!
It will haunt my dreams!
I'm sorry.
Look, really, I'm sorry.
I swear to you, I had no idea
this was going to happen.
"I had no idea it
was gonna happen.
"I'm only in charge of
all the special effects."
It was your fault! They
were your special effects!
(STAMMERING) No, I know.
That's a joke.
"Special effects"?
More like "special. ..
"Defects!"
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
Look, I promise you, I'm gonna
find out what happened.
Or they were "special rejects!"
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm sorry, Dr. McPhee.
I gotta go.
(LAUGHING AND WHOOPING)
(MUSIC BLARING)
Hey!
Nicky! Nicky!
Stop hQPPinQI
(MUSIC STOPS)
Dad, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
It's 3300 AM.
All right, party's over!
Hey- Hey'
Who are you?
I'm Sophie.
Sophie?
Bye Bye Birdie?
Right.
It was good.
Thanks.
Yeah.
See you tomorrow night?
Probably not.
Probably.
Definitely not.
Bye.
You're in so much trouble.
I know.
I didn't really know
you were coming home early.
Yeah, that's pretty obvious.
Imean...
what makes you think
this is okay?
When I'm not at Mom's you leave
me alone, like, every night.
Look, you can't be
doing this right now.
You got finals, your NYU application
is due in what, two weeks?
I'm not gonna
get into NYU.
You don't know that.
No, I do.
I do very much know that, in the
sense that I don't intend to apply.
What?
I don't think that it's the
place for me right now, Dad.
Okay. All right, fine. You want
to spread your wings a little...
get out of the city,
go to school somewhere else.
I totally support that. All
you had to do was tell me.
Where do you want to go?
What's the list?
It's a short list.
Great. I like it. Focus.
L'mma hit you with a super
short list, man, becauseifs“.
There's nothing on it.
(SIGHS)
There's...
I'm confused, because
there's not a list--
Dad?
Mmm-hmm?
I want to take a year off.
I would like to do
exactly what you just said.
I want to spread my wings.
You want to spread your
wings, that's great.
But you can't spread your
wings and fly to nowhere.
Plans change.
No, they don't.
Plans don't change.
We had a plan,
itchanged.
It's disorienting at first.
No.
You can't change the plan...
unless you check with the people
who are financing the plan...
which is,
last time I checked,
your mother and I. Okay?
Dad, we could sit here and just have
this conversation about plans...
but for now,
let's call it a night.
Let's not even
clean up, right?
Let's come back tomorrow.
Let's reboot
the whole energy,
the whole tone
of this puppy...
and we'll kill it, man.
Team Daley!
Not tonight, tomorrow.
Hey, Team Daley?
Yeah?
Stop talking.
Okay-
You're gonna clean up.
I'm gonna go to bed.
And then we're gonna finish
this conversation tomorrow.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Yeah! Get some!
Get some!
That's it. Yeah.
Hi.
I'm Larry Daley. I'm head
of the Night Program.
I know who you are.
You're the security guard.
Yeah, also head of
the Night Program.
I'm doing some research...
and I was wondering
if you could help me out.
Mmm. Night guard
doing research.
Ooh la-la!
Yeah.
Uh, I'm just
looking for anything
that you might have on
the tablet ofAhkmenrah.
Center aisle.
Great. Halfway down,
stacks on your left.
(GROANS)
Get it!
So...
what makes you so curious
about the tablet?
Oh! Just, uh...
Just a hobby, you know?
Kind of an interest of mine.
I wish I could
talk to these guys.
Well, you can't.
Yeah.
Because they're dead.
Right.
But, uh, look at that one.
Looks like a kid, huh?
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
You didn't know him,
did you?
C.J Fredericks.
He worked here.
He worked here?
Yeah, when he grew up.
No.
Yeah.
He was a night guard.
Same as you.
Wait a minute. C.J.
C.J Fredericks.
Cecil Fredericks?
Sexiest night guard
we ever had.
Present company included.
Boy, could that man move.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Larry?
Hey, Cecil.
My God, it's been years!
You look like
you're doing pretty good.
I've still got it, pal.
What are you doing here?
I need to talk to you
about the tablet.
What the heck is
Short Stack doing here?
Hey, Gus.
You're looking well.
Reginald.
Are you here to
frame us again?
Send us back
to the slammer?
I didn't frame you.
You were actually stealing.
And I was the one that got
you out of jail, so...
Yeah.
We've got a nice life here.
The past is the past.
We've moved on.
I don't think
this guy's moved on.
Listen to him,
monkey face.
REGINALD: We've put all that
tablet stuff behind us, Larry.
It's old news.
Besides, we really never knew
anything about that old tablet.
We just worked there.
Something's up with it.
I told you,
I can't help you.
Maybe this kid can.
Maybe we'd better talk alone.
CECIL: Expedition like that
is a pretty amazing thing...
for a 12-year-old boy.
I tried to move on...
but there was something
about that tablet.
It's turning green,
like some sort of corrosion.
And something's happening
to Teddy and Dexter...
Jed and Octavius.
They're all acting weird.
It's like the green rust
is affecting them.
"The end will come."
What?
The locals, they warned us.
They begged us to
leave that tomb alone.
I thought it meant
the end of the world.
But maybe it meant
the end...
End of the magic?
We should have listened.
Should have listened.
Instead, we shipped Ahk and
the tablet off to New York...
and his folks
to England.
Wait. Wait.
Ahkmenrah's parents
are in England?
It was a joint expedition.
Some of the artifacts
stayed in Egypt.
The rest was divided up between
New York and the British Museum.
Ahk said that his father knew
the secrets of the tablet.
I think I have
to go talk to him.
I need you to listen to me.
Uh...
Our esteemed chairwoman
asked for my resignation.
She said, since the Night
Program was my brainchild...
that the buck starts
and stops with me.
I can fix it.
How?
I need you to let me take the
tablet and Ahkmenrah to London.
Sorry.
I'm just processing that.
(IMITATING
ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
(ROBOTIC VOICE)
Input data analysis.
(NORMAL VOICE) I've just
told you I'm being fired,
and the first thing
you ask...
is if I'd allow you to take
some priceless artifacts...
away with you on holiday.
Yes. Please.
No way, Jose.
I'm asking you to please
go with me on this.
Nah.
Please.
Can't do it, dude.
Bye.
Are you gonna mug me?
What?
I don't know.
Just be prepared.
I need you to listen to me. Oh.
Okay?
Yep.
You want to know the truth?
Go on.
Truth is, the tablet...
The tablet is actually magic.
Things really do
come to life at night.
It's special effects.
It's not special effects.
How could it be
special effects?
How could it not
be special effects?
Because it isn't!
Of course it is!
I'm telling you, this
is what happens. What?
Sun goes down...
the tablet starts to glow...
everything comes to life.
Sure.
It's real.
"Tablet starts to glow."
Now I know
you're mental.
Look,LesHe“.
(YELPS)
Listen to me.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I know. Just...
What?
Listen, nobody cares about this
place as much as we do, right?
Yeah.
If you don't help me...
everything that's special
about it might stop...
and it may never come back.
I'm not asking you
to understand,
I'm just asking you
to trust me.
I'd like to help you...
but I don't even
work here anymore.
British Museum
doesn't know that.
The mummy and the tablet,
both.
Classic conservation job...
under authority
of me, of course...
the director of this museum,
which I still am.
Yep, okay.
You're in.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
I really could have just
stayed by myself in New York.
Yeah. No,
that wasn't gonna happen.
Beautiful, huh?
Yeah.
The River Thames.
Isn't this cool, man,
you and me in London?
Huh?
Yeah.
Hey, I've been thinking
about that, uh, year off.
Yeah?
I think it could be cool.
Yeah.
What are you thinking?
Yeah. Uh... Wow.
I think I want
to DJ in Ibiza.
In Ibiza?
Ibiza, it's a small island
off the coast of Spain.
Do you speak Spanish?
No.
But that's the beautiful thing.
It's about the music.
It's not inhibited
by the language barrier.
No, but you are.
Do you speak in beats?
Why are you freaking out?
You just said this was
a really cool idea.
I'm not freaking out.
I just want to understand
what the plan is.
You didn't go to college.
Wait, now we're talking about
not going to college at all?
Maybe. I don't know.
Nicky.
Nicky. That's not--
Dad, you didn't go to college.
You turned out fine.
I turned out okay after about
20 years in a lot of dead ends.
Whatever, man.
Don't worry about me.
It's fine.
Hey, I'm always
gonna worry about you.
I'm your dad.
Thanks.
Sun is going down.
We should get going.
All right.
NICK: Dad, what's the
plan here, anyway?
LARRY: When the tablet brings Ahkmenrah
to life, he's gonna sneak us in.
Now, get down.
What?
LARRY: Just get down! Come on, man.
Part of the adventure.
Hello. Welcome to
the British Museum.
My name's Tilly.
Hi. Thank you.
I'm Larry Daley from
Natural History, New York.
Yeah, yeah.
I got a delivery...
for your
conservation department.
All right!
So they let you travel?
This is kind of unusual.
Well, they let me travel.
You know where?
No.
Home. Here. Home.
Back here.
Off to the toot-toot.
Five-minute maximum.
(SCOFFS)
(FORCED CHUCKLE)
So that must be well wicked being
a security guard in America.
Uh... With your gun,
with a silencer,
with your ninja swords.
Right.
(IMITATING BLADES WHOOSHING)
That's not even
a little bit true.
The only thing
that I got is this.
Oh.
Hammer! It's for...
and I quote, "minor repairs
and beautifications"
to the shack.
Oh...
You just hit things?
Yeah, that's catchy.
Basically worthless.
I can't believe we're
actually still talking.
It's great, though, innit?
It is.
This is the most
conversation I've had
in the three years
that I've worked here.
I feel a connection, too.
Is it cool if
I just make my drop?
Oh, yeah.
Wonderful.
But I will have to confirm.
Actually,
that's not necessary...
because they've already confirmed
it on the slip I gave you.
Yeah, all right.
Confirming.
Okay.
TILLY: All right.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(LINE RINGING)
DR. MCPHEE: Hello.
This is Dr. McPhee.
It's the British Museum, sir.
I'm just confirming a delivery
to our conservation department.
Yes, I signed
the paperwork.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a museum to run.
You, boy, get those grubby
fingers off my Ming vase.
See? Bye.
All right.
Good?
All right, you is legit.
I is legit.
Wonderful.
Confirm it.
Thank you. All right,
I'll open the gate.
Okay-
TILLY: Yeah, so, like,
my boyfriend...
he doesn't really like
the way I do my hair.
Says it looks like a golden
poo sitting on my shoulder.
But I really enjoy it.
Mmm-hmm.
BYE, Larry!
(SNORING)
I'm not an expert...
but this is feeling, just,
really against the law.
No, they have a totally
different legal system here.
Okay-
How we doing?
All clear.
All right, let's go.
Larry, the others felt, perhaps,
we could use some help.
The others?
Lawrence,
I couldn't sit idly by.
Our very survival
is at stake.
All right.
Hey, Teddy. Good.
Good man to have
in a crisis.
Attila.
Okay, a little muscle.
SACAJAWEA:
H I, Larry.
That is a deceptively
large box.
Obviously, we came along, too!
You know you'd be lost
without us, Gigantor.
Are you serious?
(CHATTERING)
And the monkey. All right,
basically everyone.
Dada!
Oh! No, no.
No possible
benefit whatsoever.
He really wanted to come.
(LARRY SIGHS)
Yeah, this is my son...
my actual son, Nicky.
Nicky, this is Laaa.
What's up?
(GRUNTS)
He's just tracking me.
(IMITATING MOCKINGLY)
Laaa.
(GRUNTS)
TEDDY:
So, Lawrence...
what's the plan of attack?
We need to get to the Egyptian
wing, find Ahk's father...
and hopefully get the tablet fixed.
Huh?
(GIGGLING)
LARRY: All of us.
Laaa, that's not for eating.
That's not food.
Don't--
You know what?
I got a job for you.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
I want you to stay here
and watch this door, okay?
Make sure nobody
comes in or out. Okay?
Good. You're gonna be a
guard, just like me.
All right.
(GRUNTING EXCITEDLY)
No. Come here.
Stay here...
and put your hands
on the door.
Good, stay.
Stay!
Good. That's right.
You stay here.
Stay here.
Stay. Right.
No. Stay.
Stay!
Stay_
Look there. Good. Stay.
No. Good. Stay.
No. Stay.
Stay!
Don't-- Don't move.
Don't move.
No. Good. Okay.
Okay, listen up, guys.
This place is waking up
for the first time...
and we have no idea what's out
there, so stay together, all right?
(ATTILA SPEAKING
IN LOCAL DIALECT)
LARRY: I know
it's spooky, big guy.
Just stay close.
(DEXTER CHATTERING)
JEDEDIAH: What kind of haunted
hootenanny is this, boys?
We're all finding this
super creepy, right?
LARRY: They're just
a little freaked out.
First time we came alive
it took some getting used to.
Hey, there.
Just heading to Egypt.
Come on. This way.
(ANIMALS GRUNTING)
(LOUD THUDDING)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
Hear that?
Hear what?
That.
(GROWLING)
(WHISPERING) We'll just be
down here if anyone needs us.
We're not scared.
It's just more comfortable.
TEDDY: Lawrence...
I think it's safe to say that
we're in a bit of trouble.
I know how
to handle this guy.
You mind?
(SNORTING)
Thanks.
What are you doing?
How do you think
I tamed your pal Rexy?
Hi, there.
I bet you're not so mean, are you?
Huh?
I bet you're not so mean.
No, you're just
a little puppy, right?
You're just a little puppy
who wants to play.
You want to play, huh?
Want to play fetch?
Yeah?
You want to play
with this bone?
Ah! Yeah!
(WHINING EXCITEDLY)
Here you go. Go fetch.
Go fetch!
(GAGGING)
Lawrence?
Yeah?
May I suggest a different plan?
What?
(ROARING)
Run!
(ALL PANTING)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
Close it, close it!
Okay. I think we're--
(GROANING)
Get back!
Everybody, get back!
All right.
You don't want to fetch?
Fetch on this.
What?
(SHOUTING)
Oh! Oh!Ah!
Oh, that's close!
Need some help?
What?
Move.
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHS)
(ATTILA SHOUTING
IN LOCAL DIALECT)
Whoa!
(G ROAN S)
Attila, you okay?
Whoa.
Oh!
(GASPS)
(KNIGHT LAUGHING)
You might want to--
No.
Here...
hold this.
(G ROANS)
(WHINING)
That was actually very cool.
Sir Lancelot,
at your service.
Thank you.
That was amazing.
TEDDY: Theodore Roosevelt...
President of the United
States of America.
I have no idea
what that means.
I'm Larry,
and this is my son, Nick.
You have
a noble face, Nick.
Thanks.
Thanks for the help.
Now, you...
You remind me of a man
I once knew at Camelot.
Really?
One of the Knights
of the Round Table?
No, Erik.
Erik?
Our fool.
He was the funniest fool
I ever met.
He was so good, he didn't
even have to do anything.
He could just walk into
a room and you'd laugh.
Hmm.
(CHUCKLES)
You have what he had. The gift.
That's weird.
You could be a fool.
I don't know about that.
Oh, come on,
of course you could!
We'd get you one of those hats with
the funny little dangly bells.
Dangly bells?
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLING)
Hmm?
"Dangly bells."
Didn't I tell you?
The gift.
He does what
seems like nothing.
A sort of deadpan...
tiny little--
"Hmm." "Hmm."
Expressionless,
you know, sort of a...
"Hmm. Hmm."
sort of thing.
Just like Erik.
Sounds like a great guy.
We got to get going, so...
Ah, Camelot.
Okay-
Someday, I shall return
to its mighty towers...
to King Arthur...
and Queen Guinevere.
Sweet...
beauteous Guinevere.
But I'm sworn not to until
I have completed my quest.
I must find the Holy Grail.
Well, good luck with that.
And thanks for
the help again.
We got to get to Egypt,
so we'll see you.
I will lead you.
No, it's okay.
Halt, Dangly Bells!
There is strange
magic in the air,
and dangerous
beasts are afoot.
It is the duty of
a true knight...
to protect and care
for those in need.
We're off.
I guess
he's coming with us.
Larry!
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL DIALECT)
Jed and Octavius?
(CONTINUES)
They must have fallen out
while we were running.
Jed?
Octavius!
Jedediah!
Jed!
Octo!
LARRY: Oh, no.
NICK: Is that Octavius's cape?
Here.
Nicky.
Yeah.
Guys?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Gigantor!
Jed?
They won't last long in those
heating vents, Lawrence.
At their size, they'll bake like
tiny little scarabs in the Sinai.
Too dark?
Ah!
(WIND HOWLING)
(SOFT WHIRRING)
(SCREAMING LOUDLY)
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
This is the end, boy!
This is the last roundup!
Hold my hand!
Why?
Never mind.
(BEEPING)
(BOTH GROAN)
JEDEDIAH: We're a long
way from home, boy.
Did you ask me
to hold your hand?
No.
Mmm-hmm.
ATTILA: (SHOUTING)
Jedo!
Octo!
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL DIALECT)
They could be anywhere between
here and the intake vent.
(CHATTERING)
What do you see, Dex?
You know he's a monkey,
Lawrence.
He can't talk.
No, but he can fit.
Nicky...
give me your phone.
Why?
For Dex.
I don't understand one thing
that's going on here.
Idon%,eHhen
Dad, what's going on?
I'm sort of set up
to track your phone.
You're sort of set up to track my phone?
You track my phone?
Yeah, I'm your dad.
I'm looking out for you.
No. No. Hold up.
"Spying on" is not
the same thing
as just looking
out for someone.
You'll get it back,
I promise.
But right now, it's going
on the monkey's back.
All right.
Dex, come here.
Thanks, man.
Listen. I need you to go down
there and find them, all right?
Think you can handle it?
(CHATTERING)
Good man.
Stay safe.
I think
it's right here.
(LAUGHS)
"Right here."
Classic.
Ah, the gift of laughter.
Thank you, Dangly Bells.
(ELEPHANTS TRUMPETING)
First quest?
Uh, not exactly.
Ithoughtyou
were going to Egypt.
We are, but we got
to do this first.
That's not how
a quest works.
A quest is one thing. It's not,
like, "Holy Grail and a monkey."
Yeah, well,
my guys are missing
and Dexter's
gonna find them.
SIR LANCELOT:
What is the quest? Gold?
Fountain of Youth?
Magic tablet.
It's that thing
Ahk is holding.
It shouldn't be too hard
to take it from him.
He seems well-toned
andleanu.
But weak.
It would be like taking candy
from a feeble Egyptian baby.
No, we're not trying to take
it, we're trying to fix it.
There's something
wrong with it.
It's kind of complicated.
It might be less complicated if you
stopped following a chimpanzee.
He's not a chimpanzee,
he's a capuchin.
The fool seems agitated.
That's often his way.
But I assure you,
he's no fool.
Is it true what he says?
The tablet that
you carry is magic?
It is, indeed.
Everything around you has come to life
tonight for the very first time...
all because of this tablet.
(SCREECHING)
(ATTILA MUTTERING)
Amazing.
Then they're not real?
They're as real
as any of us.
Yes, but we're real people.
They're just things.
And they don't even know.
They must be
unbelievably stupid.
It can be confusing
at first.
(CROAKING)
Hello, frog!
Keep hOPPiHQ!
You're real!
Guys, I think we're gonna
have to cut through Asia.
Not a clue.
None.
I can't really see much.
We could jump down,
hope for the best.
But we have no idea
what's down there.
(METAL CREAKING)
We don't know
what's up here, either.
(SCREAMING)
(CHATTERING)
This is a Roman city.
I can feel the familiar pull of
history in its very foundations.
Where the heck
is everybody?
I've seen this town before,
I'm sure of it.
Romans?
I see you have the name
of a lady on your arm.
Andrea. Yeah.
So this Lady Andrea
is your Guinevere.
Does any man stand between
you and your ladylove?
Yeah, actually. My dad kind of
messed things up the other night.
Nick.
Oh, we're stopping.
Let no man stand between
you and your destiny.
Oh, "destiny" may be
overstating it a bit.
We just have
calculus together.
It's more one of those...
fleeting moments
of eye contact.
"Who's gonna
look away first?"
But I get you. No man...
Good.
Okay.
"LiepWOP-"
IiepWOP-
Doesn't ring a bell.
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
Now who's this
son of a gun?
(CONTINUES SHOUTING)
(MUFFLED) Pompeii!
I'm sorry.
I'm having trouble hearing you!
Pompeii!
No comprendo, amigo...
because you got the thing
in front of you!
(CROWD CLAMOURING)
What are they doing?
Where in the blazes
are they stampeding off to?
Was it something we said?
(ROARING)
(LAUGHING)
Come on back to liepwop!
There's plenty of room!
Come on back!
They're as crazy
as road lizards.
People are strange.
Oh.
Hey, guy-
We're just passing through.
(CHATTERING)
It's a Garuda from Tibet.
A Garuda?
Hi, Garuda.
How you doing?
Garuda! How you doing?
Cool, great.
Okay. We just--
You know what? We just got to get through.
I don't have time.
Please. Okay.
(CONTINUES CHATTERING)
I'm not gonna play
this game with you.
I got to go through. Really.
(WHISPERING)
Get back.
A dragon. No, it's not a dragon.
It's a--
It's a Xiangliu.
Mythical snake demon.
It looks like a dragon.
I say we kill it.
What? No, it's asleep.
You're right. It's not very sporting
to kill it while it's asleep.
Let's wake it up
and then kill it.
I shall go first,
and I shall take the boy.
What are you--? No! You're
not gonna take the boy.
Why not?
Because he's a boy!
Larry, there comes a time
in every man's life...
when he must
slay his own dragon.
Not this kid, all right?
He still hasn't finished all his
thank-you notes from his bar mitzvah.
Anyway, that's just
an expression.
Not where I come from.
He's not gonna
slay his dragon right now.
(SIGHS) We're gonna
go around it.
We're gonna go around now, or
else we're gonna lose the signal.
Come on.
IiepWOP-
(MUFFLED) Pompeii!
Liepwop. Are you sure you're
reading that right, pal?
Hmm?
Pompeii!
(RUMBLING)
Oh!
"Pompeii."
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SNORING)
(GROANING)
"Ask not what your country
can do for you... Shh.
"Ask what you can
do for your country."
There it goes again!
(SCREAMING)
Attila! Shh!
(INCOHERENT JABBER)
Teddy!
TEDDY: Charge!
(ATTILA WHIMPERING)
Whoa!
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
SIR LANCELOT: Fantastic!
It's awake!
Now we can kill it!
A-ha!
(GRUNTING)
Whoa!
Attila!
NICK: Dad!
Nicky!
(GRUNTING)
I'll get the boy!
(GROANING)
Ever used a blade?
Only in World of Warcraft!
You're about to learn.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
"The only thing we have
to fear is fear itself!"
"Doing a heck of a job,
Brownie."
(GRUNTS)
(TEDDY CONTINUES JABBERING)
(MOANS)
Behind you!
Duck!
(SHOUTING VICTORIOUSLY)
JEDEDIAH:
Last roundup, kemosabe!
Time to slap on
the barbecue sauce, boy!
Huh? What?
(ROARING)
No, no! You wouldn't!
He must!
Clear!
(SHOUTING)
We must never speak
of what happened here today.
Come on!
That wasn't necessary!
It's out!
(GROANING)
These things
really do save lives.
(CHATTERING)
Are you all right?
(GRUNTS)
Are you all right,
my dear?
You okay?
Yeah, thanks.
You fought bravely, sire.
One day, I promise you,
we shall drink dragon's blood
from the victor's cup.
I'm good with just, like,
soda or water, too.
But I like the energy
we got going.
From now on, you must
choose your own path.
And let no man
tell you otherwise.
We better let Larry know
we're okay.
Turn around.
Larry's probably
worried about us.
How are we going
to find them now?
Lawrence?
I fear we've
turned a corner.
I'm becoming wax again, son.
All right.
We'll look for them later.
We got to get
to Egypt now.
Wait, shouldn't we keep
looking for Jed and Octavius?
Nick is right.
A true knight never
shirks his duties.
If we don't get to Egypt soon
we're not gonna save anybody.
Dada say, "Stay!"
Stay!
(SNIFFING)
(SIGHS)
Dada say Laaa no eat.
Stay, Laaa!
(GRUNTING)
(SNIFFING)
This is it.
Perhaps I should
accompany you in.
No, I think
we got it from here.
Really?
Yeah. No, we're good.
Right. Well...
fﬂendsu.
Larry...
clown-faced keeper
of the magic tablet...
I shall never
forget your bravery.
Nor your jests.
Bye.
I shall not say goodbye.
I am.
What?
I'm gonna say goodbye.
I have to go, I'm sorry.
I'll see you.
Really, man, thank you.
For everything.
I haven't seen these walls
for many a moon.
Ahkmen?
Mother.
Oh!
(SOBBING)
Father.
Welcome home, my son.
I want you
to meet my friends.
I am Merenkahre...
Pharaoh of the Nile and
Father to the Son of the Sun.
And I am Shepseheret...
the Glittering Jewel
of the Nine Kingdoms.
And I am Larry.
Guardian of Brooklyn.
Yes.
I actually live
in Manhattan now.
I know, but it doesn't
sound as cool.
Yeah.
We would be very honored if you
could take a look at the tablet.
There's something
happening with it.
We don't understand
what it is.
You are speaking
with a pharaoh.
Kiss my staff.
Is it okay if I don't?
You will show respect.
I am the descendant
of Ra, the sun god.
I understand that
and I totally respect you.
I just don't pray
to Ra, so--
The Egyptian gods
are the only true gods.
Well, we try to stay
a little more open-minded.
I mean, Sacajawea, she honors
her spiritual ancestors...
and you pray to some sort
of goat god, Attila?
I'm half-Irish,
half-Jewish--
You are? I love Jews!
We owned 40,000 of them!
Such lovely people.
Here we go.
They were very happy, always
singing with the candles.
Yeah. They really
weren't happy.
Really?
No. They left.
They spent about 40 years in
the desert trying to escape.
Om
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah. We have dinner once
a year and talk about it.
It's a big deal for us.
Listen, could you take
a look at that tablet?
There's something
wrong with it.
It's losing its power.
Do you think
you could fix it?
To do that, I would have to
divulge the secret of the tablet.
I promise
we won't tell anybody.
No.
I'll kiss your staff.
Too late.
Father, why do you insist
on keeping this to yourself?
The secret was to be passed
down to you at the proper time.
Well, it has been
4,000 years.
Now seems like a good time.
You were born at midnight.
I was Pharaoh...
and I had seen wonders
most men only dream of.
But when I first gazed upon you...
(COOING)
you were instantly
more precious to me...
than all the wonders
of the ancient world.
I knew I could never bear
to say goodbye.
I commanded the High Priest to
create a gift to you, my son...
using all we had learned of the
mysteries of the afterlife.
Forged in the temple of
Khonsu, god of the moon...
and watcher over nighttime
travelers--- (CHANTING)
the Tablet of Ahkmenrah.
Our tomb was designed to channel
Khonsu's rays down to the tablet...
rejuvenating its powers
every night.
The moon god bestowed his
power upon the tablet...
so that, as long as
it bathed in his light...
our family could
be together forever,
and not even death
could part us.
It's been away from
Khonsu's light toolong.
(GASPS)
My son!
What is happening to you?
It needs moonlight...
otherwise we shall
all be dead by sunrise.
Hurry!
If the tablet dies...
nothing can bring it back!
(PANTING)
What are you doing?
The tablet. Now.
Wait, listen to me.
That thing is dying.
If it doesn't
get moonlight...
everything ends,
like, for real.
King Arthur wasted years
searching for the Holy Grail.
To think it was
a tablet all along.
Would you just give it to me? You
don't know what you're doing!
My quest is complete.
I ride for Camelot tonight.
Just keep it, okay?
Butjust put it
in the moonlight
and turn
that center piece.
Sorry, not my first quest.
And by the way, Erik was
much funnier than you!
Go get the others.
We can't let him
leave the building!
Whoa! Easy there, partner!
Slow it down!
I don't know
who you are...
but I'm pretty dang sure that
tablet don't belong to you.
(CHUCKLES)
Now wait a second!
Come back here!
This ain't over!
You'll rue the day you mocked
us with your huge sword
and hypnotic blue eyes!
His eyes are very blue.
Speak softly
and carry a big stick.
Lawrence,
we have a problem.
This one turned
to wax as well.
I have a saying, too.
"Speak loudly and
carry a bigger stick."
(BOTH GROAN)
It's over there!
You mean up there.
Come on.
Got it.
Teddy.
The tablet, now!
I shan't ask
you again, fool!
And this is giving me
a headache!
Give me the tablet!
Let me go, Lawrence.
No! Teddy, no!
Teddy!
There.
(GROANING)
That'll be mine.
Hey, that was a good one.
No idea that would work.
(TILLY SNORING)
(SNORTS)
(LAAA GRUNTING
OVER SPEAKERS)
Larry!
He)', YOU guys,
how you doing?
JEDEDIAH:
Still in one piece!
Octavius, I think this belongs to you.
Thank you.
I don't understand.
Why is Lancelot staying
strong while we get weaker?
It's his first night.
Newborns are stronger
but it matters not.
Unless we succeed, he, too,
will be dead come the dawn.
LARRY: We can't let him
leave the building.
Sir, can you go back to Egypt,
in case he comes through there?
Of course. Nicky, take Attila,
check the loading dock.
Got it. Teddy, go to the South
Wing, cover the side doors.
I got the main entrance.
(PANTING)
SIR LANCELOT: (SHOUTING) Hi-yeah!
(HORSE NEIGHING)
You! I knew
you smelled a bit off!
Didn't you just see that?
See what?
The knight on the horse
that just rode through!
Stop trying to distract me
with your magical fantasy!
I found your filthy twin,
here, in the freight room!
He's not my twin.
I got him, and what could
he say for himself?
(IMITATING GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS) Shut up!
Shut up in your face!
Shut up right now!
Do you want to be smashed?
Yeah, you can run, but if
you leave those gates...
I swear to you,
your hideous doppelganger...
who looks a lot like the lead
singer of the Counting Crows...
will get it!
(WHISPERS) Dada.
That's right.
It compute with him.
Dada.
Damn it!
(GRUNTING)
Laaa.
If you see me do something
dumb, don't imitate me, okay?
It's basically what
I keep telling Nick.
He just doesn't
get it, you know?
I mean,
he's a smart kid...
but I just want to give him
the tools that I didn't have.
I mean, get the degree,
then take a break.
Get the degree,
(SCREAMING)
Laaa! Laaa, stop that!
Stop it!
Okay-
(BOTH EXHALE)
(ATTILA SCREAMING)
What? Excuse me! Hey!
Hi. Hey. Sorry.
I'm Nick, this is Dexter,
Attila the Hun.
Oh, yes,
so lovely to meet you.
Now meet this hammer!
Don't do that.
I'm super sorry. I know it's
a lot going on, Hun, monkey.
Wow, what? So much weird.
Huge amount to process.
Right? Okay, sorry.
Thank you. You won't
get away with this!
I'm making sketches of you
in my mind right now!
Boy with freckles,
fat Asian with hair
extensions, evil monkey.
I guess it's just parenting,
you know?
And he comes from
a divorced family...
so I'm sure he has a lot of
conflicted feelings about me...
and there might be some Oedipal
stuff at play in there, or--
I get it.
I wasn't there
a lot of the time.
So I think I might be
projecting my own guilt...
and taking it out
on him in ways...
that I'm not even
aware of.
(GRUNTING)
What?
Door.
Head.
Okay, I--
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
Open...
head.
Open your mind!
Yes! Yeah, well,
you're right.
That's the challenge.
I mean, it's all
contextual, and I do.
I keep looking at him
through the lens of how
my parents raised me...
when, in reality,
he's his own person.
And, yeah, we share
the same DNA...
but honestly, he's much more
evolved than I ever was.
I don't want to let my own
ego and childhood history...
stop him from making the
mistakes he needs to make...
to become the person
that he's meant to be.
(GRUNTS)
Oh!
Open the door
with your head.
Yes!
Good, Laaa. Let's go!
Ah!
Everybody okay?
Yes, Lawrence.
Attila and your boy secured
the lady guard in her booth.
I don't know how long
it will hold her, though.
We gotta
find Lancelot...
but somebody has to make
sure she doesn't get out.
(GRUNTS)
Yeah. Laaa, okay.
You know what
you have to do?
Stay!
That's right. Just make
sure she stays in there.
Stay!
Good! Go!
Dada say, "Stay"!
TEDDY: Lawrence!
I can't move my arms.
We're becoming less useful
by the minute.
(ATTILA GROANING)
Whoa, whoa!
Come on, big guy-
What? You okay there? Huh?
Something's up
with your eye, but--
(SPEAKING IN LOCAL DIALECT)
I don't know.
It's just kind of going...
(CONTINUES)
You gotta relax, okay?
(SHOUTING)
Calm down!
Attila! Attila!
Hey]
Oh!
Attila doesn't
hyperventilate.
(REPEATING IN LOCAL DIALECT)
You pillage!
You plunder!
(MUTTERING)
You don't freak out.
Okay?
(AGREEING IN LOCAL DIALECT)
Dad, there's, like,
8 million people in this city.
He could be literally
anywhere by now.
We'll find him.
We have to.
I'm coming, my love.
(ROARING)
MAN: Blimey!
He came this way...
traveling 4 leagues
perhoun
(LIONS ROARING)
(WOMEN SHRIEKING)
No!
Never run from
a big cat, Lawrence.
JEDEDIAH: Gigantor,
get your flashlight out!
These cats want to play!
Whoo-wee!
He's got it, boy!
(JEDEDIAH LAUGHS)
Well played, sir.
Run!
Where the devil
could Lancelot be?
LARRY: Come on!
You better let me out of
here, you revolting ape-man!
What are you staring at?
Stop looking at me!
Have you never
seen a beautiful,
attractive,
gorgeous woman before...
who could be a model if she
didn't love pizza so much?
I know what
you're playing at...
and it ain't working.
Not working.
Wait, it is kind of working.
What have they
done to Camelot?
HUGH JACKMAN: (SINGING)
In short, there's simply not
A more congenial spot
For happily ever-aftering
Than here in...
Camelot
At long last!
Guinevere, my love.
Hi.
Can I help you, mate?
Itisl...
Sir Lancelot.
I have fulfilled my quest.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm not
actually Guinevere.
I'm Alice Eve, and I think
you got a bit confused.
Maybe you saw me on stage--
Your voice is like music...
but I have no idea
what you're saying.
Okay. Hey.
Hey, man.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
Hey, buddy. Um...
What she's saying is she's not
Guinevere because she's an actor.
Okay? So am I.
An actor?
Yeah.
You know?
Do the crown.
Oh, sorry, of course.
Hugh Jackman.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
It was the crown.
I know, the whole...
Huge Ackman?
Uh...
That's a ridiculous name!
It doesn't even sound real!
Only a coward would conceal
his true identity, Arthur.
No, it's Hugh Jackman.
I, on the other hand...
carry the treasure
you sought...
but could never find.
(AUDIENCE MURMURING)
Behold the key to
life everlasting!
Okay, I love the costume...
I love the enthusiasm...
but you're gonna have to
get off stage now.
Sir Lancelot, ladies and gentlemen.
Sir Lancelot.
Yes!
Very good.
Shame on you, Arthur!
You don't deserve
your crown,
and you don't
deserve your queen!
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Prepare to feel the cold
kiss of my blade...
Huge Ackman!
Hey, buddy,
this is all pretend.
See, just--
Well, that's not real.
None of it is.
It's not real.
It was a good performance.
We were right in there.
You were tonight.
But it's not real-real.
It's not real.
Not real?
Do you know how long
I dreamed of Camelot?
(SHOUTING ANGRILY)
And for what?
For nothing!
(AUDIENCE SCREAMS)
Jeez!
Nothing!
No,no,no. Please just
take your seats and--
(MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
What's up?
We're just as
God made us.
Why don't you
take a picture?
It'll last longer.
(CONTINUES SHOUTING)
Okay, I've tried being nice.
That's enough.
Get off the stage
right now!
Stay back!
You don't scare me...
Huge Ackman.
Listen, mate, you don't want
to fight me, all right?
If we go,
I will break you.
Come on!
(GROWLING)
What is that?
What are you doing?
He's doing his
Wolverine thing.
Yeah.
(IMITATING GROWL)
You know?
It's better with
the claws and no shirt.
Fair.
Lancelot!
MAN: Oi, mate!
Hey, buddy,
that's not an exit!
HUGH JACKMAN:
Yeah, come on up.
Yep. Come on up!
Oh, monkeys. Terrific.
I love the costumes.
Sorry. I just gotta say,
you're the whole package, man.
Thanks, buddy.
He recognized you.
Yeah, that was awesome.
Hey! Give me the tablet!
Stay back!
Stay back.
Stand back!
Whoa!
Back!
What?
(GROANING)
Your, uh...
Your nose, it's--
What about my nose?
Your nose is dripping.
What?
It's melting.
From the fire.
(SCREAMING)
Okay-
How bad is it?
It is not great.
But I'm Lancelot!
There never was a Lancelot!
Lancelot is a legend.
You're not real.
I don't understand!
I know it's a lot to take in, but
please, just give me the tablet.
Oh, and then what?
Back to the museum?
Stand there as little
children ogle and point?
And learn.
And get inspired
to do great things.
There are far less noble
fates, my friend.
Not for me,
there aren't!
If there is no Camelot...
there is no Guinevere
and no Lancelot...
then I'm nothing. I'm just a
sad lump of misshapen wax.
Stop looking at my nose!
I wasn't looking at it.
You were, I saw you.
You were like this.
"Hmm, hmm." Staring.
I wasn't like that.
You were!
Don't look at it!
It really is hard
not to look at.
Yes, he is.
Ah!
I didn't.
I saw you!
No, I'm looking
at your eyes.
Monkey, stop it!
(CHATTERING)
Could you give me the tablet, please?
Give me the tablet.
If you give me the tablet,
I promise I won't--
Do not look at my nose!
Give me the tablet.
Look away.
Give me the tablet. How hard could
it be not to look at my nose?
I'm not gonna
look at your nose.
I can't help it!
Look to the heavens!
(WHISPERS)
It's disgusting.
Yet, he's still handsome.
No one shall look at, or mention,
my nose from this moment forward!
I'm sorry, I forgot
what we were talking about.
(ATTILA SHOUTING)
Lawrence.
On, Teddy!
Larry.
We've run out of time.
Listen to me. You got to
straighten the pieces.
Straighten the pieces right
now or they're all gonna die!
You too!
A world without Camelot is
not a world worth living in.
(SHRIEKING)
Dad!
Dexter, what is it?
You all right?
Hey-
Hey, man, you okay?
Hey, look at me.
Yeah, you want to slap me?
Go ahead.
Go ahead,
slap me in the face.
Dex?
Dexter?
Oh! No, no. No.
Dexter? No, no.
Come on, man!
Dad, he's gone.
I'll take that hand now.
I understand now.
The monkey was the quest.
It was never
about the tablet.
It was about them.
Forgive me.
It is I who have
been the fool.
(GASPS)
We're back, baby!
Lawrence!
Whoa!
Hey!
Welcome back, buddy.
(WHIMPERS)
Hey-
OCTAVIUS:
Well done, Larry!
There he is.
That's our guy.
Come here!
Here's your tablet.
OCTAVIUS: It feels good,
doesn't it, Jedediah?
JEDEDIAH: Boy, you said it!
Hey. Thank you.
How do I look?
You look like Lancelot.
Well done, my child.
Thank you...
for bringing my son
home safely.
It's a strange thing...
seeing your boy
become a man.
There were lions
chasing us.
Hmm.
Yeah, it's crazy.
One day, they're riding a
dinosaur through Central Park...
and then the next day
they're DJ-ing in Ibiza.
You've served
my family well.
We shall build a great tomb and
bury you with many riches.
I, personally, will see to it
that your organs are removed...
and placed in separate
jewel-encrusted jars.
Thank you.
SACAJAWEA:
It's the right thing to do.
TEDDY: Then we're agreed.
Lawrence...
may I have a word?
Yeah.
The others and I
have been talking.
Ahkmenrah's place
is here with his family.
He must remain here.
And the tablet should
stay here as well, son.
This is where it
belongs, Gigantor.
Yeah, but it--
That means you guys
would have to stay.
We belong in New York.
(ATTILA SPEAKING
IN LOCAL DIALECT)
Yeah, but if you--
If you guys go,
then you...
you won't be
alive after tonight.
We're museum
exhibits, Laredo.
It's what we are.
Folks come
to look at us,
maybe learn
a little something.
That's alive, man.
But I'm...
I'm supposed to
take care of you guys.
And you have.
It's okay, Lawrence.
We're ready.
I'm not.
Let us go, son.
Okay-
Thank you for giving me
back my family, Larry...
Guardian of Brooklyn.
Dad, if we leave right now,
we can still catch a flight...
get home with everyone still
awake before the sun comes up.
Yeah, okay.
Let's go home.
Whoa!
It's all right, Larry.
We've reached something
of an understanding.
Ream]?
"Huey, s“.
Wow! That's really good.
Good job, Lance.
Thanks.
Tﬂxey,behave.
Good girl.
Steady.
TILLY: He never even
listens to me.
But you...
I just feel like
you really listen to me.
(LAAA GRUNTING)
It's like our hearts are in perfect
sync with each other right now.
Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
Do you feel what--
Oh.
Hi.
Sorry to interrupt
whatever...
is happening-
Uh, Laaa, the guys are waiting outside.
We gotta go. Come on.
What? No.
No! Laaa, stay!
I know
this sounds crazy...
but you and I could make a
life together here in England.
(G RU NTS ANGRILY)
Whoa!
Wow. Okay. Um...
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
I will never forget you.
(REPEATING INDISTINCTLY)
You are the most rugged man
that I have ever, ever met.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
Keep the scrunchies.
Okay, Laaa.
We gotta go.
Come on.
I won't say anything
if you won't.
Oh, I know you hate this job and
everything, but tomorrow night...
best job ever.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
JEDEDIAH: Sure is quiet
around here.
OCTAVIUS: Without the tablet,
it's just like any other museum.
You know what I'm gonna
remember most about you?
What?
How big you guys are.
Come here.
(LAUGHS)
Hold me.
My...
friend.
You speak English?
Okay-
Hey, listen. Um...
Up there on the roof,
when...
When you almost...
(CHATTERING)
Yeah.
I just want you to know...
I really changed my
perspective on everything.
I know we have a weird...
We have this dynamic,
we have this tension.
Back and forth.
I mean, games, right?
You know?
Roles that we
put ourselves into,
but why does it
have to be that way?
I feel like there's always
been a mutual
sort of respect
for each other.
anyway-
I'll miss you, you know?
(CHATTERING)
Okay. It's all right.
Go ahead. One last slap.
Yeah, I felt that was there
for a long time, too.
(MOUTHING) Thank you.
Who would have ever thought?
I'm wax, she's polyurethane.
But somehow, it worked.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
I guess this is it.
Indeed.
And I know young Nick
will do great things.
Yeah, he's, uh...
ready to take on the world
all by himself.
Then you've done your job.
You've done your job.
It's time for
your next adventure.
I have no idea what
I'm gonna do tomorrow.
How exciting.
Bye, Teddy.
Farewell, Lawrence.
Bully!
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHING)
Got you!
Smile, my boy.
It's sunrise.
Hey.
Hey. You good?
Yeah, I am.
Good.
So, Ibiza?
Yeah. Uh...
The whole DJ thing, Dad...
I don't know if that's
the thing for me...
I just know that
it's the next thing.
After that,
maybe college.
I'm figuring it
all out, you know?
Sounds like a plan.
I should get back to Mom's,
or something.
Okay-
I love you.
I love you, too.
All right.
I'm not gonna let you go.
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
I'll see you later.
DR. MCPHEE: Three years,
no Larry Daley.
He was the one that took the
fall for me, got me my job back.
I heard he went
back to school,
got his degree,
became a teacher.
I'm very glad.
Well, when he heard about
this traveling exhibition...
Larry insisted that I deliver
this to you personally.
Ah! The infamous, supposedly
magic, glowing tablet.
Larry Daley and
his fanciful tales.
Larry said
you could be trusted.
What do you mean?
(WHISPERING) With the top
secret knowledge.
What are you doing?
I'm winking.
You're blinking.
No, I wink with both eyes.
That's blinking.
It doesn't matter,
because right now...
you better get ready!
For what?
For this.
It does glow.
Uh-huh.
(CHEERING AND WHOOPING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
Sorry.
Go ahead.
Have fun-fun, Dum Dum.
(CHATTERING)
Ah!
Stay!
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm not going anywhere!
(SCRATCHING)