Mr. Marcus Skinner...
care of the English department,
Stanford University.
Dear Mr. Skinner,
My name is Shaun Brumder...
and I think
you are a total genius.
I live in California...
in a place called Orange County.
A year ago, I was just
another Orange County surfer--
spending my days at the beach
with my buddies...
playing volleyball...
Spike it, Shaun!
and spending my nights
around a bonfire partying.
School was always a walk for me.
I did pretty well
without trying too hard.
There’s a tropical storm off Laguna.
Let’s go, dude.
Surf’s up.
I was easily distracted.
- What about next period?
- Twenty-footers. Screw your period.
Twenty-footers?
Then last April, me and my crew
drove out to Emerald Cove...
to catch some major tsunami waves.
I don’t know, you guys.
Dude, face the fear.
This is intense!
Righteous.
Lonny always said he wanted to die
eating foam in a massive wipeout...
but I bet he’s up in heaven
right now.
After Lonny drowned,
I did some heavy meditating.
I thought, maybe there’s more to life
than extreme sports...
and trying to get laid.
Maybe there’s
a bigger purpose for me...
and I’ve just been too high
to figure it out.
I was sitting on the beach,
totally cogitating.
I looked down, and there, in the sand,
was a copy of your book.
It was like a sign, like your book
was calling out to me.
Read me.
For the next few days,
I read it from cover to cover.
Your book totally captured
what it’s like to be a teenager--
the excitement, the confusion,
the horniness.
Sometimes I laughed so hard,
I thought I was going to puke and die.
Other times, I cried.
Are you okay?
It’s just so sad.
I read your book
52 times that month...
and I finally realized
what I wanted to do with my life.
I want to be a writer.
I’ve been writing ever since.
It’s all I ever do.
All day and all night sometimes.
It was hard to get going,
but, once I did, I couldn’t stop.
I’m like a machine,
and nothing else matters.
I’m selling my board.
I don’t have time.
- I need to focus on my writing.
- What?
My friends think
I’ve lost my mind.
He’s lost his mind.
Let’s get lit and go jump off
the roof of my house.
Now you’re talking.
I need some feedback,
and there’s no one here to help me.
Got your story here. Wow.
I have the sneaking suspicion
that my English teacher is illiterate.
I noticed you used a lot of big words.
Nice. Good for you.
It was a little long, so I didn’t
read the whole thing.
But who cares?
‘Cause I gave you an A.
My brother, Lance, is perpetually
recovering from the night before.
I’m sorry.
I don’t feel good.
My girlfriend is the only one
who’s actually read my work.
But she’s always so positive,
it’s hard to take her seriously.
It’s, like, the best story
I’ve ever read.
Really?
It’s funny and original.
I mean...
I think it could be a movie.
I don’t know if Orange County
is the best environment...
for an aspiring writer...
so I’m applying to Stanford.
You are a shoo-in.
Do you think I should apply
to some safety schools?
No need.
Don’t be a scaredy-cat.
There’s no doubt in my mind
you’re gonna go to Berkeley.
Stanford.
Yes. Stanford is where
you’re going, mister.
I’m sending you
a copy of my story.
Hopefully,
with your wisdom and guidance...
I will one day be a real writer.
I look forward to seeing you
in the fall, Mr. Skinner.
Your greatest admirer,
Shaun Brumder.
Watch it, man.
What are you doing lying here?
My parole officer wants to give me
a drug test, and I need your urine.
Can I score some of your piss?
- Yeah.
- Awesome, man.
Bob?
Don’t yell at me!
Are you okay?
It’s my kitchen!
Mom. Hey, Mom.
- What?
- Something’s wrong with Bob.
- Did you feed him his pills today?
- I don’t know. Is he okay?
You gotta remember
to feed him his pills.
Lupe, did you give Bob his pills?
I’m not a nurse.
You’ve got to get rid of her
right now, okay, baby?
She has a bad attitude, and she’s--
You stole my Palm Pilot.
You did. Admit it.
- That’s it.
- You did.
Yeah. It’s over.
What? What happened?
What’d she say?
She’s sorry, and she thinks
you’re an incredible lady.
Listen, Mom, when the mail comes,
will you call me on my cell?
‘Cause I’m supposed to hear
from Stanford today.
Okay.
Come on. Don’t get upset, Mom.
All right? You knew this day
was gonna come.
I’m just goin’ to college.
It’s not like I’m leaving the planet.
Mom, get a grip.
I won’t.
I’m going back to bed.
Check this out.
You gotta help us out.
- Don’t call me a punk.
- You’re a punk.
You remember the night we all went
golfing and I paid for everyone?
- ‘Cause stinge-king over here--
- Who paid for parking?
I don’t remember you ever paying
for anything in your sorry life.
Of course you don’t remember
when someone else does.
Did you guys know
that it’s April 1 5?
A year ago today, Lonny died.
Hey, dude, that’s true.
I can’t believe
it’s been a whole year.
I was thinking that, you know...
maybe we should do something
in his memory.
We should pull a killer prank.
We should go jump off something.
Yeah, bro, or blow something up.
Maybe we should go to Emerald Cove
and have a surf in Lonny’s memory.
Shaun doesn’t surf anymore, stupid.
I forgot. He doesn’t surf or skate
or pick his butt.
- Writer boy now.
- What’s up, Dr. Seuss? Cat in the Hat?
Principal Harbert, as you may know...
there was an oil spill last week
off the coast of Redondo.
Today’s paper just says hundreds
of seagulls have been affected.
I propose a school-sponsored
fund-raiser...
with all the proceeds going to
the seagull rehabilitation fund.
As the community-service leader,
we would be morally remiss...
if we did nothing
for these seagulls.
Fine.
One more. Last one.
After this, we’ll let all sick and
endangered animals die horrible deaths.
Agreed?
Now, people,
June is just around the corner.
Let’s talk graduation speakers.
Ideas?
Toni Morrison.
She’s in town that same weekend
for a book signing.
She’s won the Nobel Prize.
Interesting.
Dana, didn’t you say you have a cousin
who’s friends with Britney Spears?
Yeah. Best friends.
Now when I say Romeo and Juliet,
who comes to mind?
- Dana?
- Claire Danes.
That’s right. Claire Danes.
Who else?
- Leonardo DiCaprio.
- Right. Who else?
You know, someone else
was involved in that movie...
who, in some ways, is as famous
as Leonardo DiCaprio.
And his name’s William Shakespeare...
and some great movies
are based on his plays.
Hamlet, West Side Story...
Talented Mr. Ripley,
Waterworld...
Gladiator, Chocolat.
Mr. Burke, as you know, my boyfriend
drowned in a surfing accident.
I don’t think I can handle
Romeo and Juliet right now...
emotionally.
Tanya, Lonny died a year ago.
Sometimes it takes decades to recover
from a tragedy like this.
You only went out with him
for two weeks.
Your mom’s outside.
She says you got into Stanford!
Hello.
- Can you do me a favor?
- Who you lookin’ for?
It’s Shaun.
Shaun, pick up the phone!
He’s not here.
What?
Will you please just go to the door
and tell me if the mail’s there?
I’m begging you.
Fine, fine.
Do I have to turn on
your computer?
Just go to the front door.
The mail would be in the mailbox.
Okay.
You owe me one, buddy.
Yeah, it’s here.
Today’s the big day, Gary.
- Wow!
- Look at me! I’m--
Where is it?
Come on. Where is it?
Where is the mail?
- I don’t know.
- Are you sitting on it?
Dude, I see it
on the floor.
Yeah.
Push him.
I’m moving your chair.
This is it.
This is my future
right here in this envelope.
Hey, you’re blocking the tube.
Sorry.
"We regret to inform you...
that your application to Stanford
University was not accepted."
Wait. What?
I didn’t get in?
But--
I don’t get it.
I don’t unders--
You’re overreacting, dude.
I didn’t get into college,
and check me out.
I’m kick-ass.
What’s wrong?
Something horrible’s happened.
Is Bob dead?
Did something break?
I got rejected from Stanford.
Baby, I’m sorry.
It’s okay.
I’m so sorry.
You’re just gonna have to go somewhere
closer to home. That’s all.
And you get to keep living here...
with Lance and Bob...
and me.
Okay, and are you
a student here?
Yes, I’m a student here.
I’m Shaun Brumder.
I’m the class president.
And you didn’t get into Stanford?
Too bad. Tough break.
Where else did you apply?
Nowhere. You told me
I was a shoo-in.
Nowhere. Not even a safety school?
You said shoo-in.
Calm down. Let’s see what we can do.
Looks here like your GPA is--
What, 2.5?
And your S.A.T.s combined are 940.
That’s low.
940? I had a 1 520.
It says 940.
That’s not my transcript.
That’s Shane Brainard’s transcript.
- And you are?
- Shaun Brumder.
You didn’t?
You couldn’t have.
You sent in the wrong transcript?
What’s up, Shane?
Hey, guys, I got into Stanford.
Cool.
I applied as a joke,
and they let me in.
I’m freakin’ out.
- I didn’t.
- Yes, you did.
- Yes, you did!
You just don’t throw accusations
around. This is nobody’s fault.
Yes, it is.
It’s your fault!
You’re screeching at me.
Because you are a moron!
Now listen to me, lady!
Code red! Code red!
Call 911! Code red!
Call 911!
Hey! Watch it.
I got into...
Yale.
I gotta get outta here.
I gotta get out of Orange County.
Where are you going?
I’m going to my dad’s.
All right. I’m gonna go in there
and I’m gonna say to my dad...
that he abandoned our family, and,
if he wants to make it up to me...
then he can start now by making
a massive donation to Stanford.
Remember when the sea lions
beached themselves in Corona Del Mar...
and nobody
was doing anything about it?
Well, me getting all hysterical
didn’t help anything.
This is it, Ashley.
I’m gonna tell my dad
I wanna be a writer.
Hey.
Good luck.
Thanks.
- Who are you?
- I’m Shaun.
I’m your brother.
- What are you sucking on?
- My poody.
Well, aren’t you a little old
for a poody?
Jake.
What did you just do?
Go pick up your poody,
or you’re gonna get a time-out.
Pick up your poody.
That’s it!
Rosa, take Jake upstairs
and give him some Ritalin.
I don’t like your attitude!
Isn’t he getting big?
So what’s up with you?
You look great.
You really filled out--
your arms and your chest.
- You been workin’ out?
- No.
Bud is getting so fat.
You should really talk to him.
He’s gonna have a heart attack.
Plus he’s fat.
Goddamn it!
Are you trying to ruin me?
Yeah, where is my dad?
If you do this,
I will eat your face!
Come, my lady
Come, come, my lady
You’re my butterfly
sugar baby
My lady--
Puppy!
God! My God! Puppy!
A writer?
What do you have to write about?
You’re not oppressed. You’re not gay.
- Not all writers are gay.
- They’re all poor.
It’s not true. What about Tom Clancy,
Three people
in the history of literature.
The truth is
I don’t care about making money.
I have a burst blood vessel
in my brain.
I could die at any moment, but I keep
plugging away day after day...
because I want to leave you with
something special-- a business...
a legacy.
- I want my poody!
- Hey, pal, control yourself.
Can you--
Give me that back.
- I want my poody!
- Where’s your mother?
- Will you get in here!
- Yeah, I’m coming!
- Can you get him out of here?
- Okay, okay.
- Doesn’t he need a nap?
- Come here.
- We want him to learn some limits.
- Come on.
Stop it!
This is my life’s work here.
When I started out, I had nothing.
Now look at me.
I’ve got 8 1 /2 million
square feet in Irvine alone.
It’s a goddamn empire,
and I want to leave it to you.
This is the life I want for you.
But what about what I want?
You want to be a writer?
Before that, you wanted to be
a professional surfer...
so it’s a little hard
to take you seriously.
Fine. I don’t want your money.
But just for the record, Dad,
you’ve never done anything for me.
It’s always been about you.
What the--
It’s over. I should just drive my car
into the ocean and get it over with.
Don’t say that.
He was running across PCH.
He didn’t have a tag.
Was I gonna leave him there?
He’d get killed.
- I have something to confess.
- What?
You know how you told me you’d pray
you’d get into Stanford?
Yeah.
The other night,
I prayed for something too.
What?
I prayed that you wouldn’t
get into Stanford.
Why?
I didn’t think
it was gonna work.
I was sitting here thinking,
whoa, my prayer was answered.
I should be happy.
I got into OCU,
and maybe you can go to OCU.
You can study creative writing,
and I can study marine biology...
and we can be together.
But I just started feeling
really guilty.
I mean, this was your dream,
and I’m just being selfish.
I just feel awful.
This is not your fault.
I want to try
and make it up to you.
Thanks, but...
I really don’t think
there’s anything you can do.
Maybe there is. Tanya’s grandfather
is on the board at Stanford.
And Tanya’s my friend,
so maybe she can help us.
My grandfather is not gonna
bend over backwards for just anyone.
Please. Can’t you just help us?
Can’t you see I’m busy?
Why don’t you go
check on the dog?
Give him some water, okay?
I’ll take care of this.
We need to have
a little chat.
Excuse me.
Look, Shaun’s my boyfriend,
and I would do anything for him...
even if that means
breaking a promise to you.
What promise?
Halloween.
Dana’s little brother.
- Everyone knows about that.
- Maybe.
But they don’t know
about Lonny’s memorial.
I miss Lonny.
Me too.
Hey, I miss Lonny too.
But you promised.
And prom night?
Hi, Grammy. It’s Tanya.
Is Grandpa there?
You are so awesome.
- But, hey, we should go.
- Yeah.
-Tanya’s grandfather wants to meet you.
-I want to meet him.
He and his wife are gonna
come by your house at 5:00.
- My house?
- Yeah.
Do you know
who lives at my house?
Yeah, that’s right.
Just cover his whole head.
Who are you?
I’m your wife. Cindy.
We met in Maui.
Hey, look.
Bob’s still bleeding.
What’s this--
What is-- My God!
He likes you. Yes.
We found him on PCH.
Get him out of the house.
I don’t allow dogs in here.
But he’s so sweet.
Call the Humane Society.
They’ll have him put to sleep.
Don’t you think we should
put out some cheese and crackers?
They’re gonna be here
in 1 5 minutes.
- Yeah, I know.
- Who’s coming?
Mom, you might want to put on
something more, you know.
More what? More what?
What’s going on?
What’s happening?
Sit down. Sit down, okay?
Just sit.
Don’t be nervous.
Someone very important is coming over,
and he’s bringing his wife.
If he likes me,
he’s gonna get me into Stanford.
- They’re coming over now?
- They’ll be here in a couple minutes.
The house is a mess,
and Bob is bleeding.
You can’t expect me to drop everything
and entertain these strangers.
Drop what?
What were you doing?
Look. This is my last chance
to get into Stanford.
I know, honey,
and it’s not a good day for me.
- I have to go to college.
- Why?
Because that’s what you do
after high school.
Please don’t do this to me.
Please don’t sabotage me.
Every time I try to depend on you,
you start acting like a total lunatic.
Mom?
I’m sorry.
So now I’m a bad mother.
You’re not.
Please just put on some clothes.
I sacrificed a lot for you.
I sacrificed Damian for you.
Your tennis instructor.
He was beautiful and Serbian!
When your father left,
I almost married him.
And if I had, we’d be living in a condo,
clipping coupons and eating lunch meat.
So I didn’t.
I married Bob for you.
I had sex with Bob four times
for you.
How can you say I’m a bad mother?
I’m not saying that.
- You know money can’t buy happiness.
- Grow up. Yes, it can.
You and Dad both have money,
and you’re both miserable.
He’s miserable?
Did he say that?
Mom, this is the most decisive
day of my life...
and all I’m asking for is one hour--
one hour with no big scenes...
and no nervous breakdowns
and no Meryl Streep impressions--
just one hour where you act
like a normal, loving parent.
Can you do this for me?
Yes, I can.
Thank you, Mom.
But I’ll need a glass of wine.
There’s chardonnay in the fridge.
Okay. I’ll be right back.
Don’t move.
I’m really nervous.
Don’t be.
Everything’s gonna be fine.
They’re early.
Some very important people
are coming over.
- Stay in your room.
- Why?
- Because you’re an embarrassment.
- Okay.
They’re here.
I look like a pinata.
You look great.
Just remember what I said.
No big drunken scenes, okay?
Yeah.
Lupe’s with Bob, Lance is in his room
and Mom is dressed.
How do I look?
Very handsome.
- Now just--just be yourself.
- Okay.
Come on.
You must be Shaun.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, Mr. Gantner.
Please come in.
Mrs. Gantner.
Thank you for coming.
- This is my girlfriend Ashley.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hello.
- You’re friends with Tanya.
- Tanya’s very upset by your situation.
I don’t like it
when my granddaughter is upset.
Tanya has Arthur
wrapped around her little finger.
- That’s right.
- Hello!
Hello.
Hi. I’m Cindy Almond-Beugler.
- I’m Arthur Gantner. My wife Vera.
- How do you do?
Hello. Welcome.
Excuse me.
Won’t you please
make yourselves at home?
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank--
So, tell us about yourself.
Well, I’m a National Merit Scholar...
a straight-A student...
and I want to be a writer.
Do you like John Grisham?
I sure do.
Shaun’s also our class president...
and he was the representative
at our model UN.
He’s a fabulous kid, Mr. Gantner.
Arthur. Please.
Call me Arthur.
Even as a little boy,
he was so smart.
I miss those days.
The last few years
have been really hard.
I helped my former husband
start his business.
Soon as he gets a little money,
he starts screwing around on me.
My goodness.
He left me for a 20-year-old
he met at the gym.
I walked in on them at a motel.
She’s got him naked
and handcuffed to the bed.
So we divorced.
I remarried.
Then this new one, Bob...
he starts falling apart, and--
and it’s just one shit storm
after the other.
- Let us in!
- Hurry up!
- Come on!
Yo, bro.
We heard you tried
to kill Mrs. Cobb.
Are you on a violent rampage, dude?
What do you want?
All right, bro.
Check it out.
We thought, in Lonny’s memory,
we could go down to Emerald Cove.
We could take his board
and push it out into the ocean.
- Or blow it up.
- Right.
That sounds like a great idea,
and we’ll do it.
But I can’t right now
‘cause I got important people over.
- More important than us, huh?
- No.
- More important than Lonny?
- Of course not.
- This is his birthday, man.
- Yeah, man.
Like, his death birthday.
Doesn’t that mean anything to you?
Just go hang
with your little VIPs.
Sorry we intruded
on your tea party.
If you need us, we’ll be out in
the van picking each other’s butts.
- Naked.
- Huh?
I visited Stanford in the fall.
It’s a beautiful campus.
Isn’t it lovely?
We go up there for football games.
And Arthur is on the board, so--
Excuse me. Sorry.
Have you seen my piss?
My parole officer called.
He wants that piss.
I know I got it around here.
Don’t you see
that we have company?
Hey, what’s up?
There it is.
I am so sorry.
Somebody’s gotta fill this up,
or I’m going to jail.
Would you just
get out of here!
Fine.
I’d like to "protose" a toast.
Shaun has been a wonderful son...
and I want him to be happy.
I’m going to be all alone.
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Dear God!
Pills!
Mom, you didn’t give Bob
his medication.
Excuse me for a minute.
Dude!
Dude! Where are Bob’s pain pills?
This is Excedrin.
It’s a decoy.
I put my stash in aspirin bottles.
Yellow are painkillers.
They go in the Excedrin.
Listen to me, all right?
I need Bob’s pain pills.
Bob doesn’t have any pain pills.
I sold them, but these are good.
Wait. Yellow are not painkillers.
What are they? Speed. They’re the X.
Painkillers are in the Tylenol.
Give him one of these.
It’ll knock him right out.
Wait. Please.
Where are you going?
You people are sick.
Your mother’s a drunk.
Your brother’s a pervert.
Shame on you
for abusing an old man.
He’s fine.
Tell them you’re fine.
I know how this looks, but I do
everything I can for Bob.
- I love Bob.
- Hey!
Stanford is for the best
and the brightest--
the future leaders of America.
You’ll never go to Stanford...
as long as I have
a breath in my body.
Watch your fingers.
What happened?
You went for a ride.
Are you okay?
I got ya, buddy!
You should sue, man.
This isn’t right. Sue the school.
Shut up.
Just go to Stanford anyway.
Go there and take the classes.
Don’t take "no" for an answer.
Just say, I’m goin’ here. Kiss my ass.
- That’s a good idea.
- What?
I should go up to Stanford.
If I talk with the dean of admissions
and tell him my situation...
he’s gotta let me in.
I can get you there in three hours.
You’re getting into Stanford.
I know it!
Thanks, man.
I have a question for you.
I got something to say.
I’m gonna do something with my life.
Yeah, man.
Good.
I got these ideas.
I got so many ideas.
They’re burning
through my skull, buddy.
I don’t know, like,
hats and shirts.
Like Stussy.
Do you know what?
Stussy got started out making
hats and shirts for surfers in Hawaii.
Now he’s, like, a millionaire.
He parties in Hawaii 24-7!
I could do something like that,
don’t you think?
Like a fuckin’ shirt
that says "Loser."
Or I don’t know. "Talk to the hand"
or something like that.
Those would sell.
Or-- I don’t know.
I got these ideas.
Like a hat,
a big hat that goes--
Watch the road, dumb ass!
People have written me off.
Do you know that?
People have written me off,
like Dad for one.
Just keep your eyes on the road.
Dude, I’m gonna have
the last laugh...
because here’s why.
Some little chumps go to college.
Some little chumps stay home.
Some little chumps eat roast beef.
Some little chumps have none.
This chump’s gonna cry "wee wee wee"
all the way to the biz-neck.
- You know what I’m sayin’?
- I love you, dude.
- I love you too.
We don’t say it enough.
It’s true, and it’s not the drugs.
- Hi.
I need to talk
to the dean of admissions.
Well, it’s 1 0:30 at night,
so he’s not here right now.
I know, but, you see,
this is an emergency.
I’m sure. You’ll have
to come back tomorrow though.
Could you maybe just
give us his phone number?
What? His phone number?
Please, you guys,
cut me some slack.
Come back tomorrow, all right?
We’re closed.
That’s such crap.
That is such crap.
Screw her.
You know what?
- You cold? Want my jacket?
- Thank you.
Man! She thinks she’s so smart
‘cause she goes to Stanford.
Well, I’m smart too.
I’m gonna pull a MacGyver.
I will break in through a window,
I’ll look around and find a--
What do you call that thing?
Directory.
You stay here.
I’m gonna be back in 15 minutes
with the directory.
Reconnoiter. 15.
The dean’s probably listed.
You could just call information.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, cutie.
What do you want?
Well...
the question is...
what do you want?
Listen...
do you want me to call
public safety?
Do you want me to get naked
and start the revolution?
I’ll take that as a maybe.
- Yes?
- Mr. Durkett?
- You’re such a liar!
- Girls! I told you. Knock it off!
- Dad, Stephanie stole my flip-flops.
- So deal with it, Gina. Go.
- Yes?
- Liar!
I’m Shaun Brumder. I need
to talk to you about my application.
It’s late. I gotta get up
for a 7:00 flight.
There’s been a big mistake.
I’m sorry. There’s nothing I can do.
Good night.
Yes?
Look, we drove all the way here
from Orange County.
Can’t you just give us
five minutes of your time? Please.
Okay. You have five minutes. Go.
Okay. Stanford University
was my first choice.
I didn’t even apply
to any other schools.
My college counsellor
sent you the wrong transcript.
Show me your transcript.
I left it in the car.
I’ll go get it.
- Please don’t go anywhere.
- Okay.
Don.
- What?
- Where are our bathing suits?
There’s a green-mesh dive bag
on the floor of my closet.
Just look in there.
Who are these people?
Get rid of them.
Could I have one of those?
Yeah.
Thank you.
My head is killing me.
Take two or three.
Thank you.
You can just have
the whole bottle.
When you’re done down there,
I need help closing my suitcase.
Okay. I’ll be up in five minutes.
Coming.
Oh, come on.
Jesus. You look like a beast.
Where’s Shaun?
I need to talk to him.
- Stanford. He’s having a crisis.
- I know all about it.
You’re such a good father,
so good to your kids.
I need a drink.
Do you have any beer, coyote ugly?
This is an excellent transcript.
You should be very proud,
but what can I tell you?
If I’d had this by January 21 ,
you might have had a shot.
I need you.
Excuse me.
What is the big deal?
He’s gonna say no.
Hey, don’t let him say no.
It’s gonna be fine.
Okay. Thanks.
So what’s up with your brother
and aspirin?
Does he get a lot of headaches,
or what?
What is that smell?
What am I sitting in?
Relax. It’s just urine.
Your son was being a real brat today,
a real pain in the ass.
- My son.
- He said I was selfish.
He said that everything’s
always about me.
He called me a drama queen,
said I was trying to sabotage him.
So, how’s Bob?
How’s what’s her face?
She’s sleeping around.
I can’t talk to her.
She doesn’t play tennis.
She’s not a good mother.
She’s not like you.
Want another beer?
Look.
Sometimes I leave the office
at the end of the day...
and I get into my car
and head home...
and, 1 5 minutes later, I’m here--
parked in front of this house.
It’s annoying.
It’s totally out of my way.
I made a mistake. I’m tired of
paying for it. I want you back.
You’re such an asshole.
Which ones were they?
- Excedrin?
- Excedrin. Okay.
Excedrin are pain pills.
- Pain pills.
- Oh, my God!
What?
We just gave the dean of admissions
three hits of--
Where were we?
Well, Mr. Durkett, to me...
Stanford’s not just a school.
It’s my entire reason
for living.
Every night, before I went to bed,
I’d pray that I’d get into Stanford.
And I worked really hard.
And when all my friends
were out having fun...
I stayed in and I studied.
That’s good.
That’s what you have to do.
Eighty-two percent--
Wait a second.
I like you.
What’s your name?
I do. I don’t know why.
I just like you.
Thanks.
I feel so good.
Is it me, or is it, like,
hotter than hell in here?
Can you help me?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yes. Yes, I can.
There’s no time.
I’m leaving.
I’m going to Bali
with my family.
I love them so much.
I need water or--
I need to lie down.
Hey, before you do that--
You’re my same height.
That is neat.
It is.
Let’s go to your office...
and you can add my name
to the acceptance list...
before you leave for Bali.
Sounds good.
Man!
The lights are, like, vivid.
Well, it’s a beautiful night.
- You’re so beautiful.
- Thank you.
You know, I really appreciate this.
That’s okay...
‘cause I feel like
I’ve known you forever.
Hey!
I have a confession.
I never went to college.
It’s overrated.
My brother wants
to go here next year.
Well, I hope he’s on this list.
What’s that?
It’s a list of people
they’ve accepted.
They rejected him, the jerks.
Don’t do that.
When I was little,
I was a total pyro.
I was too.
Put that out, man.
- Put it out.
- Whoa!
- Who are you people?
- I’m Shaun Brumder.
You’re going to help me
get into Stanford.
And we’re at your office.
Oh, my God!
Do me a favor. Back that engine out.
We got a knockdown.
That’s negatory, Julio.
I need you to wedge that popper.
Hey! What’s your name?
-Joe--John.
- What is it?
Joe John.
- Your name’s "Joe John"?
-Johnston.
Johnston, Joe.
You wanna tell me
what happened here?
Just a fire.
I don’t know.
I came by and was...
checking out the fire.
Well, that lady, Mona...
said that you two were in
the building when the fire started.
Yeah, she’s a liar,
So whatever she says is a lie.
You’re saying you weren’t
in the building with that woman?
Not I. All right.
She started it, all right?
Because she was, like...
"I hate my job!
I’m gonna burn this mother down!"
I said, "You better not!
You’d better not!"
- She said it was an electrical fire.
- It was.
It was a total electrical fire.
It was, like...
the switches had sparks coming out,
- It was like the Fourth of July.
- Why aren’t you wearing your pants?
I tripped and--
Then I had to take ‘em off
to run faster out of the flames.
I think I inhaled some smoke.
Will you excuse me one second?
I’ll be right back.
We’ve a got a sprinter.
Five-foot-five, no pants...
unkempt, portly.
- You’ll be fine.
- Wait a second.
This guy thinks
he’s the dean of admissions.
Shaun, so psychedelic.
Buddy, I light one match,
and the building blows up.
I was just trying to help you, bro.
By setting the building on fire?
Well, I was high.
You’re always high.
You’re a drugged-out loser.
You think you’re gonna create
a T-shirt company?
You can’t even dress yourself.
Harsh.
Shaun, I’m so sorry.
I should’ve seen this coming.
The one day I need my family
to come through for me...
they end up doing
what they always do.
My father goes ballistic,
my mother gets plastered...
and my brother
burns down a building.
It’s like
they’ve all come together...
in some evil conspiracy
to prevent me from getting anywhere.
Is that what you think?
What else am I supposed to think?
You know, I really believed that
you wanted to go to Stanford...
because you wanted to study
with Marcus Skinner.
- That’s not it, is it?
- What are you talking about?
You want to run away.
You want to be free of everybody.
You think by coming up here,
you’re gonna meet people that are...
smarter and saner...
and better.
You know, if you went to Stanford,
that’d be the end of us.
And it doesn’t seem to me like
that thought’s ever crossed your mind.
Ashley, come on!
Shaun, I’m sorry
you didn’t get into Stanford.
But if you think going here...
is the only way you can be
the person you want to be...
then I just feel sorry for you.
What’s going on?
What are you doing in that bathrobe?
I’m not gonna lie to you.
Did you sleep with your ex-wife?
I want a divorce.
Really?
You can have the house.
Really? What about Jake?
I thought we could share custody.
Okay. Great.
But can you take him tonight?
There’s this new club in Newport that’s
supposed to be totally bitchin’.
Oh, okay.
Thanks, Bud.
So you have my pager number
and my cell phone number.
If you need me just call me.
And I think this is a great idea.
Good.
- Later.
What are you reading?
Faulkner.
Great writer.
Yeah. Sure.
You’re an English major?
No. I don’t even go here.
So you’re just visiting?
I should probably go.
It was nice meeting you.
I’m going to a party.
You wanna maybe
come check it out?
So do you like Faulkner?
He’s okay.
I mean, he’s kind of boring.
I think I might just get
the "Cliff Notes."
There are some serious cuties
at this party.
And lock me up,
because I am horny!
Guys, this is Shaun.
Oh, my God!
This is our song!
Scrabble? I love Scrabble.
Last time I played, actually,
I threw down the word "mazer."
It’s a type
of small cherry tree.
I even got 50 bonus points.
So, you don’t look familiar.
Are you a freshman?
No, not even.
I’m still in high school.
- Did you apply to Stanford, or--
- No, no.
I’m going to
Orange County University.
- That’s where I’m from.
- I’ve heard of Orange County.
I love it there.
The weather’s great, people are nice.
I really want to be
a marine biologist...
so it’s really the perfect place
for me to study.
What about you?
I’m a comparative literature major.
I want to be a writer.
Fiction, poetry, screenplays,
whatever, you know.
Actually, I have an idea
for a TV show.
It’s about vampires, ostensibly.
But underneath...
it’s actually about
the reunification of Germany.
But it’s funny.
My boyfriend wants
to be a writer too.
Your boyfriend?
Yeah, Shaun.
He’s really talented.
He wrote this great story...
about growing up
in Orange County.
And it’s just
really funny and smart.
But it doesn’t really matter
what I think, so--
Why not?
What’s up?
Is this your boyfriend?
What are you, like,
spying on me?
No! I was--
I was just up on the balcony...
and--
Yeah, I was spying on you.
Who’s this?
I’m Kip.
Yeah, Kip. Let’s go inside
where we can be alone.
Come on, Ash.
Mr. Skinner?
You’re Marcus Skinner.
You’re a good writer.
Thank you.
I’m obsessed with you,
Mr. Skinner.
Not in a sexual way or romantic way
or anything like that.
Just your writing.
I’m Shaun Brumder. I wrote you
a letter a couple of months ago...
and I sent you
one of my stories.
"Orange County."
Yeah!
Yeah, wait.
Did you read it?
Oh, yes. Yeah.
It was a great story.
I can’t--
I’m sorry.
It’s been a long day.
Could you just say what you
just said just one more time?
It was a great story.
I really enjoyed it.
Mr. Skinner--
Dude...
you have no idea
what that means to me.
The characters are unique--
well drawn.
The mother-- drunk...
arguing with all the maids.
The brother--
always passing out everywhere.
And I love the girlfriend--
the bleeding heart animal freak.
She was my favorite.
You really love your characters.
It comes through in the writing.
Well, thank you.
I never really
thought about it that way.
My only criticism--
Yes. Oh, please.
It’s what I need.
You need an ending.
I know. I just--
I don’t know how to end it.
You should figure that out.
Maybe I can help you.
Well, I didn’t get into Stanford.
Yeah, so that means
I can’t work with you.
I want to be a good writer,
Mr. Skinner...
but I’m just afraid...
that if I don’t get out
of Orange County...
it’s never gonna happen.
You don’t have to be afraid of that.
You are a good writer.
And every good writer
has a conflicted relationship...
with the place where he grew up--
Joyce, Faulkner, Tolstoy.
And that’s what I remember
loving about your story.
It’s very conflicted.
‘Cause at the beginning,
you think these people are doomed.
I mean, this family is heading
for disaster, and then...
as you read on,
you see that there exists...
beneath the surface,
these very real connections.
These deep relationships.
What I took
from your story is this--
that even in a world
where people can be superficial...
and stupid and selfish...
there’s still hope.
Was that the message
you were trying for?
Over here.
- Sorry.
- Ow!
- God!
- Sorry.
- God! Lance!
- I’m sorry. It’s just a nick.
Dude, you will never believe
who I just met.
- Who?
- Marcus Skinner.
- I met Marcus Skinner!
- What? Who?
The writer.
He liked my story!
- He liked my story!
- Shut up!
That’s awesome,
but I am going to prison!
- What?
- Some cops are right on my ass.
Listen, I’ve been thinking about it.
We are going to Mexico, buddy.
Right now!
Please?
Oh, God.
All right, fine. We’re leaving.
But we gotta get Ashley first.
No, I’m sorry.
No, that’s not in the cards, Broseph.
Listen, she’ll be fine.
Just forget about her.
Some dude’ll pick her up
and give her a nice bed to sleep in.
- Lance.
- Okay!
We will go and get her.
But you gotta follow me...
‘cause I am an expert at "excaping."
Let’s go. Fast "excape."
Fast "excapes" are my expertise.
Come on!
Be careful.
Follow me.
Lance, are you okay?
Go get the Bronco, Shaun,
and come back for me.
- Okay.
- Dude?
Promise me, dude.
I promise.
The whole time I’m thinking
it’s the alternator.
My bro says to me,
"No, bro, it’s the carburettor."
It turned out he was right.
- Would you get in the car?
- I’m mad at you, remember?
I know, but can we talk
about it in the car, please?
Hey, you heard her.
Why don’t you leave her alone?
Butt out, dude.
Ashley, get in the car right now.
Shaun, apologize to her.
Tell her you’re sorry.
I’m sorry!
Dude, come on.
I’m so sorry.
Now tell her you love her.
Tell her you love her.
I love you.
I love you so much.
Good. You love him.
He loves you. Now get in...
the damn Bronco!
Ashley, now! Now!
Now!
Kip, it was really nice
to meet you.
Get in the car!
What?
Lance isn’t gonna be able
to hear anything.
He’s passed out.
He’s not gonna wake up. I promise.
Okay, you don’t believe me?
Lance. Lance!
See? Nothing.
He’s out cold.
Like a light.
Come on.
It’ll be fine.
I promise, okay?
Clearly, you’re not an expert
on negotiations...
so let me walk you through this.
You come in with a proposal
that’s over the top.
You want a new gymnasium--
Then I counter with a lowball offer,
like $2,000 for a medicine ball.
- That is absurd and offensive.
- What?
It’s offensive, sir.
Stanford University doesn‘t--
- We already have a medicine ball.
- You’re not hearing me.
- I believe it’s you who’s not--
- You’re not hearing me!
Drink your milk.
I don’t want milk.
I want my poody.
Well, your poody’s been retired.
You’re a little big for--
Where are you going?
What--
You don’t want the milk?
Fine. You want some juice?
Yes. Okay.
Go to the fridge, open it up
and get yourself some.
And get some for me
while you’re at it.
You’re helpful.
Finally, some help around here.
Hey, guys, what’s up?
Hey, what’s up, dude?
Hey, dude, check this out.
Last night
we were at this party...
and little Arlo here decides to
profess his undying love for me.
Did I tell you
he was a fruitcake or what?
That’s not true.
This is the real story, dude.
Chad crashed at my house, right?
And I woke up in the night.
He was fondling my--
Dude, I lost my keys.
I was looking for ‘em.
- Do you guys want to come in?
- All right.
- What are you doing here?
- Hello, everybody.
- Hey, Bob.
- How was your trip?
It was okay.
Just come back with an offer.
Well, we don’t have to
dot the I’s and cross the T’s.
You have your people,
I have my people.
I’ll call you back.
My kids just walked in the door.
Hi, guys.
Dad, what--
Mom, what is going on?
Something happened last night.
Your mother and I, we--
Well--
You banged Mom?
That’s not the word
I would use, but...
yes, we came together.
- Are you serious?
- Guess what else we did?
I’ve been on the phone
all morning with Stanford.
Your mother and I donated the money
for a new admissions building.
I guess the old one burned down.
We got you into Stanford, Shaun.
- You did that for me?
- Yeah.
Really?
- Yeah, bro, way to go, man.
- We’re stoked, dude.
Stanford!
Congratulations, Shaun.
That’s-- That is awesome.
I was just up in my room
thinking about Faulkner...
and wondering if he had left
the South...
would he have ever written a
Light in August?
Or what if James Joyce
had left Ireland?
Well, I mean, he did leave Ireland,
but not in his heart.
Do you see what
I’m getting at here?
I don’t need to go to Stanford
to be a writer.
All I need are
the people who inspire me...
Like my friends...
and my family....
and you.
So I’m gonna stay.
I’m gonna stay in Orange County.
You are!
Stanford sucks!
"Dear Mr. Skinner,
I’m writing you to say thank you...
for all your words of wisdom.
It took me a while,
but I finally realized...
Orange County
is the perfect environment...
for an aspiring writer.
Today I went down to the beach
with a copy of your book.
I left it there by the water.
Maybe another mixed-up kid
will stumble upon it.
And maybe it will change his life
like it changed mine.
Later, Mr. Skinner.
Yours truly, Shaun Brumder. "
Dude, don’t touch!
I’m lighting the fire.
It was my idea,
and you’re an idiot.
You’re gonna blow off your hand.
Give me the lighter.
Dude, Lonny would have wanted me
to blow up his board, dude.
- Lonny thought you were a tool.
- Lonny thought you were a fool.
- Hey, guys, what are you doing?
- Gonna blow up Lonny’s board, man.
- It’s gonna be explosive.
- We got so many M-80s.
It’s gonna be like
the Fourth of July.
- Dude, what are you doing?
- I’m going surfing!
All right!
Come on! Let’s go!