"Stone Village Pikchers" is:
Production Tayp Hey Films "
"Tatira Ektiv"
together with the "Grovenor Park Media."
My parents knew from childhood not want.
Aristocrats, blue blood, tightly-stuffed purses.
You are expecting a boy or girl?
We are satisfied with both.
In their permanent house guests were kings,
ministers and other power Province.
They tended not to the yellow pages of newspapers.
Therefore, they do not have
against attention to the fact
that was to be
the most happy day in their lives.
Derzhis, nice, you fare.
O Lord!
But according to local legend on the family Uilhern
it was imposed curse.
When my pra-pra-pra-pradeda Ralph
coeur occurred with the Tale Clara,
that soon became pregnant, he told
his family plans to marry Clara
and soon realized how stupid received.
Clara, in the end,
it was only a servant,
at the same time prone
to reckless act.
Sir Ralph married at a particularly appropriate,
but Clara jumped from cliffs.
That night, mother Clara, Witch City,
there Uilhernov front of the house,
determined to complete fools these aristocrats.
She nakoldovala on animal intestines,
next to a daughter Uilhernov
born with the men in black pig.
And only when someone
from your circle will say "yes"
after "until death do not you razluchit"
curse be lifted.
Time went.
They Fortunately, the next five
Uilhernov born only sons,
whose sons were born, too.
And their sons-sons.
Finally, Elly
Hugh Leonard and the Uilherna born daughter.
Century unrest proved unfounded.
They, of course, did not know that Ella zachala
not from Uilherna it zachala from Jones.
That means
that first daughter Uilherna I became.
"Penelope."
And Penelope, Penelope pretty expensive,
I hope to find the woman left,
who really understands me,
I left all hope has not met you.
I knew well.
This is it.
Very can be.
Understand, much of life as you,
I feel like in prison.
The truth?
And why?
Because appearance and loudly name?
That is true.
It seems no one managed
through this painless.
None.
And Penelope, dear, nice Penny,
no matter, there is a curse or not.
Yet I am more than appearance and name.
And you, of course, too.
Vpusti me.
Oh, Penelope, vpusti me.
No!
Hello.
What?
Help, help.
This is a pig.
This is the real pig!
Help somebody, help!
Why, Penelope, why?
As you can see, Mom, I have not escaped.
Of course, dear, they ubegut,
if both of them refused to walk.
Do you think that I showed your cell
his father birthmarks on the same third visits.
No, dear, no, I was mad enough to wait
until we pozhenimsya.
I showed him no birthmarks, mama,
I found him a person.
Mama.
Oh, nice, you really liked him.
No, Mama, do not like.
No, it is not just like your nose.
But you - it's not just the nose.
But it is precisely in the men in black.
No, this is your nose
pra-pra-pra-pradeda by the father.
He did this with you, with us.
You and your nose is different things.
You are not you.
You are a different person inside you who
waiting for the moment when the can go outdoors.
For many years, reminded me,
that I am not the only victim of a curse.
A child with pig snout.
Uilherny hiding.
To begin ...
Along with the birth of my
aunt Ella eluded coeur.
Be damned, Ella.
But no one suffered more than my mother.
This happens constantly.
Who?
And you know
some are born with zhabrami?
How?
Since zhabrami, nice, as a fish.
Oh! Oh!
So you can cut?
An interesting case.
But sleepy artery passes directly through the nose.
Or nozzle, as is the case here.
Any intervention may become fatal.
For ... , sleepy ... what you?
What he, Franklin, as he said?
She will die, nice.
He said it will die.
Sorry.
Nozzle remain.
Oh you ...
This is not true.
My mom had good intentions,
very good.
She had always done it,
that thought fit to protect me.
First of reporters.
Oh, my eye, fifth, sixth.
Because the public demanded Show
my face, and this could lead to problems
my mother did that to her place
make any loving mother.
She scenario my death.
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
I was cremation.
As long as my people are mourning the tragic care,
me securely hiding from the outside world.
Now it remains only worry
that, to protect me from my father,
that hardly adapt
the new morning's menu.
Why not me bacon?
Because we love bunting.
Is Dad does not like bunting?
No, I love bacon.
And of insensitivity
the new Jake Butler.
This went on the market.
And this little Gilt stayed home.
And this kushala Rostbeef mumps, but ...
Jake.
Oh, Jake, ICAs.
Poor child.
And from time to time she had
Protect me from the menu itself.
So I mostly played
in their room,
smth and where a friend
and learned to entertain themselves.
Until my mother, not smykaya eyes, prepared me.
Drafted me to the role of the bride for men
that would obviate the incantation.
Kehl etil op? (What time is it?)
And in my eighteenth birthday
she hired Wanda,
marital agency which served
the most privileged,
elected representatives aristocracy.
Hoping to find me one.
My circle.
Who would withdraw spell,
My taking what I have.
Hello.
Following the resignation of them now invited to the house
and keep suggested language for a tooth.
So lasted long.
And the mother took the time to understand
the need for some amendments.
Glass glass and shoes for Jake.
Today ...
This is a pig!
... no different from the rest.
Apart from the ...
I have not drawn level with him.
I always said that they should
give the non-subscription
before it will see.
Not once.
Do not worry.
We poymaem it.
Try.
The police station.
Nozzle?
Yes.
And fangs, understand?
I know that I have seen clearly?
So you arestuete it or not?
On what basis?
The girl was face-ache?
If it was a crime deformities,
I would have had to arrest
half of the inhabitants of the city.
I know what you think: Uilherny.
Nice family, as well?
I myself thought so.
And when Penny mentioned the curse,
I thought, it's simple metaphor.
This is not a metaphor, and they do not loveable.
I say to you: if I did not ubralsya time
from there, this monster would remember me alive.
Enough.
Let ponochuet in obezyannike.
Let us, friend.
Who am I?
You do not understand.
I have a statement.
It was not Vandermen?
Yes. Edward.
Svihnulsya guy.
That must be it.
None.
You know that because Edward
already should be home.
Hey, anyone.
Did anyone will call my mother?
Vandermen-mladshy suffering from a nervous breakdown.
Oh you!
It is time to stand.
Stand, stand.
Let us, dear, we leave.
Franklin!
Mama?
Rising, rising.
- What? We leave?
- Agha.
Where Bontsa Larry?
Huh?
Protection.
Poor Edward.
I had no notions.
No, not that.
He prividelas abhorrent girl
with pork snout.
Huh?
You know, they talk about the coma?
Without the concept.
This could be any woman in the city.
I am waiting for the presidency of government.
You understand
as the story to affect me?
With my father do?
This is not my problem.
Okay.
I am not a raving lunatic, so it?
So.
So you type or rebuttal, or I
vypuschu you colorectal outside, one after another.
Protection.
All will be like twenty-five years ago.
Again reporters will be to dart about,
Penelope open secret,
and then, and then that will be with us?
We could move on the coast.
Good idea.
Or to France.
You could popraktikovatsya in French.
"I could popraktikovatsya in French.
- Ugu.
Mercy. Bonjour. Penelop syui same.
(Spasibo. Good day. My name is Penny)
Nothing, all normal.
Wanda! Wanda!
I demand rebuttal.
You polomali me life.
I say to you, it was a pig.
Pigs.
I say to you, it was pork snout,
I am not crazy.
Why no one believes me?
To wait a little.
Pogodite-ka, Wick, Victor.
I think this person will with me.
Who?
I?
Okay.
First-Hubert Straus.
Who else?
- Bo.
- Excellent.
- Jack.
- Fine.
- Ripper?
Super - who else?
Guess what?
Why would I simply did not say:
these are twelve men Trust me.
Excellent, let's talk about the dowry.
I think it needs to be doubled.
If they now do not make my appearance,
why do you think,
that will help double the attached here?
Well, you know, with this approach ...
Yes, this is my approach, mama.
This guy enormous potential.
I know he is going to look at it.
What do you think about it?
He likes you? Huh?
Oh, dear.
I know, I know, this is not my face.
This person is my pra-pra-pra-pradeda.
And it is not me, and I am not he, and I, I did not.
And never forgetting to do so.
Because of this history, I lost the right eye
and neither feature of this is not poimel.
And this terrible woman
still me in a nightmare.
I think you will not see it.
Hm-m.
No, Penelope, her mother.
The child only kraeshkom eye.
I decided that I hallucinations.
Well, thank God, even though I believe someone.
Unfortunately, it
I believe that you will not help us.
We require evidence
to wash stain on our reputation.
Do you think you can go back?
Oh, I do not ... I do not know.
That is, if ...
None.
Sure?
Only a snapshot.
I did not go there.
Okay.
Naidu someone who will.
Bring them to the agency,
who sent you.
No, they deal only
with cash bags, with the aristocracy.
This is part of a curse.
I do not think
which one of them will want to help us.
They do not particularly need the money.
Well, why?
Sometimes even the aristocracy needed.
Take.
Bid.
Let the losers cry.
O features!
Maxwell Kempion plays today?
He won there.
Five-table poker room.
Hey, buddies, wait.
I know you?
No, but I know you.
Held a small investigation.
And, it seems, in several years
you have to lose all state
who created generations of your family.
Hey, Follow, I can help you.
You do not contacted so.
Five thousand you satisfied?
We need your signature on the last page.
The standard contract of confidentiality.
You are not telling, we are not talking.
How urodliva this girl?
I think young ladies waiting.
This guy just takes time to me.
Oh, it is here.
Listen, sorry, that was late.
Ok, let's.
Remove the jacket.
Okay.
Hi!
- Ok, listening?
- Yes, yes.
Camera-on lapel.
- Agha.
Equipment in the sleeve.
Wear.
Sitting on your excellent.
To make the frame, simply raise a hand.
Not now.
Ok, sorry.
Izvinyayu.
You that have played all night?
Yes, I have remained chips.
Well, as I?
Normally, gone.
Oh, I ...
Do not worry, I raise.
And you ...
I Kempion max.
I was sent the agency.
Oh yes, of course.
Campion.
That is true.
Devil.
Sorry?
Devil damned.
So, dear, we did as you requested.
They are in the wings.
Vse-vse?
Yes. All.
But I do not understand why you do not want
talk to them one at a time.
I have said to you, mama,
so it would be easier to get rid of the weak links.
Hello.
I Penelope.
And you must ...
Do not stay at the tea?
Jake!
They run!
Flee!
They all saw it.
Where is the max?
Edward, seeing Max?
Max can not see.
It's not there. No Max.
How could you?
Just accelerated interchanges.
Like piggishly behave?
That alone gave birth.
Should.
This was the last.
Where is your credit card?
Come to the store.
No, no, no, not you ...
If you want more, I will send Jake.
I am mature enough,
to buy everything itself.
And I zahvati cigarettes.
Penny, another people.
Just one.
He, too, run.
They always run away.
How can you not accept this?
I have seven years of watching their shiny heel resting.
Even though you know that while I feel?
Understand?
Sorry, but we can not stop everything.
No, it can.
We can,
because how would I either wanted to believe in it,
that there is even one man,
that does not flee, a man who ...
Smiluysya over us, merciful God.
He saw?
Must be.
He is here.
Who is he?
What is the difference, Idi.
Yes, Idi.
Devil.
You still here?
Yeah.
Ah, yes.
You saw?
Videla?
Not seen?
So you ...
What am I?
Do not confuse me.
What?
I confusing you?
Why are you still here?
All else?
Ok, why you are here?
Sorry, I withdraw?
None. None.
You Rokhema fan George?
Who?
You have his book in his pocket.
And so you noticed.
Well yes, yes, a different book.
So you read it?
Well yes.
Strange.
I thought
this was the only preserved copy.
You know, I want to read,
but the library is closed permanently.
And I saw that the first edition and decided
that this should be something that lies ahead.
So you stole it?
Well yes, I stole it.
So you love money?
I am very fond of money
although they do not pay me to reciprocate.
Maybe you simply not made for each other?
There could be verified.
If the damage brought.
In one room
three hundred and twenty-six first editions.
Of these, three hundred faces
more than fifty thousand.
About a dozen more than twenty-five thousand,
and, I fear, only one less than the hundreds.
Only one?
Little novel,
written by a young man
to whom nothing has been achieved.
Yes you?
Less than a hundred?
I am afraid that case.
And, I am afraid, it means that the time had come ...
But that is your favorite.
What?
I said, this is your favorite?
I have heard.
Upper regiment, third on the left.
"Moby Dick".
This is the first edition.
Wait until I leave, but not something you will see.
Will see? What?
Au, Au.
Get.
No?
Penelope?
You have to give tomorrow?
I knew well.
I know that you are here. Yes.
He will return.
Come back.
Hello.
Well?
Oops.
How could you not get?
Half the men in this city ...
Relax, I will come back tomorrow.
O door.
Try.
See you tomorrow.
See you.
Honey, what happened?
I thought he knew
but he just saw an inscription.
Penelope likes George Rokhema.
But he also chose her.
Of the two thousand books, he has chosen a single,
which you are loved.
You play?
Ideally you would stop it.
At this?
No, although I always like.
But you are in fact something to play.
Why are you so decided?
What do you play?
Guess.
This is really necessary?
She is looking for his instrument.
Is not the man to do so?
And again, and two, and again.
You are my sunshine, you are my light at the window,
prinosish me happiness when there is no sun.
And you do not know how you want me ...
You even on this play?
Not otnimayte my sunlight.
Ok, enough is enough.
Ok, it is not bass.
No? No?
Try drums.
Okay.
Sunshine.
Not otnimayte my sunlight.
Ok, Ok.
No More drums.
No?
Without drums, clearly not drums.
Okay.
A saxophone, saxophone!
Do you want Sachs?
Once, two times, two ...
Enough! Enough!
Enough! Enough.
No?
Try guitar.
Guitar. Guitar.
It should be a guitar.
Not sure that the guitar play that way.
You are my sunshine, you are my light at the window,
prinosish me happiness when there is no sun.
And you do not know how you want me ...
Not otnimayte my sun light ....
Ok, enough is enough.
Stop.
Please ostanovis.
Yes.
About God.
This was, it was awful.
Thus, the people, pomashem,
pomashem otvesim and Penelope cool.
And cool.
I know, I know guys,
you also have hard, but you are fantastic.
Thank you for all the great.
Weather, weather, I still do not succeed.
Ok, enough with me.
You play what?
Do you want to be the garden ... by whom?
For plants.
Know?
Those who work with plants.
Clearly.
What's funny?
No, the plants are healthy.
You simply more
police came to work.
You know, after
as you arranged all these interrogations.
Shut, your turn.
Okay.
Oh, you did not happen because of this.
Why not?
Because I am renting it.
And I will ask if there is not?
Anyway renting.
Naprashivaeshsya himself.
For example, beer.
Never saw beer?
Why, saw.
Draft?
No, no.
So, never saw.
Knight does not go.
Knight?
Horse.
Ok.
How about that walk together
in the pub "Kloverdilli now?
Pub "Kloverdilli"?
Yes. Best beer,
Better Blues, the best gam in the city.
Thank you can, then.
Penelope, I forgot.
Hey?
Let us,
the same must hold from time to time.
So it?
What do you expect?
A. ..
You know, in truth you lose a little.
The truth?
Pub "Kloverdilli" sounds tempting.
Yes, but better zamnem.
A fair?
I have heard,
selling in the streets remarkable things.
You know,
sellers also remarkable of its kind.
Oh, a park?
Park just super.
I once visited there every weekend,
sitting on the bench, stupid wrote songs about love.
There have been?
More than byvaesh?
None.
And what do you do instead?
Obygryvayu you in chess.
I said I need to renting.
Well, cool, because,
as soon as my kids will see what you did ...
The game is finished, I am renting your queen.
But korol-to still alive, but?
Without the queen, King unprotected.
Why is this?
I do not know.
Maybe not for combat forces.
King really liked the Queen, you know?
Yes, it is understandable.
My Queen against thy.
Shah and mat.
Lord, what this guy?
I have a slow time.
It is specifically.
Because of the dowry.
I would like to find myself a girl with a dowry.
Give me a chance.
What can you delay so?
I opened it immediately.
You know what?
You like it more.
Why sweat because of the five thousand,
if you can get five?
Maybe you forgot?
I saw it.
It is a monster.
Putting it.
I say, it does not potseluesh.
An ugly, terrible, abominable.
Listen, you verme.
I know such instance mamenkin son,
from whom did ...
Lord, he liznul me.
- Edward.
- What?
Not Max-skiing.
- Sorry.
Listen, you can not blame us for having
we approached.
Excellent, find someone else.
Excellent, faithful us money.
It starts, starts.
Turn down a bit.
Thus, realized piano.
You play the piano.
I now head to amputation.
Okay.
Please, never spor with a player.
Yes.
He had another jacket?
And again, and two, and again.
You are my sunshine, you are my light at the window,
prinosish me happiness when there is no sun.
No, si-bemole.
You are my sun.
B flat right.
You are my light in the window.
No, right.
Okay.
You are my sun.
You are my light at the window, prinosish me ...
Understand, left hand remains fixed,
podbiraesh a right chord.
You are my ...
Clearly?
Yes, yes, so much the better.
Devil.
I monster.
None.
This is not true, Penelope. None.
Penelope! Stand with Max.
Pretty please, do not, do not.
I said, I told you.
No, you escaped.
This time it was you.
He said: "similarities".
And similarities with him.
I said it twice features.
And then just stood there and stared at me.
So nobody has done before.
If you only gave bednyazhke
chance accustomed.
That is, Put yourself on ...
What do you do?
What?
I said to stay with it.
Is it?
I have not heard, not heard.
When you said: "Stand, Max" ...
I said: "Stand with Max."
You do not say: "Wanda, stay with him."
I said.
Sorry, I did not hear.
Mama.
Do not worry, dear, he could not go far.
Well made?
Yes, yes, did.
Hey, I want these pictures.
It is not what Edward talked about it.
Leave her alone.
Lemón? Oh!
Who is this?
Close the gate.
None. No, there is no need not close the gate!
Penelope!
Max?
Penelope, I have to tell you something!
No, he spies.
No, that is yes.
He works at the Lemon, the reporter,
that prompted me to bury you.
You told me cremation.
And cremation.
I hope you are well paid, because
you can bid farewell to their condition.
Wait.
We still have a chance,
he can still lift curse.
Max, I know that person you offs.
And I can not dream that
that you took it ...
No, no, no, Penelope.
But this is not me.
This, I internally,
and just waiting for graduation outdoors.
And you can help this.
When the curse will be lifted, I would become like all.
And if not?
And if not curse away?
What if it could not withdraw altogether?
So I end with a.
I promise.
I break them.
Married to me, Max.
Married to me.
I can not.
Get out.
Y. ..
Get out won.
Immediately.
So, that is what we will do.
I feel,
as thousands of abandoned women at the same time.
We were not through such.
Penny, may try again?
I do not sdamsya, dear.
Never, Penelope.
I chuyala heart ...
Never.
As it seriously.
We both always known that there is no guarantee.
We both did not know that there is no guarantee.
We trained her for so long for the day
when all was to change
and not trained to
all that will remain.
Maybe
enough go marry and give her puppy, but?
Expensive?
Penelope, it is you?
Yes, Mom, I have to prepare myself cocoa.
Okay.
Puppy.
And what do I say?
Sorry, that contacted me.
Sorry that you plunged into it.
I know I have a bad heredity.
I am one of Uilhernov.
And I know that.
Curse at me.
And I have a curse.
That I, I, I, me. I, Y.
Dear, dear, dear, I think
your daddy, too, would prigodilos cocoa.
Okay, Mom.
Yes, and I would not refused from the calyx.
Penelope?
Penelope!
She ran away.
Gone.
Lord, it just has me.
You must commit itself to hand.
Okay.
What do you do?
We need help.
Yes, I would like to announce my daughter wanted.
You have that in mind down?
And if it will?
And so I insisted, Jessica.
I need the toilet, went with me.
I can not leave you alone with your phone.
You know, dear, before I would be happy
praised for such a proposal, but not now.
Hello.
Mama.
Stay on the line.
Mama?
Call for your account of Penelope.
Yes, we agree.
Mama?
You can say it.
Hello.
Penelope that damned, you arranged?
You saw someone?
No, Mama, no.
Okay, fine.
Where are you?
We zaedem for you.
I call just to say,
that love you and farewell.
Penelope, do not ...
At least we know
that it all in order.
And you do not need the toilet?
No, dear.
No need.
Thank you.
Enjoy the evening.
Well, thank you much.
I can you register?
Hello.
Can I room?
Of course.
Number eight is free.
Thank you.
So you need a room?
Yes, I, I need a number.
In such a case, you would not be able to come,
so that I can register you.
Thank you.
How will you pay for the room?
Thank you, Jessica.
Ok. I zakruglyayus, guys.
At delivers a new approach.
More nostril.
As snout.
Hey, Hey, guys. Enough.
Let's round off.
And such OSCAL.
Yes, yes.
Dates deadlines.
Print need.
Even worse, worse.
Ivande Mona Lisa.
Faster.
Your newspaper, Madame.
Thank you, Jake.
Lord God, a-a-ah.
You saw this pig?
Five thousand dollars for the photos.
The devil, Edward.
Pope, they all think that I am crazy.
And what?
Help? Huh?
You also mentioned, I thought it proves.
Try to remember, I am your son.
I would just like to forget about it.
Thank you, ma'am.
God?
Well, how are you doing in this great day?
I thought you went home.
So I did.
Pospal eight hours,
children prepared breakfast,
kiss goodbye to his wife,
and apparently you raise.
So you put?
Do you play or not?
He is survived chips.
He plays.
Let him think.
He plays, it should be easy to think.
Give else.
Bleach great.
He is survived chips.
He plays.
To begin, I want a photograph.
No photos.
Generally, no?
None.
All burned.
Then a detailed description.
Chestnut hair ...
M hm-m.
Chestnut hair, Agha.
Karim eye.
Yeah.
Drawing attention to appearances.
As a pig.
That is it complete.
Not quite.
Jessica.
Only not with humans.
Not glupi.
He knows that this nevserez.
This is not so, Madame.
I could not say anything,
but I have all recorded.
So therefore, it is not complete.
What is the significance?
Just find it.
Our daughter is unclear where,
it Falcons and terrified.
Sex shop "Ekstsentrik."
You did not give me any information.
No photos, no friends, no work. Neither appearances.
About the case, but without canines.
Franklin!
Do you want to find it, or not?
But without canines.
They would indeed be thrown into the eyes.
Jake, purse.
G-r-r-r.
Guess what?
Do not take in the head.
What we need you?
Where is my ... Who took my wallet?
This is our daughter.
Please help us,
please, I ask you.
He asked,
you gave us the keys immediately.
Sorry. but ...
Rooms designed for me.
Paid my credit card. Who resident?
J.
I am your customer.
You two, ahead.
I am not an expert on the canine.
At least, she did not die from hunger.
No, no, not just any pig.
Okay. Yes.
Better stop talking.
Hello?
Yes, exactly.
Penelope?
Who is this?
It was Penny from ... From ...
Sale snapshot?
Ehh.
Then why hanged tube?
Edward, what ... what's wrong? Are you that ...
None.
Okay.
Penelope.
How did you find out that I am?
Just guessed.
Do you have something to sell us?
Yes, there is.
May I ask why you are doing this?
Not your business.
Yet you need ugly.
No one said "ugly".
So you need them or not?
Yes. Absolutely.
Yes, yes.
Thank you.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Look grandmother, pig.
Very nice.
Fangs?
There is no canines.
Must be they rooted in the skull.
Edward, I thought a lot about it.
You know, I know. Maybe enough.
Lemón half of the residents
the city considers me insane.
I must prove that it is not.
Sorry.
I must do it.
Ladies and gentlemen, the girl with pig snout.
See?
I am not crazy.
I crazy?
No, not crazy.
The girl with pig snout.
It is the truth!
Penelope free!
She issued themselves, but why?
Where is it?
Does she like?
Or it hryushka only in the city?
You were right.
Kloverdilli.
What you like?
Draft beer, please.
Of course. No problem.
Now will.
You were supposed to catch.
Oops, sorry.
Now ready?
Another thing.
Thank you.
Some problems?
Do you have toddlers?
Absolutely.
Please.
This is half of what you gave me.
The rest get when I can give.
Maybe kvity?
No, kvity.
It is not because of what can be traded.
She sold me a snapshot of herself.
Yes, obviously, it is in itself.
Strives for independence.
Hi, Jack.
Annie.
Lucky.
Last order.
How are you?
You just ask you, or interesting?
Just ask alike.
I am his "Vespu."
Where no beard
you see a guy and me melee.
I treat, okazyvayus on pavement, but it is worth
must be me and bubnit: "Sorry, you have not seen."
As he could not see me?
I have to "Vespe" latest model.
Ha.
Is not such zametish?
Zametish, so it?
M h-m.
What?
Yes.
Clearly?
I am not to miss.
You have to navigate to it, Bill.
The hour is late.
Raspishis here.
Billy moved to the suburbs.
Yes?
Yes.
- It is very unfortunate.
We would be with him it does not work.
He was such a nerd, you know.
Podumay himself,
Is beggar will meet with me?
If he does not Crazy,
but with choknutymi I no longer meet.
If only it does not want itself.
Clearly?
Clearly.
I did not hear her because of the pieces on the face.
Astronomer.
As usual.
For my account.
Thank you, Jack.
You are the best.
Your health.
Pryacheshsya from justice
plastic or abortive operation?
Plastic operation.
And you do not know, coincidence
how could such a cost?
Absolutely nothing.
Free?
M h-m.
I just thought
may I also worth something done?
Operation at the nose?
Well yes, like that.
Only on the ears.
They stick out to me a bit.
I am not, of course, Penelope, but ...
You have a beautiful ears, it is very beautiful.
Just remarkable.
Are you that napilas?
Napilas.
Hey, Jack, pour even my girlfriend with Scarf.
Beg.
What is a "Vespa"?
What?
You never lift the "Vespe"?
Hi, Sam, have not seen.
Look who came.
Listen, guys saw?
They tour.
There seems to have good prospects of the group.
Not to joke?
This is cool.
Why here again?
Yes, so, you know, just prismatrivayus.
In fact, the mere thought
play can start again?
Yes?
Ok, good luck to you.
Yes. Listen, Sam.
I would not even asked if ...
Are you that, to joke?
After all your failures?
Do not keep me for durak.
Listen, I am confused.
Sorry.
Say so, I have not been able to assess what had.
And now appreciate?
Now appreciate.
For example, and not withdraw their scarves?
None.
Well, Ok.
Zalezay.
Okay, let's put me to the end of the street.
Hey, Mozart.
Listen, Sorry, it would not be repeated.
Ok, traveled.
So you can lose the whole person.
My brother once was riding on a bicycle
type and smashed into the parked car
and so it has withdrawn from themselves
the bonnet type of teeth and bleeding,
he sat back on the bike
and went to the cinema.
Yeah.
Oh, please.
Veratrum eastern, stunning flowers.
Lilac even in winter.
Cool.
Raised without assistance.
Just as my former Bridesmaid,
if you understand what my drift.
Well yes.
You know it?
Yes.
The truth?
Yes you did not understand?
More Talk.
Another card.
I still.
What's in it?
Rides on the skaters.
Enough, I am still.
Circus.
Many months have passed.
Zoo.
How they can do it all,
while remaining unnoticed?
Oh, dear, what are we to do?
This is her scarves, see.
Penelope!
Hey, Hey, Hey!
No, it ran there.
Excellent, you are here.
Your turn.
Ok, sovrala, I buy.
O Lord!
Did anyone, remove it with scarves,
she could not breathe!
No, no!
Hey, Penny.
They did not run away.
And, no!
Penny, no, no, no, no, dear.
Otvernis.
It goes.
Here it is.
Penny, here.
This, Penelope.
Penelope, Penelope.
The truth that you kept bound in the basement?
Not potakay them.
Penny,
yet you have any pork bodies?
None.
With such a large nose, you obonyaete,
probably better than we are.
I do not know, you highlight.
Penelope.
Annie!
Mama, can you lend a little?
Money is running out.
In no case, sending in a car.
Mama, they want to know
whether related kept me in the cellar.
Three weeks is a long time.
The operation at the bow is a Hemorrhoid.
No, of course not.
So far, nice.
So far.
Let there be so expensive.
Penny,
you want to say something the public?
O, greetings.
Penny said "Hi".
Mayor: "Hi, Penelope."
News Flash: City welcomes Penelope.
Scarves are sold every success.
Bonjour: Penny said in French.
Penelope tree planting.
Pope, so what you say?
I know I say that all I know.
Was it,
that you have been accusing Penelope in the attack?
I got a police record.
No comment, ladies and gentlemen,
without comment.
Ok, I ulazhu.
This woman, this creature, a place in the cell.
What bastard.
Sorry.
You have that in mind down?
You also saw it, it is a monster.
The audience loves this girl.
They do not know her as I do.
Our shareholders, the ordinary people,
and we like what he likes, Usec?
And what do you predlagaesh?
I invite all to settle.
And what do you want me to do?
Just ulad all.
Let us, Penelope, you are in my team.
But I am a bad player.
Penelope. Penny, Penny, Penny.
Kill, I forgot.
I said.
I am a bad player.
Hello.
You get on.
That is, you look excellent.
You look happy.
Thank you.
You know, you inspired me.
When you are doing what you are doing,
came as think fit, I, I did not ...
I need to go.
Yes, of course.
Y. .. I just ...
Penelope, Penelope.
Oh, nice, I am so glad that you found.
You must be home immediately.
I have a great surprise for you.
Mama, I need to go back.
Penelope.
What is this?
Simple, that I ran away from their feelings.
And because of that you escaped?
And I am sure that from me.
Only because of my feelings for you.
This is a joke?
Penelope not unizhay boy.
Look at him, he could lift the curse.
Something has changed.
Mama, I ...
It simply can not imagine.
Why?
Because you are in all the newspapers?
No, because I have friends.
This is not friends, dear, this is crazy.
You have heard: "Pigs speaks ten languages"
"Oh, poglyadi, pig plays the piano."
For these people, you just
speaking pig.
Speaking pig.
Edward wants to marry you.
Are you ready to lose
single chance?
Single chance
on a normal life?
You get me, Penelope?
Obrucheny.
Edward Vandermen married Penelope.
Hey, Lemon.
Yes?
I think you can help me with the history
Kempionom with Max, which I do.
What history?
Something type of Duke in the mud.
Aristocrats become a bandit.
In looters?
Yes Ok, Max Campion?
Yes, I was just calling.
He has already confessed.
What?
Lift.
You, a lawyer, who sent my mother?
This is a mistake.
I came to the max Kempionu.
Yes, greetings, I-Max Campion.
No, you do not it.
No, this is me.
No, Max Campion.
I am not deaf, I hear you.
I-Max Campion.
But you ...
O. O-o-o.
Well, well, well.
No, no.
What about the guy,
that you play poker?
E-e, shaggy, medium build,
does not know how to stop.
And, as is Johnny Martin.
Johnny Martin?
Johnny Martin.
The complete lusers.
Record, Martin, in the Pirate shalmane.
Okay.
And you have ...
It was so beautiful,
so well, is it not?
Yes, fine.
Yes, it was perfect.
We necessarily have to repeat.
And now that we have become almost family,
I think this is just the beginning.
Yes, I podgonyu limousines.
Well, well, well.
Can me my coat?
Oh, Franklin, we always go in the same theater.
Why stopped?
I think because of deformities daughter.
We all refused,
because we have an ugly daughter.
May I help you, Sir.
Thank you.
It won there.
Ok, go.
But my coat!
Buy you another.
Edward, what you are doing, where are we going?
Hello.
Max.
Hi Penny.
We are just going to leave.
As the case, Edward?
Not always.
And before all this seemed absurd,
and even omerzitelno.
That you are familiar?
Actually yes.
Choosing because it?
Yes there is, rather, Bedford.
Furgonchik "Bedford."
Should.
You little of what you have done with it.
In the toilet quickly.
Edward, I ...
Penny, Edward let himself pursue.
But Mom ...
I am sick of you.
I give her what she wants.
And I do not see it is willing to commit themselves.
Apart from that of you.
This ...
- Are you ready?
- It is not that.
- It is in this.
Listen, if you want to go to her and say,
that single person,
she finished by saying "yes"
still appearing from one thought that,
to her kids, please
but you do not happen to me pain, but it.
Johnny Martin.
Son plumbing. Huh?
You have long searched for me.
You nadul me.
It seems
in the end, you decide to give it a service.
Seen this?
Hr.
Beautiful couple.
Yes, Penelope and the monster.
They both get what want, so it?
I know that he gets.
And what gets it?
Day, who had been waiting all his life -
the lifting of the curse.
Yet you do not have faith in it, right?
And you?
None.
No?
Then that you driven all these years?
I do not know.
Offended ego and lost an eye, I think.
Curse?
Should.
Yes.
Who knows?
After so much time for the poker table,
you start to believe in everything.
It is not too late to stop Edward.
She wants it so.
Weather.
If marriage-all you need,
to remove the curse, why not you?
You forgot.
I do not max.
And?
One of its terms ...
Hey, here.
I took a seat. Here is pure.
Hey, Annie, but you pohoroshela.
Weddings are cool, right?
Yes, especially strangers.
Exactly.
Jessica, just a couple of words.
Something happened?
Edward A very gracious.
Mama, I am afraid vyrvet me.
Remember, just a few minutes
the curse will be lifted.
There is no curse.
The only who are here - I cursed.
To begin ...
Eye you lost fault of their own, damned.
And what now?
I. .. I just want to apologize.
Apologies are not accepted.
What? I have a wedding begins.
Meet: John Martin.
I said: no need to rush.
This changes nothing.
How can you say so?
Not only Edward ...
As you said herself,
he does this round.
Fine.
What Max, or Johnny, or as it is?
With "how"?
You do not think,
that Penny has the right to know?
What?
What he continually lied to it?
What he loves her,
but not being able to lift the curse.
Yes it is to know why?
This is probably the only reason
to which he said "no".
I do not know, you do not know.
But if this is true, God bless him.
He had been right.
The devil, Jessica, I will not be able to just ...
Leave everything as it is.
I am really happy for her.
True, true.
Yes.
And you are glad for it, right?
If she is happy, then I am happy.
Mama. I feel very stupid.
You do not look stupid.
Are you not look foolish.
Do you agree, Edward Vandermen,
take control of the legitimate wife Penelope Uilhern,
to be with her in joy and sorrow,
in wealth and poverty, sickness and health?
To love and care for it on that day,
yet death is not razluchit you?
Yes.
And you, Penelope Uilhern, according to whether
take Edward Humphrey Third Vandermena
in legitimate husbands,
to be with him in joy and sorrow,
in wealth and poverty, sickness and health?
To love and care for it on that day,
yet death is not razluchit you?
Penelope?
None.
Stay on the ground, everything is in place.
Penny, the weather, Penelope, I stand.
Look at me.
Watching.
What's wrong, dear?
No, see me.
No, I watch.
I do not understand what's going on?
You ... Sorry.
Penelope, it is too late.
Nice, mama.
I said nice.
Honey, please, please.
One is Your "yes", and will start a completely
new life, and you will be very new.
But I do not want to become a new mother.
Honey, please, please.
I imagine such likes what I eat.
Penelope.
Penelope provizzhala no.
Penelope disappears. Where is it?
He no longer grow.
And why do you think that ...
I feel the same, I remember that you are you.
Oh, Penelope.
One of your circle.
I just assumed ...
No, we all know mother.
No, dear. None.
Are you not understand?
I could remove the curse of many years ago,
if only I was a good mother
and to give you all the love,
where you had been denied.
You also did not know.
Not aware.
Look.
You know, nice,
since sleepy artery is not there,
I think it may be a little more correct.
Podumay, as well?
Are you mad came down.
This abnormally when a young woman is not
want to fix anything in their appearance.
This is a good idea, right?
I am her mother.
That's what mothers and daughters behave.
They give advice on appearance.
Still, I was sorry mum on the day.
Why are you so otnosishsya to this?
Now I am poor.
She was expecting so much change at once.
All went ashes.
I was preparing to leave,
and after twenty-five years of living with the family ...
Jake, where you Trump?
Jake, I say to thee.
And why do you with your bag?
Jake!
Not Hami.
Povernis when I was chatting with you.
It seems I ...
Poplach. Poplach. So must ..
But I have to be very
to cope with these changes.
And while I lost the person who brought me
so many problems, the world has not stood on the spot.
Penelope is still not found.
Taxes are rising.
In laundry malchik-gorilla found.
I was determined to regain my "I"
and always follow the cry of my heart ...
Look.
My zatsvel Narcissus.
And I found chemeritsu.
... and their conscience.
Dear Edward, at the first day
in the library, you said
you are a major part of his life
feel like in prison.
In retrospect, I now believe
you said that the heart of the net.
I am afraid that fought themselves
with you on the day wrong.
I knew that you escape.
I myself want this.
But perhaps
if I had enough patience to listen to you,
we would have found a way to help each other out.
Sorry me.
I hope this letter and this obruchalnoe
ring will find you in good health.
Edward, Edward?
Your father wants to know what you are doing there.
And then come Helouin.
Thus, all beginning to ten minutes,
so let us, wearing their costumes.
Okay?
Pereodevaytes stroytes and at the entrance,
quickly.
That to me.
Hey. Hey, only without a fight.
I can be, whom want.
Girls, please.
But she also knew that I would be Penelope.
Ok, girls, going out with class.
Going out and stroytes.
Let us, stroytes.
Faster.
Let us.
Alice, nice, what's wrong?
All odelis in Penelope,
but I am frightened electric.
And you know, I like the original.
Well Ok, a nice, derzhis with me
and all will be well.
Life or purse.
All greetings.
Oh, I like this, this is my favorite.
Hey, Jess, I think you enjoy it.
Not too much?
So far.
And then Wanda
no longer able to conceal this secret.
Hey you, you are everywhere.
Where you?
For example, three hundred and fifty-seventh.
That is true.
Derzhis.
What?
Yes hot to see you the same.
Ok, go.
Okay, go.
You can.
Are you ready?
Hi, I am ...
It must sign.
Have you got a toilet?
I still cook Punsch.
No!
Yes. All normal.
Come.
A good party.
Why are you not there?
I need to meet.
So you pereezzhaesh?
Yes, rabotenka outside the city.
Just at the time wanted to leave here.
Away from the crowd?
Yes, from the crowd and from poker tables.
So you player?
Former.
Moving from temptation.
Well, this is cool.
Are you man.
I had a friend once,
that also likes gambling.
At least, I said so.
And you know, it is constantly
have a monitor.
Take the mask.
What?
Sorry.
The whole Halloween, I always natalkivayus at ...
in total, per person.
Sorry, silly.
It mean a lot to you?
Yes.
Very much.
And what happened?
I could not give her what she wanted.
And what she wanted?
Be free.
Oh you shit!
You lied to me!
I succeed piano, and you say ...
Penelope, I am sorry.
I know.
Not in my power to lift the curse.
Nothing. I did so myself.
This, I, Max.
My name is Johnny.
I know.
I am still me.
So all happened.
And we have since lived happily.
At least until happily.
I did not understand what that means?
A po-tvoemu what that means?
- Rich sediments.
Always blame mom.
We all curse?
It is not valid curse,
a valid your faith in him.
What do you say, small insect?
It is not small insect, durak.
He, too small insect.
This is not good.
Very well, Billy.
So, now cover at the tables.
After a break to go walk
and see what we can gather.
Keep together.
Director: Mark Palyanski.
Author scenario: Leslie Keveni.
Cast:
Penelope Uilhern-Christina Ricci,
Johnny MakEvoy-James,
Jessica Uilhern-Catherine O'Hara,
Lemón-Peter Dinklidzh,
Franklin Uilhern - Richard Grant,
Annie Uizerspun-Riz,
Edward Vandermen-Simon Woods,
Wanda, Ronnie Ancona,
Vandermen-starshy - Nigel Hevers,
Krull - Lenny Henry.
Produced by:
Uizerspun Riza,
Scott Steyndorf,
Jeniffer Simpson.
Executive producers:
Dylan Russell,
Michael Roban,
Chris Curling,
Robin Greenspan,
Danny Greenspan,
Andrew Molaski,
Beytel Christian Arnold.
Operator: Michael Amate.
By: Jobie Talbot.