- Pitch Perfect 2 (2015)
- Created by DonToribio (Subscence.Com moniker)
- Posted FIRST to Subscene June 14, 2015
Welcome back, a cappella enthusiasts.
My name is John Smith,
and sitting here to my left is
Gail Abernathy-McKadden-Feinberger.
This one's gonna stick, John.
Well, you save the Jew for last.
You're listening to "'Let's Talk", in front of the
world's premier, downloadable a cappella podcast
We are coming to you live
from the nation's capital,
Where the Barden University Bellas are
about to rock the historic Kennedy Center.
Boy, these girls have broken down every
single barrier in their path, haven't they, Gail?
Absolutely, John, the first all
female group to win a national title.
Three time defending champs,
and now here they are,
performing for the President
of the United States on his birthday.
Wow, what an inspiration to girls all over the
Country who are too ugly to be cheerleaders.
Here's Beca Mitchell, leader of the group.
Look at these sequins and sparkles,
oh my, their feet just don't stop moving.
Florencia Fuentes,
just earned her green card, John.
She may have to do that back flip
right back over the fence into Mexico.
- I think she's Guatemalan.
- Oh, none of that matters.
There's so much happening on stage,
I don't even know where to look.
Back in my day,
we put on our blazers and we just sang,
we maybe snapped our fingers
if we were feeling frisky.
♫ I came in like a wrecking ball,
I never... ♫ Oh! Another surprise!
A overweight girl
dangling from the ceiling.
- Who hasn't had that dream?
- Lots of us.
- No!
- She has no underwear on.
Oh, my God!
We have a commando situation.
There is a commando situation on stage.
Take her back up!
Pull her up already!
- She turning, brace yourself.
- She coming, she's coming!
Avert your eyes or take it all in!
Not the front!
Nobody wants to see the front!
Oh, no!
Happy Birthday, Mr. President.
The Australian singer who calls herself Fat Amy
gave the President a birthday gift
from down under during last night's celebration
held at the historic Kennedy Center.
In case you're wondering what I mean by
"down under", yes, I mean her xxx.
She showed her xxx...
to the President.
All eyes were on the a cappella singers,
the Barden Bellas.
Three time defending a
cappella national champion,
which is... a real thing... apparently.
Although authorities have ruled
out terrorism as a motive,
the Bellas claim the mishap was merely
an accident and issued an apology.
I am deeply sorry for the
upset that I have caused.
I fell that I have already
received punishment enough...
in the form silk burn.
Exhibit C.
Filth... women who're seen are just another
example cultural decay through loose morals.
Not wearing underwear seems
kinda intentional to me.
Yeah, you can choose to wear underwear,
or you don't wear underwear.
That choice I make every day.
Ya know, until today I thought singing a cappella
was the most embarrassing thing you could do.
Normally that group is on-point, and last night
they were off-point. off-key, and then on the floor.
It's a national disgrace.
Yeah, but I'd rather be in that
limo ride home with the president,
cut to the real President, he'd be like:
"That xxx was off the hook."
Chloe, chill out, it was a mistake,
they're not gonna burn us for witchcraft.
No, but the National a Cappella Association
is in there talking to the Dean about us,
and who knows what's gonna happen.
We won three championships, whatever
happens in there, we're gonna be fine.
Maybe it's time to
think about other stuff.
- What other stuff?
- Ya know, school, jobs, life.
This group is my life.
I've intentionally failed Russian Lit.
three times so I could be a Bella.
This is the worst thing
that's ever happened to us... ever.
Ya know, before coming to Barden,
I had diarrhea for seven years.
But, yes, this is terrible.
The Dean is ready for you tramps.
Ladies, you have dragged the good name
of Barden University into the gutter.
And you've really upset these people who...
who's names I've already forgotten.
Your little Southern Exposure in
front of our Commander in Chief ...
has irreparably damaged the
entire institution of a cappella.
- Blew it up.
- Funding drying up.
Sponsors are pulling out.
Unfortunately, an example must be made.
It is the decision of this
governing body that the Bellas
are hereby suspended from
competing at the collegiate level.
The terms of your suspension
are laid-out in this document.
I'm sorry, but it's over.
Okay, can we be reasonable?
Fat Amy apologized,
this was an accident.
- Was it?
- You're taking us off of our victory tour?
Who's gonna sing the National
Anthem at the Puppy Bowl?
You're being replaced by
the European champions.
A German group of total professionals.
In other words,
they're gonna keep their pants on.
So, we can't defend our title,
and we can't tour?
And you can't hold any auditions.
We don't need your ranks to
grow like a fungus.
Oh, so that's it then?
So, basically, the Bellas are over?
Look Ladies, I'm sorry that this
disciplinary action has shocked you.
Especially since you're all seniors.
But the truth is,
you're just women...
and you'll all be pregnant soon.
Mom, I'm late, it's orientation,
you gotta let me go.
Well, I can't.
- I just can't do it.
- Mom, you can do it.
My only daughter leaving the nest.
You want me to stop, or I could keep singing.
Mom, I don't know how I'm gonna get
by without your spontaneous singing.
Well, Honey, you're gonna love this place.
Just promise you'll call.
Oh, and Honey,
don't be afraid to express yourself.
And not with those weird buttons
they wear in their earlobes.
- Unless you're gonna get a job...
- Slow down,
I'm not gonna go anything crazy, I'm just gonna
write my songs and join an a cappella group.
Not just ANY a cappella group,
the Bellas are an institution.
- My days as a Bella were...
- ...the best of your life.
I know, and I can't WAIT to be one.
Unless they don't take me, Mom.
Oh, no, no... no, Honey,
they're gonna take you.
Thanks to me, you were born INTO it.
Then I'm gonna be your mother,
and your sister.
Gross! Okay...
All right, the next phase of my life....
begins.
Hold on, there's nothing in here
that strips us of our national title.
And, if we're still reigning champs,
then we are automatically
invited to represent America at the
World Championships this spring.
Ah, yes, the World Championships of a Cappella,
where every four years
groups from around the globe
compete for world domination.
I'm sorry, it's just like I'm
supposed to be on, ya know?
Well, look, Ladies, we can't stop you
from going to the World's Competition,
- it's not gonna help your case here.
- Not at all.
- What if we win it?
- What if you win it?
Like... you... out-perform the other groups?
How do you fit such big
dreams in such a small body?
What if you win it?
- No...
- What if... what if you win it?
- Yeah, if we win, will you reinstate us?
- Sure.
No American team has ever won.
- That's because they hate us.
- The whole world.
The whole world hates us.
Hello, freshman sons,
welcome to the Barden University.
Get off the stage, nobody cares about it.
All right, you have made
a great choice, and a cheap one.
Yea Barden.
We have a very special
performance for you guys today,
the pride and joy of Barden University,
the Treblemakers.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
We are the Treblemakers.
I'm Jesse, and this is a cappella.
Let's do this! Yo, Treble!
♫ Sucking too hard on a lollipop,
Oh, love's gonna get you down, ♫
♫ Yeah, sucking too hard on a lollipop,
Oh, love's gonna get you down. ♫
♫ I went walking with my momma one day
when she warned me what people say, ♫
♫ Live your life until love is found
or love's gonna get you down. ♫
♫ Take a look at the girl next door,
she's a player and a downright bore, ♫
♫ Jesus loves her... she wants more,
oh, bad girls get you down, sing it! ♫
♫ Sucking too hard on a lollipop,
Oh, love's gonna get you down, ♫
♫ Say love, say love,
oh, love's gonna get you down. ♫
Oh, my God, oh, my God,
oh, my God, oh, my God.
Chloe, do not blame yourself.
You're a ginger, that's punishment enough.
This is not all your fault, it's on all of us.
So, if we don't win the World, then what
are we, just a bunch of girls who hang out?
What's wrong with that?
If we don't win,
the Bellas are over.
This is the biggest challenge
that any of us have ever faced.
When I was nine years old my brother
tried to sell me for a chicken, so...
Well, I will do whoever it takes in
order for us to get back to the top.
- You mean whatever "it" takes?
- Yeah, I'll go that, too.
That's great news, yes.
No, I could start Monday.
I would be stoked to start on Monday.
Sorry, I don't say "stoked",
I don't say stuff like that.
I'm like... I'm pretty cool, you're gonna me.
That was bad, too.
We need to attack this problem head-on.
I want 100% commitment
and laser focus, right?
Great, I will see you Monday.
Beca out.
- Beca!
- Yep!
Hey, Ladies, wanna come to a party?
It's a tootsie party, you guys don't
even have to wear shoes.
Best kind of party. Here ya go.
Great job, Trebles,
you guys killed it.
Thank you.
- You like a cappella?
- Oh, yeah, I've got my heart set on being a Bella.
It's actually at the very top of all my dream boards.
Did I hear mention of dreams,
Hi, Benjamin Applebaum, at your service, hello.
I just have to say,
you are so spirited, I...
I just want to put you in
a box and saw you in half.
For magic, as a part of a trick,
he does magic.
- Right.
- It's only weird if you don't embrace it.
Dude, explain yourself.
I'll be honest, I completely blacked out.
How did I do, Man?
Honestly, I've seen you do worse.
It's been months and we're
still getting hate mail?
- God!
- "For your hairy situation"?
Okay, we are officially registered.
Update your passports,
Ladies, because we are going
to the very sunny,
very beautiful Copenhagen.
- Yeah, yeah!
- Yes! Yes!
- Where is that?
- I don't know, I failed math.
It looks like the Competition has been dominated by
that stupid German group that took over our tour.
You mean stole our tour.
We need to scout those Deutchbags.
The, how good can they be?
Germany hasn't produced a good
singer since David Hasselhoff.
We're going to crush them,
and when we do
we can stick it to these chumps who send us
all these hate mail, like... Sonia Sotomayor.
Judgy bitch.
The Bellas are back.
D'ya'll talk to Beca today?
So, any first day jitters?
No, no, ya know, I'm just gonna be
moody and distant, artists love that.
I know I love that.
Here ya go.
Okay.
Hey, why do I feel so guilty?
I've a lot to Bellas, right?
Like, three years of my life.
Yeah, Bec, you should not feel
guilty at all about taking your shot.
- This is a big deal, right?
- Yes, it is a very big deal.
Nothin's gonna stop my girl.
I do not know him.
- X in a fex show.
- You can go.
Are you ready, or...
Okay, everybody, huddle up!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Get up! C'mon!
To the table, please! To the table!
Last one at this table has to help Frank watch
YouTube videos to find the next Justin Bieber.
Hey, so, I'm turning 25 next week,
if anybody want to get some drinks... celebrate.
Frank, Buddy, less talk.
Thank you so much.
Okay, my people, check it out.
That ...
Dax... with the tech guy... did you call the tech guy?
Yeah, I talked to him.
Do you understand, everything else in my life works.
Oh-oh.
So I just need everything
here to work,too, okay?
- He said he was gonna call me back.
- Oh, my God.
- Do you want me to call him back?
- Don't do it now.
Okay, there we go.
That is the Lion himself,
That is the legendary Snoop D-Oh-Double-G
singing "White Christmas"
at a tree lighting ceremony in Moscow.
He was so moved by the power of music
to unite the world, or some shit,
that now he wants to drop
his own cool Christmas album.
And because I sleep on a bed of Grammys,
he has decided to hired me to produce it.
But Snoop Dogg already dropped
the Christmas album.
If you had listened to his album like I did...
stranded in the air with T.I.
on a golden  hang glider,
then you would have known that
none of the songs were classics.
I've had to listen to that
album on two separate occasions,
Hang glider with T.I.,
and also a rocket ship
that Eminem has built.
It doesn't go anywhere,
but he's got dreams for it, okay?
So, I need you to close your mouth.
Herein lies the problem, everybody...
Last time I checked,
there were over a million
Christmas albums with the
same ten damn songs on them.
So, Guys, I'm tellin' you man,
I need all hands on deck right now,.
to come up with ideas on how
to make this one stand out.
Okay? You got it?
Fire when ready, I wanna hear ideas.
Anything.
Anybody, anybody right now would be great,
anybody can talk right now...
- What if we got those dogs...
- Anybody but you.
What if we got those dogs that bark
"Jingle Bells" to back him up?
L'me, l'me, let me guess, let me guess, you want those
dogs to back him up because he's Snoop Dogg?
- Yeah.
- That is a really great example.
of a horrible idea.
Take a lap.
- What?
- Take a lap.
But I'm wearing skinny jeans.
- I don't care.
Go, go, let's go, I want to see knees up.
Knees up!
Guys, I should give you a little more time,
a minute, you got one minute, 60 seconds.
My time is like a toddler in a tiara,
okay, precious and short.
I need really great ideas,
Snoop is coming.
Sorry, my boobs are all crazy,
I was just jumping.
I... I just came from auditions,
you guys weren't there,
- I was hoping for the chance to sing for you.
- No, I can't help you,
we're not allowed to take anyone else in.
Oh! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
I'm a Junk.
Whaddya say about your junk?
I'm Emily... Junk.
I know it's weird.. my Mom's last name.
My Dad's last name is Hardon, so...
I'm a legacy... Junk.
My Mom was a Bella.
- Your mother is Katherine Junk?
- Who?
Only the Top Bitch of the 1981 Bellas.
She pioneered the Syncopated  Booty Shake.
And word is she has a 5 octave vocal range.
Yeah, still does... you do not want to
hear that woman doin' it with my dad.
What an odd thing to say.
True, if a Legacy wants to audition,
we have to let her.
Show us what ya got.
Right now? Right here?
Right here, right now.
Okay, I'd like to perform an original
song that I've been working on,
I'm not quite finished with it though, so ...
let's not be dicks about it.
Sorry, that was crass, wasn't it?
- Fat Amy, you have a lovely vagina.
- Thank you. proceed.
That one I'm... I'm still kinda
tinkering with... so whatever...
So nothing is completely set.
Would you excuse us for just one second?
She's pretty good.
Can we take her?
What... what do you expect us to say,
she's standing right there?
- Definitely not a soloist.
- No.
Technically she came to us,
so we're not breaking any rules.
- Yeah, it's the perfect loophole.
- You know, it's always good to have an extra body,
Just in case one of us gets kidnapped for ransom ...
is thrown into a shipping container
and is made to eat only leaves and Gazra seeds.
Yeah, I agree, we need new blood.
I don't think we should
decide anything without Bec.
I keep a pen under my tongue.
Anyone else think that it was creepy that she
never really opened her eyes the whole time?
Again, we're talking about her,
and she's standing right there.
But if we're gonna talk negative,
let's start with the giraffe legs.
Okay, let's take a vote on it.
Anyone who wants her in, sing G sharp,
anyone who doesn't, sing E flat.
One, two...
I like the sweat shirt.
Welcome to the Bellas.
- Stop, stop, stop.
- Oh, Girl.
So, when does the new hazing start.
Tell you what,
I'll go back to my dorm and pretend
to be surprised when you
throw the hood over my head
and make me solve a Rubik's Cube
while sucking vodka from a Maxi Pad.
That's what my Mom said happened.
-  Not in here.
- You might want to look around,
we don't exactly have
a Maxi Pad to spare.
All right! Grab your guts, Ladies, it's party time!
We got tickets to Copenhagen
and a brand new Bella.
Let's go!
I should... um...
I can just leave it.
Let's go get into trouble.
This bush always been here?
- Watch it!
- You know there's a gate, right?
It sure is a stylish party.
Yeah, well, this isn't just any college party,
this is a cappella angry.
So, get prepared to meet a
lot of sexually confused men.
Bellas, welcome, welcome, welcome.
Jesse, where is Beca, I thought she
was gonna be with you tonight?
- I thought she was with you.
- Benji, right?
- Right! Slarggen.
Norf-Fless-Pan-Then.
Oh, those aren't... sorry, those aren't words.
- Movies.
- Are you asking me out?
- Yes.
- Oh, that's so sweet.
It's my first day, I wasn't really
planning on rushing in on anything.
You made it.
Yeah, couldn't miss a last good night party.
So, how was the internship?
Eye opening, yeah, he does not mess around.
Chloe asked where you were,
why didn't you tell her?
Oh, she's just...
she's, like, watching the whole world right now,
and I'm lookin' for the right time.. I'll tell her.
Bumper's back.
Campus Security.
- Bumper, Bumper.
- Fat Amy's back.
Because I never left,
because I'm still there.
But I'm back, and that's a big deal,
because I'm arrived again.
Yeah, for someone who left four years ago,
you had it to shake the money.
I've got some deep, ugly news.
- What?
- I have been hand plucked
to be put on a waiting list,
to put on a very well known
TV singing competition.
- Really?
- Yep!
I know what you're thinking...
Oh! Bumper! You shut your
face and kiss me, Bumper
- G'night.
Bumper, please, just...
That is not even how I talk.
You talk exactly like this.
- I do not.
- Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
- So, shut up.
- You shut up.
I'm so excited to meet the woman who
single handedly created the Bellas sound.
We're sisters... I can't believe we're sisters.
- Oh, yeah, hi!
- Hi!
Chloe texted me that we added a Legacy,
I didn't even know that was a thing.
Remind me again why
we are at a car show.
We are here for one reason
and one reason only...
scout the competition.
Totally gonna help us win the World's
if we know what we're up against.
All right,
now where are those tour thieves?
Stacy!
Just keep it in your pants maybe.
This all should have been ours.
I hate these Germans.
Okay, the car's moved,
nothing more else is gonna be half as good.
But they're moving backwards,
with girls driving them.
We are... we are the Sound Machine.
A German collective operating in concert
to create sonic... sonic mastery.
What better way to appreciate
automotive perfection.
They really nasty! How we gonna
compete against a group that size?
They're so frickin' insane.
Did you clap?
- We clap?
- A noisy clap.
Barden Bellas, you came here to see us?
Is it because you are...
what do the American kids say... "Jelly"?
We are so not Jelly.
We should really thank you for
making this tour a reality.
You know, with your bumbling ineptitude.
We should send them something... a fruit basket?
Or would you prefer mini muffins?
Okay, we didn't come here to
start something with you guys,
we just wanted to check you out before
the Worlds where we're gonna kick your ass.
You? You are the kicker of ass?
- Oh, yeah.
- You are so tiny, like an elf.
Or is it a fairy?
- Troll.
- That's it.
You are like a troll.
You are physically flawless.
- Thank you.
- But it doesn't mean I like you.
We are not scared about the Worlds,
because when the Bellas hit the
stage we are going to blow minds.
With what?
More of Flubby Abby's baby shoot?
- That's not my name.
- I don't know your name.
Could be anything, Obese Denise,
Inflexible Tina, Lazy Susan.
My name is Fat Amy and I
eat crap like you for lunch.
Your team is like a...
how do you say that, a heated mess.
You know, a mess where
heat is applied to it,
so what once was a little
messy is now even messier.
Darlings, please take my advice,
don't try to beat us.
You can't, we are the best.
And now I must really go and rest my neck,
it's sore from looking down.
Just because you are making me very sexually
confused, does not mean that you are intimidating.
We have nothing to lose,
we have literally nothing.
Be seein' ya, Bitches.
Oh, what is happening,
I'm using my hands so much?
All right, Ladies, focus up.
We need to beat those German idiots.
We're going to beat D.S.M. at their own game,
see what they do, just better.
And we're about to do a full scales assessment
to blow out our choreography too much.
But... the important thing
is that we have fun, right?
Legacy, don't take this the wrong way,
you're the dumbest person alive.
Is it weird that we never got
around to singing today?
Well, it's kinda hard to start
singing without arrangements
And that's on me, so,
thank you for reminding me.
Yeah, by including me about A.S.A.P. so we
can start nailing down the choreography.
Right on top of that, Chloe.
I just wanted... just wanted to let you
know that I've been working really hard on,
you know, calming my nerves
and keeping my eyes open.
I was wondering if you could
give me some pointers... maybe.
You know, with the singing, I don't really know
exactly where you're gonna put me in on the songs...
I don't mean to be rude,
I just have somewhere that I need to be.
- You did great today.
- Thanks.
Wait, hold up, just hold up for a second.
Wait? Hold up? Man, that sounds awesome
right now, what are you talking about?
Naw, It's not... it's not you, it's a tech thing.
So,  just go ahead and take five.
It better be a tech thing. 'cause...
the way I sound in my ear drums...
This is immaculate, Man.
This song, there's nothing... nothing
special about it yet, you know what I mean?
- Any ideas, because...
- Hear me out ...
- Please, Dax, please.
- We can remove the sleigh bells
and put in kalimba.
Ya know, the finger thing.
I know what the kalimba does,
I know how it's operated, okay?
- Kalimba...
- Don't say it again.
Go in the corner,
go eat your lunch in the corner.
But, what am I gonna do with my Sriracha?
Say one more hipster thing, and I'm gonna shove
you in your vintage bassoon case, okay?
Turn!
Aim higher, People, okay?
And be very careful what
you pitch to me next.
Just have him sing it again... the singer.
Who are you?
Nobody, literally nobody,
I just had a thought.
No, okay, sure, sure.
Nobody else has an idea.
Let's do it exactly the same way.
Again.
Will do, Nephew.
Or it  can be something different, I can...
That was amazing, Snoop.
Thank you so very much,
you can take a small break, Man.
Everything... perfection... perfection.
Groovy like a drive-in movie.
You can sing.
Yeah, I'm like a three time
collegiate a cappella champion, so...
We're both huge successes in our field.
Yeah, yeah, let's say that.
What do you do here?
I just get coffee and burritos and stuff.
I want to produce music.
Dax, can you do me a favor?
Turn around right now
and watch this exchange.
That's "value added".
If you have any demos, You,
I can listen to, I'll make the time.
- Oh, seriously?
- Seriously, yeah.
Dax, did you see what happened there?
She did something that was helpful.
And now I'm going to reward
her by listening to her demos.
Turn back around.
Now! Turn around, please.
So, Snoop, we've got an idea.
Me too, water skis, but for dry land.
- Real play, ya know what I'm talkin' about?
- Brilliant.
- I'll write that down.
- Yeah, please.
What am I looking at?
We're pillow fighting.
You know this sets women
back like 30 years.
Just relieving some stress.
This was on the porch.
What is that?
- Says we're invited to sing at some kind of a party.
- We're going to sing?
Finally.
Well, there's just an address and a password.
How sexy and mysterious.
I count all my teeth from other people.
Anyone else scared?
Not really, I already lived
longer than I expected.
Password?
Fart noise.
Did you not see the parentheses?
Bellas, so glad Y'all came, c'mon in.
Standing in front of you, Ladies, happens
to be the world's biggest a cappella fan.
- We found you.
- Yes, hello, here I am.
What can we do for you?
So, last week, when I just happened to tinkle,
it occurred to me... do not! Do not!
That was rude, you do not come to a
gentleman's house and touch his goose.
So, we are... are we... or...
Actually, you're pretty late.
C'mon, let's go!
This is the big time.
Das Sound Machine, two o'clock.
- Tiny Mouse.
- We meet again.
Another verbal beat-down.
The highlight of my day.
So, have you abandoned your foolish
plans to face us at the Worlds?
You wish, You Gorgeous Specimen.
- Is she really in my head.
- There we were.
I'll be happy to send you there.
I'll mail you,
A large envelope costs nothing.
Well, it would cost more than nothing,
but still cheaper than shipping
by either horse or perhaps an adult moose.
Do you ever think maybe you're too big?
It'll cost a fortune to mail you.
You... you're enormous.
I think we should change her name to
"Feisty Mouse".
Yeah!
Just need to find is, like, a taller pair of shoes.
- Hey!
What are you doing here?
What's going on?
I guess I gotta go.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Welcome to the first ever showdown of
the National a Cappella
Laser Ninja Dragon League.
Can you dig it?
Okay, let's meet our teams.
First we have the Treblemakers.
Okay, we have the Barden Bellas.
We have the Tone Hangers.
♫ Sorbet, sorbet, sorbet,
sorbet, and a cherry on top. ♫
And taking a break from their national tour,
Das Sound Machine.
And the pride of Wisconsin,
the Green Bay Packers.
I could be the vixen in that man's sandwich.
Well, here's how this is gonna work...
When I point to you,
you sing a song from one of the
categories that's gonna appear
up there on the big board.
There's only one rule,
you have to meet the beat.
But you have to do it follow-the-leader style.
That was fun.
Now... if you can't carry the tune,
the whole team's out.
As in, you're gone.
And then...
Cornelius, too heavy, I told you before
'cause I hurt my arm saluting the flag.
The winners will get...
epic bragging rights.
I'm sorry, did I not mention this?
A forty-two thousand dollar
gift card to Dave & Buster's.
Clay Matthews lost it.
Okay, all right, let's get this thing started,
let's take a look at the first category?
Songs about butts.
- I know, anything on the radio, basically, right?
- Right!
Think about what you're gonna sing.
Let's start with...
Das Sound Machine.
Stop, stop, what was that, yo.
Not! How about we keep playin' the game?
You think you're a better lyricist
than Sir Mix-a-Lot,
a man who was knighted by Queen.
- Do you know the band Queen?
- Yes.. no... no, Sir, I do not.
Just... I couldn't help it, I caught a
glimpse of an angel... I got inspired.
Well, you're goin' to hell.
Because, Treblemakers,
you are...
Four left!
Let's take a look at the next category?
Oh, Country Love.
Oh! Oh! I know all about this.
Nobody in this room has love more
tender than I have. Please pick us.
- Let me have it. - Let us have it.
- Let the world have it.
I would give it to him.
All right then, well, why don't we start with you?
Tone Hangers, you're up, you're up!
We're gonna get this, I got this, I got this.
I got it, I got it.
I tender, I got nothin', Guys.
You are such a disa-aca-pointment!
Thank you,
Reginald Wilson Vankree Matthew the Fourth.
What on God's Good
Green One are you doing?
I had my mind on those 42 gees at D & B's.
I'm afraid you can kiss that goodbye.
Green Bay Packers...
Let's see what the next category is.
I DATED JOHN MAYER
Oh, I was his personal assistant!
That's so unfair.
- We got this, we got this.
- Get in there, get in there.
Okay, then why don't we start with you,
Das Sound Machine.
That doesn't deserve a boo.
It's funny... for everyone, because
it sounds like you're implying that
John Mayer and Tina Turner are having...
- Oh, yeah.
- Get him out, get him out!
- I don't know if I believe him.
- I... I'm telling the truth.
The Tone Hangers!
There we have our two.
Yeah, we have a show-down.
All right, c'mon in,
let's do this face-off style.
Okay, take a look, see what your final category is.
90'S HIP HOP JAMZ
90's Hip Hop Jamz
Okay, Y'all,
take a second to think about it.
Time's up! Go!
Sorry... what... 90's... hip hop jamz is that again?
More like a 21st century jamz.
That's it... yeah, I wrote it.
You're saying it's an original?
Yes, I'm saying it's an original.
-  Our jam is cover.
- We spit on originals.
- What is your name?
- Emily.
Emily.
I hate you.
In light of this embarrassment,
and unprofessional information,
I am forced to declare,
Sorry, guys.
Das Sound Machine are the winners.
- Did you really write that?
- You shouldn't've done that, Emily.
Now they have something
they have to drop on us.
I'm sorry, I panicked.
I understand you want me to
crawl under a rock and die.
We don't want... hey, we don't want that.
Hey, Becs, let's go meet the Green Bay Packers.
I'm just kidding,
would you like to have sex later?
No.
So, that's a "no" then?
Because of the wink and...
It's a hundred percent "no".
Da... Dax, I swear, if this kid was not my nephew.
Hey, I know you're crazy busy,
but have you had a chance to check-out those demos?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I did.
This dead air between us is a good sign.
You got a great ear,
you proved that in the booth,
and I was super excited
to hear what else you had,
and what you gave me
was more mash-ups.
That's sorta what I do.
Listen, Reggie,
is it Reggie?
Beca... that happens a lot,
though, you'd be surprised.
Okay, here's the thing,
any kid with ears and a laptop can do that...
Dax can do that.
That's fine if you want a career
D.J.ing raves out in the desert,
but if you want to write "Music producer"
on your tax forms someday,
then you've got to have an original voice, you
understand, you've got to show me what YOU have.
Right now what I have is a
demo with mash-ups on it.
Yeah, yeah, I got lots of stuff to say,
I'm just saving it all up.
Bridget... Rebec... what is it, Beca?
- Beca.
- Okay, yeah.
You're an intern,
and everybody else in here's an intern.
You're talented,
everybody else in here is talented.
So what the hell makes you special?
Do you know what I mean?
That's good.
So what I'm gonna do...
is I'm gonna give you one more shot to
show me who you are, as an artist, okay?
Do not waste it.
No, sir, will not waste it.
I really hope you don't, for your sake,
because I would hate to think that singing
covers in an a cappella group is all you can do.
Please replace the paper towels.
Hey, it's Jesse, text me.
Hey, it's me.
Hey, so, you may not get to
hear this message because...
because I have nothing to say.
That's music industry speak for "I suck."
All right, you're definitely asleep by now.
That's cool.
Text me when you're up.
The girl can't say she's gonna grab
a smoothie and return 14 hours later?
Something suspicious about that.
Why are you up so late anyways?
I was just figuring some stuff out.
You're working on the set?
- I'm not working on the set, I'm just like...
- What?
Nothin', doesn't matter.
If you did want to
share something with me,
your best friend,
I'm a good keeper of secrets,
I'm like a safe that locks,
with a key,
and the key is stashed up my bum,
- Because...
- It's fine, forget it, it's all good.
So this has nothing to do
with that internship that you sneak off to?
Come on, Beca.
You know how you always
do that thing every month where
I take twenty dollars out of your
purse and you pretend not to notice?
I saw your I.D. badge in your bag.
Don't be mad.
I... I'm... I'm not mad, actually...
about the badge.
That money I wanna come back to.
Let's just focus on your lie.
Beca, why didn't you tell us?
Or at least Chloe?
No, just... it was just easier.
There's like so much going on and
Chloe would lose her mind
if she thought my sole
focus wasn't winning World.
Sorry, just now I'm freaking out because...
it turns out, like, totally not
good enough to be a music producer,
which is cool, and fun to know
as I enter the rest of my life.
Hey, I'm just gonna stop you right there!
You're the most talented
person that I know,
and I've met three of the Wiggles...
intimately.
Beca, do you know how awesome you are?
You're Beca F-en Mitchell.
Okay, you're the big B.M.,
that's you, you're awesome.
Do you need some of my self-confidence,
'cause I can turn mine down a notch.
- Yeah, okay.
- Then I'm gonna go  rub some out.
- Oh, okay.
- Wait,
- I think you need a bit more.
- It comes from there?
- Okay, thank you.
- You just need that.
I'm gonna get you the good stuff now.
No, I don't want butt confidence! I don't want
your butt confidence! I don't want your butt...
I believe in Beca.
C'mere.
Candles, cloth napkins,
food other than salsa.
This is a little classier than a typical hook-up.
Is it? Huh. I have a patisserie,
some charcuterie, and...
a huge bowl with exotic capers.
I didn't know what those were,
but they're like salty peas.
So... I don't know if you've
seen the news lately, but...
There's a war, and also the
economy is dippin' and ebbin', growin'.
Bumper, what's goin' on?
Now you're kinda creepin' me out.
Okay, I guess I'll just lay it all out there.
The reason I brought you here tonight...
it's because I was thinkin' that...
maybe... perhaps...
if you're interested...
This is harder than I thought it was gonna be.
I want to date you, that's what I want.
Like for real, like a real couple.
Where we, like, go out in public and
hold hands and ride bikes together.
Or we can, like,
go to an orchard and pick apples.
Or we, like, do one of those, like, build a
bear workshops together and we build bears
and we name one Bumper and
I'll name one Fat Amy,
and yours'll be bigger than mine,
it'll be two,
and we can put 'em on our bed,
that we share.
Whaddaya say?
No...
I don't want to do that.
Yeah, that's cool, it was stupid...
it was a stupid idea anyways.
Obviously, we shouldn't do that, we should
just go back to how things used to be, and just...
go at it or...
on top of all this expensive food I bought.
Are you crying?
No... I'm not.
Bumper, c'mon, you can't be serious.
I can't be tied down by anything.
I'm on a walkabout,
I'm a free-range pony that can't be tamed.
- You know.
- Okay.
I'm like a firework... Pow! Pow!
- I can't be tied down.
- Okay.
So then that's it,
then I guess that's it, right?
Because I'm not gonna...
I'm not gonna keep going on like this.
- Well...
- Fine!
Fine, if that's how you feel, then I think...
then I think we're done, I think it's over.
- That's it?
- That's it then.
- Well... so, it's over, then.
- Fine, then it's over.
Fine, then.
No... too late!
You're too late!
I figured when we didn't do the serenade,
the backup plan should be to play her off, is that...
Turn around, go back,
I don't want to hear another peep!
I'm sorry.
Hey, Guys, my first performance!
Calm down, it's just a chance
for us to rehearse for World.
As far as I can tell,
it's just for a bunch of old people
It's a full house out there.
How did we get this gig again?
They called us.
You know what, Guys,
I know we're trying a lot of new stuff,
but I feel like we're gonna get out there,
and we're gonna feel the energy and
we're just gonna nail all of it!
Sorry, these braids are so tight.
No, no, no, I don't know, I mean,
I have many, many doubts.
because if we fail this,
then we don't win the Worlds,
and if we don' win the Worlds,
they'll be no more Bellas,.
and without the Bellas,
my life... without...
Malaria.
Meaning, Flo
Three, two ...
Hey, everybody, welcome back to Let's
Talk Appella, the portable podcast edition.
We are following the story of the embattled
Barden Bellas on their road to redemption.
Trying to crawl their way back
into the public's affection.
And if they can just hold off showing
us anymore of their genitalia,
- they make it to the World Championship.
- Well, I can't un-see it.
- It's haunted me ever since.
- Well, here's a picture of it right here.
No! This should not be a screensaver, John.
Stepping onto the stage, the Barden Bellas.
- This is some exciting stuff.
- So exciting.
A lot going on up there.
I think this sound, honestly,
my senses are overwhelmed, Jay... John.
You might want to turn down the theatrics.
Let's hope there are no props.
- Oh, they brought the props.
- And there are the props.
This is more of a circus act
and not an a cappella performance.
Gail, it's as if the Barden Bellas
just don't know who they are anymore.
- Look at this.
- She's on fire.
They lit one on fire.
Beating D.S.M. seems impossible for this team.
Even these common people can see
that the Barden Bellas have no shot at reinstatement.
They are an embarrassment to a cappella
and all that it stands for.
This is what happens when
you send girls to college.
Is it?
- Is that for a class?
- No, it's just that when I get stressed,
words just sorta flow right out of me and I
try to channel them in my song writing and...
Are we just gonna ignore
what happened back there?
Guys! Hello!
The Worlds are right around the corner
and you guys are acting
like we didn't just eat a big bag of "ah".
Why are you yelling at me? I almost
burned to death because of you aca-bitch.
If you almost died it was only because
you were standing in the wrong spot.
No, Flo flipped into me.
Sure, blame the minority.
I'm black, gay, and a woman.
I'm not pointing the finger at anybody...
it was Legacy's fault.
Me? But I...
Obviously we're not gonna beat Das Sound
Machine at their game, so, we need a new plan.
At times like these,
there's only one thing left to do.
Fake your own death and flee the country.
Close! We're going on a retreat.
Look, I think that the retreat would be a good thing,
you girls need to bond heading into Worlds.
- It'll be such much fun.
- I don't know, Mom, no, it's bad.
- The girls are yelling at each other.
- No big deal.
I remember putting your godmother,
Maggie Pistol, in a chokehold
because she insisted that
George Michael was gay.
Who?
I'm just worried that my entire Bella career
will be that one terrible performance.
You know, I'll never get to
solo at Lincoln Center, you know.
But you're gonna get to go to Europe.
That would have been the
highlight of my college career.
And you girls can win it,
you have to win it.
- Just me being a Bella sounds so amazing.
- And it is amazing.
It's a sisterhood that is gonna
support you for the rest of your life.
I know you're not feeling it,
but you will.
This won't be the end of the Bellas.
BARDEN TREBLEMAKERS ARE GOING
TO BLOW UP LINCOLN CENTER
Hi, Benji.
- Emily.
Listen, I think that you're missing a word here.
Oh, God, no, no, no, no, that's not...
that isn't what I meant.
I knew it, I didn't think so.
That's really embarrassing.
And text is usually my forte, so...
- Well, it looks great.
- Well, thank you, that's really sweet...
When my hands aren't covered in... in glitter paint,
you think maybe we can try that again?
- Yeah, sure.
- All right, okay.
Well, I'll... I'll look forward to that.
- You know, let me know when you're clean.
- I... that's... I will.
- Great. -You bet. - Okay. - All right, have a good one.
Girls, move into the bus.
- Okay.
- We go.
Good luck, Benji.
BLOW UP @ LINCOLN CENTER
It must be sweet.
Nice, right?
I need to find somewhere
to charge my laptop.
- How did you hear about this place?
- From yours truly, hello, Bellas.
Oh, wow, hi, you must be Emily.
Welcome to the Lodge at Fallen Leaves.
Where Fortune 500 companies send their
employees to build teamwork skills.
You run this whole place?
You know, I realized that I had a knack for
barking orders and bending people's will, so...
I made a career out of it.
Which reminds me...
FALL IN LINE, BELLAS!!!
No slouching, no straggling!
I see you, Jessica.
It is with great sorrow and regret...
that I had to watch our
once proud organization
become a national disgrace.
- Can I have the keys to the minibar?
- Zip it!
The World signifies a shot at redemption.
You don't have a chance at winning
until you find your sound again.
You have totally lost your harmony!
So, for the next two days,
you will be doing everything
together until you regain it.
Ladies, get ready to be transformed.
You are surrounded with the
strength of your fellow Bellas,
And the support of a proud, female tradition.
and a few dozen bear traps,
so don't stray too far from the marked paths.
Okay! Great! Let's go!
Well, maybe I'll just start with a shower,
maybe a little foot rub.
Fat Amy, there are no guest rooms for you.
Then, where are we staying?
I don't understand camping,
we're voluntarily living like dogs.
This is the worst.
The air we're breathing right
now is at least 90% fart.
That reminds me,
I need to see a man about a horse.
Did anyone happen to pack a spare roll
of toilet paper? Or a moist towelette?
Anyone have, like, a tee-shirt, size extra small?
Okay, so out of the tent it is.
- What are we doing here?
- We're bonding.
You seem so tense, do you need a back rub?
Several body parts are
rubbing my back right now.
You know, Beca, we're very close,
but being under this tree
is only gonna let us discover
everything about each other.
Is that right?
You know, one of my biggest regrets is
that I didn't do enough experimenting in college.
- You're so weird.
- Bollucks.
I want to go home.
I hope the sun never comes up.
Why do I get in trouble, Pillow?
- You touching my goodies?
- Yes.
Oh, oh, Guys, I've got a little... it
won't... I just need some help getting it out.
Can you sing something,
the pipe's a bit blocked?
Thanks, Chloe.
What kinda white shit is this?
It's comin' out like fray-yea now.
Up and at 'em, Bellas! Come on!
Let's go, let's go!
Let's wake up! Let's do this!
Come on, pick up the pace, Girls.
Come on! Today we are going back to the
basics to re-learn how to sing as a group.
While also enjoying doing death
defying team building chest exercises.
- What a great idea.
- Okay, so, let's begin.
...lunch!
Because he's Asian Jesus.
Okay, that was just up the
way from being almost fine.
- Chloe, what are we doing?
- We're re-discovering our sound.
Are we?
Because it feels like we're just singing
songs that would never go in our set.
Beca, come on.
No! None of us know how to beat Das Sound Machine,
but I know it's not gonna be by doing this.
This is just an exercise in finding harmony, Beca.
Sometimes you have break things
down before you build them up again.
I've got more important things to do.
- What can be more important than this?
- Nothing, forget it.
No, you don't think that we haven't all realized
you haven't been a little checked-out lately?
C'mon, Beca, just tell her.
I heard that, tell me what?
Oh, you misunderstood me, I clearly said...
Listen, I don't want you guys to fight.
You're Beca and Chloe,
Together you're Blowie.
everyone loves to go Blowie.
Okay, I've been interning at a recording studio
and a legit music producer wants to hear my work.
God forbid I have something
going on outside this group.
Okay, so why would you keep
something like that from us?
'Cause you're obsessed, you all are.
We graduating and the only person thinking
about life after the Bellas is me.
What is so wrong if we focus on the Bellas?
This has been my family for seven years.
Yeah, 'cause you're too scared to leave!
Sack-up, Dude.
- Girl fight!
- Okay...
So, you've been lying to us for the entire year,
and now you're gonna flake out?
Now you're afraid, when the Worlds
are read right after graduation?
Oh, my God, enough about the World...
I am outta here.
Oh, okay, you're just gonna leave now?
You'll have to eventually,
Chloe, it might as well be now.
If you all knew what was good for you,
you'd follow me.
Beca, the...
Well, well, well, look who needs our help.
Not cool, guys.
No, it's not cool if you're taking
your frustrations out on us.
Emily, that's what you're gonna say to me right now?
Help me, I'm dying, I'm dying.
We need to get her down,
we need a ladder.
No, we don't believe in ladders.
They suggest it could be hierarchy that is
counterproductive to my team building program.
What kind of horrible regime are you running here?
Seriously, this whole place is, like, full of booby traps.
And guess what, boobs should never be trapped.
Unless... the support if you
have lower back issues.
It's okay, if I'm about to die,
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean any of that stuff I said.
I love you, I love all of you awesome nerds,
and I love being...
Jessica and Ashley, I don't actually
know which one of you is which.
I'm Jessica.
Don't worry, we're gonna get you down.
Focus up! Get in formation, we can do this!
Everybody, come on, let's focus,
work together as a team.
All right, Beca, we got it.
She's alive.
I sleep upside down like a bat.
Because everything's changing so fast, and I'm
putting all this pressure on myself, ya know.
Well, I don't wanna fail.
- If you would have just said something.
- Yeah, I know, but I'm weird about that stuff.
I thought I could figure it out on my own,
but I can't.
Maybe I don't have
anything original to say.
I wish I could do what you do.
Wow, I feel the same way about you.
You're so good, it's intimidating.
All I ever wanted
is to be one of you.
Not a Legacy, but a Bella.
You are a real Bella.
You're one of us,
you paid the registration fee.
That's my life, You.
Wanna collaborate on something?
Wait, are you being serious?
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
- Wow!
Man! Yes!
Who else feels like a winner tonight?
It know it doesn't seem like it,
but I'm afraid, too.
To move on, to graduate.
It's really scary.
Yeah, it actually does seem like it,
because you're barely holding it together.
Well, it doesn't have to be scary, Chloe.
When I was graduating I never pictured myself
running a retreat in the middle of the woods, but...
here I am.
Take it from someone who's dealt
with some serious control issues.
Like my dad always said, "In the minefield of
life, you must be prepared to lose both feet. "
And I think you all
know what I mean.
I don't.
Then it's decided.
this year I will graduate.
The Worlds will be my swan song.
I mean it, I'll pursue my passion.
I'll teach underprivileged children how to sing,
or I'll dance exotically,
whatever offers the most money.
Check this out!
I'm moving to Maine to get hitched,
and all Y'all can come, everybody's invited.
Okay, okay, Guys,
stop asking, I tell you.
So, after I graduate there's
a chance I will be deported,
I will try to re-enter this country,
but I will probably die at sea.
So, let's live for tonight.
Lily, any plans?
I'm just going to travel through time.
You know, when I look back on this,
I won't remember performing and competing,
I'm gonna remember you weirdoes.
It makes me really sad to think
it won't ever be like this again.
I'm gonna miss you guys.
- Me, too.
Yeah, me too.
Did we just find our sound?
I think we did.
My work here is done.
Thank you.
Fat Amy, you never told us what
you're gonna do after graduation.
No, I don't have any plans, 'cause you guys
know me, I just love living in the moment.
- Ashley, what are you gonna do?
- Actually, though,
if we were to stop and really think what
could Fat Amy be capable of in the future,
I'll tell you guys...
I'd be living somewhere, like,
sick, like Tulsa or Little Rock.
By day I'm a professional jelly wrestler...
for corporate events.
And then, every night it's just me
cuddled-up with my fiancé, Bumper, and...
Wait!
I'm in love Bumper.
Okay, I've done something terrible,
and I'm not talking about crop
dusting Chloe and Beca right now.
'Pologize for that.
Ya know, I need to go right now,
I'm running to win back my man.
Screw you judgment.
Go get him, Fat Amy.
Guys! What happened?
Shake it off, Amy.
Somebody bring a S'more.
I give you our next album cover.
Look at him,
I did it all myself, today.
- I know that I only have one vote,
- You got no vote, you're not in the Group, so...
- Okay, well, that hurts my feelings.
- It's just the truth, isn't it?
Well, that hurts my feeling with my vote,
I vote "no" to the pig,
and "yes" to this "gloriousness".
Yeah, it's great,
we'll put it to a vote later.
Bumper, I'm coming.
Nope, turn it around.
I don't want to see you.
I must've misjudged the size of this lake.
Why didn't she just
walk around the lake?
Fat Amy doesn't do anything small.
Yes, I do use my shower shoes,
Yeah, I love you, too, here she is.
Whatup, Ms. Junk?
Garu.
What are you doing?
I'm soloing here.
Whatever!
Get it the house.
I mean, we can do... do you want... do you
fell like you'd want to layer a bunch of voices?
I think in the beginning
it could definitely build,
I think it starts out light, though.
- Get your cute butt in the video, then.
- Don't tell my boss that we're in it.
Wow, this is the real deal.
Don't touch anything, Leipzig,
you're very pretty, but you're still clumsy.
Great.
Okay, so... so you... produced this?
Uh, yes, Emily wrote it.
Who's own?
- I.
- This tall drink of water, right there.
- Here... Emily.
Well, um...
I don't, I don't, I don't like it.
What it is, is, I don't... I don't like
it when people can do what I can do.
Ya know, in a matter of speaking,
it's threatening.
But you just did it.
The few notes,
that I assume that you're open to,
this is a solid demo
with real potential.
Yeah, I... I look forward to working together.
It's nice to meet you, what is it?
- Emily. - Elizabeth? - Emily. - Elizabeth? What?
Emily, thank you.
I gotta jump on a call. Yeah, oh, no.
Get in there, get in there, attagirl.
- Oh, hey.
- There it is, there ya go.
- Good job, Reggie.
- I'm Reggie.
I was so nervous,
I didn't know what to say.
Guys, we're gonna be late.
We're taking a photo with or without you, we're taking a photo with
or without you, we're taking a photo with or without you.
Everybody get together.
One-two-three...
Barden High!
Topic... so, is there a restaurant in this
town that serves something other than fish?
- Oh, I did see a KFC back there.
- No, all fish. I checked.
Guys! Over here.
Oh, Chloe, I'm coming by ya.
College graduates, spread my wings, Y'all.
So many fresh things to see.
I swear, if I wasn't recently locked down,
I would tear a hole through this city.
This place is so smelly and rainy,
why would Americans ever leave America?
Culture, design, history.
- I'm not Copenhagen this place.
- I'm hungry.
Why don't we go visit Hayden
Christian Andersen's house?
That guy, he was pretty
crafty in the Star Wars sequels.
Well, here we are.
Do you think the stage is big
enough for what we want to do?
- You're kidding, right?
- It's huge.
- You guys think it'll work?
- It'll work for us, that's all that matters.
Let's go!
Let's do this thing!
Everyone knows what it means, right?
- Here it is folks, the grand-daddy of them all.
- The World Championship of a cappella.
Tonight groups from around the globe
duke it out for the title of aca-World champions.
And of course representing America,
the embattled Barden Bellas.
The Bellas making one last attempt
to repair a damaged legacy,
by becoming the first American team
to claim the title, can they do it, John?
Theoretically yes, Gail.
Realistically, absolutely not,
those girls are dead to me.
So many countries represented
here tonight, John.
We saw in rehearsal an incredible group
from the Philippines, what are they called?
The Ladyboys.
That wasn't the name of the group, I don't
think, I think that's how they described themselves.
- That's right, they're Manila Envy.
- Manila Envy, you know,
I spent some time with some Ladyboys...
in the Philippines... myself.
- That's not surprising.
- Very interesting young men.
They do amazing things
with their mouths, I presume?
When we go back to the stage,
I'll do a few for you here.
Ya know, we can get to it.
They're right there.
Maybe when the Koreans are out there,
because no one cares about the Korean groups.
Love that barbecue.
- What are you doing here?
- You know, anything to supports the Bellas.
I'm so out of it, I can't speak, I'm so really nervous.
Don't be, you'll be great,
I mean we heard you guys rehearsing, like, 24/7.
So, I should probably go find my seat.
But... before I go, I just...
I have something for you.
I'm so sorry, I thought that was going
in a different direction, that's why...
- No, no, I like it.
- Em, you ready?
Yeah, yeah, I'll be right there.
Okay, well, break a leg.
Well done! There they go!
The Indian group, The Non Stops.
Running off stage to take
a few more of our jobs.
I thought the little one was spicy!
- And coming up next, Das Sound Machine.
- A crowd favorite, John.
Do you hear that?
They cheer... for us.
Now, don't cry too hard when you lose,
it makes your eyes puffy.
Your hands are so soft.
I'm sorry, I don't speak Loser,
what did you say?
She actually speaks eight languages,
but Loser is not one of them.
Everything must come to an end,
even with Bellas.
Take care and lose nice.
Your sweat smells like cinnamon.
Damn it!
Das Sound Machine.
They've got the crowd going wild!
Okay! Channel!
Das Sound Machine, an incredible performance,
once again from the German group.
I'm telling you, Gail, though,
if the Bellas of old show up tonight,
this could be the most significant conflict
between America and Germany... in history.
Rack a book, Jack!
Pass 'em on to your friends, here ya go.
Here ya go, Buddy.
- Thanks, Man, where've ya been?
- You have no idea, Dude.
- Final performance, Guys.
- We need to get out there and beat D.S.M.
This one's for us.
Guys,
there's gonna be some haters out there,
and they're gonna look at us,
Team U.S.A., and be like,
"Why is the most talented one Australian?"
Well, guess what, I'm fat,
so that is close enough.
We are going to show
them who we are,
a bunch of ethnically diverse,
for the most part feminine,
amazing singers.
Let's just get out there and aca the World.
John, it's possible we are watching
the last hurrah of the Barden Bellas.
It's gonna be very hard to pull this off,
and if they don't...
they are out of business as an
a cappella group... it is over.
We are Barden University's Bellas.
That's my girl.
Is it possible,
the Barden Bellas are doing an original song?
It looks like the Barden Bellas are being
joined on stage by generations of Bellas,
going all the way back to the beginning.
Simple, raw, vulnerable, exposed.
I've been called a lot of things,
Gail, but let me add one more,
- I'm impressed.
- I thought you were going to say "gay".
Oh, they have touched every person here,
they've touched me, John.
Well, everyone has touched you, Gail,
but this is something else.
2015 WORLD A CAPELLA CHAMPIONS
It's ceremonial, and you should definitely not
drink it, because it's essentially poisonous...
- terrible for you. - Okay. - Okay. - Great.
Oh, it smells like cherries and vanilla.
Okay, repeat after me,
"I", sing your name.
"I, Emily,"
promise to uphold the ideals
of a Bella woman forever.
"promise to uphold the ideals
of a Bella woman forever."
And that's it, that's the end of the speech,
it's... nothing weird happens after that.
These are for you,
don't go in the basement, it's haunted.
Wait, one more thing.
Yes, every Bella must christen the house
by sliding down the staircase.
- Seriously?
- It's tradition, yeah.
Don't worry, I'll show you.
Behold!
Crushed it!
Good one.
Now I'm ready to move on.
Legacy, you're up!
All right, I'm ready!
Let's do this!