DJ: [Singing]
Get up, get up, you sleepyheads.
Get up, get out of bed.
[Talking] Good morning
Angel Beach. lt's April 12th.
This is Gene Morrison
coming from WACN, Angel Beach...
nestled by the shore
in South Florida.
lt's a bright,
beautiful spring day...
PEE WEE: Get it up.
DJ: ...and steady on the helm.
The stars are secure
in the firmament...
and the rent's
paid for the month...
so all's right with the world.
[Singing] So get up, get up,
you sleepyheads.
Get up, get out of bed.
[Talking] Let's get out there
and get America moving forward.
lt's 64 degrees,
expected to reach a high of 76.
No rain in sight.
Good news for the beach bunnies,
but bad news for farm boys.
Now, to help you start
the day...
the singing rage,
Miss Patti Page.
PATTl PAGE: [Singing]
Tra la la...
Tweedle dee dee dee...
lt gives me a thrill...
[Knock on door]
MOTHER: Edward.
You'll be late for school.
Edward! Up! Right now!
l got things to do, you hear?
Hit the floor right now!
[Alarm clock buzzes]
[Turns alarm off]
Edward Morris!
PEE WEE: Aah! Ooh.
You be at the breakfast table
in five minutes...
or you don't play ball
this week.
[Pee Wee groans]
MOTHER: What's wrong?
PEE WEE: Nothing. l pulled
a little muscle in my groin.
MOTHER: Be careful.
Your father wants you
to drop him off at work.
Car won't start.
And pick up those clothes
at the tailor's.
PEE WEE: Ahh! lnstant eunuch.
Shit!
Ohh, it is.
lt's getting shorter!
Shit!
BlLLY:
Did you get the colored guy?
TOMMY: Does a fat dog fart?
BlLLY: What's he look like?
TOMMY:
Like an African Zulu man!
Six-foot-four,
two huge gold teeth.
BlLLY: Great!
BlLLY: Where'd you find him?
TOMMY: Works for my old man's
construction company.
Doesn't know
what l'm talking about...
but he's willing,
and he'll do it for $10.
BlLLY: 10 bucks. Not bad.
TOMMY: The broad's all set?
BlLLY:
No problem there. She's--
Jarvis, you stupid redneck!
You better duck, you suckers,
when Jarvis is at the wheel!
MlCKEY:
Billy boy, y'all get the nigger?
BlLLY: Come on, you mean
the colored guy, the negro.
TOMMY: Poor white trash.
MlCKEY: Fuck you
and the horse you rode in on.
TOMMY: ''Fuck you and the horse
you rode in on''?
That's colorful redneck humor.
MlCKEY:
Right. Kiss my rebel ass!
TOMMY: That's another one.
BlLLY:
We should write these down.
MlCKEY: lmmigrants. Go back
to Oklahoma and Michigan...
and kiss ass
with all the negroes you want.
This is Dixie, baby,
where we do things right.
TOMMY: Why don't you
have four first names...
like most hillbillies?
Like Billy Joe Jim Bob
or Flora Mae Sally Sue?
MlCKEY: l had a cousin
named Billy Joe Jim Bob...
and he was killed in the war,
so watch what you're saying.
TOMMY: l didn't know, Mickey.
l'm sorry.
MlCKEY:
Anyway, did you get the negro?
TOMMY: We got one.
BlLLY:
Guy's 6'4'', has gold teeth.
He's the meanest-looking
mother you ever saw.
MlCKEY: They'll croak
when this guy jumps out!
WENDY:
Hey, Tommy! Wait a minute.
Did you get it?
TOMMY: l found a place
with one. l'll go tomorrow.
WENDY: Don't let me down.
l'm gonna get that creep.
MlCKEY: Who's she gonna get?
TOMMY: Pee Wee.
Didn't you hear
about the other night?
MlCKEY: No.
-You didn't?
-No.
TOMMY: We figured we gotta
get Pee Wee laid...
so l fix him up with Wendy.
MlCKEY: Pee Wee and Wendy?
l thought she had better taste.
BlLLY: All he had to do
was knock it off.
They're making out.
You know Wendy.
She reaches down,
unzips his fly...
and she grabs his cock.
And guess what.
MlCKEY: What?
BlLLY:
Bastard already had a rubber on.
MlCKEY: Oh, bullshit!
BlLLY: l swear. Wendy told me.
Why would she lie?
He wore a rubber to his date.
TOMMY: She got so pissed off,
she wouldn't let him touch her.
MlNDY: Hi. My name is Mindy.
Can l ask you something?
MEAT: Yeah.
Why do they call you ''Meat''?
MEAT: Uh, l don't know.
Wendy Williams
told me l should ask you.
-She did, huh?
-Uh-huh.
MlNDY:
Why do they call you ''Meat''?
'Cause you're so big?
MEAT: Uh, yeah, sorta.
MlNDY: Not sorta. Why?
MEAT: You really want to know?
MlNDY: Yes!
MEAT:
OK. Come on. l'll show you.
BOY: Meat, wait.
She's a only freshman.
MEAT: But after this,
she'll be an instant senior.
BOY: Listen,
if you get suspended again...
you'll never get that
scholarship to Princeton.
Think about that.
MEAT:
l'm sorry, babe. Can't do it.
He won't tell me.
Ah, shoot.
PEE WEE: Wait up!
MlCKEY: Speaking of
horny mothers, it's Ready Eddie!
PEE WEE: Be serious.
l'm going tonight, right?
TOMMY: l don't know. Even
nymphomaniacs have standards.
MlCKEY:
She lives with a big black stud.
lf he catches you,
he'll cut your pecker off.
BlLLY: He's bringing
a pair of tweezers.
PEE WEE:
She likes to screw, right?
TOMMY: She loves it.
Especially young guys.
The more the merrier.
PEE WEE: What's she look like?
ls she good looking?
BlLLY: She's not bad.
She's got a great body,
moves like an eel.
PEE WEE: That's the way
l like 'em, Tommy!
MlCKEY: You like 'em
as long as they're not dead.
PEE WEE: As long as
they're not too cold.
Wait! Come here!
Let's not invite too many guys.
That way we can get her twice.
MlCKEY: Midget's not invited,
and he's making the guest list.
PEE WEE: You bastards,
l'm going tonight!
You're not cutting me
out of any free nookie!
BlLLY:
All right! You're going.
TOMMY: Shut up. Jeez.
PEE WEE:
l'm going. 8:00, right?
TOMMY: Right.
MlCKEY, TOMMY:
Wear your rubber!
That lying bitch.
TlM:
Wait. l forgot which one is--
BOY: This is the raw egg.
TlM:
This is the hard-boiled one?
PEE WEE: Getting some action
tonight, huh?
-What are you talking about?
-l'm going tonight.
-Going where?
-They said l can go.
TlM: l guess she can use you
for a recess period.
PEE WEE:
What are doing with eggs?
TlM: What eggs?
PEE WEE: Those eggs!
TlM: Oh, these eggs.
They're for you.
PEE WEE: For me?
TlM: We thought you might
like to wear one.
PEE WEE: Timmy!
Funny.
You gotta let me
do it to somebody.
TlM: l don't think
there's anybody left.
PEE WEE:
There's gotta be somebody!
BlLLY: l think we've done
about everybody.
PEE WEE: Let me do Meat.
You gotta let me.
Come on, Timmy.
TlM: OK.
TlM: Now, listen,
the one on the left is raw.
That's the one you drop.
The one in your right
is hard-boiled.
That's the one you hit him with.
PEE WEE: Left hand, raw.
Right hand, smacko!
TlM: Get him, Tiger.
PEE WEE: Hi, Meat.
MEAT: Hi. What's going on?
PEE WEE: Oh, nothing.
Oh, yeah.
MEAT: Watch it, man!
What are you, a psycho?
What's with the eggs?
-What eggs?
-Those eggs.
PEE WEE: These eggs?
MEAT:
Watch my lips. Those eggs.
PEE WEE: These eggs?
MEAT: ls there an echo here?
PEE WEE: They're for you.
MEAT:
What am l gonna do with them?
PEE WEE: We thought
you'd like to wear one.
MEAT: Morris, you're dead.
PEE WEE: l know.
TlM: Watch it, it's Kong!
TOMMY: Good morning,
Miss Balbricker.
My, you look nice this morning.
Are you losing weight?
BALBRlCKER: Hup!
MlCKEY: Hot damn! Like to live
dangerously, Turner?
TlM:
She wants a piece of your ass!
PEE WEE: Miss Walker!
BRlAN: Nice pass.
TlM: Too bad, Jew boy.
TOMMY: What's your problem?
ROY: Would l like
to get next to that.
FRED: Ah, yes. Lassie.
Lassie?
Patience, my boy.
Why do you call her Lassie?
-Why do you think?
-l don't know.
Owwwoooo!
Are you kidding?
You call her a dog?
Fred, that's angel food cake.
You touch her...
the food and drug administration
gets you for fucking food.
What can l tell you?
You can tell me
why they call her Lassie.
Get her in the equipment room.
You'll find out.
What are you talking about?
FRED: But beware of King Kong.
Wait a minute.
Come here, Fred.
PEE WEE: Hi, Miss Walker.
WALKER: Hi, Pee Wee.
Tommy, Miss Walker's hot.
She just said ''Hi'' to you.
But did you see the way
she said ''Hi'' to me?
Right, Pee Wee.
TOMMY: Boy, Miss Balbricker...
you put a lot of weight
behind that one.
Coach, would you kindly...
keep your balls off
my tumbling mat?
Beg your pardon?
The basketballs.
Would you kindly keep them
in your court?
l have little enough room
for my girls as it is.
l'll take care of that.
Thank you.
PEE WEE: Girls' tumbling team
just went in.
MlCKEY:
Those broads never shower.
PEE WEE:
You ought like that, Mickey.
MlCKEY:
What about the majorettes?
PEE WEE:
They're still out there.
BlLLY: Keep looking.
PEE WEE: Billy, Jenny went in.
BlLLY: You're not allowed...
to think about her
with her clothes off.
You aren't even allowed...
to look at her
with her clothes on!
Little dip.
Hey, Tim, l think maybe
we oughta invite Brian tonight.
TlM:
Why do we gotta invite a Jew?
All we need now
is a communist and a spic...
and we'd have the whole thing.
BlLLY:
You're really the tolerant type.
l notice
you still include yourself.
TlM: Broads are broads.
l just don't see
why we gotta invite a kite.
BlLLY: Brian's a good guy.
He's only been here
a couple months.
Why don't you
give him a chance?
TlM: He's a jerk,
and a Jew jerk at that.
BlLLY:
All right! We won't ask him.
You're a case, Cavanaugh.
PEE WEE: They just went in!
Miss Walker's with them !
BlLLY: l gotta put my shoes on.
PEE WEE: Come on!
We'll miss them !
BlLLY: You wouldn't know
what to do with Miss Walker...
even if she told you!
l'm coming!
Billy!
BlLLY: Let's go.
Come on.
PEE WEE:
Damn it! We missed them !
MlCKEY: Shh!
Shh! Kong.
PEE WEE: Damn it!
l told you we'd miss them !
BlLLY: Take it easy.
We'll get them next time.
PEE WEE: But Miss Walker,
a real woman, and l missed her.
MlCKEY: You're about to get
laid by an exotic dancer soon.
That's a real woman.
PEE WEE: Yeah. You're right.
l gotta go home and warm up.
MlCKEY: Warm up?
TOMMY: Slow down. lt's about
a quarter mile on the left.
MlCKEY: You sure
they can find this place?
TOMMY: They should
both be there already.
l took Conklin myself.
BlLLY: l drew Cherry a map.
Cherry Forever.
MlCKEY: ''Cherry Forever''?
BlLLY:
That's her professional name.
-Are you bullshitting me?
-That's her name.
MlCKEY:
Hot damn! Let's step on it!
TOMMY: Shh!
Brrrrroooo.
Hrrrr-hmmmmm !
OK.
The coast is clear.
Let's go.
BOY: ''The coast is clear.''
Do you believe this dialogue?
MlCKEY: OK, hold it!
MEAT: What's going on?
Where are they going?
PEE WEE: They're first.
But l'm sloppy second.
MEAT: Your ass! l'm second!
PEE WEE: Oh, come on, Meat!
lf you go first,
she'll be so reamed out...
nobody else
will touch the sides.
MlCKEY: Shut up!
[Arguing]
TOMMY: Jeez!
Cherry's ready.
TOMMY:
Everybody get their clothes off.
MEAT: Hey, wait.
TlM: What's this bullshit?
BlLLY: She's gonna make sure
everybody's clean--V.D.
STEVE: How can she tell?
TOMMY:
She's done this so many times...
she's practically a doctor.
TlM: Who's gonna inspect her?
BlLLY: You guys wanna get laid,
or do you wanna have a debate?
OK, l'm ready!
Ooh, l'm gonna get laid!
Yes, Virginia,
there is a Santa Claus.
MlCKEY: Come on, boys.
Hey, no stripping, no dipping!
Let's go!
TOMMY: Up, you big huskies!
MlCKEY: Come on, man.
MEAT: Relax, will you?
TlM: Hey, wait a minute.
How come you guys
ain't getting undressed?
BlLLY:
We got inspected last week.
MEAT: Lucky you.
BlLLY: OK, Cherry!
MlCKEY: Take them off.
Look sharp.
TOMMY: Gentlemen...
Gentlemen!
This is Miss Cherry Forever.
[Tarzan yell]
TOMMY: Cherry, this is Steve.
CHERRY: Hi, Steve.
Cough.
TOMMY:
And, Cherry, this is Pee Wee.
CHERRY: l'll say.
What do you use
for a jockstrap, kid...
a peanut shell
and a rubber band?
Gonna have to tie a board
across his ass.
He's liable to fall in.
You bastard, Tommy.
Save your energy, needle dick.
You're gonna need it.
OK.
TOMMY: This is Tim.
CHERRY: Hi, Tim.
Howdy.
TOMMY:
Uh, Cherry, meet Frank Bell.
CHERRY: Frankie...
That's crooked, Frankie.
You been screwing
around corners?
TOMMY: This is the pride
of Angel Beach...
Anthony Tupperelo,
affectionately known as ''Meat.''
CHERRY:
My God, the boy's deformed!
CHERRY: Let's move it out.
Yo!
TOMMY: You guys take a number
and sit down.
BlLLY: We'll just be a minute.
MEAT: Yeah, we know.
CHERRY:
That boy really is deformed.
BlLLY: l know.
TOMMY:
This is my friend John Conklin.
BlLLY: Hi, Conklin.
TOMMY: Cherry, sit down.
PEE WEE: She touched your nuts!
STEVE:
Her hands felt like butter, man!
PEE WEE: This broad is hot.
PEE WEE: Hey, wait!
l got sloppy seconds...
you got ticklish thirds,
you got filthy fourths...
you got faulty fifths,
you got slip and slide sixths...
and you scrape her
off the mattress!
TOMMY:
OK, Cherry, get it started.
PEE WEE:
Timmy, that's disgusting!
Would you stop that?
TlM: Hey, shh!
CHERRY: Ooohhh!
Ooohhh!
Don't stop!
Come on. Keep pumping, baby!
PEE WEE: We're gonna get laid!
Oh, she's hot!
CHERRY: Ooohhh!
TOMMY: They're gonna shit.
BlLLY: They're gonna shit.
BOTH: They're gonna shit.
CHERRY: Psst.
Come on, Billy.
TOMMY: Go ahead. Go on.
TlM: What are you guys
doing in there?
Give it to her!
CHERRY: Oh, Billy!
Keep pumping! Yeah!
Come on!
Keep pumping, Billy.
CHERRY: Ooohhh!
MEAT: Bingo!
Tommy, come on, baby!
Come on, Tommy!
Ha! Ha! Ha!
TOMMY: Shh! Shh!
Oh, Billy! Oh, Billy!
Oh, Tommy!
Oh, shit.
CHERRY:
Keep pumping. Come on, boys!
Come on. Yeah!
Oh! Oh, yeah!
Oh, Billy, you're so good.
l can't stand it!
Come on, baby!
Oh! Ohh! Oohhh!
Don't stop. Oh!
Oh! Ooohhh!
Oh, man, this broad
must be from Brooklyn.
CHERRY: Oh! Oohh!
Come on! Don't stop!
Ohh!
-Ha! Ha! Ha!
-Shh! Shh!
Oh! Oh!
TOMMY: Cherry, break it now.
Oooohhhh!
[Glass shattering]
CONKLlN: What's going on,
you motherfuckers?!
l'll kill you white boys!
[Loud crashing]
TOMMY: We didn't know
she was your wife!
Besides, it wasn't me!
lt was him !
BlLLY: We're just boys!
We didn't know!
CONKLlN: You're both dead men!
What's this bullshit?
CONKLlN: l'll kill you all,
you white motherfuckers!
TOMMY: Don't!
Aahh!
[Loud crashing behind door]
Oh, shit!
CONKLlN: Aahh!
Aahh!
MlCKEY: This way, Meat!
Meat, this way!
This way! Run! Run!
PRANKSTERS: Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
TlM: You sons of bitches!
Ha! Ha! Ha!
BlLLY: Wait! Wait! Wait!
Meat's still running.
Let's get him !
Slow night.
Don't worry.
That will change soon enough.
What did l tell you?
Can't wait to hear this story.
l think l know that kid.
TED: Pee Wee Morris.
The basketball player?
A friend of Mickey's--
my brother.
Well, what should we do?
Pull him over.
[Siren]
TED: OK, pull over.
[Puts transmission in park]
OK, let me see
your driver's license.
BOY: How's it going, Timmy?
[Wolf whistles]
MlCKEY: Ooohhh! Ooohhh!
MEAT:
l got something you can blow on.
Hey, Mick, it's your brother.
TED: l got something
you guys lost in the everglades.
PEE WEE: You bastards!
You left me out there!
MlCKEY: Hell, we thought
you ran all the way home.
TED: lf we hadn't seen him,
he would've.
PEE WEE:
Oh, funny. A brother act.
Tommy, where are my clothes?
TOMMY: They're in my car.
PEE WEE: Stop it, Meat!
Come on, there's girls!
TED: Cindy and l are bringing
the kids over Sunday.
See you then.
MlCKEY: All right.
TED:
Get rid of the beer, Cavanaugh.
CAVANAUGH: l'm sorry
about that, Officer Jarvis.
OFFlCER: See you later, boys.
CAVANAUGH: Tim,
you get your ass over here!
BlLLY: Ginny, why don't you
and the girls go inside?
TlM: Yes, sir?
CAVANAUGH: l heard you run tail
from some nigger tonight!
-No, we did--
-What's that, boy?
MEAT: Who is this guy?
BlLLY: Tim's old man.
TOMMY:
He just got out of prison.
CAVANAUGH: You get your ass
on home, boy! Now!
BlLLY: Should have
left him there the last time.
MEAT: What was he in for?
MlCKEY: Manslaughter.
He killed a guy in a fight.
Tore his ear off.
TOMMY: Guess my old man isn't
such a bad guy, after all.
BlLLY: What are you looking
so glum about, Pee Wee?
PEE WEE: This is serious.
l gotta get laid.
l go more than a couple
of weeks, l get jittery.
TOMMY: Then you're due
for a nervous breakdown.
PEE WEE: Oh, funny, Tommy.
BlLLY:
l don't know what we can do.
lf he strikes out
with Wendy Williams...
there's nothing left
but ham hocks.
TOMMY:
Pee Wee's tired of ham hocks.
MEAT: Maybe there's some
horny midget somewhere...
eating her heart out
waiting for Pee Wee.
PEE WEE: Meat, l'm serious.
MEAT: Just trying to help.
MlCKEY: What we need here
is some professional help.
BlLLY:
What are you talking about?
MlCKEY: Porky's.
BlLLY: Don't start that again.
You crazy?
You'll get your throat slit.
MlCKEY: All you gotta do
is know how to operate.
TOMMY:
Porky is a bad ass redneck.
MlCKEY: You guys don't know
how to talk redneck.
Porky is a businessman.
Listen, he just imported
these Cuban broads.
They're fantastic.
TOMMY: How do you know?
MlCKEY: l got a source.
He's got this room upstairs
called Porky's Pen.
You can party there
with these Cuban dancers...
as long as you show them
you know what you're doing.
TOMMY: You sure?
MlCKEY:
Does a bear shit in the woods?
PEE WEE: Let's go now.
BlLLY: We got a game tomorrow.
MlCKEY:
You need about 30 bucks apiece.
PEE WEE: 30 bucks?
Yeah, but anything goes.
Friday after the game?
BlLLY: lt's 70 miles
out in the everglades!
We got a game Saturday night.
MlCKEY:
What do you say, Turner?
Meat?
TOMMY: Well, you know my motto.
''Give me pussy
or give me death.''
MlCKEY: That's my boy.
PEE WEE:
l never had any Cuban pussy.
TOMMY: Right, Pee Wee.
TlM: ''For the man
who really measures up.''
MlCKEY: What is that?
TOMMY: Something for Pee Wee.
WENDY:
Ohh! Where did you get it?
TOMMY: This place in Miami.
MlCKEY: You're kidding me.
BlLLY: lt's a 10-gallon condom.
MlCKEY: lt looks like
King Kong's rubber.
TOMMY:
lt's for Pee Wee. You like it?
TlM: Jesus, Turner.
WENDY: Hi, Pee Wee.
TOMMY:
What'd you do now, Pee Wee?
MEAT: This little jerk
put Ben-Gay in my jock strap.
PEE WEE:
You should have seen him--
hopping around
like the Easter Bunny!
MEAT: Who looks like
the Easter Bunny now?
WENDY: Hey, Pee Wee.
PEE WEE: What do you want?
WENDY: l got something for you.
PEE WEE: For me? What is it?
WENDY:
Uh, it's kinda like a trophy.
PEE WEE: A trophy?
What are you talking about?
WENDY: A trophy for you,
my little Pee Wee.
PEE WEE: All right, a trophy.
What for?
WENDY: For being the biggest
dickhead l ever went out with.
PEE WEE:
Watch your jock, Tommy.
Watch your jock.
MlCKEY: Get 'em, Pee Wee!
TOMMY: Here you go, Meat.
Use that for a spare.
MEAT: Give me a break.
TlM: Oh, Jesus.
TOMMY: Give it to me.
Wait a second.
WENDY: Pee Wee, you love it.
Wendy, l will get you.
WENDY: You had your chance.
WENDY: You know, Pee Wee,
you never looked so good.
PEE WEE: Oh, nice face.
Get out of here.
GlRL: Oww! Oh, gross!
MlCKEY: Come on! Don't be shy!
TlM: Go for it!
PEE WEE: Tommy!
MlCKEY: They love it!
MlCKEY: Tommy!
TOMMY: Yeaa--
[Balloon squeals]
TlM: Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
MlCKEY:
''Your ass is mine,'' says Kong.
TOMMY: No shit, Sherlock.
TlM: Turner, you're dead.
BRlAN:
Great defense, Miss Cavanaugh.
TOMMY: And you thought Jews
were just smart.
GOODENOUGH:
Turner, l want to talk to you.
Get in there, Young.
HONEYWELL: See you later.
ROY: Bye.
Oh, damn.
Ohh, God.
FRED: Well...any luck?
ROY: We been out twice.
Zero, man. Zilch.
That girl wants to be loved
for her mind.
FRED: Awoooooo!
ROY: You are driving me nuts
with this howling thing.
What the hell's it mean?
Come on, Fred.
Up there, Roy.
Just get her up there and all
things shall be made clear.
You're pulling my chain.
The girl's a virgin.
Yeah, and the pope is Jewish.
So how do l get her up there?
Put a rope around her neck?
Put handcuffs on her?
Guile, charm, persuasion...
And if that doesn't work,
just ask her.
Ask her.
BlLLY: So what happened?
Two day's suspension?
TOMMY:
Two games and 2,000 laps.
You're kidding?
l'm gonna nail her fat ass.
MEAT: What the hell is this?
MlCKEY: Sheriff's office.
MEAT: Sheriff of Wallacetown?
Where the hell's Wallacetown?
MlCKEY: You're looking at it.
lt's Porky's storm troopers.
Porky Wallace, get it?
MEAT: Get this.
MlCKEY:
Come on, man. Let's go!
Thank you, sir.
[Meat yells like Tarzan]
[Boys join in yelling]
PEE WEE: Look at this.
MEAT: The pigmobile.
PEE WEE:
lt's got pink interior.
MlCKEY: All right, studs.
Everyone got their l.D.?
MEAT: Yeah, right here.
MlCKEY: Whip 'em out.
TlM: Look at this one.
PEE WEE:
l left my l.D. at home.
TlM: Wherever we go,
you always fuck up!
TOMMY:
They'll take your word for it.
MEAT: Just stand up straight.
TlM: We shouldn't have
brought him along.
PEE WEE:
l didn't do it on purpose!
TlM: Well, fuck you!
MlCKEY:
Will y'all knock it off?!
Meat, give Pee Wee your l.D.
MEAT:
But it's got my picture on it.
TOMMY: That's all right.
You guys could be twins.
Got any other cards?
MlCKEY: Use this one.
MEAT:
That's my bible school card.
MlCKEY: Who'd believe
a bible school guy would lie?
Just act cool, OK?
PEE WEE: Yeah, sure.
MlCKEY: Act like you come here
all the time...
but don't overdo it.
PEE WEE: l won't.
[Men howling and whistling]
[Country music playing]
[Singing]
The mule train...
MAN: Yeah, OK.
PEE WEE: lt's been years since
l've been to the old joint.
MAN: Yeah. Sure. A regular.
Stop talking and start drinking.
PEE WEE: Hey, how's Porky?
Haven't seen old Porky in--
PEE WEE: Holy shit.
A pussy stampede.
MlCKEY: Let's go get 'em.
BARTENDER: You want a beer?
MlCKEY:
Yeah, a beer would be good.
[Singing] Heartthrob...
Bom bo-bom bom bom...
Heartthrob...
BARTENDER: That's a buck.
TOMMY: l'll take care of this.
BARTENDER: A buck apiece.
MlCKEY: Ahem.
DANCER: Wanna take a peek?
PEE WEE: Yeah! Yeah!
DANCER: Two.
PEE WEE:
Yeah, let's see 'em both.
[Snickers]
MEAT: She means it'll cost you
two bucks to see 'em, stupid.
PEE WEE: No shit. l knew that.
l'm just having fun
with the broad.
Whoa! This broad's hot!
She's really hot!
[Singing]
She took the seat beside me...
and we rode to paradise...
Heartthrob...
Bom bo-bom bom bom...
MAN: Ha ha ha ha!
Gobble gobble gobble!
[Shouting]
BOYS: Hey, Pee Wee! Get him !
PEE WEE: Aah!
MlCKEY:
Give it to 'em, Pee Wee!
MlCKEY: Way to go, Tiger!
MEAT: You sure took care
of those guys, Pee Wee.
TlM: What the hell was that?
MEAT: That guy tried
to muff dive that stripper.
PEE WEE:
He stuck his nose right in it!
Oh ho, Mickey!
MEAT: Nyah, nyah, nyah!
MlCKEY: lt's your night, tiger.
Pick the one you want.
MlCKEY: l'll take care of it.
Barkeep,
l'd like to talk to Porky.
BARKEEP: Porky's busy.
Ain't too busy for what
l want to talk about.
l want to pay for some pussy.
Pay me.
l wanna talk to Porky.
OK, if that's what you want.
[Chuckling]
You just gotta show him
who's boss, right? Now--
ln a minute, darlin'.
Sit here and do nothing.
Don't buy any drinks.
They want you buying these
broads overpriced drinks.
PEE WEE: No kidding.
Hey, Mickey. Porky.
PORKY: Who's asking to see me?
MlCKEY: Ahem. Mr. Porky, l am.
PORKY: What do you want?
MlCKEY: My friends and l here
would like to party...
with five of your girls
upstairs in Porky's Pen.
PORKY:
You want five of my piglets?
MlCKEY: Yes, sir.
For how long?
An hour.
What you got to spend,
bottle caps?
Hundred bucks.
One hundred dollars
for five ladies, huh?
Go home, snot nose.
Hey, Porky, wait a minute!
Mr. Porky.
How many girls
can we have for 100 bucks?
PORKY:
There's five of you, right?
That's a lot of horny dicks.
l'll give you two girls
for an hour...
or three girls for 1/2 hour.
-That's all?
-Nobody's forcing you.
PORKY:
lt's a long ride back home...
and it's even longer
with a hard-on.
MlCKEY: OK, we'll take
three for 30 minutes.
PORKY: Pick out what you want.
MlCKEY: Her...
her, and--Oh, and her.
PORKY:
Hey, that's cash in advance.
TlM:
Uh-uh. l don't know, Mick.
PORKY: That's the only way
l do business.
MlCKEY: OK, no problem.
l've got it here.
Here's 20, 40, 50--
PORKY: Not me.
Pay the bartender,
you ridiculous dude.
And if any of you
mistreats my girls...
l'll personally kick
your candied asses...
back to Angel Beach.
You hear me?
BOYS: Yes, sir.
See that doorway over there?
Step through there and wait.
lt's gonna to be dark.
l don't want you
to be surprised.
MlCKEY: Wait a minute.
What's all this bullshit?
PORKY: This bullshit is you're
a pack of underaged kids...
and l don't want
my liquor license revoked!
The sheriff out here
happens to be a bad-ass mother.
l don't want nobody
to see you with my girls.
That's the back way to the pen.
Go through the door
and wait for a knock.
MlCKEY: That door there?
PORKY: That door!
Wait for a knock, step through,
and you're in.
And the girls
will be waiting for you.
You like that, kid?
PEE WEE: Yeah.
PORKY: Gonna give you
a night to remember!
You little piece of shit.
PEE WEE: See those broads?
These broads are really hot!
MEAT: They're paid to be hot,
Casanova.
TlM: l don't like this one bit.
l think we're being had.
MlCKEY: No sweat, Tim.
lt's under control.
PEE WEE:
l smell pussy behind that door.
TOMMY: l can't feel any door.
TlM: See, l knew it.
PORKY: Are you ready, boys?
BOYS:
We're ready! Ready, Porky!
Are you sure you're ready?
BOYS: Yeah! Come on, let's go!
OK, here comes
your night to remember!
BOYS: God damn it!
PEE WEE: l'm drowning!
l'm drowning!
TOMMY:
lt's only two feet deep.
MEAT:
Everything's under control, huh?
PEE WEE:
You promised to get me laid.
TOMMY:
You're a horseshit procurer.
MEAT: He took us
for 20 bucks a piece.
MlCKEY: l'll take care of this!
PORKY:
Set them up, bartenders!
Whatever they want!
Shut the fuck up!
MlCKEY: l wanna see Porky,
and l wanna see him now!
Get that piece
of pig shit out here!
How was the pussy, boys?
[Laughter]
l want a piece of your fat ass!
PORKY: Sure you do.
Let's step outside.
Fine with me, fat man!
MEAT: Hey, Mick, come on.
PORKY:
Get out of my place, you punks!
TOMMY: Mickey, l don't mind
telling you this is stupid.
PORKY: Get out of here!
MlCKEY: Let me at him !
PEE WEE: Whoa! Shit!
PORKY: Go on back
to your own damn town!
[Siren]
MlCKEY: God damn it!
Damn! Shit!
SHERlFF WALLACE: Hold it!
You better fucking freeze,
buster!
What's going on here, Pork?
PORKY: l was givin'
the old place an enema...
and this pile of shit
floated to the surface.
PEE WEE: Hey.
Shut up, boy.
Just shut up.
Looks like to me we've got
five Angel Beach assholes here.
Yes, sir.
Five walking, talking rectums.
Where's your car, boy?
MlCKEY: Right there.
SHERlFF WALLACE:
You from Seward County?
MlCKEY: Yeah.
SHERlFF WALLACE: l don't know
much about Seward laws...
but we got laws here about
driving with busted headlights.
MlCKEY: l don't have
a busted headlight.
SHERlFF WALLACE:
Don't have a busted headlight?
MlCKEY: Shit!
SHERlFF WALLACE: That's
a $35 fine or a night in jail!
TOMMY: Shit. l got 15 bucks.
PEE WEE: l got five.
SHERlFF WALLACE:
You got five, you got 15, huh?
-l got 12.
-Think l got three.
PORKY: Watch this.
MlCKEY: God damn it!
SHERlFF WALLACE:
You got a busted taillight, too.
That's 20 more dollars.
Are you covered?
MlCKEY: l got 10.
SHERlFF WALLACE: Give it to me.
Give me all you've got.
l guess l can show leniency
for first offenders.
What do you say, Pork?
Should l give
these nice lads a break?
PORKY: Oh, they seem like
a nice bunch...
of clean-cut
Angel Beach pussies.
A little smelly.
Yeah, give 'em a break.
You heard the man.
You get your candy asses
back over to Seward County...
and you keep them there.
This here's a man's county.
Go on, get the fuck out.
Go on. Go on!
Go on.
Here we go!
SECOND OFFlCER: Move it!
SHERlFF WALLACE:
Going home now.
PORKY: l don't think
they'll be coming back.
Let's go back inside
and get some beer.
BlLLY: Worst thing is
you guys are out 100 bucks.
TOMMY: This kind of thing
you write off.
Again?
PEE WEE: l got it last time.
TOMMY: Great.
TOMMY: Mick, l'm telling you.
They're bad mothers.
MlCKEY:
l'm going back to get that pig.
MEAT: Yeah, right, Mick.
MlCKEY: Yeah, Meat!
BlLLY: Mickey, are you crazy?
BlLLY: What, you a big man?
MlCKEY: That son of a bitch!
TOMMY: Hey, we came, we lost.
MEAT: What are you,
a tough guy or something?
Huh? Huh?
TED: Hi, boys.
TED: You don't look
too terrific tonight.
MlCKEY: l'm OK.
TED: l understand you tried
to butt heads with Porky.
MlCKEY: l'd have whipped him
if it weren't for that sheriff!
MEAT: That scumbag sheriff
sided with Porky.
TED: That scumbag sheriff
is Porky's brother.
MlCKEY: What?
Shit!
TED: Where were you headed?
MlCKEY: Back to Porky's.
TED:
When he kicks your ass again...
then what are you gonna do?
MlCKEY:
Go back. Just keep going back.
TED: This guy's dangerous.
He's playing around
with you now...
but he'll get tired of you,
then he'll hurt you bad.
Am l gonna have
to take you home myself?
MlCKEY:
All right. l'm going home.
Good night.
TED: Redneck.
TOMMY: Do you think
he's really going back?
TED:
Runs in the family, l'm afraid.
TlM: What's up?
PEE WEE:
He wanted to go after Porky.
TED: Just hope
he lives to outgrow it.
BALBRlCKER: The girls
are waiting, Miss Honeywell.
FRED: How's Lassie?
ROY: Lassie's fine.
She's still a virgin,
but she's fine.
You, on the other hand,
are gonna be dead...
if you don't tell me
why they call her Lassie.
FRED: Awwwooooooo!
ROY: Awwwooooooo!
[Whistle blows]
GOODENOUGH: Cavanaugh,
when you gonna learn, son?
All right, give me number six!
[Whistle blows]
Cavanaugh, get off the floor.
TlM: lt was an accident, Coach.
GOODENOUGH: Bullshit.
That was no accident.
Get off the floor now.
You're suspended indefinitely.
Nobody who plays like that
plays for me.
Move!
You all right, son?
BRlAN: Yeah.
TlM: Anybody wanna
fly a kite tonight?
l think it's great weather
for flying kites!
l wonder if there are any kites
around here we can fly?
BRlAN: Hey, listen, Cavanaugh.
lt's not kites.
lt's kike.
K-i-k-e.
Kike.
You're too stupid
to be a good bigot.
TlM: Behind the gym, Jew boy!
As soon as the coaches
are gone, Jew boy!
BRlAN: Suit yourself.
PEE WEE: Asshole.
TOMMY: This guy's a ringer.
BlLLY: Yeah.
Get him, Tim !
Come on, Timmy!
TOMMY: Nice move, Tim.
Get him, Tim !
PEE WEE: Get him, Timmy!
PEE WEE: Ow.
Jeez.
ROY: All right, Tim,
that's enough! Knock it off!
TlM: All right!
ROY: lt's over!
TlM: Let me go!
ROY: All right, shake hands.
ROY: Go on.
BlLLY: How did you learn
to fight like that?
BRlAN: When you're Jewish...
you either learn to fight,
or you take a lot of shit.
l don't like to take shit...
so l studied boxing and jujitsu.
TOMMY:
That Japanese stuff, right?
BlLLY:
How often have you used it?
BRlAN: This was the first time.
TOMMY: Were you sure
you'd remember how?
BRlAN: Well, l was hoping.
BlLLY:
Look, Brian, Tim's our buddy...
but you got to understand
he's got problems.
BRlAN: Yeah, l noticed.
BlLLY: lt's easy for him
to take it out on you...
'cause he thinks
you're putting him down.
He's not a bad guy.
BRlAN: He's a prick.
TOMMY:
You're right. He's a prick.
BlLLY: He's a smuck.
-What?
-A smuck.
BlLLY:
That's Jewish for prick, right?
BRlAN: Yeah, sort of.
TOMMY: Yeah, well, anyway,
even though he's a schmuck...
and we don't like
everything he does...
but he's still our buddy,
you know?
BlLLY: Yeah.
BRlAN: l understand.
Well, listen, l got to go.
See you guys later.
BlLLY: Take it easy, Brian.
TOMMY: So long, Brian.
PEE WEE: l'm gonna get her.
This is great.
lt's great, Meat. lt's great!
l know l got her.
[Telephone rings]
WAlTRESS: Wendy,
would you get that for me?
WENDY: You got it.
[Ring]
Deadbeats.
PEE WEE: Uh, hello. Hi.
l'm looking
for a friend of mine.
He's supposed
to be there--Shh!
What's his name?
His name's Michael Hunt.
Uh, Mike. Yes, Mike.
Mike Hunt?
OK, just hang on a minute.
ls Mike Hunt here?
WENDY: ls Mike Hunt here?
MEAT: Shit. l don't know
who thought of this.
Has anybody seen Mike Hunt?
MEAT: Practically everybody
in town from what l hear!
Hey, Frank!
Ask all the car hops
if Mike Hunt's outside!
P.A.:
Telephone call for Mike Hunt.
PEE WEE: l got her! l got her!
P.A.: ls Mike Hunt
in the parking lot?
ls Mike Hunt
Do you know Mike...
Ohhh, God!
Ohh, Pee Wee!
PEE WEE: l got her, Tommy.
WENDY:
Pee Wee, l'm gonna get you.
You little prick.
And l mean that literally.
BOYS: Ooh!
PEE WEE: lt worked. it worked.
TOMMY: Way to go, kiddo!
PEE WEE: Michael Hunt!
BRlAN:
Billy, what's wrong with Meat?
l thought he didn't drink.
BlLLY: Well, he doesn't.
But he just found out today
he got turned down by Princeton.
MEAT: Princeton sucks!
lt sucks!
BRlAN: l thought he had offers
from 60 other colleges.
BlLLY: He does, but he had
his heart set on Princeton.
MEAT:
This chili tastes like shit!
MEAT: Ohhh.
BlLLY: Oh, shit.
Pee Wee, get me some sugar
from the end of the counter?
OFFlCER:
That boy been drinking?
BlLLY: No, sir, officer.
Our friend is a diabetic.
TOMMY: Thank you, Edward,
for bringing the sugar.
How many cubes of sugar
does your cousin require...
when he's had too much insulin?
Two...cubes of sugar...
usually is enough
to bring Anthony around.
BlLLY:
Oh, feel better now, huh?
OFFlCER: Gee, uh...
l've never seen anybody
drown in chili before.
SECOND OFFlCER: Me, neither.
l wouldn't even know how
to fill out the forms on that.
OFFlCER: Yeah, you're right.
lt'd be a lot of hassle.
We better save him.
Yeah, l guess we'd better.
SECOND OFFlCER:
You know, l'm not a doctor...
but l could swear
this youngster's inebriated.
BOYS: Oh, no. No, sir.
OFFlCER: Well, if you guys say
he's a diabetic, OK.
But if we find out he's drunk...
we gonna book the lot of you
as accessories.
-He's smashed.
-Bombed.
PEE WEE: Son of a bitch
does it all the time!
PEE WEE: Ahem !
BRlAN: Officer, excuse me...
but l couldn't help but notice
what's been happening.
OFFlCER: Who are you?
BRlAN: Just a bystander.
Brian Schwartz is my name.
Don't know
if this is important...
l overheard
this poor fellow saying...
that the reason
he'd gotten drunk tonight...
was that his girlfriend
had just broken up with him.
Wouldn't you toss down a few...
if the woman you loved
turned her back on you?
SECOND OFFlCER: lf my wife
left, l'd get drunk for joy.
OFFlCER: All right.
Get him out of here,
and get him home...now.
BRlAN: Thank you, officer.
BlLLY: Will do. Thank you.
TOMMY: You're
one smooth mother, Schwartz.
BRlAN: You do what you can.
[Tires squeal and car crashes]
[Horn honks]
WENDY: lt's Mickey.
TOMMY: Porky's.
PEE WEE: Shit.
TOMMY: Here we go again.
[Revving engine]
PEE WEE: Holy shit!
Oh, shit.
BlLLY: Did you whip him?
MlCKEY: Hell, yes!
l used my face to break
the son of a bitch's hand.
BlLLY: Pee Wee,
you better go call Ted.
MlCKEY: l don't feel so good.
BlLLY: l hate to do this...
but we better get him
to a hospital.
TOMMY: l'll get my car.
MlCKEY: Hospital?
TOMMY: Mickey, where you going?
MlCKEY: l'm going home,
you son of a bitch.
Don't worry, ol' buddy.
l learned my lesson.
[Tires squeal]
BlLLY: We're gonna have
to baby-sit with him.
TOMMY: That won't stop him.
PEE WEE: You see Timmy's face?
TOMMY: Yeah, we saw it.
TlM: Shorts, shirt...
MEAT: You really worked him
over, didn't you, Schwartz?
BRlAN: Hey, l didn't do that.
Hardly touched his face,
just a few little jabs.
BlLLY: No. You didn't do it.
BRlAN: What happened?
TOMMY: His old man.
BRlAN: His father? Why?
BlLLY: 'Cause he got into
a fight with a Jew and lost.
MEAT: lt's not your fault.
BRlAN: Uh, Coach, can l talk
to you about Cavanaugh?
ROY: Oh, come on.
LYNN:
You know l don't go all the way.
ROY: Who said anything
about going all the way?
We're just gonna go up
and have a cup of coffee...
in the equipment room.
LYNN: No! No, no, no, no.
ROY:
l'll tell you a little secret.
LYNN: l already know that.
BALBRlCKER:
Miss Honeywell, do you mind?
LYNN: Do l mind what?
BALBRlCKER: lt's disgusting!
The two of you...
squirming about...
like a pair of eels in heat!
You're a disgrace.
LYNN: Yeah? lt beats stomping
and waddling around...
like a frigid hippopotamus,
Beulah.
BALBRlCKER:
What did you call me?
LYNN:
Beulah. Beulah Balbreaker.
BALBRlCKER: Who do you think
you're talking to?!
LYNN: Well, if l heard
a hurdy-gurdy playing...
l'd think l was talking
to the fat lady in the circus!
But l guess l'm talking
to a ton of bad news...
named Beulah! Beulah! Beulah!
-Look, ladies--
-You butt out!
BALBRlCKER: Moral turpitude!
-What?
-Moral turpitude!
BALBRlCKER: Read your contract,
Miss Honeywell.
l'll have you fired
for moral turpitude!
LYNN: You can take
your moral turpitude...
and you can stick it up
the old gazoo, Beulah!
ROY:
Gee, Lynn, l don't know.
Moral turpitude.
LYNN: Oh, come on!
FRED: All right, Brian.
ROY: Wh-wh-whoa!
FRED:
l'll talk to Coach Goodenough.
BRlAN: l appreciate it.
FRED:
But don't expect too much.
Come on.
We're late for practice.
LYNN: Oohhh...
Oh, smell.
Oh, smell that air.
Mmmm ! Oh, boy!
Oh, boy!
The boys' locker room
always turned me on.
ROY: Really?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah!
Yeeaaaahh!
ROY: Oh!
LYNN: l mean, it turns me on.
lt always has.
l...l don't know why.
ROY:
That's really interesting...
but why don't you
give me a hand here?
LYNN: lt always turned me on.
l really--l don't know why.
ROY: Who cares?
LYNN: Oh! Oh! Oh!
ROY: Lynn, l gotta know...
l don't know why.
Why do they...
Why do they call you Lassie?
LYNN: Oh! l...l...l...
don't...don't...
knoooooow-oooooo!
Awwwoooooooo!
GOODENOUGH: What in the world?
LYNN: Awwwooooooooo!
Awwwooooooooo!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
ROY: Come on, Lynn!
Time out! Time out!
FRED:
Ah ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
LYNN: Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Awwwoooooooooo!
ROY: Lynn! Lynn!
LYNN: Oh! Mmph! Mmph!
ROY: Shh! Shh! Ow!
LYNN: Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
ROY: Shh! Shh! Shh.
Shh...
[Laughter]
LYNN: Yes.
Yes.
Yes!
-Yes!
-Yes.
LYNN: Yes!
Yes! Yes!
ROY: No. No!
LYNN: Awwwoooooooooo!
FRED: Aw, God damn it!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
LYNN: Awwwooooo! Oh! Oh!
FRED: Ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
LYNN: Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Awwwoooooo!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
[Muffled squeals]
FRED:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
BALBRlCKER: Now!
FRED:
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ooh! Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Gas.
Ha ha ha ha ha
ha ha ha ha ha!
ROY: Sorry l'm late,
but l had a case of the runs.
Boy, it hurt like hell.
You probably heard me
all the way out here.
-Must be catching.
-How's that?
COACH: l hope you haven't
grown too attached...
to Angel Beach, Coach Brackett.
All right, boys.
Fast-break drill.
-This is the best one yet.
-What now?
All you need is a watermelon
and two jelly doughnuts.
BlLLY: Forget it.
TOMMY: l'm not taking
a shower with him.
Religious fanatics.
BlLLY:
Hey, Mickey, how's it going?
MlCKEY: All right.
BlLLY: We're about to go on
a beaver shoot. Want to come?
MlCKEY:
Nah! l got some things to do.
TOMMY: You're not thinking
of going back, are you?
MlCKEY: Hell, no! They got
some bad asses out there.
MEAT: Not to worry, gentlemen.
Tupperelo's on the job.
lf he goes out there again,
l will work him over.
When l get through with him,
he'll think Porky's his mama.
MlCKEY: l'd have to be
an idiot to mess with them.
PEE WEE: Hey, you guys!
They're going in!
Miss Walker's with them.
Come on!
TOMMY: See you later, Mick.
Right.
TOMMY: Jesus Christ.
lt's the mother lode.
l never seen so much wool.
You could knit a sweater.
This has gotta be
the biggest beaver shoot...
in the history of Florida.
-Damn it.
-What's wrong?
lt's Blubber McNeil.
l can't see a thing!
Would you be quiet?
They're startin' to leave.
Shit!
TOMMY:
Hey, beat it! Would you?
PEE WEE:
But l'm missing it, man!
Would ya shut up
and stay on your side?
GlRLS: [Singing]
1, 2, 3, 4...
Up, down...
God damn it!
Will you move it, you lard ass?
GlRL lN CENTER:
Sounds like a guy's voice.
GlRL ON LEFT:
But where's it coming from?
WENDY: ls that Tommy Turner?
GlRL: Yeah, who is it?
Who's back there?
GlRL lN CENTER: Horny bastards!
Get out of here!
Uh, don't be alarmed, girls.
This is just
your health department.
We're here to check out
all unlicensed pussies.
Please step forward
and spread your legs.
WENDY: Yeah?
What are you checking for?
Uh, originality,
neatness, and hygiene.
WENDY: lt's Tommy all right.
You better get yourselves
out of there...
otherwise, you're gonna
to get in big trouble.
Hey, if Pee Wee's with you,
you better cover his eyes.
He might get confused.
They're hot.
These broads are hot!
They want us to look!
They're hot,
l'm tellin' ya! Hot!
Well, they ain't leaving.
We'll find out.
TOMMY: What are they doing?
Shit! One's coming for it!
TOMMY: No shit?
Shit! Bitch!
Funny, huh?
All right, l'll give you
something to play with.
Tommy! What are you doing?
[Screaming]
Here, chickie, chickie!
Here, chickie!
Chickie, chickie!
Here, chickie! Chickie!
WENDY: Wait a minute.
l know that guy.
Uh-oh.
What's--what's going on?
-Tommy...
-Shh! Shh! Shh!
BlLLY: Hey, hold still, man.
She's coming for it.
TOMMY: Are you shittin' me?
She's drooling.
[High-pitched voice]
Hi! l'm Paulie the Penis...
and l just loooove to have fun.
Ha ha ha!
BlLLY: Hold still, man.
She's coming for it.
Oh, boy. She really wants it.
Here she comes.
BALBRlCKER: Ahhh...
She's almost got it.
Ahhh...
She's almost got it!
BlLLY: She's got it!
TOMMY: Aaaaahhhh!
Aah! Jesus Christ.
l got you now, Tommy Turner!
And l'm taking you
to the principal!
BlLLY:
Hey, this broad is really hot!
PEE WEE: Hang in there, buddy!
Somebody get the principal.
Somebody get the principal!
PEE WEE:
You think this means...
Tommy and Miss Balbricker
are engaged?
Shit! God...
l know it's you...
you little...filthy...pervert!
-Now...you--
-Aah!
You freak!
You filthy little pervert.
l can hear you in there.
You dirty little pervert!
BALBRlCKER: Now, Mr. Carter...
l know this
is completely unorthodox...
but l think
this is the only way...
to find that boy.
Now, that penis
had a mole on it.
l'd recognize
that penis anywhere.
[Snickering]
ln spite of the juvenile
snickers of some...
this is a serious matter.
That...
That seducer...
and despoiler must be stopped.
He's extremely dangerous.
And, Mr. Carter...
l'm certain that everyone
in this room...
knows who that is.
He's a contemptible
little pervert who's--
MR. CARTER: Miss Balbricker!
BALBRlCKER: Well, l'm sorry,
but l've got him now...
and l'm not going to let him
slip through my fingers again.
Now, all l'm asking
is that you give me...
five boys for a few minutes.
The coaches can be present.
Tommy Turner...
and any four boys
you see fit to choose.
And we...
can put a stop to this menace.
And it is a menace.
Well?
What are you gonna do about it?
MR. CARTER:
Five young boys in the nude?
A police lineup...
so that you can identify...
his tallywacker?
Please, please.
Can we call it a tallywacker?
Penis is so person--uh...
Penis is so personal.
BALBRlCKER: We can put hoods
over their heads...
MR. CARTER: Hoods?
BALBRlCKER:
to avoid embarrassment.
Now, listen.
We have got to do it...
as distasteful as it is.
l know it's him.
That...
tallywacker...
had a mole on it.
And that mole is the key to it!
MR. CARTER: Miss Balbricker...
do you realize the difficulty
of your request?
Now, l would be very happy...
to apprehend
the young man myself.
But can you imagine...
what the board
of education would say...
if you were granted a lineup...
in order to examine
their private paaa--paa--paa--
their--uh...ahem.
their--the, uh, their--
hmmm--hmmm--hmmm--
their private parts...
for an incriminating mole?
BALBRlCKER: But Mr. Carter...
ROY: Mr. Carter.
l think l have
a way out of this.
We, uh, call the police...
and we have them send over
one of their sketch artists--
and Miss Balbricker
can give a description.
We can put up wanted posters
all over school.
''Have you seen this prick?''
''Report immediately
to Beulah Balbricker.''
''Do not attempt
to apprehend this prick...
''as it is armed and dangerous.''
''lt was last seen hanging out...
''in the girls' locker room
at Angel Beach high school.''
FRED:
There you are. Now let's do it.
TlM: All right.
BlLLY: Hey, Timmy, coach
gonna let you play tonight?
TlM:
Yeah, l've been re-instated.
TOMMY: That's great.
FRED: OK, guys, hit the floor!
PEE WEE: Us little guys
need our enforcer.
FRED: All right, Cavanaugh,
get with it!
RECORD PLAYER: Any time...
You're feelin' lonely...
Any time...
You're feeling blue....
You feel downhearted...
WENDY: Beep, beep, beep,
beep, beep!
BlLLY: What's that, Wendy?
WENDY: lt's a shit detector.
Beep! Beep! Beep!
Beep! Beep!
BlLLY: That is the oldest joke
in the world.
TOMMY: l know.
l liked it.
Where's Mickey?
BlLLY: Meat's with him.
TOMMY: l don't think so.
[Whistles]
Hey, Meat!
-Yo!
-Where's Mickey?
MEAT: l don't know, man.
He gave me the slip.
TOMMY: Should we go after?
BlLLY: lt's too late now.
TOMMY: OK.
CAVANAUGH: Come on, Jew boy!
BRlAN: Hey, watch it, buddy!
CAVANAUGH: [Singing]
Louie, Hymie, Abie, Sam.
We're the boys who eat no ham.
BRlAN: Really get a kick
out of this, don't you?
Oh, you got a big Jew mouth,
just like your big Jew nose.
You're a big man...
when you're kicking
the ass outta kids...
with that sneaky Jap stuff, huh?
Why don't you try
some of that shit on me?
Come on...Jew boy!
TlM: Dad, get out of here.
CAVANAUGH: What?
TlM: You heard what l said.
Well, who you talking to, boy?
Trash, pure trash.
Now, son, that's no way
to talk to your pa.
TlM: l really wish
you wouldn't have said that...
'cause you don't know
how humiliating it is...
to have anybody know
you're my pa.
-Let me go!
-You stay out of this!
TlM: Just make sure
you're finished...
'cause this is the last time...
you ever lay a hand on me
again, you son of a bitch!
MAN: All right!
What's going on here?
CAVANAUGH: Now, you got
any more smart talk?
TED:
All right, Mr. Cavanaugh.
l think we can get you one
to three for felonious assault.
Meanwhile, l'll be glad
to finish this off the record.
TlM: No! Just let him be.
l'm not afraid of him.
l'm not afraid of you!
lf you ever come
near me again...
l swear to God, l'll kill you.
Looks like l'm gonna make
a man outta you yet, boy.
TlM: A man?
lf being a man means
being what you are...
l'd rather be queer.
ROY: l'm having you put
under a peace bond.
Come near this boy again,
l'll have you arrested.
l'll see you again.
TED: l'll be lookin' forward
to that, slime.
ROY: OK, it's over.
Let's get on back to the dance.
BlLLY: You OK?
TlM:
Yeah, l think l'll be all right.
You know you're welcome
to stay with Tommy or l...
as long as you like.
TlM: All right. Thanks.
BlLLY: Why don't you...
ROY: OK, girls, if you're
gonna kiss each other...
let's get it over with.
Otherwise, let's get on back
to the dance, right?
TlM: Right.
PEE WEE: lt's a good thing
Ted stepped in...
or l'd have torn
that sucker a new one.
MEAT: l wonder if he realizes
just how lucky he was?
TOMMY: Now, wait a minute.
Just wait one minute.
Something's wrong here.
l know what it is.
lf we could just...
Yeah.
That satisfies
my sense of proportion.
PEE WEE: Man is not known
by inches alone.
MEAT: Yeah, l got something...
to satisfy your sense
of proportion.
-l'm sure you do.
-Yeah.
[Girls scream]
BlLLY: What the hell is this
tonight--Looney Tunes?
-Aah!
TOMMY: Oh, Mickey!
MlCKEY: You should see him.
l messed him up good.
l got the pig's tooth.
ROY:
Come on. Step aside! Look out.
[Mickey wheezing]
ROY: l think he's got
some broken ribs...
maybe a collapsed lung.
Billy, get an ambulance.
No! Don't move him.
Don't move him.
Take off his sweater,
put it behind his head.
Real slow.
[Siren]
TED: l'll see you guys.
TOMMY: Hey, we're going, too.
TED: No, you're not.
lt's bad enough l was going
out of jurisdiction...
without adding a charge...
of contributing
to the delinquency of a minor.
-But--
-No buts, Pee Wee!
TED: l don't wanna see
any of you guys get hurt.
BRlAN: Nobody has to get hurt.
TED:
What are you talking about?
Nobody has to get hurt...
and your career
doesn't have to be in jeopardy.
TED: Well, l'm all for that.
What do you got in mind?
BRlAN: Look, it doesn't have
to happen tonight, right?
TED: No, it doesn't have
to be done tonight.
BRlAN: Good.
Look, let me talk to you
alone for a second, OK?
TED: OK.
ROY: Count me in.
TOMMY: You could get fired.
ROY: Are you kidding?
l gotta be the worst coach
that ever lived.
l'm long gone after
this semester, anyway.
And don't call me coach anymore.
Call me Roy.
Only 23, for Christ sake.
TOMMY: You look much older.
ROY: Why don't you go
and sit on a snake?
You see that right there?
Porky gave me that
about 6 years ago.
l've always wanted
a shot at that mother.
l'd like to feed him
his nuts for lunch.
TED:
OK. Brian's got something.
We're gonna get together
at his place 4:00 Sunday.
BlLLY: What are we gonna do?
TED: Just sit tight.
We're gonna give Porky
a night to remember.
BlLLY: Hey, Brian,
where are you going?
BRlAN: Do some reconnaissance.
TlM: Hey, Brian!
Wait a minute.
Look, when we go to Porky's...
do me a favor, OK?
Don't tell him
your name is Schwartz.
Those guys
are prejudiced out there.
All right. Um...
What about
Paddy Aloysius O'Brien?
Nah, too Jewish.
Let's not take any chances.
All right. What about
Sean Mulcahy Reilly?
PEE WEE: Wait a minute.
Go ahead.
[Country music playing]
BlLLY: OK. We're just waiting
for the guys under the bridge.
PEE WEE: Ooh! Ow! Oh, shit!
MEAT: Shh!
PEE WEE: Ow! What the--
Son of a bitch.
MEAT: Go on! Will you go?
PEE WEE: Come on.
PEE WEE: Billy! Billy!
Tommy!
[Voices nearby]
[Car doors open and shut]
BlLLY:
OK. l gotta go relieve coach.
ROY:
Everything go all right?
BlLLY: Like a precision
drill team. Thanks.
ROY: Well, good luck, kiddo.
l'll have everything ready.
BlLLY:
Get ready for Jarvis' revenge!
MEAT: Hey, you know, man,
this better work.
BlLLY: Don't worry.
[Roy whistles]
[Horn honks]
BRlAN: There it is.
Whoooahhh!
BlLLY: They're ready.
PEE WEE: What do we do now?
BlLLY: Wait.
BRlAN:
All we gotta do now is wait.
PEE WEE: Billy. Billy!
BlLLY: Whoooooo!
Whoooooo!
TlM:
Billy loves those bird calls.
BRlAN: Whoooahhh!
Whoooahhh!
BlLLY: All right.
Now, listen, you guys.
lf there's any sign
of guns or anything...
don't bother hookin' us up.
We're getting the hell out, OK?
PEE WEE:
Listen, Billy, be careful.
WOMAN: Never could get one
to fit me, honey.
[Laughter]
BlLLY: Suey!
Sue...su-su-suey!
MAN: What the hell is that?
BlLLY: l want to see Porky.
MAN: Who wants to see Porky?
BlLLY: Tell him the boys
from Angel Beach are here.
Tell him
to bring the best he's got...
and meet us
in the parking lot...now.
[Laughter]
MAN: Jesus Christ.
MAN ON RlGHT:
Do you believe that?
[High-pitched voice]
Oh, Porky!
The boys from
Angel Beach are here.
BlLLY: Remember, any sign
of guns and we're gone.
PEE WEE: Yo, Billy.
PORKY: Where are
these 5 little virgins...
that think
they've reached manhood?
You want to tangle
your ass with me?
Come up here,
you sawed-off punk!
l'll educate you.
l'll wrap this right around
your damn neck.
BlLLY: Boy, Porky.
We're really scared.
l guess we better go now.
l hope shit floats.
PORKY: You'll float if
l catch you around here again.
[Horn honks]
MEAT: Come on, Billy!
PEE WEE: Look!
SHERlFF WALLACE: All right!
Grab everything that kills!
MEAT: Gun it, Billy!
PORKY: Get them ! Get them !
MEAT: Come on, Billy, gun it!
Come on, Billy!
PORKY: Get them, God damn it!
MEAT: Come on!
Porky!
PORKY: l'm gonna kill them !
l can't swim ! Somebody help me!
[Cheering and whistling]
SHERlFF WALLACE:
Don't you son of a bitches...
know the difference
between drive and reverse?
OFFlCER:
l did have it in drive, boss!
SHERlFF WALLACE:
Get me out of here.
lt's gone.
Porky's is gone.
[Cheering and whistling]
PORKY: You're dead,
you sons of bitches!
l'm gonna get you!
l'm gonna kill you
with my bare hands!
Get that pigmobile up here!
l'm coming after you!
l'm gonna break
your fucking necks myself!
PORKY: Go! Turn around!
PEE WEE: Shit!
MEAT: Forget it! Leave it!
Pee Wee, come on!
PEE WEE: Go!
SHERlFF WALLACE:
Did you check that car out?
OFFlCER: Ain't nothing
wrong with this car, boss.
SHERlFF WALLACE:
Come on, shit for brains!
''Ain't nothing wrong
with this car, boss!''
BOYS: Come on! Let's go!
Come on! Come on! Whoo-hoo!
Whoo! Yeee-haw!
PEE WEE: Come on, Billy!
MEAT: Come on! Step on it!
SHERlFF WALLACE: Pork! Pork!
PORKY: Climb in!
Let's go!
PORKY: Where the hell were you
when l needed you?
You see what those kids did
to my club?
Hit that pig whistle.
CAR: Oinnnnnnk!
MEAT: Yeee-haw!
Come on, Billy!
CAR: Oinnnnnnk!
Oinnnnnnk!
TOMMY: Come on, Billy,
they're gaining on us.
MEAT:
Whoo! All right! All right!
CAR: Oinnnnnnk!
MEAT: All right! Come on!
PORKY: There's the county line,
God damn it!
Step on it!
BlLLY: We're gonna make it.
[Marching band playing]
MEAT: Come on!
PORKY: l want
those little mothers arrested...
and l mean, like, right now.
They just destroyed
my nightclub.
TED:
How did they do that, sir?
PORKY: They've been coming
in there the past few weeks.
TED:
Which one's been comin' in?
PORKY: This one and
that little bastard back there.
TED: You mean this
16-year-old and 17-year-old...
were in your establishment?
SHERlFF WALLACE: They've been
comin' in before...
especially
that little son of a bitch--
PORKY:
We may have made a mistake.
These obviously aren't
the youngsters.
SHERlFF WALLACE:
What are you talking about?
Are you crazy? Now, look!
Those boys just destroyed
my station house...
destroyed 2 of my cars.
l want them booked
on felony charges--
destruction of private property
and assault and battery!
-Now hold on.
-Hold on, my ass!
TED: You're in my county now!
l wonder
what l could book you for?
TED: Let's see...
MlCKEY:
Whoo! Get him, brother!
Broken headlight.
That's a $50 fine
in Seward County.
PORKY: l got that right here.
PORKY: Damn.
A blown tire. That's too bad.
CAR: Oinnnnnnk...
TED: A broken radiator.
This car's a mess.
MEAT: Do it! Do it!
PORKY: Ah, shit!
Broken hood ornament.
Any questions?
PORKY:
All right. How much you want?
TED: l'll let you off
on the promise...
that you'll get your fat ass
back across that county line...
and the promise
from your brother...
that all peccadilloes that
might have occurred tonight...
will be forgotten.
Why don't you
stick it up your--
PORKY: Promise him !
For Christ's sake,
promise him !
SHERlFF WALLACE: l promise
to shove my foot--
PORKY:
Promise him, you asshole...
or you'll be back
shoveling pig shit.
SHERlFF WALLACE: [Mumbling]
l promise.
What's that?
l can't hear you, Sheriff.
l promise, you mother--
l promise.
TED: Now get this car
out of Seward County.
PORKY:
You've blown away our engine.
We got one flat tire. How?
TED: Just put
a little weight behind it.
l'm sure you boys
can manage that.
PORKY: OK, get your shoulders
behind this thing.
[Cheering]
[Marching band playing]
[Horn honks]
BlLLY: Hey, listen up!
lt's Tommy and Brian!
Let's go get them !
TOMMY: We did it!
BRlAN: Open it!
MlCKEY: TNT!
Dynamite!
TNT Turner!
TOMMY: What a perfect ending!
PEE WEE: Yeah, perfect.
TlM: What's with him?
TOMMY: Take care of that.
What's wrong with you, Pee Wee?
PEE WEE: For God's sake,
we just blew up Porky's.
That was my last chance.
Now l'm never gonna get laid.
TOMMY: Oh, no--Wendy!
Wendy! Come here.
WENDY:
Don't, Tommy. Don't make me!
TOMMY:
You said if we pulled it off...
you'd break Pee Wee's cherry.
-Turner.
TOMMY: A bet's a bet.
Now you gotta pay up.
WENDY: l should have gotten
better odds.
PEE WEE: What do you mean,
''break Pee Wee's cherry''?
TOMMY: Look, Pee Wee,
you want to get laid or not?
lf you're not cherry,
you don't get Wendy.
PEE WEE: l'm cherry!
l'm as cherry
as George Washington's tree.
You could put me on top
of a banana split...
l'm so cherry.
MlCKEY:
He's as cherry as they come!
TOMMY: Well?
WENDY: Well...
MlCKEY: Come on, baby!
WENDY: Oh, all right.
Just don't tell anybody.
MlCKEY: Don't worry.
lt'll only take a minute.
TOMMY: All right, Pee Wee!
TlM: Shh!
WENDY: Pee wee! You idiot!
PEE WEE: Shh!
l need a rubber!
-Did l tell you?
-Aw, Jesus!
MlCKEY: Do you believe this?
Do you know how to use this?
PEE WEE: Sorry.
MEAT: lt's a ramses--
curse of the pharaohs!
MlCKEY: Hey, Pee Wee.
Hey, Pee Wee!
lt fits over your dick.
[Laughter]
PEE WEE: lt's too big.
TOMMY: We don't have
any training rubbers.
BRlAN:
Pee wee, tie a knot in this one.
MlCKEY: Junior size.
MEAT:
What do you think this is...
the return desk at Macy's?
Heeeeaaahhhhhh!
TOMMY: Oh, shit!
BlLLY: Go, Tommy!
BALBRlCKER: l saw it!
l'd know that penis anywhere!
l saw it!
Arrest him !
l can identify him !
Positively!
[Tarzan yell]
TOMMY: Jeez.