Daddy, it's 7.30!
Daddy, wake up!
Morning, Daddy. Come on, wake up!
Wake up! Come on, wake up.
- There's your coffee right there.
- Where am I?
Here, I want you to drink this.
Then take a shower and get dressed.
Your clothes are there.
Then I want you to see the woman
about the job. Today. You promised.
I know. What would I do without
you nagging me all the time?
You really want me to answer that?
Yeah, I've been gettin' in kinda late
lately. We haven't had a chance to talk.
Don't worry about it.
There hasn't been a lot to say.
- Is everything all right with you?
- Yeah.
- Is school good?
- No, but it never is.
- Have you been asked to the prom?
- No. Not yet.
When was the last time
I told you how beautiful you are?
About yesterday.
- Turn around.
- What?
You know what. Let me see this outfit.
- Is this your latest creation?
- This is it.
My God, what did that cost you?
About $15 for the shoes, second-hand,
and I made the rest.
Unbelievable.
I was thinking maybe that
you could do something with this.
- Maybe put some ruffles here...
- Come on, get up!
Really, I mean it.
This means a lot to me.
I am perfectly happy
with what I'm doing.
Perfectly happy with part-time work?
- No. That's why I'm getting up.
- OK. I'll make you some breakfast.
I'm up.
- Hi, Blane.
- Hi, Kate. How you doin'?
- Fine. How are you?
- Good.
Morning! Welcome to another day
of higher education.
- Hi, Duckie. How are you?
- Not bad, considering I'm in this dump.
This is a really volcanic
ensemble you're wearing.
- Volcanic?
- You know, hot, dangerous...
- Are you going to class today?
- I don't know if I'm emotionally ready.
Go for it. It's virtually painless.
- I gotta go. I'll see you at lunch.
- OK.
I'll call the cafeteria and make
a reservation - two by the window.
Sure.
No, you don't like to sit in the sun.
OK, something else.
Listen, may I admire you again today?
Ladies. I may be able
to work out a deal
where either one or the both of you
could be pregnant by the holidays.
Some argue that the New Deal
saved the capitalist system.
There's evidence that
the Roosevelt administration
was trying to avoid
excessive governmental power,
rather than implant socialism.
In his first act as president,
Mr Roosevelt enacted
the Emergency Banking Act,
and he refused
to consider nationalisation.
Where'd you get your clothes?
Five-and-dime store? Attractive!
Is there a problem, ladies?
- No.
Andie, is there something going on
between you and these ladies?
No, not that I'm aware of.
I'd like to apologise on behalf
of Miss Strombley and Miss Henson.
They will be thinking of you tonight
as they write a summary of the
chapters that we've just covered.
Great!
- Excuse me.
- Yeah?
There's nothing wrong with me. I'm fine.
Can you just forget about the chapter?
- Yes?
- We'll take the chapter.
Fine. Let's go on.
The Emergency Banking Act.
I'll see you guys later.
Andie, you look ravishing.
So we graduate in a month.
When are you and I gonna
get together and do something?
Try never.
- I'm talking about more than sex here.
- No, you're not.
I've liked you for four years
and you treat me like shit.
I don't understand that.
What's your problem?
Can you get off of my car?
I've been out with a lot
of girls at this school.
- What makes you so different?
- I have some taste.
You're a bitch.
You oughta see a doctor. That condition
of yours could get a lot worse.
Applause, applause, applause.
This is beautiful. It's so...
modern.
I mean, is this fab or what?
It's great.
- I'm very, very good at this.
- I know.
It's such a waste that I own
a lowly little retail outfit.
- No, not if you're good at it.
- I'm good in bed. Should I be a whore?
It's great.
- Did you say you went to your prom?
- Yeah, sure.
- Was it terrible?
- It was the worst.
But it's supposed to be.
But you have to go, right?
You don't have to.
I mean, it's not a requirement.
A girlfriend of mine didn't go to hers.
Once in a while she gets a terrible
feeling, like something is missing.
She checks her purse and her keys,
she counts her kids, she goes crazy.
And then she realises that...
nothing is missing.
She decided it was side effects
from skipping the prom.
I don't know. Part of me says
just go and get it over with,
and this other part says it's a stupid
tradition and what's the point?
Well, you know...
You could say that life itself
is a stupid tradition.
Don't analyse it. Just go.
Put that back!
- You missed my eye by an inch!
- Half an inch.
This ain't the public library, lightfingers!
I'll get it!
Trax. What do you want?
Tyrone, you blow.
Yeah, I'm workin'. Leave me alone.
That's thrilling!
I cook for you, I do your laundry,
I sleep with you,
now you want a ride to work?
Grow up!
Take the bus...
How you doin'?
- Fine.
- Good.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah.
- Can I get your opinion on something?
- Maybe.
Maybe.
This any good?
It's hot. White hot.
Good, I'll take it.
OK. That'd be cash or charge?
American Express
Platinum Card, maybe?
Cash.
You know, every time you go
to the john, you lose IQ points.
It's Walter Mondale.
- Just 7.50. There's your change.
- Thanks.
- I don't need a bag.
- No?
- Thanks.
- Enjoy it.
Bondage has no place in my life.
Since when?
Since I spent the night tied up
in the back seat of your car!
- Jena.
- Yeah?
Would you ever consider going out
with somebody that had money?
I don't think it makes
a difference. I mean...
It's material.
Simon! Simon!
What would you do if your father
came home a rich man?
- Kiss his ass.
- See?
- See what?
- What Simon just said.
What...
What are you gettin' at?
Are you goin' out with a rich guy?
- I gotta go.
- Hey, you didn't answer my question.
- No.
- Good.
Simon, it's been stimulating.
- How long have I been coming here?
- I dunno. A couple of years.
- OK, so we're buddies, we're close.
- Yeah. Very pally.
OK! So how many times
have you let me in?
- I never let you in. You know that.
- You see what I'm sayin'?
- I dunno. What are you sayin'?
- My girlfriend is in there and I'm here...
Well, she's a girl and she's my friend,
so she's a girl friend.
But she's in there and I'm out here!
You're a sensitive, sexually potent guy.
- You gotta know how that hurts!
- Let me ask you a question, seriously.
Why does she come here,
knowing I don't let you in?
- Think about it.
- I don't know.
Anyway, my advice to you is...
dump her, lose her.
You don't need that.
You see what I'm sayin'?
You see the point I'm tryin' to make?
Love's a bitch, Duck. Love's a bitch.
- Ain't it the truth?
- It's the truth.
- High five.
- All right!
Wanna try a cigarette?
Let me ask you a personal question.
If you worship the Duck, why not
hang out somewhere he could get in?
Nice Dice Man! Say hello to the wife
and kids. You know what I'm sayin'?
He's dyslexic. He gets everything
backwards. He meant to say...
- It's OK, Duckie.
- OK. You're sure?
I could clean up this parking lot
with his butt.
- No, I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
- OK.
- Were you here long?
- No, no. Three, four hours.
You have a good time?
- Good. That's good. What now?
- Bed.
Yours or mine?
- Ours?
- Nice try.
OK. Can you at least
give me a ride home?
Yeah. Get in.
Can I put my head in your lap?
Can I rest my head
on your shoulder and let you steer?
- Get in, Duckie.
- OK.
These houses are amazing, Duck.
The first million I make,
I'll buy you one. I hate this song.
- They're so beautiful.
- You want beauty, look in the mirror.
This whole tape is horrible.
It must be, like, a hormone thing.
Every song is making me sick.
I mean, why can't I find
a decent song here?
- That was my favourite.
- Are you deaf?
The house!
Yeah. That's a nice little crib.
I wonder what it's like inside.
Well, what difference does it make?
You know what the really sad thing is?
I bet the people that live there don't
think it's half as pretty as I do.
You know, Andie, I'm just...
They just don't write love songs
like they used to. I...
I'm angry about this now. My evening's
shot. Just drive me home, now.
The reason I came over, other than I'd
been planning to come and say hello,
- I wanted to talk to you about Andie.
- Yeah?
She's an incredible individual.
You know that.
I mean, I'm there for her.
Whenever, however, I'm there.
You can rest assured
that she's covered.
I don't want you to worry,
because my only plans
are to make sure
that she's taken care of.
That's nice of you, Phil.
And I'd like to marry her.
Well, not today. But eventually, I figure.
Well, does Andie know
how you feel about this?
No confirmation on that just yet.
I'm layin' the groundwork.
I'm thinkin' in terms of
housing, food, basic needs.
But I'm picking my moment.
- I mean, you understand, right?
- Sure.
I felt the same way about
somebody myself.
A girl?
A girl.
I loved her and I married her.
And one day she just split.
Wait, this was Andie's mom?
Yeah.
So I haven't seen her in three years,
you know, and...
But I still love her
just as much as I ever did, you know?
You can love Andie, but that doesn't
mean she'll love you back.
It doesn't mean she won't, but...
What I'm trying to say is
you can't make it happen.
It either will or it won't.
- It's all in the heart.
- Yeah, sure. Cardiovascular.
Yeah. I understand.
I've been to school.
Well, I got an appointment with
a vacuum cleaner. Gotta go.
You're on a whole
home-improvement jag.
- Yeah. Turning the old life around.
- More power to ya.
If Tina Turner can do it,
Jack Walsh can do it too.
Thanks for taking your time.
I really... I appreciate it.
- My pleasure.
- I'm off like a dirty shirt.
Tina Turner.
Hiya.
We just got these glasses in.
They're really...
I didn't like that album
I got the other day.
What?
- The record.
I thought it was a little too...
Too hip, maybe.
- Yeah, a little too hip.
- Well...
Think you can recommend something
else? A little less political?
- Lionel Richie?
- Nah.
Well...
- Teena Marie? Madonna?
- Madonna? That's awfully deep.
Yeah, very deep.
But she's got such great style.
Listen...
That's the alarm. Can you
hold on a second? I'll be right back.
Here. Read this. It's really good.
What is this?
Hi! How was your day?
Bet it pumps out about
300 decibels, huh?
- Did you do this?
- I'm not sure.
I was just using your powder room
and I decided not to disturb you,
so I was gonna go out the back door,
but I must have touched somethin'.
- How'd you get in here?
- Are you mad?
Yes, I'm mad! There are
public bathrooms everywhere!
I'm not nine, Andie. I know that.
It's the end of the month.
They're out of toilet-seat covers.
- Blane, what are you doing?
- Hey, buddy. Nothin'. Hangin' out.
- What are you shopping for? Records?
- I guess.
- Find anything?
- No, not really.
Are we gonna shoot some trap or
what? If we are, we gotta shake it.
I don't have any place to go. I like
coming here. Excuse me very much.
OK. I'm sorry for getting mad at you.
I gotta get back. See you later.
This is a shitty alarm system! I opened
the door five times before it rang.
That's it! I'm leaving.
I'm not gonna stay here. No! No way!
Hi. It's 6.05. Duckie Dale. Give me a call.
6.15. Duckie Dale again. Call me, OK?
Andie, where are you? This is the Duck.
Give me a call, OK?
It's 6.28...
Please call. Please, please, please.
This is Duckie. Are you really home
and not picking up?
Cos if so, I feel like
a giant asshole here.
It's 6.31. Give me a call, OK?
Duckie, I'll talk to you
in the morning. Bye.
- Why are you up? I didn't wake you yet.
- I'm fixing you breakfast.
One egg over medium,
and I fed the dog.
- Did Daddy feed you, hm?
- Your egg, madame.
I don't eat eggs, Daddy.
Why don't you eat it?
- I'll bring you your coffee and juice.
- OK.
- Since when don't you like eggs?
- Since about birth. Don't worry about it.
- You never told me why you were up.
- It's morning.
You mean why didn't you
have to drag my ass out of bed?
OK.
Well, I got a job.
- No?
- Yeah.
- Where?
- Well, I'll tell you after I start.
- When's that?
- Soon.
- I'm so proud of you. You got the job.
- No big deal.
Yes, it is a big deal.
It's a very big deal.
Listen, I gotta go.
I'm gonna be late for school.
- Tell me all about it tonight.
- All right. It'll be real good.
Hi, guys.
- How you doin'?
- Fine. You?
I'm OK. And you?
- Well, I just said I was fine.
- Oh, yeah. Sorry.
- So, is this your first time out here?
- Yeah.
I don't think I'm very popular
out here either.
I dunno. You're just fine inside.
I don't know. I'm not really
into all this shit, you know?
Yeah.
I really liked your computer trick.
- Clever, huh?
- Terribly clever, yeah. Terribly.
- Are you late for something?
- Yeah, I am, as a matter of fact.
But it's no big deal.
Listen, do you wanna go out Friday?
Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
Yeah? OK!
- Seven o'clock OK?
- Yeah, that's fine.
Great. Where do you live?
I'll pick you up.
- Where do you live?
- No, I'm sorry.
I'll be working on Friday,
so just pick me up at the mall.
- OK.
- Bye.
- See you.
Hey, Blane. How you doin'?
Hey, buddy. What's up?
- What are you up to?
- Not much, going to class.
Well, I saw you outside.
- So?
- So, what were you doing?
What are you? My mother?
Come on, I gotta go. I'll see you later.
- Blane, what's goin' on?
- Nothing.
Well, not nothing. I saw you talking
to that chick, what's her name, Eddie?
- So what do you care?
- My best friend is talking to a mutant.
I'm curious.
That's no reason to get defensive.
I'm not defensive.
I just happen to like her, all right?
Listen, all right. It's your life.
It's none of my business.
You really don't think
she's got something?
No. I really don't. I'm sorry.
You're gonna be late, buddy.
The Warsaw Pact was a treaty
signed by the Soviet Union
and seven East European satellites.
What it did was it...
it established a mutual
defence organisation as...
Duckie!
What? What, what? Well, what'd I put?
You wrote "The Warsaw Pact is the
pact that was named after Warsaw. "
The teacher'll know you're bullshitting.
OK, OK. What about the rest of it?
The Russian Revolution
did not take place in Germany.
- What was Karl Marx, then?
- He was a German.
- Well, there you go.
- Yes, but his being German
has nothing to do with where
the Russian Revolution occurred!
OK, OK.
OK, can I propose something to you
without you getting upset or angry?
- That depends.
- On what?
I dunno. I just said that. Go ahead.
You're deliberately flunking your
courses so you can stay in high school.
Get out of here! Why would I do that?
- I dunno. You tell me.
- Well, I'm not, so there's nothing to tell.
- You're not always one to face things.
- What am I not facing?
The future.
Whether or not you face the future,
it happens, right?
- You run yourself down. Why?
- I am not running myself down!
You think I am? I don't think I am.
Why? Because of the way I dress?
Cos I can laugh at myself?
That's called a sense of humour.
You should get one, they're nice.
- What are we gonna do next year?
- You think I'll still be in school.
I'm serious! Not a day
has passed in eight years
when I didn't talk to you
at least 20 times!
Well, that's devotion.
I know. Even if I sometimes get angry,
you know that I secretly love it.
You see, I knew that.
I hope I'm not the only one
that knows how incredible you are.
Well, at this point in time,
I'm afraid you are, honey.
I'm gonna get something to drink,
and then we work, OK?
- You bet.
- OK. What do you want?
- Beer, Scotch, juice box. Whatever.
- OK.
Oh, God.
I love this woman.
I love this woman and I have to tell her,
and if she laughs, she laughs.
And if she doesn't love me,
she doesn't love me,
but if I don't find out...
I love her too much!
Love is real.
Thank you, thank you.
Real is love.
You're a wonderful crowd here,
you know that.
Love is living
You're fabulous. I do love you.
You're gorgeous, I love your hair.
Love is feeling
Feeling love
Love is wanting
She's gonna laugh. Would I blame her?
- There you go.
- Thanks, but I'm gonna split.
- Why? What about your paper?
- That's what I'm gonna do.
If you help me, thanks a lot, but
it won't be my work, it'll be bogus.
And I guess I'll see you in the a. m.
Drinking and driving don't mix.
That's why I ride a bike.
So, are you going out this weekend?
I dunno. I'm not sure yet.
- What are you gonna do?
- Stay at home.
- Yeah? Are you gonna study again?
- Probably. Would you put that out?
Why do you study so much? It makes
me ill. I just don't see the point.
No? I don't wanna work
in a record store my whole life.
What do you wanna be? A doctor?
Oh, God.
OK, let's go, everybody.
Get in your lines, please! Thank you.
- Vormeister!
- Here!
Bassett!
- Bassano
- Yeah!
- Look. Watch out.
- Do we smell bad or something?
Benny.
I hope they shrivel up and fall off, OK?
What was that, Miss Homan?
I said "I hope they shrivel up
and fall off".
You hope what shrivels up
and falls off?
Her breasts, Miss Dietz.
- Shut up!
- I'm sorry.
You are outta here, Homan.
Right.
Bye-bye.
Bye, girls.
So, do you share
your partner's attitude?
No, I don't.
Eat shit.
Excuse me, Miss Dietz.
You've only got a couple of months left.
You're doing extremely well
in your courses,
and I think your chances of
getting a scholarship are excellent.
- I know this, Mr Donnelly.
- Why are you in here now?
I don't know. I guess
I just got a little fed up.
- With what?
- The way that we get treated.
Look, you're getting
a topnotch education here
and I just don't want
to see you throw it away.
I'm getting a better education
than I deserve.
I'm lucky, the good people of this
community allow me to attend here.
- Again, you are misunderstanding me.
- No, I understand everything.
I don't need to have it
explained to me. I live it.
It's just, sometimes, I get
a little upset and I lose my temper.
I don't like to see my friends getting
punished for defending themselves.
Well, we'll just forget
about this whole thing, OK?
OK.
What about Jena?
- She's off too.
- Thank you.
Andie,
if you put out signals
that you don't wanna belong,
people are gonna
make sure that you don't.
That's a beautiful theory.
Andie! Andie!
I heard what happened and I came
as best I could. I cut out of Home Ec.
- Was it really bad?
- No, it was nothing.
- Are you upset?
- No.
Yes, yes, you are, I can tell.
Your eyes get all squinty.
- I know how to make you feel better.
- I feel fine!
I wanna take you away
this weekend. Do you fish?
- OK, we can go right now.
- I have class!
- Tonight. I won't take no for an answer.
- Try, please.
This woman is suffering inside.
That's all there is to it.
Yo, man. Next time, I'll kick your ass.
That'll be that.
I'm just kidding. It's a joke.
How about that stock market?
My broker is EF Hutton,
and EF Hutton says...
You see, it never works.
I've never seen it work.
Shit!
So this is what it looks like!
This is great!
Wait a minute. Wait, wait, wait.
You got doors on the stalls.
They're not stuck.
Wait a minute! We don't have
none of this stuff in the boys' room!
We don't have doors on the stalls...
What is this?
We don't have a candy machine.
- None of that.
- Who is that screaming?
I'm sorry. I want the Principal
here this instant. Now.
This instant. I'll wait. Thank you.
Shit! Why can't I do this?
What have you done?
This... You have to subtotal first.
I tell you this every time.
You never listen.
One more tune, then it's off
to enjoy a terrible relationship.
The guy next door loves this.
Evening, young ladies.
This is a very good tune.
My mother used to sing this. I love Otis.
We're closed.
- Know what older women do for me?
- Change your diapers?
Touche. You're a very
smoky alternative,
but this is the Duck Man's love in life.
- Shall we?
- Ever had one of these?
I don't think so.
Come on! Let's plough!
Do I offend?
Andie, hon!
Listen. It's after seven.
Don't waste good lip gloss.
- I know, lona.
- I don't mean to be a bitch or anything,
but I don't think
Mr Wonderful's gonna happen tonight.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Wishful make-upping.
Wait. You babes are talking
a sign language
that the old Ducker here
just does not understand.
Would you mind filling me in?
I'm a little confused.
She got stood up, twerp!
Stood up? How so? Wait, I'm here!
Is this one of those feminine
mystique deals or something?
He showed.
Andie.
I'll get that.
- Duckie, I'm really sorry.
- Is this...
You're gonna go out with this guy?
Is this, like, a date?
Yeah. I mean, you'd like him.
He's not like the other guys.
Seriously.
No. No way. Andie!
You've really pissed me off cos they
shit all over everybody, including you.
- I can't believe you'd be this stupid.
- I'm not gonna let anybody shit on me.
He's gonna use your ass and throw you
away. God, I would have died for you!
So what am I supposed to do?
He asked me out and I like him.
If I hate him because he's got money,
that's the same thing as them hating us
because we don't. Understand?
You can't do this and respect yourself.
- You can't.
- I'll make that decision, all right?
Sure, you can do what you want!
You're saying that
just because I'm going out with Blane.
Blane? His name is Blane?
That's a major appliance!
That's not a name!
Just because I'm going out with Blane
doesn't mean I can't be your friend.
- It doesn't change how I feel about you.
- That's very nice.
I'm glad. Here's the point, Andie.
I'm not particularly concerned
with whether or not you like me.
Cos I live to like you,
and I can't like you any more.
So when you get your heart splattered
all over hell and you feel low, and dirty,
don't look to me to help
pump you back up cos...
cos maybe for the first time
in your life, I won't be there.
I can't believe
you're actually saying this.
Well, I guess that's just tough shit.
- Sorry.
- That guy in the store...
- He was a friend of mine.
I've known him since I was a kid.
He's a really nice guy.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I like him a lot.
So, you wanna go home and change?
I already did.
- Sorry.
- That's OK.
So, where are we going?
You up for a party?
Yeah? No? Maybe?
No, I don't think so.
- Why?
- They're my friends. It's OK.
- Your friends.
I wouldn't go
if I didn't think they'd accept you.
Can't we go somewhere else?
Andie, I like you. I think you like me.
We know a lot of bullshit goes on,
but if you're above it, I am.
If we want to make anything out of this,
we gotta deal with it, right?
- Yeah.
- Come on, I got as much to lose as you.
We can go out with your friends if you
want. We could go crawl under a rock.
Anything you want. The choice is yours.
- We could go hang-gliding.
- I've never been hang-gliding.
Well, there's a first for everything.
If it's a bad time, we leave.
- Hi, Blane.
- Hey, Eddie.
Aren't you the girl in my art class?
Nice pearls.
This isn't a dinner party, honey.
Watch it.
- Hey, Blane. How you doin'?
- Hey, Kev, what's up?
I can't believe I actually
associate with these people.
I can't believe that I'm actually here.
- Pretty bad, yeah?
- Yeah, it's pretty bad.
I'm sorry.
Let's go upstairs, huh?
Come on.
I didn't come here to get you off.
That was not my idea.
That's not what I meant.
I haven't even tried to kiss you, have I?
Look, it's quieter up there, OK?
Come on. These hands will remain
in these pockets, I swear to God.
Look at me here. Come on.
I'm utterly defenceless.
And utterly foolish. Come on.
- What do you think of these carpets?
- They're fab.
This is gonna be great.
- Hey, Blane.
- Steff.
- How you doin'?
- All right.
- I'll get another room.
- No, come on in.
I'm just watching some 'toons here.
Who you got with you here, Blane?
Andie, this is Steff. Steff, Andie.
It's very nice to meet you, Andie.
Listen, you wanna come sit down?
Or you want the bed?
No! No, we're fine.
Come and have a drink.
Can I get you something?
This is my last serious party
of my high school career.
Hope you guys are gonna tough it out
until Sunday when my folks get home.
I think this one may just finally
kill the old son of a bitch, Blane.
Another giant step away from virginity.
You're a slut, aren't you, Benny?
Oh, my God.
- Am I having a nightmare?
- We got guests.
I know you. You're in my calculus class.
- Gym.
- Your name's Jim?
You are worthless, aren't you?
You and your friends gave me
a lot of shit the other day.