Mr. Taransky...?
She's...
She's walking?
Don't tell me
She’s walking.
She can't walk.
- Nicola!
- This, this...
- Not this.
- Nicola!
- How was your massage?
- You're in breach.
- Cigarette.
- Is this about the new pages?
Because I made
the changes,
all the changes
you wanted.
You are virtually
in every scene.
It is not the size
of the role, Viktor.
Am l, or am I not
entitled
to the biggest trailer
on the lot? hmm?
It's the biggest
on earth.
I swear.
It's a 50-foot
Airstream.
They don't make them
any longer.
- Taller, Viktor.
- Taller?
- Taller!
- What?
Eh.
You've insulted me
for the last time.
You're right.
It's actually...
It's actually taller.
- You're right. It's amazing.
- Coffee!
Wait a minute.
The tires are
over inflated.
See? It's just this.
See? Look. here.
- The air comes right out.
- This is sad.
See? It's lower already.
Nicola, I beg you.
Don't do this to me.
You know,
I had three other offers.
I only signed on
to this picture...
- Out of loyalty.
- Well, then show me some.
They're going
to shut me down!
It's not working, Viktor.
I mean, my God!
The scene
with the thousand geese?!
I don't understand
this film!
Nobody is going
to understand this film.
I already put out a press release
citing creative differences.
So just let it go.
You went to the press?
Do we have everything?
All right.
You know what?
You're right.
You are right.
And when you're right, you're right.
- Thank you.
- Let me help you with these.
'Cause you oughta go.
- I don't deserve you.
- Oh.
This film doesn't
deserve you.
It deserves much,
much better than you!
Creative differences?
The difference is
you're not creative.
To hell, please.
Jack?
Jack, are you there?
She's good.
You can hardly tell
she's reading off a teleprompter.
I'm right here.
Right beside you.
Look.
I've analyzed this footage.
We've got everything
we need in the can already.
If I could just make
the proper adjustments,
we can finish
this film without her.
Viktor, according to the writ
her attorneys filed at noon today,
they'll sue if the film is released
with N icola in a single frame.
They will sue, Viktor.
They're serious.
So let's recast.
N icola Anders is
the only actress in the world
that could play that part.
- It's a remake, Hal.
- That's right.
N icola Anders is not
bigger than this picture.
Of course she is, Viktor.
No other name is going
to sign on now.
Who needs a name?
We'll cast an unknown.
I'm not going to play
opposite an unknown.
- We can't sell an unknown.
- The numbers don't work.
If we ever want to be in
the N icola Anders business again,
we have to cut our losses
and shelve the picture.
No!
I will not give in to that
blackmailing...
Viktor,
let's take a walk.
Ridiculous performance.
I told you she was bad.
No, yours in there.
Why do you always have to make
things so difficult for yourself?
Difficult?
I'm being difficult?
Yes. Mm-hmm.
Elaine, do you know
what these are?
Mike 'n' Ike's?
They're not just any
Mike 'n' Ike's,
These are cherry
Mike 'n' Ike's.
Do you know why l,
Viktor Taransky,
two-time Academy Award
nominated director...
Viktor, that was "Short Subject."
...overseeing the most cherished
movie project of my entire career,
am walking around with...
look, look, look...
pockets full
of these... things?!
I have a feeling
you're going to tell me.
I'm going to tell you why.
Because Ms. N icola Anders,
supermodel
with a SAG card,
has it written
in her contract
that all cherry
Mike 'n' Ike's
be removed
from her candy dish,
along with strict instructions
that any room she walks into
must have seven packs
of cigarettes waiting for her...
three of them opened;
that there be
a personal Jacuzzi
within 80 paces
of her dressing room;
and that any time
she travels,
her nanny must fly
with her first-class.
So, what's wrong
with that?
Elaine, she doesn't
have children.
Don't you see?
They're mocking us.
They're mocking...
we're at their mercy.
What happened?
I mean, we always had movie stars,
but they used to be
our stars, remember?
We were the ones who would
tell them what to do.
And we would tell them
what to wear,
- Who to date...
- That's what you want?!
When they
were under contract to us,
we could change their names
if we wanted to.
- More than once.
- Viktor,
do you realize
you're nostalgic
for an era you weren't
even born in?!
I do remember why I got
into this business.
- You seem to have forgotten.
- Oh, please. Come on.
N ew York... Cassavetes.
Remember?
- here we go.
- What were we doing?
We were trying to make
something important.
I don't know.
Shine a little light
in that darkened cinema.
It's called a projector.
Illuminate hearts and minds
with a ray of truth.
I thought that's
what we were doing.
I have good memories
of those days, too.
I do, but this isn't
about that...
or you, or me,
or some high-minded ideal.
This is business.
- Spare me.
- Look around.
Who do you think pays
for all of this?
This is about investment
and return.
I'm not interested
in investment and return!
in who pays for anything!
I'm trying to make a movie!
I'm responsible
for this, Viktor.
Those days
in N ew York...
It's over, Viktor.
You're not renewing
my contract?
How can I?!
Your last three pictures tanked.
No bankable star is going
to work with you after this.
I mean, if you just
compromised a little.
Well, it's not every day
you're fired
by the mother
of your own child.
You and I both know
that I kept you on
after the divorce
for old time's sake.
And so you could still hold
your head up in front of Lainey.
- I fought for you.
- Yeah, well...
I'm sorry, Viktor.
Dad!
- Sweetheart.
- hey, Dad.
- How are you, honey?
- Good.
I'm sorry Mom canned you.
I'm going to finish
this picture.
Lainey, I'm going
to finish it.
Because it's important.
I know you will, Dad.
You'reviktor Taransky.
I'm Viktor Taransky.
'Kay.
By e, Dad.
- hi, sweetheart.
- hey, Mom.
Are you okay?
I'm Viktor Taransky.
Mr. Taransky?
Mr. Taransky,
thank God.
I've been trying
to see you.
I've been calling.
Your assistant
won't put me through.
I told her it was a matter
of life and death.
I was afraid I wasn't going
to get to you in time.
Please, just...
- Keep your distance.
- I did it!
I did it!
I licked skin,
I licked hair,
- I licked every part of her.
- I'm going to call security.
I'll call security
if you don't back off.
I have her,
Mr. Taransky.
The answer
to your pray ers.
- The answer to this.
- I was misquoted.
I have your new leading-lady
right here.
In my pants.
Please, sir,
I don't know you.
- I don't know where you come from...
- It's me!
Mr. Taransky, don't...
Don't you recognize me?
The Future of Film Conference
in San Jose.
Remember that?
Hank.
Hank Aleno.
I was a keynote speaker.
You must remember my speech.
- "Who N eeds humans? "
- Right.
You were booed off
the stage.
- Whoa, that's got to be...
- Eight y ears ago.
And that whole time
I never left my computer.
U h-huh.
Good for you, Hank.
Well, it's good
and bad.
That's what caused this.
The ey e tumor.
- Microwaves from the s creen.
- I'm sorry.
Don't be,
because it was worth it.
You have to see her.
Oh, I've seen those.
- Not like this.
- I'll take care of that.
Yeah, well, you're talking
about a "s yn-thespian."
- A virtual actor.
- No, we call them "v ac-tors."
"Vac-tors"?
I need flesh.
- Flesh is weak.
- It can't be done.
It can be done.
With my new computer code,
it can be done.
You and me...
we can do this together.
I don't know anything
about computers.
See, that's why...
that's why you're so perfect.
You have something...
- That I don't have.
- What's that?
An ey e.
An ey e for performance.
You know the truth
when you see it.
I know.
I mean, I've seen
your movies.
I love your movies.
- You love my movies?
- "Straw God."
That changed my life.
You saw "Straw God"?
I have seen every frame
of your work.
You're the only
filmmaker
with the artistic
integrity...
to realize my vision.
You and me,
art and s cience...
We're the perfect
marriage.
Hank...
I've had
a rough day today.
But, I tell you what,
I'll call you
about this next week.
- We can talk.
- I won't be here in a week.
- The tumor is inoperable.
- I'll call you about it, okay?
That's what I'm trying to say.
The tumor is inoperable.
I'll be dead.
Well, I'm already dead.
Call me!
This week!
Please.
What do you mean
she won't work with me?
She's done nothing.
She doesn't have
a single credit to her name.
Better no credits
than a Taransky credit.
Art,
you don't understand.
I've mortgaged everything
to finish this film.
The creditors
are calling me.
they're at the door
for God's sake.
hello?
Damn it!
Mr. Taransky.
Mr. Taransky!
- Mr. Taransky!
- No, I'm not him!
- I'm not him!
Mr. Taransky!
Hank Aleno!
I represent the estate
of Mr. Hank Aleno.
It was his last wish
that you have this.
What is it?
I have no idea.
he wanted you
to have it.
Valarie!
Valarie,
what are you running from?
From Valarie.
Jack, are you there?
Something like this
can happen and what...
was it for?
Why are we here?
Is that what
you're asking, Jack?
Why are we here?
No why...
just here.
Just here.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury,
I know I may be guilty
of a crime,
but it was committed with
the purest of intentions.
I wanted to send a message
to the acting community
who...
put themselves above
the work,
who put themselves above me.
So, what did
you guys think?
So fake.
Totally artificial.
Like we're suppose to believe
that was 1 9th century Lisbon.
- Come on.
- Guys...
Who's looking at the sets
when she's on s creen?
Oh, y eah.
There he is.
That's my dad,
Viktor Taransky.
- She was magnificent.
- She's absolutely unreal.
Breathtaking.
She wasn't too...
cartoony, or anything?
The nun?
Or are you talking about
the mother?
A star like that, who cares about
the supporting cast?
Congratulations again.
She's not of thisearth.
- You should bevery proud.
- Oh, not of this earth.
And the rest of the film,
what did you think?
She's a miracle.
Where did you find her?
Well...
I saw her picture...
on the computer.
A computer?
You really didn't notice
anything unusual about her?
Only her brilliance.
To be honest,
with what you had
to work with,
I was expecting
a train wreck.
- You really pulled it off.
- I did?
Yeah. I have a feeling Mom's
going to take you back after this.
Back on the lot.
That's what...
I know. I know.
Come on, let's go.
A dazzling new ingenue
has come from seemingly nowhere
to capture the hearts of movie-going
audiences around the world
in her debut film
"Sunrise, Sunset."
But who is Simone?
We know so little about her.
And why the secrecy?
All we know for sure
is that she was dis covered
by little-known director,
Viktor Tarinsky.
Taransky.
Simone!
Simone?
- Good to see you, too, Elaine.
- Where is she?
- She's not here.
- Why isn't she with you?
Why? Because she would never come
to something like this.
She's intensely priv ate.
Back to work, everyone.
She's not here.
hey, listen.
Have you read the reviews?
they're love letters.
Listen to this one.
Oh, here.
Simone has thevoice
of a young Jane Fonda,
the body
of Sophia Loren,
the grace of well,
Grace Kelly...
ha-ha...
and the face...
of Audrey hepburn
combined with an angel.
- Almost right.
- I can't wait to meet her.
Oh, I don't know
if that's going to happen.
Why not?
She is somewhat
of a recluse.
That's how she stays
so pure.
She isolates herself
in her art.
Viktor, it's my studio.
Elaine, it's my actor.
There are other studios.
There's only one Simone.
Okay, have it your way,
Viktor.
hello, Walter.
Nobody came in
or went out,
- Just like you said.
- Very good.
- Mr. Taransky?
- Yes?
Is Ms. Simone
coming in today?
She's already here.
She arrived before you got here.
She's going to leave
long after you're gone.
Remember,
under no circumstances
are you or anybody else
ever to enter this set
without my express
permission, understood?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Taransky?
What if it catches
on fire?
Let it burn.
Good morning, Simone.
Good morning, Mr. Taransky.
Simone, a star is...
digitized.
Do you know
what this means?
We have stepped
into a new dimension.
Our ability
to manufacture fraud
now exceeds our ability
to detect it.
I am the death of real.
...death of real.
Too much Meryl Streep.
A little less Streep.
And a little more...
Bacall.
Is this better,
Mr. Taransky?
Much.
While we're at it,
there's a little
something
I want to add
to your repertoire.
You've got the wrong
Holly Golightly.
Remember that thing
Audrey hepburn does
in "Breakfast at Tiffany's"?
How do I look?
Give me Audrey.
Perfect.
Perfect, Simone.
Oh, God.
I'm so relaxed
around you.
I'm so myself.
You did create me.
I just brought someone
else's dream to life.
Mr. Taransky,
we both know I was nothing
without you.
I was computer code.
I was ones and zeros.
I was nothing.
Well...
that's true.
I don't want
to boast, but...
Are you ever going to tell
the truth about me, Mr. Taransky?
I'm going tell
the truth about you.
Why wouldn't i?
Of course...
with Hank's tragic passing,
his secret did die
with him.
This is
a classic case of
technology in search
of an artist.
Someone with integrity,
someone with vision,
someone who can see.
See beyond
this irrational
allegiance
to flesh and blood.
Someone who can see
that with the rise
in the price of a real actor
and the fall in the price
of a fake,
that the s cales have tipped...
naturally in favor
of the fake.
Someone who can see
that if a performance
is genuine,
it doesn't matter
if the actor's real or not.
And what's real anymore?
Most actors these days
have digital work done
to them.
It's a gray area.
The only real truth
is the work.
I'm going to tell
the truth about you
after your next picture.
You're so beautiful.
You're too beautiful.
We're going to fix that.
Is this on?
I will not be taking any questions
regarding Simone.
I do, however,
have a statement
to read on her behalf.
"To Whom it May Concern:
I'm deeply grateful
for the extraordinary
public response
to Mr. Taransky's film.
At this time I will be
conducting no interviews,
or making
publicity appearances...
- This is unbeliev able.
- I politely request that the press
respect my priv acy and let
the work speak for itself.
Yours truly, Simone."
Viktor!
Who is Simone dating?!
Where did you find her?
- Is Simone her real name?
- Didn't I make it clear?
No questions
regarding Simone.
We're just trying
to get some answers.
I will make
my final statement.
Ms. Simone begins production
on her new film today...
"Eternity Forever."
This is a project
which has been near and dear
to my heart since I wrote it
niney ears ago.
Thank you.
Would you answer
a question regarding Hank?
Hank?
Who asked me about Hank?
Funny, why is the movie
dedicated to Hank?
Are they involved?
they were at one time
inseparable. Yes.
And now?
Now...
sadly to say,
only in spirit.
Thank you.
Your car will be ready
in just a minute.
We gave you
a complimentary car wash.
- Oh, really?
- they're cleaning the engine now.
Thank you.
- Viktor, hey.
- Hal.
I am so happy for us.
The film, the chemistry.
Nothing against
N icola Anders,
but I think
that Simone and l,
we really worked
great together.
- You were never together.
- Still, the connection was undeniable.
You can't...
Look, I have not read
"Eternity Forever,"
but it is fantastic.
And I know I would be perfect
for the part of Clive.
- Clyde.
- Clyde, right.
That's what I'm talking about.
Yes, perfect.
Come on, man.
Look, I ran into Simone
on the lot.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
- She never mentioned it.
- She's bus y right now.
People coming at her
from all angles.
Maybe she didn't want
you to know, huh?
I strongly sensed
that she thought I would be
perfect for Clyde as well.
- Really?
- Strongly.
Excuse me.
Sure.
hello?
Simone, it's so great
to hear from you.
How are you,
sweetheart?
You'll never guess
who I'm with.
- You met him on the lot the other day.
- It was more in passing.
No, you're not
even close.
Hal.
- Hal Sinclair.
- What's wrong now?
I'm getting nothing from her side
of the conversation.
No, I don't think
he put on weight.
Anyway, listen. Do you think he'd
be right for "Eternity Forever"?
he's not the right type?
You want to go
in another direction?
Well... we'll try and talk her
into it, don't worry.
Anything you can do.
- Anything.
- Yeah, listen, honey.
What is this,
some kind of jamming device?
This is a bad place to talk.
Maybe he's just
talking to himself.
Taransky's not
that good an actor.
Honey, I know you want
to do charity work.
No, they've taken
special precautions.
Some kind
of new encryption.
Why would they do that?
Well, whatever it is...
it's dark.
Dark?
Yeah. Very.
All right,
we'll talk about it
at the beach house
this weekend.
- Can you ever stop doing that?
- Why?
You'll lose yourself
in that thing.
You gotta get out more.
How you gonna meet boys?
Dad, I know
plenty of boys.
You do? Who?
Where do you meet them?
You meet them
in those chat rooms?
How do you know you're not talking
to some middle-aged freak?
Dad, I can spot a middle-aged
freak a mile away.
It's beautiful today.
Let's go outside and eat.
And Lainey,
leave the computer, please.
Okay.
Dad, it might be better
to eat inside.
Stay here.
What is this?
What the hell is going on?
What are you doing here?
- You're trespassing.
- You can't hide her forever!
Simone appears only
when I want her to appear!
Sounds like a prisoner.
- What are you, holding her hostage?
- You're the hostage.
I mean, you look kind
of captive to me.
Lainey,
don't you ever wonder
where I'm really
hiding Simone?
Just as long as I know
where you are, Dad.
- By e, Dad.
- By e, honey.
hello, Viktor.
Sorry I got her back late.
Oh, no problem.
hey, you want
to come in?
- hi.
- hi, Honey.
- hi, Vik.
- Kent.
Viktor, we simply
have to dis cuss
"Eternity Forever."
I still haven't received
Simone's s cript notes.
There aren't any.
If the filmmakers
are happy,
she's happy.
She considers herself,
you know, an instrument.
So she's really going
to do all this nudity?
It's on the page.
We have to do something
about this budget.
It's completely
unrealistic.
You allowed nothing
for limousine service.
- She drives herself.
- U h-huh.
- Hair and make-up?
- Does her own.
- Theater training.
- Oh, she was in the theater?
Where?
You want her resume?
I'll send it to you.
Okay, great. Thanks.
At least, Viktor,
contingency for wardrobe.
Anybody can go up a size.
I guarantee she will not
gain an ounce.
She is so dis ciplined.
Well, we've gotta do
something about this...
- "Stuntwoman."
- What about it?
- Well, there isn't one.
- She doesn't need one.
- Does all her own stunts.
- even the fall from the plane?
- even the fall from the plane.
- Oh.
Shoot it
on the last day.
Listen, Viktor.
I want to talk to you now,
not as Elaine, Studio head,
but as Elaine, ex-wife.
hey, second ex-wife.
Seriously.
You got lucky this last time.
But you need
to be careful.
We both know you wouldn't be
making this overblown art film
if you hadn't convinced
Simone to be in it.
Elaine...
talking to you now,
not as Viktor, Director,
but as Viktor,
your first former husband,
what happened to you? huh?
Experience, Viktor.
That's what happened
to me.
Yeah, I've seen this
a hundred times.
- Really?
- Yeah.
These young stars
destroying
thevery people
who dis covered them.
I'm worried about you,
that's all.
This woman,
she controls your destiny.
She doesn't control
my destiny.
There's something
about her I don't trust.
hi, Jane.
Thanks for taking me back,
Mr. Taransky.
I know that it looked like
I sided with the studio,
but I've always believed
in you. Honestly.
Don't worry.
I understand.
- Are they...
- they're all here.
Okay, thank you.
hello.
Viktor.
I just want to say
I am delighted
to have such
a wonderful cast
assembled here
for "Eternity Forever."
A reminder:
as a condition for working
on this picture,
you will not be rehearsing
with Simone.
You will not be shooting
Actually, you are forbidden
from contacting Simone
at any time, for any reason,
whatsoever.
- Works for me.
- How will you shoot our love s cenes?
- Body double.
- For her?
For you.
Anyway, Simone insisted
on speaking with you herself
before filming started.
I believe she's on the line now.
Simone, are you there?
I certainly am,
Mr. Taransky.
So are we, Simone.
Why don't you leave me alone
with my co-stars, Mr. Taransky,
so we can get to know
each other better?
Absolutely.
I'll be back in a minute.
H i, who's there?
Don't be shy.
Introduce yourselves.
I'm Mac.
I turned down
a Bertolucci film to be here.
hi, Simone.
I'm Corel.
hi, I'm Claris.
You used to date
my cousin, Dell.
I'm hewlitt.
We can rehearse in priv ate
if you like.
My name is Lotus.
God, I can't believe
I'm talking to you.
We are going to become
such great friends.
hi, Simone, it's Hal.
It's great to be working
together... again.
Is that everyone?
Well, ob viously,
as you know, I'm Simone.
Who else?
I just want to start
by apologizing
for my process.
I know it's an unusual way
to work,
but I just find
I relate better to people
when they're not
actually there.
Oh, of course.
Of course.
I don't have much to say,
Except, that I know
it's gonna be a great project
if we all just trust
Mr. Taransky's vision.
Always do
what Mr. Taransky says.
If in doub t,
do it the Taransky way.
I know we're gonna make
a wonderful movie together.
Together.
Absolutely.
Veronica.
What you don't understand,
Clyde, is that love...
Still too big.
I like it,
but it's too big.
All right.
Smaller teardrops this time.
What you don't understand,
Clyde,
is that love
is like a wildflower.
But that flower only grows
on the edge...
of a very high cliff.
Perfect.
Simone. Simone.
Simone.
Gonna be a little change
in plans, Simone.
You have no idea
the effect
your performance
is having on people.
We can't stop now.
These films,
they're speaking
to the human condition.
We're changing lives.
People need to believe
you're real.
To reveal the truth now,
it would be too cruel.
You're gonna get in
a lot of trouble, Mr. Taransky.
Now, why do you have
to bring that up?!
I mean,
everything's a risk.
But it's worth it,
isn't it?
We've done
enough work today.
You've been cooped up
in there too long.
So how about...
you and I going
out on the town?
Tonight, they're going
to see you
with their own ey es.
Excuse me.
I will be checking in
a very special guest.
- A Ms. Enomis.
- Ah, Ms. Enomis.
Now, Ms. Enomis
demands her priv acy.
So, you will switch off
all surveillance cameras.
I alone, will es cort
Ms. Enomis to her room
via the rear exit.
She must not be disturbed
at any time,
for any reason whatsoever.
I'm sure I can rely
on your dis cretion.
U nderstood, sir.
Thank you.
There she is!
Who is it?
It's Simone.
Okay, I think
everybody's here.
Now!
I think we're
all right now.
Oh, thank God
for you, Faith.
Thank God for you.
This is way above
and beyond
the call of duty
for a stand-in.
I must tell you,
you have no idea
the service you've
performed for Simone,
shielding her
from these animals.
Oh, no, Mr. Taransky.
Thank God for you.
- For me?
- Yeah.
How many directors
would go
to so much trouble
to protect an actress?
It's incredible.
You know,
we're gonna have
to go back
to my place,
just to, you know,
keep them off the s cent.
Of course.
You look so...
So much like...
um, like her?
Oh, y es, of course.
Like her.
But you're
so very beautiful
in your own right.
I do find myself strangely
attracted to you, Mr. Taransky.
Call meviktor.
Viktor.
- Oh.
- Oh, Viktor.
- Viktor.
- Yes?
- This is so exciting.
- Yes.
Do what you do
to Simone?
What?
What did you say?
I said do whatever
you do to Simone.
What I do to Simone?
Call me Simone!
Simone?
Yes. Say it again,
please.
I want to know what it's like
to be her just for one night.
Please, call me Simone.
You're with me so you can
be close to her?
Is that a problem?
Okay. Excuse me
just a minute.
Is something wrong?
Well, actually,
maybe we can do this
some other time
- Or something.
- Are you bus y tomorrow?
Gentlemen,
the Presidential Suite.
Ahem...
I think that should
take care of everything.
Yes, sir.
I believe it will.
Leave me for a moment.
Simone.
- Brilliant.
- Elaine!
- There she is.
- The picture...
The picture.
It's a revelation.
Thank you.
We all worked
so hard.
- It was you.
- No, it was all of us.
It was incredible.
Thank you all.
Thank you.
- Whoa!
- Viktor!
- Is she here?
- Viktor, is she here?
Oh, I'm fine, Hal.
How are you?
Somebody
said she was here.
Jesus.
That's her glass.
Jack Daniels,
straight up.
- My kind of woman.
- Come on, where is she?
I don't know.
She's, uh...
Is that her
by the fountain?
You know,
between you and me,
- She doesn't really exist.
- Simone!
- Simone's here?
- Why didn't anybody tell me?
- She's here?!
- Simone!
- I got your glass!
I'm your biggest fan!
Simone!
- Simone!
- Simone?
Get out!
Not you two.
She goes to a major
Hollywood A-list party
and we don't get
an interview,
a comment?
We don't even get a photograph?!
Is that what
you're telling me?
Nobody got a photograph.
Nobody ever gets a photograph.
We have our best people
on it, Mr. Say er.
Get better people!
What about the 2 4-hour
tail on Taransky?
they're camped out every place
he goes; every concierge,
every maitre d',
they're all on the take.
But this Simone woman
is good.
Ob viously, that is not
her real name.
She uses
an assumed identity.
She travels under
a false name.
She checks into
a hotel under an alias.
N ever stays in the same place
two nights in a row.
What about the satellite photos?
What happened?
- Nothin'.
- Nothing from space?!
What about
the fingerprints?
What happened when we dusted
that whole hotel suite?
Well, we have some
of Taransky's fingerprints,
a lot of yours...
and none of hers.
No one is that perfect,
that pure.
You know, I had something
on Mother Teresa once.
But then she died
and it just wasn't
worth it anymore.
I know how to flush out
this Simone woman.
A tell-all story
from her childhood.
You have one?
I will when you're
finished writing it.
Please don't
make me do this.
Guard, open this door
right now.
Mr. Taransky gave me
specific instructions
never to open up this door.
- What are you doing?!
- Mr. Taransky!
- Why did you do this?!
- We have to talk to her!
- We know she's in there.
- Okay.
What is this about?
We've got the tracking numbers
for "Eternity Forever."
they're in the toilet.
She's gotta get out there
and sell the film.
What do you want her to do,
go door-to-door?
even Garbo would be on the talk show
circuit if she were alive!
It is precisely because she
doesn't crave the limelight
that people love her!
- This is bullshit!
- She is about the work,
- And only the work!
- This is overshadowing the work.
If you can't handle her,
I will.
It's not a good time.
She's emotional.
Today, her mother dies.
Scene 4 2
of "Good for Nothing."
- This is not a good time.
- It never is.
- Step aside!
- We're going in!
- This is ridiculous!
- No! No!
- What are you doing?!
- Simone!
I trusted you.
- Simone?
- You can come out, it's Elaine!
- We just want to have a meeting.
- We can talk,
- Girl-to-girl. Just us.
- Where is she?
- She's gone.
- Where are the sets?
- God, that is so like her.
- Where are the cameras?
Viktor, we're not paying
for this are we?
What is all this?
Well...
I suppose
it was gonna come out
sooner or later.
I guess I'm actually
relieved in a way.
I can just say it finally.
She's a computer...
addict.
What?
She's a computer addict!
She's buried in here.
Day in, day out.
Of course.
I should have guessed.
It's why she never
goes anywhere,
- Why she's never seen in public.
- Now you're getting it.
Probably spends
her whole life in chat rooms.
- The one place she can be herself.
- Anonymous.
Only it's worse.
It's far worse.
She's extremely
agoraphobic.
She has a morbid fear
of people,
of germs,
places, heights...
- Name it.
- This is terrible.
How is she going
to plug the film?
- Yes, indeed.
- She has to do publicity.
Maybe I could get her
to do something.
Maybe a television
talk show or something.
Yes!
- Taped.
- Make it live, please.
- Live?
- Please.
She'd never go there.
It would have to be remote.
We can work with that.
I can't promise anything.
- We understand.
- Thank you, Viktor.
- Don't grovel.
Thank you.
Give her our best.
That agoraphobia...
it's like a plague.
It's out of control
in Europe.
It's so good of you
to protect her like this.
She wanted you...
No, no.
Don't touch that.
Germs.
She wanted you
to have that.
She was there.
She was right there.
Yeah.
Oh, my gosh.
She didn't,
by any chance,
happen
to mention me?
Actually, she did.
She, uh...
she said that she thought
you werevery beautiful.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Would you want to go
and get something to eat,
or something?
Viktor,
I'd love to, really.,
but don't you have
to go talk to Simone?
If I can find her.
Well.
All right. Good.
- Thanks, Viktor.
- Thank you.
I'm gonna... By e.
Tonight,
on Frank Brand Live...
Since taking the nation
by storm
in her debut movie,
"Sunrise, Sunset,"
no one has managed to land
a live television interview
with this fabulous
shooting starlet, Simone...
until now.
she's agreed to talk
with us tonight
from the set
of her new film.
Welcome, Simone.
So glad you can find time
in your hectic s chedule to be here.
It's my pleasure.
Wonderful to be
with you, Frank.
No one can accuse you
of being overexposed, Simone.
Why have you stay ed so completely
out of the limelight?
I guess I just think actors
talk too much.
Does the world really want
to hear my life story
just be cause I have a movie
opening on Friday?
Wow.
She is all woman.
Of course, the problem
with shying away
from publicity these days
is that it tends
to attract even more.
Don't I know it.
But the only reason
I'm here now,
is to put the attention
back where it belongs,
on Mr. Taransky's film.
And you don't secretly want
the attention?
I'm not even sure
I deserve it.
You see, after tonight,
I'll have just as much
s creen time on your show
as I have in my movies.
Now, how is that healthy
for a performer?
Because you have to understand,
Frank, none of this is real.
Who I am on s creen
and who I really am,
they're two totally
different people.
Change of topic.
You have been
romantically linked
to dozens of men
in the press...
Mick Jagger, Steven Hawking,
Fidel Castro,
most recently,
Viktor Taransky.
Is there a Mr. Right
in there somewhere?
You know, Frank, I'd rather not
dis cuss my priv ate life.
But Viktor and l,
we are inseparable.
Oh, Viktor.
You dog.
I wouldn't be here today
without him.
Would you like
a moment, Simone?
No, I'm okay.
Okay.
Then let's talk about
this work
you care so much about.
Sure.
Where would you like
to start, Frank?
- How about the nudity?
- I know where that is.
N udity's just never been
an issue for me.
I know that tree.
- Clothes are simply an option.
- I know that tree.
I know where that is.
What exactly was it
that attracted you
to your first two projects?
I suppose what I like most
about the movies I'm in
is that they're not about
special effects.
And they are better
for it, I might add.
We appear to be having
some satellite difficulties.
But, before we lose you
completely, Simone,
I just want to say
thank you.
Thank you, Frank.
Goodby e.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Simone.
I've been here before.
On my honeymoon
with my ex-wife.
Yeah, look.
It's the exact
same tree.
And look
in the distance.
The mountain.
It's a hotel.
I don't understand.
Could they have built
that hotel sincey esterday?
Get in the car.
Simone! Simone!
We don't do the photos,
you don't get the cover.
It's as simple as that.
Yes. Written answers
to written questions.
Didn't we have
this conversation before?
Yeah, web site interviews,
no problem.
I think people are gonna
love "Eternity Forever."
"Eternity Forever"
is my finest work.
I loved working
with the director
of "Eternity Forever."
he's a genius.
You wish.
It's wonderful being
a movie star.
But there's so many other ways
I want to express myself.
But it's not enough
to be a movie star.
You have to be
a pop star, too.
If you really want
to make a difference.
N ice boat, Taransky!
It's not a boat,
it's a yacht.
I know
what you're up to.
You know, I really
don't have time for this.
I think you do,
'cause I know it's a fake.
It's bogus.
You used an old library shot
for the background.
She never
was in N ew Mexico.
She never even left
the studio.
I've done my homework.
- I've studied her.
- I bet you have.
I've looked at every piece
of publicity she's done.
And as far as I can tell,
there's no evidence
that she hasever left
the studio.
Oh...
And for some reason,
this woman leaves
no paper trail?
Now, I've ob tained a copy
of your bank account.
I know you have
power of attorney,
but so far,
you have not turned over
a single solitary cent
to this woman.
I keep it in a trust.
I know that's what you want
people to believe,
but I gotta tell you,
embezzlement
is a serious matter.
Not to mention abduction.
- Abduction?
- Yeah.
Off the record.
I want to know
how you're doing it.
Is it drugs?
Is it mind control?
Is it blackmail?
Is it all three?
What do you do? Do you keep her
locked in a box somewhere?
What is it exactly
that you want?
I want to see her.
U nless you show me
Simone live and in person,
I show these photos
to the authorities.