...get out of here alive, I tell you.
Let's go!
Incoming!
- Sorry, captain.
- It's all right, son, just keep moving.
That's the future in your hands.
Heave! Heave! Heave!
- Starboard gunners ready, captain.
- Lieutenant.
Fire!
Prepare to take us into the channel.
Ahead a half.
- Make revolutions for five knots.
- Aye, sir.
- Range, 150 yards!
- 150 yards!
Fire!
- All ahead full.
- Aye, captain.
Stop engines.
- Captain?
- Stop engines! Run silent!
Cease firing!
Close the gun ports. Hold still.
- Cease firing!
- Close the gun ports!
Mrs. Nwokolo?
Eva Rojas, World Health Organization.
This is Dr. Hopper.
- Hello. Nice to meet you.
- Please come with me.
Sorry about the dark.
The light hurts his eyes.
- Thank you.
- What's his name?
Azikiwe. Most call him Kiwe.
Hi, Kiwe. My name is Eva.
We need to have a little look
at you, okay?
- How long has he been sick?
- For two days.
- Has he traveled anywhere recently?
- He was in Mali last week.
With his father.
- Where is his father now?
- He's at the lighthouse.
That's where he works.
Blood pressure, 80/50.
- Circulatory failure.
- Drawing blood.
- Easy, son. Easy. No, no.
- Kiwe!
- Sedative, Eva.
- What dose?
Two mils.
Easy, son. Easy. No. It's okay.
It's all right. You're gonna be all right.
Just trying to help.
It's okay. It's okay, Kiwe.
It's okay.
- Your mama... Your mama is here.
- It's okay, Kiwe. It's okay.
You all right?
- Mali, just like the others.
- Yeah, I know.
- This is an outbreak, Frank.
- We've got six cases.
- That's not enough.
- Oh, how many do we need?
Sixty?
Six thousand?
When does it start to matter?
We have to find the source, Frank.
You wanna go to Mali.
It's not gonna happen.
WHO isn't gonna lose
any more staff to a civil war.
- Here, finish your report.
- Good.
- Just in time for the autopsy.
- Eva.
I'll do what I can do.
I'll re-present to the board.
- And maybe they'll listen this time.
- Thank you.
We still need blood samples
from his father.
I'll find the father.
Hello?
Mr. Nwokolo?
Hey!
Help.
You have no business being here.
Quick, get her bag.
Are you okay?
Hey! Hey, pick that up!
What are you doing? Come on.
You're walking past...
All right, guys. Come on.
Guys, quit screwing around.
Come on. Come on, come on,
come on. All right, stop.
All right, hold it there.
Report any variances over two feet.
Here, hold on to these.
Come on, grab it.
All right. Come on, you piece of...
All right, give me a wrench.
I need the wrench.
Wrench! Anybody there?
All right, oil. I need the oil.
All right, the oil. Thank you.
That's it. All right, we're good!
We're good!
Sorry.
Here. Hi.
- Al Giordino.
- Eva.
- Eva Rojas.
- Nice work.
- Thanks.
- Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
All right, turn it on. Go down.
Go, go, go, go, go.
More. Keep going.
Hi.
- How are you? Feeling better?
- Yes, thank you.
- I'm Rudi.
- Sorry, where are we?
This is the Martha Ann,
It's a NUMA boat. Ship.
We didn't know who you were, so
we kind of patched you up ourselves.
You had an edema
of the upper tracheal track.
Rudi, I've been waiting
two months for this moment.
Don't mess it up for me
by letting him drown.
- Yes, admiral.
- Diver up!
In five, counting,
four, three, two, one.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I introduce to you
after a 772-year engagement
on the bottom of the ocean:
King Bateen!
Nice job, everyone.
Except you, Al. What the hell?
It's a 10-ton-rated winch,
my friend, not a fly-fishing rod.
You know what? You're thinking
of the Thompson 12-91.
Whereas you're astride a 12-93.
- Not that you could operate either one.
- Boys!
- Sir?
The king meets the people
at the museum in five hours.
- Don't worry, sir. He'll be there.
- He'll be there.
He better be.
Secure those cables!
Hey, look who's on her feet.
Thanks to you, I guess.
You were lucky to just lose your bag.
Dangerous city.
Damn it, I did lose my bag.
- Nothing worth dying for, I hope.
- Well, that's a tough question.
Nothing worth you dying for.
Hey, Dirk, get your butt up here
so we can scrape
some of the crap off this thing.
- Excuse me. The wife.
- Come on, ladies,
get Mr. Bateen unhooked.
Clean him up.
We got a party to go to.
- Admiral?
- Retired.
- Jim Sandecker.
- Eva. Eva Rojas.
I'm with the WHO.
You look like you could use
a cup of coffee.
- Hey, Dirk. Hey, I need your help.
- What?
- Is it left over right, or right over left?
- This better not be like last time.
I can't remember.
It's driving me nuts.
Is there something about a rabbit
going around a tree or something?
I'll be there in an hour.
- What, Dirk?
- That was Oshodi.
He thinks he might
have found something.
Oh, that's great. That is fantastic.
- Thank you very much.
- No, no, no, no, fantastic for me.
I can't wait to tell Sandecker that you're
not gonna be at the museum tonight
because one of your contacts
from the Nigerian underworld
has found evidence of a Civil War
ironclad shipwrecked
- In a storm off Africa. Yeah, right.
- Storm off Africa.
That's what you're talking about, right?
Yeah. Sandecker's gonna freak.
- Look, Al...
- And I'll be there. He'll turn all red.
The fox chases the rabbit around
the tree and down the hole.
That's how the tie works.
Don't you worry, I'll be there.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
First, I'd like to thank the Lagos
museum for this magnificent reception.
I would also like to thank
our primary benefactor on this project,
Yves Massarde.
Thank you.
We are NUMA,
the National Underwater
and Marine Agency.
And this, ladies and gentlemen,
is what we do.
King Bateen.
- Where is he?
- He's not at the buffet.
- Damn it.
- Do you want another kebab?
With the help of museums,
with the help of governments,
private organizations like ours
can work in partnership
to make sure that history,
history that has been lost
to the tides of time,
can be returned to its people.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Have a lovely evening.
Do you have a CD burner
on that ship of yours?
Yes, the same one I bought
from you last month.
I have a wonderful piece, straight
from the Iraqi National Museum.
Don't show me things like that,
Oshodi. We're not that friendly.
Okay, okay. Now, here it is.
A very special piece.
The one I spoke to you about.
It breaks my heart
just to show it to you.
Where did you get this?
Cash, please.
We are not that friendly.
This is a great party.
- Thank you for inviting us, admiral.
- The pleasure is mine.
Yves, this is the woman
I was telling you about,
- Dr. Eva Rojas.
- Hi.
I'm delighted to make your
acquaintance. I'm Yves Massarde.
Nice to meet you.
This is Dr. Frank Hopper.
- How do you do?
Yves does a lot of business
in Africa.
Some even in Mali.
Will you excuse me?
I understand you believe there is some
sort of plague coming out of Mali?
We don't like to say "plague."
- What do you think it is then?
- A plague.
So you do business in Mali?
Do you know anyone there
who could help us
by pressuring the WHO
to send a team?
Well, you see, much of Mali
is controlled by a warlord.
General Kazim. Do you know him?
Yes. He used to be a colonel
in the Malian army,
and gave himself an upgrade
the day he shot the president.
He's the man who put the "war"
back into "warlord."
And he controls the country?
Half of it. And the other half
no one controls,
but I don't know which is worse.
But I have to warn you, it is very
dangerous for foreigners right now.
I would say it's probably
more dangerous for locals.
Yes, but your death would
look very bad in the papers.
So does the word "plague."
All right, I will call some people,
but at the end of the day,
I'm just a businessman,
so be patient.
Oh, yeah, she's good at that.
He's not gonna help us.
This was a waste of time.
Eva, we can't just wander into
the middle of a Malian civil war.
The fighting with the Tuaregs
is too severe. You know that.
I think we should go back
to the hospital...
Admiral, have you ever seen
a Confederate gold dollar?
- Dear God, don't start this again.
- Of course not.
The Confederacy never made
a gold dollar.
The mint was destroyed
near the end of the war.
Dirk, I beg you on my hands
and knees. Don't.
But not before Jefferson Davis
had five samples made.
He gave four of those samples
to his top generals:
- Lee, Jackson, Stuart and Johnston.
- Every time we come to Africa,
out comes that stupid ship model.
Out come the old port journals.
We are leaving for Australia
tomorrow.
Four of those samples
have been found.
But the fifth never was.
That one was given to
an old family friend of Davis.
A brilliant young sea captain
named Mason Tombs.
Captain of the CSS ironclad Texas.
- Where in the hell did you get this?
- Frederick Oshodi.
And he got it from a man
named Indigwe.
But the important thing is that Indigwe
found this in Labbezanga, Mali.
Hey, my dad collects coins.
No, that coin and the Texas
were on the Niger River.
It's impossible. An ironclad
couldn't make it with her draft.
Let me take the Calliope
to Labbezanga, have a look around.
- You can't have my boat, Dirk.
- Three days, admiral.
Just three days. Imagine.
Imagine.
All right, if I strike out,
you'll never hear another word
about this.
You got 72 hours.
And not a nanosecond more.
You fellas just bought
yourself a boat trip.
You're a gentleman, admiral.
I don't care what they say about you.
I got a bottle says we never find it.
- Make it a case.
- All right. You're on.
- Okay, I'll see you later.
- See you later.
Hey, yo!
- You're late.
- Excuse me?
- I was told 8:00 departure.
- Eight o'clock?
- I never said 8:00.
- I said 9.
- Nine.
- It's after 10.
Who said 8?
Admiral Sandecker.
Yeah, he said to give him a call
if you had any problems.
A problem? With what?
He wants you to take us
up the river to Mali.
- What?
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
- Taking you to Mali?
- Wait.
There's been an outbreak in Mali.
- It's going to become an epidemic.
- And you wanna hitch a ride, doctor?
What, WHO's making
budgetary cutbacks?
Please. It's important.
- You guys got enough gear?
- Probably not.
Small boat. No privacy.
I'm not shy.
Where do you call home?
I have a house in Monterey,
but I'm never there.
Monterey. There's great diving
in Monterey.
Is that all you ever think about?
Diving?
No. Sometimes I think about
Petricola pholadiformis.
The angel wing clam.
- Beautiful.
- Yeah.
This river's the only place
on earth they're found.
When they're underwater,
they glow in the dark.
Now, the amazing thing is that
modern science cannot explain why.
There must be a reason.
Till then, my theory is that
they do it because they can.
Dirk! That's it. Let's go.
Angel wings.
World would be a lot cooler place
if more of us were like that, huh?
This is the center of the cluster.
Here. Asselar.
That's where we have to go.
Right in the middle
of Kazim's civil war.
Hey, you ever been
after marlins, doctors?
Oh, no, not
the marlin story again, Al.
Seven hundred
and thirty-three pounds.
Five and a half hours
in the fighting chair.
- I thought it was 600 pounds.
- Hey!
What did you catch that day?
I can't remember anything at all.
How long you guys been together?
Oh, since kindergarten.
College. Navy. NUMA.
Poor guy's always
been in my shadow.
Always the Al's-maid, never the Al.
Right?
Nice, doc.
You're pulling your weight.
- My watch, chief.
- All right, my man. Excellent.
Your friend Al told me all about
your Captain Tombs and his boat.
Oh, he did, did he?
He also said ironclads were
not made to cross the ocean.
Well, neither was man. Tequila?
And you found a coin?
Not just a coin.
I found the coin.
Now, I also have a letter
from the captain's widow
alluding to her husband's
urgent Eastern voyage.
I have a sailor's log
on an Atlantic clipper
who swears on a stack of Bibles
he saw a great iron beast
steaming two miles
off the African coast.
Now, what kind of man tries to take
a ship like that across the ocean?
Why? How?
I don't know.
But I plan on finding out.
Al loves it when people ask me that,
thinks it makes me look a bit:
This must be nice.
To have this as your office.
Well, every great thing that's ever
happened to me
happened in the water.
Every one.
Hey, Rudi, come on,
help me out with this.
Oumar.
- You got it?
- There you go.
- How long to Asselar?
- Oh, six, eight hours. No problem.
- You stay for long?
- No, not long.
All right, this one too.
- Think it'll be safe?
- Oh, it's okay.
Where we go now,
no fighting. No problem.
- Yeah, no problem.
- No Tuareg.
Listen, I've been thinking.
When this is over,
there's a place I know.
It's called Monterey.
- Never heard of it.
- No?
It's got a beautiful beach.
Golden sands, aqua-blue surf.
The place is paradise.
- Sounds good.
- Oh, yeah.
I also happen to know a woman
who has a house there.
And because she's a workaholic,
she's never at home.
Now, I haven't asked her, but I'm
pretty sure that she wouldn't mind
if you dropped by.
Can I bring a friend?
You'd have to ask her.
I already did.
You did?
You, me and the bay of Monterey.
Thank you for everything.
- You're welcome.
- And good luck to you.
You as well. Bonne route, doctor.
Mr. Indigwe, he lives...
Indigwe. He find this
one week before, yes?
You know, I'm not
too much of a linguist...
...but that didn't sound too good.
Indigwe is dead.
Yeah. Hey, the check.
What is "the check"? L'addition,
Hey, you know, my dad
collected ancient coins.
From Rome, China, Siam, Persia.
Somehow they all ended up
in a shoebox in New Jersey.
- Meaning?
- Coins travel, Dirk.
Even if that poor guy was still alive,
it could have been nothing.
Yeah, but the coin traveled
from somewhere, Al.
And unless it hitched a ride
on the back of a dolphin,
I'm gonna guess that
its jumping-off point
was a little bit closer
to where we're sitting.
Really, you can see that ironclad
steaming up the river? I mean, really?
Isn't it more likely that we missed it
somewhere off the coast of Virginia?
Right?
Hello?
Dirk.
I'll meet you at the boat.
No, I got the check.
Don't worry about it. I'm serious.
I know, I get it all the time.
Sit down, I'll get the check.
L'addition,
Ya-Sheikh.
My name is Dirk.
I'm looking for a boat.
And when would we be
seeing this boat?
About 140 years ago, in 1866.
Back when Labbezanga was
one of the greatest ports in Africa.
Do you know anything else?
We use events to find dates,
not dates to find events.
Well, there was a storm.
There was a great storm.
One that would have raised
the depths of the Niger
enough to allow the boat
to get here, yes.
It is written here.
Six days after the great storm,
a dark ship rode without sails
under the banner of a single star.
It was driven upriver,
never to return.
Bearing...
...death.
It brought a sickness
from here up to Gao
and bore over 300 souls to heaven.
It was believed a damnation
from Allah.
A ghost ship.
A cursed ship.
What does that mean?
- What?
- That's Arabic, Al.
Yeah. Sounds poetic.
What's it mean?
"The ship of death."
Great. Should we call Sandecker?
- No.
- What ship? Whose death?
He'd just tell us to come home.
- Sounds reasonable.
- Yeah, then I'd get a case of tequila.
Boys, we are going upriver to Gao.
All right. Rudi, you gonna run
the sonar on the riverbed?
Come on, I was hoping to meet
a girl on the Australia trip.
No, African war zone. Ship of death.
Bye.
- Got a profile.
- Another truck bumper?
Bicycle? VCR?
Sixteen degrees, twenty-decimal-zero
minutes north, zero...
Wait, hold on. It's just
some interference with the buoy.
- Al.
- Yeah, I got it.
When did you check the calibration?
I had it out of the water
three hours ago.
All right.
- Anything, Al?
- Hey, guys.
Take a look at this.
It's red algae.
That doesn't make any sense,
this is fresh water.
- I'd better get a sample.
- Yep.
It's okay, they're just looking
for Tuareg fighters.
Very well, thank you.
For you.
Join me.
Thank you.
These belonged
to General Mayenne.
Then one of them actually killed
the Comte de Vezelay.
Isn't that fascinating?
Beads for the natives, Yves.
What do you want?
Well, you know the doctors
I was telling you about?
I am afraid they're
on their way to Mali.
I thought your man was going
to take care of them in Lagos.
- Well, we had a problem.
- And now the problem is mine.
And another thing, general,
if I may say,
I am slightly concerned
your measures of containment
are losing their effectiveness.
Why? Because five or six poor souls
escaped from Mali
- And died in their beds?
- The disease spreads quickly.
And luckily, it kills quickly too.
General, I think you should control
the movements of your population.
What's that?
Are you trying to tell me
how to run my country?
You take care
of your business, Yves.
I'll take care of mine.
Of course.
- Rocks?
- Nope.
- River? Radio?
- Radar?
- Rudi.
- You... That's not...
- It is.
- He can't even...
- Here we go again. I spy.
- All right, something I might get.
- I spy...
- I spy with my little eye...
- Guys.
- Company.
- This is the Malian Civil Authority.
- I got it.
- Prepare to be boarded.
You are trespassing
in Malian waters.
Shut off your engine
and throw out a rope.
Hi, this is Al Giordino speaking.
Al, Sandecker. I presume you're on
your way home with my boat?
- Everyone on deck, right now.
- It's for you.
- Al, what's going on?
- Where are the doctors?
Where are they? We are looking
for the doctors.
I have to put you on hold. I don't
believe this is a normal shakedown, Al.
If you do not shut off your engine,
you run the risk of being fired upon.
The doctors. We are looking
for the doctors. Where are they?
- Where is the woman?
- I'm sorry. I don't speak English.
You are speaking English now.
No, no. I only know how to say,
"I don't speak English," in English.
- Al.
- Hi. Hold on.
Stop! Stop the engines now
before we open fire.
Whoa, hat!
- Did you get my hat?
- Sorry, it's gone.
That's my favorite hat.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Where's Dirk?
- I think he's...
Hold on.
Dirk! Dirk.
I'm gonna come in.
You jump on the front.
- You want me to jump?
- Get on the front of the boat. Got it?
- Really?
- What am I...?
- Al!
- What?
Here, flare gun.
- Signal for help?
- No, shoot them.
- Hey!
- Sorry.
Come a little closer, babe. Come.
Oh, yeah!
That is what I'm talking about.
- Are you all right?
- That was close.
- Al, pick up the phone,
- Yeah, it was.
- How about you?
- Pick up the phone,
- Glad I'm driving.
- Still there?
- I am too.
- What the hell is going on?
I shot a guy with a flare gun.
- A flare gun? What?
- Cool.
What did you...? Did you say you
shot someone with a flare gun?
- What?
- Who?
Don't put the phone...
Rudi?
Who's shooting? Al, who's shooting?
Is someone shooting at you?
You'd better not hurt my boat,
Engine two is out.
Fourth and long, man.
What do you wanna do?
- I think we need to pull a Panama.
- A Panama. A Panama?!
- Panama?
- You think? Really?
- Yeah. Really.
- No Panama,
Somebody pick up... They're
ignoring me. They're ignoring...
Everybody's ignoring me.
Pick up the phone!
Take it. We're doing a Panama.
We're doing a Panama!
- What's a Panama?
- Navy thing.
- I didn't know you were in Panama.
- Weren't. We were in Nicaragua.
- Then why do you call it a Panama?
- We thought we were in Panama.
No Panama,
What are you looking for? Al!
Al. Al, I'm really confused.
How we doing, Al?
- Go help Dirk.
- What do I do with this?
Just go!
Down.
- Open the engine hatch.
- Okay.
Let's go, Al.
Got it.
Here, light this.
- Aren't these the admiral's?
- Just light it.
What the...?
Whenever you're ready, Al.
- Come on!
- What are we doing?
- I don't think you should be doing that.
- Okay. Drop it.
- We're good.
- Yeah?
- All right, hold on.
- Hold on.
Okay.
Al!
Hey, I need a life jacket.
Crap.
He did a Panama.
Cool.
- Is that how it worked the first time?
- Well...
...it didn't really work
the first time.
- I lost my hat.
- Again?
Yeah.
Man, is Sandecker gonna be mad
when you tell him
you lost the satellite phone.
Not as mad as when Rudi tells him
it was attached to the boat.
- Wait. Why me?
- Because we're not going back.
- Right, Dirk?
- Nope. We're going to Asselar.
- No more Texas?
- Ironclad's on hold for a while, guys.
Those soldiers weren't after us.
They were after the doctors.
I got a feeling whatever bug
Eva's chasing, it must be a doozy.
- We gotta get there first.
- I'm going with you.
- Nope, you gotta tell Sandecker.
- Hold on. Hold on.
How am I gonna get across the border?
I never took survival training.
- Consider this your course.
- It's kind of pass-fail,
which I always thought was easier.
Look, Rudi. Lay up here till dark, then
make your move. The border's not far.
- Okay.
- All right.
Al, you remember
that time in Morocco?
Oh, yeah, when you made me ride
that damn camel
- That bit my ass.
- Yeah, that's the time.
Why?
God! What is the secret
to this thing?
Just wrap it around your nugget.
- What part? Here? This?
- Yeah.
Well, how come yours stays on?
Maybe you got a small head.
I don't think so.
Somebody would've told me.
Thank you.
World Health Organization.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
Frank.
Look at this.
Anyone here?
Hello?
Oh, my God.
This well was filled in recently.
I think people here knew
the water was making them sick.
I still say we should
let Oumar go down.
Oumar, you wouldn't mind
going down that well, would you?
- No, it's okay. I'll go down.
- You see?
Frank, I'll be fine.
Yeah, there you go.
All right, you're looking good.
You're looking good.
- Give her a little more rope.
- Okay.
Be careful, please.
Just take your time.
Eva.
Eva, hold on.
Eva. Hold on. We've got you.
- You got it?
- It's okay.
- Bring her up.
- No, I'm fine.
Give me more rope.
Got it. I made it.
- Got water.
- All right, great.
Get what we need,
and let's get you out of there.
Hey, looks like we've got company.
Don't go anywhere.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Hello there. I'm Dr. Hopper with
the World Health Organization.
- You have no authority to be here.
- What are you doing?
Eva, get those... Oh, my God!
- Frank!
- Charlie, please don't shoot me.
Charlie, don't...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
do you hear that?
- This is all of them?
- Yes, sir.
The UN knows that we're here. This is
a United Nations-sanctioned mission.
Where's your colleague?
No, no, no, no, no.
I mean, the woman.
She didn't come. She's ill.
This pistol, it belonged
to General Sir Henry Watkins.
.455 caliber. Very rare.
Hard to find the rounds.
I have them made
by Holland & Holland of London.
Twenty-seven pounds each.
You should put the money
to better use.
Like containing this plague.
I will give you some advice.
Tell me where Dr. Rojas is.
She's not here.
Have it your own way.
Make it look like a horde of Tuareg
swine just came through here.
- And find the woman.
- Yes, sir.
She's here.
Somewhere.
You men, set up a perimeter.
I want you to search
the whole town.
- Hey, Salim, come over here.
- Yes, sir.
Open up a few rounds
just to be sure.
Hey.
Al, little help here.
Oh, man.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, Eva.
Come on. You okay?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
We gotta go.
Wait. Wait!
Frank!
We're done here.
We're in Tuareg country now.
We're gonna drive north about
three hours till we hit the flatlands.
From there it should be a relatively
easy drive to the Algerian border.
Sorry.
Eva.