Made By Madmax12
Welcome, shoppers...
Ketchup, mustard...
Oh! Sausages and buns!
Demonstrate, boys!
Hey, look at this! We've got one!
Over here!
Yes! We're chosen!
Yes!
Frank!
We've been chosen together!
Hey, Brenda, you and me...
I'm so happy that God's
put our packages together!
- It's because we belong together.
- It's like we were made for each other!
- Get ready, boys!
- It feels amazing!
Oh, oh, yes!
I'm the first to enter eternity!
Potato!
Way to go, buddy!
Oh, Jesus fuck!
Oh, fuck! Me skin!
- She's peeling me fucking skin!
- What the fuck?!
For the love of shit, run!
Run!
I want my mommy!
They're eating children!
Fucking children!
So, you've learned
the terrible truth?
- I've got to tell everyone!
- No one will believe you.
I have to try!
Everyone will die, otherwise!
Oh, yeah! That's a good point!
Fuck me, right?
Run for your fucking lives!
Once you see that shit...
it will fuck you up for life.
Good luck! Have fun!
Made By Madmax12