- Hi! I'm Lenny.
- Hi.
Little body, did I scare you? I'm sorry.
Wake up. Wake up.
Okay, don't worry about it,
I'm gonna get you out in a jiffy.
You just keep holding your
breath, little wormy.
- Yo Lenny!
- I'm coming, Franki!
Move it, come on! Pap's waiting.
Here we go.
Got you! Okay, body you're free.
Now escape, go! Just go, cry freedom.
- You almost gave me a heart attack!
- Lenny, what are you doing?
What? I was just...
picking you some flowers!
Hey, mom said it's not okay to hit me!
Mom's not here.
Don't. Don't!
What do you mean?
It's a theme song.
Are they gone? Are they gone?
You're sure?
Good morning, south side reef,
I'm Katie Current, keep in a current!
We've just received
a visual confirmation.
The sharks are gone! I repeat,
the sharks are gone.
"Shark Tale"
'Starfish tours'
Mussel Crowe!
Jessica Shrimpson!
Cod Steward!
Up next to mother of eight hundred telses,
how she does it all?
But first, over to Jenis
with the traffic report.
Thanks, Katie.
Slight congestion here on the interreef 95,
there's an overturn microbe,
authorities are trying to calm it down.
Get out of your shell tombs
and go into the bus,
cause you'll be late!
Don't you yell at me, my mother
is your mother, okay?
SWIM
PRAWN SHOP
Yep, that's fake!
Fake? I worked ten years on that!
SUSHI TOWN
According to the latest scelephone,
buro of Sharks is at their all time high.
Join us tonight for an indepths report.
How long has this reef
leave under siege?
Is there no here among us?
Who can stop the Shark menace?
Hi, I'm Oscar, you might think you know,
but you have no idea.
Welcome to my crib! The good light
to wait to other hap lip,
check it out, I got my flat screen TV,
with six speaker surround!
CD, DVD, Play station,
I have a eight track player for those days
when you're feeling just a little...
Old school!
Cause even a superstar
mad daddy fish like me
has to have the basic necessity.
Yeah, like money!
PENTHOUSE APPARTMENTS
Come on shorties,
why mess with my fantasy!
Yourself bro, but the only
have no further name!
Oh that's funny, that was
perfect, you're granted.
Oscar! Over here!
- I got to talk to you!
- Al, I'll be right there.
- Hey yo, hang with this one.
- Oscar, you're the best!
Yo, dude!
Ho-ho Crazy Joe!
Let's do our great prawn house!
Can I be your financial advisor?
That's a billboard, Crazy Joe.
- You're living in a billboard?
- No.
That's making me crazy!
Hey Oscar! Look who came to visit!
- Got ya!!
- No, don't do that!
- Shouldn't you kids be at a school?
- Shouldn't you be at work?
Right back at me, ha?
Little smart mouth.
Look, I'm on my way. Ya all
stand out of trouble, allright?
Hey and clean that stuff up!
See ya!
See you, Oscar!
Yo, yo what's up down it?
- Big wash whales!
- Hi Oscar!
What's up?
Hey, rich side!
- Yo Johnson, is it lunch yet?
- You just got here!
That's my point!
Hey, headphone guy!
TURTLE WAX
- Looking good, ladies!
- Hey ya!
Get back to work!
I'm already punched in?
Angie.
- Good morning, can I help you?
- One wash, please.
- How about wax?
- Please.
Couple's great, we're having
special, what do you say?
Why not? It's maiding season.
And I'm feeling lucky!
Sykes whale wash.
Whale for a wash and the price,
Oh my gosh.
Oh, may I suggest a monic peel?
Removes lines and self damage.
- Good.
- Hey Ange!
Oh my gosh! Hi Oscar!
Hey, thanks for covering for me.
Yo, I'm sorry dog, Angie
needs to get a freak on,
would you hold for one moment, please?
- Thanks, dog.
- Oscar!
Come on Ange, dance with me, mama!
- Out me!
- Let me see it!
- Come on, Ange!
- Oscar! You're gonna get me fired!
Please. You? Fired?
No, that can't happen, cause then I would have
absolutely no reason to come to work.
- You don't mean that.
- Of course I do. You're like my best friend.
Let me see, tell me what
you think about this,
this is like the best idea ever, allright?
This is a short thing guarantee
cash extravaganza.
- Bottled water.
- Oh, no.
All I need, is another advance
of my paycheck from deposite,
and Ange, I am out of this place!
Oscar, it's relegating mister Sykes face,
with another one you-get-rich-quick-skims.
Go to something you're actually good at.
Your job! Which is some of
a miracle you still have!
Almost forgot.
- I brought you some breakfast.
- You didn't.
- Shelly creams?
- Your favourite!
Oh, by the way, you're still on hold.
Oh my gosh! Thank you for holding!
Busy busy busy! Go!
How can I help you?
No, I'm sorrry, mister Sykes
is at the meeting right now.
He won't be'll back till later.
How are my little babies this morning?
You missed me? You're doing good?
You see, Sykes. It's a fish eat fish world.
You eat the take, or you get taken.
True words have never been spoken.
Is that it? That all? We're done?
Now you and me, we've worked
together a long, long, long time.
- Please, Don Lino, it's hardly been like worked!
- Let me finish.
- And you know...
- And I love that about you!
Let me finish! That I'd lived my life for my sons.
- Raising them and protecting them,
- You're the best! He's the best, right?!
- Teaching them.
- Am I right or am I wrong?
- Ha? Am I right?
- Sykes, it's all been to pre...
- Right?
- To prepared.
- Sorry.
- That's all right.
For the day they run the reef.
Well, today is that day.
Luca!
Hey boss! Big butts!
Allright, to make long story short, from now on,
you work for Franki and Lenny, capish?
Lenny? Franki I understand, but Lenny?
- You can't be serious.
- That's serious.
It takes not only muscle to run things,
now Lenny, he's got the brains,
that's something special.
- Oh yeah, he's special.
- What's that supossed to mean?
- Nothing, nothing, I'm just saying.
- I bring you in here, look you in the eye
tell you what's what and what?
- What?
- What what?
- What what nothing!
- You said what first!
- I did say what first, I asked you what.
No, you said it then what, and I said what?
No, I said what what! Like what what!
- You said what first.
- Now you make a fun of me?!
No, no, no, you misunderstood,
you misunderstood.
Sorry, we're late, pap.
Lenny had an accident.
- He was born!
- He, he, he. You're comic genious!
Look, all I'm saying is
that kid ain't exactly no killer!
My Lenny is a killer, you hear me?
A cold blooded killer! Look at him!
Yeah?
That's it! That's it! You are out!
What?
- What do you mean I'm out?
- You're fired!
And on top of that, you're gonna
have to start paying me!
- For what?
- So not have us to that
little whale wash of yours!
WHALE.
Welcome to Oscar's crib.
Sixty foot slide covered tomb.
There's swimming casualties and plankton
across the deep, when you feel a little...
old school.
Oh stop your moaning, Oscar!
That could be a lot worse, you know?
Yeah, that's true. I can have
this job and look like you!
Who's behind me? Who's behind me!
Babe, give me some!
Indigestion.
She's gonna blow!
Wait! Headphone guy's still in there!
I get you! Hang on!
- Still think it could be worse?
- Yeah! I can look like you!
You're funny. We'll see
how you laugh at this!
Soap in the eye! Soap in the eye!
It's all right. It's all right. Look,
I'm gonna get you some cool pies,
we'll get you free hot wax
and all that, you like that?
- Allright, go at it, big baby.
- Thanks, Oscar.
All right.
- Ernie look, who's burning!
- Just the fish we were looking for!
- Yeah.
- The boss wants to see you right now!
- Right now!
- Ernie! Bernie!
My jelly fish brothers, voodoo!
Hey what's up, men?
Ah men, good to see you!
Fellows, I'm gonna ahead,
over there with Don Worby.
That's not the way
you sing that song, man!
Hey Sykes! My brother from another mother!
What's the day is it, baby?
What's going down?
Hey baby, this is all gravy today, allright
snap you fin, right on it. Snap it!
- You are not snapping it!
- Oscar!
Hey, don't sweat it, Sykes,
a lot of other fish can do it.
Oscar, would you just sit down, okay?
- Thank you!
- Look, I've been gone off for my markets.
Your owe to me is five grand! Five gees, okay?
- Five gees? Man, it's not five gees!
- See if this refreshes your memory!
Wow! That's crazy! Look at that!
You wrote everything down
so you wouldn't forget!
Wow! This is a perfect example why you're
in management and I'm not. You go boy.
Look, I have to start paying
Don Lino for protection,
so everything you owe me, you owe him!
- How did you figured that?
It's simple. The food chain.
You see, on top there's Don Lino. There's me.
- And there's regular fish.
- And there's me!
No, there's plankton, there's single celominas.
- Then there's me.
- I'm getting to that, there's coral.
There's rocks. There's whale poo.
And then there's you!
- There's my stuff.
- So after he's squeezing me,
he's squeezing you!
- What?
Wow! I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
- Easy boss, find your happy place.
- Happy place!
There's is no happy place with him around!
Okay, okay, okay. Please,
please just give some time,
that's all I'm asking!
I'm begging you, Sykes, please!
- Please!
- All right.
Cause I like you. I'm gonna give you
twenty-four hours to pay out.
All of it?
- How will I do that?
- That's your problem.
Bring my five thousand clams
tomorrow, or else...
- Or else what?
The boys will explain you.
Unpleasant!
Five thousand clams?!
You borrowed five thousand
clams from mister Sykes?
Oscar, why do you get yourself
into these situations?
I don't know, Ange,
it's just hard, allright?
Because I'm a little fish
in a big pot. A really big pot.
The ocean.
I'm nobody.
- I want some of that!
- Missis Sanches?
Uh, no. That.
The top of the reef. Where
the somebodies live.
I wanna be rich and famous like them!
- But I'm stuck down here.
- Well, what's wrong with down here?
I'll tell you what's wrong with down here.
Remember my dad? He worked
at the washes the whole life.
He was the number one tongue scrubber.
Every year for twenty-five years.
To me working at the wash
was the coolest job in the ocean.
But then I've learned something
I would never forget.
Ha, ha! Oscar dad's the tongue scruber!
Tongue scrubber! Tongue scrubber!
My dad was the greatest.
But nobody loves nobody.
- I wanna be a somebody!
- Oscar, you don't have
to live at the top of the reef
to be a somebody.
What's the difference, if I don't pay
mister Sykes' beg by tomorrow.
I'm dead anyway.
Wait here.
What's this?
- A pink pearl?
- Hm.
- Where did you get that?
- My grandmother gave it to me.
She said it started from a tiny grand of sand,
but then after a while,
it grew in something beautiful.
- Dreams can begin small too.
- No, I couldn't.
Take it! It'll get you the money
you need for mister Sykes.
What's new on the stand? I'd been
on all over this a thousand times,
I don't wanna to say it again.
You know, you've really given
me actually, you know that?
I don't know how else
to say this to you, Lenny.
You see something, you kill it
and you eat it. Period.
Thanks. That's what sharks do!
That's a fine tradition.
What's the matter with you?
Your brother Franki here, he's a killer.
- Right, pap.
- He's beautiful,
he does what he's supposed
to do! Wipe your face.
But you...
I'm hearing things...
You gotta understand,
when you look week,
it make me look week.
- I know, pap.
- I'm sorry.
- Lenny, Lenny, look at me.
Look at me!
This ain't nobody's business,
this is for you! It's for both of you!
And you're acting like
you don't even want it!
I need to know that you can handle that.
Right here in front of me now, eat this.
Yeah, oh Jee! Thanks pap.
Here's the thing. I'm on a diet,
and I've read an article about these
shrimps, they are not good for you,
you know how many calories are in one shrimp?
- A lot!
- It's true! It's true,
and the other thing is,
my sister had a baby and I took her baby,
cause she past away, and then the baby lost it's legs,
and it's all I wasn't suppose I gonna stop,
but I still take care of him with my wife.
It's crawling and it's fearly
happy, it's difficult, cause
I've been working on a
second shift at the factory,
there put food on the table, all the love
and I see that little guy's tears,
it's the worst in the world.
Front story.
I'm not asking you anymore, I'm telling you,
eat it!
- No! Have mercy!
- Pap, please!
- Eat!
- Don't eat!
- What are you...
- Son, eat...
- No!
the shrimp!
- Please!
- No, please, no!
- Lenny! Eat! Eat, eat, eat!
- Eat, eat, eat, eat!
- Put the shrimp down!
All right, go now. No one's
looking. Get out of here!
- You're free. Go on, go, go!
- Thank you. You're good person.
Come on, fellows!
- Papa, why can't I handle the reef?
- No! No! We're gonna do this as a family.
Franki, I want you to take Lenny
out, and show him the rules.
- Oh come on, pap.
- Son you're gonna learn how to be a shark!
Will you like it or not.
- That kid better show up, or he's dead meat!
- Yes, at a word, boss.
Get a whole load of the money,
give it to mister Sykes.
Come on, hurry up, hurry up!
- This is our chance, you don't wanna miss it!
- Are you sure about this?
A friend of friend of mine tipped me off!
- Race is rigged. We can't lose!
- Well what's the horses name?
Lucky day.
LUCKY DAY
SEABISCUIT
- We're gonna be rich. Rich!
- Top of the reef, here I come!
No, wait! What am I doing?
Remember what Angie said,
remember what Angie said.
What did Angie say?
Dreams can begin small,
you just have to bet it all!
Bet it all!
Five thousand on Lucky day to win!
That's two hundred a one!
- That would pay a million clams!
- Than I guess it makes me, Oscar la millionaire.
Lucky day! Lucky day! Lucky day!
Nice bet.
You have a name?
You wanna tell me what it is?
Well mine's Lola.
Come on man! Get it handled yourself!
So...
Lola, my name's O...
My name is Oscar, sweety.
- Missis Sanches!
- I hate when it hops,
smooth dog, don't work with me!
- No, my bad. Hey! So...
- Oscar!
I was starting to think
you skipped on on me.
Sykes! Hey! I see you...
already to your way to the cashier stand.
- What are doing?
- You mind bring us back some drinks?
- Why are you touching me?
- That'll be great man, thanks.
Oh I know, I'll bring back
some of little winner thing!
- You mean the one with the toothpicks?
- What are doing? Don't listen to him!
- Come on Lola, let me escort you to...
my box.
- Your box?
His box? You can't even afford
the gum to the seats!
He just laid five grand on Lucky day,
I think he can afford
anything he wants!
Five grand? My five grand?
- No, it was another five grand.
- You had the money to pay me back
and you bet it anyway?
- Hold on.
- Give me that!
- Sykes!
- Clearly I've made a mistake.
- No! No, wait! Lola!
Look, deep down, I'm really superficial.
And don't get me wrong, you're cute, but
you are a nobody.
Oscar, you're cute, but you are a nobody.
Wait Lola! Come back! I'm not a nobody!
I'm a winner!
You are unbelievable, you're
in trouble up to your gilles,
and still, you're asking for more?
Now go on, get in here!
Oscar, you better pray
that this horse of yours comes through.
You bet my five thousand!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Out of my seat!
You, out of my seat!
Unbelievable! Unbelievable!
- Sit tight and watch the race.
- With your good eye!
Horses are ready on the post.
Race is going special by
Seabiscuit and some of other!
The long shoulder Lucky day appears
of having trouble of getting
out of the gates.
- What?
Only a sucker could have bet on him!
No, no, no, don't sweat it man,
he does this all the time,
he just blam.
- Oh, what's this?
Lucky day has crossed his way through the gates!
And he's off for running!
That was straight away
Seabiscuit forcing on Lucky day!
Fast! Go fast!
Coming round the fall tone the Seabiscuit riding,
and Lucky day well behind the pack.
And in comes Lucky day!
Coming up from behind!
He's passing other tales! Now or never!
Sykes, you see? Who's your fish now?
Around the final turn here comes Lucky day!
Lucky day is now calling the Fishfingers!
He gets ahead.
Wait, I'm getting tired, just beg him up!
Look how Lucky day goes!
Absolutely amazing!
This is Lucky day's big day!
That's Lucky day!
What happened!
Lucky day is down!
No!!!
And here comes Fishfingers
followed by Seabiscuit yellow tail.
Fishfingers wins!
- What is it?
- Wait, wait, wait I just wanted to hold you!
Get out of my way, let me see!
Poor sad day for Lucky day!
And that's why they call him the low shot.
Yo, that was crazy, right?
Who knew? I mean everything's set,
there's a luck, we're good to go, we're in the money,
and he trips underwater. Who in a hell
trips underwater? And by the way...
That's it! That's it, I've had it.
Ernie, Bernie, I want you to find
the deepest, darkest hole in the ocean,
and when you do, dig deeper,
and put him in it!
Sorry kid, it's nothing personal. It's just business.
Don't worry about a day,
cause every little thing is gonna be all right!
- This is how you sing it, Oscar.
- Yeah.
Sykes, you like your money.
I set ticket easy on you.
- But Sykes is not here!
- True.
- Ernie, let me ask you a question.
- Yeah man, go on.
Why is it that millacscan sting on a people?
But they have no affect on you.
Ernie, I didn't mean it Ernie!
I didn't mean it man!
Ernie! You made a joke!
- Good one man! Respect!
- Respect.
Load fire!
- Franki, you know I can't do this!
- Lenny, if you wanna make pap happy,
you gotta kill something!
- Or I could find a very old sick fish
and just wait!
- Oh.
This getting around, you think
of the day in the restaurant,
you know how fish pop!
Bit of bit, bit of bob,
this that the other, then
how you're doing? Boom!
Get a body here. Dead
Okay, seriously I can't
understand why this is so
you have to be more specific.
- More specific? You want specific?
- Be a shark, for once in your life!
- Oh, what am I gonna do?
Lenny, forget about it, okay?
We do a couple of practice,
but a bim, but a bom,
pap's happy, you're a shark,
life goes on! Capish?
- Okay.
- Okay, capish.
- Wait, wait, wait. Bingo.
Right there, there you see? TV dinner.
- Don't get lousy on this.
- All right. Come on. I am the tiger.
Franki, I can do this!
What if I can't do this?
- Then don't bother coming home.
- Good point! All right.
Hit him in the tale again.
- I like his funny face, man.
- Funny face, yeah.
- Ernie!
- No!
Guys! Guys! Don't leave me alone!
Come on, there could be a shark out here!
Oh no, wait!
I'm sorry, no, no, no. I'm not gonna...
- Lenny!
- What?
Like this!
Oh my god! Just get off me!
Wait a minute!
Do me a favor, don't chew me,
I'm not for that.
- I'm not gonna eat you.
- Don't do the whole hit trip thing with me!
Listen to me, don't move until I tell you!
That's it, Lenny, here you go, body!
That's it, dig straight, baby. Dig it!
Look, I'm just pretending,
so you can get away.
When I turn around, you take off!
Tastes like chicken! Mhh.
- Oh no. No.
- What did I tell you!
I'm sorry, I didn't get it,
you want me to go now?
- What are you doing, just come home!
- That's it, I've had it up to here!
- Oh no!
- Hurry, swim!
- No, Franki wait!
- No, get your boy! Get your boy!
Franki!
Lenny,
- Lenny, is that you?
- I'm here, Franki.
- Come closer.
- Yes, what is it?
- I'm so cold.
- That's just because we're cold blooded.
Moron!
Franki, no!
No!!!
This is all my fault! I'm so sorry, Franki!
Oh my, how am I gonna
explain this to pap?
Oh no!
Watch it! Back off! I'm crazy! I will do it!
- Wow!
Oh, what a...
Don't hurt us, we're sorry!
It was all Ernie idea!
Oscar! Did you kill that shark?
All right, yeah! Yeah!
Exactly how it looked, that's how it is.
What happened!
- Oh, you want to know what happened?
- Yeah, you're standing on top of shark!
- Go on man!
- Well I'll tell you what happened!
Big old shark, seventy-five hundred feet long,
so he's swimming at me, right?
- With teeth like razors!
- Razors!
And it was all like, you want come at me like that,
you want come to all like that?
Dude, do the muscle thing, the muscle thing!
Oh right, right. So I told that dude,
I said do you see this guy?
And I pointed like this,
well he's got a brother.
And he lives right over here!
And I think it's time for a little
family reunion!
- You see man, I told you!
- Excuse me.
- We were right there, right there!
- Pardon me. Move it!
Sorry, sorry! She seems so nice on TV.
Oscar, Katie Current. As a first fish in history,
that ever take on a shark and win, tell me,
does this mean you're now
the protector of the reef?
- New sheriff in town, the big cahuna?
- Katie, I'm a keeper of reef,
- I can call you Katie, right?
- Of course!
Any shark
tries to mess around
in Oscar town,
is going down!
Yeah, just poetic, I mean poetic!
Oscar! Oscar.
Okay, get out of here, barracuda,
any further questions will be filled by me!
- And you are?
- I'm his manager, Sykes. With an Y.
And I'm his financial advisor!
You wanna see my puppets?
Hello!
Could you excuse for a moment, please?
- My manager?
- Kid, you're a superstar!
We're gonna make a fortune!
Just let me handle it.
- What about the five gees?
- Forget the five gees.
- From now on we're partners!
- So what exactly are we talking about here?
- I'm thinking about 90/10 split.
- Well, that's actualy pretty generous.
You're the 10, I take my 90 off the top.
- I don't think so!
- Talk to me.
- You get 50!
- 70.
- 20!
- 75.
Dude! You're going the wrong way!
- Fifty-fifty!
- You're happy?
- No, you're happy?
- No! Deal!
- Deal!
My manager and I are now
prepared to take your questions.
Oscar, are you going to continue
working here at the wash?
Please, I bearly work here now!
- Keep in up, kid. You're slaying them!
- No, he's slaying sharks!
Hey, that's good,
that's good, I like that!
Oscar, the Sharkslayer!
- Wow!
- A Sharkslayer!
You heard it here first, from now on,
any shark tries to bother this reef,
it's had its funeral.
I could fly high...
- Franki, we'll miss you.
- To Franki!
It's a terrible thing, Don Lino.
Everybody loved Franki.
May whoever did this, die at thousand depths.
May his stinking maggy coffered corpse rot
in a fire depth of hell!
Thank you for your kind
thoughts, Giuseppe.
Oh and may Lenny be
found safe and sound too.
- Hope he's okay.
- Oh Lenny.
- Don't worry, boss.
- I said some things to him...
- We' gotta find him.
- We're searching everywhere.
Forget about it, he'll turn up.
What's wrong with that kid?
Why does he gotta be so different?
Franki, god rest his soul,
he was perfect. Perfect!
Oh, Luca, who could have done this?
Don Lino, at this most difficult time,
please accept my deepest condolences.
Thank you, Don Brizzi,
for honouring my son with your song.
I got some news, about
the guy who took out Franki.
Hey, let's talk over here.
He come out of nowhere, this guy.
Calls himself the Sharkslayer.
- I'm here, over here.
- The Sharkslayer!
- Where do I find him?
- He's from the south side reef,
that's all we could dig up.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Any request?
- Luca.
- How about that Titanic song?
- No, no!
Get Sykes, he knows that
reef better than anybody.
I wanna find this guy, I wanna
know everything about him,
I wanna know where he lives,
I wanna know where he sleeps,
he pops to kill, I wanna know
about it. Who is the Sharkslayer.
Here he is! The Sharkslayer!
GUP
PENTHOUSE
Let's get this party started right!
- There he is, the big dog!
- Sykes?
Found that dog. Found it! Oscar,
raise the reef, raise the reef!
- Yeah?
- Oh yeah.
Hot!
- Hey, that's from desperating!
- Come on, cabbage back! Cabbage back!
- Angie! You made it!
- Hey, wait! You're gonna break my gift!
Come on, you didn't have to get me anything.
- What did you get me?
- Well, what does every bachelor need!
A lover lamp! How did you
know I love lover lamps?
You know what, I'm gonna put it
right here, next to my other one.
Hey, come Ange, I wanna show
the best thing about this place!
- Wow!
- How great is this view?
- Top of reef! It's amazing!
- I know , it's beautiful, right?
Like your, like your new appartment?
It's... wow! Awesome!
All I'm trying to say, is that...
- I'm proud of you, Oscar.
- Yeah, it was nothing, really.
You know what? Wait
right here, don't move,
I'll be right back.
Girl, you are gonna flip!
- Wow! I'm back!
- Oh you're back!
You know what Ange,
where I am right now,
this whole new life I've got,
or my dreams coming true,
you know, weird kind of way?
- I'd never could have done it without you.
- Oh, sure you could.
Well, probably not.
- Ange, here.
- Oh, Oscar!
I know, I know. Just sorry,
that it took so long.
- Oh that's okay!
- Bam!
My grandmother's pearl!
With entries! Now, I don't forget anything,
and I never forget who my friends are!
Ange, I...
Oh, hi. I'm not interrupting
something, am I?
- Yes, we're talking!
- No! Hey Lola!
Wow, you're here!
You gotta come best my meet friend, Angie.
Eat my best, my man, Wangie?
Your best friend? Oh that's sweet.
So you won't mind if I still
be here for a while and leave?
So, look who's a somebody after all!
- You know...
- Sharks! On the edge of the reef!
The Great Whites!
Okay, everbody go home,
spend the last few hours
that you have with each other!
Oh! I mean,
that's the way it used to be around here.
We were all screaming, forgot our stuff but,
now's Oscar came to town!
So Lola, baby, just wait here,
and I will be right back, I'm gonna go
ahead take care of the sharks.
Go get them tiger!
Wow!
- All right Oscar, you can do this!
- Go get them Oscar!
Lenny! Where the hack is he?
- Lenny!
- Hey! What are you doing?
There's a Sharkslayer around here!
Oh yeah, Lenny! Lenny!
- That was close.
- Super close.
Don't panic.
- Quiet, we're safe.
- No, not you again!
- Yeah, what was that?
- What is with you, man!
- Shh, he could be anywhere.
- Who?
Shh, the Sharkslayer.
- There's no Sharkslayer around here.
- Yes, there is!
- No, there is not, trust me on this one.
- Get a hold of yourself, man!
- This is no time to act crazy!
- You're the one acting crazy! Crazy!
You're right. You're right, I'm sorry.
I haven't been myself since the...
the... No, don't cry!
No, that's not all that.
- Just relax.
- It's my fault!
- Not really, but still!
- Okay calm. You just need a little time.
- Man look, things are work out.
- You think?
Yeah! So...
Look, I'll take off, and you
should just go home, okay?
- Okay.
- Hey, good luck, dog.
- Wait!
- What, man?
- I didn't catch your name.
- Oscar.
- I'm Lenny. Hi!
- Hi.
- Where do you live?
- Lenny? Where I come from,
fish don't like to get
grabbed by sharks, okay?
- Sorry.
- Go home!
There is no home for me anymore.
Don't you understand that?
- You're too big to be grabbing me like this.
- Take me home with you.
- Shh! What?
- You won't even notice I'm in!
I'm like the invisible shark!
- Are you crazy?
- Please, I'm begging you,
don't leave me alone!
- Shh!
Yo! Put you fins on the wall,
where I could see them!
- Got ya!
- Hey, yo! Shorty!
- Oscar!
- What ya doing here?
- Check out my mad bum!
- Check it out.
Bum! There is!
- Do you like it?
- You kids got some skills!
What did I tell you? You can
shooting be doing this!
And besides, it's not safe
to be here at night.
It is now, dude bro,
you're the Sharkslayer!
- Sharkslayer?
- Sometimes I'd be coughing like that.
Look, I just need you off of these streets.
- Come on!
- Get your butts home!
Cause I know your moms,
and I'm just tell them you are doing bad.
- Hey let's go make mister Sykes puff up!
- Yeah! Bye Oscar!
- Lenny! Did you see what just hapened there?
- I know. They think you're the Sharkslayer!
As if!
- I appreciate your funky tone, actually.
- No, wait up! Hey! I'm sorry.
Seriously, I don't want you mad at me.
And I certainly don't want you to 'slay me'!
You're having a good time, right?
Are you enjoying yourself?
Well, for your information,
I am the Sharkslayer!
Oscar the Sharkslayer,
that's what they're saying!
- Wait, you mean you?
- Yeah.
When the anchor...
- Oh, you're a liar!
- Hey, I didn't lie, all right?
Allright, I lied!
But that was a little lie! Come on,
no one's was gonna be hurt anyway!
What am I doing? I'm not
gonna explain myself to you.
- You know what? You're on your own!
- No problem!
And if god forbids, someone should, I don't know.
Find out the truth about the
Sharkslayer on my way back...
- You wouldn't!
- I would.
Come here!
Of course you can cup on me!
But you know, I mean, you're a shark, right?
And I'm a Sharkslayer,
so we can't be seen together.
- You dig dug?
- Dig dug, dug dig. Dig dug, yeah!
- Yo, diggy dug!
- Just come on!
Okay Lenny, follow my every
move and don't make a sound.
You got it. Wow, echo. Echo!
Now, coming for the
south side sharks, I'm fifty.
Oh, it's not okay to hit!
- Get your bum in there!
- You think anybody heard that?
- Who is that? Ha? Who's that?
- Yo-hoo! Crazy Joe!
I thought I heard something!
Did you get that shark?
- You have no idea, Joe!
- That's great! Well, gotta go, my show's on!
All right. We're safe. For now.
Hey a bed! Oh! Yeah,
that's good. That's heaven.
Snuggely buggley waggely!
- I love you man!
- Wow, hold on!
- You're my new best friend!
- Stop it! Okay, you wanna be friends?
Fine, but we gotta lay down some rules.
Rule number one, no snuggely buggely,
whatever that just was!
- You got it. Anything else?
Allright, rule number two!
And this is the most important rule.
Any event, that possibly,
you know, you're hungry...
Don't worry, I'm not gonna eat anyone.
In case you haven't noticed,
I'm different from the other sharks.
Let's put it that way,
leave it at that. Good night!
- Define different.
- You'll laugh.
- I'm not gonna laugh!
- Well that's just what you said,
and then what happens later? You laugh.
Lenny, I give you my word.
Okay, I will tell you, I'm...
I'm a vegetarian.
Hm, hold on.
So that's it?
- What do you mean that's it?
- I'm just...
You're first fish I've ever told!
I'm so tired of keeping that all a secret!
- And my dad,
- Wow, hey!
he'll never accept me for who I am.
- What's wrong with me?
- Nothing is wrong with you, man.
- I think all sharks should be like you.
- God, that sweet to say.
And stop blaming yourself for what happened.
- Really?
- If you wanna blame anybody,
blame me. Cause if I hadn't been out there,
in the first place, nothing of this would happen!
Yeah, if pop knew that,
he'd ice you for sure.
Ice? Was that a godfather or something?
- Yeah.
- What do you mean, 'yeah'?
Yeah, he is.
Hey, are you all right?
GAME OVER
- Ha, man, I told you!
- I'm doing this!
Left circle double left square right
to the down square square.
Another square! Respect.
- Respect.
Oh yeah? Well I got some news for you!
The Sharkslayer made me
his manager, so I'm now...
what I like to call untouchable!
Did you hear me?
- Sykes!
- Okay.
Hey Oscar!
- Sykes!
- Hey hey hey, there he is,
my brother, my player, the Sharkslayer!
- Yeah whatever, Sykes listen.
And another thing, from now on you're gonna
have to start paying me for protection!
Sykes, the deal is off, the shark
I killed was Don Lino's son!
- I know! Any grade?
- Not if he finds out!
What do you mean find out? I've got
him on the phone right now!
That's right, Lino. I've got the
Sharkslayer right here in front of me!
- And he's gonna slay you and all of your sharks!
- Sykes, shut up! Shut up!
Hey that's good. That's good, I like that.
Shut up, Lino! Shut up!
- What? Oh, kid, he wants to talk to you.
- I know, I'm not here! I'm not here!
Yeah, he's right here.
- Hello.
- Shut up? Shut up?
You don't tell me shut up,
I tell you shut up!
- What? Hello?
- Yeah, how you're doing?
Let me have a pie with everything on it.
Anchovies, meet balls, mushrooms...
- Luca!
- Oh, hi boss!
- What are you doing working in a pizza joint?
- Get off the phone!
But I'm hungry!
My guys are coming for you, Sharkslayer!
They are going to tear you fin from fin!
Come on, now who's your puff daddy?
Who takes care of you?
Come on you two, we've got work to do.
- I was winning!
- Sykes, Sykes, hold, look!
- You got it all wrong!
- I've been writing songs about you kid!
- All the shark bites..
- Sykes.
With his teeth dear.
- And then Oscar,
- Sykes!
- Kicked his butt!
- Sykes, Sykes, man!
- Come on!
- Maybe I can help?
Hey! Lola! What are you doing here?
You pop it up sometimes in places!
Oh you said to wait, so...
- I've been waiting.
- Look, I don't have a lot of time
for a whole hand clappy making the life's go on
music playing and the guitar thing, you know.
- What are you afraid of?
- Afraid? That's funny.
I'm not afraid of nothing, it's just...
- Oh baby, you're so tense.
- Yeah, you know. I've really been stressed lately,
like protecting the reef,
you know, I do that for myself.
- It's just too crazy.
- It's just too much.
Yeah, you know, just one
thing on top of the other.
Actually I was thinking about retiring.
- You don't wanna do that.
- I don't?
You have worked your way to the top.
You don't wanna go back
to the bottom, do you?
- No. No, no way!
- You just show them who's boss.
And the sharks will leave you alone.
Yeah, you're right!
Lenny!
- Pss! Lenny! Where are you?
- Hello, Oscar.
Angie! Hey! What are you doing here?
What Oscar, did you forget something?
Oh maybe, you forgot your shark!
Hi.
Shark! Swim Angie! I'll cover you! Quick!
- Before it's too late! Go home without me!
- Oh stop it! Your friend shark here told me everything.
- Lenny, why would you do that?
- I don't know, I like her!
Thank you, I like you too.
What were you thinking bringing him in here?
- No, I just, I'm still working at the cakes.
- Cakes? You lie!
- Everybody thinks you're slayer of the sharks!
- Who am I gonna tell that they are wrong?
- How could you lie to me, Oscar? Me?
- Don't take it personally. Come on, I lied to everybody!
All right. Look, I'm sorry. I totally betrayed you,
but listen I got just one...
little problem I gotta take care of.
- Of what's that?
- Sharks are coming to get me!
- And they should!
I mean, what did you expect?
You just take credit for killing the shark
and everything will be fine and
dandy for the rest of your life?
Yeah!
But don't you worry about it.
Me and Lenny got it,
we go fix it!
- Wow, wow, wow.
- What's with the 'we', I don't wanna 'we' part of this.
- Hey, too late now, vagie boy, they'll be looking for you too.
- Point taken. What's the plan?
- Allright, just what we will do.
Oscar! Here's the plan! You tell
the truth. And you go home!
Allright, look. This we're gonna do, right?
We will paint you up all bloody. Just mess, right?
And you go swim out and meet
the sharks before they get here.
And you will say stop!
Don't go no further! This Sharkslayer's crazy man!
He beat me senceless!
He's stone cold killer, man!
And then you can tell them I'm huge!
You know, tell them that I'm handsome.
- You're going way too far, Oscar!
- Acually he hasn't gone far enough.
Exactly!
What?
You need slay a shark,
and I need to dissappear.
This is what we're gonna do.
This is Katie Current, reporting live.
We've got uncontrolled reports of...
Shark!!!
Look, it's the Sharkslayer!
Holy microbe! Did we get that?
Hey, Ange! Oscar's on the TV!
Show me that. Allright,
do what you do best.
Do you hear them, Lenny?
They are going crazy, man!
- They love us!
- They love you, they hate me!
- What?
- Let's switch sides,
maybe I can be the Fishslayer!
- They'll never see it coming!
- Come on, man!
You saw this, you'll never
have to go home again!
You can start a new life!
- Now give me a growl!
- Okay.
- Like that?
- That was pretty good.
Let's go!
Is that what you're offering?
Do you understand how huge
my client is? Turn on your TV right now!
Lenny, hold on! Lenny, Lenny!
Turn off your TV! Turn off your TV!
- Don't swallow!
- Oscar?
No, it's Pinnoccio. Of course it's me!
Why did you do that?
- I'm sorry.
- No, no. Sorry, is when you step
on somebody's fin at the movie theater.
It is sorry. Sorry, is what you say,
Hey, where's the baby, dude?
And it turns out to burst is just fat!
This is as far away from sorry,
as you could possibly get!
- But Oscar! I think I'm gonna puke.
- No, no, no! Lenny, just open up.
Nice and easy.
- Are you not entertained?
- Go Oscar, man!
- You can't handle its rule!
- Go get them!
You had me at hello!
Turn your TV back on! What are you doing,
turning your TV off? Turn it on!
This reef is huge. How we're supposed
to find the Sharkslayer?
This is it, Lenny. Big finish!
Just like we practised.
- The flying fish?
- The flying fish!
Little more help here, body boy!
- Sorry.
- Thank you.
Curse you, Sharkslayer!
Yeah, and you tell Don Lino,
that I don't never ever ever ever never!
Want to see another shark
on this reef again!
- Ever!
Remember this name,
Oscar the Sharkslayer!
Aha! You see? You see? Ha?
Look at Oscar! Oscar!
Hey, Lol...
It seems that Sharkslayer not only
countered a few sharks today,
but maybe a few hearts?
Has the reef's most eligible
bachelor have been snapped up?
I'm Katie Current. You're live watching
the Sharkslayer making out.
Hey Angie, can you hand me the blue one?
Thank you.
Who steps in the room?
- Yeah!
- Oscar and Lenny!
What a dream baby! Give me that!
Give me some fin!
- High fin!
- Give me some fin!
- Low fin!
- Did you see me? I was like...
- That was great!
- When you punched me, the crowd was...
Yeah, the ate it up! Hey Angie, Angie
you ain't know how Lenny had me in him, did you?
- It was like an Oscar explosion!
- How good was I?
- Oh you was the ball!
- Thank you, thank you.
Hey, hey, hey! Casanova!
I saw your big finish on the news.
Nice smooch, lover boy.
It was just private, just private.
- Private! The entire reef saw you do it.
- Hey, somebody's got a bad move.
Come on, Ange. Let me see the smile!
- Show me the smile, baby!
- Knock it off!
- What is gotten in you?
- Me? I want, I swear! Sometimes I wanna
take your big dumb dummy head and just...
- Ange, Ange, what is the problem?
- Problem? There's no problem, I'm not having problem!
Maybe it's probably because
you're the one with a problem!
- Hey you guys?
- What have you got against Lola?
Not my lips, that's for sure!
- Okay, what's going on?
- I'm gonna stay out of this.
Look, why would you even
care about Lola anyway?
- I don't!
- You don't?
- No!
- No what?
- I don't know!
- You guys, you wanna get?
- No
- No!
Just tell me, Oscar, cause I'm curious.
Why do you think she's interested?
Do you think for one minute
that she would even be with you,
if you want to reach a fame of Sharkslayer?
- Come on guys, please don't fight.
- Are you that light?
- At least she treats me like I'm somebody!
- Yeah, but will she love you if you were nobody?
- Nobody loved me when I was nobody!
- I did!
Before the money, and before the fame,
before the lie! To me you were a somebody, Oscar.
Now you're nothing! But a fake. A shame.
- You're joker.
- Here I come!
Sebastian, the way you'll washing dolphin!
- Angie.
- No, forget it! Just go!
Cause I'm tired of hearing that everything
you had in your life wasn't good enough.
Including me.
- Angie?
- Oh honey, I'm sorry.
Go back and do it again.
Hey, come on. It'll be okay.
You can't have the lose!
You got shark breath!
'O' mints
'Coca cola'
'Get real'
What are you kids doing?
How many times I got to tell you?
This is past your bed time! Go on, all right.
Hey, hey, hey! What are you kids are...
Well, it looks pretty good!
You guys should do this for a living!
Preparation 'O'!
It slays hemorroids like Oscar slays sharks!
Hey Oscar!
Angie was right. I am a joker.
Hey, Sharkslayer. Why are you in here?
- All your friens are inside!
- Not all my friends.
You may not little bottom feeder
from the whale wash.
Forget about her. She's a nobody.
I'm the nobody.
Oh let me guess. She told you that she loves you,
is that it?
It's not like you feel the same way about her.
You know what? I don't think
this is gonna work out.
What? Are you dumping me?
Let me explain something to you.
We get party like at your birthday.
Ha! Young love!
CHOCOLATES
FLOWERS
- Hey Oscar!
- Hey, I can't talk, I gotta find Angie!
I need to tell her... I love her!
Where you're going, Oscar?
- Hi, whale wash.
- Give me the phone!
- We'll you got a whale to wash and the price...
- Give me back the phone! And the price is...
very very low. Consider no good washers!
- Good one, Ernie.
How many times do I have to tell you? It's gosh!
You get a whale of a wash,
and the price - oh my gosh!
- All right, we get it man.
- Whale wash,
rhymes with gush!
- Give me that!
Get out of here, both of you.
Won't you use some place else, will you?
- Sykes? Where's Angie?
- You tell me!
Whale wash, you got a whale of a wash... No?
- It's for you.
- Ha?
- Hello?
- Is this the Sharkslayer?
- Yeah, who is this?
- It's Luca the octop... I mean,
forget about it. Now you follow
these instructions, okay?
Fall cabinet, top drawer,
there's a package. Get it.
That's right, tough guy,
we got your girl.
That is gonna be a sit-down. In one hour.
- Who is it?
- Shh!
Be there if you don't want
to see her sleeping with the fishes.
The bad ones.
Now nod your head if you understand.
Now tell me if you nodded your head.
I nodded.
They got Angie. And they want a sit-down.
I never meant for anybody to get hurt,
especially not Angie. This is all my fault.
That's a classic move. I've
seen it a thousand times.
They take the thing you love the most,
and then they use it against you!
Look, we gotta go to that sit-down,
and we gotta save her.
Wow, wow, wow. Look,
I wanna save Angie too,
but I can't just sit there and say,
- Hi pap, I'm a dolphin!
- Lenny?
And my friend Sharkslayer, he is a fake!
- Fake?
- Come on!
We're gonna need
a better plan than that.
This is a joke, right? This is a joke?
Because you know, I told Lino,
Shut up, Lino! Shut up!
Tell me you didn't make it a low kid.
Tell me that's not Lenny. Tell
me you're a real Sharkslayer.
- Please!
- I'm sorry, Sykes.
I'm not.
But the sharks don't know that.
Would you stop screwing around? This will
never work. We're dead, we're dead!
Sh! Thank you, Sykes. Thank you!
My man Sykes has just begged me
not to murder you all up here, right?
Now I might listen to him.
But then I cannot might not.
And that depends on the individual behaviour
of all the individuals in here. Individuals.
Hey, is that right?
- Look, he's got dolphine muscle.
- My uncle Will got wacked by one of those.
All right. Which one of you sorry
deans caled this meeting?
That would be me.
So, this the Sharkslayer? I've been
looking forward to meet you.
I feel like we're practically family!
You know that's funny, ain't it?
I brought my kids into the
world. Full love and care.
And you took them out.
You know who I am?
Do you know who I am?
I'm the Don! The boss of the Great White sharks!
Hey boss, I saved your seat.
I've been running this reef
since before you was born!
And If you thought that guy like me,
can't get to a guy like you, guess what?
You thought wrong!
Man, you're the one who's wrong.
I barely know that girl.
- What her name was?
- Oh yeah?
Well I say he's bluffing.
- If I wasn't marry.
- How you're doing, pretty lady?
- Lola! We meet again!
- You know, Sharkslayer,
there's only one thing
I like better than money...
Revenge!
- Oh, I'm in love!
- Your shark slaying days are over!
and there ain't nothing you can do about it.
Ha? What's so funny?
You got nothing! Nothing!
Sebastian, take a roll!
Can't touch this!
Stop! Oscar time!
Okay!
New rules! Nobody!
I repeat, nobody makes
a move without my okay.
I am the pattern marker now baby!
From now on everything flows through me!
What did he do? What did he do? I can't see it!
You don't lose a two, you don't
grow one back without my okay.
- Okay?
- Okay.
If you sneeze, you don't white
dead boogie without my okay.
- Okay?
- Okay.
All right. And you don't say okay, without my okay.
Okay?
Okay! Thank you all for coming,
good meeting, we gotta go.
And one more thing. What is with
all your living in a low boo?
- Oscar!
- That was supposed to be my
get yourselves a real high-down!
- Oscar.
And take the good look, Lino. It's over!
- Your old school!
- Oscar!
What?
Excuse me.
- Ange, are you okay?
- No! I am not okay!
- He ate me!
- I had to take it.
- The taste was killing me!
- Lenny?
Is that you?
You're alive?
I thought I lost you!
What are you wearing, ha?
What is that?
Hey boss, it's Lenny!
He was wearing the disguise,
so we wouldn't recognize him.
But now he's not wearing a disguise,
so we do recognize him!
- Hi pap.
- Are you kidding me?
Are you kidding me?
Are you out of your mind?
Do you have any idea how this looks?
This is the best sit-down,
I've ever been to!
What are you doing with disguise?
You took out your own flash and blood!
- Franki!
- Look pap, just listen!
It's not that, you never take
side against the family, ever!
Hey Don Lino! Sir, listen!
It's not his fault!
- This is between you and me.
- What did I ever do to you!
You took Franki away, and you've
turned Lenny into a dolphin!
I'm gonna get you!
- Oscar! Look out!
- Oscar! Swim! Swim for your life!
You're gonna regret the day
you became the Sharkslayer!
- Look who's talking in the pot hole!
- Ha?
You're still hungry big guy!
Well say hello to my little friends!
- Try again.
- Whale wash.
You get a whale of a wash
and a price. Oh my gosh!
All right, you got it right!
- You got it right.
- Move! Everybody everyway!
Come on, Lino. It's time
to clean up your act.
Pap, leave him alone!
All right Lino! Game's over!
Lenny? What are you doing in there?
- Sorry.
- Where's Lino?
- He's right behind me, isn't he?
- You're mine now!
- Let's finish the Sharkslayer.
- Oh we're about to!
Thank you for coming to whale wash.
Okay! Somebody needs to get me
out of the bubble. Today!
- Angie?
- The Sharkslayer has done it again!
- Hey!
- This time...
- Wait!
- glorying two sharks into his
death trap of high gene.
- No!
Oscar, you're the somebody,
everybody wants to be!
The top of the food chain!
Tell our cameras, how it feels to be you.
- Angie?
- Oscar, get me out of here, quick!
I need to get straight so I get
as far away as I supposed to.
- Look what you did to him!
- No, it's all a big misunderstanding!
Sharkslayer, over here! One word
about you, Sharkslayer.
- Sharkslayer! Sharkslayer!
- Stop!
I am not a real Sharkslayer!
- I lied.
- What?
And I'm not a real financial advisor!
Okay, it was an anchor that killed Franki.
I didn't have anything to do
with it and neither did Lenny.
If that was true, why did you ran away?
I think you always wanted me to be like Franki.
I'll never be the shark you want me to be.
What is your problem?
So, your son likes calp? So?
His best friends are fishes. So?
He likes to dress like a dolphin, so what?!
Everybody loves him just the way he is.
Why can't you?
Don't make the same mistake that I did.
I didn't know what I have. Till I lost her.
Will you get me out of this?
So I can hug my kid.
- And tell him I'm sorry.
- Pap!
Give me a hue.
I love you son, no matter
what you eat, or how you dress.
- Oscar?
- Angie?
Angie...
I wish I knew now
what I knew then. I mean...
I wish you knew,
what I knew. I mean...
- Before this.
- You're blowing it, man!
Mind your business, all right?
I'm just emotional,
and there's pressure!
What I'm saying, I just...
I didn't mean the top of the reef.
Everything I wanted was right there in front of me.
The whole time.
What about being a somebody?
I'm nobody without you.
You're not helping.
Oh, come here! You big dumb dummy head!
I've never told you till this, but
you're the best henchmen
and guides I ever had.
Come on, group hug!
- Ah! Hey!
- Sorry man, sorry.
Come such, straight again
man, don't be afraid.
Oh forget, the moment's gone.
So Lino, Don, we're cool, right?
I mean like the reef is safe,
you know walk the streets,
you know without... you know?
Yeah, we're cool.
Oscar, excuse me, Oscar?
You've lost everything
you've lied so hard to achieve.
Tell me, what's next for you?
Come on! Everyone's waiting!
- Mister manager!
- Hey, I just gotta put
the finishing touch on my new desk.
I love you, pap.
- Yo, dog!
- Sykes!
All right partner,
let's see what you can do.
Sykes and Oscar's whale wash
is now opened for business!
Yo E, B, let's get this party boomed!
The other wheels of steel!
Yo Christina! Missy!
How about we have a low?
Oscar leashes furnal!
What's up with your bow? Let it go!
Hey Angie? Sorry papa and I are late,
but we brought some new customers!
- Hey, how you're doing?
- Wow!
Okay, guys! Come on in!
- Yo, yo, what's up brother?
- Hey Oscar!
What's up!
No, no snap it, snap it,
you're not snapping!
- I'm snapping, I'm snapping!
- It's okay, yo Great Whites can't do it yo!
- Yo!
- Yo, what's up?
- What's up with what?
- Yo, yo, yo.
Hey, you say yo one more time,
and I'm gonna yo you!
I'm sorry.
- Okay dude, I painted you high!
- All right!
- Paint me out!
- Hey! You think you're smart?
What am I? A clown?
Keep going with me,
don't let me lose you!
Cause I can't lose you!
In your face!
- Allright, what you got?
- You don't wanna mess with me!
Yo-hoo! Break it down, fellows!
Synced by RizzzO