Kanzaki! Wake up!
You were here all night?
Idiot!
I went over the case again.
Don't you know
what day this is?!
Yeah, I know.
Amazing!
You're looking good.
Like a leading man.
I just sit there.
You're the star today.
I figured you'd be here.
I brought your tux.
Here.
"What a friend we have
in Jesus..."
How does that go again?
The heart had been cut out,
just like in the first two cases.
Mr. Jojima?
I hear you.
Maya Ito, 22,
university student.
No connection
with where she was found.
Went missing
on her way to work.
You're not the only one
on this case.
I've seen a lot of guys who let work
screw up their home life.
It's OK. She understands.
I mean you, not Mina.
Being a detective
isn't a job, it's an illness.
Without meaning to,
you can become a burden.
Remember that.
Yes, sir.
Kanzaki...
Buckle up.
That was fast!
I feel sick...
Don't be too long.
Mina...
Sorry I'm late.
You shouldn't be here.
Mina...
Later.
I'll be waiting.
Welcome to the Gate of Rage.
I am Izuko,
Guardian of the Gate.
You have died.
You exist only as a spirit.
To the Gate of Rage come those
dead of misadventure, or murder.
Her e you may choose
one way to proceed...
...out of three.
Three ways?
One:
Accept death, ascend to Paradise,
and prepare for rebirth.
Two:
As a ghost, forever haunt
the realm of the living.
And three:
Curse one living person,
and bring about their death.
One who kills, however,
falls into Hell...
...to suffer eternal torment.
What's all this about?
What are you?
You haven't accepted it.
You were murdered.
You have 12 days
in which to choose.
You may return
to the realm of the living.
They, of course, will not
be able to perceive you.
Go and see
the world you have left.
It's the same M.O.
As the other three.
The heart cut out
and taken away.
In just a few minutes?
Unbelievable.
I don't get it.
I just don't get it.
So whoever did this
still has Mina's heart.
Kanzaki, take some time off.
We'll find your perp.
Why?
Someone murdered you.
Who?!
Will you forget and be reborn?
Become a ghost?
Find and cur se your murderer?
Do I choose?
Yes.
It is my task to guide you.
But I haven't the faintest idea
what to do!
There is still time.
Where does this go?
Any where you like.
Here, then.
Should I put this
over there?
Sure. Why not?
Work with me on this!
You're going to be living here.
Don't you mean "we"?
Then it needs both our ideas.
The kind of place you like
is where I want to live.
Well?
It's great.
Come over here.
Welcome home.
Kohei is going to kill
whoever murdered me.
Those who kill,
when they die...
...fall forever into Hell,
there to suffer eternal torment.
Suicides, as well.
Then that means that Kohei...
How did this happen?
Why was I killed?
If you wish...
...you can follow the memory
of your resentment and find out.
I want to know.
Later.
I'll be waiting.
Beretta 84, one.
Walther P99, one.
And...
...a Smith & Wesson 658.
These days the criminals
have the best guns.
I don't know how well
they've been kept.
You might want to
test it first.
Maybe...
Sorry.
Just kidding.
I won't arrest him.
I’ll stop his heart,
and get Mina's back.
That won't make her happy.
"Happy"?
The dead can't be "happy".
Death is the end of that.
You know...
...dealing with the dead
every day like I do...
...you get to sense things.
You realize...
...you're not alone.
When someone dies, their weight
goes up 35 grams.
Strange, huh?
It’s scientific fact. Some say
it's the weight of the spirit.
The spirit has negative weight.
If that's true,
then ghosts really exist.
A photographer friend took a Polaroid
of a plane he was supposed to get on.
There was this great big hand
grabbing the plane.
He decided to stay home.
The plane crashed.
You're a doctor...
That's how I know that no one walks
without a heart in them.
Meaning?
Why take the heart?
There must be a reason.
This isn't your plain everyday
serial killing.
Bullshit!
I'll find him and kill him.
Spare me the crap!
Sayuri!
Good morning, Chief.
I had some problems with
my siderodromophobia...
Then someone jumped
in front of the train I was on...
Save the excuses, OK?
What were you working on?
"How optical fibre and the development
of communications net works..."
"...affect the world economy."
Oh yeah... that.
Did I mess up again?
This is big.
What?!
It's not trouble. Do you know
who Tatsuya Kudo is?
A genetics researcher,
and a likely Nobel candidate.
Owner of Kudo Genetics,
and top-of-the-list billionaire.
Interview him.
Me?
It's not my idea.
He asked for you.
He's handsome.
I don't get it. You've never even
handled a story alone.
Tatsuya Kudo will be our
cover story, so don't screw up!
I’ll do my best.
And make sure
you're on time.
Stand up straight.
And don't simper.
The reporter?
She's coming.
Tatsuya Kudo...
Who are you?
Take us to the safe.
You want money?
Yeah!
Move it!
What the fuck?!
Scared to die?
I'd rather die than be
slime like you.
Don't kill him.
This is the best I can do.
It’s a likeness.
Who's this?
An unknown woman I saw
by the church.
All right. I’ll check her out.
You be a good boy.
Where are you going?
And three:
Bring death on a living person,
and fall into Hell.
The curse!
I don't understand
what you're talking about!
"Go, then!"
Can't you knock?
You're still dealing?
Don't you know the law?
It’s called "illegal entry".
I’m not here to hurt your business.
I just want information.
She's my girl.
Oh yeah?
Who is she?
She's connected to
a serial killing.
Serial killing?
With the hearts cut out?
I don't know people like that.
It's not my style.
Call me if you hear anything.
Why would I help a cop who couldn't
even protect his own girl?
Whoa, Chief! Take it easy!
Shut up.
Mina had it worse than this.
Talk like that again
and I’ll kill you.
With the human genome mapped...
...it's said we might soon find the cause
of diseases held to be incurable.
We do at least understand why
all the human cells exist.
With the mapping of the genome...
...we see the limits
to what people can do.
I see.
To change the subject, does a man
with your recognition and status...
...ever find himself troubled?
Troubled?
For example, I'm always late.
I wasn't late today
because I had a ride.
I mess up at work a lot,
I'm not much use to anyone...
I wonder what the point is
in me being alive.
The point, huh?
It's no big thing, really.
My troubles are small ones.
My life isn't perfect, either.
Some things don't work out.
For example...
...there are things
no amount of money will buy.
You mean, like, love?
That kind of thing.
Anyway, medicine has always been
a territorial dispute with the Gods.
They decide who's born...
...who gets sick...
...and how long we live.
But someone who doesn't want
to lose the sick person defies them...
...tries to cure the disease
and prolong life.
Yes...
Eventually humanity starts
to fiddle with its own schematics.
The genes.
Advances in research might produce
people who don't get sick.
But some say
that profanes the Gods.
But to save those we love...
We try to do that instinctively.
Even if that profanes the Gods...
...they gave us that instinct.
Therefore...
...it's completely natural
for us to defy the Gods.
But I'm rambling. Let's talk
about this in private sometime.
Not again!
Mina...
Will see you if I die?
No, Kohei!
You'll go to Hell
and we’ll never meet!
Don't!
Kohei, no!
This is that picture.
You brought me here
to see this?
Crap!
That's what they said at the airport
when Kishi showed it to them.
But three hours later...
Kolans Air, Flight 632.
Remember?
He's taken another one.
There's a hand reaching for
this woman's heart.
She might be in danger.
This has nothing to do
with our case.
No.
It does.
You're looking for this woman.
You know her?
She's Tatsuya Kudo's secretary.
Tatsuya Kudo?
Of Kudo Genetics.
Can you see me?
Vaguely.
But you’ll get clearer.
With ever y sacrifice
I get stronger...
...and more superhuman.
Who are you?
What do you have against me?
Nothing. I needed you.
You "needed" me? I never
caused you any trouble.
Why did you need to kill me?!
You took happiness for granted.
That happiness is fragile.
So you broke it!
"You broke it!"
I wouldn't cry like that.
What was stolen...
...I would take back.
What's this for?
That?
I used to be like you.
I took happiness for granted.
But happiness can shatter
at any time.
It was sudden for me, too.
One day my wife was smiling gently,
the next she couldn’t move.
I was frantic
trying to find out what was wrong.
But it happened.
There's no going back.
The question is
what to do now.
But why me?
I've already said
the question is meaningless.
Only actions have meaning.
I have another meeting.
I hope you won't mind...
Ow!
I broke something!
What are you doing?
It hurts!
You're dead, you know.
Face it.
Over here.
Who are you?
Maya Ito. Those two
took my heart as well.
Sanae and Katsumi.
All of you?
Yes. They killed all of us.
Where have I seen you before?
At the church.
We tried to warn you.
But why us?
All of you once served
as Guardian of the Gate of Rage.
Guardian?
Like you?
In your last existence,
or perhaps before that...
...you stood as Izuko
at this gate...
...and guided the dead.
That is what connects you.
That's incredible!
All of us?
Don't be surprised.
Souls here are reborn
again and again.
Many have served
at this gate.
My last existence?!
I've got no memory of that!
Why should that get me killed?
My task is to guide the dead.
It is you who must decide
what to do.
But...
You have yet to decide...
Soon you must...
...make your choice.
She's not answering!
The first victim,
Sanae Takeuchi.
Katsumi Okamoto...
...and Maya Ito.
You'd see it clearer
if I'd taken the pictures.
I've always been able
to photograph it.
It’s like I'm an antenna.
Like that kid with Bruce Willis
in "Sixth Sense".
Or like in "The Omen".
It’s a warning!
That doesn't help much now.
Enough of this talk.
OK, don't believe me.
But this picture means
Sayuri is going to be next!
Please! Save her!
She's back...
I can sort of see you.
I'm Kazuo Kishi.
His girlfriend?
What's your name?
"Mina"...
Give me a break!
Did you tell him that stuff?
No!
She's telling me to stop you.
Cut it out!
Those who kill go to Hell.
She doesn't want that.
Oh...
...I get it.
You cooked this up to stop me...
You don't believe it?
Of course not!
Tell him something
only he and I would know.
OK.
Last month...
...you two moved into
an apartment.
What?
You put the sofa by the wall,
and her picture on the chest...
...beside the bed.
And today you said...
..."Will I see you if I die?"...
...and put a gun to your head.
Trying to stop you, she screamed.
A glass table-top broke, you were
distracted, and didn't kill yourself.
She stopped you.
She's beside you now,
talking to me.
She says she loves you.
She doesn't want you to die.
The other side.
You worked hard on this.
Did you bug the place?
Where's the camera?
You don't believe me?
Sayuri? Where are you?
You don't have to shout.
Why all the messages?
Is it urgent?
Where are you?!
Now? On a date with Mr. Kudo.
Kudo?!
Get out of there!
What are you talking about?
You're in serious danger!
He's not like you.
He's a perfect gentleman.
Though I wouldn't mind
if he wasn't.
I’m telling you.
You're in real danger!
Are you jealous, Mr. Kishi?
No!
I've got to go.
The performance is starting.
I'm on a date,
so don't call me so much.
In fact, don't call me again, OK?
Sayuri! Sayuri!
She's with Kudo. Find her!
You're a detective. Are you
going to let her get killed?!
What if I'm right?
No one believed me
about the plane crash, either.
You’ll regret it!
OK.
What did she say?
Uh... something about
a performance starting...
A concert? A play?
Kyoko, check
the city listings.
What else?
I heard music...
Schubert..."Death and the Maiden".
A Schubert concert
starting now...
Yes! Organon Hall,
the Stanley Quartet.
He's after another heart.
Get out of here!
Please!
Get out!
Mr. Kudo?
You wanted to know the point
of your being alive.
I’ll tell you.
You have lived
in order to die here.
I need your heart.
The first victim was found here.
The second...
...and third.
An equilateral triangle.
And here?
I don't get it.
I just don't get it.
Wait a minute... the concert hall
Kanzaki went to is here.
What does a concert hall
have to do with it?
Look at this.
What is it?
They went there because
they think that girl's next.
A figure of some kind...
Come on.
Right.
Hey!
Halt!
Are you OK?!
Snap out of it!
The Guardian of the Gate...
...Izuko.
Hey!
What happened?!
Kishi! Are you OK?
Another victim. The killers
are Tatsuya Kudo and his secretary.
He was holding her heart.
It was still beating.
What?
I can't...
What's wrong?
As a doctor I’m not ready for this.
This man has no pulse.
But he's alive.
His heart isn't beating.
You can do what you like
in this world.
But I won't let you raise a hand
against the souls at my gate.
There's a spell on this sword.
It even cuts down the dead.
Am I crazy, or are you?
Look inside this...
"Shuho Kamina"...
She's our only hope.
Who is she?
After the plane crash
I was haunted by the ghosts...
...of the 430 people who died.
She exorcised them for me.