The sweet, uncomplicated
satisfaction of the younger woman.
That fleeting age when everything
just falls right into place.
It's magic time, and it can
render any man...
...anywhere, absolutely helpless.
Some say I'm an expert
on the younger woman.
Guess that's because I've been
dating them for over 40 years.
So, baby, you're rich?
Well, my mother is. Sort of.
I mean, not really.
If she lives within a mile
of here, she's rich.
Well, I guess a hit play will
buy you a house in the Hamptons.
- I'd like to meet your mother.
- No, you wouldn't.
She's great. She's totally brilliant,
but she's not your type.
You're overlooking
one of the great things about me.
I don't have a type.
She's over 30.
Oh, what?
Like you don't know you
have a slight reputation for...
- For?
- For...
...never dating anyone over 30.
It just so happens, my dear, that
women of a certain age don't date me.
You ever think of it that way? No.
It's always me.
Hey.
I'll call back Monday.
Say you couldn't find me.
Who?
I'll call her later.
No, no, I have the number.
Yeah.
Make a right.
It's the second driveway on the left.
Right.
Wow.
It's the perfect beach house.
So...
...what are we gonna do out here,
just the two of us, for two whole days?
Tell me the truth.
Are you at all glad we waited?
Truth?
No.
But I'm extremely glad
we're finally gonna...
Wanna go for a swim?
How long will it take you
to change?
- Thirty seconds.
- Really?
That long?
Oh, Har, by the way,
no smoking in the house.
My mom doesn't allow it.
But she allows you to
strip in the front yard?
Bring guys you're
dating here to...?
She doesn't know everything I do
or when I do it or where I do it.
Okay.
The fabulous two-story living room...
...which, I predict, we will spend
absolutely no time in whatsoever.
- It's a knockout.
- Thank you.
I'm very good at giving this tour,
by the way, although...
...l've never actually done
it while taking off my clothes.
Behind me, the requisite
Hamptons deck...
...complete with
pool and ocean view.
Your pants, please.
Ladies first.
When I first started auctioneering,
someone told me...
...if I was nervous, I should just picture
the audience in their underwear.
This gives that a whole new meaning.
You're not nervous now, are you?
- I'm always a little nervous.
- Put on your bathing suit.
I brought us champagne.
I'll put it on ice.
No, I know. I can't do anything...
Oh, God! What is this?
Okay.
Okay, you stay where you are.
We have a knife.
- Do you live here?
- Look, mister.
I am gonna dial 911,
and you are not gonna move.
- Zoe, hand me the phone.
- You don't understand.
- I'm your daughter's friend.
- Don't think so.
My daughter is in the city. You, what,
wander in here, high on ecstasy?
- Honestly, if you'd just...
- No!
Stay there.
I was in the Israeli army.
I can break you in half.
Hello. Yes! Yes, I have
an intruder in my house.
29 Daniels Lane, Sagaponack...
I'm dating your daughter, Marin.
She invited me here for the weekend.
She's in her room right now, changing.
You're dating my daughter?
Now, who would have thought
that would be worse news?
Yeah, sorry. False alarm.
No, he's not a burglar.
- He's dating my daughter.
- I had no idea you were coming.
You said you had to write.
I do, but I thought
I would do it out here.
I should have told you
I was bringing someone.
I'm sorry. I should've told
you we were coming.
Obviously. Anyway, here we are.
Hello, I'm the mother.
Harry Sanborn. How are you?
Oh, God, sorry.
This is my friend Harry.
- My mom, Erica. My aunt Zoe.
- Sorry about that.
We just totally spur-of-the-moment
decided to get out of the city.
Good, that's good.
Honey, does Harry have a robe?
You know what?
I think I should just take off, let
you gals enjoy your weekend and...
What?
No, no! Oh, I'm sorry. Of course,
don't do that. That's silly.
Zoe and I will leave...
...and you and Harry stay.
Harry.
I'm sorry.
I apologize about the near arrest.
You were very impressive.
Very strong.
Very...
...macho.
Well, I don't think
I was exactly macho.
Trust me, if I ever catch a guy
in his underwear in my refrigerator...
...I hope I'm half the man
you were, Mrs...
- Mrs...
- Right, okay. Whatever.
Alrighty, then,
I'm definitely gonna hit the road.
Ladies, sensational meeting you.
Doll.
- Give me a call.
- Hold on.
Let's not get so dramatic here.
What are we, four teenagers?
We're sophisticated people.
Why don't we all stay. Your mother
has work, I have papers to grade.
Do your thing, whatever that may be...
...and if we wanna hang out together,
we will.
If we don't, we don't. No reason
we should give up this weekend.
Seriously.
- I can handle it.
- I can totally handle it.
I mean, well, I can handle it.
- Bonjour, Madame Barry.
- Bonjour, Annie.
Impressive.
She took French lessons
after she and my dad split up.
Part of her "keep busy, don't look
back" program.
- Now she's practically fluent.
- Marin!
- Okay.
- Not bad.
Well, yeah. I am fluent.
I'll be right back.
It's an epidemic.
Buy some things.
How about pasta salad?
We had that last night.
- We did? I don't remember.
- Sure.
Why don't we get a spread
and put it on.
Oh, sorry.
Sorry about that.
- My fault.
- No. It's fine, it's fine.
So, Harry, what do you do?
I'm an owner of a record
company, among other things.
- Which record company?
- Drive-By Records.
Drive-By Records?
Is that a joke? I mean, what is that?
It's a hip-hop label.
Hip-hop? Oh, rap. Right, right.
Well, that's interesting.
Let me see if I get
where you're headed here.
I'm sorry, but look,
I hate rap. I do. I really do.
It's just crude and violent
for my taste...
...not to mention
just a tad misogynistic.
Hey, some people see rap as poetry.
Yeah, but how many words
can you rhyme with "bitch"?
Next, please.
How we doing?
Should have left
when she tried to arrest me.
How's the new play?
Are you getting happy with it?
You know the thing about me.
I'm 90 percent hard work,
10 percent talent.
And so far, the talent part
hasn't exactly kicked in yet.
Right. Right.
- What's your play about?
- About?
I'm not exactly sure,
which is a bit of a problem.
But so far, it's about
a divorced woman, a writer.
She's a high-strung, over-amped,
controlling, know-it-all neurotic...
...who's incredibly cute and lovable.
It's a comedy.
So how did you two meet?
At a wine auction at Christie's.
Harry was the big buyer
of the night.
I kept raising my paddle
just to get her to smile at me.
Before I knew it,
I bought the entire collection.
Every known bottle
of Château Margaux.
After that, the least she could do...
...was share a bottle with me.
Ever been married, Harry?
No.
- No, I haven't.
- Mom.
Wow. Now, why do you think that is?
Well, some people just don't
fit the mold, and so far, you know...
Hey, if it ain't broke...
- Exactly.
- Wait a second.
Aren't you a famous bachelor?
Well, I wouldn't say I'm famous.
Yeah, didn't I read an article
about you in New York magazine?
I guess some people find it interesting
I've escaped the noose for so long.
That was the title,
"The Escape Artist."
I read that article.
That was you?
Well, you were once engaged
to someone really big.
- Who was it? Joan Collins? No.
- No.
- Okay. Carly Simon?
- Somebody cool like that.
- Someone like that.
- Not Martha Stewart.
- No! Not Martha Stewart!
- You could ask him.
No, this is more fun.
It's like I'm not here.
Harry was once
engaged to Diane Sawyer.
- What?
- Right. Diane Sawyer. I love her.
- I'm impressed.
- Yeah.
Women your age
love that about me.
- You know what I mean.
- Yes, I do.
I mean, it's not a bad thing
to say, "women your age."
Oh, no. I'm sure it was a compliment.
It's just...
...an accurate observation. It's...
- So when was this?
- The engagement?
- Long time ago.
She was this adorable,
lanky girl from Kentucky...
...with the greatest pair of legs
I have ever seen.
Never understood her ending up on a
job where she never showed them.
You can't be serious.
I mean, she's Diane Sawyer.
She goes into caves in Afghanistan...
...with a shmatte on her head.
Who cares about her legs?
You know what?
I hate to eat and run, but...
- No!
- No, wait. No.
Come on. This is really fascinating,
what's going on at this table.
Zoe teaches women's studies
at Columbia.
- Okay. So this is gonna hurt.
- No.
- Let's take you and Erica.
- Zoe...
You've been around the block a few
times. What are you, around 60?
Sixty-three!
Fantastic!
Never married, which, as we know, if
you were a woman, would be a curse.
You'd be an old maid, a spinster.
So instead of pitying you,
they write articles about you.
Celebrate your never marrying.
You're elusive and ungetable,
a real catch.
Then, there's my gorgeous sister here.
- No, wait. What...?
- Look, please...
No, this is interesting. Look at her.
She is so accomplished.
Most successful female playwright
since who? Lillian Hellman?
She's over 50, divorced.
She sits in night after night...
...because available guys
her age want something...
Forgive me, but they want somebody
that looks like Marin.
The over-50 dating scene is geared
towards men leaving older women out.
And as a result, the women
become more and more productive...
...and therefore, more
and more interesting.
Which, in turn, makes them even less
desirable because as we know, men...
...especially older men,
are threatened and afraid...
...of productive, interesting women.
It is just so clear.
Single older women as a demographic
are as fucked a group as can exist.
Oh, God!
What are you, possessed?
How could you say those things?
It seemed really obvious, the injustice.
Thank God men die younger than us.
- It's the only break we get.
- You know what?
Write a dissertation. Don't announce
that I stay in night after night...
By the way, one "night after night"
would have been enough.
Did you ever realize that I stay in
as a part of my job?
And why do you think I married
the director of my plays?
He was the only man I ever saw.
And anyway, I like staying in,
and I like this time in my life.
Why do I have to defend myself?
I was married for 20 years. I'm done.
- What the hell was that?
- Sorry, I thought I was onto something.
Honey, what are you doing
with this guy?
He's old. He's chauvinistic.
- He's fun.
- Fun?
I mean, how is he fun?
He's, like, wrong.
- Yeah, wrong can be fun.
- No.
- Not this wrong.
- He's smart and fascinating.
If you talked about something
other than marital status...
...you would find he's smart,
owns 10 different companies.
What does that mean? It means
he can't commit. That's what it means.
- Not that I want him to commit.
- Oh, yeah, that I get.
Anyway, he said he thought you two
were very spontaneous and nice.
And then he said he's leaving
as soon as the sun comes up.
What, his car doesn't have
headlights?
Wait a minute.
I have no right to get this nuts.
I'm sorry.
He's your friend, he's not mine.
- I'm sorry and love you.
- I love you more.
No chance in hell
he said we were nice.
Please. None.
What are they listening to?
I don't care.
Marvin Gaye?
Will you stop that?
That's disgusting, Zoe. Stop it!
There.
She'll never see him after this
weekend. She can't commit either.
He does sound fun.
Admit it. He's got something.
You felt it, right?
Okay, this is nuts.
Mom!
Did she say, "Mom"?
Mom, hurry!
Mom!
I don't know what happened.
We fooled around.
And then he just said he felt
funny, and he just collapsed.
Harry, what is it?
- I'm okay. I'm fine.
- Does your chest hurt?
It's like an elephant's sitting on it.
Call 911,
tell them to send an ambulance.
Marin, now!
- My God!
- What are you doing?
Mouth-to-mouth.
Oh, you fucking guy.
We need an ambulance right away,
please!
29 Daniels Lane,
Sagaponack.
- We got him.
- Apparent cardiac arrest.
Sinus check, 120.
- BP?
- 150l95.
- Forty-one. Right here?
- On three.
- All right.
- Careful.
We've got a line in.
- Switch over to monitors.
- How we doing?
30 minutes of chest pain,
nausea, shortness of breath.
Pulse, 104. Respiration's 18.
Get a CBC, CMP, cardiac
panel and 12-lead EKG.
- Yes, doctor.
- Mr. Sanborn, I'm Dr. Mercer.
- Are you in any pain right now?
- I feel some pressure in my chest.
- It's tight.
- Show me where the pain is.
Right here.
What were you doing
when the pain started?
- I was kissing a beautiful woman.
- Were you having intercourse?
Unfortunately, no.
- Sense of humor intact.
- Yeah.
Give him aspirin, metoprolol,
5 milligrams, hang a nitro drip.
- Mr. Sanborn?
- Yeah.
EKG shows a blocked artery
which is not allowing enough...
...oxygen to get to the heart muscle.
- I'm having a heart attack?
We're gonna stop it, but I need
to know what medications you take.
- I take Lipitor.
- Chew this.
- Anything else?
- And a white one for blood pressure.
And what about Viagra?
Mr. Sanborn, did you take
any Viagra today?
- Mr. Sanborn?
- No.
- No Viagra.
- Okay, good, just need to be sure.
Because I put nitroglycerin
into your drip.
And if you had taken Viagra,
the combination could be fatal.
- Your dad's gonna be okay.
- He's not my dad.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Your granddad's gonna be okay.
Oh, thank you so much.
We're not related.
- He's a friend.
- Sorry.
I'm Dr. Mercer.
Mr. Sanborn did have
a mild heart attack.
I gave him something
to dissolve the clot, and it worked.
He's very lucky.
Another half-hour, I don't...
I don't know if this would have worked.
This was very intense.
- He's doing great.
- Yeah.
I gave him something
to help him sleep.
It might make him a little loopy at first
but then it should knock him out.
- You're Mrs. Sanborn?
- No! Oh, no. No, I'm just...
No, I'm Erica Barry.
He had dinner at our house.
I met him this afternoon.
You're Erica Barry?
- Yes.
- The playwright?
- What a pleasure. I'm a huge fan.
- Really?
- Huge fan.
Thank you.
Wow!
Thanks.
Thank you, doctor.
- Erica. Green tea.
- Oh! That's hot.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome. May I?
Yeah. Yeah, sure. Yeah.
This is very sweet of you.
In med school you learn what keeps
you up without making you nuts.
You know I heard you had a house
in the Hamptons.
I am a big fan. I've seen every play
you've ever written.
Some were written before your time.
There's some Marin's never seen.
No, I'm pretty sure I've seen
them all.
- I saw the last one twice.
- Julian, a walk-in may need stitches.
Okay, thanks.
I'll check on Mr. Sanborn.
If he's asleep, you might want some
shuteye. Come back in the morning.
Great to meet you, Erica. Ladies.
Okay.
Now, that's the perfect guy for you.
He's adorable!
Mother, I've never seen a man
less interested in me.
Or more interested in you.
Me?
- He's 30 years old.
- No, he's older than that.
Who cares how old he is?
I mean, he's not my type.
He's a gorgeous doctor.
He's perfect for you. He's hot for you.
- Which makes him really perfect.
- Okay, stop it.
He likes my work, not me.
I would never...
Shut up.
- Oh, God, is he all right?
- Harry!
Harry, over here.
Honey, I wanna go home.
Can you call Leo...?
Harry! You've got to get back into bed.
Woman, you saved my life.
Get a nurse. Nurse! Nurse!
I thank you from the bottom of my...
Even unconscious, he's a letch!
- Get off!
- You shouldn't be standing.
It's all right. Thank you.
I gotta take a whiz, girls.
We'll take care of that for you.
Okay, I'd like to see that.
Okay, here we go.
I'd love to see that.
Somebody better get it.
Now, what can I do you for?
I'm here to pick up Harry Sanborn.
Hi, I'm Dr. Mercer.
Come on, I'll take you to him.
And you are?
I'm Leo Hoffman,
I'm Harry's personal assistant.
Do a little chef, a little driving,
party planning...
...whatever the man needs.
- It sounds like an interesting job.
I'm going on six years
and never a dull moment.
Okay, Harry, looks like we're
gonna have to let you go.
Take it easy, kids.
I just...
...sat up a little too fast.
Doc, tell them.
Am I in good shape?
How were my tests this morning?
He's doing extremely well.
- Can I hug him?
- Absolutely.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Let's not get goofy.
We got nothing but good news here.
Knock, knock.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- I'll catch you on the way out.
- Thanks.
So...
...l'm some great date, huh?
Yeah, Mr. Excitement.
Tell me something.
We haven't actually had sex yet,
have we?
No.
We haven't.
You're correct on that one.
Something to live for.
Down to the cheek.
Hold on, Tarzan, we're still moving.
Slowly.
Hey, l...
Harry, I'm sorry but I can't
let you travel quite yet.
I ain't going back in there.
I can't put you in a car
and I can't leave you in the parking lot.
I won't sue you,
if that's what you think.
I'll sign whatever you'd like.
Just let me go back to the city.
Here's my best offer.
I won't put you in the hospital
if you stay nearby a few days.
Get a nurse. Let me keep an eye on
you until we get your strength back.
Stay nearby.
Doc, where do you suggest I go?
No!
Somebody please explain to me
how I ended up babysitting this guy?
This is the best turkey sandwich
I've had in my life.
- You're not listening to me.
- I am. Don't get all pissy.
I come here for peace and quiet.
Suddenly, I'm a character
in a Kaufman and Hart play.
And the phone doesn't stop.
And it's never for me.
Sorry to interrupt.
No, that's fine, Leo. I'll take it.
- No, it's okay...
- No, no, I'll take it.
I don't mind washing them.
Okay.
How you doing?
The man doesn't know my name,
and I'm doing his dishes.
I said I'll take it back tomorrow, okay?
Great.
I'll take care of it.
Just one second. Hi, Erica?
- Where shall I put this?
- Here. I'll take it.
Harry has a bad headache.
Do you have any Tylenol?
- Tylenol...
- Extra Strength would be fantastic.
Hi, I'm Tania.
- Hi.
- Harry's second assistant.
- Dave Klein, her assistant.
- Nice to meet you.
- Thank you. Appreciate it.
"What should I do with this?"
It's an empty water glass.
What are the choices?
Okay, I'm getting out of your hair.
So you're not ready to show me
any new pages?
- Dave.
- I'm not putting any pressure on you.
- I'm just asking.
- Dad!
I didn't know you were here.
Just on my way out.
I was gonna drive back to the city with
Zoe, but I'd much rather go with you.
Actually, I have someone
to meet before I go.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You're leaving? Zoe's leaving?
The entourage is leaving?
I'm gonna be stuck with him, alone?
The hospital's sending over
a nurse in the morning.
In the morning? That's, like,
19 hours from now.
Okay, I can handle this.
I'll just get myself into a Zen place.
Play music. Cook. Write. Focus.
Thank you.
Well, four mai tais at lunch...
...is a bit much for anybody.
Hi.
Can I call you right back, doll, huh?
Thank you.
Hey.
- What's up?
- Okay, here's the thing.
I don't want to play the uptight
nurse to your bad-boy patient.
If you want another heart attack,
go ahead. I have work to do.
I don't have time to make a run...
...to the hospital because you're filling
your clogged arteries with smoke.
But more importantly...
...l'd rather not have my freshly
painted house smell like a pool hall.
Have you always been like this,
or do I bring it out in you?
Just, you know.
I don't think I've ever had
this effect on a woman before.
What effect do you think
you have on me?
I don't quite recognize it.
That's how I know
I never had it before.
So you don't sleep?
I only need about four hours a night.
Me too.
I never slept eight hours
in my life.
Me either. I wish I could.
Want me to shut these? The sun
comes in strong in the morning.
- Sure.
- So, Harry...
...who were you talking to?
A friend in L.A.
- It's only 10:00 on the coast.
- That's not past her bedtime?
So you don't get
more mellow as the hours pass?
Good night, Harry.
Can I ask you one other thing?
What's with the turtlenecks?
- It's the middle of summer.
- Seriously...
...why do you care what I wear?
- Just curious.
I like them. I've always liked them,
and I'm just a turtleneck kind of gal.
You never get hot?
- No.
- Never?
Not lately.
Finally.
Okay, okay.
Holy...!
Oh, God!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, God, am I sorry.
What are you doing?!
- I was just trying to find the kitchen!
- What? Back here?
I got confused.
And it was dark and...
I didn't really see anything.
Just...
Just your tits.
And a little...
- Goodbye, Mrs. Barry.
- Goodbye?
You're leaving?
Oh, no, that's not good.
- Been fired.
- Fired? No, you just started.
Not fired, darling. Just not needed.
Not needed?
Wait, what are you talking about?
Of course she's needed. We need her.
Oh, no. I'm actually feeling
pretty perky today.
Making quite a comeback.
Sorry for your trouble,
Mrs. Gimble. Take care, dear.
You've been wonderful.
Listen...
...about last night...
Yeah, how about
we never talk about that?
I was at the drugstore.
Your prescriptions were ready.
They said to take two with food,
this one without.
You were in silhouette.
Yeah, I think that's talking about it.
- I didn't really see all that much.
- Yep, there you go.
I won't mention it again, but...
- Going to work, Harry.
- Hey.
You saw my ass.
You don't see me acting nuts...
...and wearing glasses
and hats and weird outfits!
Yes or no?
What's the deal?
- Can I go?
- You still getting dizzy?
- Not as much.
- Out of breath?
- Only sometimes.
- Good.
- How's Erica treating you?
- Who?
Erica.
Oh, her.
She is a major piece of work.
Doc, the woman wears turtlenecks
in the middle of the summer.
She's beyond uptight.
Almost makes her fun to be around.
Uptight? That's funny,
I haven't noticed that.
Try living with her.
I actually saw her naked last night.
- That doesn't sound so uptight.
- It was an accident.
She thought I was asleep,
I thought her room was the kitchen.
You know what Freud said,
"There are no accidents."
Trust me.
This was an accident.
Although, why would she walk around
naked when she knows I'm nearby?
Why would you think
her bedroom was a kitchen?
It was dark.
It was 2:00 in the morning.
That could explain why she was
walking around naked. Deep breath.
I've never seen a woman that age
naked before.
- You're kidding.
- Hey, we're not all doctors, baby.
I think she's very beautiful.
And she's a fantastic writer, you know.
No, I don't know.
She's pretty major.
- So you date her daughter?
- Okay.
Now, she's a great chick.
Must take after her father.
Which reminds me. Doc...
What about Mr. Midnight, here?
When can I be up and running
in that department?
I think Mr. Midnight needs to stay put
for another couple of weeks.
- But it won't kill me when I do it, right?
- No, it's exercise. It'll be good for you.
After a heart attack,
rule of thumb is:
If you can climb a flight of stairs,
you can have sex.
So you're saying he can't travel at all?
Not even by plane?
- Train?
- I don't think so.
Been tough, huh?
He fired his nurse after an hour,
and now says he doesn't need one.
- He's a bit of a workout.
- How are you holding up?
- Me?
- You.
Well, I'm...
I'm fine. Fine.
One more "fine"
and I won't believe you.
Wait, where's my...?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Hello?
Hi. I know, I'm sorry.
I haven't been able to get back.
Part of the play takes place in Paris...
...so I keep listening to French music,
hoping to get inspired.
Well, I'm trying.
It's not exactly flowing out
of me yet, but...
Pick you up around 7?
So, what about the patient?
Like he said, he doesn't need a nurse.
I'm walking around the house!
Oh, no.
- Hi.
- Listen...
...l've decided to get over
the "you saw me naked" thing.
- So let's not deal with it anymore.
- Good...
...because I have been hiding
from you all day.
Do you want to come in?
I don't want to break your rhythm
or anything.
That would be wishful thinking.
Nice painting.
So I'm gonna venture out there
and go for a short walk.
- You up to that?
- My doctor recommended it.
I gotta build up to climbing stairs
and stuff like that.
You wouldn't want to join me?
- That means you don't want me to?
- No. I was asking if you wanted to.
I would, but I don't like to break
once I start writing, so I shouldn't.
Not that a little fresh air would hurt.
It's just a walk, Erica,
not a marriage proposal.
- You know my name.
- Erica Jane Barry.
I looked you up on the Internet.
Do you know that there are over
8000 websites that mention you?
- That's not possible.
- Yeah, it's true.
I know everything about you now,
and not because of last night.
Yeah, no, no. I understood.