SIR.
[ Amplified ]
WHAT ?
ARE WE BEING TOO LITERAL ?
NO, YOU FOOL,
WE'RE FOLLOWING ORDERS.
WE WERE TOLD
TO COMB THE DESERT,
SO WE'RE COMBING IT.
FOUND ANYTHING YET ?
NOTHING YET, SIR.
HOW ABOUT YOU ?
NOT A THING, SIR.
-WHAT ABOUT YOU GUYS ?
- WE AIN'T FOUND SHIT !
IT'S A BIG MYSTERY.
NONE OF THE WISE MEN
COULD TELL ME WHAT IT MEANS.
WISE MEN, PSHAW.
WISE GUYS, YOU MEAN.
WHAT DO THEY KNOW ?
HERE, LET ME TAKE A LOOK.
[ Guttural Noises ]
YOU CAN READ IT !
NO, I WAS JUST
CLEARING MY THROAT.
HERE, LET ME TAKE A--
OH, YES, YES.
OF COURSE !
YOU UNDERSTAND IT ?
YES.
WHAT'S IT SAY ?
I CANNOT
TELL YOU THAT NOW.
IT SHALL BE
REVEALED TO YOU
AT THE PROPER TIME.
GREAT.
DON'T BE DISAPPOINTED.
BACK TO YOUR
SCHWARTZ TRAINING.
HERE, TAKE THE RING.
POINT IT AT THAT BIG STATUE.
OKAY, BUT I STILL
DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW I'M GONNA LIFT...
THAT BIG STATUE
WITH THIS LITTLE RING.
NEVER UNDERESTIMATE
THE POWER OF
THE SCHWARTZ !
COME ON !  CONCENTRATE.
HERE WE GO.
CONCENTRATE.
[ Grunting ]
LONE STARR, YOU'RE DOING IT !
YOU'RE DOING IT !
- HA HA HA !
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
THE SCHWARTZ-- IT'S WORKING !
- [ Yogurt ]  YES !  YES !
-HEY, BOSS !
HOW'D YOU DO THAT ?
[ Screaming ]
GIVE ME THE RING !
GIVE ME THE RING, QUICK !
UPSY-DAZSHY !
UPSY-MAZSHY !
UPSY-DAISY !
WHOA !  AAH !
-  [ Screaming Continues ]
- EHH !
SORRY, BARF.
[ Wailing ]
KEEP SEARCHING.
IT'S NO USE, SIR.
WE'VE SEARCHED EVERYWHERE.
WAIT !
I FEEL THE PRESENCE
OF... THE SCHWARTZ !
THE SCHWARTZ !
YES.
IT'S COMING
FROM SOMEWHERE...
DOWN THERE !
YOU'RE RIGHT, SIR !
THERE'S A SECRET ENTRANCE HERE.
AND LOOK AT THIS INSIGNIA.
IT'S A Y.
YOGURT !  YOGURT !
I HATE YOGURT,
EVEN WITH STRAWBERRIES.
I'LL CALL FOR
THE ATTACK SQUAD.
NO, WE CAN'T GO IN THERE.
YOGURT HAS THE SCHWARTZ.
HE'S FAR TOO POWERFUL.
BUT, SIR, YOUR RING.
DON'T YOU HAVE
THE SCHWARTZ TOO ?
NO, HE GOT THE UP SIDE.
I GOT THE DOWN SIDE.
THERE'S TWO SIDES
TO EVERY SCHWARTZ.
THEN HOW WE GONNA GET HER ?
WE WILL NOT GO IN THERE.
SHE WILL COME OUT TO US.
[ Roland's Voice ]
VESPA !  VESPA, MY CHILD.
WHERE ARE YOU ?
DADDY ?
VESPA, IT'S YOUR FATHER,
KING ROLAND.  COME TO ME.
DADDY, I HEAR YOU.
I HEAR YOU.
WHERE ARE YOU ?
-FOLLOW MY VOICE.  COME TO ME.
- [ Snoring ]
COME TO ME.
- WHERE ARE YOU GOING ?
- VESPA, COME TO ME.
DADDY, IS IT REALLY YOU ?
YES, MY DEAR.
I GUARANTEE IT.
WOULD I LIE ?
- DADDY !
- OH !
NO, VESPA, DON'T !
OH !  NO !
OHH !
FOOLED YOU !
[ Helmet Chuckling ]
TAKE THEM BOTH ABOARD AND PUT
THE PRINCESS IN MY QUARTERS.
YES, SIR.
NOW SHE IS MINE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER ?
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING ?
THEY'VE TAKEN
THE PRINCESS !
DINK, DINK, DINK, DINK !
[ Lone Starr ]
SPACEBALLS.
TOO LATE.
DON'T WORRY, BOSS.
WE'LL GET HER BACK.
YEAH.
THANKS FOR THE GAS,
YOGURT.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
AND HERE.
JUST IN CASE
THEY GET HUNGRY.
A FORTUNE COOKIE ?
YES.
REMEMBER, OPEN IT
BEFORE YOU EAT IT.
THANKS.
WELL, WE BETTER GET GOING.
I WONDER, WILL WE EVER SEE
EACH OTHER AGAIN ?
WHO KNOWS ?
GOD WILLING,
WE'LL ALL MEET AGAIN
INSPACEBALLS II,
THE SEARCH FOR MORE MONEY.
GOOD-BYE,
LONE STARR.
GOOD-BYE, YOGURT.
THE RING
OF THE SCHWARTZ.
NO, NO,
I CAN'T TAKE THIS.
TAKE IT.  TAKE IT.
YOU MIGHT NEED IT.
THANKS.
I'LL NEVER FORGET YOU.
- WISH ME LUCK.
- [ Indistinct ]
[ Shouting Good-Byes ]
SO, PRINCESS VESPA,
AT LAST I HAVE YOU
IN MY CLUTCHES...
TO HAVE MY WAY WITH YOU
THE WAY I WANT TO.
NO !  NO, PLEASE,
LEAVE ME ALONE !
NO, YOU ARE MINE.
NOT SO FAST, HELMET.
LONE STARR.
YES, IT'S ME.
I'M HERE TO SAVE
MY GIRLFRIEND.
HI, HONEY.
NOW YOU ARE GOING
TO DIE.
OH !  OH !  OH !
HEY, WHAT DID YOU DO
TO MY FRIEND ?
THE SAME THING I'M GOING
TO DO TO YOU, BIG BOY.
OH !  OH !
AND YOU TOO.
NOW, PRINCESS VESPA,
AT LAST
WE ARE ALONE.
OH !  NO !  I HATE YOU,
I HATE YOU, I HATE YOU !
LEAVE ME ALONE !
YET I FIND YOU
STRANGELY ATTRACTIVE.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
JEWISH PRINCESSES ARE OFTEN
ATTRACTED TO MONEY AND POWER,
AND I HAVE BOTH
AND YOU KNOW IT.
OH !  LEAVE ME ALONE !
NO.  KISS ME.
NO !  NO !
YES !  NO !
NO, YES, NO, YES.
AH !  OH !  OH !  OH !
AH !  OH !  OHH !
OH !  YOUR HELMET
IS SO BIG !
LORD HELMET !
WHAT ?
YOU'RE NEEDED ON THE BRIDGE.
KNOCK ON MY DOOR !
KNOCK NEXT TIME !
YES, SIR.
DID YOU SEE
ANYTHING ?
NO, SIR.
I DIDN'T SEE YOU PLAYING
WITH YOUR DOLLS AGAIN.
GOOD !
[ Urinating ]
PRESIDENT SKROOB !
AAH !
I TOLD YOU NEVER
TO CALL ME ON THIS WALL.
THIS IS AN UNLISTED WALL.
SORRY, SIR,
BUT IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
THE PRINCESS HAS JUST
BEEN BROUGHT TO YOUR OFFICE,
AND LORD HELMET
AND COLONEL SANDURZ
ARE AWAITING YOU THERE.
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
TELL THEM I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
- YES, SIR.
[ Zipper Zips ]
AAH !
[ Groans ]
[ Toilet Flushes ]
HELMET, YOU FIEND !
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
TO MY DAUGHTER ?
PERMIT ME TO INTRODUCE
THE BRILLIANT YOUNG
PLASTIC SURGEON...
DR. PHILLIP SCHLOTKIN,
THE GREATEST NOSE JOB MAN
IN THE ENTIRE UNIVERSE
AND BEVERLY HILLS.
- YOUR HIGHNESS.
- NOSE JOB ?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
SHE'S ALREADY HAD A NOSE JOB.
IT WAS HER SWEET 16 PRESENT.
NO, IT'S NOT WHAT YOU THINK.
IT'S MUCH, MUCH WORSE.
IF YOU DO NOT GIVE ME
THE COMBINATION
TO THE AIR SHIELD,
DR. SCHLOTKIN WILL GIVE
YOUR DAUGHTER BACK...
HER OLD NOSE.
[ Gasps ]
NO-O-O !
- WHERE DID YOU GET THAT ?
- ALL RIGHT.  I'LL TELL.
I'LL TELL.
NO, DADDY.
NO, YOU MUSTN'T.
YOU'RE RIGHT, MY DEAR.
I'LL MISS YOUR NEW NOSE,
BUT I WILL NOT TELL THEM
THE COMBINATION
NO MATTER WHAT.
VERY WELL.
DR. SCHLOTKIN,
DO YOUR WORST.
MY PLEASURE.
[ King Roland ]
NO !  WAIT !  WAIT !
I'LL TELL.
I KNEW IT WOULD WORK.
ALL RIGHT.
GIVE IT TO ME.
THE COMBINATION IS...
- ONE,
- [ Together ]
ONE.
- TWO,
- [ Together ]
TWO.
- THREE,
- [ Together ]
THREE.
- FOUR,
- [ Together ]
FOUR.
- FIVE.
- [ Together ]
FIVE.
[ Helmet ]
SO THE COMBINATION IS
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR, FIVE.
THAT'S THE STUPIDEST COMBINATION
I EVER HEARD IN MY LIFE !
THAT'S THE KIND OF THING
AN IDIOT WOULD HAVE
ON HIS LUGGAGE !
THANK YOU,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
[ Click ]
WHAT DID YOU DO ?
I TURNED OFF THE WALL.
YOU TURNED OFF THE WHOLE MOVIE.
I MUST'VE PRESSED
THE WRONG BUTTON.
PUT THE MOVIE BACK ON !
YES, SIR.
[ Click ]
YOU'VE GOT TO GET
THAT THING FIXED.
WE'RE BACK, AND WE HAVE
THE COMBINATION.  SCHLOTKIN !
[ Woman Moaning ]
WHAT ?
WE'RE DONE
WITH YOU.
GO BACK TO THE GOLF COURSE
AND WORK ON YOUR "PUTZ."
LET'S GO,  ARNOLD.
COME, GRETCHEN.
'COURSE, YOU KNOW
I'LL STILL HAVE
TO BILL YOU FOR THIS.
OOH !  BET SHE GIVES
GREAT HELMET.
[ Shudders ]
WELL, DID IT WORK ?
WHERE'S THE KING ?
IT WORKED, SIR.
WE HAVE THE COMBINATION.
GREAT !
NOW WE CAN TAKE
EVERY BREATH OF FRESH AIR
FROM PLANET DRUIDIA.
- WHAT'S THE COMBINATION ?
- ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR, FIVE.
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR, FIVE ?
YES.
THAT'S AMAZING !
I'VE GOT THE SAME COMBINATION
ON MY LUGGAGE !
PREPARESPACEBALL I
FOR IMMEDIATE DEPARTURE.
YES, SIR.
AND CHANGE THE COMBINATION
ON MY LUGGAGE !
AAH !
THERE IT IS.
SPACEBALL CITY,
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
GOOD.
I'M TAKIN' HER IN.
[ Thrusters Firing ]
[ Man ]
HEY !  WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT THING ?
LOOKS LIKE A WINNEBAGO
WITH WINGS.
JESUS !
HEY !
YOU CAN'T PARK HERE !
YEAH, CAN'T YOU GUYS READ ?
NO PARKING !
- [ Kissing Sounds ]
- THAT SON OF A--
ALL RIGHT.
HEADS UP.
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR ILLEGAL PARKING.
YEAH !
[ All Exclaiming ]
[ Man Over P.A. ]
WARDEN MILLER.
YOU'RE WANTED
IN B-17.
ATTENTION.
SECTION C SCANNERS
REPORT.
-SHE'S GOT TO BE
IN ONE OF THESE CELLS.
- YEAH, BUT WHICH ONE ?
NO.
[ Vespa ]
## NOBODY KNOWS ##
IT'S COMING FROM THERE.
THAT CAN'T BE HER.
## THE TROUBLE I'VE SEEN ##
## NOBODY KNOWS ##
## BUT JESUS ##
IT'S HER.
## NOBODY KNOWS ##
## THE TROUBLE
I'VE SEEN ##
SHE'S A BASS !
## GLORY, HALLELUJAH ##
AY-EE !
- WHAT DO YOU WANT ?
- IT'S ME.
IT'S US !
LONE STARR !
HOW DID YOU FIND US ?
NO TIME TO TALK.
COME ON.
- WE GOTTA MOVE !
- HOW'D YOU DO IT ?
COME ON.
WAIT !  THOSE ARE THE GUYS
THAT STOLE OUR UNIFORMS !
AND BEAT THE SHIT
OUT OF US TOO.
UH-OH.
WE GOT COMPANY.
WATCH OUT !
DAMN IT !
THAT'S OUR ONLY WAY OUT !
WE'RE TRAPPED !
OH, I HATE
THESE MOVIES.
OHH !
I'M OUT OF AMMO.
GET BACK.
I'LL HOLD HIM OFF.
I'VE GOT AN IDEA !
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN' ?
WHAT'S HE DOING ?
[ Shouting ]
[ Groaning ]
GOOD WORK.
MORE PING PONGS.
RUN FOR IT.
LET'S GO !
[ Guns Firing ]
IT'S CLOSING !
- THE DOOR'S CLOSING !
- GO FOR BROKE !
[ All Yelling ]
DON'T MOVE OR YOU'RE DEAD.
STAND UP.
CAPTAIN,
WE'VE GOT THEM.
SPECTACULAR STUNT,
MY FRIENDS,
BUT ALL FOR NAUGHT.
TURN AROUND, PLEASE.
AH.
WHAT A PITY.
SO, PRINCESS, YOU THOUGHT
YOU COULD OUTWIT THE IMPERIOUS
FORCE OF--  [ Gasps ]
YOU IDIOTS !
THESE ARE NOT THEM !
YOU'VE CAPTURED
THEIR STUNT DOUBLES !
SEARCH THE AREA !
FIND THEM !
HURRY UP !  GET ABOARD !
I'LL HOLD THEM OFF !
OPEN THE DOOR !
I CAN'T !  IT'S FUSED !
WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE ?
IT'S LOCKED.
- WHERE ARE THE KEYS?
- INSIDE.
- OH, GREAT.
DUCK !
YOU HOLD 'EM OFF.
I'LL GET THE DOOR.
I'M NOT SHOOTIN' THIS THING.
I HATE GUNS.
MY HAIR !
HE SHOT MY HAIR.
YOU SON OF A BITCH !
HOLY SHIT !
HOW WAS THAT ?
NOT BAD.
NOT BAD...
FOR A GIRL.
HEY, THAT WAS PRETTY GOOD
FOR RAMBO.
LET'S BLOW THIS JOINT.
[ Footsteps Pounding ]
PRESIDENT SKROOB !
SALUTE !
[ All ]
HAIL, SKROOB !
THE SHIP IS TOO BIG.
IF I WALK, THE MOVIE'LL BE OVER.
SIR.
YES ?
OOH !
NEVER HAVE THAT
DAMN THING DOWN
IN FRONT OF ME.
HOW DO I KNOW
YOU'RE NOT MAKING FACES
AT ME UNDER THAT THING ?
PRESIDENT SKROOB.
THERE IT IS-- PLANET DRUIDIA.
YES.
AHH.
PLANET DRUIDIA.
AND 10,000 YEARS
OF FRESH AIR.
THE WAY HE RUNS THINGS,
IT WON'T LAST 100.
WHAT ?
PREPARING SHIP
FOR METAMORPHOSIS, SIR.
GOOD.
GET ON WITH IT.
READY, KAFKA ?
LOOK, IT'SSPACEBALL I.
THEY'VE REACHED
THE AIR SHIELD.
[ Dot ]
AND IT'S OPENING !
[ Barf ]
THE SHIP'S TOO BIG.
THEY'LL NEVER GET THROUGH.
HOW ARE THEY GONNA GET
THE AIR OUT ?  I DON'T SEE
ANY HOSES OR ANYTHING.
WHAT'S HAPPENING ?
THE SHIP,
IT'S CHANGING.
OH, MY GOSH !
IT'S NOT JUST A SPACESHIP.
IT'S A TRANSFORMER !
IT'S CHANGING INTO--
A GIGANTIC--
-[ Vespa ]  MAID !
-[ Barf ]
WITH A VACUUM CLEANER.
SO THAT'S HOW
THEY'RE GONNA GET
THE AIR OUT.
METAMORPHOSIS COMPLETED, SIR.
SPACEBALL IHAS NOW BECOME...
-MEGA-MAID.
- GOOD !
REMARKABLE !
NOW, COMMENCE
OPERATION VACU-SUCK !
[ Whooshing ]
[ All Chanting ]
SUCK !  SUCK !  SUCK !
GOOD-BYE, LITTLE VESPA.
MY LITTLE...
BABY VESPA.
[ Panting, Wheezing ]
[ Groans ]
THE AIR BAG,
IT'S ALMOST FULL !
WHAT'LL WE DO ?
WE'VE GOTTA ACT FAST.
STEP ONE--
WE REVERSE THE VACUUM
AND BLOW THE AIR
BACK ONTO THE PLANET.
STEP TWO--
WE DESTROY THAT THING.
BUT ISN'T THAT
DANGEROUS ?
EXTREMELY.
PLUS...
I DON'T KNOW
HOW THE HELL
WE'RE GONNA DO IT.
- WHAT ABOUT THE RING
YOGURT GAVE YOU ?
- OH, YEAH.  BUT--
COME ON, BOSS.
GIVE IT A SHOT.
OKAY.
HERE GOES NOTHING.
[ Vespa ]
LOOK AT THAT !
WOW !
[ Barf ]
IT'S-IT'S WORKING !
-[ Vespa ]
COME ON, SCHWARTZ.
- [ All ]  COME ON, SCHWARTZ.
COME ON, SCHWARTZ !
HELMET,
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
SANDURZ,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT'SMEGA-MAID.
SHE'S GONE
FROM SUCK TO BLOW.
WHAT ?  THEY'RE GETTING
ALL THEIR AIR BACK.
DO SOMETHING !
I'M BREATHING.
AIR.
AIR !
DIM THE LIGHTS.
DIMMING THE LIGHTS.
GO TO INFRARED.
GOING TO INFRARED.
AND PRAY TO GOD.
PRAYING TO GOD.
[ Blipping ]
[ Dot ]
BE CAREFUL !
CAREFUL !
WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
SCANNING.
THERE'S GOTTA BE
A SELF-DESTRUCT MECHANISM...
SOMEWHERE
IN THE CENTRAL BRAIN AREA.
I THINK
WE JUST FOUND IT.
WHERE ?
WATCH.
[ Switch Clicks ]
[ Lone Starr ]
BINGO.  THERE IT IS.
IT'S RIGHT BELOW US.
PUT HER IN HOVER, BARF.
PUTTING HER IN HOVER.
I'M GOING DOWN THERE.
HE'S GOING DOWN THERE.
I WOULDN'T.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING ?
THE VULCAN NECK PINCH ?
NO, NO, NO, STUPID.
YOU GOT IT MUCH TOO HIGH.
IT'S DOWN HERE WHERE
THE SHOULDER MEETS THE NECK.
LIKE THIS ?
YEAH !
THANKS.
[ Female Computer Voice ]
HAND PRINT IDENTIFICATION,
PLEASE.
HAND PRINT--
[ Beeping ]
THANKS AGAIN.
IS THAT YOU, MYLAR ?
WHO ARE YOU ?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING WITH THAT ?
THIS !
[ Shouting,
Choking ]
[ Groans ]
SWEET DREAMS.
[ Beeping ]
-NOT SO FAST, LONE STARR.
-HELMET !
SO, AT LAST WE MEET...
FOR THE FIRST TIME
FOR THE LAST TIME.
- YEAH.
- BEFORE YOU DIE,
THERE IS SOMETHING
YOU SHOULD KNOW ABOUT US,
LONE STARR.
WHAT ?
I AM YOUR FATHER'S
BROTHER'S NEPHEW'S...
COUSIN'S FORMER ROOMMATE.
WHAT'S THAT MAKE US ?
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING,
WHICH IS WHAT YOU
ARE ABOUT TO BECOME !
PREPARE TO DIE.
YOU HAVE THE RING,
AND I SEE YOUR SCHWARTZ
IS AS BIG AS MINE.
NOW LET'S SEE HOW WELL
YOU HANDLE IT.
[ Screaming ]
UM, HE DID IT.
WHAT ?
SHIT !  I HATE IT WHEN
I GET MY SCHWARTZ TWISTED.
OKAY, MAYBE IF I PUT
MY LEG UP ON YOURS,
YOU KNOW, WE COULD
SPLIT APART LIKE--
GOOD, YEAH.  ON THREE.
ONE, TWO, THREE, GO !
[ Laughing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
OW !
OHH !
[ Groaning ]
SO, LONE STARR,
YOGURT HAS TAUGHT YOU WELL.
IF THERE'S ONE THING I DESPISE,
IT IS A FAIR FIGHT.
BUT IF I MUST, THEN I MUST.
MAY THE BEST MAN WIN.
PUT 'ER THERE.
THE RING !
I CAN'T BELIEVE...
YOU FELL FOR THE OLDEST
TRICK IN THE BOOK !
WHAT A GOOF !
WHAT'S WITH YOU, MAN ?
COME ON.  YOU KNOW WHAT ?
HERE, LET ME
GIVE IT BACK TO YOU.
OHH !
OH, LOOK AT THAT!
YOU FELL FOR THAT TOO.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT, MAN.
SO, LONE STARR,
NOW YOU SEE THAT EVIL
WILL ALWAYS TRIUMPH,
BECAUSE GOOD IS DUMB.
VERY IMPRESSIVE,
LONE STARR.
TOO BAD THIS ISN'T
THE WIDE WORLD OF SPORTS.
[ Yogurt's Voice ]
USE THE SCHWARTZ, LONE STARR.
USE THE SCHWARTZ !
I CAN'T.
I LOST THE RING.
FORGET THE RING.
THE RING IS BUPKIS.
I FOUND IT
IN A CRACKER JACK BOX.
THE SCHWARTZ IS IN YOU,
LONE STARR.
IT'S IN YOU !
ALL RIGHT. I'LL TRY.
SAY GOOD-BYE
TO YOUR TWO BEST FRIENDS,
AND I DON'T MEAN YOUR PALS
IN THE WINNEBAGO.
[ Screaming ]
[ Computer ]
THANK YOU FOR PRESSING
THE SELF-DESTRUCT BUTTON.
[ Alarm Sounding ]
THIS SHIP WILL SELF-DESTRUCT
IN THREE MINUTES.
WHAT'S GOING ON ?
WHERE THE HELL ARE WE ?
PARIS ?
[ Computer ]
THANK YOU FOR PRESSING
THE SELF-DESTRUCT BUTTON.
THIS SHIP WILL SELF-DESTRUCT
IN EXACTLY TWO MINUTES
AND 45 SECONDS.
YOU'VE GOTTA STOP IT.
IS THERE ANY WAY TO STOP IT ?
I CAN'T.
IT'S IRREVERSIBLE.
LIKE MY RAINCOAT.
ATTENTION, THIS IS COLONEL
SANDURZ IN FORWARD COMMAND.
ABANDON SHIP !
ABANDON SHIP !  ALL PERSONNEL
PROCEED TO ESCAPE PODS.
CLOSE DOWN THE CIRCUS.
EVACUATE THE ZOO.
THE SELF-DESTRUCT MECHANISM
HAS BEEN ACTIVATED.
ABANDON SHIP !
SANDURZ.
SANDURZ, YOU GOTTA HELP ME !
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO !
I CAN'T MAKE DECISIONS !
I'M A PRESIDENT !
THIS IS YOUR TWO-MINUTE WARNING.
THIS SHIP WILL SELF-DESTRUCT
IN EXACTLY TWO MINUTES.
LAUNCH ALL ESCAPE PODS
AS SOON AS THEY ARE FILLED !
WHAT'S HAPPENING ?
WHERE IS HE ?
## SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
WHERE IS HE ?
HERE.
WE GOT A MINUTE AND FORTY
BEFORE THE END OF THE WORLD.
HANG ON.
## SPACEBALLS ##
FULL THROTTLE.
GO TO HYPER JETS.
GOING TO HYPER JETS.
## IF YOU'RE LIVIN' IN A BUBBLE
AND YOU HAVEN'T GOT A CARE ##
HEY, GET OUT OF THERE !
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING ?
PIZZA TO GO !
[ Laughing ]
## WELL, YOU'RE GONNA BE
IN TROUBLE 'CAUSE THEY'RE
GONNA STEAL YOUR AIR ##
## 'CAUSE WHAT YOU GOT IS
WHAT WE NEED, AND ALL WE DO
IS DIRTY DEEDS ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
[ Roaring ]
HEY, HEY, HEY.
THAT'S MY ESCAPE POD !
WHO ARE YOU ?
I'M THE BEARDED LADY.
WHAT ARE YOU,
ONE OF THE FREAKS ?
[ Laughing ]
HEY, HEY, COME BACK !
THAT'S MY POD !  NO !
COME BACK,
YOU FAT, BEARDED BITCH !
ONE POD LEFT.
AND THREE OF US.
AND I'M THE PRESIDENT.
WELL, BOYS, IT'S A VERY
LOVELY SHIP.  I THINK
YOU SHOULD GO DOWN WITH IT.
GOOD-BYE !
WHAT THE HELL'S THE MATTER
WITH THIS SEAT BELT ?
[ Screams ]
[ Roars ]
[ Gasping ]
## SPACEBALLS ##
[ Computer ]
THIS SHIP WILL SELF-DESTRUCT
IN 20 SECONDS.
THIS IS YOUR LAST CHANCE
TO PUSH THE CANCELLATION BUTTON.
CANCELLATION BUTTON ?
HURRY !
## SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
[ All Grunting ]
WHERE IS IT ?
IT'S GOTTA BE HERE.
[ Helmet ]
"OUT OF ORDER" ?
FUCK !
EVEN IN THE FUTURE,
NOTHING WORKS.
[ Computer ]
THIS SHIP WILL SELF-DESTRUCT
IN EXACTLY TEN SECONDS.
[ All Gasping ]
COUNTING DOWN.
TEN, NINE,
EIGHT, SIX--
SIX ?
WHAT HAPPENED TO SEVEN ?
JUST KIDDING.
THERE'S THE OTHER END !
FASTER !
FIVE, FOUR,
THREE, TWO, ONE.
HAVE A NICE DAY.
[ Together ]
THANK YOU.
[ Vespa ]
WE DID IT !
[ All Cheering ]
WE ALL DID IT.
[ All Yelling ]
SO I GUESS YOU MIGHT CALL THAT
A CASE OF MAN BITES DROID ?
ON A SADDER NOTE,
PIZZA THE HUT,
FAMED HALF-MAN,
HALF-PIZZA,
WAS FOUND DEAD EARLIER TODAY
IN THE BACK SEAT
OF HIS STRETCHED LIMO.
EVIDENTLY,
THE NOTORIOUS GANGSTER...
BECAME LOCKED IN HIS CAR
AND ATE HIMSELF TO DEATH.
COMING UP, PONGO'S REVIEW
OFROCKY 5,000.
PONGO ?
DID YOU HEAR THAT ?
PIZZA KICKED THE BUCKET.
NOW WE DON'T HAVE
TO PAY HIM THE MILLION.
WE CAN KEEP IT FOR OURSELVES.
YEAH.
- DADDY !
- OHH !
VESPA, MY DARLING !
I THOUGHT I'D NEVER
SEE YOU AGAIN.
OH, MY SWEET LITTLE DAUGHTER.
I'M SO HAPPY
THAT YOU'RE HOME AND SAFE.
AND LITTLE VESPA,
HERE'S SOMEONE ELSE
WHO'S HAPPY TO SEE YOU.
OH, HELLO.
[ Yawns ]
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN ?
THANKS, HON.
## HELLO, BABY ##
[ Guitar Feedback ]
#### [ Heavy Metal ]
HIYA, BIG STUFF.
HI, DREAM.
WHAT'LL YOU HAVE ?
WE JUST GOT A COUPLE MINUTES
WHILE WE'RE GASSIN' UP.
WHAT'S READY ?
I CAN GIVE YOU THE SPACE
SOUP OR THE SPACE SPECIAL.
[ Lone Starr ]
UM, I'LL HAVE THE SOUP.
OKAY.
I'LL HAVE THE CLEAVAGE--
UH, SPECIAL.
OKAY.  ONE SPECIAL
AND ONE SOUP.
READY TO ORDER ?
HI.  YES.
WE'LL BOTH HAVE
THE LUNAFISH.
ANYTHING TO DRINK ?
HEY, HEY, WATCH WHERE
YOU'RE STICKING THAT THING.
HUH ?  OH.
LOOK, IT'S GOT A MIND
OF ITS OWN, SWEETHEART.
I CAN'T DO A THING WITH IT.
[ Chuckles,
Howls ]
- WHAT ?
- WE WERE LOST.
NONE OF US KNEW
WHERE WE WERE.
AND THEN HARRY
BEGAN FEELING AROUND
ON ALL THE TREES.
THEN HE SAID,
"I GOT IT.  WE ON PLUTO."
AND WE SAY,
"HARRY, HOW CAN YOU TELL ?"
HE SAID,
"FROM THE BARK, YOU DUMMIES."
FROM THE BARK !
[ Choking ]
IS HE ALL RIGHT ?
HEY, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THIS GUY ?
I DON'T KNOW !
[ Choking Continues ]
BRING HIM SOME WATER !
WATER, MY ASS !
BRING THIS GUY
SOME PEPTO BISMOL !
WAITRESS !  WAITRESS !
WHAT DID HE ORDER ?
OH, HE HAD THE SPECIAL.
THE SP--
THAT'S WHAT I ORDERED !
CHANGE MY ORDER TO THE SOUP.
GOOD MOVE.
[ Groaning ]
[ Hissing ]
OH, NO.
NOT AGAIN.
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Growling ]
## HELLO, MY BABY
HELLO, MY HONEY ##
## HELLO, MY RAGTIME GAL ##
## SEND ME A KISS BY WIRE
BABY, MY HEART'S ON FIRE ##
## IF YOU REFUSE ME
HONEY, YOU'LL LOSE ME ##
## THEN YOU'LL BE LEFT ALONE
OH, BABY, TELEPHONE ##
## AND TELL ME
I'M YOUR OWN ####
[ Together ]
CHECK, PLEASE.
FIVE MINUTES
TO MAGIC TIME.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, MY DEAR ?
YOU LOOK A LITTLE FLIGHTY.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME, FATHER.
I'M COMPLETELY OVER HIM.
HUH !  DIDN'T EVEN STAY
FOR THE WEDDING.
JUST GRABBED HIS MILLION
SPACE BUCKS AND RAN.
HE DIDN'T TAKE
THE MILLION.
HE DIDN'T ?
NO.
HE JUST TOOK 248 SPACE BUCKS
FOR LUNCH, GAS AND TOLLS.
[ Barf ]
I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU TURNED DOWN THE MONEY.
AT LEAST WE COULD HAVE STAYED
FOR THE WEDDING FEAST.
I'M STARVING !
HAVE YOU GOT ANYTHING TO EAT ?
NAH.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
YOGURT GAVE ME
THAT FORTUNE COOKIE.
HERE, CHOW DOWN.
WOW, THANKS.
I'LL SPLIT IT WITH YOU.
NO.
OKAY.
[ Together ]
YOGURT !
HELLO, BOYS.
WELL, YOU OPENED
YOUR FORTUNE COOKIE,
SO HERE'S YOUR FORTUNE.
LONE STARR, YOU KNOW
THAT MEDALLION THAT YOU
WEAR AROUND YOUR NECK...
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS ?
WELL, HERE'S WHAT IT MEANS.
IT'S A ROYAL BIRTH CERTIFICATE.
YES !
YOUR FATHER WAS A KING,
YOUR MOTHER WAS A QUEEN,
WHICH MAKES YOU
A CERTIFIED PRINCE.
HEY, I'M A PRINCE.
I'M A PRINCE,
WHICH MEANS--
WHICH MEANS IF YOU HURRY,
THERE COULD BE A PRINCESS
IN YOUR FUTURE.
NOW, IF YOU WANNA
GET BACK THERE BEFORE
SHE MARRIES SLEEPING BEAUTY,
THERE'S A SPECIAL CAN OF FUEL
IN YOUR GLOVE COMPARTMENT.
- GOOD LUCK, BOYS.
- BYE, YOGURT.
AND YOGURT, THANKS.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
AND MAY THE SCHWARTZ
BE WITH YOU !
[ Ululating ]
WHAT A WORLD.
BARF,
OPEN THAT
GLOVE COMPARTMENT.
YOU GOT IT, YOUR HIGHNESS.
WOW !
LIQUID SCHWARTZ !
- QUICK.  POUR IT
IN THE EMERGENCY TANK.
- RIGHT.
[ Lone Starr ]
LOOK AT THAT !
DONE !
HANG ON, BARFO.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SPACE TRACKS.
[ Screeching ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
DEAR ME.  WHAT ARE THOSE THINGS
COMING OUT OF HER NOSE ?
HEY, HEY,
WATCH MY HELMET !
[ Both Grunting ]
- SPACEBALLS ?
- OH, SHIT.
THERE GOES THE PLANET.
DEARLY BELOVED,
WE ARE GATHERED HERE...
TOGETHER, AGAIN--
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
HE DIDN'T TAKE THE MONEY ?
- I DIDN'T THINK
IT WAS IMPORTANT.
- MAY I CONTINUE, PLEASE ?
BESIDES, HE ASKED ME
NOT TO TELL YOU.
THANK YOU.
TO JOIN PRINCESS VESPA...
AND PRINCESS VALIUM--
I'M SORRY.
IT'S THE HAIR.
PRINCE VALIUM, IN THE BONDS
OF HOLY MATRIMONY--
I SEE IT ALL NOW.
DON'T YOU SEE HE LOVES ME ?
EXCUSE ME.  I'M TRYING
TO CONDUCT A WEDDING HERE, WHICH
HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH LOVE.
- PLEASE BE QUIET.
- [ Together ]
I'M SORRY.
- I'M SORRY TOO.
- DON'T BE SORRY.  BE QUIET !
[ All ]
I'M SORRY !
TO JOIN PRINCESS VESPA
AND PRINCE VALIUM...
IN THE BONDS OF--
HOLY MOLEY !
[ Spaceship Roars Overhead ]
[ All Gasping ]
UH, MATRIMONY !
[ Vespa ]
THAT'S HIM !
I KNOW IT'S HIM !
HE'S COME BACK !
[ Minister ]  THAT'S IT.
I'M GONNA TAKE NO MORE CHANCES.
WE'RE DOING THE SHORT VERSION.
PRINCE VALIUM, DO YOU TAKE
PRINCESS VESPA TO BE
YOUR LAWFULLY WEDDED WIFE ?
- [ Yawning ]  UH-HUH.
- DO YOU TAKE PRINCE VALIUM
TO BE YOUR HUSBAND ?
UH, WELL, I-- I SUPPOSE.
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
NO, SHE DOESN'T !
WHAT ?
[ Exclaiming ]
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU ?
- PRINCE LONE STARR.
- PRINCE ?
I JUST FOUND OUT.
THAT'S WHAT THIS SAYS.
I'M AN
HONEST-TO-GOD PRINCE.
WILL YOU MARRY ME ?
WELL, LET ME THINK ABOUT IT.
YES.
[ Minister ]
I'M SICK OF THIS.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN WHO IT IS,
BUT I'M GONNA MARRY
SOMEBODY TODAY !
WHO ARE YOU ?
I'M THE BEST MAN.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
BARF.
- YOUR FULL NAME.
- BARFOLOMEW.
- ARE YOU THE ONE
THAT'S GETTING MARRIED ?
- NO.
THEN GET OVER THERE !
OKAY, HERE WE GO.
THE SHORT, SHORT VERSION.
DO YOU ?
YES.
GOOD.  YOU'RE MARRIED.
KISS HER.
I LOVE YOU.
[ Sniffling ]
WELL, GOOD-BYE,
VIRGIN ALARM.
## IF YOU'RE LIVIN' IN A BUBBLE
AND YOU HAVEN'T GOT A CARE ##
## WELL, YOU'RE GONNA BE
IN TROUBLE 'CAUSE THEY'RE
GONNA STEAL YOUR AIR ##
## 'CAUSE WHAT YOU GOT IS WHAT
WE NEED, AND ALL WE DO
IS DIRTY DEEDS ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## 'CAUSE WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WE'RE THE MASTERS OF SPACE ##
## HEY, DON'T MESS AROUND ##
## WITH THE SPACEBALLS ##
## HUH ##
## GOIN' CRUISIN' IS A SPACESHIP
WE'RE SO GOOD AT BEIN' BAD ##
## WE'LL DESTROY
YOUR LITTLE PLANET
IF YOU EVER GET US MAD ##
## WE'RE MOTHERS OF THE GALAXY
YOU BETTER SCATTER
WHEN YOU SEE ##
## THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WE'RE THE MASTERS OF SPACE ##
## SAY WHAT
DON'T MESS AROUND ##
## WITH THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## WE'RE MOTHERS OF THE GALAXY ##
## WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE AIR YOU BREATHE ##
## OH, SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WE'RE THE MASTERS OF SPACE ##
## DON'T MESS AROUND
WITH THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WE'RE THE MASTERS OF SPACE ##
## DON'T MESS AROUND
WITH THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## WE'VE GOT
AN AWESOME LITTLE SHIP ##
## SO YOU BETTER WATCH YOUR LIP ##
## 'CAUSE WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## YOU MAY THINK
THAT YOU ARE BAD ##
## BUT BELIEVE YOU CAN BE HAD ##
## BY THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WATCH OUT ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WE'RE THE MASTERS OF SPACE ##
## DON'T MESS AROUND
WITH THE SPACEBALLS ##
## WE'RE SO BAD AND MEAN ##
## WE MAKE NIGHTMARES
OUT OF DREAMS ##
## WE'RE THE SPACEBALLS ##
## YOU BETTER ##
## WATCH OUT ####
[ Man Chuckling ]