Hey, good morning, New York.
Scott Zoe here...
...at 102.7, WNEW-FM,
where rock lives.
Beautiful autumn
day in the city...
...and a great record
coming your way too.
Ben!
Get up, get up, get up!
Late, late, late!
Ben! Come on, honey. Get up.
We're seriously late.
You may think this is funny,
but this is so not...
...funny.
I'm not kidding
anymore, Ben.
You make yourself
appear right this instant.
The clock is ticking, Ben!
Come on now!
Anna?
Oh good, you're already up.
You forgot to wash my shirt.
I told you a hundred times.
Today is purple shirt
day at school.
I didn't forget.
Actually, I was up half the
night thinking about it.
Yeah, right.
And I concluded that
you are too special...
...to look like everyone else.
So, orangey-red.
That's your colour.
Few can carry it off.
Now...
- Would you help me find your brother?
- You lost Ben?
No.
I didn't lose Ben.
All right, Ben, fine.
You explain to your teacher
why you're late.
Your daddy said he had a very
important case this morning...
...and had to go to work early.
And he left us here
to be responsible...
...that we could...
Shit!
You're so not funny.
Not funny!
And you're also late.
And that means you have
to get dressed right now!
Stay. No, stay. Ben! Ben!
This is not funny!
We've got to get you dressed.
We're running so late.
This is not a game!
Come on. Help me out.
Ben!
Come on, Ben!
Really, we're so late!
But I don't want
to go to school.
Mommy!
Hi, sweetie!
Ben, you look like you're
having such a good time!
But we're running a little late.
Sweetie, I thought you're supposed
to be wearing purple today.
She forgot to wash it.
What a hug!
I'll handle it from here, Isabel.
I'm sure you will, Jackie.
Oh, my gosh!
She made you a lunch?
Okay, come on.
Mom, why do we have to
listen to this classical stuff?
Because I like it,
and I'm driving...
...and when you get your own
car, you can pick the music.
Why does Isabel wear
Daddy's underpants?
Doesn't she have
underpants of her own?
Huh, well, I saw a whopping pile of
laundry sitting on the washing machine.
- Perhaps her underpants are there.
- Yeah, right next to my purple shirt.
I'm never speaking to her again.
Never say never.
Here's your vitamins.
She's always
messing up my life.
It's not fair to say "always."
I hate her!
She's such a witch.
Hey! No name-calling.
Use your words.
I hate when you say that.
Now, that's a beginning.
" Hate" is a totally
acceptable word...
...you just be careful
when you use it...
...and only use it when
you truly detest something.
Like what?
Well, like...
...the planet Uranus. I hate that.
It's a terrible name for a planet.
Uranus!
- And the hokey-pokey.
- Hokey-pokey?
The hokey-pokey.
I hate the hokey-pokey.
Putting your foot in and out
at weddings. It's terrible!
I hate when you do that!
I can smell your breakfast!
Point well-taken.
Ladies, let's just calm
down. She'll be here.
Isabel, where are you?
Come on. Any word?
Yeah. She's on her way.
- She's on her way. I promise.
- Oh, really?
How do you know?
I'm here! I'm sorry I'm late.
What a crisis!
White pants, black top?
And the white or black bra?
And then I picked this...
- All righty.
- I'm here. I'm lame.
You got a Froot Loop
in your hair.
Get me a digital
camera right now.
Russell, get this out
of here, please?
Quikly.
Come on, boys!
Why is she shooting this?
Isabel, we have been
waiting for an hour.
I know. I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
Why are you shooting this?
Because I'm brilliant.
And I see something you don't.
So stand back and trust me,
why don't you?
Oh, I trust you!
I just don't understand why are you
shooting the craft service guy...
...when I've got 5 male models
in very expensive suits over here?
Thank you, ladies. That's lovely.
That's a wrap, everybody!
No, it's not a wrap!
She's kidding! You are kidding,
aren't you, Isabel?
I'm not kidding actually. And if
you meet me here in an hour...
...l will prove to you
why you hired me...
...even though I
wouldn't sleep with you.
She's got such a
great sense of humor.
Wait.
Let's see...
...if I can save...
...both our jobs.
- Interesting.
- Look at that!
Wow! It's the
little guy in the suit.
- What do you think?
- I like it.
I like it. Good work.
I like it too. Very creative.
Thank you.
Congratulations, Duncan.
That suit takes
pounds off of him.
While change is exhilarating
for an adult...
...it can be quite a
challenge for a child.
I won't get that.
It's fine.
Change.
You were talking
about change.
Well, the fact that you
two are remarrying...
...obviously has Anna overjoyed.
And she's very excited about
the move to Switzerland.
She said we are remarrying?
And my concern is that Anna seems
apathetic towards her work...
...knowing she's leaving
before this semester.
- Mrs. Franklin, we are not...
- No plans on getting...
- Remarried. There's no move...
- To Switzerland.
Really?
Really.
Well, then, my
concern for Anna...
...is that she...
- Are you here?
- I'm here.
- 'Cause you don't seem like you're here.
- I'm here!
The judge is about to rule on a motion
that could make or break my case.
- But have I answered my beeper?
- So turn it off.
I'm wondering if there's anything
going at home that could possibly be...
...intensifying Anna's need
to create this fantasy.
I've been seeing another woman
through the past year.
Since we're divorced he's seen
a number of women, and...
Saw a few women when
we first split up...
...but I've been seeing one
woman for the past year.
After a lot of thought and
carefull discussion with her...
...and the kids - I might add -
she moved in last month.
- He's living with a woman half his age.
- Isabel's not half my age.
- We're not discussing your age.
- Then why bring it up?
When they go to your house,
they wanna be with you.
They want to be
with their father!
When they come to my house,
they want to be a part of my life.
Isabel's part of my life.
Mr. Harrison, I hear you talking
about your life, your needs, but...
...are you really in touch
with what Anna needs?
Anna needs a home where
she feels safe and loved.
What I'm trying to give her.
- I thought that's what she already had.
- I'd walk through fire for Anna.
Gladly. Any day of the week.
Except Thursday, when Isabel
forgot to pick them up.
Jackie, she was 5 minutes
late, for Christ's sakes!
She was 5 minutes late!
I'm wondering if Anna could be
responding to the underline hostility...
...that exists between your
girlfriend and Mrs. Harrison.
Well, of course she's
responding to it.
Mrs. Franklin, do you think
any of this is easy for us?
Do you think it's
easy for Jackie to...
...watch her kids looked
after by another woman?
Not to mention that...
...a woman who really has
no experience being a mother.
Of course Jackie's
going to be irrational...
...hostile...
...defensive.
Thank you, Luke.
I didn't say that.
Why would I say that...
...you and daddy were
getting back together?
Sometimes people
make up stories...
...about things that
they wish would happen!
I don't want that to happen.
Why would I want that to happen?
Okay, pick a card.
Any card.
Because you're upset.
You know, because
Isabel moved in and...
I'm not upset. I'm not
geting myself upset over her.
Ok. Tear it in half.
Look, sweetie.
- If it means that...
- Again.
- If you really...
If you want...
And again.
Time out.
If you don't want to talk
about this now, it's ok. Really.
You don't have to.
But don't look me in
the eye and lie to me.
It hurts my feelings,
I get angry, and...
Anyway, you're only allowed so many lies
before it starts showing in your face...
...and you wind up
looking like...
Like who?
Well, he's not President
anymore, so why be petty?
I'm sorry I said it.
I guess sometimes I just...
You know, sometimes I do
wish you and Daddy would...
Well, you know.
I figured if I said it out loud,
it just... might come true.
Yeah, I know.
It's not that I can't cook.
It's that I choose not to cook.
- There's a big difference.
- You don't have to cook.
Could we save
some of the wine?
- I need it for the sauce.
- Too late.
Hi, honey.
You better get it.
- Who's there?
- Nobody there.
I missed you today.
I missed you too.
I miss you every day.
How was your day, baby?
It was pretty good, except
I got to go back to Pittsburgh.
Yeah, I got to go
tomorrow till Sunday.
But I'll have to order in.
Well, we got the kids for
the weekend, so I figured...
...that you and the kids...
...and me could all go...
...to Pittsburgh together.
Never going to happen.
No? Come on! We could
get a great hotel room.
We could take in a
baseball game or something.
- What do you think?
- Pass.
All right. Then I'll
call the babysitter.
What for?
Well, I don't expect you
to handle them yourself.
What?
Can't handle them myself.
That's what you mean, isn't it?
No.
You don't trust me to be
alone with your kids.
- Yes, I do.
- No.
Of course I do.
It's just that...
- What?
- They're a handful.
Luke, by keeping me apart
from them, is like you saying...
..."Hey kids, this is fun.
Keep on hating her."
Oh, I don't say that.
They don't hate you.
- Really?
Look in their eyes, honey.
Look in your ex-wife's eyes.
Jackie's just protecting her kids.
What do you expect?
It's hard for her.
It's complicated.
You don't understand.
You don't have kids.
So... it's just complicated
for you and Jackie.
For me, it's pretty simple
because I don't have kids.
Look... I'm just trying to make
things work here and...
...trying to give you guys time
to get used to living together.
All right then.
Back off just a little bit,
and give me a chance, okay?
What is your problem, asshole?
You are my problem!
You're absolutely right, baby.
Your kids don't hate me.
I'm just...
I'm just paranoid.
Call your daughter.
I trust you.
Really?
I'll give you a chance
if you still want it.
- I do.
- Are you sure?
Yes.
Okay.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Don't fight with me
when I'm hungry.
So, how long will
you be out of town?
Till Sunday morning.
I'm worried.
About what?
About being alone
with her all weekend.
I mean... what if she
burns the place down?
Well, just keep an
eye on her and...
...make sure you boys got
the fire extinguisher's handy.
- You ready to launch her?
- Yeah.
Let's give her a good push.
So, why did she move
in with you anyways?
Because we love
each other, and...
...because we want to
share our life together.
You already had
a life with Mommy.
But Mommy and I weren't
getting along very well...
...and it wasn't fair to you
guys, us fighting all the time.
I fight with Anna all the time.
Can I move out?
No. But you guys
are brother and sister.
You were husband and wife.
Doesn't that mean something?
Yes...
It does.
But...
Well...
When you get older...
...your relationships get
a lot more complicated.
And there's all kinds of
feelings flying around.
And sometimes...
...some of those
feelings change.
But did you fall out
of love with Mommy?
Well...
Yeah.
I guess I did.
I still love your mom.
It just...
...became a different
kind of love, that's all.
We're still really good friends,
and we always will be.
Can you ever fall out
of love with your kids?
No.
That is impossible.
- Like Mission: lmpossible.
- Yeah.
Exactly like Mission: lmpossible.
Get over here.
Powdered lizard brains.
Crushed werewolf ears...
...and vampire eyes.
God!
Cool!
Check it out. Magic potion.
It's cocoa.
I put a spell on it.
Whoever drinks it...
...will go to sleep
for 1000 years.
Whatever.
Spill any on my drawing...
...I'll put you to sleep
for 1000 years.
You guys. I have a surprise
for you. Come over to the sofa.
Please.
With a little... enthusiasm.
Sit down.
All right.
And... close your eyes.
Please.
Okay.
Okay, now.
Don't open them until
I tell you to, okay?
And open!
- Uau!
- What do you think?
Will he eat my bunny?
No!
Puppies don't eat bunnies.
Anna, what do you think?
Well, I'm allergic to dogs.
Your daddy didn't
tell me that.
He doesn't know much
about me. He's never around.
Why don't we name the puppy?
Puppy needs a name.
I know. Isabel.
I beg your pardon?
Well, he kinda smells
like you, and...
...and I'm allergic to you too.
It fits perfectly.
Ben, why don't you name
that puppy? I'll be right back.
Listen, young lady, let's
get one thing straight.
Don't touch my things!
I would really like it
if we could get along.
- I don't have to listen to you.
- Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
You're not my mother.
Thank God for that!
What I meant, and perhaps
I didn't say it well...
...is you have a great mom.
You don't need another one.
But I... would like to be
treated with some respect...
...when you are in this house.
This is my dad's house.
Well, it's my house too.
This is my room, so treat it
with respect and get out.
All right.
"Run, run, run
as fast as you can".
"You can't catch me,
I'm the Stinky Cheese Man".
Aren't you going to drink your cocoa?
I made it especially for you.
Yes, of course.
The special cocoa.
Delicious.
"A little boy looked up and
sniffed the air and said"...
No, now you're cheating. You
skipped the part about the cow.
It's bedtime. Can't we
finish this in the morning?
No. Now we have to start
from the beginning...
...and you have to read the whole
thing. I can't sleep otherwise.
Okay.
"Once upon a time...
...there was a little old woman
and a little old man... "
"Who lived together
in a little old house."
You're onto something. Why
don't you read to me a little bit?
"They were lonely.
So the little old lady
decided to make a man...
...out of stinky cheese.
She gave him a piece of bacon for
a mouth and two olives for eyes... "
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
What's the matter?
I...
...killed her.
Killed her! Killed her!
Killed her!
- Good morning.
- It is 7:23.
You were supposed
to be here at 6:30.
She has missed her
morning riding lesson.
No. It's Monday. Her riding
lesson is on Tuesday.
Except for the third Tuesday of the
month, which switches to Monday.
And in November, when
she rides on Thursdays.
It's not that difficult!
Don't you have some kind of
little black agenda book...
...that you can write
all this down in?
May I have a cup
of coffee, please?
We don't have coffee.
Good morning, Betty Ford.
Hey, monkey man. Hi, sweetie.
How are you doing?
Sweetie, go change your shirt.
What happened to Anna?
What did you do?
Maybe you could you just
back off me a little bit.
What happened?
Nothing happened. I...
Luke was in the shower
this morning and...
...Anna sort of...
...walked in without
even knocking.
I don't see why
that would upset her.
I mean, there are
people in our family...
...that have taken
showers before.
Well, I was in there with him.
And did either of you...
...talk to her
about it afterwards?
No.
I thought it would be
uncomfortable for her.
You mean for you.
A 12-year-old girl is trying
to cope with the fact...
...that her father is never moving
back in here with his family.
She sees her father naked in the
shower with another woman...
...for the first time...
...and you think it would
be better for her...
...if everyone just pretends
nothing happened?
I am so unbelievably sick
of your imperious bullshit.
I never said I was
June fucking Cleaver.
You don't use that
language in this house.
Every time life hits her hard, you wanna
have some 12-hour conversation...
...every third Tuesday of the month...
You go right ahead, lady. I have a life.
Oh, and I don't?
Because I have children?
You know, your problem is that
you are so self-involved...
...you couldn't be a mother.
Maybe the problem here
is your daughter.
And that she is a spoiled,
wiseass little brat.
Get out of my house.
Get out!
Are you sure? I didn't
see that on the schedule.
Honey, I've got your Halloween costume.
Let's see if it's the right size, ok?
A hippie?
Didn't you say you
wanted to be a hippie?
That was last month.
Oh!... well...
Okay, what do you
want to be this month?
Elvis.
Elvis? What kind of Elvis?
You mean, like,
black leather jacket Elvis?
Gold lamé Elvis.
Gold lamé Elvis?
That's pre-drugs, pre-chubby,
pre-army, pre-bad movie...
...all of that Elvis?
- Yeah.
Honey...
When Daddy was...
...washing Isabel...
...in the shower, what did
you think that was about?
Well, sex, of course.
Why does Isabel scream?
Scream?
During sex.
How do you know she
screams during sex?
I live in the same country.
- Why are you asking me?
- Just checking.
I like to talk to you
about stuff.
I like talking to you
about stuff too.
So, since Daddy's
gonna be working...
...you want to do something
on Saturday, just you and me?
Sure, but it'll have to
be in the evening...
...'cause I'm helping Bonnie Lyons
move into her apartment, and...
...so you're going to be with...
...Isabel.
Again?
That really sucks!
Well, you're gonna be at a professional
photo shoot in Central Park.
You guys are going to
have a lot of fun.
Switch your hands.
Top hand down, bottom hand up.
Dylan, can you take just one step up
for me please? Just one big step.
Rapunzel, would you reach
your hand out there again?
Wouldn't it be cool if her
hair came out of her armpits?
Oh, sick!
I think we can get this
finished before lunch.
Folks, we like this light. We'll try
and get this in before lunch.
Come on! It's been
5 hours, we're hungry!
Yeah, we're starving!
Get yourself another ice
cream, ok? And I'll be done soon.
I promise.
We're rich!
Sleeping Beauty, wake up.
Where's your brother?
I don't know.
- What if he's kidnapped?
- He's not kidnapped! He's just...
He's hiding!
Ben!
- Maybe he's in the castle.
- That's a good idea!
Don't touch me!
You bring bad luck.
Okay, watch very carefully.
- Mommy!
- Hi, sweetie!
- Are you all right?
- I knew where I was all the time!
- We found him in the zoo.
- In the zoo? My God!
Hold his hand. Don't let
him out of your sight.
Jackie, I am so sorry.
I'm going to say this one
time, so listen carefully.
That woman is to have nothing
more to do with my children.
Our children.
Do you realize what could've
happened to your son?
How lucky we are the police found
him, instead of some lunatic?
Jackie, you don't
make it any worse.
Isabel is sorry.
She feels terrible.
- It could've happened to anyone.
- Not to me!
You've made mistakes.
People make mistakes!
Well, I am not gonna sit here
and wait for the next one.
I'm not gonna
watch our children...
...fall through the cracks
of this arrangement.
Just calm down.
I'm not going to calm down!
I'm going to a lawyer!
Don't do that! We promised
we'd never do that.
We've broken a lot of promises,
haven't we, Luke?
Don't take this out on him.
It's my fault.
Honey...
I'm so sorry!
But you're not making
this any easier on anybody.
It is not my job to
make it easier for you.
It is my job is to care of those children,
and they don't want to be with you!
I'm getting a court order,
and you are never...
...going to be with these children again
alone. Do you understand? Ever!
- Mommy...
- What, sweetie?
It's not Isabel's fault
that I ran away.
No, you're right.
That was your fault.
But It's her fault for not taking care of
my precious son as if it was her priority.
Which means, her
most important job.
Isabel's job is she works.
Mommies work too.
They work very hard!
In fact I work harder
as a mommy...
...than I ever did when
I had an outside job...
...I just don't get paid!
- Does Isabel make a lot of money?
People like Isabel who think
only about themselves...
...often do make a
great deal of money.
- I think she's pretty.
- Yeah!...
If you like big teeth.
- Mommy...
- What, sweetie?
If you want me
to hate her, I will.
What do you want?
Anna left her soccer stuff at the loft.
I figured she might need it this week.
Thanks.
- Did you talk to the lawyer?
- Yeah.
I have an appointment for
the day after tomorrow.
Don't do this.
You will tell me not to put the
kids in the middle of a war.
Luke... I'm doing this for
their own well-being.
Partly.
And partly you're doing it
because you're mad.
You know the kids
aren't in any real danger.
This is about Isabel
and you know it.
She made one mistake, but
she's trying! She's learning!
Slugs have a faster learning
curve, ok? Trees, clams...
Give her some time, will you?
Don't drive her away.
I'm supposed to
care about her?
You're supposed to care about
me, like I care about you.
Like you cared about me 2 years ago
when you walked out that door?
You kicked me out!
You were gone long before
I asked you to leave.
Don't give me this shit!
I was working, for God's sake!
I'm sorry. Look, wait
a second. Don't...
Please don't do this
thing with the lawyers.
The kids will be
okay, if we're okay.
I'd do it for you.
Okay. I'm going to give
you one last chance.
Thanks.
Thanks!
Good night.
This is the one that
I really like the best.
She's got a
really longing look.
- She's great in that.
- He couldn't be more flexed.
He's holding his
breath. C-14.
Don't you think this one is?
The way he's leaning back?
Kill that music, please.
That's passive.
This is dynamic.
He's going up.
He's gonna get that girl.
You're the photographer.
You're the genius.
Isabel, it's Anna's school.
They're looking for Luke.
Hello?
No, he's not here.
This is...
Are you sure you
have the right kids?
Because Jackie Harrison would
never forget to pick up her kids.
Are you absolutely
sure it's them?
Of course.
I'll be right there.
I will pick them up.
Thank you.
What?
Isabel, may I remind you that
the clients will be here at 4:30?
I know, so I have to hurry.
Everything is gonna be fine.
Don't worry. I'll be back.
And I will dazzle you with my
punctuality. To the button.
Isabel, don't do this!
Hi, guys.
Barbecue. I know
they're your fave.
How could she... just
forget us? I mean...
Yeah. That's something
you would do.
To tell you the truth...
...l did.
Your mother had to
help a friend with this...
...emergency...
...and so she called
me to switch days...
...but, I got caught up at work
and just forgot all about you.
Mommy!
My little chick!
How are you, sweetie? I'm sorry
you got stuck. Were you scared?
- You must be starving!
- Yeah.
Yeah? You hungry?
- You want a good meal?
- Yeah.
How'd you do
on your math?
Was it hard?
Who is it?
It's Jackie.
May I come in?
Sure.
I have another appointment
this afternoon, and l...
I need somebody...
...to take the
children to the park.
And have federal agents
jump out of the bushes...
...and serve me
with a court order?
How many years do you get in the state
for giving second-rate care to minors?
Whatever it is,
it's not enough.
Well, look. I'm on thin ice
already with my boss, alright?
When I ran out of here yesterday, I
actually thought he was gonna fire me.
I can get somebody else.
Wait. God!
I'll figure something
out. I'll do it.
After-school snack.
Refrigerate, if possible.
Band-Aids, Neosporin,
hand-wipes, Kleenex, Tylenol.
Why not just bring
the whole pharmacy?
Ben likes to be read to.
You know Dr. Seuss?
Not personally.
Do you have a word limit you have
to hit every day, or may I finish?
Here's the kid's schedule, my beeper
number, in case of emergency.
If not, I'll see you
at 5 o'clock at the park.
All I'm asking is that my children
still be alive when I get there.
Jackie, I wanted
to ask you...
...something.
There's a Pearl Jam concert on the
5th, and I would like to take Anna.
Is that a weekday?
I think it's a Thursday.
So you wanna take a 12-year-old girl to
a Pearl Jam concert on a school night?
I just thought it would be something
nice that she and I could do together.
It's ridiculous!
She's too young.
It spread?
But I did...
I did everything right!
Everything I was supposed to do.
We found some cells in your
lymph nodes. In three of them.
But you said the last time
that you got it all.
So If you were wrong
in the last time...
than there's a good chance
you're wrong this time...
...because the last time...
- Last time... was a year ago.
We found a tiny lump, we treated
it. We thought we got it all.
We were hopeful, but there
were no guarantees.
But people...
You...
We can beat it. I mean,
people beat it all the time, right?
- Every day, more and more.
- Ok! So, what's the plan?
What do we do?
Another round of radiation?
Chemotherapy.
That's necessary?
Let's give it
our best shot.
Right. Okay.
Excuse me. I got
to get the kids.
We'll discuss this at
your next appointment.
And you should share this
with your kids and ex-husband.
How would his worrying or my
kids worrying make any difference?
Sooner than later...
...you need to.
- Jackie!
- Ok.
- Think about it.
I see her.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Thanks for coming.
You're welcome.
You look pretty!
Thanks.
Listen...
I'm glad you called, 'cause there's
something I wanna tell you too.
Oh! Ok.
Well, you go first.
Let me have a drink here.
I'm going to ask Isabel...
...to marry me.
I know you don't
think much of her.
She's a special person.
She really is, Jackie.
Why are you
telling me this?
I want you to tell me
that it's ok.
- You don't need my approval.
- The kids do.
Good evening.
Would you and your wife
care to look at the menu?
I'm not his wife.
No, thank you.
Give me a drink though,
please. Whatever this is.
I think it's going to be
hard for the kids.
And I was hoping we
could tell them together.
And that would make it easier
for the kids? Or for you?
Because you know, you can't just
decide to be a "we" and "us"...
...whenever it's
convenient for you.
- We are...
- No, we're over. We are over.
We are still their parents
for the next 100 years.
Why?
Just tell me why you
think this marriage...
...is going to work
and ours didn't.
- What did you want to talk to me about?
- Nothing. It's...
I think we have...
...quite enough to deal with
just with your news.
Good morning.
Good morning, baby.
I've got something for you.
You do?
But you have to
wake up to get it.
I'm awake.
You shouldn't have?
The first time
I got married...
...we'd been together
since college.
Marriage...
...just seemed like
the next step.
It was just something
that happened.
But I think for two people
to really love each other...
...to really commit
to each other...
...it has to be...
...it has to be
an act of will.
Or a decision.
And I think two people have
to live that decision every day.
Even when things are hard
and you feel like giving up...
...you have to...
...hang on to that decision...
...that choice to...
...to love each other.
Even if it's only
by a thread.
I...
...let that thread
break once.
This time, it won't.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
Yes, I will.
- Sweetheart, don't get upset.
- I'm not upset. Why would I be upset?
I mean... No one asked me
when you got a divorce.
No one asked me if
I wanted a new mother.
No one even asked
me if I liked her.
If you guys don't care about keeping
our family together, then why should I?
Anna, daddy and I tried
very hard. Really, we did!
No, you didn't! All you did
was name-call. I heard you.
You didn't even try
to use real words.
Baby, Isabel's not going to
take my place as your mom!
It's just that Isabel's going
to be in your life and...
...hopefully, you can
learn to accept her.
Sweetheart.
Honey.
You know, life is
full of hard things!
And sometimes it
isn't fair, and...
But you know
you have a choice.
You can either take the hard things
and make your life better, or...
...or you can make it worse.
Like how?
Like...
...trying to see the
good side of Isabel, and...
...what she brings to
your father's life, and...
...to yours!
You know, there comes
a time in every family...
...when you've got to be
there for each other.
I'll be there for you.
How about you, buddy?
Yeah.
You'll be there?
Damn it!
What's the problem?
Nothing.
It looks good!
I can't get the
trees to look real.
Mind if I try?
I already messed
it up anyway.
Let's see...
First a little
brush smooshing.
"Smooshing."
Very technical term.
Cool! Where'd you
learn how to do that?
I took an art class
when I was at NYU.
Why don't you
give it a try?
It helps if you
make that little...
Thanks.
You're welcome.
I was thinking about what
you said about Isabel.
You know, seeing the
good side of her, and...
You know, you're right!
She knows all about
clothes and stuff, and...
...she knows every rock
and roll song ever written.
I mean... She's kind
like a kid herself.
- Like a big sister.
- Yeah!
She knows the cool
junk food places to eat at.
I'll bet!
Once you get to know
her, she's kind of cool.
But don't tell her
I told you, I...
- I just...
- It's our secret.
Thanks.
Ben, wait up!
Did you have a good day?
You're one lucky boy
because... guess what?
You get to watch a tape tonight.
I'm going out. Colleen's baby-sitting.
Yeah! Cool!
And you...
...are wearing make-up.
Well, no.
Isabel gave it to me.
No, she just put a little on in
the car, playing around.
You don't usually see that color in the
afternoon, except on working girls.
Anyway...
...wash your face, because...
...you and I are going
out in 10 minutes.
On a school night?
Pearl Jam?!
- Oh mom, you are the coolest!
- You only live once, right?
Isn't my mom the coolest?
It was a great idea.
Thanks.
Have fun.
Chemotherapy. There's
a day's dose stored here.
This is a portable IV. Feel it.
It's pretty light.
Yeah, nice and slim. You can
wear it everywhere...
...playing tennis, jogging...
- You can hide it right under your clothes.
- That's cool.
Side effects?
Some days you'll experience
drowsiness, nausea...
...and another days
you'll feel perfectly fine.
Am I going to
lose my hair?
Maybe.
Maybe not. It varies
with each person.
Let's do it!
Good.
When?
I'm available
tomorrow evening.
Oh, tomorrow evening is bad.
It's spaghetti and meatball night.
Ben really looks forward...
Okay, tomorrow's
good! Fine.
Hi, honey.
How you doing?
Mom, I've been
waiting for your call!
- Mom, you're not gonna believe it!
- What?
- I'm telepathetic!
- You mean, telepathic?
That's what I said.
I just discovered it today.
I can read minds.
No way.
Yeah, I just tried it with Dad
and Isabel, and guess what?
What?
I always knew exactly
what they were thinking!
That is incredible.
- Want me to read yours?
- Absolutely.
- Think real hard about something.
- I'm thinking.
- Close your eyes.
- Ok.
Concentrate.
I am concentrating.
You're thinking
about... me!
That is amazing!
What else?
And you're wishing you were
here instead of where you are.
That's for sure.
Where are you, anyway?
I'm in bed, with the flu...
...and I'm green
and barfing.
I knew that.
And you're wishing you were
here making me spaghetti...
...so I wouldn't have to eat
Daddy's sucky lamb chop.
You're right about that.
- See? I'm pathatelic!
- Telepathic!
That's what I said.
- When am I going to see you?
- Tomorrow after school.
I was wishing I'd
see you tonight.
Well, we'll just
gonna have...
...to have one of our dream
dates and meet somewhere special.
In our dreams!
Where haven't we been in a
while? How about Disneyland?
No... last time, the
lines were too long.
The beach.
Yeah!
On a hot summer day.
With gigantic waves.
And boogie boards.
And corn dogs.
Awesome.
Cool. All right, now don't forget
to put on your sunblock, okay?
It's a dream, mom.
You don't need sunblock.
That's right. I forgot!
- Mommy, you still there?
- Yeah.
Ben? Time for dinner.
I got to go.
See you tonight, okay?
All right.
- I'll see you in my dreams!
- Bye, mom.
- Bye.
- I love you.
She doesn't have that
killer instinct, does she?
Defense, fall back!
You feeling all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm great.
You look a bit tired.
I hate when people say that. It's a
polite way of telling you look like shit.
I didn't mean it like that.
I just have some
things on my mind.
You've been
really busy lately.
Are you...
...seeing somebody?
No. I wish that was the
reason I was tired. I...
I've been spending a little
time with my old boss...
...trying to decide whether or not
I'll go back to Random House.
Really?
That would be great!
Oh, Ben.
Easy, easy, easy.
Ben, Ben, be
careful, sweetie.
You're a dead guy,
Captain Blood!
Ben, that was
really cool.
- Sweetie, can you move your leg?
- Yeah.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
Are you okay?
Yeah, but can I still go to
Tucker's party tomorrow?
Probably. But we gotta get it cleaned
up, and have somebody to look at it, ok?
We'll go to the
emergency room.
- Five stitches.
- Is he okay?
- Yeah, he's doing fine.
- He's not crying?
- Can I see my son now, please?
- I need your insurance information.
I'll do this.
He's in 152.
- I don't see any broken bones.
- 'Cause you don't have any.
And I'm very proud of you.
You were awfully brave today.
It didn't hurt that bad.
Besides, it'll be pretty cool
to show my friends.
Hey, would you
do me a favor?
Maybe. Depends
what it is.
Will you ask Dad to give me
a white dove for Christmas?
We'll see.
Come on!
Every magician
needs a white dove.
A real one. They do!
Well, you know, hat's
a long way off...
...and I think we should talk to
your mom and just see, okay?
Does it hurt again?
Lay back.
Take a deep breath.
Will you sing me a song?
My mom always sings
to me when I get hurt.
Hard to think of a
song on the spot.
If I needed you
Would you come to me
And ease my pain
If you needed me
I would come to you
I would swim the sea
For to ease your pain
- Feel better?
- Yeah.
A little bit?
It puts a girl
on the spot.
Hi. It's Jackie.
Look, I just got a call
from Random House...
...and they want
me to go meet...
END OF CD 1