TOEl COMPANY LTD
presents
SHIKENBARU SENTENCED
TO DEATH
He's a karate man from Okinawa.
He challenged a karate school
and killed seven men.
A bloodthirsty thug.
He refuses to talk to
any lawyer or chaplain.
Number 1820. Execution at 3:10pm.
Be ready.
No need to be ready.
Alright, you still have some time.
He is a very prominent priest
from the Buddhist League.
He travels to pray for men like you.
You have a brother and a sister.
You can leave a message, if any.
Get lost.
Alright, leave us alone.
Five minutes.
You're a karate man, eh?
What is your school?
I'm Shikenbaru, the last
genuine Okinawa karate fighter.
Karate nowadays is like a kid's game.
Originally, karate was to kill
or to be killed.
I wish I could live long enough
to fight someone like you.
There is time still.
THE STREETFIGHTER
Don't move.
I have given you delayed asphyxia.
What do you mean?
You belong to the Daigyoku School!
I belong to nothing.
You are beginning to go numb.
If you want to live to fight me,
keep hold of yourself
just for another ten minutes.
You can do it.
Come on.
Up on your feet.
Produced by Norimichi Matsudaira
Screenplay by Koji Takada
and Motohiro Torii
Starring
Shinichi Chiba
Yutaka Nakajima
Chizuko Kazama
Shiomi Etsuko
Goichi Yamada
Masashi Ishibashi
Ken Kazama
Rinichi Yamamoto
Tatsuo Endo
Bin Amatu
Fumio Watanabe
Masafumi Suzuki
(Japan Seibukan)
Directed by Shigehiro Ozawa
- Is it heart failure?
- He has still a feeble pulse.
We can save him.
Warden?
What is your advice, Counsellor?
I've never had such a case.
Suspend the execution
and take him to the hospital.
Code 43.
An ill prisoner shall be
temporarily hospitalised.
Get out of the way.
Hey, it's dangerous.
Move!
Excuse me...
Run!
Come with me.
We made it, partner.
We made it.
Get in.
FUKUOKA 88
TA 73-53
TOKYO
The police have not traced...
...the abducted prisoner in Fukuok a.
Despite all the police efforts.
It still remains a mystery
if it w as a calculated crime.
Stupid police.
It happened right on this road.
But the witnesses differ.
Which suggests that
there were plural abductors.
The date of ex ecution w as
not publicised.
Even if the abductors had known it
they couldn't have predicted
the prisoner being hospitalised.
Carbonised chicken for lunch,
partner!
Can't I have a proper food for once?
How dare you complain?
You would have starved without me.
I even wash your underwear for you,
don't I?
The oil tycoon Hammett is dead.
He w as the president of Berunera.
The world's third biggest
oil company.
He w as also pro-Japanese.
This will be an unfathomable loss
for Japan.
His daughter is
the only heiress
to his billion-dollar legacy.
Miss Sarai Hammett is currently
studying in Japan.
Next news...
The mission is completed.
Where is my brother?
Is he alive?
Let us talk to him.
Oh, it's impossible.
How can a runaway prisoner
stay in Japan?
Where is he, then?
On his way to Hong Kong.
Pay me the rest, three million.
Not till I see him.
Please!
Stop!
We have no money.
The advance was all we could raise.
Please give us some more time.
I need some collateral.
You'll sell.
How dare you!
Give me a break.
We had to save our brother.
You make me sick.
I hate a man
who doesn't keep his promises.
Is that karate?
Is that not enough?
Give up. You'll never beat me.
Brother!
SEIBUKAN KARATE SCHOOL
Hikodachi front punch. Start!
Front block!
Start!
Master, Miss Sarai Hammett is here.
Uncle.
Sarai,
there's a bad news.
Your father died
the day before yesterday.
Oh, no!
He wrote to me
only a few days ago.
Poor Father.
Fly home immediately, Sarai.
I'll arrange the flight.
No, she'd better wait.
Uncle?
Mr Jadot will come
to take you home.
Sarai.
We talked to Mr Jadot over the phone.
Your father had a stroke.
Now listen.
You are his only beneficiary.
You are responsible for the third
largest oil company in the world.
The vultures will
inevitably start to circle.
MUTAGUCHI ENTERPRISES
Tsurugi, you are
the meanest guy I ever met.
Trading, eh?
But don't go too far.
A nice girl, though.
Alright.
Three million yen, as requested.
Stop!
I'll take care of her.
In fact, I've been trying
to reach you.
You kidnapped that prisoner,
didn't you?
Let's talk business.
Sure, let's talk over dinner.
No need for haste.
There are people
I want to introduce to you.
Meet Miss Yang and Mr Liang
from Hong Kong.
Mr Tsurugi.
I've heard quite a bit about you.
The man who makes
the impossible possible.
Skip the flattery.
Let's talk business.
Kidnap her.
Although she is well protected.
By Kendo Masaoka,
the Master of Seibukan.
This is the right job for you,
isn't it?
The fellow karate man.
Five million yen.
50 million. 20 million in advance.
Come on, that's unreasonable.
It's very reasonable.
Especially with Masaoka.
50 million cash on delivery.
No advance.
- We don't trust you that far.
- I see.
I don't trust you, either.
No trust, no business.
Good day.
Wait.
We confided in you.
You can't go just like that.
I see. The Goryu Kai!
The Hong Kong-based
assassination company.
A Mafia subsidiary outfit.
So you belong to them, too,
Mutaguchi.
But don't worry.
There's an evil code of conduct.
I have a very tight mouth.
No, Mutaguchi!
You don't know how dangerous
he can be.
Especially when you are exposed.
But not here. Liang!
You get him.
Faster, partner.
Your legs.
Higher.
Lighter.
Are you alright?
Partner!
I know too much to live, huh?
How dirty the Mafia are.
The Mafia!
It's getting fun.
Now I know what I'm going to do.
Tell your boss
that I'm her enemy now.
Liang.
How could you take
that sort of insult from him?
Why didn't you kill Tsurugi?
I tried.
But he was too good for me.
Forgive me.
No, I can't.
The Goryu Kai has never let
its clients down, you know.
Did you come all the way to Japan
to ruin that reputation?
Forgive me.
Suicide or execution.
Mutaguchi.
Tsurugi is our enemy now.
Let's ask the Hong Kong
headquarters for a better assassin.
Wait.
Kendo Masaoka is
the best karate man in Japan.
I'm worried.
Who are you?
You're better looking in person.
Let her go. What do you want?
I'm Tsuchida,
assistant to the master.
Bring your boss.
Uncle.
So you are Kendo Masaoka.
I'm Takuma Tsurugi.
I want a bout with you.
I know how inefficient
your karate dojo is.
Let me prove it.
If you refuse...
...I'll kill her.
Follow me.
Are you OK?
How unfair.
I'm Kanzengaku.
I'll get you...
That's it.
Now you fight me, Master Masaoka.
Wait.
Come.
Partner! Partner!
You said your name
was Takuma Tsurugi?
I used to know a karate man,
Reizan Tsurugi, in China.
He aimed at fusing
Japanese karate and Chinese boxing.
Is he your father by any chance?
Wait, Soldier!
Soldier, please!
Listen to me!
- Shut up!
- Daddy isn't a spy.
Let him go. Please.
Brat!
You are the son of a dirty traitor!
Get lost.
Daddy! Daddy...
Takuma.
Don't trust anybody.
You can only count on yourself.
Train yourself. Body and mind.
Be stronger than anybody else.
Don't let anybody
get the better of you.
That's enough.
Alright, I got your point.
You did? Fine.
Well then, I want you to hire me.
Somebody has hired the Goryu Kai
to work with the Mafia...
...to take over
Miss Hammett's fortune.
Anybody can escort her home.
But your job will be completed
only when you
get rid of the villains, right?
That's right.
I decided that
I was the man for the job.
That's why I'm here.
Sure, we need as many good men
as we can get.
Wait. If this is all for my sake,
forget it.
I'd rather die than
to be protected by this animal.
He makes me sick.
Master Masaoka, what's your decision?
I may in fact be worse
than the villains.
But I know the way
they think and act.
There is only one question.
What is it?
I feel some blazing anger
in your karate.
Is it your father's
unfulfilled ambition
which lies deep in your mind?
I hope it is.
Because you've got what it takes.
Bollocks. My father was one man,
I'm another.
What's your answer?
Am I hired or not?
OK. I trust you.
Not only as a fighter, but as a man.
OK. I accept the job.
Hong Kong
Takuma Tsurugi, eh?
A cheap Japanese fighter.
How could you, the Goryu Kai,
stand for that?
He seems to be tough.
Even Miss Yang is having
a hard time with him.
Dingsau, I need some of your men,
as usual.
OK.
Just a minute. Mr King...
Your client must be big this time.
You'll be paid enough.
I may go to Japan myself.
It's so rare to hear you
do it yourself!
The Tsurugi boy.
I'd like to see him die
with my own eyes.
Hello, boss.
- What happened?
- He ran away.
Endoshi, what did you do?
I killed a guy
who spoke ill of the boss.
Moroko, have you seen Endoshi?
Where has he gone?
Hey, you.
Your name and nationality,
Chinese or Japanese?
He's been hanging around
for some time.
His nationality is unknown.
Suspicious. Arrest him.
Stop!
Dingsau,
who is this weirdo?
One of your men?
Officer, just leave the man alone,
will you?
Dingsau, recently,
you haven't been paying
much respect to the law.
Now look, Officer.
I am the law in Kowloon.
Remember that.
A new arrival.
Take any one you like.
Nachi!
Brother...
How in the world...
What happened to you?
So you are alive.
Gijun didn't die in vain, after all.
You mean he died?
Takuma Tsurugi killed him.
What?
Brother.
I don't give a damn about myself.
But we have a score to settle.
Avenge Gijun for me.
So you are brother and sister.
Also Tsurugi...
How strange fate is.
Let me redeem my sister, boss.
Do you have money?
Give me a job. Any job.
Can you beat Takuma Tsurugi?
If you kill him, she is yours.
Come to Japan with me.
I promise I will.
I will surely kill Takuma Tsurugi.
Oh, karate. I know karate very well.
I'm sorry, Sarai,
I couldn't come sooner.
Vice-president Jadot
feels very sorry for you.
I thought he'd come, Mr Bayan.
He is a very busy man, you know.
He will come to see you in Hong Kong.
I know it's sudden, but
we'll fly to Hong Kong tonight.
These two men will accompany her.
Would that be OK?
That isn't necessary.
It is Master Masaoka's responsibility
to protect her.
Until she leaves Japan.
Don't worry.
They are her good friends,
both of them.
Goodbye, Uncle.
Please.
Thank you.
Partner, are we following her home?
Of course.
But protection isn't our only job.
I'm also after her money.
We're going.
Why did he stop?
We can't get out!
We've taken off!
Help!
Rakuda! Hang on!
Are you alright, Rakuda?
I think so.
But they went too far this time.
Shit!
Partner... where are we going?
To the Mutaguchis.
Partner, the Mafia is too much
for the two of us.
Coward.
Partner, we don't know
what comes next.
- Are you scared?
- I am.
What are you doing?
Wait for me in the car.
Keep the engine running.
OK.
Shikenbaru!
What are you doing here?
I've been waiting for you.
I'll kill you this time.
I've got something going on.
I don't have time for you.
Are you afraid?
Tsurugi, I know
who you're looking for.
The girl isn't here.
What?
They took her to
Mutaguchi's villa in Izu.
If you want to rescue her,
go over my dead body.
No use trying to use her for cover.
She isn't afraid to die to kill you,
believe me.
Let's go.
Here we are.
We had to make the detour for you
to see somebody.
See him quickly.
We have to catch the plane.
We aren't leaving tonight.
What?
So you lied to us.
Sorry, we had our reasons.
To be frank, we don't want you
foreigners to be meddling.
Mr Bayan, what are you saying?
These gentlemen are my friends.
Oh, yeah?
To me they seem to be a part of
a rotten scheme.
I don't believe them,
the people of this country.
Mr Bayan!
Kendo Masaoka is no exception.
He's after you for your money.
Damn you!
Let's go, Kan!
A blind man?
Kan! Onaga!
Kan! No!
Onaga!
MUTAGUCHI VILLAGE
Get off! No!
Get your hands off me!
No! Stop! No!
He frightened me.
They are trying to kill you
with me as a decoy.
Bayan is a traitor.
Mr Jadot might be dead by now.
Oh, Tsurugi, I don't know what to do.
Help me, please.
It'll be OK. You can count on me.
But the odds are against us.
Stop acting like a lady
and follow me. Understand?
It's OK. I've got you.
Partner! Quick!
This way!
Get on the boat!
Wait for me downstream.
- Don't let anything happen to her.
- OK.
Takuma Tsurugi!
You are good.
I'm Kowloon Dingsau.
Which means
'the cutthroat of Kowloon'.
But I won't use my sword with you.
Everybody stay back.
He helped the girl to escape.
We must make him tell where she is.
Please, we can't afford
to have him killed yet.
Alright.
Hands up.
Walk.
What's happened to Tsurugi?
I'm worried.
Miss, you stay here.
I'll go take a look.
Talk.
Tell us.
Where is Sarai?
Damn you...
How can you be so stupid?
What's the good of helping
such a baby?
You'll gain a lot
from co-operating with us.
Why the haste to die
at your age, anyway?
Partner!
That guy took the girl away.
Leave him alone!
Put that away.
What are you going to do?
Two more bullets.
If you want to save him,
tell me where Sarai is.
Stop!
Come on.
Please!
Kill me instead of him.
Next...
No, no! I'll tell you!
Rakuda, don't!
Partner...
We can't give up our task.
We've got to save Sarai!
Partner...
But, even if you say so...
Stop!
I'll talk.
She's waiting down the river.
Go!
Partner...
Wait!
Dingsau, you always
have to get involved.
We can't let him live.
Let me do it.
Partner!
He's alive!
Partner! Partner!
Can you get up?
There are many spas around here,
partner.
I'll take you to one. Come on.
Hold on to my shoulder. Come.
You go back to Tokyo... alone.
What are you saying, all of a sudden?
Are you a man or a mouse?
I'll never team up with you again.
But, remember...
they could have killed you.
Do you think I would die so easily?
Why did you disobey me?
Please,
I'll never be a coward again.
If I'm not your partner any more,
let me be your slave.
Ever since you rescued me
in Singapore,
I've belonged to you.
Don't leave me.
Partner!
Rakuda...
I don't think you are fit
for this kind of job.
You'd better save money
and live long.
Partner...
KOBE
Wait!
Try to escape and I'll kill you.
Rakuda...
Partner...
Don't... give up on me.
I...
...may be as cowardly as a mouse.
I keep making mistakes.
Forgive me.
Thank you.
PRINCESS S ARAI (BERUNERA OIL)
Mr Jadot!
How nice to see you safe!
Read that.
"I, Sarai Hammett,
renounce every right to
"Berunera Oil Company and...
"...transfer it to Abdul Jadot."
Get the idea, miss?
Berunera Oil Company will be
owned by Mr Jadot and
the Goryu Kai, Hong Kong.
Sign it, please.
The man who had me kidnapped
and who killed my friends...
You left one out.
The man who also sent
your old man to Heaven...
that was me.
Alright, young lady, sign it.
No! Never!
Dingsau, Tsurugi is still alive.
He followed me.
Moroko got into a fight with him,
but I'm not sure...
Shikenbaru.
I was just thinking of
my eventual successor.
A strong man like Tsurugi.
But if you get him, I'll give you
the Kowloon territory.
Have a good fight.
Lady, you'd better sign it.
Kill me.
If you want my money so badly,
just kill me and take it.
- He's here! Tsurugi!
- What?
Tsurugi!
- Tsurugi!
- Finally.
Tsurugi!
- Wait!
- What now, Dingsau?
I have a suggestion.
Tsurugi and Shikenbaru
are old enemies.
Let them fight.
We don't have time for it.
If he loses,
I'll fight Tsurugi myself.
Tsurugi.
How about that? OK?
OK.
If I win, will you give up Sarai?
Yes, I will.
Are you ready, Shikenbaru?
Tsurugi!
You played dirty!
Nachi!
Brother!
Stab us!
Together!
Tsurugi! Come on!
Tsurugi!
THE END