I just love mushrooms.
One of my favorites,
or as I call it...
...the king of mushrooms,
is the porcini.
Now, stop right there.
Don't be alarmed.
There's a lot of confusion
in this country between porcini...
...the Italian name, and cèpes,
which is the French name.
They're fat and they're earthy.
Now, the porcini is most often seen
dried here in this country.
And they would always be labeled...
...dried porcinis, not dried cèpes.
- Beck!
- Come on!
- They are very, very, very flavorful.
It's about time.
I've been waiting.
Man, you're lucky to be getting in.
It's an extremely private party tonight.
- What's he drinking?
- Jagermeister and Cristal.
Great.
- Security?
- No, but we do have a slight problem.
Have fun.
What's the problem?
That's your problem.
The guy on the left
is Jalil Johnson.
- I think he's the left tackle.
- Jamal Johnson.
Defensive end.
The best defensive lineman Notre
Dame's produced in the last 20 years.
Maybe ever.
The guy on his left
is kambui Jackson.
He ran for 2000 yards last year,
All- Pro five years in a row.
The guy in the headband,
that's Fernando Lewis.
Middle linebacker.
Plays a lot like Ray Lewis.
- He just hits harder.
- Whatever. I'm not into football.
The other two guys
are Jimmy Coggeshell...
...and David Mulaire.
One's from US C.
The other one's from Ohio State.
Stay down, bitch!
The guy you're looking for is there.
Brian knappmiller.
Throws like Brett Favre.
Bets like Pete Rose.
So I'm telling this cat, I'm like,
"Yo, I know it's you that jumped.
I saw you.
Don't tell me it's not you."
He's like, "I don't know."
- Excuse me.
- "Trust me. It's you, I know."
Excuse me.
I'm sorry to bother you guys.
- I apologize. I need- -
- My man.
I ain't got no hookups to tryout
camps. You just gotta show up.
I think you'll be all right.
So I'm telling the cat,
"I don't want- -"
Excuse me. I'm not here
to talk about tryouts.
- If I could have a minute- -
- I got it. Pass me that.
Who do I make this out to, man?
Who do I make it out to?
What's your name?
- Beck.
- Beck?
B- E- C- k.
- What's up?
- What's happening?
Here you go.
Knock yourself out.
- All right?
- Thank you.
What are you gonna do?
Are you gonna come back, or what?
Excuse me.
- I'm really- -
- What are you doing, man?
A couple of months ago, you made
wagers with an associate of mine.
- Two, three months ago.
- What's up, knappy?
- Nothing. It's good. Enjoy your drink.
- What's up?
Yo, bets? You embarrass me
in front of friends about bets?
I don't mean to embarrass you.
This is embarrassing to me.
- $50,000. You might remember.
- Yeah, I know what it is, man.
Listen, there's a G to get me started.
Now do me a favor.
Tell your man I'll see him Monday
with the rest...
...and not to send anybody else
to see me, all right?
Brian.
I'm gonna need some collateral
from you.
What?
I'm gonna need the ring.
- I'm sorry.
- You're- -? Are you- -?
Slip it under the table,
on the low- low.
- I'll make sure you get it back.
- On the low- low.
- I'll give it to you. Want a drink too?
- Thank you.
Take the ring.
That's what I think about that.
Get the hell on, man.
Go, man! Go!
- Do something with this.
- You heard the man.
Yo, man, get up!
Okay.
Yeah, that's right, playboy, walk.
Go on, man!
You wanna jump?
Get your ass out of here.
You all right?
This shit burns.
Hey, it's me.
Oh, yeah, he's here.
We got a problem, though.
He's got the entire offensive line.
The entire offensive line is here.
Let me do it another night.
How about that?
They've got a shot
at repeating this year.
I do not want to hurt them.
I don't want to go out- -
Okay, Billy.
Knappmiller!
You got two choices.
Option A, you give me the ring.
Option B,
I make you give me the ring.
I'll take B.
Wrong choice.
Okay.
Yeah, put him down, man!
- Yo, what's with all this hostility?
- You should have taken option A.
Are you all right, mate?
Are you okay?
Thanks, mate.
- There he is.
- Why'd you send him, Billy?
Martin? Oh, he was just a backup.
After I got your call,
I wasn't so sure you could deliver.
- What happened?
- He stole it from me!
He got you
with those beanbags? No.
It is gonna be 10 off your vig,
anyway, you know.
Billy, you know I've got plans!
Stop nickel- and- diming me.
It's a tough business,
the restaurant business.
I hear 75 percent of them fail
the first year. Do you know why?
Undercapitalization, that's why.
I don't think- -
Billy, I want out, I want a new life.
I want my money, and I want it now!
Now?
Now.
Okay.
One job.
One job, I wipe your slate clean...
...and you have your restaurant.
Come on, open it up.
Come on.
That's a photo
of Travis Alfred Walker.
Stanford dropout, treasure hunter.
Only to date...
...the only thing he's found
is trouble.
- Did you say, "Walker"?
- My son.
From my third marriage.
Lasted about three minutes.
That picture was taken
two months ago...
...in some gold- mining town called El
Dorado in the middle of the Amazon.
- How much?
- 250 large.
For that much,
why not invite him back yourself?
- The boy doesn't trust me.
- Kidnapping's gonna help.
Is that sarcasm?
You wanna be sarcastic,
do it to your monkey friends!
You do not do it to me!
Do you understand?
I'm sorry, Billy.
You're goddamn right you are.
- What'd he do?
- Pissed off the wrong people.
I don't have to remind you
what happens when you do that, do I?
So I bought him some forgiveness.
But if I don't bring him back
to face the music...
...you know damn well
that I can't carry a tune.
So you deliver my boy back here,
you bring him right through that door...
...you walk out of this house
a free man, with a restaurant.
Is that duct tape?
Don't worry there, little fella.
Walk by faith, not by sight.
Will you look at that?
We can't land now.
- Why? Why can't we land?
- They got the bulls on the ground.
"Booze on the grind"?
The bulls. On the ground.
Cattle down there.
- Cows?
- Yeah.
I'll give them a wee fright there.
Get moving! Come on!
Out of me way!
Out the way, you!
Move it! Move it now!
Out my way!
Out me way!
All right there, little fella.
Okay, gotcha.
What did I tell you about the lamp?
My needle was totally knackered.
Rpm's all over the shop.
- Is this the only road in and out?
- If you wanna stay alive.
- Why is that?
- There. That's the jungle, little fella.
You got anacondas in there.
Poison arrow frogs, black flies,
bullet ants.
If they don't get you,
the rebels will.
- What?
- Rebels. That's what I'm telling you.
To them, Cornelius Hatcher's
built a Babylon in paradise.
- Built a what?
- A Babylon.
Yeah, that mine is as close as a man
can come to the gates of hell...
...while his heart's still beating.
The Sunday school picnic is over,
I'll tell you that.
Stay out of the jungle,
little fella, okay?
I found these flowers growing
in the deepest parts of the jungle.
I mean, as far as I can tell,
no one's ever identified them...
...which means I'm responsible
for naming them.
I can only think of one word
that fits something so beautiful.
Mariana.
How much do you want?
- What?
- How much?
I need your uncle's boat.
A day or two, max. Mariana- -
You borrow my car,
bring it back with no windshield.
- My brother's scooter- -
- That wasn't my fault.
Now you want to borrow
my uncle's boat?
"I found it, I found it." You'll never
find this Garbo of yours.
- It's "Gato," I told you.
- Gato.
It's out there, Mariana.
I know exactly where it is.
But I need that boat.
- How much?
- I told you, l- -
No. How much is your Gato worth?
This is a very significant
academic find.
- How much?
- It's not about money.
- You lie like a little girl, Travis.
- I'm not lying.
If I get the boat for you,
you have to take me with you.
Ridiculous.
We're talking about a boat.
- And we split the take 50- 50.
- I've been doing all the work, okay?
- I found it. No way.
- 50- 50, Travis.
- 70- 30.
- 50- 50.
- 60- 40.
- 50- 50, and I get off work at 6.
Then we can go and get your Gato.
You're evil.
- Thank you.
- Whatever.
For the flowers.
Harvey! We're here
to see your brother.
Where's he from?
- He's an American.
- You got a gun?
No, I don't like guns.
Check him.
- What's the current payout?
- Give me a payout for Quadrant 3.
2425, down 20 percent.
Checked him?
All right, let's go.
Come on.
I never met an American
who didn't like guns.
Tell them to dig harder.
If only it were that simple,
eh, Mr. Beck?
- How do you know my name?
- When a man of your dimensions...
...travels all this way
to visit a place like this...
...it arouses the curiosity.
What can I do for you?
Do you know this man?
Travis Walker.
I let him excavate
around the mine...
...allow him to rent a room
in my town...
...all for a fair 60 percent
of anything he might unearth.
- Where can I find him?
- Follow the bullshit.
- Guy's mouth should be in the circus.
- Brother, please.
- Do you have business with him?
- I do.
What kind of business?
I love business.
- It's personal.
- So...
...why come to me?
- When I'm a guest in a man's house...
...I don't reach into his refrigerator
without permission.
Refrigerator.
I want to show you something,
Mr. Beck, please.
Does that look like
a refrigerator to you?
Looks more like hell.
Where you see hell, I see
a spellbinding sense of purpose.
I see the value of keeping your eye
on the ball.
When a bride slips the ring
on her finger...
...when a businessman lays his hands
on a Rolex...
...when a rapper gets a shiny new
tooth, this is that cost, Mr. Beck.
My horror for their beauty.
My hell for their little slice of heaven.
Somebody's gotta keep his eye
on the ball.
That somebody is me, Mr. Beck.
I am down here every day
keeping my eye on the ball.
That's just a simple fact of life.
And if you're bold enough
to face that cold, hard fact...
...you can make a lot of money.
- What do you want with the kid?
- I've come to take him home.
That'll cost you $ 10,000.
- I need to borrow the jeep.
- Wait a minute, friend.
I'll give you $ 1000.
I need you to take my bag back to
the plane, keep the engine running.
- Can you do that?
- For $ 1000?
- That's right.
- I'll find a way.
Declan. I'm gonna be coming fast.
American?
Yeah.
Where from?
Someplace that's got bartenders.
What can I get you?
I'll take a beer.
Nice flowers.
"The smiling fool."
Back in the States, Brazil nuts
like these go for $ 15 a pound.
Well, those fell off the tree
out back.
And around here,
we don't call them Brazil nuts.
- What do you call them?
- Well, we're in Brazil...
...so we just call them nuts.
- Fair enough.
- What brings you to the Amazon...
...other than the food and drink,
of course?
- I'm looking for a man.
- What's your type?
His name's Travis Walker.
Brown hair. He's in his 20s.
Wears a blue shirt, jeans.
Right now he's got a real
bewildered look on his face.
- Do I know you?
- Name's Beck.
- What can I do for you?
- I need you to make a choice for me.
A choice?
- Option A or option B.
- What's option A?
Option A is, you and I
walk out of here nice and easy...
...and drive back to the airstrip.
And then we begin our long journey
back to Los Angeles.
There'll be no blood,
no broken bones...
...and no problems.
- What's in Los Angeles?
- Your father.
- What's option B?
- Pretty much the opposite of A.
But I wouldn't recommend that one.
I'll take option C.
Travis, there is no option C.
Really?
Are you sure?
I mean, big boy,
there's always an option C.
So angry!
- Shut up.
- Shut up!
Like I said,
there is no option C.
- Let me introduce you to option C.
- Mr. Beck...
...there's been a slight change
in the narrative.
- An unexpected twist, you might say.
- Can I have a beer, please?
Mr. Hatcher, I was just gonna
come find you when this- -
The kid stays.
- I paid you.
- Well, fortunately...
...I had my fingers crossed
the whole time.
Apparently, young Mr. Walker...
...may have stumbled
onto a trinket of value.
And as he's located it
in my jungle...
...I'm gonna need him
to lead me to it.
Okay, so let's go, dickhead.
Don't call me a dickhead,
you dickhead.
- Did you find it or not, asshole?
- What, asshole?
- Did you find it or not?
- What's that?
- Did you find it or not, asshole?
- Don't!
Hey, don't rock the boat.
Okay.
- I don't want any trouble.
- Leave now. Don't come back.
- And the 10,000?
- Consider it tax deductible.
A contribution
to your personal health fund.
With all due respect, Mr. Hatcher...
...I'm feeling pretty healthy.
- Oh, yeah?
Walk.
Don't make waves.
You're gonna kill us all, Mr. Beck?
I tried to be reasonable.
That's not the way to do business.
You should've kept the gun.
You're dead already.
You just don't know it yet.
This is option B?
Are you kidding me?
Quiet.
You're dead. You're so dead.
We won't get out of here.
All this land, Hatcher owns it.
The road, the air,
Hatcher owns it all.
- Shut up.
- Whatever my dad is paying you...
...I will double it.
- No.
- I'll quadruple it.
- Double it and quadruple it.
- No.
You're being unreasonable!
- I'll give you a chance to reconsider.
- You get one more chance to shut up.
Is that your final answer?
For what it's worth,
I hope you enjoy the fall.
- Yeah, what fall?
- This fall.
Come on, big boy,
where's the frigging keys?
All right.
Travis?
Good God!
Travis!
- I'm not going back.
- Oh, you're going back.
No way.
- Right now.
- Who the hell do you think you are?
You come into my town,
mess up my bar...
...and you eyeball my woman?
- Eyeball your woman?
It's on.
What's this?
Who is this? Is he your friend?
Do you know him?
Do you? Say hello.
Say hello. Say hello.
Are you finished?
Let's go.
Big boy, you like thunderstorms?
Bet you do, right?
- Little thunder?
- Stop it.
- Little lightning?
- Stop!
Thunder? Lightning?
Thunder? Lightning? Ears- -
You done beating me up?
Let's go.
- I'm tired of this.
- You win.
Come on! Go to sleep.
Go to sleep. Night- night.
Night- night. Go to sleep now!
Come on!
Obviously, we got off
on the wrong foot here.
So I'm gonna be completely
candid with you.
Have you ever heard
of the Gato do Diabo?
- The Devil's Cat?
- You're gonna stop speaking now.
All right. It's- -
It's a priceless object, man.
Forged out of pure gold.
- Worth millions.
- You said priceless.
You do not want to argue semantics
with a Ph.D. Candidate.
- Ph.D.?
- Yeah.
I am really very close
to being Dr. Travis Walker.
You dropped out of Stanford
after two semesters, Einstein.
So I'm fairly close.
Closer than you.
Close to getting your ass
kicked again.
Wait, wait, wait!
The Gato is real, all right?
I know where to find it.
- I'll split it with you, 80- 20.
- Move!
70- 30?
You're a very unpleasant individual,
you know that?
You think they're dead?
What am I, psychic?
I'm gonna cut that kid's nose off.
No, Harvey.
You want the Gato
because if the bad guys get it...
...they won't need us anymore.
There'll be no one to work the mine.
You want to work the mine?
There are two men in that jungle
who are trying to steal from me.
I feel like a little boy
who's lost his first tooth...
...put it under his pillow,
waiting for the tooth fairy to come.
Only, two evil burglars
have crept in my window...
...and snatched it
before she could get here.
Wait a second. Do you understand
the concept of the tooth fairy?
Explain it to them.
You find a tooth,
you put it under your pillow.
The fairy comes...
...waiting for the tooth.
Wait. She takes the goddamn thing,
gives you a quarter!
They got my tooth!
I want it back.
I have to ask you,
back at the bar, man. That was crazy!
No guns. Strip, toss, toss, strip.
- Didn't I tell you to be quiet?
- I know, but what is that?
Some kind of nouveau samurai code?
You got a problem with guns?
They take me to a place
I don't wanna go.
Where do they take you?
To a place you
don't wanna see me go. Walk!
How often do you work out?
Let me get this straight.
- You never use guns?
- No.
- Never?
- Never.
What if your best friend
was gonna die?
No guns.
Santa would do it
to save his best friend.
Do I look like Santa Claus?
- Do I look like Santa Claus to you?
- What is it?
Guns make you um pouco louco?
Bang- bang crazy?
I pick up guns, bad things happen.
I don't like that.
- What kind of things?
- Very bad things, Travis. Walk.
- What about knives?
- Move!
My father doesn't share
the same distaste.
- He's your father. He won't kill you.
- All he cares about...
...is what's good for business.
Now, the question is, Mr. Beck...
...what's good for your business?
You don't like money?
I don't make deals
with people like you.
- You don't even know me.
- You're like every jackass I take down.
First they try to run, then fight,
then they try to negotiate.
When that fails, they do what you're
about to do when you realize it's over.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
You're gonna get down on your hands
and knees and beg me for a break.
Well, guess what.
I don't give breaks.
No breaks.
You don't understand the situation.
You borrowed money
from the wrong guy.
You slept with the wrong guy's wife.
I don't care.
Your mistake.
What about you, Mr. Beck?
Haven't you ever made a mistake?
I know! Move.
No breaks. That's lame.
No breaks!
No, I don't give breaks.
Santa Claus doesn't give
any breaks.
- Should've been at the airstrip by now.
- Like I'm gonna help.
I didn't ask for your help.
- What are you doing?
- I have to pee.
- Pee in your pants. Move.
- No.
I've let you push me around
this jungle for, like, five hours.
You've been very aggressive, and I'm
not moving until you let me pee.
If you wanna keep going, you'll have
to carry me. I'll pee on your head.
You threatening me?
You threatening me with pee?
Well, yeah,
if you don't let me pee here.
Fine. You win.
Pee.
- Will you unzip me?
- No, I won't.
- You wanna pee, you got 30 seconds.
- How can with I my hands cuffed?
Find a way. Pee.
Come on.
Don't make it weird.
Please?
Don't breathe, don't say a word.
Don't even look at me.
Look over there.
Thanks, man.
Oh, shit.
I can't get it out!
- Could you just help- -?
- No. Hell, no.
Come on! Son of a- -!
Come on, come on!
Come on! Oh, hey. Hey, I got it.
Congratulations.
You got 30 seconds. Hurry up.
Don't listen to Tiny Tim, okay?
You're the real big boy.
Everybody knows it.
Ready? One, two, three, go.
One, two, three, go, go, go, go!
Oh, yeah.
I'm going.
Oh, boy.
What- -? What is this?
What is- -?
Travis! Hey!
Welcome to the jungle, tough guy!
Looks like big boy
got himself pig- snared!
Hey! Hey!
I've got the keys to your cuffs.
- Shit.
- I'll tell you what you've got, pal.
- You've got problems.
- That's- - Don't do it, Travis.
Hey. Hey, get me down. Travis.
Oh, what's this? Is this your diary?
Your little journal?
- Give me that. Don't touch that.
- You want this? Get it!
Come on, get it! Get it! Come on!
Come on! Yeah, yeah!
Oh, yeah, come on! Get it!
Get it!
Give it to me!
You're like a little birdie up there!
I will kill you.
You better give me that book.
"Shrimp and pea risotto
with basil and mint."
- Are you a chef?
- None of your business. Give it back!
Looks like you're
Wolfgang Stuck right here.
Travis! Travis!
- Hey! I let you pee.
- Oh, yeah, you did. You did.
Thank you so much.
Do you have to pee?
Well, you got 30 seconds.
Go ahead and pee.
Oh, shit.
- Hey, I was kidding about what I said.
- Give me the book.
- I don't want it. I don't want it.
- Turn around.
- Why you always gotta hit me?
- Now listen to me.
We gotta get to this tree.
Let's go back to back.
All right. Okay.
- Kick your legs!
- I'm trying! I'm kicking my legs!
- Where are you?
- Grab me. Grab my back, not my ass.
- Got it?
- I got it. Got it.
Oh, great! You did it!
- Now what?
- Put your arm over me. Get to the tree.
- Listen.
- You're like Joe Pig- snare?
Put your arm over me!
- Just stop moving!
- The vine. You gotta grab the- -
What was that?
- Oh, shit.
- What was that?
Monkeys.
Steady.
Steady!
Oh, God!
Do not fight them!
Oh, my God!
- What's he doing? What's he doing?
- He's humping you, he's humping you!
- What's he doing?
- Establish dominance!
Establish dominance!
Get him off of me!
He's humping me!
Make him stop!
The ears! Get the ears.
- Who's that?
- It's the rebels.
Don't worry, they're my friends.
God bless you!
Say hi.
Hi.
These are your friends, huh?
What, are you kidding me?
I'm starting to long for a monkey
with a hard- on.
Whatever happens,
just keep looking into his eyes.
- Won't that offend him?
- No.
Whatever you do, do not blink.
They're like grizzlies.
Just shut up
and let me take care of this.
We know you work for Hatcher.
Were you tracking us?!
- He thinks we work for Hatcher.
- Well, tell him the truth.
Fierce gaze. Fierce gaze.
Fierce gaze.
Honorable host, unlike this man on my
left, I do not work for that evil scum.
Why does the giant stare at me without
respect? I will cut out his arrogant eyes!
- What's he saying?
- Shut up. Just hold his gaze.
He is Hatcher's assassin. Paid to hunt
all who oppose him, including me.
Why do I get the feeling
you really suck at Portuguese?
What did he say?!
He says he pisses on your ancestors...
...and that you would make
a very pretty bride!
- What's going on?
- He wants to fight you.
No. We're not fighting.
Tell him I don't want to fight.
The assassin is a great warrior! Better
to shoot him now and get it over with!
- We are not fighting.
- Don't worry, they're little people.
- What?
- You could take them. They're little.
You can win.
Why do you want to fight? Why?
I just want to get back to the airport.
Please. I just have to get home.
Okay, hip- hop.
I don't want to do this.
Please. Please.
Travis, tell them one more time
I do not want to fight.
I'd love to help you out,
buddy, but I don't think...
...they're really listening
to me anymore.
Heads up.
That's okay! That is okay!
Hey, kansas Cities!
Don't do it.
What is that?
It's like spinning Tarzan jujitsu!
Speedy little bastards, aren't they?
Head's gotta stay up.
I am not your enemy.
Mariana?
What are you doing here?
Barmaid by day,
rebel leader by night.
You are good! The whole time I was
working you, you were working me.
I was hoping you might find
O Gato do Diabo.
It couldn't have all been work.
Could it?
Man, that was some good work.
What do you think, Travis?
I knew. You know that, right?
I totally knew.
Of course.
Hey.
The herbs will keep it
from getting infected.
- Why do you do this?
- Pardon me?
- Why do you fight?
- Because of 65 cents an hour.
That's what Hatcher
pays the workers.
But in order to mine,
you need tools.
You need food, clothing,
a place to sleep.
You have no money,
so, what do you do?
You borrow from Hatcher.
Pick and shovel, a dollar a day.
A sack to haul the dirt,
another dollar.
Old Mr. Beck knows a lot
about debt, don't you?
He knows what it's like to dig a hole
so deep you can't climb out.
Call it what you want.
It's escravidão.
"Slavery."
And we intend to stop it.
Manito wants to know who would win
a fight between Tyson and Ali.
Ali, hands down.
He says, "What about
Tyson's power?"
Shit. Tell him Ali
would've done to Tyson...
...what he did to Foreman in Africa.
Rumble. Rumble in the Jungle.
Tell him Ali was too smart.
Too smart, too fast.
Would've used his jabs. Bam, bam!
Would've danced.
Would've played with his mind.
Before you know it, bam! Left
to the body. Bam! Right to the head.
Down goes Tyson.
Float like butterfly.
Sting like bee.
Float like butterfly, sting like bee.
- Yeah!
- Float like butterfly, sting like a bee!
He says he thinks
you are a great fighter...
...and he wants you to have it.
- It's for luck.
- Tell him I'm sorry, I can't.
You'll offend him if you refuse.
I'm honored. Thank you.
You'll need all the luck you can get.
It's a long walk back to the airfield.
Especially by yourself.
Nice!
You don't understand.
- I'm not going back without him.
- Oh, here we go again.
Fifty rifles say you are.
And we're rebels, not thieves.
Hatcher!
Travis!
Let's clean it up.
Not so fast, jungle boy.
Move! Move!
Come on!
Manito!
Go, go, go!
- Manito!
- Let's go!
I want hunting parties.
Small ones.
Find them.
Find them!
All right, this is the way
it's going to be.
You're going to take me
to O Gato do Diabo.
- And you're going to take me now.
- Calm down.
Don't! You saw what they do.
Don't ever tell me to calm down.
Travis, don't play with me.
- Or what?
- Or I'm going to shoot you.
Well, if you shoot me,
you're never gonna find the Gato.
- So we're gonna make a little deal.
- Deal?
You see? O Gato is an object to you.
It's life on the Riviera, a private yacht.
- You don't know anything about me.
- For us it's hope.
My heart's breaking.
It's like a telethon.
- You selfish- -
- Enough!
Sit down! Sit down!
Holy shit, you tried to shoot me!
You saw it!
- Crazy.
- Shut up.
Shut up.
The deal's this.
He takes you to the Gato.
You just show me how I get out of this
jungle so I can take him home. Deal?
Do we have a deal?
- Deal.
- Let me get this straight.
She gets what she needs,
you get what you need...
...and I get the shaft.
- I could always give her back the gun.
- I really don't like you.
- Yeah, well, I get that a lot.
Seriously.
What?
I was just wondering
how it is you came to do...
...you know, whatever it is you do.
- It's a long story.
- It's a long walk.
I grew up in a very rough place.
One thing led to another, that's all.
- Just like you.
- Like me?
Yeah, you get pushed,
you push back.
Well, with me, I pushed so hard
that word got around.
Before I knew it, I was in a room
full of the wrong people...
...with the wrong money.
So you think I'm standing
in a room full of the wrong people?
Yeah. Something like that.
I like you, Mr. Beck.
Really.
But you and I are nothing alike.
Travis!
Let's keep moving. Let's go.
What are you doing?
Let's take us a little swim,
Wolfgang.
We're not swimming. Let's go.
Come on, big boy.
You could use a bath.
Travis, we have to keep moving.
It'll be dark soon.
Why?
We're already here.
- Don't pee in the water.
- Why?
A candiru, a vicious parasite,
will swim up the urine into your pau.
Come on, big boy! It feels good!
- Swim up my what?
- Your pinto.
It'll swim up your ding- dong. And once
it gets in, you can't get it out.
Come on!
Wait.
Well, then what?
They have to amputate.
Not this boy's pinto. Not today.
The hieroglyphic code...
...said the great chief of the Marajó
people put the Gato to sleep...
...behind walls of a moving curtain.
- A waterfall.
Must be some kind of
methane buildup.
It's cool. Let's go.
- Oh, God!
- Yeah, real genius.
- You have no clue what you're doing.
- Oh, shut up!
You obviously don't know
anything about methane deposits.
- Oh, and you do?
- Shut up.
What'd you just say?
What is it?
Why do I get the feeling
we are not supposed to be here?
Because we're not.
There it is! I told you it was real!
Travis, you're never gonna get
back there. It's too dangerous.
The roof is coming down!
Wait a second.
A jaguar.
I know what this is.
Monkey.
Eagle.
- I can't hold this, Travis.
- I know what this is.
- What is it?
- It's an 800- year- old safe.
This is how they kept
their treasures protected.
There's a combination.
Jaguar, cat. Gato, cat.
It's gotta be the jaguar.
We pull the sticks closest
to the jaguar, we'll be okay.
For 60 seconds,
then the roof's coming down.
You're not gonna touch anything.
Let's go!
All right.
Follow the jag.
Follow the jaguar.
Easy. Easy.
It's coming down, Travis.
What are you doing?
Let's go!
Pass it to me.
- Is that a jaguar?
- I think it's an eagle!
Travis, hurry!
Oh, my...
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
I did it.
I found you.
Not some Oxford archaeologist
or some stiff- ass Harvard professor.
- I did it! I found you!
- Who gives a shit?
How you like me now, huh, Beck?
Go! Go! Move! Now!
Run!
Let's go!
Move!
These are konlabos.
They're very rare.
You're lucky.
And I wouldn't flirt with O Gato
do Diabo's eyes if I were you.
- They say it's dangerous.
- What else do they say?
Once restored to its rightful owners,
the rivers will be laden with fish.
And the trees will grow tall,
bringing shade for hammocks...
...so its people may rest their backs.
You think bringing this Gato
will do all that?
No, Mr. Beck. But I expect the money
selling it brings will do just that.
We can buy seed, irrigate.
Farm our own lands.
Free ourselves from Hatcher's mine.
When that statue hits the black
market, it'll vanish forever.
It's a little late for morals.
Especially after you were going
to do the same thing.
And 10 percent of that is going
to pay for your freedom...
...so I'd be a little more grateful
if I were you.
What if I told you I was gonna
give it to a museum...
...so the whole world
could appreciate it?
You can tell me anything you want,
Travis, but I know you.
What are you going to do
after you bring him home?
- I'm gonna open a restaurant.
- Yeah. He's a killer in the kitchen too.
Ten, 15 tables. Nothing fancy.
Italian. Southern Italian.
How do you...?
How do you...? How do you spell...
...konlabos?
Konlabos, with a k.
Don't worry. After four or five hours,
you'll be as good as new.
The fire will keep the animals away
until sunup.
I'm sorry...
...but money has a way
of changing people.
You did find it, Travis.
Just like you said.
No one can take that
away from you.
And I will send you the money...
...buy your freedom. I meant that.
You kept your word,
and I admire that...
...so I'll keep mine.
Go north until you reach
the Quantana Road.
Take it south
all the way to the airfield.
Good luck to you, Mr. Beck.
Oh, shit.
What? What?
- What?
- Monkey. Monkey.
Monkey? Where?
Just get him away from me.
- Get out of here.
Get out of here, monkey!
Oh, no.
- I hate this place.
- Get out of here!
I hate penis- eating minnows,
and I hate freaky fruit.
- Get them away from me.
- I wanna go home. I want concrete.
- Get out of here, monkey.
- I want homemade tortellini.
I want my Los Angeles Lakers.
That's what I want. I want to go home.
I want to go home.
I want to go home!
Get out of here, monkey.
Well, what about that?
- Been for a stroll, have you, boys?
- Where's my bag?
Where's my jeep?
Give me my bag.
You have any water?
Sit down. How soon
before we can take off?
You left a jeep at the bottom
of a mountainside.
- I'll take care of it.
- In a bloody large puddle.
- I said, I'll take care of it.
- That jeep is dead, my friend.
Look, you'll get your money.
- Just start the plane.
- What's your big hurry?
I'm trying to leave before I run
into Hatcher or more problems.
Don't go worrying about Hatcher.
That monstrosity
won't give a flying fornication...
...for the pair of youse no more.
He got what he was after.
What do you mean?
He caught up with poor Mariana
in the jungle.
He relieved her of her artifact.
- What'd you say?
- I said, he relieved her of her artifact.
It's a word in the English language.
"Artifact." Look it up.
Son of a bitch. He's got my Gato!
- Your what?
- The Gato. Don't you speak English?
- Hey. Where is she?
- Hatcher's got her in town.
- He's torturing her for information.
- He's doing what?
Freedom fighters?
Freedom fighters, my ass.
Lutadores de Louco, you ask me.
They're all gonna die.
Come on. All aboard.
Come on.
What are you doing?
- We made a deal.
- A deal?
What the hell does that mean?
I'm here at the airstrip,
she doesn't have the Gato.
Gonna go in there by yourself?
No way. No way.
Hey, Hatcher's got a small army
back there.
You don't know your way
around the town.
Oh, wait. I got an idea.
Saddle up to one of those bulls...
...ride into town like a conquistador
and challenge all of them to a duel.
Oh, yeah. I forgot.
You don't use guns.
- What's your point?
- You're gonna die, Beck.
The boy's right.
You mind if we settle the bill now?
You need help.
Are you gonna help me, Travis?
All you care about is the money.
No, Beck, you're wrong.
I'd rather die than let that
son of a bitch get my Gato.
You need all the help you can get.
You can even use him, for chrissake.
Don't bring me into it.
I got a dodgy knee here.
You can't do this on your own.
Okay, Travis.
I know you're gonna run on me.
Might not be tonight or tomorrow.
But I will find you,
and I will take you back.
- Are we clear?
- Yeah.
We'll both probably be dead
in about an hour.
So let's cancel Christmas.
Your plan of attack was a bit naive.
Man, if I was only
10 minutes younger, huh?
I suppose now we have a conversation
where you enlighten me.
Mr. Hatcher.
How many more of you are out there?
Enlighten me.
Where are the rest of your
compadres? Enlighten me!
Mr. Hatcher.
I don't get why you people
are so hostile.
I've been good to you.
I built you a town.
Why are we fighting?
- Mr. Hatcher.
- What?
We've lost contact
with Outpost 1.
There's nobody answering.
- Mr. Hatcher, are you out there?
- What can I do for you, Mr. Beck?
I have no desire to fight
with you or your men.
For that reason,
you have two options.
Option A, you leave the Gato
and the girl...
...and you walk out of town,
no questions asked.
- What's option B?
- Option B...
...I make you.
Wrong choice.
Lock down the town.
Still no visual contact. Team two
is checking the perimeter right now.
He...
...that heard the sound
of thy holy trumpet...
...and took not warning...
...he hath clearly wandered too far...
...from the word of God.
And Cornelius Bernard Hatcher...
...your heir has come.
Let's get it on, big boy!
It's time to get back on the path.
That's a lot of cows.
Hi.
What nerve.
About bloody time, huh?
Somebody just shoot him.
Oh, yeah? Oh, you want one?
Oh, okay.
A little thunder? Huh?
You like thunderstorms, big boy?
How about some lightning?
Ear, ear- - Ears, eyes, foot, face!
Take the Gato and the girl
and get to the airfield.
If you run into trouble,
use her as a hostage.
And Harvey,
when you're safely out of town...
...put her out of my misery.
I need help!
Do not go gentle
into that good night, my lovely.
Beck! I need help. Beck!
Rage, rage...
...against the dying of the light.
There shall be no mercy...
...for any force that stands...
...blocking this path
of his righteousness.
Beck, help!
Help!
Move!
No way.
Give me back my Gato,
you little bald freak!
Oh, great.
See you.
You got the moves.
I'll give you that.
You reached into the wrong
refrigerator, Mr. Beck.
Hold your horses.
What have I done?
Are we not men?
- Hatcher.
- What?
Option A is still on the table.
You can walk away right now.
Option A doesn't work for me.
Before I came here,
what did you people have?
Face it. Be fair.
I put a roof over your head,
coin in your pockets.
You barefoot Indians
didn't have pockets...
...before Hatcher came along.
I gave you a life!
I'm the heart in the darkness.
Face it...
...you can't run this thing
without me.
I am pumping the blood
of the modern world...
...into your backward veins...
...you stinking...
...ingrate...
...Oompa Loompa...
...morons!
Okay.
That's it, I'm done.
Mr. Beck...
...I'll take option A.
Clear, please.
Oh, shit.
You make a hell of an entrance,
Mr. Beck.
Yeah.
I'd offer you a beer,
but I think you blew up my bar.
Yeah, I think you're right.
Thank you.
- We had a deal.
- Yes, we did.
And I'm afraid I didn't deliver
on that deal.
How is that?
The Gato.
I promised you the Gato.
Yes, well, I promised you Travis.
You all talking about this Travis?
And this Gato?
I'm impressed.
Yeah, well, make sure
they spell my name right.
I told you it wasn't about the money.
Well, big boy...
...I guess it's your move.
I'm impressed myself, Travis.
Declan, start the plane.
"Declan, start the plane"?
What does that mean?
- I'm taking you home.
- Oh, I figured that.
No breaks. Good luck.
You too.
I will send you your cut.
Move.
- Not a penny less than 15.6 million.
- Move, Travis.
You really ought
to stay away from guns.
You ought to get yourself
a psychiatrist. Seriously.
Move.
Well, look at him.
Look at you. Your beard.
You're like a real man.
- But you're so thin.
- Running is good exercise.
Good exercise. That's funny.
Did you hear him?
Running for your life.
I love it. I really do!
You know there's not
enough aspirin in the world...
...for a headache like you?
- Well, there probably is.
- But I understand what you mean.
- Well, that's good.
Because that means you'll understand
why you'll take that trip to Chicago.
Actually, I don't completely
understand that one.
- Still the smart- ass.
- I'm not that smart, Dad.
- I didn't know she was married.
- Well, she was.
Very married.
And you. What took you
so long, huh?
Your kid was
a tough rundown, Billy.
- Him? No.
- Yeah, yeah.
But I did walk him right through
that door, right? Like we agreed?
- You did.
- We good?
We're good.
Two hundred and fifty large.
You got your restaurant, kid.
Now get out of here, huh?
Before I leave...
When I was in Brazil, they
showed me this ritual they do...
...when they have big celebrations.
What they do is, they eat this fruit,
and it's called konlabos, with a k.
So I figured before I leave,
we could celebrate one last time.
Come on, guys. Try some of this.
If he says it's good, it's gotta be.
He's the best chef I know.
Billy, here, you try the first piece.
Not bad.
Big seeds, though.
I don't like seeds.
Hey, what are you- -?
I walked him right through
that door, Billy.
Boy...
...you got a funny- looking face.
Hey, Dad.
I love you, you know that?
Because you showed me
something back there.
I thought you had character,
but I wasn't sure.
- You got it, man. You really got it!
- Get in the truck.
- You violated every agricultural law.
- That's the least of my problems.
We should go back
in there and finish him off.
You want to go back, go ahead.
- Knock yourself out. I'll wait for you.
- I'm not going back.
Right. So shut up, get in the truck
before I change my mind.
Don't push me.
- What?
- Don't push me.
I appreciate everything you did.
If you want to get technical, all you did
is even the score. I saved you first.
- Get in.
- You don't have to thank me.
But this pushing shit ain't
happening no more. You read me?
Okay. I'm gonna bust you up.
Go for it.
Yeah.
Hey, remember your friend
Mr. Thunder?
How about his buddy
Mr. Lightning?
I know you know him.
You know him real well, don't you?
I'm just playing, man.
I'll be in the truck.
I'm gonna kill you.
-= Riped by _SHDW_ =-