The assistant warden wants this one
out of the block early.
Wants to get it over with fast.
Okay. Let's do it.
Hey, wake up. It's time.
Wake up. Let's go. It's time.
This is it.
7474505B.
- What wing?
- Maximum wing, Block 9.
Standard release?
Parole, three out offiive.
Good behaviour.
Give me a minute.
One Timex digital watch, broken.
One unused prophylactic.
One soiled.
Boots, black.
Belt, black.
One black suitjacket.
One pair black suit pants.
One hat.
Black.
One pair sunglasses.
Twenty-three dollars
and seven cents.
Sign here.
- What's this?
- What?
This car.
This stupid car.
Where's the Cadillac?
The Caddy.
Where's the Caddy?
The what?
The Cadillac we used to have.
The Bluesmobile.
I traded it.
- You traded the Bluesmobile for this?
- No, for a microphone.
A microphone?
Okay, I can see that.
- What the hell is this?
- This was a bargain.
I picked it up at the Mount Prospect
City Police Auction last spring.
It's an old Mount Prospect police car.
They were practically giving them away.
Well, thankyou, pal.
The day I get out of prison...
my own brother picks me up
in a police car.
You don't like it?
No, I don't like it.
Car's got a lot of pick-up.
It's got a cop motor,
a 440-cubic-inch plant.
It's got cop tyres,
cop suspension, cop shocks.
A model made
before catalytic converters...
so it'll run good on regular gas.
What do you say?
Is it the new Bluesmobile, or what?
Fix the cigarette lighter.
What are we doing here?
You promised you'd visit
the Penguin the day you got out.
Yeah. So I lied to her.
You can't lie to a nun.
We gotta go in
and visit the Penguin.
No fucking way.
Who is it?
Jake and Elwood.
Come in.
Hello, boys.
Nice to see you.
Please, have a seat.
No, boys.
Come over here in front of me.
I want to see your faces.
The county took a tax assessment
ofthis property last month.
They want $5,000.
Won't the church pay?
They would ifthey were
interested in keeping the place.
But they aren't.
The archbishop wants to sell this
building to the Board of Education.
What will happen to you?
I'll be sent to the missions--
Africa, Latin America...
- Korea.
- Forget it!
Five grand? No problem. We'll have it
foryou in the morning. Let's go.
I will not take
your fii lthy, stolen money!
Well, then.
I guess you're really up shit creek.
I beg your pardon.
What did you say?
I offered to help you.
You refused to take our money.
Then I said,
''I guess you're really up shit creek.''
- Christ,Jake, take it easy, man.
- Elwood!
- Ow! Shit!
-Jesus Christ!
- Shit!
-Jesus!
- Shit! Goddam it!
- Son ofa bitch!
You fat penguin!
Fuck this!
You are
such a disappointing pair.
I prayed so hard foryou.
It saddens and hurts me...
that the two young men
whom I raised...
to believe
in the Ten Commandments...
have returned to me
as two thieves...
with fii lthy mouths
and bad attitudes.
Get out!
And don't come back...
until you've
redeemed yourselves.
Boys, you gotta learn
not to talk to nuns that way.
Curtis!
- You look fii ne!
- Good to see you!
Buy you boys a drink?
Boys, things are bad.
They gonna sell this place
to the Board of Education...
and I'll be out on the street.
That money's got to be in the Cook
County Assessor's Offiice within 1 1 days.
They wouldn't turn you out,
would they?
Shit. What's one more old nigger
to the Board of Education?
Curtis, you and the Penguin
are the only family we got.
You're the only one
that was ever good to us...
singing ElmoreJames tunes and
blowing the harp for us down here.
Well, the sister was right. You boys
could use a little churching up.
Slide on down
to the Triple Rock...
and catch Reverend Cleophus.
You boys listen
to what he's got to say.
I don't want to listen
to nojive-ass preacher...
talking to me
about heaven and hell.
You get wise.
You get to church!
All I'm saying is,
we got to fii gure out...
some way
to get that money honestly.
That could be a problem.
Like the Penguin says.
We got to move toward redemption.
We got to go to church.
''We got to move toward redemption.
We got to go to church.''
Bullshit.
Come on.
And now, this week's sermon...
is from our beloved,
the Reverend Cleophus James!
And now, people--
When I woke up this morning,
I heard a disturbing sound.
I said,
when I woke up this morning...
I heard a disturbing sound!
What I heard
was the jingle-jangle...
ofa thousand lost souls!
I'm talking about the souls
of mortal men and women...
departed from this life!
Wait a minute!
Those lost, anguished souls
roaming unseen over the earth...
seeking a divine light...
they'll not fii nd
because it's too late!
Too late! Yeah! Too late
for them to ever see again...
the light they once chose
not to follow! All right!
Don't be lost
when the time comes!
For the day ofthe Lord cometh...
as a thief in the night!
Amen
Say amen!
- Let us all
- All go back
- To the old
- Old landmark
As we stay
in the service of the Lord
- Let uspreach
- Preach the word
- Got topreach
- Preach the wordall the way
Do it, knowit, feelit
Jake, are you all right?
Alleluia
The band.
Do you see the light?
What light?
Have you seen the light?
Yes!
Jesus H. Tap-Dancing Christ!
I have seen the light!
The band!
- Praise God!
- And God bless the United States!
Stay in theservice
ofthe Lord
Yea, Lord
We'll put the band back together,
we do a few gigs...
we get some bread.
Bang-- five thousand bucks!
Well, getting the band
back together might not be that easy.
- What are you talking about?
- They split.
They all took straightjobs.
Yeah? So you know
where they are.
You said you were
keeping in touch with them.
I got a couple of leads,
a few phone numbers.
But, I mean, how many ofthem
visited or even wrote you?
They're not the kind of guys
who write letters.
You were outside.
I was inside.
You were supposed to keep
in touch with the band.
I kept asking you
ifwe were gonna play again.
What was I gonna do,
take away your only hope?
Take away the very thing
that kept you going in there?
I took the liberty
of bullshitting you. Okay?
- You lied to me.
- It wasn't lies. It wasjust bullshit.
- Shit.
- What?
- Rollers.
- No.
Shit.
- What? What did I do?
- You failed to stop at a red signal.
The light was yellow, sir.
May I see your license, please?
Goddam it!
I haven't been pulled over
in six months.
I bet those cops
have got SCMODS.
State County Municipal Offender
Data System.
Elwood, we show your license
currently under suspension.
Step out ofthe car, please.
First you trade the Cadillac
for a microphone.
Then you lie to me
about the band.
Now you're gonna put me
right back in thejoint!
They're not gonna catch us.
We're on a mission from God.
We are in high-speed pursuit
northbound on Courtland Avenue.
Black-and-white 1 974 Dodge sedan
with Illinois plates.
Request assistance.
We'll be all right ifwe can
just get back on the expressway.
This don't look
like no expressway to me!
Don't yell at me.
What do you want me to do,
motor head?
Try not to be so negative
all the time.
Why don't you offer
some constructive criticism?
You got us into this parking lot, pal.
Now you get us out!
You want out
ofthis parking lot?
- Will there be anything else?
- Do you have Miss Piggy?
- There's pants and burgers.
- Yeah, lots ofspace in this mall.
Disco pants and haircuts.
Baby clothes.
This place has got everything.
New Oldsmobiles
are in early this year.
Pier 1 Imports.
Oh, shit!
They broke my watch!
I'm gonna catch that sucker...
if it's the last thing
I ever do.
Nice place, huh?
Hey, Sam.
Hey, Lloyd.
- Anybody call for me on the phone?
- No. No calls.
Some guy left his card.
Cop. Said he'd be back.
This here's my brother,Jake.
He just got out of the joint.
He's gonna be staying with me
for a few weeks.
Yeah. Okay.
Did you get me
my Cheez Whiz, boy?
Well, it ain't much,
but it's home.
- How often does the train go by?
- So often you won't even notice it.
What are you doing?
Making dinner.
Want some?
Tomorrow we got to get
the band back together.
I'm gonna quit work
in the morning, fii rst thing.
And how are you going
to get to work...
Mr Lead Foot, Mr Hot-Rodder,
Mr Motor Head?
Those cops tookyour license away.
They got your name,
your address.
No, they don't got my address.
I falsifiied my renewal.
I put down 1 060 West Addison.
That's Wrigley Field.
I gotta hit the sack.
Hey, you sleaze! My bed!
This, gentlemen, is the elegant
abode ofone Elwood Blues.
Thanks, Mr Mercer.
- I kinda like the Wrigley Field bit.
- Yeah, real cute.
Hi, Sam.
Hi. Has my friend arrived yet?
He failed to report in yesterday.
I don't want trouble.
Tell us where they are,
and there'll be no trouble.
Stand back.
It's almost 9:00.
We've gotta go to work.
Hello, Elwood. Sit down.
What's on your mind?
I gotta quit.
Why is that, Elwood?
I'm going to become a priest.
I'll call payroll and have them get
your severance pay ready.
- Good luck.
- God bless you, sir.
Thankyou.
- What's this?
- This is the last known address...
of Bones Malone
and Blue Lou Marini.
The Lord works in mysterious ways.
- Mrs Toronto?
- Tarantino.
Ma'am, do you have a Thomas Malone
or Louis Marini living here?
Not any more.
They moved out a long time ago.
I don't take in boarders any more.
- May we come in, ma'am?
- Please.
Did they leave a forwarding address?
A phone number?
Did they live quietly?
What were their personal habits?
They were good boys...
but they made
a lot of racket at night.
Are you the police?
No, ma'am.
We're musicians.
Mr Man!
- Yes, ma'am?
- They left this card. Maybe it'll help.
Thanks.
Thankyou. You're marvellous.
Thankyou. I'm Murph,
and these are the Magic Tones.
Steve ''The Colonel'' Cropper,
Donald ''Duck'' Dunn...
Willie ''Too Big'' Hall
and Tom ''Bones'' Malone.
We'll be back with the Magic Tones
for the Armada Room's...
two-hour disco swing party
after this short break.
Till then, don't you go changing.
So you're out. You're free.
You're rehabilitated.
What's next? What's happening?
What you gonna do?
You got the money you owe us,
mother-fucker?
Let's get something
straight here.
The reason he got locked in the slam
in the fii rst place...
was for sticking up a gas station
to coveryou guys.
You're kidding.
He pulled thatjob to pay
for the band's room-service tab...
from that Kiwanis gig
in Coal City.
- You did?
- That's right.
So I don't want to hear
any more ofthis small-change shit.
We're putting the band
back together.
Who here at this table
can honestly say...
that they played any fii ner
or felt any better than they did...
when they were
with the Blues Brothers?
You were the backbone...
the nerve centre
ofa great rhythm-and-blues band.
You can make that live,
breathe and jump again.
Murph and the Magic Tones?
Look at you in those
candy-ass monkey suits.
And I thought
I had it bad inJoliet.
At least we got
a change in clothes.
You're wearing the same shit
from three years ago.
Jake ain't lying, though.
We had a band powerful enough
to turn goat piss into gasoline.
We'll never get that fat sound again
without more horns.
We'll never get Mr Fabulous.
- Where is he?
- Forget it.
Mr Fabulous is the top maitre d'
at the Chez Paul.
He's pullin' down
six bills a week.
- Matt Murphy got married.
- Where is Matt ''Guitar'' Murphy?
He opened a restaurant with his old lady
on Maxwell Street...
and he took Blue Lou with him.
You'll never get Matt and Mr Fabulous
out ofthem high-paying gigs.
Oh, yeah?
Well, me and the Lord...
we got an understanding.
We're on a mission from God.
Mainly French cuisine.
No, sir. Mayor Daley no longer
dines here. He's dead, sir.
Private dining rooms
are available.
Oh, no. It was supposed to be
fiive years.
Didn't you get fiive years?
No, sir, not you.
And your name, sir?
Rizzolo, for eight at 1 1 :30.
Thankyou.
Mr Fabulous,
how marvellous it is to see you.
- You're looking younger than ever.
- Wait. You guys can't come in here.
Nonsense, my dear fellow.
My brother and I
have come to dine...
to celebrate my early release
from the service ofthe state.
Wait. Let's talk outside.
- Let's have a cup ofcoffee outside.
- Why, heavens, no.
We seek a full meal and all
the compliments ofthe house.
Come, Elwood.
Let us adjourn ourselves
to the nearest table...
and overlook this establishment's
board offare.
Good evening. Chez Paul.
Wait! Hey!
Sir, do you mind calling back
in about fiive minutes, please?
We'll have a table
in a few moments.
Excuse me.
Give us a bottle
ofyour fii nest champagne...
fiive shrimp cocktails
and some bread for my brother.
We have a Dom Pérignon '71
at $1 20.
That'll be fii ne, pal.
Seriously, the food here is really
expensive. The soup is fucking $1 0!
Let's go outside.
I'll buy you a cup ofcoffee.
We're putting the band
back together.
- Forget it. No way.
- We're on a mission from God.
Hold it. Hold it.
What's this?
Waiter? Sir?
Please, waiter?
Yes, sir? How are your salads?
The salads are fii ne.
It'sjust that we'd like
to move to another table...
away from those two gentlemen.
Why? Have they been
disturbing you?
No. It'sjust that--
Well, frankly,
they're offensive-smelling.
I mean, they smell bad.
Excuse me. I'll see if I can locate
another table foryou.
Thankyou.
Wrong glass, sir.
How much for the little girl?
- The women? How much for the women?
- What?
I want to buy your women.
Your little girl. Your daughters.
Sell them to me.
- Sell me your children.
- Maitre d'!
Cut it out. The owners are gonna
ask me to call the cops.
- You wouldn't do that to me, would you?
- Hejust got outtaJoliet.
He's on parole. You can't
call the cops on him, man.
- We're putting the band back together.
- I said no.
Absolutely not!
How much foryour wife?
We're putting the band back together.
We need you, man. We need your horn.
I really can't.
We got everybody except
Matt ''Guitar'' Murphy and Blue Lou.
- We're getting them next.
- No way.
Ifyou say no, Elwood and I
will come here for breakfast...
lunch and dinner
every day ofthe week.
Okay. I'll play.
You got me.
Sir?
White men!
White women!
The swastika is calling you!
The sacred and ancient symbol
ofyour race...
since the beginning oftime.
TheJew is using the black...
as muscle against you.
And you are left there, helpless.
-Fuckyou!
-What are you gonna do about it, whity?
-Just sit there?
- Go back where you came from!
Ofcourse not!
- Son ofa bitch!
- You are going tojoin...
with us...
the members of...
the American Socialist
White People's Party:
an organization ofdecent...
law-abiding white folk...
just like you.
Go to hell, bastards!
Go to hell!
I pledge allegiance to Adolf Hitler...
the immortal leader ofour race.
To the order for which he stands.
One great cause.
Sacred and invincible.
Hey, what's going on?
Those bums won their court case
so they're marching today.
- What bums?
- The fucking Nazi party.
Illinois Nazis.
I hate Illinois Nazis.
Heil Hitler!
Ten-hut!
- Gruppenfuehrer!
- Yes, sir!
Get that car's license plate number.
We're gonna kill
that son ofa bitch.
Come on home, babe
Oh, come on home, woman
Oh, come on home, pretty baby
lloveyou
When she walk that walk
Andtalk that talk
And whisperin my ear
Tellme thatshe love me
llove that talk
That baby talk
When she talk like that
lcan't take it like that
Come on home to me, baby
Walkyour walk
Talkyourtalk
Talkyourtalk, baby
Thankyou, ladies and gentlemen.
That was ''Boom, Boom,''
a song that I wrote back in the '50s.
- No, you didn't.
- It was a hit.
- Yes, I did.
I wrote ''Boom, Boom''!
- Can I help you, boys?
- You got any white bread?
Yes.
I'll have some
toasted white bread, please.
You want butter orjam
on that toast, honey?
No, ma'am. Dry.
- Got any fried chicken?
- Best damn chicken in the state.
Bring me four fried chickens
and a Coke.
You want chicken wings
or chicken legs?
Four fried chickens and a Coke.
And some dry white toast, please.
You all want anything to drink
with that?
- No, ma'am.
- A Coke.
Be up in a minute.
We got two honkies out there
dressed like Hasidic diamond merchants.
- Say what?
- They look like they're from the CIA.
- What they wanna eat?
- The tall one wants white-bread toast.
- Dry. With nothing on it.
- Elwood!
And the other one wants
four whole fried chickens and a Coke.
And Jake! Shit!
The Blues Brothers!
- Hi,Jake!
- Matt! How you doing?
- How wasJoliet?
- Oh, it's bad.
On Thursday night
they serve a wicked pepper steak.
Can't be as bad as the cabbage rolls
at the Terre Haute Federal Pen.
Or that oatmeal
at the Cook County slammer.
- They're all pretty bad.
- Matt--
Me and Elwood--
we're putting the band back together.
We need you and Blue Lou.
Don't talk that way around here.
My old lady--
- She'll kill me.
- Ma'am, you gotta understand.
This is a lot bigger than any domestic
problems you might be experiencing.
Matt, what the hell
is he talking about?
- Don't get riled, sugar.
- Don't you ''sugar'' me!
Now, you not going
back on the road no more.
And you ain't playing
any more two-bit, sleazy dives.
You're living with me now...
and you're not gonna go sliding around
with your white hoodlum friends.
But, babes! This isJake and Elwood!
The Blues Brothers!
The Blues Brothers! Shit!
They still owe you money, fool!
Ma'am.
Would it make you feel better
ifyou knew...
that what we're asking Matt to do
is a holy thing?
You see,
we're on a mission from God.
Don't you blaspheme in here!
Now, this is my man,
my restaurant...
and you two are gonna
walk right out that door...
without your dry, white toast...
without your four fried chickens...
and without Matt ''Guitar'' Murphy!
Now you listen to me!
I love you.
But I'm the man
and you're the woman.
And I'll make the decisions
concerning my life!
You better think about
what you saying.
the consequences ofyour actions.
Shut up, woman!
You betterthink
Thinkabout whatyou're
trying to do to me
Yeah, think
Letyourmindgo
Letyourselfbe free
Let'sgo back
Let'sgo way on back when
ldidn 't even knowyou, you couldn 't
have been too much more than ten
lain 't nopsychiatrist
lain 't no doctor with degree
lt don't take too much high lQ
to see whatyou're doing to me
You betterthink
Thinkabout whatyou're trying
to do to me
Think
Letyourmindgo
Letyourselfbe free
Freedom
Yeah, freedom right now
Hey, thinkabout it
You, thinkabout it
There ain 't nothingyou couldask
lcouldansweryou, but l won't
But l wasgonna change that, l'm not
ifyou keep doing things ldon't
Thinkabout whatyou're trying
to do to me
Damn it
Letyourmindgo
Letyourselfbe free
People walking aroundeveryday
playinggames andtaking scores
Tryin 'to makepeople lose theirmind
Now, be carefulyou don't loseyours
You needme
Andlneedyou
Without each other
there ain 't nothing eithercan do
- Yeah, thinkabout it, baby
- Whatyou trying to do to me
To the bone
Thinkabout it right now
Oh, freedom
You, thinkabout it
There ain 't nothingyou couldask
lcan answeryou, but l won't
But l wasgonna change my mind
ifyou keep doing things ldon't
You needme
Andlneedyou
Without each other
there ain 't nothing eithercan do
- Thinkabout it, baby
- Whatyou're trying to do to me
To the bone, man
Thinkabout it, baby
- Yeah, right on
- To the bone
- Fordeepening
- To the bone, fordeeps
Deepening
Right now
Thinkabout it, yeah, yeah
To the bone
Fordeepening
Thinkabout it
To the bone
Don't give me the Blues Brothers
You hadbetter
Stop andthinkabout it
Think
Let's boogie.
Well, go ahead, damn it!
Shit!
Pardon me...
but we do have a strict policy
concerning handling the instruments:
An employee
of Ray's Music Exchange...
must be present.
Now, may I help you?
Ray, it's me.JolietJake.
I once rented some column speakers
from you...
for my band-- The Blues Brothers.
Hey, Ray. It's me. Murph,
of Murph and the Magic Tones.
Remember me?
I bought three Fender amps.
- Oh, we sell a lot ofamplifiiers.
- Not like these. They were beautiful.
- Upholstered with thick, red shag.
- Right!
I remember now.
I'll buy them all back for 350 apiece.
Three fiifty?
I paid 800 each
not six months ago.
You know-- depreciation, man.
Ray, we're here to buy stuff.
We need pianos, amps, mikes--
the works.
Go on! Get!
Breaks my heart:
a boy that young going bad.
Tell me a little
about this electric piano.
You have a good eye, my man.
That's the best
in the city of Chicago.
- How much?
- Two thousand bucks and it's yours.
You can take it home with you.
I'll throw in the black keys for free.
Two thousand
for this chunk ofshit?
Come on, Ray!
Really, Ray. It's used.
There's no action left in this keyboard.
Excuse me.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the action on this piano.
Well, lheardabout the fella
you've been dancing with
All overthe neighbourhood
So why didn 'tyou ask me, baby
Didn 'tyou thinklcould
Well, lknowthat the bugaloo
is out ofsight
But theshing-a-ling's
the thing tonight
But ifthat wasyou andme
out there, baby
l wouldhave shownyou
howto do it right
Do it right
Twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Here we go loop-de-loop
Shake it out, baby
Here we go loop-de-lai
Bendover
Let meseeyoushakeyourtailfeather
Come on
Come on, baby
Allright
Do the twist
Do the fly
Do theswim
Anddo the bird
Do the duck
Do the monkey
Watusi
And what about the frug
Do the mashedpotato
What about the bugaloo
Oh, the Bony Maronie
Come on, let's do the twist
Twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Okay, man.
We'll take these axes.
Naturally. And as usual,
I gotta take an IOU.
You guys go inside.
Get yourselves a bite.
I've got to make a phone call.
Does this phone call
concern our fii rst gig?
Have I ever lied to you?
What are we gonna do, man?
We don't got no gig.
How much money you got?
- I got a quarter.
- That's enough for a phone call.
Come on.
- What are you doing?
- You said we were gonna make a call.
I said I was gonna make a call.
Who are you gonna call,Jake?
Do you remember Maury Sline?
Sline? Booking agent?
What about him?
He got us some good showcases
in the old days.
He got us the Morgan Park.
He got us the Ticktock.
I got him laid.
He owes me.
Give it a shot.
There's got to be at least
seven dollars' worth ofchange here.
Sir.
- What did you fii nd out?
- Okay.
I called a friend
at the Motor Vehicle Department.
That license plate is like a rash
all over the computer.
The car belongs
to a known traffiic menace.
- What's his name?
- His name is Elwood Blues.
He's got a record a mile long.
And he's a Catholic.
- Did you get his address?
- Ofcourse.
1 060 West Addison.
Let's go.
Anybody with that kind of record
is gonna make a mistake.
I want all party members
in the tristate district...
to monitor the city, county
and state police on their CBs.
Mr Blues is gonna fuck up.
And when he does...
he better pray the police get to him
before we do.
We been in this car for three hours now.
Where is this place?
I told you it'd take
a little while to get there.
- What's the name ofthe place?
- The name ofthe place is--
Bob's Country Bunker.
- Here we are.
- Bob's Country Bunker?
The sign says, ''Tonight only,
the Good Ole Boys.''
Blues Brothers! It should read,
''Tonight only...
the Blues Brothers'
triumphant return.''
Must be some kind of mistake.
You guys unload the stuff.
Elwood, come with me.
What can I get you boys?
You thirsty, hungry
orjust driving through?
Maybe you'd like a beer
or something a little harder?
We happen to make
the state's best pepper steak.
No, thankyou, ma'am.
We may be sucking back
a few beers later on.
We'll be here all night.
You see, we're the band.
You are?
Gee, that's nice!
Hey, Bob, this is the band!
All right!
What kind of music
do you usually have here?
We got both kinds.
We got country and western.
Jake, are you sure this is the place?
Yeah, sure. This is the place.
- Hi! You the Good Ole Boys?
- That's us!
The rest ofthe band's
in the parking lot getting our stuff.
Well, I'm sure glad
to have you boys here.
I'm Bob and this here is my place.
Well, it's a beautiful place, Bob!
I guess you wanna get your steel guitars
and everything set up on stage.
Claire, get up and turn those stage
lights on and get these boys going.
Chicken wire?
What do you say
we have a sound check?
Excuse me, sonny. I'll give this
to you. You're the tallest one.
Okay. What is it?
That there is a list
ofthe songs...
that you boys
will be playing tonight.
I don't think we know
any ofthe songs on this list.
This list doesn't mean anything.
They'rejust requests.
Do our regular set.
First tune.
''Give Me Some Loving.''
One, two--
One, two, three, four.
Shit!
What are those damn freak
pecker heads playing?
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
We're glad to be here tonight.
We're the Good Old Blues Brothers
Boys Band from Chicago.
We hope you'll like our show.
I'm Elwood. This is my brotherJake.
Well, my temperature's rising
Andmy feet on the floor
Crazypeople knockin '
'Cause they wantsome more
Let me in, baby
ldon't know whatyougot
Bettertake it easy
'Cause thisplace is hot
Andl'm soglad we made it
That ain't no Hank Williams song!
Give mesome loving
Get off the stage!
Everyday
Why'd they turn off the lights?
- Maybe they blew a fuse.
- I don't think so.
Those lights are off on purpose.
We gotta fii gure out something
these people like, and fast!
I got it. Remember the theme
from ''Rawhide''?
Old favourite. Rowdy Yates.
- What key?
- ''A.'' Good country key.
''Rawhide'' in ''A.''
Rollin ', rollin '
Though thestreamsare swollen
Keep them dogies rollin '
Rawhide
Through rain and windand weather
Hell-bent forleather
Wishin 'mygal wasby myside
All the things l'm missin '
Good vittles, love andkissin '
Are waiting at the endofmy ride
- Move 'em on
- Head 'em up
- Head 'em out
- Move 'em on
- Head 'em up
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in, rawhide
Theme from the TV show ''Rawhide.''
Thankyou.
We'd like to do a favourite ofthe horn
section. We hope it's one ofyours.
Sometimes it's hard
to be a woman
Giving allyourlove
Tojust one man
Andifyou love him
Oh, beproudofhim
'Cause afterall
He'sjust a man
Standbyyourman
Give him two arms to cling to
Andsomething warm to come to
When nights are coldandlonely
Standbyyourman
Andtell the worldyou love him
Keep giving all the loveyou can
Standbyyourman
Andshowthe worldyou love him
Keep giving all the loveyou can
Baby
Standby
Yourman
Well, folks, it's time
to callit a night.
But do whatyou feel,
andkeep both feet on the wheel.
You don't have togo home
butyou can't stay here.
So, tillnext time.:
- Move 'em on
- Head 'em up
Rawhide
- Cut 'em out
- Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in, rawhide
Let's get the hell out of here.
Shit, I wanna tell you, that's some
ofthe best goddam music we've had...
at the Country Bunker
in a long time.
Well, sorry we couldn't remember
''The Wreck ofthe Old 97.''
Why, hell! You guys can learn it
next time when you come back.
Bob, about our money for tonight.
That's right.
Two hundred dollars...
and you boys drank
$300 worth of beer.
When we fii rst came in...
the bar lady never charged us
for the fii rst round.
So, like, we fii gured
beer was complimentary for the band.
Well, I'll just go out
and take up a collection from the boys.
I sure would appreciate it.
I say this trip is nowhere, man.
I say we gotta quit.
What? Quit?
I wish you guys
would make up your mind.
Otherwise I gotta call Mr Ronzini at
the Holiday Inn to get our old gig back.
Back at the Armada Room?
Listen, they want us
to pay for the beer we drank.
So you'd better split.
The next gig is gonna be dynamite!
Huge! You'll see.
I say we give the Blues Brothers
just one more chance.
Why not? Ifthe shit fiits, wear it!
Scoot over, goddam it!
Boys look a little upset.
Hey, man. Don't worry.
We got a couple ofdays.
We'll get the Penguin's tax money.
I mean, look. We got an appointment
to see Mr Sline tomorrow.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Let's skate.
Goddam it.
Excuse me. Are you
the Good Ole Boys?
That's right. I'm Tucker McElroy,
lead singer, driver ofthe Winnebago.
I'd like to talk to you,
but we're running very late.
I'mJacob Stein, American Federation
of Musicians Union, Local 200.
I've been sent here to see
ifyou're carrying your permits.
Our what?
Your union cards.
May I see your cards, please?
Suppose we ain't got no union cards,
and we go in and start playing anyway?
What you gonna do about that?
You gonna stop us?
Stein!
You gonna look funny trying to eat
corn on the cob with no fucking teeth!
Listen, let me talk to Bob,
the owner.
See ifwe can put your band
on contract waivers for tonight.
I don't want you to move
from this spot.
Just let me handle this.
We'll talk to Bob.
Get in the car and start her up.
You know you boys owe me
a lot of money for that beeryou drank!
- Goddam it!
- Bob, we loved playing here tonight.
My brother's writing out an
American Express traveller's check...
to cover the bar tab.
I sure would appreciate it.
I'd better check up, see how he's doing.
I have to sign it too.
I usually sit in the car and write it
out on the glove compartment lid.
Need a pencil.
- Were them guys from the union?
- What the hell, ''union''?
Those boys skipped out of here
owing me a lot of money for beer.
What the hell are you guys
all dressed up for?
We're the Good Ole Boys!
You're the Good Ole Boys?
''A.F.M.'' Shit!
Our Lady of Blessed Acceleration,
don't fail me now!
I don't believe it!
It's that shit-box Dodge again.
The bastards are ours now!
Holy shit!
Boys, you in big trouble.
Maury, you owe me.
We'll play anywhere, anytime,
for anybody.
Put us in the Double Up Lounge, or
the Morgan Park Theatre, or the Crystal.
We always knocked them dead
in thosejoints.
Discos. They're all discos.
Singles. Mixed singles.
Gay singles.
These people like to dance
with each other.
We are a dance band.
I don't know, boys.
I just don't know.
Times have changed,
you know what I mean?
What are you guys gonna do?
The same act?
You wear
the same farkakte suits.
You'll scare people away.
Don't you ever wear bluejeans
orjump suits...
like Wayne Cochran
and the C.C. Riders?
You gotta come through for us.
We need 5,000 bucks fast.
Five thousand bucks?
Who do you thinkyou are?
The Beatles?
You know the size hall you gotta work
to take in that kind of money?
We'll fii ll any hall in the country.
You guys familiar
with the Palace Hotel ballroom?
- Never heard of it.
- Nice place up north.
Built in the '40s
on Lake Wazapamani.
That seats 5,000.
You guys fii ll that place,
you can make 5,000 bucks, easy.
- Book us for tomorrow night.
- Hold it! Tomorrow night?
A gig like that, you gotta prepare
the proper exploitation.
I know about that stuff.
I been exploited all my life.
Forget it. There's no way
with you guys. Forget about it.
Say, how's Mrs Sline?
I might have some information
she'd like to know.
You blackmailing me?
Ifyou wanna put it that way.
Maury, we need this gig!
We're on a mission from God.
Get us the hall, and I guarantee
we'll pack them in for miles around.
What do you say?
Okay. I'll get you the Palace Hotel.
I'll print up show bills. I'll make
the place look real pretty, okay?
I don't thinkyou guys
are gonna gross dollar one.
But ifyou do, I want a taste
ofthe gig, okay?
Thanks, Maury.
Let's go, boys!
Listen, you boys heard me talk
aboutJake and Elwood.
They used to live here,
just like you.
And I used to sing to them,
just like with you.
TonightJake and Elwood are going out
to sing and play...
to raise money
to help you children.
Your lazy butts are in this too!
So get up on that wagon.
We're going up north
to put the word on the streets.
Tonight only,
the fabulous Blues Brothers...
Rhythm andBlues Revue...
at the Palace Hotelballroom,
Route 16...
Lake Wazapamani.
The fabulous Blues Brothers...
ShowBandandRevue.
There you go, boy.
All right, man!
Check it out!
- Tonight only!
- From Chicago!
- The Blues Brothers.
- Rhythm and Blues Revue.
One night only!
The fabulous--
Blues Brothers Show Band
and Revue.
You! On the motorcycle!
You two girls!
- Tellyourfriends!
- Free parking.
Two-dollarcovercharge only, folks!
- That's a lot ofentertainment.
- For two dollars.
Will you please put this in the window,
'cause it's real important.
Tonight only, from Chicago...
the fabulous Blues Brothers...
Rhythm andBlues Revue...
foryourdancingpleasure.
Andit's ladies'night tonight.
at the Palace Hotelballroom.
''Tonight only, the Blues Brothers...
genuine Rhythm and Blues Show
and Revue.
Palace Hotel ballroom.
Tonight only.''
How we doing?
So far we covered Lake, McHenry...
and part of Du Page County.
Good. Let's get to the gig.
What is it?
We're out of gas.
Oh, shit.
Wow! A classic. What a room!
This place is gonna swing tonight.
It's a fucking barn.
We'll never fii ll it.
We've gotta fii ll this hall tonight.
A lot ofyoung children
are depending on it.
Young children?
What do you mean?
Jake and Elwood are donating
the band's share ofthe door money...
to pay the taxes
on the St. Helen's orphanage...
in Calumet City.
What?
- We're out of gas.
- Yep. Mind ifwe fii ll her up?
Nope. I said ''we're'' out of gas.
Tanker truck's late.
Should have been here two hours ago.
It's always late on Thursdays.
I guess we'll have to wait.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, you. Could you fii ll it up
with premium, and check under the hood?
Sure.
You want I should wash
the dead bugs off the windshield?
No. I'm in kind ofa hurry.
Where in the hell are they?
So maybe you'd like to come by
and see the show.
I'm awfully sorry, but I do have
a prior dinner engagement.
Thanks, Marvin.
Get me Troopers Daniel and Mount.
I don't see those Blues Brothers.
We'll wait.
Okay, you're all set.
That'll be $94.
Here's 95.
Thankyou.
Okay. And that's a dollar change.
- Oh, keep the change.
- Thanks.
So, look. Ifyour date...
don't work out tonight
for any reason...
there's a motel
up on the interstate.
Maybe we could, say, meet...
around midnight?
I'll think about it, Elwood, okay?
Bye.
Son ofa bitch!
Come on!
We're really late.
You'd better step on it.
I always like to perform
for angry mobs.
You can't quit now.
What can they be doing?
My head hurts.
That Night Train's a mean wine.
You'd better get bright!
We got a show to do.
Then we gotta fii gure out
some way to collect that gate money...
get it to the County Assessor's offiice
as soon as they open in the morning.
We want the show!
Gentlemen, I'm leaving.
Man, we were so close.
Hey, you guys know
''Minnie The Moocher''?
I knew a hooker once
named Minnie Mazola.
No! The song ''Minnie the Moocher.''
- Yeah. So what?
- Hit it!
Hey, folks, here's a story
'bout Minnie the Moocher
She wasa low-down hoochie coocher
She was the roughest, toughest frail
But Minnie hada heart
Asbig asa whale
She messedaround
with a bloke namedSmokey
She lovedhim
though he was cokey
He tookherdown to Chinatown
Andheshowedherhow
to kick thegong around
She hada dream
about the King ofSweden
Hegave herthings
thatshe wasneedin '
Hegave hera home
built ofgoldandsteel
A diamondcar
with theplatinum wheels
This is glue. Strong stuff.
What the hell are you doing?
This can is from
a surplus disposal run.
Fifteen overcharged ounces
of pure, uncompounded...
isopropyl butane monosulfate.
When combined with oxygen
and a little heat...
it will cause a rapid expansion.
PoorMin, poorMin
- Let's take them!
- Wait a minute.
I've never even heard
these boys sing, all right?
All right.
They're not going no place.
All right, cover all exits! Let's go!
Come on! Hurry up!
Move it!
Who wants an Orange Whip?
Orange Whip?
Three Orange Whips.
Excuse us.
Good evening, ladies.
One, two,
one, two, three, four.
Now, ladies and gentlemen, it is the
distinct pleasure ofthe management...
to present to you
the evening's star attraction.
Here they are, back after
their exclusive three-year tour...
of Europe, Scandinavia
and the subcontinent.
Won't you welcome
from Calumet City, Illinois...
theshowband
ofJolietJake andElwoodBlues.
The Blues Brothers!
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
We're so glad to see
so many lovely people here tonight.
We'd like to welcome
all the representatives...
of Illinois' law enforcement
community...
who have chosen tojoin us in
the Palace Hotel ballroom at this time.
We certainly hope you all
enjoy the show.
And remember that
no matter who you are...
and what you do
to live and survive...
there's still some things
that make us all the same.
You. Me. Them. Everybody.
Everybody
Needs somebody
Needs somebody to love
Someone to love
Sweetheart to miss
Sugarto kiss
lneedyou, you, you
ln the morning
When mysoul's on fire
Sometimes lfeel
lfeela little sadinside
When my baby mistreats me
lnever, never
Findaplace to hide
lneedyou
Sometimes lfeel
lfeela little sadinside
When my baby mistreats me
lnever, neverfindaplace to hide
lneedyou
People, when you do fii nd
that special somebody...
you gotta hold that man,
hold that woman...
love him, please him,
squeeze her, please her!
Signify your feelings
with every caress.
Because it's so important
to have that special somebody...
to hold, kiss, miss...
to squeeze and please!
Everybody needs somebody
Everybody
Needs somebody to love
Someone to love
Sweetheart to miss
Sugarto kiss
lneedyou, you
ln the morning
When mysoul's on fire
When there ain 't no one around
lneedyou
Thankyou.
That was for Wilson Pickett.
This is dedicated
to the late, great Magic Sam.
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
Come on
Baby, don'tyou wannago
Back to thatsame oldplace
Sweet home Chicago
Six andthree is nine
Nine andnine is eighteen
Look there, brother, baby
andsee what lsee
- The Mafiia's after us now.
- You guys were hot!
You were great!
I've got to record you.
- Bullshit.
- I don't bullshit.
I'm president of Clarion Records...
the largest recording company
on the eastern seaboard.
- So what?
- Here's $1 0,000.
An advance on your fii rst
recording session.
Is it a deal?
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal.
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal!
Listen, all these cops out here--
they're waiting for us.
We gotta get out with nobody
seeing us. You know a back door out?
Sure. I used to be head bouncer here
back in the '70s.
There's an electrical service duct
behind your drummer's riser.
Do us a favour.
Take $1 ,400 and give it
to Ray's Music Exchange...
in Calumet City,
and give the rest to the band.
- You got it.
- Thanks.
Bye.
Me and Elwood are gonna make a break
for it. You and the band keep playing.
- Something's wrong.
- Where'sJake?
Where'd they go?
I sure hope this thing
leads someplace.
Elwood, we're gone, man.
Who is that girl?
Well,Jake.
You lookjust fii ne down there...
slithering in the mud
like vermin.
No problem.
You're not gonna get away from me
this time.
Check that out! Let's go!
It's good to see you,
sweetheart!
You contemptible pig.
I remained celibate foryou.
I stood at the back
ofa cathedral...
waiting, in celibacy, foryou...
with 300 friends and relatives
in attendance.
My uncle hired the best
Rumanian caterers in the state.
To obtain the seven limousines...
my father used up his last favours
with Mad Pete Trullo.
So for me, for my mother...
my grandmother, my father,
my uncle and for the common good...
I must now kill you
and your brother.
Oh, please don't kill us!
You know I love you, baby! I wouldn't
leave you! It wasn't my fault!
You miserable slug!
You thinkyou can talkyour way
out ofthis? You betrayed me!
No, I didn't. Honest!
I ran out of gas!
I had a flat tyre!
I didn't have money for cab fare!
My tux didn't come back
from the cleaners.
And old friend came in
from out oftown!
Someone stole my car! There was
an earthquake! A terrible flood!
Locusts! It wasn't my fault,
I swear to God!
Jake, honey.
Let's go.
Take it easy.
You're now going to
totally demolish that car.
You want to maybe consider
going after the Blues Brothers?
It's 1 06 miles to Chicago.
We got a full tank of gas,
halfa pack ofcigarettes...
it's dark
and we're wearing sunglasses.
Hit it.
Shit, man. Can't this damn thing
go any faster than this?
Bob, I think I've got
a little problem.
Goddam, boy.
Shit.
Don't you say a fuckin' word.
All units, we have a ten-seven-niner.
Offiicers are in pursuit:
a black-and-white
1 974 Dodge sedan...
southboundon 47.
Respondto signal, ten-seven-niner.
Occupants ofvehicle.:
oneJolietJake Blues...
one ElwoodBlues.
- Consideredextremely dangerous.
- Gruppenfuehrer!
Jake, I gotta pull over.
Southbound on State Highway 47.
Hi! Wanna hand me the mike?
Thanks a lot.
This is car--
What number are we?
Five-fiive.
Car 55. We're in a truck.
Signal ten-seven-niner
still engaged.
Vehicle travelling southbound
approaching Chicago city limits.
Commander advises will contact
Chicago precincts...
for a local intercept.
Maintain pursuit.
Use of unnecessary violence...
in the apprehension
ofthe Blues Brothers has been approved.
Well, this is defii nitely
Lower Wacker Drive.
If my estimations are correct...
we should be very close to
the Honourable Richard J. Daley Plaza.
- That's where they got that Picasso.
- Yep.
Son ofa bitch!
There they are.
- Oh, no!
- What the fuck was that?
The motor. It's thrown a rod.
- Is that serious?
- Yep.
Faster.
Holy shit!
I've always loved you.
There it is!
Come on!
Sir, where's the offiice
ofthe assessor of Cook County?
Down the hall. Turn right.
Take the elevator to 1 1 02.
Thankyou, sir.
Excuse me.
Did you see two guys...
with black suits and hats,
one carrying a briefcase?
Yeah. I just sent them down there.
Thankyou.
Hold the door.
Let's go.
Can I help you?
- This is where they pay taxes, right?
- Right.
This money is for
the year's assessment...
on the St. Helen ofthe Blessed Shroud
Orphanage in Calumet City, Illinois.
Five thousand bucks.
It's all there, pal.
Stand back!
Fire!
And here is your receipt.
Warden threwaparty
in the countyjail
Prison band was there
andthey began to wail
The band wasjumping
andthejoint began to swing
Youshould ofheard those
knocked-outjailbirds sing
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody on the whole cellblock
Wasdancing to thejailhouse rock
SpiderMurphyplayed
the tenorsaxophone
LittleJoe wasblowin '
on theslide trombone
The drummerboy from lllinois
went crash, boom, bang
The whole rhythm section
was the Purple Gang
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody on the whole cellblock
Wasdancing to thejailhouse rock
SadSack wassitting
on a block ofstone
Way overin the corner
weeping allalone
The warden said
Buddy, don'tyou be no square
lfyou can't get apartner
use a wooden chair
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody on the whole cellblock
Wasdancing to thejailhouse rock