Hike!
Martel!
Martel, you're a wimp!
I can't believe that Martel
goes for a give-up slide
-It did look cautious
-I could have scored on that!
It may be the lastplay
of the season.
The player's strike became official...
...at 4 p.m. Eastern Time.
I'm sad that the players ' demands,
which center around...
...a rise in the current salary cap,
were rejected by the owners.
I have told my union brothers to walk.
Get me Jimmy McGinty!
Have him here tonight
Yes, sir
I'm here with Eddie Martel.
A lot of angry fans out there feel
that the players are being too greedy.
Any comments?
Dwight, I know $5 million a year
sounds like a lot of money...
...but I have to pay 10% to my agent,
5% to my lawyer--
Do you know what insurance costs
on a Ferrari, mother--
Pat, back to you.
That was Washington running back
Malcolm Lamont
It's all about money, folks,
but isn't it always?
Yes. This is Pat Summerall
for John Madden saying...
...so long from Nextel Stadium.
-you look like shit
-I'm dying, Jimmy
Come on
You've been dying for 20 years
-Give me a cigarette
-I quit
Nobody likes a quitter
-See the game today?
-No
Why, you liar
Could you believe that slide
by Martel?
What a pussy
-What's up?
-Take a ride with me
How's the wife?
She had her lips done
I never even knew you could
have your lips done
Looks like a largemouth bass
I'm too old to screw around
Let me give it to you straight
I want you back
-you already have a coach
-I'll take care of it
-Like you took care of me
-Now, Jimmy
Your players all flew home
to their castles
In their private jets
We're gonna finish
the season anyway
I'm gonna use replacement players
-Jeez, what a business
-We got 4 games left
We win three, we're in the playoffs
Really? Win three out of four
with replacement players?
That's not too much to ask
You won for me once,
you can do it again
What's the matter, Jimmy?
Nobody's gonna give you
a better chance than this
After that Dallas mess
-I was right about that
-It had nothing to do with being right!
Went head-to-head with
an $8 million quarterback
Who did you think was gonna win?
That's not gonna happen here!
I'm talking about a team of poor
nobodies who play to win
Not a bunch of bitchy millionaires
Come on, Jimmy!
I'm thinking
Hello!
I want total control of my team
I want to be able to recruit anybody
that I want, no interference
My word is my bond
I want it in writing
Okay, Jimmy
Okay
We thought we'd skip special teams
for now
It'll be tough enough to put
together a team in a week
-We're gonna go a different way
-A different way?
Here's a list of people I've
been watching over the years
They've all played football,
not all of them in the pros
But they all have something
unique to bring
We'll take them and try to
put together a winning team
If nothing else, they should
be fun to watch
Daniel Bateman, SWAT team officer
Awarded a Purple Heart for losing
a kidney during the Gulf War.
A walk-on at Michigan State
before he gave up football
...to sneak back into the service
for one more tour of duty.
Clifford Franklin
Great attitude, great desire, and the
fastest son of a bitch I've ever seen
Clifford! Twinkie!
What's up, man? Got any Twinkies?
Can he catch?
That's why I have you
Andre and Jamal Jackson
Together, these guys are the best
tandem team of guards in the game
-you're kidding me!
-Andre got traded and they fell apart
He ain't our problem no more
We gonna play football
-Football?
-Football
Nigel Gruff
Striker out of Cardiff,
now residing in Hell's Kitchen.
He's "The Leg" because he can kick
a soccer ball the length of the field
Gentlemen
The drinks are on the house!
Bollocks!
Pissing away our money again?
-No, the money's on the way
-Where? To the OTB?
I got a winning horse!
I swear on my mum's grave!
Your mother's grave?
He's swearing on his mother's grave!
Nigel, listen I want my money!
-Has he kept in shape?
-By Welsh standards
Shane Falco
Shane Falco? "Footsteps" Falco,
from Ohio State?
The same.
-He hasn't played in years.
-Should be well rested then.
You look like a swordfish
I caught once
He hit the deck just like that
-you know who I am?
-yeah
You're Jimmy McGinty
That old coach from the '80s
We met just before the Sugar Bowl
I remember
Hell of a game, that Sugar Bowl
-What'd you lose that by? 40 points?
-That would be 45
A game like that sticks with you
you never shake it off
-Got 3 concussions to prove it
-That's why girls don't play
Why are you here, coach?
Back with the Sentinels
I want you as quarterback
I found the best guards
and a wide receiver
Even you couldn't overthrow
-I'm retired
-Retired?
It looks like things have gone
real well for you since
I got no complaints
It's quiet here
Nobody bothers me
The great thing about plankton is,
it pretty much keeps to itself
You know what separates the winners
from the losers?
The score
Getting back up after being
kicked in the teeth
I watched films of your games
since the Sugar Bowl
You shouldn't have been trying to
carry the whole team that first year
Your teammates leaned on you
and you crumbled
-Is that how you want to be remembered?
-I don't want to be remembered at all
If you do well, who knows what'll
happen after the strike
I'm not making you any promises,
but why don't you take a chance?
Rather than scraping crap off
the bottom of somebody else's toys?
Think it over
You could be part of something
Football fans, what the owners are
doing is absolutely unconscionable
They have blatantly hired scabs
Which goes against our Constitution,
the Declaration of Independence...
...and the Emancipation Proclamation.
Here come the scabs now!
That's Eddie Martel!
I love you, man! What's happening?
I love you, man!
I'm gonna bust a cap in your ass!
And your ass!
Piss off!
Get that bible out of here!
Sorry about this
Put God in your heart!
I'm very sorry
Get a job, you wankers!
Looking good out there! you've got
the goods, you've got the goods!
Where did you learn
to catch like that?
Roberts, make that D-back commit
before you cut, all right?
Jimmy
-My tight end is deaf
-yeah, I know
Jimmy, how am I gonna
coach a deaf man?
You won't need to
Brian Murphy would've gone in
the first round if he wasn't deaf
Played college ball here
in DC at Gallaudet
But I got to be able to communicate
with him and how
Learn to sign
Oh, horseshit!
Look at it this way, he'll never
be called offsides on an audible
-Good to see you
-you too
-How are you?
-Good, good
This is "The Leg"?
I thought you told me
he was solid muscle
He's much stronger than he looks
I'm wiry
Go get some kicks in
He's "wiry"
"Wiry"
You've been briefed
as to your situation
Coach McGinty wanted you
with us for 5 weeks
And the governor's complied
Nice watch
What?
Oh, this?
It's a fake
Damn thing's always broken
It's only right twice a day
Why don't we join the others?
No sense standing here by ourselves
Out of screaming distance
-Come on, let's fire out of there!
-Jimmy
-Falco, when's he coming?
-Relax, he'll be here
Come on, quick feet!
I am relaxed, but that's not the point
It's nervous energy
Case in point, we don't have
a quarterback, do we?
-Fire out of there!
-We don't have a game plan for Sunday
And the only good thing I can say
about our offensive weapon is
It's wiry
What the shit is that?
No, no, it's "wiry"
-However the hell you say it!
-Say it: "Wiry"
Wiry
Holy! Look at this mamma-jamma!
Have you lost weight?
Coach, don't say that
You look great
Why don't you work out on this OD?
OD
-So he's lost weight?
-Sumo wrestler
Expert at pushing people around
That's what pass blocking is, remember?
That's right
Next one, 74 Come on!
Set, hut!
All right! Way to go!
It's all about pushing people around!
Set! Hut!
Come on, sumo boy
Let's see what you can do
Set Hut!
Yes! Good hit, sumo boy!
Now get this off of me!
"That'll do, pig, that'll do"
-Screw you, cockroach
-you'll have to find your dick first
Get this off of me!
Hey, scab!
-I don't want any trouble
-you hear that?
He's taking away my job, but
he doesn't want any trouble
Not only is he taking your job,
he's taking your parking space too
What's up?
Is that right, Falco?
I didn't know it was yours
I'll move it
No, let us do that
Guys, move the new boy's ride for him
Coming right up, Mr Falco
Ready?
One Two Three
Thanks, guys
Asshole
Jesus! "Footsteps" Falco
They must be getting desperate
Hey, Falco!
You're not even a has-been!
You're a never-was!
Go!
Come on, pick it up!
Form a line here!
Let's go seven on seven
Check it out, our new quarterback
We're in business now
You're late
Car trouble
You still got an arm?
Hey, Falco
Go!
That's gonna leave a mark
-Leo, Franklin's down again
-I'm okay
I'm okay I'm okay
Let's play some football!
Danny Bateman
Shane Falco
Nice pop, Danny
Thanks, coach
In practice, we don't hit the fellows
with the red shirts on
I know, but I see that red and I just
want to go after it like a bull
Okay, Danny
Huddle up!
Get used to setting up on the run
Move fast, think even faster
-you'll live longer
-I'm very interested in that
Huddle up!
Hey! Shane Falco
I lost a ton of money on
that Sugar Bowl of yours
What a bloody shambles that was
You could smell the stink
all the way back in Wales
Nice meeting you
Ready!
Hut!
Shit! I forgot about the whole red
shirt thing! This game's confusing
Remember
Red means stop
Like a streetlight, right?
-yeah
-Get on up
Go ahead I'm gonna lie here
a moment and collect my thoughts
Work shit out, right?
-you should be glad he's on your side
-yeah
-So you have a cheer or something?
-Are you ready?
Let's hear it for the quarterback
Hey-hey, ho-ho
Could anyone play better?
Say-say, no-no
Tackle, tackle, tackle, tackle
Tack, tack, tack
Show those others boys what they
Lack, lack, lack
If I gave you a dollar
you could keep most of the change
'Cause all I really want
is a "quarterback!"
California oranges, Texas cactus
We think your team
Needs a little practice
Sit 'em in a highchair
Feed 'em with a spoon
Roll 'em up in toilet paper
Kick 'em to the moon!
-That was great, thank you
-Thank you
Can you dance?
Let me have some of that duck
-What the hell is this?
-Chinese spareribs
If you don't want it,
get the fuck out of here
I'm trying to figure out how
the Chinaman over here
Gets 700 pounds off
of eating this shit
I'm Japanese, not Chinese
-Same difference
-What?
It's the same difference!
All that big--
Nigger, please
You do know Japan and China are
two different countries, right?
-you do know I got a atlas, bitch
-Really, gangster?
Yeah
We're on the same team! We're on
the same team! Now chill out!
-The mick's right
-I'm not a mick! I'm bloody Welsh!
Whatever
-I'm going to sit with the deaf kid!
-Jesus Christ!
Praise His glory, Nigel!
you praise His glory!
Smear their blood all over town
Punch 'em, hit 'em
Make it last
Come on, boys, let's kick some ass!
I played one game in the pros,
I blew out my knee and that was it
Shit
All I want to do is score one touchdown
before I hang up my pads That's it
You'll get it
Hey, man
Wilkinson! Earl Wilkinson!
I knew I recognized you, man!
I knew it!
You played for Minnesota, baby!
Oh, shit! Earl Wilkinson, man!
Oh, my God!
You'd have been All-Pro if
you hadn't beat up them cops!
What I had meant to say
was "allegedly"
Allegedly beat up them cops
and because
A good Christian boy like you
would never do nothing like that!
That's right
The way I heard it, my man didn't
even do nothing anyway!
Them cops were just jealous of
the black man
Hear what I'm saying?
My boy been living large!
I can't stand the cops!
I better not see a cop!
-I'll whup a cop's ass! Believe it!
-I'm a cop
Look!
Bundt cake!
-Look at these yummy little monkeys!
-Hello!
Oh, hey
You-- yeah
-Are you Heather and Dawn?
-yep, we sure are
You don't know how excited I am
That I actually have some girls
with dance experience!
-I'm excited too!
-I know! Me too, too
So Heather, you were in Cats,
which is so terrific--
No, Pussycats
You know, the club next to the airport?
Pussycats?
-That style of dancing would be--
-Is lap-dancing a style?
No I mean
Oh, my God, I forgot
to tell you something
What?
Oh, she always does that
I've seen all I need to see
No way! I'm so excited!
Go suit up
- Go down the tunnel and to the left
-Okay
If you guys have any friends down at
the club, would you send them over?
-Sure
-yeah, absolutely
Where are you going, number 48?
I was watching you today
You looked good
Good release, strong arm
you're gonna do fine
Thanks
I'm Annabelle Farrell
-Shane Falco
-I know
I remember you from the
'96 Sugar Bowl game
Didn't anybody have anything
better to do that day?
You should get some help
to turn this back over
Yeah, I was thinking I'd call AAA
later or something
-Do you want a lift?
-yeah
Yeah, that would be great Thanks
Why'd you stay in the pocket
at practice?
I don't comment to quarterbacks
about style but
You need to keep scrambling
against Detroit, with Prescott back
-Prescott hasn't crossed
-Sunday
-It's a secret so you can't prepare
-How do you know?
My friend's a cheerleader for Detroit
She tipped me
He's left-sided, shotgun
formation, roll right
Van Gundy's on the right
He's been All-Pro 2 years,
but one of my cheerleaders
Is friends with a girl
who broke up with him
He's been drinking ever
since she left him
He's hung over! He's a good second
slower off the snap than usual
I'll stick to the right side
Unless what they say
about Martinez is true
-That was fun
-This is great! you live out here?
Which one's yours?
Here you see that white yacht
with the satellite dish?
I'm the old boat next to it,
covered in seagull shit
What did you name her?
Phyxsius.
-Phyxsius, what does that mean?
-"Putting to flight"
You want to come onboard for a beer?
Nothing personal, but I don't
date football players
I don't blame you
Not even quarterbacks?
Especially not quarterbacks you guys
are the biggest babies of all
The biggest babies?
Yeah
-Thanks for the ride
-Good luck on Sunday
-Be careful out there
-I will
Shane
What's up?
Just
Watching the game
Nervous?
No
I'm good
Like a duck on a pond
On the surface everything
looks calm but
Beneath the water, those feet
are churning a mile a minute
You'll be fine
Find a way to lead your team
Earn their respect
Yeah
How are you doing?
Me?
I'm just another duck on the pond
Coach, can I ask you a question?
-yeah, shoot
-Why me?
I look at you and I see two men
The man you are,
and the man you ought to be
Someday, those two will meet
Make for a hell of a football player
Get some sleep, kiddo
You play professional
football tomorrow
Welcome to Nextel Stadium,
in our nation's capital.
I'm Pat Summerall and
with me is John Madden
Detroit bought an entire semi-pro
team once the strike happened.
Washington is going with
a bunch of unknowns.
But we'll see a few guys
we know today.
Like Shane Falco, that talented
quarterback who fell out of sight...
...after a disastrous showing
in the Sugar Bowl.
Having a little snacky-poo
before the game?
-It does a body good
-you are one crazy son of a bitch
-you know how I know that?
-How?
Because only you'd eat eggs
before a game!
I need to bulk up
-you want one?
-No!
It's good for you
Sentinels, listen up
Welcome to professional football
Some will say that your
accomplishments
Will soon be forgotten, you're not
real players, this isn't a real team
And I say that is bullshit!
Because as of today, you're all
professional football players
You're being paid to play
I want you to remember that because
The men whose places you've taken
forgot that a long time ago
Bring it in here
Bring it in, guys
Let's play some football!
-DC!
-All right!
For some of these players,
this is another shot.
And a last shot for a guy like Falco.
Remember that beating he took
from Florida?
That's nothing compared to those
beatings he took in Seattle.
One thing we do know is that
Falco can take a hit
Well, I'll tell you, he's sure
had a lot of practice at it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your Washington Sentinels!
-Did you see that?
-That's a pretty good hit
Will the medical trainers please
report to the east tunnel?
Maybe he was a little
overanxious, huh?
And now, the rest of
the Washington Sentinels.
Kick-off!
Let's go, let's go!
There can only be one leader out
there, all right? you be it
-That's where I stand
-No, it's not
-That's my spot in the huddle
-It's not
-Get to your spot
-Let's go, chopstick!
Let's play football! What do you say?
-It's my spot now!
-Not for long, you tub of rice shit!
What's the problem?
You can't do jack shit!
-Pork rice!
-I'm Japanese, not Chinese!
Don't mess with my brother
What's going on?
Something seems to be going on
in the huddle.
Falco's on his back.
-Come on
They haven't had a play yet
and Falco's down.
He got hit by his own guy! He was
looking out his earhole for a minute!
This isn't a good sign.
-Am I hurt already?
-Near knocked your head off
Let's go
Come on, get it together!
I'm the quarterback I'm the only one
who talks in the huddle
-But he was in my spot
-I don't care!
Now huddle up
If you've got something to say,
raise your hand
Is that understood?
Suppose you don't feel good
Or you're hurt
Tell me before the huddle starts
Okay?
Okay, here we go
DC Right, Switch 25 Blast--
What?
-To the left?
-The right
The left!
Be quiet or they'll hear us,
and then what?
Play game!
Number 16 on the offense! 5 yards!
Pat, so far the Sentinels
Have minus 10 yards offensively
I've seen monkey-shit fights
at the zoo more organized!
DC Right pro 424 Tomahawk,
on one, on one Ready?
Ready?
I'm coming for you, Footsteps!
Green 22!
Hut, hut! Hut!
Come on, Shane!
You could hear Falco's fillings
drop all the way up here!
Detroit takes over the football
with excellent field position.
-Give me an S!
-S!
-Give me an E!
-E!
-Give me an N!
-N!
-Give me a T!
-T!
Give me a
-I!
We'll get them next time
Eagle over cover four!
On three, get ready!
All day, blue eyes!
It's Christmas morning
And Santa's coming down
the chimney!
I'm gonna bury your family!
I'm gonna bury your dog!
Champ, champ!
Now that's football!
You get it? you like it?
The Sentinels set a record for
penalties in the first 3 minutes!
We 're waiting for the stats on that.
-Personal foul!
Number 56 on the defense!
Half the distance to the goal!
Bateman on that one
Just a cheap shot
-That should be worse than a penalty.
-They're walking right through us!
Touchdown, Detroit!
Don't worry about it
Let's go!
Double slot zag, okay?
-What?
-I don't feel too good
-Suck it up
-Come on!
Jesus Christ!
-Eggs!
-That's ripe!
What'd you eat, man?
If we don't move,
I'm going to blow chow, too
We're in a huddle!
Double slot zag, 88--
Jesus!
Goddamn!
I tried to tell you, I can't be around
somebody puking or I start puking
Shit
Okay, okay, okay, okay!
On three
Everyone move left Ready
Hut, hut, hut
What the hell is that?
What?
John, how many years we been
calling games together?
19, I think.
Ever seen that?
Not on a football field
-What are they doing?
-Beats me
Look at it this way It's the first
thing we've done together as a team
-Hey!
-Clean it up! Let's go!
Break!
Ready? Blue 42!
Blue 42!
Hut!
First down, Washington.
-Was it out of bounds?
-yes, on 23
-Blue Right 60 X Post
-Blue Right 60 X Post!
Let's go, let's go!
Now we rolling!
Signs of life from Washington here.
That last completion by Falco puts
them back in field goal range
-Field goal, let's go!
-Field goal
Nigel
It's over the bar, not under
Okay? Go get 'em
-Hold that
-Here comes the field goal team.
A 40-yard attempt for kicker
Nigel Gruff, against the wind.
Here's the guy from Wales, and he's
kicking his first field goal ever.
This is a tough distance.
Yeah, she's there! She's there!
-Boom! Boom!
Nigel Gruffkicks and scores!
Halftime score:
Washington 3, Detroit 14.
That's the second time
a Washington player has been...
-knocked out by his own teammate
-There's a rule in sports:
Don't do anything great if you
can't handle the congratulations
-There is?
-yep
-Give me an S!
-S!
-Give me an E!
-E!
-Give me an N!
-N!
-Give me a T!
-T!
Give me a
All right, let's go!
Touchdown, Smith! That one gets
the Sentinels back into the game.
This guy is a heck of a player,
but I don't know him.
And according to the Sentinels,
it says Ray Smith is--
That's weird! No college given,
no high school.
He 's been a resident
of the state of Maryland...
The last 2 years,
and he likes to embroider!
-He does fancy work with the ball
-Weird
Ready!
Green 11 !
Falco's sacked and the ball
comes loose.
It's Detroit's ball with
only a minute remaining.
Danny, Danny, Danny
I need that ball Get me the ball
You need the ball
-Get me the ball
-The ball
Are you gonna get me the ball?
I hope he doesn't kill somebody
I'm back! I'm back!
Get the ball!
I got it!
Now that is all-Madden team!
-you're the man
-I'm the man!
-you got me the ball
-I got you the ball!
-Go sit down now, Danny
-Okay
Number 56 recovers the ball.
-Falco!
We gotta pass
It's gotta be in the end zone
DC Right, Zig, 90 Eagle
you can do this
All right? Let's do it! Come on!
-Blue, 25!
-Here comes the pain, baby!
Blue, 25!
-Check!
-What are you doing?
Check!
Black 32!
-What?
-He's changing the play
He's checking off the run
It's a pass!
Shit!
Falco calls an audible
at the line of scrimmage...
...and Cochran almost has a touchdown!
Heartbreaker for Washington.
Final score:
Washington 10, Detroit 14.
I didn't want Cochran
to have that ball
-I read blitz
-Bullshit
I put the game in your hands
you got scared
I read blitz
Winners always want the ball
when the game's on the line
WFAN, the Sports Fan's Show.
How do you feel about the strike?
The fans are getting screwed. I got
season tickets I can't give away!
-What about the replacement players?
-They're nobodies.
At first I was afraid
I was petrified
Kept thinking I could never live
Without you by my side
But then I spent so many nights
Thinking how you did me wrong
And I grew strong
Why'd you play that dumb-ass song?
I put on The Commodores
That shit just came on
Can somebody please cut
that bullshit off?
-We did the best we could do
-you don't get points for trying
Let's face it, boys,
we screwed the pooch today
Hey, there they are!
Ladies and gentlemen
Your Washington Sentinels!
He's the luckiest guy here At least
he couldn't hear the booing today!
Hello! Anyone home?
Did I hear an echo?
Where'd McGinty get Rain Man?
Special Olympics?
No wonder they couldn't win
He can't even order a drink!
-Lay off
-Lighten up
It's not like he can hear
I can
What's that say?
"One good thing about being deaf,
you can ignore the assholes"
You asshole
That's funny
It's cool, it's cool!
You had enough?
You got shit for brains,
but you've got balls
Thank you
Danny, remember what I told you
about red shirts in practice?
-Forget about it
-Okay
Martel
Who's the man? Who's the man?
Come on! Come on!
Come on, come on! Stop!
Let's play football, bitch!
We are all God's children here!
"And deliver thee into the hands
of brutish men!"
Ezekiel 21 :31
This is some old bullshit!
It's more of a homecoming for you.
You gonna be a funny man?
Bateman! Wilkinson! Come on,
guys, what are you doing?
Can't we all just get along?
Come on
Why are we the only ones in this jail?
-Simple They're winners
-Hell, no Not tonight
That was pretty sweet, you
sitting on Wilson's head, Jumbo
Thanks, Jamal
He wasn't the only one
who kicked ass
You the man tonight,
Clifford Franklin!
What?
You were hiding behind the jukebox
Wasn't he?
At first, I admit, I was afraid
-Shit, I was petrified
-you were petrified?
Thinking I could never live
without you by my side
-The Lord is by your side
-Have mercy
Then I spent so many nights,
thinking how you did me wrong
And I grew strong
You know I hate this damn song
I learned how to get along
And so you're back
From outer space
I just walked in to find you here
With that sad look upon your face
I should have changed that stupid lock
I should have made you leave your key
If I had known for just one second
You'd be back to bother me
Go on, now go
Walk out the door
Just turn around now
'Cause you're not welcome anymore
Remember this?
Weren't you the one who tried to
Hurt me with goodbye
Did you think I'd crumble
Did you think I'd lay down and die
Oh no, not I
I will survive
As long as I know how to love
I know I'll stay alive
I've got all my life to live
I've got all my love to give
And I'll survive
I will survive
Hey, hey
It took all the strength I had
Not to fall apart
Kept trying hard to mend the pieces
Of my broken heart
But I spent oh so many nights
Just feeling sorry for myself
I used to cry
And now I hold my head up high
And you see me
-Four, five!
Okay, all right
Frankie
If anything like this bar fight
happens again
There'll be no place
on the team for any of you
-Do I make myself perfectly clear?
-yes, sir
And just for the record
I would love to have seen
Martel get his ass kicked
Let's get out of here!
Hey, Shane
What are you doing?
My job
-you're a professional football player
-Sure, this week
When that's all over, you know
I'll be back here
I don't want to lose my customers
I was on my way to work
Do you need a ride?
I'm good
-I got my truck back
-How is it?
Flatter But it runs
And you? How are you running
after last night?
You hear about that?
I think the whole town heard
about that
Is that from the game or the fight?
I'm not sure It's all blurred
into one big beating
The good news is,
you guys got into a rhythm
Apart from that vomiting thing,
which was on Sports Center.
Oh, God
After that,
the team was really clicking
Yeah, it was starting
to come together
Yeah
-you want to sit down?
-No, I should go
Thanks for coming by
-Wow Ow
-What? What?
Oh Ow!
Jesus!
-It looks worse than it feels
-It looks like hell
-Then it looks exactly like it feels
-Here
"Wild yam"?
Yeah
Don't laugh, it works It's great
for sore muscles and bruises
-I use it all the time
-you don't have to do that
You'll put it on? you can't move
This will be a little bit
-Cold!
-Sorry, sorry
Here, your shoulders
Better?
Better
You're the first player
I can remember
Who cares more about his teammates
than himself
That's something this team's been
missing for a really long time
It's a good thing you did last night
It was just stupid
Thanks
-I'm gonna be late for work
-Practice?
No, actually, I have work
We only make 50 bucks a game
Gotta pay the bills, right?
Mac's, down on A Street
Come in, I'll buy you a beer
All right, I'll do that
Keep putting that yam on
Guys!
You gotta be kidding
I didn't park in your space
No, no, no
But unfortunately, you did park
in Lamont's space
-He's not nearly as lenient as I am
-On three, fellas
-We got this We got this
-you want to put the car back?
This is none of your business
Shane is our business
-We're the guards
-And we protect our quarterback
This is funny to them bozos
you got jokes? you got jokes?
That's your ride right there,
ain't it?
Yeah
That's my windshield--!
-Now put the car back
-Son of a bitch!
Son of a--
Oh, son of a bitch? I'm a son
of a bitch? Son of a bitch?
Stop, stop, stop!
Come on, goddamn it, help me!
You're gonna pay for this!
No, I'm not And stop messing with
my man, that includes his ride
And wax that motherfucker
Give it a tune-up too
Ready to go to practice?
Yeah, let's do that
-How's that arm?
-Good
What's that smell?
Wild yam
-That's nice
-you like that?
And so, boys and girls,
if anybody does have any firearms...
...you need to turn them in
as soon as possible.
No questions asked
Understood?
All right
Okay, coach, it's all yours
Last Sunday, I saw a team on the field
play as hard as they could
To win the football game
We lost Not because
of effort or desire
But because of lack of leadership
and trust One's been resolved
But leadership means nothing if
we don't believe in each other
Players spend years together
before they develop trust
I'm asking you to do it in a week,
not reasonable but
These aren't reasonable times
I know you all have concerns
about this Sunday
But a real man
Admits his fears
I'm asking you
to do that here, tonight
Who wants to start?
Let's talk about fears
Fears Fears
I'm scared of spiders, coach
-That's not what I meant
-I'm afraid of spiders too
Goddamn spiders freak me, too, fellas
Well, I didn't mean that--
Ever get one of those spiders
crawling up your arm?
-Crawling on you?
-Damn!
Thanks, Jumbo you can just
rock me to sleep tonight
Okay, that's great, but I'm talking
about what scares us on the field
Like spiders on the field?
Can we get beyond the spiders, please?
Bees
Bees?
-Bees?
-Bees
Anybody here afraid of anything
other than insects?
Come on
Quicksand
Shit, yeah!
Quicksand's a scary mother, man
It sucks you right in and even
if you scream, you get that muck--
I don't think that's it
That's not what he had in mind
-What's he talking about, then?
-Ask him
What's up, Shane?
You're playing
And you think everything is going
fine But then one thing goes wrong
And another
You try to fight back, but the harder
you fight, the deeper you sink
Until you can't move
You can't breathe
Because you're in over your head
Like quicksand
That's some deep shit
Some deep shit
Anything else?
-Going back to the mini-mart
-The shipping yard
The auto plant
Prison
Yeah, all right
The truth is, you guys have been
given something
That every athlete dreams of
A second chance
And you're afraid of blowing it
We all are
But now our fear is shared
and we can overcome it together
Let's lose that fear this Sunday
and put it into San Diego!
Come on!
Another vicious hit by
the All-Pro Hank Morris.
That's his third of the game.
It's just me, dickhead
I tell you, he is really putting
a hurt on Falco.
I'm not sure how much more
of this abuse he can take
Huddle up!
Same play, except let Morris by
Nobody touch him