>> may 11, 2011.
From comedy central's world news
Headquarters in new york, this
Is "the daily show with jon
Stewart."
Captioning sponsored by
Comedy central
[theme song playing]
[applause]
>> jon: Welcome to the show.
Hey, everybody, welcome to "the
Daily show."
My name is jon stewart.
We have put together a program
For you tonight that will defy
All other programs.
Tonight's guest, the great, the
Great albert brooks.
[cheers and applause]
Hey, remember like a week ago,
The president released his birth
Certificate and celebrated his
Newfound citizenship by having
Someone shoot osama bin laden in
The face?
[laughter]
It felt like the events were
Connected, like maybe we'd
Finally put all these ginned up
And ridiculously overblown
Non-controversies, like the
Birther thing, to rest.
We were going to focus on things
That matter, winning the war on
Terror, the budget, fiscal
Things, getting things done.
Well, I hope you enjoyed that
Period of time.
>> first lady michelle obama is
Hosting a poetry reading, and
One of her guests is raising a
Lot of eyebrows tonight.
He's a chicago poet and a rapper
Who goes by the stage name
"common."
>> he's a reverend wright
Defender.
It sounds like he's a promotor
Of cop-killing.
I've looked at some of his
Lyrics.
They are raunchy.
They are rough.
They are raw.
>> yeah, let's invite a
Misogynist to the white house.
[laughter]
>> jon: Are we really doing
This again, for this guy,
Common, the guy from the queen
Latifah rom com?
The guy from the gap ads?
Elmo's friend?
That's the guy?
That's the guy we're going to do
This for?
That's your misogynist copicidal
Black supremacist?
Hey, fox news, have you told the
People who work on foxnews.Com
Yet?
>> I am here with common.
How you doing?
>> what's going on?
>> you're known as the conscious
Rapper?
How important is that to you and
How important do you think that
Is to our kids?
>> jon: Well, I guess that
Explains fox news.Com's slogan,
Shhh, fox news doesn't realize
We're here.
[laughter]
I mean, for god's sake, this
Two-time, grammy-winning,
Vegetarian's invite to the white
House has the twitterverse very
Upset, and by twitterverse, I
Don't mean people on twitter.
I mean twits, who took the time
To ignore common's entire body
Of work, save for one poem he
Wrote in 2007 that they appear
To misunderstand.
>> burn a bush because for peace
He no push no buttons.
>> no weapons of mass
Destruction, how can we follow a
Leader when this is a correct
One.
>> my uzi weighs a ton.
>> he's talking about popin'
Guns and I got the black strap
To make the cops run.
They watching me, I watching
Them.
>> whoa, whoa, whoa, when we
Roll together with a strapped
Gun, we're going to be rocking
Them to sleep.
That sounds like killing cops to
Me.
>> whoa, whoa.
>> that sounds like killing cops
To me.
Sound like killing cops to you?
>> jon: No.
Well, if you enjoyed, that
You'll love this album of fox
News personalities ruining songs
From many of your other favorite
Hip-hop artists.
Now that's what those people
Call music.
[applause]
Now, those more expolice celt
Lyrics, the more explicit lyrics
Describing violent action that
Hannity was quoting, those
Lyrics actually end on the
Couplet, "no time for that cause
There's things to be done.
Stay true to what I do so the
Youth dream come."
Basically common says, you know
That violence I was talking
About earlier in my poem, let's
End that in our communities so
Our dreams can come true.
It's a call for peace.
But hannity makes a good point.
It sounds like killing cops to
Him.
[laughter]
And if fox newsstands for
Anything, it is a zero-tolerance
Policy for any individual who
Might have or actually did write
A song about cop killing.
>> and happy birthday to rapper
And actor ice-t.
He is 52.
[cheers and applause]
>> jon: Well, to be fair,
That's different because ice-t
Was not celebrating his birthday
With obama.
What about the phrase in
Common's poem, "killing over oil
Burn a bush, because for peace
He no push no button."
It appears to be a metaphorical
Call of violence against the
President, and while it isn't,
You can say it was.
[laughter]
It would be like saying to the
Critics of the president, don't
Retreat, reload, you know, or
Drawing targets over your
Political opponents.
Surely fox wouldn't defend that
Type of incendiary language.
>> we've heard sarah palin say
That her supporters shouldn't
Relax or retreat, they should
Reload.
>> which is a very alaska-type
Term.
>> political rhetoric often use
Military term, holding your
Fire, search and destroy, that
Kind of thing.
>> it's very sinister to me
Because I think there is an
Effort here to silence
Opposition voices.
>> anything to shut her down,
Shut me up, shut talk radio
Down, shut fox news off.
Then everything will be sunshine
And lollipops.
>> jon: Oh, right.
Oh, right, like the obama
Administration would allow us to
Have sunshine and lollipops.
Ha, ha, more like spf50 and
Broccoli.
[laughter]
But you know what, maybe I
Should re-examine some of these
Lyrics.
Maybe I'm being unfair by
Showing fox news personalities
Holding a musician to a much
Higher standard of language and
Behavior than a presidential
Candidate.
Anybody who wrote a song with
The lyric, "first time I
Shotter, shotter in the side,
Hard to watch her suffer, but
With the second shot she died"
Or, "early one morning while
Making my rounds, I took a shot
Of cocaine and I shot my woman
Down."
That is some hard-core
[bleeped].
I hope a killer like that is
Never allowed anywhere near a
President of these united
States.
>> johnny cash, the man in
Blake.
Major, please read the citation.
>> johnny cash, for his
Contribution to the music and
Entertainment industry.
[cheers and applause]
>> jon: I heard you shot a man
In reno just to watch him die.
[laughter]
[mimicking george bush laughing]
Seriously, hannity, what's the
Difference?
What's the difference?
Would you be this concerned
About a musician who used the
Same type of rhetoric or
Violence about president obama.
>> if this was somebody who used
The same type of rhetoric about
Violence against president
Obama, I would be against it.
>> jon: Oh, if only we had the
Tape.
[laughter]
I mean, that would really make
You look bad.
[laughter]
Too bad we spent all day having
So much fun listening to johnny
Cash album, so we didn't have
Chance to find a tape that would
Be the absolute clearest -- I'm
Kidding.
We have it.
>> you punk.
Obama, he's a piece of
[bleeped].
[inaudible]
>> that was friend and frequent
Guess of the program ted nugent
Expressing his feelings towards
Democratic presidential
Contenders barack obama and.
>> are you prepared to disavow
This low life?
>> new york I like ted nugent.
He's a friend of mine.
>> jon: This isn't even fun
Anymore.
[laughter]
I barely even get angry about
This.
I just feel sorry for you guys
Now.
It took longer to play that clip
Than it took to find it.
We've actually started burying
These tapes around the office
Just to make it sporting.
[laughter]
It's almost impossible to
Express how ridiculous this and
You all are at this point.
It's beyond a caricature of your
Own cartoon.
I think the only way to get it
Across would be through a more
Artful medium, a more expressive
Form, perhaps a musical
Iteration of the spoken word.
Give me a beat, yo!
drop some beats, yo
[laughter]
Yeah, yeah
this goes out to fox news
And all the pundits I address on
Tonight's show
yo, fox
You create shocks with now awe
you dress like eagles
But squawk like chicken hawks
you're pigeons on a statue
Leaving little lies behind you.
going after obama
Week after killing osama
let me put in a pause
Comma
because I need a minute to
Think of what would say next
that would rhyme
[laughter]
You push [bleeped]
the kind you find fall from a
Schnauzer's behind
have you lost your damn mind
You got lazy
it's crazy
Even glenn beck's leaving
because he thinks you're
Forgazy
you still got gretchen
Hannity, hannity, yo
straight up insanity
Hey, homes, let me take a moment
To power one out
for alan [bleeped] combs
[cheers and applause]
o'reilly, oh, really
I know that you feel me
because I joke to the folks
While you choke on their smoke
are you choking
Mistrust
miss greta van sus-turnen
Just ran on her show
a night ago
Cause megyn kelly said so
you know I'm about to go
Program.
I will never rap publicly again.
Welcome back to the program.
Osama bin laden is still dead,
Which creates an important
Question: Who will be america's
Next toppenmy?
With more on the search for next
Bin laden, we turn to lewis
Black and "back in black."
[cheers and applause]
>> exciting times for al qaeda.
For the first time in decades,
There's an opening at the top,
And they shouldn't have any
Problem filling it.
It's got a good starting salary,
Great benefits, plus you get
Cable.
So let's take a look at the
Applicants.
Wow me, people.
Well, the obvious choice is
Osama's second in command.
>> ayman al-zawahiri considered
By almost everyone who knew him,
Terrorism experts, to be
Dangerous and capable.
>> dangerous and capable?
I got the same performance
Review when I worked at foot
Locker.
[laughter]
You phase one eight-year-old.
Well, I'm satisfied.
He sounds perfect.
Any down side?
>> zawahiri, he doesn't have it.
He's a classic number.
Two he's not a number one.
>> I don't know.
The last number one sure seemed
Like a number two to me.
[laughter]
I'm talking about poop.
>> jon: Yes.
I know, lou.
>> who else sent in a red --
Resume?
>> an war alawarki.
He speaks english fluent
Obviously.
He speaks in a language that
Young people can understand.
>> he's down with the kids.
He even has his own app.
It's called "really angry
Birds."
Death to america and pigs.
This guy sounds pretty great,
But sitting backwards on his
Prayer mat and rapping with the
Kids isn't enough.
What's the catch?
>> he's in yemen.
He's not in afghanistan and
Pakistan with the other al qaeda
Leaders.
The last thing they need is to
Try to do this across seas,
Across ocean, across country
Country lines.
>> and he's not moving to
Pakistan.
Have you seen what $1 million
Gets you in abbottabad?
Not to mention what you have to
Pay the government to pretend
You're not there.
Now maybe we should look at a
Few resumes.
Here's an interesting candidate.
>> mastermind of a serious plot
Last year to target europe.
>> I like him, but no one would
Believe he's a terrorist.
Because he looks like he's
Disguised as a terrorist.
[laughter]
Well, let's wrap this up.
I've got time for one more.
>> once a battlefield commander
In afghanistan who rose to
Prominence for escaping from
Bagram air base.
>> is al qaeda really ready for
A black leader.
I know obama was a big hit, but
Republicans tried to jump on
That bandwagon, too, and look
How that worked out.
Laughter I don't know, though,
No one really stood out.
But if al qaeda is just looking
For a guy full of hate, to yell
Into a camera every few months,
They can do worse.
Jon?
>> jon: Thank you very much,
Lewis.
So generous of you.
>> jon: Welcome back.
My guest tonight, oh, the
Funnest writer, actor, director,
Also now a novelist.
His new book is called "2030:
The real story of what happens
To america."
Please welcome back to the
Program the great albert brooks.
[cheers and applause]
>> thank you very much.
Respect.
>> jon: Thank you very much.
>> very nice to see you.
>>I want to give you a complime.
>> jon: Please.
Is this about the food in the
Green room because we try very
Hard?
>> no.
The last week and a half of all
The shows, your bin laden stuff
Has been the best.
>> jon: Thank you very much.
[cheers and applause]
>> and you also did this thing
Last week, you had the animated
Royal wedding.
>> jon: Yes.
I got the taiwanese animators to
Do a project for us.
They came in and the greatest
Phone calls in the world were
Passed back and forth.
Can I get hitler with strapon?
Okay, thank you.
>> well, actually, they have
That in the catalog.
Stock foodage.
I want to talk about this
Wedding for a moment because I
Think I need to see a sigh die
Trisms I can't stop thinking
About this kate middleton.
>> jon: Really?
>> seriously.
I dream about her, I think about
Her.
I want to be her first jew.
[cheers and applause]
And I'm sure only jew.
I want to wake up with this
Woman, and what is all this
Hair?
Maybe I fell a sleep with a mop.
I can't stop thinking about her.
>> jon: Is this the first
Time?
What is it about her?
Is it the youthfulness of her?
>> no.
>> jon: I have not spent much
Time thinking about this, but...
You definitely need to see a
Psychaiatrist.
>> the whole world, I don't
Know, we need a king.
I want to bow down to somebody,
What can I tell you.
Anyway, go on.
>> jon: This is why... What
You have done... Remember
Defending your life painted such
A great picture of heaven and
Hell and the afterlife, you have
Now in novel form done sort of a
George orwell, kurt vonnegut,ed
A lewis huxley, this is the
World in 2030.
>> I tried to write what I
Really thought could happen,
Because most future stuff,
Nothing comes true.
You know, I mean, when I was a
Kid, I read about the flying
Cars.
>> jon: Sure.
>> come on, jon.
You ever see jews drive in
Miami?
You think they're going to be
Flying in the air?
Beep, beep, what is that?
It's just shut up.
>> jon: Is that the most fun
Part of doing this?
What I love about the book is
Every little thing that you see
Sort of as an eccentricity in
Modern society today you
Extrapolate and you create these
Great... The main conflict of
This is the old versus sort of
The younger generation.
>> yes, I feel and I can see it
In my own children that in a
Number of years these younger
People are going to try to kill
Us.
[laughter]
>> you know, it's...
>> jon: When you see that in
Your own children...
>> it's something I sense.
I made that movie "real life,"
And I was right about reality
Television, don't screw with me.
>> jon: If you ever get to see
"real life," this t greatest.
It's like nostradamus but so
Funny.
I love you.
Can I just tell you, I love your
Movies.
Their just so damn good.
[applause]
I can see...
>> yes, I wrote this as a novel
Because I'm only give an small
Budget.
I can't write... No, seriously.
You know, my screen writing is
Like... I've learned how to
Write to a few million dollars.
You write, it was a dark and
Stormy night and then you cross
Out that and you write, it was a
Clear night and then you
Realize...
>> we can't afford rain.
>> then you realize night's too
Expensive.
Then you write, "he woke up in a
Room with the blinds closed."
But here I have a pilotless jet
Quietly landing at reagan
International airport.
I wrote that and I looked behind
Like someone was going to arrest
Me.
You got to go to writer's jail.
You can't write that.
That was why I wanted to write a
Novel.
>> jon: As someone who is
Accustomed to to feedback for
Movie audiences, live audiences,
Did this drive you crazy?
>> no, this is glorious.
The thing I like least is test
Audiences.
>> jon: The feedback is the
Worst.
>> some people do well with
Cards.
I imagine steven spielberg, god
Gave him cards when he was born.
But I'm telling you, modern
Romance, you know, they pick up
The cards, right, why is all
That hair on his back?
So this was a wonderful
Experience to be able to write
For a year and a half and alone
Without any studio.
>> well, I'm going to do that.
If you have a couple minutes and
You're very gracious, I'm sorry,
We're going to throw the rest
Of... I just want to ask you
Some questions of comedy and
Things like that if that's okay.
The book is "2030" albert
Brooks, you got to go pick this
>> that's our show.
Here it is, your moament of zen.
>> art and literature are often
The first targets of tyranny
Because they're the most
Subs straight from CC