[Fireworks Exploding]
Walter.
[Speaking Portugese]
I do.
Florinda.
[Speaking Portugese]
I do.
[Speaking Portugese
Continues]
-[Cheering]
-[Whistles Blowing]
## [Salsa]
You've made me
very happy, my dear.
I am happy too.
I wish only that your son
would have come to our wedding.
-My son has problems.
-How can he have problems
with a father like you?
He has problems
because he has a father like me.
-[Man Shouting In Portugese]
-[Camera Shutter Clicking]
[Man] Dear Walter, wedding snap
of me and your new mom.
We won't be coming to New York
for the 2.9 million reasons
you are aware of. Love, Dad.
P.S. Give my best to the Cheap Girls.
They were my favourite.
[Woman]
Very pretty, your new mom.
We used to be a respectable
law firm. Now look at him.
-Looks happy to me.
-He steals the money, I get the bills.
Dad, why did you
do this to me?
-Well, I can see why.
-Good night, Walter.
[Lamp Switch
Clicking Off]
##
# I feel your every breath #
# I hear the words you say #
# And I keep turning back #
# To hear the music play #
[Echoing]
# Play #
# I'll make no promises #
# False promises
can break you #
# How can you call me home #
# Wanting me like yesterday #
# Where do we build a house #
# How do the roses grow #
# Are you and I in love #
# How do we really know #
# If love is on our side #
# You'll know
when I'm in trouble #
# That's when
my heart decides #
# To go
wherever you will go #
# The heart is so willing #
# To follow #
# The heart shows the way #
# Out of the night #
# The heart roams #
# In search of tomorrow #
# When your love takes #
# The hand that guides
the light #
[Echoing]
# Light ##
-[Walter] "New mom. '"
How old is that girl?
-[Woman] Good morning, Walter.
Don't they have any laws in Brazil?
Don't they have any police?
[Woman]
Don't be so conventional.
[Scoffs]
I'm a conventional kind of guy.
That's all I ever wanted to be,
just conventional.
A little house in the suburbs,
a white picket fence...
maybe a dog,
2.4 kids...
and just to round it out...
a wife.
Will you marry me?
Walter...
[Sighs]
my darling...
I love you very much.
But why do we need a piece of paper
from the state of New York?
One bad experience, that's all.
You just had one bad experience.
Just give me
a little more time.
[Sighs]
Okay.
But I can't live
this life of shame much longer.
You're gonna have to make
an honest man of me.
-I like the kissing part.
-[Giggling]
-[Door Opening, Closing]
-[Men Chattering In Russian]
-Did you hear that?
-What?
Somebody just came in
our front door.
[Chattering Continues]
-Be careful, Walter.
-[Bedroom Door Opening]
-Oh, my God! You're still here?
-[Laughing]
Boat has docked.
He's here, you're out.
Who the hell
are you?
[Speaking Russian]
Maestro is back!
I thought he wasn't coming back
until next week.
[Speaking Russian]
You know Maestro.
He surprise you.
What are you talking about?
Who is this guy?
-I thought I had a year.
-You did, but year has come and gone.
[Speaking Russian] What you do?
You stayed in bed all the time?
Didn't look for apartment?
I... did.
There are no apartments.
Yeah, right.
Who are we talking about?
Who is this guy? Who are you?
I'm talking to him,
he won't answer me.
-When is he coming here?
-[Man] Oh, maybe
a minute, maybe an hour.
But he will come.
It's him you're talking about,
isn't it? The lunatic is back.
Yes!
I thought he was in Europe.
[Man] He was,
and now he's back, and you're out!
Oh. All right.
I'm sorry.
Look, guys,
why don't I talk to him.
Maybe we can
live here all together.
[Laughing, Chattering]
Wait. Wait.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You're not lookin' at
a charity case here.
If this is his apartment,
we'll get out. It's no problem.
Could you just give us
a few minutes alone?
Sure, I understand.
Have a nice day.
What are we gonna do?
This is New York City. It takes months
to find a place, even if you're rich.
And we're broke!
We're doomed, homeless, penniless.
-Doomed.
-I'm sorry, Walter.
No, no, no. It's not your fault.
We both knew he was coming back.
It's just that we've
been so happy lately.
Jack can help us.
Isn't Jack in jail?
No. No, he got off
with a small fine.
-Jack's a perfectly legitimate
real estate agent.
-[Sighs]
Well, as long
as we're together.
-Nothing bad can happen.
-Mmm.
-[Woman] Good morning, Realty Office.
-Oh, here's a beautiful place.
It's only an eight-hour commute
to New York City.
You don't get in more
than once a week, do you?
[Walter On Phone] I'll even go to SoHo.
I looked at a loft there a few years ago.
It was $350 a month.
It's probably gone up, but...
SoHo, 350 a month. Let's see,
Eisenhower was president, right?
-I'm worried, Jack. I'm very worried.
-[Buzzing]
Listen, Walter,
I gotta take a call.
Meet me at
the jogging track at 1:00.
You won't recognize me.
I'm so thin!
Where have you been?
You're almost late.
Martha, in this country
we have an expression for almost late.
It's called "on time."
-You don't seem nervous.
-I'm not.
[Chuckling]
She's not nervous. I'm nervous.
You're hysterical.
How is Walter
taking it?
Taking what?
There's nothing to take.
[Gasps]
Here he comes!
Thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you.
It's a great pleasure
to be back with you again.
-I'm sure you feel the same.
-[Sparse Laughter]
When I left, you were
the finest orchestra in the world.
God knows what a season under
the heavy hand of my esteemed
colleague has wrought.
Let us assess the damage...
with the Haydn,
from the beginning.
## [Begins]
# Bring me higher
and higher #
# Give me lovin' #
# P-Please me tonight ##
-Jimmy!
-Watch it. Watch it.
-## [Continues]
-Jimmy!
Big guy! Big "W."
What's shakin'?
I've got some papers.
The band has to sign these.
-What is it?
-Well, it's the Roy Rogers
restaurants we bought into...
and I sold off
the Tucson property.
This is their share,
and this is mine.
Now, I figure that cancels out
half my father's debt...
but check your records,
make sure we agree.
-Walter, what are you
payin' them back for?
-Huh?
They're used to people
stealin' from 'em.
This is only gonna confuse 'em.
They've got too much money now as it is.
You're their manager.
Why are you telling me this?
Because I like you better
than I like them.
But they're your sister
and your brothers.
## [Ends]
The union forces me to allow you to go to
lunch in spite of the way you've played.
Those of you with consciences
will not be able to eat.
And those of you whose consciences
match your talents...
go stuff yourselves.
I hope you choke.
Jog with me, Wally.
I don't wanna break
my rhythm.
-How long have you
been doing this, Jack?
-Oh, six months. It's great.
Next month I'm gonna run in a 1 -K.
Would you believe it?
Before I started this,
I couldn't fit into these clothes.
I feel better. I look better.
I sweat better.
-So you called my office.
-[Beeping]
-Do you have some good news for me?
-Good news?
When you hear what I got for you,
just remember this is a conservative club.
Don't rip off my shoes
and kiss my feet.
-You don't have to worry about that.
-[Grunts]
You asked for an apartment?
Something nice, yet affordable?
Uh, Jack, could you sweat
the other way, please?
-Wally, will you listen to me?
-Not if you keep calling me Wally.
-[Beeping Resumes]
-Oh.
-What is that?
Oh, it's nothing.
It's a pulse alarm.
-Well, maybe we should stop.
-No, no, no.
These things are unreliable.
Walter, can you get your hands on
$200,000 by close of business Friday?
-[Beeping Accelerating]
-Well, let me see.
If I sell everything I own,
maybe I can buy you lunch.
-[Gasping]
-Jack?
-[Gasping Continues]
-Jack? Jack, are you all right?
[Siren Wailing]
-I'm fine, really.
-Take it easy, Mr Schnittman.
-Has this ever happened before?
-Yeah.
Seven times
in the past five months.
-I thought jogging was getting you
in better shape.
-It is.
Yeah. Thanks to the jogging,
now I can lift him into the ambulance.
Walter, this is
a million-dollar house, literally.
I just want an apartment. My girlfriend's
ex-husband returned from Europe today.
That's nice.
No, we have to get out of his place now.
It's an uncomfortable situation.
Why would somebody sell
a million-dollar house for 200,000?
Who knows?
A divorce, loan sharks...
drugs, sudden death.
The point is: You get to capitalize
on a fellow human being's misfortune.
That's the basis of real estate.
Have we got a deal?
-## [Classical]
-[Maestro] You are
more beautiful than ever.
-Thank you. So are you.
-[Chattering]
Why did we ever
get divorced?
-So we could look better,
for one reason.
-Hmm.
-Can I speak frankly?
-Anything's possible.
Anna, I have learned
that my life is meaningless without you.
I know we made
a mess of things before...
but I wanna put the past behind us
and begin again fresh...
and at the same time
older and wiser.
-Can we do that?
-No.
-What do you mean "no"? Why not?
-I love Walter.
-"Walter"? What Walter?
-Oh, Max, you know exactly what Walter.
-Don't be ridiculous.
He's not even a musician.
-Many people aren't.
Anna, please,
I have finally discovered...
there is only one person
in the world who matters to me.
And that's you.
I've known that for a long time.
No. You love me,
and I love you.
You love you.
I love Walter.
-Will you stop saying that?
-Max, it's over for us. Over.
All right.
Then just go to bed with me.
[Ping-Pong Ball
Bouncing]
A few of the Maestro's things.
He moves back in today, you know.
Yeah, I know. Party's over for you guys.
You'll have to go home.
Some girl called.
Said she'd taken a lot of pills...
and was gonna kill herself
if you didn't call her.
[Walter] No, no. I get those calls
two or three times a week.
-She really sounds bad.
-[Doorbell Buzzing]
I think she sounds awful,
but she sold six million records last year.
-Walter!
-Hey, how are ya?
I gotta get some food
right now!
Okay, we promised never to come to your
place again, but this is a major crisis.
It's not my place
any more.
When your father took all our money,
you were so nice to us.
-You washed my hair.
I didn't forget that.
-## [Piano]
We trust you.
We need your advice.
I am sure I did not
wash your hair.
Look, I gotta get up early
tomorrow and go see Benny.
-You see Benny?
-[Man] He sees Benny?
-What's your problem?
-We want to change the name of the band.
You can't do that!
You've spent years and a fortune...
to make your name
a household word.
Your name is perfect.
"Cheap Girls." I love it.
-I'm not sure it's us.
-[Burps]
-It is.
-We wanna call ourselves "Meryl Streep."
-[Man Shouting]
No, no. You cannot call yourselves
"Meryl Streep."
-Maybe she'll be flattered.
-No, in fact, considering your act...
I think I can guarantee
a giant lawsuit.
-## [Piano Continues]
-[Clattering]
Don't take off your coat.
Forget it.
You are not calling yourselves
"Meryl Streep."
-Come on, we're gonna go see a house.
-A house? Where?
An hour away
from everyone.
[Man]
How about "Debbie Reynolds'"?
Thanks very much.
Keep the change.
-This can't be it.
-It's the address.
[Anna]
It's beautiful.
I know.
Somethin' must be wrong.
Well, let's go see.
-Hi! Come on in.
-[Anna] Thank you.
## [Classical]
[Door Closes]
Mmm.
Excuse the way
the place looks.
I really let it go to hell
since Carlos left.
But the house
is beautiful.
Carlos and I
were very happy here.
It's all over now.
The living room's in here.
-This is great.
-Fabulous.
Listen, if you want
any of the furniture, it's all for sale.
Well, I think that we'd like
to decorate it ourselves.
I'd sell it cheap.
I need all the money I can get.
Goddam bloodsucking lawyers
are bleeding me dry.
[Chuckling]
The floor just needs a little polish.
The bedroom's up here.
I'm trying to save a few bucks on the
lights... for the bloodsucking lawyers.
-I think it's lovely.
-[Stairs Creaking]
There's a tricky step.
I keep meaning to fix it.
What a beautiful bed.
-Could I use your bathroom?
-Would you use the one downstairs?
All my personal things
are still in this one.
Oh. Sure.
Happiest moments of my life
since we left Paraguay...
have been spent
right here in this room.
You lived in Paraguay?
Ten wonderful years.
Carlos is from Asuncion.
Or at least he...
[Weeping]
I'm awfully sorry.
About what?
I don't know actually.
Do you wanna
buy the bed?
l-I think so.
You know, you think
you know somebody...
after 25 years...
and then one day...
Israeli Intelligence
comes to the door.
Israeli Intelligence?
Last Tuesday.
That's why I've gotta sell the house.
It turns out,
Carlos was Hitler's pool man.
-[Toilet Flushing]
-Mm-hmm.
Ouch!
There's a lot of grounds,
but the maintenance isn't too bad.
-I've always done it myself,
but you could hire a gardener.
-"A gardener"? No, no.
I could handle this.
This'd be a piece of cake.
[Anna]
Really?
[Car Horn Honking]
-[Brakes Screeching]
-[Anna] Fabulous car!
-What's it called again?
-It's a Lincoln.
-They don't make 'em like this any more.
-It's a beauty.
Do you like it? I'll throw it in
if you buy the house.
That's very generous.
I'm desperate.
Can we close?
Well, we need
a little time to...
There isn't any time.
Extradition is Friday.
-Extradition?
-I'll tell you later.
-I need an answer
by close of business tomorrow.
-[Walter] Oh, you'll have it.
By the way, you have the most
beautifully kept pool I've ever seen.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
[Weeping]
[Walter]
What did I say?
Jack was right.
We can't lose.
-Nothing can be this easy.
-Sure it can. You know what this is?
-This is the short line
in Motor Vehicles.
-What?
You go to Motor Vehicles
to get your licence renewed...
and you get on this line
that reaches to Spain.
And right next to it is this little
short line with only two guys on it.
But you don't get on that line, 'cause you
think something must be wrong with it...
otherwise everybody else would be
on it, so you waste three hours.
I got on the short line once.
It was for farm vehicles.
I want this house. I need this house.
We need this house.
-Could be great.
-Say "yes"!
If we do this,
we do it together.
I'm putting in half the money,
or I'm not going in.
-Great!
-I thought you'd give me an argument.
If I had any money, I would.
Where are you gonna get your half?
Max.
I'll sell him everything I got in
the divorce. What about your half?
I'm goin' straight to the top on this
one... Billboard's Artist of the Year.
-He, who last year alone
sold 22 million records.
-Benny?
-Yeah.
-Benny himself?
-[Train Horn Blaring]
-Did you hear that?
The train is coming, right when
we decided to buy the house!
-[Train Horn Blaring Continues]
-This has got to be an omen.
I can feel it! This is it!
Everything's breaking for us!
## [TVCartoon]
You say you have
an appointment?
I don't say I have
an appointment, I have an appointment!
-Hi, Mr Fielding.
-Hello.
-[Boy] What the hell does he want?
-[Man] I don't know.
[Boy] Didn't you ask him? What's
the matter, I gotta pay you to think?
[Man] Hejust told me he wants
to see you. Sorry, Benny.
Oh, well, that makes everything better.
Walter, how are ya?
Okay, you've seen me. Is that it,
or do you wanna talk too?
I wanna talk.
Figures.
[TV] Now I'll show you how easy
I can catch a woodpecker.
All right.
You've got five minutes.
Are you gonna
let her do that?
Are you gonna let my mother
clean that carpet?
-Thanks, Benny.
-Don't mention it.
-I made a nice pot roast.
-Don't mention that either.
[Chuckling]
He never eats.
Look, Mom, we're real busy here.
Why don't you go watch TV?
Hey, keep it brief.
I got a chick waiting in the Jacuzzi.
I wish I had
a hundred more like him.
There is a house
I want to buy.
Let's just cut to the chase, okay?
What do you want?
I want you to loan me
$200,000 in cash.
No.
-Benny!
-[Weapon Clicks]
-You shout at me?
-I shout at you!
I need that money,
and you're gonna loan it to me!
-I will not! No! No! No!
-Yes, you will.
Yes, you will! I saved you
ten times that in taxes last year!
-So what?
-Benny, if you don't
loan me that money, I'll...
-You'll what, huh? You'll what?
-I'll not like you any more!
[TVContinues]
-All right.
-Thanks.
-[Telephone Ringing]
-[Jack] Great!
-Great!
-[Telephone Hangs Up]
-They bought it! All right, gang!
-[Cheering, Applauding]
Way to go!
[Coughing]
-[Beeping]
-Not again.
## [Pop]
# Anyplace you would be #
-# Is certainly so perfectly
good for me #
-[Clattering]
# That any old hammer and nail
I find #
-# Just makes me high on sunshine #
-[Loud Clattering]
# Settling in our duds #
# Discovering the wonderful
highs of love #
-[Coughing]
-# A little brush and polish
and you'll see what I mean #
# We're sittin'on a dream #
# Step through that door #
# You'll see a grand room
with a view #
# And a new moon for two
out there #
# And just like real water
from those summer rains #
# Don't you know #
# Champagne will flow #
# Gold dazzle ring
upon my finger #
# Any stair we could climb #
-# Has got to be to heaven
and so divine #
-[No Ringing]
-# That all we'll ever
have to do is lie around #
-[Yelps]
# And watch the stars above us
fall down #
# We're callin'this mess
our own #
-# And tellin'all the others
it's home, sweet home #
-[Banging On Door]
# If we were really closing in
on yesterday's mess #
# We're both sittin'
on a dream ##
[Hammering Continues]
How's it going?
Fine. What's that
on your face?
The ceiling.
Seems to be coming down
in the bedroom.
Oh. Well, I'll get to that later.
I only got two hands.
-Okay. [Chuckling]
-Okay.
[Groaning]
[Squeaking, Clanging]
[Clanging Continues]
What the hell
was that?
All I did was
turn on the water.
-That's all?
-[Squeaking, Banging]
That doesn't sound good.
No.
You should see the...
I guess it's the water.
-I don't know. It's revolting.
-Okay.
So the plumbing's
not perfect.
We'll get it fixed.
It's not the end of the world.
-You didn't see that water!
-Look, this is an old house.
It's gonna need some work.
You've gotta expect that.
I didn't expect
that water. It had legs.
A little work,
a little care...
a little imagination,
and it's gonna be great!
It's gonna be fun
fixing it up. You'll see.
I don't know. I've never been
any good at that kind of thing.
-What kind of thing?
-Work.
You can't go into it with that kind of
attitude. You've gotta be more positive.
-I'll try.
-Oh.
A little care,
a little imagination...
and a positive attitude.
What was that?
Nothing, dear.
Son of a bitch.
-[Squeals]
-[Yells]
[Screaming]
[Anna Shouting]
[Screaming Continues]
-Oh, Walter!
-The stairs are out!
[Yells]
Honey,
you're on my fingers.
Oh...
[Screaming]
[Crash]
Sorry.
[Kiss]
[Thunderclap]
I'd help you with that, but somebody
stepped on all my fingers.
-I said I was sorry.
-[Thunder Continues]
I didn't expect your fingers
to be on the floor.
I know.
I'm just cranky.
I guess it's having just thrown
$200,000 into the toilet.
Either that
or the intense pain.
It's only the first day.
You're not gonna give up on it already.
-Oh, yes. Yes, I am.
-Oh, no.
No, you're not.
I'm not gonna let you.
There's a chance we could fob it off
on the Cheap Girls.
We're not
going to sell it.
The land, at least,
has got to be worth something.
The house
is going to be great!
Yeah, if we can peel
the rind off it.
-What?
-It's a lemon, honey, let's face it.
You can't just quit.
I'm a quitter,
and I'm not ready to quit yet.
[Walter]
Why not?
-[Anna] Commitment.
-[Thunderclap]
[Walter]
Oh. That.
You're right.
The house is gonna be great.
-I promise.
-[Kiss]
[Thunder Continues]
[Water Pouring]
-[Both Grunting]
-Lady, this is impossible.
-[Anna] Oh, nonsense.
You're doing fine.
-I feel like I'm gonna die.
You're not going to die.
I'm holding the ladder.
If you fall,
land on the mattress.
Hello. Yes. Yes. We're having some
problems with our plumbing, and I was...
-[Man] I can't move.
-Fielding. Walter Fielding.
-[Men Grunting]
-[Anna] Stop being a baby.
You're nearly there.
There's no reason why
you should've heard of me.
I don't have
any references. I just...
-Somebody here call a carpenter?
-Oh, yes. We did.
[Walter]
Yale. Yeah.
-Don't let go of the ladder!
-I wasn't really holding it, anyway.
How much
do I make a year?
Uh, how much
do you make a year?
Really?
-No. No, that's not a Jewish name.
-You're kidding, right?
Get out of my life,
would you?
-[Anna] Don't touch me, pig!
-[Man] Oh, you're cute
when you're mad.
-I'm serious. Get away from me.
-Hey!
-Stop it!
-Hey, let go of her! That's my wife!
Oh, yeah?
Well, I'm sorry.
She didn't say nothin'
about being married.
I just thought she was
good-lookin' wool.
This animal attacked me!
I didn't say anything about anything.
Look, I don't wanna
cause trouble.
If I came on a little strong,
I'm sorry, okay?
-No, it's not okay.
-Just get out of here.
Well, okay.
If that's what you want.
I think we should call
the police.
Hey, let's not
get nuts here.
-[Sighing]
-Who are you anyway?
Art Shirk. I'm the carpenter.
I think we spoke on the phone.
-You're the carpenter?
-Yeah. Well, I guess I'll be going.
Oh, wait a minute! Just wait a minute.
Maybe we can clear this up.
Clear this up?
What are you doing? He tried...
I know, but he's supposed to be
a really good carpenter.
-He tried to attack me.
-He just thought you were
good-lookin' wool...
an attractive woman.
-He didn't know who you were.
-I don't know who you are.
[Chuckling]
Look, uh...
do you know how hard it is to find
a really good carpenter?
Besides, I think
he's got a brother who's a plumber.
-Really? A brother who's a plumber?
-I think so.
-Do you think I should sleep with him?
-Maybe just this once.
[Chuckling]
I think I'm going to start dinner.
The house
is gonna be great.
Great.
Great!
-Hey, I'm sorry about that...
-Oh, it's all right.
You'll have plenty
of opportunities to make it up to us.
You know, usually a woman
calls a carpenter...
she's lookin' for
the old "hammer and nail."
-And I don't mean...
-Yeah, I know what you mean.
Hey, buddy,
did you really buy this house?
-Yes, I did.
-[Men Snickering]
[Both Laughing]
[Gas Hissing]
Now,
what was over there?
The stairs. It began right there
and it curved all the way...
-[Gas Hissing Continues]
-[Both Sniffing]
Oh, my God!
No, don't!
-[Pilot Light Ignites]
-What's the matter?
I was just
lighting the oven.
Just lighting... You could've
been killed! We could've all died!
Oh, well,
thank you very much.
I'm not completely helpless
in the kitchen.
I do know how
to light an oven.
Well, yeah, but...
-You mean this thing works?
-So far, so good.
Well, it's amazing.
What about the, uh...
-What do you call these?
-The burners.
-I haven't tried them yet.
-Maybe we shouldn't press our luck.
-Wanna see the refrigerator?
-No.
Water?
-[Grinding, Squeaking]
-No water.
We've got gas and electricity, though.
That's two out of three.
Art's calling his brother.
Oh, good news.
You're not gonna have
to sleep with him.
Just a little dinner,
some dancing.
-How long do you think all that'll take?
-Two weeks.
Really? That's all?
When do you think you could start?
Just as soon
as your cheque clears.
Couldn't you at least hang the door?
I've got enough cash for that.
Haven't got
the right materials.
Wood's rotten.
Won't hold a screw.
Which reminds me:
-I'm late for my next job.
-[Engine Starts]
-If you know what I mean.
-[Car Radio] # I gotta be me #
-# I gotta be me #
-Yeah, I know what you mean.
# What else can I be ##
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Coughing] In spite of
all the problems...
in spite of the prospect of indentured
servitude for the rest of my life...
in debt beyond
my wildest dreams...
I love the house.
So do I.
And I love you.
-Life is good.
-## [Violin]
[Door Closes]
## [Continues]
-[Insects Buzzing]
-[Birds Chirping]
[Zipper Zips Down]
[Water Pouring]
Prostate trouble?
-[Water Stops]
-[Zipper Zips Up]
[Birds Chirping Loudly]
[Door Opens]
-[Door Closes]
-[Footsteps Approaching]
Well, that was fast.
We have very weak trees.
"Weak trees"?
[Doorbell Chimes,
Winds Down]
I guess that's the door.
Hurry, don't let it ring again.
[Sighs]
Wait!
-You Fielding?
-Right!
My brother Art
recommended you.
-I don't usually take jobs in this area.
-I'm glad you can make an exception.
-Let's not get ahead of ourselves, okay?
-I'm sorry.
-Where should we start?
-Well, you could offer me a drink.
I don't know
where my manners are.
Here it is, nearly 11:30.
You must be parched.
What? Wait a minute! We haven't even
talked about the plumbing yet!
And we're not going to,
not with your attitude.
Oh, saving the good scotch
for the company, are we?
No wonder you've been turned down
by every plumber in the valley.
-That's not true!
-Don't make it worse by lying.
I'm not lying!
I haven't tried everybody yet.
Please,
you gotta help me!
I don't know.
Write me a cheque quick,
before I come to my senses. Five grand.
-Five grand... Five thousand dollars?
-That's just a deposit.
You didn't even...
Well...
I'm not tryin' to tell you your business,
but you haven't even looked at my pipes.
I looked at them three years ago.
You figure they've improved with age?
-[Engine Starts]
-[Car Radio] # Me #
# I gotta be me #
# What else can I be
but what I am ##
Prep school.
[Clears Throat]
Yale.
Phi Beta Kappa.
Four years of law school,
law review.
Are you all right?
Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
The secret is not to,
uh, look down.
Oh, why did you
say that?
Look down?
It's a secret.
I was fine
till you said that.
I'm sorry.
You're doin' great.
-Mm-hmm.
-Just great.
If you don't mind,
I'm gonna share this bath with you...
-because I can't do this a second time.
-Ooh!
I think that's
a swell idea.
That way you can save your energy
for more worthwhile causes.
Mmm.
Would you get the rest
of the water, okay?
-[Chuckling]
-[Sighing]
Hi, this is Julia Child with a tip
on making crepes Suzette...
that marvellous flaming dessert
that you do at the table.
You need a nice flaming set-up.
I've got a heat source there.
There's an attractive pan.
In the pan I have a mixture
of sugar, butter, orangejuice
and grated orange peel.
I'm taking a crepe,
and I'm bathing it in this mixture...
-[Crackling]
-[TV: Child Continues]
[Loud Crackling]
[TV: Child] I like to use
a no-stick pan and heat until water...
-[Tiles Breaking]
-[Electricity Crackling]
[Blender Whirring]
[TV: Child Continues]
... and on goes
some nice brandy.
Let it bubble up well,
and then dip it into your flames...
Ow!
Little problem in the kitchen.
Nothing trivial.
Well,
the turkey's done.
So is the kitchen.
Actually, it's a little overdone
for my taste.
Let's not
go there again.
-You don't want to
tell me what happened?
-No, I don't.
-I just want to relax
in a nice lukewarm bath.
-What about this?
[Walter] I don't think
that can hurt us any more.
[Laughing]
[Laughing Hysterically]
What are you doing?
-Save yourself.
-What?
I'm a menace
to anything I touch.
The Surgeon General's warning
should be tattooed across my forehead.
"Walter Fielding is dangerous
to your health. Don't touch him."
-Save yourself.
-I can't.
-I've tried, but I love Walter Fielding.
-No.
-I can't give him up.
I'm hopelessly addicted.
-No.
You must think of yourself!
I am sinking fast into the money pit...
and I don't want to
drag you down with me.
-Save yourself
while there's still time.
-Walter, brighten up.
-I hate seeing you like this.
-I hate being like this. I'm a disaster.
These are estimates from legitimate
contractors for repairs on the pit.
Those that will actually come out here
are so expensive, I can't talk about it.
Let's not talk about it.
I've just given
our last $5,000...
our last 5,000 borrowed dollars...
to the Shirks.
Walter, I don't mean
to be questioning you, but why...
They were willing to take it!
The legitimate people wanted
four times as much just to say "hello."
So it's the Shirks.
That's not so bad.
Well, that's if they show up.
Just because they showed up
to collect the money...
is no guarantee that
they'll show up to do the work.
And if they do,
I can't pay for it!
-I'm going to help you.
-Do you have a gun?
"Here lies Walter Fielding.
He bought a house, and it killed him."
If I could raise some more money,
would that help?
-Depends on how you're gonna
raise the money.
-Mmm.
-I think I know how.
-I know you know how.
Just stop.
I've got some things I can sell.
I don't wanna talk about money
or the house any more tonight.
Neither do I. We could just skip town,
borrow some bus fare.
Or we could hitchhike,
hit the open road.
Everything's gonna be
just fine.
-You'll see. Trust me.
-How?
-Don't you trust me?
-It's not that. It's just that...
We'll think of somethin'.
Who cares?
[Engines Rumbling]
-What's happening?
-Well, stay here. I'll find out.
[Men Chattering,
Shouting]
Hi. You must be
Mr Fielding. [Laughing]
-Yeah. Yeah. Who...
-I'm from Shirk Brothers.
Your number came up in the drawing
this morning. We work today!
Oh, that's great.
That's... Where is Brad?
Oh, South of France,
I think.
Uh, don't...
Shouldn't he be here?
Brad is the executive plumber.
We do all the work.
We're just about
to get started.
You're free to watch if you want,
though I wouldn't recommend it.
-Are there any living things in there?
-Well, my girlfr...
-My wife. What the hell.
-Oh, I'd get her out.
Hold it, fellas. Just a second.
There's a woman inside there.
Hold it!
Come on!
Hey, come on! Wait a minute, fellas,
there's a lady inside there.
H-Here! Here she...
H-Here you go. Okay?
Are you all right?
-Yes, thank you.
-Is everything out?
-Yeah.
-[Engine Starts]
-Okay. Have a nice day!
-Who are they?
-The plumbers.
-Are you sure?
No, and I don't care. I'm just thrilled
to see somebody actually working.
Mrs Fielding,
don't worry about a thing.
[Chattering,
Shouting Continues]
-Okay, guys, let's do it!
-Yeah!
[Anna] In our settlement you listed
the value of that painting at $ 100,000.
I'll sell it
to you for 75.
[Max] That painting
doesn't interest me.
Yes, it does.
You love that painting.
That's the only reason
I took it.
All you want
to talk about is money.
Let's talk about love and sex.
Forget love, let's just talk about sex.
Max, I'm desperate.
I need money.
I need new plumbing.
I need new appliances.
-A new staircase, Max.
-Stop, please. Too boring.
-Plastering, landscaping,
painting, a roof.
-Too middle class. Stop.
New floors, new tiles,
new fixtures in the bathroom.
Okay, okay, I'll buy it.
I'll give you the money.
Only, please, God,
stop!
Thank you, Max.
Sometimes you can be very sweet.
I know.
-How do I look in this?
-Oh, beautiful.
You look beautiful
in everything. Mm-hmm.
Hi!
Hi.
[Engine Sputters,
Dies]
What happened?
It was no picnic, but those boys
are work animals.
-Well, everything looks
pretty well under control.
-It does?
Well, not to the layman's eyes,
of course.
They completely ripped up
our house!
They sure as hell did!
They ripped the guts out of it!
They're work animals,
I'm telling you!
Look at
those holes!
Then you got
your gravel piles...
your sand piles,
your scrap piles.
-Animals!
-Animals.
Well, I like a good conversation
as well as anybody, but I gotta run.
Hasta pronto,
if you know what I mean.
-Y-You're leaving?
-Well, I ain't movin' in. [Laughing]
But we'll be back
when you get your permits.
Permits? The permit man
was supposed to be here by 4:00.
Oh, he was, but you or your wife
weren't here to meet him.
We weren't?
Anna's not here?
No, no.
I would've noticed.
The permit man
was pretty agitated.
Really steamed his clams.
Said he'd be back
when you grow udders and get milked.
-[Laughs]
-That's a long time.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, if he ever does come back,
you call me and we'll finish the job.
When I do get the permits,
how long will the job take?
Two weeks.
Two weeks?
You sound like a parakeet.
"Two weeks? Two weeks?" [Laughs]
Well, uh, two weeks.
It's... It's amazing.
-Amazing, nothing.
-[Engine Starts]
It'll be a regular miracle.
[Continues Laughing]
[Phone Ringing]
-[Ringing Continues]
-[Groans]
[Groans]
[Ringing Continues]
Hello?
Oh, hi there.
"Tone"?
My voice has no tone.
Because I'm standing
in a pile of rubble...
and we don't
have the permits to un-rubble it.
"Exaggerating"? Honey, we're living
in Swiss cheese with a door.
"Mozart"? Mozart is dead.
His troubles are over.
Help me!
[Sighs]
All right. I'm sorry.
You're right. If you had to work,
you had to work.
Oh, l-l-I love you too.
Where is the guy's number?
The permit man.
In the den, you think.
I will pick you up
at the station.
Just give me a call
when you get there. [Kissing Sounds]
"Shrapp"?
Is Mr Shrapp in?
Mr Shrapp.
Walter Fielding.
Hey, watch what you say
about my mother, now.
Mr Shrapp,
let's be adults about this.
I'm... Look, I'm very sorry
I wasn't here this afternoon.
My wife was poisoned
and taken to the hospital.
[Taps Foot]
Well, what would
cut any ice with you?
A bribe? Sure.
Can you be here in a half an hour?
All right.
Cash? No problem.
[Dial Tone]
Weasel.
Cash.
Cash, cash, ca...
[Grunts]
[Continues Grunting]
H-Help!
[Walter]
# Come on, everybody #
# I said
let's play a game #
# I bet ya
I can make a rhyme #
# Out of anybody's name #
Anna!
# Anna-Anna, bo-banna #
# Banana-fanna, fo-fanna #
# Fee-fi, mo-manna #
# Anna #
Let's try Brad!
# Brad, Brad, bo-rad
Banana-fanna #
-[Knocks]
-[Walter] Walter!
-Fielding!
-# Walter, Walter, bo-balter
Banana-fanna, fo-falter #
# Fee-fi, mo-malter
Walter ##
-[Knocking Continues]
-Hello... [Grunts]
Hello!
Hello! I'm here!
Are you in there,
Fielding?
[Continues Knocking]
Y-Yeah!
l-I'm here.
M-My chest
is constricted.
I can't shout.
O-Oww! Oww!
[Walter Groaning]
Okay, Fielding,
I can hear you in there laughing at me.
This is it,
you duck fart!
I'm leaving, and I'm never coming back!
Ya hear me, Fielding?
Y-Y-Yes, I hear you!
I'm tearing up
your permit!
There!
Nobody laughs
at Montgomery Shrapp!
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
[Brakes Compress]
[Anna]
Good Lord!
You testin' missiles here,
or what?
The house
is gonna be great.
[Truck Engine Idling,
Horn Blasting]
[Brakes Decompress,
Truck Pulls Away]
[Footsteps]
[Keys Jingling,
Lock Unlocking]
Shh.
[Door Closes]
Oh, my God.
Walter!
Oh!
Oh, A-Anna!
Thank God it's you!
Thank God! Ohh!
Walter?
-Thank God you're here, honey!
-Is that you?
[Laughs]
Is it me?
Ha! Is it me?
[Continues Laughing]
Anna, I've been here so long
I'm hallucinating.
A while ago I thought
the Care Bears were here.
Walter?
Farm animals, or geese and chickens...
[Continues Laughing]
Walter?
Upstairs!
Are you all right?
No, I'm not all right.
Not at all.
No!
-Where are you?
-I'm in the den.
No, you're not.
I was just in there.
I'm in the den. I swear it.
Please believe me.
Will you stop fooling around,
Walter? I'm tired.
I'm right here.
Look, Walter,
enough is enough.
I'm right here!
Where?
In the floor,
behind the chair.
[Laughing]
Ohh!
Oh, laughing.
[Chuckles]
-[Laughing Continues]
-We're laughing.
The permit man was here.
-Oh, that's good.
-No, it's not.
Now tomorrow I've got to
take off work, drive to his office...
and kiss his ass.
-Oh!
-[Thud]
-[Wind Gusting]
-Well, thanks to that fall
we're now the same height.
Yeah, that's much better.
[Wind Gusting]
-So, why did rehearsal run so long?
-That was my fault.
We got off to a late start because I was
haggling with Max over the painting.
How, exactly, would you
define "haggling"?
-What do you mean by that?
-I thought that was my question.
Are you jealous
of Max?
Jealous of Max?
Don't be silly.
Just because he's rich, famous,
good-looking, brilliant.
-I mean, what's he got
that I haven't got?
-Walls.
I feel much better.
Good night, hon.
Good night.
[Shouting, Chattering]
Look out for that thing.
You're gonna fall off of it.
[Shouting,
Chattering Continue]
[Moaning]
[Kissing Sounds,
Moaning Continues]
[Continues Moaning]
Get to work!
[Anna Screaming]
Four months
since I got those permits.
They're not even half done.
They said two weeks for the whole job.
You're telling me this
like I haven't been here.
We're going through
a rough time.
-Let's remember not to
take it out on each other.
-You're right.
You hear about that guy up in the Bronx,
went crazy, thought he was a pigeon?
They found him in the park
throwing bread crumbs at himself.
-He was just putting in
a guest bathroom.
-Okay.
So let's be nice to each other.
We're all we've got.
Don't forget
to get the water.
-Haven't I gotten the water
every morning for four months?
-Walter.
-Do I ever forget the water?
-Don't do this. Walter, Walter, Walter!
I'm sorry.
The bucket's
in the hall.
[Muttering]
I know where the bucket is.
You don't have to tell me
where the bucket is.
Stairs!
Ha!
A staircase!
We have stairs!
[Laughing]
Oh, hello, Mr Stairs.
I've missed you.
Anna?
Anna, darling!
Did you
get the water?
We have stairs!
[Laughing]
It's happening, honey.
Everything's
gonna be fixed.
[Sobbing]
We have stairs.
That's terrific.
-Everything's gonna be wonderful.
-Yes.
Sweetheart,
I could really use some water.
[Sniffling]
Yeah. Right away.
S-Say, Curly?
-Yo!
-Could you send up some water?
We're a little busy today, Walter,
tryin' to build a house.
I'll get it myself.
I'll use my new stairs.
That's my boy.
Tar bucket comin' down.
-Morning, James.
-Morning!
-Alka-Seltzer.
-Just a minute.
Any idea when you're going
to be finished here?
-Two weeks.
-That's what I thought.
Alka-Seltzer.
Here you go.
Oh. You know you're almost out
of birth control pills?
Thank you, James.
Walter.
Walter!
The water! I know.
I'm getting it.
[Whistles]
Hey, Walter!
You want this room painted blue,
like in the hallway?
No, I do not. That's all wood...
What do you mean, "like the hallway"?
The hallway.
Blue, right?
I want nothing blue.
Nothing!
Oh, man. Now I gotta go flush out
my paint sprayer.
Oh, that's a bummer.
-## [Radio: Opera]
-Have you seen Mr Fielding?
-Fielding?
-Yeah.
Don't know any Fieldings
around here. In Cincinnati...
Walter?
Oh, Walter!
Yeah, Walter.
He was supposed to bring me
a bucket of water.
-Bring you some water?
-Yeah. Do... No...
-Ohh! Ohh!
-How's that?
[Laughs]
It's a miracle.
[Continues Laughing]
Yeah!
## [Ranchero]
Walter.
-I wanna ask you something.
You're a lawyer, right?
-Yeah.
Last year my father
was hit in the head by a golf ball.
-## [Radio: Pop]
-Oh, can I unplug...
Now, he seemed okay...
but last week
we were watching TV...
and I put on the Bob Hope
Desert Classic from Palm Springs.
He goes friggin' nuts!
My father, not Bob Hope.
So he kicks in
the friggin' TV screen. Now...
## [Pop Continues]
I'd have to study it, but I'd say you got
a great case against Bob Hope.
Thanks, man.
[Saw Buzzing]
Aaah!
## [Opera Continues]
## [Bluegrass]
## [Continues]
## [Opera]
## [Opera Continues]
[Shouting, Screaming]
## [Opera: Finale]
-That was not so bad.
-[Musicians Laughing]
-[Man] Are you happy with that one?
-I am not unhappy with it.
It's the best that miserable symphony
has ever sounded.
You have my congratulations,
and you may go home.
-[Murmuring, Chattering]
-But don't you want to hear it back?
No, if there's something wrong
with it it's your fault...
and you will hang for it.
Do you have
a cigarette?
I'm sorry.
It was beautiful,
Max.
Better than Szell's version?
Mmm, I wondered why you did this.
I know you never liked it.
Well?
-It was better.
-Thank you.
It's a pity
that son of a bitch isn't alive...
because it would kill him
to hear that.
Have you got
a cigarette?
You stopped smoking
five years ago.
I started again
two weeks ago.
Can I have
the damn cigarette?
Mmm.
Filters.
You seem a little tense.
Your shoulders are up
over your ears.
-Are you all right?
-Don't I look all right?
In a word, no.
The only good part of our divorce
was that it seemed to make you happy.
For you to be without me
and unhappy...
is such a waste.
You are making me sad.
Walter's
in Philadelphia...
and the idea of going back
to that house, alone...
Oh, God.
Why don't we have dinner
and a huge amount of alcohol?
I'm not dressed
for a restaurant.
My place.
Our old place.
-You can have a hot bath.
-[Sighs]
We'll have a fire. Hwang will make
anything you want for dinner.
-Duck I'orange.
-[Chuckles]
Twelve-year-old scotch.
In clean glasses.
That can be arranged.
I'm not going to bed
with you.
I may not ask you.
[Sighs]
Oh, my God.
Good morning.
-Oh, my God.
-What's wrong?
What happened?
What did we do?
-What have we done? Oh, my God!
-Calm down.
-You were a little looped.
You sang a few songs.
-The Beatles?
-The entire catalogue.
-What else?
-You don't remember?
-It was duck for dinner. Right?
-Followed by crepe Suzettes.
-I don't remember the crepe Suzettes.
-You don't remember the piano?
-No.
-Under the piano?
-I don't wanna hear any more.
-It was incredible. Better than Zurich.
-Zurich?
-The police came.
You don't remember any of this?
-Oh, no.
My shoe!
-Not my shoe!
-Last night you were
the animal I remember.
-I don't need shoes!
-Come back to me, and the police
will come every night.
-I love you.
-This is a nightmare.
Last night you said
you loved me...
that we would be together
the rest of our lives.
I wasn't drunk,
I was insane!
-When are you going to tell Walter?
-Never!
-You're just going to walk out
on him without saying anything?
-I am not walking out on him.
I am in love with him.
Not you, him.
-No, this whole wonderful realization
has confused you.
-Oh!
Talk this over with Walter,
and you'll see.
-Lying.
-What?
I'm going to have to do
a lot of lying.
-No. Tell him the truth.
-I'll lose him.
-Hey, take a chance.
-[Door Slams]
[Man]
# Bump-bump-ba-bump-bump #
[Children]
[Man]
# Bump-bump-bump #
[Children]
[Man]
# Bump-bump-ba-bump-bump #
[Children]
[Man]
# Bump-bump-bump #
[Children]
[Man]
# Bump-bump-ba-bump-bump #
[Children]
-## [Continues]
-You'd better let me off here.
-I don't think you can
make it up the driveway.
-They testin' missiles here?
That's right, buddy, we are,
and it's very hush-hush. Top secret.
So forget you were up here
and forget you saw any of this.
-And forget about a tip.
-[Man, Children On Tape]
# I am a pizza #
-# Ready to munch #
-Ah, home, crap home.
-# I am a pizza #
-# I am a pi... ##
I still can't get used to the idea of
having hot water whenever we want it.
Yeah.
-So, what'd you do last night?
-Oh, nothing much.
Where'd you eat?
What?
Last night.
Where did you eat?
Oh.
The Four Seasons.
Well, I'm glad it wasn't
anything special.
Actually,
it was a little special.
We had just done probably
the finest performance...
of Haydn's
Surprise Symphony ever.
Really.
Uh, please tell me
you didn't pay.
I didn't.
Max took us.
-Well, that must have been
some performance.
-It was.
It's never been my favourite piece
of music, but we really did it well.
How was Max?
Fine!
I mean, he was very pleased
with himself.
He asked after you.
-Oh, that's... that's very nice.
-Mm-hmm.
Did you sleep with him?
I hope you don't mind.
-Of course, we can't go back
to the Four Seasons again.
-[Walter Laughs]
Did you?
Walter!
Are you serious?
Well, I know you weren't here
last night...
because I called,
and, uh, guess what.
I don't know.
You tell me.
-[Plate Slams On Table]
-No answer.
[Sawing Violently
Into Bread]
Walter, do you want to tell me
what you're saying?
I'm not saying anything.
Actually,
what I'm saying is...
that I would hope that if
there was something for you to tell me...
for example, that you'd spent last night
with Max... that you would tell me...
that it would be okay
for you to tell me.
You're just going
to have to trust me.
Oh, l-I trust you.
I do trust you. I just want you
to tell me the truth.
Well, I did.
Well, then,
that's the end of it.
You would tell me,
wouldn't you?
-Walter.
-I just want you to be honest with me.
I can take anything
except lies.
People slip up.
Christ, I understand that.
It happens all the time.
I mean, I'm not some meathead
chauvinist provincial.
-Is that all?
-No. No.
I'm jealous.
I'm very jealous of Max.
I'm not crazy about the idea
of you sleeping with him, but if
you did it and didn't tell me...
that would really
bother me.
Without changing my plea,
I would like to know why.
Because
it underestimates me.
Not telling me assumes I'm incapable
of understanding why you did it.
Not that you did it.
Had you done it.
Did you?
You want me to tell you the truth,
no matter how much it hurts.
If we can't be honest with each other,
what else have we got?
And you'll believe in me?
You'll understand?
Of course I will.
I love you.
I love you too, but I did not sleep
with Max last night.
No?
Can we knock this off
and go to sleep?
I love you.
Mmm.
[Click]
-[Click]
-Walter?
-Walter!
-[Mutters] Walter.
-Are you awake?
-Yeah!
Yeah, I'm awake.
What is it?
I have to talk to you.
Oh, I can't believe
I'm gonna do this. It's so stupid.
What is it?
What's the matter?
I lied to you
about Max.
Apparently I went
to his apartment, I got drunk...
I guess I sang
a few songs...
and apparently I, um...
slept with him.
-I know I shouldn't be telling you this.
-No. No.
It's okay.
It's only proved to me
how much I love you.
Oh, that sounds stupid too,
but it's true.
I love you, Walter.
I love you.
It's okay.
Everything's okay.
You won't hold it against me?
You can forgive me?
Sure. Can we talk about this
in the morning?
I'm so tired.
Do we have to talk about it?
Can't we just put this behind us?
Yeah.
[Chuckles]
I love you.
[Kissing Sound]
[Sighs]
[Click]
-[Click]
-[Walter] You whore!
I leave town for 5 minutes, you can't
wait to leap into the sack with old Max!
You... bastard!
-That's right! Laying it off on me!
-You hypocrite!
-I'm not the one screwing around!
-"Just be honest with me."
-How long has this been going on?
-You chauvinist meathead!
I'm not telling you
anything!
Now or ever again!
Oh, this is perfect! Guess who suddenly
turns into the injured party!
-Where do you think you're going?
-Someplace where you're not!
-Well, then, you stay here,
because I'm leaving!
-Fine!
Get out! I never want
to see you again!
[Splat]
The plasterer came?
## [Radio: "La Bamba'"]
##
# Para bailar la bamba #
# Para bailar la bamba
se necesita #
-# Una poca de gracia #
-[Loud Rattling]
# Una poca de gracia
par mi para ti #
-## [Continues]
-Hey, Walter.
What happened?
Your old lady kick you out?
I do not wish to discuss
my domestic difficulties with you, Julio.
That's okay. I figure she
threw his ass out.
-No, she did not throw my ass out!
-No, you had your chance, man.
This is between
me and Duke.
I'm not payin' you guys to stand around.
You wanna get to work?
We can't do nothin'
till the plumbin' inspector gets here.
There's no plumbing
in that wall.
-No?
-We can take off and you can
call us when he gets here.
Just stay where you are.
I fell for that one before.
Ooh! Ohh!
[Sighs]
## [Continues]
You're up
bright and early.
I didn't sleep very well.
You look great.
Got a date?
Yes,
with the Marine Corps Band.
I'm starting with the brass, and I'm
working my way to the drum section.
-Don't you think we should talk?
-This is not the time.
-I'm mad, and I'm getting madder.
-Oh! What do you think I am?
-I think you're a jerk.
-I know that.
-I didn't realize how big a jerk
I was until last night.
-Neither did I.
Let's just pack it in, then. Let's just
finish this thing right here and now!
-Fine.
-I'll pack a bag for you
and send the rest later.
-You expect me to move out?
-You shouldn't have
any trouble finding a bed.
-I got a bed, lady.
-Get the hell outta here!
This is private!
What makes you think you can
just throw me out of my own house?
You're the one
who's moving.
I have worked and slaved... suffered
and put myself in hock up to my eyes...
and you want me to move out
because you've got the hots for Max?
No way!
You hear me?
I have worked and slaved and suffered for
this house every bit as much as you have!
Actually more, because
I had to put up with you!
This is ridiculous!
You don't even like this house!
I love this house!
You've done nothing but complain
about it since we got here!
I did one other thing... I sunk every
nickel I had in the world in this house!
-And you'll get it all back!
-Me and everyone you've ever met!
"I'll pay you back"
will be written on your gravestone!
I wouldn't give lectures
on the value of promises!
-Your word didn't do too well
on this last outing!
-Yours is fine!
It's certainly a lot better
than your cheque!
[All Murmuring]
I'll get you
your money back!
I don't want the money!
This is my house, and I'm not moving!
It's a big house!
We'll divide it up!
You stay in your half,
I'll stay in mine!
That is such a dumb idea.
Sometimes it amazes me
you ever passed the bar.
I'm sure it does.
You've never passed a bar in your life.
You are so much less attractive
when I'm sober.
-Thank goodness it's not that often.
-All right, that's it!
I've had it with you, the house,
Max, the orchestra and everything!
How long will it take
to put this place together?
-Two weeks.
-[Workers Laughing]
[Man Laughing]
Two weeks! Two weeks.
Okay, we'll stick it out
until the house is finished.
Then we'll sell it, get our money back
and get the hell away from each other.
Fine.
Get back to work!
[Murmuring, Chattering]
Bam! Zoom!
[Sobs]
[Speaks French]
[Speaking Vietnamese]
What are you doing here?
-You missed a rehearsal.
-That's right.
-Did you tell Walter
what happened between us?
-Yes.
And what
did he say?
Walter and I are through.
-I hate us both.
-You'll get over it.
-You'll come back to me.
-No.
I'm just going away
someplace.
You can't go anywhere.
We have performances.
You don't understand. I have to
get away from here, from both of you.
You are leaving
the symphony?
What have I done?
Oh, it wasn't your fault.
It was my fault.
I was weak.
No, you weren't.
What?
I made it up.
You made what up, Max?
You slept in the bedroom.
I slept in the living room.
Sex would have been
a miracle.
Oh, Max!
I wanted you back, and I truly thought
I could make you happy this time.
Oh, Max.
Tell Walter the truth.
No.
He couldn't forgive me,
and I can't forgive him for that.
He's lost a wonderful woman,
and I know what that's like.
I've lost many.
-You must hate me.
-No.
I used to hate you.
Now I hate Walter.
Lucky guy.
[Workers Chattering]
-Walter!
-Well, this is an unexpected revulsion.
Are you hot?
Can I take your life?
I can see
that my presence here...
could be construed
as in poor taste.
-No!
-Do you realize what you've done?
You've taken
a woman who loves you...
one of the great women
on the face of this Earth...
and thrown her away.
I've lost her too, but I'll get over it
because I am shallow and self-centred.
But you, you won't
because you are complex.
You will suffer terrible anguish
for the rest of your life.
This is turning out to be
a pretty good day.
-Good day.
-## [Whistling]
Smooth strokes.
Up and down.
Paint,
don't tickle.
And don't smoke.
## [Whistling Continues]
Well, folks, I guess this is
hasta "so-long-a."
[Chuckles]
You know,
just between us...
there were a couple of times
when I didn't think we'd ever be
able to put this baby back up.
-But it, uh, it turned out.
-It's beautiful, Curly.
It is, really, much better
than I imagined.
Thank you.
That's very nice of you.
One more job, though.
Here's your key.
It's the only one I've got.
Who wants it?
Hmm?
Well, I'll just put it
on the bannister here.
You'll have no trouble
selling this place, that's for sure.
-Shirk Brothers'll give you
a million for it tomorrow.
-Great.
No, this wasn't an easy one, but the
foundation was good, I'll say that.
And if that's okay,
then everything else can be fixed.
Well, goodbye, folks.
Good luck.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Well, this is it.
Are you going
to spend the night here?
No. You?
I'm already packed.
I'd better get packed
myself.
I'll get my bags.
Walter?
This step.
This... This was our step.
This is where
it all started to...
Turn to crap.
[Sighs]
Too late to put it
back together, isn't it?
You slept with Max,
and I don't care.
What?
I don't care.
Well, I care, but not enough
for us to be apart.
Really?
Really.
I'm glad you slept with him, because now
I know how much I really love you.
You sleeping with Max was the best thing
that could've happened to us.
I didn't sleep with him.
Thank God.
## ["Ode to Joy'"]
##
## [Singing In German]
-## [Continues]
-[Shouting, Laughing]
##
-Ohh!
-[Man] Over here!
Always a bridesmaid, never a bride.
##
## ["Ode to Joy":
Rock Version]
Look at me! Hey! Walter!
A big smile!
Hold it! Hold it there!
One more! Ready?
Hold it! Way to go!
Thank you. I got it.
It's a very nice house,
and the price is reasonable.
[Laughs]
Reasonable? It's a steal.
Oh, honey!
It's so beautiful.
You buy or not?
-We're buying.
-[Giggles]
You can count it if you like,
but you'll find it's all there.
[Woman]
Carlos, come on!
We haven't got all day!
Let's go!
[Chuckles]
Mein wife.
Auf wiedersehen...
Ah.
Hasta la vista.
# Where shall we build
a house #
# How do the roses grow #
# Are you and I in love #
# How do we really know #
# If love is on our side #
# You'll know when
I'm in trouble #
# That's when
my heart decides #
# To go
wherever you will go #
# The heart is so willing #
# To follow #
# The heart shows the way #
# Out of the night #
# The heart roams #
# In search of tomorrow #
# But love takes the hand #
# That guides the light #
# When shadows fall #
# And there's no one there #
# To help or listen #
# I feel your every breath #
# I hear the words you say #
# And I keep turning back #
# To hear the music play #
# I'll make no promises #
# False promises
can break you #
# How can you call me home #
# Wanting me like yesterday #
# How do we fix the moon #
# How do we change the sky #
# How do I make you laugh #
# The way I make you cry #
# I'll make no promises #
# False promises
can break you #
# But love's no accident #
# Time is on our side #
# The heart is so willing #
# To follow, oh #
# The heart shows the way #
# Out of the night #
# The heart roams #
# In search of tomorrow #
# But love takes the hand #
# That guides the light #
# The heart is so willing #
-# To follow #
-# Yes, the heart
is so willing to follow #
# The heart shows the way #
# Out of the night #
# Oh, the heart is so
Oh, the heart is #
# The heart roams #
# In search of tomorrow #
# But love takes the hand #
# That guides the light #
# The heart is so willing #
# To follow #
# The heart shows the way #
# Out of the night #
# The heart roams #
# In search of tomorrow #
# And love takes the hand #
# That guides the light #
# The heart is so willing ##