Hi, and welcome back to
another episode of Télévision Educative.
Tonight, l will show you
how dreams are prepared.
People think it's a very simple
and easy process...
...but it's a bit more
complicated than that.
As you can see, a very delicate combination
of complex ingredients is the key.
First, we put in some random thoughts.
And then we add a little bit
of reminiscences of the day...
...mixed with some memories
from the past.
That's for two people.
Love, friendships, relationships,
and all those ''ships'' ...
...together with songs you heard
during the day...
...things you saw and also...personal.
Okay. Okay, l think it's one.
There it goes. Yes. Yes.
Okay, we have to run.
l'm talking quietly to not
wake myself up.
l'm with my dad.
Yes, Dad. I remember.
My father was there.
It's nice to see him healthy
and normal again.
I almost forgot how he looked.
Handsome, no?
Oh, yeah, oh yeah, we're in a concert.
A Duke Ellington concert.
Yes, my man, Duke Ellington.
And the band starts to play.
Bass, drums and all.
It's amazing, they got this super swing.
And the Duke enters the stage.
He's radiant, in a glowing white tuxedo.
Dad, this is not Duke Ellington,
but Duck Ellington.
This is a dream.
I'm sorry, Dad, but you're dead.
You've lost the battle to cancer.
No, no. I cried so hard.
I could feel my tears forming
two rivers under my eyes.
In dreams, emotions are overwhelming.
Come in, action two.
Can you complete the mission?
Ski?
-English very well.
-Oh, good, good.
-Yes, picture one is a duck.
-Me too.
Am l not supposed to design
the new calendar collection?
No, no, l'm afraid not.
Because my mother,
she told me this was a creative job.
This doesn't look creative at all.
You know,
l think there's a misunderstanding.
Can l see?
-Sure.
-Yeah?
This is nice.
Yeah, not bad, eh?
l'll tell you what.
Take the portfolio and
let's talk to the big boss here, okay?
The collection is crap anyway.
Welcome in this palace, Stéphane.
Stéphane is a great artist
with a foreign accent.
He'd like to suggest something.
What about the ski weekend?
Did you put him on the list?
You see, Stéphane, it's very, very important
to stimulate the team spirit.
Martine.
You should show him your work, okay?
Be brave, Stéphane.
Well, it's still a bit of a work in progress.
l've done 1 2 paintings for a calendar.
Hello, ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain speaking.
We will be reaching Paris' Charles de Gaulle
in 6 hours and 45 minutes.
Please enjoy the flight,
fasten your seat belts...
...and if you have any questions,
please don't hesitate to:
The pilot will never finish the sentence.
Flight 800, on July 1 7th, 1 996...
...disappears from the sky.
Spraying its 230 passengers
all over the North Atlantic.
The whole world is in shock.
Quiet morning,
like any other morning.
A huge earthquake
rattles the center of the town.
Each month has its own
most infamous disaster event...
...engraved in the collective memory.
lt's a concept l've been trying to
work on and developing.
lt's called disasterology.
Stéphane, you are not serious.
Oh, l am very serious.
lt's the customer that needs
a little bit of a sense of humor.
My customers don't have
any sense of humor.
They want puppies, trucks,
flowers or nudes. That's all.
Come on, Guy, show him his work.
lt's getting late now.
Come on, Stéphane, let's go.
You shave with a cracker?
Oh, you little asshole!
Sorry, no. No, no, no.
l need a break. No, no, no.
No, no, l need a little break.
Serge, l need a little break.
Guy, just a tiny one.
La pampa is in Argentina, you idiot!
What about Yucatán, Palenque, Kerala?
Get out.
Come in, action two.
Can you complete the mission?
lt's 7:30.
Hello?
Are you trying to mock me on the air?
A creative job,
ls that what you call it?
No, Mam-- Mama. Mama!
Excuse me for this interruption.
Yeah, that's my father.
P.S.R.:
Parallel synchronized randomness.
An interesting brain rarity
and our subject for today.
Two people walk in opposite directions
at the same time...
...and then they make the same decision
at the same time.
Then they correct it,
and then they correct it...
...and then they correct it
and then they correct it....
Basically, in a mathematical world...
...these two little guys will
stay looped for the end of time.
The brain is the most complex thing
in the universe...
...and it's right behind the nose.
Fascinating!
l'm sorry, l'm sorry.
l'm sorry about this.
Stay calm.
l think that's just that they are
renovating the studio right behind here.
-You are Spanish, no?
-No.
-No?
-l'm from Mexico.
But my mother is French.
Yeah, l just came here because
my father died of cancer.
Okay. You know,
that looks pretty bad.
You think l have to go
to the hospital?
Beause it's not looking that good....
Good stuff for you.
Okay?
-lt's strong.
-lt's mint. lt's mint.
-Yeah, l feel it working already.
-Yeah? Okay.
-So, what's your name?
-Stéphane.
Stéphane? Stéphanie.
Stéphane, Stéphanie.
Stéphanie, Stéphane.
Click-clack, catch, match.
She has no boyfriend.
-And you? You...?
-Zoé.
You know,
Stéphanie is a talented composer.
-You should hear what she makes.
-That's bullshit. l never play it.
You know, a pretty girl with talent,
that deserves to be mentioned.
Yeah.
And what's your job?
l'm a promotional calendar
maquettiste. Yeah, it's--
That's typical from Sylvain.
He asks you to help and then
he lets you do all the work.
l am sorry.
So what does it mean exactly,
promotional calendar maquettist?
Maquettiste. lt's--
l don't know.
l don't know. lt's really boring, actually.
But l mean, there's one profession
l really wanna pursue...
...which is inventor.
-lnventing what?
-Well, l can show you.
l have some glasses...
...where you can see real life in 3-D.
lsn't life already in 3-D?
No-- Yeah, but--
Come on, l mean,
Do you wanna-- Do you wanna try it?
This, for example:
Look, look, look.
-lt works, no?
-Yeah, yeah.
You know Pulfrich, the guy who
discovered the 3-D effect?
He had only one eye.
And that makes him, like, the Beethoven
of the stereo, you know?
And what do you girls do?
Are you students or work?
-No, we're--
-No, we're creative executives.
We're going to concerts
and we find bands to sign.
To sign what?
Oh, she means that we're working
in music.
What company?
Aristotle.
Like, as the turtle, no?
No, no, no.
Like the philosopher. You know?
l'm gonna go.
How do you know Sylvain?
-Sylvain?
-Yeah.
-From Mexico. Yeah.
-Oh, Mexico.
He never said anything about it.
No? l don't know why. Bye-bye.
-You want us to drive you back?
-No, l'm okay.
To screw. Maybe yes, maybe no.
Maybe rain, maybe snow.
Okay, baby.
lt's three times this week
he puts his ass on the poubelle.
-We're not gonna wait for them?
-No, no, no.
l can't believe that my mother lied
about the job just to get me over here.
lt's completely unethical to do that
to your own son. lt's horrible.
lt's the worst job l've ever had
in my life.
Your predecessor....
He committed suicide
two weeks ago.
No.
No. l'm joking.
No, he left after two weeks.
Come on, man, just get along with
the job and we'll have some fun.
Do you think Martine is pretty?
Martine? From work?
No, Martin Scorsese. Yeah.
l don't-- l don't think about that.
Well, imagine...
...if she comes and gives you a blowjob
in the darkroom....
You know, l can arrange this for you.
So getting laid is all that matters?
lt doesn't matter who the person is?
You see, l'm not a creative person,
like you.
l don't feel the need to leave a trace
behind me...
...except a fart sometimes.
Sorry. lt escaped me. Come on.
You know, the other day, l saw
an old man on the bench.
He was smiling, you know, really happy.
You know what he was thinking of?
His grandchildren?
Not at all.
lf you don't know, don't improvise.
No, he was thinking about all the dirty
stuff and naughty stuff...
...he did with the girls
when he was young.
How do you know that?
Did you ask him?
l know that because...
...this man was me in the future.
And l was happy.
l simply want to be like him
in my old days.
You know, l have this neighbor
that has a friend...
...that is very pretty, actually.
Oh, good reason to stay, my man.
Be careful, you know,
with the whole neighbor situation.
That's the problem, that l think
it's the neighbor that likes me...
...not her friend.
-Yeah.
-Danger.
l never get the one l like, anyways.
Maybe she's a good cook.
-Stéphane? Did you forget something?
-Hey. Hi.
No, no. l was just-- l was just--
You know, my hand? Because l can--
Are you looking for Zoé?
She's not here.
-She doesn't live here, you know?
-Oh, okay.
How's your dad--? Your hand.
My dad? My dad's still dead.
l'm sorry.
You want Zoé's number?
No. No, l think l'm fine.
-So l guess l'll be on my way now.
-Okay.
Bye.
l'll do my laundry later. Maybe l should
check this hand of yours.
Okay, well, yeah,
it's better to be safe than sorry.
Sorry, it's not funny.
l think it's funny.
l mean, it's not that funny--
l mean, it's not funny,
but l find it funny.
Come in.
lt's still chaos.
l'm going to put my bed up there,
to save some space.
How do you call it? A ''mezzanine''?
Mezzanine, oui, mezzanine.
Do you make those?
Some l made and others l adopted.
You have to find who.
-You made this one.
-Nope.
What's his name?
His name is...
...Golden the Pony Boy.
When l found him, he was so sad
that l had to buy him for a lot.
-He's never going to leave me now.
-Really?
l understand that you're the mother...
...but you also have to think
of his interest.
Yeah, it's possible.
But he is already damaged.
l can't take any chances.
Let me see your hand.
You know, it started to smell like a foot.
lt's a good sign.
Can you move it?
Yeah. Well, it hurts a little bit,
but it's okay.
-l have too big hands.
-Yeah?
That means you have a large penis.
l'm sorry, that was a bit inappropriate.
Look, l'll show you a trick.
lt's a brain effect.
You have to-- You have to do this:
Okay.
lt feels so weird. lt feels like if it
wasn't my hand.
l know one that you have to....
You have to put your two fingers
like this:
...and then you look into the distance,
like that:
-All you can see is a little--
-A little sausage, yeah.
l know it. lt's a good one.
Oh, you know it?
l made this boat in fabric.
l have to put it
in a small forest as a setup.
The boat is looking for its mer,
which is--
lt sounds like both ''mother''
and ''sea'' in French.
So the forest inside the boat?
That's genius.
That's like a vegetable Noah's Arc.
No, no, no, the boat is in the forest,
looking for his mer.
But l need to make the trees, though.
Okay, but you know, the forest
inside the boat...
...that's a really good idea.
l think that maybe
you wanna do that instead.
Yeah, yeah. Okay, l'll do it.
lt sounds like a good idea.
Okay, so l'll go get my dad's
old camera...
...and we can make an animated film
of the forest inside the boat...
...looking for its mother.
And the leaves grow and the wind
catches in them...
...then the boat takes off.
You'll make the sea, okay?
Okay, yeah. Well, we can do it with
layers of paper, like this:
You know, like this and they move
in opposite directions, you know?
Yeah. Yeah, but we have to find
something more special then.
Kind of retarded in a way.
Look.
-Cellophane.
Yeah. Yeah, like a Russian
animated film.
My mother, she collects thousands
of bonbon wrapping paper...
...and also cardboard tubes.
We've got boxes full of them at home.
What for?
She used to do this arts and crafts
thing and other projects...
...but she never finished them.
l actually can't stand it,
she never finishes anything.
-And look, for the clouds.
-Oh, yeah.
Oh, no, no, no. No, try it again.
Try it again, wrong chord.
No, wrong chord, try it again.
l knew it. l knew it!
Each structure has its own resonant
frequency.
You just have to hit the right chord
at the right time.
Okay, l'll go get the camera
and you go do the forest.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, by the time
you get back, l'll be sleeping.
And l need to finish the boat, anyway.
You bring the camera next time, okay?
Okay. Well, you tell me when to bring
the camera, okay?
Well, l'm leaving.
l'll start the forest tomorrow.
All right.
Bye.
-Okay, bye.
-Bye.
No, no, Martine.
Martine, no. No, no.
l'm sorry, l can't.
lt's-- lt's not you, it's me.
l feel guilty.
What is it, Stéphanou?
l can't live all my life
hiding in my apartment.
-l need to come clean.
-You are clean.
Aristurtle? Okay, okay.
Type this:
Dear Stéphanie:
-''Dear Stéph--'' Who is she?
-l am....
Forget about it, l need to write it
in French anyway.
Okay.
By the way, do you have Zoé's
phone number?
Thanks, Stéphane.
Where are you going now?
Stéphanou?
No, no, no.
''Do you have Zoé's phone number?''
Dear Stéphanie, comma.
I am just your neighbor,
there is nothing more to say than that.
This is the reason why I am writing
a letter to you...
...because I feel really bad inside
my stomach.
It's a mix between--
l don't know if what l feel is a bit
of nostalgia...
...or wanting to go to the bathroom.
l am just a new liar in your life.
A new liar that has come
and destroyed your piano...
...and maybe by doing that destroy
the huge heritage....
I want us to start a new start
and a new--
A new blank page of friendship.
And if you can embrace that the same
way I am embracing it right now...
...that l am feeling it right now,
l see the possibilities...
...once we go above that threshold
of life...
...and matters that succumb
and become trickling down...
...into this little pond
that is called life.
Full stop. The end.
Stéphanie?
-Stéphanie.
Stéphanie and Zoé lied to me.
They are not
creative executives. No! No.
Aristotle, my ass.
They think l'm stupid, but no.
You guys are gonna
help me find them, okay?
-Stéphane needs you.
-Okay.
-We've gotta find a way of--
-Go back to work.
Oh, no. To work? No, no, no.
lt's only a dream.
We don't have to work in dreams.
-No! Nothing is for real.
-You write, you write.
-You write!
-You're just the result...
...of a chemical flux in my brain,
that's all.
Do you mean we don't really exist?
Flux?
By the way,
do you have Zoé's number?
Hello?
Stéphane Miroux?
-Stéphanie?
-Yes.
Hey.
Did you finish the boat already?
No, no, of course not.
l still have some stuff to buy.
Optical tricks.
Yeah.
Yeah, l could show you one.
l got this really cool one. When?
Now?
Okay.
It'll take me, like,
35 minutes to get there.
Maybe-- l mean,
maybe l can make it in 1 5.
-Yeah, okay.
-Yeah?
-Okay.
-Okay, bye.
-Hi.
-You were quick.
-Yeah.
l brought you this.
So basically, with cards, what we do,
l mean, because...
...it's kind of difficult. The cards
are there. The cards do not lie, you know.
lt cannot change.
So if you grab the cards
and you open them...
...and you name one card
and l point at it from a distance, okay?
But remember to send it to me, you know,
before you name it.
Send it to me, name it, send, name,
send, name, send.
-Okay.
-Send it.
Okay. Yeah, l received it. lt's there.
Yup.
-You saw that? Did you see that?
-lt's amazing.
Try another one.
Ace of spades is there.
Yeah.
What are you doing?
-What?
-What are you doing dressed like that?
lt's punk.
He's Guy. l work with him.
-We work together.
-He's what?
-Guy.
He's punk.
So? What?
Does she always dance like that?
Yes. Always.
Yeah? ls it only when she gets a bit drunk
or is it always like that?
-Do you mind?
-No, l have no problem. l have no problem.
l mean, l can't imagine how anyone would
end up doing that with Guy, you know?
Hey, l composed this piece of music
for your piano.
You could play it all night.
Try it.
-lt's called, ''My Dear Neighbors.''
-Thank you.
-lt's sweet.
-l hope you like it.
-Hey.
What are you doing? What are you doing?
What am l doing? You confuse me.
So you like her or you like Zoé?
Man, l'm just talking to her.
She's my neighbor.
We're just friends. Don't you believe
in friendship with the opposite sex?
No. She likes you, it's obvious.
Don't play with her.
l mean, she's great, you know.
She's a really nice person...
...but she reminds me of my father.
-What?
-Yeah, yeah.
Hey, we're going now.
Bye-bye, bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Hey, don't forget
the forest and the boat, eh?
Okay, l won't.
-Okay.
-Be a good boy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, good, okay.
Bye.
Stéphanie?
Stéphanie.
Stéph--
You're fired. Guy, you're fired.
You're fired. Do you hear me?
Do you hear me?
You're dogs. You're like the--
The dogs that bite the hand
of the owner that gives you food.
Serge, you betrayed me.
Guy, are you betraying me?
Television Educative is back for you
this evening for a new chapter.
Love after 50.
We have two very special guests
on the show today.
Gérard and Mom.
Gérard, you are a professional magician.
You look old and you live
in a small suburban house.
Why do you think Mom chose you?
Oh, yes, you're funny. Yes.
l wouldn't like to be
the woman you cut in half.
But hold on.
Okay, then.
Gérard, you're just a bullshit guru.
Mom, why do you
always fall for gurus?
You think you will learn
some deep truth about yourself?
My dad was not a guru.
Are you in love, Stéphane?
Stéphane? Stéphane?
No, no. No.
Do you know what REM means?
Rapid Eye Monitronics.
The eyes.
l can control my eyes in my sleep.
No more sleeping slavery.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are approaching the moon-- What?
The moon, yeah.
Scary, huh?
lt's very scary, huh?
No gravitation pull.
Earthquake and fire!
Okay, that's enough. That's enough.
Please, give us our--
l mean, your world back.
Tell us what to do.
We'll do anything.
Just don't make me work
like a slave all the time.
-Okay.
-Okay?
-Master.
-Okay.
-Peace.
-Okay. Okay.
-Hallelujah!
-Praise to you and to the new world.
-No, no, stop that.
Hey, no, no. Guys, no.
Stop that shit, okay?
lt's getting a bit creepy.
Are we still making calendars?
We are here to serve you.
Basically, l wanna
see Stéphanie in my dreams.
l know. l will make your novel,
I am Just Your Neighbor, into a bestseller.
-That will attract her.
-Then we'll organize a massive wedding.
Madame Stéphanie Stéphane.
Stéphane Miroux, your novel
I'm Just Your Neighbor and a Liar.
By the Way, Do You Have Zoé's Number?
is a blockbuster.
-Yeah.
-Where does your genius end?
Painting, sculpturing,
architecturing, writering?
Today, building has began on the
Stéphane Miroux Foundation.
A museum dedicated to your work.
So, Stéphane Miroux,
did you find the key to success?
Well....
Well, l think people empathize
with what l do...
...because it comes from here.
Oh, you are talking about Stéphanie?
Oh, l don't like to talk
about my private life.
So, Stéphane Miroux,
we have a little surprise for you to do.
No.
-A song for her.
-A song?
If you rescue me
I'll be your friend forever
Let me in your bed
I'll keep you warm in winter
All the kitties are playing
And they're having such fun
I wish it could happen to me
But if you rescue me
All the cars drive so fast
Stéphane Miroux. Stéphane Miroux.
Stéphane Miroux.
Let me into your world
Go now.
I'll keep you warm and amused
All the things we can do in the rain
lt's not working because you messed up
the title of my book.
You better be here
when l come back.
Okay, l'm exhausted.
l'm gonna wake up now.
Hey.
Stéphanie.
What a coincidence. l almost thought
that l was gonna miss you.
Would you like to marry me?
Come. Come with me.
l want to show you my friends.
Hey, guys? Guys,
let me present you to my future wife.
One, l don't believe in marriage,
two, you don't want to be with me.
And three, are you out of your mind?
No, l'm sorry. l'm sorry,
l thought that l was--
You thought what?
l thought that l was here.
And that l was working here,
sleeping in my office.
And then l came here, and then
this part l don't remember very well.
There were more people there.
And then l saw you....
Where exactly are you living?
l live-- l'm staying
with my mother right now.
So you're my landlord's son?
Yeah.
Are you sure you're okay, Stéphane?
Yeah, why?
So you were not asking me for real then?
No. To marry you, no.
But...
...l think l like you.
You mean in a romantic way?
Yeah, if you want to call it like that.
Come on, Stéphane.
l don't want to have a boyfriend.
Okay.
So now you'll act all weird around me
because l didn't want to--
No. lt's not my fault, you know,
if l have feelings.
You don't have to humiliate me.
Oh, come on, Stéphane.
Stop acting like a child.
Stéphane?
Working is the best remedy then.
Keeps your brain busy.
How can you work? Love is too powerful.
You can't concentrate.
Listen. Tell her right away.
lf it's from your heart,
she will understand.
She's with somebody, Stéphane?
What? l don't understand you, Guy.
l'm sorry, l don't understand.
l don't understand you either.
l can't understand you when you
talk to me in two different languages.
lt makes me feel schizometric.
Schizo-- Schizo--
Schizophrenic.
That's the word you're looking for.
-Yeah.
-Hey, don't pay attention to those losers.
Try to be more on time
in the morning. They'll leave you alone.
No, no, no.
NPC's for film.
CPN goes with CPP.
CPP.
CPP, NPC, CP-- l get confused.
You know the....
The goat on the cliff?
-The goat on the cliff?
-Goat on the cliff. No?
-lt's a sex position.
-l know it's hard for you to understand...
...but not every man is
a sex maniac, you know.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
Like every woman is romantic?
l don't know, but....
I am collecting beautiful objects.
A pair of shoes.
Some glasses.
Telephone.
Typewriter.
They are made from wood and felt.
With apparent stitches.
Their delicate and finished
appearance is friendly.
And they are quiet.
Stéphanie made them, and I will
expose them in an exhibition.
Stéphanie, do you think l could
take the red blanket as well?
Of course, Stéphane. Are you kidding?
There's this amazing blanket.
It's thick, red felt
with big white stitches.
Wild animals are running on it.
She smiles.
I bend over a rock to try to reach her.
My stomach, compressed, hurts.
Stéphanie?
Can you hold my hand?
l cannot sleep.
She takes it. I fall asleep.
The sea.
And the forest.
You should put more whites in.
You should put more whites.
Yeah?
No, a bit--
A bit more to the left, here.
-Oh, yeah.
-Randomness is very difficult to achieve.
Organization always merges back
if you don't pay attention.
Death to organization.
Hey, what's this?
-lt's the....
-ls it your mom's?
No. That's the one-second time travel
machine l told you about.
l finished it. For you.
You wanna try it?
What are you going to do
with one second?
Well, it just adds up.
And life is too precious.
So, basically, you put this here.
-Can you hear me?
-Yeah.
Oh, can you-- Okay.
So....
Just one second.
This is for the past.
And this is for the future, okay?
So let's try some for the past.
You have to press
this button, okay?
Let's try some for the past.
Hey, it's working.
Amazing scientific breakthrough.
...scientific breakthrough.
Yeah. No, wait, wait.
Let's save some for the future.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hey, what are you--?
Let me just....
Why did you do it twice?
The first time was the future...
...and the second one
was just the present.
Well, maybe we have different
perspectives on the future.
No, no, no. This is just a machine.
lt's objective. lt's just a machine.
Yeah, okay.
l'm not sure l should accept this gift.
Why do l deserve a present, anyway?
Because for the occasion
that you are pretty.
Oh, shut up.
You're sweet.
So you think l'm only pretty.
Like, l'm pretty and stupid.
-Well, no, maybe you shouldn't have this.
-No, no, no. This is my present.
Okay, let's go back to work.
The ocean's drying.
-What--?
-l'm just seeing....
You have one thing.
-Do you have something to say?
-No, no.
Focus and concentration.
Distraction is an obstruction
to the construction.
for the construction.
Distraction is an obstruction
-Oh, look.
-What?
Skiers.
Oh, look, look!
A lake what?
-Weird. That's really weird.
-Stéphane, talk with your heart.
-Yeah, be gentle.
-Fuck her.
No, no. Don't rush.
-The goat on the cliff, remember?
-What?
What's the goat on the cliff?
lt's a little children's story.
lt's, it's silly, don't listen to that.
Don't listen. Don't listen.
-On the cliff.
-The goat on the cliff!
Martine, the goat on the cliff.
Serge.
-l'll go first.
-No.
-l don't know how to ski.
-Come on.
-l don't wanna go.
-lt's easy. Courage, pretty boy.
Wait, wait, wait.
lt's not gonna hurt.
Okay.
Okay, good.
-Good.
-Hey, you take the glue gun, and l'll try this.
No, no, no.
Why don't we,
why don't we do the scene...
...when you walk
into the apartment...
...and you discover the pony, yeah?
-Yeah. Okay.
-Yeah?
Okay. So come, come, come.
You must be.... Okay. Yeah, there.
-Oh, wait.
-All right, okay, you're there.
So basically you're just
walking into the apartment...
...and you discover
that the pony can run...
...and you feel very excited, and....
Ready? And action.
Damn it, Stéphane,
you've ruined my pony.
-Why did you do that?
-Cut. What are you doing?
What are you doing?
No, you should be ecstatic about me.
You should be, like,
praising my ingénue and genius.
Of course, my handsome.
No, don't play with me.
This is never gonna happen.
-How do you know?
-Because l know.
Why are you trying
to give me hope?
Hope? Maybe you should try.
Try.
Well, next time l'll see you,
l'll kiss you?
-ls that what you're asking me?
-Yeah.
-Really?
-Yeah, you should try.
l should just
go out there and kiss you.
Yeah.
Okay.
-Yeah.
-Go on.
What are you doing?
l'm sorry. l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
Can you pretend that l,
that you didn't see me?
-l was just leaving, right now.
-This is stupid.
-You broke into my place?
-l'm sorry.
-What are you looking for?
That's creepy. No, this way.
-Good night.
-Oh, l forgot my keys.
-Hello?
-Stéphane?
Are you okay?
I love my pony.
I can't believe you did that.
How did you do it?
l'm sorry about what l said.
l didn't mean one word.
-No....
-Okay?
No, l'm a creep.
Just like you said.
Listen, Stéphane.
You have to toughen up a little.
lt's not attractive for a girl
to see a guy crying.
I know, it sucks.
You know I named
Golden the Pony Boy after you.
No, come on. Come on.
lt's not true. You had him
before we met.
No, no, it is true.
l improvised his name when
you saw him for the first time.
He didn't have a name.
Now, tell me how you did it.
Golden is galloping for real.
It's unreal.
Well....
lt's just an application
of the chaos theory.
Random control.
Each leg has one engine...
...and it moves backwards
or forwards depending on...
...the movement on the other leg.
lt's like life.
But in a simplified version.
And it doesn't reproduce.
l'm glad we live
next door to each other.
Will you....
Would you marry me when we're 70?
You've got nothing to lose.
Okay.
Would you mind...
...keep on talking to me
for a little while?
Because l always thought
it was possible to talk from my sleep.
l feel that l'm falling down
into a black hole.
You know that you could never see
someone fall in a black hole.
Because the image of the traveler
who passes the horizon...
...would slow down till it would remain
stuck in the same position...
The state he was
when he crossed the line.
Only it's getting redder.
The traveler gets crushed into spaghetti.
I don't wanna be a spaghetti,
I don't wanna be spaghetti.
No, you won't be a spaghetti.
I don't wanna be a spaghetti.
Stéphane?
-Are you here?
-No, I'm there! I'm there.
It worked! I'm not a spaghetti!
Tell me, tell me. Describe all you can see.
I feel some grass under my feet.
And it's a bit windy.
And cold. And damp.
And there's forest all around me.
And l can see Golden the Pony Boy.
Galloping here. Here, right in front of me.
And I can hear some water.
But I cannot see it.
Oh, here it is. The river.
ls the water made of millions
of tiny pieces of cellophane?
No, it's real water.
Oh, look. l just found the time machine.
The time machine is here.
And it works.
Stéphane, are you asleep?
Stéphanie, you know my mom, Christine.
two months later
Yeah, l cannot talk French
because whenever l speak...
...l feel that my moustache grows
more than when l speak Spanish.
Stéphanie.
l....
l wanna dedicate this
to all the victims....
Okay, thank you, Mr. Miroux.
Without them, without them,
it would not have been possible.
l'm sorry. Are you upset?
This girl is at once all the women
that broke my heart.
She's so beautiful and generous
and she's asking me to leave.
Because she's dumping me.
She's dumping me because
I am a cheap drug dealer.
And I am a drug dealer
because she wants to leave me.
The police are going to get me now.
This is all my fault.
He is my opposite.
She feels safe around him.
She's in love with him.
Things will turn out the way you want.
lf you could just stop doubting
that l love you.
Call me home. Next door.
lt's not fair.
She changed exactly the second
l started to like her.
lt's like a big bang.
The first instant, it's very small...
...and then the next nano instant:
Huge. lnfinite.
l wish l could travel back to the time
when l didn't find her attractive.
You should have asked me.
She has a really good ass.
Shut up, Guy. l thought she was lonely,
and somehow l could help her.
But no. She doesn't need me at all.
You know, l don't know
Stéphanie and all.
But maybe she has a pattern.
She doesn't wanna get hurt,
and by that she's hurting people.
And by hurting people, she thinks
she's not gonna get hurt, but she gets hurt.
l don't know. l love her
because she makes things.
You know? She makes things
with her hands.
lt's as if her synapses
was married directly to her fingers.
Like this. ln this way.
Yeah, yeah.
Man, l wish l could talk to my dad.
l miss my father. l cannot talk
with my mom when l'm sad.
You know, you can't let things
bother you all your life.
A man has to take matters
in his hands.
This TV is brainwashing my weekends.
l should be....
lnstead, l'm just watching this.
l'm sorry, l wasn't sure l was awake.
Awake? l will awake you for sure
if you carry on like this.
Here, help me,
instead of being stupid aleck.
lt floats, yeah.
Stéphane?
Stéphane. Wait.
Do you feel better?
l'm going to work.
l just want to know if you're okay.
Yeah, l'm super-fine. Thanks.
So l get it. So you don't want
to be my friend anymore.
No, l don't wanna be your friend anymore.
l don't wanna be your friend anymore.
Do l have to nail it on your door?
l don't wanna be your friend.
No, you-- You can't.
You can't stop being my friend.
-lt's not something people can decide.
-Yeah, they can.
People have an argument and then
they stop talking to each other.
Okay, then let's have a date or something
and we can talk about things.
-lf that's what you want.
-What's the point?
You'll want me as a friend. You'll have
a nice boyfriend and that'll kill me.
By the way, where's the boat?
Where's everything? Let's face it.
You never finished anything.
Like the mezzanine and everything else?
That's not true.
That's absolutely not true.
l'll show you.
You're manipulating me or....
l don't, l don't understand.
Look, here it is.
Here, here it is. Zoé's number.
That's what you want.
Screw her.
''l'm only your neighbor and a liar.
''By the way, do you have Zoé's number?''
Do you remember the letter that night?
How did you get that?
Wait, wait. Wait, l'm sorry.
No, no, no. Stop crying.
Stop crying.
l'm sorry.
-Guy, Guy.
-Hey.
Did you see the red on?
l'm doing your work.
l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
Something amazing happened
between Stéphanie and l.
-Come on, shut up, now.
-lncredible!
Stop bullshitting. l'm sick
of breaking my balls with you.
-l'm doing your work. Know why?
-Why?
Because you're virtually fired,
my sleepy man.
And mother or not mother
to cover your ass.
Okay, you don't know
what happens between us.
Nobody has a clue what happens...
...and everybody has an opinion.
Fuck that.
l wrote her a letter in my dream
and l never gave it to her.
And she read it. l don't know how,
but she somehow read it.
And she just recited it to me just now.
Word by word. She knows it.
And you know why?
Because l think our brains...
...are creating this loop
that is incredibly complex.
lt's not as if our brains are communicating
or telepathy or nothing like that.
lt's as if we were evolving
each step into the same direction.
lt's called PSR.
Parallel synchronized randomness.
lt's incredibly rare. lt's as if
we were jigsaw puzzles, you know?
-And we're falling to, into the....
-Stéphane, you will never date her, okay?
-She will drive you crazy, believe me.
-No, she just asked me for a date.
ln 20 minutes at the Bar de l'Oreille.
l have to go.
Minutes at the Bar de l'Oreille.
lt's my travel, time travel machine.
You just walk in, Pouchet didn't
see you, so you won't go.
Oh, come on. Guy, Guy, come on!
lt's just once. Okay, just this time.
You will never date her, okay?
-She will drive you crazy.
-Drive me crazy.
I refuse to believe only friendship
from Stéphanie.
There are signs that can't be mistaken.
Can't be mistaken. Look, look.
She kisses me at less than
a centimeter of my lips.
It is a sign, the most evident,
that she desires me.
Where should she kiss to her friendly
goodbye? On the forehead?
No, halfway between the ear and the lips.
That's what's considered normal.
Besides, if I don't move my head back,
she hits me right on the lips.
Why did you move away
from her kiss, then?
Maybe I tried to kiss her, who cares?
The point is that she will torture,
torture, torture me all my life.
She simply doesn't care about me.
No, this is not true. She cares a lot.
She worships my presence.
She feels sorry for me.
Pity. That's the worst.
Exactly. My feeling has reached
the point of pathology...
...and I can't seduce anyone
without pathology.
You believe you can seduce her with
your creepy, pathological little gifts?
They all ended up in the trash,
blinded by your....
-No.
-Nobody is waiting for you at the bar.
Stéphanie never came.
She lost interest in you long ago.
-lt's too late. Stéphanie moved on.
-No.
-Stéphanie moved on. Moved on.
-Go away.
Will never change her mind.
Girls never change their mind
when it's over.
Open the door. l know you are there.
Open the door.
You forgot about me.
Stop playing with me.
l never want to see you again.
Say it.
Say it, you have to say it.
-Listen to me. Listen to me, say it.
-Camera there.
-Say it.
-Okay, it's all in order. Okay.
-lt won't happen. You have to say it.
-Yeah, just wait a second, wait a second.
-Go on, say it.
-Okay. Perfect. Yeah.
Just-- Okay. Right there.
Okay, now look at the camera.
-Will you marry me?
-Yes.
l've changed my mind.
-Hey, Stéphane.
-Hey.
What's going on?
Nothing's going on. l'm just leaving.
Yeah, l know.
Are you still upset with me?
Well, let's just say that
there are some unsolved issues.
Yeah.
You're not gonna let me in?
lnstall a toilet paper dispenser
because people are wiping...
...their dirty Sanchez here
on your door.
Oh, shut up.
How is your head?
lt's okay.
lt's not normal, though.
Oh, well, of course it's not.
-lt's never going to be.
-Yeah, well, it is not attractive to you.
l'm glad l made it
through your door, though.
Don't be glad.
Be sad.
Your English is very good.
What about your French?
No, l can't speak French with you.
l'm too shy.
The only thing l can say is:
Oh, damn it, Stéphane.
What if someone catches fire?
We've got to help him. Quick.
Go, go, go!
Anarchy in the cellophane!
You've been crying?
l like it when you cry
because you have to wear your glasses.
l actually don't like it when you cry.
l find it horrible.
Especially when it's not for me.
Will you cry a little when l'm dead?
l hate people that pretend that they want
everyone to celebrate their death...
...you know, and everyone is having
a blast at the party...
...and nobody gives a shit
for the dead.
That's horrible. That's bullshit.
lt's like, ''Hey, sleep with my girlfriend
after my cremation. Do you mind?''
You know? Well, my problem is that
l don't have a girlfriend.
And l'm not dead.
Look. Put your finger here.
Touch here.
At the back of the ear and the glasses.
lt feels like the glasses were
part of your body.
Oh, true. That's weird.
-l always liked that.
-My contacts are killing me.
lt's like if you were touching
your penis with your left hand.
l don't have a penis.
You have a left hand.
Why do you always have to be a pig?
l'm teasing you.
Will you fix your teeth one day?
-You're mean.
-No, l'm just saying because--
l mean, it's gonna be 40 years
until we marry.
And l might as well take care
of my goods now, you know?
Well, actually, you know?
Don't do anything.
Maybe no teeth is good
for a blow job.
Okay. l think you should leave now.
You gonna be late.
You know, sometimes l wear my jeans
for more than a week...
...until they're really bad. And it
makes me feel a little bit closer to you.
-What do you want me to say to that?
-Nothing. Nothing.
So how is your boyfriend?
You have a new boyfriend?
A new boyfriend with long hair...
...and goes bungee jumping and surfing.
Does he take you surfing?
lnvite me, l'll go with you.
l don't know how but maybe--
l mean, if you want me to.
l don't have a boyfriend.
And you have a serious problem
of distorting reality.
You could sleep with the entire planet
and still feel rejected.
-Please, l'd like you to go now.
-l like your boobs.
l like your boobs. They are very friendly
and unpretentious.
l'll appreciate if, one day,
you'll show them to me?
-Not much to see. Now, go.
-Hey, the mezzanine.
You finished the mezzanine.
l thought you were never gonna finish it.
Like the boat and everything else.
ls it solid?
Can it hold a boy? A couple?
What are you doing--? Get out.
-Get out of here.
-No.
-Get out or l'll call your mother.
-No, my mother? No. No.
Not my mother.
-You're gonna miss your plane.
-l don't care. l don't care.
Why do you do this to me?
What have l done to you?
Tell me what do you want me to do?
l don't know.
Maybe touch my hair or something?
l can't do that.
Why me?
Because everyone else is boring.
And because you're different.
You don't like me, Stéphanie.
Stéphane?
Subtitles by
SDl Media Group
(ENGLlSH)