♪ Volare
♪ Oh, oh
♪ Cantare
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh
♪ Let's fly way up
to the clouds
♪ Away from
the maddening crowds
♪ We can sing in the glow
of a star that I know of
♪ Where lovers enjoy
peace of mind
♪ Let us leave the confusion
♪ And all disillusion behind
♪ Just like birds of a feather
♪ A rainbow together we'll find
♪ Volare
♪ Oh, oh
♪ E cantare
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh
♪ No wonder
my happy heart sings
♪ Your love
has given me wings ♪
(AIRPLANE SOARING OVER)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
(AIRPLANE APPROACHING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Who is it?
MAN: Room service.
Is it eggs?
I don't know, sir.
I didn't order it.
You want some water with that?
No, no.
No, I don't.
Looks like you had a night.
They look perfect.
Get out.
I intended to bring that to the
attention of a member of staff.
I had some difficulty
getting it to open.
It's the little key
on the door key, sir.
Right.
I was looking for some nuts.
I tend to avoid alcohol.
When I can.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I don't speak Spanish.
Cuatro cincuenta.
No change.
(MUTTERING)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(FEEDBACK SCREECHES)
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
No, no, no, no,
you're not listening.
I said the Pirates,
not the Yankees.
It's going to be Roberto's
year, I'm telling you.
Looking for Mr. Letterman.
End of the room.
No, no, the Pirates.
You guys are going
to be all over.
It's Roberto Clemente, man.
And by the way, I
want to talk about...
LOTTERMAN: Not now!
He's having the Friday crisis.
You Kemp?
Yeah.
He was expecting you yesterday.
We had some weather.
Yeah, I heard.
Big snow in New York.
He's still on a call.
You want some coffee?
No, thanks.
What's all the fuss out front?
You came in the front?
We don't use that door.
Not when los jibaros pitch up.
What do they want?
I don't know.
Some fucked idea
of a living wage.
They've been out there
on and off for months.
By the way, my name's Sala.
Bob Sala, staff photographer.
Pleased to meet you, Bob.
Yeah.
He's off.
You might want to try
another subservient knock.
Yeah.
Kemp.
Don't notice the wig.
LOTTERMAN:
Yeah. What?
If you're who I think you
are, you better sit down.
You find it
a little bright in here?
I'd take them off, but I
have a medical condition.
What do you mean, you're blind?
Conjunctivitis, sir.
The old red eye, huh?
(CHUCKLES)
You arrive at a very,
very trying time, Mr. Kemp.
One of those days stacking up.
So, uh, why don't we cut
through the niceties
and just get right to it, huh?
That's how I like to proceed.
Okay.
Your resume here.
(SPITS)
Very impressive CV.
Yeah.
You worked your way up
some interesting titles.
I really like
the "fluent Spanish."
Mmm.
Wow.
(CHUCKLING)
This CV... This CV is
a bunch of bullshit.
Is it?
This is two days on the wire.
A day dead.
We don't have it.
Oh.
What is the matter with Moburg?
He's about as useful
as a dug-up body.
(CHUCKLES)
You see, the problem with
this newspaper, Mr. Kemp,
is that I am among many
who don't enjoy reading it.
We have an ailing circulation,
and I just have to
look around this building
to understand why.
Lack of commitment and
too much self-indulgence.
Mmm. Mmm.
So what I'm looking for
is some enthusiasm,
some energy,
some fresh blood.
And the question
that I'm asking myself
is how much alcohol
is usual in yours.
My fresh blood?
How much do you drink?
I suppose at
the upper end of "social."
I'm poised to give up.
Well, Puerto Rico may not be
the best place on Earth
to do that.
Mmm. Mmm.
Don't look so
anxious, Mr. Kemp.
I wouldn't have paid for your hotel
if I hadn't already hired you.
But this is not
the Last Chance Saloon,
and I do not need
another heavy drinker.
Which I perceive, from the condition
of eyeballs behind glasses,
that you might
very well qualify as.
This is a medical
condition, Mr. Letterman.
I know it might look like
something else, but this is a...
Looks like a fuckin' hangover.
Does it?
(WHISTLE BLOWING OUTSIDE)
(CLAMORING)
Come here.
That's the kind of commitment
I like to see in a man.
Oh! Determination, balanced
with appropriate humanity.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Which side do you dress, Kemp?
I beg your pardon?
Politics.
I kind of hang in the middle.
(LAUGHS)
This is a schizoid
society, Kemp.
They got two languages, two flags,
two loyalties, two anthems.
We bring them stuff
they never had.
They either hate it or
they want more of it.
It's a reluctant part
of America.
It's like an England
with tropical fruit.
Bob.
Just the man I wanted to see.
This is Paul Kemp.
He's joining us from New York.
Yeah, yeah, we already met.
Uh, that's...
That's Mr. Clive Donovan, sports.
And this is Mr
. Hubert, accounting.
Listen, do me a favor,
will you?
Show him around,
the dos and don'ts.
Introduce him
to some of the guys.
I'll take him up to Al's.
Oh, the hell you will.
You take him to the library.
You pull out some volumes.
I want him to get
a sense of the paper.
You know, make some notes,
go back a few years,
paying particular attention
to bowling alleys.
There's bowling and
bowling alleys.
Very big here.
They're up like mushrooms.
A new one premieres every week.
Been to Puerto Rico before? No.
Oh, you're going to
fall right into it.
There's a boom on here, Kemp.
It's an open door.
You play it right,
you can surf the place.
Ah.
What do you know
about horoscopes?
Nothing.
Ah, well, if I can
write one, you can.
So it's every day with
a special "Star's Star"
featured Saturday
with Betty Grable
and Neil Sedaka,
things like that.
So here, everything you
need is right there.
It's called
"Madam La Zonga Predicts."
What happened to
Madam La Zonga?
He got canceled.
What do you mean, fired?
They raped him to death.
They raped him to death?
There are very few
places on this island
I decline to visit,
but the toilets
frequented by sailors
on the west side
of Candado Pier is one.
They raped him to death?
La Zonga died in a cubicle.
Say, you're not, uh,
artistic, are you, Kemp?
Oh, no.
You might want to rethink
those menthol cigarettes.
They don't do a thing for you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Come by the house.
I will.
I like your stuff.
The cuttings you sent
to Letterman.
Oh.
It's good writing.
Thanks.
We'll talk.
SALA:
One more floor!
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
They put in automated packing
machines about six months ago.
They mechanized
almost everything.
There used to be 50 guys down here.
Now there's five.
Hence happiness in the street.
Souvenir, day one.
SALA: Here's to pretty women
with filthy thoughts.
(CHUCKLING)
Want a burger?
No.
Burger?
No, thanks.
Try it. Dos.
So how was the induction?
Somewhat fraught.
No disrespect, Paul, but he
didn't have a lot of choice.
You know how many people
applied for the job?
One. You.
Is that right?
Even then,
I thought I'd blown it.
Zeroed in on my weakest spot.
WOLSLEY:
Which is what?
Two and a half
unpublished novels
and references
of equal fiction.
Oh, you're a novelist.
Mmm, in a manner of speaking.
Can't even get read.
So I figured I'd do
some words for money,
see how it's looking
in a year or two.
SALA:
At El Star?
Hate to tell you this
on the way in,
but this publication's
on its way out.
And as far as I'm concerned,
it can't come soon enough.
Not going to happen.
SALA: You like
a little vonga on that?
I'll give you 13 to 2
this thing's over by June.
They're going to cut the cord.
Then why put in
all the new machinery?
Precisely my point,
and he can't answer it.
Well, like I'm tired
of arguing the obvious.
Come on.
Let's eat.
Now, I got to go and see
a man about a horse.
Good to meet you, Paul.
(SIGHS)
Another night unfolds
over Old San Juan.
You been here long?
Too long.
This place is like
someone you fucked
and they're still under you.
Why don't you quit?
Life's full of exits.
Because I'm waiting for it to
collapse so I get the payoff.
Three grand redundancy
puts me in Mexico.
Don't look left.
That's an introduction
you don't want to have.
Who's he?
Living example of everything
that's wrong with this paper.
His name's Moburg.
Our Crime and Religious
Affairs correspondent.
Letterman can't fire him
because he never sees him.
He's rarely out in daylight.
Looks like he enjoys a drink.
The entire substructure of his
brain is eaten away with rum.
I'm telling you,
this enterprise is doomed.
There's maybe three or four professionals
in the building running the entire show.
Wait a minute.
Who is Hal Sanderson?
In the library.
Who's he?
He used to work for the paper.
Now he's what he says he is.
A PR consultant.
Selling this place street
by street to the Yankees.
Keeps a greasy little bastard
of a contact called Segurra.
Mmm.
I saw him.
We didn't meet.
Wouldn't bother.
Piss on the make.
The boy, Segurra, is at
the property wickedness.
I'm not sure
where Sanderson fits.
But Sanderson's
worth cultivation.
He's got some good connections.
He's good for some freelance.
This place is depressing me
beyond belief tonight.
You're at Plage Xanadu, right?
Mmm.
Come on.
I'll give you a ride.
(TIRES SCREECH)
I was thinking,
if you need somewhere,
I got a room for rent.
Not the best address in town,
but it's got a fridge and TV.
60 a month.
Sounds inviting.
I might remention that.
Meanwhile, bleed it dry.
Uh, sir...
I was hoping for a swim.
The pool is closed tonight.
Really? Why?
What's going on?
It's a Union Carbide party.
It's a private function.
(MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
(SIGHS)
Sorry.
I didn't realize
anyone was there.
I thought it was just floating.
It is just floating.
You doing what I'm doing?
I don't think so.
What are you doing?
Escaping the dreadful party.
I just snuck out and unzipped.
Well, that's very
courageous of you.
I thought maybe
you were a mermaid.
They tell me the coast
is infested with them.
I'm from Connecticut.
My boyfriend's making a speech.
Takes exactly 21 minutes.
Well, then I guess
it's pointless,
me inviting you for a drink.
What you got?
No, I mean at the bar.
Pointless.
I'd better go before
they wonder where I went.
Wait a minute.
What's your name?
Let's keep that a secret.
I don't even know it.
Well, then you'll
keep it even better.
What about your star sign?
I'm an experienced astronomer.
Could try Pisces.
The fish.
Oh, God.
Why did she have to happen?
Just when I was doing
so good without her.
KEMP: What would you say you
like most about Puerto Rico?
The bowling alleys
and the casinos.
Course, she likes
the duty free.
Well, the more you spend,
the more you save.
KEMP: Have you seen
a lot of the island?
We don't leave the hotel.
It isn't safe.
KEMP: But
you're having fun?
Oh, yeah!
A lotta, lotta fun!
KEMP: Have some fun
with a fucking Luger.
These alleys are magnets
to the glutton.
They come off the boats
like locusts.
Beasts of obesity.
Asses that wouldn't
feel an arrow.
The great whites.
Probably the most dangerous
creatures on Earth.
SALA:
There's your baby.
Walt and his woman.
Bowling alleys isn't exactly
what I had in mind.
Tread it till the snow melts,
then join the exodus.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Red light!
LOTTERMAN:
Looking for Kemp.
Too many adjectives,
too much cynicism.
Nobody wants what's
wrong with the place,
they want to read about
what's right.
It's a rewrite.
Yeah, I'm aware of that.
And while you're at it,
you might want to rewrite
the title and call it
"Ten Things That I Love
About Puerto Rico."
So,
how's the sobriety
coming along?
I'm cutting down.
Oh. By that, I assume you
mean the size of the bottles.
How does anybody
drink 161 miniatures?
You're averaging
93 miniatures a week.
What, do they stock the
place four times a day?
Are they not complimentary?
No, Mr. Kemp,
they are not.
And neither is wine and
long-distance phone calls.
So, as of Monday, you are no
longer a resident of the Xanadu.
And what exactly brings
you into the building?
Don't hazel me.
I got the X-rays back.
I got less than a week to live.
LOTTERMAN: Hazel you?
What are you talking about, you Swedish twerp?
You know, it may have crossed
what's left of your mind
that I have a newspaper
to run here,
that we have something called
news going on out there.
But as far as you're concerned,
I might as well look out
of the fuckin' window!
What are you doing here?
This is a newspaper.
There's nothing here for you.
Two of the best scoops
you ever had
came out of my brain.
And you better
moderate your language
or I'll go elsewhere.
Elsewhere where?
You couldn't get work
as a fly repellent.
You're worthless, Moburg.
The last onion in the jar.
Don't push me, Letterman.
I'm dangerous when pushed.
Oh, I know why you're here.
It's payday. (LAUGHS)
But in your case,
deferred on a permanent basis.
You're fired!
You can't fire me.
You owe me money.
And you better pay it,
or I'll come through the roof
and turn this place
into an insurance claim.
LOTTERMAN:
Are you threatening me?
Hey, guys, let's take it easy.
You want to suffer some voodoo?
You twerp!
Eat the death pill, Letterman!
Come on, we're walking.
Did you hear
what he said to me?
This guy's my blood pressure.
This guy's going to kill me.
And I want the negative
of that picture destroyed!
I don't want that animal
in this building again.
He is hygienically
unacceptable.
Did you see the side
of his nose?
Blackheads like Braille.
They should have him put down.
(PANTING)
Moburg is history.
He's out of here at the
earliest opportunity.
And the earliest opportunity
is you.
You understand
what I'm saying, Kemp?
I think I get the drift.
I want you to immerse
yourself into this paper,
'cause you got the talent and
I think you got the will.
You make it grow and you
grow right along with it.
I'm not best placed to do that.
You think it's my
intention to keep you on
horoscopes and rewrites
and bowling alleys?
(CHUCKLES)
Matter of fact, I'm gonna
move you right now.
Take a cab to the airport.
The mayor of Miami's coming in.
Make him sound nice.
I want a picture
and an interview.
Make it work, Paul.
(WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON PA)
You leaving us already?
I'm moving into an apartment if
this mayor guy ever shows up.
They keep changing
"delayed" to "delayed."
You want to have
some breakfast?
Little lobster on the beach?
Twenty minutes away.
Sounds inviting, but I got
to wait for the mayor.
Isn't coming.
Canceled.
That's not what it
says on the board.
It will in a minute.
I just called Miami.
Come on, let's have
some breakfast.
I got a couple things
might interest you.
I better call in.
You can call from the car.
All right.
Yeah, thanks.
There's only two of
those on the island.
Maybe three.
No one told me it
was so pretty here.
God's idea of money.
You know what makes
this place a gold mine?
Something that doesn't exist.
How's that?
Land.
There isn't enough of it.
Those who know how to
get it get the gold.
Chenault?
Paul's joining us
for breakfast.
Looks like it's
gonna be a lunch.
This is Chenault.
You two know each other?
I don't know, I thought
maybe we met on the plane.
Oh, I don't think so.
I flew Boyfriend Airlines.
Tell me, do you
like lobster, Paul?
You know what, I might
not have time today.
I didn't realize the drive
was gonna take so long.
How much time you got?
In 15 minutes, I'm late.
I'll cut up a pineapple.
SANDERSON: You might want
to put on some clothes.
She sunbathes in the nude.
A few of
the over-tanned locals
tend to treat it
as a tourist attraction.
Doesn't surprise me.
I mean that in a...
In a very tasteful way.
It's a private beach.
They shouldn't be here.
Sit down, Paul, sit down.
We'll grab you a cab.
(CHUCKLES) His name's Harry.
Got the idea from a book.
Paul, I wanted to talk,
because I'm looking
for someone who can
assimilate contradictory
points of view
and make them into one voice.
You're a novelist, right?
Who told you that?
Oh, please.
Newspapers are full of gossip.
I'm looking for someone who's good
with words, next day, you turn up.
And 'cause I believe
in good luck,
I thought maybe you were it.
What I need
is someone with
the right kind of eyes.
For looking at what?
Looking at that.
An ocean of money.
(DOG BARKING)
Hey, you made it.
Door at the end.
Hey.
Hey. Just give me
two minutes.
Walk right in.
All right.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING QUIETLY)
(ROOSTER CLUCKS)
(CROWS)
(CLUCKING)
I was trying to get the place
shipshape before you arrived.
Adolf Hitler Speaks?
Not mine.
Nazi stuff belongs to Moburg.
Moburg lives here?
He keeps his uniform here.
I never see him from one
month's end to the next.
So, you can see,
it's quite spacious.
Don't look in the kitchen.
The water's off.
There's a problem with the valve.
Thought you said you had a TV.
I said I kind of have a TV.
The guy across the alley has
a TV, I have binoculars.
His wife's deaf.
With the window open,
you hear every word.
Oh, here it comes.
Water's coming up.
I, uh, noticed you had some
chickens in the bedroom.
Cockerels.
Yeah, I'm sweating
the grease out.
Don't worry about them,
I'm moving them to my room.
What do you do with them?
You eat them?
Eat them?
Nah.
I don't eat them.
(ALL SHOUTING)
Come on, baby, come on!
Get in there, get in there!
Come on!
(CHEERING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Hey, on a trade wind, my boy!
On a trade wind!
Come on, bump it up,
there, Bobby.
Bump, bump, bump, bump.
Yes, sir!
(CLUCKING)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(MEN CHATTERING IN SPANISH)
Hey. They call him
El Monstruo.
Say he's never lost
a fight in three years.
Come on, we're out of here.
Come on, rapido, rapido.
(KIDS CHATTERING IN SPANISH)
Hey, hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Come on. Come on. Go on.
(KIDS CHATTERING IN SPANISH)
(COINS CLINKING)
(KIDS CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
I tell you, we were on a roll
til that thing turned up.
That's $217.
Not bad.
$217 is a shitload of money.
Relatively a shitload.
They're expensive to train.
I've seen guys win 2,000,
ten on North Beach.
10,000?
Why didn't he take
El Monstruo down there?
You're talking the environs
of the Hilton Hotel.
They wear bowties
and shiny shoes.
There's no hope for
his kind of hat.
The question, again,
is not one of goals.
We're for those goals.
It's one of means.
MAN: Were you claiming that the
Eisenhower administration...
How long can this
blizzard of shame go on?
Look at this ingrate besotted
with his own righteousness.
Black is a very dark
shade of white.
Well, thank you
very much, Mr. Nixon.
I can't listen to
any more of this.
Lies like he breathes.
Imagine spending
your entire life lying.
Holy Christ.
Never got worse.
The only eventuality worse than
him is you know that one day,
some filthy whore-beast
is gonna show up,
make him look like a liberal.
The only upside with Nixon
is he ain't gonna win.
He's got the grin.
He ain't gonna win.
Irish guy's going to win.
But they'll never let him live.
How do you know that?
I do "horror-scopes."
(DOOR OPENS)
Thought you said
he never came here.
He's got filters.
What filters?
He goes over the wall
at the Barcardi plant.
These filters are the last in
line in the distillation process.
They contain more ethanol
than rocket fuel.
What's it like?
A hand on the brain.
Off the scale.
470 proof.
No such thing
as 470 proof alcohol.
Certainty you might be
required to moderate.
Ah.
No smoking in the extraction
area, if you please.
Don't be ridiculous.
Not for the social drinker.
You want to quaff?
No.
Not right now.
I got to write.
I got a deadline.
Oh, what's he writing?
He's lifting the stone
on the American Dream.
Guayanilla Bay.
Oh, yeah.
It's bad down there.
You might find such a topic
attracts a limited readership.
Only need one.
Taking it to Letterman.
Yeah. Oh, did I hear
somebody say "good luck"?
(LAUGHS)
Yeah, I went down
there this morning,
he unfired me on a temporary
basis, maggot that he is.
I'd like to bring something
in to Letterman.
Like a slide-action,
"fuck you" gun.
Don't drink that here.
(GROANS)
Just a nipperoo, old boy.
Quality test.
Man, slow-motion murder, just
like they do in the movies.
See him flying back,
fuckin' arms
flapping in the air.
Okay, mother.
Look upon the last face
you'll see this side of hell!
Bam!
(LAUGHS)
Down he goes, morsels
of vital organs
spinning off into flesh orbit.
Bam!
There goes his asshole.
There goes his dick.
Bam! Bam!
Fuck you, Letterman!
You're in a B-fucking movie,
and I am the death machine!
Shall we have some Adolf?
Definitely not.
On your way, on
your way, Moburg.
Hey, we're expecting guests.
I thought you said
he was writing a book.
Said I was writing an essay.
And it requires
some shut mouth.
Oh, don't waste your time
on those junkyard losers.
This country was built
on genocide and slavery.
We killed all the black
guys that were here,
and then we shipped in new
black guys of our own,
and then we brought in
Jesus, like a bar of soap.
Let's go.
You know it.
I am the religious
correspondent.
Fuck off with
your Jesus Police!
If the Bible's God's book, why
didn't He give it to everyone?
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SIGHS)
"We give more money to parking
meters than we do to kids to eat."
Don't read me like that.
I've done the research.
12,000-ton rust bucket
went down in the bay
full of hydrochloric acid.
Killed off
everything in the sea.
Killed off the fishermen.
Their kids are picking garbage.
All right, don't get angry.
It's hot outside.
You want a Scotch?
Yeah.
Ten years ago...
Five. Five years ago,
I might have said go after it.
Now I say go with it.
There's nothing you can change.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Sometimes you just got to spew
over the side and keep rowing.
(CHUCKLES)
Into a nut brown sunset.
It's the land of
multiple outrage.
Thousands trodden on before
you wake up for breakfast.
That isn't news,
it's a commercial reality.
And providing it
isn't their sunset,
nobody gives
one-fifth of a fuck.
You underestimate your readers.
I don't think so.
You underestimate me.
You told me to make it work,
that's what I want to do.
Wind down this La Zonga crap
and make a newspaper.
Let me tell you
some home truth.
This paper's been on its knees to
a bank since the day it opened.
And like most every other
newspaper on Earth,
it's financed
by its advertising.
And without advertising, not
only is there no La Zonga,
there's no paper
to put it in, so, thus,
there are one or two things
that we don't write about.
In other words, nothing at all.
In one other word, discretion.
You're not
a foreign correspondent
in some far-flung foreign
land, this is America.
This is Puerto Rico.
This is America.
You think some plumber
from Normal, Illinois,
saves up for 25 years to
come here on a cruise ship
to read about bad times
in the sugar plantation?
They don't give a fuck!
The average guy
don't rock the boat,
'cause he wants
to climb aboard it.
And our readership
is vividly average.
(CHUCKLES)
They don't care
who the losers are.
(CHUCKLES) They want
to know who won.
Who won the bowls,
who won the races, who won the
pot at the slot machines.
Look at me, Kemp.
You're not sleeping,
you're wide awake.
And this is the American Dream.
So many hotels,
you can't see the sea.
You can see the sea by
checking into the hotels.
Pay to see the sea?
What's the matter with that?
You're paying to be
in the dream.
There's a thin veneer, Kemp,
between the dream
and the reality.
You wake them up and the people might
start asking for their money back.
You're the boss.
Not quite.
The editorial policy of this
newspaper is owned by the dream.
Oh, God.
Oh, Christ.
Oh, God, look at that.
Oh, God!
Hal?
Oh.
No, no, I'm a friend of Hal's.
I was looking at his boat.
She's a sweet little beauty.
You been aboard?
No.
Great little island hopper.
We've all been down on her.
It's a wonderful experience.
You two are early.
Oh, you got lucky.
SANDERSON: Yeah.
Did you meet?
Oh, yeah, we got first names.
Art Zimburger, late of the U.S.
Marines, great friend of mine.
This is Mr. Paul Kemp,
New York Times.
Oh, you're the writer.
Paul's a novelist.
Uh-huh.
(MR. ZIMBURGER CHUCKLES)
New York Times?
He don't know one
from the other.
Just go with it.
This guy's key.
Key to what?
Key to the discussion
we're about to have.
Look at those mothers.
Come with me, Kemp.
This is a private beach.
We are not on it.
No, but we are!
And what we do is private!
Now get the fuck gone!
Get the fuck out of here!
I see your face again,
you're gonna have
a 12-gauge shotgun
telling you what to do.
Talking about Satan...
if there ever was a kingdom of
Satan, the Soviet Union is it.
The only way to come to terms
with Communism is to destroy it.
Hit it before it hits us in a
devastating democratic strike.
No more for the major.
They're looking for a man
to push that button,
I am that man.
MRS. ZIMBURGER:
Yes, you are, honey.
You look ravishing, Chenault.
Thank you.
You need rescuing?
Oh, don't take him away.
He's very entertaining.
(CHUCKLES)
We were discussing Cuba and, I don't
know, we kind of veered off, didn't we?
Paul presents us with a
somewhat liberal point of view.
MR. ZIMBURGER: There is no
such thing as a liberal.
A liberal is a Commie with a college
education thinking Negro thoughts.
Well, here's a fact for you.
76.4% of all Negroes
are controlled from Moscow.
That's why Castro gets
such an easy ride.
In my view, we ought to bomb
Cuba off the face of the Earth,
let its people live in peace.
Art.
Hey.
Come on, let's eat.
Come on.
Who's the guy in the shades?
Segurra's Daddy.
It's who you're waiting for.
Oh.
Thank you for my roses.
I didn't think you noticed.
Of course I noticed.
SANDERSON: Paul, would
you mind joining us?
Oh.
How do you do, sir?
Mr. Kemp.
Nice to see you.
Okay.
Let me just start by saying
this is a purely
informal meeting.
And, incidentally, you don't
worry about Letterman, okay?
Letterman?
What the hell's Letterman got
to do with The New York Times?
Mr. Kemp subs for
a variety of newspapers.
Occasionally, he writes
for the news.
What he does in his spare
time is his affair.
That's how I like it.
We'd like you to do
some writing for us.
So I gather.
About what?
SANDERSON: In a sentence,
we want to set something up,
and have the public
as our friends.
And there are a variety
of ways we can do that.
Let me tell you how this kind
of thing works, Paul.
Suppose, by way of example,
you wanted to put up taxes
by five percent.
The smart way of doing it
is to float the idea
of a ten percent hike.
Let them all shout about it,
get themselves in a fuss,
then you offer concessions.
"How about seven percent?"
"No way," they'll say.
"All right, let's stay friends
and make a compromise at five."
Bingo.
They think they won something,
you get the five percent you
wanted in the first place.
Same thing applies
to real estate.
You want to build five houses,
you put in a planning
application for 50.
How many do you want to build?
None.
We want to build one hotel.
Well, looking
around this place,
I don't think
anyone would notice.
It isn't in this place.
It's an island.
Sensitive for a variety of reasons
we don't want to get into now.
Nobody wants a paradise
choked with hotels, but
everybody will be pleased
to compromise at one.
This is going to require
some clever writing
in various
carefully placed articles.
Isn't that
kind of thing illegal?
MR. ZIMBURGER:
If I may say, Mr. Kemp,
that's an
inappropriate comment.
Where's the island?
Can't tell you.
Not yet.
Discretion is paramount,
Mr. Kemp.
If you want to join us, you'll
have to sign some papers.
We're having a meeting
tomorrow in Hal's office.
If you want to be
part of what will be
a very exciting project,
come along.
There's a man outside in a
funny little car for Paul.
Oh, yeah.
Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me.
I have to run.
Can't stay?
I hear the mermaids
come out in the moonlight.
(TUNING RADIO)
From the moment we met, I knew
there was going to be
something between us.
It's called her fiance.
God, I'm so hopelessly
and progressively in love.
Do not confuse love with lust,
nor drunkenness with judgment.
(ROOSTER CLUCKING)
You want my advice?
No. if it involves her,
no, I don't.
Stay away from her.
And stay away from Sanderson.
You're way out of depth.
I got no brief for Sanderson
or his pissy rip-off island.
I just want some apple
blossom lipstick and fucks.
You are in total denial.
She's fucking someone else.
Oh!
And as I understand it,
about to be married to him.
La-la-la-la-la-la!
You won't even make an invite.
(TIRES SCREECH)
I don't believe this.
We're right back
where we started.
That is the same
Cabrones we passed
ten minutes ago.
(HORN HONKING)
We need directions.
Let's get in there and
get something to eat.
(GASPS)
(HOARSELY) No.
Please, no.
I haven't spent
all day on a beach
munching lobster
with criminals,
and I'm starving.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING QUIETLY)
(VOLARE PLAYING)
Two beers, two rums, one steak.
The kitchen is closed.
All right then,
two beers and two rums.
And one steak.
Cerrado, Mister...
Yeah, but let's not
bother me with that.
You got a sign down there saying, "Food
til midnight," and I want a steak.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Girl of the swamp.
Which reminds me,
we need a map.
You know what I think?
I think we're drinking
too much rum.
There's no other way.
I'm getting double ashtray
and double salt pot.
(CHUCKLES)
You got a Moburg bifocal.
Christ, this is heinous.
Imagine what it must be like
to be an alcoholic.
$2.
You pay and you go.
I don't see a steak.
No steak.
What do you mean, no steak?
I think he means no steak.
The kitchen is closed.
I got no way of serving you.
Listen, you don't want
to hear about my bad day,
and I don't want
no grave side out of you.
If you can't cook it, bring it like it is.
I'll eat it raw.
Two dollars, you pay and go.
Don't bother me.
You pay now,
or I call the cops.
If you have no intention
of serving me steak,
why don't you do
your best to fuck off.
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
it seems to me there's
a bad vibe developing.
There are one or two oddities
giving us the eye.
Don't get paranoid.
He's on the phone.
For what?
Ordering food in a restaurant?
Let's hope
he's through to the FBI.
Si, la policia?
What's the matter?
What are you smiling at?
I'm not smiling.
I'm maintaining a casual face.
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
A man just walked in
and has good reason for regarding
us in a negative light.
Us?
Me.
And he's just seen me.
And he wants revenge
on the white man.
The fuck are you talking about?
How about the one
with the dent?
The one with the eye?
The very same.
Do we walk or run?
Walk.
I'll push the car.
Let's walk and hope he's happy.
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hey, Yankee.
Yankee!
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Don't let me see headlights.
Please don't let me
see headlights.
I just seen headlights.
Put your foot down.
Where exactly do
you think I got it?
(MEN SHOUTING)
Can you go faster?
Going fast as I can.
(MEN SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
KEMP: Jesus Christ, man.
(ROOSTER CLUCKING)
(SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CLUCKING)
We're gonna be killed!
Hey!
Get ready to run.
Run in opposite directions.
Give me the brew!
Give me the fucking brew!
(SCREAMS)
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
Paul!
(PEOPLE SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
(MEN MURMURING)
Piece of luck.
I just saw Moburg.
At least I think he saw us.
(MAN SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
They got some kind of
night court going.
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
He says we were animals
on a rampage
of drunken anarchy,
poured gasoline
on one of his cops.
(GROANING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
Oh, my God, we're doomed.
You have something to say?
Yes, Your Honor, I do.
Firstly, this guy handcuffed to
me, I never seen in my life.
And second, we'd like a
translation of the charges.
You heard what they said?
With respect, I heard
people speaking Spanish.
What kind of language do you think
we speak in this country, Mister?
(VOMIT SPLATTERING)
(GROANING)
He's not with us.
The cops attached him
to get a conviction.
Did you leave the Cafe
Cabrones without paying?
Did you set fire to the
police officer, yes or no?
Unfortunately, Your Honor, he
got in the way of our flame.
That's right.
No way did we pour gasoline on
his head and laugh as we did.
(LAUGHS)
it wasn't like he said.
Like he said?
Like you say
you don't speak Spanish.
Mr. Kemp doesn't
speak Spanish.
JUDGE: Well, he will have
plenty of opportunity to learn.
The charges against you
are grave.
Resisting arrest carries a tariff
alone of one year in prison.
Never mind assault
with a deadly weapon.
I'm going to refer this case
to a higher court.
Meanwhile, I remand you both
in custody for 30 days.
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
(SANDERSON SPEAKING SPANISH)
if I may, Your Honor.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Go ahead, Mr. Sanderson.
Thank you, Your Honor.
It isn't my purpose
to interrupt proceedings,
but if the intention is to
remand these gentlemen,
I would respectfully ask
for a brief recess
to allow me to contact
their counsel.
JUDGE: Who is who?
Alfredo Quinones.
It would necessitate getting
him out of bed, of course.
But given the importance
of these gentlemen to
various interests,
I'm sure that he would
be as pleased as I
to come down here
at 3:00 in the morning.
How much did we cost him?
About $1,000 apiece.
(ENGINE STARTS)
I can't thank you enough.
Don't be late.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(GULPING)
SALA:
Mother of balls!
We got to rescue the car.
Not now.
We'll do it later.
I've got a meeting.
We do not have later.
They've already
had it 12 hours.
I know how these bastards work.
They can strip a train
to axles in 12 minutes.
We'll be lucky
to find an oil spot.
How long is this gonna take?
How would I know?
I can't be late.
I don't know
why you're going at all.
That guy is bad company.
He's a manipulative prick.
He manipulated us
out of jail, didn't he?
Now he fucking owns us.
I got a tongue like...
Like a towel.
Want a beer?
Do I want a beer?
No, I do not.
I am never gonna
touch alcohol again.
What fresh hell is this?
Front seat's gone.
That's a write-off.
Isn't it?
(PANTING)
You know what,
I've got a brilliant idea.
(CAR RATTLING)
What's that?
SALA: There's too much
weight on the axle.
Try and move forward a bit.
Ugh, gonna be late.
I'm gonna be a week late.
What are you doing, Sala?
I suddenly realize
how much I like you.
What do you mean,
what am I doing?
There's something wrong
with the axle.
Oh, my God, it's the
cop we set on fire.
Try and look normal.
(SIREN WAILING)
Make a right!
What right? There is no right.
Any right!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(CAR CRASHING)
SANDERSON: Oh, there he is.
Paul, come in.
Sorry. There were
unexpected developments.
I had to go home
and start the day again.
Tell me about it.
Some days are two sizes too small.
Well, I'm afraid some
of us had to leave.
But, Mr. Zimburger
you know.
And this is Mr. Green of First
National Maritime Bank.
You want some coffee?
I think we should
move right along, Hal.
I gotta go.
Sure.
Sit down, Paul.
As you may know,
Mr. Kemp,
the island is owned
by the U.S. government.
Part of it presently used as
a target range by the Navy.
We know from
internal sources...
Is that what you're calling me?
(MEN CHUCKLING)
...that the government is preparing
to relinquish the lease,
and this place wakes up
as 32 square miles
of magnificent and
untouched real estate.
Knock your eyes out.
No prettier beaches
in the Caribbean.
Orientated around one hell
of a beautiful marina.
Thought it was one hotel.
We start with one hotel.
It's a foot in the door.
Once we're up and running,
we're servants of a market.
Like here?
Like here.
You look worried,
Mr. Kemp.
He's not worried.
Paul and I shared
a tricky little night.
Right, Paul?
Oh.
Neither of us got much sleep.
(CHUCKLES)
I gotta go, guys.
Well, we'll leave
you gentlemen to it.
Has Mr. Kemp
signed the papers?
Doing that right now.
What... What am I
actually signing?
Just a confidentiality agreement,
affirmation of trust.
Just so we're all sitting
in the same Jacuzzi.
In case a turd floats up,
if you know what I mean.
Come on, Paul,
let's go over here.
Here you go.
(SIGHS)
it's just a technicality, Paul.
Means you promise not to talk
to anybody about the project.
How's the head?
Unpleasant.
Gotta thank you again
for putting up the bail.
It's held on my cognizance.
And I think it more than
likely to slip various minds.
This place is a sea
of money, Paul.
Unbelievable money.
Practically every major corporation
hides its cash offshore.
No, thanks.
And that is good news for us,
because we are the shore.
Not one dollar that wings
its way into Puerto Rico
pays a cent in tax.
Nothing?
Not penny one.
That includes
chemical companies,
oil companies,
mining companies.
There's $12 billion
worth of copper
in mountains less than
20 miles from here.
A dozen billion dollars.
And there's people like me
who know how to get it out.
So, putting it into context,
I don't envisage
the breaking of bones
to get at a thousand bucks.
Because you weren't here,
I agreed to an itinerary with
Zimburger on your behalf.
You'll be traveling down in the morning.
Hope that's okay.
What do you need, Paul?
Well, just in the context
of this Zimburger thing,
do you think there's a
possibility of an advance?
I don't like to ask, but
Letterman's pretty erratic
with the paycheck, you know.
Need to get a hold of a car.
You don't have a car?
Nothing too reliable.
Plus, sooner or later, I'm gonna
have to find a decent place to live.
Well, we can
help you with that.
When you get back, we'll sort
you out something with a view.
Carol, what do we
have in the garage?
No, no, no, no,
no, no, not that.
Yeah, that's fine.
Okay, thank you.
Got you a car.
She'll give you the keys on the way out.
Feels like 500?
Yeah. Thanks.
Oh, Paul...
How's your afternoon?
A half-written horoscope.
Do me a favor, will you?
Drive out to the beach and pick up Chenault.
I need her
downstairs by 6:00.
All right.
(ENGINE REVVING)
So, this one?
Or...
This one?
What are these for, a party?
It's for carnival.
Didn't he say anything
to you about it?
No.
Oh, you've got to come.
We're all going down
on the boat.
He didn't invite me.
Well, it isn't his carnival.
Oh, this one.
Um...
I like the other one.
Yes.
Love this car.
Did he give it to you?
(CHUCKLES) I wish.
Fast.
You want a little bet?
A bet about what?
That you scream before I do.
That I scream before you do,
in relation to what?
Well, how fast does it go?
I don't know.
That's the bet.
I already crashed
one car today.
It's okay.
I'll just go sit
in the foyer and wait for him.
What do I get if I win?
I'll let you know if you do.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Come on, I'll take you back.
KEMP: Christ,
where'd they get this?
I don't remember.
I've been slightly avoiding Letterman.
You have me to thank
for your freedom.
Thanks.
I got a feeling
of total anxiety
trying to put my anxieties together
in a single, coherent lump.
I'm fucked without a car.
I got us a car.
It's the Chevy downstairs.
It belongs to Mr. Sanderson.
So what?
I gotta go type this up.
(LOTTERMAN SHOUTING)
I don't know what's going on.
He's freaking out
and we're down 12 pages.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
You better frigging do it!
I see your filthy animal
face in here again,
I'll have you locked up!
What part of the building are
you creeping towards, Sala?
Darkroom.
Cops are looking for you.
Looking for me?
Looking for you.
And it ain't just your
mug in the paper!
What a day.
What a week.
I tell you, I'm out of here.
One way to friggin' Mexico.
Listen, I got a trip tomorrow.
Sanderson's island.
No, no, no.
Oh, dear.
It's green money, and I'm thinking
of cutting across for the carnival.
You know they got that
carnival in Saint Thomas.
I know.
Why don't you come with me?
Give the cops
a few days to forget.
Yeah. Fun.
(LAUGHING)
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
Our guys.
12-inch Naval, 14 miles out.
Nobody lives here?
No one who's staying.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
Lazar!
Mr. Zimburger.
(LAUGHS)
This is Mr. Lazar, our much
put-upon site architect.
How do you do.
Hello.
Mr. Monk,
I think you know.
I assist Mr. Green,
First Maritime Bank.
This is Mr. Kemp
from The New York Times.
What did you say your name was?
Bob Sala.
Yeah, Sala.
From American Travel
Writers Association.
(CHUCKLES)
Mr. Kemp is preparing
our brochure.
"Wish you were here."
Beer in the cooler, gentlemen.
I have everything next door.
This and this are
the main hotels.
22 floors.
Guardians of the bay,
so to speak.
Why the different colors?
Blue is for public dissemination,
red is for the investors.
Yeah. Hill villas, ocean condos.
Marina.
(CHUCKLES)
Parking for 2,000 cars.
There's no roads.
Damn it, Lazar,
you forgot the roads!
(LAUGHING) We're building them.
We're building them.
Let's have some lunch.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
10,000 waiters, maids,
bellhops, janitors, clerks.
Plus, whores for the fat man.
Hard to believe they'd do it.
I was talking to that
architect kind of guy.
He's going to Saint Thomas,
if you want a ride.
When?
How do I know when?
When he's finished here.
You know what Oscar Wilde said?
"They know the price
of everything,
"the value of nothing."
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
Two rums.
I thought you'd given up.
Finally beat my willpower.
Come on, let's go here.
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hey, mi amigo!
Hey, Rosie's a singer.
Paul!
Where's Hal?
Boat.
Boat?
Help me find my girlfriend.
CHENAULT: Hey!
How are you?
Watch your step.
Thank you.
All right.
There we go.
Thank you.
Hi.
Look at you.
SANDERSON: Good.
Grab some champagne.
Hey, Captain.
Hey.
Did you take Sala
to the island?
You shouldn't have
done that, Paul.
It's why we have
a confidentiality agreement.
He isn't interested.
He's got a mouth
like an AP wire.
I just don't know
what he was doing there.
And I sure as shit don't
know what he's doing here.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Not going glum on us, are you?
Just thoughts.
What's the book?
The Rime of the
Ancient Mariner.
It was written in 1797 by
a junkie called Coleridge.
He wrote that when
he was 25 years old.
I've been dragging a typewriter
around with me for 10.
I've written nothing.
You've written some books.
Nah.
They had no voice.
I don't know how
to write like me.
I resent that.
No, I really have
to say he's all right.
I have to admit.
Fair is fair.
Thank you for the afternoon.
Maybe we'll see you in town.
Where you going?
Her friend's playing in a band.
We're gonna go check it out.
Oh, we want to come.
SANDERSON:
I'll rephrase that.
We don't want to come.
Yes, we do.
Us girls want to dance.
SANDERSON:
You're dancing tomorrow.
CHENAULT: What's the point
of going to carnival
if everything is preplanned?
I want to dance, and if
you're not going to take me,
I'm gonna go with them.
DIGBY: She's got you trumped, Hal.
Sit down. You're drunk.
So what?
So is everyone else.
Come on.
Come on, let's do it.
It might be amusing.
Oh, cuidado.
Careful.
Here we go.
(WOMAN WHOOPING)
(PLAYING ROCK 'N' ROLL)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Oh.
Yeah.
(CROWD CHEERING)
We're done.
We're spent.
You're gonna go?
Yes, we're gonna leave.
You're done?
I can't dance no more.
Really.
Hold on. You know what? I'll be out.
Let me just get Chenault.
SALA: You want
rum or beer?
Um... Both.
Dos, uh, rum, uh, dos cervezas.
Oh, whoa, whoa.
We're gonna go.
Hey.
CHENAULT: What?
SANDERSON: Natalie's leaving,
so let's go.
CHENAULT: Hey, hey.
Come on, come on.
No, no, no, no.
(MUSIC BEGINS) (GASPS) Oh!
Chenault, come here.
We're leaving.
Chenault.
Stop it!
Chenault!
♪ Hey, what?
♪ I hear you
♪ Yeah
(SINGER LAUGHING)
♪ You all right?
♪ Try it
♪ Try it again
♪ You try it again
♪ Shall we just sit?
♪ Try again
♪ Like a baby
♪ Won't you try it?
♪ You might like it
♪ Honey
♪ Yeah
♪ Yeah, ha
♪ it's all right
♪ I tried
♪ That's right
(PATRONS CHEERING)
Chenault, come here!
Chenault!
Get your hands off me,
you motherfucker!
♪ Yeah ♪
You want to fuck with me?
You know who I am?
You motherfucker!
You're a dead man!
Go! Go!
Get your hands off me.
You're a dead man!
Go!
Forget it.
We'll call you a cab.
Fuck off!
I gotta get the girl.
She's having a good time.
We closed.
You deaf?
I said we closed.
No way, Paul.
No way.
(SIGHS)
I looked everywhere.
I went to the gendarme.
And?
We went up there.
Nothing. Nobody there.
But an old woman with a mop.
She was more help
than the cops were.
"What can I do if your girlfriend
likes someone else?" he said.
He's right about that, Paul.
She's not your girlfriend.
Maybe... Maybe she
went back to the boat.
Huh?
Did you...
Did you try the boat?
No.
I don't think
he'd let her back on.
Is she with you?
Why don't you mind
your own goddamn business?
I want the keys.
The Chevy.
(KEYS JANGLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
You blew it, Kemp.
KEMP: it's all rust.
I've seen better tires hanging
over the side of a tug.
You want it or not?
Yeah, we want it.
Everyone turns up for their
Friday check, right?
No check, no Letterman.
So I go around to see that
unforgivably ugly wife of his.
She tells me
he's gone to Miami.
For what?
You don't know, I don't know.
But the scabs are back.
Since Merell went, the paper
took a turn for the worse.
Is there anything
in the spinner?
We need a fresh sack.
Well, maybe I can interest you
gentlemen in something else.
Like what, death?
Like the most powerful drug
in the history of narcotics.
I'm not at liberty
to discuss or disclose.
All I can tell you
is this stuff is so powerful,
they give it to Communists.
Who does?
The FBI.
Why would the FBI
get Communists high?
That I can't help you with.
You take it like eye drops.
In the eye?
So I understand.
It makes the eye see things.
You see a different reality.
What do you want for it?
I'll throw it in with the bike
if you do me a favor.
What's the favor?
I want you to come
to the bathroom with me.
He's your man.
$50, right?
Yeah.
(CHICKEN CLUCKING)
He wants me
to look at his dick.
I flatly refused.
What does he want you
to look at it for?
Says there's something
wrong with it.
It's a gentleman's matter.
I'm not looking at it!
All right, give me
the drugs back.
No! Wait.
I'll look at it.
I'll view it in the mirror.
Is it clap?
A standing ovation.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
You see anything?
No.
Neither do I.
We'll give it another
five minutes.
ANNOUNCER: Trouble
making ends meet?
Then, you need the Lending Man.
Right.
♪ When money dries up fast
♪ You're welcome to our cash
♪ So borrow from
the Lending Man ♪
Call the Lending Man now.
How long since we took it?
I don't know.
A while.
Bullshit, isn't it?
Is it bullshit?
(STRIKES MATCH)
(SIZZLING)
(HISSES)
(GRUNTS)
Jesus.
Your tongue is like
an accusatory giblet.
(GROANING)
For Christ's sake, keep it out.
What are you talking about?
Your tongue belongs to Satan!
Are you out of your mind?
Keep it out!
If it goes back into your
mouth, it'll kill you.
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
We've got to get it
into the sink!
(GRUNTING)
You're giving me fear.
Stop it!
I've got fear!
Fuck you. So do I.
You're high, you fool.
Drink some rum.
(BUOY BELL CLANGING)
I thought I was
losing grip in there.
What did we take?
I don't know.
We need to get some more.
That explains it.
Doesn't it?
SALA: Explains what?
The world.
And us.
KEMP: I wonder
what it is
you might think about
our different worlds.
He looked at me kind
of sideways and said,
"Human beings are the
only creatures on Earth
"that claim a God.
"And the only living thing that
behaves like it hasn't got one.
"Does the world belong
to no one but you?"
And when he said it,
I was taken aback.
Not because of who
was doing the talking,
because I finally
understood the connection
between children
scavenging for food
and shiny brass plates
on the front doors of banks.
Gotta go.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Shh. Come in.
Come in.
SALA: We gotta go.
Give me a minute.
I'll be waiting
for you downstairs.
Oh, how nice of you to drop in.
I was covering the carnival.
That's not what I heard.
I heard you were in the
moonlight for Sanderson.
I was what?
Moonlighting for Sanderson.
Where's Segurra?
Mr. Segurra's
no longer with us.
I got a story for you.
Yeah, you may have noticed
that I'm somewhat busy.
This is real important, involving
Mr. Segurra and Mr. Hal Sanderson.
I'm gonna tell you
how important it isn't.
I got 21 jobs on the line
and a newspaper going under.
Print this, and you'll sell it.
A planning scam.
Literally despoliation
of a paradise.
A thousand people will be swept
into the sea like garbage.
You are weird, Kemp.
It's not what it's doing to them,
it's what it's doing to you.
It's called journalism.
Oh, make me laugh.
I asked you
to tidy up the booze,
you couldn't even
sweep out a room.
Why do you think
you're working here?
'Cause you're everything that's
wrong with a journalist.
And you're everything that's wrong
with this insult of a newspaper.
Unanimously agreed.
Why don't you shut it, Moburg?
You are a waste of human sperm.
MOBURG: Die a prolonged and
relentlessly agonizing death!
Enjoy her.
(WHISTLING)
Made you some tea.
You should try and sleep.
I stole your bed.
(CHUCKLES) it's okay.
I'm going to write.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be sorry.
You did me the best
favor I ever had.
There is no dream, Chenault.
Just a piss puddle of greed,
spreading throughout the world.
KEMP: I want to make a
promise to you, the reader.
And I don't know if I
can fulfill it tomorrow
or even the day after that.
But I put the bastards
of this world on notice.
That I do not have their
best interests at heart.
I will try and speak
for my reader.
That is my promise.
And it will be a voice
made of ink and rage.
Sit down.
I made you coffee.
Oh, thanks.
One for you and one for me.
Oh, man, I would rather not
start the day with this.
What is it?
It's a writ.
Means we're going to court.
It means they can arrest
us, should they so desire,
any damn minute they please.
We need to speak to a lawyer.
We don't even have a phone.
I know an old guy,
Spanish Advocate.
Kind of owes me one.
You should get dressed.
We'll go down there.
Water ran out.
I'm covered in soap.
Fuck it.
See what I can do.
What's it for?
Uh... it's Hal.
He put up a bond for us on this
thing, and now he's pulled it.
Here.
You know he's a crook, Paul.
And we get the writs.
(RECORDING OF ADOLF HITLER
SPEECH PLAYING)
What is it?
Lt's, er... Hitler.
(RECORD SCRATCHES)
it's over.
What is?
They shut us down.
DONOVAN: He just stood
there and lied to us.
He hasn't got the morality
of a clapped out cash register.
I hate to tell you this, guys,
but it was to avoid severance.
We all know what
it was for, Charlie.
What are we gonna do?
Nothing.
There's nothing we can do,
except report him
to the labor board,
which is the same thing
as doing nothing.
I disagree.
We gotta strike back
and nail this bastard
to his own front door.
DONOVAN: And how,
pray, do we do that?
By printing the paper.
We got tons of stuff
on Letterman.
Every happy maggot with
his hand in the till.
It may be
the last-ever issue,
but we go out
in a blaze of rage.
What are you talking about?
It costs $2,200 a shot.
We bring in the scabs.
They're picketing for money.
You're through
the looking glass.
We haven't even got
enough money for drinks.
It's not worth the fight.
This has been coming down
the pike for a long time.
You got to know
it's over when it's over.
This lousy little
Caribbean rag is nothing
but a wrapping for fish heads.
Plus, it's a lockout.
Fuck the locks.
I say we just walk in.
Anybody with me?
Bob?
You know I'm with you.
SALA: We didn't
pay the bill.
Where's Chenault?
(STRIKES MATCH)
She's gone to New York.
She left me $100.
I don't believe it.
She didn't have any money.
You should use it
to go with her.
Red-eye for 50 bucks.
No.
I'm not going anywhere.
By some means or another, I'm
gonna put the paper out.
Print the bastard,
then we're gone.
Face the reality, Paul.
There's no job,
no money, no girl,
and a warrant out
for our arrest.
There's no contest.
Donovan's right, it
ain't worth the fight.
I'm not Donovan!
And I'm not like the others.
I'm telling you right now,
next time some greasy moron
starts bullshitting me,
I'm going after him.
All the way up to the president
of the United States.
I just want to win one once.
(STRIKES MATCH) One sheet.
You ain't gonna
get far on $100.
MOBURG: Some of the scabs
will do it for nothing.
We're gonna need
20 guys, plus vans.
No, no, all you need
is two grand.
We're out of rum.
It's as if God,
in a fit of disgust,
has decided to wipe us all out.
(ROOSTER CROWS)
Yea, the cock crows thrice.
What about El Monstruo?
Bet the $100 on El Monstruo.
How do you know he lives here?
I saw him come out.
You better let me
do this on my own.
If he gets it, we should
bring it to Papa Nebo.
Who's that?
My witch doctor.
She's a hermaphrodite.
MOBURG: Stop here!
Stop here!
By day, she drives
a garbage truck.
By night,
she becomes Papa Nebo,
the hermaphroditic
oracle of the dead.
When permission is granted
from Papa Samedi,
the keeper of the cemetery,
she'll visit,
and she'll dig up a corpse.
Certain organs of
the disgrounded stiffs
are indispensable
for use in ouangas.
(WOMAN BABBLING)
This is horseshit, isn't it?
She cured my prick.
(WOMAN MUTTERING)
(BEADS CLATTERING)
(BABBLING)
She wants to know
what you want.
We want her
to empower this fowl.
We want it blessed
and anything that tries
to fight it, dead.
(BABBLING)
Bring forth the fowl.
(CLUCKING)
(BABBLING)
(CHANTING)
(PAPA NEBO SPITTING)
(BABBLING LOUDLY)
(LAUGHS)
(BABBLES)
She says that no fowl on Earth
could challenge this
cockerel and survive.
Great.
How's she off for curses?
MOBURG: Pretty good.
Let's have a curse on Sanderson.
Make his dick fall off.
And that fucker
at the bank, Green.
Mr. Green.
(PAPA NEBO BABBLING)
(GAGGING)
Jesus!
MOBURG: Curse active!
(CHICKEN CLUCKING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING SPANISH
ON PA)
Okay, come on.
(CROWD WHISTLING)
(SQUAWKS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CHEERING)
One down, two to go.
Okay. I'm gonna
call Moburg.
Okay.
(LINE RINGING)
Come on. Come on.
He isn't there.
He has to be.
(DISTANT PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING)
KEMP: Where have you been?
Sorry.
I never heard the phone.
How's it going?
Winning, man.
We're winning.
Is everyone there?
Yeah, everyone's here.
What about the vans?
What about the vans, Moburg?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, vans.
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING SPANISH
ON PA)
(CROWD CHEERING) You hear that?
We're on our way.
What the hell is going on?
He said he had the men.
"All claims against the
former owners will be..."
(MUMBLING)
"Signed on behalf of First
Maritime Bank, Miami."
Sanderson's pal, Mr. Green.
Sorry, Paul.
I didn't know how to say.
They... They took
all the machines out.
Not everything,
but just the parts that matter.
I'll let you in.
(DOOR SLAMS IN DISTANCE)
All I wanted was a front page.
Probably for the best.
Probably would've
never pulled it off.
How much...
How much did you guys win?
Just under six grand.
Oh, yeah, well, you...
At least you can
pay off the bond now.
Screw the bond.
We're out of here.
It's over with.
SALA: There's
a midnight Pan Am.
I'm not risking the airport.
No.
I figure this island
owes us a boat.
And I'm fuckin' taking
one of Sanderson's.
You smell it?
It's the smell of bastards.
It's also the smell of truth.
I smell ink.
♪ Always think
♪ About the days gone by
♪ When the childhood
I have sown
♪ Appears in the sky
♪ But I'm not the simple man
♪ The boy I used to be
♪ No, I learned
to picture life...
I got to take the hen back.
♪ And I found
♪ After all the searching
♪ Life was only what I made it
for new games to play...
Find yourself a trade wind.
♪ After all the searching
♪ Life was only what I made it
for a new game to play
♪ Live my life away
♪ Saw a dragon
shake the theater walls
♪ While the steeple bell
♪ Rang out in anguished calls
♪ And I turn my eyes
♪ To see a bird fly overhead
♪ And I dreamt
its wings of freedom
♪ Could be mine instead
♪ And I found
♪ After all the dreaming
♪ Life was only what I made it
♪ Of new games to play
♪ I drink my life away
♪ Love you all
♪ And livin' on
♪ Livin' life the way... ♪
♪ Do you remember me?
♪ The ocean rolled
Time was slow
♪ We felt an energy
♪ The cock was crowing
♪ The rum was flowing
♪ A mermaid burns to see
♪ Beyond the sea
♪ I long to see
♪ if there's a page for me
♪ A page for me
♪ In your diary ♪