"Question number two.
"Describe a challenge, hardship
"or misfortune you have
experienced in your life.
"What have you learned from this "and
how has it prepared you for the future"
Dear Dean of Admissions, my name is
Sutter Keely, and up until yesterday
I had the best fucking
girlfriend in the world.
Hmm... I know I
probably shouldn't say
"fuck" right there, but
I'm sorry, I have to.
Like, we had
this connection, serious.
Everybody knew us.
Everybody loved us.
We were a force
to be reckoned with.
Now, I'm not gonna say that we
were the life of every party,
but we were.
We were the life
of every party.
Before Cassidy, I wasn't
much of a relationship guy,
but once we started
hooking up, that all chang.
I'm fucking horny.
I liked her.
A lot.
Everything was going great in my world.
I don't know what happened.
I was just trying
to get my best friend Riy
some much needed
sexual attention.
All right. Okay.
Colleen Marshall. She's nice.
RICKY: She's way too tall. I'd
look like her son or something.
Man, dude, I'm tired
of your excuses, man.
Like tonight...
Tonight's the night.
And what night is this?
Tonight's the night I'm gonna
get you some action, Ricky.
(SCOFFING)
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Some sweet, sweet action.
You know, I don't know
about this, Sutter.
Why?
They're just girls, man.
Relax. It's fine.
(CAR HONKING)
What is that?
Uh, looks like potential.
Just the man
we were looking for!
What's up Tara, Bethany!
How are you girls?
You know where
we can score some beers?
Uh, yeah. I think I can
help you out with that.
Okay. Let's do it!
- Let's do it.
- (SCREAMING)
Potential, man.
That's potential.
- My hero. -That's what I do.
That's what I do.
Uh, Bethany, you know
my friend Ricky, don't you?
SUTTER: Ah, shit, dude, I forgot
my cell phone in the car.
RICKY:
Well, Sutter, I've got...
No, you guys go ahead, we'll
uh, we'll get the next one.
- Bye.
Aww.
- That was bullshit about the phone.
- Totally.
(RADIO PLAYING)
I can't wait
to get out of this place.
Can we put on
something else maybe?
Hmm? You don't like this?
I love this. It relaxes me.
Gotta listen to the lyrics too. Who's this?
- Oh. - SUTTER: It was harmless.
I was just there
helping out a friend.
Is there something
wrong with that?
- Hey! -But next thing
I know, I'm being
accused of, like, crossing
a le or something.
I mean, seriously, it was a
complete misunderstanding.
I mean, I still can't
make sense of it.
This is for Ricky. I put
him in a canoe with...
You are a lost cause, Sutter!
- Cassidy, are you... You can't be serious right now.
- We are done! We're done!
To be honest though,
I wasn't that worried.
We'd had our ups
and downs, sure.
But what great couple
doesn't, you know?
I'm sorry.
All I had to do was calm her
down, explain the situation,
tell her how important
she was to me,
how good we were together,
and how much
our relationship meant.
Sutter.
What are you doing here?
(SIGHING) Ah, Cassidy, that is a really
pretty dress that you're wearing right now.
It's goddamn stunning,
that dress.
- That dress. Wow!
- Thank you.
- Is he drunk or something?
- Probably.
Well, let's just say
if drunk equals A,
and then somethin'
else equals B,
the answer is definitely not B.
- Sutter. -Look, man, I know
this is awkward, okay?
- Maybe we should talk... -No,
it's really not awkward at all.
Marcus West talkin' to me?
What an honor, man!
- Hey, man, let's go to my car.
- What an honor!
- Sutter! -I completely understand
the meaning of the phrase
"kicked to the curb,"
so, I will bid you both
a pleasant evening.
- Sutter, what happened here? -Just let him go.
He drives better this way.
Thank you for that
vote of confidence, beautiful.
You are a very understanding
woman, in everything but love.
Arrivederci. Fuck you.
You want hardshi? Misfortune?
Well, there you go. Will
I wallow in my misery?
No. I won't, Dean of Admissions.
Not Sutter Keely.
And in the meantime,
why should she be
the only one having fun?
It's a beautiful night outside
and I am just getting started.
- Hey, bro, I need to see your ID.
- Hey, what's up, man?
- I need to see your ID.
- Oh, I forg...
Like, I, I had it and then I,
I forgot it.
I think I left it in there
maybe in the bathroom...
I'm sorry,
but there's nothing I can do.
(STAMMERING) You know...
I know the manager.
- No ID... -John? Big John?
The little one?
It's the...
The manager, the Big John?
Yo, what's up, ladies?
I'm, uh... So I'm 18 and I just got dumped
by my girlfriend, and I need a drink,
so, would somebody, like anybody,
please have a drink with me?
Whoo, red shit!
Where are you guys going?
Whoa! Hey! Hey! Wait, wait.
I thought we we're
all comin'...
I thought we we're all
hanging out after this.
Come on, please, please!
I don't wanna...
I'm not gonna beg you.
I will beg you.
Bye.
Hey, you're beautiful!
Your totally down
with the king!
Down with
the motherfucking king!
Whoo!
Hello?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Hey.
Hello?
Hello. Hi.
Hi.
(CHUCKLING) Hi.
Oh, my God, you're alive.
I thought for a second
that maybe you were dead.
I don't think I'm dead.
Where the hell am I?
Um, you're in the middle
of a yard.
Do you know who lives here?
No.
Jesus, I must have
fallen asleep.
Here, let me help you up.
(SUTTER GROANING)
Where the hell's my car?
I don't know.
Do you live
around here, Sutter?
How do you know my name?
We go to the same school.
You wouldn't know who I am.
I know you. You're, uh...
- Uh... -(CHUCKLING) I'm Aimee.
Aimee Finicky.
That's what I was gonna say.
Nice to meet you, Aimee.
(CHUCKLING)
Nice to meet you too.
What time is it, Aimee?
Uh, it's like 6:00 a.m.
Are you just getting back
from a party or somethin'?
No. No.
I'm just on my paper route.
I mean it's not really mine.
It's my mom's, but,
(INHALING DEEPLY) she was out with
my step-dad last night at a casino
so, um, they didn't
get back till late.
- Do you need help?
- So, I just...
- With my route?
- Yeah.
No, no, no.
I'm okay. Thank you, though.
I can help you.
I'm good. Thank you.
Aimee, you know,
you're driving around
the neighborhood,
and I don't know
where my car is,
so, I think that
we can help each other out.
What do you say?
Try aiming ahead
of the driveway.
Okay.
I didn't realize newspaper
throwing was such big business.
- You must make a lot of money.
- Yeah. I mean, my mom does.
- And you get nothing?
- No, I get a little.
Um, most of it goes towards
paying the bills, though, so...
That doesn't sound fair. You
do all the work, don't you?
Some of it. Most of it.
Aimee, she's your mom! She
should be paying all your bills.
- (LAUGHING) -I'm serious. That
doesn't sound fair to me.
I think you're getting the raw end
of this newspaper throwing deal.
It's fine.
I think I'm getting
the hang of it.
You should have seen me
back in the day.
- When I was in Little League I
had a pretty good arm. -Yeah?
Yeah. My dad said...
He said I could have
went pro if I stuck with it.
Yeah, dude, you're a natural.
Good job.
Whoo!
- Ah, shit, I hit a dog!
- (DOG YELPING)
(AIMEE LAUGHING)
- I'm serious!
- Sutter!
It's still walkin'.
- Whoa! Went way downtown!
- (LAUGHING)
You know, Aimee Finicky?
I was having a really rotten night
last night until you came along.
I think that we should
get lunch sometime.
Okay.
- How about Monday?
- Okay. Monday it is.
You're up early.
Yep.
Hmm...
They have me
on a double shift. Again.
Oh, damn it, Sutter.
Didn't I ask you
to hang this for me?
Look!
Look how wrinkled this is.
It would have taken you two
seconds to hang this up for me.
Is that too much to ask?
I forgot. I'm sorry.
You know, it's not like
you do so much around here.
- Hey! I do a lot around here.
- Hey!
Oh, I'm sorry. I hate to interrupt
your, uh, cheerio eating.
I'm sorry, Mom.
(SIGHING)
Sometimes you remind me
so much of your dad.
All right, there's
leftovers in the fridge.
I won't be home for dinner,
or, you can call your sister.
(SIGHING)
- And Sutter...
- Mmm-hmm?
Next time I ask you
to do something...
(CLICKING TONGUE)
I love you so much it hurts.
It hurts me
how much I love you.
You know what's
gonna really hurt?
Who knew dinner and a movie
would cost 30 bucks?
Pretty much anybody
who's ever been on a date.
Oh, but the best part
is, dude, she didn't care.
She paid for the popcorn
and everything.
She's just...
- What?
- (SIGHING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Did you kiss her?
- Check.
- Yeah? Did you get a little tongue action?
- Double check.
- Nice. Nice. Yeah.
- (CHUCKLING)
Thanks, man.
So, what you wanna eat for lunch, man?
I'm starving.
Uh, aren't you eating
with what's her name?
Oh, shit. Yeah. I forgot.
You know, I gotta tell you, Sutter.
Aimee Finicky?
It's just a strange choice
for a rebound.
Dude, she's not a rebound.
Dude, she's not! Look.
Do I look like I have any
interest in dating Aimee Finicky?
I think she's a nice girl, man.
Whose mom makes her deliver newspapers
at 5 o'clock in the morning
six days a week,
pays half the bills...
- Aimee doesn't say shit about it.
- That sucks.
It's bullshit is what it is.
All right, so where
do you come in?
Um, I mean, I think
I can help her out.
So, if two planes intersect,
they intersect in exactly,
give it to me,
A one plane, B one
point, C one line...
(BELL RINGING)
Oh, that's lunch.
You lucky sons of guns.
Don't forget to do the homework.
Sutter, a word?
- Huh? -Please, Mr. Keely, sit
down, I have to have a word.
- I have somewhere to go.
- Good bye. Good bye, Hannah.
Don't be late tomorrow please.
Thank you.
You button up.
- What's up?
I noticed you didn't turn in
the homework.
Which is... That's fine man.
Cause I...
I did it last night and I...
Yeah. Stop talking.
Do me a favor. Stop talking.
All right. What's up?
You tell me, Sutter. I only
want to see you succeed.
- You know that, right?
- I know. I know.
If you fail,
that means I failed.
I like my job, I like you.
I don't wanna fail.
I know. I don't want you to... I
don't want you to fail either.
That's why
I'm not gonna let us fail.
- Uh-huh. -And I'm gonna
get it together.
- And I'm turning that corner, I can feel myself...
- Make me believe you.
Make me... I wanna believe you.
- I'm feelin' smarter already.
-All right.
Let me see you answer this.
All right.
If one acute angle is two
times larger than the other,
what's the measure
of the two angles?
That's what I thought.
- That was not in the homework.
- That was the homework.
- No, it wasn't man! -Stay right
there, I'm gonna show you.
- We gonna do it together.
- (SIGHING)
We gonna do your homework together.
I love it.
That's crazy!
How fast were you going?
Like 20, 25 miles
an hour or something.
- And you just jumped out of the car?
- Yeah.
(LAUGHING) What?
It was snowing so
I didn't think it would hurt.
But it did.
That's amazing.
That's awesome.
You're such a good listener.
- No...
- Um, all right, you go.
Um, I remember, um,
I think it was sophomore year.
You came to gym class
and you were wearing
the mascot head
and you refused to take it off.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Yeah. (LAUGHING)
- Yeah, that was funny.
- Yeah, it was really funny.
Yeah. No, I mean, like
what's a story about you.
- About me?
- Yeah.
Um...
I don't really
have any stories.
What do you mean?
Everyone's got a story.
(CHUCKLING) Not me, I guess.
Um, all right, so, like, what's,
I don't know, what's your thing?
- My thing? -Yeah, you know,
everybody's got a thing.
Larry Rourke, stoner.
Uh, Greg Jacoby
is the rich kid.
What's, what's your thing?
I don't know,
I'd like to think that there's
more to a person than just one thing.
You know?
- Yeah.
- GIRL: Hello, Aimee.
- So, he, uh, finally got here, did he?
- Hey. This is Krystal.
- Hey, Krystal. Sutter Keely. Nice to meet you.
- Yeah. I know who you are.
Uh, Aimee, come on,
French Club.
They're waiting for us.
Chop-chop!
I'm so sorry.
Oh, my God, I totally forgot
about French Club.
- I'm sorry.
- No. It's all good.
Um, hey, did you have, uh,
Mr. Aster for geometry class?
Yeah. Freshman year.
Probably thought
it was pretty easy?
Kind of. I don't know.
Yeah. I bet you did.
Uh, would you mind
like tutoring me?
'Cause he's talking
all the time,
I have no idea
what he's saying.
Yeah. Sure, totally. Um...
Yeah. Just, uh...
You can just like,
call me and...
Yeah.
Just call me.
Awesome.
Nice meeting you too. Pleasure.
- See you later.
- All right. Bye.
- You have great taste in bow ties.
- Thank you.
That was my favorite. I would
have bought it if you didn't.
MAN: See you at home.
Hmm...
- What do you think of that?
- You're getting better.
- That's really good. That's the
best I've seen yet. -All right.
When you gonna adopt me?
(CHUCKLING) I'm sorry, uh,
- two's my limit on mouths to feed.
- Okay.
Offer's still there.
- What were we talking about?
- Um, Cassidy.
Ah!
- Yeah.
- (EXHALING) Pfft...
I liked her.
Yeah. Me too. (SCOFFING)
Kinda thought she'd be the one
to yank you out of neutral.
Neutral? What are you talking about, Dan?
I'm in overdrive.
- (CHUCKLING)
- What?
- Aimee!
- Shane, shut up!
- Hey!
- Hey.
- How are you?
- Good.
- All right.
Come on in.
Hey.
- This is my brother Shane.
- Hey, Shane.
- He just learned that. Yeah.
- Charming.
- We can study in my room.
- Lead the way.
Wow! This is...
It's really nice.
Thank you.
I try to keep it clean.
There's a lot of stuff everywhere.
(LAUGHING)
SUTTER: You read a lot?
You like books?
AIMEE: I do, actually,
I love books.
They're mostly
just science fiction.
A few mysteries
and other things.
- That one is really weird.
- This is the weird one?
- You picked a really weird one.
- Weird is good.
Let's embrace the weird.
It's really weird.
- Is this backwards? Why... -Yeah.
It's just the way that you read them.
Let me see. You start...
Back here. It's the beginning.
- Yep.
- Cool.
Gleaming...
- BOTH: Planet.
- Gleaming Planet. (LAUGHING)
- Is this... Is that you
flying through space? -No.
No. She's just a character
from those books.
It's, like, really stupid.
No, it's not stupid. If you
like it, it's not stupid.
Yeah. Well...
What makes her so special?
Um, she's in charge of this
thing called the Neexo Ark.
And it's up to her to
escape the Dark Galaxy,
and save the Gleaming
Planet's star system.
Yeah. I don't know, like, I
know it's odd and stuff, but...
She's actually really awesome.
She's kind of my hero.
Well, you will be my hero if you can
help me out with this geometry business.
I have no idea what I'm doing.
- Is this the right book?
- Yes.
How much of
it have you studied?
- Studied's a strong word.
- (LAUGHING)
Angle C and angle B are...
- Complimentary... -Complimentary.
Got it. Got it.
Man, you're a wonderful
teacher, Miss Finicky.
- So, you understand it?
- Yeah.
Well, what I don't understand is
why I need to know this stuff.
Because, I mean seriously,
like, who, like,
cal... Coplanar lines
and angles and stuff,
like, who calculates slopes at their job?
Who needs this shit?
MRS. FINICKY: Aimee! Come on
out here right now, will you!
I thought you were going
to get us some milk.
- I will!
- Do it now, for crissakes!
- I am so sorry.
- That's okay.
- I should probably...
- Yeah...
Um, hey, there is
a party on Saturday
and I think that
you should go with me.
- Me?
- Yeah.
- What? -Yeah. I'll come
by and pick you up.
- How's that sound?
- Um...
Okay?
- Is that an answer or a question?
- No, no, it's an answer.
- If you don't wanna go...
- No, I do, I do.
I would like that. Thank you.
(ONLINE MESSENGER PINGING)
(ONLINE MESSENGER PINGING
CONTINUES)
Hey, do you want me
to carry that?
- I got it.
- You good?
- Yeah.
- All right.
- You see the water?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, do not go in there.
- No?
It's disgusting. I mean
people poop in there. Here.
I'm good. I don't really drink.
Just hold it. Gives off the
illusion you're having fun.
- Yeah. You don't have to drink it.
- (LAUGHING)
Hey, what's up, guys? How you doin'?
This is, uh, Aimee Finicky.
I don't know
if you guys know her.
Hey, Cody, you're a reader,
aren't you?
You ever read those
Gleaming Planet books?
- One or two.
- One or two?
I forgot to tell you. I started
reading one last night.
- You did?
- Yeah, it's really cool.
- Which one? -Yeah. The one
where Shirei Migoto uh...
Fights that Cosmic Super Lord,
just starts fucking him up.
- AIMEE: I know, right? She's awesome!
- SUTTER: She is awesome.
I love those books.
Have you read Solar Bull?
Yeah.
Yeah, Solar Bull is great.
It's like so many
awesome rad parts between...
Hey, sorry to interrupt. I... I don't
think we've met. I'm Sutter Keely.
- I'm Cassidy. -How are you? How's it going?
Oh, that's a nice handshake.
- Thank you. -Um, do you
wanna go get a beer?
I'm having a conversation
right now.
She'll be here. You'll be here, right?
We'll come back.
We're just gonna grab a beer.
Come on.
- You're unbelievable. I will be back, I guess.
- Please. Thank you.
- (LAUGHING) Don't smile at me like that.
- I can't help myself.
- You know that I can't help myself.
- Sutter! Please.
Maybe just a little...
That's good.
- Cassidy.
- Hey!
- Hey.
- Sutter.
Marcus.
I gotta get going.
You riding with me?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? Let's go.
- It was good to see you.
- Next time.
Just a flick of the wrist.
Works every time. Really.
- Hey, What's up, man? Everything cool?
- What's up, Sutter?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- I'm just gonna go for a walk. You wanna come with me?
- Yeah. I would love to.
- All right, cool.
- Cool.
- All right.
- Cheers.
- Nice to meet you. -It was,
it was good to meet you.
Motherfucker.
- Hey, I'm sorry if that guy was bugging you.
- No, he's fine, really fine.
Yeah? Okay. Done?
- Ooh, can I try that?
- What, this?
- Yeah. -I don't know. This is
some pretty serious stuff.
- Just a taste.
- You sure?
- Yes. -All right. Here you go.
Go for it.
It's pretty strong.
- Oh, my God!
- Yeah.
- Eww!
- Yeah. Yeah. I know.
- Whoa! - I know. - I told you.
- How do you drink that?
I don't know, I guess I've just been
doin' it for a while. I don't know.
- (LAUGHING) -You know who
gave me my first beer?
- Who?
- My dad.
- Really? -Yeah. I was
probably six years old.
He used to take me to baseball games every
Saturday and then let me have little sips of it.
- Did you get drunk? -No, I
didn't get drunk, but I mean,
it tasted really nice
and felt warm.
Where is he now, your dad?
- He's an airline pilot.
- Really?
- Yeah, he flies all across the country.
- Sutter, that's awesome!
Dude, he is awesome. I don't know what
he was doing with my mom for that long.
- Are they, like, divorced? -Yeah. She
made him leave us a long time ago.
- Want some more? Try it. Yeah?
Why not? -Um, sure.
- Kind of sounds like we have the same mom.
- Yeah? How so?
Um... Well, for example,
I got into college today, but there's no
way that my mom will let me go, so...
- You got into college today?
- Mmm-hmm.
- That's awesome!
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- In Philadelphia.
Which is really cool, 'cause that's
where my sister lives, but...
Aimee, I don't know what to say. That's...
Dude, that's awesome.
- Congratulations! Very cool.
- Thanks.
Doesn't matter, I mean, It's
not that big of a deal.
- There's no way that I'll go, so it's not.
- What are you talking about?
Well, I mean my mom, I have
to help her with the route.
What does your mom have to do with this?
The route?
- She has the route, she's alone.
- The paper route?
- Yeah, she's alone, she needs...
- Aimee, your mom
is a grown woman. She can take
care of the paper route herself.
You are definitely
going to Philly.
Yeah, 100% you're
- Yeah, no, but...
- Yeah, you are.
No, dude, there's no buts about it.
Aimee, don't you understand?
You are this, like, incredibly
gifted genius person,
and you've got all these people around
you telling you that you can't do shit.
And that's gotta stop. You need to
start standing up for yourself.
- How?
- How? I'll teach you.
Take another swig
of that stuff.
Get that, get that down there.
Down the hatch!
Okay. Now repeat after me.
"Mom, get off
my motherfucking back!"
- What!
- Yes!
- No!
- Yeah.
- I can't!
- Say it.
- Mom... Get off of my back.
- No.
- You gotta do the motherfucking.
- I can't.
Yes, you can. Do it. Say it.
- Mom, get off of my fucking back.
- Motherfucking!
Fuck! Motherfuck! - Go!
Motherfucking!
- Motherfuck, yes!
- Get off my motherfucking back, Mom!
- Yes!
God! Yeah!
- God! Motherfucking!
That's good. - That's awesome!
Good. Who else?
Who else? I like this.
I don't know. Stay out of my
motherfucking business, Krystal.
- Fuck you, Krystal.
- Yeah, fuck you Krys...
What about...
What about like ex-boyfriends?
- Um... -We need an
ex-boyfriend in there.
- No, I don't have any. -Who's like an
ex-boyfriend that really pissed you off.
- That you just, like, hate him and they're just, like...
- I don't have an ex-boyfriend.
- What?
- Yeah.
You don't have a single, you're 17 years
old and you don't have an ex-boyfriend?
No! - Really?
- Guys don't look at me like that.
That's shocking.
- I mean, guys... -Yeah, absolutely
guys look at you like that.
- No, no, no... -I just saw two
Uh, Erik Wolff and Cody Dennis
were 100% hitting on you.
- No, we were just talking.
- A hundred percent.
- No, no, there was absolutely no way...
- Yes, they were.
- Why don't you think they were hitting on you?
- Because I'm just...
- They weren't.
- Because you're what?
- Aimee, you're absolutely beautiful.
- Oh, my God! No.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
SUTTER: Of course
you're going to the prom!
I'll take you.
Please go to
the prom with me, Aimee!
Yes.
- So, you're taking her to prom?
- Yeah. It's no big deal.
It's you making plans, Sutter.
It's kind of a big deal.
Relax! I'm just trying
to help this girl out.
- Right, I forgot. Sutter to the rescue.
- Exactly.
(SUTTER HUMMING A TUNE)
And if she falls for you?
What happens then?
Shut up.
Are you kidding me?
VOICEMAIL: Hey, Sutter, it's Aime.
Um...
I didn't know if we were
gonna study today or not,
but I hadn't heard
from you, so...
Yeah, yesterday was...
I had a really great tim.
Thank you. (GIGGLING)
Okay, I'll talk to
you later. Bye.
- Or the lightning storm.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
On the roof.
That was amazing.
I've never felt like
that with anyone.
- It's not very often.
- Except with you.
Actually, I think I'm feeling it right now.
I'm feeling a moment.
- Stop it. - What?
Cass, look, seriously, when we're together
it's like we're invincible or somethin'.
All the shit of the world, like the
responsibilities, all the problems, that stuff,
man, that just disappears
when I'm with you.
Well, you can't just have fun all the time.
You have to be serious.
- Hey, I'm 100% serious.
- Yeah? About what?
About not being serious.
Did you even
apply to college yet?
I don't need college.
Who needs that shit?
Look, I got everything
I need right here.
I've got a job, I've got a car, I've got
a beautiful girl sittin' next to me.
You think beauty's in some classroom or
some text book or something and it's not.
That's not what it's about. This,
right here, this is beautiful.
All of this...
That's all you need.
You're drunk.
I'm drunk. You, whatever, you're drunk.
It doesn't matter.
Okay, whatever,
I'm right, you're right.
I'm just saying
you gotta live in the moment.
The moment? I want...
I want...
I want more than a moment.
- I want...
- What?
I want a future.
And you can't do that.
Wow.
(SIGHING) Uh...
Okay.
- (SOBBING) Please just go, Sutter.
- Don't...
Please just go.
All right.
What's up with you and Cassidy?
- Look, man, I don't want any trouble.
- Tell me the truth.
Nothing's up, man. She's moved on.
I've moved on...
- You've moved on? -We just
hang out and we have...
Oh! Okay, wow.
Come on, come on.
We have fun but there's nothing going on.
I promise you.
- Can I ask you something?
- Yeah.
Why can't it be me
she has fun with?
- What? -Why can't it be
me that she has fun with?
I'm not like you, Sutter. I don't
know how to make her laugh and stuff.
Dude! You are Marcus West, man.
You are the star athlete,
you're the class president.
Like, you are awesome. What's the name
of that charity that you started?
- The Hope Squadron. -The fucking
Hope Squadron, man! That is awesome!
- Seriously, you do not need my help. You're the man!
- No, no. It's not the same,
okay? Look, the way
she talks about you, man.
I want her to like
me like that. And she doesn't.
Dude, Marcus, trust me.
You don't wanna be like me.
I make jokes, yeah. But, I
mean, you get shit done.
You're gonna change the world, man. You
and Cass are perfect together. Trust me.
You're just too tense, man. A little tense.
You gotta loosen up, you know?
Yeah. Maybe, maybe.
- Hey, not everything has
to be so serious. -Yeah.
Man, I'm just saying like,
you can relax, you know?
You're awesome, man. Enjoy being who you are.
Live in the now.
- Embrace that shit.
- Yeah.
Hey, uh, thanks for, uh,
thanks for talking to me like this, Sutter.
I appreciate it.
- Hey, absolutely, man. Pleasure.
- I appreciate it, I really do.
- Any time.
- Sorry about the...
It's cool. Good.
- Hey, Sutter?
- Hmm?
They're wrong about you.
What's that?
You're not the joke
everyone thinks, man.
GIRL: Just who do
you think you are?
The King of Mexico.
You're not gonna joke
your way out of this, Sutter.
Aimee told me about
your little party by the lake.
And?
- And now you're avoiding her.
- I'm not avoiding her.
Really? Have you seen her since the party?
Have you even called?
Okay, look, why don't you get off my
back a little bit? Give me some space?
- I knew she got that from you. She said
the exact same thing. -Good. Good for her.
No, it's not good for her.
Aimee isn't like you, Sutter.
She's a sweet girl. She doesn't need
you causing problems in her life.
Okay, what Aimee doesn't need is you bossing
her around like she's your personal assistant.
- You shouldn't treat her this way.
- Thank you. Good talk.
(EXHALING)
- Hi!
- Hey.
- Hi.
- What's up?
(LAUGHING) Nothing. What are
you, what are you doing?
I didn't know you were
coming over today.
Yeah, I wasn't planning on coming
over, but I was driving around
and I thought, "I don't care how busy I am.
I should see what Aimee is doing"
- so, what... How are you doing, Aimee?
- (GIGGLING)
I'm good. I'm really good.
How are you, Sutter?
- I'm, I'm good. - Good.
Yeah, listen, my sister, she's having
this, fancy dinner party for her friends
and she's making me go. I
didn't know you had a sister?
Yeah, well,
we're not really that close.
Yeah. But, would
you wanna go with me?
- To your... To dinner?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Absolutely.
- Okay. Cool.
- Yeah. What time?
- 10 minutes?
- Oh, 10 minutes from now. -Yeah.
Okay.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
So, then I go back up
to the table and I say,
you know, "Can I get you
boys anything else?"
And then he says...
Okay, I'm gonna let
you say it, what did,
what did you say?
Well, I leaned back in my chair,
puffed my chest out and I said,
"You can give me
your number, gorgeous."
- (PEOPLE TITTERING)
- That's right.
(CHUCKLING) And I didn't even know
that he was a big fancy lawyer.
You know,
I just gave it to him anyway.
And I am so glad that I did.
And she hasn't worked
a day in her life since.
He's right. That's true.
(CHUCKLING) That's...
Wow. You guys sure are
a breath of fresh air.
Oh, thank you, Sutter.
It's rare to see such
a happy couple nowadays.
I feel like everyone's
getting divorced.
Well, that's not true.
Isn't it? Well, our parents, Aimee's
parents, most of my friend's parents...
- Kid's got a point.
- SUTTER: Thank you, Joe.
- Mine didn't. -I thought you
said your parents were divorced.
- No.
- There you go, Sutter. See?
Not everything is doomed.
- My dad died.
- What?
I am so sorry...
- (EXHALING)
- AIMEE: No.
- It's okay, it's not your fault.
- I'm so... What happened?
AIMEE: Um...
Well, I mean, he was
a really great guy.
He just kind of had like a slight
problem with painkillers, mostly.
Yeah.
It was really crazy. I mean, he
tried to stop a bunch of times,
but my sister came home one day
and he was just lying there
on the kitchen floor.
And she had to, like,
close his eyes and everything.
- Wow.
- It was pretty, yeah, intense.
(CHUCKLING)
Sorry. That was really dark.
Um, anyways, I just...
I know that
my marriage will work.
- Oh yeah?
- Mmm-hmm.
I've thought it all out.
My husband and I will both
live on a horse ranch and
I will work for NASA
and he'll do something
completely different.
Just so that we offset
each other, you know.
Like, we'll have some
things in common
but then we'll also bring all these
different dimensions to the table.
So that, you know,
life doesn't get boring.
I know it's gonna work.
Sounds like a dream.
I think it's good
to have dreams. Don't you?
- To dreams.
- HOLLY: To dreams.
- I wanna ask you somethin'.
- Okay.
Did you mean
what you said at the party?
What? What?
(CHUCKLING) What?
- You know.
- No, I don't.
Yes. Like the kidding about,
like the prom, or whatever.
Yeah, of course I remember that.
Are you kidding me?
How could I forget
something like that?
No, I just mean like, if
you changed your mind
or you didn't wanna go,
or anything, I totally get it.
- What are you talking about?
- No, I just...
I wouldn't have asked you to go
if I didn't wanna go with you.
- Look, I know...
- I wouldn't. I wouldn't have.
- Okay.
I'm just saying that I know
people change their minds,
- and it's not that big of a deal.
- Not me.
And I'm totally okay
with it if you want to not go.
Listen to me.
I would not have
asked you to go to the prom
if I didn't wanna go
to the prom with you.
- Really?
- Really.
Okay.
Come here. Come here.
- Bye.
What?
Look, man, it's under control.
What's under control? Okay, look.
Did it ever cross your mind
- that maybe I'm attracted to that girl?
- No! No, not at all.
Yeah. It's because you haven't
really looked at her.
I'm telling you, like once you actually,
like, talk to her you see who she is.
And, I don't know, man.
She's really beautiful.
Beautiful?
This isn't you, Sutter.
What, dude? Hey.
You're gonna break her heart.
Okay, all right.
Well, you know,
worst case scenario,
I'm just giving her the, you
know, boyfriend experience.
That's worst case scenario?
No way, no!
Well, I don't know...
You and I both know
a month tops she'll be done with
me and then she'll move on.
Okay and if she doesn't?
- What happens then? -Well, if she
doesn't then that would be a first.
(AIMEE LAUGHING)
I like you so much.
I like you.
Should we take our shirts off?
Yeah.
Yeah. You go first.
All right.
- Well done?
- You're amazing.
So amazing.
Your turn.
- (CHUCKLING) To take mine off?
- Yeah.
Don't laugh, okay?
All right.
I promise I won't laugh.
- Wow!
- Stop! No, you promised.
- What?
- Don't say anything.
- Are you kidding me?
That's awesome!
(LAUGHING)
I like you so much.
So much.
Do you want to do this?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Do you? Yeah?
- I'm good.
- Here.
- Wow!
- (LAUGHING) -Where did
you even get this from?
I don't know.
It's better, good to be safe.
Got all your bases covered.
- You got it?
- Uh, yeah.
- Do you need any help?
- No.
Are you sure? You okay?
Okay.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
- Oh, my gosh!
- What?
Nothing.
- You wanna do it? Yeah.
- Hey!
- Yeah.
I'm so glad that I met you.
I'm so glad that I met you too.
Okay.
Go slow, go slow.
Go really slow.
- So... Sorry. That's okay.
- Sorry.
(GASPING)
- It's okay?
- Yeah. Okay.
- Can I tell you a secret?
- What?
- My Dad's not a pilot.
Yeah, I actually don't know
what my dad does.
Or where he is.
- What? Sutter!
- Yeah.
I just made that up
'cause he's been gone
for half my life and...
Well, I guess I just miss him.
Oh, my God!
And no one knows where he is?
Um, my mom knows where he is,
but she won't tell me.
- What?
- Yeah.
She can't keep him from you.
He's your dad!
I know, but she does. She has.
Sutter, Sutter,
that's not like...
- What?
- Yeah.
Hey, I'll make you a deal.
Mmm-hmm.
I will stand up to my mom,
if you'll stand up to yours.
What do you think?
I think that you're wonderful.
Can I look?
- Sorry, I didn't get you a limo.
- That's okay.
But, this is my way
of making up to you.
Okay, you totally did not
have to get me anything.
I know. I wanted to.
- I wrapped it.
- Should I open it?
- Yep.
- Wait, you wrapped this?
- In newspaper.
- It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Took me forever.
- Okay. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I don't even know what it is,
but, thank you.
(SUTTER VOCALIZING)
- What?
- Yeah.
- What? You come here.
- I know. You like it?
- I love it!
- Do you? All right. Good.
It has my name on it?
- Uh-huh.
Thank you. -I'm glad you
like it, you're welcome.
- And the best part is...
- You did not need to do this.
I know, but the best part is,
it's full.
- It is full.
- Yeah. Mostly.
- You took a sip. -I took a
sip to make sure it worked.
- For good luck?
- Yup. Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Cheers.
- To you, Aimee Finicky.
- To you, Sutter Keely.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoo!
Ricky, looking good, brother!
Looking good!
- For you. My lady.
- Thank you.
- This is so nice.
- Mmm-hmm.
- You want some?
- Yeah.
- Good?
- Yeah. Thank you.
- She's a good dancer.
- Hmm? Who?
- Cassidy.
- Oh. I didn't even notice.
- Cheers.
Why aren't you guys dancing?
Yeah, we're gonna
get out there next song.
Come on! It's the prom.
Aimee, dance with me!
No. No, I'm good.
I don't really dance.
But, lucky for you,
I'm a phenomenal dancer
and I can teach you some stuff.
AIMEE: No. I'm fine.
You guys, you guys should go.
- Are you, you sure?
- Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
- Okay.
- All right. Well.
Have fun.
She looks very nice.
So, um, have you
turned her into a lush yet?
Uh, do you wanna lecture me
about Aimee or you wanna dance?
Okay. I wanna dance.
I wanna dance.
Pump the arms. Pump the arms.
Yep. That's what we're doing!
- Cheers.
(SIGHING) God, this is awesome!
Seriously, like...
Everybody just singin'
and dancin',
falling in love...
I'm so happy.
I mean, this night,
this is our night.
This is the youngest
that we're ever gonna be.
I love these people.
(AIMEE GIGGLING)
I do, I love these people.
I love you all!
Come on. Dance with me.
Come on. Come on.
I'm sorry I don't know
how to dance like Cassidy.
Hey. You dance like Aimee
and that's perfect.
(SQUEALING)
Mmm...
- Ah... Oh, my gosh.
- What?
- What? What?
- Sutter.
- Sutter. Guess what?
Guess what? -What?
- My sister called me today.
- Uh-huh...
And she said
that she could probably
almost 100% likely, get me
a job at the book store.
- In Philadelphia?
- Yes!
That's awesome. You love books!
I know! I know. It's perfect.
That's the perfect job for you.
It really is.
It'll help pay for college
and... Yeah.
Yeah.
Did you talk to your mom yet?
No, but, I will.
Eventually.
(SIGHING)
It's pretty.
- Okay.
- Hmm?
- (LAUGHING) I'm sorry.
- (LAUGHING)
Come here. I'm sorry.
- So abusive.
- So sorry.
Back to what I was saying.
I have been thinking
a lot recently.
A lot more than normal.
And I think that
you should come with me.
To...
- Philly.
- Philadelphia?
- Yes. Yes.
- Uh-huh.
I've been, like,
looking all into it
and you can go
to a junior college,
and we could both
get jobs downtown.
I mean it could be,
like, really awesome.
- Have you ever seen, or been, to Philly?
- (LAUGHING)
- Have you seen the Liberty Bell?
- No.
(STAMMERING) I haven't either,
(LAUGHING) but, but, the pictures
of it are really beautiful.
It's awesome.
You've been thinking about
this for a while, haven't you?
I have. I have, yeah.
And, like, the coolest
thing ever, also...
When I was talking
to my sister...
- Besides the Liberty Bell? -Yes.
There's just so many cool things!
She said that there's, like,
tons of vacancies available.
- Listen to me. I'm talking!
- I'm listening, I'm listening.
Um, she said that there's tons of
vacancies available in her building,
- because of, like, the economy
and stuff, so... -Mmm-hmm.
Um, we could totally just move there
at the end of June, together.
And it would be really
inexpensive and awesome and...
What do you think?
Uh...
I think that's great.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I, uh... I did it.
- What?
I talked to my mom.
I just walked in and I said
"It's my life and I'm not gonna
let you stand in the way of it."
- How'd that go?
- It was pretty ugly at first.
She said all these things and
tried to guilt me into staying.
But, I just said,
"Look, like if I can afford it
then I'm leaving,"
"and there's really nothing
that you can do about it."
- That's awesome. I'm proud of you!
- Yeah. Thank you.
I'm proud of me!
It wasn't that bad. You'll see.
- What?
- When you do it.
What are you talkin' about?
Sutter! We had a deal!
Ah, yeah. I don't know.
What?
- You can totally do it.
Trust me. -Different.
No. Okay. Look.
Repeat after me.
Say "I wanna call my dad, Mom."
"I wanna motherfucking
call him!"
That's not fair.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I just wanted
to ask you something.
- Okay. What is it?
- It's about Dad.
- Oh, Sutter...
- I wanna talk to him.
- Yeah, I don't think that's a good idea.
- Why not?
- He's my dad. -And I'm your mom
and you live under my roof.
Okay.
Well, I just wanna call him.
Sutter, this is my job.
We can have
this conversation later, okay?
No wonder he left you.
How do you like the
landscaping we did back here?
Joe and I planted some day lilies back
there, I don't know if you saw them.
- Yeah, it looks really good. It
looks really good. -Really pretty.
So, like I was talking on the phone,
I wanted to ask you about Dad.
You want to
dredge that up, huh?
Dredge? What are you talking about?
Dad's not somebody that you dredge.
He's awesome.
Hey, do you remember he used to tell
stories in the tent in the backyard?
- Remember that?
- I think that was mostly you.
Well, do you remember when we
made that trip down to Mexico?
And he had us going up to people asking
where the belt buckle museum was?
And, "Why is there
no artichoke ice cream?"
That was hilarious!
- Don't, look... It was funny!
- It was embarrassing.
No, it wasn't. It was funny.
People loved us.
They loved you because
you were little and cute.
The guys liked you.
They loved you.
Thought you were a hot little muchacha.
Mmm-hmm, you liked it.
(SIGHING) Well...
Yeah, uh-huh.
He did know how
to make friends, at least.
Damn right he did.
So...
Do you know what happened
between him and mom?
He cheated on her.
Yeah. Well,
that's her version of it.
And you think it's a lie.
I don't think she's lying, but I think
there's two sides to every story.
- Think about it.
- Sutter...
Okay look, she won't let us see him. She
won't even let us know where he is.
Let's talk about something else.
How is your friend Aimee?
Okay, no, you gotta admit,
it's a little suspicious.
I mean, I don't even... She won't
even give me his phone number.
I can't talk to the guy.
Every time that I ask her for his
number, she refuses to give it to me.
Can you please ask her
for his number for me?
Please?
I don't have to ask her.
I know where he is.
What?
(DOOR SHUTTING)
Thank you. Thanks.
Thanks.
- Hey, Sutter?
- Hmm?
Come by for lunch sometime.
Okay?
Okay. I will. Promise!
(CLEARING THROAT)
- MAN: Hello?
- Uh...
- Dad? -No, you got
the wrong number.
- No, it's, it's me, Sutter.
- Sutter?
- Sutter, how, how you do?
- Uh, yeah, I'm all right.
You sound like a... You sound
like a man from here now.
Well, yeah, you, uh...
Well, hey,
you still playing ball? What?
I mean, you know, your arm, you were
small for your age, but, you...
You were a hell of a pitch.
You still playing ball?
Wow. Yeah. I'm surprised
that you remember that, Dad.
What are you talkin' about "do I remember that"?
Of course I remember that.
- Are you still throw?
- Naw, not really.
- Haven't thrown much lately. -Well, it's a shame.
You were a hell of a pitcher.
You had a great . So how...
(COUGHING) How's your, how's
your mom and, and Holly doin'?
They're, they're good.
Yeah. Real good.
Oh, good, good. That's, that's tremendous, son.
That's good. That's good.
Listen, Dad...
I was thinking, could I come
see you sometime? Come see me.
Well, yeah, of course. What do
you mean "can you come see me?"
- You can come see me any damn
time you wanna see . -Really?
What do you mean "really?"
Of course you can come see me.
Yeah, you come over, like, Friday,
like around 3:00 or somethin'
maybe we go
see a game or somethin'.
Yeah, uh, wow, really?
Dad, that would be so great.
I'd really like that.
AIMEE: How much further is it?
Uh, it's about three hours.
- Hey, Aim, thank you.
- For what?
I wouldn't have done
this without you.
All right. Here we are.
- I think I need that shot of whiskey now.
- (LAUGHING)
- Knock again?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
SUTTER: Hey!
Dad! Uh...
It's Sutter.
Oh, shit, of course! You, uh...
Oh, man, I...
Look at you. Of course, you...
- You're taller than I am! -Yeah.
I grew a lot last summer.
Yeah, you...
I was, no, I was just, um...
I was...
- How are you? Come...
come here! -Hey!
And, who...
- Oh, sorry. This is Aimee.
This is my girlfriend. -Hi.
This is my...
Aimee, this is my dad.
- Aimee, how you doin'?
- Nice to meet you.
It's very nice to meet you.
It's very nice to see that Sutter's
got immaculate taste in the ladies.
He, uh... He gets that from
his old man, you know.
He gets that from his old man.
Look at you, man!
Uh, you caught me
at just a bad time right now.
I was gonna head out to catch
up with some friends of mine,
but since you're here now, if you wanna
come along, that would be great.
- Yeah.
- Would you like to do that?
Yeah. I'd love to, right?
We'd love to come with you.
Yeah, absolutely.
- Is that right? - Yeah.
Well, listen, take your car and
you can follow me up there.
It's just up the street and we'll
go get a drink. Sound good?
Yeah. Cool. Yeah, let's do it.
Hey, guys. Hey, this is my son Sutter.
Sutter, this is the guys.
And this, this is the most beautiful
woman in the entire state.
- This is Roberta.
- Hey. How you doin'?
Last week you said the country.
And I meant the entire country.
And this, again,
is the amazing Sutter Keely.
Roberta, and this is his
amazing uh, lady friend um...
- Aimee.
Get your good looks
from your mother, did ya?
(GIGGLING)
She can be touchy sometimes.
Listen... Hey, let's sit down
over there.
Sit down, I'll get us
some drinks, all right?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Go on.
Hey, Sal. Give me two pitchers.
You've never been to Key West?
- No.
- Key West is the place to be.
Key West has got sunsets...
That are like
butterscotch sundaes
with strawberry swirl mixed in and
it just melts right into the ocean.
And everybody has got
a drink in their hand
and a smile on their face.
That's Key West.
- Wow. That sounds perfect.
- Yeah.
It was perfect. And I wish you
could have been there with me.
So how come you left?
What do you mean,
how come I left?
Uh, Key West.
How come you left Key West?
'Cause I ran out of money,
that's why I left Key West.
If I could have stayed down
there I would have, believe me.
Hey, I'm gonna play
a song on the jukebox.
- Good. You do that, I'll get us a refill.
- Sound good?
All right, yeah.
Good.
- Yes. That's it. That's the song.
- Um...
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CLEARING THROAT)
- Fresh pitcher.
Here we go.
- Here you go, buddy.
- Thanks, Dad.
- What do you say, Aimee?
- Thank you.
- It's pretty good, huh?
- Thank you. What's that?
The song. You like the song?
This?
Yeah, it's all right.
This was always
your mother's kinda thing.
Mom? What?
This is fun. I can't imagine mom
listening to fun music like this.
What the hell you talkin' about?
When I married your mother,
your mother was more fun than anyone I knew.
Your mother was
the definition of fun.
There was nobody more
fun than that.
You know what, don't say anything
bad about your mother either, huh?
So, uh, what happened?
What do you mean what happened?
Between you and Mom.
What happened?
Things didn't work out.
That's what happened.
Yeah. Well, you know
she blames you for everything.
- I defend you. I always defend you.
- Well, I appreciate that
'cause, you know what?
It wasn't all my fault.
- Yeah, exactly. There's two sides
to every story. -That's right.
Yeah.
And no matter what happened
between you guys,
I mean she shouldn't have kicked
you out of the house like that.
Your mother didn't kick
me out of the house.
What do you mean?
I mean your mother didn't kick
me out of the house. I left.
What?
Let me tell you somethin'.
I had to leave. I wanted to be
there for you. I really did.
More than anything in the world, I wanted.
You guys meant more to me than anything.
But the fact of the matter is that
things between your mother and I,
they were very uncool.
I guess you could say I wasn't
cut out to be a family man,
not in the traditional sense. I did
some things that I'm not proud of.
But I'll tell you something. I don't
live in the past, I live in the now
because that's what it's all about.
Do you understand that?
Yeah. Yeah.
- Hey. Uh...
- Yeah?
Do me a favor, will you? Pick up this tab
real quick, all right? I'll be right back.
Dad.
Calm down. The boy found me.
Well, I didn't know that you had a son.
Thanks for that info.
What? I didn't give him
the damned address!
- You okay?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Well, I gotta pay the tab
and he doesn't have any money.
- Do you have some money?
- Yeah.
This isn't enough.
- That's all you got?
- Listen, um...
Roberta's had too much to drink so
I'm gonna give her a ride home,
if you know what I mean.
All right?
- Do you want us to follow you? -No, no, no.
There's no need for that.
I won't be more than an hour.
Yeah, dad, we're not doing anything.
We can totally come...
- Yeah...
- No, that's not necessary.
You know what'd be best? Why don't you
guys just meet me back at my place, good?
- Yeah, Dad, we came all this way to see you.
- I know you did.
And I'm glad you did, but I'll meet you
back at my place in about an hour.
Is that good?
- Uh, yeah. We can do that. Yeah.
- Yeah, that's fine.
- All right. I'll see you then.
- Yep.
- We should head back. -Let's keep waiting.
It's only been... Sutter!
- I'm sure that he wanted to come back.
- Aimee...
No, if it wasn't for her, I'm sure
he would have come right back.
Yeah. And if he didn't cheat on my
mom then we'd still be a family
and I'd be president of
my Sunday school class.
Sutter.
What?
I love you.
It's just...
- Did you hear me?
- Yeah.
- Sutter, I love you.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
- No, you don't, you're wrong.
Sutter, I'm not wrong.
- You don't love me.
- Yes, I do!
You're wrong.
You don't love me,
okay, you're just drunk and
you're grateful that somebody
- came along and showed interest in you.
- Okay, stop.
Stop. Do not try
and mess this up!
Mess what up? What do you
think that this is, Aimee?
What are you talk... Sutter!
(YELLING)
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Are you okay?
- What?
- Are you all right?
- No... -Are you hurt? Is
there anything that...
Aimee, stop. No, I'm not.
I'm far from okay.
- Jesus!
- Are you hurt?
Aimee, what is the matter with you?
I almost just killed you
and you wanna know if I'm okay?
Yeah, I wanna make sure
that you're okay.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
Do you not see that I am bad for you?
You need to get away from me!
- What are you talking about? -You
need to get the fuck away from me!
Aimee, just...
Get out of my car.
No, I'm not gonna
get out of your car!
Get out of my car! Get the
fuck out of my car! Get out!
- Get the fuck out of my car!
- Oh, my God, Sutter!
Jesus Christ!
I'm sorry, Sutter. (SCREAMING)
What are you...
Holy fuck! Aimee!
DOCTOR: I'll give you a choice, kid.
The cops or your parents.
(MUFFLED VOICES)
Sutter!
Now.
It's not an F.
- I thought you were getting help.
- I am.
I am.
All right. Well, you need a C on
the final or you fail my class.
I'll try harder.
No, you won't.
I don't get you, Sutter. I mean
you're a smart kid. Thoughtful.
- I mean, do you even want to graduate?
- I don't know.
- Excuse me? -I'm just being honest with you.
I... I don't know.
Everyone's telling me I gotta move
on, I don't see what's so great
about being an adult.
Are you happy?
Hi.
Hey. How you feelin'?
I'm good. How are you?
It's good to see you.
Should we talk about it?
I agree.
I'm so sorry, Aimee.
- Sutter, stop.
- Okay.
It's okay. I know. It's okay.
We can just pretend that it,
like, never happened.
We don't ever have to talk
about it again, okay?
I don't want anything
to get in the way of Philly.
(SIGHING)
You're all that matters to me.
- Hey, babe.
- Hey.
- Hey!
- Hold this.
- Mmm-hmm.
- You want some?
- No, I'm good.
- Really?
- Yeah. I'm good.
Okay.
Is your family here?
Naw, I told them
it was next week.
- Yep. Yeah.
- Really. Okay.
- Oh, hey, I should probably
go say hi to her. -Okay.
(CHUCKLING) Well, we made it.
Yeah, I guess we did.
- I'm really glad.
- Yeah.
I'm really proud of you, Sutter.
Congratulations.
Uh, so, when are you
going to Texas?
I thought that you heard.
I'm not going to Texas.
I'm going with Marcus.
California?
- That's right.
- (CHUCKLING) What? Cass...
- Sutter? -Come on, man.
Are you serious?
I mean, I don't know, don't you
think that's like a little...
- What? -I don't know,
it seems a little...
You're really going?
Yes, I'm really going.
Well, maybe I'll, you know...
I could come visit you guys or something.
Never been to California.
It'd be cool.
I don't think that's
a very good idea, Sutter.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, yeah,
it's not, probably not cool.
Sorry, it's just I'm, I'm...
Hey. I get it.
- I'm trying to do things...
- It's fine. It's cool.
...right now that
aren't bad for me.
I get it.
Good.
It's cool. It's cool.
Sutter.
(SIGHING)
I'm not mad at you.
I know.
You'll always be
my favorite ex-boyfriend.
- DAN: Sutter!
- Yeah?
Pop upstairs, would ya?
You've probably noticed, uh,
we haven't been
too busy these days,
and, uh, because of that,
I can only keep one clerk.
Now, I like you, Sutter,
but, more importantly,
the customers like you.
(CLEARING THROAT) So I think
you should be the one I keep.
- That's excellent.
- Oh, no, one second. I...
I've given this
some hard thought,
and, uh, the only way
I can let you stay,
is if you promise me, 100%,
that you will never
come in here loaded again.
And I'm serious.
Not even a light buzz.
Because if you do,
then I have to let you go.
You understand?
I do.
So, can you promise?
You've got me there, Dan.
You know
I can't promise you that.
Well, I appreciate
your honesty.
(CLEARING THROAT)
I've always been
up front with you.
Thanks for the opportunity.
- (CLEARING THROAT) Yeah.
- Thank you.
I suppose if
I was your father, I...
This is where I might give you
a lecture or something.
You know, about what
you're doing to yourself.
Well, you know, Dan, if you were
my dad, you wouldn't have to.
MAN OVER INTERCOM: ...now boarding for
Washington DC, Baltimore and Philadelphia.
WOMAN: Miss.
I need to keep going.
Just two more minutes, please.
I promise.
WOMAN: I'm sorry.
I'm gonna have to go.
Okay. Thanks.
So, yeah, do you think
I did the right thing?
For you or for her?
You had to let her go.
You had to save that girl.
That's what I'm saying. I saved her.
I saved her.
You're not wrong.
You're a hero. You're a king!
I'm a king!
Look at you, Sutter.
What are you 22, 23?
- Yeah.
- Beautiful!
You got your whole life
ahead of you.
- Hey, so do you, man.
- You think so?
Absolutely.
Look at you,
hey, you're a young man.
- You're, you're a kid.
- I'm a kid?
You got... You got plenty
of life left in you.
Hey,
how 'bout we get
a round of shots for us kids?
(CRASHING)
Ah, shit! Ah, shit!
Ah, shit! Shit!
What the hell? Sutter?
Jesus Christ! We just went through this.
What the hell is wrong with you?
- What do you care?
- Excuse me?
- You don't care about me. You've
never cared about me! -Sutter?
Is it 'cause I remind you of him?
Is that why you hate me, Mom?
That's why you can't even
stand to look at me? Can you?
What are you talking about?
You're my son!
You know what I'm talking about.
I'm his son too.
I'm exactly like him.
You are nothing like him.
Sutter?
I'll give you your dad's number
and you can go to him and see.
- See how different you are. -I thought
that you didn't want me to see him.
I was... I was trying
to protect you from...
- I was wrong, okay, so, I want you
to go now and... -I already went.
Holly gave me his number, I drove
up there last week and I saw him.
- You were right, Mom.
- Sutter...
- You were right the whole time.
- You are not your father.
Sutter, listen to me.
Listen to me. That man... That
man has never loved anyone
but himself.
His heart is this big.
But you, you love everybody.
You have the biggest heart
of anyone I know.
When you were in 3rd grade
and Ricky was on crutches,
do you remember that?
You carried his books.
Carried that back pack
every day.
Or when you were nine and
Rosemary Clark lost her mother,
you invited her
to come live with us.
You told her that
I would be her new mom.
You've always been
so special, Sutter.
That's why everyone
loves you so much.
Nobody loves me.
Sutter, you are so wrong. Do you hear me?
You are so wrong.
(SOBBING)
My name is Sutter Keely
and I'm 18 years old.
Compared to other kids, I haven't
had that many hardships.
Not really.
You know. Shit's happened.
Stuff's happened, sure, bu,
stuff always happens, right?
But the real challenge
in my life,
the real hardship, is me.
It's always been me.
As long as I can remember,
I've never not been afraid.
Afraid of failure.
Of letting people down.
Hurting people.
Getting hurt.
I thought if I kept my guard up and
focused on other things, other people...
If I couldn't even feel, well,
then no harm would come to me.
I screwed up. Not only
did I shut out the pain,
I shut out everything.
The good and the bad.
Until there was nothing.
It's fine to just
"live in the now".
But the best part about "now" is
there's another one tomorrow.
And I'm gonna start
making them count.
Sincerely, Sutter Keely.
P.S. I don't know if this
was due a long time ago.
Probably was. But that's fine.
It may be too late
for this essay.
It's not too late for me.