(INDIAN MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN SPEAKING HINDI)
(VENDORS CALLING)
(CUSTOMERS CLAMORING)
(CHICKEN CLUCKING)
MAN: Side, side, side!
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Hassan! Stay with me.
Oh, bhaiya.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Oh, ma!
Hassan!
Come on!
(CLAMORING)
AKHIYA: Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I will take the whole lot!
Wait, stand back. Stand back, now.
We got here first. It is mine. No.
No, one minute, bhaiya, please!
Listen. (ARGUING IN HINDI)
You stand back. Stand back.
Stand back. No, no. No.
(SNIFFS)
OFFICER: Your name?
HASSAN: Hassan Iqbal Kadam.
OFFICER: Date of birth?
HASSAN: July 5th, 1990.
OFFICER: Place of birth?
HASSAN: I was born in Mumbai, India.
MAN: Oh! Oh! Oh!
Sold!
(CLAMORING STOPS)
To the boy who knows.
OFFICER: Your occupation?
I'm a cook.
(SCOFFS) You mean kitchen porter?
No, cook.
My family has run restaurants
in India for many years.
My great-grandfather
fed soldiers during the time
of the British Raj.
But now we have come
to try our luck in Europe.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(OFFICER SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
HASSAN: Me and my family.
OFFICER: And you're planning
to stay in Europe
as a cook?
Oh, yes.
You have qualifications?
Yes.
My mother taught me.
But no proof on paper?
(PAPER RUSTLING)
Only grease-proof paper.
Samosa.
No, thank you.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
HASSAN: My school
was our family restaurant
in Mumbai...
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
No more playing, okay?
Come on, bedtime. Chalo.
MUKHTAR: Hello!
Good night, Mama!
HASSAN: ...and my mother
was my instructor.
The sea urchins taste of life,
- don't you think?
HASSAN: - Mmm.
Life has its own flavor.
Hidden in that shell, raw, beautiful life.
HASSAN: It was an education
for all of the senses.
AKHIYA: But to cook,
you must kill.
You make ghosts.
You cook to make ghosts.
Spirits that live on in every ingredient.
HASSAN: But mostly, I was taught
(SLURPING) how to taste.
(SNIFFS)
Can you taste them?
HASSAN: One night
my schooling ended.
Very good. (LAUGHS)
Hi. Congratulations on the election,
Minister.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING ANGRILY)
PAPA: Mansur! Mansur!
MAHIRA: Get out.
Hey, what?
(SPEAKING HINDI)
- Huh?
- Grab the kids!
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(ALL SHOUTING)
HASSAN: There was an election
of some kind,
and there was a winner...
- Arrey, Hassan...
- ...and there was a loser.
Hassan! We are being attacked!
- Get out, Hassan! Quick!
- We are being attacked!
(AKHIYA SHOUTING IN HINDI)
Oh, my God.
(SHOUTING)
Papa! Come on, Papa, we have to go!
Get out, Hassan!
(SHOUTING IN HINDI)
MAHIRA: Come on! Come on!
(MAN SHOUTING IN HINDI)
Mukhtar, Mukhtar!
- Mama...
HASSAN: - We lost everything.
(MAHIRA SCREAMS)
PAPA: Akhiya!
AISHA: - Papa!
- Akhiya!
MAHIRA: Mama!
PAPA: Akhiya!
AISHA: (CRYING) Mama!
(INAUDIBLE)
HASSAN: Everything.
After my mother was killed,
Papa decided to bring
the family to London.
I attempted to continue
my education on my own.
(SIZZLING)
We found a home
quite near to Heathrow.
(AIRPLANE APPROACHING)
(GROANING)
PAPA: Yes, we are the Kadam family.
When we fled from Mumbai,
we were given asylum in London.
Uh, we were there for one year.
And, uh, it's too cold,
so we decided to open
a restaurant in Europe.
OFFICER: Where in Europe?
PAPA: Somewhere in Europe.
FEMALE OFFICER: Well, Mahira,
we just need to establish that you're not
being taken to Europe
for an arranged marriage.
(CHUCKLES)
Trust me,
nothing in this family is arranged.
And why exactly are you
leaving London?
I found in England that
the vegetables, they had no...
Had no soul. No life.
You see?
All right.
Maybe we'll find it here.
Maybe.
MANSUR: Please, stop complaining.
MANSUR: Arrey...
Try one each and give marks out of ten.
MUKHTAR: - Can I have that one?
- No salt.
MAHIRA: Very big.
MUKHTAR: Lovely.
- Mmm.
MAHIRA: - It's an eight.
MUKHTAR: Trust me,
I learned this in school.
They are not the same country.
AISHA: Papa, my ears buzz.
MAHIRA: Aisha, look.
PAPA: Well, that's a good idea.
Then, uh, Switzerland can be starter
and France can be main course.
MUKHTAR: Then what is our dessert?
PAPA: (LAUGHING) Good question.
- Papa!
- Papa, Papa, slow down!
I can't.
MANSUR: - Papa, slow down!
- I can't!
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
- Slow down, Papa!
PAPA: - I can't!
My foot is to the floor!
MAHIRA: You need to go slower, Papa!
(ALL SCREAMING)
MANSUR: Arrey, do something!
PAPA: The brakes have failed!
Look! It's a tractor!
(AISHA SCREAMING)
(HORN HONKING)
AISHA: Papa!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Papa!
(ALL PANTING)
Everyone okay?
Mukhtar? Aisha?
MUKHTAR: I'm okay.
I'm no mechanic, but I think
it's something to do with brakes.
HASSAN: Let's get out.
(AISHA GROANING)
(COUGHS)
Come on.
- Come. (GRUNTS)
MUKHTAR: - Come on.
Papa, come on!
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
MAHIRA: I'm alive!
(COUGHING)
Are you all right?
I can't do this anymore, Papa.
What are you trying to do? Kill us all?
We've been driving for days
in this piece of junk.
Enough of this crazy wandering.
You know what?
We were happier living under
the flight path at Heathrow.
(CHUCKLES)
(ECHOING)
At least we had a bloody home!
Wherever the family is, that is the home.
Oh, really?
And where is the family right now,
Papa? Huh?
Answer me.
Where is the family right now?
France.
(CHUCKLES) France. France!
Exactly.
Papa, in case you didn't realize it,
the French don't even eat Indian food.
They have food of their own.
It is famous all over the world.
This is the end of the road.
Hassan, talk to your father, huh?
(SPEAKING HINDI)
HASSAN: Papa...
Oh.
There must be someone down there
who can fix the brakes.
- What did Mama say?
- Huh?
I know you talk to her.
What did she say to you?
She said, "Find a good mechanic
and go on with your search."
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Mmm.
(DOOR OPENS)
MARGUERITE: Bonjour.
MUKHTAR: I like her car.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
HASSAN: Uh... No.
Uh...
(STAMMERING IN FRENCH)
- Oui?
- Uh...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Brakes.
Do you speak English?
(EXHALES)
- Do you?
- Yes.
- Okay, good.
- I'm Marguerite.
Hassan.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you. Um...
- Bonjour.
PAPA: - Bonjour.
- My father.
- Okay.
Do you have, uh, any rope? Or...
Yes. Yes, I do, in the trunk there.
(CALLING IN HINDI)
(ALL RESPONDING)
(GRUNTING)
MANSUR: Papa?
(GRUNTING) Papa?
(MANSUR SPEAKING HINDI)
Push, everybody! Chalo!
(PAPA CALLING IN HINDI)
(ALL RESPONDING)
HASSAN: Slow down, guys!
MAHIRA: Slow down.
MANSUR: Guys, slow down!
(MAHIRA SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
MANSUR: Okay, to the right a little.
MARGUERITE: You can just park it here.
It's okay.
MANSUR: We're very grateful
for your hospitality.
No, it's my pleasure.
Do you want some more tea?
MANSUR: Thank you.
That would be nice.
(AISHA GRUNTS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
MARGUERITE: Bless you.
MANSUR: You have lots of antiques.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Some more tea?
(CONTINUES SPEAKING HINDI)
Thank you.
All right, so the mechanic says
that he has to send out for parts
and the van won't be ready
until tomorrow.
So where do we sleep?
Here, in St. Antonin.
I found a guest house,
and they have rooms.
PAPA: - How much?
- Approximately...
Papa, no. You will not barter.
We will just pay the rate
like normal people.
Normal people get the best value?
Only Europeans accept the first price.
Papa, it's not like in Mumbai, all right?
MARGUERITE: Voila.
(ALL GASP)
I thought you might be hungry, so...
(PAPA LAUGHING)
HASSAN: Beautiful.
PAPA: Thank you.
MANSUR: Very nice.
MARGUERITE: Thank you.
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
MARGUERITE: My pleasure.
This is very, very kind of you.
- You're welcome.
MAHIRA: - Thank you.
HASSAN: So, uh, what is all this?
MARGUERITE: That's just
some cold things
we had in the larder. So...
MAHIRA: Amazing.
PAPA: Oh.
But please eat it, it's all yours.
Thank you.
PAPA: Mmm!
Where did you buy this?
MUKHTAR: - Mmm.
- Oh, the bread? I bake it.
- Nice.
MARGUERITE: - Yes.
Oh, God, Papa, try this.
This oil, where is it from?
MARGUERITE: Uh, from
the olive trees in the garden.
And my uncle press it every year. So...
And the cheese is from the cows
in the field at the back.
It's totally natural.
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
ALL: Mmm.
HASSAN: Mmm-hmm.
- This is amazing.
MUKHTAR: - The cheese...
Mmm.
Do you want some sweets?
AISHA: Mmm.
Thank you.
MANSUR: Not too many, okay?
PAPA: Forgive the silence, Marguerite.
I think my family is afraid
that they died in the accident
and now we enter heaven.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
- Thomas?
- Yes, ma'am?
Who are these people?
THOMAS: I don't know.
Papa, what are you doing?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
For sale.
Look at this.
It's perfect.
Please...
Papa,
speak to Mansur, please, first.
Why?
It's not Mansur's money.
Not until I die.
Until then it is mine and Mama's money.
And she loves this village.
She said brakes break for a reason.
(DOOR CLATTERS)
Look.
Wow.
It has a covered yard,
like the one in Mumbai.
Fifty covers at least.
There.
There we would have our tandoori oven.
MADAME MALLORY: Bonjour?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Can I help you?
HASSAN: Sorry. Sorry.
We were just looking around here.
This is private property.
Okay. Papa, chalo, let's go.
Excuse me, do you own this property?
- Oh, no. No.
PAPA: - Oh.
(CHUCKLES)
Then you are trespassing, too.
Do you know the owner of this place?
Papa, please. Time to leave.
MADAME MALLORY: Yes, I know them very well.
- One minute.
- They have gone back to Paris.
But they asked me
to keep an eye out for them.
Oh, I bet you do.
How much are they asking?
(WHISPERING) Papa, please!
One minute. Relax.
MADAME MALLORY: Oh...
You must understand
that a property of this size
in this village, would be very expensive.
Well, I heard you asked for
a discount in Claude's hotel.
Papa, you didn't!
(SHOUTING IN HINDI)
We asked you not to.
(SPEAKING IN HINDI)
Madame,
asking for discount
doesn't mean I am poor.
It means I am thrifty.
I want to make an offer,
to buy this restaurant.
(WHISPERING) Enough. Let's go.
Come. Let's go.
- Don't push me!
- Chalo.
One, two. Here.
Here you go.
- Merci.
- Merci beaucoup.
HASSAN: - Mansur! Mansur!
- Huh?
Let's go.
What? Where?
He's gone crazy.
MANSUR: What?
HASSAN: He's just stuck on that place.
(WAITER SPEAKING FRENCH)
Ah, merci.
More?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MANSUR: Papa!
You know them?
WOMAN: Never seen them before.
Papa, if you won't listen to me,
then listen to Mahira.
You always call her the sensible one.
Papa, it is a very sweet location
and the building is fine,
but there is a problem,
which makes it impossible
for us to open a restaurant there.
There is already a restaurant.
Just across the street.
100 feet. We measured.
MAHIRA: That is why the people
moved back to Paris.
They couldn't make it pay.
Papa, the restaurant across the street
has a Michelin star, hmm?
I know, I saw it.
Twinkle, twinkle. So what?
(CHUCKLES)
MANSUR: Papa, it is the best restaurant
for 50 miles in any direction.
The President of France dines there.
Is the President of France
able to order murgh masala,
with cashew nuts and cardamom?
And ka saag aloo? Dal?
Our secret family spices?
No, but they are
a Michelin star restaurant, Papa.
They have frogs' legs,
escargot, ratatouille...
Is the President able to order
tandoori goat,
cooked the way Hassan cooks?
MANSUR: Excuse me.
PAPA: Sprinkled with roast spices?
Papa, the restaurant doesn't
serve those things,
because the people here don't
like to eat those things.
Because they don't know.
They have never tried. Now they shall.
- Hassan, speak to him.
PAPA: - Can you count?
The kind of variety we can produce
is absolutely amazing.
And the aroma.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh.
This must be
the restaurant owner calling me back.
- Give the phone to me.
MANSUR: - No.
- Hello?
MAHIRA: - Arrey...
Hello?
(PAPA PROTESTING)
Papa, please don't do this!
- Let me answer it.
PAPA: - Give it to me!
- Give it to me!
- Please.
- Papa, don't.
- Mansur! Papa!
I am still head of the Kadam family!
(CONTINUES RINGING)
Hello? Bonjour.
Yes, uh, indeed, this is Mr. Kadam,
chairman of Kadam Enterprises.
Sir.
(CROWING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(CONVERSATIONS CONTINUE)
(JEAN-PIERRE SPEAKING FRENCH)
(STAFF AGREEING)
(BEEPING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(STEAM HISSES)
(BEEPS) Hmm.
MAN: Madame Mallory.
Good morning. Bonjour.
ALL: Good morning.
Menus.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CUTLERY CLATTERING)
Hey, Mukhtar, look,
I'm cooking paneer! Oh!
(CLATTERING)
Oi! (EXCLAIMS)
Go, go, go!
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
So sorry I'm late.
Les chanterelles.
I wish to take advantage
because they are perfect at the moment,
because of the heavy rain last night.
With a little cream then?
Yes, but smoke the cream first, please.
Now, last night,
we served this.
Miserable, overcooked asparagus.
In this restaurant,
the cuisine is not an old, tired marriage,
it is a passionate affair of the heart.
(DOOR OPENS)
MARGUERITE: Sorry. Pardon.
(DOOR CLOSES) I know I'm late,
but they were growing by the river.
I couldn't resist them.
- Oh, red Currants!
- Yeah.
Jean-Pierre, the red Currants
will go with the duck, n'est-ce pas?
Yeah, okay, why not?
(MADAME MALLORY AND
MARGUERITE SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(ALL AGREEING)
MARGUERITE: I see they have started work
on the new restaurant across the street.
Oh, Marguerite,
that cannot be called a restaurant.
In fact the mayor's office
tells me it is fast food, something ethnic.
JEANPIERRE: - The old man
who bought the place is insane.
He will last about as long as it takes
to dry-cure a good winter ham.
(SCOFFS) Which is how long?
Uh, Marcel?
- Huh?
- Five to eight months, madam.
Marguerite.
In return for the red Currants,
I want you to miss the prep
and go to the market for me.
With pleasure, madam. Thank you.
(MARGUERITE AND VENDOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Hello.
- Oh, hi!
I hear you're staying. That's great.
I didn't even know you were chefs.
- I'm not a chef. Just a cook.
- Oh.
And it will be fast food, yeah?
Actually,
my father's signature dish
takes three days.
- Oh.
- That is a lot of mushrooms.
Le Saule Pleureur is a big restaurant.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You... You work for the madame
of Saule Pleureur?
Yes.
Huh. So you are a chef?
No, uh, I'm a sous chef,
but I'm studying to become
chef de cuisine.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MARGUERITE ORDERING)
I hear the madame is not happy
to have competition?
(LAUGHS)
She's not happy no matter what.
Why is she not happy?
She has one, she wants two.
Children?
(LAUGHS) No. No, stars.
Children will get in the way.
- Of the stars?
- Yeah.
In France, all that matters to a chef
is the Michelin stars.
Michelin?
I found a Michelin book in the kitchen.
Yeah, that's the bible.
The stars are holy here.
So, one is good, two is amazing,
and three is, um...
Three's only for the gods.
I would like to learn
about French cuisine.
Perhaps you could recommend a book?
And why would I do that?
You're the enemy now. No?
(ENGINE STARTS)
- See you on the battlefield.
- See you.
(INDIAN POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Oi, careful.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(PAPA GRUNTING)
MANSUR: Hey, Thierry,
come and help me!
THIERRY: Right away.
- Fayed, come here.
- Yes, sir.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Hassan, jaldi karo,
there's a lot to be done.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SQUEALING)
Aisha!
You have to be safe in the kitchen.
These are not toys.
You can't run around.
HASSAN: Hey, let's go.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
(INQUIRING IN FRENCH)
PAPA: Hassan,
why are they blocking the road?
THOMAS: Come on, hey. Hey.
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
We use ancient spices, classical spices.
My son is the best Indian chef
in Europe...
It's too much, Hassan. It's too much.
PAPA: ...in fact
the whole Western world.
He is standing there
in that corner with my daughter.
Raise your hand.
Raise your hand, don't feel shy.
- Don't raise your hand.
PAPA: - Raise your hand.
Don't raise your hand.
PAPA: Raise your hand,
Hassan, I'm talking to you.
Hassan, don't raise your hand.
PAPA: Haan, he is my little genius.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
We open Saturday night.
Tasting menu half-price.
JEANPIERRE: - You know, I saw that Indian guy
buying things in the convenience store.
His cart was full of cat food.
They don't even have a cat.
I guess it was for the curry.
MARGUERITE: Combine the milk, sugar,
vanilla, eggs, kirsch and salt.
Mix until silky to the touch.
Pour into a pan,
spread your cherries over the top
and bake until the skewer inserted
into the batter comes out clean.
A golden-brown crust will have
formed on the top and on the bottom.
(MUSIC CONTINUES ON STEREO)
(MUSIC TURNS OFF)
You may like this kind of music,
but the rest of the village does not.
HASSAN: Sorry, madam.
Welcome to our humble abode,
Madame,
and thank you for barging in.
MADAME MALLORY: I knocked,
but you couldn't hear me,
because the music was so loud.
Ah.
I, um, just came to see
how things are coming along.
PAPA: Well, we are doing pretty well.
Mmm. What is this?
It is an oven.
Oven? It's not a drum? To play?
No. Tandoor oven for chicken tikka.
Sometimes small children.
(CHUCKLES)
Joking.
(METAL BANGING)
Plastic.
Hmm.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Did you get my invitation
to our opening night on Saturday?
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
But Saturdays we are very, very busy.
Oh, I see.
Um, but could I look at a menu?
Yes. Of course.
Uh... (SPEAKING HINDI)
Relax, Papa. Right.
This is our menu.
The specials,
they will change from day to day.
Mmm.
Well, curry is curry, is it not?
Obviously you've never
eaten Indian food,
especially cooked by my son.
Yes, I understand you people
like to keep everything in the family.
Well, if your food is anything like
your music, I suggest you turn it down.
(CHUCKLES)
(THANKING IN FRENCH)
Bonne chance!
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(TURNS DOWN VOLUME)
(WATER SPLASHING)
PAPA: 18 hours until we open the gates.
(GRUNTS)
You might need this.
I thought this was lost in the fire.
(SNIFFS)
Mama wants you to have it.
(CLOSES LID)
(SNIFFLES)
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
It's your day. (CHUCKLES)
- Ah! Crayfish.
VENDOR: - Bonjour, monsieur.
PAPA: Ah, bonjour.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Huh? What did he say?
The crayfish are sold, he said.
All of it?
(SPEAKING FRENCH) Completely?
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
We will pay you... We will pay you more.
There's not another box?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
All right. Uh...
Two kilo...
Shit. Two kilo, uh, the saumon.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Sold?
- Salmon, too, are sold.
PAPA: I don't understand.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
All the cepes are sold.
Madame Mallory purchased
all the mushrooms.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
He's sorry.
I showed her the menu because I
thought she wanted to come for dinner.
I'm sorry, Papa.
I didn't know she was going to do this.
I knew it was a mistake.
We can go to another town here.
Where's the bloody time?
War.
(DOOR SHUTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
War it is.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Mansur, get the ice!
MAHIRA: Did you break down?
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
HASSAN: Mansur, get the ice!
MANSUR: I'm coming!
MAHIRA: What took you so long?
We had to drive 50 kilometers
to get fish.
MANSUR: Here.
MAHIRA: What happened to the market?
Chalo, quickly, let's go.
MAHIRA: So what happened
to the market?
Madame Mallory
happened to the market.
MANSUR: Huh?
MAHIRA: Mansur?
MANSUR: Yeah?
MAHIRA: Is everything okay?
MANSUR: Yeah, yeah, yeah,
everything's good.
MAHIRA: Don't burn it, right?
MUKHTAR: Here you go.
MAHIRA: Mukhtar,
please give me the spice.
AISHA: I'll get it.
MAHIRA: Crush them nicely, huh?
Boning knife.
MAHIRA: Mukhtar...
HASSAN: What is the time?
MAHIRA: You don't want to know.
MANSUR: Hassan,
now we won't have enough time
to cook the mutton properly.
We should just
take it off the menu, yeah?
No.
Rest it in a little red wine,
and add crushed cardamom.
Wine? We don't use wine.
HASSAN: This is an emergency, Mansur.
Wine will flavor the meat.
When in Rome.
Yeah, well, we're not in Rome, are we?
Mansur, to survive here,
we're going to need to adapt.
We have to make use
of what is close to us.
Then we pray to God that it works.
MAHIRA: Careful.
MUKHTAR: Okay.
Right.
I'll go and get the wine.
(CLUCKING)
PAPA: Pull, pull.
Yay!
Magic!
(WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CHILD PROTESTING)
Nice?
(EXHALING) Wow.
AISHA: It's perfect.
(HINDI MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
Papa,
it's not like in India,
where you stand by the gate
and drag people in
as they're passing by.
Papa, you should come inside.
You don't want to look foolish.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Bonjour.
BOTH: - Bonjour.
Oh, going for a walk? Oh!
Hello, baby.
- I love dogs.
MAN: - Oh, yes.
Is it a boy or a girl?
- It's a girl.
- It's a girl. Oh. Ooh.
Very frisky. Mmm.
- What's her name?
- Uh, Bonnie.
Bonnie. Bonnie, come,
I'll feed you something.
This is a new restaurant
we opened today.
It's a Indian restaurant.
Great food. Chicken tikka...
(MANSUR GREETING IN FRENCH)
Thank you, but, my dog?
(LAUGHING)
You should also be there.
- Why?
- You're looking nice.
- I don't know what to say.
- Go on.
Stand there.
See, somebody coming there.
PAPA: - Bonjour.
- Bonsoir.
Smile. You've got good teeth. Just smile.
Ça va?
MAHIRA: Namaste.
(MAHIRA GASPS)
MANSUR: Oh, God!
PAPA: Oh, my God.
MANSUR: So sorry.
PAPA: Don't worry, don't worry,
young man.
We have...
We put in the food turmeric powder,
which is like a medicine.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(TIRES SCREECH)
PAPA: Hello, little angel.
(GIRL GIGGLING)
You are in for a treat!
(HUFFS)
Welcome to Maison Mumbai!
(HINDI MUSIC PLAYING)
PAPA: Be careful. Be careful.
You're trying green chili?
Let me explain to you.
You take a bite, and start chewing it.
And take a small bite of the chili,
mix it with the food...
(DOOR OPENS)
(INDIAN MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
- Ah, Lady Shepherd.
- Madame Mallory.
Bonsoir, monsieur.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Is it a wedding party over there?
A funeral.
The death of good taste in St. Antonin.
Oh.
WAITER: - Bonjour. Bon appetit.
- Bonjour. Merci.
Darling, you've only just had breakfast.
Oh, it was very light.
MADAME MALLORY: There you are,
Mayor. You're not at the town hall.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Madame Mallory, good morning.
"Good morning"? I don't think so.
Yes, my secretary said something
about a complaint about noise.
Oui. I wish to make it officiellement.
Madame, may I offer you
a word of caution?
These people are different.
They are not French.
Some in the village, the worst sort,
say ugly things about them.
Be careful, you are not seen
in sympathy with them.
I am rarely accused
of being in sympathy with anyone.
Au revoir, madame.
Marguerite!
Thank you for the books!
(CHUCKLING) What books?
The books!
Bonjour.
Hello.
Did you catch anything yet?
Mmm. No.
Uh, maybe use smaller hooks
for this kind of perch.
Those ones are big, I think.
And use worms, not bread.
You're not supposed to be helping me.
(CHUCKLES) I thought, uh...
I thought I was the enemy.
Perhaps I'm deliberately deceiving you.
You don't know.
Maybe you are.
See you.
Marguerite!
Marguerite, you know, uh,
the sweet corn from the market?
Yeah.
I'm finding it quite tough, dense.
Do you know what, uh,
I should do with it?
(CHUCKLING) No.
You don't?
Okay.
You can put them on the barbeque.
Two minutes on really high heat,
and then 30 minutes
on a really low heat.
Huh.
- Really?
- Yeah.
It will... It will make them softer.
Oh, sorry!
Make them softer.
Is that the French way?
I don't know.
How did you learn about all this stuff?
Uh, I was 12,
and I started with the five basics,
which is bechamel, veloute,
hollandaise, tomato, espagnole.
You have to master
those five basic sauces first.
And you can find all five in the books?
Of course, but they're no use in books.
You must find them in your heart,
and then bring them to your pots.
That's the secret.
Marguerite!
- Hello!
- Come here!
Voila.
The five sauces of French cuisine.
(CHUCKLES) I can see that.
But you have to try it with the veal,
which I made.
(STAMMERING) You made this?
Yeah. Try it.
Tomate, veloute, hollandaise,
espagnole, bechamel.
(CHUCKLES)
Um, you know, Madame Mallory says
that she knows in just one mouthful
if a chef has the potential to be great.
When someone comes to apply for a job,
she never interviews them. She, um...
She asks them to make her an omelet.
And she takes one bite of the omelet,
and then her tongue decides.
Oui ou non.
That's it.
And?
Oui!
(CHUCKLING) It's incroyable.
It's...
It's incroyable.
(CHUCKLES)
Thanks. Thank you.
What's your favorite dish to cook?
Jalebi.
What is that?
Uh...
Fermented dal and flour,
- deep fried.
- Mmm.
(SIGHS)
The smell reminds me of my mother.
You're lucky.
The smell of pigs' feet in vinegar
reminds me of my father.
(SIGHS) Food is memories.
Food is memories.
(RATCHETING)
(MARGUERITE LAUGHS)
Wow!
HASSAN: I caught one!
Could I have some more?
It's so delicious.
PAPA: He went fishing
especially for you.
MAYOR: You're joking.
PAPA: No, seriously.
Oh, yeah, okay.
Thank you.
Well, it's fish!
PAPA: I love people who eat well.
MAYOR: Yeah, but it doesn't
change anything. Mr. Kadam,
if you don't turn your music down,
we have the power
to close your restaurant.
Mr. Jacques,
my son foolishly did her a favor.
He thought he'd be able
to win her over with kindness.
The restaurant is her entire life.
Ever since her husband died,
she keeps it up for him.
But she has always been...
I'm sorry, but in French we say,
"Tetu comme une mule. "
Stubborn as an ox.
There you are. (CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
Very well, I will turn the music down.
But you tell her from me,
I will turn the heat up.
Excuse me, um, if there's some left,
could you doggy-bag it for me?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MAN REPLYING)
- You sold them?
- Oui, madame.
MADAME MALLORY: You sold all the pigeons?
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SCOFFS)
Mmm.
All the pigeons are sold.
- They sold all the pigeons?
- Every pigeon is sold.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
THOMAS: What should we give the minister?
MADAME MALLORY: I don't know.
Nightmare.
(IMITATING TRUMPETING)
(PAPA SCOFFS)
Madame Mallory has some
government minister
dining in her restaurant tonight.
And she always serves him
this.
(CHUCKLES)
- Where did you get this?
- Huh.
She should pay
her kitchen porters better.
Then it will not be easy to bribe them.
MANSUR: Arrey, bribe?
(MAHIRA SPEAKING HINDI)
Pigeon with truffles.
It's not easy to cook this recipe
if you have no pigeons.
We don't serve pigeons.
What is he on about?
No.
Papa, this is not right, please.
- Well, she did it to us.
- No.
I do it to her. War.
Papa is smart, yes?
Chicken?
Chicken for the minister?
Oui.
Chicken for the minister.
(DOOR SLAMS)
HASSAN: Pardon.
Pardon me.
I would like to apologize
on behalf of my father,
for his poor behavior.
It's pigeon with truffles.
I found the recipe
in a very old cookbook.
(LID CLOSES)
I'm sorry. You wasted your time.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(ALL AGREEING)
Madame Mallory.
Madame Mallory has thrown this gravel
right in the middle of the road,
which is a public road
against the law.
And it is in front of my restaurant.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- I deal with it.
- Merci. Merci.
It is vulgar, it is a horror. Look, look at it.
Did they have a building permit for this?
Of course, they did not.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
AISHA: No! No, no, no!
Hey, don't fight.
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
(AISHA SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(MADAME MALLORY SPEAKING FRENCH)
Madame Brenda,
these are not vaccinated.
My goodness, how many are there?
PAPA: She is wrong,
they have been vaccinated.
Here is the certification. See.
Ah! Finally!
Now, now he vaccinates them.
No, they have been...
Last week, they were not vaccinated.
For a long time
they have been vaccinated.
And beside that... (SPEAKING HINDI)
(MADAME MALLORY SPEAKING FRENCH)
(BOTH ARGUING)
(SIGHS)
The smell of curry, it's everywhere!
Honestly!
No sense of culture or tradition.
And they're staying open tomorrow,
on our Bastille Day.
It's time to stop them.
You make a good soldier, Jean-Pierre.
(FRENCH MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(MADAME MALLORY LAUGHING)
Oui.
Ah, merci.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Bye, everybody.
- Bye-bye. See you tomorrow!
- See you tomorrow!
(SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT)
(GRUNTING)
MARGUERITE: It's you.
My God, you scared me.
Marguerite.
- Look.
- These are beautiful.
These cepes, they're right there.
- You found those here?
- Here.
Wow.
- They're really nice.
- Right.
You know that you can
eat these raw, right?
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
Just like this.
But in salads, too, it's delicious.
- You can eat them...
- Yeah, it's very good.
Where are you coming from?
- Oh, just from work.
- How was it?
- All right, I think.
- Yeah?
The usual Bastille craziness.
- You got...
- What?
You got something in your hair.
It's just a leaf.
- You have something.
- Where?
I'll get it.
Uh...
I don't think that's a good idea.
Why not?
Because, um...
Because we do the same job,
and you know how it is.
You know, we get very long days,
and we never sleep
and we have no time.
Chefs shouldn't be together, I think.
But you think of me as a chef?
- Yes.
- A real chef?
A real chef.
I do. I think you're more a chef
than anyone I ever met.
Hmm.
Really.
(GATE CREAKS OPEN)
(MEN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(GRUNTS)
Hey!
(EXCLAIMS) Papa!
(GROANING)
Fire, Papa!
Fire!
Oh, my God!
(GROANING)
What happened?
Hassan!
(GRUNTS) Mansur!
Mahira!
(MANSUR SPEAKING HINDI)
MAHIRA: Oh, my God!
Papa! (SCREAMS)
PAPA: Water! Bring water!
(GROANS)
PAPA: Where are the kids, Mahira?
(ALL CLAMORING DISTANTLY)
MADAME MALLORY: Thomas!
Yes, Madame.
Call the team together.
I wish to speak with them.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(MADAME MALLORY SPEAKING FRENCH)
Uh, sit down, please.
Do any of you know the words
to the Marseillaise?
Jean-Pierre?
Of course. It's our national anthem.
Do you know all the words?
(RECITING IN FRENCH)
"They come to slit the throats
of our sons, our wives."
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(RECITING)
And in English,
so we can all understand?
"To arms, citizens, form your battalions,
let us march."
"May their unpure blood..."
"Flow in our fields."
And that is what it means to be French,
n'est-ce pas, Jean-Pierre?
Yes.
MADAME MALLORY: Well,
there are other ways to be French.
Liberty. Equality. Fraternity.
Why are you talking only to me?
Because you know who set the fire,
don't you?
Would you surrender to these invaders?
You tell your friends
that these bombs have ended a war.
They have brought peace.
Bravo.
You're a chef.
I do not pay you to burn things.
Take your knives and go.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Not enough cardamom.
Arrey, not enough gratitude.
You know,
I think it's time we got rid of these.
Why?
It's about good food. It's just different.
Don't be afraid.
You know they hate us.
Aren't you angry?
No.
(JEAN-PIERRE SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
HASSAN: We're not visitors anymore,
Mahira.
This time we will not run.
(ENGINE STARTS)
You know what they say.
If you can't beat them, join them.
(SIGHS)
I can clean my own wall.
The outer wall is not your wall.
Technically, it belongs to the village.
Ask the mayor.
I know, because I had the clever plan
to have it raised many feet
so nobody could see your restaurant.
Merci.
Madam?
I would like to...
I would like to make you an omelet.
Would you be interested?
But I'd need your help to break the eggs.
(INAUDIBLE)
Oh.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CHUCKLES)
You have it.
Hmm.
Your pigeon had it, too.
I know.
I knew then, and I know now.
Hmm.
Arrogance.
A chef must lead.
Mmm-hmm.
Sharp and cool and hot in the mouth,
all at the same time.
Do you know how long
it takes chefs to learn that?
What will Papa say?
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Papa, it would only be a six-month trial.
Mama would want this.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
I'll get a more classical training.
Don't you want that for me?
India is not classical?
We are the oldest civilization
in the world.
She thinks she owns everybody in town.
Do you hear me up there? I say no!
Don't try to steal my children!
I will report you, Mr. Kadam,
for making too much noise.
And I will report you
for attempted child abduction!
Have you even asked the boy
what he wants?
You deliberately seduced him!
(SCOFFS)
You seduced his mind,
with your awful, tasteless,
empty sauces!
With your pitiful little
squashed bits of garlic!
That is called subtlety of flavor.
It's called meanness of spirit!
If you have a spice, use it!
Don't sprinkle it. Spoon it in!
MADAME MALLORY: What you do not seem to understand
is that there is such a thing as enough.
Enough is enough, arrêtez!
PAPA: Yes, enough of you.
Always up there like a queen
or something.
You tell him, it's "classical."
What is "classical"?
"Classical" comes from the word "class."
And that is what he will learn
in my kitchen.
He will learn how to cook with class.
Indian cannot become French,
and the French cannot become Indian.
Mr. Kadam,
I think I have just spent the whole day
washing those words off your wall.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Excuse me,
Madame Mallory...
We're actually closed.
Yes.
Is there
anything I can help you with?
No.
It's just that I was wondering what...
You were...
I'm waiting.
Waiting for what?
For Hassan Kadam.
Or death, whichever comes soonest.
Papa?
MAHIRA: Is she sleeping?
(QUIETLY) Marguerite!
Marguerite!
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Sorry, sir.
HASSAN: I was trying to get Marguerite.
Marguerite!
(MAN CONTINUES SPEAKING)
(SIGHS)
HASSAN: Sorry, sir.
Sorry, sir.
(MARGUERITE SPEAKING FRENCH)
I need to talk to you. Now.
Stay there. I'll come down.
I'm happy to see you.
I was so worried. Are you all right?
I'm okay.
It looks bad.
Does it hurt?
A little.
I need to talk to you
about something important.
MARGUERITE: Okay.
HASSAN: Today,
after I got home from the hospital...
MARGUERITE: Mmm-hmm?
Madame Mallory asked me
to work in her kitchen,
at the Saule Pleureur.
Really?
Actually, that's not entirely true.
I had her cook me an omelet
to my recipe.
Oh, I see.
You're, uh... You're smart.
You've been planning this
for a long time, or...
What do you mean?
I mean, ever since I told you
she asks chefs to cook her an omelet,
have you been...
I don't know,
working on your secret little
recipe for success? Or...
What are you accusing me of?
I'm not accusing you of anything.
I'm saying you're smart. It's good.
Are you angry?
No.
(SIGHING)
I thought you'd be pleased.
I am, I am. Um...
In what capacity will you work?
I will start at the bottom, of course.
And, of course,
you will work your way up, right?
Yes.
That is the point.
No, no, it's good, it's good.
Since I loaned you those books,
you have not looked back. It's...
Loaned?
I thought they were a gift.
No, return them
when you no longer need them.
Which I'm sure will be very soon.
Marguerite, I came here
to ask you for your...
For what? For my permission?
For your blessing!
- My blessing?
- Yes.
I'm not a saint.
Yeah.
Neither am I.
I know.
We're just two chefs
trying to make it to the top.
Mmm. It's true.
Then may the best chef win.
Stop.
(GROANS)
Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
Did I hurt you?
I'm really sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
It's fine.
(PAPA SIGHING)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Fair point, but let him go.
(GROANS)
You want Hassan
because you want another star
for yourself, yes?
Oh, yes.
Yes, I will not lie.
But I will also offer him
a stepping stone to the world.
He deserves it. He has a gift.
You are very
stubborn.
(ROOSTER CROWING)
Oh.
It's morning already.
(EXHALES)
A new dawn.
So...
How much will you pay him per week?
200 euro.
(CHUCKLING)
Now you are proving you are insane.
250, plus food.
If you sit in cold all night, he's worth 600.
(SCOFFS) In your dreams.
450, or I walk.
MADAME MALLORY: 320, but 350 after three months.
Do we have a deal?
- No.
HASSAN: - Yes.
We have a deal.
(SPEAKING HINDI)
Okay, relax, Papa.
What do you mean, "relax"?
Spoiled the whole game.
Papa, we have a deal.
Madame...
- No.
- I'll drop it there for you.
They have their own spices.
AISHA: It's not fair. I wanted his room.
Come down, Aisha.
Say bye to your brother.
I don't want to.
PAPA: - What?
- Nothing.
PAPA: What's the matter?
AISHA: Nothing.
MUKHTAR: He's going. Come on.
So I guess the cooking
is now down to me.
Yes, mister.
- Oh, God.
- What do you mean, "Oh, God"?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Are you nervous?
Because, you know,
you cannot be nervous
and make a sauce hollandaise.
The eggs will feel it, they will separate.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Start again. Start again.
That is a beautiful bechamel sauce.
White as snow!
Perfect!
But be careful with the heat though.
MADAME MALLORY: Oh, no, no, no.
Non, ça, non! Regarde.
- This is poisonous!
MARGUERITE: - Oh, God.
This is Satan's boletus!
- Oh.
- Poisonous!
They looked like cepes to me. I'm sorry.
MADAME MALLORY: No, no, no.
(CONTINUES TALKING
INDISTINCTLY)
Sorry! That's mine.
- Bonjour.
- Hello.
(DISTANT LAUGHTER)
(INDISTINCT)
(DOG BARKING DISTANTLY)
Mmm! (SNIFFS)
What is this flavor that is
fighting against the chicken?
I added some spices
for flavor to the sauce,
and coriander for garnish and freshness.
But why change a recipe
that is 200 years old?
Because, madam, maybe 200 years
is long enough.
- Good morning!
ALL: - Good morning.
Marguerite, menu.
Attention!
This evening,
the minister is coming to the restaurant,
so, of course,
we will serve his special dish.
(ALL AGREEING IN FRENCH)
Hassan,
you will prepare it.
Hassan will prepare the pigeon
in truffle sauce. Alone.
(ALL AGREEING IN FRENCH)
MADAME MALLORY: Uh, also I want to serve a souffle.
A souffle with a parfum...
(ALL AGREEING)
And also, I want a feuilleté,
with a cepe, because this...
(STAMMERING)
- Am I late?
- Yes, of course you are late.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
PAPA: How is he doing?
Well, why don't you cross
the road sometime
and try one of his dishes?
I'm afraid I can't possibly
afford your exorbitant prices.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
It would be on the house, of course.
Is he as good as I think he is?
Better.
(PAPA CHUCKLES)
PAPA: Mmm.
MUKHTAR: Hassan!
HASSAN: Yep.
What's in the pot?
Boeuf Bourguignon.
It's a pure French dish
with carrots and vegetables.
- Do you want to try it?
PAPA: - Mmm.
MUKHTAR: - Ah...
- Buff bubble... Bubble gum?
Boeuf. Boeuf.
- Is it good?
- Yes, very good.
Hey, Mukhtar. Aisha, come!
It's vegetables...
- Is there wine in the sauce?
- ...carrots...
- A little, yes. But it's...
- Mmm!
(SPITS)
AISHA: Ugh! It's French food!
(BOTH GROANING)
- Mmm.
- Well?
- You like it?
- Yeah!
Now this is classic French dish,
but with a little twist.
It's Boeuf Bourguignon 5': la Hassan.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(INDISTINCT)
Aisha, Mukhtar!
MAHIRA: Mukhtar.
- Aisha, come on!
- Aisha!
Come! It's started!
MAHIRA: You don't want to miss it.
AISHA: Coming!
Oh, God!
(BOTH GASP)
A special surprise for you.
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
To make the fireworks more fun.
- And for the beautiful one.
- Oh, uh...
Thank you. Very kind.
The pink one, yes. You like pink, I know.
You're wearing pink.
(CHUCKLES)
Hello.
Very nice.
MAHIRA: Mansur?
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
Sorry.
And for Papa.
Uh...
Here. No. May I suggest...
Voila.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
MAHIRA: (CLEARS THROAT) Papa?
Mmm-hmm?
You know, I, uh,
hear she's a wonderful dancer.
Hmm.
- You like to dance, too, no?
MUKHTAR: - Oh, look.
(AISHA GASPS)
MAHIRA: You should take her dancing.
(CHUCKLING)
Don't be absurd.
(INHALES) We are not children.
Hmm. If you say so.
MUKHTAR: So, Hassan?
What's a Michelin star?
- What does it look like?
- They're like...
They're like flowers.
Star flowers.
Then they print them in the book
I told you about.
Who gives them to you?
They're called, um...
They're called critics.
They're like restaurant gods.
Have I got a Michelin star?
HASSAN: (CHUCKLES) No. Not yet.
Oh.
AISHA: Will you get one today?
PAPA: How long have you
been wanting to open this?
We won our first star 30 years ago,
so I have been waiting ever since.
- They always call at 7:00?
- Yes.
Always a Monday?
Yes.
Then they are bloody cruel
to make you go through
all this every year.
Yes. Cruel.
Like the gods. (SIGHS)
(SIGHS)
To hell with them.
You deserve to taste it. (GRUNTS)
What are you doing? Oh, no, no, no.
Wait. Excusez-moi. No.
You cannot do this. What...
Give that to me, please.
Give it to me, please.
- Forget their stars.
- You cannot...
- You are the star.
- No.
Give this... No...
- Ah!
- Give it to me.
(PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
Saule Pleureur. Madame Mallory.
(INHALES)
Merci.
Should I put it back?
With champagne, that is not possible.
Deux.
Oh!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(SOBS)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS)
(LAUGHING)
Thank you. That's better.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
We did it.
(SCOFFS) We did?
Yeah.
The star is for all of us.
No.
No, it's for you.
(SNIFFS)
Thank you. Merci.
MANSUR: What? What happened?
Everyone okay?
MAHIRA: What's going on?
MANSUR: What happened?
- What happened?
- Huh?
- Two.
MANSUR: - Two stars?
(SQUEALS)
MANSUR: Two stars?
Two stars!
And now the gods will take him.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
The rest of the world is waiting for him.
MARGUERITE: The Saule Pleureur
has had one star for 30 years.
You came for one year, and now it's two.
You see how it works?
I don't think so.
Cuisine in France is a secret society
with no secrets.
They will have sent people
from Paris already.
- They know about you.
- Of course.
MARGUERITE: Tomorrow the offers will come.
All the two-star places
that are looking for three stars.
The world now knows you are a chef
who can bring down the stars.
There is no refusing them.
You will be fine.
Take care.
Ah, come on, they were a gift.
Keep it. Keep it.
But I hear only your voice
when I read them.
I needed an excuse to come here.
Thank you.
Marguerite,
I'm glad that our brakes failed here.
Maybe brakes break for a reason.
What do you mean?
What am I going to do?
You should just go.
It's okay.
Go.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
PAUL: Hassan, you have reached
the very highest level of cuisine.
Up here, cooking is no longer an art.
It's a science.
At La Baleine Grise,
we believe that eating
is a multi-sensory experience,
and certain combinations
of flavors and aromas
activate enzymes
and stimulate specific parts of the brain,
evoking pleasure,
and also recollections
of pleasurable experiences.
Like a certain scent
will remind you of your first love.
HASSAN: Yes, with food you remember.
This is the beast
with a thousand mouths,
that must be fed twice a day.
And what does the beast like?
Innovation.
(HISSING)
FEMALE CRITIC 1: La Baleine Grise has always
been known for experimental
food combinations.
But on my most recent visit,
the oysters with nitro pearls
of sturgeon and oyster dust
were made exceptional
by the addition
of ground cardamom seeds.
Cardamom.
MALE CRITIC 1: While it's only been a few months
since my last visit,
I was pleasantly surprised
by the appearance of coriander,
fenugreek and masala.
FEMALE CRITIC 2: ...glutinous sauce resonant of tandoori.
This was a surprising triumph.
MALE CRITIC 2: ...the most unexpected ways.
With a marinade of tamarind
and smoked chili,
the fish swims into my top five
of all time.
It's sugarcoated beetroot with carrots,
also garam masala.
MALE CRITIC 3: An established
molecular cuisine favorite
in Beaubourg
appears to have discovered
the spice of life.
MADAME MALLORY: "...cauliflower ice cream
with a skim of egg yolk and capers."
Cauliflower ice cream? Hmm.
Interesting.
FEMALE CRITIC 3: The word is
the restaurant's regeneration
is mostly down
to a young chef from India.
MALE CRITIC 4: He is a chef
called Hassan Kadam,
who arrived in Paris
just over a year ago.
"...petals cooked
in hay-infused chamomile."
He's cooking with hay.
(CHUCKLING) What?
Why hay?
He's cooking with hay.
(LAUGHING)
Is he cooking for a horse?
(PAPA SPEAKING HINDI)
PAUL: Ladies and gentlemen.
The new La Baleine Grise
chef de cuisine, Hassan Kadam!
Paris is all yours.
(WHISTLING)
Innovation. Innovation. Innovation.
REPORTER: In just one year,
culinary star Hassan Kadam
has transformed the restaurant
with his introduction
of bold spices, explosive taste,
and unusual combinations.
Hassan is no stranger to Paris nightlife.
He is hot in the kitchen,
and very popular with the ladies.
The question on everyone's lips:
Will Chef Hassan Kadam
stay at the Baleine Grise?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
HASSAN: Marguerite,
remember that perfect recipe
for the raw cepe ravioli?
Did we sweat the onions
in oil or butter?
I'm not sure what it is,
but I can't make them taste as good
as when we made them,
together.
Mr. Kadam, excuse me,
but could I take a picture with you,
please?
MARGUERITE: Hassan,
it's not how you sweat the onions,
it's where you pick your cepes.
And the good ones, they grow here.
Remember?
MADAME MALLORY: Look.
Oh. Hassan!
(CHUCKLING) Hassan.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Look, look. Oh.
"Hassan Kadam, the boy from the gutter,
is going towards his third star."
Merci. Merci, Madame.
(CHUCKLES)
He looks like a bloody terrorist.
MADAME MALLORY: No. He's a terrorist
who is about to win a third star.
(MOUTHING)
(PAPA TRYING TO READ FRENCH)
PAPA: What did you say? Gutter?
What... What does that mean?
Um...
It means, uh, you know, where the...
The water in the street,
the drainage in the street.
Drainage?
He's from the drainage? Is he a worm?
No, no. That's the press.
They twist everything.
And he does nothing to untwist them.
What rubbish! I mean, what the...
MADAME MALLORY: Oh! Oh!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Take it, take it.
No. No.
No.
No, bring it, bring it.
Bring it.
My son.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(WOMAN SPEAKS FRENCH)
HASSAN: Service.
Two crayfish.
(MAN AGREES IN FRENCH)
Service.
Sea urchin.
HASSAN: Wait.
FEMALE CHEF: Is that okay?
You've ruined it.
I'm sorry, chef.
(DISTANT CLATTERING)
(SPEAKING HINDI)
You want some?
Please.
My wife cooks it.
Over the fire in the courtyard.
Do you like it?
My wife cooks much better than me.
Where did she get the spices?
I have them send it from home.
You know,
it's cheaper than a flight ticket.
(CHUCKLES)
It's got amchur.
Yes.
And kala jeera.
Yes. A little bit of garam masala also.
Every bite takes you home.
(DOOR OPENS)
Mmm.
Welcome.
(SIGHS)
Pleasant surprise.
Cheers.
You can't sleep, huh?
Mmm.
It's cold.
Mmm, beautiful.
I have been thinking about Hassan.
MADAME MALLORY: Mmm.
PAPA: I think I'm going
to write to him tonight.
MADAME MALLORY: What will you tell him?
PAPA: Oh, lots of things.
I will tell him
that the restaurant is doing well.
That we have been spending
a lot of time together.
We go to dance classes.
(CHUCKLES)
And we go to the market together.
MADAME MALLORY: Yes.
PAPA: Remember that time
we were taking a walk along the river?
We picked flowers.
We did not pick flowers.
We were looking for mushrooms.
And we found flowers.
Which we picked.
Yes, picked flowers, of course,
but we were looking for mushrooms.
Anyway, anyway, I'll write him,
it's almost
like having a girlfriend.
(STAMMERING)
Almost.
What... What happened?
(STAMMERING) I'm sorry. I said almost.
(MUTTERS)
Bloody crazy Frenchwoman.
(ROMANTIC FRENCH SONG
PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
I thought you might like to dance
with your "almost" girlfriend.
(FRENCH MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
You haven't changed. (CHUCKLES)
You did. (CHUCKLES)
A little bit.
I have.
MARGUERITE: What are you doing here?
You'll know about your star today, no?
You should be in Paris.
I came because I have
a proposition for you.
A business proposition.
Okay.
No one knows about it
except Madame Mallory,
but I've asked her if I could use
the Saule Pleureur kitchen tonight,
because I want to cook a dish
that I haven't cooked in a long time.
With you.
With me?
Mmm-hmm.
(SNIFFING)
Just, uh, one more thing I need.
Okay.
PAPA: Well done.
MAHIRA: Aisha, Mukhtar!
- Coming!
HASSAN: You still haven't said
if you accept
my business proposition.
(CHUCKLES)
I accept.
- Welcome. Come in.
- The Kadam family is here.
Of course. Oh!
You are very chic this evening.
And how beautiful is your daughter?
- I know.
MAHIRA: - Thank you.
You look beautiful, too.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MADAME MALLORY: Come in, come in.
Merci.
MADAME MALLORY: Mes amis, my friends, um,
I just want to say welcome,
and tonight we have
a very special occasion.
We eat at the Maison Mumbai,
but with food prepared here
in Le Saule Pleureur.
And I want to introduce you
to our very special chefs for tonight.
Chefs, s'il vous plaît.
Voila. Marguerite.
(ALL CHEERING)
And...
(GASPS)
Arrey, Hassan.
Hassan?
Arrey, when did you become
so good-looking? Huh?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What are you doing here?
You should be in Paris.
I have come back from Paris.
What?
I'm moving back to St. Antonin.
You see, these are my real stars.
Marguerite and Hassan.
And I have given
total control of the Saule Pleureur
to Hassan.
Well, not total control.
I have a new business partner.
PAPA: Business?
What are the terms?
(ALL LAUGHING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I'm serious.
Michelin! Michelin!
(BEEPS)
Hey, why did you disconnect?
- Take the... Call back.
- Leave it.
Call back, it's Michelin!
It's okay.
7:00. Come, come here.
Call him back.
- Papa...
- Call him back!
Listen to me.
No, no, no. You call him back now!
Papa, relax. I know what to do.
Everybody,
this is where we will get our third star.
Together.
(APPLAUSE)
Alors, for God's sake, come on, let's eat!
Yes!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
AISHA: Excuse me!
Where's my hairband? Mahira!
Oh!
(LAUGHS)
(INDISTINCT)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh!
(ALL CHEERING)
(COMPLIMENTING IN FRENCH)
PAPA: Yay! Hurray! Cheers!
Toast. Toast.
(HINDI SONG PLAYING)