¿Clouseau?
The first time that
listen to say that name...
...Clouseau was alone a gift
Nobody. A policia in the estacion...
...of a city in
The outskirts of Paris.
Vivia in the Village Bidit.
¡Idiotic! But ahead.
Mr. Doumon, should leave
Of the via immediately.
I am very sorry official Clouseau.
My chair does not move.
That is the problem.
Leave that help it.
We see, the positive one with the negative...
...And the negative with the positive one.
Well, already can go.
We go, they continue ahead.
I am lnspector in Leader
Of the policia national.
I have listened many histories of
of the officials in the land...
Clouseau, generally
Has many, many histories.
Remains low arrest by
The murder of Tiato Kay.
¿Tiato Kay?
The case this closed.
I should I tell it, Clouseau never
I qualify for ningun I work.
Never pair in utilizing it
for something, until...
...I arrive that I gave fatal.
Was the I gave perfect for a murder.
France against China, with the
Reno, arriving at the ends.
Present investors been and
Inspectors of other national stations.
And by my nominacion to
the medal of honor...
I have been nominated 7 times.
Never I have earned none.
But even asi, 7 nominations...
...Is something.
Good, the coach
Of the team frances.
...Yves Gluant, salio for
Beginning its usual one show.
I raise its fist toward the multitude.
With its ring of the diamond
Of the Panther Rose.
Was a simbolo of triumph and
Victory for the team frances.
Its girlfriend at that time was Xania.
An international star of the hip-hop.
Tenian a relacion quite serious.
To ends of the time to regulate,
The fight was tight.
The play was put a little bored.
The French that always
habian state well...
...They were 3 to 2. The victory
Was practicamente dificil.
And suddenly, a miracle.
¡If!
And just then, in front
of all the people...
...Gluant dead key....
A dart poisoned gave him in the neck.
And the Diamond of the Panther Rose...
...Habia vanished.
THE PANTHER Rose.
Disappeared person.
All the periodicos spoke
Of the death of Gluant.
For them, the world
Itself habia paralyzed.
For my was, the best
Opportunity, for my triumph.
We be needed what
For the case of Gluant.
- ¿That?
- An incompetent one.
An incompetent one without
Imaginacion, of low level.
Who investigated without
arriving at none splits...
...and that tendra to all the
Media observing its steps.
And while the investigates without
arriving at none splits...
...I joined to all the
Better detectives of France.
And we will recover the diamond.
And then, the medal
Of the honor to be mia.
¿ AND who is this incompetent one?
I believe to know al better
Man for this work.
Find it and bring it to Paris.
Its name is, Clouseau.
- Good you gave young lady.
- Immediately I am with you.
The new Minister
command an its... portrait
...therefore I faint itself
While they painted the other.
I expect that see us
All as its friends.
Paris can be a place very politico.
I hate the politica. It but
Important is the morality.
That was very well. You said that?
If, I I went.
- ¿Podria to help to descend?
- Of course.
If.
Alone... Quizas...
Expect.
If, all this well.
I believe that if puts its leg...
- ¿Aqui?
- If, aqui.
Very well.
- Do Not I see where...
- Perhaps alli.
- This well.
Or quizas aqui.
I believe that I should pass to
Seeing al lnspector now.
If that seems him well.
Good you gave Clouseau.
- Clouseau.
- This al to enter.
Well.
Official Jacques Clouseau.
Policia of the Unit 6.
- ¿It gave Him in the corazon?
- ¿In the corazon? For nothing.
Clouseau. The razon by
the one that we call... it
Is a strange charmer,
What we have aqui.
And if the strange continuous one...
Looked at that the room was insured.
Thanks.
Clouseau, I have read its
reports and me this very clear one...
...that the magnitude of its talent
deserves but responsibility...
...Of the one that has had up to now.
I have determined to promote it there is lnspector.
The charge but high for any
Official in the Republic.
- ¿Lnspector?
- Exact. And its first case is...
...the death of Gluan and the robbery
Of the Diamond of the Panther Rose.
- Is a honor.
- Very well.
Jacques Clouseau, by the
being able that is granted... me
...I declare it lnspector
to complete... time
...with all the blablabla...
Blablabla.
If was so kind, please.
- It Take, use my feather.
- Thanks.
¿Since when they do not see the
Traditional Panther Rose of France?
And we will carry this by always.
Is not a gift. Me it
It gave the mail of Paris.
Thanks, but I cannot accept it.
The press Conference.
If. Clouseau, there is a
Press conference in...
...some minutes, al final of the
Walkway. Present it to the media.
We find us alli.
- ¿Entendio, Clouseau?
- If.
- Good luck.
- Good luck to you.
¿Where is the press Conference?
Leave, even by the door of the
Right, and is al final of the walkway.
The room even this policyholder.
Thanks.
¡Is perfect!
Already we find our man.
¿Because I feel humedo?
Due to the great importance
of the murder of Gluan...
...we have assigned the case
Al lnspector Clouseau.
¿Mr. lnspector?
- If.
- ¿Which to be its first task?
- To Assure that nobody leave injured.
Seems to be friends, that the
I liquidate mature, I flow for...
- ...An afluyente.
- ¿As it believes to find al murderous?
Take note. In these moments the murderer
it is surrounded for the team of disturbance...
...for 5 or 6 companions, and
by tecnologias special...
...As the radio and the mail of Cuba.
Appoint a man so that report...
...Of its progresses all the time.
¿That class of man?
One that continue orders and
That ask not questions.
Mr. lnspector. It believes that the
Murderer be man or woman?
Of course that it itself.
¿That is that? A joke?
¿It believes that the murderer it this
Seeing in these moments?
If I was a murderer, by
Supposed that estaria looking at.
And even recording for
Revising all but late.
But they know that serious dificil
Trap it through the T.V.
But I have a message for the murderer.
Not habra place in the
that can be hidden...
...Neither place where cannot be seen.
Murderous, I found you.
Because I am a man
That serves to its nacion.
Because the justice, is the justice.
And France is France.
- Good you gave, Nicole.
- Good you gave, lnspector.
Welcome to its new office.
Deberia to begin for
Revising these forms.
Is a strange charmer,
What we have aqui.
I expect that the strange one,
that this man...
If the strange continuous one, we will do a...
...Charming cut.
The room this policyholder.
- ¿It is found well?
- ¿That asks is that?
And it organize those minutes.
- ¿That?
- Nothing.
Deberia to begin for
Revising these forms.
¡God mio! Who shot that?
Now that is lnspector,
It needs new clothes.
If it wants I can take him the
Measures and to send him to do something.
- Perfect.
- It be Removed the jacket.
If.
- ¿ Lives alone, Mr. lnspector?
- If.
- ¿Does Not it know anyone?
- Not, in reality not.
- At least, not for now.
- Already this this.
- AND welcome to Paris.
- Thanks.
Good you gave Mister.
- ¿ AND you are?
- Gilbert Ponton. Class 2da detective.
- They assigned Me to their case.
- ¿ AND that calificacion has?
My family has been in the policia
Of Paris for 9 generations.
- ¿ AND previous to that?
- We Were policias in the zone...
- ... It surrounded by 200 years.
- ¿ AND previous to that?
They emigrated of various European countries.
And all they worked in the policia.
- ¿ AND previous to that?
- Farmer.
Asi that you are a farmer that
Comes to work with Clouseau.
Gilbert Ponton. I taught him all
What itself of the police work.
And together...
...We are going to trap a murderer.
Look at, the Chinese tenian
Seats in the zone of the murder.
The poison was Chinese. H to state
Any Gluant time in China?
Three years ago Gluan
I carry a group of...
...players for a
I play of exhibicion.
Gluan was in China.
The poison is of China.
The Chinese are of the China.
Quizas very is hurried...
...but I believe that ours
Murderer is of China.
I want that go to Beijing. And
Ascertain that toward Gluan alli.
To whom saw and where was.
I want a report on each
One of the Chinese present.
¡We go, we go!
Mr. lnspector, is so late.
I finish to analyze these intrusive.
I believe that needs a little rest.
- That is not the best, Nicole.
- Has razon.
You know...
Always I have wanted to test me to my same one.
And they have given me this opportunity.
And I have the eyes where they should be.
Exact where they should be.
I can be done it that.
I cannot fail.
- AND it not hara. Itself that not.
- Thanks Nicole.
- Nicole.
- If.
- ¿I can be clear with you?
- Of course.
Has enlarged a lot of weight.
With that weight...
You forget it.
¿Him gustaria that remained me to help it?
I thank a lot its offering Nicole.
But I am very sensitive
With the politica labor.
And in this world...
the but minimo gesture...
...it can be misinterpreted
As... harassment.
It is late. and preferiria not to put it...
...Or to my, in that delicate one situacion.
- ¿We Agree?
- If.
Then you give me a kiss.
And you leave me to return al work.
Lre al grain.
As is alone a
class... 2da detective
...does not seem to have clearly
The metodos of work.
And according to the report that
leader does me, he draw a plan...
...to maintain you warning
Provided that being possible.
¿ AND which is?
Immediately and
without notifying, I attacked... you
...with the arm,
When except it expect.
In this sense, mantendre
Eye contact and the high hand.
- ¿In agreement?
- If.
- Good work.
- Thanks.
Is aqui.
Among when the light to stop blinking.
Permission.
I want that, if...
...do them some questions on...
¡They stop, they stop!
¿Who they are and that devils do?
- We interrogate It.
- First, she does not be able oir what says.
And by if it they have not noted, they have
It interrupted my sesion of trial.
- ¡Asi that leave!
- In the event that want... not
...blocking the justice, should leave me
Interrogating the young lady Xania.
This well, Boby. As
This Mr. lnspector?
I am Xania.
You does not know me, but...
...but I am very
It familiarized with its work.
Is very kind.
¿You said that of
Inside itself oia nothing?
If.
Well. You were in the stadium
When Gluant was murdered.
If. Already me habia moved with the.
Of course.
We go to what is important.
Six witnesses saw it
fighting with Peter and shouting...
¿That was what shouted Ponton?
I am going to kill you. I am going to kill you.
Was angry.
It sorprendi with another woman.
And was despues that told me that loved me.
Poor small alitas of angel.
Despues that me deceit...
...It hate it a lot.
- But it kill not.
- Of course that not.
¿Which was its finalizes presentacion?
It stops tormenting it.
¿Do not you see that this afflicted?
Three months ago in Shangai.
¿It knows about someone but that
It could hate to Gluan?
- Bizu.
- Is a star of soccer.
I salia with Bizu,
When conoci to Gluan.
Told me that Gluan was evil, alone
Maintain me far away of the.
I invite me to leave.
You are the proximo.
But I have a flight to
Monserrat. I go with Xanai.
Not ira. I need to do him
Some questions.
- I itself nothing.
- Quizas not on the life.
But if on the love.
Your, cachorrito slippery.
It is maintained quiet, if wants to leave.
Lnspector.
¿I should remain in the city?
Because the proxima week I have something...
...Simple that to do in New York.
If in reality has something that to do...
...It is free to go where want.
I cannot carry them to see Bizu.
But if I can carry them
To see al Mr. Jacquard.
Was the assistant of the coach.
I suppose that now be
The main coach.
- ¿Queria to see me?
- ¿You are Jacquard?
If. And you who is?
I am the lnspector Clouseau. Such
Time have listened on my.
Not.
Do not you write that.
- ¿That wants?
- I Have understood that Bizu hated to Gluan.
Many people hated to Gluan.
¿You tambien?
I was 6 years under its command,
Bearing verbal abuse.
If, was not fan of Yves Gluan.
But now the this dead person.
And you occupy its position.
- ¿Is Not an ironia?
- Not, is a tragedy.
Well, ¿but, where was?...
Listen.
Is a young woman. Of 30 or 35 years.
1 meter 52, 54. Of brown hair.
And it carries tacones high and a wardrobe...
...Too formal for the late.
And it carries...
...Channel 5.
¿ Authorization a woman with you?
- Not.
- ¿It Carries tacones in that market?
- ¿It Carries algun perfume?
- Not.
- ¿Who is?
I am Yuri, the coach.
¿ AND that you do you,
''Yuri, the coach''?
I coach.
So you are Yuri the
Coach that coaches.
- Go Not.
- But I should go to Asia.
Very well.
Do not leave despues that come of Asia.
We have a competence in Brazil.
Very well.
Do not leave despues of
Asia and America Southern.
- Very well.
- ¿ AND where this the famous player?
This outside, in the country of practices.
Then we be going to see al Mr. Bizu.
I have to Bizu seated in
The room of interrogacion.
- ¿Which is the plan?
- First I am going to take a Capuchin.
- ¿You Are a player of soccer, Bizu?
- If.
- ¿You Know what step with Gluan?
- I am glad that their gave you have finished.
Its you gave has not finished.
¡The this dead person!
- Is an idiot.
- ¡Gluan he is not ningun idiotic!
Well...
Unless want not to pass the
remainder of its life in the prision...
...respond the following one
It asks. The murderous thing?
- Me encantaria to have killed.
- ¡God!
But algun bastard
Fortunate itself me advancement.
¡You are despicable!
I return immediately.
- ¿A cigar?
- Not...
- ...I find him sense.
- You Do well.
Bizu.
Itself that it did not you do. Someone it
It caused trying to save your group.
- ¿ You Are going to help me?
- Clear that I am going to help you.
¿You have some idea of who they were
The small gansters that Gluan veia?
They are the of that estupido restaurant.
- Marroque.
- Manuel Marroque.
Is the owner of the casino Monart.
Gluan robbery money of the
Restaurant and I send it to Gapa.
I believe that they discovered it, and they killed it.
Bizu, you fall me well.
I am going to help you.
Now you are going to know to a great team.
The cups to do
Capuchin they function very well.
In reality use different cups.
¿You know that we do to the
Prisoners that do not collaborate?
We connect it to this box.
- ¿That is that box?
- ¡Ldiota!
We catch this cable electrico...
...We put it aqui.
I take the other.
And I put... it
- ¿ AND well, that believes?
- Bizu is innocent.
I do not understand.
Gluan suspendio to
Bizu. I remove him the girlfriend.
If I was the, there was it
It killed, alli and that same one I gave.
And that is exactly what Bizu did.
Ponton.
Is like the trail and the source.
You need the trail and
You need the source.
You have a trail, but not the source.
¿Where this your front?
Good its señoria wanted
analyzing the case...
... But everything that I have is a trail.
- ¿That?
- Nothing.
Crei that habias said, '' AHAHAh''.
Not.
Strange.
¡Even you say!...
Oh, you are your.
I feel a lot of what step Mr. lnspector.
Look at.
Already I have the clothes of the sewing box.
- AND tambien some pants.
- Thanks.
- ¿It Desires a little water?
- If, please.
It knows Nicole...
This crime has obliged me
To use all my knowledge.
Everything that I have learned
since I am investigating...
- ...Comes me for parts.
- ¿It imports Him if I take this?
- I have Not eaten.
- Not, please, ahead.
As now use but the head...
...I have realized that...
¿You have seen it?
¡Wait!
Of backs, of backs.
¿Feels better?
If. Was so well. Where it aprendio?
I have practiced many
Things, this and it another.
But frankly was the
expresion in its face...
...What I show me what needed.
Ponton, ¿that you have for my?
Seems that tenia razon on Bizu.
They found it dead person
in the installations...
...Of the training camp.
- They shot Him in the head.
- ¿This fatal one?
- If.
- ¿How fatal?
Completely.
- I want to speak with the now.
- This dead person.
Good friend.
It is Yuri the coach that coaches.
If, asi is.
I seek a dead body. Quizas
Can tell me where this.
If, listen that was in
The room of those of soccer.
You arrive to the end of the
walkway, you double to the right...
¿ It Sees somewhat amusing aqui?
I was honest with you. I find
Its very dazzling eyes.
- ¿Of where is?
- Of Russia.
They recruited me of the Russian military team.
Reclutarrrrron, militarrrrrr.
You have to be careful with your accent.
- ¿That?
I do not have time to lose it aqui.
- Dime that you saw.
- Good...
...I did not see anything.
It passed for aqui. Was late. Already
The not deberia to have been aqui.
Listen sounds of the
Another side of the door.
Listen that said, ''oh, you are your''.
And then someone him shot.
Expects.
We have a trail.
I want that they interrogate
to all the people...
...Of Paris that are called, '' your''.
¿Do not you believe that is a lot of
coincidence that the body...
...have fallen perfectly
Inside that linea?
The experts did the linea despues.
They should have been a class of teachers.
Ponton, I want that
You interrogate al such Marroco.
¿Where this its casino?
Park it close, please.
Unless want to know
That is good for you.
Does not it stop surprising me, lnspector.
You have not seen anything Ponton.
The owners not even expect us.
Gentlemen, today we have new rules.
Ponton, locates to security.
It looks to see if you can locate
To our luxurious man.
- The Mr. Marroco.
- ¿Do Not you come?
I should attend something.
As they can appreciate, the roulette...
...It began when do the deals.
I tambien cause I comply the law.
- ¿It is noted me so much?
- ¡Not!
Put you the ties for other things.
- Aqui this its mojito.
- It Calls.
¡Lmpresionante!
Almost it did not recall.
I am the lnspector Jacques Clouseau.
I am in a very important case.
Ausborn, Najon Ausborn. Agent W6.
- ¿It Knows what I mean?
- If.
These in the show of Avoids.
I tambien am in a
very important... case
...for which I expect that
himself be not bothered if I tell... him
...That nobody should know that I am aqui.
Him meti the I number of
My movil in its pocket.
Call if needs aid.
It not haria, lnspector.
Among.
- Mr. Labargue impresses Me.
- Mr. lnspector impresses Me.
They are put comodos. In
That I can help them?
Lnvestigamos the murder of Yves Gluan.
¿Of Yves? A very fascinating man.
¿Has idea of as much as
Payment by its Panther Rose?
I inherit it. Him not cost swims.
¡Him cost the life!
Me gustaria to revise its balls.
- ¿My balls?
- Its vessels.
Me gustaria to throw him a
Look to its large vessels.
- Very well.
- Thanks.
¡Precious!
I have many of these.
Some they are green...
...As cups. It can tell me which desires.
Second century. Very well done.
They held these
Bovedas since inside.
Because if not, the grease of the
Hands ruined the painting.
¡Alabastra pure!
¡Beautiful!
Funny. As it hacian?
Seems that they do not want to leave.
¿Because hill the account
Of the insurance, Andrian?
The compañia not cubriria the murder.
Tenia that to remove it
All before losing it.
They pagarian nothing, ¿understands it?
¿But you had profits
With the death of Gluan, not?
¿Profits? That profits?
You remained with the restaurant.
The restaurant is a disaster.
Gluan expense a lot in the and I do not gain anything.
The unico relief is that to
Times utilized it to play.
But despues of a time, itself
I get into debt so much that querian to kill it.
Me prometio its testament,
In the shape of payment.
If someone I kill Gluant,
Should have been someone large.
- ¿Is Not asi?
- Not.
¿Did not you cut him the
legs and despues the...
...you crushed to
Leave them throw dust?
Not.
It is the same thing that say in the T.V.
Care, they can join him themselves
The hands in the vessels.
Seems that the place of
This, was where was this.
Al to seem my telefono this sounding.
Hello.
If, is the lnspector...
If, I can see it.
¿In the restaurant?
I was ahi immediately.
Gentlemen, surgio something.
Please, they excuse.
- ¿Mr. Labargue?
- If.
¿This is original or is a copy?
Is an imitacion without ningun value.
Well.
But that buro was...
...Very valuable.
- ¡Clouseau!
- Najon.
I need your aid.
Is important, that when you
Count do not look at toward atras.
Look not at toward atras when to tell me.
Detras of you, in the casino...
...Extends a smoke.
¡God mio! The smoke is expanded!
- Every Europe seeks me.
- ¿As I can help you?
- Alone you give me your shelter.
- Aqui you have.
Well.
Deberia to be in the sky.
But I cannot leave
That the smoke be expanded.
- Aqui you have.
- If, the shelter. This humedo.
Himself is not supposed that this aqui. Recalls?
Lnspector.
¡God mio, that was fantastico!
¿It says in the first page
That suspendio to the types?
¿It sought Clouseau
Connect them to the Panther Rose?
¿Something it can tell us Mister?
I cannot give comments al respect.
I...
¿Lnspector?
¿Clouseau?
- Very well Gilbert.
- Thanks.
¿ AND well, that has for my?
We have a great I number of people
In Paris that are called '' Your''.
Finally, we are approaching.
You read it again.
Can be gone.
- ¿You Speak Chinese?
- ¿Because? Does not it believe that speak Chinese?
If did not it speak Chinese, ¿that
Estaria doing aqui?
It should be very funny to say, '' The
Lnspector Clouseau does not speak Chinese''.
Carry it to have lunch.
Gilbert does neither speak Chinese.
And they do not know about what she this speaking.
¿That is what you
Gustaria to do? Is that?
¡Of course that I speak Chinese!
¿Clouseau?
Good you gave Nicole.
- ¿A minute can come?
- I Go immediately, lnspector.
- If, lnspector.
- Nicole.
Algun strange has been sniffing out.
It asked me if you believe
That remain a lot of time.
It said, that not.
¿But do not you believe that that
Strange it be going to sing?
We maintain the fingers crusaders...
...So that remain 5 minutes.
¡Sight what have for you!
We see who is.
Is supposedly the lnspector Dreyfus.
In reality is alone a chewed.
¡But I am going to remove itself it!
¡You remove them to me!
It seems that you have it well hit.
¿Feels better? It
I feel a lot of lnspector.
- Better we forget it.
- Listen...
...as no longer this uncomfortable one, him
I counted as we go with the case.
I...
I remained aqui.
These leaders are so utiles.
Is fantastico not to have that
aiming something with the fingers...
...and to be able to utilize these
stupendous popsicles...
...for seem not some
Estupidos primitive.
And if someone does not attend,
alone he has that...
¡The case, the case!
If, the case.
The case goes very well. I have
A list of suspects.
- ¿ AND as many as has?
- 27 thousand 608.
Edge that is alone cuestion of time.
- ¿ AND it has not eliminated to ningun suspicious?
- If.
Good...
- ¿ AND who could be?
- Gluan.
- Gluan is kills it.
- Excellent lnspector.
I see that we are connected.
A key trail carries us to something close.
¡Alone leave it!
I assure him lnspector
that its play of karma...
...remained as a...
...as... as...
...As something that your.
- ...Your.. your you can use.
- Good word.
I see it in the theater.
Not to have swum better than
An I gave after of another.
Federal Jubstin.
I am pleased with its report.
I call it to have lunch.
There is something but that to treat in
The program of this Comite.
The nominacion that does each
year our nacion for...
...The medal of the honor.
The two they nominated are...
Shall Dreyfus.
And the Sister Mathew Get.
The car recognition
that our nacion offers...
...is an inspiracion
For all of us.
I bring another name so that
be considered in the Comite...
...the lnspector Jacques
Clouseau, the man that came...
...of that small village for
Take charge of the case of Yves Gluant.
And that already has captivated
The atencion of the media.
Is a very interesting idea.
- The fans enlarge.
- Exact.
¡Excellent idea!
¿They are all to favor?
¿As it was that me did not they report
That Clouseau went for the casino?
- Was average night.
- ¡Was average night!
¿ AND not querias to awake me?
I want to know what does
Clouseau the 24 hours of the I gave.
If to you stop calling an alone one
Time, to be thrown of the force.
- ¿I Remain clear?
- If, mister.
- ¿Because not this with the now?
- Because I am aqui.
¡Was!
- Clouseau.
- Ponton.
Lba for the Prent Tyle.
Me gustaria to know for where
You went in the investigacion.
I want good ideas, Ponton.
Alone the men with a good one...
...subconscious they are able
Arriving rapido really.
Dime, ¿which are the facts?
Yves Gluan was fined in the semifinals
of the Championship lnternacional...
- ...By a blow in its head.
- ¡That is the fact!
Bizu queria to kill it,
But the already this dead person.
¡That is the conflict!
Gluan was accompanied by the luck.
- ¡AND was it!
- AND quite close, this the singer.
Xania, is not Shakira. But
MYSELF suspect that knows but...
...Of what told me. Where this now?
Went. I travel from sudden to New York.
lremos detras of her, for
Ascertaining that this doing.
If I am going to go to the States
You united, I have to perfect...
...my accent, for
Seem not suspect.
Asi that beginning to
Working in my accent.
Me gustaria to buy a hamburger.
Me gustaria to buy a hambur... guesa.
Not, not. We are going to divide the oracion.
Me...
- gustaria ......
- gustaaaaria ......
- guuuustaria ......
- guuuuustaria ......
- gustaria ......
- to buy ......
- cooomprar ......
- Cooomprar. ...
- one ......
- a ......
- Hamburger. ...
- Hambuerg. ...
- Hambra. ...
- ham ......
- bur ......
- Guesa. ...
Me gustaria to buy a hamburger.
Is not '' damburguesa''. Is '' hamburger''.
I did not say '' damburguesa''. I said '' Me
Gustaria to buy a hamburger''.
Me gustaria to buy a hamburger.
Hamburger.
Me gustaria to buy a damburgu.
- Quizas we should we stop.
- We can Not yield us.
Again, again.
Me gustaria to buy a hamburger.
Me gustaria to buy a damburrrrr.
Me gustaria to buy a hambur.
Me gustaria to buy a hamburger.
Me gustaria to buy a hamburgggg.
hamburggg ......
¿Habias eaten hamburger before?
¡By God, not! Is the filthy one
American food.
- Never I have seen you with women.
- I Am married.
- ¿ AND because do not you carry the ring?
- To protect it.
I am afraid that some rogues threaten it.
¿You like a lot of?
I consider it the woman
But beautiful of the world.
- ¿ AND that such your?
- Not.
Me do not I consider a pretty woman.
I mean that if exists
Some woman in your life.
The love himself there is not crusader by my road.
Unfortunately the lnspector Clouseau
Has always been a romantico single.
It is seen as a man
Ordinary without alegrias.
That is hard.
- ¿That is it?
- It yours. Finding a woman.
Oh, if.
Tomorrow we will have an I gave hard.
Lremos al hotel of Xania.
And we will ascertain in which walks.
- Good evening.
Thanks.
Revise the calls telefonicas.
Xania did two calls
to an it recognized jeweler...
...Of the black market of the diamonds.
¡Ahi this! The periodicos.
¡Periodicos!
Flat 12.
Someone wants to fish us.
¿I can help them in something?
Good work of team.
¡They stop! Leave what are doing!
They are defenseless. We have tests...
...Of this reunion mysterious.
- ¿I Owe algun imposed?
- ¿Not the pay?
Ponton, I believe that we owe him
An excuse al mister.
¿ AND that was cutting?
I work with diamonds rose. A '' cleart''.
- ¡''Cleart''!
- Is Not the Panther Rose.
¿ AND that you do your aqui, sniffing out?
This market was of Josephine Baker.
It was being destroyed, asi that...
...debia to fix the diamonds for
Using it in the dance of the President.
¿But because me did not you tell it?
¿Because to come to aqui?
Me they cannot see with a
Cutter of diamonds.
Not despues of what step.
Is better than I lame now your messages.
Hello.
If, I am the one that is entrusted
Of the foundries.
My name now it does not matter.
A great commerce in one minutes.
Less payments, but entrances.
If, clear that interests me.
Jacques Clouseau. Card of credito...
...with the I number 1400023...
...14151 1 12...
...782892 BWD.
Clearly that is an if.
If, clear that I give him my key.
Doctor player.
I believe that I have just done a great business.
- ¿That time was in the city?
- I go tomorrow.
I should seduce it Ponton.
But it knows that not...
...almost neither to speak
And much less to say jokes.
- ¿To Speak that?
- I want to know in which avion itself ira.
- ¿Because him do not you ask?
- Is too obvious.
- I Need to seek informacion.
- Already I see.
Lnspector.
¿Him gustaria to have dinner with me in the hotel?
Of course, young lady.
We tell... the 8:00 exactly.
- ¿Where?
- We Say, that itself... not
In my room, in the second flat.
Itself not, in my room in the second flat.
We see us.
- My it wanted key.
- Then you seek it.
Welcome to my room, lnspector.
Is a strange charmer,
What we have aqui.
Oh, if, baby. If!
¡Care!
- ¿That?
- ¿That that?
¿Because parecias so nervous today?
Tenia fear of Labargue.
Podia to be continuing me.
¿Lavargue? Is of the casino or not?
It said that mataria al that had
The diamond of the Panther Rose.
The it believes that belongs to the.
¿But because you perseguiria to you?
I was in New York for
Seeing a cutter of diamonds.
Podria to remove its own conclusions.
You know...
...being in this city so
sweet, so near you...
...it causes removes me
Conclusions erroneas tambien.
Or podrian to be the correct.
I have listened many things
On you lnspector.
- ¿ AND which are those things?
- That does not know as to treat a woman.
If.
We begin the play.
You leave me alone...
Prepare me. ...
It exaggerates pildora for
The force of the man.
¡Unfortunate!
¿Lnspector?
¿This all well ahi inside?
Even that querias that prepared me.
¿Lnspector? This
Insurance that this well?
If, I am well.
Alone I enter a new phase.
Hello.
We need vegetables and two services.
Do not you ask because and alone do it.
It takes the flight and when leave
Tomorrow, you change him the suitcase.
It is facil to recognize. Has
White hair, a rare mustache.
Walks with a lot of confidence
And this completely it lost.
- ¿You Bought the stews?
- If.
Well. You give them to me to my.
As by seconds. Not
I want that they remove it us.
- Hello Xania.
- Hello.
¿You believe that hides something, Ponton?
¿That?
It asked him if creia
That she to hide something.
Very well, thanks.
Well, we go.
We go.
Cannot continue.
- ¿That is its suitcase, mister?
- If.
- Tendre that to revise it.
- Ahead.
I do not have anything that to hide...
...In my suitcase.
We go, mister.
Expect its shift.
Is a pocket knife.
It is a... ¿you Arm of monks?
I am not going to lie. Not even
Itself of where came all that.
Never I have seen all that in my life.
¡Drunk!
Does not it need to ningun Drunk.
- Drunk, quiet.
- ¿That has in the pocket. mister?
Mister, it dire again,
¿That has in the pocket?
Nothing.
I asked it again, ¿that
Has in the pocket, mister?
Very well.
I have in my pocket...
...A pair of hamburgts.
¿That?
I have in my pocket...
...A pair of hamburgtsss.
- ¿Mister?
- Hambrtssss.
- Mister, in its pocket has...
- Very well.
I have a for of habrtss.
- I feel It, ¿that?
- Hambrgtsss.
- Again.
- Dambuerguesas.
Damburgsssaaas.
- Mister, I get angry.
- Not. ¿The these losing?
¿Your these getting angry?
I repeat him, and I repeat him
That I have Damburgsssaaass.
High security, among please.
¡Move not mister!
¡Rise the hands!
Not, not, not.
Be remained aqui mister.
¡You catch it!
Clouseau shames to France.
Verguenza National.
¿Lnspector?
¿Lnspector, that is a damburgsssaass?
¿lnspector, as feels
By it to have defrauded al pies?
That was all for the
Heroic lnspector Clouseau.
Well...
...This is a glory for France.
¿A social offense as that, lnspector?
Because the estupido idiotic
called Clouseau goes to...
...being private of its rights,
While I take its case.
¿You have a second
Called man Clouseau?
¡By God! Leave us alone for a moment.
Your.
Certainly lnspector Clouseau...
...Understand something Clouseau.
When I did it lnspector, not
it was because to believe that had...
...Some ability as the detective.
Was because tenia that to work with
An imbecil to deceive to France.
An idiot without hopes
And facil to deceive.
¿Then I was not
It promoted by my meritos?
I did it lnspector because
it needed someone that...
...Really did not arrive at none splits.
While I expected for
Take charge of the case.
- I tried to kill a murderer.
- Your, you were...
Your you tried to become heroe.
And pursuing that,
you ridiculed the pies...
Finish with you. Asi
that if excuses... me
...former lnspector, I was going to prepare
The arrest that gave me.
...the prize that offers the Assembly
National. And despues of that?
Who knows.
- Adios Clouseau.
- ¿We should enclose it?
You look at. This it finished.
Leave that go home. To the darkness.
¿Your the wise thing?
Ponton.
The things did not you leave
As they must have left.
And it fight to do you
Remaining as a fool.
I feel it.
Was a honor service, Mister.
Good luck.
Already this, lnternet.
We seek the club of fans.
To descend something should use
The linea of its telefono.
Pressing the boton that says '' to descend''.
We take the mouse, and then a click.
But not two, because itself
It overloads the boton of '' to descend''.
Serious error of the system.
Ladies and gentlemen. Good you gave.
Know al Dr. Him How Hwang.
It was photographed coming out with Gluan.
The Dr. Him, it sent large
Quantities of money to Gluan.
Al to seem, Gluan invirtio
A little in the business.
Tambien tenian a great play.
Hwang transported the money.
Having the motive,
Tenia the opportunity.
Now this aqui in France.
And was in the dance...
... of the President this
Night. We will arrest it alli...
...By the murder of Yves Gluan.
lnformo that I am myself
taking charge of the...
...Investigacion of the death of Gluan.
And that the arrest is imminent.
lnspector, they said that
Yves habia dead person of a...
...perfect shot and the
Chinese are very bajitos.
- ¿Algun comment?
- ¿Very bajito?
We will arrest them.
They are bajitos.
An error, that me does not cause feels well.
Zoom.
Clearly.
Ponton, I need to see you immediately.
Resolvi the case.
Nicole. I believe that Gluan and Bizu were
They murdered by the same person.
And I believe that the murderer it
Tried again this night.
I want that you see me in
The Presidential Palace.
And it carries my suitcase for the Palace.
¡You hurry you! Xania this
In a serious danger.
¡Ponton! We go al Palace, immediately.
- Ponte the cinturon.
- Do Not I need it, alone...
Clouseau should not be in the list.
Is not of the guests.
Has been a desverguenza
And a humillacion.
Already the reporters arrived.
¿ It Is going to say something?
When the moment arrive,
Leave that they alone come.
Clouseau.
I feel it, but its name
Not this in the list.
¿Not this in the list?
Dreyfus I am assured of
That could not enter.
Ponton.
- Lnspector, aqui this its suitcase.
- Good luck, Nicole.
- ¿That is that?
- My suitcase. We go.
- Nicole.
- If.
- ¿ You See well?
It is infinite, and is seen
Precious without its lenses.
Thanks lnspector.
Lnspector.
I come to report him
That Clouseau this aqui.
Cannot be, wine to
Doing the arrest the same one.
If you see Clouseau,
you put it in the cabin...
...so that be not able
Entering the festival.
The Dr. Hwang, has just arrived.
We will arrest it despues
Of the first one cancion.
- Very well Ponton.
- Very well.
Looks.
Is the murderer. Detras of the!
- ¡We Go for the!
- ¡It Hold!
Turn around.
- ¿Who they are? That they do aqui?
- We Are...
We are...
We are two...
Him dire exactly who we are.
- We Are...
- I have been Them seeking...
...All over.
¿Where devils were?
- ¿It knows Them?
- Of course that I know them.
They are of the group of dance of Xania.
They are the ones that leave this new one
It plots, in the third act.
- ¿Of where it believes that they removed those suits?
- ¡Test it!
We have not to test...
¡Do not you see that they are exhausted!
It sees to seek them water.
- ¡You Were fantastica!
- ¿It believes It?
You are...
...A woman increible.
Lnspector, the murderer.
¡Now if I am prepared
To trap a murderer!
¡Stop!
¡Stop, in name of the law!
¡Alli!
Your it sees for alla, and I lame by aqui.
¡It hold!
Turns around.
- Remains...
- Remains low arrest.
¡Ponton!
¡Now!
We go, we go.
Dr. Hwang, in name of
the statutes and of the...
...law of ours
great nacion, France...
...it arrest by the
Murder of Yves Gluan.
Is Clouseau. Arrest it!
¿Which to be?
That is the.
In the name of the
statutes and of the law...
...Of our great nacion, France.
It arrest for the
Murder of Yves Gluan.
Yuri, this is our friend.
- ¿ AND who you are you?
- I Am the lnspector Jacques Clouseau.
¡Gluan was nobody!
I merecia that place.
I gain fame by a defense
That i him permiti.
And they treated me as if was
They died, therefore now the it this.
By Chinese poison.
lnspector, ¿that him
Caused thought that was the?
Ponton, you think it. Your you were alli.
¿Because I bother me? Because
It brought me? Was very busy.
Its player was murdered with
Chinese poison. Deberia to seek...
Should have a knife
Sharp of the Chinatown.
She tenia razon, because...
...according to the 8722,
a great coach of soccer...
...It should know the Chinese secrets.
It was very facil for the to kill Gluan.
- ¿ AND to Bizu?
- Lgual.
Bizu tenia charges in
Its against by Gluan.
Asi that Bizu I begin to investigate
And that I cause that they killed it.
Oh, you are your.
A certain shot to the head.
Entering deep in its sense.
It speaks of a coach of soccer.
That owes itself done by an expert.
Insurance this familiarized
With the Russian soldiers.
- Statute 1 1.
- Of course.
All should be experts
Of the martial arts.
- To Understand in all moments
- To Understand...
- AND to put...
- ¡Clear that I remember it!
- Very well.
- If, mister.
Xania was the girlfriend of your
Friend, but you hated it.
And therefore you tried to kill it.
You hated it because was
with Bizu, with Gluan...
...And treated yourself as if did not you be anything.
But you forgot something
Fundamental of the women.
A woman is... like
...is... like
...Art collision.
You should delimit the world.
Or you arrive at its corazon.
¿That such the diamond?
¿That such the Panther Rose?
If, thanks. The lnspector
Clouseau seguia my orders.
- You Give me the diamond, Yuri.
- It forgets your putrid diamond.
- The does not have the diamond.
- ¡The murderer does not have the diamond!
- Not.
- ¿ AND then where this...
- ...Lnspector Clouseau?
- This alli.
- In its market.
- You Leave me to see.
I feel it, Clouseau.
But the diamond not this.
Give me that.
Maintain this.
When Gluan I approach itself, me
It said that not queria to deceive me but.
Me pidio that married me the.
The ring in the hands put me.
Despues that killed it, even that...
...if me ponia the ring, all
Pensarian that I it habia done.
If Gluan gave you the
ring before dying...
...according to the
civil statute 914B...
Your you are the heir.
You can remain you with the Panther Rose.
Lnspector, ¿as knew that she it tenia?
Was very simple, Ponton.
Looking at the photo that me
they took in the airport...
...Something I call me the atencion.
They were registering the market of Xania.
Enlarge the photo.
And ahi inside was... the Panther Rose.
The case this closed.
¡Clouseau, Clouseau!
lnspector, I thank him
The opportunity that gave me.
If me did not there was placed in the case...
...who knows, quizas someone
But was in my place now.
In reality I owe him
A lot, Mister lnspector.
If had not been for
You, not serious nobody.
Quizas be it.
Nothing can stop me mister.
Ldiota.
- ¡Oh, not!
- We Go Ponton.
- ¿That?
- Nothing.
Did not you say, '' Stop the car, by God''.
'' God you it request, they stop the car''.
Not.
Mister lnspector.
¿That?
It do not I understand.
I believe that wants that they raise it.
- The boton not this aqui.
- Sight to see on the other side.
I cannot reach it.
A moment.
Themselves not because they do it asi.
Deberia to be for control,
so that any power...
They know...
- Ponton.
- If, mister lnspector.
This is a very important moment
For the lnspector Dreyfus.
Is important that him
We show compasion.
We can use the great and
Genteel to be able of the laughter.
That is going to hurt.
¡Clouseau!
That leap was good.