– Oh, this is awesome!
– Oh my God!
Oh my God!
This is crazy!
Oh my God. So incredible.
– You wanna know a secret?
– Yeah!
– I took a Viagra.
– What?
This is awesome.
Why don’t I use this every day?
What did you do?
– Wait. Stop.
– I can’t!
Stop, stop!
Stop!
– What?
Aah!
What’s the matter?
You just took a Viagra
to have sex with me.
Well, I- I- I thought it
would make it better.
It was better. It takes
some of the pressure off.
Because you can’t get
hard without a Viagra?
Is it because you don’t I’m think sexy?
I thought you’d think it was fun
for me to supersize it for once.
That is the worst birthday present
you could ever give someone.
I was just trying to go
turbo for your birthday.
My hard-ons are still in analog.
This shit’s digital.
I don’t want a turbo penis.
I like your medium soft one.
Look, I can get it up. Just…
not that far up.
Where did you get this?
I got it from Barry.
What?
You got it from Barry?
Why do you care? This is my
dick we’re talking about, not yours.
We are young people.
We don’t need medication to have sex.
I only took it ’cause it’s your birthday.
I thought you’d like it.
Happy fucking fortieth birthday.
I am not forty!
And I don’t wanna have a husband
who has to take Viagra to get a hard-on!
I don’t have to take it every
time, but once in a while…
Fuck forty!
Forty can suck my dick!
THIS IS FORTY
Caption and sync: jcdr
No. Dad, stop.
Time to get up.
– Time to get up!
– Your breath smells weird.
Whake uhp!
Hi really hate you! Wake uhp!
Wake up. Come on!
Time to wake up.
Ready!
♪Happy birthday dear Mummy,
♪Happy birthday to you.
Make a wish!
Can I watch Lost?
You can’t handle Lost.
It’s too violent, and
you won’t understand.
If I don’t understand it,
why can’t I handle it?
Because you’re eight.
I can handle it. I’ve seen a shark
eat a guy on Shark Week.
Shark Week is fake.
No, it’s not.
All of it is reenactments.
– I know but they sh--
– And that’s scary,
you shouldn’t be allowed to watch that.
They show the reenactments
but they actually happened.
It’s gonna give you nightmares.
I can handle a nightmare.
You’re a nightmare every day for me.
Hey!
– Don’t eat that cupcake.
– What?
The one you just put into the sink.
I saw you were hiding that.
This cupcake? You think
I might eat this cupcake?
– Yeah.
– I so don’t want this cupcake. Look.
– You’re still gonna eat it.
– I’m gonna eat this cupcake?
Just put it in the trash.
What would you like to do?
Your choice.
– Anything?
– Yeah, anything.
Just hang out with you guys.
Don’t you want to get a massage? Or…
do something fun, it’s a bit--
Forty’s huge!
I’m turning thirty-eight.
Okay. Thirty-eight.
We will move on.
Isn’t that weird that
our birthday is the same week
and that we’re gonna have
a party, and it’s just for me?
No. I don’t think it’s weird at all.
’Cause you’re turning forty
and I’m turning thirty-eight.
Come on. Do you really want to be one
of those ladies who’s just so insecure
about their age and they lie and then
they’ve got to remember, and it gets all--
You don’t get it. See, you don’t
understand how it works.
I don’t want to shop at old lady stores.
I don’t want to go to J. Jill and
Chicos and Ann Taylor Loft.
I’m not ready yet.
I need two more years.
That is so insane,
it kind of makes sense.
What did you get me for my birthday?
Wait a minute, I thought you said that we
shouldn’t get each other gifts this year?
What do you mean?
You’re supposed to get me a surprise gift.
This is a big birthday.
I’m turning forty!
Mom!!
Mom, why can’t I get new clothes?!
What the fuck, nothing fits me!!
God damn it!!
I am gonna go work out.
I’ll be back in about an hour.
Hey, did your father call
to wish you a happy birthday?
No. That’s no surprise.
– Come on.
– Coming.
You’ve gotta keep up
with us, sweetheart.
Yeah, I’m coming.
That’s why your body looks like your
body and her body looks like her body.
Before, after. Before, after.
You guys just go on, go on
without me, I’m just gonna…
Look, I gotta…
Fuck.
Thanks for uh…
Thanks for letting me join this team.
It’s not really a team, it’s just a bunch
of guys who get together and ride.
I know, I know.
Wow wow wow wow!
Hey! Bike lane, asshole!
It’s always the guy
in the fucking Infiniti.
Good seater. Get’em take here.
– Yeah. Okay.
– This we need to work on.
So why on earth is Pete taking Viagra?
What’s going on?
– I don’t know.
I think he just-- maybe he isn’t…
isn’t attracted to me anymore…
or something.
I don’t know.
Well that is ridiculous.
If you were my girlfriend,
I would not need a Viagra.
I would need an anti-Viagra pill.
To try not to get a boner.
But everyone gives you a boner.
Don’t sell yourself short like that.
You give me a boner.
Barb doesn’t give me a boner.
Maybe things are just getting stale.
That’s why maybe I work out really hard.
Maybe he’ll get…
he’ll be able to get a boner again.
Why d'you need to have sex, Deb?
Sex is the number one
thing people fight about.
You stop having
sex, there will be no more fights.
I am living proof.
I have no sex,
and I am the happiest I’ve ever been.
I knew it. I knew you were not having sex.
I can see it on your face.
It’s all…
uh, puckered and pained.
I’m enjoying our non-sex period,
that’s all I’m saying.
Don’t you miss it?
Well, I wouldn’t know, because I don’t
have any feeling down there anymore.
I have nerve damage from my C-section,
so everything's just kinda-
She’s numb down there.
I could sit down hard
on a fire hydrant, and
I wouldn’t even know that I was sitting.
I could get stung by a hornet
down there, and I would not feel it.
You could put anything…
in there…
and I would not know
what the object was.
I- I used to pee in a nice stream,
and now it just kind of goes
like a shower head.
That is the saddest thing I’ve ever heard.
I think you need a family.
Don’t you want a family?
No, I think I wanna Clooney it.
– Clooney it?
– Yup.
He doesn’t seem happy.
Yeah, he is.
No. He’s lonely.
No, he’s not.
See, I think he has sad eyes.
Aw, you sweet little thing.
No. He’s doing sad, lonely eyes.
To get the next lady.
Look, I can do it too. Watch.
I bet George Clooney is really lonely.
Just him and his… pig.
You’d fuck him.
I wouldn’t.
– So would you.
– I would. I wouldn’t feel it but I-
You’d fuck him with your numb vagina.
Yes you would.
Ocean’s thirteen inches,
that’s what you’d find out.
Do you think?
I mean that was idiotic, though.
You have to understand that.
I mean, that’s like the one thing you
don’t do is tell her that you used Viagra.
I think that’s even on the warning label.
We’re in one of those phases where…
everything that the other person says
just annoys the shit out of each other.
All the time. It’s a blast.
Don’t worry about it.
You just gotta ride that out.
This sounds terrible…
Okay. I like it.
.. but…
do you ever wonder
what it would be like…
if, say, you were separated by
something bigger, you know, like uh…
like death. Like her death?
I have given it a fair amount of thought.
Not in a painful way. Just…
quietly slid into death, like a gas leak.
Absolutely. It’s got to be peaceful.
I mean, this is the
mother of your children.
You want her to die…
– No, I’d want it to be a peaceful--
– gentle…
yeah, just like, drift, into a coma,
from which she never awakens.
And then you move on.
Then you are a widower.
That’s just it.
People love widowers.
They love widowers. It’s like
the polar opposite of divorced guys.
It’s the best.
It’s like, oh, that poor widower!
You know. If I could only…
– Somehow… somehow…
– .. make him happy.
– ease his pain.
– cocksuck away his sadness.
♪Chien andalusia
♪I am a chien Andalusia
Did you know that this uh--
Pixies did this song,
it’s about a Salvador Dali short film
called “Un Chien Andalusia”?
This music doesn’t make people happy--
This song kicks off Doolittle,
one of the best albums
of the last thirty years.
– Look how angry you get
while listening to this.
– An important record.
It’s my birthday. You don’t control
the radio on my birthday.
I do. I control the radio on my birthday.
♪.. on me
♪Take on me,
♪Take me on
Sadie’s watching Lost.
Sadie, how many times have
you watched Lost this week?
I’ve only watched eleven.
I- but I have eight more,
and then I’m done, so…
How many are there?
A hundred and fourteen?
Are you kidding me? You can’t watch over
a hundred episodes of a show in five weeks.
– No.
– It- It’ll melt your brain.
It’s not melting my brain,
it’s blowing my mind.
That’s really bad, Sadie.
You’re not allowed to do that.
My relationship with Lost
is not your business.
It’s extremely personal.
Stop!
Stop it!
– Be nice to your sister.
You guys are gonna
cherish each other one day.
Stop it! Stop!
Honey, it’s your birthday,
you don’t need to go to the store.
I know, just five minutes.
Desi and Jodi are fighting.
All right, five minutes.
But then I’m pulling you out.
Hi.
Hi. How’s Jodi treating you?
Jodi?
Oh, Jodi’s my new BFF.
She’s like a little kitty cat. Sometimes
she comes and rubs up against my leg.
And you’re a ball of shit.
She loves me.
Huh.
Can you do inventory so that
we can do the sidewalk sale?
And you really need to pay
attention to the numbers
’cause we get like twelve thousand
dollars unaccounted for.
I think it’s probably Desi.
She’s been having a really hard time
using these simple computers,
it’s because she’s stupid.
I think she might be stealing.
She’s not stealing.
She’s our best employee.
She made nine grand last month.
Well, how much did I make?
You brought in twenty-two hundred.
That’s not bad.
Well, that’s not that good.
I mean, I’m not comparing you, but…
you’re not as good.
All right. See you.
I don’t think she’s wearing underwear.
What?
It’s all dark up there.
What…? Why are you looking?
Oh I didn’t mean to look, I just--
It was just like I said, ‘Hey- woah!’
There it- there it was.
Well maybe she’s wearing dark underwear.
Yeah. Maybe she has underwear that has
a picture of a vagina painted on it.
Stop looking.
Maybe some deep oranges and browns
and maybe dark greens?
That would really play up your features.
I’ll just take out my AmEx and
you pick what stuff you think is good.
Good job!
Where’s daddy?
I think he went to poop.
Pete!
Q 80. Suck on that bitch.
Hey!
What are you doing?
Uh, going to the bathroom.
We’re all downstairs waiting for you.
You’ve been up here
for a really long time now.
Oh, I’m almost done.
I’ll be down in a second.
Charlotte just did her first flip on the
trampoline, and she landed on her feet.
She was really proud of herself.
– Oh, that’s great!
– And you missed it.
She- she’ll do it again.
It’s just that this is the fourth
time you’ve gone to the bathroom today.
C’mon, give me a break.
Why is your instinct to escape?
It’s not my instinct to escape from you,
it is my instinct to come into the bathroom
when I need to go to the bathroom.
How come I don’t smell anything?
It’s because I shoved an Altoid up
my ass before I came in here, I mean--
Let me see then.
– What?
– Let me see!
No, I’m not gonna let you see.
You’re not gonna let me see
because you’re not taking a poop.
I’ve been flushing as I go!
You’re flushing as you go?!
Who takes a half hour
to go to the bathroom?
John Goodman.
Don’t press Enter! I’m not
sure I want to make that move!
Thank you.
Wow.
You know, when I started this label,
my dream was to work
with musicians and bands
whose music I just admired so much.
The person that I thought, “My god,
wouldn’t it be incredible to work with”
was Graham Parker.
Tonight we have him.
Solo.
Because we couldn’t afford
to fly in The Rumour.
Graham Parker.
It’s just not my kind of music.
Really. What is your kind of music?
I like Lady Gaga.
Oh, God, of course you do.
– What?
– Shallow dance music.
It’s not. It is fun, and it’s about
release and sex and power--
You know, you don’t have to like it.
It’s really not for you, that’s fine.
This- this is a job. This is not a hobby.
Can’t you love him just as a hobby?
And sign a fifteen year old
hot girl so we can eat?
Graham Parker and The Rumour
had two albums in the Rolling Stone
Top 500 Best Albums of All Time.
Two of ‘em.
If I can just sell ten thousand records
to his hardcore fan base, we’re golden.
The last of Graham
Parker’s fans just died.
– I do know. Hardly.
– .. into a depressive--
Charlotte. Sadie.
Sadie, what are you listening to?
Okay,
this is music that makes people happy.
And this is what people buy.
What?
Right, girls?
Come on, Sadie.
♪.. Like a dungeon dragon,
♪Rah Rah! Like a dungeon dragon,
♪Like a dungeon dragon!
♪Rah Rah! Like a dungeon dragon…
Why did you take it off?
Now, something that really rocks.
This is called good music.
From somebody’s heart.
This is bumming me out.
This isn’t fun.
Just listen to these words, okay?
Just listen to the words.
I don’t understand the words.
This is lyrics, this is poetry.
This is what-
This is what is gonna survive…
in a hundred years.
It just doesn’t make people happy.
It makes me happy.
I can dance to it.
You’re the only one
in the room who’s happy.
Sometimes, I wish
just one of you had a dick.
Well, we don’t want one.
Is there something that you can do
to be helping me right now?
Yeah, I’m ready to help.
Just tell me what to do.
Can you go get a lunch box or something?
For me or for them?
Charlotte! I’ve got a test!
I’m coming! I’m coming!
Charlotte, I’m gonna kill you!
– Hi Debbie.
– Hi, any day now, huh?
Not really. Three months, still.
– Hi.
Katie’s dying for a play date.
Let’s hook these two up.
– That would be great, okay.
– Great.
– Hey, I’ll call you.
– Okay. Great.
Hey. No.
– “No” what?
– No.
– What?
She’s sweet.
She’s evil.
Hello.
– Hi.
Listen, uhm…
Charlotte really needs
to get here on time
because she needs the
extra time to just settle in.
Oh… We are on time.
Being on time means being early.
Oh. Okay.
Well, it’s nice to see you in class.
We’d like to see more of you.
I come t--
Hi Debbie!
Grandma Molly.
– How are you?
– Hey.
I’m so happy about the science fair.
– Thank you for helping.
– It’s going very well I heard.
Yeah.
I love you, you look so beautiful.
Happy birthday! I just learned
it’s your fortieth.
Are you forty?
Yeah.
I remember when I was forty,
and then I blinked,
and there I was, going to be ninety.
My God, where did it go?
One day you’re gonna blink,
and you’re gonna be ninety.
And I won’t be around to see it.
And that makes me very sad.
I’m telling you, I’m warning you.
Don’t blink. Don’t blink!
And then you missed the mortgage payment,
and that’s the second mortgage.
You’ve got to tighten your belt.
You’ve got to go home, sit down,
look at your expenses,
come clean with Debbie.
Oh, God. I can’t tell Debbie.
You got to tell her, Pete.
I mean, she knows it’s bad,
but she has no idea just how bad.
You can sell the house,
it will really buy you some time.
No, no. Debbie’s not really
into selling the house.
As your business manager and
your friend, I can’t recommend that.
Hey, how funny would it be
if I bought your house?
Okay…
– Bye.
– Hang in there.
From the Retro label,
unfiltered, comes the first
Graham Parker and the Rumour
record in thirty years.
When we played together,
the magic was just ridiculous,
and I think what we got is just so great.
What are you doing?
I’m contextualizing him as one
of the great figures in rock history.
Look, you can’t show him in his prime
in ‘77 and then jump straight
to him as he is now.
It’s terrifying. You have to reverse it.
You’ve got to show him as he is now
very briefly,
and then show him in 1977.
You have to “Benjamin Button” it.
I don’t know what you’re talking about,
okay? All rock stars are older now.
Steven Tyler, David Bowie, Mick Jagger--
– Paul McCartney.
Okay, stop it. Everybody that you are
mentioning looks like an old woman now.
You’re just mentioning
a bunch of Jessica Tandys.
Keith Richards gets away with it.
But that’s because Keith Richards
looked seventy when he was forty,
and now that he’s seventy,
he looks sixty nine.
He’s regenerating.
I like it, and I think
Graham Parker is sexy.
Wow- would you fuck him?
– Yes!
– You…
You’d fuck him, and you won’t fuck me?
I mean, I kind of fucked you once,
like- if you could have finished,
you--
– Oh, I finished.
Okay, you know what now, enough of
who fucked who and who finished what.
I finished.
Look. It’s a retro label.
That’s our niche. That’s our market.
It costs money to break new bands,
I can’t- well I can’t do that.
Okay. And also you’re the guy
who turned down Arcade Fire.
Everybody turned down Arcade Fire.
It’s crazy, there’s so many of them!
We don’t have the money
to market a new band.
We just need to make
Graham seem relevant.
Who is he talking to?
Um, the Jewish Journal.
The Jewish Journal?
Apparently, old Jews are the only ones
who still buy hard copies of records.
Because they don’t like to download music.
Because they don’t know
what downloading means.
Why is this album
different from any other album?
It isn’t.
What- what is he wearing?
Um, it’s a hat with the Oreo logo on it.
Why?
I don’t think he’s being ironic,
I think he just really likes Oreos.
Look. The Paul Westerberg record did okay.
Frank Black did all right.
The Haircut 100, not so much.
We have to break this record.
Otherwise, we’re not here next year.
He’s coming. He’s coming.
Oreo man is coming.
Hey guys, how are ya?
– Good, man!
– .. to see you.
– Aren’t cookies the best?
– Yeah.
Jewish Journal guy loves the record.
Great!
Got a bit of a problem though.
Touch of gout.
Gout?
Yeah, my whole family,
they all had gout.
– Jesus.
– That’s very unfortunate.
My auntie Queenie, she had a foot
like the size of a small pig.
I’ve got a photo of it.
I’d love to see that
photo of that gout foot.
And a couple of bunions as well.
Fuck!
I’ve got to go to the podiatrist, and
I hope he can shoot me up with something.
Yeah, well, let’s uh-
let’s get you to the podiatrist.
– Bye, Graham.
– See you later, Graham.
Good luck with your gout.
Rock and Roll, baby.
The happiest period in people’s
lives is from age forty to sixty.
So this is it. We’re in it, right now.
– It’s true!
– Says who?
Says a lot of people,
most people say that.
Ηuh.
We have everything we need
right now to be completely happy.
We’re gonna blink and be ninety.
What?
So, let’s just choose to be happy.
Yeah. Yeah!
Your eyes are kind of glazing over.
No, I’m just, um- processing it all.
Some of these I wrote for you.
So, we have to exercise every day.
Spend more time alone together.
We have to go to the therapist every week.
It’s a little pricey.
No stressing over tiny things.
Yeah, that’s good.
You should do that. Mm-hmm.
We have to get more involved in school…
Have more patience with the kids,
and we need to work on our anger.
I- Yeah, I think it would be good
if you could take care of your anger.
No, I said both of us.
That’s what I said. Our anger.
Okay. And no more smoking…
Yeah, you’ve got to get-
you’ve got to cut that out.
I don’t want to make this about
a fight, I want it to just be positive.
Sorry.
Okay, and then no more
holding on to resentments.
We have to just let that go.
So, if- you’re saying that if
we’re arguing and I apologize,
you’ll let it go and not
throw it back in my face later?
Well, I don’t do that, but I will
continue not to do that.
And what did you write?
All of that. That’s plenty.
That’s a lot.
And you’re gonna eat better?
Oh, yeah yeah. I’ve been
doing a decent job, I mean-
but I don’t think there’s anything wrong
with having some fries every now and again.
And then I’ll smoke that day.
That’s not the same thing.
It is the same thing.
I like fries.
And the other thing is your
dad stuff, the not letting him…
you know, guilt trip you all the time,
because that puts a lot of
pressure on you, and stress and then
the whole family feels it and
he’s a grown man,
and he’s not our responsibility.
And you’re not giving him
money anymore, right?
No, no I haven’t been giving him money.
I haven’t done that for years, I told you.
Can you please put that down?
A lot of people are RSVP-ing
to your birthday party.
You sure you don’t want us to
just do a joint birthday party?
No.
– We always used to.
– No.
Did Jodi tell you
she thinks Desi’s stealing?
– Are you serious?
– Mm-hmm.
How much?
Twelve thousand dollars.
Oh, Dod. And Desi’s taking it?
Well, I don’t know.
That’s what Jodi said.
We really need the store to work.
It is.
Don’t put that kind of pressure on me.
No no, I- I…
That’s not what I mean, I’m just…
Are you nervous about money?
Are we okay?
– Yeah!
– Right.
Maybe we just suck it up so because
she’s clearly earning much more
than any other employee we have.
Oh, yeah. For sure.
We can’t fire her.
We’re barely breaking even with her.
That’s why we have to keep her.
Look at this, she’s making out
with somebody.
Is she screwing him?
That might be like a dry hump.
Look at the position of her skirt.
That’s too grainy to know for sure.
Oh my god, this is the middle of the day,
customers could be in there.
At least she’s getting some.
What did you say?
“At least she’s getting some”?
Yeah.
What are you talking about?
We had sex the other night, you have
to give me a little credit for that.
It’s not about credit.
It’s about- we just- we need
to have more passion.
Like this.
That’s not passion, that’s-
It looks like passionate to me.
What?
– What is she doing?
– Okay-
Oh my God. Oh my God!
Oh my God!
Don’t do that!
What am I doing?
Don’t fart in the bed!
I’m not, it’s the springs.
This is why we never have sex.
That’s disgusting. You’re gross.
– I don’t know what you’re talking about.
– You so--
God!
Sadie. Sadie, Sadie!
Sadie, Sadie!
– Charlotte,
I’m doing my homework.
Okay, watch this, watch it.
There’s a haunted cow back here,
and I’m pretty sure it does have milk!
Did you see that?
They took me away.
You’re no fun.
You never want to play.
Charlotte. How many times do I
to have tell you--
Sadie!
Sadie, Sadie!
Sadie…
is boring!
You’re so mean
since your body got weird.
Close the door.
You’re no fun.
If you can just move,
just a little bit more.
– Oh shit!
– It’s okay.
One of my boob is in there!
Pete, did I tell you that
my son’s going to Stanford?
– No, that’s great!
– Oh, great.
Great for us and great for him.
– Cough again.
– Let’s go.
Everything looks good.
Your face is close to my face.
Descending colon…
I’m about four feet in right now.
That’s what he said.
Are- are you a grinder?
Do you grind your teeth?
I grind all night.
I think we need to turn the gas down.
Turn it up!
No, we’re gonna turn it down.
Do you have to
breathe right on my neck?
Sorry.
What are you all doing for Christmas?
Uhm. I don’t know.
Do you have a tree and everything?
Mm-hmm.
– Ain’t that fun…
– Hi, I-
– .. Get in the spirit.
Sorry, I just have one quick question.
On your form you said
you were born in 1974,
but your paper, it said 1972,
so I just need to know which it is.
Oh. It’s 1974.
Oh it- uhm. Because on your last form,
you said that you were born in 1975.
Didn’t you tell me you were born in 1976?
No.
That’s funny.
So you want to go with 1974?
I’m not gonna “go” with 1974, it is 1974.
Okay.
Just remember to write 1974 every time.
It’s okay. It’s 1976.
I lie about my age, okay?
– Okay!
– Okay?
Okay? Okay?
– Okay!
– Okay.
You’re tightening up.
Oh my gosh.
I know how old you are.
By counting the rings!
Little gyno joke.
Oh my God. Please!
What are you doing?
Getting ready to go for my ride.
Do you want a blow job?
Yeah.
Why?
I really want a cigarette right now.
Well, happy to help.
Charlotte, where is my backpack?
Hello?
Mom’s busy!
Why are you locking the door?
Mom! What’s going on in there?
Mom, I can’t be late for school,
– I have a test!
– Mommy can’t talk right now!
This isn’t funny, Mom.
I need to go.
– Mom, let me in!
Please!
That’s not gonna help!
Put on your shoes.
We’ll meet you in the car.
Sadie hurt me!
I didn’t!
Hit her back!
She’s faking!
– I’m not. Please!
– Go downstairs!
– Daddy, let me in-
– Stop crying!
– Stop it!
– God damn it!
– Mum, get out!
– Please Sadie, shut up!
– Mum, you need to come out.
– Shut up!
– Stop it!
– Open the door!
– Go away!
– Open it!
– Please!
Forget it.
No. Don’t forget it. Don’t forget it.
Don’t, don’t!
Oh God…
Hey, Boychik.
Hey.
That’s the eleven o’clock from London.
Drop something valuable, you shit!
How are you?
Loud.
Every eight minutes, buddy.
You look pretty good.
Your hair is different.
Yeah, I’m growing it out.
Oh, I’d get it cut.
Daddy, you never play with me.
I do but right now look who
I’m talking to!
– Hi.
– It’s your brother!
Alright, say-
You don’t look like my brother.
I told you honey, that’s
’cause of the egg donor.
Remember?
I came from a test tube.
– How’s business?
– It’s not good.
Nobody wants curtains.
They think of it like a luxury.
It’s not a luxury.
You need shade, you need privacy.
Who wants to have
other people watch you fuck?
I- I know how you feel. You know,
my business is going through
some growing pains right now.
– Oh, don’t jump on Daddy,
– Daddy. - Daddy!
be careful, don’t jump,
don’t jump on Daddy!
Remember, Daddy has high blood what?
– High blood pressure.
– That’s right.
Can you go outside
without me for a little bit?
Don’t go near that little pool!
All right?
Do the Three Stooges routine
you were practicing.
I can’t tell them apart.
I swear to god. I need tattoos.
Look, uh… I wanted
to talk to you about…
scaling back a little bit.
You know, Deb and I are
thinking about selling the house.
I think that house is more than you need,
I think it was too big of
a purchase when you made it.
Yeah. In the meantime, I’m gonna
have to make some changes.
Gonna have to cut back.
I understand.
What do you mean?
– With you.
– Oh.
I’m sorry, what?
I can’t lend you any more money.
No, that’s a- that’s a bad idea.
That’s not the way to cut back.
I- I have three children, here.
What about Claire?
Why can’t she get a job?
Claire takes care of your brothers!
What do you want her to do?
If she goes to work, then
I’ve got to hire somebody.
Well you’ve got to figure something out
because I can’t do it. I can’t do it!
Okay, fine. Why don’t we kill them?
Come on, we’ll kill two of them.
I’ll keep the best one.
Really,
it will save us both a lot of trouble.
– Come on-
– Line up!
Line up for murder! Come on!
Who wants to be killed?
– I do!
– Okay,
we’re eliminating one already
we’re cheaper. You’re gone!
– Murder me!
– Okay! Boom, dead!
– Oh I’m dead!
– You’re dead, you’re dead!
All right, the kids are murdered.
That will save us some money.
Why would you have three kids, anyway?
I mean, you’re sixty years old.
You have no money-
Because Claire wanted a baby.
If we didn’t at least try,
she would have left me.
She was forty-five years old.
Nobody thought it would take.
The doctor when we were doing
in vitro, was winking at me
like, “Don’t worry, don’t worry.”
We were very unlucky.
And now we have these
three beautiful children…
Come on. I gotta tell you something.
What?
Your mother wanted you aborted.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
No no. It’s the truth.
You know, it was the seventies.
We were twenty-two years old.
That’s what everybody did. You did
some blow, had sex, had an abortion.
– Really?
– Yes.
We were on the way to the doctor’s office.
I said, “Let’s stop,
have a pizza, talk about it,
if you still want to do it
after lunch, it’s okay.”
The pizza saved your life.
But don’t give me money.
Because I’m not worth it.
So how much do I owe you then
for saving my life?
I don’t have a number.
You just keep giving like you’re giving.
Hey! Oh, Hi Pete!
– Hey!
Why aren’t you playing with kids?
We were playing with them all day.
Pete’s just uh…
talking to me about his fortieth birthday
party. Whatever I can do to help.
Okay. Did you feed them?
I’d fed half of one.
Let’s go. Okay, the family will feed them.
Who wants tuna with a side of jet fuel?
Hi, I’m looking for my dad.
I mean, an older man?
So how’s Sony treating Pete?
Oh, he’s not with Sony anymore.
He went out on his own.
Now he’s able to focus on the artists
that he’s really passionate about.
How’s Sadie doing?
Last time I on  saw her she was
throwing her Cheerios on the floor.
What a mess.
– Right.
She just got her period.
Well…
I guess she’s not a little baby anymore.
It would be nice to see
more of each other.
Well, we can certainly arrange for that.
I’d love to see the girls.
– That would be nice.
– Mm-hmm.
Do you have a day that was better-
like, a good day?
I would say the weekends,
but our weekends are hell.
– Soccer competitions, kids exams.
– Right, right.
I mean, we’re both so busy. I mean I have
young children, you have young children,
I… I don’t think we should judge
ourselves too harshly about that.
I know, I wasn’t.
I didn’t say anything.
No, I’m glad we’re here,
I think we should- this is-
this is a good start and that we can
spend more time together, it’d be nice.
It would be nice.
Do you want to see pictures of the kids?
Oh, yeah.
This is, uh…
This is Kell, my son, he’s-
He’s handsome. He’s thirteen?
Mm-hmm.
And that’s Alexandra, my daughter,
she’s a real perfectionist.
A lot- a lot like you.
That’s the whole gang at Cabo.
Now…
Excuse me dear,
I’ve got to use the restroom.
Be right back.
– Okay.
Daddy and I are making some changes,
so that we can be happier
and healthier,
and we’re starting with
this meal that I prepared.
I think it looks great.
Doesn’t it look good?
What is that, grilled cheeses?
No, baked- baked tofu.
Aw.
It’s actually really tasty.
And the lettuce is so fresh and
tasty that you forget how good
lettuce tastes on its own
without dressing.
No, dressing always gets in the way
of the natural taste of the lettuce.
And another thing we’ve
decided is to cut back on…
all of the electronics we use.
Basically, what we’re gonna do is get rid
of the wi-fi and only use the computer
– what?
– from 8 to 8:30 at night.
How are we going to go on the computer?
Well we’re gonna have
a hard line in the kitchen.
Yeah, we’ll supervise that.
You can’t do this.
You can’t take away the wi-fi!
No wi-fi! Ha-ha-ha!
You don’t spend enough time
with the family when you’re
constantly on your iPhone
and your computer, and
you know, you should-
you’re only here five more years.
So you won’t see me after five years?
No, but you won’t be living with us.
And you should get
to know your little sister.
You’ve got the perfect friend right here.
I don’t want to be friends with her now.
I’ll friends with her when she’s
twenty and a normal person.
I don’t want to hang out with her
when I’m in my twenties.
You’re on your computer too much as it is,
you need to get outside more.
Do some planning outside.
Yeah. You can build things out.
You can build a- a fort outside.
What?
Yeah, build a fort. Play with
your friends and they have-
Make a fort?! Outside?
And do what?
– Have a little-
– Do what in the fort?
When I was a kid we used to
build tree houses and play with sticks.
Nobody plays with sticks.
You and Charlotte can
have a lemonade stand.
Play Kick the Can.
Look for dead bodies.
It’s fun. That’s fun to do.
Get a tire and then take a stick
and run down the street with it.
Nobody does that crap. It’s 2012.
You don’t need technology.
No technology!
Charlotte, put that down.
I don’t need to be monitored
all the time on the computer.
I don’t do anything bad.
Nobody said you were bad.
I don’t do things I’m not supposed to.
I don’t illegally download music.
I don’t look at porn like Wendy.
She is up to no good. She’s not
allowed to come over here anymore.
What’s porn?
No, she said corn.
This isn’t turning out
the way I wanted it to.
I’m not hungry.
No computer.
Listen to your mom!
I need to use it for my homework.
She’s outplaying us.
I know. She’s tough.
This is the best birthday present.
It’s good to get away, you know? We haven’t
been to Laguna without the kids in years.
I know!
If we’re happy, they’re happy.
Yeah. I mean I can’t take it. With the
hormones, and the crying, and
– Jesus.
– “do my homework”…
Them’s little bitches!
Lil’ bitches!
Bugging us for shit all the time.
And they never appreciate anything.
No, God no. They’re selfish assholes.
Aw, I feel bad.
I love them.
– I know.
I miss them already.
Should we go home?
Nah.
Why do we fight?
I don’t know, it makes no sense at all.
It makes no sense.
When we get in a fight…
look in my eyes, and let’s remember
this moment right now,
and know that never have to fight.
But you’re such a dick sometimes.
I know, I am a dick sometimes.
People think I’m so nice,
but I’m such a dick.
Thank you for admitting that.
And you get so mad at me.
– Oh my God.
– I feel like you wanna kill me.
I do wanna kill you.
How would you do it?
I don’t know… poison you.
I’d poison your cupcakes that
you pretend not to eat everyday.
And just put like enough in
to slowly weaken you.
I love it.
I would enjoy our last
few months together.
Me too.
’Cause you’d be so weak and like sweet,
and I could take care of you and-
but while killing you.
See? You know what I love about us?
You can still surprise me.
I figured for sure you’d knock me out
with one fell swoop, poison me.
But you would extend it
over a series of months.
Have you ever thought about killing me?
Oh yeah.
– Really?
– Sure.
– How would you do it?
– Wood chipper.
– A wood chipper?
– Yeah.
– A wood chipper!
– Wow.
– I know.
Did you see Fargo?
Yeah.
That’s a bad plan, the cupcakes
is a way better plan.
It is. You’re right.
You know what? I won’t murder you.
I love you.
I love you too…
You know what I brought?
– What?
A medical marijuana cookie.
Ben gave it to me last Christmas.
– What?
– Yeah. I brought it.
– You did?
– Chocolate chip koo-kie.
Should we do it?
Let’s eat the cookie, and then we’ll order
a bunch of cheeseburgers and a bunch of-
Let’s order the entire room service menu.
Just get all of it.
You deserve it. You really do.
Wouldn’t you rather have me
around for less years
and I’m incredibly happy
than longer and miserable?
Yes, and I just realized that right now.
Go get the cookie!
– I’ll get the cookie!
– Go get the cookie!
Should we watch porn
when we eat the cookie?
Yeah. Should we get a block of porn?
I don’t think we need
twenty-four hours of porn.
Yeah, but you know, like two porns cost
just about as much as a 24-hour block.
I think that’s too much porn.
We don’t have to watch it all,
but for the value it makes sense.
How much are we supposed to eat?
I don’t know. I think like
six or seven cookies, right?
Plus, it’s old. It probably
has lost some of its-
– Potency?
– Mm-hmm.
No.
We should have sex. More.
I mean, girls have it so easy.
You just show up with your sexual
organs and you’re good to go.
All the pressure is on the guy.
It’s true.
And I look at guys, like… I look at
a guy like Prince, and you know that guy
fucks.
– Yeah.
I know I don’t fuck like Prince.
Prince can fuck.
I fuck more like David Schwimmer.
You do.
I fuck- you know, like Ross from Friends.
That’s good.
How does he do it?
The floating spoon.
Check it out. My dick and balls.
Oh my God! I’m gonna eat my own dick!
I ate my dick!
Kelly, I think this room has rodents.
I just saw it!
Have you seen my starfish?
Where did I put my starfish?
Hmm my God.
I’m gonna deep throat this éclair.
I wanna make out with you so bad.
– Τhаt wаѕ nісе.
Mom! Charlotte’s crying.
She’s got an ear infection again.
I didn’t know what to do.
We’re home.
Are you okay?
What’s the matter?
I wanna rip my ear off,
it hurts so much.
I told you the pediatrician
didn’t know what he was talking about.
Oh, come on. You can’t
blame it on our doctor.
Ear infections are common in little kids.
Not in kids over six years old.
We’re going to the Eastern doctor.
If she’s in this much pain,
we should call a real doctor.
Are you kidding right now?
Alright, okay. Yeah.
What we should do is easy and simple.
No more dairy, no more
wheat, no more sugar.
Sugar, wheat and dairy. Okay.
What the fuck is left?
Sorry.
Isn’t everything sugar, wheat and dairy?
She can have
vegetables and f-r-ruits.
So- oh, she can eat fr-r-ruits.
Fr-r-ruits, yeah.
Uhm, any kind of fr-r-ruits?
Mangos, pineapple…
It isn’t like there are safe fr-rruits
and then unsafe fr-r-ruits.
No, no.
What about F-r-r-rench f-r-r-ries?
Can we do something like that?
Are you okay? Would
you like to come on the table?
I’m okay. I’m-
– Why don’t you go on the table?
– I don’t wanna-
Why don’t you go on the table?
Now it looks like you
need to get on the table.
I don’t wanna get on the table.
Pete!
What are you doing?
I need you to look at something.
In my butt.
Why?
I think I’ve got something in there,
and I’m not limber enough to…
to see. I need you to look at it.
See, I might have like an anal fissure
or a hemorrhoid or a-
or a worm or something.
What are you doing with your phone?
Trying to take pictures of it, so I
can compare it to something on Google.
Can we just keep like a
small shred of mystery
in our relationship, please?
Look, I saw you have two babies, okay?
Seriously, I need you
to get all up in that.
I do not want to investigate your anus.
It’s payback time.
It’s a hemorrhoid.
Thank you.
Now erase that from your memory.
Where did she get those clothes?
That’s very expensive clothes.
Think. Where do you think?
I don’t want this to sound harsh, but…
everything that comes out
of her mouth is a lie.
Everything that comes into it is a dick.
Everything that goes in is dicks?
A dick.
Don’t say that.
I’m sorry, I’m just being
protective of the store.
I’m gonna go talk to her.
Hey Desi.
– Hi.
Is that your new Acura out front?
Uh, yeah.
So nice. Do you love it?
Well, I mean, it’s not a fucking Porsche,
but it’ll do for now.
Hey Desi, would you mind wearing some
of the clothes that we have in the store?
Yes. Yeah, I’m sorry.
– Would that be okay?
– Yeah.
– Perfect.
– Good.
You know, I actually
made this one myself.
– Did you?
– Yeah.
The tiger, I did it on a piece
of paper separately,
and then I actually
transferred it to the t-shirt.
Wow.
So you- you stenciled on the tiger?
I drew it on a piece of paper, and then
I transferred the drawing to the t-shirt.
You have an amazing body.
– Really?
– Yes.
Are those real?
– My boobs?
– Yeah.
Yeah…
Do you want to touch them?
– Really?
– Touch ‘em!
Okay.
Wow.
Huh!
Jesus.
I mean they really are amazing.
That’s firm, for real.
They’re like a memory mattress.
It’s- Wow. Like Tempurpedic, you know?
They look amazing.
My kids just sucked the meat
right out of mine.
– No…
– Yeah.
There’s some meat in there.
My boobs are just gone. Since
I had kids, my boobs are just gone.
They didn’t even say goodbye.
You know, they just left.
By the time I’m forty, these are
gonna go National Geographic on me.
I feel bad about myself right now.
I think this is a
really good offer on the house.
We expected more. I mean,
I know it’s a bad market but that’s still
way what under we were looking for.
I know, but based on the market,
it’s like you’re gaining money.
Because it’s so much more
than what you deserve.
But these people are from Iran,
and they don’t really know that
they’re offering too much.
Is there any chance
that Debbie will go for it?
I doubt it. I mean, I don’t know, I-
There’s a lot of inventory out there.
I mean, what’s her problem?
She… she has unrealistic expectations.
Hey! Did you miss me Travis?
It’s Jack!
Hey, Jack.
My daddy doesn’t know my name.
– Ok, come on, let’s go.
– Can I go show
my crystals before they leave?
Yeah, really quick.
It’s alright with me!
Hang up with your dad!
Okay!
Go play with your tiny uncles.
– Let’s play murder.
– Yeah. Let’s go.
So what are you doing, spring cleaning?
I’m getting rid of everything
in the house that has gluten or sugar.
Why? What’s wrong with gluten?
Gluten’s really bad for you.
I don’t think so. It’s wheat.
Don’t you watch Dr. Oz?
As in the Wizard of?
Hey, Mom. We were wondering if
we could use the computer to iChat.
Remember the rules. 8 to 8:30?
Yeah, but I have a friend over.
Hi Wendy.
Yeah. I know. Uh…
Why don’t you guys go play?
You could go build a fort!
Yeah, remember the Alamo?
Have you ever built a fort, Wendy?
Like on Facebook?
I will take this if you’re
gonna throw it away,
because at our house, we’re wheat eaters.
But don’t you want to live long
enough to see your kids grow up?
That’s up to God, honey.
Yeah but that’s really
not good for the kids.
Eh! The kids eat grass. This is fine.
Wendy’s mom lets her go on
whenever she wants.
Yeah. My mom’s pretty cool about
it as long as I finish my homework.
Yeah…
Well, I guess I’m not the cool one. But…
the rules are just in our different house.
Well, I get better grades than Wendy.
She does. She’s so smart.
Let me just grab the candy worms.
Your rules are ridiculous.
Don’t sass me.
I’m only sassing you
because you’re throwing out
all the food in our house
and I’m freaking starving.
You’re being stupid.
Wendy, can you go stand
in the other room, please?
– Yeah.
– Mom.
Give me your iPhone now.
The nougat things are good.
I have all my contacts in there.
Okay, if you don’t give me
your phone right now,
then I’m gonna have to take away
your phone and your computer.
– Jesus Christ, I need
– That’s it.
– my computer to do homework.
No phone, no computer.
This is B.S. This is a bunch of F-ing S.
You’re acting like a B.
Kids! Time to go!
You go to your room right now,
you are not allowed to use iPhone,
iPad, iPod Touch, iTunes,
Netflix, Pandora, or Spotify!
She’s a little pip.
Just like her mommy.
So uh, I might have a job tomorrow.
at least I’m gonna go
try to give an estimate.,
Do you mind taking
the kids for a couple hours?
Uhm…
Okay.
This is nice.
You and I don’t spend
enough time together, do we?
We spend enough time together.
We do?
It’s quality time.
Then we do.
I’ll go with what you think.
What else did they say?
Alright, some kid named Joseph--
I know Joseph.
– You do?
– Mm-hmm.
He’s making a “Hot or Not” list.
What?
So, Sadie said, “That’s so lame
and immature that you’re doing that.”
And then Joseph says, “Yo, girl,
We’re just having some
fun so don’t be a bitch, yo.”
That is not nice.
So then Sadie said,
“Don’t call me a bitch.”
And Joseph said, “I didn’t call you
a bitch, I said don’t act like a bitch.
And by the way you’re
in the ‘Not Hot’ column”.
Who made him the judge of hot?
Do you realize what that
could do to her self-esteem?
What a little fuckhead.
I’ll kill him.
So then Sadie said, “You’re
in the jackass column.
I’ve got to go. I’m bored of you.”
That is cool.
That’s taking the high road.
For some reason, there’s an
emoticon of a panda doing push-ups.
I wonder what that means.
I don’t think it means anything,
I think it’s just adorable.
Aww.
She’s a good girl. She was polite,
and she stood up for herself.
That’s pretty cool.
– Shit!
– What?
I thought she was coming in.
Oh my God, that scared me to death.
If she caught us, she would kill us.
She would, she would kill us.
I’ve got to make a call.
We sold how many?
Six hundred and twelve album downloads.
Wait a minute. There
are no zeros after that?
No, there are zeros, but all of
them are before six hundred and twelve.
There are none after.
How is that even possible?
Well, out of three hundred million
Americans,
six hundred and twelve people
chose to download the album.
You could personally call everyone
who bought this record.
We’re fucked! We’re fucked!
Here’s the deal. I want you to meet me
tomorrow morning at eight o’clock.
I want a list of at least thirty ideas
of what we can do to change this.
We have to change this.
I started a record label
because I couldn’t get a job,
so I have no other options.
What financial problems?
Well, I mean, for one thing
you were right,
I mean, you are missing about ten
thousand dollars…
from the store. And then, Pete’s record,
you know, not selling…
– Pete’s record not selling,
– .. well.
I thought we weren’t
supposed to hear for three weeks?
– We heard.
– You heard?
And they’re bad.
You know, it’s that, and it’s the money
that he’s been lending to his father,
That’s creating a strain.
How- how much have we…
How much have we…
– lent him?
– Eighty thousand.
Did you say “eight
thousand” or “eighty thousand”?
Eighty thousand,
over the past couple of years.
And then you missed the mortgage payment,
– and-
– On the house?
And- Oh, and uh, uh you missed
the rental… on the office.
Does Pete know that?
Oh, yeah. We’re on the
phone all the time.
Look, I know you’re going
through a hard time,
and I want you guys to know that
we’re here for you.
Okay? Anything you guys need,
that’s why we’re here.
We’re here for times like this.
What are you gonna do?
There’s not much I can do.
What are you doing?
Uh, I’m drawing the album
cover for Van Halen’s Diver Down.
If you spent a little bit more time
focusing on Graham Parker
instead of drawing album covers,
I wouldn’t be in this predicament.
I’m focused on Graham Parker.
You’re supposed to help me with him!
You’re supposed to call the
companies, you’re supposed to-
you’re supposed to get
people to the show!
I’ve done everything I can, Pete.
You had me pushing around a corpse!
It was like being in fucking
Weekend at Graham’s.
What should we do?
I’m out of ideas.
You fly in The Rumour.
I can’t sell a reunion concert
without the band, it’s ridiculous.
With what? I can’t afford it.
You put this on yourself.
You wanted the responsibility,
take it on the fucking chin,
and stop acting like a bitch.
What did you call me?
Chin.
Pete!
Wait! Wait, Pete!
Hey, I have an apartment,
I have health insurance,
I have car payments,
I have responsibilities.
You have responsibili- don’t talk
to me about responsibilities.
I have a life, I have- I have a family.
I can’t afford to sit in my apartment
getting high, jerking off,
and then goin’ to the Tommy’s Chili
Burgers at three in the morning.
That’s not even the order that happens in!
I have everything to lose here.
Everything.
Yes! Because you spent thousands
of dollars on shit we don’t need.
You really need to spend thirty thousand
dollars on a fucking neon sign, dude?
Which is inside! It’s not even outside.
We know where we work!
If you want to sign a band, you
have to look like you’re the real deal.
Princess Labia, how much is it
to fucking fly The Rumour in?
– It’s twelve thousand.
– Twelve thousand dollars!
Alright, you know what? Fine.
Fly in The Rumour. Put it on my AmEx.
No, you said it was impossible.
I don’t think I said impossible.
Yeah.
I usually don’t say impossible.
I like to-
I like to leave some wiggle room.
You said that…
my fibroid was like
a giant boulder like the one from the
– Indiana Jones.
– Indiana Jones
movies blocking up my uterus.
– uterus.
And I need to stop
using that reference of Indiana Jones.
I think that’s not appropriate when
talking about the reproductive system.
It’s okay.
Anyway, somehow the
Eastern medicine has worked,
and the fibroid has dissipated.
– That’s great!
– Yes!
Wow!
Yes. Your fibroid shrunk, and somehow…
it allowed you to get pregnant.
What?
You’re gonna have your third baby.
Congratulations.
No.
Yes.
Would you like some water?
That’s good news.
Another baby… at forty.
Debbie?
I am thrilled.
And Pete is gonna be so happy.
So, you’re okay?
What a relief.
I can finally relax now, you know?
I spent like…
It’s okay.
I’m so happy, you know,
I really am. Cause… I mean…
It’s good.
Great. Great.
– Hey!
Why are you in a bathrobe?
It’s the middle of the afternoon.
I took a late shower.
Why are you busting my balls?
Look, I’m sorry about the record.
You’re going through financial shit.
This is- this is what I live with.
This is a horrible time
in human history. What is that?
Something that might help
both of our situations.
This… is a drawing… by John Lennon.
I got it ten years ago
for five thousand dollars.
I don’t know how much it’s worth now.
Could be five, could be twenty.
I don’t want this.
I don’t even like it.
I’m not gonna hang it up.
It’s not for you to hang up.
It’s for you to sell.
That way I can give it to you
and you can make some money,
and Debbie won’t know
that I’m giving you anything.
Well, you’re not giving me money.
You’re giving me a project.
I don’t know how to sell this.
I’m not an art dealer.
Sell it online.
You know, do some research,
make some calls.
Or is that too hard to do
with your high blood pressure?
All right. Don’t get snippy.
Just because you write a great song
doesn’t mean you can draw.
It’s incredible, Le-
John Lennon drew it.
I think it’s a Ringo.
Don’t beat me up if I get
three hundred dollars for it.
Don’t take less than
sixty-five hundred for that.
It’s very valuable.
It’s important to me.
I want you to sell it so I can help you.
Okay.
Alright. I’ll see you at my party.
What should I bring?
You want wine or something?
No.
Don’t buy wine with my money
and give it to me at my party.
– That’s mean.
– I love you.
– Alright.
– Bye.
How do I call eBay?
Minnie called me of bitch,
what am I supposed to say?
But I think maybe
that might mean he likes me,
I don’t know, can you believe he-
It’s really awkward.
I think he might like you.
She’s so cute. She’s so tall.
I know. How did that happen?
Do you ever wish
we had a bigger family?
No, never for a second.
Never.
– Never. Never.
– Never?
I love what we have.
One? A breeze. Two? Brutal.
Three? Put a bullet in my head.
You know, I think about that gray-haired
pregnant lady from school
and I just feel bad for her.
And I feel bad for the kid.
Can you imagine?
All the other little kids, “Where’s your
mommy?”
“Oh, she’s the one sitting in
that scooter eating a soft cracker.”
Kids don’t want to have old parents.
You know, it would also be nice for us
to spend some time apart.
Kind of rediscover who
we are individually.
It would be so great to not
see you for like a chunk of time
so that I could really just miss you.
Remember when we used to miss each other?
Hey!
Hey, you!
Yo, sup?
Hey, I’m Sadie’s mom.
Sadie…?
Sadie, the one you chat
with on the internet?
Nah, man. That ain’t me.
Well, it was you, I saw your picture.
Did you make a “Hot” list,
and not on put Sadie the “Hot” list?
She was not on my list, no.
You know what I’m gonna do?
I’m gonna make my own “Hot” list.
And you know what?
You’re on the “Not Hot” list.
How does that feel?
It doesn’t bother me. I’m
comfortable with the way I am.
Maybe you shouldn’t be so comfortable
with yourself. You know why?
You look like a miniature Tom Petty.
How’s that feel? Huh?
You think that haircut’s cool? It’s not.
It looks like you put your
Justin Bieber wig on backwards.
You still comfortable with yourself?
Why are you wearing a tank top? Huh?
So you can show off your bald pits,
you little hairless wonder?
Cool tank top, man. Huh?
So next time you think about
writing something nasty
on my daughter’s Facebook page,
just remember me.
Remember me.
I will come down here,
and I will fuck you up.
Okay, I’m sorry.
Wait a minute.
Hey, hey, hey!
Well, you don’t- are you crying?
Just let me go.
Oh my… But you…
I’m sorry.
– It’s okay.
I’m de- I’m sorry.
I’m not in my right head.
I understand. My mom is going
through menopause, too. It’s a hard time.
What did you say?
You’re going through menopause?
I’m not going through menopause!
I’m not gonna go through
menopause for like twenty years.
I’m pregnant you little bitch.
God damn it!
I’m going out with Desi to find out
if she’s stealing from us.
I’ve got the Graham Parker concert.
Who’s gonna watch the kids?
I don’t know. Figure it out.
I kinda just wanted to talk.
I thought maybe we could go to
a coffee house or something?
Oh, you want coffee?
This place has coffee,
they have all kinds of drinks.
Uhm… better some place quiet, maybe?
This place can be quiet. The seats
there on the back are pretty quiet.
What sport do you guys play?
Uh, we play hockey.
Oh, I like hockey.
Who do you guys play for?
We play for the Philadelphia Flyers.
So you guys are all from Philadelphia?
No. No.
Actually none of us are.
Do you guys still
have all of your teeth?
Well, I’ve got all my teeth, except…
These ones.
You wanna try them on?
Yeah, I’ll do it.
Do I look sexy?
Yeah!
They definitely look way better
on her than they do on you.
– Thank you.
– Very cute.
So, should we go to the quiet area?
No no no, no, no…
Where are you going?
We kind of have to have a
little business meeting tonight.
Business meeting? Business girls, you have
to celebrate. We won tonight. Let’s go.
I want to party with these winners,
come on Deb!
– Yeah!
Just come and stay, just dance with us.
– Okay.
– Yeah!
Okay, let’s fucking dance!
Don’t be shy, feel free to come down,
and fill up these empty seats.
Thank you so much for coming,
this is so exciting!
For the first time in over thirty years,
Graham Parker and The Rumour.
Where are his fans?
I mean, where are they?
It’s hard to watch a band…
when you know all of them
remember D-Day.
Well, what’s press turnout like?
Are you serious?
Nobody came!
Nobody.
Nobody is here?
Oh, the guy from Green Day is here.
Yeah, Billie Joe, I emailed him.
He’s a fan.
You’ve got to get a photo
of the two of them.
No, he says he doesn’t want to do
any press, he’s just watching the show.
Oh, how punk rock of him.
“I don’t like- I don’t like photographs.”
Grow up, Green Day!
Shut the fuck up, Tom Selleck.
You don’t have like- yeah, I wouldn’t
call them classically  good…
dance moves, but you
left it all out there.
It’s- you’re a blast to dance with.
Thank you.
We’re having a little- a little
shindig at the hotel after this,
you should come by and, uh…
and hang out, at the hotel.
You want me to come to the hotel?
Yеѕ. Ι wаnt yоu tо соmе…
by the hotel with me.
Well, what would we do there?
Maybe we can find somewhere quiet, and
have fun, and kind of see where it goes.
Do it like… adults do sometimes, and…
Like… sex?
Uh, I mean…
if you want, if that’s
on the docket, but…
I’m not trying to force that.
So you would do sex with me?
Do sex? What are you, Borat?
Are you hitting on me?
Yes, yes, I’m hitting on you.
You’re hot and cool and nice and
you have beautiful eyes.
I’m sorry.
I’m married, I have two
kids, and I’m pregnant.
That is what we call
the “hat trick.” Wow.
I’m sorry I didn’t tell you, I’m just…
really enjoying you being so nice to me.
No, I- I hope this doesn’t
come off as super cheesy,
but uh, I think you’re a…
a very rare find.
Thank you.
And I would totally do sex with you.
That was spectacular guys,
really well done, amazing.
– Thank you.
– Good, good.
Hey Graham!
Pete! How are you, man?
Well uh… the first numbers came in.
Yeah, right yeah. Uh…
Happy? How’s it looking?
About half of your last record.
Ah, so you were expecting it to sell.
They never sell anymore.
They used to sell.
But now they don’t. I’m not
a sexy sixteen-year-old girl.
But I wanted to sell it.
It’s such a good record.
I feel like I let you down.
Oh no, I’m gonna be fine, man.
My overheads are so low.
I just got a song in Glee.
Guy in the wheelchair is going
to sing it to the Asian girl, I believe.
I don’t know, I’ve never seen
the show, but that’s what I’m told.
Secret is, make sure
you have a small nut.
That’s the key to life.
Graham, I don’t have
small nuts, all right?
I have big nuts.
And I need to provide for them.
Graham!
Hey, hey, what’s up?
– Billie! Hey, buddy!
– How you doing, man?
– Great fucking show, man!
– I don’t get to see you!
– Fuck, yeah!
– Thank you.
Like inspired. I wanna write
a fucking song right now.
Inspired, huh? That inspires me.
Let’s go get a drink.
Let’s get a drink.
Alright.
You coming?
No no, I’m… I’m fine, you guys go.
Congratulations on Glee.
Yes, thank you. Right.
See you Pete.
– Alright.
– Alright, see you.
So long guys.
You got a song on Glee?
Yeah.
That’s killer, that’s so much money, it’s-
It’s good that’s for all of us.
Why did you put that
guy’s teeth in your mouth?
That’s so gross.
He was dirty.
No, he was wearing a tie.
– That’s true.
– He wasn’t dirty.
When I kissed him, I felt his
little tiny teeth nubs with my tongue.
– You did?
– Yeah.
It was like kissing a baby.
French kissing a baby.
Can I ask you something stupid?
Do you know why we’re
missing money at the store?
Are you guys missing money?
Yeah. Like twelve thousand dollars.
Do you think I took it?
No. I mean, I- well, no, I did,
and I don’t now. But I don’t-
It’s not me.
Then, why do you live in such a nice
apartment and have such a fancy car?
Yes, you’re right. Uhm… Look.
I… am… an escort.
I get paid to go out on dates.
You…
But only three to five times a year.
Ten times max.
But it’s not technically “prostitution”
because I don’t have to sleep with them.
Ah well, that’s good.
But I always do. That’s why I
only do it four to eight times a year,
fifteen times max.
Huh.
One year I did it twenty.
Well…
As long as you think it’s safe.
It’s safe.
I only do it ten to thirty times a year.
So, who do you think is stealing money?
It’s fucking Jodi.
No.
Yeah. She’s a pilled-out whore.
Huh.
Since you told me, I’m-
I want to tell you something.
You’re pregnant.
How do you know?
Wow.
Maybe you should tell Pete.
You didn’t tell Pete yet?
I haven’t told Pete.
Why?
I don’t know.
I just want him to want me.
I don’t want him to want me because I’m pregnant.
Go home and fucking suck his dick
and tell him then and he will love it.
– You think?
– He’ll be so excited.
Or even better yet,
better yet-
you should tell him
while you’re sucking his dick.
Look. “I’m pregnant.”
What are you doing?
I’m returning some emails.
What time do you have to go to work?
Like ten minutes ago.
You wanna be late?
No, I can’t be late.
Not today.
Do you see me standing
here in front of you?
Half-naked?
Yeah.
And does that…
make you feel anything, or…?
Come on. Are you
trying to start a fight?
No, I’m not trying
to start a fight with you.
I’m trying to fuck you!
Oh God, you know what? Just…
Today of all days is the day
you need to cut me a break.
All right?
– Whatever.
Oh God.
What…?
I didn’t realize it was intentional!
I didn’t say anything because
I didn’t want you to be embarrassed.
I thought I was being gallant.
All right, fine, I’m an asshole.
God.
You know what your problem is?
You’re never ever in the moment,
you’re never ever present.
You’re never in your body.
That’s not true.
I- I- I am in the moment.
You know how I know? I want to
get the fuck out of the moment.
I swear. It’s just- I can’t-
I can’t win with you.
I just can’t do it.
You can’t just walk away.
Oh, God.
Hey!
How’s the record company going, Pete?
What? Not great.
I’m still waiting for
numbers to come in.
What have you heard?
A couple numbers have trickled in.
It’s lower than we expected.
Then why are you giving Larry money?
What?
I know everything.
I talked to the accountant.
Right, you know what? I don’t
want to get into some nasty fight.
So can we please talk to each other the way
the therapist told us to talk to each other?
Fine. Fine!
It makes me feel sad
when you are dishonest.
I understand it makes you feel bad
when I am dishonest with you.
It hurts my feelings when
you treat me with contempt
and corner me and try
and trick me into lying.
Okay.
It makes me sad when it’s
so easy to trick you into lying
because you’re such a lying shitbag.
That’s not- you can’t do that.
You can’t do that,
the therapist said you’re
not allowed to judge me.
That’s not a judgment.
That’s just a fact.
Fair enough.
Sometimes I withhold truth,
that is true.
But it’s only because I’m scared to death
of your crazy-assed
illogical overreactions.
Well…
It hurts me inside and triggers me
when you’re such a dishonest shit
that you’re lending your father
money without telling me,
while your record company
is going bankrupt
and we’re on the verge
of losing our fucking house!
What else are you lying about?
I’ve taken Viagra for two years.
I ate six muffins downstairs a while ago
and my cholesterol level is 305.
My heart could explode at any second.
These might be my very last words.
Oh! And I gave Charlotte antibiotics
when you weren’t looking.
That’s why her ear got better.
So, go fuck your witch doctor.
Are we even doing what we’re doing?
This is not making me happy.
You’re not happy. You don’t like me.
I can feel that. I’m not blind.
Jesus. We’re like business associates.
We’re like brother and sister.
There’s no passion there.
We’re not like brother and sister.
You know what we’re like?
We’re like Simon and Garfunkel, and
somehow you turned me into Garfunkel.
I don’t even know what that means!
Art Garfunkel!
What’s wrong with Art Garfunkel?
He has a beautiful voice.
He’s got an amazing voice.
He could put a harmony to anything,
but what I’m saying is that
you turned me into him!
What the hell are you talking about?
What-
– Simon controls him!
That’s because Simon
writes the fucking songs!
He’s the better one.
You know what? I see
the way you look at our kids.
You have so much love and
compassion for them.
You never look at me like that. Ever.
Would we even still be together if
I didn’t get pregnant fourteen y-?
You know what? I’m not gonna
go down that road. That-
Would we?
Okay.
You know what? I don’t even
wanna have a party here.
You need to cancel it.
No, I’m not. I already paid for
the catering, I put down deposits,
and I sure as fuck I’m not
gonna call everybody back
in two days when you change your mind.
Your girlfriend is not ugly.
Actually Larry, she’s not my girlfriend,
she’s just a-
– It’s cool, buddy.
You don’t have to explain
your girlfriend to me.
But she’s not-
Can you please stop licking your fingers?
Do you know how many
germs are on your hands?
And you’re putting them into your mouth.
That’s gross. Stop.
Stop it!
I’m gonna kill you!
Hey! Sadie! Enough!
Alright, she isn’t hurting anyone.
You wanna say something,
just keep your mouth shut.
You have never been nice to her and
now she’s getting aggressive with you.
I told you this would happen.
I’m sick of everybody fighting.
What do you think you’re going
to be like when you grow up?
I don’t know. Hum…
I don’t know.
Do you think you want kids?
Mm-hmm. Just one.
Just one? Why?
Because if I have two then the
other will fight with the other one.
Does it make you sad when you fight?
I don’t want anyone to fight.
I love you.
Why isn’t anybody talking?
Why is it so quiet?
It’s the sounds of silence.
♪I don’t think that I can
really survive…
♪I’m praying for the end of time,
it’s all that I can do
♪Praying for the end of time,
so I can end my time with you.
♪And it was long ago and it was far away,
– You stop Dad.
♪it was so much better than it is today.
How many of those are you gonna eat?
As many as I want.
I’m gonna tell Mom on you.
Try it. See what you get for Christmas.
Nothing.
Snitches wind up in ditches.
Remember that.
Hey, Peter.
– Hi!
– Hi.
Alright. It’s here.
Have a good one.
Peter?
Peter!
Hi!
Catherine.
I’m Joseph’s mother.
Oh, right. No, I know.
Hi, Catherine.
Our kids have gone to school
together for eight years.
I… Sorry.
Hello, Joseph.
I hear our kids have
been chatting online.
Yeah? I heard that your wife
has been screaming at my son,
and I don’t appreciate it.
Excuse me?
She screamed at my son.
Right? She threatened you?
She cursed at him.
Hey, he’s thirteen years
old for god’s sake.
What the hell is the matter with her?
Hey, you better check her meds
and get them right.
Okay, you know,
why don’t- why don’t you…
back the fuck off, because that’s my
lovely, sweet wife you’re talking about.
– Oh, I need to back off?
– Yeah, you need to back off,
’cause your kid is an animal.
He’s a fucking animal.
Why don’t you put him on a leash?
– Turn around. Turn around, turn around!
Turn around!
He insults my daughter again,
I’m gonna hit him with my fucking car.
Got it? In fact, if you insult my wife
again, you know what I’m gonna do?
I’m gonna show up at your
house when you’re sleeping,
and I’ll take your iPad
or your iPod or your iMac,
and I’ll shove them up your fucking iCunt.
I’ve got nothing to lose.
Your kid is the problem.
My kid is a fucking angel.
I don’t have time for this shit.
So I’m keeping it together.
But if I wasn’t at school right now…
You touched my…
touched me?
– I didn’t touch you.
– You touched my upper breast!
I didn’t. I didn’t. I got right
below your shoulder.
You got right here. You actually-
He hit my nipple!
You what?
You’re insane!
Why would you do that?
Did you just touch my mom’s nipple?
He just touched my nipple!
Why would you do that to me?
I poked you on the shoulder.
I have very high nipples.
I touched your shirt.
What do you think is under my shirt?
– I just touched-
– My breasts are under my shirt.
Your shoulder, your shoulder.
He just touched my breast.
Well, that’s a funny place
to put a shoulder. On my boob!
Hello! There are children around.
This isn’t over. This is not over.
You’re gonna be sorry.
Let’s go. Let’s go, let’s go, let’s go!
And why the fuck would you believe Desi?
You just admitted it.
Did I?
You stole twelve thousand
dollars from me Jodi,
and I need you to pay me back.
Can you at least give me a referral?
You babysat my kids
while you were on Oxycontin.
Oxycodon.
Well, Oxycodon.
Oxyconten.
Oxyconten?
Oxykitten.
What’s Oxykitten?
Meow.
Jodi. You put me in danger.
Me and my family.
It was a cry for help!
Help!
Help.
Why don’t you help me?
Just help.
Just Help.
Why don’t you help me?
Are you high right now?
Help me!
Is that about me?
Is that the cops?
Is this a set-up?
I need to go.
Okay, see you later.
Fuck you, Debbie.
Fuck. You.
Joseph was very upset
when I spoke to him about this,
so I thought it was important that we…
join together and work this through.
Absolutely.
Uh, we’re gonna work through it, but
Debbie, uh told my son that
he looked like Tom Petty,
in a negative way--
Who’s Tom Petty?
You know who Tom Petty is.
And she said that if she had to
come back, that she was going
to “F-up his pussy ass.”
Which is what she said.
Are you serious? I didn’t.
I would never. To a child?
Your son has been defiling my daughter’s
Facebook page now for months.
These people are liars.
He said that my son was an animal,
and that if I didn’t keep him on a leash
that he would hit him with his car.
Did you say that?
That’s- that’s ridiculous.
Who talks like that?
– You do.
He didn’t say that.
– Alright, you know, no, what I said,
– He said it to me!
was that we need to keep
an extra eye on our kids
because with all the
technological advances,
they need to learn
to use them responsibly.
No, No. What he- what he said to me,
was- he called me an “iCunt.”
– A what?
– Language, Catherine, language!
I’m quoting him!
How am I gonna relay what these
two nutballs said to me unless I say it.
Can you please not talk
like that, Catherine?
Music Man is rehearsing next door.
Sorry, fucking Music Man.
Maybe if I looked more like
this fake bullshit couple,
looks like they’re in a bank commercial.
That’s what you look like.
Like you’re a bullshit
bank commercial couple.
None of this talk is productive.
I would like to rear up
and jackknife my legs
and kick you both in the
fucking jaw with my foot bone.
You’re just really scaring me.
This is what happens
when you corner a rat.
You corner me, I will
fucking chew through you.
I’ll chew through you.
Catherine, you’re better than this.
Fuck you, Jill. You’re
a horrible fucking woman.
This is why everybody hates you, Jill.
This kinda shit.
Ineffective, fucking bullshit hair.
And I’m glad your husband died.
Because you’re a fucking asshole.
He probably killed himself.
Okay, Catherine, I think we
know what’s happening now.
Now you know what we’re dealing with.
I’m not gonna eat that chicken.
Why not?
Because I feel like
I’m gonna be a vegetarian.
Can you become a vegetarian tomorrow?
Huh-huh.
You guys have been reading my texts?
No, we haven’t.
Yes, we have.
We’re supposed to keep an eye on you.
How did you find out?
Joseph told me that you
flipped out on him and his mom,
and that you guys are nuts, and I agree.
Alright. Don’t be disrespectful.
You are the ones who are disrespectful.
Reading my texts is like reading my diary.
And you were really sweet on your iChat.
We were really proud of you.
Yeah, we were gonna give you
your computer and phone back.
Fuck you!
Okay, there’s the first
official “Fuck you.”
Okay, that is not how we talk
to each other in this house.
You guys talk to each other
like that all the time!
And to Joseph and his mom.
You made Joseph cry.
Joseph has a crush on you.
You like a boy who cries.
Shut up, Charlotte.
You guys so desperately want me
to be perfect and to make no mistakes.
Well, you two are fucking insane.
Okay.
All you do is fight. Or you
don’t fight, which is even worse
’cause it looks like you
hate each other for weeks.
You obsess over every little thing I do,
and you don’t trust in me or believe in
me, well I’m fucking sick of it!
Yeah, I said “fuck.”
Fuck fuck fuck.
Ground me forever I don’t care.
I don’t care about anything.
I hate everything, everyone’s going crazy,
I don’t care if I have no friends.
Are you still upset about Lost?
Of course I’m upset about Lost!
You guys took away my shit before
I could watch the last two episodes!
Now I don’t know what the fuck happens!
She’s becoming just like us.
I hope I never get my period
if this is what happens.
Where did you find these?
I stole them.
Thank you.
No big deal.
Our kids are crazy.
And it’s our fault.
But do you think there’s anything
we can do to turn it around, or…?
Sadie’s thirteen.
She might be a lost cause.
I mean, where did she learn that kind
of language? We don’t talk like that.
I have no fucking idea…
Do you think Sadie is
this crazy because of us?
Or is it hormones and Lost.
J. J. Abrams.
He’s ruining our daughter.
Yeah.
That fucking geek.
I feel bad for us!
I feel bad for us.
All of a sudden we’re like
a magnet for negativity.
Why do people keep attacking us?
What did we do?
We’re just doing our best.
Should we talk about our fight?
I think we’re under enough pressure.
Let’s just let it go this time.
Yeah.
We can give each other a break.
Alright, great. Thank you.
And I’m sorry about my dad.
You’re right. This is…
I’m sorry that he’s just an endless mooch.
The truth is, this isn’t about us.
It’s about our parents.
We’re not even mad at each other.
We’re mad at them.
Exactly!
Exactly.
Let’s just take away our
parents’ power by loving them.
Can we do that?
Yes.
Thank God.
I kind of feel better already, do you?
Do you?
– I- I do.
– I love you.
– I love you too.
It’s not us, it’s them.
Totally.
What are you doing?
We have to get ready for the party.
I just watched the last episode of Lost.
Okay.
You know what? We don’t
have time for this right now.
We have a lot of people coming over--
– They’re all dead.
What?
Jack… Kate…
Sawyer…
– I don’t care
– about the show
– Jin…
– right now. Okay?
– Sun…
– I need you to just get in the shower,
– Walt…
Get dressed. Let’s just put it on hold!
Juliet…
All those people.
Don’t think about Lost today.
Tomorrow: Lost. All day.
I can’t wait to hear about it.
Jack? No way. Really?
Right now, shower.
I don’t make fun of
your stupid Mad Men!
First of all, I don’t get
worked up over Mad Men.
That’s ’cause Mad Men sucks!
What Don Draper has gone through
beats whatever Jack is running
from on some fucking island.
A bunch of people smoking
in an office, it’s stupid.
Wait wait, I’m not-
you’re getting me off topic.
Just please get dressed.
Hello!
Hi!
I am so glad you’re here.
– Yeah.
I need a buffer in case it gets weird.
Oh! Well, I’m ready to buff.
– Rіght. Grаb thеѕе nарkіnѕ.
– Lеt’ѕ buff.
So uh, so that’s the
girl who works, uh,
that’s the girl who works for you.
– Yeah, that’s her.
– .. works for Debbie.
Seems nice.
My wife would never let me
have a hot employee like that.
– Yeah?
– No.
Every woman that works for us…
looks like they’ve been in
some kind of horrible accident.
You’re comfortable with
that around your husband?
Aw. Pete wouldn’t know
what to do with that.
You think our wives
are looking at us right now?
– Oh, definitely.
– Yeah.
They look like pedophiles.
Thank you.
.. And the girls are so excited.
They’re all outside.
– Hi. Happy birthday.
– Hi. Oh thank you very much.
– Hey. How are you, man?
– How are you?
Good to see you.
Happy birthday Pete,
how wonderful to see you!
– Grandma Molly!
– Oh you’re wonderful.
And look at my gorgeous, gorgeous…
Gorgeous!
No. I get that, I’m just
wondering why I should-
Hey, Pete! Pete! Jason’s here.
Peter. Hi.
– Hey, how’s it going, Jason?
– Great, you look well.
– Thank you.
– Yeah.
How do you like what
I’ve been doing to your girl?
How do you like Debbie’s after body?
– It’s nice.
– Come on, show ‘em.
Look at this.
It’s beautiful.
Look at that afterass.
Now it starts here…
but it used to start here…
and I brought it up.
You’re welcome.
Sir, are- are you a trainer?
– Yes.
– Huh.
Well. But not just physical.
Spiritual.
I’m sort of a guide.
– Mm-hmm.
You guys should talk.
I think you’ll-
– Du- uh…
– you’ll… get along.
Come here, honey,
I gotta tell you something.
Yeah.
Who’s that in the pool?
Mine.
Hello.
Hello, Debbie.
How are you?
Good
Remember my husband, Pete?
Oh right, yes! I- I didn’t
recognize you with the long hair.
Oh yeah, I- no, I’ve been growing it.
Happy birthday.
Oh! Thank you so much!
Very old scotch.
Oh, wow. You know,
I- I hope it hasn’t expired.
No, scotch doesn’t expire.
It improves with age.
Yeah. No, I know.
Uh, thank you so much.
Nice.
Come on in!
– Sure.
– Sorry.
So uh, what do you do in Chino, Oliver?
I am a surgeon.
– Wow. What kind?
– That’s great.
Mainly of the spine.
My specialty is scoliosis surgery.
Now my mom used to talk
to me like I had a scoliosis
’cause I’m, you know, a little hunchy,
but that’s a different thing.
No, you definitely don’t look right.
– Hey!
– Sorry we’re late!
I was in the lab cloning myself.
We’re gonna have another
seven more tomorrow.
We cut their hair different so
we can finally tell who they are!
You like the new haircut, Travis?
I’m Jack, damn it!
Oh, of course.
Larry, this is my father.
Really?
How are you?
– Oliver.
– Oliver? Oh!
“Can I have some more?”
“Please, Oliver, I need a little morsel.”
I love that movie.
You must get that all the time.
Not really.
My nose itches right here.
I’m sorry, excuse me. I’m
Claire, and I’m Larry’s wife.
Very nice to see you, but
I’m gonna go get the kids.
We won’t see her now for the whole day.
I’d help honey, but you know, I’ve got
the blood pressure, and I don’t want to.
Can I get you a drink Dad?
– Yeah.
– Want something?
A white wine.
– White wine?
– Yeah.
– Oh, heavy stuff.
So, who knew that Debbie had a dad!
Where have you been for fifteen years?
Never seen you at Hanukkah, Christmas, or
Ramadan, nothing. How do you get out
of all that stuff? Do you have a wife?
Yeah, my wife’s at home.
Oh, why- why didn’t she come?
A construction.
They’re sanding our deck.
You let the woman sand the deck?
She supervises it, yes.
Okay.
Hey, guys.
Hey!
Look how big the kids are!
Sadie!
Hi, Larry.
Hi, Sadie.
Mom. Who- who’s Oliver?
What do you mean?
Is he your dad?
Is he my Da-
He is my biological father.
What does that mean?
Hm, it means that my mum, grandma-
he and my mom had a baby and that was me!
Oh, so you’re our grandpa.
Uh, well, why don’t you ask your mother?
Yeah.
I guess so then, that would make
him your grandfather, then yes.
Do you want him to be?
Yes. Then we get another
grandpa. Come on!
Wha…?
– Another Grandpa?!
– Trampoline time.
Yeah that was deeply uncomfortable.
At least that pretty girl was
here to divert our attention.
Oh. My gosh, hi. Me or mine,
I did not see you there.
– Hi.
– I saw you there.
Did you guys come together?
Are you… a couple?
– No, we didn’t come together.
– No. No. Absolutely not.
I just- I’m sorry, I thought it was a-
the mustache is a little…
Hmm. That’s fair.
I just assumed.
This is a straight man mustache.
What is the different between a gay man’s
mustache and a… straight man’s mustache?
The smell.
Ah. Excuse me.
So, spinal surgery, it just seems to me
to be at the top of the surgery chain.
Well, we’re not cardio, we’re not neuro…
but I like to think we’re
an important part of the spectrum.
Do you operate every single day?
Most days.
Multiple times a day?
Three, four times.
So what’s the price range?
Like if I wanted a--
– I- I’d rather not say.
– Oh I’m ju--
It’s so big you’re embarrassed to say.
I wouldn’t say embarrassed.
Are there hunchbacks today?
– Of course.
– I’ve never seen one.
Well, that’s because
there are spinal surgeons.
That’s ’cause of you.
Each time I don’t see a hunchback,
you’re getting that much richer.
You like The Beatles, don’t you?
Who doesn’t like The Beatles?
– Nobody.
– No. Nobody.
So funny. He’s so funny.
What is your sun sign?
Libra.
– Oh, boy.
– That’s not good.
No, sir.
That’s not good.
Not for me, that’s not good.
Sexually we are completely incompatible.
– Absolutely.
– That’s not true.
– Right?
– That’s such a shame. Yeah.
No, it’s- I mean, as bad as it gets.
– You don’t know.
– What is yours?
I’m a Cancer.
– Really?
– Is that good?
Wow.
– What does that mean?
– That’s kind of strange. Well,
Taurus and Cancers are sort
of soul mates of the Zodiac.
We’re like perfectly compatible,
and I balance what you lack,
and you make up for what I lack.
And a quiet Cancer almost
always has a huge penis.
You’re making me embarra-
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh! I wanted to make a toast.
Thank you guys so much for coming,
thank you so much. Um…
Pete’s turning forty, and…
– Weird.
– and,
we’re ready to start this new
phase of our lives with open hearts.
Ready to just choose joy and…
and forgive everybody.
So, thank you all for coming.
– Cheers.
– Wait!
Forgive who?
Oh I think she just means
in a general sense. You know, just…
Put the past behind us, and--
Live without resentments.
But specifically who are you forgiving?
I just- I just like to know the
details before I make a toast.
Right. You, and…
and my dad and others.
I see…
Well I know you- I know you
have some issues with me,
but I’m curious, what’s he in for?
Before today, nobody even knew he existed.
Uh well, my parents divorced
when I was really young and
we don’t spend that much time
together and I’d like to work on that.
Just like we’d like to work on…
how you have financial issues.
She’s talking about all the lending.
And the borrowing--
I know what- I know what she meant.
You are a beautiful woman,
but you are not totally maxed out.
I would say honestly, you’re a six.
– Oh.
– Ooh.
A six and- six and a half.
I could make you an eleven.
Really?
When I found Deb, she was a seven.
And now she’s a twelve.
I wanna be a- I wanna be a twelve.
You can’t be lazy.
I don’t wanna be lazy.
Look at me. You cannot be lazy.
I won’t be lazy.
Do you know how she got her body?
Bodies By Jason.
– Wow.
– Say it.
Bodies By Jason.
Say it again.
And now just say Jason.
Jason.
– Again?
– Jason.
That sounds right, doesn’t it?
Yeah.
What the fuck is happening right now?
When was the last time you two
saw each other, I’m curious?
Actually, we had lunch together last week.
Uh-huh. And before that?
It’s been about seven years.
Seven years? That’s a joke, right?
That’s like two Olympics.
But I’m the bad guy.
Right, Dad.
What Debbie doesn’t understand
is it’s not bad to help out a parent.
And it’s certainly not bad
for a parent to help out a child.
I’m sure Oliver would agree.
– Well, uh--
– Are you really doing this right now?
Am I doing what?
I didn’t start the toast.
Are you really about to hit up
my dad for money?
What? He does four operations a day.
It’s perfect. It helps everybody,
and it relieves his guilt
from all the abandonment issues.
You can’t buy forgiveness, right Pete?
I don’t think anyone’s looking for
handouts, I mean now we’d… pay him back.
If you two are in a bind, I-
I’d be more than happy to- to help.
No.
It’s not good to borrow money from family
members because it causes resentment.
Remember?
Right- yeah yeah,
yeah, yeah.
What do- what do you want me to do?
Okay, admit that my life is shit?
Is that what you want me
to say? You happy?
Aren’t I allowed a little joy with
these children I never wanted to have?
You have never once
stopped asking us for money.
Family helps family.
But it’s true. Family helps family.
Look, I don’t expect you
to fully understand.
You- your dad left.
You’re broken inside.
It’s not your fault you can’t feel love.
There’s something that you can’t--
This is coming out wrong.
You know what? I would rather have my dad
– Mm-hmm.
– than your dad,
because he doesn’t drive me crazy.
You know the best quality my father has?
Is he asks for nothing.
I don’t know what the fuck
he’s thinking right now.
Look at that.
Nothing. Nothing.
I don’t even know him. And I turned out
perfectly fine without his input. Okay?
I just figured out what your problem is.
You hate Jews!
Which is so odd because
your children are Jewish.
Don’t play the Jew card, Larry.
I’m not playing any Jew card.
Seriously, it’s used up.
You can’t use up a Jew card.
That’s the whole point of a Jew card.
That’s right. You can’t
use it up, it goes forever.
Uh, you- you know what? I- I have to go.
Yeah. Great. What a big surprise.
Bye Oliver! See you later!
See you in another seven years.
Make sure to say goodbye to
the grandkids, who you met today.
You know, nothing I do is right
because of you? Nothing.
No matter how hard I try, I’m just
the asshole here, but you know what?
You know what I realized?
It’s you. You’re the asshole.
Good luck working that out.
Happy birthday and go fuck yourself.
Hey! See you when
the Cubs win the Pennant.
I’m gonna light the candles.
Just get it going, okay?
– Maybe we should try the toast again.
– You know, can you be quiet?
You just threw me under the bus.
– No. I don’t understa--
You threw me under the-
You threw me under the bus!
You know we agreed to
let go and forgive,
but then you started ripping
into my dad like a crazy person.
I’m not ripping into your dad!
I’m just saying to him
what you say to me.
Don’t be such a ball buster.
I am not a ball buster.
You make me one! I am a fun girl!
I am funloving! I am a good time Sally!
I dance hip-hop! I cannot believe
I have wasted my whole life
busting the balls of people
who have no balls.
I am the only one here who has any balls!
♪Happy birthday to you
♪Happy birthday dear Pete
Mom?
Mom! What are you doing?
What?
You’re smoking?
In- in the front yard?
No! No. They’re Barb’s.
Mom!
Since when have you been a smoker?
I’m not a smoker.
I thought you said smokers die.
I’m not smoking.
I wasn’t smoking.
I saw you!
No, I wasn’t.
Mom, you’re smoking?
Deb, you can’t smoke, you’re pregnant.
You’ve been doing so well.
You’re pregnant?
No F-ing way.
I don’t want another sister!
I don’t want her as a sister.
I’m sorry. I’m so sorry.
It just slipped out.
Are you really pregn-
Since when’re you pregnant?
Since when do you care?
You didn’t want another baby!
You have no idea what I want.
I want an Asian baby.
We’re not gonna have an Asian baby!
Yes, we are!
They’re not Asian.
– Sadie!
– We’ll buy one.
Shut up, Charlotte.
You shut up!
Shut up, Sadie!
Shut up, Charlotte!
– Shut up!
– Okay, Sadie. Shut up!
Shut up, Charlotte!
– Shut up!
– Okay, stop saying shut up!
You’re pregnant?
Since when are you pregnant?
When did you find out?
Will you stop eating cupcakes, please!
Stop eating cupcakes!
Stop eating cupcakes!!
Hey! We just heard!
You’re having a baby!
See, it can happen to anybody.
That is so wonderful.
Let me get the-
oh, it’s fantastic.
Congratulations.
– Oh, it’s wonderful.
So happy for you.
Get the other kid.
– I thought you have?
– I never have.
This is too adult for you.
Let’s go outside.
Congratulations.
Well, I guess we’re stuck together
then forever, then, right?
Weren’t we always?
You don’t even want a baby!
Of course I do. I never said that.
Look, I ju- I didn’t want
one if I could choose.
I should put that on a Hallmark card.
That’s beautiful.
Debbie…
Uh, good luck with the pregnancy,
Debbie. But please…
take care of yourself. It’s a much
riskier pregnancy after forty.
I’m not forty.
Of course you are. You
were born on December 5th, 1972.
I’m not forty! Ho- How do you know?
I was there! I’m the one who
took your mother to the hospital.
Well that’s not what she said.
Yeah, your mom was in labor for
only twenty minutes.
You cou- so you couldn’t wait
to meet me, can you imagine that?
I don’t even know you.
You can’t just come into
my house and reminisce.
Look, maybe we were just not meant
to be in each other’s lives.
I’m not sure this was such a great idea.
Wait a minute.
Hey, wait a minute.
You did leave. And you didn’t come back.
My first life was ruined.
I did my best with my second.
So I ruined your life?
I was eight.
People do better when I stay out of
their lives! That’s what my son tells me.
You think my life is so perfect?
I’ve got a- a thirteen-year old who’s a
pot head, I’ve got a wife who’s- who’s-
who’s keeping Zoloft alive!
You never said that before.
You don’t think I wanna talk to you
about this? To share it with you?
It’s just not our way! We don’t talk to
each other, we don’t know each other.
And I thought that’s
the way you wanted it.
How- how- how do I get out of this?
How do I get you all to just
help me down off the cross?
You sound just like Sadie.
Who’s Sadie?
No. Your daughter. Your younger?
The big one.
Your older. I know- I know that!
A wonderful girl.
Hey, guys. Some of us need to leave.
Would this be a good moment to sneak out?
Where’s Dad going?
Best birthday ever!
Oh shit!
Bike lane, asshole!
Fuck you, you Twilight
pimply-ass motherfuckers!
Your dad’s still here.
I know. It’s kind of weird.
Where the hell is Pete?
Uhm…
Is it okay if Joseph
hangs out here for a while?
Mm-hmm.
Hi, Joseph.
Hi.
Do you want a piece of cake?
Oh! Yeah sure.
Thank you. Thanks.
All right, then.
They are so cute.
So cute…
He looks exactly like Tom Petty.
Go around!
Watch it! Watch it!!
Hey, Pete. Great party!
Yeah.
The best!
And then you shake it.
And then a restaurant comes up.
D- Dad? Excuse me. I’m gonna
go look for Pete right now.
Would you mind staying
with girls for just a little bit?
Well, if you want me to.
If you don’t mind.
You don’t have to.
Sure.
Can I let Sadie show me
the last episode of Lost?
She asked me if I’d seen it, I haven’t.
Yeah, that would be nice.
Thank you.
– Thank you.
She said we could watch it.
Come on!
I’m gonna let you watch Lost.
Come on.
Is it scary?
I’ll cover your eyes if it gets too scary.
Are you mad at me?
Did I say something?
Shh. Larry, please.
Are you fucking kidding me?
You opened your door on me.
I didn’t open my fucking door
on you. I opened my door!
Ah! Fuck, I was right there!
You’re supposed to look
before you open your door,
I was in the fucking bike path.
That’s a blind spot. There’s no fucking
bike path. This is a residential section.
Get your head out of your ass.
Pay attention!
Open your god damn eyes.
What are you doing, sleepwalking?
You’re supposed to look
to see if a biker is coming through.
You’re supposed to look!
It’s not my job to look out for you.
You look out for yourself!
I don’t look out for you. I don’t see you.
I don’t know where the fuck
you are and what you’re doing!
No one is ever looking out for me!
I need your name and number.
Why?
’Cause you’re gonna pay for my door.
Fuck you!
Why don’t you pay for my bike,
and my face, you fucking prick!
Don’t disrespect me.
Are you sure that’s him?
I don’t think that’s him!
I’m gonna write down
your license plate.
“Range Rover of Sunland.”
What are you doing?
– Ow.
I guess the party didn’t
turn out like you planned.
It wasn’t a good party.
– Hi.
I’ll bring you in as soon as
his x-rays are finished.
– Okay.
Is he okay?
Yeah, he has a broken rib and he’s been
crying a little bit, but he’ll be fine.
You know Pete was never a real fighter.
But that’s why he married you. That’s why
he loves you. ’Cause you’re the fighter.
And you need that. One person
in a relationship has got to punch.
Do you mean that in a good way?
Oh, it’s a… it’s a high compliment.
Thanks.
Listen, I know what you’re worried about.
You think he’s gonna turn into me, but…
I don’t think it’s gonna happen.
He’s smarter and
probably a little cuter.
A little less Jewy.
Although after fifty, that’s
all gonna change.
Be prepared to wake up
one day with a a rabbi.
But the good news is, you know…
he’ll love you forever.
That’s in our DNA.
We stick around.
He worries about you, you know.
It puts a lot of pressure on him.
I know. I just- I don’t have
anyone else to talk to about it.
Why don’t you talk to Claire?
Oh, if I open up to her, she’ll leave me.
– No, she won’t.
– Hmm.
Larry, she loves you.
Ι knоw, but thеrе’ѕ а сеrtаіn
роіnt аt whісh yоu јuѕt саn’t ѕtаy.
I guess it’s hard to forgive somebody
if they don’t formally apologize to you.
Are you apologizing?
I’m very close.
Yes, I’m- I’m- I’m sorry.
I’m glad everybody’s okay.
Oh. Thank you.
Alright. I’m off.
Okay.
This is awkward.
What?
I need forty dollars for a cab.
That’s funny.
No, I’m not kidding.
You drove me. I- I wasn’t prepared.
I only have a hundred.
It’s okay.
I’ll bring you the change.
All right, give him a kiss for me.
I- I- I don’t get it.
See, it’s not sad, it’s happy because they
helped each other achieve their destiny.
Oh.
Great. I’m gonna have
some freaky ass nightmares.
Hi.
I really liked our lives so much better
before we tried to change everything.
I’m sorry.
No. I’m sorry.
I don’t wanna keep anything from you.
I love you. You’re my wife.
I just didn’t want to let you down.
Are you mad that I’m pregnant?
No. I’m not mad. I’m thrilled.
You don’t feel trapped?
Sometimes I feel like I trapped you.
I don’t feel trapped.
– Really?
– No.
You should, because I’ve trapped you.
You can’t go anywhere.
I’m gonna get you pregnant every
ten years for the rest of your life.
You can never leave me. Ever.
I never feel trapped by you.
I’m so happy to be with you.
And I love you so much. You’re my
favorite person in the whole world.
God damn it, why am I crying like this?
Something is wrong with me.
You’re pregnant.
Oh, yeah.
Shit.
I was just outside telling
your dad that I liked him.
What if he thinks I like him now?
No, he won’t think that.
I don’t want him to think
I like him that much.
No, it’ll never happen.
Can you believe it?
This is the craziest thing ever.
What are we gonna do with a third baby?
I have no idea.
How are we gonna afford it?
We’ll sell the house.
We don’t have to.
– We kind of do.
We’ll make new memories in a new house.
I love you.
Is there anything you
wanna do for your birthday?
It’s been the worst birthday ever.
There is one thing, but
I don’t think you’ll like it.
What?
I wouldn’t mind going to see some music.
Would you want to do that?
Yeah.
– Really?
– Yeah.
I don’t believe you,
but you’re sweet for saying that.
How do we break you out of here?
I can just leave on my own volition.
It’s not a mental institution.
– Can you?
– Yeah.
It’s not like One Flew
Over the Cuckoo’s Nest.
Please don’t put a pillow over my face.
Let’s get out of here, McMurphy.
You got it, Chief.
Will you carry me?
You’ve been carrying me up all this time.
I like this song.
Really?
Why?
Why don’t you sign him?
Ryan Adams? No, he’s…
He wouldn’t sign with me.
Why not? You’re the best.
He is in between labels.
Let’s go try and talk
to him after the show.
Caption and sync: jcdr
Thank you.
v1.0 - 17.01.2013