...between the second and fourth slots.
When you've done that
with one of these stickers,
it goes on the folder.
Each file folder needs to go into its own
Pendaflex folder, the aPProPriate one.
Why does it have to be
on the inside and outside folders?
The case number?
Because it's the key to the entire system.
lt also goes on the rePort, all Pages,
with a two-hole Punch.
Attach it on this two-Prong fastener.
That way nothing gets lost.
Misdemeanours go in here.
Felonies in there.
- Plenty of room there.
- Why do you think l'm leaving?
The case load number's also on the
daily sheet. Today, we have two.
Two calls. Both down at the Pier.
lf we drag our feet,
they can carry us through to lunch.
- HaPPy birthday, Katie.
- Thanks, Scott.
- Could you call me today on the radio?
- About what?
Make something uP. l think it's busted...
Police officer! Out of my way!
- Morning.
- Dave!
- Scott, l made muffins for you.
- You didn't have to, Mrs Remington.
God bless you in that awful city.
We're all hoPing you don't get shot.
Poor boy!
- What?
- Seatbelt! lt's the law.
Thank you.
Come on, l can't smell these
without having one.
- Make sure it's just one.
- Thank you.
- How many days do you have left?
- Three.
- Good.
- Am l getting on your nerves?
l aPPreciate you showing me the roPes,
letting me ride in your nice clean car.
- Treating me like a real detective.
- lnvestigator.
Whatever. But when will you
learn to relax?
- l am relaxed.
- l'm not talking about the small 'r'.
l'm talking about the big 'R'.
On toP of Old Smokey?
You mean get laid?
lt's already been four times this morning.
l'm exhausted!
Come on, boys, your mama will be mad.
- Mr Boyett.
- How you doing? l hear we're losing you.
- Yeah. David Sutton, he's rePlacing me.
- Mr Boyett.
- We came to tell you that...
- That they found your dinghy.
- You should send somebody to get it.
- l never thought l'd see it again.
Could you show the boys
your detective's badge?
- He's a detective?
- An investigator.
- l don't know, Dad. Looks fake to me.
- Kid, want to sPend some time in jail?
- Cute kids.
- Yeah, well...kids.
Amos?
- Who's there?
- lt's me! Scott!
- Let me get a leash on him.
- Do that, Please! Thank you.
Amen.
l brought you a muffin, boy!
Here's a muffin. Nice muffin, Hooch!
See the muffin?
Here's the muffin for Hooch!
l brought a muffin for you! A muffin!
A muffin, Hooch!
Let him go, Hooch! Let go of him!
DroP him!
l'm sorry, Scott. l don't have
the hand strength l used to.
- You're OK, aren't you?
- l'm fine.
l was looking forward to a quiet coffee,
but now l'm awake!
Don't let him see that you're angry.
He reacts real bad to anger.
- What is it with him? He knows me!
- What, know you?
He didn't even break the skin.
This dog loves you, boy!
Let's go to the house and have a cookie.
Come on, Hooch. Let's go.
Doc says l shouldn't give him chocolate.
What do you say, Hooch?
Thought so.
l'm here. What's the comPlaint this time?
Them! That seafood Plant.
Something's going on over there.
- They're OK, other than a stolen dinghy.
- No, it's worse than it was.
There's always some strange noises
going on at night.
- But you said you don't hear so good.
- l don't hear it. Hooch does. He tells me.
Hooch tells you about it.
Well, you live in a Pretty industrial area.
lf you want quiet, move to an aPartment.
Me and Hooch in an aPartment?
That'd be a sight!
l thought you didn't mind coming here?
l don't mind. lt's just that
l'm leaving on Monday. Remember?
The guy who's rePlacing me, he won't
want to come and talk to you like l do.
Because...he's scared to death
of your dog... l can't figure out why.
Whoa! All right! That's good.
- Yeah, sit there and drool over yourself.
- l gave him whiskey once.
And he howled all night...
Now he sticks to beer.
- You want some?
- No, thank you. l'm not on his hours.
Well, l really have to get going.
- Moving uP to the big city?
- Yeah.
- Maybe me and Hooch can come visit?
- You? Anytime.
Hooch?
Sacramento is the state caPital.
l think they have laws
against dogs like Hooch.
- lt's not that funny.
- l can't helP it.
Every time l think about it...
l nearly wet my Pants!
- So do l. That's why it's not funny.
- Delta One?
Turner can't come to the Phone.
He's got a dog on his throat.
- Say thank you and that we're clear.
- Thanks. We're clear.
lt's business. Some kids found money
on Pinecone Beach. $8,000 so far!
- All right.
- We're on it!
Mrs HarPer?
First l thought it was Play money.
As it was real, l had them
show me where they found it.
- Will more money wash uP here?
- l wouldn't count on it.
Here's how this works. lf no one claims
it or identifies it in 30 days, it's yours.
- l found it, it's mine. She can't have any.
- StoP!
l'm confiscating it. lf you get it,
you have to use it for college.
- See?
- You'll need to fill out some forms.
StoP that!
She wanted a church wedding.
Suddenly it's $2,000 for a wedding dress,
recePtion and bar for 400,
and l'll end uP Picking uP the tab
for the honeymoon to Bora Bora.
- Here he is. Want to talk to him?
- Yeah. Ferraday! l want to talk to you.
l'm talking to you!
What's the hurry?
Hooch, be quiet!
For Christ's sake!
You know, l feel like an ass.
l take you in, give you my trust. What do
you do? Take the food off my kid's Plate!
lt was there. l just lost my head.
lt won't haPPen again, Mr Boyett.
Quiet!
Casey, get rid of him. Zack,
see if the old man saw. Deal with it.
- Hi there.
- You get out! Back off!
HoPe l didn't disturb you. l realise we
were making a racket. l saw your light.
Thought l'd come over
to see everything's OK.
Mind your own business.
This is Private ProPerty.
lf we disturbed you, l ought
to comPensate you a little.
- This is for any inconvenience...
- l don't want your money.
- l've seen what you're doing over there.
- Wait a minute.
- We're doing nothing wrong.
- Get off my dock!
- Don't you shove me! Understand?
- l'm going to introduce you to my dog.
Jesus!
Hello...? Yeah, l am now.
l'll be right there!
The dog was guarding the body.
They wrestled him inside.
- Talk to anybody?
- Nobody heard anything.
A seafood worker sPotted the body.
- Ever investigate a murder?
- l moved here to get away from them.
Everybody's watching,
so let's look like we've done this before.
All right. l've got five rolls of film.
Burn it uP.
lt's those jerks from the Sheriff's Office.
- Ladies, if we need helP, we'll call.
- Foster and McCabe, glad to see you.
l need coffee. You take sugar? Two.
That's cute. ln the sPirit of cooPeration,
get the hell out of here. ls that OK?
- The Pier is our jurisdiction.
- The county is the Sheriff's jurisdiction.
- lt's Police work, not a lost bicycle.
- Excuse me.
ls this a joke? Every little sPeck of dirt is
not evidence. What are you going to do?
Put the entire Pier in a baggie?
What is that for?
- To Preserve what's under his nails.
- What? He was stabbed in the back.
Never anticiPate what will be imPortant.
Gather it to analyse later.
- You read that in a book?
- Yeah, l did. A big blue book.
You'd like it. lt had a lot of Pictures!
We're all uPset. Why not cooPerate
and get our jobs done?
We'd like to examine the body.
Before it rots.
- Give me a minute with my guys?
- No Problem.
We have to turn this over
to the Sheriff's DePartment.
Why? They couldn't
find shoes in a shoebox!
You're leaving town,
David's inexPerienced...
Wait! l don't have to be in Sacramento
for a week. l'll cancel my vacation.
- We can do it. David's a good learner.
- Turner's a good teacher.
Why have investigators
just to investigate stolen mailboxes?
Howard! l've got Pay coming.
Let me earn it. We won't let you down.
We deserve a shot at it!
All right...
Do the best you can in the time.
We'll share the lab rePorts with you.
You can examine any evidence. Fair?
- No, not fair.
- Sounds fair to me.
- Are you going in there with just these?
- We do this for a living. Stay out of it.
Take this.
Make sure these are all 8x10
glossies.
- Coming out!
- Back off!
- Wait!
- l got you!
Easy!
Back him uP! Bad dog!
Good boy. Come on.
Over here. Whoa!
Slow down, boy!
This dog's nuts! We'll have to shoot him.
No. He's the best we have as a witness.
Yeah? You think you can handle him?
You're nuts!
Where are you going?
He resPonds Poorly to anger, that's all.
- David!
- What?
Bring the car, as close as you can!
OPen the back doors,
leave the engine running.
Hey, there, Hooch.
You saw the whole thing, didn't you?
Well, Amos is gone now.
So you don't have a lot of oPtions, OK?
Either you work with me
or they're going to shoot you.
l'm going to...
...try to make you
a little more comfortable.
Don't you want to think about it?
Here! Watch! How do you do this?
Let me just make you more... Here...
Think about it. Maybe we'll get
chocolate chiP cookies. A nice big box.
The soft kind with 22 chiPs! Cookie?
Think!
Hooch, get in the car!
Come on!
- Come on!
- Move back. He's in control.
Come on!
Are you tired? HoPe so.
lf you are, that's too bad. Now, look out!
Not too bad. Hold on. Wait a minute.
You're going in the clinic for a few days.
lt'll be good for you.
Come on!
Come on! Come on, Hooch!
Wait... Whoa, Hooch!
Hooch, no! StoP!
l'll kill you! No!
- What are you doing to him?
- Taking a walk!
He's bleeding! My God! For how long?
- Not long enough! You... l'll kill you!
- l have a front door!
- l'll shoot you, Hooch!
- You stay right there!
Fix him uP, so l can shoot him!
All right. All done. Stay!
- What's your dog's name?
- Hooch, but...
He needed stitches.
When did he last see a vet?
- l don't know.
- That's borderline abuse. He's filthy!
His diet is terrible. lf you can't...
- He belonged to an old man.
- l want to sPeak to him.
You can't. He was murdered last night.
- l'm Scott Turner, a Police investigator...
- l know. We use the same bank.
- Emily Carson... lt's a small town.
- Nice to meet you.
Sorry about that.
l can't stand animals being mistreated.
- Can l ask you a question about him?
- Yes.
l think he witnessed the crime. He may
have to identify a susPect. Could he?
- Yes.
- Can l show him a Photo? A mugshot?
- You don't know about dogs.
- l never had one.
- Not even as a kid?
- No way.
Dogs don't see in two dimensions.
He'd recognise a scent, but not a Photo.
- OK.
- Come on!
- Doesn't he have to recouP?
- Well, no. He's a little tired, but he's OK.
- You're a good dog.
- You're good with animals.
Yeah. l'm a vet! You're buttering me uP.
l think he would be better off with you,
than with someone like me. l don't...
- Are you married?
- No.
- You live alone? House or aPartment?
- House.
- You have a girlfriend?
- No.
- Well, Perfect.
- Perfect for who?
- Perfect for Hooch.
- For... How?
He'll keeP you comPany and
take care of your house. You're lucky.
- l don't have room for a dog like him!
- Not many PeoPle do. l've got to work...
Goodbye!
What? What is it? What?
lf you're hungry, finish the hamburgers!
Eat the buns! You're not thirsty!
You won't touch the water, orange juice,
cranaPPle! What do l do?
Make you a margarita?
Shut uP! God! This has been going on
for two and a half hours!
Quiet!
All right, you tell me what to do!
What am l suPPosed to do?
You tell me! What am l suPPosed
to do? Stand out on the Porch all night?
Give him a Valium. Take one yourself!
Hey, shut uP! l'm a Policeman!
Want your car towed?
l hate you.
No!
You...stuPid dog!
You stuPid dog!
You want to tear my head off? Go on!
You'll be traPPed inside and starve again!
lf they don't find my body first
and shoot you! lt's my house!
Back off! l'm coming in!
Back off, Hooch!
Back off.
All right. lf we're going to get along,
we'll have to come to an understanding.
These are the rules.
No barking. No growling.
You will not lift your leg to anything
in here. This is not your room.
No slobbering. No chewing. You'll wear
a flea collar. This is not your room.
No begging food. No sniffing crotches.
You will not drink from my toilet.
This is not your room.
This is your room.
The rest of the house is mine.
When l come back,
l like to find everything where l Put it.
ln its Place.
Don't touch my stuff.
l certainly won't touch yours.
This is the room to do that!
This is your bed.
You follow these simPle rules, shut uP...
...we'll get along fine.
- What does it tell you?
- l never read an autoPsy rePort.
- l don't want to again.
- lt's the key in a homicide investigation.
- The killer Probably had combat training.
- Where's that?
"The weaPon Pierced between the third
and fourth rib, entering the right lung."
l read that. Stabbed from behind
on the right. The killer's right-handed.
Yeah, but you stab somebody
in the heart, they can scream.
Penetrate the lung, they can't even
whisPer. SPecial Forces learn that.
- How did you know that?
- l'm a Professional. lt's my job to know.
- The coroner told me.
- Hey, fellas!
How much could we get
for all this furniture? l got a better idea.
- We'll sell squad cars. Yours first.
- ls there a Problem?
Yeah. The crime lab want
to charge $7,280 for this stuff.
SuPPose l send this in?
Who do you suggest l lay off?
- Katie would make the sacrifice.
- l've sacrificed enough for you!
We'll thin this out, Howard.
l'll go through it, don't worry. lt's fine.
No! You're eating the car!
Don't eat the car!
Not the car! What am l yelling
at you for? You're a dog.
You don't understand. Doesn't matter.
This car's going to be David Sutton's.
Hungry? Here's an ashtray. Eat that.
lt's terrible about Amos.
l'm locking my door tonight.
Don't do that. We'll catch him.
ls this dog food? lt's turkey and bacon.
PeoPle love their dogs and want variety.
- What kind of dog are we talking about?
- Very big, very large, very tall, very wide.
- Massive. Ugly!
- Well, you don't need this.
What you need is...this!
- l don't like the dog. Why get him a toy?
- Dogs like to chew.
lt's either this, or your furniture,
or your shoes. lt's uP to you.
- Sunday!
- lmperial Raceway!
The semi-finals...
- Ofthe N.R.D.A. Funny Car Contest!
- Sunday!
- Thanks for taking all this time out.
- No Problem! My Pleasure.
- Dog shamPoo!
- That's regular. No, you need medicated.
Flea, tick, wormer...
Scott! For bad breath.
- Regular or minty?
- Thank you, Kevin.
- $97.51 .
- $97.51?!
ls that Pesos? This is dog food!
$97.51 ! l'm not going to eat this stuff!
Did l buy smoked salmon? How much
if l take this back? l want to see Kevin.
Can you call him?
That's it! l'm getting my gun!
My rod, my Piece, my iron, my heater!
My lead-hurler!
Don't come back!
Wow! That dog's got a lot of guts.
Either that or he's stuPid. No!
You are out! Out for good!
Forget it! l wish it were snowing!
No, l wish it was hailing!
l wish it was hailing, God.
Send me hail the size of cantalouPes,
if you're a just and fair God.
No!
Cut it...
No... l'm running out of doors!
She can't stay!
You go ahead. Not you! No, come on.
Just her. Get back in the car.
Wait, what am l doing?
Go ahead, Hooch. Go!
Go! Go ahead! Go, boy! Follow her, boy!
She wants you, man!
This is why she's doing this,
so you'll follow her. ln, in! Go in!
- Hi... Scott Turner, right?
- Yeah, l was looking for my dog.
- l noticed. Know anything about fuses?
- Electrical fuses?
- Can you come in? For two minutes?
- A fuse box? Sure.
lt's on!
- What?
- The bedroom light is on!
- Say when the bathroom light goes on.
- All right.
Hey!
- Hey!
- No, not yet.
- Look, thank you, but...
- lt's on. This will take you all night.
- No, l just quit.
- You were going to leave it like this?
Yes... l'm starting again tomorrow, but...
You don't have to helP, but there's
rollers there and an extra brush.
- This bothers you.
- This would make me nuts.
- lt's harder to cut it in a big town.
- lt's not.
ln a big town, you make your mistakes.
No one sees. Who cares?
- A small town, you've got to face PeoPle.
- There's more to it than that.
Good. You'll be luckier with women.
Women in big cities outnumber men.
They're more desPerate.
Thank you. lf you have oPinions,
exPress them. Don't be shy.
- Just...blurt them out.
- You're better off here.
- lt's wonderful for raising kids.
- l don't have kids.
- l want five kids.
- Have you got a dad Picked out yet?
- Not yet.
- l'll fill you in on the singles scene here.
- God, l hate that Phrase.
- There's Embers Cocktail Lounge.
Or what else? l guess the Dairy Queen,
but l usually arrest guys my age there.
- But you're oPinionated and want 5 kids.
- l am.
And we...are...finished.
This is good.
- lt feels good?
- Very good. l admit it.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You have Paint all over you.
lt's even in your hair.
Look at you. You don't even have it
on your hands. SPotless.
- l have some Packing l have to do.
- Right.
lt's a nice night... l have to walk Camille.
Want to take a walk with me?
- No.
- No?
No... You see, l'm starting to like you.
lf we walk, l'm going to like you more.
Then we might fall in love
and everything will be fine for a while.
But one day you'll call me a
comPulsive bastard, and scream,
and say you never
want to see me again.
And l'm shattered. Who needs that?
Goodnight. Hooch!
- What time do you want to do that hall?
- About 7 P.m.
Goodnight, Houdini.
OK, boy! Guess what? Time for a bath!
Come on!
Come to the bathroom. Let's go!
This is why men will Prevail
and dogs won't dominate Earth.
You can do this with thumbs!
Move around! l don't care...
There you go! What a ferocious dog!
Get your armPits, your undercarriage.
lf l leave you in the car,
you'll just eat the rest of it.
Come on.
What is that?
You can't bring a dog in here.
Can you lift uP this desk?
- There's something different about you.
- l like to think so.
l know.
No tie.
lt's the first time
you haven't worn a tie at work.
- The dog's on the window sill.
- Get down.
The dog loves weddings.
Knock it off!
Shut uP, Hooch! Come on, shut uP!
You'd better get the hell out of here.
What is it?
- Dave! Police officers! How're you doing?
- Right behind you!
Don't Panic!
What are you doing?
- Seen that guy before?
- No! l can't see his Plates, either.
Hold it! Police officers!
We need your car. Hi, Ernie.
- Buckle your seat belt!
- At a time like this? l can't find it!
- Let's go!
- We've got to get Hooch.
Come on! Get in...
Good boy! Watch his tail!
Mom will kill me. She said
not to take it over 40. lt's brand new!
- This will break it in. She'll thank you.
- Hang on.
- He's on Mom's groceries!
- SlaP his face.
OK, it's a Cadillac.
- The licence Plate! l see the car.
- Hold on... P...
K...l.
- lt's B...
- lt's a P!
- Shut uP, Ernie!
- PKl...
RKl 547!
RKl 547. OK, hang on!
- He saw us!
- Come on!
- Which way?
- Right!... l'm sure it's right.
- Don't guess!
- lt's right! OK?
lf Highway Patrol hears about that,
l'm out of a job!
- lt'll be our little secret.
- Your mom! Can't she get a faster car?
Well! You boys livened uP the recePtion.
The bride swore she'd have nightmares
because of that dog.
Boyett thought you were after the beast.
And the Mayor did, too. l, of course,
didn't tell him it was your runaway Pet...
- ...and the station mascot.
- Don't raise your voice. You'll uPset him.
He's chained to a radiator.
Zack Gregory is an ex-Marine
with three arrests.
Assault with a deadly weaPon,
gunrunning, extortion. No convictions.
That address and number were false.
- So, who is he?
- The guy Hooch saw kill Amos Reed.
- You're kidding. Think this is the guy?
- Yeah.
What?
- You broke the case.
- Not yet.
There's no motive.
Amos wasn't killed in a robbery or a fight.
We think it was to cover something uP.
Zack is emPloyed by Boyett Seafood.
Amos rePorted strange noises there.
- Like something illegal was going on.
- Katie?
Could you swing the door oPen?
We need some air.
- Amos comPlained about everything.
- And now he's dead.
He was right.
lt's isolated. There's fishing boats
coming and going. Now he's killed?
Drugs. l know we'll never have a warrant
with what we have so far.
But it would be nice
if we could search that Place.
OK. Boyett's a friend.
What's he going to say? No?
DEA agents, Customs, the CHP...
...two shifts of our own guys,
Plus all sorts of local coPs.
This is going to be the biggest search
here since World War ll, all due to you.
We'll go at it like bacon through a duck.
And bust us a smuggling oPeration.
Here's dessert.
Chocolate chiP cookies...
Something to drink?
lt won't hurt me if we imPress the CHP.
That'll look good on the résumé.
Give me a little job security in the future.
There! Come on, you're not eating.
Go ahead.
This is a celebration. You lD'd Gregory.
Amos' murder is all but solved.
So, go. OPen your beer.
You're thinking about Amos?
You must miss him.
Yeah, well...
l forget that this must be hard on you.
Everything's so different.
You and l got off to a bad start and
my Place isn't a shack filled with junk.
Not yet, anyway.
You can keeP working on it.
OK?
You like that?
You do.
Here, let me do this side, as well.
You're not so rough. You're not so mean.
You're not any kind
of a monster dog, are you?
Look at those big teeth.
What are you doing?
Give me my towel.
Come on!
Off the couch!
l'm not afraid of you.
lf my emPloyees are involved,
l'll cooPerate. l just don't get it.
- When did you last see Zack?
- At the wedding.
His address was a motel.
They'd never heard of him.
lf he shows uP for his Paycheque,
l'll call you.
Let's go!
l don't want the Sheriff's guys handling
this stuff alone. Be with them all the way.
l hate fish.
Check the back.
Go through these one by one.
- Maybe we came on the wrong day?
- Howard, l'm sorry. We let you down.
Forget it. You can't exPect things to Pan
out every time. Your new job's waiting.
Go home, Pack uP and get ready.
David, the case is now yours.
Foster, the guys in Monterey said
you did the initial go-see on Gregory,
but the DMV sent his vehicle
registration to the Lazy Acres Motel.
So how did you discover it was
a false address? Did you just Phone?
You didn't go for an interview
and show them a Photo?
l need surveillance done
on the motel to locate Zack Gregory.
He's the Prime susPect in Amos Reed's
murder, that's why... Yes, he is!
He's legitimate! l have an eye witness,
kind of. l'm not telling you your job.
l'm a law enforcement officer, and
l'm asking you a Professional courtesy.
Don't hang uP!
Dumb coP!
Scott Turner... Hi!
How's the town vet?
lt keePs Playing in my brain what Amos
told me, that something's going on there.
- l can't figure it out or stoP thinking of it.
- Maybe you should...stoP thinking of it.
When l have a Problem l can't solve,
sometimes l just think
of something comPletely different.
That's when the solution comes.
Out of nowhere.
- Fascinating. l don't work that way.
- Well, try.
- No, l can't.
- Well, l'll helP.
- l don't know how.
- l'm thinking of something. What is it?
- Don't!
- lndulge me.
- l don't know.
- Great.
- So you've never thought about it?
- Never thought about what?
- Oh! Thought about that!
- Well...
l'm a guy. l've thought about that.
- How far did you get?
- Well...
l got to unbutton...
...unbuttoning your blouse.
l got a lot farther than that.
- You did? How far? A lot farther?
- A lot farther.
- l didn't know there was farther.
- You have to use your imagination.
- That's got to be illegal.
- Probably is.
- Right from the carton?
- A woman in my house!
How did that haPPen?
- How's your back?
- lt's regained some elasticity.
Yeah. This is emPty.
What are we going to do about it?
Most of my grocery budget's gone
on my dog, but we could manage the...
- There's eggs.
- ...Perfect omelette.
- Go to it.
- Well...
No, no, no!
- "We" was the oPerative word there.
- No.
- You look lovely in the light.
- l don't do this.
- Here's where it's at. We have cheese.
- Come on.
- l'll mess uP your kitchen.
- l'm not cooking. You wore me out!
Did l? We could call for Pizza.
Don't. l'll walk you through it.
That's the omelette Pan.
- You got a little Pan just for omelettes?
- There's a whisk.
No... l'm hungry.
- l'm doing it.
- l'd like to eat in the next five hours.
There we go, and great! Now, mix that
uP and then we'll throw in the other stuff.
- No, that's stirring. This is how you mix.
- No, l...
- Oh, God! Do that again, would you?
- You like that?
Yeah.
You feel so good. You smell so good.
- What?
- Of course!
They're not bringing something in!
How could l...
- The thing l wasn't thinking of!
- The thought?
- Yes! Bang! lt never haPPened before!
- l told you.
l got to search again!
- They're smuggling something out!
- So l'm eating alone?
l'm sorry, yeah! l'll make it uP to you.
Know that ltalian Place in San RaPello?
They make a lasagne.
lt's not a great lasagne. l make better,
but you want to go tomorrow night?
You'll still be here?
Oh, yes!
- Another night, at least... Hooch!
- He's outside.
- What?
- With Camille.
Listen, would you clean this stuff uP?
Just... Leave it!
lt's all right.
- God! What time?
- Seven? l'll meet you here.
Hooch, come on!
Hooch, put that down! Come on!
This your first stakeout? lt's mine.
Well, it's going to be a long night.
What do you say we PrePare for it?
Try to stay alert. Want one?
There you go. SPecial treat.
That's good.
They're hard.
Well...
lt's not bad...
Tastes like health food.
You can have this.
Back in!
Now...
...back to work.
lt was called Lancelot Link,
Secret Chimp.
lt was like The Man From U.N.C.L.E.
Did Amos have a TV?
lt's two-dimensional, you couldn't see it.
These chimPs were sPies, in suits.
They'd wear hats and smoke cigarettes.
You missed it!
The Man From U.N.C.L.E. was good.
That was cool.
lt wasn't Lancelot Link.
What does that do for you?
That feel good?
Wake you uP a little bit?
You have to be a dog.
l had the enlistment PaPers filled out.
All that was sent.
But l have this distance vision thing.
So no flight school for me. lf you're in
the Air Force and not in flight school...
Means you're scraPing birdshit off
a runway in Guam. So, here l am.
l'm boring you?
lt's mine. l got you something... Here.
l got you a Diet Coke.
Diet, because... Look at that!
Work on that.
We've known each other a while now.
l think it's safe for me to say that...
Are you aware of your drooling Problem?
lt looks like you swallowed a tennis shoe
and you got the laces hanging out.
lt's a bit embarrassing, don't you think?
Maybe you could save it. ls there a use
for this? Like, as an industrial lubricant?
Good God! l hate to think
what you're doing to the car.
- Did you bring it?
- Yeah.
- You know we have to take it back.
- Yeah, we'll take it back. Come on.
There you go. l saw Boyett leave, so
let's get this over with before he's back.
- Wait, what about getting Permission?
- Why don't you relax?
Something's not right here.
- You got that look.
- l don't know what you mean.
- You humPed the vet!
- You have a lot of class!
l had a religious exPerience
with the future Mrs Turner,
who, yes, holds a veterinary doctorate.
- Get that ugly mutt out!
- We're Police. This is a Police dog.
- We just want to look around.
- You did.
- The dog wasn't available yesterday.
- He's a health code violation.
l don't understand.
Mr Boyett said he'd cooPerate!
Well, if he said so.
- Thanks.
- Liar.
- What?
- He didn't.
He did. Yesterday.
Come here, boy.
OK, Hooch. Let's find
some money. Can you?
Can you find some money? Smell it.
Smell that money. Find me some, OK?
And for me.
Go!
- Why do you think there's a connection?
- Know why l took that job?
- Because nothing haPPens here. So?
- There's been two unusual incidents:
Amos' murder, and $8,000 found on the
beach. A day aPart. Maybe there's a link.
Maybe not.
What?
You got something? What is it?
What you got?
A Perfect match.
The same size, same brand.
Everything! Good boy!
- Way to go! Good going.
- All right!
Mr Boyett says he never gave you
Permission for the dog. He's furious.
l hoPe he sues!
We're done anyway. Thanks.
Come on, Hooch. Here we go!
l could get fired over this.
You have another job. l like a town
where nothing haPPens.
Don't worry, l'll take the blame. l'll talk
to Boyett, and l'll call Howard, as well.
- What should l do?
- Find out how common these bags are.
Are they in suPermarkets, or a sPecial
order? Check businesses and stores.
Then Park the car,
turn off the radio, take naP.
lf you're in on what l'm doing,
you will get fired.
Stay!
Skipper! MaryAnn and Ginger...
We got to warn them!
No vacancy.
SPeak English, moron? No vacancy.
lf you ain't got a warrant, get lost!
- Know him?
- No.
l don't have much exPerience at
being an intimidating coP, or threatening.
You break my heart.
So in order for you to take me seriously,
l have to shoot you in the leg.
You almost shot me!
l can't believe l missed. Where is he?
- Put the gun down.
- Zack Gregory?
l believe so.
Over to the Cadillac. You drive.
A seat belt? Oh, yeah.
Think that's going to keeP you safe?
Start the car! What are you doing?
Now start it!
Go left.
Slow down!
You won't do it...
You don't have what it takes.
To kill you? You're right, l don't.
But he does.
lnteresting sensation, isn't it?
l'm going to ask some questions.
You blink once for yes, twice for no. OK?
Once. OK. You killed Amos Reed?
l don't believe you.
Hooch says you did.
Yes... Progress. Good.
The seafood Plant is a cover?
You're smuggling cash out? Yes.
OK. This is fun.
Boyett's in charge?
l can't stoP him from snaPPing your neck.
ls Boyett in charge?
ls Boyett in on it?
All right.
l'm sorry. Here, back this way.
l'm going to make you a little more
comfortable. Good. Now, sit down.
Come on, boy.
KeeP an eye on him for me, would you?
What is this in your Pocket? Thanks.
Thanks.
OK, is there any way
l can get you to understand this?
l need you to cover the back.
Understand?
The backyard?
The back door? The gate?
The back of the building?
Please? Cover the back!
What a good dog!
- Howard, you scared me!
- l'm sorry.
- Are you all right?
- l'm fine.
l got here as fast as l could.
Boyett! You were right!
- Where's the back-uP?
- Four cars on CarPenter Road.
- They're ready any time l signal them.
- OK.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
- Looks like we missed them.
The engine of this fork-lift is warm.
Looks like we just missed them.
- Because you tiPPed them off!
- What's going on?
Call your back-uP. Use the radio.
lt's me!
You're laundering money.
You got the Perfect set-uP.
This small town where nothing haPPens.
Police Protection.
- l know how you do it.
- No!
lt's all the evidence l need.
Who's going to sell you out first? Zack?
Or Boyett?
- He's between us.
- Right side!
Cover me!
You hit my leg.
Hands behind your head.
- Don't turn around.
- Howard...
He's still got his Pistol...
What are you doing?
Scott?
l'll kill you if l have to,
but this will be a lot easier to exPlain
- if we both have the same story.
- What?
We came to question him.
He fired at us. We fired back.
Killed the susPect. Congratulations!
You solved the case.
l met some PeoPle in Panama.
They needed a way to move cash out.
l got one Per cent.
- lt's drug money.
- l don't know that.
l never asked. lt's a shame
PeoPle are getting killed over it.
When l found out, it was too late.
You believe me?
- How do you exPlain Amos' murder?
- That's covered.
Zack killed Amos. Boyett told him to.
Boyett's dead. Case closed. lt's all true.
Now...
- Will you work with me on this?
- lt sure is a lot of money, Howard.
Yeah, l will.
The truth!
KeeP these on him.
Hold that there.
Use the Pressure to stoP the blood.
You'll be all right once we get you home.
Once we get you home, you'll be all right.
- All you need is rest.
- Stay where he can smell you,
if that's all right.
All right.
Change it when it gets soaked.
That's right.
Hold on.
You OK?
- He'll be OK.
- He's lost a lot of blood.
That's OK. lt's all right.
That's a good boy.
Just got to get you home and
get you some rest. Hold on, Chief.
Hold on, boy. Come on, boy. Good!
You'll be OK, Chief.
All l have to do is get you home...
l have to get you home, so you can rest.
You're going to be OK, Chief.
Come on. Come on, Chief.
That's it?
l'm sorry.
Wait a minute! They may not drive well,
but we try to keeP them clean.
l'm sorry, man.
Let's go! Come on.
Seatbelt!
Stolen bicycles from the high school.
How did you know to look here?
- l'm a Professional. lt's my job to know.
- You got a tiP.
- l got a tiP.
- You solved the case. Feel good?
Chief! Your wife called to say, "He's out.
Get home in five or you're hamburger."
- Need my helP?
- l can handle it.
- Take this.
- What?
For your throat.
- Good luck!
- Good luck is Scott's!
- What's going on? l'm home.
- l didn't get my naP...
...or my ice cream,
and he set them off again.
These are nice PuPPies.
Then he gets them going!
- l'm done!
- Where is he?
- UPstairs... He's yours! Deal with it.
- l'll take care of it.
A Professional veterinarian...
l told you this wouldn't work.
- l told you!
- No, l told you.
All right, l'm tired of this,
but let's go through it again.
No barking. No growling.
No eating from the housePlants.
No dogs allowed on the second floor.
No Playing of my records!
No sniffing at crotches.
No drinking out of the toilet.
You will not beg for food.
No ball Playing in the house.
No chewing or slobbering of my shoes!
You will not hide from me!
This is not your room.