CINEART
Dedicated to our fathers and their children
Once upon a time there was a land
which had as capital Belgrado.
April, 6th 1941
I'll kill them all, mate!
Watch out!
I'll kill them all!
It's to dangerous.
Ivan!
Brother!
The vice-president talked
about tightening the relations
between the states of Yugoslavia...
That's my brother...
and his best friend, Blacky.
Idiots!
What can I do?
I don't have anyone else on the world.
Marko!
Come over and have a cup of coffee.
I can't, I'm in a hurry!
My friend is tired!
I'm tired!
Tomorrow I'll take you out for lunch
in the Russian Czar!
Go back inside!
Vera,
I'm a free man.
A free man? Come on.
Damn!
Vera, I need to
tell you something important.
What?
-Don't get mad.
We wrote Petar
in the Communist Party.
You mean in the brothel.
He is now one of us.
Inside! -I come.
A last word to my friend.
I got business to take care of.
You see what I have to go through.
Come over here, so I'll kiss you.
Not on the mouth, idiot!
Blacky, inside!
It's the same thing each morning.
I'm going to leave you,
just like Marko's wife.
I'm a free man!
Ini Mini Moo...
First part - The War
A garret
Under the roof
On the wall...
Looloo... breakfast!
On the wall does a clock
Ticktack
A garret
Under the roof
Does she obey you,
your mother?
Soni!
Yes, that's the way...
Continue...
It comes...
-Let me go!
Go? You have to come here.
Come back!
Bloody fascist swines.
How can you continue your meal?
I can, don't you see?
How can you, with all these bombs?
Just because.
Do I have to die on an empty stomach?
My shoes!
Don't touch my shoes!
Stupid bastard!
This is the end.
Enough!
My city!
They are bombing my city!
What are you going to do, Blacky?
I'm going to welcome these criminals
who are distroying my city.
I know where you are going.
-Oh, you do?
I know.
To your whore.
What whore?
You are hallucinating.
Your actrice.
-What actrice?
I'm going to defend my country.
Don't lie!
You are going to defend your whore!
Impossible to talk with you.
What do you say now?
You are driving me to a nervous breakdown.
I say what everyone says.
Blacky!
Yes, my love? What is it?
You are always at the theatre!
Every night you are at the theatre!
Because I love the theatre.
You love the theatre?
You love the theatre?!
Is it that strange?
You love your whore, not the theatre!
If you were not pregnant...
What then? You dirty liar!
Me?
-Yes You!
Son of a bitch! Liar!
What? What is it?
You should be ashamed of yourself, Vera.
Blacky!
What happens?
Don't cry.
I'll build a new zoo for you.
Look.
You, go away!
The animals will eat the survivors.
Here some money for you.
Buy some milk for that little monkey.
Stop crying.
The germans will laugh with you.
NATIONAL THEATRE
CLEARING WORKS
At work, artists?
You could say so!
Bato, candy.
Uncle Blacky!
Are you afraid of me? Playing is over.
You can be sure about that.
What do you mean?
You know it very good.
No, really I don't.
Do you want me and Bato
in the working camp?
-What?
The whole city is talking about it.
You are a thief!
- Me?
What are they saying?
Don't act like you know nothing about it.
You are stealing their gold, their money.
Thief!
I steal from the rich...
what they stole from the poor.
Stop it.
- Stop it also.
At work?
Do you love me?
Yes.
Give me a kiss.
She loves me.
I've been looking for you for days.
I'm scared.
You are getting on my nerves.
You on mine! Did you see this?
They are looking for you.
Ten thousand!
Is that all? Ridiculous.
Franz!
Franz?
Fräulein Zovko...
Franz, good morning.
I have been waiting for you.
Our table is waiting
in the Russian Czar.
Yes, and my brother?
Seisenberger, do me a favor...
Take that vehicle and follow us.
But careful!
Franz...
Ivan, open up!
Stay at the door
and don't move.
Damn, what a smell.
Vera, sit down.
My brother is just like Noach.
He saves the world after the flood.
Don't move and be quiet.
What are you doing?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
When will you stop trying to hang yourself?
God.
I've had enough
of this life.
Enough? Instead of helping me
and become a hero
you hang yourself like a girlie.
Shame on you.
Message from the Gestapo
to all citizens of Belgrado
and surroundings.
A train with weapons and munition
has been attacked tonight.
This is the work
of communist bandits.
Petar "Blacky" Popara,
and Marko Dren.
What did you do?
Nothing, we just
hit these thieves a bit.
Marko, good Lord!
What will become of me?
Someone has betrayed us.
A dirty traitor.
Our comrades have been busted.
Do they have Blacky? Busted?
With his balls, yes.
Just like me by the way.
Come on, hurry up!
Why do I have to go?
Because you are my brother.
Leave him!
Come on, children!
No problem. I'm okay.
Who is there?
- It's me, grandpa.
Who is out there?
It's me, Marko.
Who?
Marko, goddammit!
It's me, Marko! Open up!
Is that you, Marko?
-Yes!
Quick!
The germans can be here any minute.
Go to the cellar,
I'll take care of your stuff.
The cellar is behind the stove.
Let them pass!
What are you doing with these animals?
My cellar is a hideout
for people, not a zoo.
I'll close it off.
Terrible.
Terrible...
Where are you, Blacky?
Son of a bitch.
Yes, it started!
Grandpa!
Marko!
Blacky's wife is about to give birth!
Move!
Fast, please!
Get me some water, a blanket,
and a cloth...
Hurry up, he's coming!
Don't be afraid.
Are you okay?
Yes, but I don't see a thing.
There he is!
Lift the bicycle!
Higher!
Ivan!
I'm not feeling well.
Everything will be allright.
No, I'm feeling terrible.
If something happens with me,
call him Jovan.
Vera!
Three years later
Belgrado was in
a terrible mental state.
Easy, easy
Wild water of the Ibar
Why are you in such a hurry?
All together!
I'm also
in a lot of grief
More
Then you can imagine...
It's on me!
For the birthday of my son.
Here is my Jovan. Look!
A handsome boy, Blacky. Congratulations.
He will be, Mustafa.
He will study in Moscow
and become an officer,
and not a thief like you, cheat!
We work together,
but how much longer will it last?
Well?
Are the thieves getting nervous?
Mate!
Happy birthday for Jovan,
best friend!
My good old pal!
Look!
Completely my replica.
He has something from Vera too.
Do you think so?
Where were you?
There is a traitor.
We have got problems.
The three are downstairs.
I've seen it. Don't run away.
Excuse me for waiting.
Good evening.
Please, gentlemen.
I'm doing this for your own good.
Gentlemen, please...
Franz!
Flowers for Natalija!
He fucks her and kills us.
Excuse me.
Get me a huge bouquet.
Allright.
And the priest?
-I'll fix it.
Great.
Boy...
there is gonna be a wedding!
Put your cards on the table!
My gun.
Put yours next to mine.
This is fair play!
Here is your gold. You see?
That's the gold, right?
How much do you make with it?
Look!
How much did you get for it?
How much did you get for the gold?
200.000. - 200.000?
Mustafa, you were talking about 120.000.
Tell me where you put the weapons
and we are even.
On my mother's grave,
the germans toke all.
You don't have to swear
on your mother.
Bastard!
Are you stealing my money?
I rob banks
and juwellers,
and you steal from me, mother fuckers!
Filthy thieves!
I kill you all, dirtbags!
I shall liberate Belgrado
from scum like you!
Our comrades die and
starve to death, and you steal!
Are you out of your mind?
No, boys...
you are not playing it well.
Hold this for a moment.
Faster and harder!
Here I come, buddy!
Invincible!
Attention!
Here I come!
Not in the ear!
Left, left, left!
I have to tell you something,
you as party secretary...
If something hurts us,
it's that scum of
thieves and tramps.
We commit robberies for weapons
and food for our comrades,
and these bastards steal from us!
I want to commit suicide.
You say you are gonna commit suicide,
but you won't do it.
Are you sure?
Do you think a man can live...
Quiet!
...without anything or anyone
to live for?
You are capitulating?
No, I'm doing a peace
proposal!
He devours her.
I'll kill him.
You don't even see the actors.
I really like the captain.
Oh yeah?
-Yes, look.
Quiet, this is a theatre.
I'm leaving, mate.
Left!
Keep your hands off!
Watch the stage!
Goodnight!
Tell me honestly
the truth
and I'll forgive you.
Is Berta my child?
I can't be guilty from
something I didn't do.
Leave me!
Shame on you!
...and make his dishonesties public?
Is Berta my child?
I'm coming!
Bato!
-Quiet!
Uncle Blacky!
Natalija is the best.
Franz!
It's a shame.
-Yes.
Captain!
Good evening, miss.
Captain...
A moment please.
I'm Berta's father.
I'm the father
of your child.
Please...
Do you understand?
Tie them up. Fast!
I came to collect my Laura.
We love each other.
Faster!
We leave your house
to live together.
Please, don't be angry.
Ready?
-Yes.
Thanks, captain.
I'm the actor.
I know him.
But where from?
Goodbye, captain.
You are playing for the germans,
bastard!
What an actor, my collegue.
Is that electricity?
Sit down!
Hands up, traitor!
Hands up!
Is that the robe?
Yes, mister, but...
Uncle Blacky! Sister!
Uncle Blacky! Attack!
Do you want my sister?
You won't get her!
Hands up, my friend!
They will kill my brother!
Blow!
I'm not getting married every day!
Congratulations!
Good, Golub. Where is the priest?
On his way. I ordered to get him.
Congratulations, miss.
I'm not getting married!
Yes you do, my love.
You don't even know it, that's all.
I destroyed your life by killing
Franz. Thank you, Natalija.
Who will take care of Bato's medicine?
Franz or you?
You give me stolen gold.
Stolen from traitors.
Think about it.
Listen to me...
I never loved anyone like you.
But there are rules.
No collaboration with the enemy.
That's right!
-What the fuck are you saying?
I'm just an actrice.
The backers are also open?
Yeah, but you are not the backer's wife!
You don't sell bread.
You sell your soul!
He who sells his soul,
I shall judge myself.
At first I'll kill
your theatre director.
I'll strangle him myself.
Because I love theatre.
Congratulations, Mr. Blacky!
Does the dinner eat us,
or we the dinner?
I'm gonna roast that fish!
No problem.
Aren't you ashamed?
Your collegues are nursing the partisans
and you play for these bastards.
It hurts.
Oh, does it hurt?
I love you.
Golub!
That fish needs to be roasted.
Come on, I'm going to pee.
Guard my fiancee, my friend.
Forward!
Marko...
Come on!
I don't want to.
I do not want to marry.
Don't force me to come
over and clear things out!
Don't fear.
You might not know,
but he actually isn't
an electrical engineer.
He is a simple electrician
who climbs up in the masts.
He has been all his life up in the
masts with pincers and clips.
I got him out of there.
I asked him wether he wanted
to be on our side and he said yes.
"Shall you respect our statutes
and rules?"
"Yes"
And that way it continued until he got rich.
Natalija...
An electrician?
A mast worker!
Natalija,
you are our best actrice
Our people in peril
need you.
You need a man who is
reasonable, intelligent,
civilized...
An intellectual.
That's true.
Comrade Leka wants you
in front of the court martial.
Where are the weapons we have
been waiting for for a week?
Here, aboard.
I'll get married and we'll sail off.
They'll hear the music in Belgrado.
They should. Blacky is getting married.
Enough wining.
Aren't these weapons?
After the priest marries me, I'll go to
the White Rock.I'll be there before you.
Comrade Tito!
When will you come to Uzice?
"Your hands are so white,
so fragile and tender,
like the wings of a bird...
If I only could see them fly
and land on my face..."
Stop it!
Go away!
What's this?
We were talking about theatre...
What? What are you doing?
I'll kill you!
No, my good friend!
I've killed two men for her
I know.
Why are you doing this to me?
And you...
-It wasn't me.
Wasn't that you?
Who then? Me?
Are you my best friend?
I am your best friend.
I didn't hear you.
Who's gonna get married?
We, my love.
We are getting married.
You are getting married.
We are getting married, my love.
We are getting married, honey.
You wanted to drive, no?
Go, stallion!
Old chap!
Where is that priest?
He'll be here soon.
Moonshine at noon?
Or sunshine at midnight?
From heaven above
shines a light...
The germans! What a disaster!
Nobody knows
where the light comes from...
Together you would be
the ideal man!
You are getting on my nerves.
Get out!
And cover yourself!
Left and right from the boat!
Marko!
Petar Popara!
Bloody idiots!
Your game is out!
Franz...
Show yourself!
And bring Natalija with you
or I'll kill you!
Didn't I shoot him?
No.
He wears a bulletproof jacket.
Next time aim for his head.
I'll smoke another cigarette,
and then my patience ends!
Then I have to see you.
Understood?
Don't shoot!
Thank you.
What a disaster!
My beloved saver!
Honey...
Schulz, get out!
And finish that
criminal scum off quickly!
My white dove...
Lot's of pleasure, idiots!
You won't forget me soon!
Shoot, old chap!
Golub, don't shoot!
What a disaster!
Shoot, man!
Where are the guns, Blacky?
Where is the train with guns, bastard?
Dirty traitor!
I'll smash Tito out of your head.
And?
Does he talk?
No.
He's only cursing us.
Petar Popara...
Go to hell, fascist swine.
No.
Lick my ass.
Run the current incrementally up.
Marry uncle Blacky, sister.
He is the strongest.
Forget uncle Blacky, there comes Franz.
He's the strongest of them all.
Don't be such an ass.
What did he say?
He asks
when you can leave the hospital
Next week.
He's going to a sanatorium in Austria.
A sanatorium in Austria?
There he will be safe.
I can't help me here
and it's to dangerous for him.
Good Morning.
Did our young friend
throw up tonight?
Yes.
No.
Is it yes...
or is it no?
I don't know.
No, he didn't throw up.
Tell me that he doesn't has to worry.
Please.
Let him explode!
Dirty fascist nazi kraut!
Let him go!
Let him blow apart
like a paper bag!
You killed my Franz.
Is he dead?
Not yet.
Forgive me. Franz. I'm sorry.
Your Franz can fuck himself! Come on!
What's wrong with that piece of crap?
Put it on level 5.
That's lethal.
Lethal? My ass!
Let me try.
It doesn't work.
Put it on.
Colleague...
Wake up!
Good morning, gentlemen.
Everything under control?
What's wrong with him?
He tested the generator.
And did it work?
-Yes, he's dead.
But he isn't hurt.
He's an electrician.
Electrician?
A mast worker!
Mate! Give me a granade.
If they might find me.
Here's your granade.
Come on!
Thank you, Marko.
What piteous, all this loonatics
Sure, sure.
We are all crazy, Natalija.
The only thing is the diagnosis
hasn't been said.
Where is uncle Blacky?
In the basket, my boy.
In the basket?
Mate?
-In the basket?
Uncle Blacky!
Bloody fascist swines.
Ivan!
Golub!
Get us bandages.
Carry on,old friend.
Where is that bandage?!
Come and help us...pick Jovan.
Get rid of that monkey, Help him!
Step harder.
We need more light.
Caution for his leg.
Comrade Blacky,
what did they do?
Bloody fascist swines.
What a disaster!
Jovan...
Comrade Marko!
Get your granddad, he will cure him.
The water of the well his healthy.
Bring the weapons to our comrades.
Don't worry, I'll do it.
Look, here's Jovan.
Here's your daddy
Let him see his daddy.
Jovan...
My son...
Give your daddy a kiss.
Give him a kiss.
This room is dedicated to me.
My room!
Okay...
Yes.
This room...
and the whole house.
And the country, heaven and the stars,
the sun, the moon, the clouds...
even if it unclouded
Is this all mine?
Sure, everything.
Who is bombing us?
The Allies.
If it isn't the Germans,
it's the Allies.
Where are you going?
To the cellar.
-Come...
Come with me.
Are you afraid?
Not if I'm with you.
Drink.
I never drink.
Don't be afraid, drink.
It's not strong, but gentle.
Really.
I don't know, sweety,
wether this is a dream
And what year, which day it is
And I don't know,
My love,
Wether I'm your dream
Or you mine...
For who did you write that?
Tell me.
-For you.
You're lying.
You are lying
-I'm not
-I never lie.
Never.
Marko,
you can lie so deliciously.
Easter, april 1944
The Allies ar bombing
what the nazi's had left standing up.
Freedom!
They are trying to steal
a part of our country!
With the weapons we won
the plebiscite and
defended the freedom!
With weapons we will defend Triëste!
Second Part - The Cold War
Years go by, Marko became
a collaborator of Tito.
In 1961 he pays off
his debts to Blacky.
Comrade Marko...
I ask you once more
wether comrade Natalija can
play in my movie.
-No.
But I'm filming you memoires,
and she is our greatest actress.
Exactly.
The movie is dedicated to the revolution,
not to us.
Do you want to honour us
with a visit during the filming?
Sure.
Comrades,
I have the great honour
to open this Cultural Centre
with a statue of our hero
Petar Popara Blacky.
Blacky symbolizes
our battle against the fascists.
He will live eternally in the hearts
of his friends,
his battle comrades,
and of the generations to come
which will come from childhood on
to this Centre to find
inspiration from this believe
for which our brother,
our comrade, our friend,
our Blacky
gave his life and youth.
I'll use this opportunity,
allthough I waste some of your time,
to bring you some poems
from my last poetry book
about the Freedom Battle.
Why is the wind always blowing
If we are commemorate our beloved?
Why does the wind hit the windows
And the doors of our brothers?
Is it only the wind that blows
Or howls the heaven with us?
Petar Popara Blacky, our friend,
glory to you!
Glory to him!
Moonshine at noon?
Sunshine at midnight?
From the heaven up there
Shines a light
Nobody knows...
The sovjet divisions
are surrounded.
The units of general Von Kleist
have broken through...
Continue, sister.
More light!
Daddy!
Bring some water!
What has happened?
It's okay.
The gestapo got me.
Bloody fascist swines
Bloody fascist swines!
Marko, let me out
and in 3 days the war ends.
Not yet.
Where are you waiting for?
Tito asked you to wait.
Tito?
He said:
"Greet Blacky from me
and tell him to wait.
I want to spare him for the last battle."
Did he say that?
-Literally.
He asked me to give you this watch.
Ho, Marko, I can't...
with a mission.
For me?
For you.
Comrade Tito
We promise you formally
That we'll never depart
from the path you showed us
Comrade Tito
Hope of the people
You are beloved
by old
and youth
Comrade Tito
Our spring flower
Serbia
Shall never forget you
a blue violet
blossomed
on the pillow
of comrade Tito...
Congratulations, Blacky.
Shake hands with comrade Marko.
Not with me. Comrade Marko.
Are we washing ourselves?
-Yes.
And our business, grandpa?
It's... difficult
Are you watching the time?
I turn the hours back,
as you told me to do.
Six hours a day.
Do not exagerate to much.
On 20 years time
I have saved them 5 years.
Can you imagine
what that means...
5 years less in a cellar.
Air strike!
Fast, comrades!
Hurry up! Leave the guns!
Everybody in the tank!
The enemy is attacking again!
No panic!
What are you doing, moron?
Come on, idiot!
You'll kill us all.
Quick!
Comrade Tito
We promise you formally...
Tito, Tito, Tito!
Everybody was singing
and thinking that outside
the fascists of World War II
were still at reign.
What are you doing, Marko?
You'll see.
Ringe, ringe, raja
Here comes uncle Paja...
And now?
Natalija!
Natalija, spring is coming
on a snow white horse!
Stop! Stop! Cut!
Stop? Why are you cutting?
Yugoslav, dammit!
Are you calling this rain?
"Stop! Stop!"
Can you never say "Play"?
Thanks, people. Take a break.
The water has to flow!
There he is! Music!
"The spring comes",
scene 34a, second take
Action!
The Germans!
Natalija, honey!
The spring comes
on a snow white horse!
I am being raped!
Nobody gets
Petar Popara alias Blacky!
Natalija!
Long live the Communist Party
of Yugoslavia!
I'm being raped!
Cut!
Comrade, Marko!
Get up, all of you!
Stop the rain!
Comrades artists,
work full of despair
You interprete...
great men
who are no longer amongst us.
Let's honour them.
Never will they be forgotten.
To a long life, comrades!
Music!
Cheers, comrade Marko!
Comrade Marko,
let me introduce you to
the heroes from your memoires.
Not now!
Who are you?
Marko!
Yes, I am you.
Amazing...
Exactly my portrait.
Where did you find these people?
The casting is half of the work.
True. Unbelievable.
We exchanged our books
for rifles from the same wood.
Shoot, my rifle,
So that mother hears.
Never will I give my country up
To the enemy.
Come on, say something.
Well?
-She is nice.
Sure she is.
Franz?
Franz the vampyre.
Very beautiful, but I got the impression
that someone is missing.
Is this the real Franz or an actor?
Who knows?
An actor.
Yes, an actor.
Unbelievable.
Everything is just like it was back then.
When you killed eleven Germans,
dived...
-What a memory.
...and Blacky and Natalija saved.
True, true.
Excuse me.
Blacky!
My friend!
God, Blacky.
Why did they have to kill you?
Why?
Comrade Marko,
can't you protect the actors?
I got burnt for the third time.
Three times!
Comrade Marko,
it will be an awesome movie!
Are you afraid for God?
Are we afraid for God, you mean.
You should better
learn your script.
Literally.
Understood?
Goodnight.