Touchstone Pictures was formed in 1984
as a separate brand of The Walt Disney Company
to produce films containing
mature elements.
Amblin Entertainment
is a production company headed by
Steven Spielberg, Frank Marshall,
and Kathleen Kennedy.
SilverScreen Partners III was the last
of three limited partnerships offered
to the public to help finance productions.
Investors received a portion of a film's gross.
Artists studied titles of
various cartoons of the 1940s.
They decided on a look most reminiscent
of Warner Bros. cartoons.
Notice how the wood floor
is also animated to move as
the camera changes perspective.
Animated backgrounds
were unusual due to expense.
Mrs. Herman
was voiced by April Winchell.
Who was April Winchell's father,
who voiced a famous Disney character?
Paul Winchell voiced Tigger,
in addition to other characters.
He also hosted a children's TV show
and even invented an early version
of the artificial heart.
Animation pioneerTex Avery was
probably the single biggest influence
on the animation comedy style
of Who Framed Roger Rabbit.
The next shot of Roger is known as a "take;"
a character's sudden reaction.
In an Avery-style take, eyes pop out,
jaws drop to the floor, bodies become
stiff as boards, to visually show
in extreme how a character feels.
Avery exaggerated action gags,
through speed and body changes,
as never before.
This influenced everybody's animation.
Born in Taylor, Texas, Tex Avery
was a leading Animation Director
at Warner Bros. from 1936 to 1942.
Then at M-G-M, he did his most
distinctive work from 1942 through 1954.
Later, Avery created TV commercials.
His best known ad shows an insect world's
view of a leading bug spray.
Avery developed a following
of young admirers who rediscovered
his work after his death in 1980, at age 72.
This is classic "cause-and-effect"
comedy structure.
Something happens that causes another event,
which causes a wilder event,
and gags keep building layer upon layer.
Silent-film comedians like
Charles Chaplin and Buster Keaton pioneered
comedy stories as a "chain-of-events."
The early Disney animation staff
studied Chaplin's movies.
Director Robert Zemeckis stated,
"Moving out of the cartoon into reality
was the crucial scene in the movie.
That shot had to work or everything would
be over three minutes after it began."
"The last three shots are
subtly rendered so they are not flat
cartoon animation but watercolours.
We built a three-dimensional set and painted
it flat, with even the shadows painted on.
All of a sudden the director walks in."
Baby Herman was animated
here by Richard Williams,
the film's director of animation.
Director Zemeckis first got excited
about this project-in-development in 1982.
He felt this opening transitional scene,
"was the ultimate concept shot," meaning
it was a great sounding premise for a movie.
Zemeckis feels that a key opening shot
in his movies sets the tone for what follows.
Raoul J. Raoul, the live action
director of"Somethin's Cookin"
is played by Joel Silver
better known for his role as producer
of big budget action films such as
Die Hard and the Lethal Weapon series.
Born in England,
a 25-year-old Bob Hoskins
(Eddie Valiant) was sitting
in a pub next to a theatre
when a stranger told him to go upstairs
and read for the lead in a play.
He actually got the part.
After his first performance,
an agent advised him to take up
acting professionally.
Previously, he had been a porter,
circus fire eater, steeplejack, and seaman.
Eddie glances down at a small
Mickey Mouse figurine on the table.
The editor hunched over the moviola
is Morgan Deare, who also voices
Bongo, the ape bouncer
of the Ink and Paint Club.
The dialogue is a parody of lyrics
from an Irving Berlin song, "There's
No Business Like Show Business,"
written for Annie Get Your Gun.
The filmmakers thought Bob Hoskins
fit the 1940s style of detective better than
a contemporary star such as Harrison Ford.
Also considered were Robert Redford,
Jack Nicholson, and Ed Harris.
Said Bob, "I got the job because I'm a bit
cartoonish looking myself, don't you think?"
Before Roger Rabbit, Actor Bob Hoskins
was in Mona Lisa (1986), which drew acclaim
and an Academy Award® nomination.
This put producers on his trail
to cast him as Eddie Valiant.
Alan Tilvern (R.K. Maroon)
spent his early days
as a street market pitchman
where he learned to use his voice in
different ways to lure prospective customers.
Using this skill,
Tilvern appeared in more than 50 films,
including Bhowani Junction (1956)
Superman (1978), Little Shop Of Horrors (1986),
and the TV mini-series "Anno Domini."
Co-Executive Producer
Steven Spielberg had already
created seven of the top ten
grossing movies of all time
when he stepped in to help bring
Who Framed Roger Rabbit to the screen.
Spielberg drew top talent to this project.
He personally negotiated for
the appearance in one film of characters
owned by various movie studios- a first.
Trusting his Roger Rabbit production team,
Spielberg spent a good deal of this time in
China, directing Empire of the Sun (1987).
The musical chairs play
"Stars and Stripes Forever"
by John Philip Sousa.
This scene was the first completed
effects section. It generated tremendous
excitement and enthusiasm in the crew.
In what movie
did this elephant learn to fly?
Dumbo (1941) tells the story of
a baby elephant with ears so large he can fly.
In what film did
this ostrich ballerina make her debut?
The Ostrich ballet dancer
Mademoiselle Upanova was first seen
in the "Dance of the Hours" segment
of Fantasia (1940).
These famous brooms gave
Mickey Mouse a difficult time
in the "Sorcerer's Apprentice"
sequence in Fantasia (1940).
Hyacinth Hippo was the prima ballerina
in the "Dance of the Hours"
segment of Fantasia (1940).
Eddie's stroll through Maroon Studios
involved more than 180 individual elements.
When assembled, the various cel and
film pieces were in stacks eight feet tall
for only 30 seconds of screen time.
Maleficent's Goons
(Sleeping Beauty, Disney, 1959).
Brer Bear (Song of the South,
Disney, 1946); Koko the Clown
("Out of the Inkwell" series,
Fleischer, beginning 1919).
Co-Executive ProducerSteven Spielberg
asked screenwriters Jeffrey Price
and PeterS. Seamen for an underlying
subplot that motivates the villain.
Remembering the corrupt
water works officials in Chinatown
the writers developed
Judge Doom's scheme for the demise
of Los Angeles' transit systems.
Cloverleaf Industries is a take-off
on the name for the winding ramps
of freeway interchanges
which from an overhead view
resemble a four-leaf clover.
In 1935, Los Angeles had one of
the largest mass transit systems
in the world, known as the Red Car.
Each year more than 3,000 electric
trains carried 80 million passengers
efficiently over a 75-mile radius.
Roger Rabbit satirises how certain
American corporations collaborated
to use fake companies as fronts
to privatise the nation's streetcar systems
and drive them out of business.
This created a heavier reliance
on automobiles, which consume
more oil and rubber products.
In 1949, the bogus companies
were convicted of violating the Sherman
Antitrust Act and fined $5,000 each.
By 1960, 88% of the nation's highly efficient
transit systems had been eliminated.
Eddie is in the Terminal Bar,
representing the transportation terminal
that was in downtown Los Angeles.
You can hear a train running
on one of the underground lines.
Since Bob Hoskins normally
speaks with a bit of English cockney,
he had to learn to sound American.
"It was tough. Accents are a pain.
It takes time. I really have to work at it,"
said Hoskins.
Joanna Cassidy left
her New Jersey home at 27
for a career in Hollywood
making her debut in
The Laughing Policeman (1972)
with Walter Matthau.
Before Roger Rabbit,
Cassidy worked as a model,
in addition to commercials and TV.
Her films included The Bank Shot (1974)
and The Late Show (1977).
She gave a memorable performance
in Blade Runner (1982) as an exotic
"replicant" who dances with snakes.
In real life, Miss Cassidy had pet snakes.
Although a sequel was often rumoured,
Zemeckis was once quoted as saying
"The film was
a once-in-a-generation thing, like E.T."
A "prequel" with the working title
"Toon Platoon" nevergot
out of the development stage.
The nightclub was named after
the Ink & Paint building on the Disney Studio lot
where all the animators' pencil drawings
were hand traced with ink onto
clear celluloid sheets and painted.
"Walt sent me" refers to "Walt Disney."
Use of code words like this was a way
to gain admittance to private clubs.
The interiors were shot
at London's Elstree Studio.
Some sets were built 10 feet above
the soundstage floor to allow the puppeteers
to manipulate props from below.
Puppeteer David Alan Barclay
was also the chief puppeteer
forStar Wars' Jabba the Hut.
The Ink & Paint Club set was built
to the dimensions of a real nightclub
capable of seating 250-300 patrons.
"Hey, hey! Cut it out!"
The Toons' tune is
the "Hungarian Rhapsody" by Franz Liszt.
The classical composition was featured
in numerous cartoons, frequently
with characters on stage battling
to finish the piece.
"Doggone stubborn little... I'll get it!"
"Oh, yeah?!"
In the 1950s,
Stubby Kaye was a favourite on
the New York musical stage, television
and in films such as L'il Abner (1959),
and Guys And Dolls (1957) in which
he sang, "Sit Down You're Rockin' the Boat."
Warner Bros. Studio's Toon agents
agreed to this first time loan of their
cartoon stars Daffy Duck and Bugs Bunny
only if the pairgot equal screen time with
Disney stars Donald Duck and Mickey Mouse.
"This is hot stuff."
Who is this white fowl
and when did he make his screen debut?
"Wow!"
Donald Duck was introduced
in "The Wise Little Hen" (1934).
His first dialogue?...
"Who, me? Oh, no. I got a bellyache."
Who is this black mallard?
Daffy Duck made his debut in
"Porky's Duck Hunt" (Warner Bros., 1937),
directed by Tex Avery, with key scenes
animated by Bob Clampett.
Daffy got named in his second cartoon,
"Daffy Duck And Egghead" (1938).
This story is set in 1947. Not counting
Jessica, all the Toons in the nightclub
had appeared in movies
by that time except who?
The Penguins had been working
as waiters but were not cast in a film
until Mary Poppins, released in 1964.
However, that story took place in 1910,
so the penguins might have been
available for Roger Rabbit's tale.
In the 1930s, Betty Boop
was a very popular character in
mostly black and white cartoons.
She was created by
the FleischerStudios, who also started
the Popeye the Sailor cartoon series.
Mae Questel was the voice
of Betty Boop from 1930until
the character was retired in 1949.
Miss Questel recreated
her famous character in this
memorable cameo appearance.
Jessica's song by Joe McCoy
was a hit for singer Peggy Lee in 1943.
From what film
did these jazz musicians come?
The Crows helped Dumbo gain
the confidence to fly in 1941, where they sang
the hit tune "When I See An Elephant Fly."
Betty's voice was fashioned af ter Helen Kane,
a popular novelty singer of the 1920s and '30s.
Miss Kane coined the "Boop-oop-a-doop"
on stage while making fun of a song
she didn't like, and the phrase caught on.
Jessica fashioned herself af ter
the glamorous stars of old Hollywood,
such as Rita Hayworth, Lauren Bacall,
and Jane Russell.
Her hairdo was inspired by
Veronica Lake's famous "peek-a-boo" bangs.
Jessica's sultry stage style is an homage
to Red Hot Riding Hood from M-G-M cartoons.
Actress Amy Irving provided
the singing voice for Jessica.
Irving was known for her role in Yentl (1983)
and was married to Steven Spielberg
at the time.
Jessica was the most complex
character in terms of effects.
Separate elements were needed
for her shadow, hair, skin, and dress.
Her costume alone required three layers
just to make it shimmer and sparkle.
Ed Jones at Industrial Light and Magic
supervised photographing the 1,035
optical illusions needed for Roger Rabbit.
Each effect required from 15 to 185 shots.
Effects supervisor Ken Ralston commented,
"It was the equivalent of 10 films."
The dark look of the movie was inspired
by the "film noir" black and white
detective mysteries of the 1940s.
Director Zemeckis called this "cartoon noir."
Eddie's character was a spoof
of Humphrey Bogart's portrayals
of cynical detectives
Sam Spade in The Maltese Falcon (1941)
and The Big Sleep's Philip Marlowe (1946).
The movie Chinatown (1974) was influential
in the making of Roger Rabbit.
That film was a stylish detective film set
in 1930s Los Angeles, and was a favourite
of the Roger Rabbit screenwriters.
Roger's angst is styled after
Burt Young's character chewing
the Venetian blinds in the movie Chinatown.
In keeping with the 1940s period,
Director Robert Zemeckis wanted
classically cartoony sounding voices
for the new characters.
Before creating
the original voice of Roger Rabbit,
Charles Fleischer was a stand- up comic
who performed regularly
at the Comedy Store in Los Angeles.
Zemeckis remembered seeing Fleischer
on stage eight years before making the movie
and ultimately called him in
to audition for various Toon roles.
Roger morphs into a whistle
once common to signal important
times of the day at factories.
Fleischer also read the part of
Roger Rabbit during screen tests
for the Eddie Valiant character.
By the third test,
everyone agreed Charlie should be Roger.
No one else was considered.
Aftergrowing up in Washington, D. C.,
Charles Fleischer spent 15 years
working night clubs and in minor film roles.
He had parts in The Hand (1981), Night Shift
(1982), Nightmare On Elm Street (1984),
and laterStraight Talk (1992).
Zemeckis encouraged
Charles's Roger to talk fast and develop
some kind of speech impediment
believing most of the best, classic Toons
had unique speech mannerisms.
In addition to Roger, Fleischer
also created the voices of Benny the Cab,
and two weasels- Greasy and Psycho.
The rabbit couple dined at
the Brown Derby in Hollywood,
which was famous for
celebrity drawings on the walls.
Find the portrait of Mickey Mouse.
The words on the glass door to Eddie's
office are classically photographed
from the inside in the style of
film noir detective movies.
Eddie hangs his hat
on a Maltese Falcon, like the prop
in the classic 1941 Warner Bros.
detective movie of the same name.
This scene was re-shot and re-edited
after the character design of Jessica changed.
After the film, Bob Hoskins took
his family to Antigua for a vacation.
Hoskins' wife insisted that
he keep his shirt on while on the beach
since the actor's body was covered
with bruises from the shooting.
She did not want to look like a husband basher.
Eddie's brother, Teddy, is portrayed
by Eugene Guirterrez only in stills.
Richard Le Parmentier
(Lt. Santino) seen in Rollerball (1975),
Star Wars (1977) as General Motti
Superman II (1980), and
the TV mini-series "London Embassy" (1987).
The Acme Warehouse was actually
an empty electrical testing station
in the Shepherd's Bush area of London.
Since they were altering the appearance
of the building, it was necessary
to complete photography
as quickly as possible.
There was around-the-clock filming
going on five days a week for six weeks.
The palm trees were shipped over from Spain.
Who is this ornery pint-sized cowboy?
Yosemite Sam first roared onto the screen
in Warner Bros. "Hare Trigger" (1944).
Yosemite Sam was
originally voiced by veteran Mel Blanc
but the vocally tough character
was recreated here by Joe Alasky.
The mallet knocks stacks
ofSinging Swords, which are
featured later in the final duel.
Roger Rabbit merchandise
available to the public ranged from
coffee mugs and t-shirts
to expensive jewellery and jackets
with character appliqués.
One rejected proposal
was for an inflatable Jessica doll.
Every frame was animated
(24 frames per second) as opposed to
the short cuts taken forTV animation
which repeats frames
so that drawings only change every
2nd or 4th frame; sometimes even less.
All scenes were hand-drawn.
There were no short cuts and
no computer-assisted graphics.
82,080 frames
(with multiple layers of animation)
were hand-drawn for the film.
Including concept and story sketches,
Richard Williams estimates that
a million drawings went into making
Who Framed Roger Rabbit.
Christopher Lloyd was previously
seen in Back To The Future (1985)
and on the TV series "Taxi."
Born in Stamford, Connecticut,
Christopher Lloyd explored his craft
through New York stage work along with
Meryl Streep and Christopher Walken.
Director Milos Forman asked
Lloyd to make his film debut in
One Flew OverThe Cuckoo's Nest (1975).
His later films included Mel Brooks'
What Disney film was also
infested by weasels?
Although these weasels
are unique to Roger Rabbit,
they bear a suspicious resemblance
to the slithery villains of
the "Wind in the Willows" segment
of The Adventures
of Ichabod and Mr. Toad (1949).
There, a pack of weasels manage
to overrun the Toad Hall estate.
"The Sneezing Weasel"
(Warner Bros. 1938, directed by Tex Avery)
may be a distant cousin.
The ingredients of"dip" - turpentine,
acetone, and benzene - are all commonly
used as paint thinners and solvents
which of course would destroy
cartoon characters painted on cels.
Actor Lou Hirsch
(voice of Adult Baby Herman)
was spotted in the TV mini- series
"London Embassy" (1987)
and the movies Superman III (1983)
and Haunted Honeymoon (1986).
In the book that inspired the movie,
Baby Herman is 33. Here, he is 50.
The comic strip characters of the book
were changed to cartoon stars
to be more cinematic.
For character design, artists looked
at dozens of vintage magazine ads
of the 1940s showing babies,
as well as the "Baby Weems" sequence
of The Reluctant Dragon (1941).
326 animators and support staff
worked on the film;
254 in London for more than a year
and 72 in Los Angeles for eight months.
Roger Rabbit slightly resembles
a very early Walt Disney character,
Oswald the Lucky Rabbit.
Both are white rabbits who
walk upright and wear overalls.
Early on, Animation Director Williams analysed
the design of Roger
as having a Tex Avery neck
and a Disney body
with the lower face
in the style of Warner Bros. characters.
Richard Williams on Roger;
"With the red overalls, white body,
and blue bow tie, he became like
an American flag."
As a youngster,
Richard Williams was knocked out by
Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs (1937),
saying, "I was fascinated
by the fact that cartoons could appear
to walk and talk and even think."
That experience started his animation career.
Notice how the camera
moves throughout the movie.
This made animation extremely difficult
but added to the dimensional look
of the Toons.
Roger does a take-off of square-jawed,
comic strip detective Dick Tracy.
Animation Director Richard Williams
filmed Charles Fleischer saying
"P-P-Pleeeese" as a guide for animating
the movement of Roger's mouth.
As with all the live-action/ animated scenes,
Roger Rabbit was added months later.
Hoskins was up to the challenge
of acting alone, but considered
this scene the hardest one to do.
To prepare for scenes like this,
Hoskins studied his three-year-old daughter
with her imaginary playmates.
Richard Williams and Robert Zemeckis
agreed there could be no cost cutting
that could spoil the illusion.
All animation would be
hand drawn for each frame of film
(24 frames equal one second on the screen).
Animation Director Richard Williams
commented about how Toons had been
combined with humans in past films;
"You see the trick and are not able
to suspend your disbelief."
Animation Director Richard Williams
set out to break three rules that previously
had been conventions for combining
live action with animation.
1. Move the camera as much
as possible so the Toons don't look
pasted onto flat backgrounds.
2. Use lighting and shadows to an extreme
that had never before been attempted
(each shadow required at least
five optical effects elements).
3. Have the Toons interact with real world
objects and people as much as possible.
Each weasel in these scenes had five layers
of special, hand painted, lighting effects
to give them a three-dimensional quality.
That added up to 25 pieces of artwork
for each frame or 600 drawings per second.
Before the weasel got a hold
of this soap, it was carried around
the live-action set by a puppeteer.
The puppeteer with the thinnest hand
was chosen so that his hand could
later be covered up by the Toon.
Because the camera kept moving,
changing the point of view
animators had to work extra hard
so the Toons wouldn't appear to be
slipping or sliding around over the set.
Mae West was an actress who gained
great popularity in the 1930s. Her comedy
was marked by its campy, suggestive humour.
Dolores's upcoming line is a parody of
a typical Mae West line, "Is that a gun in
your pocket or are you just happy to see me?"
Animation Director Williams commented
how an early comedy team
influenced this film;
"Laurel and Hardy are funny
because they're constantly getting
tangled up physically with each other."
"We thought the cartoon characters
should always be affecting their environment
orgetting tangled up with the live actors."
Filmmakers originally planned
to have 40 minutes of animation,
but ended up with 55 minutes
out of the total 104 minutes of the film.
The animation took two years to complete,
with animators sometimes having
to work 20 hours a day to meet deadlines.
Following this scene, the film's original script
included Marvin Acme's funeral.
Planned as a major animated sequence,
the idea went only as far as storyboards
and preliminary dialogue recording
before being abandoned.
At the funeral,
Eddie was to get a clue that lead to
another scene that was also deleted here.
In that sequence, Judge Doom caught
Eddie snooping around Jessica's room.
To teach him a lesson, Doom had the weasels
take the nosey detective to Toontown.
Moments later in that deleted scene,
Eddie is kicked out of Toontown
with a cartoon pig on his head.
To cover the deletion, Eddie answers Dolores
off camera - a line change dubbed in later.
He returns to his office to wash
the painted pig head off with turpentine.
That's why he is coming out
of the shower here.
As with most films,
many bits like that were trimmed out
of the movie to keep the pace going.
In addition, co-writer Jeffrey Price
thought it was funnier to show
the similarity between humans and Toons
rather than bringing attention
to their differences.
Portions of the "Pig Head Sequence"
were cut back into
the 1991 CBS telecast of the film.
The original theatrical trailer
also contained some of the footage.
"You'll never work in this town again,"
is a cliché line about how film industry
executives abuse power
to threaten people into cooperation.
Actress Kathleen Turner wanted to
work again with director Zemeckis
after Romancing The Stone (1984).
As Jessica's voice, she asked for
her performance to be uncredited.
It didn't stay a secret for long.
Joanna Cassidy changed
her hair colour because her natural red
was too similar to Jessica's red hair.
Perhaps Jessica didn't want any competition.
The film had been in and out of development
for four years when exterior filming
finally began in Los Angeles, California
in December, 1986.
On Richard Williams' first trip
to Disney Studios in 1948, he stayed
at the YMCA on Hope Street in
downtown Los Angeles... this same street!
This tune became so well known
because it was used
as what theme music?
"The Merry-Go-Round Broke Down"
is the familiar theme song for
the Warner Bros. Looney Tunes cartoons.
The original Friend-Franklyn song
has lyrics, although they were
not used for the cartoon overture.
Roger's lyrics were written
just for this film.
"Toon" was popularised
for the first time in this film
to describe an animated character
from the cartoon world.
Costume Designer
Joanna Johnston specialised
in period costumes
withThe French Lieutenant's Woman (1981),
Pirates of Penzance (1982), and
Indiana Jones and the Temple Of Doom (1984).
Miss Johnston won Academy Awards®
for her clothing designs in Tess (1979)
and Death on the Nile (1978).
Production Designer
Elliot Scott began
designing sets in 1933
and became
Supervising Art Director
at M-G-M's British studio.
Scott helped create the atmosphere of films
like Mogambo (1953), Tom Thumb (1958),
The Haunting (1963)
The Americanization of Emily (1964),
Dragonslayer (1981) and
the second Indiana Jones film in 1984.
The bar patron introduces Judge Doom
to a non-existent "Harvey."
Harvey was a comedy play produced in 1944
about a man with an invisible rabbit friend.
Jimmy Stewart starred in
the 1950 film adaptation.
Before CDs, music was played on records.
This vintage 1920s-style gramophone
had a heavy needle that projected
the sound through a metal horn.
The first records only played one song
and rotated at 78 revolutions per minute (rpm).
78s, as they were called, were easily
breakable before soft vinyl was developed.
Doom is tapping out the rhythmic phrase,
"Shave and a haircut..."
which is answered musically, "Two bits."
Two bits is slang for a quarter- 25 cents.
Zemeckis described
giving feedback to the animators;
"I worked with the performances
[not details of the drawings],
the same way I would an actor in rehearsal.
They'd sketch a pose as I explained."
Animator Dave Spafford commented,
"Bob Hoskins was so good
he stole the show in every shot."
"We knew we'd be in trouble
if he was more animated than we were.
We had to pull all the stops out
to compete with him."
This arguing banter to confuse
someone by changing pronouns
was a standard comedy routine.
Warner Bros. first used it
in "A Wild Hare" (1940).
The classic cartoon, "Rabbit Seasoning" (1952)
was built around repeating this gag
with Daffy Duck declaring his
now famous realisation, "Pronoun trouble."
A longer, more involved fight in the bar
was filmed, but cut for pacing.
Each frame of a live-action scene
was transferred into a large
black and white photograph.
The animators registered their drawings
on top of each photo to know where
the characters should be in a scene.
Later, the finished, colour animation
was combined with the colour,
live-action film through special cameras.
Director Robert Zemeckis expressed
his trust in Animation Director
Richard Williams by stating
"I never worried about the animation.
I knew it would be breathtaking."
Benny refers to a running joke in this era
that it never rained in California,
known as the land of perpetual sunshine.
Benny makes a period joke about
the Brooklyn Dodgers baseball team.
Later than the time of this film,
they moved to California.
In the novel, Benny was a beetle,
not a cab, and had a very minor part.
Some scenes of Eddie Valiant
in the taxi are actually drawings,
not live-action footage of Bob Hoskins.
The sign suddenly appearing
is a Tex Avery-style gag.
Benny references a "bridge,"
as the middle section of a song,
which connects two musical ideas.
This is the Hyperion Bridge
in Los Angeles' Silverlake-Atwater
region, near DodgerStadium.
In real life, this street
leads to the site of the 1930s
Walt Disney Studios on Hyperion Avenue
where Mickey Mouse and Snow White
were created just a few blocks ahead.
The cartoon is "Goofy Gymnastics" (1949).
The success of the cartoon at the beginning
of the feature led to the creation of
three more Roger Rabbit short subjects.
"Tummy Trouble"
was released in the summer of 1989
with the feature, Honey, I Shrunk the Kids.
It was the first new Disney
short cartoon release
since "Goofy's Freeway Trouble" in 1965.
To maintain the quality established
in the feature, "Tummy Trouble"
was the most expensive
short cartoon ever made.
It took four months to create.
AnimatorTom Sito
pointed out that for "Tummy Trouble"
they had to develop an ending format
since the cartoon in the feature
stops before the story is finished.
For "Roller Coaster Rabbit,"
Director Rob Minkoff said they tried
to "keep Roger up in the air and take
Tex Avery's style to the Nth degree."
"Trail Mix-Up" was released in 1993
with A Far Off Place.
A key animator for Roger Rabbit
was James Baxter, who was
the main animator for Belle
in Beauty and the Beast (1991).
Already a successful animator,
Richard Williams said, "When I saw
the tiger in The Jungle Book (Disney, 1967),
I was bowled over.
I thought,
I don't know beans about animation."
Williams then went on a new 10-year
training effort to further improve his craft.
On the screen is a newsreel.
The Studios produced these
10-minute summaries of world events.
Like short cartoons, they were
shown in theatres before features.
That's how people saw
the news before television.
There was a theatre in the old theatre
district of downtown Los Angeles
that showed nothing but newsreels.
Newsreels were produced up into the 1960s.
This scene was shot during a two-day period
at Gray's State Theatre in Essex, England.
At 2,000 seats it was the largest
single screen theatre still operating in Europe.
The Ren MarStudio in Los Angeles
doubled for Maroon Studios.
The close-up of the soundstages
at Maroon Cartoon Studios were filmed
at the Shepherd's Bush Bus Depot
in London, England.
Universal Studios
put Steven Spielberg
under contract after seeing
his short film, Amblin
which he made as a student at
California State University at Long Beach.
Spielberg scored his first hit with
the made-for-TV suspense thriller Duel (1971).
Feature films followed with
Sugarland Express (1974), Jaws (1975),
and Close Encounters of the Third Kind (1977).
Born in Cincinnati, Ohio,
and raised in Phoenix, Arizona,
Spielberg started making movies at age 13.
Spielberg went on to become a successful
filmmaker, and in 1984 he formed his own
production company, Amblin Entertainment.
Co-producer Robert Watts helped bring
to the screen numerous landmark films
such as Thunderball (1965), 2001 (1968),
Star Wars (1977), and Return of the Jedi (1983).
Robert Watts said Roger Rabbit was
the most difficult of all the films he'd done.
But in the end it was worthwhile
because it was unique.
Editor ArthurSchmidt "cut his teeth"
on Marathon Man (1976)
and later edited Idolmaker (1980),
Back to the Future (1985),
and Ruthless People (1986).
Schmidt received an Academy Award®
nomination for his work on
Coal Miner's Daughter (1980).
Co-producer Frank Marshall
gave up law school for film production.
Marshall's credits include
What's Up, Doc? (1972), Paper Moon (1973),
Raiders of the Lost Ark (1981), E.T. (1982),
Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom (1984),
and Back to the Future (1985).
Richard Williams received
240 awards prior to Roger Rabbit
among them an Academy Award
in 1972 for "A Christmas Carol"
as the Best Animated Short Subject.
This movie inspired
a whole new land at Disneyland Park®,
called "Mickey's Toontown."
This tunnel to Toontown was also used as
The tunnel was photographed near
the Griffith Park Observatory
in Los Angeles, California.
The plaque inside of Eddie's Toon
gun case reads, "Thanks forgetting me
out of the Hoosegow. Yosemite Sam"
Hoosegow is slang for jail.
The left bullet is voiced by character actor
Pat Buttram, whose voices for Disney included
The Aristocats (1970) and Robin Hood (1973).
The inscription and bullets suggest
the previous, close relationship
Eddie had with the Toons.
Bob Hoskins exaggerated
his movements once inside Toontown.
Bob Hoskins said, "Eddie had to be
part cartoon himself, yet not too broad,
in order to make the film believable.
I hallucinated all the Toons."
The song "Smile, Darn Ya, Smile"
is featured in a 1931 Warner Bros.
Merrie Melodie cartoon with the same title.
Step through or slow motion.
Mickey's Orphans, Chicken Little
(red vest), Wynken, Blynken and Nod
(riding blue bird)
Cupids, Baby Pegasus (Fantasia)
Ground hogs (Song of the South)
Peter Pig (The Wise Little Hen)
Girl bunnies (Tortoise and the Hare)
More Disney characters in next shot.
Right to left: Brer Bear (Song of the South)
Ferdinand, the Bull
Danny (lamb, So DearTo My Heart)
Jenny Wren (Who Killed Cock Robin?)
Fiddler Pig, Fifer Pig (Three Little Pigs)
Elmer Elephant (behind pigs)
The Merry Dwarfs
The Reluctant Dragon, Jiminy Cricket
Resume Play orSlow Motion
Press "Pause" on your remote
and try to identify the Disney
characters in downtown Toontown.
Step frame by frame, or advance
by slow motion to see the entire
scene. Answers appear briefly
as characters exit.
Left: Fifer Pig, Fiddler Pig, Red Riding Hood
Right: Snow White, Old Hag
Back of fire engine: J. Thaddeus Toad
Centre: Goofy on pogo stick
The Reluctant Dragon chased by Sir Giles
Right: The Big Bad Wolf
The Seven Dwarfs marched upper left.
Resume play.
Discarded ideas included chasing
Jessica through several buildings,
and across a desert.
Who is this cute, quiet canine critter?
The basset hound Droopy was
a Tex Avery creation at M-G-M.
Droopy's personality was based on
the voice of Bill Thompson as Mr. Whipple
on the "Fibber McGee and Molly" radio show.
Directing Animator Richard Williams
gave voice to Droopy.
Apparently he spoke for Droopy during
storyboard meetings and got the job.
The gags with Lena Hyena were inspired
by Grandma in the M-G-M Tex Avery cartoons
"Red Hot Riding Hood" (1943),
"Swing Shift Cinderella" and
"Little Rural Riding Hood" (both 1949).
The Doorknob
(Alice in Wonderland, Disney, 1951)
Who is the cute canary?
Tweety played "This little piggy..."
in his screen debut, "A Tale of Two Kitties"
(Warner Bros., 1942),
and it became a trademark gag.
Bob Hoskins was excited
about playing Eddie Valiant
"because I wanted to tell my grandchildren
I once co-starred with Bugs Bunny."
Mickey Mouse celebrated his 60th birthday
during the release of this film.
Although Wayne Allwine had performed
as Mickey Mouse previously
Allwine became Mickey's new
official voice at the time of this film
through the establishment
of the Disney Character Voices
department in 1988.
Lena Hyena (Toon Hag in the credits)
was voiced by actress June Foray
best known for
Rocky the Flying Squirrel and Natasha in
"The Adventures of Rocky and Bullwinkle."
June Foray also voiced Granny
for the Warner Bros.
Tweety and Sylvester cartoons
and the weasel Wheezy's voice in this film.
Eddie's shadow
impersonates Dick Tracy.
"Cartoon" is derived from
the Italian "cartone," (cardboard).
Originally it referred
to an artist's preparatory drawing
copied onto another surface
as an outline for creating paintings,
tapestries, and other forms of finished art.
Later, newspapers published single-panel
editorial cartoons and comic strip stories.
After motion pictures were invented,
pencil drawings came to life on film.
Those animated shorts in the early 1900s
were called cartoons, and the name lasted.
The poster behind Jessica
is for Blamo exploding cigars.
Bob Hoskins' son was reportedly upset
that his father hadn't brought any of
Dad's cartoon co- stars home to meet him.
Director Robert Zemeckis had previously
directed Romancing the Stone (1984)
starring Kathleen Turner
and the mega hit Back to the Future (1985).
Born in Chicago, Zemeckis
won a Best Student Film award
at USC for "Field of Honor" in 1973.
Steven Spielberg was so impressed with
the film, he hired Zemeckis to direct
the feature about Beatles' fans,
I Wanna Hold Your Hand (1978).
Zemeckis directed
and co-wrote 1941, released in 1979,
and Used Cars (1980) starring Kurt Russell.
Russell later screen tested as Eddie Valiant.
Zemeckis said Who Framed Roger Rabbit
was "akin to scaling Mt. Everest."
Robert Zemeckis originally saw a draft
of the script in 1982 and was intrigued.
The project did not progress until 1985 when
the new management at Disney teamed with
Steven Spielberg to combine their resources.
Zemeckis, who had just directed
Back To The Future (1985) forSpielberg,
was offered the new script.
The search began for a suitably zany,
unconventional animation director
who could help bring the project to life.
London-based animator
Richard Williams
had previously created
beverage commercials forTV
that combined dimensional-looking animation
with live action in a realistic way.
Williams had also finished some
unusual scenes on his pet project
The Thief and the Cobbler.
These works caught the attention
of Roger Rabbit producers
Frank Marshall and Robert Watts
and the whole team realised
Williams was the talent
for whom they'd been searching.
Animation Director Richard Williams
animated the opening titles for
Return Of The Pink Panther (1975)
The Pink PantherStrikes Again (1976),
What's New Pussycat? (1965),
and Casino Royale (1967).
The yellow hole
is a silhouette of Mickey Mouse.
The filmmakers chose 1947 for
a "Once upon a time" quality to make
the premise more acceptable,
like a fairy tale.
Judge Doom, Dolores, R.K. Maroon,
the weasels, and the transit system subplot were
inventions for the film
not in the original novel.
The number 10 was Los Angeles' first freeway.
It travelled the route Doom describes
but has fewer lanes.
His comments were sort of an inside joke
for L.A. audiences.
Originally budgeted at $27.5 million,
the film ended up costing around $45 million,
making it one of the most
expensive movies of its time.
The animation averaged between
$250,000 and $300,000 a minute.
A menacing shadow is cast on the back wall.
George Gibbs supervised
30 special effects technicians
in advanced servo-hydraulics
computerised electronics,
and micro-robotics
to manipulate the real objects that
the Toons would later appear to be moving.
His special effects work can also be seen
in Superman (1978), Flash Gordon (1980)
Conan the Barbarian (1982) and
Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom (1984).
On this film, Gibbs said he was
most proud of inventing the Dipmobile.
Bob Hoskins believes there's
a little bit of a toughguy in everyone.
"The good thing about being
an actor is that you can let it out,
then go home and be a nice guy."
Freeze frame the shot when
Eddie presses a button for the calliope,
and check out the "tunes."
Find the "hidden Mickey"
when Eddie dances.
The bowling balls formed into a V
create that familiar silhouette.
Cinematographer Dean Cundey
became adept at handling effects films
withThe Thing (1982)
Back To The Future (1985),
and Big Business (1988).
He also worked with Zemeckis
on Romancing The Stone (1984).
Cundey originally studied to be
an art director. After a cinematography
course at UCLA, he switched.
"I discovered you could change
the mood of a scene or the look
of a set just by different lighting.
I wanted to deal with (those elemente)
instead of backgrounds."
The upcoming "Singing Sword" gag may have
been inspired by the Academy Award®
winning Warner Bros. cartoon
"Knighty Knight Bugs" (1958).
The Singing Sword bears the likeness of
singer Frank Sinatra and croons several bars
of his Coleman-Leigh hit "Witchcraft."
The ends of the lightning bolts
have hands on them trying to pull
Judge Doom's sword away from him.
Composer Alan Silvestri plays drums,
piano, guitar, and woodwinds, and
originally started out to be a musician
touring with bands.
Silvestri got stranded in Los Angeles
when a record deal fell through,
but was hired to write
music for the TV series "CHiPs,"
which began his composing career.
Silvestri was hired by director Zemeckis
to compose Romancing the Stone (1984)
followed by Back to the Future (1985),
whichgarnered two
Grammy® Award nominations.
Silvestri also scored Flight of the Navigator
(1986) and Outrageous Fortune (1987).
BothSteven Spielberg and Terry Gilliam
considered directing this movie,
but ultimately chose different projects.
Richard Williams was reluctant
to accept the Roger Rabbit project.
Williams was concerned about the years
away from his established commercial work and
his continuing pet feature project,
The Thief and the Cobbler.
Veteran Animation Director
Chuck Jones encouraged Williams
to join the Zemeckis-Spielberg team,
saying, "You can't turn down a chance
to work with these guys."
Jones also consulted on the film.
After 27 years in and out of production,
The Thief and the Cobbler was finished
and released in 1995 by Miramax,
under the title Arabian Knight.
The video release
went back to the original title.
Academy Award® winner Ken Ralston,
previously supervised effects for
StarTrek II (1982), Cocoon (1983)
StarTrek III (1984),
What famous lines does Doom use?
Doom quotes the Wicked Witch of the West's
death by water from The Wizard of Oz (1939).
Play the moving train frame-by-frame
and look for cameos in the windows.
The two trees embracing were the stars
of "Flowers and Trees," Walt Disney's
first colourSilly Symphony cartoon (1932).
After the film's success, there were
a slew of TV commercials that tried
to imitate Roger's combination
animation-and-live-action techniques.
Peter (Peter and the Wolf, 1946)
Animals (Johnny Appleseed, 1947)
Tree couple (Flowers and Trees, 1932)
PRESS PAUSE orSLOW MOTION:
How many characters
can you recognise in the finale?
Answers will appear on their first appearance,
reading left to right.
Pinocchio, Pluto, Daffy Duck, Baby Herman,
Minnie Mouse, Goofy, Mickey Mouse,
Dopey, Yosemite Sam, Bugs Bunny, Peter,
Betty Boop, Donald Duck, Tweety
Road Runner, Droopy,
Cyril (Mr. Toad's horse), Jose Carioca,
Bambi, Singing Harp, Koko the Clown
Monty (pelican), Brer Bear, Sylvester,
Marc Antony (bulldog), Woody Woodpecker,
Big Bad Wolf, Snow White, Penguin,
Marvin Martian, Foghorn Leghorn
What was Steven Spielberg's
Amblin Entertainment's
next association with
Warner Bros. cartoons?
Steven Spielberg teamed
with Warner Bros. to produce
the TV series "Tiny Toons."
Based on a youngergeneration
of Looney Tunes characters,
the series debuted in 1990-
sixty years after the first
Warner Bros. theatrical cartoon was made.
Animators sang for the final reprise
of"Smile, Darn Ya, Smile."
Who is this "hammy" actor?
After his 1935 debut, Porky Pig closed
many of the early Warner Bros. Looney Tunes
cartoons with this now familiar signature.
Screenwriters Jeffrey Price
and PeterS. Seamen met working
together at an advertising agency.
The team also wrote Trenchcoat (1983),
and later Wild, Wild West (1999) and
How The GrinchStole Christmas (2000).
Kathleen Kennedy began her career at
a San Diego TV station while still in college.
Kennedy went on to co-produce movies
such as E.T. (1982), The Color Purple (1985),
and Back to the Future (1985).
Some live actors turned down the role
of Eddie Valiant because they were
concerned about being upstaged by a Toon.
Don Hahn went on to produce
such Disney classics as
Beauty and the Beast (1991)
and The Lion King (1994).
Audiences frequently applauded
the film's original trailer when it
played in theatres prior to release.
Tony Anselmo became
the new official voice
of Donald Duck
at the time of this film.
He learned the craft directly from
Donald's vocal creator Clarence Nash,
and spent two years developing
the correct technique.
The exceptionally talented Mel Blanc
created voices for nearly all
the Warner Bros. characters.
For this film he once again gave
voices to Bugs Bunny, Daffy Duck,
Porky Pig, and Tweety Bird.
Mel Blanc passed away in 1989,
the year after this film.
The film premiered at Radio City Music Hall
in New York on June 21, 1988 and went into
nationwide release the following day.
The film itself got mostly glowing reviews-
especially for its groundbreaking
technical achievements.
With 743 people having worked on the film,
reviewers commented this was the longest list
of credits in a movie up to that time
running more than six and a half minutes.
Who Framed Roger Rabbit received
Academy Award® nominations
for Best Art Direction,
Cinematography, and Sound.
It won Oscars® for Best Visual Effects,
Editing, and Sound Editing.
Richard Williams also received
a Special Achievement Award from
the Academy of Motion Picture
Arts and Sciences.
Many of the animation crew embellished
what they learned from this experience
in subsequent Disney features
like Oliver & Co. (1988),
The Little Mermaid (1989),
and Beauty and the Beast (1991).
In its first five days of release,
Who Framed Roger Rabbit
made twice the money of any other
film in theatres at the time.
It went on to become the year's
top grossing movie in the U.S.
International successes followed, with
the film breaking attendance records
in Great Britain, Sweden, Switzerland,
Italy, Japan, and New Zealand.
Industrial Light and Magic (I.L.M.)'s
Academy Award® forSpecial Effects
on this film was the company's ninth win.
Industrial Light and Magic (I. L. M.)
was founded in Van Nuys, California,
a suburb of Los Angeles
in the mid-1970s to create
never-before-seen visual effects
for George Lucas' Star Wars (1977).
What Disney animated feature
used existing rock 'n' roll songs
in addition to new music
by Alan Silvestri?
Alan Silvestri wrote the score
to Lilo & Stitch (2002).
The score for
Who Framed Roger Rabbit
was recorded by
the London Symphony Orchestra.
Although the film's title is a question,
no question mark appears in the title
as that is considered bad luck
in the film industry.
Didn't see some of your favourite Toons?
Perhaps they weren't around in 1947.