ANNOUNCER:
The following program
is brought to you
in living color on NBC.
(fanfare plays)
MAN:
Hyah! Hyah!
Freddy... I'm homesick.
Would you buy me a drink?
Me buy you a drink?
(scoffs)
Your job's hustling drinks
from the customers.
But I've been trying!
I can't get anybody
to buy me anything.
Maybe if you'd stop crying
in their beer
all the time
about being homesick...
- (ruffles cards)
- ...you'd make out better.
It's a long walk
back to Memphis, Tennessee.
You'd throw me out
in the street, wouldn't you?
Your cut on them drinks is
what we're gonna
have to eat on tonight.
I haven't been able
to start a game all day.
HOSS:
Go on in and get me a beer.
I'm going to go in here and see
Dave Stone a minute.
LITTLE JOE:
Right.
Sherry, those boys just
coming in--the Cartwrights--
they own a big ranch.
Get busy.
The young one is just a baby.
So sell him milk.
Long as you get your cut.
Howdy, boys, and welcome.
My name's Sheribelle.
You can call me Sherry.
Uh, pleased to meet you.
I'm Adam Cartwright.
This is my brother Joe.
Howdy-do?
It's my pleasure, ma'am.
Would you like to have
a drink with us?
Why, thank you.
I believe
I might just do that.
Hey, Dave,
let me have four beers.
Hoss will be along in a minute.
(coin clinks on table)
ADAM:
Uh, my turn to pay, isn't it?
LITTLE JOE:
No, I've got it.
(chuckles) Let's play blackjack
and win enough to buy champagne.
Is the only thing
you ever drink champagne?
You'll have to catch me
to get your dollar back.
Oh, honey, I'm going
to catch you.
You can bet on that.
(Sheribelle laughing)
(shrieks)
(screams)
I'm sorry.
I... I didn't know
you were there.
Now... I'm trying
to apologize like a lady.
The least you can do is...
Will you let go of my arm?
Ow... ouch!
Take your hands off of me!
You're hurting my arm!
Will you let go of me?!
Let go of me, you big ape!
You're the ugliest man
I've ever seen!
(theme music playing)
(breathing heavily)
You got somethin'
to say to me?
No, not me.
Whiskey.
Well, I got money.
Don't suppose he's human.
Well, I'm not fixing
to find out.
You don't have to.
Well, he's a customer,
and customers are my business.
Hey, Sherry, better not.
I don't think
it's a good idea.
Well, maybe he'll buy me
some champagne.
Hey!
Big man!
Buy me a drink?
Wow. I like big men.
Even if they are
uglier than sin.
(laughing)
I don't especially
like 'em stupid.
(growls)
Why'd you call me that?
Look, uh, the lady didn't
mean anything by that.
Why'd you say that to me?
I'd like to apologize
for the lady.
I ain't talking to you!
Look, if you don't want
to accept an honest apology,
why don't you go back
to the bar and forget it, huh?
(Sherry screams)
(horse whinnies, gallops off)
(grunting, struggling)
One hour and 15 minutes...
and they ain't even moved
the last ten.
(both grunting)
Dad-gone!
I'm sure gettin' tired.
How 'bout you?
What are we
fighting about, you know?
I don't know!
(Hoss laughing)
(coughing)
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
You know, you're dang near
as strong as I am.
(coughs)
And you smell
nearly as bad, too.
(both laughing)
Come on... (laughing)
Hey, you don't suppose
they done something
to their heads, do you?
My goodness!
Two great big boys like you
fighting over
a little thing like me.
Gracious.
A body would think
you'd have better sense.
Not that it isn't flattering,
of course you understand, but...
My goodness...
where did you get
those shoulders?
Boy, Arnie, I swear, I...
I know some mules
that would like to be able
to kick as hard as you can hit.
Boys, please, you're...
you're making me
all butterflyish inside.
All that trouble over little me.
Uh, name's Sheribelle.
You can call me Sherry.
Sheribelle...
Now ain't that a purty name?
Ain't that a purty name, Hoss?
Yeah, that's... that's
a real pretty name.
Hoss, we got to get moving.
Pa's probably waiting
supper for us.
Arnie, these are my brothers.
This is Adam and Little Joe.
Hi, Arnie.
Purty, ain't they?
Well, they're not...
they're not really as bad
as they... they seem.
You fellas go on.
Me and Arnie's got
some talking we got to do.
Now, uh, Hoss, haven't we, uh,
lost enough time
on this already?
Go on, Adam.
They don't like me.
You'll... You'll learn
to like one another
once you get acquainted.
There!
I bet that didn't
hurt you a bit, did it?
Hurt me?
No, ma'am.
I've never seen anyone
with such big muscles.
Well, I sure hope Hoss
knows what he's doing.
Ah, you know he's always
picking up stray critters
bringing them home,
patching them up.
Remember that,
remember that grizzly cub
he found up on the Tahoe rim?
Yeah, well,
that was just a cub.
This time he's got himself
a full-grown bear.
(coyote howling)
ARNIE:
This is it, Hoss.
Arnie, this is where you live?
Oh, it's got a good roof on it.
HOSS:
Yeah.
Well...
I got you home
in one piece anyhow.
Hoss?
Yeah, Arnie?
Wasn't she the purtiest...
(chuckles)
the purtiest girl
you ever did see?
I ain't never seen nothin'
like her.
That's... That's her job,
being nice to folks, Arnie.
I wouldn't give her
too much credit.
Oh, no, Hoss,
she can't help being nice.
I can tell.
I'd like to see her s-some more.
Arnie, you don't, you don't
think for one minute that...
Well...
Well, what I'm, what I'm
trying to say is that...
Arnie, girls like Sheribelle,
they, they ain't interested
in a man unless he's got money.
Oh, I got some money.
A feller...
a feller give it to me.
What feller?
Some feller.
I don't know who he was.
I forget.
Oh... look here, let's...
let's get you out of here
and get you
into a rooming house somewhere.
I don't want that.
I don't like houses much.
Arnie, you can't just live here.
Well, this is a good place.
They ain't
nobody else a-around.
Hoss...
you're my friend,
ain't you, Hoss?
Sure I am, Arnie.
You ever have a friend before?
Sure I have.
Well, I was raised
with my brothers, Arnie.
Brothers is different.
I ain't never had
a friend before.
Course you have, Arnie.
No, I didn't!
You know why!
People get scared of me.
People just take one look
and-and they don't like me.
Well, I like you.
And I took
more than one look at you.
Well, well, well,
maybe...
you're...
a-a little more like me.
Your brothers--
they just took one look.
I can tell.
I always been able to tell.
Oh, I don't blame nobody.
Well, I ain't exactly
a palomino, myself.
Looks don't mean
everything, Arnie.
I-I guess I ain't
too smart, too.
People don't leave me alone.
I get mad sometimes.
I oughta be used to it,
but I get mad.
What I need's money, Hoss.
It's gonna take a lot of money.
What's gonna take
a lot of money?
My farm.
I-I used to live on a farm.
Y-You ever live on a farm, Hoss?
Yeah, I... I guess I sort of
live on a farm now.
Yeah?
Ain't nothin' like a farm.
I used to get up
real early in the morning
and go out and slop the pigs.
Whole bunch of
little old baby pigs.
They ain't hardly got
no hair at all--
just a-squealin'
and a-eatin' away.
And that ol' sow,
standin' over 'em,
making sure every one
of her little babies
gets enough to eat.
How come pigs
is better'n people?
You really liked it back there,
didn't you, Arnie?
They, they ain't nothin'
like a farm.
When I get my farm, ain't
gonna be nobody mean on it.
I'm gonna have cows and pigs
and maybe even some sheep.
And they all gonna get along
good together.
And just them animals and me.
And, well, maybe...
maybe somebody else.
How'd-How'd you like to come out
and go to work on my place?
The Ponderosa.
Well, what'll your brothers say?
Well, they ain't got
nothin' to do with it.
It's-It's up to me.
Me and my pa.
I-I could make some money.
Hoss, you think
Sh-Sheribelle would like me
i-if I was making some money?
(sighs):
I...
I wouldn't count on it
too much, Arnie.
That-That Sheribelle--
she's a... she's a funny girl.
That's the way I feel,
and I know Adam will
back me up all the way.
That's right, I do;
and I'm sorry, Hoss.
Now, wait a minute.
There ain't nothin' wrong
with Arnie.
He-He's just
a great big strong man.
He-He ain't too smart,
that's true.
But that don't mean
he can't do a job.
I'd just as soon have
a wild animal working for me.
He's strong as a bull
and just as dangerous.
You can't trust him!
That ain't true, Adam.
He don't mean no harm, Pa.
He-He don't mean no harm?!
I just won't be able
to use my jaw for a week.
Well, that'll be a relief.
All you do with it
is jaw, anyway.
Come on, the sun's up.
We got work to do.
Just remember, Hoss...
we didn't do anything
to make him that mad.
If you hadn't come along
when you did,
he might've killed somebody.
What about it, Hoss?
Is that the way it was?
Oh, it... wasn't
all that bad, Pa.
Sounds as though it were.
Why do you want to get mixed up
with somebody like that?
I guess I just understand him.
I sort of put myself
in his shoes.
When... When you're as big
as-as Arnie and me, Pa, you...
Well... there's some things
he's got to learn, Pa,
some things that I learned.
Don't you think he'd be
better off
learning those things
by himself, the way you did?
Pa, I didn't learn 'em
by myself.
I had you and Little Joe
and Adam to back me up.
Arnie ain't got nobody, Pa.
You mean he needs a friend?
He's got a friend, Pa.
A man like Arnie just
can't afford to go around
losing his temper
like ordinary folks.
He's got to learn to put up
with a little teasing.
Sometimes even from a girl.
He needs me, Pa,
to help him learn those things.
Can you teach him
to control his temper?
I won't stand
for any troublemaking.
Aw, Pa, Arnie ain't gonna
start no trouble.
He's pretty good at ending it.
Well... all right.
We can always use a good hand
on the Ponderosa.
Thanks, Pa.
Soon as I finish work,
I'll go into Virginia
and get him.
(door opens, closes)
(piano playing inside saloon)
(laughter in saloon)
(laughter)
SHERIBELLE:
Hey, everybody, look!
Look at the big muscle!
- (whoops)
- Hey!
(laughter)
Let's have a little drink, hmm?
ARNIE:
Mm-hmm.
SHERIBELLE:
All right, here we go.
(laughter)
Hello, Arnie.
Hoss, y-you come back.
Sheribelle,
this here is my friend.
You got lots of friends, Arnie.
S-Sit down, Hoss.
We're havin' a good time.
Yeah, I can see you are.
This here's Freddy.
He's a friend of mine, too.
- Any friend of Arnie's.
- Yeah, sure.
Take all you want, Hoss.
I-I paid for the whole bottle.
I was just saying, Arnie is
the strongest man I ever saw.
ARNIE:
Yeah, I-I'm awful strong.
Only, I guess Hoss
is about as strong.
Arnie, I got good news for you.
Yeah?
Me and my pa want you
to come to the Ponderosa
and go to work for us.
Sheribelle...
you hear that?
I-I got a job.
Whoopee!
That's wonderful.
Now you can buy me
some presents. (chuckles)
Sure I can.
I-I never thought of that.
I-I can buy you presents
and-and purty little things.
(Sheribelle laughs)
Arnie, aren't you
forgetting something?
What am I f-forgetting, Hoss?
Your-Your farm.
You was gonna save your money
and buy yourself a farm,
remember?
Oh, no, I wouldn't
forget that, Hoss.
I-I'm gonna have a farm.
You're going
to be a farmer, Arnie?
Uh-huh.
I'm gonna have a big farm.
Gonna raise pigs.
A pig farm.
(snickers)
Did you hear that, Freddy?
That's what you ought
to have Sheribelle--a farm.
You're too nice a girl
to work in a place like this.
That's exactly
the way I feel about it.
Well, I-I've always wanted
a little cottage
somewhere out in the country.
With roses.
Oh, yes!
With lots of pretty roses.
And maybe some
pretty little moo-cows.
FREDDY: Every girl ought
to have some moo-cows.
Shut up, both of you.
W-What's the matter, Hoss?
Well, Arnie, you're a long ways
from being ready
to raise moo-cows.
Well, a feller's got
to start somewheres.
They ain't nothin' wrong
with roses and-and stuff.
Hoss Cartwright,
you're just an old grouch.
I think it's wonderful
that Arnie wants me to have
all those pretty things.
And if Arnie wants moo-cows,
I think he should have moo-cows.
Fine.
I know where there's
10,000 of 'em, right now,
need to be taken care of.
Come on, Arnie, you got to
get up early on the Ponderosa.
Aw, Hoss, n-not right now.
Right now,
if you still want the job.
Oh, okay, Hoss.
Don't you worry none,
Sheribelle.
I-I'll come back, and
I'll bring you somethin' purty.
Sure.
Maybe just a little moo-cow.
(Arnie laughs,
others laugh at him)
There's your pony, Arnie.
He's all yours. Mount up.
This is my horse?
For as long as you want him.
That's the purtiest thing.
I-I come here,
I just had the clothes
I was wearin'.
Now I got a friend...
I got a job and...
and people are good to me,
and now you give me a horse.
(sobbing softly)
I-I don't know what to say.
Aw... you ain't
gotta say nothin'.
Go on, mount up. Let's go.
(cattle mooing)
Uh, hey, Pepe.
Uh, how do you say, uh, "pony"?
Caballo.
Come on, uh...
ca-ballo.
Let's go to work.
(Pepe laughs)
(cowhands shouting,
whooping in distance)
(cattle bellowing)
Doing real good, Arnie.
Sure a big fella.
Maybe bigger than you,
Señor Hoss.
Well, he ain't no smaller,
that's for sure.
And he eats twice as much.
I'd sure hate to have him
get mad at me.
Won't have to worry about that
as long as you feed him good.
We've got plenty
of frijoles, Señor Hoss.
(Pepe laughs)
(coyotes yipping,
howling in distance)
(Arnie sighs)
Well, I-I ate an awful lot.
Uh, did I eat too much, Hoss?
You always take what you want--
that's what it's here for.
I don't think you did
much good eating before.
Well, I-I used to get
awful hungry.
I-I ain't never
had a job before.
Arnie, you, uh,
you told me once
that a man gave you some money.
I don't want to talk about that.
(Pepe speaking Spanish)
(men laughing)
- What'd you say?!
- I say you'll never tire,
because you're the biggest
bean-eater in the country.
- You're a liar! You're a liar!
- No, Arnie, no! No! No!
- Señor Hoss! Señor Hoss!
- Arnie!
(Arnie panting)
Arnie, what'd he say to you?
They was laughin' at me!
Th-They was talkin' 'bout me!
We didn't laugh at him,
Señor Hoss.
We were only having
a little joke.
HOSS (panting):
I told you, he don't joke easy.
Arnie... we're your friends,
don't you understand that?
I-I'm real sorry, Hoss.
I just got mad.
I-I won't do it no more.
Honest, Hoss.
Arnie, I told you
you could work here, as...
as long as you didn't
cause no trouble.
Now that goes for fighting.
Anybody.
You gonna...
kick me off the ranch?
By golly, I ought to.
Well... I got it coming.
I'm sure gonna miss my horse.
Aw, shut up,
you ain't goin' no place.
But you said you was gonna--
I said I ought to,
and I oughta!
But I ain't gonna.
(horse approaching)
Go on and get you
a cup of coffee.
(horse whinnies)
What are you doing out here?
Pa sent me out to tell you...
- Hoss?
- In a minute, Arnie.
What's the matter,
you having trouble with him?
I can handle Arnie.
Ain't nothin' wrong, is there?
Yeah. Remember that squatter
you threw off the ranch
a couple of weeks ago?
Yeah, I ain't, I ain't likely
to forget Jake Staple.
Next to Arnie there, he's the
biggest man I ever tangled with.
Yeah, well, he's not
so big now; he's dead.
- Dead?! -Yeah, Sheriff rode in
late this afternoon.
Told Pa they found his body
up on the Carson.
He'd been robbed.
- Sheriff said--
- I want to tell you something...
Arnie, I told you I'd
talk to you in a minute.
Now, go on, sit down.
How was he killed?
Somebody broke his neck.
Snapped it like a matchstick.
Wow. That'd take some doin'.
- Yeah, it would.
- (Arnie panting)
What I got to say is,
I-I never mean to hurt nobody.
I just get...
well, I just get mad.
I-I don't know why,
I just get mad!
I don't wanna...!
(gasping, whimpering)
(sighs)
It's a scorcher out there.
Let's have another.
Hoss, there's something
I got to do
before Sheribelle gets here.
Oh, I got to buy her a present.
Oh, Arnie, you ain't
got to buy her nothin'.
But, Hoss, I promised her.
She likes me, Hoss.
Arnie...
Sheribelle's a...
a saloon girl.
It's her job
being nice to fellers.
But... well, dang it, that
don't mean she really likes you.
I never know'd a girl before.
N-Not never.
They didn't even want
to talk to me.
I-I just gotta
buy her somethin'.
I-I just gotta!
(Hoss sighs)
All right, Arnie, you...
you got your week's wages;
don't spend it all.
HOSS:
Dave...
Where's your tame grizzly?
He's out spending
his week's wages.
On a present for me?
Why don't you leave him alone?
He ain't never done
nothin' to you.
Ah... why don't you buy me
a little old drink?
You know, uh, it
wouldn't be too much trouble
for a girl to get to like you.
No, no, I reckon not.
No more so than...
getting to like Arnie.
Oh! That big ape?!
If you think he's such an ape,
why do you bother with him?
Well, he's a customer.
Besides, they pay me
to be nice to customers.
And he's good for laughs.
And around here, a girl needs
all the laughs she can get,
let me tell you.
(Sheribelle chuckles)
Well, don't push him too far.
He ain't got much
of a sense of humor.
Now, don't you worry--
Arnie bores me.
And once the novelty
wears off...
he's just a joke.
If that's the way you
feel about it, then...
you won't mind
not seeing him anymore.
Mind?
I'd be tickled to death.
And if you don't want your
big dumb friend coming in here,
then just keep him
away from me.
Hoss!
Lookit here.
Ain't it purty?
Uh, cost me
purt near all my money.
Sheribelle's a-gonna love 'em.
Arnie, Arnie, I don't think
you're gonna be able
to give 'em to her right now.
Why not, Hoss?
Well... Well,
she ain't in there now.
The bartender told me she
wasn't gonna be back till later.
But I-I ain't never bought
no presents for nobody before.
Sheribelle's a-gotta see these.
I want to give 'em to her now.
Arnie, I-I done told you,
the bartender said
she wasn't gonna be back
in there till late tonight.
But that's a long time, Hoss.
Aw, it'll pass
before you know it.
Anyhow, while you're waiting,
I want you to come
take a ride with me--there's
something I want to show you.
- Wh-What is it?
- Well, now, I can't tell you.
I got to show you.
Well, where are we going?
Up to the Tahoe Rim.
It's... sort of
a favorite place of mine.
Uh, then can I come back and
give Sheribelle her present?
Uh, promise?
If you still want to.
Come on.
Take a look at that, Arnie.
ARNIE:
Oh...
Pretty, ain't it?
I-I wish I was a tree
a-growin' here
so I couldn't never move away.
There's a little place all the
way across the lake over there,
about 150 acres, I'd make it.
Seems almost a shame
to waste it on cattle.
Sure would make a fine farm.
Good meadow, water.
Fine stand of timber.
Wouldn't take too much
for a man to buy it, neither.
Well, who owns it, Hoss?
Well, I do right now, but...
Arnie, you could own it
in a couple years,
if you'd work real hard
and save your money.
(gasping happily)
Oh, it's prettier than I-I even
e-ever did dream it could be.
A little ol' cabin over there,
s-some roses.
Well, I don't know
one flower from another,
but Sheribelle likes roses.
Arnie...
come here and sit down.
Arnie, I... I spend
a great deal of time up here.
This is grizzly country.
Old big grizzly,
he likes it up here
where the air's clean.
He can live and...
hunt like a grizzly's
supposed to.
He likes it by himself, 'cause
he don't need nobody else.
But...
you get down lower, you...
you get into the wolf country.
The wolf travels in a pack.
He'll track down
a herd of deer, and...
cut out the weak ones and...
tear 'em down.
The sick ones.
The old deers
that can't run no more.
People are sort of
like that, Arnie.
They... There's them that,
like the wolf,
they run in packs.
And then there's others that...
like the grizzly, they... they
like to get up in the country
where the air is clean.
They can make their own way.
'Cause they don't need
nobody else.
Arnie...
me and you...
we're bears.
We ain't wolves.
I-I don't understand you, Hoss.
Arnie, I don't want you
to go back into Virginia City,
tonight or no other time.
But I got to.
I-I-I got to give Sheribelle
my present.
Arnie...
you can have that land
over there,
you can have it tomorrow, but
that girl don't go with it.
You can move on your farm, now,
if you'll promise me you'll
never see that girl again.
You want her--
that's what it is!
Now, Arnie, wait a minute.
You want her yourself.
And you call yourself
a friend of mine.
Arnie, don't you understand?
She don't care nothing
about you.
She's been laughing at you
all along.
You're a liar!
Arnie, I swear it.
She's been
making fun of you, Arnie.
She admitted it to me.
You're trying to make me believe
something that ain't true!
I'm going into Virginia City
and get her right now.
Arnie, wait a minute.
(groans, sighs)
You said you was my friend,
but you ain't!
Hoss?
Don't you understand, Hoss?
I ain't never had a girl before.
(sighs)
Arnie?
Arnie!
Wait a minute.
Where you going?
My feet are killing me.
I've got to change my shoes.
It has been a long night.
I'm kind of tired myself.
I'll only be a few minutes.
Take your time.
Suppose I bring you
a little nightcap.
Sure. Why don't you do that.
(door closes)
(sighs with relief)
You.
All right.
What are you doing here?
Well, I-I didn't mean
to be late.
Hoss wanted
to show me something.
Will you get out of here.
B... I guess I shouldn't have
come back here.
I-I should have stayed outside.
Can't you understand English?!
I don't want to see you in here,
out there or anywhere!
Look, I brung you
these here beads.
You dumb fool.
(beads clattering)
You stupid fool.
Do you think I care
what you bring me?
You're just something
to laugh at.
You're just good for laughs!
Now, will you get out of here
before you stop being funny.
No! You better not mean that!
(laughing)
You stupid clown.
You're a stupid, ugly,
smelly clown!
- No!
- (Sheribelle screaming)
(Arnie gasping)
- Sherry?
- (thud)
Sherry?
(Arnie gasping)
(Arnie descends stairs)
FREDDY:
Help...
Somebody, help.
Help!
SHERIFF:
...but be careful.
He's big enough
to tear a man in two.
I believe I'd as soon see him
brought back dead as alive.
Yeah, I shoved that door open,
I saw Arnie standing there
like a, like a ape or somethin'.
Sheribelle laying
on the floor like a broken doll.
Arnie took one look at me,
let out a roar,
yelled he was going to kill me.
You boys know
I'm no hero or anything--
he's about twice as big
as I am,
but I tried
to stop him anyways.
And there's the man
who's responsible for all this--
Hoss Cartwright.
If it hadn't been
for Hoss Cartwright,
Sheribelle
would be alive right now.
SHERIFF: Now that's just
about enough of that.
Maybe the Cartwrights
did make a mistake
by giving that man a job,
but it was an honest mistake.
- Where's Arnie?
- Pa...
Hoss, if you know where he is,
tell us.
He killed a girl last night.
Huh...
And you're ridin' after him?
He worked for us.
We have a responsibility.
It's all my fault, Pa.
No, it wasn't your fault.
You tried to help him.
Hoss, do you know where he is?
(sighs) Well, I ain't...
I ain't for sure.
I... I know where he might be.
I'll tell you where it is, Pa,
but you gotta promise
to give me a head start.
Why?
'Cause I gotta see him.
I gotta try to explain
before they get to him.
Look at 'em--
they'll tear him apart.
Hoss, you can't let him go.
Now, he...
he has to be punished.
If you try to get in between him
and the posse,
they-they'll tear you apart,
too.
Yes, sir, I...
I know what's got to happen,
but he's my friend, Pa.
I don't know
what I'm going to do,
but I can't just leave him
out there to die all alone.
Where is he?
He's at Granite's Point
on the rim.
At least, I... I think he is.
All right.
You go to him.
Hoss... be careful.
Thank you, Pa.
We're about ready, Ben.
FREDDY: That's Hoss Cartwright
riding down the street.
I want to know
where he's going.
SHERIFF:
Will you shut up?!
Ben, where is Hoss going?
Well, why do you want
to know, Roy?
You ain't letting him
get the jump on us
so's he can warn that Arnie,
are ya?
Hoss knows Arnie
better than any of us.
He's just trying
to keep anyone else
from getting killed.
By helping that murdering maniac
to get away?
Now, Roy,
you know that isn't so.
If it was, I wouldn't have
let him ride off like that.
Ben, I should have known
that you and Little Joe
was just as anxious as we are
to get that woman-killer
to a rope.
We're anxious to see
justice done.
It's the same thing.
FREDDY: I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna shoot
that wild man on sight,
and if any of you
have any guts,
you'll do the same thing.
SHERIFF: Now, if you want
to go on this posse,
you're gonna do what I say.
Get back there.
You about ready to lead us
out to this Granite Point?
I'll get you there.
All right.
SHERIFF:
All right. Mount up, boys.
But don't any of you
take any chances.
(horse neighs)
You was right, Hoss.
She was laughin' at me.
(sniffles)
Hit me with the beads
I brung her.
I know.
I... I hurt her real bad,
didn't I, Hoss?
Arnie...
Arnie, you...
you killed her.
I-I guess I knowed I did.
I-I loved her, Hoss.
Why didn't she know that?
You killed Jake Staple, too,
didn't you?
Well, I didn't mean to.
I-I come in his camp
and he just took one look at me,
and he flung hot coffee
in my face.
It hurt awful, Hoss.
Well, I got mad.
I-I guess
I just hit him too hard.
And you took his money?
Wasn't going to do him no good,
and I was hungry.
Don't you see, Hoss?
I didn't mean to hurt nobody.
That feller, he burnt me and...
and I got mad.
And... And Sheribelle,
she was laughing.
Arnie, it's all right.
It's all over now.
They're coming after me, huh?
They got to, Arnie.
I always knowed
they'd be comin' some day.
I'm... I'm terrible sorry,
Arnie.
Hoss?
Yeah, Arnie.
I'm glad you brung me up here.
This is a good place.
I almost had it, didn't I, Hoss?
Little ol' farm.
Little bunch of squealing pigs
slopping out their trough,
and ol' mama nosin' 'em around.
I-I come awful close.
Arnie, turn around.
Wh... What's that for, Hoss?
We're gonna go down
and meet 'em.
I-I want to stay here.
Arnie, get your horse.
I ain't goin'.
Arnie, we... we're going
to ride down there together,
just you and me.
Now, I ain't gonna
let 'em hurt you.
You try to stop 'em,
they'll hurt you, too.
No, they won't.
I'll talk to them.
They ain't gonna hurt nobody.
You're right, Hoss.
You wasn't lying to me.
You're the only person
I ever knowed
who wouldn't lie to me.
I'll go with you.
You're doing
the right thing, Arnie.
Come on.
I couldn't let you do a thing
like that, Hoss.
They'd have killed you, sure.
LITTLE JOE:
Hey, wait a minute.
I thought I saw
something up there.
BEN:
Arnie?
LITTLE JOE:
I don't know.
Granite Point's only about
a quarter mile up now.
(panting)
(fierce scream)
(gunfire)
(Arnie yells)
(thudding)
I tried to help him, Pa.
I know, Hoss.
He didn't want me to get hurt.
He never wanted
to hurt anything.
I'm going to take Arnie
to his farm.
ANNOUNCER: This has been
a color presentation
of the NBC Television Network.