[footsteps approaching]
Bring him down!
I gave you a choice that day.
[Chains rattling]
That boy didn't have to hang.
No, he didn't.
But you do, for all you done.
The council welcomes
Bishop Joseph Dutson.
Please be seated.
My God.
[Chains rattle]
Why has heavenly father
brought this man
before me today?
[Western folk music]
♪
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
The charges include murder,
trespass, and sedition.
State your name,
for the council.
The bishop asked you
to state your name.
Unh!
- [Gasps]
- Oh!
[Both grunting]
I killed you,
you son of a bitch!
You're dead!
Get off him!
- [Chokes, sputters]
- Get off him!
- [Grunts]
- [Gasps]
[Coughs]
[Grunting, fighting]
Oh!
[Groans]
- Oh, my God.
- Back up, back up.
[Coughs]
[Overlapping chatter]
Damn you!
And your overzealous militia!
Bringing yet another viper...
[Gasps]
to our holy house.
[Grunts, sniffles]
I will ask again, hmm?
Your name?
Thor Gunderson.
[Coughs]
Write that down.
"Thor Gunderson."
That's his name.
His real name.
This is Bishop Joseph Dutson.
Mmm, no.
Goes by "The Swede" back east.
Murderer of innocent men
and women.
He is elder of the highest
priesthood office!
He is president
of the priests' quorum,
and father of the ward!
He's evil.
That man right there,
he's evil, I'm telling you.
Perhaps you mistake him
for someone else.
- No, that's him.
- Who gave you authority
to dignify this gentile's lies?
- But--
- Do you preside over this ward?
Then you speak when spoken to,
hmm?
Good.
Blaspheming in
the gathering place
of the Kingdom of God
is a crime.
Heavenly father decides when
a man is
to be taken from this life.
And be aware, be advised,
that I have been anointed
by him,
and appointed with the power
and the keys of the priesthood.
Your fate is in my hands.
Now...
I ask again...your name?
You know my name.
[Indistinct chatter]
Mr. Ferguson.
Are you heading back
to the cut?
You're chief of railroad police.
Mr. Bohannon is gone.
You need to do something!
Damn you!
You got a mouth on you
for a church lady.
You should have gone after him.
I thought you were his friend.
How will you feel
at his funeral?
Ain't gonna be no funeral.
Mr. Bohannon sat in my home,
shared a meal with my family,
and then took everything we had,
including my son's life.
After you murdered
my chief of police.
I told you,
- stay off my land!
- [Laughs]
All right, can I just--
can I--damn it!
Can I talk?
Now there's lots of things
I done
should have ended in
a hangman's noose,
and this ain't one of 'em.
He ain't told you
the whole truth.
No, I haven't.
Stand up, daughter.
Is this the man
who violated you?
He is the father of my child.
This council has heard enough.
I will deliberate
on a just punishment...
as revealed by heavenly father.
They hurt you bad?
No.
You?
I told them I wasn't forced.
I wanted you to know.
Appreciate that.
Guess it don't make
much difference now.
It does to me.
It will to this unborn.
I know what
you must be thinking.
This child is yours.
Can, um...
may I touch it?
Lately, I can feel it move.
Eva!
You trying to get me
thrown out of here?
What you doing
with all them guns?
I think the Mormons
got Bohannon at Fort Smith.
I'm gonna bust him out.
You're going alone
through Indian territory
to a Mormon fort?
That don't make sense.
It ain't make no sense
for him to stop the railroad
to look for my baby,
but he done it.
What are you doing here, then?
I just wanted to say...
I don't know why
you done what you done.
Guess you thought
it was the right thing.
Don't go.
I got to.
Elam.
Elam!
Please.
I got a bad feeling.
Please, stay?
Hyah!
Come on!
[Indistinct chatter]
Mrs. Palmer, I believe this
to be the finest staircase
in the Dakota territory.
I believe this to be
the only staircase
in the Dakota territory,
Mr. Durant.
You look like a queen.
And you look like
an old, tick-fevered hound.
You've won New York.
Why so down in the mouth?
I haven't won anything yet.
Bohannon has
an irritating habit
of slipping out of tight spots.
Hmm.
[Door opens]
Ah!
Hmm.
Our humble railroad town
has finally arrived.
General Grant, Chairman Ames,
Miss Ellison,
may I introduce the proprietor
of this fine establishment,
Mrs. Margaret Palmer.
Welcome to Cheyenne, gentlemen.
Pleasure to meet you,
Mrs. Palmer.
Oh, well,
the pleasure is mine, general.
I do hope your stay with us
will be comfortable.
So far, there is much
to recommend it.
Congratulations on
an excellent investment.
I have to hand it to you,
Thomas.
The town appears to
be everything you promised.
Yes, if you and Bohannon
would dispense with the mutual
pettiness, you might be favored
with greatness.
Where is Mr. Bohannon?
It's a few hours early
for his deadline,
but I have a bottle of bourbon
and a box of cigars
I'd like to open.
Well, I'm afraid
we will have to mark
this milestone
without Mr. Bohannon.
You all missed quite
an adventure.
Masked bandits turned our town
into a shooting gallery,
before snatching Mr. Bohannon
and dragging him away.
With your permission, General,
I'll telegraph the fort
and order
more troops for your escort.
I killed one of his abductors
at close range,
and I also managed
to save a child.
We were outgunned,
plain and simple.
We did everything we could
for Mr. Bohannon,
even at great danger
to ourselves,
especially Mr. Durant.
Now let me show you
to your room, General.
And what can I get you
to drink?
Bourbon, madame.
A double.
He has until 6:00.
There's still time.
You got any last words,
you be a man.
Say 'em to me, not my daughter.
You done enough to Naomi.
Been doing some hard thinking.
I wanna make things right.
You were my guest.
I gave you shelter.
And you repaid the kindness
by stripping
my most beloved daughter
of her chastity and virtue.
Now she'll live this life
in shame
and spend eternity
in outer darkness.
No God-fearing man
will have her.
I'll have her.
I'll marry her.
If she'll have me.
No. I will not
let her be a party
to your coward's attempt
to escape justice.
I ain't a coward, sir.
I'm that child's father.
I'll stay here at Fort Smith
till the child's born
and our first crops
are in the ground.
Now, you have my word:
I'll give them a good
and honest life.
I ain't never broke my word
to you for ill or naught,
and you know that.
She was my joy.
She could have married a bishop
or an apostle.
Brigham young himself
would have been proud
to call her his wife.
But now...
her only suitor is a gentile.
And a killer.
I will seek counsel.
But the bishop's word is final.
Shit.
[Cocks gun]
Hyah!
[Men shouting]
[Gunshots]
[Gunshot]
[Grunts]
[Arrow whizzes, gunshot]
Come on!
Come at me,
or get the hell out my way.
I've been praying
for your soul.
You can drop the pious bullshit
and the phony accent.
We both know you're that Swedish
son of a bitch,
Thor Gundersen.
Thor Gundersen was Norwegian.
And he was a troubled soul...
who fell from a bridge
in Nebraska.
Not far enough.
And I am Bishop Joseph Dutson,
reborn in the holy
baptismal waters
and blessed with the gift
of the Holy Spirit.
You're a bloodthirsty murderer.
You are not without sin...
Mr. Bohannon.
It does not matter
what you believe.
I am bishop here,
and I have had a revelation...
on the subject of your fate.
I ain't gonna hang, am I?
What makes you believe that?
Those gallows are strong.
The rope secure.
I'm marrying Hatch's daughter.
I'm the arbiter
of the law here,
not Brother Hatch.
No, I've seen a dozen men
stake their lives
on his word, not yours.
Besides...
got the feeling you ain't
real popular around here.
Now, why would you say that?
You always ain't popular
wherever you turn up.
My credibility here
is more secure
than yours has ever been.
Maybe.
But I got the feeling
you done something real bad
to end up here.
Truth can't be far behind.
That ain't the real reason
you ain't gonna hang me.
Hmm.
Real reason is...
you can only kill me once.
That ain't gonna be
good enough for you, is it?
You'd rather see me
suffer and die,
little by little, each day.
Yes.
But heavenly father
wishes to see...you live.
[Chuckles]
[Laughing]
Mr. Cullen Bohannon
is in absentia.
And, as the largest
single shareholder
of Credit Mobilier stock,
I propose that all further
contracts and construction
be assigned to me,
Thomas C. Durant.
Do I have a second?
Very well.
Then this will be the terminus
of the Union Pacific Railroad!
This enterprise shall end here!
I second.
[Sighs]
Aye.
All opposed?
[Men grumbling]
Motion carried.
In the powers vested in me
as chairman of Credit Mobilier,
I hereby confer
all further construction
of the Union Pacific,
from this spot forward,
to the charge
of Thomas C. Durant.
[Men grumbling]
[Chains clinking]
She's yours.
Do you want to be mine?
Yes.
It's God's will.
Well...
all right, then.
Let's do it.
Sister Naomi,
do you receive this man
to be your wedded husband,
observing the legal rights
belonging
to this condition for time
and all eternity?
I do.
Brother Cullen,
do you receive this woman
to be your wedded wife,
observing all the legal rights
belonging to this condition
for time and all eternity?
I do.
In the name
of the lord Jesus Christ,
and by virtue of the laws
of country
and authority vested in me,
I pronounce you...
husband...
and wife.
And may God add his blessings
and keep you to fulfill
your covenants
from henceforth and forever.
Amen.
[Knife being sharpened]
It is a tradition
that the groom
carves the pig.
That would be my pleasure.
[Chuckles]
Not before grace.
Of course.
Heavenly father,
to whom all hearts are known
and no secrets are hid,
bless us these thy gifts
that you have placed before us.
And this man...
and wife,
may they live a long
and happy life together.
- Amen.
Amen.
Hmm.
It's my tradition
that the meat's carved
at a side table
so as not to soil
the lady's table linen.
Thank you, son,
for your thoughtfulness.
You will call her mother.
And you will call me father.
Yes, father.
Pig skin's slick.
Wouldn't stand too close.
My hand might slip the blade
into your liver.
You're a different man,
Brother Bohannon...
with a new wife
and a child on the way.
I'm still liable to kill you.
Know that.
Don't you think it possible
for a man to change?
[Knife clinking]
Can't you believe...
I am not the man I was?
I don't trust you
farther than I can spit.
If you do not believe
that we can change,
how can you yourself believe
that you have changed?
If I'm not Bishop Dutson,
how can you be
Brother Bohannon?
New son to this family.
Who did not take that knife
and put it into my heart
the moment I handed it to you.
I made a promise.
The old Bohannon
wouldn't have cared.
He would avenge the murder
of Mrs. Lily Bell.
Meat's cooling.
Serve it.
[Tuba playing]
♪
What is that
infernal noise outside?
I'm afraid
your celebratory band
consists of a solitary
tuba player.
Ugh, will someone
please shoot him?
[Gunshot]
[Crowd gasping, tuba clanks]
You know, Durant,
a poor winner is unbecoming
regardless of the battlefield.
[Sighs] All I want
is for this day--
this hour--to pass,
so I can return to building
my railroad.
You mean the railroad.
In the meantime, it's good form
to acknowledge the rivals
who knock off
our rough edges...
and shape us.
Do you mean Bohannon?
Barkeep!
I was planning a toast
all along,
but since you insist.
To your worthy war enemy...
who championed the cause
of human bondage
that tore this nation apart
and killed many fine young men.
Ahh.
[Slams shot glass on table]
To your savior of the railroad,
whose antics have put
Huntington ahead
and us behind in this,
the greatest race
of modern times.
To your man of integrity,
as you call him
in your newspaper.
Apparently his integrity
has lost him his life
to men who took exception
with his integrity.
I take exception to
the sincerity of this toast.
To Cullen Bohannon, then.
May God speed him
to his just desserts.
And to us.
May God bless us all
as we drive our steel forward
into the waxy heart
of the Central Pacific.
- Hear, hear.
[Horse whinnng]
[Growling]
Whoa, come back here!
Get back here! Whoa!
[Growling]
[Roars]
[Gunshots]
[Click]
Uhh!
[Roars]
Hyah! Hyah!
Hyah!
[Screams]
[Water sloshing]
[Sighs]
How old are you?
18.
19 next month.
I don't reckon
this is how you figured
on spending your wedding night.
Mother said nobody'd want me
since I was unchaste.
Never thought I'd even have
a wedding night.
[Grunts]
Never thought I'd have
more than one myself.
What was it like?
Mm, it's what you
could imagine, I suppose.
Got married in a big church
in New York
and then took a trip
up to the mountains.
No, the--
the wedding night.
That's kind of personal.
You're my husband.
Yeah.
Well...
for one thing, we had--
hadn't been chaste about it.
That's a sin.
[Both snicker]
Yeah.
Mary was a lot of fun.
Are you gonna leave me
once you can?
No.
I ain't like that.
What if I'm not fun?
Seem to recall us
having fun in that barn.
What if I'm not fun
anymore to you?
It's been my experience...
that the fun will come.
Morning.
These look more like church
clothes than work clothes.
It's what the men wear.
[Sets bowl down]
We'll figure it out together.
[Overlapping chatter]
[Women laughing]
Quite a step-up
from the mud hole shit pit
I allowed you to escape from.
[Chuckles]
Gaming tables...
new women...
real whiskey.
I'll take the shop, then,
next door as well.
For my campaign headquarters.
[Whispering]
Consider it a donation
in my standing for mayor.
[Scoffs]
I determine who's mayor here.
That is why
you are running unopposed.
That's my contribution.
So I can count
on your vote then?
My vote is the only vote
that counts.
You will be the only
female editor
of a daily newspaper
in the entire country.
You're welcome.
I haven't said yes.
Yet.
You're not going to say no.
Those are railroad workers.
We're building our own
spur line to the south.
Crossed my mind that's why
the Mormons kidnapped me.
Mm, Brother Hatch
wanted to hang you,
not put you to work.
Same as you.
Yes.
But heavenly father has
more appropriate labors for you,
Brother Bohannon.
♪ Books of Moses
Lift!
Come on, fellas.
- Nice and slow!
- Bring it in here, boy.
♪ Wet in the water
Keep it straight.
♪ Weeping in the sun
Bring it right on in.
Get them ties ready.
There we go.
Gonna lock that in.
- Lock that down.
- Bring it on in there.
♪ Got some splinters
Ah, you there.
Big fella.
What's your name?
They call me Psalms,
Mr. Durant.
Psalms, Psalms.
You make sure your people
put their backs into it.
I'm behind schedule.
♪ Flaming heart
Yes, sir!
♪
♪ Beating swift
No good white devil...
put his heel on my neck.
Better watch out.
♪ At your feet
♪
♪ Books of Moses
♪ myth and truth
♪
♪ Books of Moses
Eva?
♪ Bring me back to you
Eva!
♪ Hero's welcome
♪ there stands your king
What's wrong?
♪ Where the serpent shudders
and the angels sing ♪
Elam's dead.
I felt his spirit pass.
♪
♪ Happening again
♪ yes, he knows us
♪ welcome him, your friend
[clacking]
♪ Books of Moses
♪ bringing stone news
♪ wet's the water
♪ blood covering the sun
♪ books of Moses
♪ got some splinters,
didn't you ♪
♪ books of Moses brought me ♪
♪ right here back to you
♪
♪ Flaming heart
♪ ain't it sweet
♪ lighting the world
♪ at your feet
♪
[Thunder crashes]
♪ Books of Moses
♪ myth and truth
♪ books of Moses
♪ bring me back to you
♪ hero's welcome
♪ there stands your king
♪ the serpent shudders
and the angels sing ♪
♪
♪ Books of Moses
♪ happening again
♪ yes, he knows us
♪ welcome him, your friend
Ho!
♪ Books of Moses
♪ bringing stone news
♪ wet's the water
♪ blood covering the sun
[train whistle blows]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com