[Horse snorting]
[Horse neighing]
[Speaking native language]
He thinks you're the white spirit.
I was lost in the wilderness
after them Irish boys run me out of town.
Was near death when yellow dog
and his men... [Chuckles]
They found me.
I am the white spirit.
Allow me.
Igluwiyeya.
[Speaking native language]
Sync by honeybunny - corrections by chamallow
www.addic7ed.com
Gently!
[Groaning]
[Indistinct whispering]
[Heart beating]
[Train whistle blows]
Lily: Thomas?
Can you hear me?
Thomas?
I telegraphed your wife.
She's going to meet you in Chicago.
[Man yelling in distance]
I hope that's some comfort to you.
Stay... with me.
No, I can't.
Your wife.
[Groaning]
Please.
Somebody has to stay here.
Keep your railroad running.
[Gasping]
Lil... Lily, if...
if I don't make it...
Shh. No, Thomas.
We'll go to Chicago.
You'll be on the mend in no time.
You hear me?
[Groans]
You going somewhere?
Yeah, I'm seeing Mr. Durant to Chicago.
You think it's wise
traveling in your condition?
My condition ain't none of your business,
Mr. Ferguson.
Come on.
Mr. Durant don't need you.
Like hell he don't.
He asked for me himself.
And he's paying me. Just like he pays you.
Only difference being, I
don't got to kill nobody.
So when you coming back?
Maybe I won't. Maybe I'll stay in Chicago.
What do you suppose they
going to make you in Chicago?
What do you mean by that?
I'm just saying, this is
where you belong, girl.
Tell me you're coming back.
I got a train to catch.
[Train horn blowing]
Where are you going?
Going to find doc.
[Sighs] Good. They'll be underway soon.
Doc ain't getting on that train.
- What?
- You read that telegram.
Weston's on his way and that
train don't leave for two hours.
I got to get him out of here right now.
Thomas could die.
Doc will die if I don't
get him on this horse.
Now if you'll excuse me.
Thomas saved your life.
He saved your life,
and now you're just willing to let him die?
Well, look on the bright side... at least
now you won't have to share his bed no more.
Don't you dare talk to me like that!
Calm down.
You're hurting me.
Who's Lieutenant Weston?
That right there is the man
who was going to execute me.
Now he's coming for you.
Finds out you're on that
train, he's going to have men
waiting to arrest you in Chicago.
I'm staying with my patient.
They're going to kill you.
Hawkins.
And them boys?
They robbed and they killed.
And I patched them up so they
could go out and do it again.
You think this is going
to make up for that?
[Sighs] It's a start, son.
All right, I can respect that.
Just promise me...
you'll get off that train
before it gets to Chicago.
I promise.
All goes well,
you won't see my sorry ass again.
[Train horn blows]
How's he doing?
His fever came down a little.
Good.
Maybe it's breaking.
Think he's going to make it?
Ahh.
This fever keeps breaking,
he's got a good chance.
He's a strong man.
That surgery?
It would have killed most men half his age.
[Gasps]
How far along are you?
What?
The baby.
Um... 3 months,
or so.
You got a man?
Doc, what I got is a
whole lot of heartache.
Ruth.
Ruth?
[Clears throat]
[Sighs]
When I woke this morning,
this was laying by the end of my bed.
And it was open to this page,
and there was a passage marked.
Jesus said to them, "if
you don't have a sword,
sell your cloak to buy one."
What does it mean?
Have you seen father?
No.
What do you suppose he's up to?
I don't know.
[Train horn blows]
Damn!
[Engineer yells]
[Indians whooping]
[Groaning]
Just stay with him.
Keep him calm. Keep him calm.
[Whooping continues]
Hey! You got any firearms on board?
Try the desk!
[Speaking native language]
[Whooping] Get in there.
Aah! Get in there!
[Speaking native language]
I'm putting it down. I'm putting it...
Fine!
[Groaning]
The glory of the lord will be revealed,
and all people will see it.
For the mouth of the lord has spoken.
[Speaking native language]
[Chuckles]
You... you need to tell me
what's going on here.
Well, you'll have this manifesto
published on the front page
of the "New York Tribune".
You're insane.
I won't do it!
Everyone on board the train dies.
Starting with her.
[Eva gasps]
No...
No, please... please! Please.
You... you win.
You win, Reverend, you win, you win.
I'll do it.
That thing is going to
take hours to telegraph.
I have all the time in the world.
Well, I don't think he does.
Well, you better just keep him alive.
For your own sake, doctor.
Cullen: You wanted to see me?
Look at this.
[Sighs]
It's from Thomas' train.
All of them are.
How's he sending telegrams
from a moving train?
I have no idea.
But Thomas didn't write
it, I'm sure of that.
Listen to this...
"the crimes of this guilty land
can only be purged away with blood."
Let me see that.
[Sighs]
Who'd have written this?
It's John Brown.
John...
Cullen: Count 3 rifles.
Elam: Those our rifles?
Looks like it.
Eva's in there.
Yeah, well, so is doc.
Get your weapon down.
Need to get onboard that train and
find out what we're dealing with.
Hey, you in there!
That you, Bohannon?
Damn it.
That's right, Reverend.
Need to come aboard.
I think not.
Please, Reverend.
All I want to do is talk.
See?
Keep pecking on that thing, chicken man.
Reverend...
What are you doing?
What's going on in here? Huh?
Reverend?
You been drinking?
Not a drop.
Well...
say let me buy you one, huh?
Let's go to the Starlite.
How'd you know the train
had been stopped here?
Council bluffs wired.
Train was supposed to pull in an hour ago.
So...
How's everybody else doing?
They're fine.
Why don't you let me take a look, Reverend?
I want to make sure nobody's been hurt.
- I don't think so.
- It's all right.
[Speaking native language]
All right, ok.
That's good.
Why are you doing this? Huh?
You of all people should
understand the situation.
We're fighting an invading force.
Yes, sir.
I know firsthand the firestorm
that's going to rain down on these people.
Killing nocents ain't going to change that.
It's going to make it worse.
I'm done talking.
Ahem.
I want you to think about
this, Reverend, all right?
Pray on it.
I know God will lead you
to do the right thing.
Mr. Bohannon.
Blood is God here.
Lily: How many hostages are there?
6 left.
Is he drunk?
Sober as a judge.
Mad as a hatter.
And do you think he's
willing to kill Thomas
if his demands aren't met?
See that body lying out there?
We'll have to take him by force.
I'm with him.
No, I think we need to
take time to negotiate.
He tried that already.
He's way past negotiating.
Why do you think Durant
sent us that telegram
instead of sending it on back east?
- This is what he wants.
- No, this is what you want.
He's in a rush to get
his friend out of there
before Weston arrives, and he's
willing to put everyone else's
lives at risk to do it.
Is that true?
You want to see eva
dumped off that train next?
And how do you know Durant
won't just bleed out in there?
We storm that train, I can't guarantee
we'll get any of them out alive.
But it's our best chance.
[Dog barks in distance]
[Chanting in native language]
You know...
we're not so different, you and I.
[Chuckles] You're crazier than I am
if you believe that.
Well, we are both men
with a mission in our life;
willing to sacrifice
anything to achieve our goals.
Even our own families.
[Chuckles] Yeah, I've been...
I've been a terrible father.
Great men often are.
Do you have... do you have children?
I had a son.
His name was William.
We lost him...
when he was 12.
Cholera.
My wife, uh,
she's never forgiven
me for not being there.
But I was building this railroad for him.
Your legacy to him.
Yes.
That's what this is.
A legacy to mine.
Your legacy will be nothing but death
and blood.
I'm afraid that's all
you'll be remembered for.
Yeah, well, that's what the
rebels said to John Brown
before they hung him.
There was another man
willing to shed blood
for his righteous cause.
His name was John Wilkes Booth.
[Chanting in native language]
You are on the wrong
side of history, Reverend.
The nation wants this railroad.
Anyone who stands in its way
will be vilified.
Is that what you want for Joseph?
What you doin'?
Moving things along.
On three.
One...
You can end this now, Reverend.
Two...
Do it, for your children.
Please.
Three.
Eva: Oh!
[Groaning]
Ahh!
[Eva screaming]
[Indistinct screaming]
Hold him, hold him!
[Screaming]
[Groaning]
He's dead.
Ah, he's dead.
[Groaning]
You missed me, you rebel son of a bitch!
Now you stand down or
I'm going to kill 'em all.
Don't shoot. All right?
I'm standing down.
Drop your gun.
See?
Get the hell out of here!
Move!
[Eva gasping and groaning] Get over there.
You lied to me, didn't you?
Yes.
Did you really think
I would allow your manifesto
- to be published?
- Shut her up!
Your fate was sealed
the moment you walked in that door.
Well, you sealed their
fate as well as your own.
Please, let the lady go.
She's with child, for God's sake.
[Sniffs]
[Sighs] I want to see my children.
[Bird screeching]
Hyah!
Elam: You would have took that shot
if it was anybody but
your friend out there.
What the hell are we doing
just sitting around, anyway?
We need to be doing something.
Just sit tight till
Ruth and Joseph get here.
Sit tight?
The man said he need to see his children.
He ain't giving up, he's saying good-bye.
You think I ain't worried?
I don't get that train moving
before Weston gets here,
doc's as good as dead.
It ain't the same, damn it!
It ain't the same.
Eva carrying my baby.
Sure it's yours?
Seem to be.
Well, where do you fit in?
I reckon I don't.
Yeah.
It's probably for the best.
That child ain't got
a chance in this world.
But I guess you know that
better than anybody, don't you?
Have you heard about the train?
Yes.
Is he dead?
No.
No, he's not.
Then why are you here?
He wants to see you.
To see you and Joseph.
Why?
Don't know.
Maybe you can talk him into giving up.
Why would he listen to me?
You're his daughter, Ruth.
How can you just sit there?
He hates me.
He has made that very clear
- my entire life.
- Ruth...
he's going to kill everyone on
that train if we don't do something.
I'm sorry, but there's nothing I can do.
We have to try and stop him.
I know you don't love me anymore.
But please,
just do this one last thing for me.
He's dying, you know.
Yeah, well...
who the hell isn't?
Cullen: Hey, Reverend!
Got some people here who
want to talk with you.
Sending them in, all right?
Sure you want to do this?
Yes.
All right.
Be careful in there.
[Knock on door]
Come in.
Come to father, Ruth.
[Clears throat]
Please, Ruth.
I want to be at peace
before I leave this world.
Go.
You...
and your mother... [Clears throat]
didn't deserve the way I...
I treated you.
But look... look what a... [Chuckles]
strong person you turned out to be.
You're...
you're a beautiful, strong woman.
You're st...
stronger than I ever was
or c... could be.
Please...
forgive me.
[Gasping]
[Sobbing] I forgive you, father.
You think it'll work?
One way or the other.
Shit!
We got it under control.
Is the siege over?
We don't need you here.
Well, I've come to fetch my prisoner.
Mr. Swedinforms me that he's on that train.
Just doing my duty as a citizen.
- Son of a bitch...
- Hey, hey.
Easy now, fella.
This ain't over.
Jesus will forgive you,
but only if you let these people go.
I'm willing to risk that for you, Joseph.
What are you saying?
I'm gonna kill them all.
Father, please.
I'm doing it all for you, son.
I don't want this.
It's too late.
Die is cast.
No.
Yeah.
All that's left for us is to...
say good-bye.
I love you, son.
I love you, too.
[Grunts]
[Groans]
[Gasps] Oh, my God!
Behold...
Your legacy.
Ohh...
[Sobbing]
Your knife.
Take that man into ctody.
Move out.
Don't go to Chicago.
I have to.
I made a promise.
When you come back,
we need to talk about that baby.
You mean your baby?
The track is being repaired.
We'll have you on your way soon.
Thank you.
I've been thinking about...
my son.
William.
I was a terrible father.
No, don't say that.
Terrible husband.
I need to see...
my wife.
You will.
I need her to forgive me.
[Sighs]
For what?
Everything.
[Breathing hard]
And...
when I... when I return, I...
Good-bye, Thomas.
Being a country doctor's about
a lot more than you might think.
One of my many duties
is to see people out of this world.
I'd hold their hand or talk to 'em.
Usually I'd just listen.
It was an obligation I took great pride in.
Cullen...
I would be truly honored
if it was you to see me out of this world.
Are you asking me to pull the trigger?
Well, I sure don't want them Yankees
to be the last face I see.
Uh...
I can't... I can't do that.
I could still bust you out of
here. You just say the word.
I am not gonna let you pay the price
for me running like a
cwe can go to Mexico...
Listen to me.
I am done running.
There's no honor in the
way I've been living.
The least I can do is die with some.
My 3 boys died in the war.
I never got a chance to bury them.
But...
I had a good life.
Probably better than I deserve.
You want me to read some words?
I'm ready.
I don't know if I can do it.
You be strong, son.
You be strong.
Sync by honeybunny - corrections by chamallow
www.addic7ed.com