Previously on AMC's Hell on Wheels...
***
Somebody took her.
Someone came and snatched up
my baby and took her away.
They ain't had time to get far.
Hey!
[Chicken squawking]
- Chicken?
- I didn't do nothing.
Get the hell out of here.
Who would steal a little baby?
Where is she?
- Baby?
- I know who got her.
- No, Elam.
- [Sighs]
What the hell you doin'?
Same as you'd do.
It's a good way
to get yourself shot.
He's been wanting
my little girl.
- She ain't here.
- He ain't neither.
Declan Toole got our baby.
I know he do, Eva.
Elam.
- Where is she?
- Get off me!
- Get off me, boy!
Where's my baby?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
- Easy, Psalms.
- Where's my baby?
Easy!
Mr. Toole, did you take
Mr. Ferguson's baby?
No.
Mr. Toole,
if you know where she is,
- you've got to tell us.
- I don't know.
You lyin'.
I'm not a liar,
Mr. Bohannon.
I don't have the child,
and if I did,
I wouldn't let her
be taken away
and right from under
me own nose.
- Where you take her to?
- Where you take her?
Mr. Quinn?
He's been with us
all morning, sir.
Let him go.
We ain't got no reason
to believe him.
Ain't got no reason not to.
Irish lie for Irish,
Mr. Bohannon.
That's true.
Elam, don't.
It ain't worth it.
She's gone.
[Western folk music]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
All right,
Elam and Eva's baby's been took.
We got to find her
before we go,
but that don't give us
much time.
The river's up a foot
since Sunday.
Our surveyor's reporting
heavy rains out west.
We don't get loaded up
and moved,
we could get washed out.
We're not to move
without finding the baby,
are we, Mr. Bohannon?
I know that's not
what you're suggesting.
I ain't sayin' we stop
looking, but we keep packing.
Livestock and railroad supplies
ship first,
but we need to be
out of here by midday.
Moving this town more important
than finding me and Eva baby?
I ain't said that.
But you ain't said
we don't move till she found.
I got no concern
for the whore's child.
[People murmuring]
If this rain sets in,
how are we to load these wagons?
600-pound rails,
tons of steel and gear.
We'll be swallowed up
for certain.
[All grunt in agreement]
Thank you, Mr. Quinn.
We don't move, you don't work.
You don't work,
you don't get paid.
If there's no pay,
you'll have no men.
- That's right!
- We'll walk off this railroad.
- Hold on, now.
All: Aye.
- Hold--hold on.
- Mr. Bohannon, I know
we got jobs to do, but speaking
on behalf of the freedmen,
we got to find Elam's baby
before we do much anything else.
That child is no darkie's baby.
What? What the hell
you talking about?
It's me brother's,
Gregory Toole's.
Bullshit!
Here I stand,
her bona fide uncle.
- That Elam Ferguson baby.
- Yeah?
We gonna find her,
don't you worry about that.
- What y'all talkin' about?
- I don't have time
- for this ar--
- My baby been took.
The Irish'll find her, not you!
[All shouting]
Stop it!
Stop it, all of you!
It's my baby that's been took!
This ain't got nothin'
to do with y'all!
Eva.
It's the injuns
that came and took him, Elam.
- I know that's what happened.
- What you talking about?
Ain't no Indians come in and
out of here in broad daylight.
That don't make no sense.
All I know is we ain't never
gonna see her again.
[Men murmuring indistinctly]
Uh, it's your railroad now,
Mr. Bohannon,
and none of my business
how you conduct yours,
but surely you would agree
a short delay is in order
until the child is found.
[People murmuring]
I will guarantee
20 of these gold eagles--
that's more
than two months' wages--
to the man or woman
who finds the child and returns
her safely to her mother.
[All murmuring]
Hold up--
hey, hold up!
All right, I can spare
five teams, five men per team.
You search every corner
of this camp.
The rest of you keep packing.
Once that baby's found,
we move.
[Overlapping chatter]
Sir, you've done a lot
of low down and dirty things,
but this ain't one of 'em.
Thank you.
You're welcome,
Mr. Ferguson.
We gonna find her.
Eva, this ain't your fault.
We was only out the house
a minute.
Bohannon got a search--
They ain't gonna
find her, Elam.
It's the curse on me
for all the wrong I done
to Mr. Toole.
No, don't say that.
I told you something bad
was gonna happen, and it did.
It happened.
Stop that, woman.
I want you to stop that.
That foolish talk.
It ain't no curse.
Somebody done took our baby
out this camp, that's all.
I'm gonna bring our baby
back to us.
I'm gonna make
all this right again, Eva.
I promise you.
Eva, you hear me, woman?
Hmm.
Rail cars have all
been searched,
the hotel, whore tents,
and slaughterhouse as well.
There's a lot of mudsills
and shit heels in this camp,
murderers, layabouts,
backstabbers.
- Yes, sir.
- And Durant shows up
right when that baby's took
and we're supposed to move camp,
and he offers a reward
that further slows
our progress.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you, Sean?
No, sir.
I do know Mr. Durant
is about to leave town
on the noon coach...
if that's any help.
Yeah.
Hold them horses.
[Sighs]
Now...
where you going?
Business elsewhere demands
my immediate attention,
I'm afraid.
I trust the search will continue
in my absence.
That baby didn't go missing
till you got here.
[Scoffs]
Surely you're not suggesting
I had anything to do
with the child's abduction.
Never was one for coincidence.
Perhaps you'd like
to search my bag.
[Scoffs]
Our personal enmity aside,
Bohannon,
my offer of the reward
is sincere.
If the child is found,
I will make good on the gold.
Mr. Bohannon, come quick.
It's, um--it's about the baby.
This here's
railroad property, Durant.
You come back, I'll have you
arrested for trespassing.
Don't be surprised
if someday soon,
I return the favor.
He, uh...
he knows.
He as much as said so.
Sean, if he knew,
you would have a hole
in your head right there.
Find your manhood
and embrace it.
We're in the endgame.
[Knocks on carriage]
[Man whistles, shouts]
Two of 'em--
they was right there,
tacked and ready to move out,
and then they was gone.
- Two horses all they took?
- And the tack.
Hell, the tack's worth
more than the horses.
Herschel there said
they went straight south.
Couldn't say if they was
carrying a baby or not,
- but hell, he's half blind.
- Horse thieves.
Ain't no horse thieves
riskin' a hanging
and leavin'
out in broad daylight.
He's right. It doesn't sound
like rustling to me.
What I'm saying is, what would
horse thieves want with a baby?
But baby thieves
need horses, sure.
- Where you going?
- Drop my reins.
You don't know
who these people are, Elam,
or if they even have the baby.
We ain't found her yet.
This got to be them.
Now, drop my reins like I say.
I can't wait for you.
Got to move this camp.
Then move it.
Come on, now.
Come on.
Come on, move!
Ezra Jacob Dutson, on this day
of your eighth birthday,
per the teachings
of the prophet Joseph Smith,
you are baptized into the Church
of the Latter-Day Saints.
- [Chuckles]
- Kneel down, son.
Yes, father.
O, Lord...
pour out thy spirit
upon thy servant,
that he may do this work
with holiness of heart.
I have baptized thee,
having authority
from the almighty God,
as a testimony that ye have
entered into a covenant
to serve him until you are dead
as to mortal body,
and may he grant unto you
eternal life.
Happy Birthday, Ezra.
[Distant hoofbeats]
[Hoofbeats approaching]
Thought the camp couldn't move
without you.
Can't and won't.
Those the tracks?
Look like.
Can't tell which way they gone.
Denver.
Denver?
That's where that trail leads.
Other one leads
to an old surveyor camp.
- Ain't nothin' for 'em there.
- Denver 150 miles from here.
They get to Denver,
she gone for good.
She ain't got her mama's milk.
How's she gonna make it
to Denver?
She ain't.
Ha!
It's Declan Toole.
What do you want?
- May I come in?
- Go away.
I have nothing to say to you.
[Grunting]
Now, we gonna talk some.
You holler,
I'm gonna gut you like a fish.
You hear?
[Grunts]
[Coughs]
- I'm a New York City copper.
- Out here...
that don't make no nevermind.
Enough!
I've not taken the child.
I was looking for her,
same as you.
You was looking for her
in Elam tent?
That don't make no sense.
Why would I take the baby?
On account of you don't want
no negroes raising her up,
that's why.
She's my own flesh and blood,
she is,
and I'd do nothing
to endanger that child.
You tell me,
where my baby niece at?
Hmm?
Easy.
I don't see no horses.
Damn it, Elam.
[Rustling]
What?
What'd you find?
This is hers.
It's a fool's errand.
You know that, don't you?
You got the whole story
right there.
We don't know
if she dead or alive.
- What you think?
- I don't know.
I ain't gonna stop till I do.
Might be best you never know.
You killed them men.
Wasn't to bring
your family back.
Why?
Made you feel better?
It give you peace?
You go on back if you want.
I'm gonna go do what I got to do
for my little girl.
Ha!
Come on!
Shit.
Eva.
I've been looking for you.
She's better off...
away from me.
I couldn't give her nothing.
You could give her
a mother's love.
You don't know nothing
about it.
Eva.
Eva, there--there was a time
I was intimate with Joseph.
It destroyed my father, but...
I had fallen into darkness
and sin.
As time went on, I...
discovered I...
was with child.
I was frightened.
Mm.
I...
thought through
all the possibilities
if I were to have the child,
and...
none of them were good.
I prayed to the Lord
every night to...
take it away.
Then...
nature took its course.
I was not to be a mother,
and I felt...
unworthy of God's love.
I was a sinner...
and I had sinned.
But God did not spurn me...
as others surely would have.
Even though I had been thinking
evil thoughts,
he was not ashamed of me.
The good Lord gave me permission
to feel how I was feeling,
and however you're feeling
right now, Eva,
it's all right with him.
The good Lord
has infinite capacity
to take our sins.
And all you have to do
is let him.
[Sighs]
[Sobbing]
Shh. Shh.
[Continues sobbing]
Shh.
[Gags]
[Breathing heavily]
Ugh.
There's kindness
in you yet, Psalms.
Not much.
[Chuckles]
You were named
for a book in the Bible.
Mm-hmm.
My mama named me
after verse 37,
the one about God
slaying the wicked
and offering comfort
to the suffering.
Have you considered
what you're doing?
I know what I'm doing.
Is it Christian?
I'm gonna make you
give me back that baby.
That's Christian enough.
I can't give you
what I don't have.
[Chuckles]
You've given me
enough pucks to the face
for me to confess by now.
You're gonna have to kill me...
or let me go.
You're not a killer, Psalms.
You think you'd be
the first white man I ever kilt?
You gave me water...
comfort.
You don't want the blood
of an innocent man
weighing on your soul.
Release me,
and I swear by Holy Mary,
the mother of God,
I won't raise a mob
against you.
All my life...
I done did
what the white man told me...
so he won't kill me.
White man tell me when to work,
where to work,
how long to work.
Mm.
White man give me
what food he got left over,
not what he got to share.
White man take
all the best women for hisself,
even take out
the best part of the Bible.
Mm-hmm.
See, white man don't leave much
for old Psalms
except for what he don't want
for hisself.
Mm.
But old Psalms--
he get the last laugh.
Hmm, Mr. Toole?
Now, you gonna tell me
where she is,
or Mother Mary
gonna sit right here with me
and watch you die.
[Hoofbeats approaching,
horses whinnying]
- Where's my baby?
- I'm sorry.
- Where is she?
- I didn't mean it.
Can't tell you if he's dead,
now, can he?
I thought we'd be
in Denver by now.
She's fine--
a real sweet child.
I think she's
getting hungry, though.
Please don't hurt him.
- Elam.
- He done it for me.
Killing them won't make you
feel any better.
It might.
We didn't mean no harm.
We was gonna be a family.
It didn't seem
Eva wanted this baby.
We got her now.
Let's go.
Sara's bleeding bad.
I don't know what to do.
Can she ride?
Not much and not for long.
We got to go.
My baby girl gettin' hungry.
You take this and ride on.
Come back to hell on wheels,
I'll hang you both.
You run into Indians,
you hold two of these back--
one for her, one for you.
Her first.
Leave 'em be.
We got to ride.
Mr. Bohannon...
don't leave us out here.
We all been left out here, son.
[Train bell ringing]
[Train whistle blows]
I hear you're getting ready
to move the trains.
I'm ready to move
the trains, yes.
Even though Mr. Bohannon
isn't yet back with the baby.
Mm-hmm.
And who knows when he will be?
That'd probably suit you,
wouldn't it?
When Mr. Bohannon
comes back,
his train is ready, all right?
And if he doesn't,
the train will be ready
for your friend, Mr. Durant.
I've got work to do.
Run along back to your whores,
all right?
You're playing a very
dangerous game here, Sean-o.
The wrong bet may cost you
your life, man.
Smart money
always hedges its bet.
The smart money's on Bohannon.
[Baby cries]
[Baby fussing]
Look here.
She doin' it.
I'll be damned if she ain't.
[Exhales sharply]
Weather's getting close.
How you know?
Caught a bullet in the war.
My knee swells up every time
the weather's coming.
- [Baby coos]
- You done enough.
Go on back.
Move the camp.
We'll be along directly.
What was you doing out there?
I'm only gonna say this once.
This here baby white.
I know that.
I do, but she mine.
I don't care what color she is.
She mine.
She ain't got
no other father but me.
Who else gonna love her?
Elam...
that baby ain't gonna bring you
nothing but a heap of trouble
and pain
for the rest of your life.
Don't matter what you think.
My family was took from me,
just like yours.
And she the first thing
I ever got...
that's mine, all my own.
I'm keeping her.
See her grow up...
real smart, real pretty.
She gonna know I'm her daddy...
and I love her.
Tell you true, Elam.
You'd do best to unwrap
your heart from her right now.
I can't do that.
It's too late.
I'm in it now.
[Sighs]
We'll leave at first light.
[Baby fussing]
[The Be Good Tanyas' What Are
They Doing In Heaven Today?]
♪
♪ I'm thinking of friends
♪ whom I used to know
♪ who lived and suffered
♪ in this world below
♪ they've gone off to heaven
♪ but I want to know
♪ what are they doing
there now? ♪
[Men shouting]
♪ Oh, what are they doing
♪ in heaven today?
♪ Where sin and sorrow
♪ have all gone away
[Cheers and applause]
♪ Peace is fine
♪ like the river they say
♪ but what are they doing
there now? ♪
♪
♪ There are some whose hearts
♪ were burdened with care
♪ who spent their moments
♪ so frightened and scared
♪ they clung to the cross
♪ with trembling and fear
♪ but what are they doing
there now? ♪
♪
Hmm?
What'd I tell you?
Told you I'd find her.
She all right.
I told you, ain't nothing
gonna come between me,
this little girl, and her mama.
I thought I weren't never
gonna see her again.
What'd I tell you?
♪ Peace is fine like...
Rain's coming!
Got to move this camp!
♪ But what are they doing
there... ♪
[Thunder rumbles]
♪ Now?
♪ Mm, mm
- [Grunts]
- [Breathing heavily]
[Thunder booms]
"And if they be evil,
"they are consigned
to an awful view
of their own guilt
and abominations..."
[Thunder booms]
"Which doth cause them
to shrink
"from the presence
of the Lord...
"into an awful state of misery
"and endless torment
"from which they can
no more return.
"Therefore,
they have drunk damnation
into their own souls."
"O...
"That ye would awake...
awake from a deep sleep."
"Yea...
even from the sleep of hell."
"O...
"That ye would awake...
"awake from a deep sleep.
"Yea...
"even from the sleep of hell,
"and shake off the awful chains
"by which ye are bound,
"the chains which bind
the children of men."
[Horses neighing]
"They are carried away,
"captive down...
into the eternal gulf..."
"of misery...
and woe."
[Thunder rumbles]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com