Previously on Longmire
Ignore the polls.
I do. But there are some things
I cann't ignore.
You know what would help?
Dirt.
You got any juicy Longmire secrets,
now would be the time to spill 'em.
Where did you get those eyes?
My dad and my ex-boyfriend are in
the middle of a nasty campaign fight.
- And recently I found out that my mother...
- Your mother what?
- I know what happened in Denver.
- No you don't.
Word of your wifes' murder
won't leave this room.
But I think that right now your daughter
might need you more than the county does.
Walt: Your family's
been coming here
every summer since the '80s,
right?
Woman: The '70s, actually.
And we're here year-round now,
so I can finally vote for you.
We just got to get out
that vote!
May I borrow the sheriff
for just a moment?
Uh, what for?
I think she's asking you
to dance.
I'm not sure that's such a...
such a...
Go on.
Come on!
[ Music ]
Woman:
All right, sheriff!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Man: Nice one, Walt.
[ Laughs ]
Hung me out to dry there.
Price of politics.
[ Laughs ]
You, uh, want to dance?
Two vodka tonics, ma'am.
Thank you.
Ruby.
Ooh, thank you.
Mm-hmm.
I thought maybe you got lost.
That block of ice was charming,
but it's not a very efficient
way to make a drink.
[ Chuckles ]
Look at Ferg.
Ooh, light on his feet.
Woman: You go, boy!
[ Cheering ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ Music ]
[ Glass dings ]
I have been asked to say a few
words about tomorrow's election.
We have all grown accustomed to
the modern drumbeat for change.
Our opponent seems particularly
fond of the word.
And while I believe
that change can be good,
I do think people too often
underestimate the value
of things that never change.
[ Cheers and applause ]
My friend Walt
is one of those things.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Who would ask him to change
his loyalty,
his honesty,
his intelligence,
and compassion?
Not me.
Though some of us do think
that maybe it is time
he got a cellphone.
[ Laughter ]
But other than that, sheriff.
Speech!
[ All chanting "Walt!" ]
Man: Thataboy, Walt!
Uh...
[ Feedback ]
Okay?
[ Laughter ]
Uh...
Thanks.
[ Cheers and applause ]
[ All chanting "Walt!" ]
Walt, come on.
That's not necessary.
I'll get that in the morning.
Doesn't seem right to leave you
with a mess.
Who said anything
about you leaving?
Hmm?
I'm sorry. I...
I got a big day.
Yeah, got to get your rest.
Right.
I, uh... yeah.
[ Crickets chirping ]
[ Door opens ]
[ Clatter ]
Longmire 02x10
Election Day
Original Air Date August 5,2013
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com
It's votin' day!
Hello?
Dad?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
- Thank you.
Hey. Hi. Oh.
[ Applause ]
Thank you. Thank you.
[ Car horn honking ]
Thank you. You too. Oh.
[ Air brakes hiss ]
You got to be kidding me!
Hey, we're stepping up
to retail politics now, man.
Look at this.
[ Laughs ]
No, seriously.
You know, a town this small,
the whole thing could
come down to, you know,
getting a few more of your
people to show up at the polls,
a few less of the other guy's.
Got to get the vote out.
In this thing?
Yeah.
Dress for the job you want,
not the job you have.
The job I want is sheriff,
not '80s heavy-metal
lead singer.
I think I'll take my own car.
- Nah!
- Yeah.
Aw.
Look at this.
He's gonna take his own car.
Man of the people.
Thank you.
[ Car horn honking ]
Walt has rubbed off on you
more than you realize.
- Hey.
Cady: - Hey.
Cady, what brings you here?
Oh, I just came to wish my
dad luck on the big day. Oh.
Oh, he hasn't
come in yet today.
That's weird.
I was just at his house,
and there was no sign of him.
Oh, maybe he stopped to vote.
Why don't you have a cup of coffee
and wait for him?
Oh, um...
Thanks, but I promised Henry
I'd go get out the vote.
You know, a lot of people
on the Res don't have cars,
so I'm gonna shuttle them
to their polling places.
See you guys later.
[ Door opens, closes ]
[ Object thuds ]
Bob.
Huh?
How did you get in here?
Through the front door.
The front door has been locked
since 2:00 A.M.
Well, I fell asleep
in the bathroom,
and then I came out here
and everyone was gone,
the door was locked,
and I fell asleep out here.
After helping yourself
to some drinks.
And food.
Look, I didn't mean to steal
anything, Henry.
You know that.
I just...
There just wasn't anybody here
to serve me.
Why did you not think to call
someone to come get you?
Well, I would have called
my lady friend,
but Yelena broke up with me,
if you can believe it.
Heartbreak or no,
you need to call someone
to come pick you up.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
I was starting to wonder
if you were even gonna show up.
I just wanted to wait for
the lunch crowd to clear out.
Yeah, makes sense.
Any idea which way
things are leaning?
I can't tell you
anything like that.
You know that.
Just one? [ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles ]
Man: They took away
my driver's license
on account of my vision.
I didn't think I was
gonna be able to vote.
Well, I'm happy to help.
You know who I voted for?
It's really none
of my business.
Longmire!
[ Chuckles ]
[ Music ]
All right.
Now, you all know me.
I'm an Indian,
and I'm proud of my heritage.
So you must understand how
strongly I believe in this man
when I say to you
we all need to forget the past.
It's time to look to the future.
The future has stepped out
of his patrol car as we speak.
Give it up
for Mr. Branch Connally!
Thank you.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Get 'em, big guy.
Thank you very much.
Think fast!
Looking good, people.
Vic: Hey, Henry.
Thought you could use these.
He was supposed to hand them out
to people,
and I found them in a closet.
Oh, yes. He preferred to run
a silent campaign.
[ Scoffs ]
Can I get you something to eat?
Yeah, sure.
I wouldn't mind
a little something.
[ Cellphone rings ] Oh.
Hey.
Ferg: Hey, Vic.
Sorry to bug you.
I didn't think I should bother
Branch or Walt.
What's up, Ferg?
Somebody just called in
a car accident.
[ Sighs ] Sucks.
[ Chuckling ] I know.
And I got to stay here
Manning the phones
until Ruby finishes
counting the votes.
No, it's fine.
Tell me where I have to go.
[ Music ]
[ Crow caws ]
[ Phone ringing ]
Ferg:
Sheriff's station.
Hey, Ferg.
It's me.
So, I'm out here
at this accident site.
It's the weirdest thing.
It's like a double hit and run.
Who'd you say called this in?
Guy didn't leave his name.
He just said he saw the wreck
as he drove by.
Ferg, send an ambulance
right away, okay?
Cady.
Henry: [ Echoing ] Walt.
We just spoke to the head of trauma.
She was unresponsive
when she came into the E.R.,
so they rushed her
straight to surgery.
Vic: [ Echoing ]
It's gonna be a few more hours
depending on what they find.
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Beeping intensifies ]
[ Beeping stops ]
Walt, did you hear
what we said?
Lizzie: Oh, my God.
I just heard.
She okay?
I need to take a walk.
Okay.
Woman: Oncology,
paging palliative services...
Extension 3609.
[ Keys thud ] She okay?
It's hard to say.
She was in surgery.
It's pretty bad, though.
Just wish there was something
we could do.
Well, we could find
the son of a bitch who hit her.
You're right.
[ Sighs ]
Looks like
you took some photos.
Yeah.
So, I went out there,
and as far as I can tell,
Cady was out of the car
changing a flat tire.
I found car Jack
and these lug nuts
on the side of the road.
Now, when the Pontiac
smashed into her wagon...
[ Voice breaking ]
It must have sent her flying.
It's okay, Ferg.
How could somebody
do something like this
and then just leave the scene?
I know.
[ Clears throat ]
So, who owns that car?
No plates, and I couldn't
get through the door,
so I broke through
the passenger window
and I checked
the glove compartment
and found
a expired registration.
Guy named Darren Tooman
in Montana is listed on it.
And I found a fifth of bourbon
on the front seat on the floor.
Now, I know that with Ruby away
somebody's supposed to be here,
but I'm going to Montana to
find the owner of that car.
Shoot.
We got voicemail.
I'm going with you.
[ Keys jingle ]
[ Door closes ]
Hey, Ferg.
No sticker?
What?
Don't forget to do
your civic duty today.
I am doing my civic duty.
Why's he so upset?
Because his friend,
your ex-girlfriend,
is in critical condition
after getting hit by a car.
Cady?
Yeah.
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Careful, Ferg.
Paper on the windows can
sometimes mean meth house, okay?
[ Humming ]
[ Gun cocks ]
Oh, shit!
Ferg.
Darren Tooman?
Yeah?
Get up.
Okay.
Come on with us.
I owned that Sprint
since high school,
but it was just sitting
in the yard,
so I sold it a few months ago.
There's no record
of that sale, Darren.
Well, I sold it on Craigslist.
The guy paid cash.
He kind of...
He overpaid, to be honest,
but I sent in my part,
the transfer of sale
to the state of Montana.
But if the buyer didn't file
his paperwork,
the sale never posted.
That car is still
legally registered to you.
Can you describe the guy
that bought the car, anything?
'Cause if you don't, you might
be liable for manslaughter.
Oh, well, he was a white guy,
a brown baseball cap,
and he called himself "K-Dawg."
[ Woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A. system ]
Any news?
No.
Yeah... uh...
Coffee or something?
No.
[ Man speaking indistinctly
over P.A. system ]
Great. Great.
Thanks. Okay!
K-Dawg, the guy who responded
to the Craigslist ad,
is Kellen Dawes,
and he lives in the county
right on the Montana border.
Let's get there!
Hey, Ferg. I know that you want
to do a good job for Walt,
but you need to
take it down a notch.
Why? Why do I need to take it
down a notch?
I want to find this guy,
and I want to...
And what?
You want to do what?
You want to hurt him?
Because if you go out there
like this, all jacked up,
you're gonna do
something stupid.
You're either gonna
get yourself in trouble
or you're gonna get the bad guy
out of trouble.
[ Sighs ] [ Keys jingle ]
Maybe I should go talk
to Kellen Dawes by myself.
[ Sighs ]
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe you should.
[ Bag rustles ]
It's gonna be okay.
[ Door closes ]
Man: [ Echoing ] You know,
it's supposed to be them
sitting out here
and us in there.
They're supposed to break
their leg on a trampoline
or get stitches when their hand
slips carving a pumpkin,
you know?
[ Normal voice ] It's not
supposed to be like this.
[ Clears throat ]
[ Sighs ]
My, uh, my son Troy,
he's a football player,
a damn good one.
And then suddenly
out of nowhere,
he just starts losing
all this weight.
[ Echoing ] I mean, it's crazy.
Like 30 pounds in a few weeks.
[ Normal voice ] And they
don't know what's wrong.
Centuries of science
and they can't tell me
what's wrong with my son.
It's our fault.
We're supposed
to take care of them.
We forget to and start thinking
about ourselves.
We go out
and have a good day...
[ Exhales sharply ]
Thinking
about our own happiness
instead of theirs.
The world decides
to even things out.
Kellen Dawes?
Yes?
[ Gun cocks ]
You mind putting the gun down,
showing me your hands?
I do.
But I will anyways.
Thanks.
That's a nice rifle.
Only because I take care of it.
I can see that.
I'm more interested in a car,
an old Sprint.
You know that car?
'Course I do.
Worst $500 I ever spent.
And a couple weeks ago,
somebody stole it.
Why didn't you
report it stolen?
Why do you even care
about that stupid car?
'Cause it was involved
in a hit and run.
That's really too bad.
Everybody okay?
No.
Well...
I can tell you I didn't have
nothing to do with it.
Then you won't mind me taking
a look around your property?
Knock yourself out.
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Alarm sounding ]
[ Alarm continues ]
[ Monitor beeps, alarm stops,
steady beeping continues ]
Branch: So, what are we doing
to find the guy that hit Cady?
What are we doing?
Well, Vic and I
went to Montana and back,
but I'm not really sure
what you've been doing.
You... you pissed at me?
Honestly, I've been pissed
at you for months now.
Me?
What'd I do?
You could've dated anybody.
Why'd it have to be Cady?
[ Sighs ]
Wow. Uh...
I had no idea
that you even liked her.
Yeah, well, there you have it.
[ Sighs ]
I don't know what to say.
Just forget it.
[ Clears throat ]
[ Dog barks in distance ]
[ Sighs ]
Where'd they take the cars?
Print shed.
You want to come along?
No, I got to... stay here
in case Vic calls.
[ Door opens, closes ]
[ Object rattles ]
[ Monitor beeping steadily ]
She's gonna be okay, Walt.
Uh...
[ Clears throat, sighs ]
Thought you'd want to know
where we stand with the driver.
The owner of record sold the car
to a guy named Kellen Dawes.
Kellen says the car was stolen
a couple weeks ago.
Whoever drove the car
left behind blood.
There'd be cuts,
scrapes, worse.
[ Sighs ]
Kellen didn't have any
that I can see,
so I'm inclined to believe him.
Checked at all the hospitals
to see if anyone's come in
with consistent injuries
in the last 24 hours,
and, uh...
Nothing.
So I guess...
That I'm nowhere.
[ Beeping continues ]
[ Voice breaking ]
I'm so sorry, Walt.
Check the drug stores.
Security cameras.
Look for anybody who came in
to buy first-aid supplies...
Gauze, bandages, disinfectant.
After what they did,
they'd stay away from hospitals,
doctor's offices.
Okay.
[ Beeping continues ]
Hey, Walt.
You won.
What?
The election.
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
Vic: We must have
gone through
half the pharmacy security tapes
in Montana.
I got a couple left.
[ Sighs ]
What are we supposed to do
if our mystery driver had all
the first-aid stuff on hand?
We're supposed to try
everything, right?
No, I know.
[ Key clacks ]
Just seems like
a long-shot.
I got one.
Check this out, Vic.
Oh, my God.
I know.
Bandages,
pain meds, ice packs.
No, I know that guy.
That's the kid that said
that his car was stolen.
That's Kellen Dawes.
Vic: Kellen?
[ Door slams ]
Kellen, stop!
[ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
What are you doing?
I'm in Montana now.
You don't have jurisdiction
over here.
That's the state line?
Yeah.
That's the state line
right there.
How can you be so sure?
I've lived here all my life.
I know where the state line is.
Yeah.
Hey!
[ Grunts ]
Hey, you can't do this.
You don't have authority
over here!
You're overlooking one thing,
Kellen.
I don't give a shit whether or
not I have authority in Montana.
You hit a girl with your car
and you ran.
You're under arrest!
It wasn't me. I swear.
Then what were you doing
buying first-aid supplies
at a pharmacy an hour
after the accident?
It was for a friend!
I loaned him my car!
He came back all messed up.
What friend?
[ Both breathing heavily ]
[ Tires skid ]
Bob!
Open up!
Billy, where's your dad?
He's not here.
Ow!
You're hurting me!
You're under arrest!
Get up!
What?
What did I ever do?
You hit my daughter with a car
and left her to die!
Get in!
How drunk were you?
I wasn't. I swear.
Bullshit.
Found a fifth of bourbon
in the front seat,
not to mention the fact
that you felt the need
to flee the scene
of the accident.
Nobody does that...
Unless they have something
to hide, so...
How drunk were you?!
I told you...
I wasn't drunk.
I mean...
Not very.
But I was okay to drive.
My unconscious daughter...
Would argue otherwise.
My dad called me
from the Red Pony,
and he asked me
for a ride home.
And my car's in the shop,
so I borrowed
my friend Kellen's.
And while I was on my way over
to get dad,
Kellen texted me.
[ Sighs ]
I didn't think it was
a big deal to read it, but...
I must have taken my eyes
off of the road for a second.
And that's when I hit
the parked car.
I was dazed
'cause I hit my head.
I didn't even see
your daughter at first.
It wasn't until after I got out
that I saw her
over in the grass.
If you saw her...
Why did you run?
[ Sighs ]
I was sc... I was scared.
You realize she could have died
if nobody found her?!
[ Crying ]
I'm so sorry, sheriff.
I did call 911.
I swear.
Book him.
Driving while intoxicated,
reckless endangerment,
driving an
unregistered vehicle,
fleeing the scene
of an accident...
And anything else
you can think of.
[ Cellphone rings ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Birds chirping ]
Branch: Yeah?
Morning, Branch.
Look, I know it sucks,
but that was no way
to handle it.
What are you talking about?
I had a room
full of people, man,
60 supporters of yours
waiting to drown their sorrows
with you,
and you don't even show up.
Can't get you on the phone.
Nobody likes
losing an election,
especially not
by such a slim margin.
How slim was it?
You lost by 17 votes.
And if you want to win
the next one,
you're gonna have to learn
to give the people
who helped you
a little more respect.
Honestly, Jacob,
I got bigger things
to worry about.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
[ Engine sputters, shuts off ]
[ Footsteps approach ]
[ Knock on door ]
Walt, I've got to talk to you.
It's about Billy.
There's nothing I can do
for your son, Bob.
He did a bad thing.
There's gonna be consequences.
Except he didn't.
Billy didn't do
what he said he did.
It was me.
I was driving.
I've been drinking
for a few days,
and Yelena broke up with me,
and... Billy came
to pick me up.
But I made him let me drive.
Trying to prove something
to him, I guess.
Then...
When we hit Cady's car...
He told me to take off.
Said he wasn't as drunk as me.
Because of my record,
I'd probably get
in more trouble.
So you have to
arrest me, Walt...
Not Billy.
I did it.
[ Yells ]
[ Piano plays discordantly ]
Get...
Get up!
Come on!
You're coming with me.
Come on.
[ Door closes ]
There it is.
That's the car you hit.
That's the car you were driving
before you walked away.
Get in.
Get in there behind the wheel.
Tell me what happened.
[ Door hinges creaking ]
[ Grunting ]
Walt: Stop.
You didn't crawl out
of this wreck, Bob.
[ Sighs ] Your son did.
He was skinny enough and
panicked enough to tear free.
He squeezed his way out.
And this car was heading
towards the Red Pony,
not away from it.
Your son hadn't even
picked you up yet.
[ Sniffles ]
Now, tell me, Bob, how'd you
really get those cuts?
These cuts are not
from yesterday.
They're fresh.
You tell me the truth, Bob.
[ Crying ] When I found out...
When I found out
you arrested [Kicks car]
When you arrested Billy,
I had to do something!
I mean, this whole damn thing
was my fault!
If I wasn't such
a worthless drunk,
Billy wouldn't have even been
in the same place!
He wouldn't have even
been there!
[ Sobbing ] Oh, God.
[ Sobs ]
And so [Sniffles]
I broke a bottle.
I cut myself up because I wanted
to convince you...
that I did this
to your daughter, Walt.
I did it.
I may not have been driving
the damn car,
but I did this!
It was my fault,
and I should be punished!
Not Billy!
[ Sobbing ] Please, God, Walt!
[ Moans ]
My life is over.
And I have wasted it.
[ Sniffles ]
But don't let me ruin
my son's life.
[ Sobs ]
I deserve to be punished,
not Billy.
[ Sobbing ]
Ferg: Do we need to put this
in triplicate?
No.
Just initial it.
[ Door opens ]
A signed confession
Bob Barnes was the driver.
I got a signed confession
from Billy
saying the same thing.
He said/he said.
I believe Bob.
Walt:
Release him, Ferg.
No.
I won't.
[ Hinges squeak ]
Dad?
What's going on?
Walt: Come on.
[ Latch clicks ]
[ Dog barks in distance ]
[ Door opens, closes ]
Branch, there's nothing
in the tread walls.
You sure?
It's practically
brand-new.
I know.
It's crazy.
[ Bell dings ]
No nails, screws, nothing.
[ Drill whirs ]
You want to buy a new tire?
No, I want to fix this one.
Look, maybe...
Maybe the leak's
not in the tread.
Maybe... maybe
it's in the sidewall.
All right.
[ Bell dings ]
Man: Hey, come on.
Listen, I got to go ring up
those customers.
I'll be right back.
Yeah, sorry for the wait.
Let me go get that part.
[ Squeaking ]
[ Monitor beeping ]
Hey, punk.
[ Sighs ]
I thought if I could...
if I could figure out
who hit you,
I can find who to blame...
that would somehow fix this.
And here you still are.
I haven't fixed anything.
They say this is all
a horrible accident.
This wasn't an accident.
This is because of me.
I found Bob Barnes in here
yesterday morning...
Drunk.
I told him to call someone
to come pick him up.
I-I keep thinking...
What if I had
driven him home myself?
If I had just...
This isn't about
any of that, Henry.
This is our fault.
You don't do what we did
in Denver
without there being
consequences.
I need to make things right.
You cannot confess to a crime
you did not commit.
I'm not talking
about confessing.
I need to set things straight
with the world.
With myself.
With Cady.
I've been selfish.
I have to make a sacrifice.
What are you saying?
I need eagle feathers.
I need your blessing
to do something
a white man is not
supposed to do.
No.
I need to do this, Henry.
There's nothing else I can do.
Henry: We are nothing
but flesh and muscle...
bones and blood.
It is all we have to give.
It is good you made
this vision quest
to help your daughter.
You will suffer...
and shed blood
for the one you love.
This is honorable.
Her suffering
will not be in vain
as long as you maintain your
focus on the healing vision.
[ Thunder crashes ]
You will return
to the umbilical connection
to mother earth
with this piercing.
Your communication with Maheyo
will be through the love
of our mother.
This way, your own thoughts
will not cloud
the healing vision.
Your sacrifice
will be made tangible
through the shedding
of your blood and body.
Your silence will be heard.
[ Chanting loudly ]
[ Thunder crashing ]
[ Chanting echoing ]
[ Wind whistling ]
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com