- Previously on Wynonna Earp.
- What the sweet hell is this?
I'm ready to help.
(Wynonna): You're supposed
to be normal, Waverly.
I scoured every archive in the country,
and you know what I never found?
The reason why I can't break the curse.
- (Wynonna): What is that?
- Maldito, New Mexico.
This is what victories
might have to look like.
(Waverly): There's something about him.
Where are you staying?
A trailer park proprietered
by one Bobo Del Rey.
You do not know what I am.
I know what you're supposed to be.
My name is John Henry, but most people
just call me Doc.
I'm gonna tell you a
tale about the last time
I saw my best
friend, the man who happens
to be your forebear.
I'm all ears, Hank. Hit me.
(coughing)
(door closing)
I'm all packed up, ready to go, Doc.
Headed for a burg called Purgatory.
See, a corrupted
lawman there out of fix
and in need of a little adjustment.
I've heard some things of
the particular corruption
of that damn sheriff.
Save your hoodoo-voodoo
talk for your Calico Queens.
They say he's part devil.
Ain't no such thing as devils.
Only men and the good and evil
they do in this
world. What say you, huh?
You got enough breath in
you for one more fight?
I think this is farewell, Wyatt.
Ah, fiddle-faddle. You'll be fine.
Farewell, old friend.
I'll see you on the other side, Doc.
It's a cute story.
But if you want me to
believe you're Doc Holliday,
you're gonna have to prove
it. Not only was Doc famous
for having the quickest
draw in the West but also...
- For the sharpness of my eye.
- (gunshots)
Now, has my little
demonstration convinced you?
(rock music playing)
Not yet.
♪ One man washes the other ♪
♪ One eye open when I sleep ♪
♪ One thing leads to another ♪
♪ One's sleeping six feet deep ♪
♪ Two faces in the mirror ♪
♪ The two rights erase the wrong ♪
♪ Two choices, which one's clearer ♪
♪ Do I fight or do I run ♪
So you're... you're Doc Holliday.
Well then, what are you?
'Cause if you were a
revenant, you'd be blown off my land.
So what? A ghost?
Now, if I were a ghost
would my heart be pounding like it is?
You were reported dead 130 years ago.
I made a barter for eternal longevity.
Cured me of chronic tuberculosis
and freed me from the ravages of time,
unless I catch a bullet, a
knife, or an oncoming train.
With that mouth, I give you 10 minutes.
What did Wyatt think about that?
I brokered the deal long after
Wyatt and I bid our fare thee wells.
What about the curse?
Did Wyatt say anything about
why his descendants
have to battle the
outlaws he killed over
and over and over again?
Wyatt never mentioned it. I am sorry.
Why are you here? Why Purgatory?
Unfinished business.
Well, that makes two of us.
Ma'am.
Doc freakin' Holliday.
I didn't mean to do it,
Sam. It was an accident!
Please! Please, forgive me!
Please! Say it!
You need help, Megan.
I do.
Please, somebody,
help me.
(man's voice): Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
Forgiven? Or not?
I need more time.
(man's voice): No, Megan.
Your time is up.
- (Megan screaming)
- (slashing sound)
♪ ♪
♪ 'Cause I gave you all
I've got to give ♪
♪ And no, that ain't
no way to live ♪
♪ I told that devil ♪
♪ To take you back ♪
♪ I told that
devil to take you back ♪
"Repent sinners." Written in blood!
- Good times.
- Mm-hmm. Neighbour found
the body, and Nedley's
outside keeping rubberneckers at bay.
He is slowly learning how this works.
And I haven't seen this
much blood since Kandahar.
- What were you doing in Iraq?
- Afghanistan,
and I'm gonna get you a map.
And I'm not at liberty to discuss.
You've brought it up.
God damn. Megan Halshford.
- Friend of yours?
- Hell, no. Couldn't stand her.
Megan Halshford?! Aww,
I always loved her.
You didn't know her like I did.
Waverly, do you know any revenants
that leave messages like that?
Do I!
Father Robert Malick.
A hellfire revivalist
minister known to rail against women,
demanding they repent. Wyatt hung Malick
for murdering his wife
and his girlfriend,
and some hookers too.
Any idea where this guy is so
I can shoot him in the dong?
Don't know. Hiding like the rest of 'em?
So we flush him out.
Yeah. Ooh! Hey!
Uh, I was kind of
wondering if I could tag
along with you guys today.
Uh, don't you have to work?
Well, you know, it's super slow,
and Gus said I could. Plus
seeing as I've done
the research, you know, I
know what questions to ask.
I think we got this.
Sure.
- (door closing)
- Ok, so don't freak out.
Our friend, Henry, I
spent the morning testing him,
and it's offish. He is...
What? Doc Holliday?
You knew and you didn't tell me?!
Well, I bet he can help us.
Look, I don't think so. OK, Wynonna?
I followed him to a
secret meeting with Bobo Del Rey.
And something happened.
Oh, my God, what did he do to you?
He kind of shot at my head.
And there was some pinching.
- Let's just talk about this.
- You threatened my sister!
- What's to talk about?
- I will confess only to this,
a sorry state of
finances, which compels me
to ply my trade.
- Dentistry?
- No. My other trade, poker.
Now, I have spied, lurking
in those dark corners,
a number of
revenants, so my aim was to steer
little sister from their foul company.
Back up a sec.
You're saying Bobo's hiding revenants
in the trailer park?
I'm only speculating on a hypothesis.
All right, I get it. But let's just say,
hypothetically, that I was looking
for a certain revenant,
let's call him Father Malick,
should I look in the trailer park?
Hypothetically? I'd say yep.
So who told you Malick's here?
Not at liberty to discuss.
So it's your friend Henry? One
of these days I'm gonna have
- to meet this guy, right?
- One of these days you will.
- Let's go "talk" to Bobo.
- Look, I
know you got a score to settle.
You think? Give me one good reason why
I shouldn't just walk in
there and shoot Bobo in the face.
Because we're outgunned and outnumbered.
Rules of engagement... we do
not fire unless we are fired upon.
- Yeah, but if I take him out?
- Then, you'll die
- in a hail of gunfire.
- Blaze of glory.
More like a blaze of stupidity.
If you want to win this war,
- we do it my way.
- Party pooper.
Bobo.
Wynonna Earp.
Hello.
It's been a while.
No?
I see.
Baby sister has better manners.
- Don't talk about Waverly.
- Why is that?
It's not like I'm a
stranger to your clan.
I knew your Daddy Ward very well
- while he was alive.
- Yeah, you know
- damn well how he died too.
- Now you see,
that's that wild
imagination, always gets you into trouble.
You'd think that after all the months in
St. Victoria's Psychiatric,
you would know the
difference between what is real
- and what ain't.
- OK.
So you want to get real?
Yeah.
Black star.
Wow!
You're a long way from home,
Marshal, uh... "Dolls."
Deputy Marshal Dolls.
And you don't
have much in the way of, uh,
back-up. Just one crazy girl.
"One crazy girl" and a very big gun.
Look, this badge is
all the back-up I need.
One phone call and I can cause
your world a whole lot of pain.
Let me guess,
black choppers,
Tomahawks and one steaming crater
in the ground. Am I right?
Did you know I had friends in Maldito.
We're looking for Father Robert Malick.
We thought you might know where he is.
Say... I did know
where Father is,
and let's say that I gave you
permission to speak to him,
I would suspect that if
he came to harm in any way,
there would be, uh, consequences.
(guns cocking)
Now, the good Father doesn't
believe that cleanliness
is next to Godliness, so you will find
his tent by way of smell.
Oh.
You have my permission.
We'll see you soon, Bobo.
Time will tell.
Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
(insects buzzing)
(Dolls coughing)
Robert Malick?
- Father Malick to you.
- We're here to talk
- about Megan Halshford.
- Sounds like a whore!
Then again, you're all whores.
You had me at whore. Still,
would you take a look?
Struck down by the
blade of immortal reckoning.
It was her guilt sharpened the knife.
Always the guilt.
- Guilt about what?
- Sinners sin.
Killers kill.
Whores whore!
Only she can tell you why she needed
- to repent.
- Is that why you killed her?
Me?! I'm always here,
ever since they took my legs!
OK. Put the sheet back on, stumpy,
I just ate breakfast.
(Malick laughing)
So you're not the killer.
But you know him, don't you?
His blade thirsts for you.
He will drink from the cup
of your sins, whore!
- (Dolls): What just happened?
- I saw him in the mirror.
(Dolls): Earp?
He was here, the psycho with the razor,
and on the night of the attack.
He's another one of the Seven.
Or Reverend Skanky's not the crazy one.
Okay, you think I'm
bonkers, right. Seeing mental shit
like revenants
appearing and disappearing?
But as far as we know, they
don't have that power.
No.
So what? We're dealing with the
David Blaine of revenants?
Well, we better not
be 'cause that would be
- a game-changer.
- (ringing)
A neighbour saw a car leave
Megan's home around the time
she was killed. Officer Haught
ran the plates, and got us a name.
Samantha Baker.
(imitating gunshot sound)
Samantha "Perky Tits" Baker.
Another one of the
Britneys that froze me out.
Let me guess, you two were real close?
Like this.
I've barely spoken to
Megan since high school,
and out of the blue, she calls me,
says I have to come over right away.
She's freaking right out, saying
she needs to confess.
Confess for what?
Sorry, I'm still
trying to wrap my head around
why anyone would
give Wynonna Earp a badge.
- Me too, sister.
- What did she need to confess?
OK.
On the last day of school in 11th grade,
there was this big bash.
You were there, right? Getting destroyed
as usual?
Go on.
I remember walking home,
seeing the red lights, spinning.
The officer talking to my mom.
My dad was killed in a hit-and-run.
I remember.
Last I heard, they didn't
find the person responsible, right?
That's what Megan
wanted to confess to me.
It was her. She was the one.
She begged me to forgive her,
- like her life depended on it.
- So did you?
She killed my dad.
And some people you
just can't forgive...
no matter how hard they try.
♪ Gotta do whatcha do ♪
- ♪ You gotta do whatcha say ♪
- Well, hello, little sister.
I'm gonna need a bottle
of whiskey, a glass,
and some of those ice
squares. I am gasping.
Management reserves the
right to refuse service
to jackasses.
I'm management,
and you're the jackass.
♪ She'll put her
night shift on you ♪
Hm!
Friend, you seem to be
at the intersection of
misery and despair.
♪ You know you've been told ♪
- ♪ About things bought and sold ♪
- Done some things,
bad stupid things
over and over.
Wife can't forgive me.
I deserve what's
coming, but it's gonna hurt.
Yeah, we have all made mistakes, friend.
I have spent many a night
wherein I ruminated on
the errors I've made.
But then it strikes me,
it was the wrongs done
to me that put me down
the well of
tribulations. So I set myself
upon a mission of
vengeance. And let me tell you,
friend,
it shall be biblical.
♪ You gotta do whatcha say ♪
♪ You gotta do whatcha do ♪
♪ You gotta do whatcha say ♪♪
I reckon I've said too much.
(man's voice): Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
Forgiven? Or not?
(unsettling music)
(footsteps)
(squeaking)
Oh, my God.
(man whistling a little tune)
No. No.
No!
No! No!
This is why I never
wanted to come back here.
Spit it out, Earp. We
don't get overtime.
OK, I was 16 and fresh out
of my 8th foster home,
and even for Purgatory High,
Megan was... Ugh!
You know, her dad owned
the local slaughterhouse,
and she used to fill
my locker with entrails.
Every Friday.
Because my clothes were
wrong. Because I'd been in juvie.
Because I was the crazy
girl who killed her own father.
Where are you going with this?
Uh, that bash Samantha talked about...
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, I was there.
But I wasn't getting wasted,
I was hooking up with
Megan's boyfriend, Brad.
Didn't even like him. Really.
I just wanted to hurt Megan
the best way I knew how.
And so she found
me on top of him, and...
Payback's a bitch. She lost it.
Bawled her eyes out, total mess.
Grabbed Brad's car keys and peeled out.
Problem is
Megan... (clearing her throat)
Megan couldn't drive.
And I never thought about how she
got home that night, and now
- I find out...
- Wynonna...
No, stop. I have heard
that tone my whole life.
Actually, I was gonna
say you were only 16.
We all make mistakes.
It's the most un-Dolls
thing you've ever said to me.
(small chuckle)
Pardner, they're looking
to settle up the tab.
Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
What a shit.
Waverly, I can explain.
There is a face that I
didn't want to see again.
Jay Novak, my probation officer.
Why would your friend Henry kill him?
- He didn't.
- The only other person in here.
Yeah, but we know he's
not a revenant, and the killer
- has to be.
- I still don't trust him.
Why not?
What are you two not telling
me about your friend Henry?
OK. Guess I'll have to
find out for myself.
(Dolls whistling a tune)
Wynonna's told me a lot about you.
Peculiar. She has told me
- nothing about you, Mr...?
- Dolls.
Deputy Marshal
Dolls. And you're in serious
trouble, Henry. You are looking good
for two homicides.
Oh, now, that is one thing we can
- agree on. I do look great.
- You know, I ran your prints
through IAFIS, then Interpol,
then every single
national database I could think of.
And you know what I found on you?
Nothing.
You're a non-entity,
which means you have no rights.
So start talking.
I am a professional card
sharp, Mr. Dolls,
so I can read a man's eyes.
And I do not like what I see in yours.
No shit.
- (knock on metallic table)
- Tell me.
(chair scraping the floor)
Ooh, I see a captain
piloting a ship full of secrets
through a stormy sea.
And as a gentleman who
cares about Wynonna,
I will recommend that she quit you,
lest she drown.
(Dolls laughing loudly)
Is Deputy Marshal Dolls laughing?
I've never been so scared in my life.
You know what I see in your eyes?
A man who doesn't like small spaces.
You been in prison?
Solitary confinement, ooh.
Was that fun?
I have said all I intend to say.
Mm-hmm.
It's nice talking to you,
"Hank."
(door closing)
You're gonna release him?
He's still a suspect.
Earp, when were you gonna tell me
you were kicking it with
the ghost of Doc Holliday?
How did you find out?
He's not a ghost. He's
got eternal longevity.
I was definitely gonna tell
you before Christmas.
Because then you could be
each other's Secret Santas.
How cute would that be?
(knocking on door)
- (door opening)
- Poor dead sucker's wife
just called, asking for Wynonna.
- For me?!
- Did I stutter?
I said I wanted to talk to you,
Wynonna, who's this fella?
Boss-man. Package deal.
OK, Suzie, start from the beginning.
This afternoon, my husband comes to me,
says for 10 years he's
been a big time drug dealer.
I thought he was a probation officer.
Yeah, well, that's a
good cover, isn't it?
Sometimes, Jay would put his
probationers to work too.
Unpaid minions.
Making a delivery one
night, I got arrested.
Didn't snitch.
Got sent back to
juvie for the third time.
- Another nail in my coffin.
- Did you know he was dealing?
Oh, a little weed. I didn't know
he'd become Purgatory's
answer to Walter White.
Not until today. It was like
he'd lost his mind! He
kept going on about this spectre
coming for him, that
I need to forgive him.
And then, the spectre comes to me.
- The mirrors.
- Oh shit, Wynonna.
Gives me two hours.
I only have a few minutes left!
We need to split up, cover
every reflective surface
you can find. We gotta block his
way from going in. Go! Now!
- We need to talk.
- Yeah, can it wait?
I'm kind of trying to
save your ass here.
You're gonna save me, all
right. I need you to forgive me.
Why?
Because I... I was to blame for
- you being sent back to juvie.
- What?!
One day, Jay comes to
me. He says that the police
are starting to circle him,
that he's needing something.
I called an anonymous tip on you.
- You ratted me out?!
- It was you or my husband.
You selfish...
You need to forgive
me before it's too late.
Yeah? I don't know that I can.
(man's voice): Tick-tock.
Tick-tock.
Forgiven? Or not?
Yeah, I forgive her! OK? I forgive her!
(man's voice): No, you don't.
Not in your heart.
I can't move!
(whispering) Help me.
(man's voice): Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
Time's up.
I can taste it. Guilt!
Gross!
Repent, Wynonna Earp.
Two hours to find forgiveness
from the souls you've hurt.
- (glass shattering)
- Tick-tock.
Earp, what the hell happened?
She's gone.
And I'm next.
It's Simple. I take
peace maker and right
- between the revenant's eyes...
- You shoot.
Boom! Back to Hell they
go. This guy can't throw in
a reflection clause. That's not fair!
Fair? He's a demon, and
you shot a mirror.
Yeah, that he traveled through!
Totally cheating.
No, no, no. What I mean
is you shot a reflection,
- not the revenant itself.
- So what does that mean?
- Itself, itself, itself.
- Dolls!
Shhh! Just give me a minute, OK?
OK, but too many more
minutes, and he turns me into a plate
- of sashimi.
- Unless we transmogrify him.
Do you come with a translation app?
We have to draw him from his
reflection to make him flesh
- and blood. Yes!
- So we need
his body? How hard is that for
you to say, "We need his body"?
I've encountered this before
at the BBD. In Kandahar,
we dealt with an
Iblis with a similar power.
You were fighting
demons in the Middle East?
Now, the ritual wasn't a
total success, four people died.
That's like saying the
Titanic almost made land.
But I know why it failed.
They didn't have the right tools.
But leave that to me. That is plan A.
- And what's plan B?
- You need to find
everyone you've hurt and
beg for their forgiveness.
- It didn't work for the others.
- That's why it's called plan B.
We need the killer's
name. It's very important.
I'll put Waverly on it.
Meet me back here in 90 minutes.
- Also, bring extra hands.
- Dolls!
How bad is this?
I'll get what we need.
Here I go!
Plan B for begging.
(indistinct chatter)
Pete. Pete?
Oh, my God! Hey, it's
been a long time. Can we talk?
I'm kind of busy, Wynonna.
- Hey!
I know it's been, like, a million
years since we dated, but, um,
remember your 19th birthday
party? I left early.
- You said you had cramps.
- Yeah.
- "Mega cramps."
- Mega lied. I, uh...
Oooh, I
- I went home with another fella.
- Bro, the table's
- getting cold.
- Shut up, Kyle.
Who'd you go home with?
Hmmm... Ohhh...
Brother.
You are such a shit, Wynonna!
Wait! You have to forgive... me.
Hey, what just
happened with the York boys?
Funny story, g-good
story. Uh, we found the killer.
He gives his victims two hours to, uh,
be forgiven for their
sins, or he cuts them up!
- Oh, not that funny!
- He also travels through
mirrors, and guess who
his next victim is.
Wynonna, we need to get you
on the first bus out of town!
No, I'm done running. And
there's a lot of mirrors
on busses. God, I hate busses.
- OK, what's the plan?
- OK. I need you
to find the revenant's original
human name and then
meet me back at Black Badge. Dolls
says we need extra hands.
Wait! For what? Hey, Wynonna,
- I need more to go on!
- Uh...
Uhhh, scary guy, mutton chops.
Sorry, I'm supposed to go
find all the people I've hurt
and beg their stupid forgiveness!
- But everyone hates you Wynonna!
- I'm aware.
I used to get a good night's sleep
in the old grey-bar hotel,
but now it's pure torture.
Which I gather you've
come to enjoy watching.
You said some really mean things.
You tracked me like
a common horse thief.
- Then you shot at me.
- No, I shot near you.
Nonetheless, I regret the episode.
Is that why you came down here?
No. No.
I come with a proposition.
You saw the revenant,
right? The guy in the mirrors?
So you help me identify
him, I'll get you out of here.
Ha!
I will most happily oblige.
OK. Here.
Newspaper clippings, municipal records,
police reports that I'm
totally not supposed to have.
Waverly, you have put
together the most thorough resource
on the revenants. You are one
natural-born investigator,
just like your great-great-granddaddy,
and I reckon, the true keeper
of the Earp flame.
Can't blame you for being miffed.
What? "Miffed"? Who said I was "miffed"?
Well, I'll be damned.
Here.
This is the face of the man I saw.
- "August Hamilton"?
- Everybody went to see Auggie
for a shave and to confess their sins.
What was he?
- Like, the Father Confessor?
- Well, in a town
with no church, you needed
one. But Wyatt found out
about a cattle rustler
who confessed his crimes
to ole Father Auggie.
So Wyatt aimed to put
Auggie on the witness stand.
Let me take a wild guess.
- Auggie never made it to court?
- Mm-mm.
Disappeared the night before the trial.
People say foul play was involved.
Wait. How can August be a revenant,
I mean, if Wyatt didn't kill him?
Oh, but he did. Most definitely.
See, by forcing him to testify,
Wyatt signed his death certificate.
- Wynonna needs my help.
- Hey, you promised my release.
You know,
Dolls is gonna kill me.
I really should ask him first.
You let me out of here,
we go see him
together? He won't mind a bit.
- You belong in gail!
- Oh, you know damm well
- I didn't do it!
- (loud whistling)
Hey! You should be ashamed
of yourselves!
The Barber is
coming to slice up Wynonna,
and you guys are blubbering
like a big bunch of bratty babies!
Thank you.
♪ ♪
(Dolls): That's the black
mirror. Made from Obsidian.
- Was it on special at Ikea?
- Funny.
Black Badge collects
artifacts from all over the world.
What else do you have
in your storehouse, Dolls?
The Ark of the Covenant?
It's actually called the
Ark of the Testimony.
And we don't have it anymore.
You surprise me, Dolls. I
never would have figured you
for a practitioner of the hoodoo-voodoo.
This ain't no joke, Doc.
It's our best way at beating this guy.
This ritual calls the spirit by name,
and then the spirit will become flesh.
And you, Earp, will shoot him.
- So I'm bait?
- More like brunch.
(Dolls blows dust off the book.)
You studied ancient languages, right?
- (Waverly): Yeah.
- You have?
- How is your Latin?
- Ego sum totaliter
stupet balls. That's Latin for
"I'm totally amaze-balls."
OK then.
We will be invoking August by name...
but other spirits
will try and slip through.
And some of them...
still have a bone to pick with me.
Kandahar?
We're all guilty of
something, right, Earp?
We're just gonna flap our
gums or we're gonna get to it?
August Hamilton,
"extra velum dicam
audite vocem meam.
Quia audisti vocem"
August Hamilton "te iubeo
velum coram me transire."
- (old woman's voice): Xavier.
- (woman's voice): Xavier!
No, Mictian, you will not pass.
- (woman's voice): Xavier.
- Waverly, don't stop. Go.
Hm, "apparueris mihi spiritus
carnem ipsum praecipio tibi."
(screaming in pain)
Ah.
(deeper, demonic voice) I'll dine
on your souls.
- Grr! Hahah!
- Sorry, friend,
- that's not on the menu.
- No, Doc, wait!
Uh... Oh, here! Try 50 000 volts!
- What?!
- Zap him!
- No! That'll kill him!
- Well, he's gonna kill us!
(Dolls growling)
- (electric buzzing)
- (Dolls screaming)
Wynonna!
(gasping)
Dolls!
Dolls! Hey! Hey!
He's not breathing!
Wake up. Wynonna! Quck!
- Yeah, give us room!
- OK.
- ♪
♪
- Oh, God.
Hmm.
Dolls, please.
(Dolls gasping)
(Dolls coughing)
Hey.
Ah, we need to regroup.
Gotta make a plan. He's
gonna come back for you soon.
Wait, I don't get it.
Wynonna shot him right between the eyes
- with Peacemaker.
- No.
He wasn't made flesh.
He was toying with us. (Dolls coughing)
Well, he might be traveling by mirror,
but he's still a revenant.
OK? His body has to exist
somewhere.
- Ah!
- (Dolls coughing)
- (Doc): Eurgh!
- (Wynonna): Oh,
my God, he's coughing up water.
Well, if you give
him a bit of laudanum,
- he'll be all right.
- That's not what I mean. Look!
OK, OK, water! That's reflective, right?
OK. So what if his body
is in water? What
if he's using the water
to project himself? I
feel so smart right now!
We gotta go. We need to go.
No! You need
to sit your ass down and rest.
We got this, hombre.
Look,
she'll need back-up.
You mess this up,
and I will end you.
I don't mess up.
I seem to recall long ago
some men of negligible
character telling me
of a certain lake they'd go
to make certain "problems" go away
with an anchor and a chain.
Mm-hmm.
What if some scoundrel was paid
- to make Mr. Hamilton go away?
- (Wynonna sighs)
OK, "scoundrel," what's
this lake called?
I guess "Tiny Muddy
Shit-puddle" was taken.
Yeah. They might have
drained the lake for fracking,
but at least, it'll make it way
easier for us to find the Barber.
(Wynonna): Yeah, super easy.
Here he is.
(Doc): Another reflection.
♪ ♪
He's here.
Somewhere.
- Wynonna, move!
- I can't! He's done
something to me! Ah-ah-ah!
Tick-tock.
Forgiven? Or not?
Oh, come on now, Auggie,
you know it's me you want.
It was these hands that
secured those chains
- and put you in that lake.
- Yes.
You're the guiltiest of all, Doc.
But you feel no remorse.
Not like this one.
- (Wynonna moaning)
- Search your heart, Wynonna.
Who have you hurt the most?
It's you.
- Wav, of course, it's you.
- No!
I mean, sure, you've done dumb stuff,
but you're my sister, OK?
- I'll always forgive you.
- Not for this.
What wrong have you
done that she could never
forgive? Hahaha!
Ugh! Ewww!
I'm... I'm sorry I killed Dad!
(Barber chuckling)
Sorry I let them take Willa!
- (Barber): Hahaha!
- Is it 'cause I left?
Right? I'm sorry!
No, God, I'm over it, OK? You came back!
You came back and now you're here,
and you're the chosen one,
and... that's definitely
not what I'm mad about.
Then what are you...
What do you mean, "the chosen"?
- Wav, just say it, say it.
- I should be the heir!
Yeah, you should.
- I'm sorry.
- I forgive you.
- Not in your heart.
- I Forgive her!
- Say goodbye.
- No!
Guilty, sinner,
forgiveness.
Just another dude telling me
what I've done wrong. But now...
I'm about to do some right.
(Barber groaning)
Sure you're gonna be ok out here?
Sleeping under the
open sky? I'll be dandy.
But what about you, little darlin'?
Had yourself one hell of a pony ride.
Yeah. I'm just glad it's over.
This one cut pretty close to the bone.
Back in my day, I
wronged many a persons,
and some done me wrong in turn,
but the only regret I have is that
I never apologized to Wyatt.
You told me last time you
saw him, it was all good.
I do not recall what lie I
told you. I was probably drunk.
- It was 8 a.m.
- I was definitely drunk.
I do not have much in this world,
besides memories and regret.
It would be nice for you to have more.
♪ ♪
Sorry.
You ate all the corn chips again?
No.
Yeah.
I'm serious. I'm
really sorry about being the heir.
Pfff, no.
I only said that because Vidal Sassoon
would have killed you if
I didn't find something
to be mad at you about. I
didn't actually mean it.
- Yeah, you did.
- Well, it was a stupid thing to say.
OK.
We're gonna do this the hard way.
The bubblegum sake I
imported from Japan!
- Hey!
- Oh, that's gross!
- It's unique!
- Try it.
See? Not-not so bad.
(Waverly coughs)
Wav
it's OK to just be honest.
For once.
Fine.
I spent years
compiling research on the revenants.
I did a four-year
university degree by correspondence
on ancient cultures and languages
because I thought that maybe
maybe I could break the curse.
And you, who's never tried
to be good at anything in
life, got to be the special one...
while I just got to be Waverly.
Who everybody loves
because you're so awesome.
I mean, you have a
million reasons to hate me,
and you still love me.
It's what I love about you, dude.
Pass me the booze.
Isn't this the part
where you say you love me too?
♪ ♪
You know,
you're awfully needy for a lone wolf.
(guitar music)
- (women laughing)
- Look.
- Ooh, a cowboy!
- ♪ Long-haired child ♪
(women and Doc laughing)
♪ Swaying all around ♪
Both of you girls, out with you!
Go on!
I paid them fillies for
the entire evening,
seems an awful waste.
Too sick to ride with me to Purgatory,
but here you are,
carrying on like a horse gone to stud.
Your countenance, Doc, it is...
A bona-fide miracle. I am cured!
How, Doc? How did you do this?
♪ I see the black You see the moon ♪
Sweet mercy.
Have you made a pact with the devil?
Now, you never mind
that. I am strong again.
Let's fight, let's ride together,
like we used to. I did this for us.
You did it because you're
selfish and a coward!
All men must die!
Who says it was you? C'mon! Men like you
so high and so almighty?
And cursed by Hell itself.
I thought they only
existed in fairy tales...
angels, devils...
yet demons walk among us,
and they mean to end my line.
But what you have done pains me more.
It's still me, Wyatt.
Your friend, your brother!
Doc Holliday is dead.
And that makes you nothing but a memory.
One I surely hope to forget.
(female singer "oohing" melodically)
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -