[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Soldiers Continue
Speaking Spanish ]
[ Soldier
VAMOS.
i　VAMOS!
[ Grunting ]
[ Soldier ]
HE DIES FOR A RIFLE.
[ Laughing ]
[ Sobbing ]
真MURIO嗷 BIEN, EH?
真PERO PARA QUE鰭?
真PARA ESTO?
i　PARA NADA! i　PARA NADA!
[ Sobbing Continues ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Soldiers Shouting
In Spanish ]
WHOA.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
LET'S GO, MEN.
[ Laughing ]
i　ALTO!
i　CHICA! VA疏MONOS!
[ Chattering In Spanish ]
GOOD MORNING, AMIGO.
MAYBE YOU CAN HELP ME.
NO HABLO INGLE鰭S.
ESTO ES MEXICO.
I'M SORRY.
I DON'T SPEAKESPANOL.
CAN I HELP YOU?
- WHAT WAS HE SAYING?
- THAT YOU'RE IN MEXICO NOW.
THAT ANYONE COMING TO MEXICO
OUGHT TO BE SPEAKING SPANISH.
YOU, UH, IN COMMAND HERE?
NO, BUT I SPEAK ENGLISH.
SEEN THIS MAN?
[ Woman ]
HEY, JOE.
- MORNIN', DARLIN'.
- WHERE YOU GOING, JOE?
WELL, I'M, UH--
I'M ON MY WAY.
YOU SAY ALL DAY,
ALL NIGHT.
ALL NIGHT, ALL DAY?
[ Laughs ]
DID I SAY THAT?
YOU SAY.
AH.
WELL, UH,
THINGS IS DIFFERENT NOW.
[ Crowd Chattering,
Shouting ]
THE SOLDIERS.
YEAH.
I GOTTA GO.
WHY DON'T YOU
TRY THIS HOTEL.
HE MAY BE IN THERE.
YOU MEAN
THEY LET INDIANS
IN THERE?
ANYONE WHO CAN PAY,
SIR.
ONE MOMENT, PLEASE.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
I AM LIEUTENANT FRANZ VON KLEMME
FROM THE IMPERIAL GERMAN ARMY.
I'M WHAT YOU'D CALL AN ADVISER.
I'M LYEDECKER.
POLICEMAN.
[ Cheering ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Engine Off ]
YOU GOT SOME MONEY?
MONEY?
WHAT THE HELL FOR?
GET OUT OF THE WINDOW!
FOR ME, YES?
SOME DOLLARS FOR ME?
I SAW YOU GOT DOLLARS.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU LOVED ME.
SURE.
YOU GIVE ME MONEY?
YEAH, WELL,
LATER, MAYBE, HUH?
I YELL PRETTY LOUD.
THEN THE SERGEANT COME UP.
YOU WANT TO TALK TO THEM?
[ Crowd Chattering,
Shouting ]
[ Speaking Spanish ]
WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO DO WITH THEM?
WELL--
WELL,
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THEY WERE PULLING OUT
THE RAILROAD TRACK.
YOUR TRACK.
OH, MY COMPANY'S.
NOT MINE.
WHY DO THEY DO THAT?
DAMN IT!
WHY?
WHY HAVE THEY BEEN
FIGHTING US FOR 400 YEARS?
BECAUSE THEY'RE
YAQUI INDIANS, THAT'S WHY.
THEY CALL THEM
LOS TIGRES DE LA ROCAS--
THE TIGERS OF THE ROCKS.
THEY SAY YOUR TRACK
IS ON THEIR LAND.
WHAT SHALL WE DO ABOUT IT?
OH,
WHATEVER'S CUSTOMARY.
WHATEVER
YOU THINK IS RIGHT.
OF COURSE.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Soldier Responds
In Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Hammer Clicks ]
MUY BIEN.
VERDUGO--
VERDUGO...
I'M NO PART OF THIS.
DO WHAT YOU LIKE--
A TRIAL.
I'M NO PART OF THIS.
LOOK.
I KNOW
THE VALUE OF THINGS.
BULLETS ARE VALUABLE.
THESE ARE NOT.
NO.
LISTEN.
DON'T BE LIKE THAT.
YOU CAN
GIVE ME MONEY,
OR I'LL MAKE YOU
SOME TROUBLE.
COME HERE.
SARGENTO PALETES!
SENOR.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Pistol Cocks ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
RUN! RUN!
[ Onlookers Laughing ]
RUN, INDIANS!
RUN, INDIANS! RUN!
RUN!
[ Woman Continues
Shouting In Spanish ]
HEY!
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Groans ]
[ Spanish ]
i　VAMOS! i　RAPIDO!
i　CABRO嗷N!
[ Onlookers Laughing ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Paletes
Speaking Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
MI GENERAL.
HE IS OUR PRISONER.
[ Spanish ]
TOO BAD I HAD TO
INTERRUPT YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT UP THERE.
[ Chuckles ]
YES, YOU DISTRACTED
MY SOLDIERS,
DISBANDED THE INDIANS--
[ Chuckles ]
VERY CLEVER.
BUT NOW I GOT YOU.
YEAH.
WELL, YOU WOULDN'T HAVE ME
IF THAT HOTEL HAD A BACK DOOR.
[ Chuckling ]
VERY CLEVER.
[ Chuckling
Continues ]
NOW, GENERAL,
YOU DON'T WANNA DO THAT.
HE'S A VERY VALUABLE MAN.
IF YOU GOT TO KILL HIM,
WHY DON'T YOU LET ME HAVE HIM?
PERHAPS
I WILL KILL YOU TOO.
THAT WON'T GET YOU
VERY MUCH EITHER.
- HE'S YOUR FRIEND?
- HE'S NO FRIEND OF MINE.
WELL, THEN,
WHAT IS HE TO YOU?
BANK ROBBER.
[ Wanted Poster Unfolding ]
HE STOLE $6,000
FROM THE CITIZEN'S BANK
IN PHOENIX, ARIZONA.
MR. LYEDECKER,
HOW MUCH DID YOU SAY
HE STOLE?
SIX THOUSAND
DOLLARS.
UH-HUH. WHEN?
TWELVE DAYS AGO.
TWELVE DAYS, HUH?
I SEE.
FIFTY DOLLARS.
WHERE IS THE REST?
YOU LOOK MEXICAN,
BUT YOU DON'T TALK MEXICAN.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU?
WELL, I SURE AS HELL
AIN'T NO DAMN MEXICAN.
[ Chuckles ]
MY MAMA
WAS A YAQUI INDIAN,
AND MY DADDY
WAS FROM ALABAMA.
[ Joe Laughs ]
[ Verdugo ]
I SEE.
WELL, I HOPE YOU KNOW
HOW TO DIE.
I ADMIRE A MAN
WHO DIES WELL.
NOW, TELL ME--
WHERE IS THE MONEY? HMM?
THE MONEY.
ALL THOSE DOLLARS
YOU SPEAK OF.
WHERE ARE THEY?
WOMEN AND WHISKEY.
THAT'S WHAT I'D DO
IF I WAS HIM.
OH?
[ Chuckles ]
SIX THOUSAND DOLLARS
IN 12 DAYS?
OH!
YOU COULD BE THE BIGGEST
STALLION IN THE WORLD,
$6,000 WORTH OF WHORES
IN 12 DAYS?
NOW--
[ Laughs ]
NO.
NO, IT WAS NOT SPENT
ON WOMEN OR ON WHISKEY.
NOW, FOR THE LAST TIME,
WHERE IS THE MONEY?
JUST LIKE HE SAID,
JEFE.
HALF OF IT I SPENT
ON WHISKEY AND WOMEN,
AND THE OTHER HALF
I WASTED.
EXCUSE ME, SIR,
BUT IF HE SPENT THE
ENTIRE NIGHT IN THE HOTEL,
DON'T YOU--
YES.
YES, LET'S GO
AND TAKE A LOOK.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
WHERE IS THE MONEY?
HEY, FRIEND,
I HEAR YOUR MAMA
SELLS IT ON THE STREET.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
I DON'T THINK
HE UNDERSTANDS ENGLISH.
[ Giggles ]
ALL THAT'S FINE.
BUT WHERE'S THE MONEY?
YOU REALLY
THE HONEST-TO-GOD LAW?
SOMETHIN' WRONG WITH THAT?
NO! NO.
YOU CAUGHT ME, DIDN'T YA?
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW I GOTTA SEE ABOUT
GETTIN' YOU OUT OF HERE.
SEE, YOU BEIN' THE YANKEE LAW
DON'T CUT NO ICE
WITH THE MEXICAN ARMY.
THEY AIN'T GONNA LET YOU
GET OUT OF HERE.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU
BUY US OUT?
THE MONEY AIN'T WORTH
GETTIN' KILLED FOR,
NOW, IS IT?
I AIN'T GOT NO MONEY.
BANK SAYS DIFFERENT.
OH, I TOOK IT,
ALL RIGHT.
BUT I SPENT IT
TWO DAYS LATER.
WHAT DID YOU
SPEND IT ON?
RIFLES.
RIFLES?
ONE HUNDRED RIFLES
FOR THE YAQUI INDIANS.
THEM POOR DEVILS HANGIN'
ON THEM TELEPHONE POLES
OUT THERE,
THEM'S YAQUI INDIANS--
MY PEOPLE.
WELL, IF YOU
TELLIN' THE TRUTH,
THAT GENERAL'S
GONNA KILL YOU REAL SLOW.
WELL, LET ME TELL YOU
ABOUT THAT GENERAL.
THEY TOLD HIM
TO GET RID OF THE YAQUIS
ANY WAY HE COULD,
AND HE TOOK THE EASY WAY.
HE'S JUST
KILLIN' EVERYBODY.
WELL, YOU'VE SPENT
ENOUGH TIME IN THE STATES.
YOU AS AMERICAN AS ME.
AND YOU KNOW
YOU JUST CAN'T GO AROUND
STICKIN' UP BANKS.
YEAH.
BUT I AIN'T GOIN' BACK.
YES, YOU ARE.
ON FOOT, ON HORSEBACK,
OR HANGIN' ACROSS A SADDLE,
YOU'RE GOIN' BACK.
HOW IS IT OVER THERE?
IT'S CROWDED
OVER HERE.
HOW ABOUT OUT THERE?
WELL, I THINK, WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF LUCK, WE MIGHT
BE ABLE TO GET OUT OF THIS.
- OH, YEAH?
- YEAH.
I'M GONNA JUMP
RIGHT OUT THAT WINDOW
BEHIND YOU.
GO AHEAD.
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Shouts In Spanish ]
[ Soldiers Shouting
In Spanish ]
i　SARGENTO PALETES!
[ Spanish ]
i　VAMOS! i　RAPIDO!
[ Whinnies ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
YAQUI!
[ Engine Off ]
[ Spanish ]
MI CABALLO.
i　SARGENTO! i　VAMOS!
WELL, I THINK WE LOST 'EM.
ALL OF 'EM.
[ Grunts ]
WELL, DO YOU BRING
THE RIFLES?
YOU DAMN BETCHA.
ROMERO SEND YOU?
WHERE ARE THE RIFLES,
JOE?
HOW COME HE SENT A WOMAN?
THEY'RE EXPECTING
A MAN.
OH.
NOW, UH,
WHERE ARE THE RIFLES, JOE?
ON THE CHILINA TRAIL,
NOT TOO FAR FROM HERE.
WELL, I HOPE SO.
THEY'RE THERE.
AND WHERE IS THE PROFIT
FOR YOU, JOE?
THERE AIN'T NONE, SARITA.
LOOK, YOU TOLD ME TO GET
THE RIFLES, AND I GOT 'EM.
WHAT ARE YOU BEIN'
SO TOUGH ON ME FOR?
BECAUSE I KNOW YOU.
BOY, YOU SURE HAVE SOURED UP
IN THE LAST FEW YEARS, AIN'T YA?
YES.
I HAVE CHANGED.
I WATCHED THEM
HANG MY FATHER,
AND I HELPED HIM
TO DIE.
YOU HEAR THAT?
I HELPED MY FATHER
TO DIE.
YOU SAY
THE CHILINA TRAIL?
YEAH.
[ Exhales ]
WE'LL SEE.
MARA.
OH, SHOOT.
[ Blow Lands ]
NOW, WHY'D YOU DO THAT?
I WASN'T GONNA DO NOTHIN'
I COULDN'T HAVE DONE BEFORE.
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD, JOE.
I CAN'T TAKE
ANY CHANCES WITH YOU.
LET'S GO.
WHERE WE GOIN'?
BACK TO PHOENIX.
HOW COME THEM TO GIVE YOU
A BADGE IN THE FIRST PLACE?
WELL, I GUESS I TOOK A JOB
THAT NOBODY ELSE WANTED.
EVEN AT THAT,
IT TOOK ME A WHOLE YEAR
TO GET IT.
- HOW MUCH THEY GON' GIVE YOU
FOR TAKIN' ME BACK?
- TWO HUNDRED DOLLARS.
AND THE JOB
PERMANENT-LIKE.
SHOOT, THAT AIN'T EVEN
HARDLY WORTH BOTHERIN' ABOUT.
WELL, JOE, THAT DEPENDS
ON WHAT YOU GOT
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
YEAH.
I AIN'T NEVER BEEN WORTH A DAMN
IN MY WHOLE DAMN LIFE.
AIN'T NEVER BEEN WORTH NOTHIN'
TO TALK ABOUT.
I NEVER EVEN HAD A JOB
PERMANENT-LIKE.
BUT NOW I FINALLY
DONE SOMETHIN' FOR SOMEBODY--
ME.
I FINALLY AMOUNTED
TO SOMETHIN'.
YEAH.
YOU ROBBED A BANK.
LET'S GO.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN.
YOU LIED TO ME.
THERE'S NO SIGN OF TRACKS.
NO PEOPLE. NO GUNS.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
THEY'RE THERE.
COME ON. I'LL SHOW YOU.
YOU AIN'T
GOIN' NOWHERE.
WHERE DO YOU FIND HIM?
I DIDN'T FIND HIM!
HE FOUND ME!
WILL HE HELP US?
SENOR,
WILL YOU HELP?
HELL, NO.
WHY NOT? YOU AIN'T GOT
NOTHIN' BETTER TO DO.
IT AIN'T MY PARTY.
COME ON.
[ Rifles Cocking ]
[ Verdugo ]
SO, WE MEET AGAIN,
HUH?
YOU MURDERER!
YOU ASSASSIN!
[ Screams, Groans ]
TOO BAD I DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH TIME FOR YOU
RIGHT NOW.
LOPEZ!
- [ Spanish ]
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Spanish ]
NOW YOU,
MR. SHERIFF.
[ Badge Lands On Ground ]
MR. HALF-BREED.
BY THE TIME
I'M THROUGH WITH YOU,
YOU'LL BE READY TO TELL ME
EVERYTHING I WANT TO KNOW.
[ Spanish ]
I'M NOT AFRAID.
[ Groans ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunting ]
DAMN IT!
STAY ON YOUR FEET!
GO TO HELL!
DAMN YOU,
YOU BIG SON OF A--
[ All Grunting ]
MUY BIEN.
AY. LOOK WHAT
THERURALESFOUND.
RIFLES.
TWO INDIANS
WITH THESE MULES.
NOW, HOW WOULD
TWO INDIANS...
FIND 100 RIFLES,
HUH?
THEY WERE
SKINNED ALIVE.
SLOWLY.
BUT THEY WOULDN'T SAY.
TSK TSK.
NICE DAY, VERDUGO.
INDEED IT IS,
MR. GRIMES.
[ Spanish ]
HELLO.
MY NAME'S GRIMES.
STEVEN GRIMES.
OH, THAT'S--
THAT'S NICE.
MIGHTY NICE.
WELL--
[ Chuckles ]
YOU KNOW,
FELLOW AMERICANS.
AND, UH, WHAT'S
A NICE FELLOW LIKE YOU
DOING IN A PLACE LIKE THIS?
I'M WITH SOUTHERN PACIFIC.
WE RUN THE RAILROADS HERE.
THEN, UH,
YOU'RE REALLY ALL RIGHT
WITH THAT GENERAL, AIN'T YOU?
LOOK, LYEDECKER,
WHAT'S THE POINT
OF ALL THIS?
IF YOU DON'T TELL HIM
WHAT HE WANTS TO KNOW,
HE'LL HAVE YOU KILLED.
WELL, MAYBE PUT
A GOOD WORD IN FOR US.
[ Laughs ]
WHY DON'T YOU
GET THE HELL OUTTA HERE?
TELL HIM SOMETHING.
ANYTHING.
[ Chuckles ]
SIX THOUSAND DOLLARS
IS NOT WORTH DYING FOR.
AND HE'S JUST
GONNA LET US GO.
IS THAT RIGHT?
WHY DON'T YOU GO AWAY
AND STOP BOTHERIN' US?
LOOK.
IF HE HAS YOU SHOT,
IT'LL CREATE TERRIBLE PROBLEMS.
- IT'LL BE A TERRIBLE THING
FOR ALL OF US.
- SURE AS HELL WILL.
- FOR US OR FOR THE RAILROAD?
- FOR BOTH.
THE WAY RELATIONS ARE
BETWEEN THE UNITED STATES
AND MEXICO-- WELL, YOU KNOW.
LOOK,
WE DON'T WANNA
TALK TO YOU.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
WE DON'T WANNA TALK TO YOU.
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE, JOE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
HE'S GOT THE RIFLES,
AND HE'S GOT US TOO.
WHAT DO WE GOT TO LOSE?
TELL YOU WHAT YOU DO.
YOU GO TELL THAT GENERAL
I WANNA SEE HIM.
[ Grunts ]
[ Verdugo ]
WHAT ABOUT MY MEN?
HOW ARE THEY PROGRESSING?
WELL, SIR, THEY FIGHT WELL,
THEY TRAIN WELL.
THEY DON'T SEEM TO TAKE
TOO NATURALLY TO THE DRILL.
WELL, THE PARADES
WILL COME LATER.
AS LONG AS
THEY CAN FIGHT.
SIT DOWN.
WHAT DISTURBS YOU?
THE RIFLES, SIR.
SOMEONE IS ARMING THE YAQUIS.
IF THEY GET HOLD OF
ANY MORE GUNS, YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE THE TIGER BY ITS TAIL.
THE YAQUIS
DO NOT HAVE THE RIFLES.
I DO.
YES, SIR,
AT THE MOMENT YOU DO.
VON KLEMME,
YOU WORRY ME.
THAT WAS MY INTENT, SIR.
NO. I MEAN,
YOUWORRY ME.
- OH?
- YES.
YOU-- YOU SEEM AFRAID.
OF WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
PERHAPS IF YOU WOULD
RETURN TO MEXICO CITY--
I WOULD PREFER NOTHING
MORE THAN THAT, SIR,
IF MY ORDERS COULD BE CHANGED.
YOU KNOW
THAT I DON'T NEED YOU.
BUT, YOU SEE, SIR,
WE GERMANS ARE HERE TO ADVISE,
SO WE ADVISE.
OH, YES.
NOW, TELL ME,
WHAT PERFECT PIECE OF ADVICE
HAVE YOU THIS TIME?
FINISH OFF THE YAQUIS
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE
BEFORE MORE GUNS COME THROUGH.
I KNOW THAT, DON'T I?
OF COURSE YOU DO.
THEN SEND THEM SOUTH AND SELL
THEM TO THE WOOD MERCHANTS.
NO. IT ISN'T WORTH IT.
THE PRICES ARE TOO LOW.
I HAVE TO FEED THEM,
SEND SOME OF MY MEN WITH THEM.
BY THE TIME WE SELL ONE,
THE PRICE WILL BE LOWER
THAN THE PRICE OF A COW.
THEN KILL THEM ALL.
THAT IS YOUR ADVICE?
THAT IS MY ADVICE, SIR.
VERY GOOD.
[ Laughing ]
SO, ALL THE TIME, EH?
ALL THE TIME
THE $6,000 WAS RIGHT THERE
IN MY FRONT YARD, HUH?
[ Chuckling ]
[ Chuckles ]
INCREDIBLE.
I'LL TAKE HIM BACK NOW, GENERAL.
THAT'S THE DEAL. RIGHT?
NOW WAIT.
WAIT.
TELL ME SOMETHING.
WHERE ARE
THE OTHER RIFLES?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WHEN DO THEY ARRIVE?
ANSWER THE QUESTION,
INDIAN.
- YOU GOT 'EM ALL.
- THAT IS NOT THE ANSWER!
- THERE AIN'T NO MORE GUNS!
- HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU KNOW, LYEDECKER,
AS I TOLD YOU BEFORE,
I THINK YOU'RE PART OF IT.
I AIN'T A PART
OF ANYTHING!
THIS MAN STOLE $6,000.
FOR THAT AMOUNT OF MONEY,
THERE CAN'T BE NO MORE GUNS.
YOU REFUSE TO ANSWER, EH?
LOOK, THERE AIN'T
NO MORE DAMN GUNS.
VERY WELL.
TOO BAD, GENTLEMEN.
i　SARGENTO PALETES!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
- [ Spanish ]
-[ Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
WHAT DID
ALL THAT MEAN?
LOOK LIKE
THEY'RE GONNA SHOOT US.
VERDUGO, I SUGGESTED
THAT IF THEY TOLD YOU
ABOUT THE MONEY...
YOU'D LET THEM GO.
GRIMES,
YOU RUN THE RAILROAD.
I'LL RUN
THE STATE OF SONORA.
AND DON'T YOU
EVER FORGET IT.
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Gives Command
In Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
- [ Spanish ]
- [ Spanish Continues ]
POR FAVOR, GENERAL--
i　NO, SENOR!
i　ALTO!
[ Spanish ]
[ Shouts Command
In Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Spanish Continues ]
[ Women, Children Screaming ]
[ Shouts Command
In Spanish ]
YOU KNOW SOMETHIN'?
WHAT?
I THINK OUR STRING
HAS DONE RUN OUT.
THE HELL IT HAS.
WE'RE GONNA
GET OUT OF THIS.
YEAH?
YEAH.
HOW?
WELL,
THERE'S NOTHIN' TO IT.
A BIG, GIANT HAND
IS GONNA REACH IN HERE,
PICK US UP,
TAKE US AWAY
AND PUT US DOWN
SOMEPLACE...
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF A WHOLE BUNCH
OF WOMEN AND WHISKEY.
THAT AIN'T FUNNY.
WELL, I AIN'T
LAUGHIN' NEITHER.
THAT AIN'T FUNNY AT ALL!
STAY OUT OF
OTHER PEOPLE'S BUSINESS.
THAT'S WHAT I ALWAYS SAID
AND THAT'S WHAT
I ALWAYS DONE.
BUT LOOK AT ME NOW.
SMART LYEDECKER.
HUNG UP ON A FENCE
WITH A BUNCH
OF SCRUFFY INDIANS.
WELL, THAT'S TOO BAD
ABOUT YOU.
YOUR NUMBER'S
COMIN' UP OVER THERE,
AND IT'S JUST TOO DAMN BAD.
YOU KNOW WHY?
NO, I DON'T KNOW WHY.
WHY?
'CAUSE YOU'D HAVE BEEN
A HELL OF A LAWMAN.
YOU DAMN RIGHT!
'CAUSE YOU DON'T CARE
ABOUT NOTHIN' OR NOBODY,
JUST LIKE ALL THEM BIG BOYS
WITH THEIR BADGES.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT BADGES?
YOU'RE JUST
A PISSANT BORDER HALF-BREED.
I KNOW A LOT ABOUT IT.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
THEM SMALL-TOWN, BARBERSHOP,
HAIR-CUTTIN' SHERIFFS.
AND I KNOW ALL ABOUT
THEM BIG-TOWN, BIG-BELLIED,
BILLY CLUB-SWINGIN'
POLICEMEN FROM ST. LOUIS.
YOU DON'T KNOW
NOTHIN'!
THE HELL I DON'T!
THEY LOOK YOU UP AND DOWN,
AND YOU'RE GUILTY!
YOU DON'T GET NO TRIAL,
JUST LIKE WE AIN'T
GONNA GET ONE NOW!
'CAUSE THEM GUYS OVER THERE
DON'T CARE ABOUT NOTHIN'
OR NOBODY, JUST LIKE YOU!
THAT'S WHY YOU'D HAVE BEEN
SOGOODWITH A BADGE.
WASHINGTON'S GOING TO
REACT VERY BADLY TO THIS.
WHAT ARE THEY
GOING TO DO?
SEND A NOTE SAYING,
"WHERE IS OUR
BLACK POLICEMAN?"
- AND THEN WHAT?
- THEY'LL ASK QUESTIONS.
THEY'RE GOING TO ASK MY COMPANY
A GREAT MANY QUESTIONS.
AND THEY WILL GET ANSWERS,
I'M SURE.
YOUR COMPANY
CARES FOR ITS TRAINS,
NOT FOR TWO GRINGOS
THAT DISAPPEAR IN MEXICO.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Spanish Continues ]
[ Spanish ]
i　FUEGO!
HOLD IT,
GENTLEMEN.
PADRE.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
MY SONS,
ALLOW ME TO HELP YOU--
WE AIN'T NO DAMN
SONS OF YOURS.
THERE'S PROBABLY MORE THAN ONE
SCATTERED AROUND HERE SOMEPLACE.
FEAR AND DESPAIR
ARE HUMAN FAILINGS.
YET WE ARE HUMAN.
MAKE YOURSELVES READY
TO DIE IN PEACE AND LOVE.
WHY DON'T YOU
TALK TO VERDUGO ABOUT
SOME OF THAT PEACE AND LOVE...
INSTEAD OF TRYIN'
TO GET SOMEBODY
READY TO DIE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AIN'T NO MAN EVER DIED
READY FOR IT.
I WANT YOU TO GO
WITH LOVE IN YOUR HEARTS.
I WANT YOU
TO GO TO HELL.
ALLOW ME TO HEAR
YOUR CONFESSION.
WHATEVER YOU GOT
IN THAT BOOK,
JUST PUT ME DOWN FOR IT.
[ Shouts Command
In Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
LYEDECKER.
WHAT?
I'M SORRY YOU GOT
MIXED UP IN THIS.
YOU AIN'T
HALF AS SORRY AS ME.
[ Mouths Words ]
[ Officer Shouts
In Spanish ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Shouting ]
i　ATAQUE!
[ Whinnies ]
- [ Shouting In Spanish ]
-[ Gunshots Continue ]
WHAT THE HELL?
GODDAMN IT!
COME ON! COME ON!
[ Yells ]
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
i　RAPIDO!
i　VAMOS! i　VAMOS!
HYAH! HYAH!
[ Spanish ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
I WANT THEIR HEADS.
SOME KIND OF WOMAN,
AIN'T SHE?
YEAH. KINDA STOUT.
[ Chuckles ]
NOW THAT YOU
GOT THEM RIFLES,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH 'EM?
- TAKE 'EM TO GENERAL ROMERO.
- GENERAL.
WHY EVERY TIME FOUR MEXICANS
GET TOGETHER, ONE OF 'EM
MAKES HIMSELF A GENERAL?
LOOK, YOU.
ROMERO CAN CALL HIMSELF
ANYTHING HE WANTS.
I KNEW HIM
WHEN HE WAS YOUNG,
WHEN HE BROUGHT
THE PEOPLE TOGETHER TO FIGHT.
GOOD OR BAD,
HE'S ALL WE HAVE.
IT'S A GOOD THING YOU HAVE HIM,
'CAUSE ME AND THAT ONE THERE,
WE GOIN' NORTH.
WE ARE, HUH?
YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE WAIT TILL WE GET THEM RIFLES
TO GENERAL ROMERO?
THEN I'LL GO EASY-LIKE.
[ Chuckles ]
UH-UH. NO GOOD.
LYEDECKER,
YOU'RE A MULE-HEADED
SON OF A BITCH.
YOU SAW ALL THEM INDIANS
HUNG UP LIKE A SIDE OF BEEF.
- AFTER ALL THE TROUBLE WE WENT
THROUGH TO GET THEM RIFLES--
- WE?
- YEAH, WE!
- [ Chuckles ]
LOOK, I SPENT 15 YEARS
IN THE 9th CAVALRY...
KEEPIN' THE LAW
AND CHASIN' BAD INDIANS.
BUT THIS ONE AIN'T MY BUSINESS,
IT AIN'T MY FIGHT
AND IT AIN'T MY JOB!
AND BESIDES,
I DON'T MUCH LIKE INDIANS
ANYWAY.
[ Spits ]
WE SHOULD HAVE KILLED HIM!
YEAH.
I THINK SHE'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW YOUR TROUBLE,
BIG MAN?
YOU'RE DUMB.
JUST PLAIN OL'
BLACK-ASS DUMB!
[ Groans ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Wheezing ]
[ Yells ]
- [ Yells ]
- [ Grunting ]
NOW WHO'S DUMB,
YOU HALF-BREED?
HUH?
I AM!
LET ME UP!
COME ON!
[ Grunting Continues ]
THANK YOU.
[ Yelling ]
[ Rifle Cocks ]
DON'T SHOOT HIM!
AND LET HIM KILL YOU?
THE RIFLES,
THEY ARE MORE IMPORTANT.
I DON'T WANNA
DRAG HIS BIG ASS
ALL OVER MEXICO.
- WHAT'S IT GON' BE?
- I GUESS I AIN'T GOT
MUCH OF A CHOICE, HAVE I?
[ Joe ]
WE SPLIT UP HERE.
YOU TAKE THE GUNS
UPRIVER.
I'LL MEET YOU
IN DELGADO.
[ Chattering ]
[ Speaking Spanish ]
I'M GLAD TO MEET YOU.
AH.
[ Spanish ]
WOMAN, WHAT ARE THEY
LOOKING AT?
IT'S THE FIRST TIME THEY'VE
SEEN A BLACK MAN BEFORE.
WELL, IF THEY WAIT A WHILE,
THEY'LL SEE THIS ONE
TURN INTO A CHILI BEAN.
[ Spanish ]
I SURE WISH I HAD MYSELF
A FRIED STEAK.
WELL, TWO OR THREE TIMES NOW,
YOU COULD'VE KILLED ME.
SI様.
THAT IS TRUE.
I NEED YOU.
WHAT FOR?
MIRA.
THOSE RIFLES,
THEY ARE WHAT KEEPS
JOE HERE.
HE IS WHAT KEEPS
YOU HERE.
I WANT YOU
TO HELP US.
NO, I WON'T DO THAT.
ARE YOU AFRAID?
YEAH. YEAH,
I RECKON I AM.
OH, NOT OF BEING SHOT AT.
THAT'S HAPPENED PLENTY BEFORE.
LYEDECKER, IF--
IF YOU WOULD JOIN
WITH US...
FOR JUST A LITTLE WHILE,
I WON'T WORRY
ABOUT YAQUI JOE.
AFTERWARDS,
YOU CAN HAVE HIM.
YOU AIN'T, UH,
PARTIAL TO HIM?
NO.
I DON'T TRUST HIM.
HE'S A BAD MAN.
BUT HE'S SMART,
AND HE'S IMPORTANT
FOR US NOW.
NOTHING ELSE?
NO.
NOTHING.
NO DEALS.
I'M GONNA TAKE HIM BACK, AND
THERE AIN'T GONNA BE NO DEALS.
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
WE GOT PROBLEMS. VERDUGO'S
ABOUT ONE MILE BEHIND US,
BUT I DON'T THINK HE SAW US.
GET THE RIFLES.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
i　VA誓MONOS!
[ Whistling ]
[ Shouting, Indistinct ]
ADIOS.
GRACIAS,KID.
[ Clicks Tongue ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Gunfire ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gunfire Continues ]
KEEP GOIN'!
GO ON!
i　SARGENTO!
MI GENERAL.
COLLECT ALL THE CHILDREN
AND TAKE THEM
TO THERANCHO.
[ Spanish ]
WITH THE GENERAL'S PERMISSION,
THE TIME MIGHT BE BETTER SPENT
COLLECTING THE RIFLES.
VON KLEMME, I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING
ONCE AND FOR ALL,
AND LET IT BE
A LESSON FOR YOUR FUTURE.
I NEVER DO ANYTHING
WITHOUT A PURPOSE,
AND REMEMBER THAT.
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
HUMARA.
[ Spanish ]
LOS NINOS. LOS NINOS.
EL RANCHO.
[ Groans ]
[ Sarita ]
YAQUI.
THE CHILDREN.
THEY'VE TAKEN
ALL OF THE CHILDREN...
AND HOLDING THEM
FOR THE RIFLES.
THEY'RE HOLDING 'EM
FOR US TOO, YOU CAN BET.
WELL, WE HAVE TO GO BACK.
LOOK, SARITA,
I THINK WE OUGHT
TO GO ON TO ROMERO,
GIVE 'EM THE GUNS,
AND GET SOME MORE MEN, HUH?
NO. WE HAVE TO GET
THOSE CHILDREN.
WE WILL.
WE'D BETTER MAKE THIS
QUICK AND QUIET.
[ Gasps ]
SHH!
[ Screaming ]
WELL, I WONDER IF HE DIED
READY FOR IT.
[ Hoofbeats Approaching ]
- [ Spanish ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Man Shouting
In Spanish ]
GET THEM KIDS
OUT OF HERE!
HEY, BIG FELLA.
HOW YOU DOIN', MAN?
[ Laughing, Shouting ]
WHERE'S JOE?
WHERE'S THE WHISKEY?
I GUESS YOU NEVER CAN TELL
WHERE THEY MIGHT GO
TO DRINK, HUH?
[ Gunshot ]
DON'T-DON'T SHOOT, LYEDECKER!
FOR GOD'S SAKE,
DON'T SHOOT!
I DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS YOU.
OBVIOUSLY!
[ Hysterical Laughter ]
HEY, JOE, LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
HEY, BIG BEN.
YOU AIN'T STILL THINKING ABOUT
TAKING ME TO PHOENIX
WITH YOU, ARE YA?
YOU'D BETTER BELIEVE IT,
HOMBRE.
WELL, YOU'RE A STUBBORN,
SON OF A--
DAMN.
[ Chuckles ]
WELL, WHAT'S YOU GONNA DO
WITH HIM?
WELL, UH, WHATEVER'S CUSTOMARY
AND WHATEVER YOU THINK IS RIGHT.
I'LL-I'LL BE GLAD
TO TAKE CARE OF HIM FOR YOU.
LYEDECKER, THIS IS SILLY.
THERE'S NO NEED FOR--
KEEP HIM ALIVE.
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO USE HIM LATER.
I'LL DO IT.
DIDN'T TURN OUT TO BE MUCH,
DID IT?
HMM?
[ Exhales ]
PRETTY FANCY, HUH?
FOR ME?
TOO FANCY FOR ME?
SHE HAD ONE LIKE IT
WHEN MY FATHER WORKED HERE
A LONG TIME AGO.
SHE'S DEAD NOW--
VERDUGO'S WIFE.
I ALWAYS WANTED ONE
LIKE IT.
IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU WERE BORN FOR IT.
IT'S A LIE.
BUT YOU'RE A PRETTY GOOD MAN
AFTER ALL, LYEDECKER.
I GUESS I KNOW THAT.
I KNOW WHAT I AM.
I DON'T HAVE TO GO
LOOKING FOR IT.
THEN WHY ARE YOU
A POLICEMAN?
IT'S A JOB.
EVERYBODY HAS TO DO SOMETHING.
WHAT THE JOB IS AIN'T IMPORTANT.
IT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
ARE YOU GOOD
AT WHAT YOU DO?
WELL, IT AIN'T MUCH DIFFERENT
THAN THE CAVALRY.
I DO THE BEST I CAN.
WELL, THAT IS
A HARD THING TO DO.
FOR ALL THE BAD THINGS
I HAVE SAID TO YOU,
I GIVE YOU THIS.
NO. NO! NO!
NO! NO!
PLEASE, NOT LIKE THIS!
NOT WITH YOU.
[ Moans ]
R!
[ Man ]
i　VIVA LYEDECKE
i　VIVA LYEDECKER!
LYEDECKER.
- [ Spanish ]
HE DIED YESTERDAY.
AH, SI様.THE BLACK GRINGO.
WE HAVE HEARD OF YOU.
[ Man ]
BUENOS DI様AS, MI GENERAL.
L.
[ All ]
BUENOS DI様AS, MI GENERA
BUENOS DI様AS, MI GENERAL.
BUENOS DI様AS,
MI GENERAL.
GOOD DAY FOR TRAVELIN',
AND WE'RE GONNA TRAVEL.
[ Spanish ]
HEY.
WHAT IS THIS STUFF?
WHAT IS THIS
"MI GENERAL"?
YOU MEAN YOU DON'T KNOW?
NO, I DON'T KNOW.
WELL, IT SEEMS THAT
YOU HAVE BEEN ELECTED
THE NEW GENERAL.
I AIN'T NO DAMN GENERAL.
THAT'S JUST--
THAT'S THE DUMBEST--
THAT'S JUST PLUMB CRAZY!
COME ON!
[ Together ]
BUENOS DI様AS, GENERAL.
[ Laughing ]
LOOK, YOU TELL THEM
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
TELL THEM I DON'T
WANT 'EM FOLLOWING ME.
[ Man Shouts In Spanish ]
[ Cheering ]
TELL 'EM TO GO AWAY.
TELL 'EM
I AIN'T NO GENERAL.
NOT FOR NO BAD-ASS INDIANS.
NOT FOR NOBODY.
YOU TELL 'EM.
IT LOOKS TO ME LIKE...
YOU'RE BACK IN
THE CAVALRY BUSINESS,
MI GENERAL.
[ Whistle Blowing ]
I'M SURE THE RIFLES
ARE SOMEWHERE UP THERE.
I CAN PROMISE YOU THAT,
WITH ROMERO.
NO.
IF HE GETS THE GUNS
AND THE AMMUNITION,
HE WILL PROBABLY
COME DOWN THAT MOUNTAIN,
AND WE'LL HAVE WAR.
I KNOW ROMERO.
HE'S A DYING TIGER.
HE WOULDN'T COME DOWNHILL
WITH AN ARMY OF
10,000 CANNONS.
NO.
LYEDECKER IS THE ONE.
I WANT HIS HEAD ON A STICK
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE PLAZA
FOR EVERYONE TO SEE.
LYEDECKER AND THE OTHERS.
SIR, I PERSONALLY THINK
WE OUGHT TO BE GOING
AFTER ROMERO.
[ Whistle Blowing ]
NOW, LISTEN TO ME,
VON KLEMME.
I KNOW ROMERO.
I KNOW THESE MOUNTAINS.
I KNOW MY COUNTRY,
AND YOU DON'T!
SO SHUT UP.
SHUT UP AND FOLLOW
MY ORDERS.
I WANT LYEDECKER.
BUENOS NOCHES, MI GENERAL.
BUENOS NOCHES,
MI GENERAL.
LYEDECKER?
OH. YOUR SUPPER
IS ALMOST READY.
TORTILLAS?
NO.
LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
YOU SAID FRIED STEAK.
[ Sighs ]
IS THAT, UM,
THE WAY IT IS?
IF THAT'S THE WAY
YOU WANT IT.
NO.
LET ME GET THAT.
HERE?
[ Spanish ]
LYEDECKER,
YOU ARE MY MAN.
YOU KNOW, YOU GOTTA BE, UH,
CAREFUL ABOUT A THING LIKE THAT.
I DON'T HAVE TO BE CAREFUL.
I AM YOUR WOMAN
FOR AS LONG AS YOU WANT IT.
DO YOU WANT ME?
WHAT DOES VERDUGO
USE THAT TRAIN FOR?
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
ANSWER THE QUESTION.
NOW, LOOK, YOU CAN'T BE--
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO WRECK THE TRAIN?
IN ONE MINUTE, I'M GONNA
PINCH OFF YOUR HEAD...
AND MAIL IT BACK
TO THE HOME OFFICE.
THE TRAIN CARRIES
TROOPS AND SUPPLIES
FROM NOGALES TO HERMOSILLO.
IT'S WELL-GUARDED.
DOES IT MAKE ANY STOPS
ALONG THE WAY?
NO.
NO STOPS.
[ Sarita ]
THERE IS A WATER TOWER...
IN THEPLANO,
THE FLAT PART.
HE STOPS THERE.
NOW, LOOK, YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO WRECK THE TRAIN.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT
IN THE MORNING.
LYEDECKER--
GOD!
DEAR GOD!
HE AIN'T GONNA HELP YOU.
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Spanish ]
i　HEY, MUCHACHOS!
i　UNA MUCHACHA!
[ Yelling, Shouting ]
[ Spanish ]
[ Sarita ]
NO, NO, NO, NO.
[ Spanish ]
[ Gunfire ]
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
HE AIN'T HERE.
WELL, MUST BE HE DIDN'T
MAKE THE TRIP THEN,
'CAUSE I'VE BEEN WATCHIN'
THIS CAR ALL THE TIME.
- HOW MANY DID WE LOSE?
- I DON'T KNOW FOR SURE.
HEY. YOU DID
A REAL FINE JOB.
YOU SEEN GRIMES?
NO.
LAST TIME I SAW HIM,
WE WERE DIGGIN' IN.
I SAW HIM.
HE HAD A HORSE.
I GUARANTEE YOU,
HE'S ALMOST TO NOGALES
BY NOW.
WHAT THE HELL ARE
WE GONNA DO NOW?
LOAD THE TRAIN UP.
WE'RE STILL GOIN' IN.
[ Spanish ]
UH, HELLO.
BUENOS DI様AS.
?
真VERDUGO AQUI様
WELL, IS HE HERE?
GRIMES, I SHOULD
HAVE YOU SHOT.
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO DO,
BECOME AN ADVENTURER?
WELL, THAT'S GOOD,
BECAUSE THE ROLE
DOES NOT SUIT YOU.
TELL ME, MR. GRIMES,
HOW DID YOU HAPPEN
TO BE WITH THEM
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
I WAS TAKEN AT
THE POINT OF A GUN.
I WAS A PRISONER.
FOR SO LONG?
ALL RIGHT.
HE DID RETURN...
FINALLY.
YOU ESCAPED, HUH?
YES.
UH-HUH.
THEY'RE GOING TO ATTACK
THE TOWN.
REALLY?
[ Laughing ]
HOW?
THEY'VE TAKEN THE TRAIN.
ARE YOU SURE?
YOU SAW IT?
I HEARD THE PLANS.
THERE WAS NOTHING
I COULD DO.
OF COURSE NOT.
LOOK.
LET THEM COME IN.
AND AFTER THEY'VE
GOTTEN OFF THE TRAIN,
WE CAN CATCH THEM
IN THE STREETS.
MR. GRIMES,
THAT WOULD BE AN INCREDIBLY
STUPID THING TO DO.
FIRST, YOU HAVE THEM
NICELY TRAPPED ON THE TRAIN,
AND THEN YOU ALLOW THEM
TO GET INTO
THE STREETS AND HOUSES?
GRIMES,
YOUR TRAIN WILL BE
A SMALL SACRIFICE
TO OUR CAUSE.
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Spanish ]
GO CHECK UP THERE--
THE MACHINE GUN.
YES, SIR.
i　ALTO!
i　FUEGO!
SARITA!
[ Shouting, Yipping ]
[ Shouts In Spanish ]
[ All Shouting ]
WE DID ALL RIGHT,
DIDN'T WE?
YEAH, I GUESS WE DID.
I MEAN, WE WON,
DIDN'T WE?
WELL.
WE WON, HUH?
YEP.
I THINK I CAN PUT THE TRAIN BACK
INTO RUNNING ORDER. I THOUGHT
YOU'D LIKE TO KNOW THAT.
IT'LL TAKE TIME, AND
I'LL NEED MEN FOR THE LABOR.
YEAH.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT, UH,
WE KNOW WHERE WE STAND,
HUH?
WHAT THE HELL FOR?
WELL, LOOK OUT THERE.
YOU'RE THEIR LEADER NOW.
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT THAT.
I AIN'T NO DADGUM
SUCH THING.
THEY THINK YOU ARE.
THEY DO?
THIS PLACE IS YOURS,
AND YOU HAVE AN ARMY.
WITH THEM, YOU CAN
CONTROL THE ENTIRE AREA
FOR GOOD OR BAD.
YOU'RE READY TO SAY NO
TO THAT?
DAMN RIGHT I AM.
[ Chuckling ]
OH, NO, YOU'RE NOT.
A MAN LIKE YOU...
WITH YOUR INTELLIGENCE?
THE WHOLE STATE CAN BE YOURS.
ALL OF SONORA.
NO. HELL, NO.
YOU HAVE TO.
THE CHOICE ISN'T YOURS.
THE DECISION'S BEEN TAKEN
OUT OF YOUR HANDS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT'LL HAPPEN
IF YOU WALK AWAY FROM ALL THIS?
THERE'LL BE ANARCHY.
WHAT--
THESE PEOPLE--
YOUR PEOPLE, THEY'LL
DRIFT APART WITHOUT A LEADER.
AND THEN ANOTHER GENERAL
WILL COME FROM MEXICO CITY...
WITH ANOTHER ARMY,
AND THESE STREETS'LL RUN
WITH BLOOD AGAIN.
YOU'LL NEED TO MOVE
MEN AND SUPPLIES.
YOU'LL NEED THE RAILROAD.
I'M SURE WE CAN COME
TO AN UNDERSTANDING.
LYEDECKER!
HEY, YOU AIN'T LEAVIN'
ARE YOU?
YEP.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
I MEAN, I AIN'T
GOIN' WITH YA.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA TELL 'EM?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA SAY?
WELL, I'LL TELL 'EM I JUST
DIDN'T BRING YOU BACK, JOE.
OF COURSE, THEY'LL BE ABLE
TO SEE THAT FOR THEMSELVES
ANYWAY, WON'T THEY?
YEAH, BUT YOU'RE THE LEADER.
I MEAN, IF YOU GO,
THERE COULD BE ANARCHY.
THERE COULD BE
BLOOD IN THE STREETS.
LOOK, JOE,
THEY'LL FOLLOW YOU NOW.
IN FACT, IT COULD BE
A GOOD DEAL FOR YOU.
YEAH, BUT, LYEDECKER,
WHAT DO YOU GOT TO GO BACK TO?
YOU CAME DOWN HERE WITH NOTHIN',
NOT EVEN A JOB PERMANENT.
AFTER ALL THEM YEARS,
NOTHIN'.
YEAH, I THOUGHT ABOUT THAT.
YOU DID?
WHAT'D YOU THINK?
I THOUGHT I OUGHTA GO BACK
AND GIVE IT ONE MORE SHOT.
LYEDECKER, MAYBE
I OUGHTA GO BACK WITH YA.
YOU DON'T WANNA
DO THAT, JOE.
YOU BELONG HERE,
AND I BELONG UP NORTH.
LIKE I SAID,
I WANNA GIVE IT
THAT ONE MORE SHOT.
AND, JOE,
GOOD LUCK, AMIGO.
ALL RIGHT, DADGUMIT,
LET'S GET THIS DADGUM
ARMY TOGETHER!
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
ALL RIGHT!