# Davy, Davy Crockett
# The man who don't know fear
# King of the Wild Frontier
# Born on a mountaintop in Tennessee
# Greenest state in the land of the free
# Raised in the woods
So's he knew every tree
# Killed him a bear
When he was only three
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# The buckskin pioneer
# In 1813, the Creeks uprose
# Addin' redskin arrows
To the country's woes
# Now old Andrew Jackson
As everybody knows
# Is the general they sent
To fight the foes #
[Jackson] Major. Major Norton.
- Yes, sir?
- Where's that scout I told you to find?
They say the best man is one
of the volunteers, Crockett.
- Where is he?
- Matter of fact, he's out hunting.
- Hunting?
- We need food. He's across the river.
That's enemy territory.
What you're short on is brains, not rations.
- He didn't take a gun, sir.
- I want this Crockett fellow now.
- Fetch him.
- Yes, sir.
[Norton] Crockett.
Crockett.
Davy Crockett.
Where's Crockett?
Speak up, man.
Where is he?
- [Growling]
- What's he doing in there?
He's tryin' to grin down a bear.
Grin down a...
You backwoods buffoons think
the rest of us'll believe anything.
Crockett. Crockett, can't you hear me?
[Growling]
Come out of there.
I've got a message...
- [growling]
- [Grunting]
You sure spoiled things good.
Now I gotta do it the old-fashioned way.
Yee-haw. Give him what for, Davy.
[Crockett grunting]
Stick with him, Davy.
[Growling]
Now, Major, what was it
you wanted to see me about?
[Panting] General Jackson
wants to see you.
As soon as we get that bear pulled up.
It's a fair-to-middlin' size critter.
[Cheering, indistinct chatter]
Full bellies tonight, boys.
- I hear you want to see me, General.
- That's right. Come inside.
Now, how'd you kill that brute?
With my knife.
I was figurin' on grinnin' him to death,
but this stumble-footed major
busted my concentratin'.
Grinnin' him to death?
What in thunderation is that?
It's somethin' I've been
experimentin' with.
You see, there's nothin'
so absolutely unresistable
as an old-fashioned,
good-natured grin, like this.
I started on 'coons.
I got so good at it,
an old 'coon throwed up his hands
the minute he seen my teeth.
"You got me," he hollered
and he skinned down that tree
and plopped himself in my sack.
I figured the same thing ought to work on
bears, but I never got a chance to find out.
The major come along
and busted up my concentratin'.
I wound up havin' to wrestle
this critter into table meat.
- Why was you hankerin' to see me?
- We're on the edge of enemy territory.
I want a scouting party to see
what them redskins is up to.
Major Norton and a squad of regulars
will accompany ya.
That wouldn't make the chore no easier.
Be sure the major brings back
the information I want.
Come on, Major.
Some of your boys rode water pretty deep.
Better look to their powder.
Re-prime your pieces.
From here on, don't make
no more noise. No talkin'.
Everybody keep close up.
Better stick closer to us, Major.
You've led us through swamps,
canebrakes, and briar patches all day.
I see a trail and
there's no sense in not taking it.
Has the general got your wife's address?
Take that trail and he's apt
to write her a sad letter.
We're here to locate Indians and
I don't like the way you're doing it.
We'll cover more ground if we separate.
I'll take that trail.
We'll be back here in this clearing
by dawn. See that you are.
Better fix up a signal to identify ourselves.
Can you do an old hoot owl?
Certainly.
[Hooting weakly]
That ought to fool the redskins just dandy.
[Laughing]
Come on.
[Davy] War party, a big one.
Here comes another bunch.
Head for cover.
[Speaking native language]
- That was Red Stick.
- What makes you so sure?
Creeks only got one young chief.
Gotta be him.
Let's leave the horses here.
[Chanting]
[Chanting, drums beating]
Looks like Red Stick's finally
talked the tribe into listening.
I don't know what he said,
but I sure don't like it.
I hope they keep that up a spell longer.
[Shouting, chanting]
We'd better get back to the major fast.
[Hooting]
[Gunshots]
Everybody take cover.
Take cover, men.
Sounds like the major
got himself in trouble.
- And we'll have to get him out.
- How?
- Surround 'em.
- Think there's enough of us?
We'll give 'em the ol' Crockett charge.
- [Crockett] Brigade, halt.
- [Russel] Company, halt.
Brigade... charge.
Company... charge.
It's the general and the whole regiment.
[Cheering]
All together now. Fire at will.
Charge. Yee-haw.
Advance on the line of skirmish.
Dragoons, dismount.
[Russel] Yippee. Yee-haw.
We got 'em on the run, men.
Company B, close up.
[Indistinct shouting]
Charge.
[Russel shouting]
Company A reportin'.
[Russel] Here's the rest of us, Major.
Company B reportin'.
- You mean, just two of ya?
- Two was enough, wasn't it?
- These varmints were just a little party.
- The Creek nation is gatherin'.
Take care of your casualties.
We'll get the news to the general.
The general's expectin' me.
- Sorry to disturb you, General.
- Never mind. What did you find out?
They aim to fight.
They had a big war dance last night.
- Where?
- Back in the mountain.
Red Stick, sir.
Red Stick? I'd sure like
to get my hooks on him.
We gotta move fast.
He's whippin' 'em up quick.
- Where's Major Norton?
- He had a little trouble.
Sentry.
What kind of trouble?
- Injun trouble, lost some men.
- Yes, sir?
Tell the sergeant major to order
the camp struck.
- Lookouts are accounted for.
- Good.
When we catch Red Stick,
this war will be over.
There's only two ways he can escape.
I got him stoppered.
As soon as the regulars are in position,
jump in and stir up them red hornets.
[Yelling]
Give it to 'em, boys.
[Gunshots]
Fire and fall back.
[Shouting]
Fire.
Sound assembly.
[Bugle]
I reckon Red Stick's tomahawk's
got an awful nick in it.
- Got away, didn't he?
- Yeah, but a lot of 'em didn't.
Much obliged for savin' my scalp.
Mrs. Crockett might have
a kiss for ya when we get home.
- [Man #1] Feelin' better, boy?
- [Man #2] I'll make it.
- Don't call it a victory around me.
- Their casualties were enormous.
We captured three chiefs and they
want to discuss terms for a peace.
- Peace?
- Excuse me.
- What do you want?
- Dropped in to say good-bye.
Good-bye?
Where do you think you're goin'?
Home.
You're going after Red Stick
with the rest of my command.
We ain't quittin' the war.
We'll be back.
You see, General, we only volunteered
for 60 days and that's long since up.
Catchin' Red Stick could take
the rest of the year.
We gotta take care of our families
before we start anything like that.
You're confined to this camp.
That's an order.
My missus'd worry about me.
Sorry, General.
If he leaves, it'll destroy
the discipline of the whole camp.
- He's attached to your command, Major.
- Then I'm gonna stop him.
Halt.
- I'm warning you. Turn back.
- You know we're goin' home.
Prepare to fire.
Careful, don't burn yourself.
Bring us some bear meat
when you come, Davy.
Sure. Anything you want, Major?
Blamedest bunch of volunteers
I ever saw.
When they volunteer to fight,
they fight.
When they volunteer to go home,
they go home.
# Off through the woods
He's a-marchin' along
# Makin' up yarns
and a-singin' a song
Hey, Ma. Pa's back.
Davy, you're back.
- Hello, Pa.
- Hi, Pa.
Whee.
Well, reckon now's as good a time
as any to collect what I got comin'.
Georgie Russel, what happened to you
while you been gone?
Davy allowed as how I had a kiss comin'
for savin' his life.
- He sure did.
- Well, in that case.
You ain't never gonna
get a woman that way.
Reckon I gotta learn ya how.
Missed ya an awful lot.
Missed you too.
The young'uns like
to pester me to death.
Not a mornin' passed they haven't said,
"Maybe Pa'll be home today."
But now, thank the good Lord
you're home for good.
Well, not perzactly.
The war ain't quite over yet.
- You goin' back?
- Well, not for a few days.
Not 'til I get in a supply of meat
for you and the young'uns this winter.
- You gonna be gone all winter?
- Well, I hope not.
- But I don't know how long it's gonna be.
- Oh, Davy.
Now don't take on. I had enough trouble
with the Army over me comin' home.
My major and I didn't see quite
eye to eye on it.
But I figured I was right.
And you know me.
When I'm sure I'm right, I go ahead.
# Headed back to war
From the ol' home place
# But Red Stick was leadin'
A merry chase
# Fightin' and burnin' at a devil's pace
# South through the swamps
On the Florida trace
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Trackin' the redskins down #
- Halt. Who goes there?
- Just us, me and Davy.
How the devil did you find us
way off down here?
You left a good trail: Army gear,
lame horses, sick men all the way.
- That's us, all right.
- Reckon we better report to the general.
General Jackson ain't here.
He done been called to New Orleans.
- Who's in command?
- Major Norton.
If I'd knowed that,
I wouldn't have come back.
Let's get it over with.
I have to admit I'm glad
to see you, Crockett.
You too, Russel.
I'm at my wit's end.
Most of my men have swamp fever.
I got a touch of it, too.
Still chasin' Red Stick?
It's a question of who's chasing who.
Every patrol I've sent out
has failed to come back.
He can't have many warriors left.
If we could just locate them, but they
can hide forever in this infernal swamp.
Me and Russel are rested up a mite.
It's only fair we take a cut at it.
No, no, that Indian has cost us
enough lives already.
I refuse to let you two go out alone.
Looks like we'll have to start
disobeyin' orders again.
Baby 'gators.
Kinda cute, ain't they?
I'm more scared of snakes and 'gators
than I am of Injuns.
Two days old, maybe more.
Moccasins just about wore out.
Headin' around the lake.
Suppose we scout both sides,
meet at the other end?
If you see any fresh sign, whistle like
a thrush. Like a Tennessee thrush.
[Bird whistle]
[Speaking native language]
Where are others?
You not come alone.
I come alone.
Creek warriors. Hear me.
Any more of you varmints
think I ain't worth listenin' to?
Speak, white man.
I ain't a soldier. I'm a settler.
- I'm a hunter like you.
- Hunter? You hunt Indians.
Only because you made war on us.
Your chiefs, the smart ones,
have give up.
They've found out that war is no good.
White man talk.
War no good because soldiers all die.
How many Creek warriors have died?
How many women
are crying for their men?
How many young'uns
ain't got no fathers?
- You talk like woman.
- I'm talkin' sense and you know it.
You're brave, Red Stick,
and your warriors is brave.
But in the end, they're all gonna die
because you're a bad chief.
Because I take many white scalps?
Because soon I burn white man's friend?
No, Red Stick, because you could all go
home in peace if you'd listen to reason.
But seein' as you won't,
I reckon I got to challenge you
accordin' to Injun law.
- Injun law no good for white man.
- Why not?
White man's law would be good for Injun
if you'd give it half a chance.
- How about it, Red Stick?
- Tomahawks.
[Cheering]
[Choking]
[Growling]
Well, it worked on a bear.
Ready to listen to reason now,
Red Stick?
I listen.
Turn my friend loose
and lay down your arms.
Join the other chiefs in a treaty.
Do that and I promise
the government'll let you
live in peace on your own lands.
Promises no good.
White government lie.
Davy Crockett don't lie.
Here's my hand on it.
Why you no kill me?
Maybe because of another law.
We have trouble livin' up to it.
It ain't bad for red man
or white man alike.
Thou shalt not kill.
[Speaks native language]
# Home for the winter with his family
# Happy as squirrels in the ol' gum tree
# 'Til spring set in and he started to be
# Restless for places he wanted to see
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Itchin' to move again #
For folks who've said good-bye as many
times as we have, it don't get easier.
I hope this is for the last time, Davy.
Now the Indian war's over,
try and find a piece of land
you'll be satisfied to settle down on.
I aim to, Polly. They say
that new territory's a paradise.
Don't kill all the bears
'til we get there.
Guess I better get goin'.
- Keep your sights clean, fellas.
- You got plenty of time.
Yeah, there's gonna be
a whole mess of kissin'.
You young'uns hold the fort down now.
Take care of yourself, Davy.
You take care of yourself too, Georgie.
When you get back, I suppose you'll
have more outlandish songs about Davy.
Feel one comin' on right now.
# Lookin' for a place
Where the air smells clean
# Where the trees is tall
And the grass is green
# Where the fish is fat
In an untouched stream
# And the teemin' woods
Is a hunter's dream
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Lookin' for paradise #
- You goin' any further?
- Not me. I like it fine right here.
[Mooing]
[Barking]
Hold on there, mister.
Who do we see about filin' a claim
on some land?
Why, me. But you'll have to wait 'til
after I judge a shootin' match.
A shootin' match? Any objection
to a couple of strangers buyin' in?
Save your money.
You'll be shootin' against Big Foot Mason.
- Reckon we can risk a dollar?
- [Gunshot]
Sounds like they started without ya.
- You should have waited for me, Big Foot.
- You wasn't here.
Right in the notch, Big Foot.
- That's the last round. The beef's mine.
- Wait a minute.
This ain't fair judgin'.
Them's friends of yours.
Don't hear no complaints
from the losers.
Hey, what do you figure
that beef you won's worth?
$15 cash money, why?
Never went to a shootin' match
without gettin' at least one shot off.
One shot it is.
Hey, Bruno, charge up my other rifle.
Give it two extra thimbles.
Take care of these cartwheels.
This time you do the judgin'.
Mighty fancy shootin' iron
for this part of the woods.
Yeah, ain't it?
Dead center for Big Foot.
This one's dead center too.
You'll have to fire another round.
You was lucky.
Less'n a finger off the notch.
Better save your powder, stranger.
Why, he didn't even cut paper.
That'll take the turpentine
out of your bark.
- I was a-fearin' you fired too fast.
- Let's take a look.
- He missed the whole blamed board.
- [Old man] I ain't so sure.
Looky here.
One bullet right on top of the other.
Yee-haw.
That's the kinda shootin' makes
the ol' possum squeal.
Come on.
Here.
You're the first ones
in over to them parts.
Nearest neighbor's a Cherokee,
name of Charley Two Shirts.
Nice folks.
Thank you, Mr. Russel.
Davy Croc... you Davy Crockett?
- Why, sure.
- Davy Crockett.
No wonder you won Big Foot's beef
away from him.
[Russel] Didn't seem too happy about it.
No, Big Foot ain't used
to things goin' again' him.
Got folks pretty well
buffaloed around here.
So I noticed.
We had the beginnin's
of a decent community here,
before him and his riffraff moved in.
- What are they doin' here?
- Nobody dares talk much about it.
They been runnin' the Injuns off
their land, sellin' it to newcomers.
Government guarantees the Indians
their lands by treaty.
Treaties don't mean nothin' to Big Foot.
- Why don't somebody stop him?
- Fella that was magistrate here tried.
Went over to serve a warrant on him.
Never come back.
He had the prettiest rifle
ever seen in these parts.
Nobody knows what happened to him,
but we know where his gun is.
Yeah, Big Foot was shootin'
with it against Davy today.
That's right. Crockett, you're the only one
I know that could stand up to him.
Will you take on the job as magistrate?
- What would I have to do?
- Get us some law and order around here.
Well, I ain't crawfishin',
but I kinda got my hands full.
We gotta finish our cabins,
so I can bring my family.
It ain't no fit place for families
as long as they're runnin' loose.
What do you say?
Well, take some thinkin'.
- I'm drier than a powder horn.
- Fetch me some too.
[Whistling]
Hey. This what stood your hair up?
[Speaking native language]
- I was sure I seen a man.
- Nobody's gonna hurt ya. Come on out.
Come out of there.
- Who are you?
- Charley Two Shirts.
- He's our neighbor.
- What happened to you?
Three white men come to my farm.
Tell Charley Two Shirts, "Get off."
I say, "This my land."
They say, "Indian got no land."
I show paper.
This land belong Cherokee.
They tear paper up,
then Charley Two Shirts fight.
Reckon I'm gonna take on that job
of magistrate right now.
Hey, Big Foot.
Lookin' for somebody?
Yeah, the man that run my friend here
off his land.
I know who you are. Since when
is Davy Crockett a friend of Injuns?
Always been a friend of the Cherokees.
Got no bones to pick with the others
since we made peace.
This land's too good for Injuns.
I'm filin' on it.
No, ya ain't. Injuns got rights.
They're folks same as anybody else.
Take a powerful argument
to convince me of that.
- That's what I come for.
- I've ate better men than you whole.
- How'll you have it, Big Foot?
- Rough and tumble. No holds barred.
Now ya got him, Big Foot.
Oh.
[Big Foot screams]
[Speaking Cherokee]
That goes for me too.
[Russel] Give him what for, Davy.
[Gunshot]
Get 'em, Charley.
Come on.
Get up. I said, get up.
- Much obliged, Charley.
- Come on, get goin'.
- What you aimin' to do to us?
- Me? Nothin'.
But you're gonna stand trial.
You two varmints got a lot to answer for.
Now get.
[Caller indistinct]
Davy Crockett.
- Howdy.
- Howdy, Mr. Russel.
- Quite a frolic you got.
Ain't it?
Since Davy's been magistrate here,
we can enjoy ourselves
without it turnin' into a brawl.
I'll do the tradin' and meet ya out
by the dance. Save a pretty girl for me.
Before that fiddle gets into your foot,
I got some tidings for ya.
Come over to my place.
I'll tell ya about it.
Folks around here is pretty proud
of the job you done for us, Davy.
Since you got rid of Big Foot,
honest settlers is movin' in.
There's so many of 'em we're gonna
get us representation in Nashville.
That's what I want to talk to you about.
We held a meetin' last night to pick
who we want to run for state legislature.
- You won hands down.
- [Chuckling]
Well, I'm plumb flutterated by the honor,
but I ain't no politician.
You got the wrong bear up a tree, Judge.
Better get somebody more fittin'.
Like Amos Thorpe?
That lawyer who tried to get Big Foot off?
- You wouldn't run him?
- We wouldn't, but the opposition is.
Thorpe's got plenty of money
to spend on a campaign.
Money he made off
them Injun land grabs.
We figure you're the only man
that's got a chance of beatin' him.
Will ya run again' him?
The way you put it,
I ain't got much choice.
[Cheering, applauding]
Hey, I got a letter for ya.
Be right back.
It's only a month old too.
This ain't Polly's hand.
It's mighty poor writin'.
See if you can make it out.
- From your sister-in-law.
- Why'd she be writin'?
"Dear Davy, I take my pen in hand
to tell you some very sad news."
"Your beloved Polly was took...
was took down with a fever
and died in spite of all we could do.
The end was peaceful.
We buried her on the knoll
near your cabin.
Don't worry about the boys.
They are living with us
and getting along fine.
Little ones need a mother and
already they seem like my own.
We know you are suffering
the greatest loss a man can endure,
but the good Lord knows best.
Your loving sister-in-law."
[Sigh] Wish there was somethin'
I could say, Davy.
Anything I could do?
Just give me some time by myself.
# Now he lost his love
And his grief was gall
# In his heart he wanted to
Leave it all
# And lose himself in the forest tall
# But he answered instead
To his country's call
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Beginnin' his campaign #
Well, here it goes.
My honorable opponent knows
I ain't much shucks at speechifyin'.
Kind of him to let me speak first, so he
can make a lie out of everything I say.
[Crowd laughing]
Truth is, I don't know nothing at all
about politics. I'll leave that up to him.
But I do know the woods
and the folks in 'em.
If you send me to Nashville,
I'll represent you as honest as I can.
Hooray for Davy.
I reckon that's all I got to say.
If this here speech seems a mite brief,
looks like my worthy opponent's
all set to make up for it.
If his speech is gonna be
as dry as I think it is,
maybe we better go over
to the tavern and wet our whistles.
[Cheering] Come on, boys.
Voters of the sovereign state
of Tennessee, I am well aware
of the sacred responsibility
you're about to bestow on me...
# Sent up to Nashville
The best they could find
# A fightin' spirit and a thinkin' mind
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Choice of the whole frontier #
- Is Colonel Crockett at home?
- No, but I'm expectin' him directly.
I'm Tobias Norton.
He served under me in the Indian wars.
Would you like to wait in his room?
- You remember me, don't you?
- So you're Tobias Norton.
Never did know your first name, Major.
No rank any more, Davy.
I resigned from the Army three years ago.
- It's just plain Mr. Norton now.
- Sit down. What can I do for ya?
Just a sociable call.
I've been meaning to look you up.
Wish I could offer you something.
No, thanks. I never drink
before sundown, Colonel.
I ain't rightly a colonel. That was
in the militia, out in the canebrake.
We've watched your career
in the legislature with a lot of interest.
- Just who's "we"?
- Why, General Jackson and myself.
As you may know,
we're opening a political battle
with the present administration.
We're going to make Andrew Jackson
the next president of the United States.
I had a notion old hickory-face
was travelin' along on his own shanks.
Well, everyone needs help, you know.
I'm sort of a campaign manager,
unofficially of course.
Ever been out to the Hermitage?
No, but I sure heard about it.
I could get you an invitation.
The general would be glad to see you.
I'd admire that just fine.
- Howdy, General.
- Welcome, Crockett.
Come in. I'll be right down
soon as I get my boots on.
Don't hurry, General.
Good afternoon, Mr. Crockett.
Take your hat, sir.
Glad you could come out, Crockett.
It's been a long time
since we've seen each other.
You ain't changed, except
you ain't so fearsome out of uniform.
And you ain't so gamey without
your buckskins. Come on in.
Yes, everything's imported.
Except this.
Been savin' it for home folks.
Can't keep it in a decanter.
Eats the bottom out.
To your health, Crockett.
Here's somethin' else
I have to keep out of sight.
Exploits of Davy Crockett
in the Rocky Mountains.
I ain't never been west of the
muddy ol' Mississip. Let me see that.
Somebody's got a mighty
powerful imagination.
"As told by his friend,
G.E. Russel."
Georgie Russel.
I might've knowed.
They're making you famous.
Next to me you're about the most
famous man in Tennessee.
No wonder people's
taken to pointin' me out.
It's not only these yarns.
You've made yourself quite
a name in local politics.
Soap is only good for
washin' dirty hands.
Well, it's a fact.
Now, you listen to me.
I'm going to run for president.
My enemies will lift my scalp
if I get to Washington City.
I intend to take theirs first,
if I can get the right kind of help.
Crockett, I want you
to run for Congress.
Congress? General, you sure an old
head wound didn't trouble you a little?
I mean it.
I want men I can trust.
Men I know are with me.
Men that can get the country behind me.
If I was to do what
you asked and I did get in,
I wouldn't be takin' orders from you.
I'd be takin' 'em
from them that elected me.
That's just the answer I hoped I'd get.
# The votes were counted
And he won hands down
# So they sent him off
To Washington town
# With his best dress suit
Still his buckskins brown
# A livin' legend
Of growin' renown
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# The canebrake Congressman #
Good mornin'.
Just a minute, Your Honor.
Hiya, Davy.
I wondered when you
was gonna show up.
You ol' bear wrestler you.
How are you?
I put up with your singin'
them lies about me,
but printin' 'em is goin' too far.
- They helped put you here.
- Now I gotta live up to 'em.
You think I can go in dressed
like a respectable congressman?
I gotta go like the King of the Wild Frontier,
thanks to you.
That's ungrateful.
I come all the way from the Obion River,
to wish ya luck
on your maiden speech.
You just get yourself up in the gallery.
You're gonna hear a gullywhomper.
[Indistinct chatter]
[Gavel pounding]
Before we get to the order
of business for the day,
the chair will recognize the
new gentleman from Tennessee,
the honorable David Crockett.
Mr. Speaker, gentlemen.
The fella around called
a Master-At-Arms
tells me a new congressman's
supposed to make a speech.
Well, here she goes.
I'm David Crockett,
fresh from the backwoods.
I'm half horse, half alligator and
a little attached to a snappin' turtle.
[All chuckling]
I got the fastest horse, the prettiest sister,
surest rifle and ugliest dog in Tennessee.
My father can lick
any man in Kentucky,
and I can lick my father.
I can hug a bear and eat any man
opposed to Andy Jackson.
Some congressmen take pride in sayin'
a lot about nothin', like I'm doin' right now.
Others don't do nothin' for their pay
but just listen day in and day out.
I wish I may be shot
if I don't do more than listen.
The next time I get up before ya,
I'll have somethin' to say worth sayin'.
Made yourself at home here.
Buildin' that stable for your racehorses?
Man's got to have a way
to get his mind off his troubles.
This job's twice as tough as
fighting Injuns and ain't half the fun.
I know what you mean.
More government business is done
at fancy dress balls
than on the floor of Congress.
A man's got to skin the cat
any way he can. You know that.
What's important is keepin'
men like you behind me, solid.
You put a strain on a fella sometimes,
Mr. President.
You're bound to make mistakes,
and you've made some humdingers.
Davy, the President can't
think of just one group.
We're growing too fast.
There's nearly 13 million of us now.
We're bustin' at the seams.
We need room to grow.
Expansion.
That's what I'm thinkin' of.
And by the eternal, I'll not let
anything stand in the way of that.
Good morning, Congressman.
I'd like to speak to you a moment.
I see ya ain't combed all
the nits out of your hair, Davy.
Norton's changed.
He's been a lot of help to me.
I was planning to see you later.
How long have you been in town, Russel?
I've arranged for you to do
a speaking tour of the big Eastern cities.
- I got work to do.
- That can wait. This is more important.
You're the logical choice.
- Now, hold on. Why me?
- You've become a national figure.
Everybody's heard of you
and wants to see you.
- You can do a service for the country.
- By tellin' backwoods jokes?
I'm serious, Davy.
This tour is an opportunity.
You've got to think ahead.
Jackson's in his second term.
In three years, they'll be
electing a new president.
And some of us have been
seriously considering you.
Under the circumstances,
you can't afford to pass this up.
- Is it convenient to leave Sunday?
- Well...
- I guess so.
- I'll arrange your passage.
I enjoyed talking to you, Russel.
Davy, you used to have a motto.
"Be sure you're right,
and then go ahead."
Well, I sure hope you're right.
# Him and his jokes traveled
All through the land
# His speeches made him friends
To beat the band
# His politickin'
Was their favorite brand
# And everyone wanted
To shake his hand
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Helpin' his legend grow #
Citizens of Philadelphia,
this here's the most beautiful rifle gun
I ever hope to see.
She's so pretty, I'll give her a name.
Betsy suit you folks?
Now you all heard about me baggin'
105 bears in one winter.
Betsy here ain't gonna
come to no such use.
I don't get no joy out of
killin' critters like that no more.
Why, the last bear I treed
I brung home alive.
We tamed him and now he sits
at the table like a man.
Named him Death Hug.
I wouldn't wonder if he was smart enough
to travel and maybe go to Congress.
[All laughing]
Now, I hate long-winded speeches
and this one's long enough.
I'll always treasure this here
testimony of your friendship.
With a gun like this a man could
put a rifle ball through the moon.
First chance I get, I'm gonna try it.
Thank you.
What sliver's under your toenail?
Remember you tellin' me
how helpful Norton was?
He helped you out of Washington
'cause you was in the way.
- Of what?
- The President's Injun bill.
- That's not on the floor.
- It's in debate now.
What?
Couple of your friends are tryin' to stall,
but no tellin' how long they can hold out.
Looks like my tour's over now.
How's the quickest way back?
- Way I come, in the saddle.
- I know where we can get fresh horses.
Haven't you been able
to force the vote yet?
The opposition won't yield the floor.
Get them to call that vote.
- I didn't expect you back for a week.
- I know.
If you're worried about the Indian bill,
it's over. They've passed it.
They'll have to change their minds.
I'm warning you. Go in there
and you commit political suicide.
Know what I think about your politics?
I yield to the gentleman
from Tennessee.
Mr. Speaker,
fellow members of the Congress
of these United States,
I've stood before you a good
many times in fights and fun.
We've had a laugh for the country
and our own digestion.
But you can fold up your grins
and put 'em away,
for you'll hear no jokes
from Davy Crockett today.
You have before you somethin'
called an Indian bill.
I don't aim to keep you here
much longer arguing.
You've had enough of that.
But before it comes to a vote,
I want to remind you of something.
Expansion is a mighty fine thing.
Sure, we gotta grow.
But not at the expense of the things
this country was founded to protect.
The government's promises in the treaties
is as sacred as your own word.
Expansion's no excuse for persecutin'
a whole part of our people
because their skins are red
and they're uneducated to our ways.
You wouldn't be doin' the settlers
no good votin' for this bill.
You'd only be makin' rich men out of
the land grabbers tryin' to get it passed.
Now, just who are these scalawags?
One of 'em could be the President,
usin' this Congress for his own purpose.
But I've known General Jackson
for half of my born life,
and I'm sure he's got nothin'
but the good of the country at heart.
No, it's just a few thievin' varmints
hangin' on by givin' dinners and parties,
reachin' for whatever
they can get a hold of.
But they're a no-count lot,
'bout as natural as flies around molasses.
The real scalawags in this capitol
of the brave and free is us, you and me.
I'm the worst of the lot. Reckon I've
missed as many sessions as any of you.
Out shootin' my mouth off
when I should have been here.
It's nobody's fault but our own
if a bill like this gets passed.
We got a responsibility to this strappin',
fun-lovin' young bear cub of a country.
We got a responsibility to help it grow into
the kind of nation the Lord meant it to be.
If we showed we were the men our friends
figured we was when they sent us here,
a bill like this would never live
long enough to even get on our desks,
let alone come to a vote.
# He knew when he spoke
His career was done
# But he spoke out strong
And his point he won
# Then packed his gear
And his trusty gun
# And lit out a-grinnin'
To follow the sun
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Hittin' the trail again #
Oh, there you are.
Hey, Davy...
ain't you gonna get no sleep?
- I've been doin' some thinkin'.
- Me too.
We're pretty far downriver.
Ain't it time we decided where we're goin'?
- Always have had a good idea.
- Where?
"Texas independence threatened."
"General Santa Ana
vows to expel settlers."
Texas?
We got the whole country to choose from,
and you gotta pick...
- Nothin' there but a mess of trouble.
- Americans in trouble.
A bunch of crazy fools tryin'
to take on a whole army.
They're so far away from the rest of
the country, they know they won't get help.
A bunch of rock-headed idiots that won't
quit because they think they're right.
How soon you reckon we'll
be headed out that way?
Right after we get to Little Rock.
A magnificent birthright,
flung willfully into the gutter.
A superb inheritance of mind and body,
squandered recklessly
in the muck of the common herd.
Talents dissipated, courage abandoned,
character destroyed.
Gentlemen, the very one
for whom I've been waiting.
'Tis truly written,
"Hope springs eternal."
I've been thinking I might yet
find redemption in the company
of some peerless paragon of manhood
and virtue such as yourself.
You too, of course.
In other words, you want
Davy to be your backbone.
Backbone?
That's putting it rather bluntly, sir.
I am offering the Colonel
my incomparable companionship.
Me and Russel are figurin'
on headin' down Texas way.
That ain't no place for a riverboat gambler
with wobbly knees.
There are times when cowardice
is a virtue, my dear Colonel.
It makes choosing a course simple.
I know nothing of this Texas,
but I do know the fury
of the outraged minions of the law,
and as a consequence,
I fear what lies behind me
far more than the unknown,
which lies ahead.
Surely, you'll not deny me
the pleasure of your illustrious company.
Look, in the mornin'
don't forget this was your idea.
# He heard of Houston
And Austin and so
# To the Texas plains
He just had to go
# Where land was free
And there was room to grow
# And freedom was fightin'
Another foe
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# King of the wild frontier #
Well, there she is.
[Davy] Texas.
There's room out there
for every dream I ever had.
Yeah, there's room, all right.
Too much of it.
A desolate, desiccated desert,
untouched by the hand
of man and God alike.
Well, there's somebody around,
and they know we're here.
- Indians?
- Probably Comanches.
You mean, that barbaric horde
they call the Cossacks of the Plains?
Same critters.
We better be gettin' out of here.
[Low rumble]
Whoa.
- What unearthly manifestation is that?
- Supposin' we find out.
[Davy] There's your Comanches.
That's what stampeded 'em.
He's crazy. He's headed
into that prairie dog town.
Don't just stand there.
Give me a hand.
Bite off more than you could chew?
He might not look it, but he's
a powerful lot of Indian.
If we can patch him up,
he'll make us a good guide.
I can hardly wait to sink my teeth
in this buffalo meat.
- Your friend's awake.
- [Davy] Good.
Think I'll have a palaver with him.
Can the Colonel actually
converse with that aborigine?
Watch.
He's tellin' Davy about himself
but I can't get it all.
Near as I can make out,
this Indian's had a hard time.
He's been on many war parties
and never got a scalp.
The medicine man took his squaw
and kicked him out of the tribe.
On top of that, his pony fell
and he lost a buffalo.
With all his busted luck,
sure you want him for a guide?
Lucky we ran into him. If we'd have
kept on goin', we'd have lost our hair.
Lost our hair?
Mmm, smells good.
Says he's willin' to lead us
to a white settlement.
I, for one, do not trust
that perfidious savage.
You better trust him. He's the only one
that knows the trail to the next water hole.
Mornin'.
There's a settlement of Texans
down this way. Know where it is?
- You mean San Antonio de Mexar?
- Yeah, that's her, San Antone.
It is not safe to go over there.
General Santa Ana
has already taken Mexar.
If he's taken the town,
where are the Texans?
In the Alamo,
an old mission across the river.
- We got here a mite late.
- Let's see if we can make up for it.
You must not go there. The Alamo
has been surrounded by a big army,
and there's many patrols all over.
We got through Injun country
without trouble.
Company, forward.
[Speaking Spanish]
- They don't look very friendly.
- Let's get.
[Gunshots]
[Rifle shots]
[Distant gunshots]
Cover 'em.
- That was a tight squeeze. You all right?
- I reckon.
- You in command?
- I'm second.
- Col. Bowie's commander.
- The fella who invented the knife?
That's him. Come on.
He's been laid up. He took a fall
helping us mount the cannon.
The fever's been giving him
the devil ever since.
Colonel, we have more reinforcements.
- I'll see your men are taken care of.
- Thank you.
- Colonel Bowie?
- Yeah.
I brought a company in
and wanted to report.
I'm Davy Crockett
from Tennessee.
Davy Crockett.
I should've known.
By God, I never hoped to see you
in this neck of the woods. Sit down.
[Coughs] I can't get rid of this cough.
- Tell me. How many men did you bring?
- Four, includin' myself.
Four?
Two acres of wall to defend.
It'd take 1,000 troops to man
this garrison adequately.
I've got less than 200 volunteers.
200 stubborn men
can do a lot of fightin'.
Crockett, I'm gonna be honest with you.
This miserable excuse
of a fort is our last chance.
If we can't hold Santa Ana until Houston
reorganizes our army, Texas is lost.
Well, we'll just have to hold her.
Right.
I want to tell you
what we're up against.
We're practically encircled.
On top of that, we don't
have enough rations left
for a good-sized family dinner.
Powder? There's about enough left
for a turkey shoot.
None of this goes
outside this room.
Sure, Colonel. These 200 you got,
ain't there any more Texans around?
We've been sending messengers out.
One did get back from Gonzales
with 32 men.
There's a fair-sized force at Goliad.
We sent a courier a few days ago.
- But I don't think he made it.
- I'll take a crack at gettin' through.
No, we need your breed of men here.
Half horse, half alligator.
The amount of powder in the gun's
not near as important
as the spirit of the men
behind the sights.
Half any battle's
knowing you'll win.
Crockett, for the first time since
I've been here, I believe we can hold out.
With old Betsy here, and this here
Arkansas toothpick of yourn,
how can we lose?
Look at that camp. Every morning
there's twice as many as the night before.
I bet there's 2,000 of them.
Why did Santa Ana call that truce,
sent for that messenger?
[Russel] Whatever it is, it ain't good.
With His Excellency's compliments.
Crockett, come down here.
Listen to this, Colonel.
[In Spanish]
It's so flowery, it must've
been written by some other attorney.
Roughly translated, it means
we surrender on his terms or...
- I ain't much authority on surrenderin'.
- Neither am I.
Moriarty.
His Excellency's
offered to let us surrender.
He's waitin' for an answer.
Let's give it to him. Fire in the hole!
Hit the dust.
They say that war is the most
exalted experience a man can endure.
To me, it's the most miserable
and untheatrical method of suicide.
Shelled us all night and all day,
ain't hit a man yet.
You ain't got nothin' to worry about.
Ain't nobody gonna hit you.
You're too shifty.
You volunteers better get
food and rest while you can.
Sorry, no rest for the
gunners and officers.
Go get some food.
You too.
Take your relief, men.
I'll get yours for you, Davy.
Some of the boys are gettin'
worn pretty thin.
Four days and no casualties yet.
Incredible.
How much longer
will our luck hold up?
This ain't luck.
It's the hand of Providence.
- You really believe that?
- I sure do.
So do I, Davy.
You call that a serving?
It's difficult to maintain
manly courage on this provender.
Would you care to tempt lady luck,
double or nothing?
Why not?
My stomach sure ain't gonna miss this.
You hold the stakes, Busted Luck.
Come, my sporting friend.
We'll venture our fortunes
with the elusive pea.
Neither voodoo, hoodoo nor Hindu.
Prestidigitation, an old and honorable art.
Now you see it, now you don't.
Choose.
Oh, you'd risk your pittance of food
for a chance of a full belly?
Very well, my hungry aborigine,
since you thrust the wager upon me...
Choose.
There.
- How ya doin'?
- Keepin' awake.
I just found out somethin'.
We're sittin' here like a bunch
of treed possums.
We're about out of ammunition.
There's no help comin'.
I knowed that since the day we got here.
We're still holdin' out.
Since the day we...
You knowed it since then?
Colonel asked me not to say anything.
You knowed and
you couldn't trust me,
after all the tight ones
we've been through?
I thought we was in this together.
We're both wore out.
Go get some sleep.
All right. From now on,
it's every man for hisself.
- What do you want?
- I had to see you.
Was it necessary to wake me up?
I ain't scared of fightin',
but this is gonna be a massacre.
- Not if we get help from Goliad.
- But you ain't got it.
You ain't got no way of tellin' unless
you get a messenger through.
You think you can make it?
I've been in and out of bear traps
all my life. I ain't lost no toes yet.
- When do you want to try?
- Right now.
I'll have the Colonel's
horse saddled up.
Good. Now, how do I get
to this Goliad town?
That's a good question.
Here's a drainage ditch,
sort of a sunken road.
If the moon's behind a cloud
and the sentries are asleep,
and if you have more luck
than one man's entitled to,
you might get through
their lines here.
- Why, that man's deserting.
- Deserting?
That's Russel trying to make it
to Goliad for help.
Russel?
If you're worrying about Russel, don't.
He's only been gone two days.
It's nearly 100 miles to Goliad.
- Couldn't make it back, then.
- Not yet. He'd have to wait for darkness.
[Explosion]
- There she is.
- Gun crew, over there in that draw.
Save the big pop gun.
It eats too much powder.
They ain't as far off as they think
they are, are they?
Obligin' of 'em to move in so close.
Moriarty, hold it.
- Leave a mite too much windage.
- Raise my sights a mite.
Guess you boys haven't
had enough practice.
He says old Betsy'll reach.
[Cheering]
That's more like it.
Hey, it's Russel.
- Open the gates.
- [Rifle shots]
- How many men will they send us?
- They can't spare us none.
You eternal idiot.
You was safe, in the clear.
- What'd you come back for?
- Just got lonesome, I reckon.
Notched you up like an ol' razorback.
They can't shoot for sour apples.
We won't get any help from Goliad.
I can't keep this from my men any longer.
Break it to Colonel Bowie.
Have him move to a room in the chapel
where there's more protection.
[Gunfire]
Oh, it's you, Davy.
Mighty good of you
to keep lookin' in on me.
When a man's laid up,
he gets tired of his own company.
I'm glad to see a friend's face.
Friends for less than a week.
Pity we didn't meet before.
Russel made it back from Goliad.
Tell me, did he...
No help.
I brought those men in here.
Reckon I better be with 'em now.
Take it easy, Colonel.
I'll get you outside.
Hornbuckle. Contreras.
Move the Colonel outside.
I've called you all together
because it's time you knew the truth.
Russel brings bad news, men.
The defense of the Alamo
rests on us alone.
General Santa Ana has nearly
5,000 men massed against us.
I can't force you beyond patriotism
and your own conscience.
While it's still dark,
there's time to slip off to safety.
I won't blame any man
who doesn't stay.
Those who stay,
cross over the line.
Boys, I don't think
I can make it myself.
I'd appreciate it if some of you
would help me across.
Thank you, men.
- It's been a long time for us, Georgie.
- Yeah, a lot of years.
A lot of things to remember.
Play us a little tune.
Why don't you play one, Davy?
That piece you made up when we was
leavin' the green hills of Tennessee.
- Figured you'd remember that 'un.
- Yeah, it's the only one you ever writ.
Fellas like it too.
# Farewell to the mountains
# Whose mazes to me
# Were more beautiful far
# Than Eden could be
# The home I redeemed
# From the savage and wild
# The home I have loved
# As a father his child
# The wife of my bosom
# Farewell to ye all
# In the land of the stranger
# I rise
# Or I fall
# Farewell to the mountains
# Whose mazes to me
# More beautiful far
# Than Eden could be
# The home I redeemed
# From the savage and wild
# The home I have loved
# As a father his child
# The wife of my bosom
# Farewell to ye all
# In the land of the stranger
# I rise
# Or I fall #
Hadn't you better get a little rest?
It's a capital idea.
It may be our last.
They're on us.
Here they come. Wake up, men.
On your feet.
[Military bugle call]
Ya-hoo. We're holdin' 'em.
Colonel, what's that bugle call
they were playin'?
That's their signal for no quarter.
Yeah?
Well, they'll be playin' that again.
Here they come.
They've breached the north wall.
Let's swing the cannon.
Come on.
Fire in the hole!
Give 'em what for, Davy.
# Storybooks tell
They was all cut low
# But the truth of it is
This just ain't so
# Their spirits'll live
And their legends grow
# As long as we remember
The Alamo
# Davy, Davy Crockett
# Fightin' for liberty #