(Majestic music)
(Dramatic orchestral music)
(Fast-paced orchestral music)
Easy, Vern.
You want to get me caught again?
I can hurry him up.
Would we have yanked you
out in the face of that mob
Just to get you caught again?
Them people back in
town want to burn me.
Burn me alive.
You had a bad fall, Vern.
Maybe you're hurt inside
worse than you think.
You gotta go easy.
What's, what's keepin' him?
We always been able to
hold up at Wilson's.
Easy, Vern.
We ain't gonna be able
to hold up there anymore.
Wilson's dead.
I saw his grave,
And then I looked through the window and,
There's new people livin' there.
[Vern] All right. We'll keep on going.
The horses won't last another mile.
Neither will you.
(Cocks gun) I said we go.
(Slow dramatic music)
(Knocking)
Sorry to bother you, ma'am, but
This man's hurt badly.
Please bring him in.
Over there.
I'll get my husband.
Gil.
Ellie, we're in trouble.
Gil, there's a man in there...
Mr. Barrett's mare
should've foaled before now.
The man's hurt, Gil.
Good evening.
What's wrong?
Horse threw him.
His ribs hurt so bad, he can hardly talk.
Take a big breath.
(Vern inhales shakily)
Easy. Easy.
Stand up.
That's it.
You got to stand up.
I don't guess you live around here, or...
You wouldn't have come to me.
Gil.
We're just passin' through.
Guess you're on your way into town.
I hear they're gonna burn
that man they caught tonight.
We're headed that way.
Uh, hold this end for me.
(Vern grunts in pain)
Is it tight?
Well, if you can't grip
it, why, perhaps my wife...
[Banta] They do the work of five.
Just hurry, please.
Thanks.
I guess that man deserves
whatever's done to him.
You reckon he does?
But we're not the ones to do it.
That's what we have laws
and a government for.
It'll see justice done
if we give it a chance.
I'd stand or fall by it.
And I fought against it.
You did, huh?
That should do it.
What are you chargin'?
There's no charge.
I'm not a physician.
But when you get to town,
you better see Doc Jennings.
Why wouldn't we come to you
If we lived around here?
(Laughs) Well, they're
all Yankees around here.
Like I said, I fought for the South.
It's hard for the winners to believe that
The licked man can come to
admire what they fought for.
Be a while before they
get to think I'm human.
Where's Ault?
Horses in the corral were fresh.
Ault's gettin' the last one now.
Vern, not them.
You're crazy as they say you are.
(Suspenseful music)
[Banta] Vern, come 'round
here! (Approaching hoofbeats)
(Suspenseful music)
Ault! Come on! Hyah! Hyah!
Anybody home?
[Ellen] Neill Price.
Ellie, Gil.
Hello, Neill.
I know, some of your cattle
have come down with anthrax,
And you need Gil. (Laughs)
One of our only visitors, and
he keeps his cattle healthy.
Only visitor?
Why, you had somebody
leaving as I came in.
On their way into town to
watch what happens to Brechene.
Well, that's what I came for.
We can ride in together.
As far as I'm concerned,
there's not much reason
To go into town tonight.
Not much reason?
Well, maybe you don't
think there's much reason,
But I do.
Goodnight, Gil.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Ellie.
(Sighs) Things would be a lot simpler
If there were more like him.
(Retreating hoofbeats)
This is gonna be a matter of waiting.
It only takes one to wait.
Goodnight, Ellie.
Gil...
Is it what you really want?
Staying here, trying to make a go of it?
What I want, I've got.
You.
(Romantic music)
Now, you get to bed.
Thanks.
You keep it on.
Well, just like all
the other places, sir.
Been some in, been some out.
I hope the other patrols had better luck.
This one's a veterinary.
You wanna try him?
(Mumbles) said to try everybody.
(Dog barking)
Look around.
(Knocking)
Oh, won't you come in?
You're name Hanley?
That's right.
Can I help ya?
Maybe.
You mind if we look around?
Help yourself.
What's going on?
Last night a butcher shot down
An army lieutenant and a peace officer.
A butcher named Brechene.
And he got away?
What makes you think he got away?
Well, you're not here
to pass the time of day.
You must be looking for something.
[Lieutenant] You were
a rebel in the war.
I fought for the South.
[Lieutenant] Anything
unusual happen here last night?
Well, about 4 o'clock,
we had a little colt.
Before that, I bound up the ribs of a man
Who'd been thrown from his horse.
He was half out of his mind with pain.
Everything all right?
[Soldeir] Seems to be, sir.
A horse doctor takes care of a man?
And that's not unusual?
Well, when they can't
get to Doc Jennings,
Why, I sometimes get human patients.
I don't do much for them, but
I don't charge them either.
Gil.
Is it all right if I put
a blanket on the foal
'Til Mr. Barrett comes?
Thanks, Ellie.
Let's go.
Better wait a minute, Lieutenant.
(Slow dramatic music)
You ever see this before?
I don't think so, no.
Those your horses out in the corral?
[Gilman] Certainly.
Tell him.
They've got the Randall's brand on 'em.
Two weeks ago, Brechene
stole a Randall herd.
You're not talkin' sense.
A man was hurt.
He couldn't find anyplace else to come to.
I s'pose you never saw
Vern Brechene before.
Didn't know what he looked like.
Make the answers good, reb.
[Gilman] You ever seen him before?
You know what he looks like?
I haven't been helpin' him get away
For the last two years.
[Gilman] You trying to say I have?
You trying to say he
didn't pay you this money
For the fresh horses
you had waiting for him?
Just left it as a gift.
Is that it, reb?
What does all this mean?
It's simple.
For a year, we've been looking for the man
Who has helped Brechene
hide out in this area.
And now we've found him.
You're under arrest for
criminally conspiring
With Vernon Brechene against
the United States government.
Oh, no.
You're out of your mind.
Now, get outta here, before I...
[Ellen] Gil.
(Dramatic music)
And in view of the
fact that the accused,
By willfully aiding and
conspiring with a deserter
From the United States Army,
Has forfeited all rights
to trial by civil court.
We will prove, beyond a doubt,
That this man is guilty.
(Dramatic orchestral music)
I saw those strangers
turnin' down Hanley's lane.
(Dramatic orchestral music)
No, Gil didn't say
who the visitors were,
Except one was a patient.
All he said was there wasn't much reason
For goin' into town.
That doesn't make him guilty.
(Dramatic orchestral music)
The only horses in Hanley's corral
Was the ones Brechene
stole from the Randalls.
(Dramatic orchestral music)
And this is the saddlebag
that Private Benson found
With over $5,000 in it.
The court, having
materially and carefully
Considered the evidence produced,
Finds the accused, Gilman S. Hanley,
Guilty.
The only guilt here is yours.
Silence.
This once, you're going to listen to me.
Has one of these witnesses actually proved
I ever saw Brechene before that night?
Only Brechene can do that.
Or one of his men.
Find Brechene.
Find any of his men.
Let them declare they ever in their lives
Had anything to do with me!
The prisoner will maintain silence.
[Prison Guard] On your feet, Hanley.
Hanley, on your feet!
Someone to see ya.
Can't open the door, lady.
Better make it quick.
Oh, Gil. Gil, darling.
Ellie.
Ellie, you've got to get
to somebody higher up
Than these people.
Once they learn what's going on in there,
Even if it's too late,
Get to them.
You haven't heard?
They haven't told you?
Oh, what's there to hear?
They've caught Brechene, darling.
They've caught Brechene!
(Approaching footsteps)
Take these two along.
Brechene, this man claims he's not now,
And never was connected
with you in any way.
Do you deny or confirm his claim?
Tell him the truth.
You didn't do a very good job, did ya?
With the money I left ya,
You could've bought your
way outta this scrape.
You can't save yourself.
What further harm could it
do you to tell the truth?
And save a man that helped
you when you were in pain.
I don't know what you're mad at me for.
You wouldn't want me to lie, would ya?
[Soldier] Place him in his cell.
I got a hundred men they can't find.
Maybe you can tell 'em where they are.
And what they're gonna do next.
(Dramatic music)
You were the one who requested
That Brechene, himself, identify you.
Oh, Gil.
Gil.
Time's getting short, lady. Come on.
- No. No, no. (Crying)
- [Guard] Come on.
(Sorrowful music)
(Dramatic music)
But my husband's alive. He's alive.
He wasn't executed with the others.
That means he wasn't guilty.
He's free. Free to come home.
By what right do you refuse to tell me
What you've done with him?
Does a human life mean so little to you?
Mrs. Hanley, I've done
all I can for your husband
By commuting his sentence
to a prison term.
Take my advice.
Forget him.
(Dramatic music)
[Prison Guard] Get movin'.
[Prison Guard] Prisoners
on the water wagon!
Prisoners on the water wagon!
Tell the Comman that
new scurvies are comin' in
On the water wagon!
(Orchestral music)
Get 10 men to unload the wagon!
Still afraid to drive inside, huh, Frank?
I'm called on to deliver
water to the prison,
Not inside.
Here's the consignment.
Let's take a look at the livestock.
Six new scurvies.
That means six less barrels of water.
Get 'em outta there!
[Guard] All right, out of the wagon.
Come on outta there!
All right, you
scurvies, get outta there.
Come on, get a move on.
Come on.
On your feet.
From now on, anybody gets
a callus on his butt,
He can take a free swing at me.
All right, inside. Quick step!
All right, you scurvies,
move along! Come on, move it!
Come on, move.
Prisoners, halt!
Address is right.
Now, I want your hats off.
You're gonna meet somebody.
You're gonna meet the Commandant.
Lieutenant Voorhees.
Maybe you're not gonna like him.
More important, he's not gonna like you.
Come to attention!
[Guard] Easy with those water barrels.
Take care of that water!
Consignment from Fort Jackson
and Fort Jefferson, sir.
Jackson?
That mean, well, we must be honored by
The presence of Mr. Gilman Hanley.
Which one is Hanley?
Right here.
Now, why wouldn't they
shoot a mad dog like you?
Look him over Doctor Pelham.
It's like this, Mr. Hanley.
In your little group here is a deserter,
A mutineer, a thief, and a murderer.
But you're the only one that
has gorilla on his record.
Gorillas burn down homes,
With women and children in them.
You'll find I have a special
regard for gorillas. Hm?
Now, because you're our new boarders,
And because we want you
gentlemen to be happy here,
We're gonna conduct you on a little tour.
All right, you scurvies, move along!
(Desolate music)
At their lowest point, those
cliffs are 208 feet high.
Even if you found a
way up out of the pits,
And somehow managed to climb these walls,
You know what would hit you in the face
When you got on the outside?
Hundreds of miles, in every direction,
Of the deadest, driest desert
you ever thought existed.
No man who's ever been
here ever knew of a way
Across that desert to the Mexican line.
Just bear in mind that
no man has ever made it.
And none of you is gonna be the first.
Let's say a guest did manage
to wander out into the desert.
You don't think we'd
let you perish out there
With a thirst, do you?
Why, we wouldn't be that inconsiderate.
[Sgt. Maj. Kearn] On your feet.
They look like Apaches.
Beside them, Apaches are tame.
They're Pimas.
You know how they earn their pay?
For every escaped prisoner they bring
Out of the desert alive,
They get $25.
For every dead one, $50.
They'd like to see you
get out into the desert.
[Sgt. Maj. Kearn] As you were.
(Desolate music)
As an extra service,
We have, what our guests
refer to, as the bake oven.
You can see its effect for yourselves.
With these majestic walls, and the desert,
You can see for yourselves
why we don't stress the use of
Iron bars and numerous guards.
I feel that you should also
know that we have no water here.
Absolutely none.
However, we are making every effort
To discover a source on our own premises.
Now, we need water here. Very badly.
Because, occasionally, we
are visited by the fever.
And that makes it very bad for everybody.
But until we discover a source of water,
We receive a supply once
a month from Copper City.
Well...
This concludes our little tour.
We bid you welcome.
Hope you enjoy your stay.
Get their shackles off.
Mark 'em and assign the cells.
All except the gorilla.
I want him to come with me.
Guard!
Blacksmith!
Now, you can put your hats on.
To send you here,
they must've wanted you
To remain alive.
That sort of ties my hands, doesn't it?
Why did they want you to
stay alive, Mr. Hanley?
I'm here because they
couldn't kill me on the
Evidence they had.
You really believe that, don't ya?
Well, you don't have to worry
about being here too long.
If you brought me here to tell me that,
You're wasting your time.
A few years ago, I used
to bayonet that uniform.
It'd take a good deal to
make me change my mind.
You're the one to prove I made a mistake.
Well, it's clear that
you're one prisoner
They don't want killed.
Yes, sir.
But these orders don't apply
to a man who tries to escape.
You thinkin' of forcing one to try?
Well, I...
I have to admire your spirit, Mr. Hanley.
That's the kind of spirit
it took for you gorillas
To burn down homes,
Without letting the
women and children out.
One of ya burned down mine.
With my wife and daughter in it.
You're not gonna like what
happens to you here, gorilla.
You're probably gonna want
to make a break for it.
Get these shackles off,
and put him in his cell.
Put him in with Redfield.
(Ominous music)
From now on, just think
of this as your parlor.
Open the grate!
(Metal scraping)
Down you go.
(Ominous music)
Right turn, gorilla.
Now, left.
Get 17 open!
Like the Commandant said...
Welcome.
(Dramatic music)
Here's one of the reasons your water's
Gonna be short this month.
Let him settle, Jumper.
Jumper Hall is the name.
If you think we're glad
to have you with us,
You right.
We are not.
But as long as you're
here, meet the family.
This is Artilleryman Nye, Fifth, Ohio.
Still standing too close to the guns.
You make too much noise, Jumper.
This is Gundy Boyd, New York Infantry.
Hi. Sorry to see you.
You met the Pimas on the outside?
This one is on the inside.
Ever seen a deformed Indian?
Killed one of his own people.
Now, nobody likes you, do they, Hunchy?
[Redfield] Hey, cut it
out, both of you guys!
Sorry, Hunchy.
I said get him settled.
All right, Red.
You can see we are a happy family in here.
I'm the only who's got a
chance to walk out of here.
My time in, you can count.
Come over here.
You got a long time to go in here?
Not very long.
Same with me.
Less than a year.
Ah, you didn't ask to be put in with us,
And we didn't ask to have you.
Now, I think the smartest
thing is for you and us
To make the best of it, right?
Well, what's that mean?
Just don't ever talk about
what you see to anybody.
Not even to us.
We got an understanding?
Who says we need an understanding?
Fine.
In this hole, we've got to
breath together to live.
And you don't want to breath with us.
Now, what are we gonna do about you?
That's up to you.
[Sgt. Maj. Kearn] Open 17.
(Gate unlocking and opening)
Here's you playmate, Red.
Any of you got any complaints
about short water rations,
See him.
Well, you don't see anybody
rushin' for the water, do ya?
You got 'em all too well
trained, if front of me.
Just once, don't slam it.
Sargent...(slams gate)
Sargent, let me see Doc Pelham.
He can't get you outta
work in the cistern.
He can if he knows what
the noise does to me.
Voorhees knows.
The cistern,
I-it's like a thousand
explosions inside here.
To a gorilla?
I'm an artilleryman.
You were.
All Voorhees knows is what you turned into
After you skipped the artillery.
This is one noise he
wants you to get used to.
(Retreating footsteps)
I won't ever work in that cistern again.
Get your cup, Nye.
What about him?
Oh, don't worry about the killer.
Guess he must like this
better than water. (Thuds)
(Dramatic music)
Bleeding from the nose and mouth
Means internal injuries.
A man can die that way.
I don't want you helpin' him along.
You don't?
You come in here new,
And start tellin' me what you want?
Red!
Let him go.
Is this what you meant
by an understanding?
Get your cup.
(Thuds)
(Gate unlocking)
You, against the wall. Lean!
Turn around!
Now, lean.
Would you say everything's all right, Red?
No disturbance.
Yeah, I'd say.
You know...
They like nothing better
than target practice.
In case you're ever thinking of running.
Thanks.
Still trying to make
it good for him, gorilla?
The man's dying.
Well, he better not die.
I hear you're some kind of a doc.
Can you keep him alive?
I'll do better than you've done.
As long as you do, we'll
leave our business unfinished.
(Brass horn playing)
(Suspenseful music)
I told ya I won't go
down in that cistern again.
Go ahead and shoot.
Why, you.
Prisoner loose! Prisoner loose!
Hold your fire.
Hold your fire!
On the rim, hold your fire!
Why don't you shoot? Go ahead and shoot!
Why don't you shoot?
Go ahead! Why don't you shoot?
Why don't you shoot!
(Dramatic music)
What a gorilla wants
is a run for his money.
(Dramatic music)
Go ahead! Why don't you shoot?
Why don't you shoot!
All right, Sargent.
Commence firing!
(guns firing)
(Dramatic music)
Bring him down, Sargent.
Mapes, Calard, on the double!
Man ended up one of
your kind. A gorilla.
Move 'em along.
Detail, forward! Quick step!
(Desolate music)
Keep goin'.
Keep goin'! Close it up!
Close it up!
(Desolate music)
Go easy, when it starts.
We've been digging for years.
There's no water below us.
That's the way Voorhees keeps us busy.
Just watch the dust.
Right turn!
All right, get diggin'.
(Desolute music)
(prisoners coughing)
Post number four!
All secure!
Post number one!
How is he?
He won't get any better in here.
That's it, killer.
The last thing we want
is to lose you for good.
He's a chicken dirt robber of the dead.
Real careful, Mott.
Mott didn't wanna be a soldier.
He lived all his life a
hundred miles from here.
Copper City.
You know what he was?
A prospector.
You know where he prospected?
In the desert.
You're never going to...
Easy, Mott.
He's the only man who's ever been in here
Who knows the way across that desert
To the Mexican line.
And Mott's gonna tell me, when I'm ready.
First, you've gotta
get out in the desert.
I'll show you how things
can be done around here.
Come over here, and learn something.
Hey, Red. I'll watch the door.
No, you won't.
Hunchy.
Keep an eye out.
Look close.
Hundreds of years ago, the Indians had
A fire going right here.
Now, I figure that where there's fire,
There's gotta be a way
out for the smoke, right?
Took me over a year to find out
That none of these cracks
went up high enough
To be the outlet.
You know where that smoke traveled?
It curled in and out of these,
'Til it found its way up that one.
(Soft thudding)
(Approaching footsteps)
(Retreating footsteps)
Think we got somethin' worthwhile here?
All right, let's get started.
He follows me up.
(Slow dramatic music)
(Dramatic orchestral music)
This is as far as we've gone.
Broken pick heads.
Made to order, for in here.
Kearn's still lookin' for 'em.
Well, we oughta break
through this part tonight.
Yeah, even if you make
it over these cliffs,
You've still got the desert
and those Pima Indians.
Three days before we go, I
write a letter to Copper City.
It's an innocent letter to a shoe shop.
Sayin' I need a pair of shoes.
The third night, you know what's hidden
100 yards outside these cliffs?
Horses.
And on those horses will
be full canteens and guns.
I hope you make it.
Where are you goin'?
You gonna work with us, or not?
All Voorhees needs is to find out
I'm part of this.
It's kind of important
Voorhees doesn't find out
Anything about it.
Gundy, get Mott up here.
He can work in the gorilla's place.
This kind of work
won't be good for Mott.
You can't take a chance on Mott dying.
That's not the way.
Look at it like this.
The most of us are a long time here.
This way, we have a chance.
You can't stay awake all
night, for many nights.
There's six of us. We'll be watching you.
One morning, we'll come in
find you had an accident.
Then, whatever it is you wanted to prove
Won't be proved.
You won't have helped Mott,
You won't have helped us,
And you won't have helped yourself.
(Melancholic music)
[Voiceover] My dearest.
It's dark outside now,
And already the dawn
seems an eternity away.
In the morning, I leave for St. Louis,
Where Neill has arranged for
me to meet Senator Caldwell,
Who's staying over there,
before returning to Washington.
Neill says the Senator is an
honest man of great influence.
Perhaps he'll help us.
If necessary, I'll go back
to Washington, myself.
(Approaching footsteps)
[Sgt. Maj. Kearn] Hanley, sir.
Oh, Mr. Hanley.
I have a letter here from
Lieutenant Colonel Woods,
The judge advocate at your trial.
He wants to know if you have
any inclination to talk.
You got any inclination?
Talk about what?
Brechene had over a
hundred of you gorillas.
They'd like to know where
the rest of them are.
That all?
Good. Good.
I'm glad you have no inclination,
'Cause if you had, I might've
had to turn you loose.
I hope you hold out, gorilla.
I hope you hold out 'til it's too late.
That's all.
What about the letters from my wife?
You sure there were some letters?
I'm sure.
Like these, maybe.
Well, yes, your wife has written you.
I felt it best not to bother you with...
Letters like these.
Does she say anything about
the reopening of the trial?
Oh, yeah, she's written to Washington.
She's been to Washington.
She's done everything she can for ya.
Tell me, gorilla...
Are you growing tired of our cistern?
Do I get my letters?
Take him back to his cell.
Don't!
It might ruin its shape.
Some kids learned arithmetic.
I learned to pick locks.
Can you pick that one?
Sure.
But where you gonna go after it's picked?
Maybe the guards on this level
Asked the guards on the main level
To pull up the grate.
And the guards at the tunnel
mouth and the main gate
All decide to go to sleep. (Laughing)
You're beat.
You won't stand many days
double-shift in the cistern.
Voorhees is in for a surprise.
I'm gonna get used to it.
You feeling any better?
Voorhees...
[Gilman] Lie back.
I scratched it on
the inside of the door.
The way across the desert.
Scratched,
Right above your eyes.
What door?
You (mumbles), didn't ya?
I told him I hope they
bake you in the oven
Until... (gasps, thuds)
It don't make any difference
whether you go along,
Just give me what he told ya.
He said somethin'
about marks on the door.
There's nothin' there.
Post number six, all secure!
(Scraping)
(Dramatic music)
Hey, gorilla.
Come out of it, come on.
You won't have to fight
that cistern anymore.
We're there.
We've broken through.
Take a look.
(Dramatic music)
All this time,
And now a foot outside, it's free.
Well, the rest is just like walking out.
Now, the rest is up to you.
Not up to me.
We've broken through.
We're gonna rot waiting
for him to change his mind.
(Dramatic music)
How close to outside?
He's through.
You mean, they can try it now?
Well, there's nothin' in their way.
Except the climb to the top,
The guards,
Getting down the outside of the cliff,
The desert, and the Pimas.
Yeah, they can try.
You didn't tell 'em what Mott said?
Look, can you work that lock tonight?
What for?
All it gets you is on the
other side of this gate.
After that, you can't get nowhere.
There's some things I want
in the Commandant's office.
Commandant's office?
You crazy?
Open it.
Not now.
In less than an hour,
they got guard relief.
They'll leave the grate
at the top of the ramp
Open for eight minutes.
Whatever you're gonna do,
You got eight minutes.
(Suspenseful music)
This is crazy.
Maybe you got a chance to
walk out of here, like I have.
If Voorhees catches...
(Suspenseful music)
(Suspenseful music builds)
(Approaching footsteps)
Hup! Hup!
Hup! Hup! Hup!
(Suspenseful music)
[Guard] Who's there?
That you, Corporal?
Halt!
(Gun fires)
Get Sargent Kearn!
(Suspenseful music)
In here!
(Indistinct talking)
Couldn't make him out.
Open it up.
Who was it?
Don't give me the "I don't know".
Who just came in here.
Nobody.
You know what happens to liars, Gundy.
Well, maybe I gotta
go through this again.
I said nobody came in here.
I meant nobody.
You, you, and you. Outside.
You know what's gonna happen.
Why them?
What difference does it make?
Sooner or later, one of 'em will talk,
With some urging.
You can save the effort.
I was the one who was out.
You lied to me, Gundy.
You know the penalty for lyin'.
Outside.
I told ya, I'm the one you want.
Sure.
Only Voorhees will want
to handle you himself.
Let's get it off, liar.
And I want to know how
that gate got opened.
All on account of you.
You wonderin' whether you're worth it?
(Dramatic music)
Their way, it takes all night.
And we got to wait for each one, too.
[Prisoner] Speed it up! Speed it up!
[Prisoner Two] Get it over with.
[Prisoner] Speed it up!
[Prisoner Two] Get it over with!
[Prisoner Two] All right, all right!
[Prisoner] That's enough.
[Prisoner Two] All right,
enough! He's had enough!
[Prisoner] Let him down. Let him down!
[Guard] Quiet! Shut up, in this cell!
(Whip lashing)
[Prisoner Two] Get it
over with. Get it over with.
[Guard] Shut up!
(Whip lashes)
Shut up, you scurvies!
Quiet!
(whip lashes)
[Prisoner] Let him down! Let him down!
(Whip lashes)
(prisoners shouts overlapping)
You gonna help us, or do
you like what you started?
(Whip lashes)
[Prisoner Two] Get it over
with. All right, all right!
(Whip lashes)
All right!
Open up.
Not that way.
You're more good to us alive.
(Whip lashes)
(prisoners shouting)
Gundy's had enough on account of me.
Now, get it open!
[Prisoners] Now! Now! Now!
(whip lashes)
[Guard] Shut up, or we'll
give you some of the same!
The more you yell, the more he'll...
(Dramatic music)
(Whip lashes)
(Guns firing)
Come on!
Grab those torches!
Get Kearn! Get Kearn!
Kill 'em!
Get a move on it!
Open the grate!
(Suspenseful music)
(Ringing)
Ah!
(Dramatic music)
(Ringing)
Hold it, that mug
Hanley'll get himself killed.
(Suspenseful music)
(Thuds)
(Dramatic music)
You crazy mug! Come off there!
(Indistinct yelling)
Get up. Who's responsible?
Him. All the way.
Inciting a riot.
Well, providing nobody's been killed,
It'll be a long time before
you'll see the sun again.
But you'll feel it.
(Desolate music)
Any life in there?
He ain't much on food.
But he don't leave no water.
[Guard] In a couple more days,
He'll be leaving ya his water.
(Desolate music)
(Breathing heavily)
[Voiceover] I crossed the desert.
I, I scratched it, right above your eyes.
Come in, Neill.
You remember Mr. Price at the trial.
This is Colonel Wood, the judge advocate.
Neill, it's happened.
They're letting Gil come home.
For a fair trial?
As I told Mrs. Hanley,
Her husband hasn't been acquitted.
He's to be released under my custody,
To report to me twice a month.
I'll want a complete
account of his every move.
As well as a list of
the visitors he's had.
But that's not freeing him.
Oh, he'll be home.
That's what's important.
Sounds to me like Gil's
being used for bait.
Neill.
You're hoping what's
left of Brechene's gorillas
Will try to contact Gil, and
give you a chance to grab 'em.
That's your own conclusion, Mr. Price.
Please, Neill, it's all right.
Hanley isn't being
forced to leave the prison.
The full facts will be presented to him.
If he decided to cooperate,
There's a chance his
sentence will be reduced.
I want to remind Gil to thank you.
Good day, Mrs. Hanley.
Mr. Price.
When will Gil come home?
I'll send a dispatch today.
It should reach the prison tomorrow.
But the prison officials
have three weeks to decide
Whether the prisoner's
record justifies his release.
Thank you.
Open it up.
Come on, come on.
(Door creaks)
Well, Hanley.
Dr. Pelham tells me you might die
If we left you in there any longer.
We can't have anything like that happen,
Inside the prison.
Get him out.
Come on, on your feet.
Three or four days
rest down in the cistern,
You'll be able to come back here
And pay off the time you owe the oven.
Go on, take him down.
Easy.
You've had a bad time.
[Gundy] Welcome back.
We didn't think you'd make it.
Anytime you're ready,
You can send that letter to the shoe shop.
You're gonna give me the way.
I'm gonna show it to ya.
Post number one, nine o'clock!
All secure!
(Horn blowing)
Now, exactly where?
Right above that ridge.
Hm.
Now, how do they know where
they're gonna come out?
Oh, Redfield's got
it figured to the inch.
What time tonight?
Right after the midnight guard change.
What makes you so sure that
Mott told Hanley the
way across that desert?
Oh, I'm not so sure.
Redfield's sure.
That's good enough for me.
Mm hm.
All right, take him back to his cell.
You're not gonna put me back there now.
But I don't wanna make the try.
I want to walk out of here.
In less than a year.
And I won't, if you make
me go with them tonight.
You'll never let 'em get to
the top of that cliff alive.
Take him back to his cell.
(Door closes)
Well...
You get your wish to
get back at a gorilla.
One of the ones that tries tonight
Was a gorilla.
(Suspenseful music)
Hey, Red. What if
Voorhees knows about it?
He'll shoot us as we come out.
There's no way he can know.
But what if he does?
And he's out there,
waiting for us to come out.
Well, then I'd say somebody told him.
Long as you're the one worrying about it,
Maybe you better climb out first.
I was just thinking
of what could happen.
[Redfield] We'll follow you, Jumper.
(Suspenseful music)
Now, Lieutenant.
No, he's not outside yet.
Hold your fire.
I want him far enough away to send
My retrievers after him.
(Suspenseful music)
Jumper. You tried to inform on us.
No, I didn't. No, I didn't!
(Thuds)
(Dramatic music)
Come on!
(Horses whinnying)
Let's get going.
Where's Jumper?
He didn't make it.
Well, there were five
of us. Only four horses.
You said guns and water.
I've got 'em.
Let's get outta here before they find out
And turn those Pimas on us.
(Dramatic music)
(Wind howling)
[Redfield] Well?
Another 15 miles, and we're halfway.
Let's go!
Are you crazy?
All you been telling me is we
gotta stay in a straight line.
Bog down in this storm,
and lose that line,
What'll we do, go back to
the prison and start over?
No, we wait here for
the Pimas to catch up.
But they're on foot!
All right, you stay here.
You tell the men to cross
the desert and get free.
I've sweated to get this far.
Do you think I can't take care of
A few rat-faced, lousy redskins?
You're waiting 'til I say.
I've wasted too much time on this.
You're not gonna get us lost.
You try finding the way by yourself.
(Wind howling)
(Horse whinnying)
(Thuds)
(Thudding and grunting)
(Thudding)
(Whooshing)
(Pimas whooping)
(Dramatic music)
(Gun fires)
(Gun firing)
(Dramatic music)
(Suspenseful music)
(Gun fires)
(Pimas whooping)
(Dramatic music builds)
(Gun fires)
Hold your fire!
[Sgt. Maj. Kearn] Hold your fire!
Come on down here, Hanley.
Where's the rest of 'em?
Dead.
Well, I almost didn't get here in time.
That would've been too bad for me.
They sent for ya. Officially.
They want to turn you loose.
But they've left it up to me.
You boys did your job.
You'll get paid in full,
Even if it has to come
out of my own pocket.
Soldier, pick up his horse!
(Desolate music)
How long overdue?
Oh, two hours.
Looks like they'll
come back as empty-handed
As the other details.
If they come back.
Well, a man can go
three weeks without food,
And three days without water.
Tomorrow'll be the
second day without water.
We had enough water here for two weeks.
All the barrels were
dumped, thanks to you.
Who knows about typhus fever?
Decimated the Roman Legions.
Out here, one of our own guards fall dead,
And it's here.
Did he get it out of the filth
of the underground cells?
Did he breathe it out of the air?
All we know is, it can
contaminate the water they drink.
That's why I emptied our supply.
And unless we get fresh water...
Oh, get away from me! Don't talk to me.
Go give him a pill, that's
all you're good for.
Good citizens have erected a
barricade outside the town.
They're afraid we'll come in contact with
Their wives and kids.
They've fired on every detail
I've sent in there for water.
[Guard] Detail coming in!
(Approaching hoofbeats)
No water, sir.
You gotta give me more men.
They shot Mapes and
Clark at the barricade.
We need a whole company to get through.
Guards!
Get him to dispensary.
He's got it, sir.
We can't touch him.
Now, you do like I tell ya.
Get him to the dispensary.
Come on, hurry up.
Go on back.
Go on back, and tell 'em I
got half this prison down
With typhus fever.
Dying 50 a day, and no water.
Tell 'em they oughta
be proud of themselves,
Shootin' my men down.
All we ask is water.
Go on!
Ah, hold up, soldier.
Hold up.
Dismount.
Never mind. Get yourself some rest.
There's one way to get water.
Dream it up?
There's a prisoner...
Knows how to cross the desert into Mexico.
He could bring back enough to get us by.
The gorilla?
He could do it.
(Men moaning)
[Patient] Doc, you've
gotta give me some water.
I-I'm gonna die without it.
I won't put it that
you'll be helping them.
Or that there are three times this many
That we haven't been able to bring up here
From the cells below.
They mean nothing to ya.
All you can think of is that you
Might be helpin' me,
And that's the last thing you want to do.
I'm sure I'd feel that way,
if I was in your place.
I can't promise you your freedom.
I can't even honestly say that
It'll change my attitude towards ya.
'Cause you were a gorilla.
All I can do is ask ya
to decide for yourself.
(Dramatic music)
(Mumbles)
How sick is this man?
He may, or may not, regain consciousness
Before he dies.
If he comes to, he can
prove I never saw Brechene
Before the night he came to me.
I don't know his name,
But he was with Brechene
the first time I saw him.
(Mumbling indistinctly)
Well, it's up to you
whether you go or not.
(Mumbling indistinctly)
Speak up.
If he doesn't go,
Will you give him permission
to remain here in the tent?
On the chance that this man may recover
Long enough to clear him?
To prove he wasn't a gorilla?
Yes.
Well, there's enough money here
To pay for the water.
There's a letter of authority,
in case you need it.
You might need this, too.
I've still got a few guards
that are on their feet,
They can go along with ya.
I told you I go alone, or I don't go.
Well, I'm countin' on you headin'
Straight across the desert.
And not turnin' toward town,
as soon as you're outta here.
That's up to you.
All right. You go alone.
Remember, Hanley,
straight into the desert.
Go ahead.
Prisoner escaping!
(Guns firing)
All right, all right.
Cease fire!
So, Hanley decided to escape.
But if he thinks he'll get to Copper City,
He'll never make it.
They'll get him at the barricade.
What I came to report,
The man Hanley counted on
to clear him just died,
Without regaining consciousness.
(Orchestral music)
[Gilman] Put down your rifle.
Now, come over here.
It's one of the prisoners.
[Gilman] Hold it.
If you'd shot me,
Everybody around here might've
been dead in 24 hours.
What do you mean?
I want all of you to hear what I mean.
Now, let's walk toward that barricade.
(Dramatic music)
Wait a minute.
You start shootin', he will.
Now, he could've killed us, and didn't.
He has something to say to us.
Give him a couple of seconds.
(Gun fires)
I don't blame you.
You're like me.
You don't trust what you don't know.
You're right in being scared of me,
I've been with the fever.
I told these men that if you killed me,
You'd all be dead,
And that's true.
The very fact that you're here with guns
Means you're afraid the fever will be
Carried to your families.
How?
You don't know.
Your barricade and your rifles
Won't stop the fever from reaching you.
Somehow, it's going to creep under
Or over those walls out there.
There's only one way
you can stop the fever
From reaching you.
Kill it where it is. At the prison.
Don't give it a chance to come find you.
All we need, for a start, is fresh water.
I could've gotten it in Mexico,
But it's six days there and back.
I came here because it's
a matter of one day,
For you, as well as for us.
One wagon-load of water.
And you'll stop it where
it should be stopped,
Where it began.
And if it's stopped, it can't touch you.
It's your decision.
[Guard] Lieutenant!
Lieutenant Voorhees!
Lieutenant! Lieutenant Voorhees!
Lieutenant! Look what's comin' in!
(Hopeful orchestral music)
Whoa!
Well, ya came back, Mr. Hanley.
What about that man?
Did he come to? Did he say anything?
[Voorhees] You somehow
managed the water.
I'm sorry. Banta died before he...
Before he could sign his
name to what he told me.
He cleared you completely.
He told me you never were a gorilla.
And I believed him.
You understand?
Yes.
I not only understand, I
feel kinda good, Lieutenant.
I'll get your case reopened.
I'll stand witness for ya, myself.
But you'll be home before
anybody knows about it.
Guard! Come on, let's
get that water unloaded.
(Lovely orchestral music)
(Orchestral music swells)