NARRATOR: Before 1877, southwest Texas
was pouring cattle northward...
... over the newly opened Chisholm Trail.
The Texans of the open range
could see wealth and power just ahead.
But this is the year of the great breakup.
The outlaws of the wide open West
have learned how easy it is...
... to raid the lonely herds.
In this country, where the ranch houses
are 20 miles apart...
... the thieves hit hard and often,
stampeding the wild cattle.
Rustlers gather from the length
of the frontier for the easy kill...
... and the range is without defense.
Night after night, they drive the cattle off
by hundreds that mount into thousands.
And the vast herds are melting away,
ruining the men who built Texas.
The outnumbered ranchers
have fought back...
... but the savage range war
has smashed their leaders...
... and driven them into exile
across the Mexican line.
Only a few men
like Charlie Bell of San Antonio...
... still keep
the banished fighters posted...
... hoping against hope
that the great days can be brought back.
Maybe a peace officer.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
- I'm Charlie Bell of San Antonio.
- You have pass?
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
The border is closed, señor.
Is new order.
Look here, you people.
I can go and wade the river
a mile below here without any trouble.
But I don't mean to do anything of the kind.
If you try to cross, there is nothing
what we can do but try to stop you.
It is not our fault if your law breaks down
so your best men come live with us.
We will have peace in Mexico,
even if every day we must fight.
Clay Hardin is in Nuevo Laredo
and I mean to see him.
Other men have come after him before.
It only means more fight.
I know all that,
but I'm Clay Hardin's best friend.
Then you know he is going back to Texas.
You can see him then.
If you wanna save his life,
you'd better let me see him now.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
- Go on in.
CHARLIE: Thanks.
[MAN HUMMING NEARBY]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[WOMEN SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
He is gone. He's not here.
We never heard of him.
That horse is the horse of my husband.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
WOMAN:
Help! Help!
Juan, Jose, Rita, Rosita!
We're attacked. We're stricken.
A bad stranger is upon us.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Looking for someone?
I ought to take that thing
and bend it over your head.
Ha, ha. You look like the time
you sat on the cactus. How are you?
Ha, ha.
What's the matter with these people?
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[LAUGHS]
You could've saved yourself a long ride.
I wrote you I was coming home.
I guess you wrote other people. Everybody
knows you're gonna make a try at it.
They do? Well, why burn up horseflesh
coming all this way down here to tell me?
Clay, I rode to tell you not to come.
At least not now.
[SINGS]
I love you
You're not ready to ride, Clay.
I never see a man
shot up so bad as you was.
[SINGING]
Be mine
Yahoo!
You think that's why
I stayed in Mexico, huh?
Oh, don't go back, Clay.
It ain't worth it.
All southwest Texas is busted.
San Antonio is just gonna be
another dog town all falling down.
[SINGING]
You're sweeter than any wine
That's just why I'm going back.
Now, you listen to me, Clay.
We've counted more than 5000
wanted outlaws loose in Texas.
They got a chain of stock thieves
all along the border.
Them fellows can run a herd into Mexico
every night.
Mexico can't help it, Charlie.
Us neither.
Look at the way we fought them.
You tied into them harder
than anybody else. And what did it get us?
Your ranch burned out, your cows run off
and yourself all shot to pieces.
Everybody knows
who I blame for all that.
Clay, don't you see that's why
you'll never get back to San Antonio?
You think Roy Stuart
don't know you're after him?
I left Texas to find out something.
I found it. If Roy Stuart thinks
I'm coming after him now, he's right.
He's right about something else too.
The only way you'll get to San Antonio alive
is to stay away.
- Can you get a bet on that?
- Anywhere in Texas.
The gamblers
are making book in the streets.
Laredo's practically put up a grandstand
and sold seats...
...to see you shot as you cross the line.
- Yeah?
Well, cover every cent you can get.
I'll pay it.
[WOMAN SCREAMS,
SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
[DOG BARKING]
Don't run away, honey.
We won't look. Ha. Will we?
Now, listen, things got so bad up there,
the governor asked for military aid.
Colonel Johnson's cavalry
is policing San Antonio.
And the colonel himself swears
he'll outlaw you the day you come back.
Yeah? Charlie?
Roy Stuart has gotta be convicted
and hung.
You'll never get him that way, Clay.
I've got him now.
What do you think I've been doing
down in Mexico?
We were whipped before because
we lacked proof. We don't lack it now.
- Does Stuart know?
- Of course he does.
All the more reason
it's sure death to cross over.
What do you want me to do?
Send somebody else?
All right, Clay. What's the next move?
Cross over into Laredo.
Get me seat on the San Antonio stage.
- In whose name?
- In my own name.
- What?
- Sure.
Onyx. He looks good.
How come you haven't lost him
in a poker game by now?
Because I don't gamble the way you do.
Oh.
- Hi, boys.
- Hi, Charlie.
He wouldn't be here
if Clay Hardin didn't aim to go through.
There'll be a fight if he tries to.
- You gonna put into it?
- Not me. But there's plenty as will.
Three-to-one, gents, 3-to-1
Clay Hardin never sets foot in San Antonio.
Place your bets
with Honest Jay Witherspoon.
Never run out on a bet yet.
Or at least, with two exceptions,
it was never proved.
- Three-to-one Clay never makes it.
- Why should Clay come back?
His cattle is scattered
from Stinkwater to breakfast.
- Half his friends is dead, other is foolish.
- It's worse than you say.
But here's 100 that says he will be back.
Another 100 says it will be
the best thing that happened to Texas.
Thank you, Mr. Streeter, I can use this.
Any more bets?
Three-to-one. Three-to-one.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Ain't that Lafe McWilliams?
Had all them gunfights in San Antone?
Sure is, brother.
Five-to-one. Make it 8-to-1.
Clay Hardin never makes San Antonio.
Get your money here, boys.
It's 8-to-1 here.
I got the signal.
Clay Hardin has left Nuevo.
- He may be over the Texas line by now.
- Well?
They lost him, he just disappeared.
We should've rode the river like the others.
Clay can't ride the brush 150 miles.
- There must be lead in him yet.
- That's right.
Even if he tried it,
the lookouts would get him easy.
They can see a rider 20 miles
as he comes through.
The Monterey coach is coming up.
Do you suppose he'd be fool enough...?
No.
Wait. That ain't the Monterey coach.
That's old Jaime Rosas driving.
That's a charter coach from below.
How do you do? How do you do?
- Oh, sit down.
MEN: Ha-ha-ha!
I don't sit down. Don't argue with me.
- Always the opposite.
- Oh.
One side. One side or a horn knocked off.
Scatter, you slickers.
BOZIE: No, no, no, go leave, please.
She don't see somebody now.
Nobody is talking to her
without they don't see her first.
Now, wait a minute,
my fat-headed friend.
[BOZIE WHIMPERING]
Don't you ever take off your hat?
Of course not.
He needs it to shade his eyes.
[MEN LAUGHING]
Go keep an eye on Charlie Bell.
Real desperate character you got there
riding with the driver.
That's my desperate manager.
See, I'm looking for a gentleman.
We haven't seen one in a year.
I'm sorry, ladies.
This is for your own protection.
Clay Hardin's on the loose,
and he's a dangerous outlaw.
He's liable
to smuggle himself through here.
Do you want to look under the pillows?
- Here.
- Hold on, will you?
BOZIE: No, no, no, inside is not.
You must be stay out.
What's that? You are stealing, I hope.
[MEN LAUGH]
You right away steal those back.
Such thing begins, I don't know.
Please, make more careless.
If I break that, you sue me.
Ah, shut up!
[MUTTERING]
Oh, sit down.
[ROSAS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Come here.
Well, what do you want?
Charlie Bell bought a seat
on the San Antonio stage for Clay Hardin.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I saw him do it myself.
Don't worry. I'll take care of that.
You'd better do something.
This stage never runs
without a shotgun guard, you know that.
Clay's name is down
and the company's gotta take him.
I don't gotta ride shotgun.
There's enough graveyard bait
in the strongbox without Clay.
And I've got kids to support.
I didn't think them things
was jackrabbits.
Maybe you wanna holler for the Army.
- The company reserves the right...
- I'll ride shotgun myself.
There's my bond.
San Antonio stage, get aboard.
It will roll without me.
I'm too young and good-Iooking
for a one-way trip.
I can't do nothing. I just work here.
Even money, gents. Even money
against Clay Hardin, and lucky to get it.
I don't see him.
What's the matter, is he afraid to show?
Maybe he invisible-ized himself.
Clay ain't here. He's changed his mind.
That's what he wants us to think.
He's circled the town already.
The stage will pick him up.
We might outrun the stage
and wait at Cotulla.
Get into that coach.
You can get Clay easy
when he comes out of the brush.
I'll tail the stage,
and as you fire, I'll get Charlie Bell.
- What about my saddle?
- Move, or you won't need it anymore.
Here she rips.
Anybody change their mind?
- I'm going along. I'll settle my ticket later.
- Right.
- Go ahead, Charlie.
- Hyah, hyah, hyah!
[DRIVER SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
DRIVER:
Whoa!
Yippee! Yippee!
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN MOCK SPANISH]
[WOMEN GASP]
[SIGHS]
Well, hello.
Move over, honey.
Now, now, after all, Don Quickshot,
the show doesn't start till after supper.
Oh, we're gonna have supper too?
Would you like to land on your head
or get out peaceably?
Sorry, but I've planned on this
ever since you left Monterey.
I don't like the society
in those public coaches, do you?
If I scream, a man will come down here
with a shotgun. And I'm going to scream.
- Now, wait, Henrietta.
- Let her go ahead.
I'll help you.
[HIGH-PITCHED YELP]
BOZIE:
Look, look, look!
There goes an empty horse.
This is really for your own protection.
I'm sorry. We've heard that one.
No, on the level.
- There's a desperate character loose.
- And his name is Clay Hardin.
This is monotonous.
Why doesn't one of you Texans
bring out a new lie?
One that will astound people.
Honestly now, wouldn't you like
to be protected?
Just a little, on one side, huh?
Is it a Western custom
to push yourself in on other people?
Yes, ma'am.
That's how the West was settled.
We're not Indians.
Go on, get out of here, scat.
You know,
I saw a poster of you down Mexico way...
...and it didn't half do you justice.
Thank you.
Maybe I do need you to protect me
from this Clay Hardin person.
Well, on second thought,
I don't know if I can.
- But I can protect you, ma'am.
- Oh, don't mind me.
I've stood almost everything in the show
business, I guess I could stand that.
Then you must be
one of those rich cattlemen.
- Are you married?
- Me? Uh-uh.
No. And I haven't got any cattle left.
You see? You was very rude.
He wouldn't marry you anyway.
I wasn't asking for myself.
Well, don't ask him for me either.
You see, out here, we've got a class of men
who sort of work in the dark.
Those night raiders got away
with just about every cow I own.
I suppose it never occurred to you
to put your cows inside at night.
No... Inside?
What on earth is this? Cast iron?
No. Bear jerky.
- Oh.
- That's good.
Do you know what's happening
at Delmonico's this minute?
Monico's? Who's he?
He is a famous New York restaurant.
Some actress,
not a bit more talented than I am...
...is sitting at a lovely table
having lobster and crêpe suzettes...
...and champagne.
Sounds like she's a cinch for the hiccups.
And then every head will turn and watch her
as she goes sweeping out.
Oh, she's got the job
sweeping out, huh?
- Of course not. She's an actress.
- Oh.
Or, uh, do you know
what an actress is?
Oh, sure.
Sure, she's a girl Roy Stuart hires
to sing and cut up in his saloon, huh?
Saloon?
Is the Bella Union a saloon?
Well, you wouldn't exactly
call it a saloon.
It's more of a drinking joint.
[COUGHS]
But I have a contract with Roy Stuart.
Why, he's the partner of a man
I worked for in New Orleans, Mr. Legare.
I could never understand
why he lets the pigs in there.
They keep running in and out,
getting into fights with the dogs. Tsk, tsk.
JEANNE:
I won't play there.
I won't even go in the town.
Bozie, you make me so mad, I could cry.
Oh, don't you worry.
Bella Union isn't really that bad.
Mm, ha?
Don't you worry about a thing.
As soon as we start changing horses
at Cotulla, I'm gonna take you dancing.
You have a much better chance
of dancing with the horses.
Ha, ha. You don't mean that.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC]
MAN [SINGING]: Put your little foot
Put your little foot
Put your little foot right out
Put your arm around
Put your arm around my waist
Keep your arm around
Keep your arm around my waist
Take a step to the side
Take a step to the rear
But forever stay near
Do a little whirl
Do a little whirl about
Do a little twirl
Do a little twirl about
Walk a little bit
Put your little foot right out
Sing a little bit
Why, you do this like you were born to it.
Took me years to pick up.
This must be the only thing
that took you that long.
Well, we don't see pretty girls like you
down here very often.
Ha, ha.
I guess that's why
we have to pay for it, huh?
The regular stagecoach
stops here overnight.
They don't have to sit up all night
bouncing their brains out.
It is not my brains is tired.
Well, use them, then,
and get us on the regular stagecoach.
Look, Tuesday, it is last night
we played already...
...so we got to be there yesterday yet,
because the day before we ain't no place.
- You know?
- What?
[SIGHS]
Look, next day it is last night
we don't start...
...and Tuesday evening
is the morning we ain't coming.
- Now you understand?
- Of course not.
I'm sorry, I'm not a teacher. Sheesh.
[CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING]
[BAND PLAYING WALTZ MUSIC]
Hi, Charlie.
Pony Smith was on the stage with me.
Lafe McWilliams tailed us.
I saw them.
They're in the street right this minute.
Public street.
We gotta do something
to get you out of this.
- They'll never give you a fair break.
- Did I ask for one?
All right, Clay. It's your carcass.
[CLAY CHUCKLES]
He called you Clay.
Uh-huh.
- You never told me your name w...
- Well, you never asked me.
- Are you really Clay Hardin?
- Uh-huh.
Well, are they going to arrest you?
I hope not.
Break up our whole evening, wouldn't it?
I'd like this better
if Charlie Bell was out of it.
Yeah, I guess you'd like
Clay Hardin out of it too.
I can handle my job.
- Then let's not waste any time.
- Don't worry about me.
[LOUDLY]
Well, Pony, I'll see you in San Antonio.
All right, Lafe.
[MUSIC STOPS]
CLAY:
Thank you.
We get from out now. Maybe?
Well, I think we ought to tie on the nosebag
before we get from out now, maybe, huh?
You'll tie on a nosebag,
won't you, Jeanne?
Uh, waiter. Two more nosebags, please.
Waiter, I will take one too.
Big size.
This next dance is mine.
I'm sorry, but I'm tired now.
Give us some music, boys.
Don't make me ask loud, lady.
BOZIE:
Wait a minute.
I am her management.
She got to have advance billing,
or else: Poof.
No wiggles.
HENRIETTA:
Shut up, Bozie.
Surely you heard what the lady said,
didn't you, Lafe?
I don't believe I'd horn into this, Hardin.
I've known people
to get hurt bad sometimes...
...just by leaving too much slack
in their rope.
Uh...
Don't you find it a little crowded in here?
Maybe you'd sooner talk this over
in the street.
After you.
Sure.
I think I smell a polecat.
[GUNSHOT]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
CLAY:
Thanks, Charlie.
[GUNSHOT]
What's the matter, Lafe?
Something go wrong?
Did you see that potato draw on me?
He tried to gun me from the side.
Yeah, I saw him, Charlie.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[WHIMPERING]
- Charlie.
- Yeah?
Tell you what you do.
Go over to the telegraph office.
Send an overnight wire to Roy Stuart.
Say: "Deal went through as planned."
You've got a buzzing in your head?
Sign it "Lafe McWilliams."
Such a business:
Boom, boom, boom.
Just like burying people was no trouble.
Hmm. Heh.
I, uh...
I never thought of it
just that way before.
I'm a failure. I don't know how
to take care of her in such a madhouse.
If I ever get her back to New York,
I'm gonna have her locked up...
...and spend the rest of my life
in some nice, quiet insane asylum.
But you must have known this would
happen if you showed yourself here.
Kind of noisy for a minute, wasn't it?
I believe you've been delaying here
just to fight those men.
Me? Oh, no.
No, I just like music.
[TELEGRAPH MACHINE CLATTERING]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[MAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[PIANO PLAYING UPBEAT
SALOON MUSIC]
You see Mr. Roy Stuart?
Up in his office.
[BO Y SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Five hundred dollars
to this Jeanne Starr woman for one week.
Who is she?
Another one of your flea-bitten canaries?
Roy, why don't you leave
the artistic end of our business to me?
Because your figures don't tell anything.
The way you run this place,
nobody knows where the money goes.
What is this,
New Orleans style or Chinese?
I can't tell you, Roy,
how it hurts me to hear you say that.
What a tone of voice
to use to your partner. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Did you ever stop to think
what would happen to you, Legare...
...if I caught you shorting me?
You might keep the accounts yourself,
you know.
That is, if you can add.
[LAUGHING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
For Mr. Roy Stuart.
Think over what I said.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Muchas gracias, Mr. Stuart.
Look at that. This was sent last night.
Took it 20 hours to come from Cotulla.
They must have brought it on foot,
walking backwards.
Why can't they?
Lafe McWilliams must have gone crazy.
I told him 50 times never to wire me.
But I can use it.
Some kind of an accident
seems to have happened to Clay Hardin.
May I see it?
I don't think you'd be interested.
Your odds are way off kilter.
The Laredo stage has been in for an hour.
And was Clay Hardin on it?
- Nobody was on it except Charlie Bell.
- That's right.
Funny thing, I've taken more bets
since the coach came in than I did before.
ALL: Ah.
- Still fussing about the odds, boys?
Well, I guess maybe
they are a bit tough, at that.
MAN:
Fifteen-to-one.
That I'd have to take,
if I was betting on my own funeral.
- Give them all they want.
- Right.
Get it out, boys. Come on.
Here's a hundred.
[TELEGRAPH MACHINE CLATTERING]
- Yes, Mr. Legare?
- I'm very sorry to bother you, Mr. Pratt.
Mr. Stuart just now received a telegram
and tore it up by mistake.
I wonder if you possibly have a copy.
- Yes, I think so.
- Ah.
We don't usually do this, you know,
but, uh, seeing that you're his partner.
Yes, of course.
Thank you very much.
He'll appreciate this.
Thank you.
[CROWD CHEERING]
It is the lady! She has come.
The lady from Monterey!
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
See there? We got us a female visitor.
It's Jeanne Starr. In her own coach.
I wish it was Clay Hardin.
Not me. Come on.
Do you mean to tell me this
little mud Indian village is San Antonio?
Oh, it is nice. You will like it.
As far as I'm concerned,
it's just another place full of wild savages.
Try to look gorgeous.
Remember, hold in your stomach.
Oh, Henrietta.
[CLAY LAUGHS]
Hurry up. Get over there.
Here. Stand straight.
Pay attention.
What's the matter with you? Stay here.
Now, listen, boys,
if you can't make it good, make it noisy.
Do you understand that?
Good.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[ALL CHEERING]
Mademoiselle Jeanne.
It is a pleasure to see you again.
Oh, Monsieur Legare,
what a lovely reception.
But then, you always
arrange these things so beautifully.
My dear, for such beauty as yours,
receptions arrange themselves.
[JEANNE LAUGHS]
[RO Y CLEARS THRO AT]
Oh, yes.
Miss Starr, this is my partner, Roy Stuart.
Mr. Stuart,
I've heard so much about you.
You're really a very famous man.
Miss Starr, that's the greatest
thing that ever happened to San Antonio.
[LAUGHS]
I was just telling Legare
how lucky we are...
[BAND LOUDLY PLAYING
"CAMPTOWN RACES"]
I said, I was telling Legare...
[ALL LAUGHING]
[ALL CHATTERING]
MAN 1:
It's Clay Hardin! He's back.
MAN 2:
There's Clay Hardin.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
MAN 1:
Why, it's Hardin.
MAN 2:
It's Clay Hardin.
MAN 3:
Clay! Clay Hardin!
[CROWD CHATTERING]
MAN:
Get back there. Get back.
- Better stay back, out of the line of fire.
- This can be anything.
- Here it comes.
- Don't make any play unless Roy does.
You'd better go inside.
How are you, Roy?
Why, you look a little surprised to see me.
So? Why should I be?
I thought maybe
you might have heard something.
There was some talk of you coming back.
And vice versa too, I'll bet.
Did you bet on it, Roy?
It don't mean a thing to me.
I've handled you before, remember?
That's why I've come back.
They don't want any more shooting
in San Antone.
Colonel Johnson and the cavalry
will grab you inside of 15 minutes.
Unless you get smart
and save them the trouble.
Roy, that's just what I'm gonna do.
You're gonna do what?
Save them the trouble.
[SIGHS]
They eased past the killing point.
For this one minute, they have.
Colonel Johnson left town
about an hour ago on Army business.
And he won't be back until tomorrow.
But he told me to tell you,
if you showed up in San Antonio, he'd run...
Wait a minute, captain.
I haven't come on any personal business.
I came because I've got the evidence...
...on what and who started
the whole Beyar County cattle war.
Here it is.
I brought it straight to the colonel.
And give it to him yourself tomorrow.
I don't want it on my hands overnight.
- Who was it?
- Roy Stuart.
I can show what brands were raided,
where cattle went, and what Stuart got.
That's no good
until it's shown in court.
I know that. All I want is three days.
Give me two days, and I'll prove
every charge I ever made against Stuart.
I can't promise you anything, Hardin.
I only work here.
The colonel told me,
the first man who starts shooting...
...during their nesting season,
we're gonna grab him and jump all over him.
And abuse him
in every way we can think of.
Uh...
Who is "we"?
Well, that's what the colonel says.
I'll be back in the morning.
Come on, Charlie.
We'II, uh, be glad to see you, Hardin.
It looks like
we got the Army against us too.
He wasn't much help.
I'll tell you what you do.
Get a hold of Tip Brice, Ricardo Torreon,
and Cleve Andrews too, if you can find him.
- Bring them up to the hotel.
- Pronto.
[MEN CHATTERING OUTSIDE]
CLEVE:
Should've bribed him, Charlie.
- Reach for the sky, you!
- Oh, cut it out, Clay, will you?
Clay, I'm glad to see you.
- How are you?
- I'm glad to see you.
[BOTH SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Say, Texas ought to make this a holiday.
Horsefeathers.
Come on, light and squat, you Indians.
I got something to say to you.
I want you to listen and listen fast.
What's on your mind?
I sent for you because you were always
too dumb to know when you were licked.
All right. Now I want you
to back my play just once more.
We're in awful poor shape
for any more fighting, Clay.
Cleve, you stand up to Roy Stuart
just one more day...
...and I guarantee you by tomorrow night
we'll have the state of Texas on our side.
- One day can be a long, long time.
- Show them the tally book, Clay.
Is that what you were after in Mexico?
What did you think he was doing?
Picking flowers?
Just a minute, 500 head of Bar nine.
That's my brand.
I didn't sell those cattle.
It's signed by Roy Stuart.
How did you hook onto this, Clay?
Well, one night we saw a whole herd
of cattle stampeding through the Rio.
We tied into them
and stampeded them back.
- Get any of the rustlers?
- Uh-huh. One only, one of Roy Stuart's men.
We found his body in the brush
by the river.
He had this tally book inside his shirt.
You caught them
running my cattle into Mexico?
What do you mean, your cattle?
Everyone had cattle in that herd.
You see how he's worked?
He'd drive those stolen cattle
down into Mexico.
Then he'd sell them back into Texas
across a thousand miles of border.
Now, get Stuart
and Beyar County will come back.
It's no use unless you all
get on the witness stand...
...and swear
that you never sold these cattle.
I might as well tell you that witness stand's
the hottest seat in Texas.
So all the boys should come in.
Notes, notes, music.
If you're gonna rehearse that orchestra,
don't you think you'd?
No!
JEANNE:
What on earth is that?
- Something usual.
- You never looked like that before.
I want to surprise you.
Oh, Bozie, this is no time for jokes.
[BAND TUNING INSTRUMENTS]
This is legal evidence
which we never had before.
It amounts to yes or no
for southwest Texas.
As long as we've got these bills of sale on
our cattle signed by Stuart, we've got him.
- It's about time, Clay.
- All right, now here's our...
[BAND PLAYING
SLOW WALTZ MUSIC]
Here's our first move.
Wait, wait, wait a minute.
You must not go:
"Doodle, doodle, deedle."
You must go:
"Deedle, deedle, doodle."
Always the opposite.
I have never seen in my...
Look, look. Upside down, he's got it.
You think the audience
is sitting on its head? Turn it.
Now, here it is.
[BAND PLAYING
SLOW WALTZ MUSIC]
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
Am I supposed to sing to that?
It is a nice arrangement.
I think of it myself.
It will tear down the dump. You will see.
Oh! I don't suppose it makes any difference
whether anybody hears me or not.
Probably some professional
horseback rider will come in...
...and everybody
will turn their backs on me.
Hey, how about a little quiet in here?
JEANNE: Are you always every place?
- Just keep it quiet, will you, please?
- Oh!
- Better run for it, young man.
Never touched me.
You're getting closer, but I can't wait.
I'll see you tonight in the saloon.
If you had common sense,
you'd stay out of that bear's nest tonight.
What are you talking about?
The more lights, the more people,
the more peace, you know that.
- I don't know anything of the kind.
- Ahh.
Can you imagine a man
wanting to miss that Jeanne Starr? Oh.
Sometimes I worry about you. Come on.
CHARLIE:
Oh, shut up.
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
- Waiter.
- Yes, sir.
- Take these in to Ms. Starr, will you?
- Right away.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Not for me. I'll be at the bar.
We can keep an eye on everybody
that way.
Hello, Ed. Where did you get the parrot?
It's a southern parrot.
It came from Mississippi.
- Ha, ha. Parrots don't come from the South.
- Oh, they don't, eh?
How y'all? Awk!
[PARROTT LAUGHS]
Fine, thanks.
- You sent for me, Mr. Stuart?
- Oh, not sent, Miss Starr.
I just said whenever it was convenient.
Oh.
- Well, I haven't much time to change.
- Oh, there's no hurry.
They'll hold the curtain for me.
- Shall we have a little drink for luck?
- No, thank you.
I hope you're going to enjoy San Antone.
I'm sure we're going to enjoy you.
After the show, if you'd like...
...I thought we might have
a little dinner up here.
It's more private, nobody will disturb us.
[CLAY CLEARS THRO AT]
No, no, Roy.
Not now, just a friendly call.
I'll tell you when the shooting starts.
RO Y:
What do you want here?
Oh, Miss Jeanne,
Mr. Legare said he'd like to see you.
- He's right next door.
- Thank you.
You'll excuse me, Mr. Stuart?
- I asked you a question.
- I know.
You were asking another when I came in.
Is that your girl?
Could be.
We haven't made up our minds yet.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Come in.
You sent for me, Mr. Legare?
Did I?
Oh, yes, of course.
Please, won't you sit down?
- I should be getting backstage.
- Oh, don't worry, they'll wait for you.
And for me.
You know, my dear...
...I have been looking forward so much
to this visit of yours.
Really, like a young boy.
What a pity it was in New Orleans
that we didn't see more of each other.
Mm, but now...
Pardon me, I just came in to tell you
Bozie's looking for you, Miss Jeanne.
He's going crazy downstairs.
Thank you, Mr. Hardin.
I really must run now.
Roy, you want us to do something
about Clay Hardin?
Not till I tell you.
It's really a pity, Roy...
...that you don't take
fuller advantage of my brains.
As I think of it now, I'm afraid
you have made another wretched mistake.
Don't talk so much.
I'm thinking now
of a very interesting tally book...
...that I accidentally looked into once.
One accident
can lead to another, Legare.
As I recall, the book contained
some very curious bills of sale...
...transferring cattle.
I write bills of sale everyday.
Yes. But this time you were selling cattle
that didn't belong to you, Roy.
I suppose you learned that
by accident too.
Did it never occur to you
that some of the people who work for you...
...may also be friends of mine?
I've always suspected it.
That's how I know that this tally book...
...this convicting evidence against you...
...has fallen into the hands
of someone else.
Don't you know what's going to happen
if you don't get it back?
You'd like to get a hold of it yourself,
wouldn't you? Ha-ha-ha.
I wonder
who has that book of yours now.
I suppose it might be someone
sitting at one of those tables.
It might even be someone
standing at that bar.
I suppose one man's guess
is as good as another's, isn't it?
Now, don't step on your dress and trip
and spoil your number.
I think I'll send Clay Hardin a note
and thank him for his flowers.
Now, hold still. You look like a rag doll.
Jeanne, if you follow my advice,
you let that fellow alone.
He was born for trouble.
Gentlemen, tonight is a night
you will never forget.
I hasten to present Jeanne Starr.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
[BAND PLAYING SOFT MUSIC]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[SINGING]
I'm so happy, oh, so happy
And why shouldn't I be?
There's a reason
And the reason is as simple as ABC
Some Sunday morning
Is going to be
For someone and me
Bells will be chiming an old melody
Specially for someone
And me
There'll be an organ playing,
Friends and relations will stare
Say, can't you hear them saying
"Gee, what a peach of a pair"
Some Sunday morning
We'll walk down the aisle
He'll be so nervous
And I'll try to smile
Things sure look rosy
For someone and me
Some Sunday morning you'll see
Have you ever gazed at the silvery moon
Hanging low in a Texas sky?
And looked out across the plains
While the breeze hummed a tune
To the tumbleweed tumbling by?
Have you ever walked
By the old Rio Grande?
Have you ever seen sage all in bloom?
Have you felt the delight
Of just roaming around
Way out there
Where there's plenty of room?
Or did you ever ride down
An old cattle trail
While the stars like a million eyes
Seem to look down and say
"When you're down Texas way,
You're really in paradise"
[SINGING]
Some Sunday morning
We'll walk down the aisle
He'll be so nervous
And I'll try to smile
Things sure look rosy
For someone and me
We're waiting patiently
To see how heavenly
Some Sunday morning
Can be
[CROWD CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC]
CHORUS [SINGING]: Some Sunday morning
There's going to be
Some Sunday morning
For someone and me
Bells will be chiming an old melody
Specially for someone and me
I got a note from the gal to Clay Hardin.
What will I do with it?
CHORUS [SINGING]:
Friends and relations will stare
Say, can't you hear them saying
"Gee, what a peach of a pair"
- Give it to him.
- Lf that's the way you want it, boss.
CHORUS [SINGING]: Some Sunday morning
We'll walk down the aisle
He'll be so nervous and I'll try to smile
- Get that drunken cat off the bar.
- Yeah, he is a little drunk, isn't he?
CHORUS [SINGING]:
For someone and me
From Miss Starr.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
Some Sunday morning
You'll see
Wait a minute, Clay. Don't go back there.
You can't trust anybody
in San Antonio tonight.
- This girl's a complete stranger.
- Yeah?
Who brought her here?
Who's she working for?
- Stuart and Legare.
- You didn't always scare this easy.
Oh, all right, go on.
At least let me carry the tally book
while you're dilly-dallying.
- You got no right to risk everything.
- Ha, ha.
- Sure, if it will make you any happier, here.
- Careful.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
There'll be an organ playing
You're like a ticklish girl
at a strawberry festival. Here.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
Say, can't you hear them saying
"Gee, what a peach of a pair"
Fair and lovely
Some Sunday morning
We'll walk down the aisle
He'll be so nervous
And I'll try to smile
Henrietta, will you please
open the door to the gallery?
It is open.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
We're waiting patiently
To see how heavenly...
Well, don't stand there like a ninny.
Come in and shut the door.
This is nice. I'm so glad you came up.
Now, don't talk all night.
You need your rest, you know.
It was sweet of you to send me
those flowers you picked yourself.
- Well, I can see you needed them.
- Ha, ha.
And, uh, I'm sorry
I threw those things at you this afternoon.
Oh, that's all right.
Usually, you have to stand in line
to throw things at me.
Oh.
It's stifling in here, Clay.
- Let's go out on the gallery.
- Sure.
What's out on that gallery,
the pay window?
I feel sorry for the rest of the country.
Struggling along in plain
and fancy ignorance.
Poor Louisiana, poor old Arkansas.
What's the matter?
Is Texas going to take them in?
Just think of all the other towns there are.
And only San Antonio
rates a performance by Miss Jeanne Starr.
Oh, now, wait a minute.
Where does a cowboy learn
to talk like that?
And then to the south
of our little house...
...nothing but mile upon mile
of button-hole bushes.
They're lovely.
I guess I'm supposed
to sew on all the buttons.
Why, of course. Oh, I can see it all.
Birds singing in the trees,
flowers coming up.
Oh, yes, and here's the main event:
The whole thing's completely surrounded
by millions of assorted cattle.
Oh, that really settles it.
Your old cows scare me to pieces with
those long antlers or whatever they are.
Antlers?
[BOTH LAUGH]
[FOOTSTEPS APPRO ACHING]
So you can't get away from it, Jeannie.
Everything either begins in Texas
or ends up there.
That's just it.
Who wants to end up?
[GUNSHOT, GLASS SHATTERS]
Well, if that was a Texas kiss, l...
Maybe I shouldn't have broken up
those two meetings you had.
Get inside.
Tell me, Bozic.
What do you see?
L... I don't think I see nobody.
Just remember that.
And remember this:
Nothing was ever more important
in your life.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
[WOMAN SOBBING]
The whole play went wrong.
There'll be guns talking all over the place
in another 24 hours.
Joey, you ride to Hondo.
Ride to Sabinal if you have to,
and get Harkness' bunch.
Rebel, you swing out to Pilgrim.
Bring in the High-Five
and the Jingle-Bob outfits.
You others fetch in your own.
I want the wild bunch in San Antonio
by tomorrow night.
The cavalry's still here, Roy.
Pretty tough mixing with that outfit.
If you'd sooner hang...
...I'll see you get the prettiest flowers
ever thrown on a corpse.
HILL:
Come on, boys.
HAWKER:
Break out of it.
On your feet. He's coming right in.
- Yeah?
- Get your boys and ride into San Antone.
Roy Stuart wants a hundred gunfighters
by sundown tomorrow.
- What for?
- Never mind what for, just get in there.
Well, Stuart's got a lot of brass,
that's all I got to say.
Okay, I'll tell him that.
No, wait a minute.
Tell him we'll come in.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
JOHNSON: I'm sorry to have to continue
pressing these questions, Miss Starr...
...but I think you understand the importance
of your testimony in this inquiry.
- I'll do anything I can to help.
- Yes, I'm sure you will.
How close were you to Clay Hardin
when he was fired on?
Quite...
Quite close.
- This was outside your dressing room.
- We were standing on the gallery.
Someone shot at Mr. Hardin
out of the dark.
It broke the window behind us...
...but no one told me
to have him stand there.
No one made any suggestion about it.
I swear they didn't, no one.
JOHNSON:
Tut, tut, tut. Nobody said they did.
That was your own bring-up entirely.
- Don't you believe me?
JOHNSON: Yes, yes.
Did you see anyone on the patio?
No, sir.
I don't know anything else.
That's all, Miss Starr.
Thank you very much.
Uh, who is this Sacha Bozic
or Beezic or something?
Bozic, Bozic, Bozic.
B-O-Z, zic, Bozic.
- That's me, Your Highness.
- Don't call me that.
Yes, please.
Now, you don't have to give any answers
incriminating yourself...
...but where were you
when this hurrah broke loose?
I...
l... Please, I was breathing air.
- What?
- Thank you, thank you, thank you.
I mean, I come outside the dump
from inside...
...because there is no air
inside the dump.
And I think maybe there is air outside,
so I am outside now.
Oh, never mind the climate.
What did you see outside the dump?
Ha, ha. I mean, the Bella Union?
I see nothings. It is so dark.
You can't see nothings.
Great catfish, man.
You just admitted you were there.
- Yes, Excellency.
- Don't call me that either.
- Yes, please.
- Go on.
All of a... All of a...
All of a click, the gun start to go shoot.
I run one way... No, I run two ways.
I try to go someplace else...
...then I come to this man
who lies down.
I make a look.
- He's dead.
- Who else did you see?
BOZIE:
A-After that...
It is after that
a lot of people comes out...
...and helps me look at the deceased.
He's still dead.
- Is that all the light you have to shed?
- Yes, please, that is all I shed.
JOHNSON: Well, we found out
a sum total of nothing.
Thank you, Your Highness.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
We haven't heard anything to prove
that Mr. Stuart was in his office...
...as he says he was,
the time the killing took place.
I think I can dig up
a few witnesses to that.
If someone has shown a reason
why I should.
JOHNSON:
No one has.
It would be
much more to the point, Hardin...
...to produce one witness who knows
he was not where he says.
There's gotta be some connection.
Otherwise, he's innocent.
You ought to know that.
I know all that, colonel.
I'm sorry we can't get
better results here.
Especially since I have to call your attention
to our bulletin of this morning.
The military aid we've been giving here
is withdrawn.
Stopped, pulled out from under,
as of at once.
I don't like to leave
in the face of a blowup...
But I've been ordered to go put the quietus
on an Indian whittle whang.
My cavalry will leave tonight.
You people are on your own,
and heaven help you.
In that case, colonel,
there's something I'd like to ask.
If you're pulling out,
you gotta leave a peace officer here.
The post of town marshal is vacant.
I think I'm the man to fill it.
- Why?
- I'll tell you why if you want.
I was raised by Charlie Bell, ever since
I was about 2-and-a-half feet high.
When I was a kid,
Indians were playing up bad.
He'd have to take me out
and hide me in the brush.
I wouldn't be alive except for Charlie,
and he wouldn't be dead except for me.
You give me the authority,
and I'll get you the man that killed him.
All right, I'll appoint you for 24 hours only.
By that time, a new marshal...
...can be designated in the regular way.
So that's how long you've got to get...
...the killer in a legal manner.
- I'll try to see that it's long enough.
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT
MARIACHI MUSIC]
What's happened to that Starr woman?
How can you speak of her
marvelous attraction as "that woman"?
Where's her manager?
Hasn't been around since the inquiry.
Well, it's about time
you were asking me that.
He's probably shut in his room,
but I advise you to go and see.
You advise me?
Didn't you gather that Bozic was wandering
around outside our dump, as he calls it...
...at the time
you were shooting up these people?
- I shot nobody.
- Yes, yes, of course not.
Stick to it, by all means.
I got no more notion of who shot
this infernal Charlie Bell than you have.
But you were having
a little gun spree in the patio, weren't you?
That's a great plenty to hang you,
you know?
Yet you just casually
let an eyewitness go kicking around...
...without the least precaution.
- Who's taking care of him?
- Nobody, Roy.
Nobody at all.
Then you don't know
whether he's still in that room or not.
No, I don't.
For all we know,
he is wandering all over the place...
...talking freely to all kinds of people.
Don't you ever take care
of anything yourself anymore?
Jeanne. Jeanne.
- Feeling better, Bozic?
- I feel... I feel terrible.
- Terrible.
JEANNE: Oh, I'm sorry.
HENRIETTA: He always feels terrible.
- But never like this.
If he feels like he's dying,
there's beginning to be justice around here.
You are a heartless old wrinkle.
Always the opposite.
- Come on, Jeanne.
- No, Jeanne, I must speak to you.
- We haven't time to hear...
- No, no, no, only Jeannie, please.
Go ahead, I'll be with you in a moment.
If he tells you he's run us
out of money again, don't be surprised.
What's the matter, Bozie?
Jeanne, a terrible thing
make itself to happen next.
- Wait a minute.
- It is true, I don't know how to tell myself.
Jeanne, it is a murder wants to happen
and I'm it.
Oh, for goodness' sake, Bozie.
Now, tell me. What is it?
It is so necessary nobody can help.
I don't hope.
You see, l... I know... l...
I know who was the murderer
who kills Charlie Bell.
- Who was it?
- I can't tell you, I don't dare tell you.
- You should have told them at the inquiry.
- Yes, I know, but then I could not think.
And now it is too late.
He has people helping him.
They are all around us.
They are in the patio, in the stairs.
- Well, what do you want to do?
- We must try to get away, get away.
Maybe they will let us go when they see
we are just quietly going from out.
Oh, Bozie. I can't go.
I...
- You would just wait for them to kill me?
- No.
But, well, you can get out of here
a whole lot better without me.
Now, grab what you need and
get away from here this very minute.
No, no, I could not leave you alone.
If you don't, I'll march straight
to Clay Hardin with the whole thing.
No, you mustn't, you mustn't.
It's the worst you could do.
Then you would be in danger too.
Well, then, get out of here.
Don't argue with me.
Please hurry up.
All right, Jeanne, if you want me to.
- Jeanne...
- Bozie, go on.
[MONKEY GIBBERS]
Aah!
[GIBBERING]
[WHIMPERING]
I can't do it. I can't leave.
You can't do what?
I can't...
Mr. Stuart.
I understand that you're known
to roam around some at night.
L... I didn't mean to. I was only breathing air.
You were behind the Bella Union
when Bell died, weren't you?
You don't need to say it.
Don't, please. Don't.
I wouldn't tell on Mr. Legare.
I wou...
[WHIMPERING]
You wouldn't tell on who?
L... I didn't mean to see him.
I didn't know Mr. Legare was there.
I...
I was just running away.
You saw Legare shoot Bell?
No, no.
I swear I don't tell somebody.
Shut up.
Yes, please.
I never thought
he had that kind of gravel in his craw.
And you'll be out of town in 15 minutes?
Fifteen minutes. Yes.
[WHIMPERING]
Make it 10 minutes.
Ten minutes.
Ten minutes. Ten...
Five minutes.
[SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
Where's Legare?
He's eating,
down in the middle of the plaza.
Keep a close lookout on Clay Hardin.
I like to know where he is.
Right.
WOMAN:
Jackson.
Worried, Legare?
Well, I was just thinking
of borrowing some of your artillery.
As we say in New Orleans:
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
What does that mean in Texas?
The same thing, Roy.
"There is no one
who isn't dangerous for someone."
The Bozic matter is taken care of,
naturally.
He's out of reach.
Including your reach, Legare.
I have no objection
to your killing Charlie Bell.
Probably saved me the trouble.
Without actually admitting anything...
...let me say I am happy
that you take that view.
But, uh, wouldn't it be strange...
...if I were to find
that the tally book is in your hands now?
Ha, ha. Considering that it might easily
hang you, I might say yes.
Wouldn't that be odd?
I have thought for some time, Roy,
that you need me as a partner...
...in your cattle business.
As well as in the Bella Union.
So you do have the tally book?
I can be a great help to you, Roy.
At the present moment, you are perhaps
the most feared man in South Texas.
You're certainly the richest.
You will still be one of the richest
if we divide it all.
Can you think of one good reason
why I don't kill you?
I can.
You don't know where your tally book is.
Or where it will turn up if I die.
You not only will not kill me, Roy...
...you will defend my life
as if it were your own.
It almost works, Legare.
Oh, I think it will.
Every time you look at me, Roy,
you must say to yourself:
"There sits my very life
and about $ 10 million."
You think you're smart, don't you?
You are smart.
But not smart enough.
Sure, now it's too early,
and later, it will be too late.
Mr. Hardin, Mr. Clay, that lady,
Jeanne Starr, she wanna see you.
Gracias, hombre. Take it.
- I tell her something?
- No, nothing.
Something's happened
and we don't know about it.
Unless we can find out
before the cavalry leaves...
...it's no use finding out at all.
We can't fight until the cavalry leaves
and after that, we can't win.
Roy Stuart's mavericks
are piling into town, hand over fist.
That wild bunch could have gone
into town last night.
I wonder why they didn't.
Because you did not tell them to,
I suppose.
I wonder why Stuart didn't need them
until after Charlie Bell was dead.
If he hadn't killed Charlie Bell,
Texas would have blowed up in his face.
Ah. He's still afraid of that.
You know something, Tip?
I don't think Stuart killed Charlie.
He's dead, ain't he?
Someone else killed him
and took that tally book.
- I don't think Stuart knows where it is.
- But then, neither do we.
Someone does.
I've got an idea who it is.
- Go find me Sacha Bozic.
- Sack of what?
Bozic, you know, Jeanne Starr's manager.
A little round fellow like a beer barrel.
- Go ahead, quick.
- All right.
Excuse me, Miss Jeanne.
I'm looking for your Mister...
You know, the little fellow
that handles your freight for you.
Oh, Bozic? I think he...
Uh, I don't know where he is.
Miss Jeanne, uh, Clay Hardin
is right out there in the plaza.
LEGARE:
Jeanne.
Have you talked to Bozic?
Yes, I see that you have.
[CHUCKLES]
How does it seem to be in love
with San Antonio's leading crack-shot?
Yes, Clay Hardin.
When there are 200 men in the room,
you see only him.
I have noticed it.
Do you realize that you yourself are likely
to put Clay Hardin in the greatest danger?
I understand Clay Hardin is very good
at taking care of himself.
Hmm. Look about you.
How many guns are in this plaza
and behind those shutters?
If a man receives 30 bullets in his body
in the 10th part of a second...
...what is his next step
in taking care of himself?
What kind of people are you here?
Peace-Ioving people.
But so many would love
to see Clay make a wrong move.
It would be too bad
if you told him something...
...that would occasion a sudden accident.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
I don't need to talk to him at all.
I won't even speak to him.
You will talk to him if it's unavoidable.
But do not seek him out, because if you do,
I'll know I've made a mistake.
I'll be forced to correct it.
[CHILDREN CHATTERING
IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Are you sure
you ought to be out here by yourself?
The last time we spoke, I think
you were accusing me of trying to kill you.
Or of helping someone
who wanted to kill you.
What was it you wanted to tell me?
Nothing.
This town is full of men who look
as if they'd step on baby chickens.
Is that all you wanted to say?
Or are you sure Legare
didn't just give you some new instructions?
Clay, will you take me away
from San Antonio?
Right now, this very minute?
You know
what that building is over there?
JEANNE: What, that old broken church?
- You ever hear of the Alamo?
- Of course, everyone has, but...
- That's it.
- Clay, will you listen to me, please?
- No, you listen to me.
Texas was born inside those walls.
Those old-time Texans
died for something pretty important.
I wouldn't want them to know I pulled out
just because it got rough.
- It's hopeless to talk to you, isn't it?
- No.
All you have to do
is to be honest just for a minute.
What is it you haven't told me?
Nothing. I swear there's nothing.
If I tell you I believe you,
will you stand on that?
- Yes.
TIP: Oh, Clay.
Oh, excuse me, miss.
Bozic isn't around here.
He isn't even in town.
Some say he pulled out for Austin
by special coach.
Send Bud and Windy after him
on the best horses you've got.
Get him back here fast.
- We didn't know he was so important as...
- You know it now, andale.
How did you know that Bozic...?
Who told you?
You did.
You haven't played enough poker.
I guess that ends it, Clay.
There go our troops.
Well, they had to go sometime.
If only Bud and Windy had got back.
They didn't, though.
We couldn't fight them
till we had a legal reason.
Now we can't fight at all.
Well, I'll be seeing you, boys.
- Wait, Clay, we'd better go with you.
- Not this time.
What are you gonna do, Clay?
There's always one more drink
left in the jug.
I wonder what he meant by that.
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC]
Aren't you ever going to forgive me
for something I didn't even do?
Uh, did you ever hear
of an animal called a Judas goat?
- No, but never mind that now, Clay.
- But I do mind now.
When sheep are driven to be slaughtered,
they balk and won't go in.
So a goat is put in to lead them.
- I don't care anything about that.
- I do.
Sheep trust the goat.
They go where she leads.
The goat walks through untouched,
but the sheep following are killed.
Is that what you believe of me?
Clay.
Funny part of it is,
Charlie Bell warned me.
If I had listened, he'd be alive tonight.
Wouldn't he?
I wish I'd run away when Bozic did.
LEGARE:
Excuse me, Mr. Hardin.
It's time for you to take the stage,
my dear.
All right, I'll go.
I hope you have no objection, Mr. Hardin.
Should I have?
Why, of course not.
I know you won't believe me.
But I'm worried about Bozic.
He still isn't here,
hasn't even been heard from.
Well, I have to go on anyway.
You know something about this
you're not telling me.
You think because I scold Bozie,
I don't care what happens to him.
Well, I scold you too, and I've stuck to you
through whistle stops and high water.
I think that's my cue.
You're not ready to go on.
Oh, let me get it over with, Henrietta.
- There's no time.
- There is time.
The orchestra will ad-lib.
I wish you'd look at yourself.
Sit down, Roy.
I don't think you came here
just to sit around and scratch fleas.
That's right.
I came to make an arrest.
Clay, as it so happens,
I didn't kill Charlie Bell.
I know that, Roy.
Then what do you want?
I want the man who did.
Secondly, I want an end to raiding
in Beyar County.
I know only one way to get that.
But there's another way
to get the man who killed Charlie.
Let's watch the show, huh?
[BAND PLAYING SOFT MUSIC]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[SINGING]
That day I crossed the border
He tossed a glance and I lost my heart
Somewhere in Monterey
In broken Spanish
I spoke in Spanish
Love is a Spanish art
So we had lots to say
And then sighing, "hasta mañana"
He ran away
Back to his hacienda
His wife and 10 little chicodees
Somewhere in Monterey
[CHORUS VOCALIZING]
[CHORUS WHISTLING]
Enjoying the act?
Once, for about five minutes...
...that one girl could have straightened
this whole thing out.
Maybe.
But she can't get you out of it now.
Hmm? What's that?
I'll make a deal with you.
Drop all charges against me,
give me full immunity...
...I'll give you the man
who killed Charlie Bell.
When I've got him, I've also got you.
You know that, don't you?
I know my tally book of cattle sales
was taken from Charlie's body.
But if you had it again,
you could blow up half this state.
Right.
That's why you've got no chance
of making a deal with me.
Then that's also why you haven't got
a chance of getting the killer.
Because I'll have to stop you.
[CHORUS WHISTLING]
[CHORUS VOCALIZING]
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
CHORUS [SINGING]:
That day she crossed the border
He tossed a glance and she lost her heart
Roy, for a moment,
I almost thought you could do it.
I'll see you later.
She spoke in Spanish
Love is a Spanish art
So they had lots to say
Well, what's out there? Bill collectors?
You may as well tell me
so I can deal with them.
We've gotta get out of here.
Go back to the hotel.
Hire a coach and put our stuff into it.
- Where are we going?
- I don't even know.
CHORUS [SINGING]:
And 10 little chicodees
Somewhere in Monterey
[LOCK CLICKS]
[SIGHS]
LEGARE:
Good evening.
Nope.
Come here.
It comes to me that I have been wrong.
I haven't said anything.
Nothing's happened.
Something has happened.
You have done
what I expressly forbade you to do.
- What harm can it...?
- I believe I warned you not to seek him out.
I'll leave San Antonio if you want me to.
I'll get out of here tonight.
I'm afraid it's a little late for that.
[BANGING ON DOOR]
Drop your hand.
I got a friend here to see you.
Come in, Bozic.
L... I run away, but I came back.
You're under arrest, Legare,
for the murder of Charlie Bell.
I think you'll find it isn't as easy as that.
Don't move.
In about 10 minutes,
my job will be done.
May I point out that your next 10 minutes
are infinitely uncertain?
Roy Stuart and I detest each other,
as you may know.
Yet he has become extremely valuable
to me...
...so that I would defend him
at the risk of my life.
I'm sure you would.
Conversely, Roy Stuart
has a very special reason for valuing me.
Believe me, there hasn't been one moment
since you entered the Bella Union...
...when you could have left the building
without my help.
I expect to have your help.
You're gonna walk ahead of me
until I get outside.
Not too fast and not too slow.
Shall we start?
Not that way.
We're gonna walk
through the Bella Union.
[BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC NEARBY]
Look out, Clay!
[GUNSHOT]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
[HENRIETTA YELLS]
[BOZIE MUTTERING]
[GUN CLICKS]
Behind you, Clay.
[GRUNTS]
[DISCORDANT NOTES PLAYING
ON PIANO]
You never were smart enough
to be my partner, Legare.
I...
I have been waiting for you, Roy.
CLAY:
Don't move, Stuart.
Drop that gun.
[PEBBLE CLATTERS]
[GUN CLICKS]
[HORSE APPRO ACHING]
No, no, no.
The big one must go under,
so it won't be on top.
That is why the big one is smaller.
Give a push up
so it don't stick in so far out.
Sheesh, shoosh.
Always the opposite.
JEANNE:
Bozic.
BOZIE:
Yes, darling, what can I do for you?
There must have been some answer.
No, Jeanne. No answer is from.
Well, didn't he even say anything
to the boy who took my note to him?
The boy don't know where is Clay Hardin,
so I send him to look where he ain't...
...to see if he is back.
I don't see the boy since after.
Now, go inside, please,
before you change my mind some more.
Maybe Clay never got your note at all.
We got to get her out
of this terrible town.
If you can't say nothing, don't speak.
[GRUMBLES]
If she can't get her mind off that rider,
there's no sense in taking her 200 miles.
She'd only turn around and come back.
I'd do the same thing myself.
Jeanne, if you feel so bad,
we don't go someplace.
We don't leave
until after we all get killed yet.
If that is what you want. Ah.
No, Bozie. We're leaving now.
If he can't even walk across the plaza
to say goodbye to me...
...I don't want to see him again
or think of him or hear his name.
Now we pack.
Quick, quick, quick.
Begin putting the stuff on the...
Huh?
Gee. You...
I was very happy to meet you.
Thank you. See you again.
It was very nice. Thank you.
You've searched the Alamo again
since daylight?
There was only one body in the Alamo.
The body of Legare.
Nobody knows what happened in there.
Oh, we'll know more about it
when we find Clay.
- Lf we find him.
- Yeah.
Aye.
[GUN CLICKS]
Move over, honey.
BOZIE:
Look, look, look.
There goes an empty horse.
You look like they drug you through
in an irrigation project, backwards.
He looks as though
they completely killed him.
- Just where do you think you're going?
- Out of Texas, you can bet on that.
- How can you even think of leaving Texas?
- Well, l...
Can't you see the sad look in the eyes
of those poor little cattle out there?
Look at them.
- You mean, that Matagorda knot-head?
- Yeah. Huh?
Matagorda?
Now, just a minute.
Since when did Easterners
start talking about Matagordas?
Well, l... I guess I just wasn't thinking. L...
I'll say you weren't.
I always thought
there was something phony about you.
Now, are you going to tell me the truth?
Just where
were you born and raised, huh?
Fort Worth.
A Texan, I thought so.
I could have gotten away with it
if I'd really tried.
You let go of her, Clay Hardin.
We're going to New Orleans alone.
No, ma'am, we're not.
There is only one place for us Texans.
Amigo, turn around.
- Always the opposite.
- Ha, ha! That's right.