[ Bugle Blowing ]
[ Bugle Continues ]
[ Cannons Firing ]
[ Cannon Fire Continues ]
They come closer
every day, Pa.
- They on our land?
- No, sir.
Then it doesn't
concern us.
Does it?
You have
somethin' else to say?
No, sir.
Lord, we--
[ Door Closes ]
What'd I do?
It's what
you haven't done, boy.
A man eats with his hat on
is goin' nowhere in a hurry.
Now, your mother
wanted all of you raised
as good Christians.
And I might not be able
to do that thorny job...
as well as she could,
but I can do a little somethin'
about your manners.
Now, shall we--
Lord, we cleared this land.
We plowed it, sowed it
and harvested.
We cooked the harvest.
It wouldn't be here,
we wouldn't be eatin' it if
we hadn't done it all ourselves.
We worked dog-bone hard
for every crumb and morsel,
but we thank you
just the same anyway, Lord,
for this food
we're about to eat. Amen.
Where'd you come by
the hat, boy?
Down by the creek, sir.
Some fella down there
passin' out hats?
I found it.
It was just lying there.
Jacob,
you look like you've got
somethin'on your mind.
Go on,
say what you're thinkin'.
We've been through it all
before, Pa.
Now, don't paddle 'round
with me. You were raised
to say what you think.
You were all raised
Anything I can't stand
is a lot of noisy silence.
Now, come on, let's have
some talkin' here.
If you're gonna
make a speech,
I'm sorry I said it.
I know how you feel
about this war, Pa.
I guess we all more or less
feel the same way.
But I don't see how we can just
sit by and ignore it any longer.
Now, you say it's not
our business, not our fight.
Well, we're Virginians.
And I believe that anything
that concerns Virginia
concerns us.
- You do?
- Yes, sir, I do.
All right.
John?
Sir?
what are you
gonna do?
You gonna keep your slaves
or let 'em go free?
You know I don't have
any slaves, Pa.
That's right,John.
You don't have a slave
to your name, do you?
James,
what about you?
You ever think you
might like to own a slave?
I guess I never thought
about it, Pa.
well, think about it.!
Think about it.
If you had the money,
would you go out
and buy yourself a slave?
No, sir, I wouldn't.
why not?
If I can't do my own work
with my own hands,
it'll never get done.
Now, suppose you had a friend
that owned slaves...
and suppose somebody's
gonna come and take 'em
away from him,
would you help him fight
to keep 'em?
- No, sir.
- Your name's Nathan,
isn't it?
Aw, you know
my name, Pa.
Well, I seem to remember
somethin' about that.
I was talkin' to Henry.
Sir?
well, what do
you think?
- No, sir, I wouldn't.
- Why not?
I don't see any reason to fight
for something I don't believe
is right, and I don't think...
a real friend would ask me to.
Then why we have to have
this same conversation...
every Saturday
before Sunday meetin',
I'll never know.
But I'm gonna pray to
the Almighty that this
will be the end of it.
Pass the biscuits!
[ Church Bell Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Papa?
we're ready to go, Papa.
You still miss her,
don't you, Papa?
Miss her?
Oh,Jennie,
you don't know what I feel
when I come up here.
Even after all these years.
Sixteen years gone.
Sixteen years.
And even so,
I somehow feel...
that she's not dead at all,
but only resting.
And it's like I'm...
just waitin' for her to get up
and walk home with me.
[ Church Bell Ringing ]
[ Congregation Singing
""Rock of Ages'"]
Be of sin
the double cure
Safe from wrath
and make me pure
Could my tears
forever flow
Could my zeal
no languor know
Did you bring it?
No. Licorice.
I'll see ya after.
Could not atone
Thou must save
and thou alone
In my hand
no price I bring
Simply to
thy cross I cling
While I draw
this fleeting breath
When my eyes
shall close in death
When I rise
to worlds unknown
And behold thee
on thy throne
Rock of ages
cleft for me
Let me hide
myself in thee
Amen
There are no doubt some present,
Charlie Anderson,
who wonder why you and yours
are never on time
for the Lord's services.
Have I kept the Lord waiting,
Pastor Bjoerling?
You have not.
[ Laughing ]
Our message for today...
is duty.
Now this means many things
to many people.
But for a Virginian,
they all lead to one.
[ Whispering ]
James.
Get that fish line.
The three...
most important duties
are..
[ Whispering ]
Tell him to stop.
duty to Fod...
Stop him,
will ya?
that created us
and loves us,.
duty to the state
that gives us sustenance...
and provides for us,.
and duty to our neighbor,
[ Figgling ]
our fellow man,
without whom...
we... could not live.
When you good people can
find it within yourselves...
to refrain from doing
whatever it is you're doing,
I'll get on
with the Lord's word.
Duty to a Virginian...
is not just a word,
my friends.
Now, for the last time,
Charlie Anderson,
I need that mule of yours.
I don't understand your
reluctance in talking to me
about the sale of it.
Now, that mule you want
is a matched Kentucky red;
matched with another
Kentucky red that pulls
just like she does.
Matched, Abernathy,
matched! Do you understand
what matched means?
How much?
Thirty dollars
Federal.
I'll give 5O Confederate.
I'll let lightning
strike her first.
Uh, Miss Jennie,
I'll be leavin' soon,
and--
I'll be leavin' soon, and--
You said that already,
Sam.
I did?
Oh, yes, I did.
I, uh--
I would be eternally grateful
if you'd permit me
to call upon you this evenin'.
Eternally's
a long time, Sam.
Not when one carries
the memory of you,
Miss Jennie.
I look forward to seein' ya
after supper, Sam.
Abernathy,
your idea of a deal
makes my stomach hurt.
You want me to get
that mule now?
The boy say I--
Get in that wagon,
Gabriel.
Charlie Anderson,
I wonder if you'd be
good enough to tell me...
exactly why do you bother
to come to services?
Meaning no disrespect,
of course.
It was my wife's
last request,
Pastor Bjoerling.
Meaning no disrespect,
of course.
Whoa, boy.
Doc.
Mrs. Witherspoon.
Charlie, looks like I'll be
paying you a visit soon.
Uh-huh.
You haven't said a word.
I don't know what to say.
I mean--
Well, I know what to say,
I just don't know how.
It must be all
very complicated then.
No, it's, uh,just all memorized.
Everything I wanted to say
I've said a dozen times
before I got here.
[ Sam ]
I said it to my horse
and it sounded good.
I said it again to the trees
and it sounded better.
I said it to the moon
and it sounded perfect.
The moon
can't hear you, Sam.
He smiles and smiles,
but he never hears.
I do.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
Well, I'm sure
gonna miss her.
Is she goin' somewhere?
Oh, every woman goes
somewhere sooner or later.
You don't expect her to stay
around here and take care of us
all her life, do you?
I hadn't thought about it.
I hadn't planned
on her goin' anywhere.
Well, you better get used
to the idea, boy.
Your sister's ripe
and the pickers are here.
Of course, I don't s'pose
you know what I mean,
do you, boy?
I'm not as dumb
as you think I am, Pa.
[ Chuckles ]
Whoa. Halt!
You get back up
to the house, boy.
Mr. Anderson, there's
a rumor around here...
that you have the coldest water
this side of the Shenandoah.
That's right,Johnson.
The best
east of the Mississippi.
Six foot deep, 2O foot down.
Come on, help yourself.
Dismount, Sergeant.
I'm glad you're here,
Johnson.
I've been meanin' to have
a little talk with your people
about those cannon of yours.
My chickens
have stopped layin',
the cow's dried up.
Who do I send the bill to?
You might try Abe Lincoln.
They're mostly his.
When are you gonna take
this war seriously,
Mr. Anderson?
Let me tell you somethin',
Johnson, before you get
on my wrong side.
My corn I take serious
because it's my corn.
And my potatoes, tomatoes
and fences I take note of
because they're mine.
But this war is not mine,
and I take no note of it.
Well, maybe you'll take notice
of it when the Yankees drop
a cannonball in your parlor.
I might as well tell you
right now that I can't think
of another thing...
I wanna hear you say.
You have six sons,
don't you, Mr. Anderson?
Does the size of my family
have some special interest
for you?
As a matter of fact
it does.
We need men.
Two of these men here
are no more than 1 6.
Seems strange to quite a few
people around here that none
of your sons are in the army.
It don't seem strange to me
with all the work there is
to do around here.
I'll come right to the point,
Mr. Anderson.
Came out here to get 'em.
[ Laughing ]
Did I say
something funny?
I think so.
You came all the way out here
to get my boys, huh?
Yes, sir, I did.
Where are your sons now,
Mr. Anderson?
You wanna see 'em,
do ya?
Yes, sir, I do.
Jacob!
James!
John.!
Nathan.!
Henry!
Boy!
If you've got anything
to say to 'em, go ahead.
They'll listen.
There's a Yankee army
breathing down your neck.
I don't think you realize--
You're town bred,
aren't ya?
I don't see what that--
I've got 5OO acres
of good, rich dirt here.
As long as the rains come
and the sun shines,
it'll grow anything
I've a mind to plant.
We've pulled every stump,
cleared every field; and
we've done it ourselves...
without the sweat
of one slave.
So?
So? So, can you give me
one good reason...
why I should send my family,
that took me a lifetime
to raise...
down that road like a bunch
of damn fools to do
somebody else's fightin'?
Virginia needs
all of her sons,
Mr. Anderson.
That might be so,Johnson,
but these are my sons!
They don't belong
to the state.
When they were babies,
I never saw the state comin'
around with a spare tit.
We never asked anything
of the state,
and never expected anything.
We do our own livin',
and thanks to no man
for the right.
But seein' as how you're
so worried about it,
I'll tell ya.
If any of my boys thinks
this war's right...
and wants to join in,
he's free to do it.
Did ya all hear that?
Did ya hear it?
If you wanna dress up
like these fellas, go ahead.
Here's your chance.
Patrol, mount.
Mr. Anderson,
if you can sit in the middle
of this war and not get touched,
I congratulate you.
Where are
these Yankees now?
'Bout ten miles
that way.
'Bout ten or twelves miles
that way, and about
five miles that way.
Which way
are you headed?
That way.
[ Rifle Shots ]
[ Rifle Shots Continue ]
What do you do
with dead soldiers?
Where's their army?
Harrisonburg.
All right, you ride
over there, Nathan.
Take Henry with ya.
Tell 'em to come get 'em.
Yes, sir.
Does it concern us now?
You go to the house,
get somethin',
and cover 'em up.
Come on.
Uh, don't you think
we oughta wait?
No!
Papa?
Sam would like
to talk to you, Papa.
All right,Jennie.
Good evening, sir.
Sam.
It's bedtime.
Bedtime?
Why, it's only--
Picker's here,
Pa.
What did he mean by that?
It's nothin', Sam.
Have a seat.
I prefer to stand,
sir.
No, sit down, Sam.
I never talk to a man
who's lookin' down on me.
Now, there's something
you wanna talk to me about?
Yes, sir.
Sit down, Sam.
I've--
I've, uh, wanted to talk to you
for a long time, sir, but--
Well, to come
straight to the point
of the matter, sir, I--
I wanna ask
for your daughter's hand.
You mean,
you wanna marry her, Sam?
Yes, sir.
[ Lamp Rattling ]
Why?
- Sir?
- Why do you wanna marry her?
Well, I, I love her,
Mr. Anderson.
Well, that's not
good enough, Sam.
- I beg your pardon?
- Do you like her?
Well, I just said--
No, no,you said
you loved her.
There's some difference
between lovin' and likin'.
When I married Jennie's mother,
I didn't love her.
I liked her.
I liked her a whole lot.
I liked Martha
for at least three years
after we were married,
and then one day
it just dawned on me
I loved her.
I still do.
You see, Sam,
when you love a woman
without likin' her,
the night can be long and cold,
and contempt comes up
with the sun, and--
Do you understand
all this I'm tellin' ya?
Yes, sir.
Well?
Oh, well, I...
I likeJennie, sir.
I've always liked her.
All right, then,
you be good to her.
Because if you don't,
it's between you and me, boy.
Well then, you have
no objection, sir?
I didn't say that.
Oh.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
[ Door Closes ]
Yee-ee.!
[ Feet Stomping ]
Yee-hoo.!
Yee-haw-haw!
Whoo-haw!
whoo-hee.!
I suppose that means
Papa Charlie
gave his permission.
Sam'll be a couple miles
down the road before it
dawns on him to tell me.
It was Mother's.
You'll look beautiful,
Jennie.
Being married to someone
you truly love...
must be the most wonderful
feelin' in the world.
When I was a little girl,
I slept all alone in a big room.
My bed had
a feather mattress.
Outside there was thunder,
lightning, rain
fallin' on our tin roof.
I'd lie there in the dark
under my blankets...
feelin'so snug,
and good and warm...
because I knew I was safe.
I was loved,
and somebody cared.
And now, married toJames,
it's that same
little girl feeling.
I'm loved and somebody cares.
Oh, I'm so happy
I wanna shout!
That what
it feels like too.
[ Whinnying ]
Well, first-rate-lookin'
animals you got here, son.
They should be.
I do everything but
sing 'em to sleep at night.
[ Man ]
Anderson's the name,
Mr. Carol.
Nine horses
and two mules.
[ Carol ]
You're right, Mr. Tinkham.
These'll dojust fine.
One thing about these folks,
they sure know quality.
I'll take these two...
and four
out of the pasture.
what do you mean,
you'll take 'em?
Well, howdy, Mr. Anderson.
I ain't seen you
in quite a spell.
I don't get around
to visitin'jails much,
Tinkham.
This here's Mr. Carol.
Mr. Osborne.
Mr. Marshall.
They're Federal
purchasing agents, buying
horses for the cavalry.
That's right, Mr. Anderson.
Although we've got
a set price we can pay,
I'd like to hear what you think
these animals are worth.
The horses aren't for sale.
What my son tells ya is
the gospel truth, gentlemen.
And you can carve his words
in stone if you've a mind to.
The horses are not for sale.
[ Chuckles ]
That may be, but
I think I ought to tell you...
that we're authorized
to confiscate any we can't buy.
- What's confiscate mean, Pa?
- Steal.
[ Chuckles ]
You know, I don't think
you quite understand.
You're not gonna take
one horse off this farm,
so you might as well forget it.
I thought you said
these were reasonable people.
Mr. Carol, everybody
in the county...
knows they'rejust
sitting out the war.
I think what Mr. Tinkham means
is that, uh,
he sort of figured
that anybody too, uh,
too yellow to fight...
wouldn't mind making
a couple dollars off the war.
Yellow?
I apologize for
my son's manners, Mr. Carol.
He was taught to have
more respect for his elders.
I accept your apology,
sir.
Jacob, I don't know
what gets into you
once in a while.
You know you shouldn't hit
this gentleman...
as long as
I'm around.
James! Henry!
[ Funshot ]
Yike!
I'm not in the habit of makin'
promises to strangers, mister;
but you have my word on it.
If you and these other animals
don't get off this farm
this minute,
I'm gonna shoot you
stone dead.
That fella Tinkham,
he's the only man
I know that started
at the bottom...
and went down
in the world.
He used to steal horses
for nothin'.
Now he gets paid for it.
Come on, boy!
Get out of there
before you catch cold.
Go on in the house.
See what you
got us into?
Me?
You hit him.
Well, you would've
if I hadn't beat you to it.
Pa...
first it was Johnson,
and that
was on our land.
And now they come drivin'
right up into our yard.
Aren't we gonna do
anything about it?
Well, I must be
gettin' old.
Seems to me
we just did.
It's no easy job, Sam,
takin' care of a woman.
No, sir.
Mm-hmm.
Yep.
They expect things
they never ask for.
And when
they don't get them,
they ask you why.
Sometimes they don't ask.
And they just go ahead
and punish you for
not doing somethin'...
you didn't know
you were supposed to do
in the first place.
What for instance,
sir?
That's a very difficult
question to answer, Sam.
You're never quite sure.
It's just that it's
sort of you might say...
relative.
Relative to what,
sir?
To how they're feelin'
at the moment.
And how's that?
You never know.
Uh, I don't believe
I really understand what
you're trying to tell me.
I know, I know.
I never understood it myself.
I never understood it.
It's just one
of those things, Sam.
It's around.
You just don't ever see it.
Now suppose--
SupposeJennie started
to cry one day.
You don't know
what she's crying about,
so you ask her why.
Do you follow me,
Sam?
Yes, sir.
You ask her,
and she won't tell ya.
And that's when
you ask her...
what it was you did
that caused her to cry.
She still won't tell ya.
And that's when
you start to get angry.
But, don't get angry,
Sam.
She won't tell you
why she's cryin'
because she doesn't know.
Women are like that,
Sam.
And it's exasperating.
It's, it's... mmmph!
But don't let it
make you angry.
No.
When she gets like that,
just walk up
and hug her a little bit.
'Cause that's all they
really want...
when they're like that,
Sam.
A little lovin'.
You understand me,
don't ya?
No, sir.
You don't, huh?
[ Ann ]
There's somethin'else
you must remember.
Husbands like to be alone
once in a while.
Why?
You never know why.
But I can always tell
when James wants to be alone.
A mood comes over him.
I can always see it in his eyes
before it gets there.
I don't know where...
the mood comes from or why,
but that's when
I leave him alone.
It seems sometimes things get
so thick around a man...
that he comes to feel that
everything is closin' in on him.
That's when he wants
to be left alone.
You understand,
don't you?
No.
[ Organ Playing
""The wedding March'"]
[ Skipped item nr. 434 ]
""Dearly beloved,
""for as much as marriage...
""is a holy estate
ordained by Fod...
to be held in honor
by all--'"
To love and to cherish
till death us do part.
[ Bjoerling ]
"According to Fod's
holy ordinance,
and thereto
I plight thee my troth. '"
[ Sam ]
According to Fod's
holy ordinance,
and thereto
I plight thee my troth.
""I,Jennie,
take thee Sam...
to my wedded husband... '"
I,Jennie, take thee Sam
to my wedded husband...
to have--''
to have and to hold
from this day forward...
for better, for worse...
for richer, for poorer...
in sickness
and in health...
to love,
cherish and to obey
till death us do part...
according to Fod's
holy ordinance,
and thereto
I plight thee my troth.
[ Bjoerling ]
""Receive this ring as a token
of wedded love and troth. '"
Receive this ring as a token
of wedded love... and troth.
Join your right hands.
""For as much as Sam and Jennie
have consented together
in holy wedlock...
""and have declared the same
before God...
""and in the presence
of this company,
""I pronounce them
man and wife.
""In the name of the Father,
and of the Son...
""and of the Holy Ghost,
Amen.
""What God
hath joined together...
let not man
put asunder.''
Congratulations,
Sam.
Jennie.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, sir.
The captain's
compliments, sir.
Go on, Corporal.
He wishes
to see you immediately.
It's the Yankees.
They have broken through
at winchester, sir.
Very well,
Corporal.
I'll have to leave now.
You know that, don't you?
Do you understand?
Do you?
[ Groaning ]
It's started.
Pa!
You just sit quiet.
Pa.! Somethin'terrible's
gonna happen...
if we don't get
Ann home.
All right, all right.
Take the carriage.
Jennie and I will go
with Harkens.
Jacob, you drive 'em home.
Nathan, go with 'em.
Henry?
Yes, sir.
Find Doc Witherspoon.
What shall
I tell him, sir?
Tell him nothing.
When I send for him, he knows.
Yes, sir.
I'll be back, sir,
just as soon as I can.
You take care of yourself,
you hear?
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Crying Continues ]
Congratulations, son.
It's a boy.
I know the sound.
[ Brothers Laughing ]
Congratulations,
James.
How wonderful!
Ann wants to see you.
Something went wrong,
Charlie.
I'm sorry.
It's a girl!
[ Brothers Laughing ]
[ Baby Crying ]
James?
No.
I might break it.
How do you break
an Anderson?
I don't know how you could
bring yourself to do this
to me, Tom Witherspoon.
After all the business
I've given to you
over the years!
It's not that I have
any objection to girls,
you understand.
It's just that it's
awful hard to break a habit.
[ Chuckling ]
How old are you now,
boy?
[ Clears Throat ]
Eighteen, sir.
That means you'll be 2O
in four years.
Eighteen to you
is sixteen to me.
Just a little bit, sir.
I've never tasted it.
That's no good reason.
I've known men that've been
drinkin' hard and steady
all their lives.
They've never tasted it,
either.
Isn't that right, Doc?
[ Chuckles ]
All right,
here we are.
Here we go.
Here's to the ladies.
[ Coughing ]
These are busy days.
Good night, boys.
Night, Doc.
Tom?
Tom,
what's happenin'?
Virginia's losing,
isn't she?
Looks that way,
Charlie.
How do you feel
about it all?
I was born in Virginia.
Lived here all my life.
Raised three sons
and two daughters
under her flag.
My oldest son Paul is buried
somewhere in Pennsylvania.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know that.
They said Gettysburg
is where he fell...
at a place called
Little Round Top.
My youngest boy
came home last week
with tuberculosis.
He won't see
another Christmas.
My third son rides
with General Forrest.
I don't know where they are.
You, uh, you were asking me
how I feel about it all.
That's... the only way
I know how to answer you.
If she needs me,
send for me.
There's another baby due
up the river. Come on.
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Barking ]
Get out of here! Git!
Either get out,
or go find yourself a tree.
Just don't draw
no fire to me.
[ Soldier ]
Boys, now get outta here.!
Fet outta here now.!
[ Barking ]
C'mon,
get outta here!
[ Hoofbeats ]
[ Soldier ]
Fet outta here.! Fit.!
You hear?
Agh!
Yah!
Whoo-haw!
Yee-haw!
Well now, look how young
this one is.
[ Laughs ]
I swear to goodness,
if these here rebs...
ain't gonna be
sendin' out grandpappies
and old ladies next.
Let me hold that rifle,
Johnny.
My name
isn'tJohnny.
Let me have
the rifle.
What for?
Somehow
it just don't set right
with the officers...
when they see prisoners
walkin'around armed.
Now gimme that rifle
before I put a ball through
that dumb head of your'n.
I admire spunk
in a boy.
But if you don't do
what I say from now on,
you're gonna find out
spunk don't come free
for nothin'.
All right, reb,
let's go.
I'm no soldier.
I don't look
that ignorant, do I?
We've seen enough of them...
Johnny Reb caps
to last us a lifetime.
Go tell my pa.
Where they takin' you,
boy?
I don't know.Just go
tell him what happened.
You don't have
to tell his pa nothin'.
You're free.
Massa Anderson.!
[ Panting ]
They took him.
What are you saying?
Who's they?
Who'd they take?
The Yankee men.
They took the boy.
- How many Yankee men?
- I don't know.
Five, six.
I don't know.
Now it concerns us.
Nothin'. There's some
footprints near the trees,
but they don't lead anywhere.
We haven't seen another man
since we left the house, Pa.
What do we do now?
Well, we'll...
go home.
And we'll pack up...
and we'll leave tonight.
It's late, Gabriel.
Won't Mr. Abernathy
be lookin' for you?
He's gone, missy.
Gone to Richmond.
Left the field boss in charge.
Won't he be wonderin'
where you are?
Old Jethro don't care
nothin' about me.
When my mama died,
he even took our cabin.
I don't gotta go back,
do I, missy?
Man say I'm free.
Don't that mean
I don't gotta go back?
Well, if the man said
you're free, Gabriel,
I guess that means you can
go anywhere in the world
you wanna go.
You mean I can just
walk on down that road
and keep on walkin'?
You can run if you like,
Gabriel.
Good-bye, missy.
We can probably make
better time, Pa,
if we stay off the roads.
We can cut across here
to the Rapidan.
There's a union camp
the other side of the fort.
Is that the closest?
Yes, sir.
Far as I know.
The ones that took the boy
were probably a few skirmishers.
I don't think we could find 'em.
You think they turned him
in as a prisoner?
It's about all they can do.
All right.
We'll try that one.
If you mount up,
I'll be with you directly.
[ Ann ]
Come in.
Hello, Papa Charlie.
Well,
I think she's gettin'
bigger than you are.
Ann, we're leaving,
and James is staying
with you.
I don't know how
these people dare
take a son of mine.
When I catch up with 'em,
it's gonna be
a horrible thing to behold.
The boy means
a great deal to you,
doesn't he, Papa Charlie?
All my sons mean
a great deal to me.
But the boy--
My Martha died the night
he was born.
I look at him,
I see her.
I'll pray
for you all.
I'm afraid it's too late
to do any prayin' for me...
and expect
satisfactory results.
There.
You and James
decided on a name?
Martha.
She'd like that.
My Martha'd like that
very much.
Ann,
I haven't told you,
but we're all mighty proud
to have you in our family.
I love you very much.
[ Door Closes ]
You take care of yourself,
you hear me?
We'll be back
just as soon as--
[ Hoofbeats ]
- Where do you think
you're goin'?
- Wherever you go, Papa.
From what these preachers
tell me,
where I'm goin',
you wouldn't like it there.
You may be on your way,
but you aren't there yet, Papa.
Just never mind that.
You're not goin' with us.
So unstrap, unhook, get out
of your brother's clothes.
You're a woman!
Yes, I'm a woman. But I don't
see anybody here that I can't
outrun, outride and outshoot.
I'll unstrap for you,
Papa,
and unhook.
I'll even sit here
and watch you ride
out of sight.
- And then what?
- Then I'll follow.
That's what I thought.
Don't worry about
the place here, Pa.
We'll manage.
You just keep that
little Martha warm and fat.
She'll probably turn out
to be the only one
around here with a brain.
Bye, son.
Good-bye, Pa.
You the leader
of this band of fools?
Colonel Fairchild
is my name.
Whether or not
I'm the leader of fools...
is a question which
has often entered my mind.
To whom do I have the pleasure
of speaking, sir?
Charlie Anderson's
my name.
You better decide later,
Colonel, whether speaking
with me is a pleasure or not.
Got business with me,
Mr. Anderson?
Yes, sir, I do.
All right, Mr. Nelson.
What can I do for you,
sir?
You can return my son
for a start.
And then you can issue
some kind of an order,
whatever it is you do,
and instruct your people
to keep off my farm
and leave my family alone.
Your son?
My youngest son.
Your people came on my farm,
and they took him.
Why?
That's what I'd like to know.
But he's a prisoner,
and your army's got him.
He isn't a Confederate?
No, sir.
He's an Anderson,
and that's all he is.
How old is he?
He's sixteen.
Could you show me on the map
where your farm is?
Well, it's
Shenandoah Gap.
It shows here.
Right there.
It couldn't have been any
of my men who took your son,
Mr. Anderson,
because we haven't been
in your section.
But I think you
should understand something.
My men fought a battle
with rebels
who threw stones at them...
'cause that was all
that they had.
We took 1 ,5OO prisoners...
and there wasn't 5O rounds
of ammunition among them.
What are you tellin' me,
Colonel?
Only that what
you're trying to do
is nearly impossible.
Every corps in our army
is taking thousands
of prisoners each day.
How do you expect to find
one sixteen-year-old boy?
[ Army Officer ]
Hut, hut,
hut, two, three, four.
If I had him, Mr. Anderson,
I'd give him to you.
I don't have any prisoners here.
We sent them to the railroad
for shipment north.
If you happen
to find the boy,
give this slip to the officer
in charge, it may help you.
What is it?
It's just a statement from me
that your son
was taken by mistake.
And that it would be considered
a personal favor to me
if he is released to you.
Where's that railroad
you send your prisoners to,
Colonel?
It's at Ivy Glen.
I do wish you good luck.
I have a
sixteen-year-old son too.
He's in school in Boston.
Thank God!
Those stragglers
back there!
All right,
keep movin:
Go on inside.
Keep those men movin'
back there.
All right, move along!
The boy couldn't be with them,
could he, Pa?
I have a note
for Captain Richards.
Sir?
You Anderson?
I'm Anderson.
There's nothin'
I can do for ya.
I don't recall askin' you
to do anything for me.
I'm lookin' for my son.
I don't have him.
How do you know that?
All I'm askin' is to look
through these cattle cars.
Is that too much
to expect?
If your son is among these
prisoners, you're too late.
There's a war going on,
Mr. Anderson.
Sergeant,
lock 'em up!
Lock 'em up.
we have schedules to meet.
[ Sergeant ]
Lock 'em up!
What'd he say, Pa?
He says he
has schedules to meet.
Sergeant!
Get this stuff off
of the track, mister!
Who are you?
I'd like to know what
you think you're doin'!
You know the penalty--
You'd all please me very much
if you'd drop your guns
and stick your hands in the air.
You drop the rifles
right now!
Now I remember.
Anderson.
Your name is Anderson.
Now you can all turn around,
and start walkin'.
I don't care where you go
just as long as
you get out of my sight.
You're the man
who's lookin' for his son.
You're the man that's
got schedules to keep.
Come on, move out.
Come on,
let's go.
Let's go, Captain,
you heard him.
Come on, move!
Get on it, boy.
How long do you intend
to keep my train here, sir?
I'm glad you asked me that.
I believe in a man knowin'
all there is to know
about his business.
First I'm gonna empty your train
and then I'm gonna burn it!
Burn it?
Open up those doors!
Why,
you can't do that!
You can't burn
my train!
Maybe I can't,
but you gotta give me credit
for tryin'!
But why? Why?
It's not the kind of a train
I favor.
You can get out.
You're free.
Boy!
Jacob!
Boy's not here,Jennie.
Sam!
Jennie.
Oh!
You better leave here soon,
Mr. Anderson.
There's a regular cavalry patrol
on these railroads.
[Jacob ]
Pa, what
about the train?
Sir?
Sir, I've been the engineer
on this train for ten years.
She's been a good train
all that time.
Well, it ain't right
to burn her just 'cause
she come on to hard times.
You run a sad kind
of a train, mister.
It takes people away
when they don't wanna go...
and won't bring 'em back
when they're ready.
But I'll leave it to the ones
that were on it. Sam?
Burn it.
Burn the train!
Burn it.!
Ya-hoo!
Let's take it out of that car.
Bring another torch.
Henry, give Sam
the boy's horse.
The rest of you get mounted.
Come on.
[ Cheering ]
You bein' the only officer
here, sir,
well, some of the boys
are after knowing what to do.
- Go home.
- Home, sir?
The war is lost.
Go back to your families.
I had no right
to tell him that,
Mr. Anderson.
But those men can't
go through another fight.
We knew before
we went into the last one
we couldn't win.
Why'd you go, Sam?
Easier than runnin',
I guess.
If there's a cavalry patrol
around here, we better move.
[ Ship Whistle Blowing ]
Hello, Carter.
You can have your chance
tonight, boy,
if you wanna take it.
Chance for what?
To run.
They don't waste many men
on prisoner duty.
They're usually
the worst of the lot.
[ Carter ]
They plan on herding us
on that stern-wheeler.
Some of us don't fancy
no sight-seeing trip up north.
When they open that gate
tonight, you stick as close
to me as a flea on a hound dog.
And somethin' else.
Once we get goin',
you're on your own.
I gotta forget
that you ain't nothin'
but a lap baby.
[ Thunderclap ]
Nathan, you and Henry
take the horses
over to that barn there.
Yes, sir.
[ Thunderclap ]
Jacob, see if you
can get a fire started.
Yes, sir.
[ Banging Noise ]
Say, what's Pa
doin' in there?
Sleepin', I guess.
I can hear him movin'.
[ Thunderclap ]
Sure gonna taste good
about now.
For somebody
it is.
Sam?
Sir?
You too,Jennie.
Here,just, uh--
Your mother and I had it
a little better than this.
It's not very comfortable.
But when you've lived
together for a dozen years,
you'll realize that
comfort's not what counts.
It's customary for
a gentleman to carry his bride
across the threshold.
So, if... if you wanna--
Right.
Yes, sir.
[ Thunderclap ]
What are you
lookin' at?
Nothin', sir.
Come on, move along,
move along.
All right, inside.
Move along there.
Now!
Get that other guard!
Aaah!
Come on! Come on!
This way, boy.
Get down! Get down!
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
Get in.
Get in!
Come on.
Them blue bellies
must be everywhere.
We're gonna do our travelin'
at night headin' south...
always south.
Then we can't hardly help
comin' on
somethin' friendly.
But our farm is north.
[ Dog Barking ]
You hear somethin'?
I smell somethin'.
Wood smoke.
[ Carter ]
That's a Confederate camp.!
Wood smoke ain't all
you smelt!
You smelt country boys!
Hee-haw!
Whoo-haw!
I got these over at
the hospital wagon.
Fellas they belong to
won't be needin' them
no more.
The lieutenant over there
says they be pullin' back
in the mornin'.
We're welcome to go
with 'em if we want to.
That was good of him.
What is this?
Don't ask.
Ain't nothin' your mama
ever set the table with.
You can believe that.
We're walkin'
in tall cotton, boy.
Down in Vicksburg,
I hear they're eatin' rats!
[ Horse whinnies ]
[ Sentry ]
Yankees.! Yankees.!
[ Bugle ]
Here, take this.
[ Bugle Continues ]
Don't fire
till I tell ya!
I've never shot
at a man before.
They ain't
gonna know that.
[ Cow Bell Ringing ]
[ Moos ]
Lieutenant?
Yes, sir?
Is that a Confederate cow
or a Union cow?
Must be a Union cow, sir.
Union cow's tasty?
Quite tasty, sir.
Then take her prisoner.
Yes, sir.
[ Cheering ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Soldiers Froaning ]
Sorry, sir.
That's all right, Lieutenant.
You scared a few pounds off her.
Get ready.
Fire!
Charge!
Fire.!
Whoo-haw!
You might as well know
somethin' right now, boy.
In case you got any doubts,
we ain't got
a dog's chance in hell.
I ain't never seen nobody
get so peevish
over a cow before!
Hee-haw!
What... What you--
[ Groans ]
Howdy!
Hello.
What can I do
for ya?
Oh,just a drink
of your water
if you don't mind.
Come a long ways.
Got a long ways to go.
You're welcome
to all you can drink,
and all you can carry.
Obliged.
- Nice place you got here.
Must support quite a few.
- Nine.
Nine? Imagine that!
How come I don't see
none of'em around...
'cept you?
They're all away from home
for a while.
Oh, Mule, you sure do a job
up right.
Yeah, I'm bound to say it.
You sure do.
You two look around.
See if they got any horses.
I'll see
what's in the house.
Yeah.
James?
[ Gasps ]
- Mule?
-James!
James!
This all there is?
We used the last of the flour
yesterday and this is
the last of the coffee.
You don't think we're gonna
find him, do you, Sam?
No, sir, I don't.
Boy could be anyplace,
Pa.
He may even be somewhere
up north by now.
Federal prison,
you mean?
Yes, sir.
Horses haven't had a good feed
in a long time, Pa.
They're almost spent.
I wanna say somethin'.
I've known since the train
that we weren't liable
to find him.
It was just a hair of a chance
that we got Sam back.
I knew that--
Maybe I knew even before
we left home,
but somehow
I just had to try!
And if we don't try,
we don't do.
And if we don't do,
why are we here
on this earth?
I--
I hope
you all understood.
We understood ya, Pa.
We're all with ya.
Now, tomorrow morning
we'll start back.
Pa?
I'll admit to you that I don't
feel the same way I did before.
I'll admit that
I'd sure like to get home.
But I don't want you giving up
because of us.
I'm with ya.
I don't wanna go home
unless you really want to.
Thank you, son.
We'll go home.
Maybe the boy is there.
[ Hoofbeats ]
Hold your fire, men!
Hold your fire!
Dead!
How old are you?
How old?
Sixteen.
Six-- Sixteen.
I'm not gonna kill you.
I want you to live!
I want you to live
to be an old man.
And I want you to have
many... many, many children.
And I want you to feel
about your children then...
the way I feel
about mine now!
And someday,
when a man comes along
and kills one of'em,
I want you to remember!
I want you to remember.
[ Sobbing ]
We'll bury him on the farm
near his mother.
[ Door Opens ]
Somebody sick, Tom?
Where have you been?
What's wrong?
The baby--
The baby's all right,
Charlie.
Uh,James and... Ann...
are dead.
[ Moans ]
We, uh... we figured
scavengers did it.
From what I could tell,
James died instantly.
It wasn't until two days later
I just happened to come by.
Ann had--
She was dead too.
I, I had them buried
near Martha.
I thought you'd like that.
It somehow seemed
the only place.
Where's the baby, Tom?
Upstairs. I found a woman
to take care of her.
She's all right, Charlie.
The child
is my granddaughter.
Her name is Martha.
It's been a long time, Martha,
since I held a baby.
It's been a long time.
[ Charlie ]
O Lord,
we cleared this land.
we plowed it
and sewed it...
and harvested.
We cooked the harvest.
We--
It wouldn't--
It wouldn't be here,
we wouldn't be eatin' it...
if we hadn't done it all
our--
all ourselves.
I don't even know
what to say to ya anymore,
Martha.
There's nothin' much
I can tell ya
about this war.
It's like all wars,
I suppose.
The undertakers
are winnin' it.
The politicians will talk
a lot about the glory of it.
And the old men will talk
about the need of it.
But... the soldiers,
they just want to go home.
I guess you're not
so lonely now, Martha,
with James and Ann...
and Jacob,
maybe the boy.
Y-You didn't know Ann,
did you?
Well, you'll like her.
You'll like her a lot,
Martha.
Why, she and James
are so much alike.
They're just like--
No.
No, we were never
that much alike,
were we, Martha?
We just sort of--
We just sort of grew alike
through the years.
But I wish--
I wish I could just know...
what you're thinkin'
about it all, Martha.
Then maybe things wouldn't
look so bad to me.
If I only knew
what you thought!
[ Church Bell Ringing ]
Ah, you...
you never give up, do ya?
[ Ringing ]
Thought you'd get away
with it, huh?
Why didn't one of you
tell me it was Sunday?
Come on. Get cleaned up.
We're late.
- You have somethin' to say?
- No, sir.
Well, then saddle your horses.
Get my carriage.
Kindred go
This mortal life also
The body they may kill
God's truth abideth still
His kingdom is forever
Amen
[ Baby Cries ]
For our second hymn--
[ Crying ]
For our second hymn,
we'll turn to page--
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Crying ]
How long, O Lord?
With God's help,
we'll turn to page...
1 3 7.
Shall we all rise and sing?
Praise God
from whom all blessings flow
Praise him
all creatures here below
Praise him above
ye heavenly host
Praise Father, Son
and Holy Ghost