♪♪ [Bugle Call]
These hills here are full of Apaches.
They've burnt every ranch building in sight.
He had a brush with 'em last night.
Says they're bein' stirred up by Geronimo.
Geronimo?
How do we know he isn't lying?
Ah, he's a Cheyenne.
They hate Apaches worse than we do.
- Clear the wires to Lordsburg.
- [Telegraph Receiver Clicking]
That's Lordsburg now, sir. They seem to have
something very urgent to tell you, sir.
- Well? Well, what's wrong?
- The line went dead, sir.
- What do you got there?
- Only the first word, sir.
"Geronimo."
[Man Shouts]
[Driver]
Whoa! Whoa! Steady, whoa!
- Well, so long, Buck!
- Nice trip, Buck?
- Oh, so-so.
- Got the payroll for the mining company?
- Yes, sir. Right here in this box here.
- Good. Give me a lift here, Jim, will ya?
Jim, I'll pay ya that two bits
when I come through.
- Okay, partner.
- Hey, now, you kids get away from that wheel.
Well, sir, we run into
a little snow up there.
'Tweren't bad, though, but you fellas
better prepare for a good frost.
Passenger out for Tonto.
You'd better get out and stretch your leg -
I mean, your limbs, ma'am.
We're gonna change horses here.
- Is there a place here where I can have a cup of tea?
- Well, yes, ma'am.
You can get a cup of coffee
at the hotel across the street there.
- Thank you, driver.
- Uh, you look a little peaked -
- I'll be all right, thank you.
- Yes, ma'am.
Why, Lucy Mallory.
Nancy.
- How are you, Captain Whitney?
- Fine, thanks, Mrs. Mallory.
Why, whatever are you doing
in Arizona?
I'm joining Richard in Lordsburg.
He's there with his troops.
He's a lot nearer than that, Mrs. Mallory.
He's been ordered to Dry Fork.
That's the next stop for the stagecoach.
You'll be with your husband in a few hours.
[Nancy]
Oh, I'm so glad to see you, Lucy.
Sit down, darling. We'll have a cup of coffee.
You must be tired from that long trip.
- Who is that gentleman?
- Hardly a gentleman, Mrs. Mallory.
I should think not.
He's a notorious gambler.
Hello, Mink! Hidee, Frank!
Well, Marshal, I'm looking for
my shotgun guard. Is he here?
Out with the posse, Buck,
trying to catch the Ringo Kid.
- Ringo? I thought Ringo was in the pen.
- He was.
Busted out?
Well, good for him.
My guess, the Kid's aimin' to get even
with them Plummer boys.
It was their testimony
sent him to the penitentiary.
Well, all I gotta say is that he'd better stay
away from that there Luke Plummer.
Why, gosh, Luke's run all of Ringo's friends
out of Lordsburg.
The last trip there, I seen him hit a rancher
on the head with the barrel of his gun...
and, well, he just laid it wide open
like a butchered steer.
- You seen Luke Plummer in Lordsburg?
- Yes, sirree.
Hmm.
You boys take care of the office
for a couple days.
I'm going to Lordsburg with Buck.
Gonna ride shotgun.
Oh, gosh, if I could learn
to keep my big mouth shut -
Here's the payroll, Mr. Gatewood.
Ever since I opened this bank,
I've been trying to tell those people...
to deposit their payroll
six months in advance.
It's good, sound business.
Good business for you, Mr. Gatewood.
Well, there's your receipt - $50,000.
And remember this - what's good for the banks
is good for the country.
[Man]
Now, now, now, my dear lady -
Good riddance to bad rubbish!
Get out and stay out!
I'm keeping your trunk
'cause you ain't paid your rent.
"Is this the face...
"that wrecked a thousand ships...
and burned the towerless tops
of Ilium?"
Farewell, fair Helen.
Doc. Doc, can they make me leave town
when I don't want to go? Do I have to go?
Dallas, don't you go makin' no fuss.
Do I have to go, Doc,
just because they say so?
Dallas, I've got my orders.
Don't blame these ladies. It ain't them.
It is them!
Doc, haven't I any right to live?
What have I done?
We're the victims of a foul disease
called social prejudice, my child.
These dear ladies of the Law and Order League
are scouring out the dregs of the town.
Come on.
Be a proud, glorified dreg like me.
- You get going, Doc. You're drunk.
- [Scoffs] Two of a kind.
- Just two of a kind.
- Take my arm, Madame la Comtesse.
The tumbril awaits!
To the guillotine!
Oh, wait till I get my badge, girls!
I'll join you!
[Clears Throat]
If ever you go East, brother...
come out to our house for dinner.
No one in all Kansas City, Kansas,
sets a better table than my dear wife, Violet.
- Jerry.
- Yeah, Doc.
Jerry, I'll admit,
as one man to another...
that, economically,
I haven't been of much value to you.
But...
suppose you could
put one on credit?
If talk was money, Doc,
you'd be the best customer I got.
I'm leaving town, Jerry.
- Honest?
- Yes, old friend.
And I thought you might,
out of memory of our many happy -
All right, Doc. Just this one.
Thank you, Jerry.
Here's a man
goin' on the stagecoach with you.
- He's an Easterner from Kansas City, Missouri.
- Kansas City, Kansas, brother.
To your health, Reverend.
[Clears Throat]
I'm not a clergyman.
My name is Peacock. I'm a -
[Jerry]
He's a whiskey drummer.
A what?
[Doc Sighs]
Well, well!
How are you, Mr. Haycock?
- Peacock.
- Don't tell me, sir.
I know, I know.
A familiar name and an honored name.
I never forget a face or a friend.
Samples? Hmm!
Ahh! Rye.
[Chuckles]
[Buck]
Well, Brownie!
- Blackie! Belle! Bess!
- Giddap!
Well, lookee here.
Got a pretty good team there.
Whoa! Back up.
Come on in.
Yeah. Back it up.
[Buck]
Got my favorite team there, Slim!
Yeah, Buck, they're all good and fresh.
They'll take you right there.
I want five dollars, Henry!
Certainly, my dear. Certainly.
What is it to be this time, my dear?
A pair of shoes -
I want to pay the butcher.
Dinner's at 12:00.
Don't worry, my dear.
I'll be there.
I've invited the ladies
of the Law and Order League.
All - [Clears Throat]
All aboard for Dry Fork...
Apache Wells, Lee's Ferry and Lordsburg!
- I'll take that, Dallas.
- Oh, thanks.
- In you go, Dallas, and a pleasant voyage.
- [Man Whistles]
Leave your baggage, Doc?
Thank you.
Thank you, my friend.
Curley, my shingle.
Carry it with honor.
- I'll take it, Doctor.
- Oh, no. No trouble at all.
No trouble at all.
I'll carry it on my lap.
Here we go.
Here we go, Reverend.
Mrs. Whitney, you're not going to
let your friend travel with that creature.
She's right, Lucy. And besides,
you're not well enough to travel.
It's only a few hours, Nancy.
I'm quite all right.
[Nancy] But you shouldn't
travel a step without a doctor.
There is a doctor, dear.
The driver told me.
Doctor? Doc Boone?
Why, he couldn't doctor a horse.
Lucy darling, you must be very careful.
Take good care of yourself.
- Watch that step now.
- [Buck] Lady folks ride facing forward, please.
There you go.
- Pleasant journey, Mrs. Mallory.
- Thank you. Good-bye!
- Good-bye!
- Bye! [Chuckling]
Like an angel in a jungle.
A very wild jungle.
What are you doin', Hatfield -
talkin' to yourself?
You wouldn't understand, cowboy.
You've never seen an angel...
nor a gentlewoman...
nor a great lady.
- I raise, gentlemen.
- [Chips Clatter]
Well, so long, Buck! So long, Curley!
Nice trip, boys!
- So long, kids!
- Wait a minute! Hold it there, Buck!
Cavalry comin'!
- [Dogs Barking]
- [Buck] Steady, girls!
Captain Sickels asks if you'll deliver
this dispatch in Lordsburg the moment you arrive.
- The telegraph line has been cut.
- Sure.
We're going with you
as far as the noon station at Dry Fork.
There'll be a troop of cavalry there,
and they'll take you on to Apache Wells.
From Apache Wells, you'll have
another escort of soldiers into Lordsburg.
But you must warn your passengers
that they travel at their own risk.
- At their own risk?
What's the trouble, Lieutenant?
- Geronimo.
- Geronimo? Well, then I ain't go -
- Will you sit down!
Of course, the army has no authority
over you gentlemen.
- If you think it's unsafe to make the trip -
- This stage is goin' to Lordsburg.
If you think it ain't safe
to ride along with us...
I figure we can get there
without you soldier boys.
I have my orders, sir,
and I always obey orders.
[Buck Whimpers]
Did you all hear
what the lieutenant said?
Yes, we heard.
Well, me and Buck are taking
this coach through, passengers or not.
Whoever wants to get out can get out.
- It's -
- Courage. Courage, Reverend.
- Ladies first.
- Oh. Excuse me.
How about you, Dallas?
What are you tryin' to do,
scare somebody?
They got me in here.
Now let 'em try to put me out.
There are worse things than Apaches.
If you'll take my advice, ma'am,
you won't take this trip.
My husband is with his troops in Dry Fork.
If he's in danger, I want to be with him.
[Clears Throat] You see, brother,
I have a wife and five children in Kansas City.
Then you're a man. By all the powers
that be, Reverend, you're a man.
- All right, folks.
- [Hatfield] Marshal!
Make room for one more.
I'm offering my protection to this lady.
I can shoot fairly straight,
if there's need for it.
That's been proved too many times, Hatfield.
All right, get in. We're late.
- May I trouble you to move over, sir?
- Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
[Curley]
Close the door.
- Aw, Curley, we shouldn't -
- Get going, Buck!
Bessie! Brownie! Bill!
- [Doc] Farewell, ladies!
- [Screams]
- [Buck] Sweetheart! Come on now, girl!
- Good-bye!
[Buck]
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
- Room for another passenger?
- Sure is, Mr. Gatewood.
- Goin' to Lordsburg?
- That's right. Just got a telegram.
Had to stop to pack this bag.
Oh, I got it in.
[Buck]
Hyah, hyah! Sassy! Blackie! Brownie! Bill!
Yow!
All right, Brownie.
Queenie, steady, girl.
Good boy. Get along.
If there's anything I don't like,
it's drivin' a stagecoach through Apache country.
Funny catching Gatewood
outside of town that way.
I just took this job 10 years ago
so I could make enough money...
to marry my Mexican girl, Julietta,
and I been workin' hard at it ever since.
Bonnie, get over there! Ho!
- Marriage?
- Well, certainly.
My wife's got more relatives
than anyone you ever did see.
I bet I'm feedin'
half the state of Chihuahua.
Sweetheart! Ho!
That seem funny to you about Gatewood?
Yeah, and then what do I get to eat
when I get home in Lordsburg?
Nothin' but frijole beans. That's all.
Nothin' but beans, beans, beans.
Bessie! Brownie! Blackie girl!
Yow! Get along!
Excuse me, ladies.
[Chuckling]
Close quarters.
[Sighs] Warm today.
Your wife made it warm for me, Gatewood.
She was chairman
of our farewell committee.
[Clears Throat]
Fine-looking bunch
of soldier boys back there.
Always gives me great pride
in my country...
when I see such fine young men
in the U.S. Army.
Anybody know where they're going?
Brother, aren't you aware of what's happened?
Happened?
I - I don't follow you, Reverend.
I'm not a clergyman. I'm a -
My friend's a whiskey drummer.
We're all gonna be scalped, Gatewood.
Massacred in one fell swoop.
- That's why the soldiers are with us.
- He's joking, of course.
Oh, no, he's not.
Oh, dear, no. I wish he were.
It's that old Apache butcher, Geronimo.
Geronimo - nice name for a butcher.
He's jumped the reservation.
He's on the warpath.
Geronimo? Why weren't the passengers notified?
Why wasn't I told?
- We -
- We were told, Gatewood.
Yes.
Weren't you told when you got
that message from Lordsburg?
[Clears Throat]
Oh, yes, yes. Y-Yes, of course. I - I forgot.
Steady now! String out! Sweetheart!
Now, doggone it,
they're bringing up her grandfather...
all the way from Mexico
to live with us.
I can't figure out
how he got that message.
- Who? Her grandfather?
- No, Gatewood.
Sweetheart!
- Said he got a message.
- Sweetheart!
- Telegraph line ain't workin'.
- Sweetheart.
[Gunshot]
[Horses Whinnying]
Hold it!
[Buck]
Whoa! Steady! Ho. Ho.
- Hey, look, it's Ringo.
- Yeah.
Hello, Kid.
Hello, Curley.
Hiya, Buck! How's your folks?
Oh, just fine, Ringo.
- Except my grandfather came up -
- Shut up.
Didn't expect to see you ridin' shotgun
on this run, Marshal.
- Goin' to Lordsburg?
- I figured you'd be there by this time.
No. Lame horse.
Well, it looks like
you've got another passenger.
Yeah. I'll take the Winchester.
You may need me
and this Winchester, Curley.
Saw a ranch house burnin' last night.
You don't understand, Kid.
You're under arrest.
- Curley -
- [Horse Whinnies]
- Everything all right, Marshal?
- Everything's all right, Lieutenant.
- Hope I ain't crowdin' you folks none.
- The more, the merrier.
Bonnie! Brownie! Blackie! Hyah!
Hyah, Bessie!
Ain't Ringo a fine boy?
I think so.
You're just smarter than a trade rat.
You knew all the time he was goin' to Lordsburg.
Hey, reckon what he meant
he saw ranch houses burnin'?
- Apaches.
- Oh, Apaches.
So, you're the notorious Ringo Kid.
My friends just call me Ringo.
Nickname I had as a kid.
Right name's Henry.
[Doc]
Seems to me I knew your family, Henry.
Didn't I fix your arm once
when you were, oh - bucked off a horse?
- Are you Doc Boone?
- I certainly am.
Now, let's see.
I'd just been honorably discharged
from the Union army...
after the War of the Rebellion.
You mean
the War for the Southern Confederacy, sir.
I mean nothing of the kind, sir.
That was my kid brother broke his arm.
You did a good job, Doc,
even if you was drunk.
Thank you, son.
- Professional compliments are always pleasing.
- Yes, they are.
What happened to that boy
whose arm I fixed?
He was murdered.
Put out that cigar.
You're annoying this lady.
Excuse me, madam.
Being so partial to the weed myself...
I sometimes forget
that it disagrees with others.
A gentleman doesn't smoke
in the presence of a lady.
Three weeks ago, I took a bullet out of a man
who was shot by a gentleman.
The bullet was in his back.
- Do you mean to insinuate -
- Sit down, mister.
Doc don't mean no harm.
- Hiya, Pete! Hi, Joey!
- Hello!
[Buck]
Be careful of old Bessie up there now.
Take it easy.
Hold it steady, girl.
[Soldier]
Prepare to dismount!
[Buck] Take a look and see if there isn't
a stone bruisin' that hock down there.
If it isn't my old friend,
Sergeant Billy Pickett!
- Well! How are ya, Billy?
- He's fine, Doc, and mighty glad to see ya!
Great heavens to Betsy! Didn't figure
on no stagecoach comin' through...
with them Apaches raisin' Cain.
I was just telling Billy to hitch up the buckboard
so we could get the young ones in -
Wait a minute! You mean to say
there are no troops at this station?
[Mrs. Pickett]
Ain't no soldiers here but what you see.
But my husband, Captain Mallory -
I was told he was here.
He was, dearie. Got orders night afore last
to join the soldiers at Apache Wells.
- [Buck] That means we gotta go back.
- [Gatewood] I can't go back!
Driver, you started this coach for Lordsburg,
and it's your duty to get us there.
And it's your duty, young man,
to come along with us!
It's my duty, Mr. Gatewood, to obey orders.
I'm sorry, sir.
Well, if the soldiers go back, Lieutenant,
that means we all have to go back?
My orders are to return from here immediately,
and I can't disobey those orders.
I think we can
get through all right, Curley.
Oh, now, don't egg him on, Kid.
I'm drivin' this here outfit,
and, well, if the soldiers go back, so am I.
I call this a desertion of duty.
I'll report you to your superior officer.
If necessary,
I'll take the matter up with Washington!
That's your privilege, sir,
but if you give us any trouble here...
I'll have to put you under restraint.
Now, don't lose your temper.
Don't lose your temper.
I'll tell you how we'll settle it. We'll take a vote.
Inside, everybody. Come on, Buck.
Oh, Curley, I don't wanna go to -
Now you girls set yourselves down.
I'll get you something to eat.
Now, folks, if we push on,
we can be in Apache Wells by sundown.
Soldiers there will give us an escort
as far as the ferry.
Then it's only a hoot and a holler
into Lordsburg.
- Well, that old mare, I don't -
- We've got four men can handle firearms.
Five with you, Ringo.
Doc can shoot, if sober.
I can shoot?
Now, Miss Mallory, I - I ain't gonna put
a lady in danger without she votes for it.
I've traveled all the way here
from Virginia.
I'm determined to get to my husband.
I won't be separated any longer.
- What's your vote, mister?
- [Clears Throat] Well -
Where's your manners, Curley?
Ain't you gonna ask the other lady first?
Well, what do you say?
What difference does it make?
Doesn't matter.
I vote that we go on. I demand it.
I'm standing on my legal rights.
What do you say, Hatfield?
Lordsburg.
Four. You, Doc?
I'm not only a philosopher, sir.
I'm a fatalist.
Somewhere, sometime, there may be
the right bullet or the wrong bottle...
waiting for Josiah Boone.
- Why worry when or where?
- [Curley] Yes or no?
Having that philosophy, sir,
I've always courted danger.
During the late war, when I had
the honor to serve the Union...
under our great president,
Abraham Lincoln...
ah, and General Phil Sheridan...
well, sir, I fought 'midst
shot and shell and cannon roar!
- Do you want to go back or not?
- No!
I want another drink.
[Laughing]
That's five.
How about you, Mr. Hancock?
It's Peacock. [Clears Throat]
I'd like to go on, brother.
I want to reach the bosom of my dear family
in Kansas City, Kansas, as quickly as possible...
but I may never reach that bosom
if we go on.
So, under the circumstances -
You understand, brother -
I think it best we go back with the bosoms -
[Stammers] I mean, the soldiers.
One against. Well, Buck?
- I want -
- Buck says aye. That's six.
I'm voting your proxy, Kid.
You go with me.
Ain't nothin' keeping me
out of Lordsburg, Curley.
There sure ain't.
Well, folks, that settles it.
We're going through.
Sit down, folks, and eat your grub.
Come on, Buck. We'll change them horses.
- But, Curley, ain't we gonna eat? Ohh!
- You can eat later!
Here you are, folks.
Food's on the table. Help yourselves.
You got a long ride ahead of ya.
You ain't drinkin', Billy.
Sit down here, ma'am.
Thanks.
May I find you another place, Mrs. Mallory?
It's cooler by the window.
Thank you.
Looks like I got the plague, don't it?
No. No, it's not you.
Well, I guess you can't break out of prison
and into society in the same week.
Please! Please.
You're ill, Mrs. Mallory.
No, it's just that I -
I'll be all right.
You've been very kind. Why?
In the world I live in,
one doesn't often meet a lady, Mrs. Mallory.
Have you ever been in Virginia?
I was in your father's regiment.
I should remember your name.
You're Mr. Hatfield.
That's what I'm called, yes.
- Why do you look at me like that?
- I'm just tryin' to remember.
Ain't I seen you someplace before, ma'am?
- No. No, you haven't.
- Hmm.
- I wish I had though.
- [Chuckles]
I know you.
I mean, I know who you are.
I guess everybody in the territory does.
Yep.
Well, I used to be a good cowhand, but...
things happened.
Yeah, that's it.
Things happened.
And now they'll take you back to prison.
Not till I finish a job in Lordsburg.
But you can't.
You're going there as a prisoner.
All aboard for Apache Wells, Lee's Fer -
All righty, folks, the horses are changed.
We'd better get going.
- And Lordsburg, maybe.
- All right, get going, Ringo.
Mrs. Pickett, tell Billy the buckboard
is all ready. Let's get going.
[Mrs. Pickett]
All right, Marshal, we're ready.
- Come on, folks, let's move.
- [Lieutenant] My compliments to your husband.
Thank you.
[Peacock] I still feel that we
ought to go back with the soldiers.
[Curley] We've got to hurry
if we wanna be there by sundown.
- [All Chattering]
- ♪♪ [Doc Singing]
Bridesmaid! Baby! Yow!
- What'd you say?
- Nothin'.
Well, why don't ya say somethin'?
A fella gets nervous, sittin' here like a dummy,
nothin' to think about but the Indians.
You say something! You've been sitting there
all day talking without making any sense!
All right, I'll say somethin' that makes sense.
If I was you, I'd let 'em shoot it out.
- Let who?
- Luke Plummer and the Kid.
There'd be a lot more peace
in this territory...
if that Luke Plummer was so full of lead
he couldn't hold his liquor.
I ain't sayin' I don't share
your sentiments, Buck.
- But you're a born fool.
- Well, I know that.
In the first place,
Luke would kill the Kid in a gunfight.
In the second place, if Luke did get shot,
he's got two brothers just as ornery as he is.
Nah, the only safe place for Ringo is in the pen,
and I aim to get him there all in one piece!
Well, I'll be doggoned
if I didn't do you an injury, Curley.
- I figured you were after the reward.
- Reward?
Why, the Kid's old man and me was friends.
We used to punch cattle together.
Besides, I could use that 500 in gold.
- Bridesmaid!
- Uh-uh! Steady!
Steady, girl!
Bridesmaid! In line!
I can't get over the impertinence
of that young lieutenant.
I'll make it warm for that shavetail!
I'll report him to Washington!
We pay taxes to the government,
and what do we get?
- Not even protection from the army.
- No.
I don't know what the government
is coming to.
Instead of protecting businessmen,
it pokes its nose into business.
Hmph!
Why, they're even talking now
about having bank examiners.
As if we bankers
don't know how to run our own banks!
Why, Boone, I actually had a letter
from a popinjay official...
saying they were going
to inspect my books!
I have a slogan that should be blazoned
on every newspaper in the country -
America for Americans!
The government
must not interfere with business!
Reduce taxes!
Our national debt is something shocking!
Over $1 billion a year!
What this country needs
is a businessman for president!
is more fuddle.
- What?
- Fuddle!
You're drunk, sir!
I'm happy, Gatewood.
Boo!
How come you're taking this road?
It's gonna be cold up there.
I'm usin' my head.
Those breech-clad Apaches don't like snow.
Maybe you'd like to -
to sit next to me.
I - You could put your head
on my shoulder.
No, thank you.
How are you feeling, Mrs. Mallory?
Is there any water?
Driver! Canteen, please!
Just a minute, Mrs. Mallory.
Haven't I seen this crest before?
Isn't this from Greenfield Manor?
I wouldn't know, Mrs. Mallory. I -
I won this cup on a wager.
- Oh.
- How about the other lady?
Thanks.
Sorry. No silver cups.
This is fine.
No.
[Wind Whistling, Blowing]
Please, Doctor.
Yow, girls!
[Men Speaking Spanish]
[Spanish Continues]
[All Shouting]
Whoa, steady. Ho.
Howdy, Chris. Seven hours from Dry Fork.
Pretty fast drivin', amigo!
Get the folks a bite to eat, Chris, while we
change horses. We're pushing on to Lordsburg.
You come without soldiers?
Oh, we weren't a-scared.
We didn't see one Apache, did we, Curley?
- Where's the cavalry, Chris?
- Uh-huh. Where's the soldiers?
There ain't no soldiers.
- Huh?
- Soldiers have gone.
Where's Captain Mallory?
Where's my husband?
Where is he?
You're his wife, I think?
Yes. Where is he?
Did he go with his men?
Si, señora.
Little what you call it -
scrimmage with the Apaches last night.
Soldiers take Captain Mallory to Lordsburg.
I think he get hurt maybe.
Badly?
Si, señora.
I think so.
Mrs. Mallory, I'm awfully sorry.
If there's anything I can -
I'm quite all right, thank you.
Marshal! Come here! Quickly!
Come on, Doc.
Let's go, Doc.
- [Peacock] Poor woman.
- [Gatewood] A sick woman on our hands!
- That's all we needed!
- [Buck] I feel kinda sick myself.
We're in a fine fix, my friends.
It's a fine country we're living in.
The army has no right to leave
a public place like this undefended.
Looks to me like the army's
got its hands pretty full, mister.
- Have you a wife?
- Si, señora, I think.
- Call her.
- Yakima! ¿Dónde estás?
Ringo, go in the kitchen and get some
hot water, lots of hot water, please.
Yes, ma'am. Hey, Chris!
¿Dónde la cocina?
[Chris]
Aqui está, Kid.
A fine member
of the medical profession.
Drunken beast.
Coffee.
Give me coffee.
Black coffee.
Lots of it.
- More! More! More!
- Ain't it enough, Doc? That's four.
- Blacker! Stronger! Keep it comin', Curley!
- You'll have it coming out your ears in a minute.
Drink it down, Doc. Go on.
Drink it down.
- Get it down.
- That'll make you feel better.
All right, Doc.
Isn't that drunken swine sober yet?
- He's doing the best he can!
- Well, hurry!
- Shh! Está malo.
- [Curley] Tinhorn.
- How you feeling?
- [Exhales] Fine.
[Gasps]
Thanks. Again.
Sit down here, Doc.
Keep the fire going, Chris.
- Plenty of hot water.
- Si, señor. Si.
Savages!
[Chuckles]
That's my wife, Yakima. My squaw.
Yes, but she's - she's savage!
Si, señor.
She a little bit savage, I think.
Ándale pronto. A calentar agua.
A la enferma, pronto.
Something funny about this.
That woman's an Apache.
Sure, she's one of
Geronimo's people, I think.
Maybe not so bad to have Apache wife, eh?
Apache don't bother me, I think.
- All right, Doc?
- All right.
[Sighs]
All right, Dallas.
♪♪ [Guitar, Slow Tempo]
[Woman]
♪ Al pensar en ti ♪
♪ Tierra en que naci ♪
♪ Qué nostalgia siente ♪
♪ Mi corazón ♪
♪ En mi soledad ♪
♪ Con este cantar♪
♪ Siento alivio y consuelo
en mi dolor♪
Ahora, muchachos. Váyanse.
♪ Las notas tristes de esta canción ♪
♪ Me traen recuerdos de aquel ♪
♪ Amor♪
♪ Al pensar en él ♪
♪ Vuelve a renacer♪
♪ La alegria en mi triste ♪
♪ Corazón ♪♪
[Horses Galloping Away]
Ringo!
[Whooping, Yelling In Spanish]
It's them vaqueros!
They've run away!
Yeah, with the spare horses.
[Howling]
[Baby Crying]
- [Howling Continues]
- [Crying Continues]
Them coyotes give me the creeps.
It sounds li -
Well, it sounds just like a baby.
Black eight.
[Cooing]
- It's a baby.
- [Curley Chuckles]
It's a little girl.
[Buck]
Well, I'll be doggoned.
Why didn't somebody tell me?
How's Mrs. Mallory?
She's going to be all right.
Well, I'll be doggoned.
- Did-Did you know?
- Why -
Well, I'll be doggoned.
- [Babbling]
- Don't do that.
Dr. Boone.
Come on, boys.
Three cheers for ol' Doc Boone.
- Hip, hip -
- Quiet.
- Well, we oughta be -
Mrs. Mallory.
[Curley]
Oh.
[Exhales]
Kid, I know why you want
to go to Lordsburg.
I like you. I know your pop.
He was good friend of mine.
If you know who in Lordsburg,
you stay away, I think.
You mean Luke Plummer?
Luke, Ike and Hank - all there together.
I saw them.
- Are you sure of that, Chris?
- Sure. I can tell you the truth.
- I know.
- Thanks.
- That's all I wanted to know.
- You crazy if you go.
I think you stay away, Kid.
Three against one is no good.
You oughtn't to go too far, Miss Dallas.
Apaches like to sneak up
and pick off strays.
You, uh, visitin' in Lordsburg?
No. No, I have friends there.
And maybe I can find work.
Say, look, Kid,
why don't you try to escape?
- Why don't you get away?
- I aim to - in Lordsburg.
Why Lordsburg?
Why don't you make for the border now?
My father and brother were shot down
by the Plummer boys.
Guess you don't know how it feels
to lose your own folks that way.
I lost mine when I was a kid.
There was a massacre
on Superstition Mountain.
That's tough, especially on a girl.
Well, you gotta live
no matter what happens.
Yeah. That's it.
Look, Miss Dallas, you got no folks.
And neither have I, and, well...
maybe I'm taking a lot for granted, but -
I watched you with that baby...
that other woman's baby.
You looked, well -
Well, I still got a ranch across the border.
And it's a nice place, a real nice place.
Trees and grass, water.
There's a cabin half built.
A man could live there...
and a woman.
Will you go?
But you don't know me.
You don't know who I am.
I know all I want to know.
Will you go?
[Crying]
Oh, don't talk like that.
[Curley]
What are you doing out here, Kid?
Stick close to the reservation.
[Chris]
Curley! Oh, Curley!
Oh! Curley! Curley!
- What's wrong, Chris?
- My wife, Yakima - she run away.
- When I wake up, she was gone.
- The way you come busting in here, you'd think -
- Whoa.
- Excuse me, Kid.
Come busting in here,
you'd think we were being attacked.
- You can find another wife.
- Sure I can find another wife.
But she take my rifle and my horse.
Oh, I never sell her.
I love her so much.
I beat her with the whip,
and she never get tired.
- Your wife?
- No. My horse.
Oh.
I can find another wife easy, yes,
but not a horse like that.
Mala Yakima.
I knew that woman was a thief, by -
What's the matter with you, Gatewood?
My valise! Where's my valise?
Which one of you have got it?
Here it is. I was usin' it for a pillow.
I didn't think you'd mind.
I thought I told you
to keep your hands off my things!
Yes, sir.
That squaw of yours will find some Apaches
and bring 'em back here.
My wife's people don't bother me, I think.
Well, they bother me, I think.
Chris, is this bar open?
Sure, all the time, señor. Si.
Good.
Here you are, Doc.
Well, what are we wasting time for?
Let's make a break for it.
- We've got a sick woman to think of.
- Do you want her to stay here
and be butchered with the rest of us?
- Why don't you think of somebody else for once?
- Do you realize who you're talking to?
Easy, easy! Quiet, boys. Quiet.
We ain't been butchered yet.
But you're right.
We'd better get going for Lordsburg
as soon as we can.
Might be a good idea, Curley, if, uh,
Doc took a look at the patient.
Yeah, and Little Coyote.
You'll join me, Doctor?
[Clears Throat]
No, thanks.
Morning.
Well, you're looking pretty chipper.
Hmm. You're up early, Dallas.
She didn't go to bed, Doctor.
I'm afraid she sat up all night
while I slept.
Oh, I slept a lot in the chair.
Well, anyway, it was nice to stay awake
and hold the baby.
Hmm. Well, we've got to get you
to Lordsburg, Little Coyote.
That's what the boys christened her last night
when she squalled - Little Coyote.
- How do you feel?
- Fine, thanks. A little tired.
- Doctor, do you think my husband -
- Never mind him.
The best medicine he can have
is to see you two safe and sound.
You just make up your mind
you're gonna get there.
- I have made up my mind.
- That's the stuff.
- I am going to get there.
- You need strength, so get all the rest you can.
Dallas, do you suppose
you can fix up a little broth?
- She has already.
- Good.
How about making some coffee
for the boys?
Now you get some sleep, Mrs. Mallory.
And don't look so proud.
I've brought hundreds
of those little fellas into the world...
once upon a time.
And the new one
was always the prettiest.
Doc.
Ringo asked me to marry him.
Is that wrong for a girl like me?
If a man and woman love each other,
it's all right, ain't it, Doc?
You're going to be hurt, child.
Worse than you've ever been hurt.
Don't you know that boy's
headed back for prison?
Besides, if you two
go into Lordsburg together...
he's going to know all about you.
He's not goin' into Lordsburg.
All I want is for you
to tell me it's all right.
Gosh, child, who am I to tell you
what's right or wrong?
All right. Go ahead.
Do it if you can.
Good luck.
Thanks, Doc.
- Ringo -
- [Curley] Well, Doc?
Oh, both doing nicely.
She's a real soldier's wife,
that young lady.
Good, good.
Then we can leave immediately.
Well, not for a day or so
if you want my professional advice.
What do you mean a day?
Stay another day? Why?
Where were you when the stork
came last night, Gatewood?
I refuse to allow Mrs. Mallory to travel
until she and the child are out of danger.
What do you mean danger?
Aren't we in worse danger here?
[Clears Throat]
I don't wish to intrude.
But I've had five children.
I mean, my dear wife has.
And much as I dislike discussing it,
in this hour of our trial...
I - I believe the doctor's right.
Spoken like a man, Reverend.
I say we ought to leave here before the
Apaches find us. That's common sense.
I wish you were 10 years younger,
Gatewood.
- Don't let my white hairs stop you -
- Now just a minute!
- [Both Shouting]
- Quiet! Quiet!
- Now, Curley, I haven't said a word!
- Will you shut up!
Now, if we argue this thing out right,
we can get somewhere.
Let's all sit down and talk sensible.
Come on, Buck. Sit down.
There's a young woman in the kitchen
making coffee.
She needs help.
Thanks, Doc.
Say, Kid.
How old were you
when you went to the pen?
Oh, I was... goin' on 17.
[Grinding]
Mornin', ma'am.
Morning.
I, uh, laid awake most of the night...
wondering what you'd have said
if Curley hadn't busted in.
Guess you was up kind of late too.
I could hear you moving around.
You didn't answer
what I asked you last night.
Look, Kid, why don't you try to escape?
There's a horse out there in the corral.
Curley won't go after you because he can't
leave the passengers in a fix like this.
I gotta go to Lordsburg.
Why don't you go to my ranch
and wait for me?
Wait for a dead man.
You haven't got a chance.
It was three against one when the Plummers swore
that you killed their foreman, got you sent up.
It'll be three against one in Lordsburg.
Well, there's some things a man
just can't run away from.
How can you talk about your life and my life
when you're throwing them away?
Yeah. Mine too.
That's what you're throwing away
if you go to Lordsburg.
What do you want me to do?
Would it make us any happier
if Luke Plummer was dead?
One of his brothers
would be after you with a gun.
We'd never be safe.
I don't want that kind of life, Ringo.
Well, I don't see what else I can do.
Go now. Get away.
Forget Lordsburg. Forget the Plummers.
Make for the border, and I'll come to you.
- Do you mean that?
- Yes, I do.
Will you go with me, Dallas?
Oh, I can't leave Mrs. Mallory
and the baby.
I'll come to you from Lordsburg.
I swear it.
Well, I oughta have a rifle and -
I've got one. Right here.
- I got it last night when they were all asleep.
- You mean you thought of this last night?
Yeah. Don't ask any more questions.
Not now.
Aw, gosh, Curley,
there ain't no Apaches behind us.
We can still go back to Tonto.
- No! I insist we go on to Lordsburg.
- What do you think, Chris?
Geronimo between here and Lordsburg -
with my horse, I think.
- [Chuckles] ♪ My horse has gone ♪
- No, Doctor. Oh! [Mutters In Spanish]
♪ She has gone astray with the sun - ♪♪
Quiet, Doc.
This is a serious matter, ain't it?
My dear Buck...
if I have only one hour to live,
I'm going to enjoy myself.
Doctor, I don't begrudge you my samples,
but I think -
Now you hush! I've stood enough of you.
Now this is a serious problem,
and I'm the only one that's talkin' sense.
- Now, Curley, if -
- If we can get across that ferry,
we'll be all right.
Question is, what are we gonna do
about the lady and her baby?
Dr. Boone has settled that for us, sir...
and I demand respect
for his professional opinion.
Hatfield.
Ringo.
Ringo!
Hurry, Ringo.
- [Curley] Ringo!
- Hurry!
- Bye, Dallas.
- Good-bye!
Ringo! Don't stop! Go on! Go on!
[Dallas]
Keep riding!
Ringo, go on! Go on!
Curley! No! Let him go! Stop it!
You don't need them, Curley.
- I ain't gonna run away.
- I'll say you ain't.
Look at them hills.
- Apaches.
- War signals.
[Gatewood] Hurry up, Marshal!
What's - Why don't we start?
[All Chattering]
[Buck]
Come on, Bridesmaid! Yow! Yow!
Nice girls! Yow! Go!
Hey, Curley, why don't you take
the cuffs off the Kid?
- He's mighty handy with a gun.
- You drive them horses.
- I'll take care of the Kid.
- Oh!
Can't you drive any faster?
You thick-headed lout!
We've got to make that ferry.
A man works all his life to get ahold
of some money so that he can enjoy life...
and has to run into a trap like this.
A trap, brother? You mean the Apaches?
There's been no sign of them.
You don't see any signs of them.
They strike like rattlesnakes.
If you hadn't insisted on waiting for her,
we'd have been across the ferry by this time.
You talk too much, Gatewood.
Your threats don't faze me, Hatfield.
You're nothing but a tinhorn gambler.
How would you like to get out and walk?
You can't put me out
of a public conveyance.
Now, now, gentlemen. Gentlemen.
Take it easy, Gatewood.
We may need that fight
before we get to the ferry.
You wouldn't be much good in a fight,
you jailbird!
[Hatfield]
Oh, leave the Kid alone. He's handcuffed.
[Peacock Clicks Tongue]
Gentlemen, please.
Let's not forget the ladies, bless them.
Let's have a little Christian charity
one for the other.
Well, folks, we're coming in
to Lee's Ferry now.
Lordsburg - next stop!
Nice girls! Get along! Get along!
Curley, look. Look at the ferry.
It's burnt too.
Hatfield, stand guard over there.
[Gatewood] Where's the army?
What are the soldiers doing?
- [Doc] Curley, what can I do?
- Are they going to let Geronimo
burn and pillage the whole country?
Ringo, I need you. Will you give me your word
you won't try to escape again?
I'll give you my word - till Lordsburg.
- Get in the coach with them women.
- I gave you my word.
- [Dallas] Ringo, don't!
- [Doc] Dallas.
Buck, drive into the river
up to the hubs.
Brownie! Bessie! Bridesmaid!
Come on, girls! Hah! Get down!
Move out! Ho!
Whoa, Duchess! Come on, baby!
Come on, girls. Steady now.
Look out, Curley.
Kid, take your suspenders
and cross-tie them wheelers.
Sorry about the saddle, Kid.
- [Curley] Ready, Kid?
- All set.
- Ready, Buck?
- All ready, Curley.
[Curley]
Here we go! Here we go, Buck!
[Ringo]
Hyah! Hyah!
Just sit quiet, folks.
You'll be all right.
[Buck]
Come on, girl. Ho, Bridesmaid!
Come on, baby! Good girl!
Ho! Steady, Duchess! Steady there!
Attagirl!
Honey child!
[Shouts]
[Buck]
Easy now. Ho!
Good girl. That's a girl!
Whoa!
[Curley]
Ho, girl! Take it!
♪ All aboard for Lordsburg, Lordsburg ♪
- Hey, Curley.
- Yeah. What?
You think I ought to charge
Mrs. Mallory's baby half fare?
- [Mutters]
- Sweetheart!
Well, we'll soon be in Lordsburg.
Uh, sorry I flew off the handle, Hatfield.
My apologies, Doctor.
No hard feelings, I hope.
[Clears Throat] All in all, it's been
an exciting, very interesting trip.
Has it not?
Well, now that the danger's passed, Mr. -
Peacock.
Ladies and gentlemen,
since it's most unlikely...
that we'll ever have the pleasure
of meeting again socially...
I'd like to propose a toast.
Major...
Gatewood...
Ringo.
- To your health.
- [Hatfield] Thank you, sir.
[Arrow Whooshes, Thuds]
[Gasping]
[Gunshot]
Giddap, girl!
Run them! Dry Lake! Ringo!
- Git, girls! Go!
- [Gunshots]
- [Buck Shouting]
- [Gunshots Continue]
- [Whooping, Shouting]
- [Gunshots]
[Buck]
Bridesmaid!
Bridesmaid! Yow!
- Yow! Ho!
- Hatfield!
Yow! Yow, girl!
Yow! Yow! Yow!
Giddap! Ho! Ho!
Hurry up, girls!
- I warned you about this - this danger!
But you wouldn't listen to me!
- [Gunshot]
Gatewood, will you shut up!
I've got a patient here!
No, you can't stop me.
Let me out of here, I tell you!
- Will you shut up!
- You sot! Take your -
[Gunshots Continue]
[Buck]
Yaah!
Yow! Yow! Yow! Yaah!
[Gunshots Continue]
Yow! Hyah! Yow! Yow!
Yow! Yow! Yow!
Yow! Yow! Yaah!
Hey, Kid!
Ringo! Help!
[Gunshots]
[Groans]
Kid! Kid!
The leaders, Kid!
Get the leaders!
[Gunshots Continue]
[Gunshot]
[Weakly]
Yow!
Yow! Yow!
[Trigger Clicks]
Curley! More ammunition!
[Gunshot]
[No Audible Dialogue]
- [Gunshot]
- [Hatfield Groans]
♪♪ [Bugle Blowing In Distance]
Do you hear it?
- ♪♪ [Continues]
- Do you hear it?
It's a bugle!
They're blowing the charge!
♪♪ [Continues]
If you see Judge Greenfield...
tell him his son -
♪♪ [Bugle]
♪♪ [Honky-tonk Piano]
[People Chattering]
[Horse Blusters]
♪♪ [Piano Continues In Distance]
- [Captain] Thank heaven you're safe, Lucy.
- Where's Richard? Is he all right?
Oh, he's all right.
Don't you worry.
- [Woman] It isn't a bad wound.
- We'll take you to him immediately.
Where's the baby, dear?
I'll take the baby.
Dallas.
If there's ever anything I can do for -
I know.
[Captain]
Orderly.
[Hoofbeats]
It's the Ringo Kid!
Yeah!
[Man]
Hey, Curley! How are you?
Aces and eights.
[Laughs]
Dead man's hand, Luke.
- [Old Man Stammering]
- Ringo Kid's in town.
Yeah. Drivin' the stage.
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
- Mis hermanos.
- Si, patrón. Un momento.
Cash in.
[Glass Clinks On Counter]
♪♪ [Piano Continues]
[Man]
Easy now. Easy. That's right.
Good-bye, Miss Dallas.
If you ever come to Kansas City, Kansas,
I want you to come out to see us.
- Oh, thanks, Mr., uh -
- Peacock.
- Hello, Buck.
- [Man] They got here all right.
- You got through all right.
- [Man] All right, folks, you're here.
All right, folks. You're all right. Unload.
Here you are, Doctor.
Will you sign this?
Well, Lordsburg.
[Express Agent]
Thank you. And you, Doctor.
There you are. Thank you.
Well, Kid.
Curley, how long will they give me
for breakin' out?
Oh, about another year.
- You know where my ranch is?
- Yeah.
Will you see that
she gets there all right?
Dallas.
Yeah.
This is no town for a girl like her.
Will you do it?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
How are ya, Marshal?
Get my man through all right?
I don't need them.
If you don't want to lose your prisoner, Sheriff,
you'd better take care of him yourself.
- What's your name, mister?
- My name is Gatewood. Ellsworth H. Gatewood.
Oh. Gatewood. You didn't think they'd have
the telegraph wires fixed, did you?
[Man]
You thought you escaped.
[All Shouting]
- [Crowd Laughing, Chattering]
- [Man, Laughing] We got our banker!
Can I meet you back here in 10 minutes?
I gave you my word, Curley.
I ain't goin' back on it now.
No ammunition.
I lied to you, Curley.
Got three left.
Come on.
Good night, Kid.
- Is this where you live?
- No.
I gotta know where you live, don't I?
No. Don't come any further.
It's all been a crazy dream.
I've been out of my mind just hopin'.
[Crying]
Say good-bye here, Kid.
We ain't never gonna say good-bye.
[Glasses Shatter]
[Footsteps]
Could I have that?
Give me the shotgun.
Shotgun!
Luke! Luke, please don't!
♪♪ [Honky-tonk Piano]
[People Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
♪♪ [Fiddle, Piano: Traditional]
Well, Kid, I -
I told you not to follow me.
Dallas.
I asked you to marry me, didn't I?
I'll never forget you asked me, Kid.
That's something.
Wait here.
- [Door Squeaks]
- [Crowd Gasps, Shouts]
Uh -
[Stammering]
Ringo said he'll be passing this way in...
six or seven minutes.
Come on.
I'll take that shotgun, Luke.
You'll take it in the belly
if you don't get out of my way.
I'll have you indicted for murder
if you step outside with that shotgun.
We'll attend to you later.
Don't ever let me do that again.
Luke.
Hey, Billy! Billy, kill that story about the Republican
convention in Chicago and take this down!
"The Ringo Kid was killed on Main Street
in Lordsburg tonight!
And among the additional dead was" -
Leave that blank for a spell.
- I didn't hear any shootin', Ed.
- You will, Billy. You will.
[Laughs]
Hank missed him - at four feet.
[Woman Exclaims]
[Hammer Cocks]
[Gunshots]
- [Women Screaming]
- [Gunfire Stops]
Ringo. Ringo.
[Gasping]
Ringo.
[Footsteps]
[Curley]
Ready, Kid?
Thanks, Curley.
Curley's gonna see that you
get to my place across the border.
Well, good-bye, Dallas.
Good-bye.
Maybe you'd like to ride a ways
with the Kid.
Please.
[Curley, Doc Shouting]
- Yea! Yea!
- Yea!
[Both Laughing]
[Doc Sighs]
Well, they're saved
from the blessings of civilization.
Yeah.
[Laughs]
Doc?
I'll, uh, buy you a drink.
- Just one.
- [Laughing]