[gunshot]
[running footsteps]
- [gunshot]
- [man groans]
[gunshot]
# [chatter]
# [guitar]
# From June until September #
# Hearts are innocent and gay #
# For a few brief
fleeting moments #
# Summer love
drives cares away #
# Summer love comes
oh so quickly #
# Summer love goes oh so fast #
# Summer love's
a lonely highway #
# For the broken hearts
that pass #
# Now summer love's
infatuation #
# In that carefree
time of year #
# But when autumn leaves
start fallin' #
# Summer love will disappear #
# Summer love
comes oh so quickly #
[woman groaning]
# Summer love goes
oh so fast #
[groaning]
# Summer love's
a lonely highway #
# For the broken hearts
that pass #
# There's one chance
in a hundred #
# If good fortune
smiles on you #
# That your summer love
will be true love #
# And will last
your whole life through #
# Summer love comes
oh so quickly #
# Summer love
goes oh so fast #
# But if fortune smiles
upon you #
# Then your summer love
will last #
[gunshots]
[scraping]
[burps]
[pouring liquid]
Two...
and a Mexican.
Huh?
A Mexican?
Let's go.
I'm not gonna hit
a blind man anyway.
What's this about anyway?
It's simple.
Each puts money down,
and then every one of us
takes a punch at him.
And then we do it again
in different order.
[knuckles crack]
The ones that I make out lose.
The others split the bank.
[punch]
[punches]
You have lost.
[men laugh]
Next time you want to play,
lose the bracelet.
We need to go.
I've got to get
my money back.
What's at stake?
[screams]
We go on.
- Giddap! Giddap!
- [neighing]
[laughter]
[toot]
[kisses]
[burps]
[hisses]
[laughing]
[men laughing]
[laughter continues]
[horse neighs]
No.
The sheriff is not here.
And the nearest town
is a week's ride away.
[laughing]
[laughter continues]
I can cash the bounty for you.
[punch]
[laughter]
You've lost your touch.
[coughs]
You need a woman.
Shit!
[burps]
You want to get
your bounty back?
We can play all night.
[burping, laughing]
Hit him now,
if you can do it.
You lost your bounty...
to a blind man.
To a handicapped veteran...
who lost his eyes
defending his country.
But...
if you want it back,
you'll have to take it
from a healthy man.
You wouldn't want
to shoot a lawman.
Would you?
[laughing]
[laughter continues]
$500.
You can buy
a new life for that.
How could she take
any pleasure with you?
Vodka...
doesn't accept
a straight line.
That's why those
drunk on vodka...
move with no coordination.
No balance.
They dance.
The ones drunk on whisky,
they're up, down,
hit the ground...
and don't get up.
She's sure friendly...
when she wants to be.
Ain't she?
No, sir.
Not a word.
[gulp]
Suppose I shoot you?
You wanna know
what it sounds like?
[chuckles]
[giggling]
Drop the gun.
[screams]
[gunshot]
[men screaming]
- [screaming]
- [gunshot]
[gunshot]
- I got him!
- [gunshot]
- [clicking]
[screams]
Fuck!
[screaming]
The drifter shot him!
He's run!
You were a tracker
in the war.
Yeah.
And I was... good.
Aren't you gonna
go after him?
You are the sheriff!
Ah.
And you got amped up
for the hanging.
The drifter's hit.
All we need is
to pick him up.
Nobody gets hanged
unless I say so.
Not without the law!
# [indistinct whispering]
You know where it is.
Blood money.
You want to play
a soldier again?
I'll be back.
He was taller than you!
I got him.
I never miss.
Did you see her eyes?
I'll put it back
where it belongs.
No gun has that range.
He's not gonna know
what hit him.
We're not going
pigeon hunting.
# [woman chanting]
There will be no hanging
without a trial.
Why would he
circle around?
Doesn't make sense.
He's going east.
Bad country.
We'll cut him off
at the pass.
[panting]
[whinnies]
Nothing.
There won't be any hanging.
This has his name on it.
[sniffs]
Could this be him?
You know what that means?
What?
Absolutely nothing.
But you did not know that.
What is it now?
Surrender, or I'm coming in!
[gunshots]
[laughing]
[shooting continues]
[shooting stops]
[glass shatters]
[horse whinnies]
He was here, all right.
You'll never catch him.
Have you ever wondered why he
doesn't cover up his tracks,
while I'm getting further and
further away from the town,
which I left un...
...protected?
[simmers]
[panting]
Anyway, he will never be
able to follow the tracks.
And...
I'm heading back.
[glass shatters]
It's the booze!
[horse neighs]
You've run out of booze!
That's why,
you drunken dumbshit!
That's enough!
# [female vocalizing]
[woman]
Call me wherever you want.
You can call me "Bitch"
or "Pussy."
"Baby."
"Honey."
"Love."
"Sweetheart."
"Sunshine."
Yeah.
You better call me
"Sunshine."
We met in the rain.
Please, like before.
[hammering]
[grunts]
[neighs]
Where are these
fucking tracks?
I want to...
to send a telegram.
[telegraph tapping]
[hammering]
[fly buzzing]
No bad habits?
No.
Just bad company.
[fly buzzing]
What's the matter?
I thought you got
some more meat last night.
I got no quarrel with him.
He drew us in.
He was a tall man,
wasn't he?
I'm gonna have to check
the thickness of his neck.
To make an adequate noose, I have to
take everything into consideration
If the rope is too thin,
it won't break his spine.
Not without the law.
Give me a smoke.
I thought that you don't smoke.
I do now.
[knock on door]
A telegram.
[man coughing]
[coughing]
[neighs]
It's the sheriff's horse.
How did it get here?
Where are the others?
Relish?
[coughs]
Would bread be all right?
Chaser?
We only have a porter.
You want it in a tall
or short glass?
Please.
Please!
[train whistle]
And you will
take off my clothes.
First, the skirt.
It will probably
get ripped.
Slightly.
It will take awhile before you
will take off all the rest.
And my breasts...
will be firm,
and my legs, strong.
You will kiss my nipples.
And my stomach will be hard.
And after...
After, we'll lay down
side by side,
and we'll be smoking
our cigarettes.
We will talk...
really quietly
to each other,
although we could very well
be speaking out loud...
in the bed.
[chuckles]
I will feel...
slightly uncomfortable.
And you will feel the taste
of my hair in your mouth.
There will be...
plenty of little pale scars
on my stomach.
You'll feel them
with your fingers.
I know... you'd like them
to be there.
You will kiss
each one of them...
once.
And I will be shy no more.
And later...
Later you will
stop being shy,
and I will be
kissing you.
And later...
Later the whole room
will smell of you.
Not of me, but of you.
You never loved me.
No!
I was never anything
but a barmaid.
[screaming]
[screaming continues]
You know what happens to an
eyeball when it gets punches?
Uhh!
I could hit you
in the nose.
The bone goes
right into the brain,
and you'd be dead.
Uhh!
[whinnies]
A perfect site
for an ambush.
We should go around.
There!
Wait!
Yaah!
[all yelling]
[gunshots]
[train whistle]
[distant hammering]
[hammering continues]
[spits]
[door closes]
She doesn't like you...
anyway.
[snoring]
[gunshots]
[ricochet]
I got him!
[groaning]
[train whistle]
[hammering continues]
I like what I see.
[whinnies]
I had a dream.
I dreamed that
I was a bad sheriff,
and that I was drunk.
That every one of my memories
starts with a drink...
and ends with a hangover.
I dreamed that
everyone I met...
laughed at my last
drinking binge,
my last fight.
That my woman didn't want
to have a child with a drunk...
got sick...
and died.
That I have no friends anymore,
that everyone has left me,
and that I am completely
alone in this place.
I dreamt that I wanted
to forget about my drinking
with all my strength.
That...
That I wanted to give up
all the people I drink with,
the saloon,
the memories.
I've dreamed that I could not
run away from them.
But it's only a dream,
wasn't it?
Talk back.
[whistles]
# [male chorus humming]
[neighing]
It was your baby.
I wrote you about it
many times,
but there was never a reply.
Later, I would only
write to you
to ask for money...
for the baby.
And there was just one letter
that came from you.
An army document.
It said you got
decorated and promoted.
Then I wrote no more letters.
I didn't want the baby anymore.
I went down to the stable...
with a stick.
I did it by myself.
It was laying down there.
There was this
little white dog
which came to me...
and started to whimper out loud.
It whimpered louder and louder
and wouldn't leave,
attracted by the smell of blood.
I heard someone coming,
so I grabbed the dog.
There will be no life
for me here
if they knew that
I've killed the baby.
When I left the stable
that evening...
I left two dead bodies behind.
I knew I would be not able
to have children ever again.
Hit me.
# [humming]
It takes a lot of time
to hang a man.
[grunts]
The rope... needs to be...
tested three times.
[grunting]
I use a sandbag that's
the same weight as he is.
[chuckles]
[choking]
My-- My leg.
If...
my leg...
m-my leg...
[groaning]
[horse snorts]
Shit!
[groaning]
We need to get him.
[neighs]
[groaning]
[muffled scream]
[sobbing]
# [chorus humming]
I received no letters.
I wore...
a uniform.
I looked good in gray.
I used to be the best scout.
Perhaps...
the best in this country.
He used to be...
the best scout.
Perhaps--
[coughs]
the best... in the country.
He was...
one of the finest men we had.
[coughing]
[neighs]
[strikes match]
[chuckling]
[laughing]
With you?
Never with a man like you.
[horse neighing]
[gagging]
Why can't you?
My story is short.
I like life stories,
and I like them short.
People should be able to tell a story
of their stupid, short life in short.
I hate men that
ponder around forever.
I'm different.
Come here.
Kneel down.
Think this is Paris?
Pig!
How was it with that scumbag?
I loved...
every minute of it!
Did he...
or didn't he?
[panting]
# From June until September #
# Hearts are innocent and gay #
# For a few brief
fleeting moments #
# Summer love
drives cares away #
# Summer love comes
oh so quickly #
# Summer love goes oh so fast #
# Summer love's
a lonely highway #
# For the broken hearts
that pass #
# Now summer love-- #
[woman screaming]
You don't know anything
about the battle.
[coughing]
Four slugs I took in the gut.
[coughs]
He wouldn't let me die.
[coughing]
Yes or no?
You remind me of my mother.
#
# I was born in the blast
of a furnace of steel #
# And I wondered
what shape I would be #
# I was hard, I was cold
I was just a day old #
# And I wondered
what future I'd see #
# Then a rough pair of hands
fashioned pieces of steel #
# And a handle of smooth
silky wood #
# And an arm held me out
while the eye of a man #
# Kept staring as hard
as he could #
# O whoa, whoa, whoa-whoa
whoa-whoa, whoa #
Good.
I've got something
that belongs to you.
[gunshot]
It's him.
I told you.
[gunshot]
[neighs]
# #
# I tried to call out
but my steel has no tongue #
# To men, I am only a slave #
# I've never forgotten
that terrible day #
# And that man
that I couldn't save #
# No one knows what it means
to be held in a hand #
# To be pointed
and triggered to kill #
# To be labeled a gun
with no power to stop #
# All the blood that
man's shooting will spill #
# O whoa, whoa, whoa-whoa
whoa-whoa, whoa #
# It's a pity a man cannot
live to the age #
# Of a mountain
the desert or sea #
# Only then would he learn
that to kill or be killed #
# Was something
that needed to be #
# Maybe someday, somehow
when all men will meet #
# They will bury their guns
in the ground #
# I hope that they bury me
deep, so deep #
# So deep that
I'll never be found #
# I'm a gun #
# Till the day
that man destroys me #
# I'm a gun #
# It's not the gun
that kills a man #
# It's the man who fires a gun
# It's not the gun
that kills a man #
# I'm a gun #
# A gun #
I don't want any trouble.
Get rid of your guns.
It's gonna be
all right.
Keep your hands up
and your fingers spread.
You'll have a fair trial.
Let's get out
of this place.
Together.
You know you won't get
away from here alive.
The city...
with the tall houses,
with the streetlamps.
[sobbing]
Where the people take walks
on the street in the evenings.
[sobbing]
Yeah. It could work.
Yeah!
[sobs]
It could work!
[Sheriff]
You are finished.
Give it up!
Promise!
I'm gonna count to three.
Hold this.
Hell no!
I ain't no deputy.
What's wrong with you?
Are you sick or what?
[no audible gunshots]
[audio fades in]
Don't touch me!
[gunshot]
Did you ever...
He took the wedding ring
off my hand before.
The tears I cried...
he thought it was the rain.
Simply a whore.
Not a profession.
A position.
[coughing]
Major.
[coughs]
Hard day?
Hard life.
[coughing]
[coughs]
[wheezing]
[grunts]
Could I fix you once more?
No, thanks.
I just had one.
Is there any
special way?
Oh, no.
Whatever you say.
And then?
And then...
we'll live in the...
big city.
Together forever.
# From June until September #
# Hearts are innocent and gay #
# For a few brief
fleeting moments #
# Summer love
drives cares away #
# Summer love comes
oh so quickly #
# Summer love goes oh so fast #
# Summer love's
a lonely highway #
# For the broken hearts
that pass #
# Now summer love's
infatuation #
# In that carefree
time of year #
# But when autumn leaves
start fallin' #
# Summer love will disappear #
# Summer love
comes oh so quickly #
# Summer love goes oh so fast #
# Summer love's
a lonely highway #
# For the broken hearts
that pass #
# There's one chance
in a hundred #
# If good fortune
smiles on you #
# That your summer love
will be true love #
# And will last
your whole life through #
# Summer love comes
oh so quickly #
# Summer love goes oh so fast #
# But if fortune smiles
upon you #
# Then your summer love
will last #
Subtitles by LeapinLar