Bullwhip, Bullwhip
Bullwhip Griffin
Let villains and ruffians beware
His path never swerved
and justice was served
When Bullwhip Griffin was there
[chirping]
[Galloping]
[Bell rings]
Speaking of
Californias legendary heroes
Whose praises have been
novelized and sung
Its time that we acclaim
A certain gentleman whose name
was once upon the tip of every tongue
Back in the gold rush days
in wicked San Francisco
He cut a figure dignified and prim
Although extremely frail
and physically doomed to fail
He had purity of heart
in back of him
Now, to begin our story
we must go to Boston
The scene
wherein our hero is employed
A home of quality
bespeaks of aristocracy
And comfort
that is soon to be destroyed
Here is a family friend
arriving in his carriage
His person we will presently portray
Attention, first, is due
the man in the doorway
Who will be a legend one day
Bullwhip, Bullwhip
[Pemberton] Good day, Griffin.
- Miss Arabella is expecting you, sir.
- Thank you.
I'll take your coat, sir.
Mr. Pemberton. So nice to see you.
Hello, my dear. Thank you.
You're looking very beautiful, as usual.
Thank you.
Griffin, are the others ready?
They're all in the library except
Master Jack. I'll bring him.
- He should be there, shouldn't he?
- By all means.
- Isn't it pleasant to have snow again?
- Very much...
Roll it about.
[Knock on door]
[Griffin] Master Jack?
Hey, Griffin. Come on in.
Pour off the water.
Try some soap and water in there
sometime if you really want results.
Soap? You don't need soap.
This is how you pan gold.
Pan gold?
It tells in there.
How to swirl it about...
...gradually pour off the water...
...until you get down to the nuggets.
Oh. Oh. Of course. Well...
[Griffin] "Bullwhip Brannigan.
Or a son of the mother lode."
Bullwhip took Tom Wingay with him
to the gold fields.
Tom was just my age and he wrestled
with a grizzly bear. Bullwhip did.
The bear got loose and ran away,
so Bullwhip really won!
Mmm. Well, it would be nice,
Master Jack,
if you would become better
acquainted with the classics
rather than wasting your time
upon such trivia.
Trivia? What do you mean, trivia?
It's educational.
How?
I bet you can't show me
in any of those books
where it tells how to pan gold,
or how to wrestle with a grizzly bear.
Hmm. Quite true. They do, however,
give an amazing insight
into the rather peculiar behavior
of growing boys.
Shall we be going?
The lawyer is waiting.
[Lawyer] "I, Alonzo J. Flagg,
being of sound mind,
do hereby declare this
to be my last will and testament.
And I bequeath to my coachman,
Harry Silwell... Silway..."
Sidwell, sir. Harry Sidwell.
Oh. [clears throat]
"Harry Sidwell,
fifty thousand dollars."
- [Gasps]
- Would you say that again, sir?
Fifty thousand dollars.
"To my cook
and breakfast table confidante,
Miss Abigail Gucken... kick?"
Abigail Guckennick.
Oh. Miss Abigail Guckennick.
"I bequeath $90,000."
Ninety thousand!?
"To my housekeeper of many years,
guardian of my health
and custodian of my morality,
Miss Irene Chesney,
I bequeath $100,000."
Oh... What an angel he was.
"To my butler, Eric Griffin,
who at a young age
promises to surpass his father
and his father's father
in doing the proper thing
in the proper way at the proper time,
I bequeath $500,000,
in profound confidence that he will not
so much as arch an eyebrow
when he learns of this bequest."
Half a million dollars?
What a kind, saintly man he was.
[Lawyer] "All the remainder of my estate
plus, specifically,
the family residence in Boston,
together with all of its furniture
and furnishings,
I bequeath to my two grandchildren,
my sole surviving heirs,
Arabella and Jack Flagg."
The document is duly signed,
and is quite legal, I assure you.
There never was a finer person born
than the old gentleman.
Rest his good soul.
[Sidwell] Amen to that!
So much for the will.
Now for the facts.
During the later years of his life,
Mr. Flagg lived not only
on borrowed time...
...but on borrowed money.
You mean, he died broke?
Dead broke.
[Sobbing]
Ornery old coot.
Probably thought it was funny.
[Sobbing]
Even the mortgage
on this house was past due,
long past due.
However, the bank has promised
not to foreclose for 90 days.
[Lawyer] I'm sorry, my dear.
[Sobbing] Think of poor Miss Arabella.
Not even a home to live in.
And a little brother to look out after.
And she's got no training.
Never had to go out and face the world.
What's she going to do?
Excuse me, miss.
Is there anything I can do?
[Laughs]
I'm sorry, Griffin. I know I shouldn't
be laughing, but I can't help it.
But, miss, this is a serious matter.
Don't you see?
Even writing out his will,
he had to have his own little joke.
Well, if that is what one considers it.
Well, Grandpa used to say
people are 98 percent water.
If you don't stir them up
once in a while, they stagnate.
The disturbing thing is, miss,
that he has left you and Master Jack
without any financial security.
Unprotected.
Well, I think that's what he wanted
most of all.
For us to be free
to make our own lives.
But Master Jack is only 12 years old.
Grandpa was only 11
when he ran off to sea.
What about you, miss?
It's different for a young lady.
I'm not afraid, Griffin.
There's a lot of Grandpa in me.
I'll think of something to do.
Lf, uh...
If there's anything you want...
- Griffin?
- Hmm?
What will you do? Get a job
somewhere else as a butler?
I suppose so, miss. I really had not
given the matter much thought.
Do you remember
your ninth birthday party?
You threw a serving tray
through the window
and said you wouldn't ever
be a butler when you grew up.
I remember, miss.
But I had rather hoped
that others had forgotten.
How could I forget that, Griffin?
You're the only boy I knew in Boston
who ever broke a window deliberately.
Thank you, miss.
And now, if, uh,
you will excuse me, I shall, uh...
...prepare the dinner menu.
[Sighs]
I don't know, Grandpa. I guess some
people just can't be stirred up, huh?
Miss Arabella! It's Master Jack.
Quickly. Where's Miss Arabella?
Miss Chesney! Now, really!
- I was just in Master Jack's room.
- What is it?
Master Jack. He's gone.
"Dear Arabella. I have set out
to seek my fortune
so you will not
have to take care of me.
When I am rich, I will come back
and take care of you.
Would you please
feed my goldfish? Jack."
- Goldfish, indeed.
- [Sobs]
No, not now, Miss Chesney. Go tell
Harry to get the carriage ready.
We have to find him and
bring him back before it's too late.
Look. I'm afraid he has succumbed
to the California gold fever.
[Arabella] Oh, no,
what are we going to do?
I think I know where I can find him.
With your permission,
I shall stop him
before he gets too far.
Yes, yes, Griffin. Please do.
Oh, uh, yes, miss.
Uh, right away, miss.
I have it, gentlemen. A ticket.
Gather round, gentlemen, up here.
A ticket for the sailing.
A ticket on the Lady Wilma
to San Francisco.
[Man] Step right in, gentlemen.
Now, this is an unclaimed ticket
that I am going to sell
to the highest bidder.
This is your ticket to fortune,
to the gold fields of California.
What am I offered?
Will some gentleman start this bidding,
say at $500?
- [Man] Five hundred.
- Thank you, sir, $500.
Remember. This is the last ticket
on the beautiful Lady Wilma,
sailing now for San Francisco.
I have five,
I'm looking for 550, anybody?
- [Man 2] I'll make it 550.
- Thank you. $550.
[Auction continues in background]
Stay where you are.
- [Jack] Are you trying to stowaway too?
- Stowaway? Oh, no, lad.
What I needs must shake the
murderous hounds pursuing me.
- Are the police after you?
- Shh!
[Man] Ah. Here, boy.
In with you. Come on. Give me that.
Who will make it 1200? 1200?
- 1200!
- Thank you, sir. 1200.
I have 1200. Who will make it 1250?
Oh, come on, gentlemen.
You can wash that much gold
out of your socks every night
- after you get to California.
- [Laughter]
All right, gentlemen, who will
make it 1250? Going once...
Going twice...
Are you all through, gentlemen?
You're gonna hate yourselves
in the morning.
Going...
...going...
...and gone!
- Yahoo!
[Crowd clamoring]
Oh, yes, sir. Right away.
You got a great wagon there, sir.
Put that in the envelope for you.
There you are.
- Oh, I beg your pardon, sir.
- Oh, pardon me.
- I am sorry.
- I'm sure it was my fault.
I'm so excited. I'm going
to California for the gold rush!
Good for you! Oh, my hat.
Well, I'm sorry I was...
But I... Well...
- Your ticket.
- Oh!
The ticket, it's gone.
But I just bought it.
Somebody stole my ticket.
[Shouting] I've been robbed!
Search everybody!
- You, sir. You were over there.
- Yes, I was.
He is absolutely right. He bought
a ticket. I was there. I saw him.
- You just keep out of this...
- I beg your pardon.
I, sir, am Judge Higgins
of the appellate court,
and I demand that you search
every single man along this...
Wouldn't do any good, though,
would it?
Everybody going aboard
is bound to have a ticket.
- Let us handle it, Your Honor.
- Yes, of course.
Step off the gang plank.
I say, you. Oh, I didn't get your name.
- Brown. Brown, sir.
- Mr. Brown.
Why don't you go over there
with the aid of these two officers
and carefully go through all your
pockets and see if you can't find it.
You were terribly excited.
It's not good to get that excited.
- Yes, sir. Thank you, Your Honor.
- Yes. It's quite all right.
- Ready?
- Yes, sir.
- [Man 1] Your ticket.
- [Man 2] Thank you.
You, sir. Are you
the captain of this ship?
Captain Swain.
If you've any business with me,
say your say
and be quick about it.
I have reason to believe
there is a 12-year-old boy
- stowed away aboard your ship.
- I have reasons to believe there isn't.
He is the grandson
of the late Alonzo Flagg of Boston.
Now, I want no part in no stowaway.
[Swain] Will you give me your word,
as a gentleman,
that you and him'll be ashore
before we sail.
Unquestionably.
All right.
I'll show you how to get below.
Thank you.
If the police aren't after you,
then who is?
I could a tale unfold whose lightest
word would harrow up thy soul.
Freeze thy young blood.
And 'tis better you take heed also,
for 'tis true, lad,
he who runneth with the fox
must beware the hounds.
Or is it dogs?
[Stammering] Yes, well,
I think I'd better be going.
[Door rattles]
[Banging]
Breathe softly and beware.
For it is often said
that jackals run in pairs.
[Jack] Good grief, Griffin.
What are you doing here?
You know him?
You've just knocked out our butler.
Griffin?
- You gave me your word, didn't you?
- I have tried to explain, sir.
You took advantage
of my good disposition.
Well, you'll work your passage
in the bunkers
and you'll rue the day you ever
heard the name of Captain Swain!
I am making a formal request, captain,
that you set us both ashore
at your first port of call.
[Laughs] I'll put you ashore
right enough
but it's what happens
between now and then,
is what you've got to worry about.
Get away from that.
That's not for you.
I appreciate that, sir.
You'll take your scoffings
with the crew,
unless I put you on bread and water.
I think I would prefer that, sir,
if we have a choice.
We'll leave it to the paying
passengers to malign the chow,
if ya don't mind.
If I may make a suggestion, captain.
Rather than waste my talent
in the bunker, sir,
if you would permit me
to prepare and serve your food
in the fully proper manner,
for your own safety, sir,
with the help of Master Jack,
my apprentice.
- You'll do what I say.
- By all means, sir.
Hey.
Have you ever tried
your hand at galley grub?
- Galley grub?
- He knows all there is to know...
...about food.
- Knowing and doing
is two different things, especially
for a landlubber put to sea.
My grandfather, sir,
prepared and served the meals
for Admiral Lord Nelson
at the Battle of Trafalgar.
All right.
One chance, I'll give ya.
And one chance only.
Thank you, sir.
And if you don't serve me
a fair to middling meal,
then it's off to the bunkers for you!
"And while the captain had agreed
to set us ashore at first port of call,
he now refuses to release us
from our duties:
Preparing his meals
and tending his cabin.
Consequently, we shall continue
on to the gold fields,
praying that fortune shall smile upon us
and that you may forgive us
the anxiety we have occasioned.
Master Jack has made friends
with an old judge
who has agreed to post this
when we reach Rio."
Doesn't that beat all?
The two of them bound for California.
Isn't that just like Griffin?
Even if he were assigned to a rock pile,
he'd make himself indispensable.
I can't get over it.
Griffin and Master Jack.
All alone in that wild country out west.
Well, we won't let them be all alone.
You may start packing my things.
- Don't you say you go.
- Why not?
There's nothing I can do here
I can't do in California.
- It's not a right place for a lady.
- Oh...
- Oh, sorry.
- Some of the stories I've heard.
Men outnumber women
100 to one in San Francisco.
Well, there's nothing wrong
with those odds,
especially when a young lady
has to earn her own living.
Oh, Griffin wouldn't approve
of you going to California.
But I think Grandpa
would approve of it heartily.
He wanted me to be free
to try my wings.
To find my own place
in this beautiful and exciting world.
I'll go lay out my things.
- That's about all.
- Oh.
Tell you what, miss.
Just to make it a clean deal,
I'll add $5 for the frame and picture.
Oh, I wouldn't part with Grandfather
for $1,000.
But if you're
going to California, miss...
Oh.
Well, in that case,
I'll leave him in your custody.
I'll take the five.
Griffin and Jack
who spent theirjourney in the galley
At last were nearing
San Francisco Bay
Their culinary art won over
the captains heart
As the menu grew
more elegant each day
As soon as we drop anchor
in San Francisco Bay,
every blasted member of the crew
is going to be over the side
and headed for the gold fields.
Hasn't been a ship left port in months.
Oh.
Do you have any idea
what time we'll get there?
We should get within spitting distance
during the graveyard watch.
We should get in tomorrow morning?
Tomorrow afternoon more likely.
[Swain] I'm not picking me way
through no floating graveyard
- and early morning soup.
- Oh.
Now, now, now, sonny.
[Swain] A few hours isn't going
to make all that difference.
Why don't you go and start
getting your donnies together?
I'll see you get to shore
in the first boat tomorrow.
- You're very kind, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
[Slurping]
[Jack and Griffin] Oh, Susanna
Oh, dont you cry for me
For Im off to California...
- Well, well. Griffin.
- Uh, by all means, sir.
[Laughs] And my
little friend Jack, huh?
What a beautiful day for singing.
Watch this.
- [Guffaws]
- Very good.
Oh, I'll bet you can
hardly wait to reach port.
Just barely. Are you going up
to the gold fields?
The gold fields?
Oh, I may, eventually.
But there are things in the world
more important than gold, son.
This is a new land, and it needs laws
and courts and justice.
Laws, courts, justice. Those are the
things I'm concerned with most of all.
Oh, yes. Laws, courts and justice.
Oh, yes, sir.
I really like that Judge Higgins.
Don't you?
Well, I don't know, Master Jack.
Sometimes I think
he tries almost too hard to be friendly.
What's wrong with being friendly?
You told me...
- Wait a minute.
- [Muffled banging, mumbling]
[Groaning]
- Mr. Bartlett, what happened?
- Who did this to you?
- They followed me.
They are on this ship.
The thread of life spins out.
- Did you see who hit you?
- A coward's blow from behind.
When I came to, I was blindfolded.
I could hear the man
ransacking my room.
[Bartlett] I suppose you do know
what he was seeking.
[Sighs]
- But he found it not.
- Found what not?
Hidden there lies ample bait
to lure the most treacherous of hounds.
A map given to me by a dying man
whom I had befriended
in a boarding house in Salem.
A map... to the mother lode.
Oh. Yes, well, um...
We will report this to the captain
immediately.
Oh, no, it would do no good
for I know not mine enemies.
And I do not greatly trust
that Captain Swain.
Oh.
Well, sir, I'm afraid that
under the circumstances,
there is nothing we can do for you.
Stick with me, you two.
If you'll a willing ear incline,
what's mine is yours
and what is yours is mine.
- You want us to be partners?
- [Bartlett] Aye, lad.
These are the crucial hours
as our journey nears its end.
For mine enemies,
the time is ripe to strike swiftly.
Seize the prize if they can find it
and be gone. What say you, friends?
[Stammering] Oh, uh...
I'm afraid that, uh...
we cannot remain with you here.
We have our duties
in the captain's cabin.
Oh, well. No matter.
I will remain locked in here.
You can look in on me occasionally.
- Bring me my remaining meals.
- Oh, by all means, sir.
And if another living soul
should dare to cross that threshold,
t'would be foolishness indeed.
I'm sorry.
Griffin! We'll be partners
in the mother lode!
- Shh.
- Master Jack!
Please?
Very well.
Mother lode indeed.
Don't forget my remaining meals.
[Jack] Griffin. Griffin. Hey, Griffin.
- Hmm?
- You can see 'em, Griffin.
Lights across the water. Somebody said
they're on boats in San Francisco Bay.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Don't you want to see them?
Oh, yes. All in due time.
You should be preparing for bed.
Oh, no. Just when we're getting here?
After all these months?
- Don't you realize...
- Master Jack,
you're going to have a busy day
tomorrow. You need your rest. Obey.
Oh. I stopped by to tell
Mr. Bartlett. Boy, is he excited.
Just think, Griffin.
If we do find the you-know-what,
and we're partners, we'll be about
the richest people in Boston.
You won't have to be a butler.
You can buy into a business.
Master Jack...
Sit down, Master Jack.
I want to tell you something.
I am proud to be a butler,
as was my father,
as was his father before him.
And, uh, I don't
understand why everybody...
[Swain] Fire! Fire in the hole!
Quick! Up on the deck!
[Swain] Hurry! Hurry!
[Panicked shouting]
It's a fire, a fire, I tell ya!
[Shouting]
Get back, I tell you!
[Man] Bring that over there. That's it.
- Excuse us. Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
Abandon ship!
[Higgins] Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
Come on. Be quick. Don't stand there
like a fool. The whole ship's on fire.
Caution, my friend. Caution.
If you have any small thing of value,
you'd better take it along.
Fire! Fire!
Oh. Thank you.
- Turn around. Turn around.
- What? Oh.
I think it's the pistol. If you'd be
so kind as to hold the pistol...
Fire! Fire! Fire!
[Commotion]
[Swain] Hands up on decks! Hands up!
Get them buckets moving! Come on!
[Man] It's a false alarm!
It's a false alarm.
Just oily rags. The whole engine room
is full of smoke.
A false alarm?
What are you saying, man?
Some bilge rat done it on purpose?
Good heavens. It's a trick.
- Excuse me.
- Get in there. Come on.
[Coughing]
- Mr. Bartlett!
- What happened?
- Higgins, it was.
- Higgins?
- Judge Higgins?
- Yes.
I turned my back for a second
and he hit me.
[Moaning]
You stay here.
Do what you can to help him.
- Captain Swain.
- Captain's on the poop deck.
- Captain Swain?
- You'll have to see me later.
Some bilge rat took off
in my starboard boat.
That's exactly what I was afraid...
Waiting there just for the findin
Shinin bright
Its nearly blindin
California gold
Waitinjust for me
Gotta claim my golden mountain
Gold that flows just like a fountain
Ill just spend my time
a- counting California gold
- Step right in! Show on the inside!
- [Singing continues]
Come on in, everybody. Come on in.
California gold
- California gold
- Oh. Come along. Come on.
Waitinjust for me
[Griffin] Come on.
We shan't achieve our purpose
by standing there.
I'll bet Judge Higgins won't
waste time getting to the gold fields.
However, do you realize
that if we are to find this gold,
- we shall need a grubstake.
- Oh, yes. Hmm...
Look!
Oh! What prices!
My mind will not believe
what mine eyes have seen.
Nor mine.
A-ha.
I believe I have a thought which
obviously will be of service to mankind
and, I think, gain us the money we need.
[Sighs]
Permit me, dear friend. I think
perhaps I have more experience.
What?
[Laughs] All the world is a stage,
you know.
Oh. Huh.
Romans, countrymen and lovers.
Griffin, what are you doing?
You just gave me a haircut a week ago.
Shh, Master Jack. Not so loud.
Costly thy habit as thy purse.
Hey! Look what's come to town!
There's nothing so becomes a man
as modest stillness and humility.
To be...
To be or not to be?
That is the question.
Um, I was wondering
if any of you gentlemen
have seen a man around town
with a scar on his forehead.
His name is Higgins. Judge Higgins.
- I ain't seen him. Have you?
- No.
- You?
- Uh-uh.
How much you charge for a haircut?
Oh, well, sir. Uh...
For you, I...
Oh, I think the same modest price
as a tub bath. $10?
- I'm first in line, then.
- Oh.
You go over there
and set up as cashier. Sir.
- I'm after him.
- Right. Oh.
Oh, sir. I'm very much afraid
that for you it will be $15.
- [Clears throat] Same for me?
- Well, yes.
[Laughs]
I'll make it ten.
You can even keep your hat on too.
[Laughter]
Sir?
If you prick us, do we not bleed?
If you tickle us, do we not laugh?
And if you poison us, do we not die?
- And if you wrong us...
- [crowd shouting]
This is a respectable place and
I don't want any of your kind here.
[Sam] Don't you ever forget it.
Hey, boss.
I go a little while. Mosey around town.
No. Go back inside. I want to keep
you from getting into trouble again.
Aw, gee, boss. You promised me.
All right. But only for a little while.
And remember,
keep your hands to yourself.
Sure, boss.
Uh, somebody said you been asking
about a man got a scar on his forehead.
Yeah, like down across here,
kind of, sort of?
- Yes, yes.
- Well, have you seen such a man?
- Sort of a big man, had a beard?
- That's right. It's Judge Higgins.
We saw him come ashore in
a small boat about sun-up, I'd say.
Do you know where he went?
Well, he tried to sell us his boat.
That's all. We says no.
Then he asks how can he get to Fry Town.
- Thank you, sir.
- No, no.
He asked how would he get to Hang Town.
Don't you remember?
- Fry Town!
- Hang Town!
You get everything wrong.
Don't you...
Thank you, gentlemen. I'm most
grateful for your information.
There will be, uh,
no more haircuts today.
You never listen when people talk!
How are we gonna find out which it is?
Fry Town or Hang Town?
Well, now, Master Jack,
how do you think it can be done?
Well, one way, Mr. Bartlett could go to
Fry Town and we could go to Hang Town.
Exactly. And if either picks up
the trail, he can inform the others.
And we can leave any messages
at Sutter's Fort.
Idea, lad, 'tis well said,
and t'were better soon be done.
Hmm.
How much do you think it's worth,
what we have here?
Oh, well now. I certainly think
that's enough to purchase our supplies
and get us started on our way.
Do you have anything
to take your share in?
I saw no need to buy a poke
when I had naught to put in it.
These should do adequately
for the moment. Would you hold on?
- Oh, yes.
- Thank you.
[Blows]
[Bartlett] Oh.
- Here you are.
- Well.
- Are you the man who cuts hair?
- Correct, sir.
Oh, but I have terminated
my activities for the day.
No. I want you to cut my hair now.
For me.
- Mountain Ox.
- Hmm. I reiterate, sir.
I have terminated my activities
for the day.
Oh, and uh, well,
even if I were to continue, sir,
there are other gentlemen...
I don't care about other men!
I tell you to cut hair, you cut hair!
Would you please keep
your vulgar hands off my apparel?
[Bartlett] You, sir, are a devil.
A born devil upon whose nature
nurture could never stick.
Nobody don't call no names
on Mountain Ox.
- How dare you, sir!
- You big bully!
Why, you little...
[man] He knocked out the Mountain Ox!
[Crowd yelling]
Here's the fella that did it!
[Man] He's out cold!
- [Man 2] You got him a good one!
- [Man 3] He knocked the Ox out!
[Sam] All right. Coming through.
What happened?
[Repeating] Didn't I tell you
to stay out of trouble?
All right, fellas. Get back.
Give him some air.
What happened? How many were there?
Did they gang up on him?
I do hope he's not badly hurt.
I am terribly sorry.
You did this?
Well, sir, you see, um...
Well, to tell you the truth, I...
His name's Bullwhip Griffin.
- You oughta see him wrestle a grizzly.
- Master Jack!
[Crowd laughs]
Bullwhip? My name is Sam Trimble.
Oh! How do you do, sir? [coughs]
I'm the owner
of the Lucky Nugget Saloon.
Oh. I'm honored, sir.
Now perhaps you will allow me...
I'll make you an offer.
I guarantee a $2,000 purse.
You take on the Mountain Ox
for the bareknuckle championship
of San Francisco.
Winner take all!
[Crowd cheers]
My friends! My friends.
I am most flattered
and I do thank you
but it is impossible as my partners
and I must leave for the gold field.
- Immediately.
- [Crowd groans]
He'll be back
and more willing to listen to reason
after he's tramped up enough hills
and missed enough meals.
[Gunshots]
How many want to live?
Hold up your hands, please.
Now!
Please, do not complain.
The land belongs to us.
You come take our gold?
[Laughs]
We start taking yours!
It don't come out even, though.
[Laughs]
Eh, Chico?
[Speaks Spanish]
[Bandit] Everybody come down.
Pronto!
[Bandit] Yoo-hoo.
You come out.
Oh! [laughs]
Turn around.
No funny business! Get in line!
- Judge Higgins!
- [Laughs]
Yes. Yes, it is, Jack.
Well, how do you do?
Griffin, I saw you get aboard and
I was hoping we might avoid this.
Oh, naturally.
Uh, please, senores.
First we take care of our business,
then you can talk.
Oh.
Hey, Chico? The ring.
Come on.
Gracias, senores.
You are most kind.
Now to please take off your coats.
- Why would he want us to do that?
- Move!
Oh!
In the lining is a good place
to hide the extra gold coins.
[Laughs] I have learned that trick.
No, sir. No, sir.
I have given you my gold,
you have taken my watch.
But I refuse to give up my coat.
You will have to shoot me first.
You make up the rules,
senor, not me.
[Bandit] But I will do anything
to make you happy.
- Oh!
- [Bandit laughs hysterically]
Gracias, senor!
Gracias, senores. You have been,
how you say, most generous.
Goodbye!
[Whooping]
[Gunshots]
Oh! Now that is marvelous,
absolutely marvelous.
- Oh, do stop that!
- Stop what?
What you're doing. By the by,
it is fortunate that fellow
did not blow your head off,
for I do believe Mr. Bartlett
has a prior claim to that privilege.
- Because of the map?
- [Griffin] Correct.
I now demand you hand it over,
immediately.
- Oh, you do, eh?
- We're partners with Mr. Bartlett.
Oh, you are, huh?
[Laughs]
The reason I didn't want to give up
my coat to that bandito...
I had the map sewn into the lining.
And as your friend Bartlett might
have said, there's the humor of it.
- I don't think it's very funny.
- Neither do I.
Oh, you don't, huh? The two of you
working your passage all those months.
[Laughs] And the infinite pains
I took to get it.
And now we lose it to a bandit
who doesn't even know he's got it!
[Man] You'll get used to things like
this, time you've been here a while.
Will I? You, sir. Will you please
hand down our packs?
Right there. The lad and I will not
continue the journey.
[Jack] But Griffin...
Don't blubber. As we have no gold...
Here, put this on.
We have no heavy coats
to keep us warm.
There.
Thank you, sir. It would be foolish
for us to continue.
There. Good day.
Are you ready? Press on.
I don't see why
we couldn't have gone on anyhow.
I mean,
even if the map is gone, that's...
Shh. I do not think
those banditos will ride far
with an unwieldy bundle of jackets.
And if they're just feeling around
for hidden coins...
[laughs] They may not
detect the map. Mmm. Come on.
Let's get aboard.
Get that door closed.
No, wait.
Toss it down. That's my bag
right there. Toss it down quickly.
Oh, I have
a very important engagement.
[Griffin] It is.
Oh, see. Look! Look!
[Laughs]
[Griffin] There we go.
[Higgins] Wise plan, then, Griffin.
Oh, splendid.
Oh, I'll take that now, thank you.
[Higgins] Strange, isn't it,
how our paths continue to cross.
Oh, I won't trouble you to help me
into it. Just toss it up gently.
No, sir.
I refuse to give you the coat.
You'll have to shoot me first.
- No! Don't shoot!
- Toss up the coat.
[Laughs]
Oh, I have no doubt
that you are a scoundrel, Higgins.
But you're not the type
who would shoot an unarmed man.
Well, that is purely
a personal opinion on your part.
You're certainly not the kind
to shoot an unarmed man in the back.
Shall we go, Master Jack?
[Stammering] Sir? My back was turned.
Shall I count to three?
- One... two...
- Wait!
No, no, no, Master Jack! Wait!
- Throw, Jack!
- Here!
[Laughs]
Oh, smart boy, Jack.
And if I may once again
quote your friend Bartlett,
"Parting is such sweet sorrow."
[Griffin] Or as he might remind you,
"The path is smooth
that leadeth onto danger."
Oh, and I assure you, sir.
Our paths will cross again.
Our paths... [laughs]
Going from camp to camp
They searched for old Judge Higgins
Who kept himself so cleverly disguised
Their quest would not be through
until they found every clue
And every clue was promptly utilized
Let's ask him.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir?
Uh, we wanted to ask
if perhaps you had seen
a rather large man pass this way.
His name is Higgins. Judge Higgins.
A-ha.
He was wearing a white suit,
through Hang Town, headed this way.
[Speaks Chinese]
Maybe we should go ask some others.
Very well.
You're just wasting your time.
And just what
makes you say that, sir?
- Don't none of them talk English.
- Oh! Hmm.
Y'all want a dish of chow?
Just go in and help yourself.
I always do, every time I pass by.
- Don't they mind?
- Well, now, they ain't never said.
At least not so
I can understand them. [laughs]
[Laughs] Yes. I'm afraid
we must be on our way.
Now, hold on now.
This man you're looking for,
he sure sounds like old Cut Eye
over at Shirt Tail camp.
The only trouble is, he's a dentist.
He ain't no judge.
Well now, uh... Are you sure?
Did you meet him?
Meet him? I was the first one
he ever pulled tooth for
after he come over to Shirt Tail.
He got me all hooched up so I
wouldn't feel nothing. Look here.
Oh.
Skunk pulled every dagbusted tooth
that had any gold in it.
We thank you, sir,
for the information. Good day.
[Shouting]
It's Judge Higgins they're hanging.
I demand to be heard
and I will be heard.
Open your mouth.
- In. Inside.
- Oh!
Wait!
[Griffin] Please! Wait!
Oh, we've come 50 miles. 50 miles!
We must use your dentist
before you hang him.
[Gasps]
[Moans]
Well, it looks to me like a
compound infection of an abscess root.
- [Higgins] Come closer, boy.
- [Moans]
- Open your mouth.
- No! He can't do that.
- He can't?
- The air. It's very bad on the tooth.
- The air.
- Oh. Oh, yes, yes! The air!
[Moaning]
Don't touch him! A thing like that
could be fatal to a boy his age
if he isn't treated immediately.
What are we gonna do?
We gotta do something.
- We can't let that poor boy suffer.
- Please, please.
You must do something
to help this poor lad.
All right, boys.
Old Cut Eye been duly tried
by miners' court.
And found guilty of thievery,
and sentenced to be hung.
- However, this one time,
- [crowd murmuring]
We gonna temper justice with mercy.
- We gonna let you live long enough
- [moaning]
To pull this suffering boy's tooth.
Why, you'll never regret it, sir.
Thank you, sir. Oh, thank you.
[Crowd murmuring]
I was never so happy
to see anyone in my whole life.
Ow! [whispers]
Do you still have the map?
It's where nobody will find it
in 100 years.
Why don't you tell us where it is?
It won't do you any good
after they hang you.
Get me out of this alive...
...and I promise you the map is yours.
You are absolutely ridiculous. How
can we possibly do a thing like that?
- They'd shoot us all.
- Give me your word
- you'll do what you can.
- Oh, come along, Master Jack.
[Higgins] I have it. I have it.
Tell them I can't pull the tooth
till the swelling goes down.
It'll take several days.
You.
Give us the map first,
and I promise we'll do everything
we can to help you.
- You promise?
- I promise.
You said it was where nobody
would find it in 100 years.
That's the first place we'd look.
Not if I had been buried
with my coat on.
[Laughs] That's very good.
[Griffin stammering] But this map
is no earthly good.
The most important part is missing.
The end of the trail.
Shot away by that insolent varmint
who held up the stage.
You gave me your word
to do everything you can.
- We won't do anything.
- Master Jack.
Quite right.
Wait, Bullwhip! He tricked us.
Nevertheless, a gentleman
does not go back on his word.
Get away from that window, sonny.
Gentlemen, gentlemen!
You simply must wait
until another dentist arrives.
But he been convicted.
He gotta be hung!
[Crowd roars]
Have you ever been awakened
in the middle of the night
by an excruciating toothache?
One that throbs and pounds?
Like 1,000 hot knives
jabbing and searing
until you can feel it
down to your toenails?
[Gasps] It could happen tonight.
Yes, it could. Yes, to you.
Or you.
And you. It could happen
to any one of you.
Ah. But how?
How will you feel then, tonight,
when you have hanged the only
available dentist this morning?
For the time being, he's worth more
alive to us than he is dead.
But he gonna be
under guard every minute.
And we gonna get on with the hanging
as soon as another dentist shows up.
Oh, and one thing more.
As head of the miners' committee,
I'm ordering you and that boy
to get his grave dug.
[Miner] Have it ready and waitin'.
Kind of a reminder to him
that we mean business.
Dig her plenty deep, too.
We're gonna get rid of that crook
once and for all.
You know what was nice
about Bullwhip Brannigan?
Towards the end of the book,
after he built his rock palace
and married the Indian princess...
Indian princess?
- Oh!
- He told Tom Wingay,
"No matter where you travel
in this life,
you'll always have a home
to come back to. Here. With us."
Bullwhip, why don't you get married?
Well, Master Jack, for one thing,
I never happened to meet
an Indian princess.
It wouldn't have to be that.
What about Arabella?
Oh, now really, Master Jack!
[Stammering] You shouldn't talk like
that. That's not proper. She's a lady.
- You like her, don't you?
- Look, that is not the question.
You're always peeking
at her picture when I put it up.
Please, Master Jack.
She carries the locket
you gave her in sixth grade.
That is enough.
I thought it would make us
really brothers. Brothers-in-law,
and then if you and Arabella
had a house...
Oh, look.
[Stammering] Look here.
- Do you think it's a mother lode?
- Well, you know it could be, Jack.
It certainly could be. Look. Oh!
That's the first time you've
called me Jack, not Master Jack.
We're partners. That is gold! Gold!
Nuggets! Look!
Oh! Oh, look!
It is, it is, it is.
Look at that.
We have to get word to Sutter's Fort.
We have to alert Mr. Bartlett.
Oh, look! We're going to be so rich!
Stop. Careful.
You promised to keep me alive
until another dentist showed up.
Well, we just found out.
Old Bixby, there. He can pull teeth.
Why, he's no certified dentist!
He's pulled teeth before.
He can do it again if he has to.
- Come on, boys. Let's get on with it.
- You'll trust your teeth with Bixby?
Cut Eye, I don't know
what you're stewing about.
You ain't gonna need no dentist,
not where you're going. [laughs]
[Miner] Strike! Big strike!
A man and a boy was digging a grave!
Hit a vein of pure gold!
- Come on, come on.
- Pete, don't... Hold it.
Pete? Pete? Pete.
[Stammering] Don't go.
[Stammering] Don't let loose!
- Don't. You'll...
- [stammering] He'll be all right.
- He's used to this. Don't worry.
- Whoa, boy.
Oh!
[Whinnies]
[Shrieks]
Help! Somebody help!
Sailing up through the Golden Gate
came Arabella
Of whom we momentarily lost track
At once it must be told
She did not search for gold
But to find her butler
and her brother Jack
Thank you.
Permit me, if you will.
My name is Sam Trimble.
Merchant and civic leader
at your service.
As one who appreciates the pulchritude
and charm so rare in our young city,
may I say welcome to San Francisco.
Thank you.
May I ask what brings such a lovely
young lady alone to a place like this?
Well, I'm not really all alone.
My brother is here.
Oh. Big brother?
Little brother. Twelve years old.
Our butler is with him.
- Gold seekers, by any chance?
- Yes.
Boys, bring those things inside.
There's no point in staying out here
in the wet and cold.
And we'll have to figure out a place
for you to stay, a respectable place.
I'm afraid
there aren't too many of them.
Well, isn't there a hotel?
Yes, but you wouldn't want to spend
20 or 30 dollars a night, would you?
There's no telling
when they'll be back.
If the rains ease off, they may stay
in the hills two or three more months.
[Arabella] Oh, really?
Winter had blown its icy breath
into the mountains
The miners could not tolerate the cold
Their tools were strewn about
while their claims gave out
And the gold rush
at last rushed out of gold
Bullwhip, Bullwhip
Bullwhip Griffin
As homeward their recollections roam
Onboard and afloat
Downriver, by boat
Upon theirjourney back home
Remember the first time
we saw the lights of San Francisco?
I sure do. Right after that was
when Judge Higgins stole the map.
Now there's a lesson to remember.
He was the one with the clever,
crooked, cunning schemes
and yet you, Mr. Bartlett and I,
we end up with all the gold.
[Griffin] Come along.
We'll be docking soon.
We should put our things together.
Oh, and one other thing.
There is no advantage
to wearing a money belt
if you keep fussing around and letting
everybody know you've got it.
Passenger Griffin!
[Higgins] Eric Griffin report
to the captain in the wheel house.
Immediately.
Well, now, that is most peculiar. Huh!
I wonder what the captain wants with me.
Excuse me, sir.
Did you see somebody pass by this way?
[Speaks fake Chinese]
I see. You go back there.
All right! You go to our cabin.
I'll see what the captain wants.
Shhh!
- Judge Higgins!
- [Fake Chinese]
I'm gonna have to
ask a little favor of you, boy.
[Struggling]
Give me your word you won't
call, holler or try to run away.
[Muffled struggling]
I don't want to hurt you, boy.
Now, we've been good friends, remember?
Besides, I'm very grateful
to you and Griffin
for excavating my share of the gold
and transporting it from the hills.
Now you listen, Jack. Listen carefully.
It's a very fine point of the law.
But a man's grave is his castle.
Did you know that?
- Mmm...
- Did you know?
- No, sir.
- Well, it is.
A man's grave is his castle.
If you find gold in my grave,
it's no more than right that
I should share in part of it, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
You're a smart boy, Jack.
I knew you'd see it my way
if I explained it clearly to you.
Now, you understand, of course,
that I'm going to have to gag you
and tie you up, huh? But we're
still friends, aren't we? [grunts]
Help! Somebody help me!
Help me! Somebody! Help me!
Help me! Bullwhip!
- Bullwhip, help! Somebody help me!
- [Higgins] Part of this belongs to me!
Jack? What's the matter? Jack?
Help!
Thank you.
[Captain] Man overboard!
Throw the line!
- [Whistle blows]
- Another man overboard!
Bullwhip, the gold.
It's all right. [coughs]
It was Judge Higgins.
He was after me.
- Higgins!
- [Captain] Haul away, men.
Steady, now. Steady on those lines.
[Captain] Hold. Easy, now. Steady.
That's it. Steady.
Easy, now. Give me your hand, son.
Easy, now.
[Captain] Come on. Up we go.
Easy. There we go.
Let me have that blanket.
Keep you warm, son.
There's a big man...
dressed like a coolie.
But he's Judge Higgins.
And he tried to rob me.
Round up the coolies
and take 'em to the wheel house.
All right, folks. Break it up.
Back to your cabins.
- [Captain] We'll be docking soon.
- [Splash]
It's not fair. It isn't.
Everything gone.
After all we've been through.
- It's all my fault.
- No, come on, now. That's silly.
- Come on. Buck up.
- [Sighs]
After all, we are still in California.
And there's still enough gold
for all those who know how to get it.
Fortunately,
we did not lose our scissors.
[Man] All right, boys.
Here's your chance.
In two days, the Robert Emmet
leaves for New York.
Howdy, neighbors.
Where you boys from?
- Charleston, Savannah, New York?
- Boston. Why?
Boston! You gentlemen
are in the best of luck.
I can book you on the Robert Emmet,
leaving in two days.
Step in here,
I'll arrange for the passage.
- We got the tickets...
- Now, will you wait?
At the moment, we are hardly prepared.
$250 each, you can't beat
a price like that to Boston.
That's quite a few haircuts.
[Stammering] Therefore, we had better
waste no time in setting up shop.
Thank you. Good evening.
[Jack] "Haircuts, 50 cents."
Absolutely impossible.
No waiting, gentlemen.
Step right inside.
Fifty cents? It used to be $15.
Times have changed, boy.
Thousands of men flocking into town,
willing to do anything
just for the price of a square meal.
[Barber] I'm telling you the truth.
I'll make it 35 cents for each of you.
[Jack] I'm hungry.
Yes.
Oh, well.
Think about something else.
But how can I when I'm hungry?
Well, concentrate your thoughts on...
What would happen if we went in,
ate our fill and then couldn't pay?
We would be thrown out.
And none too gently.
Step inside, gents.
I'm game if you are.
We shall risk the consequences.
All right, gents.
Where else but in the Lucky Nugget
can you get the best steaks
west of the Mississippi?
See the dancing girls and hear the
Boston Belle. Step right up, gents.
- Come on, Griffin.
- Wait.
[Whistles]
If we are going to be thrown out,
at least let it be
from the best place in town.
[Announcer] Hear the only piano
in San Francisco
and listen, listen to the voice
of the Boston Belle!
Come on, everybody!
The best show in San Francisco.
Move right on to the inside.
All right. Come right on in.
They ate a big meal inside,
run up a big bill...
- Oh, dear.
- Maybe we better go to the other place.
We will not. Come along.
[Shouts]
I'll throw you out.
Will you let us through, please, sir?
- Will you please?
- Ah, Bullwhip!
[Mountain Ox] I wait a long time.
You come back.
Now I fix things good.
I am not aware
of anything that requires fixing.
[Laughs]
- Who is he?
- The great Bullwhip Griffin.
I seen him knock out the Mountain Ox
once with his open hand.
- Why...
- Fight, fight, fight!
You better leave him alone.
This time he might close his fist
and you never will come to.
- Jack!
- [Laughter]
All right, Bullwhip.
Close your fist.
And show everybody
how you knock out Mountain Ox.
Go ahead. Hit me.
Please hit me!
You do rather tempt one.
- However...
- [Sam] Wait, wait. Hold it.
Ox? How many times have I told you to
stay out of trouble? Quit fighting.
Now I'm not gonna tell you again!
You two get outta...
- Bullwhip?
- Yes.
Bullwhip! When did you get back?
It's good to see you.
- Oh, thank you.
- Everybody, Bullwhip Griffin is back!
[All cheer]
Don't fight him here. Not here.
Don't even touch him.
[Crowd moans]
Aw, gee, boss.
Everybody say Bullwhip
knock out Mountain Ox with one hand.
[Ox] Not even closed fist.
Now you say don't fight.
You break Mountain Ox heart.
[Crowd murmurs]
There are men who would pay
thousands of dollars to see this fight.
Thousands of dollars.
You understand, you big ox?
Yeah, boss.
Go inside and have a drink.
I'll talk to you later.
Everybody.
The drinks are on the house.
[Cheering]
As I said the last time you were here,
I'm still willing to guarantee
a $2,000 purse.
Winner take all. What do you think?
- Naturally, one must discuss that...
- We can't think on empty stomachs.
Of course not, of course not.
I'll set you up
a nice, juicy steak dinner.
- And then we'll talk.
- It is a bit past our dinner time.
Good, good! I'll get a table ready.
[Laughs]
Oh! Oy.
I wish you were Bullwhip Brannigan,
so you could fight the Mountain Ox.
- Sure you do.
- Boy, that'd serve him right.
[Laughs]
[Music plays]
Jack, this is not a proper place
for a boy of your age
and you certainly should not
display such an interest
in, um, the ladies who perform here.
[Chuckles]
[Cheering, applause]
[Ladies] And now, gentlemen,
the moment you have awaited.
Presenting the Boston Belle!
[Cheering, applause]
[Piano music plays]
The nights are bright
in San Francisco
Theyre just as bright as gay Paree
Because the girls of San Francisco
Do the dance
that youve all come to see
So if youre new to San Francisco
And want some hometown hospitality
Just pull up a chair, boys
Youre welcome to stare
But open your pokes, boys
and pay for the fare
- The girls of San Francisco...
- Jack! You must not do that!
Griffin. It's Arabella singing.
So pull up a chair, boys
Youre welcome to stare
But open your pokes, boys
and pay for the fare
The girls of San Francisco
will treat you right
At the Lucky Nugget tonight
[chorus] The nights are bright
in San Francisco
- Theyre just as bright as gay Paree
- Arabella! Look over here!
- Because the girls of San Francisco
- Jack!
That youve all come to see
Jack! Oh! Let me look at you.
[Jack] We found a whole bunch of gold,
but we lost it when I fell in the bay.
Oh!
Griffin! Oh, Griffin,
you look so different!
You're tan and I don't think
I've ever seen you without a tie.
[Stammering] Oh, Miss Arabella,
you should not be here alone.
Not in a wild town like San Francisco.
- Certainly not in a saloon.
- Oh, Griffin. I'm not alone.
I'm with you and Jack. As for
singing in a saloon, I love it.
Gosh, but you look pretty, Arabella.
And you sing good too.
[Exasperated] Wait a minute!
[Stammering] The steamship
Robert Emmet.
It leaves in two days for Boston.
You are going to be on it.
- Oh, Griffin...
- You can't do that, Griffin.
Well, well, well. Arabella.
I see you've found your butler and
your brother. I'm very happy for you.
- [Crowd cheering]
- However, the world cannot stand still.
- You have another number to sing.
- Oh, yeah.
Well, you two wait right here, huh?
Maestro.
Last night
I was rolling round the floor
With a lot of handsome fellows
I had never met before
Then abruptly someone stole a kiss
I couldnt see who it could be
But I can tell you this
If you would kiss me again
Whoever you are
Hold me again, whoever you are
Never again would I let you get far
From your lovin mama
Whoever you are
So if youre fat or youre skinny
Youre tiny or tall
You come from Virginny
St. Lou or St. Paul
Come out, come out
from wherever you are
Cause Im yours forever
Whoever you are
[Arabella continues to sing]
Bullwhip? How are you gonna
get the money for Arabella's ticket?
The day after tomorrow, Miss Arabella
and you are going to be on that ship.
Yours forever
Or maybe yours forever
Oh, baby
Yours forever
Whoever
Whoever you are
[crowd cheering, whistling]
Well, Bullwhip. What about my offer?
One question.
If I agree to fight the Mountain Ox,
will you give me $1,000
cash advance immediately?
- No, Bullwhip. Don't do it.
- No, we find it makes a better fight
- winner take all.
- Oh, a better fight.
[Chuckles] We haven't agreed
there's going to be a fight.
Oh, well. If you are reluctant,
it really doesn't matter.
Wait. Let's not quarrel over it.
Uh, Joe.
It's a gentleman's agreement then.
You'll fight the Ox, let me
set the time and place. Right?
Oh, well, I'd need a place to train,
a place to stay.
No problem. There's a little room
next to the stables at my hacienda.
[Sam] It's not very fancy, but...
Tell Mr. Trimble how
you knocked out Mountain Ox.
Mr. Trimble is not interested
in technique.
All Mr. Trimble wants is a match.
Right?
- Right.
- [Man] Hey, Sam?
Bullwhip, are you out of your mind?
[Moans] Possibly.
You can't pull that glove trick
in a bareknuckle fight.
- That is not important.
- You wanna get yourself killed?
- Oh...
- [drum roll]
Gentlemen, may I have your attention,
please? An important announcement.
I'm very happy to announce
that the fight of the year
will take place here at the Lucky
Nugget Saloon one week from tonight!
[Cheering]
A boxing match?
No, gentlemen. A grudge fight
for the bareknuckle championship
of San Francisco
between the present undisputed
champion, the Mountain Ox!
[Cheering]
Facing the challenger, the only man
who has ever knocked out the Ox,
the legendary and much-talked-about
Bullwhip Griffin!
[Cheering]
[Sam] Tickets go on sale tomorrow
for those of you who can afford them.
Those of you with heavy pokes,
if you want to sign up now,
go over to the bar.
We'll save some good seats for you.
Bullwhip Griffin?
Do you have even the remotest idea
what you're doing?
I have seen the Mountain Ox take
three men twice the size that you are
- and destroy them.
- He's doing it for money, Arabella,
to send us home.
He doesn't care what happens to him.
- Oh.
- I wouldn't take that.
That's blood money.
What do you think I am?
I know what you are. You are a lady.
You don't belong
in a place like this.
No. And neither do you. Come along.
Come on!
Then he took the glove filled with gold
and he swung it like a blackjack.
My brother Jack
told me the whole story last night.
Why, that shifty little shyster.
He had everybody fooled, even the
poor Ox. He never suspected anything.
So, you see, Sam,
you've got to call it off.
Well, it really doesn't matter.
It may not be much of a fight,
probably won't last long,
but they can't say it's my fault.
Sam? He's not a fighter, he's a butler.
He could get killed.
What are you getting steamed up
about? Why do you need a butler?
Sam. Here's your money back.
Now call the whole thing off.
Call it off? Are you serious?
You and I are in a position
to make some pretty shrewd bets.
We know something that
those men don't know.
Oh. Well, suppose I go out there and
tell them the same story I told you?
- No, I wouldn't do that.
- They wouldn't place their bets.
I imagine they wouldn't
buy tickets for your fight.
Probably not. They'd be too busy
stringing up your butler by the neck.
Honey, a lot of bets have been made.
They'd lynch him before sundown.
Well, you'd better think of something.
Or I quit.
Now, wait a minute, wait a minute. Uh...
Look, I'll have the Ox go easy on him.
You know better than that.
Once the big Ox gets wound up,
there'll be no stopping him.
He'd beat Griffin to a pulp.
Why don't you stay with me? It's
more fun to be on the winning side.
- You are a beast!
- Maybe so.
But remember I'm still your friend
and if you ever want your job back...
I always thought you were
real smart about everything
but this doesn't seem very smart to me.
Master Jack.
Now, I have a feeling that brute force
is not always decisive.
I shall endeavor to combine agility
with a certain basic knowledge
of fisticuffs.
Fortunately, I once read the
Gentlemans Guide to Boxing.
All he'll have to do
is land just one blow.
[Arabella] Griffin?
Griffin? Jack?
I quit my job and sent word
to the captain of the Robert Emmet
to hold places on board for us tonight.
I'm so glad you've come to your senses.
- Yes, well, three places.
- Three places.
There's more than enough
here for the three of us.
We could sneak on board
and we'd be out to sea
before anyone realized you were gone.
Miss Arabella, I couldn't do a thing
like that. I've given my word.
What, to Sam Trimble?
Why, he'd double-cross himself.
Well, even so.
Wouldn't you rather break your word
than break your neck?
Sure.
Well, I am going right down
and book two passages.
You can book as many as you like
'cause I shan't be aboard when it sails.
Neither will I.
Oh, dear.
Well, look, even if you are going to
stay here, you're going to need this.
You go out and get killed
and we spend your money? Don't be silly.
How are you going to live?
You have quit your job.
But I can get my job back.
I will not have you singing in a saloon.
I will not permit it.
- You will not permit it?
- [Griffin] No!
Nor do I wish you to associate with
Sam Trimble. The way he looks at you!
Well, for your information,
I like the way he looks at me.
Master Jack.
Griffin is jealous.
Well, since you insist on going
through with this fight, Griffin,
I guess we're all in it together.
All right, gents.
You all heard what Sam Trimble said.
He's giving 20-1.
20-1, mind you,
on the Mountain Ox to win.
- Joe?
- Yes?
This is the new bookkeeper
to give you a hand.
Good. Start with those pokes.
Weigh 'em out.
- And then put 'em in the safe.
- Don't you worry.
I will take care of everything.
Gents, gents!
Where's your sporting blood?
Get out those heavy pokes.
[Sam] I'm offering 30-1
on the Mountain Ox to win.
[Crowd clamoring]
I sure hope the Mountain Ox
would rather dance than fight.
Very good.
[Arabella] Oh!
[Griffin] Oh!
You know, I haven't quite
figured out how I'm going to win
- merely by staying out of his way.
- For now, let's just concentrate
- on how you're going to survive.
- [Moans]
The first thing I'm going to do
after this is over
is buy three tickets to Boston.
Your best chance with the big Ox
is to get him angry
so he loses his temper
and then he goes berserk.
- I've seen a sample.
- Well, let's get started.
- Fine.
- Come on.
Now, I'll be the Mountain Ox.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
[Grunting]
Mr. Bartlett!
Hey! Wait till Bullwhip sees you!
Desist a moment, dear lad.
They hold the stage.
Let them play out the play.
You didn't hear about what happened to
us, coming back from the gold fields?
No, but let us exchange such tales
within the shadows of this rampart
whilst observing yon gladiators.
This is all we wound up with, but I'm
sure Bullwhip will let you have a third.
Well, thank you,
but by a happy circumstance,
while being pursued by a grizzly bear,
a great hairy beast,
I perchanced to stumble
into a deep hole,
and upon striking the bottom,
struck upon a bed of golden nuggets.
Of course, it is not the mother lode
we share among us.
And yet, uh, who can gain say?
Might it not lead on to equal fortune?
[Arabella] Whoa!
Methinks David and Goliath,
and at 30-1 odds.
Now, let us take our gold
and make haste to the Lucky Nugget.
Don't you want to talk to Bullwhip,
meet Arabella?
There is a tide in the affairs of man,
which, taken at the flood,
leads onto fortune.
Now, let us not tarry
until the tide has turned.
[Grunting]
Oh, Bullwhip...
I'm telling you,
it'll be the fight of the year.
- Good luck, Sam.
- We can't lose.
Get them seated,
let's get the fight on.
All right. Take your seats.
The fight will start in a while.
[Drum roll]
Knock him out, Bullwhip.
I bets my poke on you!
I got everything I own riding on you.
You just gotta win.
Good luck, Bullwhip.
I'll lose my shirt if you don't win.
Those men who've wagered on me,
they expect me to win.
So does Mr. Bartlett.
He bet all his gold on you, Bullwhip.
- On me? To win?
- At 50-1 odds.
This saloon,
his gorgeous hacienda,
all his gold, he will forfeit to us.
- And you know that $1,000?
- Jack, you didn't.
No. Mr. Bartlett did it for me.
Oh, well, then.
I shall be forced
to trounce the scoundrel.
[Cheering]
Hold it. Save it for the fight.
Just one blow and it'll all be over.
[Crowd booing]
[Bell rings]
Go get him, Bullwhip.
There's gonna be one minute
between rounds.
And the round ends when any part
of the anatomy touches the ground,
excepting the feet.
Now I don't want no strangleholds.
- [Cracking]
- [Booing]
And no stomping a man
when he's down.
Now, let's have a good, clean fight,
and let the best man win.
[Cheering]
Now that was not fair.
You simply must observe
the Marquis of Queensbury rules.
Huh?
Stop using them cuss words!
I said a clean fight.
[Bell rings]
[Jack] Come on, Bullwhip! Hit him!
Come on, Bullwhip!
Hit him! Will ya hit him?
Attaboy, Bullwhip! He can't hurt ya!
Make him stand still so I can hit him!
No rules says he's gotta.
Let's get on with the fight.
- Boo!
[Sam] Come on, Ox! Move in!
All you have to do
is land one good blow.
[Sam] Behind you, Ox!
[Laughter]
No, Griffin, no.
Don't stand there. Move around.
Hit him, you big ox!
[Bell rings]
You big bully!
[Referee] The winner of round one,
the Mountain Ox.
[Crowd roars]
Water, quick!
We can't let them see he's out.
20, 21, 23...
- Uh, 22.
- 22? 22...
- I sure hit him, didn't I?
- You sure did.
25, 26...
[trumpeting]
[Man] Attaboy! Attaboy!
Don't let him get you mad.
Finish him off this round.
I want to open up the bar.
Dance around. Make him chase you.
Get him mad!
- He's gotta catch you to hurt you.
- He's terrified of you.
[Bell rings]
[Arabella] Move around, Griffin!
[Bellowing]
Quit playing around.
Get in there and hit him!
[Sam] Now! Hit him!
[Sam] Ox, will you hit him?
Yoo-hoo! Oxy-Woxy?
You're supposed to be dancing with...
I mean, fighting with Bullwhip, not him.
Why don't you just hit him? Hit him!
[Grunting]
[Man] Watch it. He's coming back.
[Man] Do it, Bullwhip!
You know, there's a lot more
where this came from.
May as well be greedy, huh, partner?
[Screams]
Stop! Wait for him!
Aaahhh!
- Trip him! Trip him!
- That's a good idea.
I didn't mean him. Come on, Ox.
You're not hurt.
The winner of round two,
Bullwhip Griffin!
[Cheering]
- Easy! Take it easy!
- What happened?
Oh! I don't know
if I can run another mile.
Now, don't get mad.
Who's mad!
Take it easy, Ox.
It's gonna be all right. Take it easy.
Go get him, Bullwhip. You can do it.
[Bell rings]
He's in back of you, Bullwhip!
[Sam] Ha-ha!
You've got him now, Ox! Hit him!
I got him now.
You've got him now. Finish him off.
Wait, wait! It's not over.
Both fighters has got one minute
to reach his scratch line.
Come on!
[Jack] Bullwhip, Bullwhip!
Bullwhip, don't just lie there.
[Jack] Bullwhip, wake up!
You gotta win, you've just gotta!
Ox, get up!
You gotta win or I'm ruined!
[Bookkeeper] 21, 22, 23, 24,
25, 26, 27, 28,
29, 30...
- Help me get him to his feet.
- Jack, help me lift him. Uh!
[Trumpeting]
- [Griffin moans]
- Come on, Griffin, get up.
- Good heavens!
- Good heavens! 56...
- 57...
- Toe the line, Griffin.
59, 60!
My good man,
were you looking for this?
[Bell rings]
The winner
and new bareknuckle champion
of San Francisco...
...Bullwhip Griffin!
- [Cheering]
What are we gonna do, boss?
You're wiped out.
Get the gold out of the safe.
We'll take it out the back way. Go on!
The bookkeeper!
He's stolen all the gold!
He's getting away!
[Man] Fire! Fire!
The gold. It's ours. Part of it, anyway.
I'm letting you out to fight a fire.
Head for the Lucky Nugget!
Here we go. Come on, let's go!
Gentlemen... Gentlemen?
- Gentlemen, you are...
- Judge Higgins!
- Let him speak!
- Use your intelligence.
Do you think I could have run
that fast with all that gold?
- What'd you do with it?
- On the mule.
I strapped it to the back of a mule!
What are you doing just sitting there,
you big ox?
- The boss says he's gonna kill me.
- Sam isn't the boss anymore.
- I am. Start carrying things out.
- Sure, boss.
Watch out. It's on fire.
Hey, Bullwhip! Arabella! Look!
- [Jack] It's all the gold.
- Jack! Good boy!
Well, well, well. Good.
You found the gold. Excellent.
Uh-uh!
[Whistles] Ox? Come here.
Get me those saddle bags.
You're not my boss no more, see?
I don't take orders from you now!
- Let him go, Ox.
- Aw, boss!
Let him go.
- Thank you, my dear.
- Remember, I'm still your friend.
And if you ever want your job back,
you just let me know.
[Laughs]
Ox, would you take care
of the mule, please?
Sure, boss.
Over the flames and ashes
Bullwhip dreamed a city
Whose charm all other cities
it would dwarf
With buildings fireproof
and social dancing on the roof
And fishermen
with their own special wharf
There was a hill for nobs
and streetcars pulled by cables
A golden bridge was also in the plan
Suffice it now to say
The city you see today
Was inspired by the vision of this man
Bullwhip, Bullwhip
Bullwhip Griffin
All San Francisco should cheer
And close up the ranks
Look up and give thanks
That Bullwhip Griffin was here