Looks deader
than a Paiute's grave.
Well?
That guy's awful slow
gettin' there.
I feel sorry for him.
Always in reach and never able
to do anything about it.
I got a feeling
she could do better.
You're boasting.
- What'll you have? Whiskey?
- What've you got?
- Whiskey.
- You ever see such a guy?
All winter I've been thinking--
And all he's got is whiskey.
- That's rotten, ain't it?
- Rotten.
Two glasses
and a bottle.
[ Clears Throat ]
Well, what's on
you boys' mind?
- Does somethin'
have to be on my mind?
- Well, there's mud in your eye.
Friendly cuss, ain't he?
He's just getting around
to asking if his girl is still in town.
His girl? If you mean
Rose Mapen, no.
She went to Frisco
the first stage out this spring.
That's a lie.
She said she'd wait.
It's a fact.
What a town.
It's my guess
the married women run her out.
Oh, no tar and feathers.
No rails.
They just righteously
made her feel uncomfortable.
Not that she ever
did anything, but--
They just couldn't get over
being afraid she might.
Say, what is there
to do in this town anyway?
- Unless you wanna get in line
and woo Drew's daughter.
- We don't.
The only other
unmarried woman I know
is 82, blind and a Paiute.
That leaves you five choices.
Eat, sleep, drink,
play poker or fight.
Or you can shoot some pool.
- I got a new table in the back room.
- That's just great.
- I see Risley's still around.
- The sheriff?
I thought he never
got closer than Reno
except on special calls.
Hey, it wouldn't be
that rustling folks we're
talking about last fall?
Could be.
Gettin' to be a kinda
touchy subject, huh?
They don't like
to talk about it except
with fellows they sleep with.
- Afraid they'll find out
it's somebody they know?
- Maybe.
- They lose some more this spring?
- Some.
- How many?
- About 600 head.
They got any leads?
They picked up a small-herd
trail and signs of shod horses
down the south draw.
Wouldn't everybody know
if there were strangers around?
Sure.
And there hadn't been any.
Except you two.
- That ain't funny.
- [ Chuckles ]
Now who's touchy?
You're talking about my business.
Stick to my pleasures.
No offense, Carter.
I just wanted to let you know
where you two stand.
- Listen--
- Take it easy, Gil.
He's had five whiskeys,
and he's sore about Rose Mapen.
- Keep your mouth shut
about Rose, see.
- Okay, Gil.
I was just jokin'.
You can take a joke, can't you?
Sure I can take a joke.
Some jokes.
Lost any
over your way?
No more than the winter
and the coyotes are to account for.
You haven't got any ideas,
have you Farnley?
Except not to have ideas.
Make that clear.
There are a lot of things
around here ain't clear.
You still talkin'
about rustling?
And strangers.
[ Man Whistles ]
Yippee!.
Looks happy, don't he?
He just needed exercise.
Whenever he gets low in spirits
or confused in his mind...
he doesn't feel right
until he's had a fight.
It doesn't matter
whether he wins or not.
He feels fine again afterwards.
Ain't that guy got there yet?
[ Retching ]
Holy cow! Now I'm gonna have
to start all over again.
Somebody's sure in a hurry.
- Did Darby use his fist?
- [ Chuckles ]
No, a bottle.
- That's all right then.
- Hey, lay off Farnley, will ya?
- Why should I?
- Because you hit him pretty hard.
You made him look foolish.
- Did I really get him?
- I thought you busted his neck.
- No foolin'.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Why, that no good--
- Shot right through
the head, I tell ya.
- Where'd it happen?
- Down in the southeast corner
of the valley...
- about eight miles from his ranch.
- You see him?
No, sir, but Olsen did.
He found him laying
in a dry wash in the sun.
[ Man Continues ]
Shot right through the head.
- [ Farnley ]
When?
- Well, about 2::00.
He must've
been shot a lot earlier.
They picked his horse up...
- clear over near the ranch road.
- Any cattle missing?
They couldn't tell.
There been so many working
that range down there.
- Olsen send you for us?
- No, he's in such a hurry...
he just yelled at me
to go get the sheriff.
Hey,Jeff,Jeff--
- Rustlers?
- Looks that way.
- Who was it they got?
- Kinkaid.
Kinkaid? Farnley's buddy?
Yeah. They've been working together
ever since they were kids.
All the way from
the Panhandle toJackson's Hole.
Sure, I knew him.
Short, dark Irishman.
Didn't say very much.
Liked to sing a lot.
These fellows will go
a long way to get the guy
that killed Larry Kinkaid.
Lynchin'?
I judge.
- Got plenty of sand
but when he's mad, he's crazy!
- Wait, wait,Jeff. No rush.
Even if they have got
a five-hour start.
It's a good 500 miles
to the first border.
Besides, there may
be a bunch of'em.
It won't help Kinkaid now
to get yourself killed.
That kid, Greene, got no
idea which way they went.
Better wait till we
know what we're doing.
We're all with you about Kinkaid.
You know that.
Only, we ought to take our time
and form this posse right.
So if we go, we're sure
to get what we go after.
Okay. Make your posse.
Somebody better get
the sheriff first thing.
And Judge Tyler.
Oh, what do we want with
old Tyler and his trials.
Yeah, one good fast job
without no legal papers
and that's all there is.
Remember, this ain't
just rustling. It's murder.
Wait a minute, men.
Don't let's go off half-cocked...
and do something
we'll be sorry for.
We want to act in a reasoned
and legitimate manner.
Not like a lawless mob.
Trouble with you, Davies,
you've been storekeepin' too long.
You don't see
no profit in this.
If any of you fellas had offered
to buy the rope from him--
If we go, you're going
with us, fat gut.
Brother, I wouldn't miss it.
Only thing that'd bring me out
any faster would be your necktie party.
Who knows,
maybe this is yours.
I'll remember that
and see you handle the rope.
In Texas where I come from,
we go and get a man
and string him up.
That's right.
I say stretch 'em.
It ain't just a rustler
we're after. It's a murderer.
Larry Kinkaid, one of the finest,
most God-fearing men that ever lived...
is lying out there right now
with a bullet hole in his head.
If you let this go by,
there won't be nothing
safe around here.
Our cattle, our homes.
Not even our womenfolks.
I'm with ya, Farnley.
I'm going to get me
a gun and some rope.
I'll be right back.
And if nobody else
will do it...
me and you
will do it ourselves.
Count me in too!
Come on, boys.
Get your guns!
Listen to me, men!
Don't lose your heads like this.
You mustn't do this thing.
You must not!
Shut up, Grandma.
Nobody expects you to go.
Don't take it so hard, Mr. Davies.
You did all you could.
- Will you do me a favor, Carter?
- That depends.
I'm sending Joyce here
for the sheriff and Judge Tyler.
I want you to go along
and help explain.
You know how Art and I stand here.
We came in at a bad time.
I've got to stay here
and see if I can't...
stop 'em till they realize
what they're doing.
If I can make this thing regular,
that's all I ask.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Oh, wait a minute.
- Do you know Mapes?
- The one they call Butch?
Yes. The sheriff's made him deputy
for times he's out of town.
And we don't want Mapes.
Well, they said I was
to be the executioner,
so I come all fixed.
Think I don't know
my business, huh?
[ Gagging ]
You don't look very well,
Mr. Davies.
Maybe you'd better stay home
and rest up for the funeral.
Maybe you could get the flowers.
Boys wouldn't begrudge
a few flowers, even for a rustler.
So long as he's a good dead one.
[ Laughing ]
Get your hat and gun.
I'm not going, Father.
I don't wish any argument.
Do as I say.
Perhaps this will do what
I've obviously failed to do--
make a man of you.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Scrape your boots,
put your hat on your hand
and straighten your wig.
- Well?
- Why, is the judge at home, ma'am?
- Yes.
- Can we see him?
You got business?
No, we just
dropped in for tea.
Very funny.
Mr. Davies sent us, ma'am.
It's awfully important.
It's not
regular office hours.
That the judge's
better half?
His housekeeper.
His wife's dead.
Well, you can see why
there's times when...
the judge don't seem to be able
to make up his own mind.
[ Man ]
Come in!. Come in!.
He says come in!
Well, well, Carter,
how are things out
in your neck of the woods?
- All right, I guess,Judge.
- You don't appear to have been...
pining away, exactly,
since last I saw you.
- And what can I do
for you gentlemen?
- We're here for Mr. Davies.
Oh. How is my friend Davies?
Well, I trust.
Yes, but could we see you alone
for a minute,Judge?
- Oh, a matter of a private nature, eh?
- Yes, sir.
[ Art ]
Mr. Davies said particularly
just you and Sheriff Risley.
- Risley ain't here.
He deputized me.
- Where'd the sheriff go?
Down to Kinkaid's ranch
early this morning.
When will he be back?
He didn't say.
Couple of days maybe.
But anything you can tell him
you can tell me.
Sure, we know that, Butch,
but we're here for Mr. Davies.
If the judge thinks
it's your job, he'll tell you.
Certainly, Mapes, certainly.
All right. But if
it's a sheriff's job, call me, see.
Naturally.
Well, what can I do
for you gentlemen?
[ Horses Galloping ]
Ain't so much that Mr. Davies
don't want 'em to go.
It's just he wants to make sure
a posse's sworn in to bring
him in for a fair trial.
That's why we wanted
you and the sheriff to hurry.
Confound it, men.
The sheriff's not here.
Today of all days.
You can talk to them.
They'll listen to you.
No. No, no, that's not my job.
I haven't any police authority.
- Where are you going, Mapes?
- There's a posse forming,
in case you hadn't heard.
That's sheriff work, ain't it?
That's no posse. That's
a lawless, lynching mob.
It'll be a posse
when I get there.
I'm gonna deputize
them all proper.
But you can't do that.
Risley's the only one
empowered to deputize.
[ Sizzles ]
Should we tell Davies
you're coming,Judge?
Yes. Yes, of course.
I suppose I'll have to.
But doggone it, this is
the sheriff's job. Not mine.
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
Coming along, Sparks?
No, sir, Mr. Smith.
I don't guess so.
Oh, you better
come along, Sparks.
Ain't every day we have a hanging
in a town as dead as this one.
You won't have to do nothin'.
All the real work's signed up.
I just thought we ought
to have a reverend along...
'cause there's gonna be
some prayin' done.
Maybe you're right, Mr. Smith.
Maybe somebody ought to go along
that feels the way I do.
[ Smith ]
Davies'll loan you his Bible...
so all the reading will be
done right at the burial.
Thank you, sir.
But I knows my text
without the book.
They're kidding you, Sparks.
I know, sir.
But maybe Mr. Smith's
accidently right.
Maybe I ought to go along.
There's an old horse
in my shed you can use.
Thank you, sir.
I'll go and fetch it.
Ya-haw!
Here comes Ma!
- [ Cheering ]
- Come on! We're ready to go.
Hiya, boys!
[ Indistinct ]
Whoa. Well, boys,
what are we waitin' for now?
Judge Tyler.
Davies asked him to come over.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
I understand
how it is, men.
My old friend Larry Kinkaid,
one of the finest and noblest--
Cut the stumpin', Tyler.
All we want
is your blessing.
Of course you can't flinch from what
you believe to be your duty.
But certainly,
you don't want to act hastily...
in the same spirit of lawlessness
that begot this foul crime.
Ah,Judge, before you get
ready to act...
them rustlers will be
clear down over the Rio.
One more word, Smith, and I'll
have you up for impeding
the course of justice.
Judge, you can't impede
what don't move anyway.
[ Laughing ]
And you,Jenny Grier, a woman...
to lend yourself to this.
- Ha!
- [ Laughing ]
Now, listen.
Listen, men.
I've just found out
that Sheriff Risley's
already down at Kinkaid's.
- That right,Judge?
- Yes. He's been there all morning.
Yes. So you see,
probably everything's...
being attended to
right now, legally.
All you'll get out of it
is a long, hard ride.
It'll be dark before long
and mighty cold.
My advice is to come inside,
Have a drink...
and let's wait till
we hear from the sheriff.
Drinks on the house.
But only one round. I'm not
filling any bucket bellies.
- I'll make it two.
- Any of you fellas wanna
stay in town, I can take six...
if you don't mind
sleeping doubles.
[ Davies ] It's not like
you were giving up, boys.
It's just good sense.
[Judge ]
Farnley, come back!.
I'm not asking you!
I'm telling you!
You don't have to worry,Jeff.
This business is going
to be taken care of.
Yeah, and I know who's
gonna take care of it. Me.
I tell you now, whoever shot
Larry Kinkaid ain't coming
back here for you to...
fuddle with your lawyers' tricks
for six months.
Then be let off because Davies,
or some other whining old woman...
claim he ain't bad at heart.
Kinkaid didn't have
six months to decide
if he wanted to die.
Disbanding, men?
[ Ma ]
Davies has just about
convinced us, Major Tetley.
- Of what, Mr. Davies?
- Why, of-- of--
I take it you were acting
on the assumption...
- the raiders left
for the south draw.
- Yes, of course.
They didn't.
- They went east by Bridger's Pass.
- That's through the mountains?
[ Tetley ]
Over the old stage road
to Pike's Hole.
- But that's 8,000 feet up.
- [ Tetley ]
Approximately.
They'd be crazy
to go that way.
Not so crazy perhaps,
Mr. Davies, knowing
how crazy it would look to us.
How come
you're so sure, Tetley?
Pancho saw them.
He was coming back from Pike's.
- Had trouble getting
by them in the pass.
- Si. He not see me, I think.
So, he was headed down the hollow
and I drive my horse out of the way.
At first I think I say hello.
And then I think it's funny
how to drive the cattle then.
- Cattle?
- Sure.
- Why do you think I had
to get out of his road?
- Go on.
When I see what mark
those cattle had,
I be very, very quiet.
- [ Mapes ] What kind of marks?
- Oh, in the throat.
Three little whatchamacallem.
That's Kinkaid's mark.
- The dirty rats!
- [ Clamoring ]
- How many were there?
- Forty head.
- I mean rustlers.
- Three.
Why were you so long
in bringing us this word, Major?
I knew my son
would want to go along.
He was out on the range.
Major Tetley,
you mustn't let this
be a lynching.
It's scarcely
what I choose, Davies.
Promise me
you'll bring them in
for a fair trial.
I promise that I'll
abide by the majority will.
Tetley, you know what's
legal in this case as well as I do.
[Judge ]
All we ask is a posse...
to act under a properly constituted
offiicer of the law.
That's where I come in.
Risley made me a deputy.
In that case, Mr. Mapes,
suppose you deputize the rest of us?
That's not legal.
No deputy has the right to deputize.
- How 'bout it, boys?
- Suits me, Butch.
Go ahead and pray.
Mapes, you're
violating the law.
Raise your right hands.
I hereby solemnly swear that
I am duly sworn in as a deputy...
in the case of the murder
of Larry Kinkaid.
And am willing to abide by
the decisions of the majority.
So help me God.
- Say ""I do.''
- [ All ]
I do.
Tetley, you bring those men
in alive. Or as I'm justice
of this county...
you'll pay for it
and every jack man
in your gang!
- Tetley!
- You coming?
Get my horse.
I'm going with them.
Then get down to Kinkaid's.
Get the sheriff.
We'll stop here
for a minute, gentlemen,
and breathe our horses.
Winder, take one man with you,
go up to the top of that ridge...
and see what you can see.
Doin' this in the middle
of the night's crazy.
I thought
you liked excitement.
I got nothin' particular against
hangin' a murdering rustler.
It's just, I don't
like doing it in the dark.
There's always some crazy fool
to lose his head...
- and start hangin' everybody in sight.
- Us?
- Funnier things have happened.
- Well, we didn't have to come.
It'd looked kind of funny
if we hadn't, wouldn't it?
Besides, I like
to pick my own bosses.
Whether we picked them
or not, we sure got 'em.
That's what I don't like.
That Smith and Bartlett
shootin' off their mouths.
Farnley...
and that renegade Tetley.
Struttin' around his uniform
pretending he's so much.
He never even saw the South
till after the war.
Then only long enough
to marry that kid's mother
and get run out by her folks.
Figured there was something
fishy about him dressing up like that.
Sure. Why do you suppose
he'd be living in this
neck of the woods...
if he didn't have
something to hide.
Let's get out of here before
we all freeze to death.
Or else give it up.
We'd be the laughingstock
of the country if we went home
on account of cold.
That's right.
But I'm telling you...
this rope's gonna
have to be thawed out
before it's fit to use.
Mind if I come in
a little closer, Mr. Carter?
No, come on. I'm finding it
kind of lonesome myself.
-Powerful cold tonight, ain't it?
- I got a blanket if you want it.
No. Thank you
just the same, Mr. Carter.
But it takes all my hands
to stay on this old horse.
- Better have
a couple of shots.
- I never use it.
I sure wish we was well
out of this here business.
Ah, it's a way
of spending time.
It's man taking on himself
the vengeance of the Lord.
[ Snickers ]
You think the Lord cares
much about what's happening
up here tonight?
He marks the sparrow's fall.
I seen my own brother
lynched, Mr. Carter.
I was nothin'
but a little fella.
But sometimes now,
I wakes up dreamin' about it.
Had he done what they...
picked him up for?
I don't know. Nobody never
did know for sure.
[ Inhales, Exhales Slowly ]
Well, a couple of shots more whiskey
can't do my soul any harm.
Darby sure sells rotten liquor.
Warms you up though.
Feels like fire
creepin' in the short grass.
I guess I'll just let her
spread a little while.
[ Farnley ]
Put out that light,you fool.
You wanna give us away?
Who to?
Chuck that butt
or I'll plug you.
Start something.
For every hole you make,
I'll make two.
Looks like you're gonna have
a lot of shootin' to do, Mr. Farnley.
Listen, something's coming!
Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa.
Hyah! Hyah, hyah, hyah!
Fools! Stop him! Stop it!
- What's the matter, Art?
- Shot.
- Where?
- Left shoulder.
You fool, you must be drunk.
Nobody but a drunken idiot...
- would drive down a grade
in the dark like that.
- I thought it was a stickup.
If those horses weren't
a sight smarter than you...
that coach would be
at the bottom
of the canyon right now.
[ Ma ]
Rose Mapen!.
Hello, everybody.
This is my husband,
Mr. Swanson of San Francisco.
And, uh, my sister-in-law,
Miss Swanson.
- Did you just get married, Rose?
-Just today.
[ Laughs ]
No wonder you were
in such a hurry.
[ Ma Cackling ]
My name is Tetley, sir.
I can understand why
Miss Rose is in a hurry...
to show the other ladies
what can be done
in the way of matrimony.
- Thank you, sir.
- Say, what's everybody doing
up here this time of night?
[ Clears Throat ]
Why, uh--
Art's shot.
[ Clamoring ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
- Gee, I'm sorry.
- [ Art ]
You couldn't tell.
You hadn't ought to come
barging out like that.
In the dark especially.
I couldn't tell who it was.
Everybody yelling like that.
Aw, shut up!
Here. I'm good
at this sort of thing.
[ Art ]
Look, do women
have to watch this?
[ Art Screams ]
[ Davies ]
There's room in the stagecoach
for you, Art.
Yeah, I better get you
on back to Darby's and get
some hot food into you.
- I'm all right.
- Come on. Be a good boy.
Don't be stubborn.
- Yeah, don't be a fool.
- Mind your own business!
Bring his horse over,
will ya?
- She's his wife now and kind of new.
- Yeah, looks that way, don't it?
I take it you've had
the privilege of knowing...
- Miss Mapen before
she became my wife.
- That's right.
And possibly you imagined
at the time there was some
understanding between you?
Yeah, sure.
- My wife is a very impulsive woman.
- That's what I'm saying.
Needless to say,
I'm pleased to regard...
any friend of my wife's
a friend of my own.
However, I don't need to
remind you that the pleasure
of such an acquaintance...
depends upon the recognition
by all parties...
of the fact that
Miss Mapen is now my wife.
She must be given
a little time...
to become accustomed to her
new responsibilities.
As yet, I must
confess that I'm jealous
of her least attention.
You'll forgive me, I know.
A bridegroom is prone
to be overly susceptible for a time.
Later, when we've had time
to get accustomed
to our new relations...
I shall be delighted
to welcome you and others
of my wife's friends...
to our home
in San Francisco.
If it is still her desire.
Until then--
Why, that superior little--
Looks like Rose's took
onto herself a lot of trouble.
Giddap! Giddap!
[ Gunshot In Distance ]
[ Cattle Mooing ]
- Where are we?
- The Ox-Bow.
There they are, gentlemen.
I suggest we avoid any shooting
or rough work until they've had
a chance to tell it their way.
Mr. Mapes and I
will do the talking.
- The one that got Kinkaid
is mine. Don't forget that.
- He's yours when we're sure.
[ Tetley ]
Ten men will go with Mrs. Grier
and come up from behind.
Bartlett, take six men
and work through those woods
in back of the cabin.
Gerald, you and Farnley
and the rest will go with me.
Would you
like a gun, Mr. Davies?
- No, thank you.
- Sparks?
Thank you.
No, sir, Major Tetley.
As you choose.
- Get up!
- Drop it!
Now put up your hands.
No sabe.
It's all right, brother.
You will.
[ Yawning ]
[ Groans ]
Take it easy, mister.
Stay where you are
and put your hands up.
Gerald,
collect their guns.
- What do you want?
- Shut up! We'll tell you
when we want you to talk.
This ain't no stickup, brother.
This is a posse if that
means anything to you.
But we haven't done anything.
Gerald!
Get 'em up!
[ Tetley ]
Tie them up!.
- Get in--
- All right, get in there.
Well, at least
you might tell us what
we're being held for.
- I'd rather you told us.
- [ Horses Approaching ]
Well, we must be pretty important.
Or else awfully dangerous.
It ain't that
you're so dangerous.
It's just that most
of the men ain't never seen
a real triple hangin'.
A hangin'?
What have we done?
Aren't you even gonna tell us
what we're accused of?
- Rustlin'. Ever hear of it?
- Rustlin'?
And murder.
Murder?
Oh, Mr. Martin,
what did we do?
It's all right, Dad.
There's some mistake.
Remember me?
- [ Grunts ]
- He's talkin' to ya, mister.
- No sabe.
- He don't speak English.
- I got a different notion.
- I'll make him talk.
- That'll do, Farnley!.
- Listen, your wife had enough
of you playin' God Almighty.
Who picked you
for this job anyhow?
We got him. I say
let's swing him before
we all freeze to death!
You cold? Here's a fire.
Warm yourself.
And I'll advise you
to control your tongue too.
We'll get along better.
- Who's boss of this outfit?
- I am.
- And your name?
- Donald Martin.
- Where you from?
- Pike's Hole.
- That's a lie!.
- This gentleman's
from Pike's Hole.
Would you like
to change your story?
I just moved in three days ago.
I'm on Dave Baker's place
up on the north end.
Dave Baker moved out
four years ago,
and the place is a wreck.
The barns are all fallin' down
and the sagebrush is stickin' up
through the porch.
Well, I bought the place
from him for $4,000
in Los Angeles last month.
- [ Laughs ]
Then, mister, you was robbed.
- Well, that may be.
But surely it's not so far
to Pike's Hole you can't go
over there and find out.
My wife's there right now...
- and my two kids.
- That's really too bad,
just too bad.
Even in this godforsaken country,
I've got a right to a trial!
You're getting a trial with 28
of the only kind of judges...
murderers and rustlers
get in what you call
this ""godforsaken country.''
So far, the jury
don't like your story.
Well, I'm not
gonna say another word
without a proper hearing.
[ Ma ] Suit yourself.
But this is all the hearing
you're likely to get...
short of the LastJudgment.
Have you any cattle
up here with you?
Hey, Mr. Martin?
[ Gagging ]
[ Laughs ]
I'm not gonna
ask you again.
- Yes, I have.
- How many?
- Fifty head.
- Where did you get 'em?
From Mr. Kinkaid.
That's just
what we figured, son.
I'm no rustler though.
I didn't steal 'em!
I bought 'em
and paid hard cash for them.
My own cattle were so bad,
I didn't want to risk bringin' 'em up.
So I sold them out at Salinas,
and I had to stock up again.
Well, you can wait can't ya,
till you can see Kinkaid?
- Or ask about me
over at Pike's Hole.
- That's a good one.
He's wants us to wait
and ask Larry Kinkaid.
Gotta hand it to ya, Martin.
You're a cool one all right.
You know as well as we do,
Kinkaid can't tell us anything.
- He's dead.
- Dead?
What do you think
we're up here for?
Well, how should I know?
He was all right yesterday afternoon.
Listen. Why don't
you stop this farce
and take us in!
'Cause the law's
slow and careless
around here sometimes.
We're here to see
it's speeded up.
- Who sent you up here?
- The sheriff.
-[ Gil ] That ain't true!.
-[ Smith ] Let's don't get
started again.
- It's gettin'late.
- The sheriff didn't
even know we were comin'.
I beg your pardon.
I should have said
the deputy sheriff.
Listen, men.
I'm not trying to obstruct justice...
but just as this young man says,
this is a farce.
And it'll be murder
if you carry it through.
All he's asking is what
every man's entitled to--
a fair trial.
You say you're innocent, Martin,
and I, for one, believe you.
[ Ma ]
Then I guess you're
the only one, Arthur.
If there's anyjustice
in your proceedings, Tetley...
it will only be
after a confession.
And they haven't confessed.
They say they're innocent...
- and you haven't proved they're not!
- Shut up!
- [ Punch Landing ]
- Have you a bill of sale
for those cattle?
Well, no, I haven't.
But Mr. Kinkaid said
it would be all right.
I couldn't find him at the house.
He was out on the range!
He didn't have
a bill of sale with him.
He said he'd mail it to me.
Moore. How long you been
ridin' with Kinkaid?
- Six years.
- Ever know him sell cattle
without a bill of sale?
N-N-No.
Can't say that I ever did.
[ Sniffles ]
Course, I can't remember
every head he sold in six years.
- But it's customary for him
to give a bill of sale?
- Y-Yep.
Ever know him to sell
cattle after spring roundup,
this or any other year?
I can answer that.
I heard him say myself
just a couple of days ago...
- he wouldn't sell a head
to nobody this spring.
- Well?
I know it looks bad giving a dead man
for a witness, but it's the truth.
- You don't believe me.
- Would you in my place?
I'd do a lot of finding out,
before hanging men
who might be innocent.
If it were only rustlin'
maybe, but-- but murder?
No.
[ Ma ]
What are you tryin'to do,
play cat and mouse with 'em?
I would prefer
a confession, Martin.
[ Sobs ]
If you've got any doubts,
I say call off this party.
Take 'em back toJudge
like Davies wants.
This is only slightly any
of your business, my friend.
Remember that.
Hangin's any man's business
that's around!
If your stomach for justice
is coolin', Carter...
I'd advise you to leave now
before we proceed any further.
Otherwise,
your interruptions are gonna
become very tiresome.
- I still don't like it!
Hangin' murderers is one thing,
- Take it easy.
but to keep guys
you don't know for sure did it...
standin' around sweatin'
while you shoot your mouth off...
- that's another.
- Take it easy.
This ain't our picnic.
If you keep on buttin' in,
I got a hunch it might be.
You called
this old man, ""Dad.''
Is he your father?
- No.
- Speak up, man.
You're taking it like a woman.
Keep your chin up.
You can only die once, son.
- No. He works for me.
- Uh-- U-Uh--
- I didn't do it.
I ain't even got a gun.
- Then who did?
Uh, uh--
The Mexican did it.
He told me so.
Eh, no--
Uh,
I-I saw him do it.
Juan couldn't have done anything.
I was with him all the time.
Uh, yes, he did,
Mr. Martin.
He was asleep,
and he didn't mean to tell me.
But I was awake, and...
I-I heard him
talkin' about it.
The old man's feeble-minded.
He doesn't know what
he's talking about.
He invents things.
Well, if you've
got to go through
with this filthy comedy...
-you can at least
let him alone, can't ya?
- Shut up!
Lay off,Mapes!.
First, he won't talk.
Now he talks too much.
What's his name?
Alva Hardwick.
- And the other?
-Juan Martinez.
No, it ain't.
Still don't remember me, eh?
I'm talkin' to you, mister.
- No sabe.
- The devil you don't.
Your name's Francisco Morez,
and the vigilantes would
like to get ahold of you.
He was a gambler.
They want him for murder.
- How about that?
- I don't know.
Stick together nice,
don't they?
Why do you keep asking me
all these questions? You don't
believe anything I tell you.
There's truth in lies too,
if you can get enough of them.
What do you know
about the old man?
I don't know,
he-- he was in the army.
- Confederate or Union?
- I don't know. He's not
clear about it himself.
Maybe both...
at different times.
A half-wit
in the army?
Attention!
- Oh, he's forgotten.
- Not that.
I'll make a deal
with you, Martin.
Tell us which of you shot Kinkaid,
and the other two can wait.
- None of us killed anybody.
- Then that's all, I guess.
- Bring 'em along.
- You don't mean you're
gonna do it, really?
- Pull!
- You got to wait, I tell you!
- You got to give us some time!
- [ Men Chattering ]
You've got to give us some time!
You got to listen to us!
- We haven't done anything.
- Throw the other rope up.
Remember,
the Mexican's mine.
My kids--
One of'em is just a baby.
Just a little baby,
and they haven't got a thing
to go on! Nothing!
I've got to write a letter!
If you're human, you'll give me
time to write a letter!
- That ain't askin' much.
- They're scared and trying
to put it off, that's all.
Yeah. You want Tyler
and the sheriff to get here
and the job not done?
- They won't come in time.
- I believe you're right, Mr. Davies.
Though I doubt
if you want to be.
What time is it?
Five minutes after 3:00.
All right. We don't want to give
anyone cause for complaint.
With your permission, gentlemen,
we'll wait... till daylight.
Bring 'em back.
That'll give you time, Reverend...
to finish your business at leisure.
Sure. And them time
to think it over.
- I can't write like this.
- Very well, untie them.
[ Speaking Rapidly
In Spanish ]
He's says he wants to eat.
He's much hungry
from so much of the talk.
Thank you.
Why, look!
Fresh beef.
Oh, Ma.
Fix up a spread for everybody.
Can't call it stealin',
because at the time of death
there won't be any owners.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Chatter, Laughter Continue ]
olol[ Harmonica:: ""Red River Valley'"]
olol[ Continues ]
What are you
thinkin' about?
The sheriff--
he's an awful long time
gettin' anywhere.
Suppose he don't
get here at all?
That's what
I'm thinking.
- olol[ Continues ]
- [ Murmured Conversations ]
[ Ma Cackling ]
[ Man Laughing ]
d There's a great camp meetin' d
d In the Promised Land d
d Walk together, children d
d Don't you get weary d
- olDon't you get weary ol
- [ Ma Cackling ]
ol There's a great camp ol
- olMeetin'in the Promised Land ol
- [ Cackles ]
olA line to meet your Savior ol
olDon't you get weary ol
olA line to meet your Savior--ol
I'm not disputing
that fact, Mr. Davies.
It may be a fine letter.
But if it's an honest letter,
it's none of my business to read it.
And if it isn't,
I don't want to.
- Is that my letter you're showin'?
- Yes.
What right have you got
to show my letter?
- Don't raise your voice, rustler!
- He's right, Smith.
-I told him I'd keep it for him.
-I asked you to make sure
that it was delivered.
I'm sorry. I was just trying
to prove that you were--
It's enough to be hanged
by bullying outlaws...
without having your private thoughts
handed round to them for a joke.
I said I'm sorry.
I was merely trying--
I don't care
what you were doing!
I didn't write that letter
to be passed around!
- It's none of these
murderers' business!
- I made no promise, son.
I thought there was
one white man among you.
But I was wrong.
- Give me my letter.
- I'll see that she gets it.
Oh, I wouldn't have her
touch it now.
In that case,
give him back the letter.
Your wife ought
to hear from you, son.
None of us could be as kind
and understanding as this letter.
She'll want to keep it...
for your children.
- I'm sorry.
- [ Ma Shouting ]
Hey, the Mex!.
- [ Gunshots ]
- Spread out! He might have a gun!
Mapes. Winder.
Keep an eye on those two.
[ Gunfire Continues ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Sound of Gunfire
Fades Into Distance ]
[ Gunfire Stops ]
- Where's he hit?
- In the leg.
Here's his gun.
Well,
I guess we know now, don't we?
Look.
- Say, that's Larry Kinkaid's gun.
- Where did you get this?
Somebody will take this bullet
out of my leg, I'll tell you.
Ha!
So he speaks American!
And ten other languages,
my dear.
But I don't tell anything
I don't want to in any of them.
My leg, please.
I wish to stand upright
when you come to your pleasure.
- Somebody lend me a knife.
I'll take it out myself.
- Don't give him no knife.
He can throw a knife better
than most men can shoot.
Better than any of you,
no doubt.
But if you're afraid, I promise
to give the knife back...
handle first.
I'll do it.
[ Fabric Ripping ]
He's very polite, but has
no stomach for blood, eh?
dd [ Singing, Indistinct ]
olol[ Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
That was very fine shooting,
my friend.
You should try again
with that one.
[ Murmuring ]
- Now where'd you get that gun?
- Found it.
- Where?
- Lying in the road.
- You're a liar.
- I thought we might find
somebody to send it back by.
You're a liar!
And you're a blind fool.
I asked you
where you got it.
No sabe.
- Well, that's the truth.
He did find it.
- Undoubtedly.
Won't you even read it?
Is it because you've
made up your minds?
Or you believe
everybody else has...
and you're afraid to stand up
for what you feel is right?
You heard what Martin said
about showing his letter.
What does it matter
to the man or his wife
who sees this letter...
if it saves him
from hanging?
It's a beautiful letter.
Read it, and you'll know...
- he's not the kind of man
who could steal or kill.
- Maybe.
But all that kind
of argument in the world
can't stand up against...
branded cattle, no bill of sale
and a dead man's gun.
Gentlemen, I suggest
we act as a unit...
so there will be no question
of mistaken reprisals.
Mr. Davies...
are you willing
to abide by majority decision?
- How about the rest of you?
- Sure. Majority rules with me.
Everybody with Mr. Davies
in putting this off and
turning it over to the courts...
step over there.
Excuse me.
Seven.
Not a majority, I believe,
Mr. Davies.
[ Tetley ]
Any other message
you'd like to leave, Martin?
[ Sobbing ]
I-- I don't wanna die.
- I'd like to make a confession.
- I didn't do it.
- And about time.
- To a priest.
There's no priest here.
This man can hear me
and take it to a priest.
- [ Old Man Whimpering ]
- All right. Get along with it.
I don't want to die.
- I don't want to die.
- Bring him along.
[ Old Man Sobbing,
Protesting ]
I didn't do anything.
I didn't--
That must have been
an awfully busy life.
[ Pancho, Mexican
Praying, Indistinct ]
[ Chattering ]
Farnley, you,
Gabe Hart and Gerald...
- will whip the horses out.
- No, not me.
Any volunteers?
I'll do it
if no one else will.
- I won't do it.
- You'll do it.
- I-- I can't.
- We'll see to it that you can.
The kid's seen enough already.
Why don't you let him alone?
This is not your affair, Carter.
Thank you just the same.
I'll have no female boys
bearin' my name.
You'll do your part...
and say nothing more.
- What did he say?
- I ain't no priest.
For God's sake, man.
At least say whether
we'd better wait.
Well, I ain't no priest.
I don't know.
[ Sobbing ]
No, thanks.
[ Sobbing Continues ]
I'll give you
two minutes to pray.
[ Praying In Spanish ]
[ Prayer Continues ]
Time's up.
Will you find someone
to look out for my wife
and children?
Take some older woman along.
It's not going to be easy.
- Your family will be all right.
- My parents are dead,
but Miriam's live in Ohio.
Kinkaid didn't want to sell
those cattle, so maybe his wife
will buy them back...
- for enough to cover their travel.
- Tie 'em up!
[ Martin ]
I suppose it's no good telling
you again we're innocent.
- No good.
- It's not for myself I'm asking--
Other men with families
have had to die for this.
It's too bad,
but it's justice.
What do you care
about justice?
You don't care
if you've got the right men!
All you know is somebody's
got to be punished!
There's nobody to look out
for them in a strange place.
Can't you understand that?
This is a fine company
for a man to die with.
- Shut up! You shut up!
- You shut up!
[ Overlapping Shouts ]
Get 'em off me!
Pull that guy off.
Come on. Tear 'em loose.
Don't let 'em do that.
- Stop it! Stop it, you fools!
- Aw, you stop it!
[ Tetley ]
Keep him there!.
All right.
Put them up.
- [ Old Man Protesting ]
- [ Chattering ]
- Miriam.
- I don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
[ Muttering Prayer
In Spanish ]
Anytime you're ready,
Mr. Mapes.
[ Gunshot ]
Finish him.
[ Sparks ]
ol You got to go through
the lonesome valley ol
ol You got to go
there by yourself ol
olNobody here
can go for you ol
ol You got to go
there by yourself ol
d Oh, you got to stand
before your maker d
d You got to stand
there by yourself d
d Nobody here
can stand for you d
ol You got to stand
there by yourself ol
ol Oh,you got to ask
the Lord forgiveness ol
ol You got to ask
him for yourself ol
olNobody here
can ask him for you ol
ol You got to ask
him for yourself ol
ol Oh,you got to go
to the lonesome valley ol
ol You got to go
there by yourself ol
olNobody here
can go for you ol
ol You got to go
there by yourself olol
Hey, there!
What's all that shootin' about?
[ Mapes ]
We got 'em, Sheriff.
- It's all right.
Everything's been attended to.
- What are you talking about?
Kinkaid's murderers,
we got all three of'em.
Yeah,
and we hung 'em too, Sheriff.
- Aaah!
- Larry Kinkaid's not dead!
- Not dead?
- But we just--
I just left Larry Kinkaid
with the doctor at Pike's Hole.
- Caught the fellas
who shot him too.
- But, Sheriff.
They had Larry's
cattle down there.
They even had his gun.
Give me that badge.
Mr. Davies, I know you
well enough to know...
that you didn't have
anything to do with this.
I'm depending on you
to tell me who did.
All but seven.
God better have mercy on ya.
You won't get any from me.
All right. Let's go.
If you've got
no objections, Mr. Davies...
I'd like to read
Martin's letter now.
It would be a good idea
if a lot of people read it.
If you ask me, that Tetley's
the one we ought to lynch.
You're a great one for hangin',
ain't ya, Smith?
[ Locked Door Clicks, Rattles ]
[ Rattling Continues ]
You loved it.
That's why you kept them
waiting so long.
I saw your face.
It was the face of a depraved,
murderous beast.
There are only two things
that have ever meant
anything to you--
power and cruelty.
You can't feel pity.
You can't even feel guilt.
You knew those men
were innocent,yet you were
crazy to see them hanged...
to make me watch it.
I could've stopped you
with a gun,just as any animal
could be stopped from killing...
but I couldn't do it
because I'm a coward.
[ Laughs ]
Aren't you glad
you made me go, Father?
Weren't you proud of me?
How does it feel to have begot
a weakling, Major Tetley?
Does it make you afraid
that there may be
some weakness in you too...
that other men might discover
and whisper about?
Open the door, Major.
I want to see your face!.
I want to know
how you feel now!.
[ Gunshot ]
They're getting up a pot
for Martin's wife.
Even Mapes chipped in.
I didn't know
he was showin' his face.
He ain't.
He sent it by Sparks.
That reminds me,
I put in $25 bucks apiece for us.
- How much they got?
- About five hundred.
Hmph. Not bad for a husband
who don't know any better...
than to buy cattle in the spring
without a bill of sale.
Maybe you ought to read
this letter too.
You know I can't read.
I'll read it to ya.
""My Dear Wife, Mr. Davies will tell you
what's happening here tonight.
""He's a good man and has done
everything he can for me.
""I suppose there are
some other good men here too...
""only they don't seem
to realize what they're doing.
""They're the ones
I feel sorry for...
""'cause it'll be over
for me in a little while...
""but they'll have to go on rememberin'
for the rest of their lives.
""Man just naturally can't take
the law into his own hands...
""and hang people
without hurting everybody
in the world...
""'cause then he's notjust
breaking one law but all laws.
""Law's a lot more than
words you put in a book...
""or judges or lawyers or sheriffs
you hire to carry it out.
""It's everything people
ever have found out
about justice...
""and what's right and wrong.
""It's the very conscience
of humanity.
""There can't be such a thing
as civilization unless people
have a conscience...
""because if people
touch God anywhere...
""where is it except
through their conscience?
""And what is
anybody's conscience
except a little piece...
""of the conscience
of all men that ever lived?
""I guess that's all
I've got to say except...
""kiss the babies for me
and God bless you.
Your husband, Donald.''
olol[ Organ:: ""Red River Valley'"]
Where are we goin'?
He said he wanted his wife
to get this letter, didn't he?
Said there was nobody
to look after the kids, didn't he?
olol[ Continues ]