Previously on AMC’s Hell on Wheels…
- She soot a man.
- You are the law.
You arrest the church lady
for shooting Sidney Snow.
Sidney's bleeding out.
He needs a doctor.
In the event he dies first, it must be
seen that she's held accountable.
This here is "Dandy" Johnny Shea.
And from this day forward,
he is the new proprietor
of this establishment.
He's dead, isn't he?
I'll figure a way out.
You do swear by almighty God,
the searcher of all hearts,
that the evidence you
give shall be the truth,
the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth,
as you shall answer to
God on the last great day?
In the matter of the United
States versus Ruth Cole,
the defendant stands
accused of unlawfully, feloniously,
and of malice aforethought
shooting into Sidney snow
two mortal wounds of which he died,
contrary to the law, peace,
and dignity of the Wyoming territory.
Having heard these charges, what say you?
Guilty.
Miss Cole,
in my hand,
a written statement by
head of Railroad Police,
Cullen Bohannon.
He says you aided and
protected an officer of the law
from an armed felon.
This would not only prove you innocent,
but mean you saved a life, if not several.
Now, this court asks a second time.
What say you?
I say I am guilty.
Ruth, don't do this.
- Ruth.
- Order, sir.
Miss Cole, it is unclear to
me whether you're of fit mind
to defend yourself.
I move for a continuance to afford miss Cole
time to acquire proper counsel.
I murdered that man, Governor.
Not out of fear, nor aiding the law,
but for no purpose other
than to end the man's life
who took my son's.
I am guilty. I have pled so.
Mm.
You, Ruth Elizabeth Cole,
are guilty of murder
and shall be hanged by the neck
until you are dead tomorrow.
[Crowd murmuring]
May God have mercy upon your soul.
[Gavel bangs]
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
Have the gallows constructed
in the town square.
A public execution?
Transparency, judge,
followed by a strict adherence to the law.
A death warrant should be drawn up.
Do it.
No mistakes.
You got nothing to gain by this.
I gave miss Cole every
opportunity to acquit herself.
Her refusal to do so means
that justice must be served.
Hanging a grieving mother,
that don't serve nobody.
Neither does allowing a
confessed murderer to walk free.
No one is above the law,
not even a church lady.
Then pardon her.
You got that power as governor.
I do,
but a pardon must be affirmatively accepted
by the guilty party to be
recognized by the courts.
The woman in that courtroom
did not appear interested in clemency.
I get her to accept a pardon,
you'll sign it?
With pleasure.
The law requires the noose go on tomorrow.
All right, keep your guilty plea.
Take your stand.
Then you'll accept a
pardon from the governor.
The governor hasn't pardoned me.
He'll give you one. He told me so hisself.
I never asked for that.
Hanged by the neck until dead.
Did you hear him in there?
Pardons are for cowards like Sidney snow.
Taking a pardon,
that ain't a coward's choice.
Dying is.
Either way, the choice is mine.
And my choice is no.
[Piano music playing]
♪ ♪
My father was a judge.
After a bad ruling,
well,
he'd sneak out and take my mother dancing.
Do you waltz?
I haven't come to dance, John.
Come on.
It's simple.
A waltz requires a man to lead.
I've never excelled in that arena.
I've come for comment on the kangaroo court
you authorized on your arrival
and your acquisition of McGinnes'
casino thereafter.
Ancient history, miss Ellison.
I prefer to call it context.
This is the story I won't like?
It starts and ends with a
federally-approved hanging.
I extended miss Cole a pardon.
If she should refuse,
that would be her decision.
Mr. snow's appointment to marshal,
I suppose that was her decision as well?
And his subsequent burning of her church.
We are all complicit, John.
Men with power and money are guilty,
while a woman with no currency
except her own convictions
is set to hang.
Burn this city down,
you'll have no friends left but the ashes.
Exactly as much as Ruth Cole.
You'll cast her as some Saint?
I'm still deciding on the devil.
Come on, ain't got time to waste.
Train leaves in five minutes.
Train?
For New York.
Mary, my first wife,
still got folks in the city.
I sent them a telegram.
They said you could stay with them
till you get back on your feet.
I'm not going to New York.
Yes, you are.
I'm putting you on that train.
You're putting this behind you.
I won't be a fugitive from the law.
No one will come after you.
You'll disappear.
That'll be that. You can start fresh.
The only life I have is here.
Yeah, I thought that once in Mississippi.
Train ride changed all that.
I intend to stay and accept
the consequences for what I've done.
You'll stay, and you'll die. And for what?
Teach everybody some lesson
about right and wrong?
It's not your responsibility to save me,
Mr. Bohannon.
You're getting on that train.
- I've made my decision.
- Yeah?
Well, I just unmade it.
What? No, no. [Stammering]
Let me go.
- Come on, you're leaving.
- No.
No!
I was ready to leave
after Sean died.
I was ready to go back to Omaha with Ezra.
You asked me to stay.
And I stayed for you.
This time, I stay for me.
Bohannon.
Delaney is quite capable
of putting the final pieces
in place if you need to be somewhere else.
I'm right where I need to be.
[Grunting]
Son of a bitch.
When we lost my only son to cholera,
I was away working.
Do you know where I was
and what I was doing?
No.
Neither do I.
There ain't nothing I can do for Ruth.
The thing to do is be with her.
[Train whistle blows]
The church lady's not gonna hang.
The casino you can keep.
But if you think you can prevent
me from enforcing the law
through intimidation,
you haven't been paying attention.
If Ruth Cole sees an early grave,
you best be digging too.
She refused my pardon offer.
There's nothing else I can do.
You'll find a way.
I'm sure of it.
Step aside.
[Grunting]
[Melancholy music]
♪ ♪
Why don't you go get a drink, Dutch?
I couldn't sleep.
Me neither.
Would you do anything different
if you could go back?
[Hammering]
I would be a better husband,
a better father.
I would be more patient with Ezra.
[Chuckles]
They don't get more patient than you.
Boy didn't make it easy on you,
setting fires,
rustling horses,
kicking frogs.
What I would give for
a church full of frogs.
I'd let the both of you go to Omaha.
I don't blame you.
I would kill Sidney snow.
So would I.
After the war,
I found myself walking the streets of D.C.
What were you doing in D.C.?
There was this crowd
outside a federal building.
Political rally, I thought.
Some senator speaking on national unity.
Come to realize it wasn't a rally.
It was a execution.
They march this poor bastard out
and read him his rights.
I swear, it felt no different than
you and me talking right now.
Civilized, even.
But his...
His neck didn't snap right, and...
We spent ten minutes
just watching him choke.
I know what you're doing.
Piss ran down his leg at five minutes in.
The shit come at eight.
The worst part was the
popping sound his neck made.
It was like a firecracker
on the fourth of July.
And there I am,
in the nation's capital,
watching this...
Savage...
Act.
They call it civilized.
There wasn't no civility to it.
You won't scare me out of this.
There ain't no worse way
to leave this world, Ruth.
Burning alive is worse.
I hated the sight of you
when you came back to Cheyenne...
The three of you.
I got myself wound up so tight that day.
I stormed out of the church
and trudged through the mud and the rain.
And I saw your tent,
and I was ready to say it all.
But what you don't see
when the anger grabs hold over you
are puddles.
Giant ones in the street.
One wrong step, my feet slipped,
and I fell hard into the mud.
[Chuckles]
What I thought was mud,
but then I smelled it.
It was...
Well, horse...
Shit?
[Laughing]
It's not funny.
Oh, what'd you do?
What else could I do?
I walked back through town.
Covered in...
[Laughter]
No walk has felt so long in my life.
When I got back, Ezra was there.
You know what he said to me?
[Laughing] "You smell like shit."
[Laughs]
Well...
[Laughter]
What did you tell him?
I told him, "Don't say 'shit, '"
and went and washed myself off.
That was God answering my prayers.
He was telling me I already
had a family of my own,
Ezra and me.
[Sighs]
Still, I don't know
why it took you so long to come see me.
I didn't want you to explain.
I just wanted to see you.
I never thought you'd show
up at the church that night.
[Sighs]
I'll always show up, Ruth.
Come on out here.
Just to the window.
Come on.
This town needs their preacher.
I'm nobody's preacher anymore.
The hammering stopped.
Mm.
Hmm.
They finished.
Yeah.
It's almost dawn.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
But do you love me?
I can't lose you, Ruth.
I love you.
I was a coward.
I should've told you how I felt.
I should've taken you and made you mine.
The three of us could've been a family.
Do you love her?
It's all right. You can say.
I don't know.
You always know,
deep down.
I think I might.
Go to her.
Tell Naomi.
I don't know if she'd have me.
The brave choice is always family.
Come on, get up.
[Solemn music]
♪ ♪
[Footsteps]
Cullen.
[Gasps]
Mr. Bohannon, please step out of the cell.
Just... just give us a minute.
The law requires the death warrant
be read aloud the morning of the execution
by the officer on duty.
You asked for this role, Mr. Bohannon.
I didn't ask for this.
Badge on your chest says different.
Miss Cole
will accept her pardon now.
Is that right, miss Cole?
No, Mr. Campbell.
I won't be party to this.
Cullen.
Say you'll be there.
Please.
[Door opens and closes]
13 coils,
hemp, from St. Louis.
It's the only kind I trust.
Your hair, ma'am.
- [Sniffs]
- It's the oil.
Sees the knot don't catch.
March you out five minutes before,
exactly five minutes before.
There will be a crowd.
You don't got to worry. I'll be there.
13 steps up to the platform
where I'll tie your hands
and your feet first.
Noose comes next.
The hood is last.
Will it hurt?
Daddy never hung nobody before
who come back to have it done over.
You don't got to worry.
I'll be there.
[Sniffs]
There's $50 in an account
in the Cheyenne bank
and a pile of clothes at the laundry.
See that they're donated to
the Council Bluffs mission.
Wallace comes in to talk on Tuesdays.
Someone should look in on him.
Tomorrow's Tuesday.
A pittance and some laundry.
You're forgetting about
a city full of people
who you've touched.
You have my word they won't forget you.
You're writing an article about me?
Don't.
It won't be remembered, and neither will we.
It's time.
Is there anything you need?
Anything at all?
Have you seen Mr. Bohannon?
I haven't.
But I can find him.
No. Thank you.
[Somber music]
♪ ♪
[Camera flash snaps]
[Breathing unsteadily, sniffing]
[Whimpering]
Looser, please.
No, ma'am.
Wait!
♪ ♪
Any last words?
[Sniffling]
[Panting]
[Fly buzzing]
[Rope twisting]
[Unsteady breathing]
[Footsteps]
[Heavy breathing]
All aboard, train to Council Bluffs!
All aboard!
Final call!
We're ready to escort miss Cole's body
to the Council Bluffs Mission.
Buried her this morning.
She's with her son.
God hasn't given up on this place yet.
This wasn't God's doing.
"The railroad may be America's dream,
"but what's left behind in
Governor Campbell's Cheyenne
is a nightmare."
This is how you see Cheyenne?
I told you you weren't going to like it.
I thought we shared a vision
for what this city could be.
The only vision that I have is
a poor girl swinging from a rope.
What befell miss Cole was a tragedy,
but printing this won't bring her back.
The governor controls a great many things.
The press is not one of them.
I'm not asking you as governor.
I've always been a terrible dance partner.
By this time next week,
you'll be back covering America's dream,
having authored
nothing substantial but
the end of a relationship.
This is far more important, John.
In your nightmare, I'm a monster?
Enjoy your ashes.
Everybody back out of the way.
[Steam hissing]
[Metal clicking]
The pressure's too high.
Yeah!
[All cheering]
All right. All right.
All right,
y'all quit your yapping
and get back to work.
Heard the man. Back to work.
[Reverberating din]
I'm afraid the champagne and cigars
will have to wait until
we've taken the summit.
Send for 300 workers from Omaha to lay track
and two trainloads of lumber from Chicago.
Oh, and throw up a wire to general Grant.
Tell him we'll summit before month's end.
Well, what is it, Bohannon?
I quit.