Previously on AMC’s Hell on Wheels…
I will do whatever's necessary
to rid this city of corruption,
then seize your railroad.
My name is [Speaks comanche]
I got magic!
- I made you a fortune!
- And it costed me everything!
You can sell me, and get Eva back!
You are not savage, you are not like them.
Jessup is dead.
This baby needs four walls
and a door that locks.
[Cow mooing]
[Whispering] Shh, shh, shh.
Hey.
What you looking at, huh?
You need to get on from this place.
Good morning to you too.
I've been praying the
blood of Jesus over you,
the missus, and the baby.
But I ain't strong enough
for whatever coming next.
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Me and them... they can bury
us in that blowed-up Mountain.
Yeah, well, I got an idea about that...
That don't matter none.
You and her and the baby...
You still got a chance.
Go.
Yeah.
Come on.
[Door closes]
Durant...
Open up.
Need to talk.
Dur...
Hello?
Doc?
- Hey, whoa. Hey. Hey.
- [Shouting]
Easy. It's me... Bohannon.
Here...
Here, drink this.
Somebody left you for dead.
Did you see 'em?
It was one of Campbell's men.
Well, scalp's gonna need some stitches.
Best get you to the doctor.
No. No, no, no, no.
There's...
There's a kit in the desk.
Sew me a couple of field knots, will you?
[Groaning in pain]
I'm surprised at Campbell.
Mm.
This is gonna hurt like hell.
I want justice.
Oh, damn blast it, Bohannon!
Oh, God.
[Groaning in pain]
The world's catching up to us
in the form of The United
States government.
I've gone up against them and lost it all,
just like you're about ready to.
Shit, that hurts!
Oh!
We're done here, Durant.
You and I both know it.
We only have to get through that mountain.
Over it.
And I'm the only that can do it,
not you, not Delaney...
Nobody but me.
And if I'm wrong, they can bury us
underneath that rock pile out at the cut,
'cause that's where we're headed anyways.
[Groaning in pain]
Aah! [Groaning in pain]
Should have been a surgeon
instead of railroad man.
"Railroad man"?
Looks like it.
What do you need from me?
Sign that.
This is... this is blank.
I may need it.
Trust me.
They come back, they're coming to kill ya.
Not...
If I kill them first...
All of them.
Best set them thoughts aside,
otherwise you'll bring
everything down on our heads.
There are some men who need killing.
You and I both know that, Bohannon.
Uh...
I've drunk from that cup.
It don't quench.
Over the Mountain and out of this place...
I'll get us there.
[Breathes heavily, groans]
[Bird squawking]
Frog legs jump out of the skillet
when you fry 'em up...
Don't they, boy?
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com
***
They're using 'em to dig canals back east.
Now, this is what one looks like.
Fascinating,
but I have no use for a steam dredge,
Mr. Bohannon.
[Chuckles] No. It's me who does.
I wasn't trying to sell you one.
And what are you trying to sell me?
Well, I know you wouldn't loan
Durant the money for this.
[Chuckles] Hell would freeze first.
So I was hoping you'd see
clear to loan us the money
for a down payment.
Hmm.
- You have collateral?
- No, ma'am.
- Stop making me feel old.
- No, Maggie, I don't.
But they're starting to
stockpile barbed wire
in Chicago.
We can send a letter
forbidding union pacific
to ship it west.
That's not collateral...
But I will take it.
Fill it out how you like.
What about for the loan?
Only for your wife and son will I do it.
You need to move them out of here.
You're the second person
to tell me that today.
Oh.
[Door opens, closes]
[Sniffs]
[Footsteps approaching]
God, man, were you kicked by a horse?
One of your men...
I believe his name is Heckard.
What did you do to provoke him?
Provoke?
He broke into my car,
accused me of killing his... his paramour,
and then he tried to kill me.
Oh.
Yes, he's upset at Jessup's passing.
They were very close.
I had nothing to do with Jessup's killing.
And I will enjoy taking
your railroad from you,
but killing you would spoil
the sport of it for me.
I did not send Heckard
to your car last night.
I give you my word.
I want justice.
In this case, I understand.
I'll put Heckard on the  first
train back East this afternoon.
This afternoon?
I want more.
Well, that'll have to suffice.
The man is grieving.
You're lucky to have survived at all.
Good day.
[Sighs]
I can't take any more of this, Abby.
Go over, confront Durant, be done with it.
I don't have the strength. He scares me.
You don't have the strength,
or is it conviction?
There is doubt in your mind.
My own thinking disgusts me.
What if I'm wrong?
We'll never know, Abby.
There was never a trace of your father.
The detective seemed sure.
The detective was here one day.
Go home...
Grieve with your mother,
find some comfort in that.
You're miserable here.
And I'm making you miserable too.
I'll wire you if I discover anything.
Write me letters...
Not too rude, in case mother opens them.
What is it?
[Sniffs] It's harder for you to leave
Durant than it is to leave me.
But... go.
I know you pray for me...
F-for us, and, uh,
I think your prayers have been answered.
I just got the money
for a piece of machinery
to get us over that mountain
and out of this place.
Few weeks,
we won't ever have to see Cheyenne
or the Wyoming territory again.
Or my family?
Will I ever see them again?
If you really wanted to, yeah.
I would really want to.
All right, then.
We'll take the train.
By then, I'll have my own private car.
Your car?
Will the baby and I be there?
That's what I meant.
Cullen!
Elam.
God almighty, son.
Elam...
It's me... Cullen.
Can you see me all right?
I see you in my path.
Looks like something got at ya.
Bear?
I am bear killer.
Yeah.
Yeah, I own that's true
from the looks of it.
So these yours wives?
Huh?
Hey...
I got me a wife.
Can you imagine that?
A son too.
- Elam...
- What'd I tell you?
You want to buy these slave?
Please help us.
You don't speak unless you spoke to.
You want to buy 'em?
Elam...
I don't know what's messed you up,
but don't go riding into
Cheyenne like this.
I'm riding straight in.
Yeah, uh...
Yeah, we got a, uh, auction house.
Slave market?
Yeah. Why don't you
camp yourselves right here?
I'll come fetch you and the slaves
when the market opens.
That sound about right?
Mm-hmm.
All right.
This is a third-class ticket, sir.
[Scoffs]
[Laughter, indistinct chatter]
I got you on two pair.
And you, my friend, are bluffing.
[Chuckles]
I see your dollar.
Come on. This can't wait.
Leave the pot.
You're saving me from a busted flush,
but I'll lose my seat!
Elam's back.
Wait.
Something's happened to him.
I...
Something bad. He ain't right.
Well, take me to him.
Now, you listen to me, Eva.
He's right messed up, especially his mind.
I don't care.
I seen something like it in the war.
Some wounds you don't want to survive.
What are you talking about? It's Elam!
I know! I...
What I'm saying is...
We got to be gentle, all right?
His... his... his remembering is wrong.
He don't seem to know me,
but he might know you.
- I can't believe he's back.
- He may not be back.
[Train whistle blows]
[Woman coughing]
Abby...
What are you doing here?
I'm going home to Boston.
This train doesn't go to Boston.
This is a private train.
We have to get you off.
Uncle Thomas, please.
I have to ask you something.
Why are people saying
you had something to do
with father's disappearance?
People don't think that.
They even say you killed him.
Yes.
I killed your father, Abby.
Would you like to know how and why?
Elam?
Elam...
It's Eva.
It's me.
You been with them arapaho?
Who you belong to?
We used to belong to each other.
Can't no slave own no slave.
Go find your master, unless you a runaway.
Cut your heels for that.
Elam.
How come I want to hurt you?
For something I done to you.
I want you.
And I want to hurt you bad.
I don't blame you.
Now, who own you, I say?
- Nobody.
- You're a liar!
Whoa, Elam. It's all right. It's all right.
I'll come with you if
you let them women free!
- Eva, that can't happen.
- Elam!
Elam, listen to me. Listen to me.
Buying, trading, selling...
That can't happen, all right?
Times has changed. They won't let it.
I won't let it neither.
It ain't up to you.
I don't even know you.
Get up! Get up!
Come on! Let's go! We going to market!
Come on!
On my advice,
he invested your estate's treasury
heavily in Union Pacific bonds.
When we had to default...
He became desperate.
I take the blame.
He was prone to despondency,
as you know, Abby.
He came to me begging for help.
I couldn't.
Then one night he... he simply disappeared.
I can only imagine the worst.
He took his own life?
That's what you want me to believe?
He tried once before, you know.
Ask your mother, Abby.
But he lives on.
He sustains me
through my own nights of the black dog.
Are you lying to me, Uncle Thomas?
[Coughing]
No, Abby.
No.
Did I kill your father by including him
in my railroad dreams?
Will I regret that for the rest of my life?
Absolutely.
Am I a murderer?
Obviously not.
[Train squeals, rumbles]
[Steam hissing]
Is there trouble?
I'll go and check on it, and you stay here.
What I hear bid for these slaves?
Huh?
It's a good breed.
Can we handle the merchandise?
[Laughter]
They breed good.
Why don't you take your
drunk ass and go home,
you black man? [Crowd gasps]
Somebody put a stop to this!
I need to hear a bid.
Somebody give me a bid!
Shit!
- Wait right here.
- Come on!
This a good breed right here.
They make good babies.
They work hard.
Sunup to sundown, they work hard.
Once you separate the
negro from his prisoners
and he refuses to surrender, kill him.
What's your plan?
Separate the negro from the women.
If he should refuse,
then we'll have no choice, but...
Now, hold on. I don't think that's the way.
We don't even know what's going on.
Never hand me again.
There will be no trade in
human commerce in my town...
Neither involving squaw, white women,
nor addled negro.
All right, now, he ain't done nothing.
Contrarily, he's stated his intent
at the most heinous of crimes,
and he is guilty of
kidnapping at the least.
Look at him. He's a
danger to public safety.
[Shouting indistinctly]
Mr. Campbell...
You're a veteran.
You know what violence can do to a man.
Mainly to the weak-minded
and predisposed to violence.
The negro is an inferior race,
but human nonetheless.
That is why we fought your war,
Mr. Bohannon.
The emancipation proclamation,
the constitution...
Those are his rights.
He ain't in his mind.
He'll fight you if he's cornered.
Then that is his choice.
Field the perimeter when he makes a run.
That man right there...
That's my friend.
Okay.
You have 15 minutes to solve this charade.
Hey. What the hell is this?
Your stop.
This ain't no stop!
Hey, what are you doing?
Get your... get your hands off me!
[Grunts]
You're a dead man!
Do you... you know who I am?
Do you know who I am?
I do.
[Grunts]
How did Mrs. Delaney get on the train?
We didn't see her, Mr. Durant.
[Whimpers]
Straight to Cheyenne after this.
[Both grunting]
Look at her. She breed good for you!
- Gone crazy.
- She got everything you want.
She breed good and get you good business.
- What you gonna do?
- Get over here.
[Whimpers]
Look at her.
I'm gonna retell him who he is.
- Elam?
- [Screams]
Get over there!
Elam!
Look hard at my face, all right?
Cullen Bohannon.
I hear of you.
[Softly] Yeah.
[Normal voice] We been friends a long time.
You got some slaves to sell?
That there one of yours?
This ain't a slave market.
This ain't Charleston, new Orleans neither.
This is Cheyenne.
You even know where you are?
[Crowd gasps]
You trying to fool me?
No.
I'm trying to save your damn life.
Come on.
Y'all get on home!
This ain't a damn show.
Elam: Prime, healthy.
It ain't gonna cost you a lot.
- Beat it, kid.
- Elam: Come here!
- Mr. Campbell.
- Elam: Look at her! This one...
Get!
You've left Mr. Bohannon to
defuse this situation alone?
Interesting to watch Mr. Bohannon
confront the monster of his own creation.
- Interesting?
- Mm-hmm.
Those women's lives are at risk.
I'm well aware.
I've ordered my men not to spook the negro.
His name is Elam Ferguson,
an honorable man.
At least I've known him to be.
Elam: Come on!
Get your head up!
Act like you got some dignity!
You trying to be uppity on me?
You trying to be an uppity negro?
Nothing in his past will save him
from his fate today.
And killing a negro makes
you a little more formidable,
doesn't it?
Elam: They work hard.
Those women's lives are at risk.
We are in agreement on that, are we not?
Elam: I need to hear a
bid for these slaves now.
They're worth more than that.
Just keep in mind,
you'd be walking into five drawn guns.
Come on, now.
Do I hear a bid for these women?
Get up. Look at me. Good lord.
Look at them. Show your face.
- What do you do? What do you do?
- Elam!
My brother.
[Both laughing]
Oh, I knew you'd know me.
Mm-hmm. Heard you was back, huh?
- It's good to see you.
- You too.
You about finished here?
I need... I need you to
get something for me.
Anything.
Run to the big house and tell mamma
to get me something for my head.
It's starting to hurt.
- Go ahead and run.
- Sure, Elam.
She most likely in the
kitchen right about now.
Now go on ahead.
Why don't you come with me, huh?
Be faster.
No, shoot, man.
You know what'd happen
if the missus catch me
round the big house.
Now go on.
Come on, I got business.
Elam.
God, please listen to me.
The men here gonna kill you
you try to sell these women.
I know.
They gonna try.
Something they don't know...
Can't nobody kill me, mo.
Nobody.
What's my name?
Moses Then.
Go on ahead, man.
Go. Come on.
Time's up.
Elam, Elam!
It's Eva!
Just let me talk to him
one more time, please!
I know it's me he wants underneath.
I know it. Just let me talk to him!
Eva, he's liable to kill you.
I don't care. I'll take my chances.
Laws exist to protect us,
not only from others, but from ourselves.
Gentlemen. Man on the roof with a rifle.
Ms. Ellison, do something!
- There's nothing I can do, Eva.
- Time's up, Bohannon.
You're talking to the Governor.
Please say something to him.
I'm just a newspaper lady.
I don't have the authority...
But it's Elam! It's my Elam!
These women's lives are at risk, Eva.
You think it best he be killed, don't you?
Don't you?
Now, you need to listen to me right now.
Hey!
You got to let these women go.
There's men drawing down ready to shoot.
Elam!
My name is...
[Speaks comanche]
"Bear killer."
I got bear magic.
Your name is Elam Ferguson.
Railroad police.
Lawman.
You and me,
we had some times.
Put down some bad men.
We found your lost baby. You remember that?
We even beat the hell out
of each other one time.
Friends always.
You owned slaves.
[Whispers] Yeah.
Long time ago.
You was a slave yourself,
but you're free now.
Everybody's free.
Even these women right here, they're free.
[Groaning]
Elam, let me help you, all right?
- Let me help you.
- [Grunts]
Hey, hey. Hey.
Hey, it's all right.
[Groans]
It's all right.
Listen to me.
Why don't you...
Why don't you give me that knife, huh?
It's all right. Hey, hey.
Let's let these women go. What you say?
Here.
[Yells] [Crowd gasps]
No! [Groans]
My name is [Speaks comanche]
"Bear killer."
I got big magic.
I got big magic!
Cullen!
Get out of there!
$100!
I bid $100. I got money.
Can't no slave buy no slave.
I told you that.
What about trade, then?
Please, Elam. Take me, and I'm yours.
- For God's sake, that's her.
- Quiet, woman!
- The woman!
- That ain't her!
Eva, the one you're looking for,
she's right there!
- That ain't her!
- [Groans]
I told you that ain't her! It ain't her!
I told you!
Elam!
Come on, get up.
Come on! Come on, get!
[Whimpering]
Don't run away from me!
- Don't run!
- Let's go. Go.
They mine!
You need to get on your horse and ride.
Can't promise you they won't shoot,
but I'll cover you as best I can.
You ain't my boss.
No, I'm your friend.
You a white devil.
You ain't did nothing but
took from me and mine!
- No.
- You're gonna pay today!
You're gonna pay!
[Both grunting]
Don't do this, Elam.
I ain't gonna fight you.
[Both grunting]
[Crying]
Somebody go get him his damn horse!
[Mooing]
Get up, Elam!
[Groans]
Wake up.
Wake up!
Come on.
[Both grunting]
I'm sorry.
[Screams]
[Sobbing]
He went looking for you.
[Baby coos]
What give you the right?
Huh?
You saw.
[Shouts] What give you the right?
Whoa.
Please...
Put Mr. Ferguson in the wagon.
[Shouts]
You want to come?
He ain't in that box.
[Clicks tongue]
Cullen.
Please go away.
Please.
[Grunting]
[Kicking coffin]
[Breathing heavily]
[Sobbing]
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com