- Hey, morning.
- Hey.
Hey... is that my jacket?
I left that at Heather's.
All right, Officer Sherlock.
Yeah, I slept at Mary's the other night.
Heather told me to give you this.
She also told me to give you this.
What the hell you do that for?
Well, now it's
awkward 'cause I kissed you,
not 'cause I'm banging
your girlfriend's mom. [clicks tongue]
You know what, I ain't
gonna be super-interested
in joking about this for a while.
Look, Colt... [sighs] Sorry
if it's awkward for you,
but I'm really into Mary.
That being said, you are my brother,
and if you want me to stop datin' her...
just say it.
I want you to stop datin' her.
All right, bluff called.
Seriously though, man,
if you want me to give up my chance
at a happy relationship and die alone
just 'cause it makes
you a little uncomfortable...
you just say so.
Thank you, I appreciate that.
Shit, bluff called again.
All right, look...
if you're serious about Mary,
and you promise not to screw things up
with me and Heather...
it's your life, I'm not
gonna be an asshole about it.
Cool.
And for the record,
I give you my
blessing to date her daughter.
Oh, hey, uh...
I heard old Kenny proposed to Abby.
Yeah. Why, you wanna date her, too?
Been there, done that.
So... them getting
engaged, that mess you up?
No... I'm fine with it.
You should've seen the
ring though, too big.
Yeah...
Women hate when things are too big.
Yeah, and he proposed to
her at the Cracker Barrel.
I mean, who does that?
Uh, lots of people.
Rich Weiner proposed to Allie there,
Jeff proposed to Leslie.
I proposed a
threesome to the Flet sisters.
They proposed I go fuck myself.
Later that night, I took
'em up on that proposal.
Let me ask you a question...
I texted Mary a couple
of times last night,
she never hit me back.
Check this out. Uh, 1:12...
"'Sup, girl? You up?"
Nothing. 1:27...
"You down to clown? I'm around."
Nothing.
1:45, I pull out the big guns, right?
I sent her this video of a cat
who's scared of a cucumber. [chuckles]
I mean, how is that not
worth at least one "LOL"?
Apparently, we got different ideas
about what the "big gun" is.
- Mornin', Dad.
- Mornin'.
Hey, what time is that buyer comin'?
He's not. I called him off.
- We're not sellin'.
- What?
Cattle prices are at rock bottom...
Anderson sold last week. They
didn't even turn a profit.
We're not gonna sell right now.
We're gonna hold out.
Are you serious? I... When
were you plannin' on tellin' us?
To be honest...
If I'm not looking right at
you, I try to forget you're here.
Dad, we don't have any electricity!
[stammers] We gotta
sell. You ever see The Shining?
Jack Nicholson killed his entire family
with an ax. You know why?
They didn't have a TV!
Look, we can't afford
to keep the calves.
We can't even afford
to keep the lights on.
What are we gonna do for
the winter, huh? I mean...
me and you, we can eat
Colt. What are the cows gonna eat?
I didn't work my ass off all year,
so I could go in the hole.
We can hold on a little
while, things will turn.
And what if they don't?
Maybe you two can get a second job.
[Colt] Ugh.
There aren't enough hours in the day
to take on more work.
We should take what we can get now
and keep our heads above water.
All right, look, I
don't normally say this,
but Rooster's right.
You know, I don't normally say this,
but I don't give a shit what you think.
You say that all the time!
[theme song playing]
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -
Damn it.
We both saw that. Colt did it.
[Dale] Beau, you in there?
If I say no, will you go away?
I see you're as chipper as ever.
What are you doin' here, Dale?
I heard that you might be
thinkin' about not sellin'.
- How'd you hear that?
- Huh?
Said, "How'd you hear that?"
I hear everything.
I think you're makin' a big mistake.
Look, Dale, don't tell
me how to run my business.
I don't tell you how to run yours.
Well, that's all you do! The
last time I was out here,
you tried to tell me how
to castrate a bull.
I'm not gonna sell, Dale.
Look... we're getting
up in age, both of us.
Now I'm 73 years old,
and I don't know if you knew it or not,
but I'm beginning to lose my hearing.
Really? I had no idea.
Yeah, it's just a Timex, but thank you.
And look, at your age,
do you really want
to take on this fight?
You know, what they're
offering is criminal.
I'm not sayin' you're wrong.
Look, you deserve a lot more,
but a little is better than nothing.
For all you know, the
market might keep going down.
You don't think I know that?
What are you gonna tell me next?
Sky is blue? Water's wet?
Next thing out of your
mouth is gonna be "What?"
What?
Look, just make the sale.
Go inside, turn your power
on, enjoy your family.
If this is your last winter on Earth...
do you want to spend
it without television?
I'm not selling. Say
hi to Charlene for me.
Well, suit yourself.
You know, your gate's busted.
Colt did it.
Mmm-hmm. He also clipped
your mailbox on the way in.
Hey, Ab.
Hey.
[sighs]
You still got time to
take a look at my truck?
[grunting]
Yeah. [sighs]
What was that noise it's making, again?
[mimics engine growling]
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I remember.
I just wanted to hear you
do that bad impression again. [chuckles]
Why don't you do an impression
of a guy who's not a jackass
and just fixes my truck?
[laughing]
So, what's going on with you?
Well, Dad decided he didn't
want to sell the calves.
Why?
Said he wanted to hold
out for better prices.
Same thing he used to say when I used to
bring over the Girl Scout cookies.
[Colt chuckles]
Well, let's take a
look at that truck, huh?
Yeah.
[grunts]
Look at that rock. Whoo!
Guess that's what Kenny's Marriott
money gets you, huh?
Yeah, he went to Jared. [chuckles]
You know, about the other night,
that wasn't how I wanted it to happen.
What's that?
Me finding out or
you getting proposed to
at a Cracker Barrel?
[laughs
sarcastically] It was actually sweet.
And they gave us 20 bucks to
spend in the general store.
We got a big bag of those sour rolls.
- [exhales] So good.
- [chuckles]
Anyway, if it was awkward for you...
I'm sorry.
[grunts]
Why would it be awkward?
Well, it was weird for me.
I mean, I didn't expect to get engaged
in front of my ex-boyfriend.
- [laughs]
- Although I do have this dream
that I get married to Channing Tatum
in front of every
guy who ever dumped me.
Kenny's a good guy.
He's smart, he's got a great job.
I'm sure he's got one of them 400k's.
It's 401k.
[scoffs] Even better.
Look, you guys are great together.
I think you'll have a long,
happy life here in Garrison.
Unless Channing Tatum shows up
to shoot the Colt Bennett story.
- [chuckles]
- Peter Dinklage is gonna play Rooster.
[motorcycle approaching]
Oh, hey, Mary.
Nice hog.
Hey, Colt. You cheatin' on my daughter?
'Cause I will murder you.
No, no. No, no... No,
no. This is, uh, Abby.
She's my ex-girlfriend.
We hang out sometimes.
That does not sound better, does it?
Mmm-mmm.
Hi, I'm Mary. Nice to meet you.
Actually, we've met. I was
Heather's history teacher.
Oh, yeah! How'd she do?
[smacks lips] Well, she
wasn't my worst student.
I'll take it.
[chuckles] Oh,
damn! Look at that Harley.
I did not think you could
get any more awesome.
Hey, if you can name three
Denver Broncos, I'll marry you.
Peyton Manning, CJ Anderson,
Emmanuel Sanders, Demaryius Thomas.
Whoo! I'm gonna pass out.
Rooster, can we, uh, go inside?
You know we can.
Oh, Abby, by the way... congrats
on that engagement.
Is it cool if I bring Colt's
girlfriend's mom to your wedding?
Uh, okay.
[Mary chuckles]
I have a name, you know?
Yeah, I know. Sorry about that.
It just pisses off Colt a shit-ton
more when I do it this way.
So what's up? Did you get my text?
My sexy pics come through?
Yes, Rooster, I got the
picture of your balls.
Thank God. I thought I sent it
to the other Mary in my phone.
Sister Mary from Immaculate Heart.
Okay, we need to set a
few ground rules here.
Number one being, don't send me
pictures of your fucking balls.
Yeah, everyone sends dick pics.
The Rooster sends ball pics.
'Cause it's funny and sexy.
No, uh-uh. It's stupid and disgusting.
Agree to disagree.
Listen, if you think
you're interested in
and capable of being in
an adult relationship...
- I do.
- Then... Okay.
You say that, but you texted
me a picture of your balls.
I did.
Yeah. Do you... do you see how those
two things might not go together?
I don't.
No, I'm kidding. I'm
kidding. But, you know, I mean...
You're asking me to change who
I am, you know? It's like...
you date the Rooster, you get the beak.
I'm fine with the beak. I
just don't want the balls.
You think about it.
If you decide you want to give this
a real shot, you give me a call.
- Wait, you're leaving?
- I got the dinner shift.
You just came over here to talk?
See, that's what...
that's what adults do.
All right, well, before
you leave, can you, uh...
name off a couple more Broncos?
Von Miller...
Brandon McManus.
[chuckling] Oh, my
God. You know the kicker!
[Mary chuckles]
[country music playing]
[Maggie singing along]
[gasps]
You scared me. Why are you
standing there like a creep?
I like listening to you sing.
That's sweet.
Still creepy, but sweet.
Did you bring the rolls?
Oh, didn't think I had to mention
that they needed to be baked.
But dinner will be in 12 to 15
minutes or until golden brown.
How're you doin'?
I called off the calf sale.
Whoa. You sure you wanna do that?
I'm not sure about anything.
I'm dead tired.
Boys have been working
hard. They deserve a break.
Don't tell 'em I said that.
I won't, but you should.
They need to hear that you
think they did a good job.
I'll put it in my will.
They think I should sell.
Dale thinks I should sell.
Based on your reaction,
I guess you feel the same way.
Maybe I'm just being stubborn
in my old age.
In your old age?
Beau, you've written in Ronald Reagan
the last three elections.
My gut's telling me to hold out longer.
Then trust it. It's gotten you this far.
What about us, Mags?
You comin' home?
Okay.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Maybe it's time to give it a shot.
Even if you are a broke old man.
We said in our vows
for richer or poorer.
No, we actually didn't say vows.
I read a poem by Robert Frost,
and you said, "Yep."
I still feel the same way today.
Do you?
Yep.
Sorry I didn't answer your texts.
I had my phone on silent
'cause my sister was passed out.
I didn't wanna wake
up her baby. [chuckles]
If you add a pick-up
truck and an American flag,
you get yourself a
country song. [chuckles]
Can I ask you something?
Yeah, what's up?
Just... you were acting kind of weird
after Kenny and Abby got engaged.
Is there something going on there?
No. Me and Abby is just friends.
Yeah, but you kept saying they
don't belong together and...
I just don't think you were talking
about the chicken and waffles.
Look, there's nothing
going on with me and Abby.
I'm just saying,
if you saw me acting like
that with an old boyfriend of mine,
you'd have some questions.
No, I wouldn't. I'd believe you
when you said there
was nothing going on.
So just drop it.
All right, it was just a question.
- You don't have to be a dick.
- [scoffs] I'm not being a dick.
I'm in a great mood.
My ex-girlfriend got engaged.
The ranch's running out of money.
My brother's dating my girlfriend's mom.
Old Colt's doin' great!
All right. You know what?
I hope you are upset about
them gettin' engaged.
Otherwise, you're just an asshole.
I'm not upset.
I swear, I'm just an asshole.
- [Rooster pounding at door]
- Colt, wake up.
Dad, wake up. Get your ass out of bed.
This is not a drill.
This better be North
Koreans, or I'm shooting you.
What the hell? Is it fire or zombies?
If Rooster got bit, don't
wait for him to turn.
Just shoot him now!
What are you doing sleeping
out on the porch?
I don't like vomit in
my own bed, smart guy.
This better be good.
I was horseback
riding with Channing Tatum.
Why'd you wake us up?
Listen, "State of emergency declared
after EPA spill in Animas River."
- [Maggie sighs]
- Let me see that.
I can't read that.
Keep going.
Uh, says the EPA was trying to reinforce
the dam, and they screwed up and...
they spilled a couple million gallons
of poisonous sludge in the river.
God, thousands of ranchers draw water
from that Animas River.
Those poor people.
Damned disaster. Could be good for us.
- I know, right?
- [Colt] Yeah, it is.
Why?
Nobody's gonna buy their cattle
off contaminated grounds.
Yeah, of course.
So?
- So our calves are gonna be worth...
- A lot more money!
Yeah, way ahead of you, Dad.
That's a tough way to make
it but we need the money.
This looks like a real mess.
But, hey, we're
still gonna throw a party
when we sell the calves, right?
Oh, we'll do a little something.
[Colt laughing]
Man, we're gonna have money again.
Hear that, little buddy?
We're gonna fix you up real good.
I'm gonna buy separate shampoo
and conditioner. [chuckles]
Fuck you, Pert Plus. [laughing]
- [tapping]
- Excuse me.
I know we're all
having a good time, but...
I'd like to take a minute and
acknowledge all the ranchers
that are affected by the spill.
Let's just be thankful we came down
on the side of grace on this thing.
Yeah, and hopefully, the EPA will
step up. But, in the meantime,
10% of every drink
you buy over at my bar
will go out to help these folks.
Finally, reason to feel
good about my drinking.
[Mary chuckles]
We don't pay.
Shut up, Colt.
Hey, Mom. This is Mary.
Hi, Mary, nice to meet you.
Hi, you, too. Your son is great.
The son I'm dating.
Not the son who's dating my daughter.
He's... he's great, too.
Small towns, huh?
[chuckling]
- Dad, you guys know each other.
- Hey, Mary.
Yeah, between the Cracker
Barrel and the bowling team,
first time I've ever seen you
without your name on your shirt.
- [Mary] Oh.
- Wow, look at that tie.
Yeah, just got it. Now I got three.
One for funerals, court... and other.
I might have mentioned
- it's time to grow up a little.
- [chuckles] Well...
Hey, then I'm already a fan of yours.
Now, can you tell him that crumbs
left in his beard are not leftovers?
Ah...
Don't you think he'd look
good without the beard?
[laughs] All right, you
guys are done talking.
There's Abby and that little guy.
His name is Kenny. You've
met him a dozen times.
Don't care and won't remember.
How you doin' there... Kenny?
- Hey.
- Hey, Abby.
- Sir.
- Congratulations, you two.
Aw, we're really excited.
Oh, come on, tell me the
story. How did he ask you?
Oh, well, it's not the
most, uh, romantic place.
We were at Cracker Barrel.
Oh, well, who the hell am I to judge?
Beau started his proposal to me with,
"Oh, before I forget."
Got the job done. Am I right... Kenny?
- Yeah, Beau.
- Mr. Bennett will do.
Yes, sir.
You all have fun.
Especially you... Kenny.
- [both chuckle]
- Your ex-boyfriend's family's so cool.
Yeah, they're great.
I didn't even know Mr.
Bennett knew my name.
It's awesome.
- Hi, sweetie.
- Oh... hey, Mom.
You know what, it's weird.
I always thought you and
Abby would end up together.
Yeah, well...
shit happens.
I also thought I'd have
four Super Bowl rings by now.
Two MVPs.
A Nationwide commercial.
[in sing-song] "Colt Bennett's
so damn handsome."
It's okay to be upset about Abby.
It's hard to shut the door on someone
you've loved for a long time.
But, darling, you don't
wanna miss what's right here
because you can't let go of the past.
I'm glad I've only had a six-pack.
I'd like to remember some of that.
Well, look who's here, Heather.
You must not have screwed it up too bad.
How'd you know I screwed it up?
You, a girl... Just playin' the odds.
That's fair.
Got any motherly advice for me?
- Don't fuck it up again.
- [chuckles]
- Hey.
I'm... I'm really sorry.
Yeah, you should be.
I'm glad you came.
I wasn't gonna miss
this over a little fight.
Plus, my sister's kid was
having a tantrum and...
I figured if I have to
deal with a screaming child,
it might as well be you.
You've got yourself
another country song.
- [laughs]
- Look...
I, uh...
The thing with Abby caught me off guard.
My feelings for her are all in the past.
If you were around 15 years ago,
maybe you'd have
been my first girlfriend.
Hmm.
Except, 15 years ago I was eight.
Hey, math is still not my friend.
[Heather chuckles]
- Look, neither one of us want drama so...
- Yes.
Why don't we just start being
honest with each other?
All right, agreed. Which reminds me...
the other night, when you
were storming out of that bar...
Mmm-hmm.
I checked out your ass.
- [laughs] You're such an idiot.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- [Colt exclaims]
He's at the ten!
He's at the five. Touchdown, Bennett!
Kenny and Abby go wild.
God, this family is cool.
Do you think I should grow
a mustache like Mr. Bennett?
No.
- Congratulations, Beau Bennett.
- [bottles clink]
It's good you trusted your gut.
It just proves I should
never listen to anyone.
Everything proves that to you.
God, what a year, huh?
Colt comes home...
all of our rough spots...
the ranch.
Feels good to get a win.
Well, you deserve it.
We both deserve it.
It's your ranch, too.
Oh, thanks for saying that.
I love you, Mags.
I love you, too.
Hey, now that everything's
turned around, you know...
all we have to do is fix our kids.
What do you mean?
Well, somebody's gotta make them
into mature responsible adults.
One miracle at a time.
I think I'll go back to the Airstream
and I'll get my stuff together.
Need a hand?
No, I... You got Rooster, and Colt,
and a whole bunch of alcohol.
Somebody better stay here and make sure
the place doesn't burn down.
You're all right, Hank?
Been better.
I lost my job at the EPA today.
Man, that was a fun day.
Yeah... we deserve
it after such a shit year.
It wasn't that bad. You
know, I came home this year.
- I said what I said.
- [Colt chuckles]
I don't understand why we're
wastin' time talking to each other
when we can be inside making
quality time with the new TV.
You know, I ask an
awful lot of you boys.
[sighs] Fact is...
I couldn't have done it without you.
Thank you.
Beau Bennett... best
rancher in the state.
Mmm-hmm.
[country music playing on radio]
[Colt sighs]
- It tastes different.
- It's the good stuff, that's why.
Nah, it ain't the whiskey.
I mean drinking while happy.
I got something for you.
My championship ring?
Oh, that's cool.
Fifteen years of free
labor, I never abandoned you,
I don't need nothing.
Dad...
you didn't have to do this.
I know the calf sale went
well and all, but...
you shouldn't be throwing
around this much money.
All right, I wasn't
gonna say this but...
the guy at the pawn shop
threw that in with the TV.
I'm just kidding you. I paid for it.
But it was heavily discounted.
[grunts]
Where are you goin'?
Goin' to help your mom.
[sighs] Hey, we're
happy she's moving back in.
Yep, really happy for you, Dad.
- [door slams]
- [engine starts]
[sighs]
All right, he's gone.
Let's go watch TV.
Yep.
- Hey, Maria.
- Hey, Beau.
- Maggie around?
- No, she left a while ago.
She told me to close up.
- All right, thanks.
- Mmm-hmm.
Well, that's gotta be a new
record for breaking a TV.
Well, if someone would
learn how to catch a ball.
Well, maybe you should've taken that
Orlando quarterback's arm
instead of his girlfriend.
If the ball hits your
hands, you make the catch!
That Abby?
Yeah... the hell does she want?
Probably me.
Sorry, Abby, I'm taken.
- [Colt] Hey, Ab.
- Hey.
Hey... you notice anything?
Yeah, it's the new tie.
Can I, uh, talk to you, Colt?
If you're looking for a
compliment on those bangs,
you can keep on waiting.
So your truck stopped
making that noise, huh?
- [mimics engine growling]
- [chuckles]
- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- You want something to drink?
- [smacks lips] Uh...
Nah. Nah, thank you.
Suit yourself.
What do you want to talk about?
[chuckles nervously]
I'm not really sure.
[both chuckle]
It's just, uh... you ever, um...
think about where you're
gonna be in 20 years?
- [sighs]
- [Abby chuckles]
Probably sitting on this porch...
watching Rooster and Mary's
kids play with my kids...
who are also cousins and brothers
and sisters and her grandkids.
Sorry... I don't know why I came here.
What do you mean?
I was just driving around and...
[chuckles] I'm not even
sure where I was going but...
I ended up here.
[Abby] Hmm.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
But...
I keep...
gettin' all these pictures in my head...
of where I'm gonna
be in 20 years and, uh...
[clicks tongue]
And?
I'm not sure Kenny's the
one I'm supposed to marry.
[somber country music playing]
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -