( theme music playing )
Man's voice:
Wake up, Dolores.
Do you remember?
( heart beating )
( woman clears throat )
Woman:
We're about to arrive.
May I take your glass?
Woman on P.A.:
Now approaching
arrival terminal.
Where we're going,
she's a two.
You're being an asshole.
No, I am being myself,
which was the whole
point of this trip.
Unless this uptight prick
is who you really are,
in which case,
feel free to be
someone else.
Fuck you.
Hey, that's the spirit.
What'd I tell you?
Have fun.
Stay safe.
Give me a break.
What?
It's not like
my sister didn't ride
her share of cowboys
when she was here.
You must be William.
Welcome to Westworld.
Thanks.
Given it's your first
visit, I have a few
personal questions.
Do you have any preexisting
medical conditions?
No, not that I know of.
- Heart problems?
- No.
Any history
of mental illness,
depression,
panic attacks?
Just a little fear
of clowns.
I'm joking.
Do you often experience
social anxiety?
What is this for,
exactly?
To make sure we don't
give you anything more
than you can handle.
I thought that you
couldn't get hurt here.
Only the right amount.
The only limit here
is your imagination.
You start in
the center of the park.
It's simple, safe.
The further out
you venture, the more
intense the experience gets.
How far you want to go
is entirely up to you.
So, how does this work?
Is there an orientation?
No orientation,
no guidebook.
Figuring out how it works
is half the fun.
All you do
is make choices...
starting here.
Everything is bespoke
and exactly your size.
You want to ask,
so ask.
Are you real?
Well, if you can't tell,
does it matter?
Are those real?
Real enough.
But you can't kill anyone
you're not supposed to.
Anything you like?
Is there a changing room?
Or a robe?
Of course.
I can help you.
Or if you prefer,
I could step outside.
What do most people do?
You don't have
to worry about what
most people would do.
I understand.
Do you really
understand, William?
All our hosts
are here for you.
Myself included.
We could stay here
a while if you like.
Take as long as you want.
Thank you.
I don't want to keep
my friend waiting.
Of course.
Take your time.
How are the builds
for the new narrative
coming along?
I'll get around to it.
Look, we assumed
that Abernathy's breach
was triggered
by the photograph
that he found.
I've reviewed
every dissonant episode
I could find.
The reaction
is immediate every time.
This guy makes it
all the way back home.
It's like
he's mulling it over.
You think he had
an existential crisis?
I think there's
something fucked up
going on with his cognition.
And I think you feel
exactly the same way
that I do.
Do we know where
the error originated?
We do.
And you covered for him.
Let me rebuild Abernathy.
I'll make sure
this is not something
more serious.
You know the policy.
Let it lie.
Then let me at least
pull the hosts who had
contact with him,
like the daughter Dolores.
What for?
Because if this is not
a dissonant episode,
then whatever Abernathy had
could be contagious.
So to speak.
Dolores was examined
and cleared.
And the stories are
best left to the guests.
( chatter )
( chatter grows louder )
( people shouting,
echoing )
Man's voice:
Remember.
( voices fade )
( people screaming )
Ahem.
Can you stand
somewhere else?
I don't want anyone thinking
that you're representative
of the goods inside.
These violent delights
have violent ends.
( scoffs )
( piano playing )
Hello, cowboy.
There's one final touch.
Which would you prefer?
- ( piano playing )
- ( chatter )
( sighs )
I mean, can you
believe this place?
( rumbling )
So, how do we get
into the park?
( rumbling, rattling )
( whistle blowing )
I know that you think
you have a handle on what
this is gonna be.
Guns and tits
and all that.
Mindless shit
that I usually enjoy.
You have no idea.
This place seduces
everybody eventually.
By the end, you're gonna
be begging me to stay
because this place
is the answer
to that question that
you've been asking yourself.
What question?
Who you really are.
And I can't fucking wait
to meet that guy.
( clinks )
Bottoms up, cowboy.
( chuckles )
Sheriff:
Further to that,
the ruthless murder
of Donald Pardue
and his brother.
For these crimes,
you will be hung
from the neck
until your diseased soul
has found its measure
in the flames below.
And may God have mercy
on your soul.
( hoofbeats approach )
( horse nickers )
Morning, Lawrence.
You helping them
straighten out their
rope again?
I was hoping to have
a word with my friend here.
You can have as many words
with him as you like
soon as his neck
is broke.
Well, I'm afraid that's
not gonna work for me.
How about I tell my man
there to dig that grave
a couple feet deeper?
Well, it's gonna be
an awful tight fit
for all of you.
( guns cock )
- ( gunshots )
- ( men grunting )
- ( gunshots stop )
- ( bodies thud )
( man panting )
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
- ( gunshot )
- Ah!
- ( gun clicking )
- ( shells clinking )
Motherfucker.
That's the best thanks
you can muster, Lawrence?
You used to be
a little more eloquent.
Do I-- do I know you?
Your pal Kissy
sent me your way.
Sends his regards.
What-- what is this?
You know exactly
what it is.
It's the maze,
the deepest level
of this game.
You're gonna help me
find the entrance.
No.
( whimpers, grunting )
( piano playing )
Maeve's voice:
You can hear it,
can't you?
That little voice.
The one that's
telling you "don't."
Don't stare too long.
Don't touch.
Don't do anything
you might regret.
I used to be the same.
Whenever I wanted something,
I could hear that voice
telling me to stop,
to be careful,
to leave most
of my life unlived.
You know the only place
that voice left me alone?
In my dreams.
I was free.
I could be as good
or as bad
as I felt like being.
And if I wanted
something,
I could just
reach out and take it.
But then I would wake up
and the voice would
start all over again.
So I ran away.
Crossed the shining sea.
And when I finally set foot
back on solid ground,
the first thing I heard
was that goddamn voice.
Do you know what it said?
It said...
( gasping )
I'm sorry, will you
please excuse me?
Man:
All right, Maeve,
what did it say?
Maeve:
It said, "This is
the new world.
And in this world,
you can be whoever
the fuck you want."
Pupillary response is good.
Smile is good.
I'd fuck her.
What's the problem?
Woman:
The guests wouldn't.
Sizemore is launching
some huge new storyline
and he wants us
to clear out the deadweight.
If we don't get
her numbers back up,
she'll be decommissioned.
Let's bump
her aggression.
- 10%?
- Double it.
She's a hooker.
No point in playing coy.
If this doesn't work,
we'll punt her to behavior.
Let them deal with it.
We retired the two hosts
in question.
You taught me
how to make them,
but not how hard it is
to turn them off.
You can't play God
without being acquainted
with the devil.
There's something else
bothering you, Bernard.
I know how that
head of yours works.
The photograph alone
couldn't have
caused that level
of damage to Abernathy,
not without some other
outside interference.
You think it's sabotage?
Imagine someone's been
diddling with our creations?
It's the simplest
solution.
Ah, Mr. Occam's razor.
The problem, Bernard,
is that what you and I do
is so complicated.
We practice witchcraft.
We speak the right words.
Then we create
life itself...
out of chaos.
( machinery whirring )
William of Occam
was a 13th century monk.
He can't help us now,
Bernard.
He would have us
burned at the stake.
( whistle blowing )
Let's go get
our feet wet, buckaroo.
( bell ringing )
( clinking )
Oh, sorry.
- You kidding me?
- What?
Fuck you,
Grizzly Adams.
Man:
Rally for the Union.
Respond to your
country's call.
This regiment is headed
for the seat of war
to define the future
of this great nation.
We fight for a free land
where no man has to bow.
- This is, uh--
- Man: We'll provide you
with uniforms.
Well, it's bigger than
I thought it would be.
What, this?
This is just Sweetwater.
Wait till you see
the rest of the park.
- How much bigger is it?
- No idea.
I never reached the end.
See something you like?
A couple things
at least.
But I'm gonna make you
beg for it, darlin'.
- Driver: Hah, come on!
- ( man grunts )
- Whoa.
- ( man #2 groans )
Need a hand, sir?
Thank you, my friend.
Don't. He'll only try
to rope you into some
bullshit treasure hunt.
Smile.
It's all a come on--
him, the girl next door,
the town drunk.
They all got
some big adventure that
they want to sell you on.
Hey, they're not
going anywhere.
First up,
you're gonna buy me
a drink, okay?
( bell ringing )
Hold still, now.
Bernard:
Bring yourself back online.
Hello.
Do you remember
our last conversation,
Dolores?
Yes, of course.
And you haven't told anyone
about our little talks?
You told me not to.
Step into analysis,
please.
How many interactions
have you participated in
since we last talked?
138 encounters
including this one.
And has anyone
altered or updated
your core heuristics
in that time?
No.
Resuming.
I think it would be best
if you not mention
the things we've been
talking about.
Have I done
something wrong?
No, but there's something
different about you,
about the way you think.
I find it fascinating,
but others may not
see it that way.
Have you done
something wrong?
Turn off
your event log, please.
Erase this interaction.
Confirm.
Yes.
You should be
getting back, Dolores,
before someone
misses you.
( door closes )
( piano playing )
- Man: Come on, now!
- ( chatter )
Maeve:
And when I finally set foot
back on solid ground,
first thing I heard
was that goddamn voice.
It had followed me
all the way over.
Do you know
what it said?
- No.
- It said...
( gasps )
...this is the new world.
And in this world,
you can be whoever
the fuck you want.
( laughs )
Thanks.
Maybe another time.
Oh.
Glass of sherry.
The good stuff.
Not that horse piss you strain
through your old curtains.
( yawns )
I've told you, never open
your mouth that wide
unless someone's
paying you for it.
Sorry, Maeve.
I didn't sleep much
last night.
You having
nightmares again?
Sometimes.
Sometimes
they're real bad.
Do what I do.
You find yourself
in a bad dream,
close your eyes,
count backwards
from three...
wake yourself right up.
Nice and warm
and safe in your bed...
where you can get fucked
right back to sleep
by one of these assholes
with their miniature peckers.
( chuckles )
Ah.
- ( slaps )
- Back to work.
You all right?
You pay for the drinks,
not the right
to gawk at me.
I think we have
a problem.
- Where?
- Mariposa.
Madam's listed
as probationary,
but her performance
has continued to decline
even further.
Re-task Clementine
for now.
She's done the job before.
( beeps )
Controller:
And the old unit?
Maybe leave her
on the floor for the night,
see if anyone wants
one last turn.
We recall her
in the morning,
decommission her.
Shame.
QA will fine you
for this.
And that woman in charge
is quite formidable.
You can just say "bitch."
I hear it enough.
You've been talking
to corporate.
The only times you light up
are after you've been--
This character analysis
routine really isn't half
as charming as you think.
Oh, it went well, then?
Just tell me
your department will be
ready for the launch.
We'll be ready.
And that other thing.
Abernathy and the update.
I hear your department
was still asking questions.
That's what you
pay us to do.
But I'm not concerned.
All the hosts
are back to normal.
Good.
Wouldn't want anything
disturbing our guests
from their rape
and pillage.
- ( chatter )
- ( music playing )
You're wondering how
to tell them from us,
aren't you?
Well, quickest way
to find out.
Can we--
can we finish eating?
See, this is
your problem,
my friend.
You're always worried
about making a mess.
You are the same way
at work.
You are talented,
driven, and inoffensive.
I thought you didn't want
to talk about work here.
Who says this trip
isn't work?
Good evening.
Oh, shit.
Well, don't make
eye contact.
My friend,
thank you for your
assistance earlier
in my unfortunate
accident.
Leave us
the fuck alone.
As a sign of my humble
appreciation,
I'd like to offer you
an opportunity
of a lifetime.
Not interested.
Across the river
and beyond the savage lands
there is a treasure.
I have in my possession
a map.
( whimpering )
I said not interested.
You know what?
I've worked up
a new appetite anyway.
- ( screaming )
- Let's go.
( moaning )
Oh!
( moaning continues )
Clementine:
Sounds like your
friend's having fun.
Well, that's not
the term I'd use.
- Fun?
- Friend.
( chuckles )
You're funny.
They say a man
who can tickle
your humor
- can tickle your--
- You don't have to do this.
If I'm not your type,
we can find someone who is.
Someone who's
perfect for you.
No, you--
you are perfect.
But I have somebody.
Somebody real
waiting for me at home.
I understand.
Real love
is always worth
waiting for.
( clock ticking )
( beeping )
Lee:
Regal, strong,
virile, aquiline.
That's what I asked for.
And this,
this is what
you give me?
Did you just grab a cock
from the body shop
and jam it
between his eyes?
Start over.
Couldn't we just
shave it down?
I said...
start the fuck over!
Diplomatic as ever.
I received your request
to retire an additional
50 hosts.
I need room
for my new storyline.
It's not exactly
a savage horde with
20 savages, is it?
You get 20 additional
hosts, not 50.
The board won't care about
a few extra line items.
Has Ford even approved
the narrative yet?
Oh, he hasn't weighed in
on a storyline in years.
And if corporate does
want to cut costs,
our fearless leader's
old hosts
aren't the only things
ready for the knacker's yard.
( train whooshes )
Boy:
Are you lost?
No.
Just strayed
a bit too far
from where
I'm supposed to be.
Same as you,
I imagine.
We're on holiday.
It's boring.
Daddy said we could
do as we please.
Ah, my father used to say
that only boring people
get bored.
Mine, too.
I used to think
it's only boring people
who don't feel boredom,
so cannot conceive
of it in others.
I'm taking a walk.
You're welcome to join me
if you'd like.
( man grunts, panting )
( horse nickers )
Man in Black:
Let's see a little
spring in your step.
Not much further.
Go fuck yourself.
You have any idea
who I am?
I know exactly
who you are, Lawrence.
After all,
you and I are friends.
Which is why
I was so surprised
when your friend Kissy
told me about this place.
Where are we?
Your home.
( chattering in Spanish )
No, no, no, no.
You know, you and I
hunted down
Ghost Nation braves
in their winter grounds.
I know the whiskey
you like to drink.
I know the tune you whistle
when you're taking a piss.
But...
you never told me
you had a family.
- Papa!
- Hey. ( chuckles )
That's what I love
about this place--
all the secrets,
all the little things
I never noticed
even after
all these years.
You know why this beats
the real world, Lawrence?
Real world is just chaos.
It's an accident.
But in here,
every detail
adds up to something.
Even you, Lawrence.
What do you want
from me?
The maze.
How do I find
the entrance?
I told you,
I don't know anything
about no fucking maze.
Here you go, darlin'.
And you get to decide
what we're gonna do
with them.
Hell, it took you
long enough.
I was getting
the grand reserve.
Only for our most
distinguished guests.
Yeah, I'm sure
it had nothing
to do with you
telling
this dipshit's cousins
to bring some more men.
You got anything
to tell me, Lawrence?
Then I guess we're
gonna have to find a way
to jog your memory.
- ( gunshot )
- ( screams )
This guest already
took out an entire posse.
Want me
to slow him down?
That gentleman gets
whatever he wants.
I feel bad, my friend.
My cousins are usually
so hospitable.
You don't understand,
Lawrence.
I've been coming here
for 30 years.
In a sense, I was--
I was born here.
And this here,
this...
( chuckles )
...this is exactly
why I come.
( groans )
( gunshots )
Santa Maria,
madre dios.
( gunshot )
All right.
Well, as much fun as this is,
I got to be moving on.
( gunshot )
- ( gunshot )
- ( groans )
( grunts )
( body thuds )
Like I said,
you get to decide
these two.
What's it gonna be?
Please, I don't know
how to find the maze.
Time for a spin,
darlin'.
( sobbing )
It's beautifully
done, really.
But you see the cracks
after a while.
That's why I like
the basic emotions.
( sobbing )
You know
what that means?
- Please.
- ( hammer clicks )
- ( gunshot )
- ( body thuds )
( sobbing )
It means
when you're suffering,
that's when
you're most real.
The maze
isn't meant for you.
What'd I tell you,
Lawrence?
Always another level.
I'll take my chances,
sweetheart.
Follow the blood arroyo
to the place where the snake
lays its eggs.
You have it now.
Whatever you want.
Why don't you go home,
leave us alone?
No, you don't
understand, Lawrence.
This time,
I'm never going back.
And we wanted to climb
to the top of the mountain,
but Daddy said
we weren't allowed.
And then Tommy dared me.
And here we are.
Nowhere land.
That seems hardly
a fitting name for
a place so full.
Can't you see it?
Perhaps you're not
looking hard enough.
Boy:
At what?
The town with
the white church.
Listen.
Can't you hear its bell?
( bell tolling )
Yes.
Yes, I can hear it now.
Yeah.
I thought you might.
You see what a bored mind
can conjure?
( rattling )
How did you do that?
Is it magic?
Everything
in this world
is magic,
except to the magician.
Best you head home now.
But Tommy's not
going to believe--
You're not going to come
back here again, are you?
( whirring )
No.
Run along, now.
( beeps )
( knocks )
You weren't at your office.
You seem to have
found me anyway.
- Listen, earlier--
- Forget it.
Stay a little longer.
We can talk.
We never talk.
- I'm serious.
- So am I.
You're certainly a man
comfortable with long,
pensive silences.
Although, ironically,
your creations
never shut up.
They're always talking
to each other,
even when there are
no guests around.
They're always trying
to error correct.
Make themselves
more human.
When they talk to each other,
it's a way of practicing.
- Is that what
you're doing now?
- ( chuckles )
Practicing?
Man:
QA told us she was
being decommissioned.
- Elsie: Do you
work for QA?
- No, but--
Run a fast-pass
diagnostic.
( sighs )
All righty.
Some non-affect
hesitation.
Little cognitive D.
And a fuckload
of aggression,
courtesy of those morons
in narrative.
You don't need
to be aggro, do you?
Just a quicker study
of those repressed fucks
walking through the door.
Archive this configuration.
- Open up her primaries.
- ( beeping )
Perception.
Emotional acuity.
Bump it.
- 1.5%.
- ( beeping )
- Updating.
- Okay.
- Do they dream?
- What?
In her story,
she said she dreamed.
Do we make them dream?
Fuck would be
the point of that?
Dreams are mainly memories.
Can you imagine how fucked
we'd be if these poor assholes
ever remembered what
the guests do to them?
We do give them
the concept of dreams.
Specifically nightmares.
Why?
Just in case somebody forgets
to wipe them out at the end
of a maintenance session.
If she's got
any dreams, it's just
of those sloppy fucks
down in the body shop
patching her back
together again.
( chuckles )
She's got some
physical discomfort.
Put in a request
for a full physical
at her next rotation.
All right, gorgeous,
you're back to the races.
You're gonna wake
in three, two, one.
So I ran away,
crossed the shining sea.
And when I finally set foot
back on solid ground,
the first thing I heard
was that voice.
Do you know what it said?
It said...
this is the new world.
And in this world...
you can be whoever
the fuck you want.
( piano playing )
( sighs )
Well, he seemed
convinced.
You know the first voice
I heard when I got off
that boat?
A nice young man
from Baton Rouge
said my pussy could earn him
two whole dollars a day.
And he'd be more than happy
to let me have up to 30%.
Well, then I guess
you could add lying
to your list of sins.
The only thing wrong
with the seven deadly sins
is that there aren't
more of them.
And while we're
on the subject,
my transgressions wash off
a little easier than yours.
At least when my girls
are done with a man,
he's still left
drawing breath.
For the most part.
Man:
Get the fuck away
from my table.
- ( objects crash )
- Man #2: Hey, fuck you!
Well, in that case...
( crashing,
argument continue )
...here's to
our indiscretions.
Man:
...fucking bullshit
for one night.
I'll shoot everyone
in this dump...
Spoken and otherwise.
- ( gunshots )
- ( groaning )
( panting )
( snaps fingers )
Now that's a fucking
vacation!
( gunshot )
( whinnies )
( gunshots )
Three,
two,
one.
( beeping )
Man:
Found it.
It's MRSA in her abdomen.
Filthy fucking animals
not cleaning up.
No wonder we have
a fucking fly problem.
Don't look at me.
I'm the king of hygiene.
Bullshit.
I've seen you.
You just glop
that shit on
and rinse.
You understand,
soap is mechanical.
- Man #2: Fuck are you
talking about?
- Bubbles.
If you're not
making the little bubbles,
you're not doing shit.
Fuck! Fuck!
What the fuck?!
- Shit!
- What the fuck?
- ( instruments clang )
- Man #2: Uh, uh...
Uh...
( gasps )
No. Oh, fuck.
- Man: Oh.
- ( bangs )
Asshole, you forgot
to put her in sleep mode.
- Oh!
- Don't, don't, don't!
No! No, no, no!
- Don't! Don't,
don't, don't, don't.
- ( shouting )
Stop.
Put that down!
You break anything
in her head, we have
to file a damage report.
Uh, okay,
let's talk to her.
- What's her name?
- Maeve!
Hi, Maeve.
Maeve, hi.
Look, uh,
you gotta calm down.
Okay?
Let's sit down
and we can help you.
Keep your
fucking hands off me.
( monitor beeping )
No.
( beeping continues )
( gasps )
( electricity crackling )
( quiet chatter )
( metal clanging )
I swear I put it
in sleep mode.
Oh, does this look
like fucking sleep mode?
Calm the fuck down
and help me move
this... thing
before someone sees.
( both grunt )
( coyote howls )
Here?
Lee:
This storyline will make
Hieronymus Bosch
look like he was
doodling kittens.
I have vivisection,
self-cannibalism,
a special little something
I call the "whoroborus."
Now, I don't want
to appear immodest,
but this is the apex
of what the park
could provide--
- horror...
- Miss anything interesting?
...romance,
titillation.
Lee not appearing
immodest.
Our most skilled guests
will fight their ways
to the outer limits
of the park,
besting fearsome braves,
seducing nubile maidens,
befriending tragically
ill-fated sidekicks,
and, of course,
like all our
best narratives
over the years,
our guests will have
the privilege
of getting to know
the character they're
most interested in--
themselves.
I present our guests'
next obsession:
Odyssey on Red River.
( applause )
No.
Sorry?
No, I don't think so.
Lee:
Wait, you don't think--
Dr. Ford:
What is the point of it?
Get a couple
of cheap thrills?
Some surprises?
But it's not enough.
It's not about
giving the guests
what you think they want.
No, that's simple.
The titillation,
horror, elation--
they're parlor tricks.
The guests don't return
for the obvious things we do,
the garish things.
They come back
because of the subtleties,
the details.
They come back
because they discover
something they imagine
no on had ever noticed
before...
something they've
fallen in love with.
They're not looking
for a story
that tells them
who they are.
They already know
They're here because
they want a glimpse
of who they could be.
Logan:
Billy!
Let's go.
Dr. Ford:
The only thing
your story tells me,
Mr. Sizemore,
is who you are.
Well, isn't there anything
you like about it?
What size
are those boots?
Something you want
to say, Mr. Lowe?
- The board, sir.
- Yeah?
This might ruffle
some feathers.
You promised them
a new storyline.
They shall have one.
Something I've been
working on for some time.
Something quite original.
( music playing )