Previously on Wynonna Earp.
You're safe here amongst your sisters.
- My name is Wynonna Earp.
- Yeah.
[shouts]
Sorry I didn't tell you about
stupid Bobo's stupid powers.
- Looking for this?
-I thought you were
just happy to see me.
I am finished here, Waverly.
This was your plan the whole time?
You told me to learn to drive.
[Waverly] I didn't mean
leave Purgatory without a word!
You came back. I knew
our connection was real.
- [humming]
- Ah!
- What the hell was that?
- The impossible.
Would you girls kindly get
your butts in here! Willa!
♪ ♪
How much propofol did Dolls give her?
Enough to calm her down.
I thought she was gonna
hyperventilate to death.
Yeah, I know how she feels.
How can a woman recently sprung
from a hippie forest cult...
Be our big sister Willa?
I don't know her at all.
Dude, none of us do.
How do you think she feels?
She doesn't even know
she's herself, Wynonna, so...
[Gus] Girls, please.
I know this is all... overwhelming,
but it's also a second chance.
Good Lord! The whole town
will be upended.
We can't tell anyone.
Not until we know for sure.
- [knocking on door]
- [door opening]
[sighing] It's about damn time.
[door closing]
[Wynonna] Ah, blablabla.
"In conclusion, 44 markers tested
with a sibling index of..."
blablablabla"
and indicated by these patterns."
You're sure?
I mean, science doesn't lie, right?
But nobody knows
whose saliva sample this is
or that you were comparing it
to mine, right?
You know, her being here
could be dangerous.
Hey, don't worry. Black Badge
doesn't know anything, OK?
Plus I got a buddy down
in the forensics lab who did
a no-questions-asked... favour.
But you don't believe me.
Only the part about you having a buddy.
If she really is our long-lost sister,
- then...
- Technically, she's the heir.
Or an heir. Then, there'd be
both of you. Two of you.
I was just gonna say, if she really
is Willa, then we stopped
looking for her a long time ago,
and we're really horrible people, but...
[Willa gasping]
Get... Eve.
- Yeah, it's OK, you're safe.
- It was real, wasn't it?
I killed a man.
Lou got pulled into the ground.
He didn't get pulled into the
ground. You sent him to Hell.
- Hell?
- Well, she did.
[Wynonna sighs.]
I-I think I should go.
[Dolls] Whoa, whoa,
you can't go anywhere.
Sorry.
Excuse me, I don't want
to be rude, but I don't know...
...any of you.
- Or what's happening.
- Here, have a drink.
- I don't drink.
- You will.
'Cause according to
the fresh-out-of-the-oven
DNA test, you...
...are officially an Earp.
Welcome home, Willa.
Now, Zed, don't, as in do not,
make eye contact with them.
They've been in storage
for about a year;
- they'll be hungry.
- Yeah, yeah.
You need help with those bolt cutters
or should I stand here all day?
[ominous music]
- Hello!
- [woman] Help me!
The boss will be real mad
if we don't get what he needs.
[woman] Please help.
Oh shit! There's
something wrong with 'em.
Maybe they're sick. Come on, Zed.
Jesus, what happened to you?
Ah!
That's what people would ask you
- if you survived.
- Shut your eyes, Zed!
Oh! Take me.
- I think I'm in love.
- That'll change.
- [biting sound]
- [men screaming]
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
♪♪ 'Cause I gave you
all I've got to give ♪
♪ And no, that ain't no way to live ♪
♪ I told that devil ♪
♪ To take you back ♪
♪ To take you back ♪♪
[door creaking]
This is...
...was my bedroom?
Yeah. Dolls thought this might
activate some memories.
Looks like I liked horses.
I guess every little girl likes horses.
Oh, I didn't.
They don't like me. Haha!
I remember him. Mr. Plumpkins.
Poor guy is missing an eye.
Yeah.
My big sister used to steal him from me
- and torture him for ransom.
- Alright, my bad.
Not you.
All this time I was missing...
...our parents never redecorated?
Mom was already long gone
by then, and Daddy...
...had passed.
Anything memory-wise?
A switchblade.
What kind of people
give a kid a switchblade?
Unless I was dangerous.
More like... special.
I think
I'll take a shower.
- Is that OK?
- Yeah, of course.
This is your home, Willa.
Oh, it's just... just the cult.
Free living au naturel.
It's groovy.
[Wynonna sighs.] She hates us.
- She doesn't know us.
- Ah!
- [door opening and closing]
- Uh, gotta go.
Yeah, I said I'd see Nicole
before the Poker Spectacular.
Are you and Nicole best friends now?
And what the hell
is a "Poker Spectacular"?
Stuck in Purgatory for another
- goddamn Poker Spectacular.
- [clicking]
There was a whore I knew,
used to poke her spectacular.
I find my lead out there,
I don't have to listen
to your goddamn awful jokes
in here again.
Concentrate, Del Rey, I got six whales
coming into town. A lot of cash.
They expect a certain type of service.
A certain level of sophistication.
Details I certainly don't
care about, you pompous twat.
Suddenly, you don't care
about making money?
What do I care for money? In four
more days, I'll be in the wind.
Ha! You say that every year.
Cryderman.
Got it for you, like I said I would.
A small taste of things to come.
Hello, babies.
[indistinct rock song playing]
[Bobo sniffing]
- I'll need more than this.
- On the way.
- You lock up law enforcement?
- Don't I always?
- What about Black Badge?
- I'm handling it.
- I promise.
- I put a lot of stake
in a man's word, Cryderman.
But I no longer find
the exploits of Wynonna Earp
and Deputy Marshall Dolls
particularly entertaining.
Speaking of entertainment...
The twins are locked and loaded.
You want your Johnson serviced
before we part ways?
Nice try. I'll see myself out.
Sad Bobo is my least favourite Bobo.
Is there anything we can do
to make it better, baby?
Not my types.
Then again...
...it's goddamn Poker Spectacular.
- [metal snap]
- Why not?
[woman laughing]
[rock music playing]
[metallic clatter]
- No teeth.
- [woman giggling]
♪ ♪
Mr. Stokes,
welcome to my humble little town.
With this high a buy-in, Judge...
...I don't think humble will cut it.
What's a high-stakes
poker game without the stakes?
All cash then?
I'm gonna check in my hotel,
relax a little bit
before the games begin.
I made sure you were
in our most prestigious room.
- It's to die for.
- I'll be the judge of that.
[Wynonna] How is this even possible?
I still can't believe it.
Feels like a piece that's been
missing from our lives.
And now it's back.
Last time I saw her, she was being
pulled out a window.
I didn't do a damn thing.
We couldn't.
We shouldn't have given up, Gus.
Oh, we didn't think we had.
After six months of searching...
...we found part of Willa's nightgown
- coated in dried blood.
- Oh, Jesus.
Well, it was a Thursday.
I remember 'cause you'd
just been released
from St. Victoria's.
Tried to burn down your classroom.
Ms. Hanson called
my diorama an aberration.
Stayed up all night handcrafting
those little papier-mâché demons.
This is crazy.
You don't look a miracle
in the mouth, Wy.
This could heal us all.
We need to get her memories back,
and I don't have a magic pill for that.
You could start by telling me the truth.
I did.
[Gus] The whole truth.
Oh, I'd hate to see
their second best, hmm?
- What the f...!
- We've been waiting for you.
It's been so long
since we've had a man.
A real man.
[man grunting]
[woman giggling]
Oh, hello.
- [woman moaning]
- [man groaning with pleasure]
- [woman laughing]
- Oh, that feels
amazing!
Ah, aaaah!
That's, that's a little tight.
[man groaning in pain]
Shhhh, baby.
- It'll all be over soon.
- [man moaning in pain]
We gotta get this to Bobo. Hurry up.
- [woman] Coming.
- [man groaning]
[man moaning in pain]
[gunshots]
Demons?
Like Beelzebub and Lucifer?
Hell no.
Hell yes, apparently.
And that's where they come from?
And where we send 'em back.
These revenants are the bad guys
Wyatt Earp put down.
When they resurrect...
...they come back
demon-adjacent. With powers.
Are there any Angels?
Sure. Snow, Charlie's and Los.
[Wynonna chuckling]
How can you think this is funny?
How can you not? This curse, our burden;
if you don't laugh...
...you'll go crazy. And I've been crazy.
Didn't care for it.
You hate having to do this.
What would it make me if I didn't?
Here's the kicker. I was never supposed
to be hunting revenants or...
...breaking curses.
It was supposed to be you.
[clicking]
Daddy, it's 4 in the morning,
and I have school tomorrow.
Every one of your little classmates
will be slaughtered if you don't
learn to protect them.
This town. Your sisters.
Now aim.
Don't hesitate.
Because they sure won't.
- DO IT!
- AH!
- [gunshot]
- [panting]
Are you OK?
Daddy.
Gus, Wave... Waverly.
Nona.
I remember you.
[laughing]
- You're a brunette now.
- Look who's talking!
[both laughing]
Willa, do you remember what
happened after you were taken?
No. Just, just being kids.
And Daddy training me to be the heir.
[gunshot]
Wynonna, where the hell have I been?
Hey, Earp. Oh, uh...
Wynonna Earp.
Yeah, we got something.
I'll be OK.
It's fine. Go.
- So breakthrough? Revelations?
- She had flashes
of training with Daddy
when she fired Peacemaker.
- Is she a good shot?
- You mean, better than me?
♪ ♪
[snoring]
Well, if you're as ornery
with your car as you are with strangers,
I can see why the engine quit on you.
Oh, you say ornery.
I say vigilant.
Well, seeing as you're not dead
or looking for help, I'll be on my way.
Now, hold on!
You know cars?
Yeah, I tinker here and there.
- Shit!
- What?
On my maiden trek,
my horse should
go hooves up exactly here.
You're a strange fella, aren't you?
Been told I have character.
Carrying a flask of tabasco
on your hip is character;
drawing a pistol on a good Samaritan,
that's just being a dick.
Do you think you can assist
with my vehicle, please?
I am stranded.
[sighing]
Alright. Try starting her up.
[Doc Holliday chuckling]
Well see, here's the clinker:
I got angry; I threw them keys away.
Now, I looked for 'em
for a spell, but then I decided
tired eyes, they're poor tools, so...
In which direction did you throw 'em?
Just past that marker.
Uh-huh.
[sighing]
Oh, I found them!
Yeah, you sure did, son.
This mean you help me?
Oh, where are my manners?
Henry.
Mm-hmm.
[Willa] You kept my death certificate.
Yeah. To remind myself
it was actually real.
You know, that you were actually gone.
I was 6, right?
I saw the little white coffin,
but I knew that you weren't
actually in there.
They'd filled it with sandbags.
Was it a nice service?
All I remember was a lot of crying.
And the food.
The grown-ups let me eat as many
marshmallows as I wanted.
I threw up all night long.
Gee.
That must have been so hard for you.
I'm sorry. It's just...
It's really intense.
You guys killed me.
What did you bury in Daddy's coffin?
Daddy.
[man and girl screaming]
[girl screaming]
[screaming]
- Did you remember something?
- Oh, I feel faint.
Are you scared of me?
Willa!
Alright, so Nedley caught
a scene at the hotel.
Blood everywhere, but no body.
Cool.
Yeah. So only thing left was a laptop
belonging to a guy
by the name of Bradley
Stokes. Hedge-fund type from Seattle.
Hmm, cool.
Nicole searched
for any connected devices
and came across an active smartwatch
currently transmitting
from this abandoned railyard.
- And let me guess.
- [cocking shotgun]
You cool? Now you snap
out of it, alright?
Yeah, I wonder what's
got me so distracted, right?
Look, the guy may still
be alive in there,
and I'm gonna need
your help. OK, Wynonna?
Come on!
You're the Earp that I need right now.
Try the only one
who'll fall for your bullshit.
Alright, so the smartwatch
is transmitting from in there.
OK.
What?
Daddy trained Willa.
She was prepared to do this.
Unlike me, the off-key drunk
of an understudy.
Whoa, whoa, look.
You know you're good at this,
and you're only getting better, OK?
Thanks.
Now maybe what you're
really freaked out about
is just getting replaced.
From hero to punch-worthy
in ten seconds flat.
- [clanking]
- Shh.
Save your punching
for what's in there. Gun now.
Clear. Go.
[Dolls, whispering] You go that
way, I go this way, got it?
♪ ♪
[groaning]
Ah!
Honey, I'm flattered, but
for a whole whack of reasons,
you're not my type.
[gunshot]
- Stupid sexy hair porn!
- [Dolls] Earp!
You good?
Yeah, I'm OK, but definitely
something in here, Dolls!
Should have kept your pants on.
[Dolls] Ahhh, shit.
[woman] Ugly words
from such a beautiful man.
Oh, wow!
You're one of a kind.
[woman] Close.
Ah!
You kiss different. You're powerful.
[groaning]
Whatever that is, way down deep,
just let it out, baby.
- I try so hard not to.
- Hmm...
- I want him.
- You got the banker.
Yeah, but this one
- is a rare bird.
- He likes me better!
- I'm prettier.
- Yo, Ms. Congeniality!
Ugh!
Nothing a facelift won't fix.
- Wake up, Hugh Hefner.
- I taste strawberries.
You smell of man-whore.
- Where are those girls?
- Here.
- One got away.
- I think I can lure
- the other one back for sure.
- Ew.
Right. Go.
Hey, love.
Don't be scared.
Why don't we just finish
what we started?
There you go.
[strange electronic music]
So...
What is a pretty girl like you
going around attacking men like me?
A favour.
Judge wanted to cash in,
and we get hungry being all alone.
Hungry for...
I could just eat you up.
Nice. We double-teamed her.
Mm-hmm.
Any idea why the vampire twins
went after Stokes?
Yeah, well, she said "the judge."
[phone ringing]
Yo.
Wave, slow down.
Shit! Willa took off. She's gone.
[Doc] I sure appreciate your care.
Well, I looked in my truck,
and it just so happened that I had
a fan belt for a '78.
This is your lucky day, son.
Oh, I try to make my own luck.
Well, you can't fix your own car.
You kids today and your "iPodes"
and your "Netpix"...
You couldn't find a sparkplug
if your life depended on it.
I do like your hat, though.
Much obliged.
So, where are you headed?
Ooh, wherever suits me.
I've always been a bit of a drifter.
Suppose some find that
something to be proud of. My experience
says drifting is just
another word for running.
Running ain't in my nature.
Well, maybe it didn't use to be,
but enough time in the dark...
- ...a man can change.
- What did you say?
- Or maybe it's a woman.
- Well, it ain't.
You ever spend any time at war, son?
My father did a long time ago. You?
On my first tour of duty,
I couldn't wait to get home.
Then I did. I couldn't figure
out what to do with myself.
So I went back...
...to the desert.
Nothing hollows out a man
quicker than completing a mission.
Because after that...
...you still gotta live.
Dig into that toolbox and fetch me
a 5H socket, would you?
When did you finally give it up?
I didn't.
[echoing] Neither have you, Doc.
[honking]
Oh, men, I need to start drinking less.
Or much, much more.
Hot chocolate?
What are you playing at?
I'm not sure what you mean, son.
How in hell did you get this?
Why? Is it something to you?
This is Wyatt Earp's deputy
badge. He gave this to me.
And I threw it in a fire
many weeks ago, far from here.
Sounds to me like you were done with it.
No more bullshit.
Now, who are you?
Who sent you?
Questions with complicated answers.
For simplicity's sake,
you can call me Juan-Carlo.
And nobody sent me.
I just am.
Well, if not a revenant, then what?
You keep asking all the wrong questions.
But then again, most people do.
What am I even doing here?
That's more like it.
My associates and I have
a vested interested in what you
call the Ghost River Triangle.
You only have four days
- until Winter Solstice.
- Well then, I'll be sure
to raise a glass of spiked cider
- to your enigmatic ass.
- Four days
until the door opens. And if it does,
she will lose, Doc.
Even with your help.
You have to choose.
Keep drifting on down the road
or face the darkness again.
This time with Wynonna Earp
at your side.
Not everyone gets a second chance.
Most of them stay in the ground.
Well, I ought to put you in the ground.
Well...
That'd be a choice, too.
Speaking of...
You can take the fan belt...
...or the badge...
...but you can't have both.
What were you thinking, showing Willa
- her own scrapbook of death?
- She was curious.
- Wouldn't you be curious?
- Well, it freaked her out!
Yeah, more like pissed her off.
I wish Doc were here.
He bailed on me... on us.
But he's a hell of a tracker.
Yeah, good point.
How are we gonna find a girl
we know nothing about?
Half price drinks
at Shorty's slash Bobo's?
What is that musk ox playing at?
Hey, you think?
- She is an Earp.
- Bet she drinks 'em dry
- in 20 minutes.
- Why not?
♪ ♪
- [indistinct chatter]
- ♪ Daddy, where you going ♪
♪ Going out again ♪
Well, ain't you pretty as a peach.
Can I buy the peach a drink?
[Willa] I don't even know what I like.
I was living in a cult in the woods.
We drank tea made from dandelions.
Darlin', that's weird.
Barkeep, send up some shots.
- What are you having?
- One of everything you've got.
- [bearded man laughing]
- ♪ Bridges and money ♪
♪ And everyone you love ♪
♪ When you run with the devil ♪
- I hate when I'm right.
- What? You love it
- when you're right.
- I meant sober.
- I hate when I'm sober. Oh!
- ♪ Run, run amuck ♪
No sign of Bobo at least.
Well, let's not wait on him.
We should go salvage her; we might
have to get out of here fast..
Yeah, I'm gonna go get the jeep ready.
Wait a minute. Do you know Lou?
Oh my God! You're
one of them, aren't you?
An exit, find one.
♪ You'll be tweakin' ♪
You shouldn't be here.
And you shouldn't have shot our daddy.
[Wynonna sighs.]
I was gonna tell you. In time.
I did what I thought was best.
You were trying to save us.
Maybe he deserved it.
Willa!
He told me I had nothing to worry about,
to just stay calm.
He knew the attack was coming, Wynonna.
♪ When you run with the devil ♪♪
I don't remember anything else,
except that our daddy
let those bad men come
into our house tear us apart.
- [glass shattering]
- Whores.
I thought I told you to leave.
You and your bitch friend
owe me a drink.
[screaming]
- Wynonna!
- Give me back my gun!
- I think you mean, my gun.
- There are real people here!
- Real regular human people.
- And how do we deal
- with the non-regular ones?
- The old fashioned way.
- Hey!
- ♪♪ When you run ♪
♪ With the devil, you burn
everything you touch ♪
♪ Bridges and money ♪
♪ And everyone you love ♪
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Just like cow-tipping
on Wilson's half acre!
- I'll take your word for it.
- ♪ When you run ♪
♪ With the devil,
he's gonna press your luck ♪
♪ Still you run ♪
- That was amazing!
Yeah! Ha, ha, ha!
And Dolls is gonna kill us!
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ Run, run amuck ♪♪
- I'll put the kettle on.
- [door closing]
Shit, that felt good!
Yeah. So does base jumping
without a chute.
I'm sorry, maybe I'm unclear
about this whole curse thing.
There are revenants; there are Earps.
The Earps... that's us by the way...
- Willa...
- ...make sure all the revenants
get a bullet to the brain
from Peacemaker, or die trying.
- Am I missing something?
- [Dolls] Yeah. Civilians.
And as far as human
witnesses are concerned,
you just shot a random person in a bar.
- Ah! In Purgatory, that's old news.
- Yeah?
Well, that's the type
of thing that can get
Purgatory on the wrong side of the nuke.
She didn't know. I made
the same mistake.
Wynonna, why are you listening
to this buzzkill in army boots?
- [Dolls] Buzzkill?
- [Willa] Yeah.
Buzzkill? I'm a U.S. Marshall
with Black Badge, you hear me?
He's been helping us.
You mean, you're following
his orders, and not
- your own instincts.
- [Dolls] Aw, come on.
- We're a team.
- I thought I was the brainwashed one.
Great.
I'm her sister.
I got it.
[door opening and closing]
[door opening]
[sigh]
- [door opening]
- [Willa] Wynonna...
I'm so, so sorry.
I... I don't even know
who that person was.
Pretty sure that was an Earp. Ha!
Dolls was right.
I lost control.
I was angry at everything. Everyone.
I let it in my head.
At least you didn't have a
meltdown in front of your boss.
Gummy bears.
Fuzzy Peaches.
I remember we used to play
in here with gummy bears.
We would dance them across
the beams and into our mouths.
[Wynonna] Then you turned
11 and you wanted
to practice making out
with the gummy bears.
Oh... And you promised
- to never tell anyone that.
- I never did.
Then you went and died on me.
We were two peas, you and I.
It's always been you and I.
[Wynonna] Yeah, I remember.
It can be like it always was.
And different too in all the right ways.
You're not alone anymore.
♪ ♪
Are you gonna tell me what happened
here or am I gonna use your head
to clean the toilets again?
[Asian man speaking Cantonese]
It was the two Earp girls.
[Asian man] Bobo.
[people screaming]
Not two Earp girls.
Three.
[Asian man] So what do we do now, boss?
- Everybody clear on the target?
- Yeah.
Not that it matters.
This is a clean sweep.
- No witnesses, gentlemen.
- You got it.
[The engine starts.]
♪ ♪
- [Waverly] You're quiet.
- Yeah, I'm just thinking.
There's a lot going on right now
that just doesn't add up.
Like, if Cryderman is dirty...
...that means someone
is feeding him some BBD intel.
Someone we know or someone you work for?
I don't know.
Black Badge isn't just a...
- ...a job for me.
- Yeah, no kidding.
I get it.
Feeling like you're about
to lose something.
It's OK if you don't like her, you know.
I'm happy she's back,
I really am. It's...
I never really knew her,
you know. Still don't.
Yeah, we'll get
to the bottom of it, alright?
- Yeah, I'm sure you will.
- All of us.
You're good at what you do.
Doesn't matter how many
Willas come back. Doesn't.
We're still gonna need you.
Earp.
- You called me "Earp." -Yeah, I did.
Don't let it go to your head.
And there's only three of you, right?
Ha, ha, ha!
[Dolls] Smoke bomb! Clear! Clear!
- Go, Waverly! Get down!
- [gunshots]
I thought you said
they can't come on our land.
Revenants can't. Human assholes can.
Go find the basement now!
Anything without windows!
Go! Go! Go!
- [gunshots]
- Ah!
Oh, my God!
Lucky for us, they don't know
we're in here.
Take 'em by surprise?
Get out of my head!
Grenade!
YA!
Ugh!
(shout)
- [gunshots]
- Waverly, hide!
God, I wish people
would stop saying that to me!
- Come on!
- ♪
♪
Let's go, bitches!
Come on!
Dolls gave use these for protection.
They're a bit tricky,
but you think you can do this?
Why do I even ask?
Ah, you wanna get all up in my kitchen?
Eat shit, shit-eaters!
AH! Ah!
♪ ♪
[grunting]
This place is lit. Fall back! Fall back!
Waverly? Dolls?
We're OK. We're OK.
- Good to go?
- Wait.
For what? They just tried to
kill us in our own home again!
Uh, guys,
I think I got a little bit shot.
Waverly!
- They're getting away!
- It's OK. You're OK.
- WYNONNA!
- Just a second!
- OK, it's just a graze.
- Just?
- Shit! Willa!
- Go, we can't lose her again.
Go.
Take care of her.
[groaning]
It's OK. Hey, hey, hey. You got
it. You're gonna be alright.
[grunting]
[gasping]
[Bobo roaring]
[Wynonna] Get away from her!
Bye-bye, Bobo.
Ah!
[gunshot]
- Ah!
Shit! What?
I finally had him!
- Did he hurt you?
- Hurt me?
Wynonna, he saved me.
Do you think it'll scar?
- Dudes dig scars.
- [door opening]
- Do chicks?
- [door closing]
Perimeter's clear.
You know, most of those guys had
top-shelf gear, military tattoos.
- Mercenaries?
- Wasn't a siege,
it was an assassination attempt.
Other than revenants,
who wants to kill us that badly?
Is it about Willa?
Do they know she's back or
that there might be two heirs?
This isn't really about Willa or you.
I pulled this off
from one of the bodies.
The target was me.
[Willa] Wynonna?
I need you to tell me
everything you know about Bobo Del Rey.
[Cryderman groaning]
[man speaking Cantonese]
No kidding.
I thought I was doing what you asked.
Dolls and Black Badge, done.
The Earp heir, done.
[man speaking Cantonese]
♪ ♪
Please. Please don't kill me.
I'll do whatever you want.
- Anything!
- Oh, I know.
You see, what I want...
...is for you to throw me a party.
Ha!
♪ Forever ♪
♪ That's how long it is, forever ♪
♪ Sins I had to change to never ♪
- [Doc coughing]
- ♪ Or lose your love again ♪
What in tarnation! Ah!
- [Doc coughing]
- ♪ Forev... ♪♪
[Doc coughing]
Oh, Jesus!
[coughing]
Whatever the hell you are, Juan-Carlo,
a decent mechanic you are not.
[Clunk!]
♪ ♪
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com