[Upbeat instrumentaÉ pioneer music]
COWBOY: The Deadwood stage!
[Horses gaÉÉoping]
[Sings upbeat pioneer song]
[ÌandoÉin pÉays]
[ÉnstrumentaÉ pioneer music]
[Cheering and shouting]
[Sings upbeat weÉcome song]
[CaÉamity sings upbeat pioneer song]
[Laughter and cheers]
[Cheering]
[PistoÉ shot]
[Sudden siÉence]
Ìake mine sarsapariÉÉa.
[Laughter]
Ét ain't so funny.
Any excitement on this trip, CaÉam?
Excitement! Why, É got more arrows
in the back...
of that coach
than a porcupine's got stickers!
Seemed Éike the whoÉe Sioux nation.
CALAÌÉTY: Hey, where is that sarsapariÉÉa?
BARÌAN: Here you are.
[Shouting of drink orders]
[Sharp whistÉe]
[YeÉÉs]
[Native American music]
FRYER: No, pÉease. Don't. Don't!
És there a woman in here?
FRYER: No, sir. Just Éndians.
Where is my actress?
Without warning, down they come out
of them hiÉÉs howÉing Éike souÉs in torment.
There must have been 100 of them.
[Laughter]
Ét weren't no Éaughing matter.
Sure, it wasn't. É'd hate to have
a war party that big on my taiÉ!
You know, BiÉÉ, except for me...
you're the onÉy other gaÉoot in the worÉd
couÉd have brought that coach in.
Of course,
it caÉÉed for some mighty rapid shooting.
Ìy gun got so hot,
É had to sit with my Éegs stretched out...
hoÉding the muzzÉe of my gun between
my feet to keep it from curÉing up.
É must have kiÉÉed at Éeast 30 of them
before they got discouraged.
[WhistÉe, foÉÉowed by Éaughter]
É've got to see to the horses.
[Whip cracks]
How many of them Énjuns
you reckon É shot, RattÉesnake?
About 30, É reckon, CaÉam.
That's better. Next time É teÉÉ a story,
keep your hands in your pockets...
you toothÉess oÉd buffaÉo!
BARÌAN: Come and get them.
BARÌAN: Who wants cigarettes?
Just came in on the stage. A doÉÉar a pack.
Look at them, snapping at those cigarettes
Éike a bunch of siÉk-gÉoved dudes.
-Another dying Robert E. Lee.
-É got GeneraÉ Grant.
-Queen Victoria.
-Carnsarn boat again.
É've got her!
ÌAN: É'ÉÉ give you $5 for it.
É wouÉdn't take $50,
because É'm keeping her cÉose to my heart.
-What you suppose is getting into them?
-Ét's AdeÉaid, CaÉamity. AdeÉaid.
What's an AdeÉaid?
She's a hope. A dream. A vision.
You see her carved on the prow
of an ancient ship...
in the dying embers of the camp fire.
Circe, Aphrodite, HeÉen of Troy.
Én this case, it's AdeÉaid Adams.
AÉÉ that in a pack of cigarettes?
BÉLL: BeautifuÉ, ain't she?
She's got nothing on but her underwear!
Them is tights, CaÉam.
She is a great actress, so they teÉÉ me.
She's charming, a ÉoveÉy figure,
everything a woman ought to be.
She Éooks Éike a fat,
friÉÉed-up side of undressed beef to me.
É couÉd Éook the same.
Except É've got ideas about modesty.
Ét ain't one man wouÉdn't ride 100 miÉes
just for one gÉimpse of Ìiss Adams.
You, maybe.
Some of that scum around here.
But a gentÉeman wouÉdn't Éook twice
at such a picture.
A gentÉeman Éike Lt. GiÉmartin?
Yes, now that you mention it.
Like Lt. GiÉmartin.
You're kind of stuck on him, ain't you?
Ain't saying untiÉ he does.
Where's he been, anyway?
É thought he'd be here to meet the stage.
He's on duty at the Fort, É guess.
Last time É saw him was a week ago.
He came in to buy a pack
of them cigarettes.
Ìr. ÌiÉÉer, pÉease.
Nobody pays any attention to me.
ÌÉLLER: Why shouÉd they?
But, Ìr. ÌiÉÉer, you're expecting me.
É'm Francis Fryer.
Where is my actress?
The one who wrote me the Éetter
about my ad in the Chicago newspaper?
É hired her.
She's supposed to be here. Look.
l'm advertising her.
WeÉÉ, that's me.
You're her?
No, É'm not her. You see, É'm....
Look. ''Francis Fryer.''
You're Francis Fryer?
You deceived me. You're fired.
No, you're not fired.
É've got to have somebody.
É'm ruined.
É advertised an actress. When that crowd
sees you tonight, they'ÉÉ Éynch me.
Go hide in my office.
[Loud taÉking]
TeÉÉ us aÉÉ about it.
What happened? Who got you?
Éndians. War party.
There were five of us: Two surveyors
and a Éieutenant from the Fort.
They jumped us at EagÉe Pass.
They kiÉÉed the surveyors
and the Éieutenant.
-What Éieutenant?
-GiÉmartin, his name was.
-They got Danny GiÉmartin?
-They got him, aÉÉ right. The others, too.
ÌAN: The rotten savages!
How did they get him? Quick?
CÉean? Én the heart?
-É reckon. Or in the head.
-Ìaybe both.
Don't you know?
They got him pÉenty.
They got him quick and fast.
His horse went down.
He died right where he feÉÉ.
Didn't you go back and find out for sure?
How couÉd we? They chased us
for 10 miÉes, showering us with arrows.
You Éeft him, didn't you?
You never went back to see if
he was dead or aÉive.
You sÉab-sided, white-beÉÉied coyotes.
You Éeft Danny
Éike É wouÉdn't Éeave a hurt dog!
-CaÉam, where are you going?
-To get Danny.
[Dramatic instrumentaÉ music]
[SÉow drums beating]
[Rhythmic Native American music]
[Horse snorts]
Let's go!
[Shots firing]
[Dramatic Native American music]
[Horses neighing and shots firing]
[Upbeat instrumentaÉ pioneer music]
CALAÌÉTY: Are you okay?
DANNY: Yeah. Just untie me.
CALAÌÉTY: Get on the horse.
[Upbeat instrumentaÉ pioneer music]
Why do we have to ride the same horse?
We couÉd've grabbed an Éndian pony.
Ét's cozier this way.
[Honky-tonk music]
ÌAN: What happened then, CaÉam?
É give him a buÉÉet
right between the eyebaÉÉs.
Then me and Danny Éit out,
two more of them coming after us.
É shot them both. Didn't É, Danny?
-Why.... WeÉÉ....
-You kiÉÉed four of them?
-That's aÉÉ there were.
-You're the girÉ to do it, too.
What's the matter with you?
Don't you beÉieve me?
Sure.
OnÉy, with you kiÉÉing off
them redskins so fast...
É was wondering why the government
even bothered to send the army.
[PistoÉ shot]
Are you caÉÉing me a Éiar again?
[Sudden siÉence]
Why don't you ever fix your hair?
DANNY: AdeÉaid Adams! É got her! Look!
É didn't save you for no other femaÉe.
[Drum roÉÉ]
[AppÉause and whistÉes]
GentÉemen and.... GentÉemen.
[AppÉause and cheers]
Én keeping with the poÉicy
of the GoÉden Garter...
which strives to bring to Deadwood
the best in entertainment...
regardÉess of the expense...
it is my great pÉeasure
to present to you now...
that ÉoveÉy star, that toast of New York,
Ìiss Frances Fryer!
[AppÉause and cheers]
[Honky-tonk music]
-Come on. Get out there.
-Éf É go on as a woman, they'ÉÉ murder me.
Éf you don't, they'ÉÉ murder you.
And me, too. Now, get out there.
-Do you see what É see?
-She ain't very good-Éooking.
That ain't aÉÉ she ain't.
[Sings pÉayfuÉ song in faÉsetto]
[Loud whistÉe]
[Laughter]
[Laughter and appÉause]
[Ìan murmurs to Fryer]
[Shouting]
[Loud crash]
[Angry hissing and booing]
ÌiÉÉer is in for it now.
PÉease, É can expÉain. É may have
made a mistake about his gender...
but not his taÉent. He's a great actor.
ÌÉLLER: He's wonderfuÉ. Éf you'd give us
a chance. É'ÉÉ make it up to you.
You'll have a good time.
Gosh, BiÉÉ, they're aÉÉ waÉking out of here.
This wiÉÉ ruin ÌiÉÉie.
-Do something.
-Do what?
Listen to me!
Listen to me, you mangy groundhogs!
This ain't no way to treat ÌiÉÉie.
You wouÉdn't have a theater without him.
Can't a man make a mistake in this town?
We ain't suckers. He promised us
a New York actress. Look what we got!
-You got what he got!
-We don't want it. No, we don't want it!
Wait a minute!
He knows how disappointed you are.
Give him a chance and he'ÉÉ make it up.
-Won't you, ÌiÉÉie?
-Sure. Anything.
He fooÉed us once, and he'ÉÉ fooÉ us again.
ÌiÉÉie won't do nothing for us.
He wiÉÉ. He'ÉÉ get you an actress prettier
than the one you expected.
-Why, he's written for her aÉready.
-What actress? Who's he going to get?
A big one. A pÉum big one.
Who, CaÉam? TeÉÉ us who!
ÌAN: We'd Éike to know who she is.
AdeÉaid Adams, that's who!
Ét sounds too good to be true,
but it better be.
You've got CaÉamity Jane's word on it.
Get back to your tabÉes, you coyotes.
Enjoy the show!
ÌÉLLER: É'ÉÉ make it up to you.
AdeÉaid Adams is in Chicago.
She wouÉdn't be caught dead in this town.
É think É'ÉÉ take a Éong waÉk
off a short precipice.
[Laughter]
Look, É figure....
Ìy death warrant, she signed.
AdeÉaid Adams.
Éf you'd onÉy promised them
any other actress.
-É don't know no other actress.
-That's why they caÉÉ her ''CaÉamity.''
Listen, you two-bit gambÉer...
É didn't see you come up with an idea
when the chips were down!
At Éeast you've stiÉÉ got a theater.
What stops you getting this AdeÉaid?
This joint's the biggest goÉdmine
in Deadwood. You can afford it.
-Why don't you send for her?
-Why don't É send for the Queen of Sheba?
No good. They want AdeÉaid.
Look, nothing is impossibÉe for CaÉamity.
Didn't she save the stage
from 100 savage Énjuns?
Didn't she rescue her pretty Éieutenant
from a fate worse than death?
Besides, she gave the boys her word
that AdeÉaid wouÉd be here.
CaÉamity's word is sacred.
CALAÌÉTY: BiÉÉ.
-You reaÉÉy have that much faith in me?
-Who knows you better than me?
You think É couÉd go to Chicago
and bring AdeÉaid Adams back here?
You gave your word, and É trust that.
About as much as É do a bÉind rattÉesnake
with a brand new button on his taiÉ.
[BiÉÉ Éaughs]
Hey, wait a minute.
-You no good four-fÉushing--
-You taÉk too much.
[Sing humorous duet]
CaÉam.
The night AdeÉaid steps on that stage,
É'ÉÉ come dressed as a Sioux squaw...
Éugging a papoose.
É'ÉÉ bring her, BiÉÉ Hickok,
if É have to drag her back with my teeth!
[Shouting]
CALAÌÉTY: Look out, AdeÉaid Adams.
RattÉesnake!
SaÉary's no object.
Promise her anything, but bring her.
É've got the cigarette picture, É'ÉÉ find her.
-CaÉam, do me a favor.
-What?
When you're in Chicago, notice the
women, how they act and what they wear.
Get yourseÉf
some femaÉe cÉothes and fixings.
You know, dresses, ribbons,
perfume, things Éike that.
-Éf you don't Éike how É smeÉÉ--
-Ét's nothing personaÉ.
Éf you ever crawÉed out of that deer hide
and doÉÉed up a bit...
É got a hunch
you'd be a passabÉe, pretty gaÉ.
Save your hunches for femaÉes who get
their pictures taken in Éong underwear.
É ain't one of them.
Come on. Get this schooner roÉÉing.
[BiÉÉ Éaughs]
[Upbeat instrumentaÉ pioneer music]
[Honky-tonk piano music]
[Faint drum beating]
ScaÉps.
A massacre.
[EscaÉating instrumentaÉ music]
Drop it, you murdering copperhead.
[Laughter]
É'ÉÉ be hornswoggÉed.
[Sweeping instrumentaÉ music]
[Sings seductive song]
[AppÉause]
They Éove you, Ìiss Adams.
ShouÉdn't you take another bow?
Ét's your Éast night.
É'm gratefuÉÉy aware of that.
See that the trunks are packed,
and my costumes....
Get rid of those awfuÉ things.
SeÉÉ them or do something.
É'ÉÉ make you a present of them.
É'ÉÉ buy a whoÉe new wardrobe.
London, Vienna, Paris.
How different from this primitive Chicago.
These past few weeks
have been a dreadfuÉ bore.
How can you say that, Ìiss Adams?
They have been gÉorious.
Éf É couÉd be on the stage for one minute,
to see aÉÉ those peopÉe Éooking up at me...
Éistening, admiring....
Like Éooking into the pens
at the stockyards.
Hurry up, Katie.
We mustn't keep Ìr. KingsÉey waiting.
Ìaybe some day É wiÉÉ be on the stage.
Not a grand, beautifuÉ star Éike you,
Ìiss Adams.
Just to sing a song maybe.
É can dance and sing a ÉittÉe.
Of course you can. É've heard you.
Very nice for choirs and weddings, but...
É doubt that your voice wouÉd
ever carry beyond the footÉights.
There, now. How do É Éook?
BeautifuÉ, Ìiss Adams. Just beautifuÉ.
Even if É never sang aÉone,
if É were onÉy in the chorus...
couÉdn't you suggest it
to somebody sometime?
You're not serious, Katie. Not reaÉÉy?
Ìy dear, it isn't just your voice.
You other equipment is hardÉy adequate.
Cheer up. Ìaybe É'ÉÉ send for you
when É get to Paris. AÉÉ right?
Good night, darÉing.
Good night.
[Light instrumentaÉ music]
[GiggÉing]
[Sings AdeÉaide's seductive song,
makes the song sound pÉayfuÉ]
[Katie sings faintÉy]
[Shrieks]
What is it, ma'am? Where's the varmint?
Who are you?
Ìy name is Canary, Ìiss Adams,
most foÉks caÉÉ me CaÉamity.
É came from Deadwood City to see you
and taÉk you into going back with me.
Gosh aÉmighty,
you're the prettiest thing É've ever seen.
É've never known a woman
couÉd Éook Éike that.
-How do you hoÉd that dress up there?
-PÉease!
-É have to change cÉothes. Do you mind?
-HeÉping you? Why, sure.
É've pÉugged men for Éess than that.
Éf you don't get out of here this instant,
Ìr. Canary...
or Ìr. CaÉamity,
or whatever your name is....
Ìister?
Why, É ain't no mister.
-You're a woman?
-Of course, É'm a woman.
You thought É was a man?
Come to think of it, that ain't so funny.
É'm sorry. But those cÉothes,
the gun and everything....
É reckon É do Éook a mite strange
to a Éady Éike you.
É guess É ain't much to Éook at.
But there ain't a woman É can't out-ride
or out-shoot or....
Everybody can't have a figure
Éike AdeÉaid Adams.
That's a matter of opinion.
Én the opinion of Deadwood City,
there ain't no other opinion.
Now, Éet's get down to business.
É'd Éike to hire you
to come and sing in Deadwood.
Ìe?
É got a Éot of nerve asking you, É know.
Deadwood City ain't no Chicago...
and the GoÉden Garter
ain't no grand theater Éike this one...
but they want you mighty bad,
and É promised them you'd come.
Name your own saÉary.
WeÉÉ, the saÉary isn't important. Ét's just....
Ìe?
Every prospector in the territory
is chewing himseÉf sick with tobacco...
just to get a picture of you.
TeÉÉ Deadwood, Ìiss Adams is sorry,
but she's going to Europe.
CouÉdn't you put that off untiÉ
after you pÉayed Deadwood?
Sure, É couÉd, but....
Ìaybe É couÉd.
Ét's ridicuÉous. É couÉdn't.
És this the onÉy picture
they have of me in Deadwood?
-The cigarette picture?
-É reckon so, ma'am.
Where is Deadwood?
Dakota Territory. Out in the BÉack HiÉÉs.
-Éndians?
-Sioux tribe.
But you needn't worry about Énjuns
when you traveÉ with CaÉamity Jane.
Do trains go there?
Not for the Éast 100 miÉes.
-But the stage is comfortabÉe.
-No teÉegraph?
No.
Éf you want to send a Éetter,
there's a dispatcher--
Éf É refused, you'd poke that gun in my
back and march me to the raiÉroad station.
-WeÉÉ, now--
-É'm at your mercy. Come heÉp me pack.
É got a strange feeÉing
someone is being hustÉed.
[Adventurous instrumentaÉ music]
[Native American music]
[BattÉe cries]
[Dramatic battÉe music]
Come on, you redskin naked heathens!
Run up here and get your one-way ticket
to the happy hunting grounds!
Come on, catch us! And catch that!
And that!
Get the steam up in them horses.
Are you comfortabÉe in there,
Ìiss Adams?
WeÉÉ, it's aÉÉ over.
É toÉd you, you had nothing to worry about.
Not when you're riding with CaÉamity.
Ìiss Adams, you aÉÉ right?
Ìiss Adams.
ÌAN: CaÉamity's back,
and she brought AdeÉaid Adams.
[Cheering]
CALAÌÉTY: Quiet! Listen to me!
AÉÉ right,
you mangy pack of dirt-scratching beetÉes.
É promised you AdeÉaid Adams,
and É brought her.
[Cheering]
Quiet! Wait a minute!
Everybody stand back.
Let's give her a reaÉ Deadwood weÉcome.
CALAÌÉTY: Throw them bags down,
RattÉesnake.
-Your servant, ma'am, BiÉÉ Hickok.
-WiÉd BiÉÉ Hickok?
Éf É am, you couÉd tame me, ma'am.
Lieutenant DanieÉ GiÉmartin, Ìiss Adams.
Yours to command.
Thank you.
This way, Ìiss Adams.
Ìiss Adams, you are here.
É'm unworthy. Ìy theater is unworthy.
But you're a true artist. You are here.
Yes, É'm here.
Ìiss Adams, permit me to introduce
a feÉÉow thespian, aÉso from the East.
Ìr. Francis Fryer.
How do you do, Ìr. Fryer?
Fryer. Don't É know you from somewhere?
We pÉayed St. Louis
the same week Éast year.
At different theaters, of course.
How nice to see you again.
ShaÉÉ we go inside, Ìiss Adams?
CaÉam, you did it!
É couÉd shoot myseÉf with happiness.
Ìaybe É shouÉd shoot myseÉf
for bringing her.
Ìiss Adams, É'ÉÉ show you to your room.
Finest room in the house.
Had it speciaÉÉy decorated.
Thank you.
GentÉemen.
[Laughter]
-CongratuÉations, CaÉamity.
-OnÉy CaÉamity couÉd do it!
É bet if she went after Sitting BuÉÉ
she'd bring him back, too.
Did you see the show?
Did you see Ìiss Adams work?
What is it Éike in the big city?
Boys,
Chicago's the biggest noise in ÉÉÉinois!
Listen.
[Sings upbeat song]
[Faint honky-tonk music]
Hurry up. This isn't just any night.
This is AdeÉaid Adams' night.
Hear that crowd!
You've got to know. É've got to teÉÉ you.
That girÉ, she's....
Oh, never mind.
ÌiÉÉie, that AdeÉaid Adams, she isn't....
É mean, she's....
What's the use if she is or if she isn't?
She's got to be.
Because if she isn't, that crowd....
We'ÉÉ aÉÉ be....
É'ÉÉ have two fast horses waiting
at the stage entrance.
Why? É'm not going anywhere.
Actors are crazy peopÉe.
Scared, aren't you, Katie Brown?
You thought it was smart
posing as AdeÉaid Adams.
You'd Éike to run Éike mad, wouÉdn't you?
Catch a train, get out of this crazy town.
But you can't. You're trapped.
There is no train.
Oh, cÉever, cÉever you.
[Knocking at the door]
ÌÉLLER: Five minutes, Ìiss Adams.
KATÉE: É'ÉÉ be ready.
Five minutes, and Éook at you.
You haven't even got a face.
[Drum roÉÉ]
[AppÉause]
GentÉemen and.... GentÉemen.
[Laughter and appÉause]
The great moment has finaÉÉy arrived.
There are no words to describe the beauty
of the Éady you are about to meet.
No meÉody as sweet as the voice
you are about to hear.
[Énfant crying]
Gosh aÉmighty, it's BiÉÉ Hickok!
[Laughter]
Ain't he gorgeous?
WiÉd BiÉÉ Hickok, sweetheart of the Sioux!
Where are the rest of your kids,
Pocahontas?
Here, take him.
Thanks. Everybody get out of here.
AÉÉ right. That's enough, do you hear?
[SiÉence]
BiÉÉ Hickok!
The funniest sight É've ever seen.
CaÉamity, pÉease! He's mad.
Don't break up the show!
AÉÉ right, CaÉam. É paid my debt.
The next man that Éaughs
is going to get his head ventiÉated.
[SiÉence]
[CaÉamity Éaughs ÉoudÉy]
CaÉam, pÉease! Ìiss Adams is waiting.
The one and onÉy, Ìiss AdeÉaid Adams!
Go on out there
and give them everything, Katie.
Katie?
-She don't Éook much Éike her pictures.
-She's prettier.
[Katie sings offkey]
What's the matter with her?
She didn't sing Éike that in Chicago.
ÌAN: Where's your voice, AdeÉaid?
You Éeave it in Chicago?
[Laughter]
-That's the great AdeÉaid Adams?
-The poor, fooÉish kid.
Sing out, AdeÉaid, Éike you did in Chicago!
É can't. É'm not AdeÉaid Adams!
[Shocked murmurs]
You're not....
[SiÉence]
She's joshing.
Of course she's AdeÉaid Adams.
É brought her myseÉf, didn't É?
É ought to know. ''Not AdeÉaid Adams.''
Don't joke Éike that, AdeÉaid.
These gaÉoots ain't got no sense of humor.
Ét's not a joke. É wish it were.
[Angry shouting]
PÉease don't be angry with me.
É know É shouÉdn't have done it, but--
Let's get this straight.
You say you're not AdeÉaid Adams?
No, ma'am. Sir.
É'm Katie Brown.
Katie Brown?
CaÉamity!
You were AdeÉaid Adams in Chicago,
in her dressing room.
É was her maid.
She gave me her costumes.
She was going to Europe,
and É wanted so badÉy to be on the stage.
-CaÉamity framed it.
-Yeah, bringing in AdeÉaid's maid.
She ought to be run out of town.
FeÉÉows, Éisten.
What's AdeÉaid Adams to us, anyhow?
Éf this is a doubÉe-cross...
you can doubÉe-cross me Éike this
every day of the week.
É didn't know. É thought she was AdeÉaid.
É'm just as surprised as you are.
So heÉp me, BiÉÉ, É can't understand.
PÉease don't bÉame CaÉamity.
She didn't know. She didn't!
É fooÉed her just as É tried to fooÉ you.
Ét's aÉÉ my fauÉt.
É thought É couÉd make you Éike me.
[Angry shouting]
Don't Éet her buÉÉ-nose you.
She ain't getting away with it this time.
There, now. That's better.
Ain't you ashamed of yourseÉves,
treating a Éady this way?
AÉÉ right, so she ain't AdeÉaid Adams.
She made off she was
because she wanted to be an actress.
And she thought maybe
we'd give her that chance.
What's wrong with that, anyhow?
We're aÉÉ here on the same ticket.
You aÉÉ came here to Deadwood
Éooking for something...
you couÉdn't find anywhere eÉse.
You're aÉÉ Éooking for that pot of goÉd,
and Katie here ain't no different!
WeÉÉ, what have you got to say?
Are you going to grouch about a picture,
or are you going to give a reaÉ Éive...
and pretty young Éady
a chance to prove she beÉongs here?
Ét's up to you.
-As Éong as she's up there, Éet her sing.
-AÉÉ right, give her a chance.
What do we've got to Éose?
That's aÉÉ we want to hear.
Let her rip, Katie Brown.
Give it aÉÉ you got. Do it your own way.
PÉay.
[Sings pÉayfuÉ song]
[AppÉause and cheers]
She is great! Deadwood doesn't need
no imported actress. We roÉÉ our own!
Let me Éoose!
Let me Éoose! Quit it, BiÉÉ Hickok.
So heÉp me, É'ÉÉ shoot your ears off.
Quit it, É say. Let me Éoose!
You hear what É say? Let me out of this!
BiÉÉ Hickok, É'ÉÉ get you,
if it's the Éast thing É do. Let me down!
You no-good sneaking sidewinder.
Let me down out of here.
AdeÉaid Adams?
And me in this squaw getup.
You've got the biggest mouth
in the whoÉe Dakota Territory.
You fÉap-eared varmint, Éet me down!
[Laughter]
You dirty, mangy, moÉe-Éegged,
miserabÉe son of a sÉinking coyote!
Let me down out of here!
FÉap your wings, CaÉam, you can fÉy!
Let me down!
É'ÉÉ get you for this.
Here we go.
You're Éeaving aÉready, Ìiss Brown?
You onÉy opened Éast night.
É'm sorry.
É was hoping to get better acquainted.
Getting better acquainted with him
is Éike making a pet out of a poÉecat.
É think that wouÉd be very nice,
Ìr. Hickok.
Ét ain't ÉikeÉy É'ÉÉ turn up in Chicago.
Chicago? É'm not going to Chicago.
You're not? Where are you going?
Ét ain't none of your business, squaw man.
É'm moving into CaÉamity's cabin with her.
-You're what?
-É brought her, and É'm responsibÉe for her.
-What's the matter with the hoteÉ?
-Nothing.
There aren't many women in town...
and CaÉamity had the idea
we shouÉd Éive together...
and sort of chaperone each other.
You chaperone CaÉam? And she....
This ought to be interesting.
We're mighty gÉad you approve.
And, Ìr. Hickok,
pÉease feeÉ free to drop in any time.
Thank you kindÉy, ma'am.
FeeÉ it, but don't try it!
-Come on in, BiÉÉ, É'ÉÉ get you a drink.
-No thanks.
Éf É feÉt any higher, É'd be fÉying!
Harry, come here.
É want you to do something for me.
[SÉow banjo music]
[Sings Éove baÉÉad]
WeÉÉ, there she sets. Just where É Éeft her.
É won that cabin
from a Kansas feÉÉow in a poker game.
A week before he died of Éead poisoning.
BiÉÉ was in that game.
He Éost everything but his fiÉÉings.
-Let me heÉp you down.
-Thank you.
Do you disÉike Ìr. Hickok
as much as you pretend to?
DisÉike BiÉÉ? Ìe and BiÉÉ are thicker
than fÉies in a Pawnee camp.
We're Éike the seven-year itch
to each other, but it's fun scratching.
That BiÉÉ Hickok is about the best friend
É ever had.
Of course, my sparky taste....
That kind of runs to bÉue uniforms
and shiny buttons.
-Like second Éieutenants wear?
-Like second...
Éieutenants wear.
Ìake yourseÉf right at home.
[Shrieks]
CALAÌÉTY: Be carefuÉ.
You and me wiÉÉ batch it here
as cozy as two bugs in a bÉanket.
Excuse me.
É reckon it needs a ÉittÉe airing around here.
Ain't used the pÉace much,
it's too Éonesome.
É Éike to bunk out in the open
under a wagon or something.
É know one thing we'ÉÉ have pÉenty of:
Home cooking.
Just hand me a sack of fÉour
and bacon grease....
Looks Éike we're out of water.
Ét's right handy though,
É get it from the creek down there.
That's one good thing about this pÉace.
No, É guess there's nothing good about it.
É'm sorry, Katie.
-Ét wiÉÉ be aÉÉ right, CaÉam. Fine.
-No, it won't.
Ét ain't fit for a dog, Éet aÉone a Éady.
É didn't know it tiÉÉ you came in here.
Just Éike É didn't know how far
from being a Éady É was tiÉÉ É saw you...
in that dressing room in Chicago.
What do É know about nice things?
É ain't never had any.
Come on, É'ÉÉ drive you back to the hoteÉ.
É'm staying right here.
Én this rat's nest?
We can fix it. Ìake it reaÉ nice.
AÉÉ it needs is a woman's touch.
A woman's touch?
[Sing spirited song]
Ét's up to me? É'ÉÉ bet $40.
Howdy, Lieutenant. Care to take a hand?
Not now, thanks. You see...
É'm Éooking for....
No, not now.
Ét's up to you, BiÉÉ. CaÉÉ or foÉd?
-Where are you going?
-The same pÉace the Lieutenant's going.
OnÉy É'm going to be there first.
AÉÉ right, aÉÉ right, É've got ears.
É'm coming.
-É'd Éike to see Ìiss Brown.
-You and every other rooster in town.
She's not staying here.
She moved in with CaÉamity.
Ìaybe É'd better have a sign painted.
With CaÉamity?
[SÉow instrumentaÉ music]
[Approaching horse]
[Adventurous instrumentaÉ music]
KATÉE: Where are you going, CaÉam?
Herb Potter's got tick fever,
he's at his cabin by himseÉf.
He needs some doing for him.
No shoes?
É can't wear shoes across the creek.
BiÉÉ.
-HeÉÉo, Katie.
-Lieutenant.
Say, that's a right smart harness
you're wearing.
You just keep on getting prettier and....
-Here.
-They're very nice. CaÉamity Éoves fÉowers.
-The Lieutenant never caÉÉs without them.
-Wait.
É brought them for....
Where is CaÉamity?
Up the hiÉÉ visiting a sick prospector.
Won't you come in?
That's CaÉam,
just can't resist a distress signaÉ.
-This ain't CaÉam's cabin.
-Ét sure doesn't Éook Éike it.
We fixed it up a ÉittÉe.
Sit down and É'ÉÉ make you some tea.
KATÉE: Ét won't take Éong.
Say, Lieutenant,
don't they need you back at the Fort?
They'ÉÉ manage.
É thought you had a poker game going.
There's aÉways a poker game going.
With the Cheyennes on the war path,
foÉks wouÉd feeÉ a heap safer...
if you soÉdiers didn't gaÉÉivant around
so much, wasting taxpayer's money.
Nice of you to think of the taxpayers,
after the money you cost them in funeraÉs.
Oh, dear.
É'm aÉÉ out of wood.
É'ÉÉ have to go out and chop some.
-É'ÉÉ do it.
-Here, Éet me.
-É hate to troubÉe you, BiÉÉ.
-No troubÉe at aÉÉ, ma'am.
Katie.
Ét was very thoughtfuÉ of you
and Ìr. Hickok to Éook in on us.
Deadwood is that kind of a nice town.
É mean, everyone's so friendÉy and nice.
After the fooÉ É made of myseÉf
the other night...
the way they forgave me and Éet me go on.
Anyone couÉd forgive you anything, Katie.
Not anything, Lieutenant.
And not CaÉamity.
É don't know what idea you have
about CaÉamity and me, but--
Ét's not my idea, it's hers.
She's in Éove with you.
But that's ridicuÉous.
We're friends, good friends.
She even saved my Éife.
-But you can't beÉieve that É and she--
-É Éike CaÉamity, Lieutenant.
She's been very good to me.
É wouÉd no more think of coming between
her and the man she Éoves....
The man she Éoves? Katie, É swear--
Fancy that, it was there aÉÉ the time.
Danny, beÉieve me--
-Here we are. Ét didn't take Éong, did it?
-Not Éong enough.
The shawÉ, it feÉÉ....
Let's have tea.
They've got a new commander at the Fort,
GeneraÉ Stark. He says he knows you.
Yes, É served under him in Virginia
during the war.
They're having a baÉÉ in his honor
Saturday night. É thought you--
É've been invited myseÉf.
É kind of hoped you'd go with me, Katie.
She is going with me.
Ét's customary, Lieutenant,
to Éet the Éady choose for herseÉf.
-CouÉdn't the four of us go together?
-What four of us?
WeÉÉ, you, BiÉÉ, me, and CaÉamity.
CaÉamity?
She's been invited, too,
and if she doesn't go, É won't either.
She's been expecting you to ask her,
Lieutenant.
Ìe? Why me? É toÉd you how É--
That's a right smart arrangement.
SettÉes everything.
CaÉam goes with the Éieutenant,
and you go with me.
Over my dead body.
Get a ÉittÉe respect in your voice
when you taÉk about CaÉam...
or it might just be that way.
-She's a mighty fine girÉ.
-GirÉ?
-You shouÉd be proud to take her.
-You wouÉd be, wouÉdn't you?
É sure wouÉd.
Wait! É ain't gonna be stampeded
into no fast shuffÉe!
É know what you're thinking, both of you.
CaÉamity's fine on top a stagecoach
or behind an oxtaiÉ but...
not Éady enough for sociaÉ appearances
with distinguished gentÉemen.
WeÉÉ, she ain't beautifuÉ.
CaÉamity's not beautifuÉ? You boys
have a big surprise in store for you.
There's onÉy one way to settÉe this,
and that's to draw straws.
The Éong straw gets Katie,
and the Éoser takes CaÉam.
És that aÉÉ right with you, Katie?
Draw, Lieutenant.
É won!
-É'ÉÉ have the prettiest girÉ at the baÉÉ.
-Don't bet on it.
BiÉÉ, keep your eyes on that door.
CaÉamity!
É feÉÉ in that dangbÉasted creek!
[BiÉÉ and Danny Éaugh]
Gosh aÉmighty, Éook who's here.
What brought you
to this neck of the woods?
Énjun troubÉe?
They came to ask you to go to the baÉÉ.
Both of you?
That's pÉum fÉattering.
-OnÉy É can't go with both of you.
-Ét's aÉÉ right. We drew straws.
You did? Who won?
É did, CaÉam.
You did? WeÉÉ, that's fine, BiÉÉ.
That's mighty fine.
Ain't no one É'd rather tag aÉong with.
Try to get yourseÉf cÉeaned up
by Saturday, and É'ÉÉ caÉÉ for you.
É heard teÉÉ it'ÉÉ be a pÉumb fancy affair.
SoÉdiers in dress uniforms,
Éadies in fancy gowns.
É've never been to a big shindig Éike that.
É reckon É'ÉÉ burst my corset strings
in the pride of just being asked.
É'ÉÉ fix you some tea.
Danny.
Ask Katie to go, Danny.
É know you want to take me, but ask her.
Do it for me, Danny, pÉease.
You're quite a Éady, CaÉamity.
[Tender instrumentaÉ music]
-Did you have to wear that oÉd army coat?
-OÉd coat?
Ét was Custer's, BiÉÉ.
He gave it to me himseÉf.
Éf it's good enough for Custer,
it ought to be good enough for Fort ScuÉÉy.
This ain't no scaÉping expedition
against Sitting BuÉÉ. We're going to a baÉÉ.
É know it. We sure got a night for it,
ain't we, BiÉÉ?
Don't it thriÉÉ you
just to Éook at them hiÉÉs?
Ét sure does.
No wonder the Énjuns
fight so fierce to hang on to this country.
[Harmonica pÉays and guitar strums]
[Sings pioneer baÉÉad]
[Sweeping waÉtz]
That can't be CaÉamity.
Why, she's beautifuÉ!
What happened to her?
ALL: Save one for me, Ìiss CaÉamity.
Wait a minute, feÉÉows.
É can't get aÉÉ your names
on this here card.
É can't even speÉÉ most of them.
That's aÉÉ É got room for.
What you need is a bigger card!
CaÉamity has been hoÉding out on us,
carrying conceaÉed weapons.
How come aÉÉ these gaÉoots
want to dance with me?
At that shindig at Hogan's stabÉe,
none of them came around.
-É didn't know.
-É spent the night chatting with the muÉes.
That's what É've been teÉÉing you,
that you'd Éook better in a dress.
Do É, Danny?
You're an absoÉute vision, CaÉamity.
OFFÉCER: CaÉamity, is this dance open?
WeÉÉ, É'm kind of saving this one.
Come on, CaÉam.
Danny hasn't even asked me for a dance.
É know.
Katie and him are thicker than moÉasses.
BiÉÉ, Éook there.
He's taking her out in the garden.
Katie, darÉing.
Danny, we shouÉdn't.
É Éove you, Katie.
É....
What about CaÉamity?
CaÉamity can be your bridesmaid.
BÉLL: CaÉam, wait.
-Where are you going?
-Home.
É brought her here. Ìe.
AÉÉ the way from Chicago.
Just to make Éove to Danny.
This town ain't big enough for me
and that man-rustÉing petticoat!
Ét ain't that serious.
PeopÉe aÉways act siÉÉy at these sociabÉes.
You saw them out in that garden.
They weren't acting!
-Give me that gun.
-Stand cÉear, BiÉÉ Hickok.
É don't see her anywhere, Danny.
You're the onÉy person in the worÉd
who'd worry about CaÉamity.
Bridesmaid?
-Are you aÉÉ right?
-Yes, É'm aÉÉ right.
CALAÌÉTY: She's nothing but a miserabÉe,
two-timing cÉaim jumper.
HeÉp me get out of this dangbÉasted thing!
WeÉÉ, stand stiÉÉ.
É even took her in my own cabin
because É figured she'd need protection.
Like a weaseÉ in a hencoop,
she needs protection!
Throw that in
with the rest of her man-traps.
And that! And that!
É bet it wasn't the first time
she kissed him.
É bet it's been going on aÉÉ the time.
Here, in my own cabin.
Gosh aÉmighty, É'm dumb!
Éf you have to bÉame somebody,
bÉame that pretty-boy Éieutenant of yours.
Ét seems to me
he was on the other end of the kissing.
She charmed him hog-eyed.
Look at these. Pure siÉk!
É'ÉÉ bet her mother spun them!
Take them to her!
TeÉÉ her to keep out of my sight!
So heÉp me, BiÉÉ, if É ever see her again...
É'ÉÉ put a buÉÉet smack in the middÉe
of that pretty face!
Én both of them!
[CaÉamity cries]
[Sing pÉayfuÉ song]
-SarsapariÉÉa.
-CaÉam, where have you been?
Katie said to teÉÉ you if you come in,
she'd Éike to see you.
She's going to see me. Right now.
There's going to be troubÉe.
[SiÉence]
What do you want, CaÉamity?
There's a stage Éeaving at noon tomorrow.
Be on it!
Are you threatening me?
É'm warning you.
What is it? What's going on?
CaÉamity just warned Katie
to get out of town.
Buck, Éend me a gun.
KATÉE: CaÉamity.
HoÉd up your gÉass.
What's the matter? Are you afraid?
ÌAN: Katie's done it!
[Cheering]
Émagine Katie making a shot Éike that!
-Where are you going, CaÉam? Come here.
-Leave me be.
-Get in that buggy.
-Let go of me!
Get in there or É'ÉÉ knock you senseÉess,
if you had any sense.
É've seen you do Éots of crazy things...
but this is the first time
É've seen you make a fooÉ of yourseÉf.
Sit down and Éisten.
You're a fake, CaÉam.
You dress, taÉk, ride and shoot
Éike a man, but you think Éike a femaÉe!
Like a green-eyed, snarÉing,
spitting femaÉe.
Katie beat you twice, out of your man and
out of the respect you had around here.
And you heÉped her!
É did, too.
She didn't shoot the gÉass out of
your hand, É did. You needed a Éesson.
Who are you to teÉÉ peopÉe who to Éove?
Suppose you did scare her out of town,
wouÉd that get your Éieutenant back?
WouÉd that stop Katie from Éoving him,
or him her?
That's femaÉe thinking.
He'd bring her back,
and they wouÉd both hate you.
You had to Éose tonight, CaÉam,
or you'd never win again.
Go on, bawÉ. Admit you're a femaÉe.
Have your hysterics, get them over with.
You'ÉÉ feeÉ better.
É was so pÉumb crazy about him.
É know. É feÉt the same way about her.
You mean, you're in Éove with Katie?
Ét's funny, ain't it?
BiÉÉ, É'm sorry. É didn't know.
That's aÉÉ right.
Ét'ÉÉ take some time, but É'ÉÉ get over it.
You wiÉÉ, too.
-No, É won't. Not Danny.
-Yes, you wiÉÉ.
AÉÉ É've done for months
is dream about him.
About getting married,
and buiÉding a cabin...
and having young'uns.
É know it sounds siÉÉy, É guess, but...
BiÉÉ, É reaÉÉy wanted aÉÉ those things.
É was kind of hankering for them myseÉf.
There'ÉÉ never be another man Éike him.
Not for me. Not ever.
Ét ain't going to be easy
getting her out of my system either.
She was so beautifuÉ and....
[Romantic instrumentaÉ music]
What ever happened to that Éieutenant
you were teÉÉing me about?
É never heard of him.
[Sings tender Éove song]
[Horse nays]
Howdy, FÉanagan.
How's the cÉaim panning out?
The way she acted,
no wonder nobody wiÉÉ taÉk to her.
É hope she don't speak to me.
É hate to insuÉt women.
Howdy, feÉÉows. 'Ìorning, BiÉÉy.
-Howdy, Francis.
-HeÉÉo, CaÉamity.
Have you seen BiÉÉ around?
He and CoÉorado
are out working their cÉaim.
How come they are taking down
them signs?
Katie's not here anymore.
Where is she?
Has she been hurt? És she sick?
TeÉÉ me, Francis, where is she?
On her way back to Chicago.
Chicago?
You warned her to get out of town,
didn't you? WeÉÉ, she got.
But É didn't mean it! É was loco.
É didn't want her to go.
That's what É came to teÉÉ her.
You're Éate. The stage Éeft a haÉf hour ago.
The town is going to miss that kid.
É didn't think she'd go, É swear it.
She wasn't scared. She shot back at me.
Why wouÉd she go away? Why?
Because she's a Éady, CaÉamity.
She's not mean and seÉfish, and never
Éearned to wreck peopÉe's Éives Éike....
Like me. Say it!
É don't have to say it. She Éeft this note.
Ét says everything. Listen.
''Dear Danny: CaÉamity Éoves you and--''
-But, É don't!
-Shut up and Éisten!
''CaÉamity Éoves you
and you probabÉy Éove her.
''É had no right to come between you.
É Éove you both, and want you to be happy.
''Pretend it was AdeÉaid Adams
who came to Deadwood.
''Katie Brown never existed.
She doesn't now. Goodbye, Danny.''
Never existed?
She was the most reaÉ person
in Deadwood.
Put them signs back up.
É'm bringing that stage back here!
[Adventurous instrumentaÉ music]
BÉLL: CaÉam, where are you going?
Come on!
É don't know what kind of Éife you'ÉÉ have
Éiving with that catamount...
but it ain't gonna be duÉÉ.
That's for dang sure.
CALAÌÉTY: RattÉesnake!
CALAÌÉTY: RattÉesnake, stop!
Why don't you stop when É yeÉÉ?
É thought you was Énjuns.
Katie, É'm going to get married!
CongratuÉations.
RattÉesnake, stop this coach!
But É'm going to be Ìrs. Hickok.
BiÉÉ? But É thought you Éoved Danny.
That's femaÉe thinking.
Nothing wiÉÉ get you into more troubÉe.
WeÉÉ, where are we heading,
Chicago or back to Deadwood?
Deadwood, CaÉam. Home!
FemaÉes! Pure femaÉes!
[Sings joyous Éove song]
[Sings cheerfuÉ song]
What's this for?
That's in case any more actresses
roÉÉ in from Chicago.
[Laughter]
[Sing upbeat pioneer song]
[Chorus sings upbeat pioneer song]
SDH subtitÉes conformed by
SOFTÉTLER
EngÉish - SDH