I never figured Hal Crane would
have the nerve to string up barbed wire.
It's more than barbed wire.
It's a thousand head of my steers,
dying for feed and water.
You just have to drive your herds
across his land once a year.
You could still work out
something reasonable.
I'm through being reasonable.
I told Crane what would happen
if he strung that wire.
Blaise...
We've pulled over some hard hills together
and I've rode behind you all the way.
A wire fence is a poor excuse
to make a widow out of Crane's wife.
What have you been
thinking about all winter?
Crane's barbed-wire fence
or Crane's pretty wife, Helen?
Oh, hi, strangers. It's good to see you.
- Hi, Ernine.
- Ernine.
Be with you in a minute, Blaise.
I didn't think you men
would get out in this weather.
Ernine, put up some coffee.
You boys must be eating
pretty good at your place.
Sure ran through that last batch
of supplies awful fast.
I didn't come to town for supplies.
I came here to get a shave.
Look, Blaise, these farmers
got a right to live too.
Never saw so much stock on your shelves.
You're doing a pretty brisk trade
with them, Vic.
They're decent, hard-working folks.
All they ask out of life
is a break from the weather
and a chance to work their lands in peace.
Ever known me to break the peace, Vic?
No, but I've seen you
put away some who tried to.
- I don't hold for killing.
- You don't have to.
As long as you got somebody
to do it for you.
I'm beholden to you
for what you've done in the past
but things has changed
and we got to change with them.
I don't object to change, just fences.
Barbed-wire fences.
I warned Hal Crane he was foolish
for ordering that load of wire.
Still ordered it for him,
didn't you, though?
Well, a man has a right
to spend his own money as he sees fit.
You've declared yourself, Vic.
That's all I want to know.
Crane's a proud man.
He won't knuckle down.
But he's a farmer.
That gun he carries is mostly bluff.
You call his hand,
it will be plain murder.
Hello, Mrs Crane.
Why, hello, Vic.
Dan.
Mr Starrett.
If you'll just give me a list,
I'll get right to it
so you can leave town before dark.
We're not leaving. Hal wants to stay
overnight to settle some business.
Coffee's on, boys.
Oh, hello, Mrs Crane.
Won't you join us
for some nice hot coffee?
Why, thanks, Ernine.
I don't know if I should.
This is the first time
we've been away in months.
I promised Mrs Preston
that we'd come over.
Come on, boys.
I make much better coffee
than that ranch mud you drink.
Go ahead. Have a nice friendly
cup of coffee the way neighbours do.
Won't you sit down, Mr Starrett?
You know, I'm glad your husband
is stringing up those barbed-wire fences.
We want more farmers around here
and less cattle.
That's not a very friendly thing
to say, Ernine.
Oh, I'm friendly enough, all right.
It's just that you and Blaise
are keeping me from getting married.
I want a husband and not some ranch hand
that makes $30 a month
with a bed in a bunkhouse.
I want a young farmer,
homesteading a quarter section.
I'm afraid Mr Starrett's more concerned
with keeping the range open
than your getting a husband.
You've got the best excuse I've heard yet.
Ernine, where did you put the shortening?
Oh, Father, just when
we were getting sociable!
Excuse me.
How's the winter at your place?
Oh, it's been colder and harder than most.
Excuse me, Mrs Crane.
This coffee made me think
how good whiskey would taste.
Excuse me.
See you at the Wyoming.
Do you want to tell me something, Helen?
I don't love you anymore, Blaise.
- I want you to understand that.
- I don't.
- Can't you see how wrong it was?
- I can see what's true.
I don't care what's wrong or right.
Loving you has made me
a stranger in my own family.
It's made me feel cheap
every time Hal looks at me.
It's not a nice feeling.
It's better not to love at all.
You met him first, you married him.
Right now you can't even remember why.
Spending the rest of your life with him,
that would be the cheap thing to do.
When Hal and I first came here,
you could have had me for the asking.
I'd come to a new country
with a new husband.
I would have given up anything
if you'd only taken me then.
I made a mistake.
- I'm not proud of what we did, Blaise.
- I'm not proud I let you stay with him.
I could have been stronger with your help.
I'm only concerned
with what's going to be.
We're going to meet in town
once or twice a year.
I'm going to call you Mr Starrett
and you're going to call me Mrs Crane.
That's what has to be.
That's easy to say,
not so easy to do.
I was more lonely this winter
than I've ever been before.
But I had time to think.
I'm gonna be Hal Crane's wife forever.
I'm sorry you had to say that, Helen.
Everything has to be
on Blaise Starrett's terms.
You don't want the farmers
to fence their farms.
You back your orders with guns.
You want another man's wife
but the man has to be dead
before you'll take her.
You don't have much mercy, do you, Blaise?
You won't find much mercy
anywhere in Wyoming.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Funny weather we're having.
If that warm wind keeps blowing,
the road will be belly-deep in mud.
You might have to stay in town a few days.
I wouldn't count on that.
Hey, George.
My horse seems
to be favouring her left foreleg.
Give it a good rub-down
before you turn in tonight.
You might not be needing a horse tomorrow.
He's coming.
I see you brought the kerosene.
Five gallons, like you ordered.
We've been having a meeting.
- Doesn't look like a prayer meeting.
- It wasn't.
I'm speaking for all present, Blaise.
We're not going to stand
for any gun play in Bitters.
I won't start it, Vic.
I'd like that tin of kerosene back,
Blaise.
- Didn't you pay for it?
- It's paid for.
Take good care of it.
I'd like to have a word
with you, Mr Starrett.
You must have passed my wagon
on your way in.
I did.
Soon as the road's in shape
I'm moving that wire up to my place.
- And I'm stringing it up.
- That's what I thought it was for.
HAL: What do you intend to do about it?
It's going to be cold
riding home tomorrow.
I thought it'd be nice
to stop and make a fire.
I hear kerosene is the fastest way
to burn up a wagon.
- HAL: You burn my wagons and I'll...
- Hal...
Hal.
Please.
HAL: What do you intend to do about it?
I intend to go upstairs
and get a good night's sleep.
I asked you a question, Mr Starrett.
BLAISE:
When I wake up I'll know what to do.
- I usually do.
- I've got to know.
You want to know the future, Mr Crane.
That's wanting too much for any man.
I'm not afraid of you, Starrett.
Mr Starrett and I have
some business to discuss.
Would you excuse us, please?
I'm sure Mr Starrett doesn't object
to my presence here.
Mrs Crane being with you
doesn't influence me.
I'll fight for what I believe,
Mr Starrett.
I'll die if I have to but I'll fight.
I want you to know that.
You've got a big mouth, farmer.
You got big eyes too.
You came here a year ago
in your broken-down wagon,
looking for a choice spot to settle.
And you think you found it.
But you never stopped to think
what made it such a good place.
When Dan and I came here
Bitters was the nesting spot
for every thief and killer
in the territory.
A man's life wasn't worth
the price of a bullet.
No woman was safe in the streets,
let alone in a lonely farmhouse.
It took more than a big mouth
to get rid of the lice
who infested every bend of the road
you ride so safely on.
I'm not saying Dan and I did it alone.
But we did more than our share.
We hunted them down in the freezing cold
while you sat back in the east,
hugging your pot-bellied stoves.
Nobody thanked us. Nobody paid us.
We did it because we felt we belonged.
We'd earned the right to belong.
And all you've done is ride in here
and put down your stinking roots.
And now you tell us
that you belong and we don't.
Mr Crane,
you said you'd fight
to keep what you wanted.
Well, I've been doing that for 20 years
and I intend to keep on doing it.
And no pig-bellied farmer's
going to stop me.
Give me a bottle, Tom.
Don't kill my husband.
He intends to kill me.
Hal's never fired a pistol
in his whole life.
Then he shouldn't wear one.
He's not a coward.
He won't beg for his life.
I'm not that courageous. I do beg you.
You should be telling this to him.
I have.
- He won't listen.
- What made you think I would?
Do you want me, Blaise?
Do you want me
to ride out to your ranch with you?
I'm offering myself to you,
on any terms you want, but leave Hal live.
Your husband's a stubborn man.
He won't give up his fences.
Why should he give you up?
I'll tell him I no longer love him.
He'll only come after you.
It'll still have to end the same way.
You're not a cruel man.
I've been close enough to you to know.
Why must you act like one?
Because I can't feel sorry
for someone I hate.
Do you hate me too, Blaise?
Tell your husband to load up his wagons
and take you out of Wyoming.
Don't you think I've tried?
I knew this was coming.
I've waited all winter long for this day.
You have to do it, Helen.
Make him take you away.
He's afraid of you
but he's not a weak man.
He'll die before he'll run.
Then that's the way it'll have to be.
I'm sorry to have troubled you,
Mr Starrett.
Dan?
I'm no good to you, Blaise.
I'm no good to you.
Hold it.
Don't touch that kerosene.
We want you to go home.
There are three of us.
Dan.
Dan!
Roll the bottle down the bar.
When it hits the floor, that's it.
Roll the bottle, Dan.
Anything we can do for you strangers?
Yes, could be.
I was looking for a quiet place.
We were settling a little private quarrel.
I apologise.
I don't like to break in on a party.
But we'll take your guns.
You won't find anything to take
in this town.
You'd be surprised
at what we can find to take.
Trail ends in this town.
No place to go but back.
The trail back is closed.
Who's following you?
- Cavalry.
- Two days' hard riding behind us.
Cavalry doesn't bother
tracking seven men like you.
Captain Jack Bruhn,
United States Army,
formerly.
BRUHN: Hey, you.
I want food and service for my men.
- We'll pay.
- Yes, sir.
That cavalry won't stop for food and rest.
My men rest.
Now, listen, do as you're told
and you can go about your business
just like we're not here,
almost.
But we are here so it's best you know
with what you're dealing.
Pace here, he derives pleasure
out of hurting people.
Tex, rile him and you're gonna hear
some screaming in this town today.
Denver,
half Cheyenne.
Him hate white men
but he doesn't feel half so badly
about white women.
Vause,
bones covered with dirty skin
but even half-drunk
he's the fastest draw
in Wyoming territory.
Shorty,
we soldiered together.
The young fella, he's a fresh recruit
but he's learning fast.
I believe you.
You just killed a man for no reason.
There will be no more killing
and to make sure,
Denver, Vause,
take that drunk
and round up every gun in town
and destroy them.
And don't waste time arguing with anybody.
How many people live around here?
About 20.
- Who's the law?
- We handle our own law.
Not now.
Let's get started, Bruhn.
We can do whatever we want in this town.
I'm edgy to get doing.
Where do you hide your women around here?
Leave our women out of this.
We only want to borrow 'em.
TEX: We'll give 'em back.
No women.
And no whiskey and no gunning.
With 40,000 in gold in our saddlebags
and a long ride ahead?
We'll pleasure ourselves
at the end of the trail.
It's gonna be a long day, Captain.
You wanna argue, Pace?
No, just reminding you.
I gotta have a drink.
One.
I'd like one,
but it's the order of the day.
Is there a doctor in this town?
BLAISE: Doc Langer.
Vet, back of the barbershop.
BRUHN: Can this horse doctor
take out a bullet slug?
- BLAISE: He has.
- (BOTH SNIGGER)
BRUHN: Freeze it, Pace.
You seem to think a lot
of your women in this town.
Who does she belong to?
She's my wife.
Change your mind about no women, Captain?
There are only four women in this town.
Do you want your men
killing each other over them?
Tex, Pace...
Search upstairs.
Bring anybody you find down here.
Shorty,
take these two to the store.
Then round up all the women
and put 'em in the store
and tell 'em to get inside
and stay inside.
My wife is upstairs.
My men won't molest your women
unless I give them permission.
(SHRIEKING)
- We found one more.
- Get down here!
Lady, you go to the store
with the rest of the women.
Hey, you. I told you
to prepare the rations.
Now, get going.
We've been riding hard
for over a month, Captain.
Hey!
Hide your liquor and hide it good.
(COUGHING)
Now... let's go see that horse doctor.
When the boys come back, keep them here.
No man leaves this saloon till I return.
And no whiskey.
That's an order.
- You handle your men well, Captain.
- They need me.
Come along with me.
That bullet's way in deep.
I don't see how he's still walking around.
- Has he got a chance?
- If he was a horse or a cow, I'd know.
I just ain't had too much practice
on humans.
It says that a person with a deep wound
can die of internal bleeding
even though nothing shows on the outside.
- Is he bleeding internally?
- I couldn't tell.
Do you want me to kill him?
Kill him?
If Bruhn dies, this town gets torn apart.
They'll go after you first.
You got to keep him alive.
But how?
Look, I don't know how. I can't operate.
I haven't got the instruments.
- I wouldn't know how to use them.
- You're gonna operate.
What are you two talking about?
The Captain's waiting
for you to take the bullet out, Doc.
He's waiting for the water to boil.
If Bruhn dies, I'll kill you.
What are we waiting for?
Sit down.
You'd better have some of this.
Put it away.
Hide the liquor.
BRUHN: Mr Starrett, talk to me.
What about?
Anything, Mr Starrett.
Anything.
BLAISE: Where did you serve
in the cavalry, Captain?
Why do you ask?
I remember hearing about a Captain Bruhn.
Some incident with the Mormons in Utah.
I just wondered if you were the same.
DOC: Would you help me, please?
What did you hear?
BLAISE: No.
Couldn't be you.
Yes, it was.
BRUHN: Strange, how one word
can change a man's life.
I could have ordered, "Retreat!"
My command was, "Fire!"
At West Point I made up my mind
to be all soldier,
which doesn't leave much room
for being human.
Thanks.
Keep your people in check.
I'll control my men.
Gene,
stay with me.
I'm sleepy.
What are his chances, Doc?
I don't know.
It was in real deep.
I'd say if he lasts through the night...
I just don't know.
Shorty.
I found a bottle in the barbershop.
The Captain says no whiskey.
- He'll never know.
- He knows everything.
They'd have hung you back in Casper
if it hadn't been for Captain Bruhn.
And I'd have been an old bum in Adeline.
I wish you hadn't busted
the bottle, Shorty.
We could have had just one drink.
Did you ever see what the Captain does
to men that disobey?
- I've never seen anybody disobey him.
- I have.
Be glad I busted that bottle.
I'll get it.
It's a relief to see
you and Mr Starrett friendly again.
Mr Preston and I were so worried.
That's all over, isn't it, Mr Starrett?
Doesn't seem very important right now.
- Hal and you can be good friends.
- Yes, we might try it sometime.
What Blaise needs
is a wife to steady him down.
Clagget stole a horse from 'em.
He's just saddling up.
He's gonna make a run for it.
He's crazy. He'll never make it.
- He knows they're watching the road.
- Keep the women inside.
Clagget, hold it.
My wife's alone at the farm.
I got to go to her.
You can't get through.
They got a man watching the road.
I'll get through.
(GUNSHOT)
Bruhn is dying.
I saw him a little while ago.
He looks strong and healthy.
He might not last the day.
- What will happen if he dies?
- They'll start drinking and fighting.
- I've got to get Tommy out of that place.
- No, you can't help him. You better stay.
- They'll be here too, soon enough.
- They mustn't find you here.
ERNINE: Where can we hide in town?
DAN: Beats me. Even if we had horses
you couldn't get away through the snow.
The ladies will have to walk.
Get back to town.
Get out of here.
Gene.
That's your name, isn't it?
Don't make me use this gun.
I don't think you ever shot anybody.
I could start with you. What do you want?
Let those women go by.
I can't do that.
They're coming. Are you gonna shoot them?
I can't cross Bruhn. I got to warn him.
No. I don't think you want
those women to get hurt.
I don't think Bruhn wants it either.
Only Tex and Pace want it.
You gonna do it for them?
(GUNFIRE)
- Why didn't you stop 'em?
- GENE: I was trying to.
Go back to town.
BRUHN:
I told you your women would be safe.
All you had to do was wait.
Why didn't you believe me?
You've got all the cards, Bruhn.
Go ahead and play.
Only don't take it out on them.
It was my idea.
I'm gonna have some fun
with them now, Jack.
The name is Bruhn.
Ain't no reason
to give 'em a break now, Bruhn.
- I put my claim on that one first.
- I'm gonna make the little one happy.
You won't turn your men loose, Bruhn.
Why not? They wanna get drunk.
They wanna have some fun.
They could swallow this town whole
and nobody would be alive to tell the tale.
You won't let that happen.
- Say the word, Captain.
- I'll toss you for the pleasure.
Mr Blaise, you broke your word.
Only because I don't believe
you can hold your men.
Tex, put down the gun.
Go back to your homes, everybody.
Stay on the inside.
You, stay here.
He's all yours, Texas.
No gun.
(LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
Thought you'd make yourself
a big man in this town, huh?
Vause, Denver,
finish him.
With your fists.
BRUHN: Shorty,
bring that boy.
- SHORTY: Come here, sonny.
- VIC: What do you want him for?
BRUHN: He comes with me.
Your friends will sacrifice you
but they won't cause
a young boy to be hurt
by acting foolish.
Don't worry about the boy.
I'll take care of him.
I promise.
Now, go on back.
Please.
He'll be leaving as soon as it's daybreak.
Sure.
Bruhn seems to be getting better.
They're staying close to the Wyoming.
Good.
Hal is grateful for what you did.
Deeply grateful.
Go back to him.
I told him I was coming here.
I asked him to come with me.
But he told me to come alone.
I believe he knows and understands.
What's to understand?
You're his wife, I'm a stranger.
Go back to your husband, Mrs Crane.
Thank you, Blaise.
Thanks for understanding.
- You mustn't come in here.
- I've got to see Bobby.
He's all right.
This is no place for you to be.
Please.
Go home.
I wanna see Bobby first.
BOBBY: Please don't. Ow! No, no!
- Ow!
- Say you'll do it
or I'll break your little arm.
No, no. Please don't. Ow!
- Let the kid go, Pace.
- Bruhn's got the whiskey here.
I want the kid to find out where it is
and get a bottle.
If you want a drink, ask Bruhn.
Are you giving orders now?
In this case I am.
Forget it, Gene. We're all getting jumpy
from not having any liquor or fun.
When he cools off, give him his gun back.
(SNORING)
Get out of here, Ernine.
I'm taking him with me.
Stop.
Look, I'm sorry. You can't do that.
She hasn't done anything. Don't hurt her.
I'm not gonna hurt anybody.
He's all right.
He's as rotten as the rest of them.
You shouldn't have come here.
I'm taking Bobby back with me.
That'll just make things worse.
The boy's got to stay.
I saw what happened.
I heard him screaming.
It won't happen again.
The boy has to stay.
There's no other way, Ernine.
How do you do, Miss?
She was worried about her brother.
She's leaving.
No need to be.
What's your name, Miss?
Bruhn said to leave the women alone, Pace.
I didn't bring her.
She's here because she wanted to be.
- That gives me certain privileges.
- Freeze, Pace!
This sure is a night for tangling.
I got a better idea.
Let's toss a coin for her.
Leave.
Bobby, tell your sister to leave.
Go ahead. I'll be all right.
You didn't have
to pull that iron on me, Gene.
I'm your friend.
We ride together, don't we?
Sure, Pace.
We ride together.
We're friends.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
Yeah, thanks.
I'm worried about Bruhn, Doc.
- How is he?
- Coming along.
He ain't hurt bad, is he, Doc?
Not like dying?
- You don't want him to die, do you?
- No, of course not.
He never answered you.
I tell you, Tex...
there's something really wrong with Bruhn.
There is?
- What?
- TEX: You sure look fine, Bruhn.
- Where's that little boy?
- PACE: In the kitchen with Gene.
I don't want that boy
harmed or frightened.
We all like the kid, Bruhn.
I want the boy with Gene.
How about breaking open a bottle,
just one drink?
I'm getting a chill. Just one drink.
I want every man cold sober.
We pull out of here at dawn.
(WIND HOWLING)
We don't ride tomorrow or the day after.
Did you see the weather coming in?
My tongue's salt-dry for whiskey.
We took that army pay wagon,
fought hard, shot our way out.
For what?
Sitting around on our butts
like this was Sunday school!
Captain, you ain't letting
nature take its course.
Men don't act like you make us act here.
We've got this town under our thumb
but we ain't getting no pleasure.
Two more days like this
is gonna seem like two more years.
Maybe not even you
can keep us in line, Bruhn.
I gave my word to the people of this town.
Why did you?
To make you look big and us little?
Maybe you better answer, Bruhn.
You'll drink, fool around,
then kill each other over these women.
I'm a-riding out of here
at daybreak with six men.
It's Saturday night.
Invite the ladies over for a social.
There's no harm in coffee and cookies
and a little dancing.
- It'll take the edge off for a while.
- Yeah.
And all I'd like is a chance
to talk to that little girl.
I won't even ask her to dance
if she don't want to.
With no liquor
it'll be a quiet Saturday night.
We need it bad, Captain.
Very well.
(HONKY-TONK PIANO)
BRUHN: Tex!
One dance and I get her back.
If I was drunk
I'd really show you how to dance.
Maybe Bruhn will open up
the whiskey pretty soon.
I won't let Pace touch you.
Are you any better?
I'm sorry, I didn't mean it.
No, you're right.
I came with them, I'm one of them.
I said I wouldn't let Pace touch you
but you don't have to dance with me.
Don't leave me.
Why don't we dance?
I want to look at you.
I think Tex has got to the point
where he can't stop.
Tex.
May I dance with the lady?
Now.
I'm gonna get Bruhn one of these days.
It's been tried by a lot of dead men.
Why did you have to do
this terrible thing?
There are things worse, Ma'am,
than dancing with lonely men.
- Please let us go.
- Soon.
Why did you have to come here?
You should be grateful.
Our coming saved the life of your husband.
I don't believe
Blaise would have gone through with it.
Mrs Crane,
when my men and I leave here
there will be a showdown
and you will be a widow.
Shorty.
- Having a good time, gentlemen?
- Yeah.
How long can Bruhn live?
Well, I gave him a big shot of morphine.
It deadens pain,
makes the patient feel fine.
As soon as that dose wears off,
he's gonna start coughing.
The cough's gonna rip the lungs
a little bit more.
A few hours after he starts coughing
he's gonna die.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
I didn't expect to hear music tonight.
They took the women
to the saloon with them,
to dance.
Dance?
What are the men gonna do about it?
Nothing, just talking.
Crane is talking about going to see Bruhn.
If he does,
looks like you'll get what you wanted
without doing a thing.
BLAISE: Hold it, that's enough.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Are you giving the orders now?
No.
You don't know about the weather
up in these mountains.
It's storming up here
but not down in the valley below.
You came here to talk about the weather?
Those soldiers you think are days
behind you are riding over the trail
and they're heading this way.
Your concern for my men and me,
Mr Blaise, is very touching.
Your position is hardly a tactical one.
You can't fight those soldiers here.
Even a private
would realise that, Captain.
Can you suggest an alternative?
Yes, if you stop this party.
There's another way through the mountains.
No trail, no pass, but there's a way.
- I've been through it.
- He's lying.
Why didn't you take your women
that way this morning?
It's too rough for the women.
Might be too rough for some of your men.
He's lying. I tell you, Bruhn, he's lying.
I'll find out.
You ride with us, lead the way.
(WIND HOWLING)
You couldn't find it without me.
Shorty...
Pack your gear and assemble the men.
We're moving out at daybreak.
Gene, get the ladies out of here.
(COUGHING)
Don't be frightened anymore.
We'll be gone in a few minutes.
Can I get you something? Some tobacco?
No, thanks. I don't smoke.
I'll always remember you.
Goodbye, Gene.
Goodbye, Ernine.
You mustn't go with them.
I have to.
I might come back later but I have to.
If you go, you'll never come back.
There's no way through that mountain.
Blaise.
There is no trail to Cheyenne.
I never said there was a trail.
I said there was a way through.
Stop manoeuvring. There's no way.
Kill him.
Wait, Gene.
I'd like you to know why I lied to you.
I'm not interested.
You're a dying man, Bruhn.
That interest you?
How do you want to die?
You're a man, not an animal.
You can ride out here with me
and die clean,
or turn your men loose on this town
and die like a pig in the mud.
Do you want another Mormon massacre?
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
How do you want to go, Bruhn?
Ernine told you there was no trail.
- I didn't say who told me.
- Ernine must like you.
Have you any idea what Pace
will do to her when Bruhn dies?
- I can stop him.
- Are you sure?
I won't be here to help you, son.
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
Just a minute.
I know what I'm doing
and I know what Gene's doing.
But you, what's your reason?
- Why do you want to die?
- I know what I'm doing too, Bruhn.
Let's leave it at that.
I guess every fool has his reason.
Ernine spoke the truth.
- There is no way across the mountain.
- Who knows?
Maybe I'll find a trail.
I'm not even sure they're going.
But if they do go,
you know you won't come back.
Probably not.
Why are you doing this?
I'm not doing anything special.
I'm just taking some bad men
out of a good town.
You're the same man
who would have killed Hal.
I don't know you at all.
No reason to.
Are you doing it because of me?
I'd like to know, Blaise.
I'm doing it because of myself.
That night in my room in the Wyoming
you asked me not to kill your husband
and I took a good look
at myself in the mirror.
I didn't like what I saw.
I'm not any different from the men
who rode in and took over this town,
only they don't pretend to be
anything but what they are.
And that's all there is to it, Mrs Crane.
Let's move.
Ah, I feel better now.
I'm beginning to hope we're gonna make it.
None of us are gonna make it.
Hey, Blaise,
how are we gonna get out of this?
(WHINNYING)
I'm gonna need me another horse.
Ride one of the pack horses.
Gene, get off your horse.
Bruhn said get down.
And I'm saying
leave your saddlebags where they are.
There's 6,000 in gold in 'em.
You can't carry it anyway. Get down.
Just follow the tracks.
If snow covers them, keep the wind
at your back. You'll be all right.
Down!
Hey!
You won't be needing that gun.
We're both giving this party, Mr Blaise.
Move out, son.
Say hello to the soldiers for us, kid.
TEX: That's right.
SHORTY: Captain Bruhn! Captain Bruhn!
What's wrong?
Hey, Starrett, help me.
Hold it. We have to stop here
till the Captain can ride again.
We're not stopping.
(GUNSHOT)
Get on your horse.
Thanks,
Captain Bruhn.
What are you thanking him for?
Get on your horse.
I don't think you wanna kill me.
We got to have Blaise, Tex.
We're gonna stop and bury these two men.
You know,
it's kind of a lucky ride after all.
Lucky?
Yup. We started out
with about 6,000 in gold apiece.
Now we got 18,000 more to split four ways.
Cayenne,
here I come.
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
What are you looking for?
You see anything?
Not much.
There's nothing to see.
You know where you're taking us?
Yes.
You lie, you know it.
I know it.
Turn around and go back to camp.
I'll show you
what a Cheyenne does with a liar.
Get up. You're not hurt.
Vause gave Tex and me the idea himself.
Let's ride.
Come on.
Come on! Come on!
Come on back there. Come on back there!
Not much shelter.
(WIND HOWLING)
PACE: Stop him.
Stop him, Tex.
(GUNSHOT)
Now we have to go out and bring him back.
We need him.
I shot his horse.
He'll come crawling back to us.
Now, let's get this fire started.
We got the horses, the grub and the guns.
He can't live out there.
Damn wind!
Horses can't stand it either.
Now, let's get this fire started.
What are you doing?
(NEIGHING)
I don't have any matches.
I don't have any matches. No matches.
(WIND HOWLING)
(WIND HAS DROPPED)
(NEIGHING)
Welcome home, Mr Starrett.
Wait a minute.
I thought it best he stay here
while the soldiers will be around.
I'd like to work for you, Mr Starrett,
if you'll have me.
All right, Gene.
Then you won't need this.