(music)
(music) Old Yeller
Old Yeller (music)
(music) Old Yeller (music)
(music) here, Yeller (music)
(music) come back, Yeller (music)
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) Old Yeller was a mongrel (music)
(music) an ugly lop-eared mongrel (music)
(music) fancy-free
without a family tree (music)
[ dog barking ]
(music) but he could up and do it (music)
(music) and prove there's
nothin' to it (music)
(music) and that's how
a good dog should be (music)
(music) here, Yeller (music)
[ whistling ]
(music) come back, Yeller (music)
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) Old Yeller
was a hunter (music)
(music) a rarin', tearin' hunter (music)
(music) in any chase
he knew just how to run (music)
[ dog barking ]
(music) and when
he hunted trouble (music)
(music) he always found it double (music)
(music) and that's when
Old Yeller had fun (music)
(music) here, Yeller (music)
[ whistling ]
(music) come back, Yeller (music)
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) Old Yeller was a fighter
a rootin', tootin' fighter (music)
(music) in any scrap
he knew just what to do (music)
(music) knew what to do (music)
(music) a rough and ready feller (music)
(music) although his coat
was Yeller (music)
(music) his bold Texas heart
was true blue (music)
(music) true blue (music)
(music) here, Yeller (music)
[ whistling ]
(music) come back, Yeller (music)
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) here, Yeller (music)
(music) come back, Yeller (music)
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) best doggone dog (music)
(music) in the west (music)
What's pop gonna
sell our steers for ?
For money, of course.
What's money ?
It's what you
buy things with.
What do you
mean by "buy things ?"
Well, if you
got money, you give it
to people for stuff.
They say you can get
anything for money.
Anything ?
What's it look like ?
Well, I never seen
but one piece:
A dollar bill Papa had.
It's paper.
What'd Papa get
with this dollar ?
Nothin'.  It wasn't no good.
But you just said you could
get anything with money.
Well, ya can.
But Papa's was Confederate.
- What's Confederate money ?
- Confederate money ?
Well, it's--
Well ?
Don't you ever run
outta questions ?
I wish you
didn't have to go.
Right now I feel
sorta the same way, but...
I put 100 head of our steers
into that pool herd.
And in Kansas, we can get,
maybe, four or five dollars
a head fer 'em.
Cash money too.
I know but--
Ain't nothin' to be sad
about, Katie girl.
When you think on it,
we're lucky.
There's us and the young 'uns,
good land,
Plenty of water
game for the killin'.
Cash money is all we need
to get a tight tail-hold
on the world.
Will you really be gone
three months ?
All of three months,
maybe four.
Now, honey,
it ain't nothin'
to cry about.
It's just that we've
never been separated before.
You know what I'm gonna do
when I sell them steers ?
What ?
Get you a store-bought dress.
The first one you've had
since we come to Texas.
Let's see.
Is this about
the right size ?
Papa !  I aim
to go with ya !
You better stay here
and take care of your Mama.
Aw, gee, Papa.
But I wanna go.
I tell ya, I wanna go !
I wanna go !
Wanna go !
Arliss.
[ Arliss ]  let go !  I wanna go
with Papa !
You ride a piece
with me, Travis.
I wanna go !
[ grunts ]
but I wanna go !
I can ride them old cows
same as you.
You can't go on no cow drive,
boy.  Them injuns would
scalp you for sure.
You think so, Papa ?
I'm certain.
Good-bye, Katie.
Good-bye, Jim dear.
[ clicking tongue ]
Well, son, while I'm gone,
you'll be the man
of the house.
Yes, sir.
There'll be the pigs to Mark,
fresh meat to shoot.
And mainly,
there's the corn patch.
If you don't work it right,
we'll be without bread
this winter.
It's sure enough
a man-sized job.
Think you can handle
Old Jumper when
he's hooked to a plow ?
I'll handle him,
or I'll bust his jawbone
with a club.
[ chuckles ]
well, all right, boy.
I'll see you this fall.
Papa, you ain't
forgettin' the horse ?
What horse ?
Now, Papa, you know
I've been achin' all over
for a horse to ride.
I told you time and again.
Well, what you're needin' worse
than a horse is a good dog.
Yes, sir, but what I'm wantin'
worst is a good horse.
All right, boy.
You act a man's part,
and I'll bring you
a man's horse.
Wanna shake on it ?
[ clicking tongue ]
Whoa.
[ dog barking ]
[ barking continues ]
Whoa !
Whoa, Jumper !
[ barking ]
Whoa !  Whoa, Jumper !
[ Travis ]
get away from that mule !
[ barking continues ]
Let that mule alone !
[ sighs ]
Papa ain't gone a full day
and look what a mess.
It's not your fault, son.
Maybe not, but--
[ barks ]
Get, you crazy fool dog !
Get !
I know one thing.
That old dog better not
come around here while
I got me a gun in my hands.
Who busted down the fence ?
[ Katie ]
where have you been ?
Bear huntin'.
Who busted the fence down ?
Danged old stray dog.
Dog ?  Where is he ?
You won't never see him.
I done rocked him
clean off this place.
But I need me
a good huntin' dog.
Arliss, go wash up
before supper's all cold.
Aw, Mama.
Go on !
- What do you got
in that pocket ?
- Nothin'.
Let's see what you got
this time.
Aw, Mama.
Come on.
Oh, Arliss !  How can you
even touch those ugly things ?
They aren't ugly.
Look it here at his belly,
how soft and smooth
and pretty it is.
I know.  Everything
you catch is pretty.
But take him outta here.
You can't keep him in the house.
You mean I gotta
throw him away ?
And everything else
you got in those pockets.
My frog too ?
[ croaking ]
Arliss, what all have you got
in those pockets ?
[ gasps, screams ]
Aw, Mama, it's just
a little old garter snake.
I don't care.
Get it out of here !
Arliss, if you don't stop
catchin' things and bringin' 'em
into the house,
I'm gonna switch you good.
And don't you ever,
ever pick up a snake again.
Ya understand ?
Yes'm.
Now, go wash up for supper.
Little old garter snake
ain't harmful.
If he'll pick up
one kind of snake,
he'll pick up another.
Next time it could be
a rattler.
I wish he did have a good dog,
like Old Bell.
When you were little,
Old Bell wouldn't let you
near anything harmful.
Ain't another dog
in this world
like Old Bell was.
Sure would've made
short work of that
Old Yeller stray.
[ birds twittering ]
[ rooster crowing ]
Mama.
[ sighs ]
I was just thinkin'.
About your Papa.
I guess he's eaten
his breakfast by now.
Probably wanted to get
an early start.
I wonder how far
they got yesterday.
Oh, I don't know.
Papa says 15 mile a day...
Is a long haul
for a trail herd.
I guess he made
about ten mile.
Mush is about ready.  If you
want middling meat with it,
better go out and cut some down.
All right.
[ rooster crowing ]
Mama, what happened
to the middling meat ?
Why, you no-account,
thievin' rascal !
Get outta here !
[ barks ]
[ door opening ]
A dog !
All right !
You hit my dog and
I'll wear you to a frazzle.
[ Katie ]  Travis, Arliss,
whatcha doin' out there ?
[ Arliss ]  let go of my stick !
Arliss !  Arliss.
Don't you dare hit your brother.
He was tryin'
to kill my dog.
He's not your dog,
and I never even touched him.
Where did he come from ?
He's that same stray dog
that wrecked the fence.
Stole that middling meat too.
He's my dog.
Ain't nobody gonna
try to hurt him.
Well.
Looks like
we've got us a dog.
Mama, you don't mean we're gonna
keep that old, ugly Yeller dog
after what he done ?
He isn't a ugly Yeller dog.
He's a pretty Yeller dog.
Come on now.
[ barking ]
come on.
[ chattering ]
Why not let Arliss
claim him ?
And have him stampedin'
Jumper again ?
You could break him of that.
He's a thief, Mama !
He'll steal us blind.
Most creatures will steal
when they're hungry enough.
All right, but I still
don't want him !
Now, Travis,
you're not bein' fair.
You had a dog
when you were little,
and Arliss has never had one.
He's too little
for you to play with.
He gets lonely.
[ barking ]
After breakfast,
you can take to the woods
and get us a deer.
And, Travis, do some thinkin'
on what I said about Arliss
and that Old Yeller dog.
Come on, boy.
[ chirping ]
Jumper, you jug head !
A bunch of bobwhites,
and you act like...
You ain't got the brains
of a blind goose
in a hail Storm.
[ rustling in brush ]
[ squirrel chittering ]
[ chuckles ]
[ chittering continues ]
Arliss, get that dirty,
old dog outta
our drinkin' water !
Aw, mind your own business !
- Get outta there !
- [ barking ]
You quit rockin'
my dog !
- Quit chuckin'
them rocks at me !
- [ barking ]
Ow !
Stop it, Arliss !
Stop it !
- You rock my dog again
and I'll bust your head open !
- [ Katie ]  Arliss !
Arliss !
Travis, what are you doin'
to your little brother ?
Him and that dirty, Old Yeller
dog were in our drinkin' water.
He was rockin' my dog !
Look here, young rooster.
If you wanna keep outta trouble,
start minding your big brother.
You mean I gotta mind him ?
He ain't my Papa.
Mm-hmm.
You start mindin' him just
the same.  Now go inside
and take off those wet clothes.
What I oughta do is get me
a sprout and give him
one good thrashing.
Take it easy, son.
He's only a little boy.
Papa wouldn't
want that old dog
in our drinkin' water.
Papa wouldn't have started
a rock fight
with Arliss either.
I never started
no rock fight.  He--
[ panting ]
Arliss rocks me.
Mama blesses me out.
And you.
You get off scot-free.
What I oughta do is run you
clean off this place.
You touch a bite
of this meat,
And come mornin'
I'm gonna shoot you
right between the eyes.
[ rooster crowing ]
[ groans ]
I'll be dogged.
Mama ?  Did you feed
that old dog anything ?
Well, no, I forgot to.
Been so long since
we had a dog.
Well, he's sure gone
and rustled up some grub
somewhere.
He ain't touched
a bite of that venison.
You might know
he'd be too smart for that.
You could've put it
on the ground and
he wouldn't have touched it.
You better get dressed
if you want an early start
cuttin' fence posts.
Yes'm.
[ barking ]
Come on, Yeller boy,
get him !
Get him, Yeller !
There he is !
There he goes, over there !
Missed him !
That's got him !
Good for you, boy !
Mama !
Mama, look at the fish
that I caught !
Ain't he a whopper ?
Oh, Arliss !
You're all wet
and muddy again.
But, Mama, I had to.
Had to ?
Had to dive way down
deep under to catch this fish.
He was way down deep under
where there was this cave...
And it was
real dark and muddy.
And there's about
a million other fish
and they all tried to eat me.
And I had to throw rocks
at 'em.  And then there's
these two big snakes and--
Sounds like that cottontail
you roped this mornin'.
But I did rope him.
Didn't I, Mama ?
He came runnin' by, and
I roped him right by the ears.
Well, you certainly
brought home a rabbit,
and now this big catfish.
- You're gettin' to be
as good a hunter as Travis.
- Here, Mama.
Come on, Yeller !
Come on, boy !
[ barking ]
yeah !
Mama, you know them
is just big windies
Arliss is tellin'.
Now, Travis,
let him tell his stories
the way he wants to.
But, Mama, I just seen
that Old Yeller dog
catch this fish.
Arliss is just a little boy
with a big imagination.  Won't
hurt him to let him use it.
[ disgusted sigh ]
we keep that Old Yeller dog
much longer...
And it's gonna make
Arliss the biggest liar
in Texas !
[ chickens clucking ]
Here, boy,
come and get some bread.
Here.
Come on.
A little closer.
Come on.  I'll give you
some more bread.
Come on.
[ low growl ]
come on.
[ loud wailing ]
[ wailing ]
what's that ?
Come on, boy.
[ wailing continues ]
Arliss,
turn it loose !
[ loud growl ]
Arliss, watch out !
[ growling continues ]
[ Travis ]
turn it loose !
[ barking ]
[ growling ]
Go on, ya old fool,
before she kills ya.
[ barking ]
Oh.
[ panting ]
[ crying ]
Oh, you crazy,
wonderful dog !
He acts like
it's a great big romp,
doesn't he, Travis ?
Crazy as a bull bat.
But he's a heap more dog
than I ever had him figured for.
[ whining ]
[ birds twittering ]
Just listen to those
songbirds this mornin'...
Singin' their heads off.
[ sighs ]
it's like the year
your Papa and I settled here.
We meant to build over
at the salt licks settlement...
Where it would've been safer
from the Indians, but...
That last day,
we camped by the spring.
And the bee myrtle
was in blossom...
And full of singin' birds,
like now.
And it was all so pretty,
I just couldn't go on.
And I said to your Papa,
"Jim, this is it.
This is home."
Hello, the house !
It's Bud Searcy
and Elizabeth too.
You might know he'd land
right at mealtime.
Howdy, Miss Coates.
Howdy do.  Howdy, boy.
How's everybody ?
Hello, Mr. Searcy.
Slide down, child.
Hello, Elizabeth.
Just dropped over to see if
there's any thing I could do.
Travis, take this pony
to the corn crib and strip
the saddle gear off him.
Yes, Mr. Searcy.
Might feed him a bit of corn
while you're at it, boy.
Won't you come and set a while ?
Well, I believe I will shade up
for a spell, Miss Coates.
Come on, Elizabeth.
Hot, ain't it ?
We don't get some rain
pretty soon, this country's
gonna burn up bad.
Corn crop ain't gonna
be worth nothin' more
than a whirlwind nubbins.
Some folks'll be scrapin'
the bottoms of their
meal barrels come wintertime.
This here's
hanged too long.
Elizabeth, honey, run down
to the spring and fetch your
poor old pappy fresh water.
I'll tell you, Miss Coates,
[ sighs ]
It's a heavy responsibility
ridin' herd on the settlement
while the menfolks is gone.
Wears a man
right down to a frazzle.
But I ain't complainin', though.
I was chose for this job
and I'll get her done.
I, uh, kinda figured
to head up that cow drive
to Kansas myself.
But when man after man called me
all spoke private like...
Beggin' me to stay,
look after you womenfolks and
the young ones, I seen my duty.
Knowed I was bein' called on
for a bigger job.
Jim said you were gonna
protect us all.
Mighty lucky thing too.
Know what happened
the other day ?
That fool kid of Jed Simpson's
shot at a bunch of hogs
and wounded one of 'em.
Set it to squealin'.
Ha !  Be dogged the rest of them
didn't tree that boy.
Kept him up there
till I happened along and
see'd what a pickle he was in.
Of course I couldn't chase
those pesky javelinas off.
But I did go tell
that boy's Mama where he was,
so she could rest easy...
Till the varmints left out
and give him a chance
to climb down.
Yep.  Lookin' out
after you womenfolks...
And the young ones
sure keeps a man
a-hoppin' around.
Biggest bother I've had, though,
lately is the thievin' what's
been goin' on at salt licks.
[ chuckles ]
meat stole out of smoke houses.
Hen's nests gettin' robbed.
- Mama, I'm hung--
- hush, baby.
Mr. Searcy's talkin'.
Womenfolks losin' bread
what they set out
in their "winders" to cool.
Sounds like some varmint.
There ain't no varmint
that clever, boy.
Mama, I'm hungry.
When we gonna ea--
Arliss.
I told you, don't butt in.
Mr. Searcy's talkin'.
[ chuckles ]
that's all right, Miss Coates.
Ain't nothin' like
a little old boy
to know when it's time to eat.
Well, I guess it is gettin'
on toward dinnertime.
Travis, will you go down
to the corn patch and pick us
some roastin' ears ?
Now, just a minute,
Miss Coates.  That boy need
help to tote all that corn.
Yes, sir.
[ chuckles ]
Elizabeth, go along
with Travis.
Be sure you pick out ears
what is sweet and juicy.
Why, coons been
in this corn !
Them thievin' rascals !
You'll have to take
to doggin' them overnight.
I got me just the dog for it.
Old Yeller will wipe up
the ground with them
pesky varmints.
You think
he can't do it ?
Oh, no.
It-- it ain't that.
Well, I didn't
wanna tell you
at the house, but...
It was him what done it.
What done what ?
What stole all them eggs
and bread and meat and stuff.
You mean Old Yeller ?
I seen him suck
a batch of eggs.
Seen him swipe a pan of
grandma's corn bread too.
- But I ain't gonna tell.
- I bet you do.
No, I won't.
Wasn't goin' to even before
I knowed he was your dog.
How come ?
Because Miss Priss
is gonna have pups.
Your dog'll be
their Papa.
And I wouldn't want him
to get shot for stealin'.
Just an old arrowhead
I picked up.
Comanche, Papa said.
Well, you can have it.
I won't never, never tell.
When you git right down to
hogs, just about the best eatin'
there is alive.
And I reckon just about
the meanest critter alive
go after his meat.
Cut you 14 different ways
before you can get fixed to rot.
They scare me to death.
Always dread the time when
Jim comes to do the markin'.
Yep, hogs is bad, mighty bad.
I had me an uncle once
down in east Texas.
- Tangled a bad hog, he did.
Got cut all to pieces.
- Kill him ?
Kill him ?
Why, it killed him
deader than a doornail.
Mr. Searcy, I roped me
a rabbit once.
Arliss, be quiet.
Mr. Searcy's talkin'.
Well, I did.
A mean old bitin' one.
[ laughing ]
Well now, boy,
that's really doin'
some ropin'.
[ chuckling ]
You know, speakin' of ropin',
I always done my hog work from
up a tree.  Heap safer that way.
How can you work hogs
from a tree ?
Why, it's slick
as a whistle, boy.
Pick out a tree with
a low hanging limb,
but out of hog reach.
Get your dog to rally
them hogs around the tree.
Reach down your loop,
pull up your pig and
go to work on him.
By golly !  That sounds
like it might work.
Work ?  Why,
of course it works !
Them old hogs can fuss and
charge around all they please,
but up a tree...
You're as safe
as at home in bed.
Travis, boy, you go fetch
my pony, and we'll be
pullin' out for home.
I've got a powerful lot
to do before suppertime.
[ loud sigh ]
it was right neighborly-like
of you to feed us, Miss Coates.
Now don't you fret yourself
at all while your man's gone.
We'll be lookin' in on you
again a-fore you know it.
Bye, boy.  Bye, Miss Coates.
Bye, Elizabeth.
Bye.
No wonder
they don't want him
on no cow drive.
By the time he finished eatin'
and visitin' with everyone
this side of Abilene,
Them cows would be
dead of old age.
Mama,
Elizabeth says
it's Old Yeller...
What's been doin'
all that stealin'
out in salt licks.
Claimed she
catched him at it.
Why, the old rogue.
We'll have to break him
of that...
Or else everyone
in salt licks'll be mad at us.
Somebody'll shoot him !
Yeller !
[ chickens clucking ]
come here !
You old rascal.
You been stealin' !
Maybe we better take
to pennin' him overnight.
I reckon we won't
have to bother
for a while.  Listen !
I'm gonna keep you
so dang busted busy...
You won't have time
to go off prowlin' !
[ Travis ]
no, you don't !
We're stayin' right here and
keepin' them coons run out,
you hear ?
Look at all
them stars, Yeller.
Bushels of 'em.
I wonder if maybe
Papa's lying out there...
On the trail somewhere
lookin' at 'em too.
I wish I was with him...
Way off yonder...
Up in Kansas...
Seein' all that...
Big...
Country.
[ growling ]
[ barking ]
[ barking continues ]
- Get 'em, Yeller !
- [ barking continues ]
Wipe up the ground with 'em !
- [ raccoons screeching ]
[ moos ]
Yeller sure has been givin'
them coons the mortal fits.
You tired, son ?
No, ma'am.
[ chuckles ]
Where's old Rose ?
She didn't come up last night.
I figured she hid out somewhere
and had her calf.
I guess I better go
hunt her up.
Come on, Yeller.
Remember now.
If she's had her calf,
she'll be on the fight.
[ cow mooing ]
come on, Yeller !
[ barking ]
Quiet, Yeller !
Don't rile her !
[ barking ]
[ mooing ]
- That's gettin' her, boy !
- [ barking ]
Get her, Yeller !
Bust her again !
Try it again, sister,
and Old Yeller'll
bust you wide open.
- All right, Yeller,
get her home.
- [ barking ]
[ growling ]
All right, old sister,
you take it easy.
I aim to milk you
if I have to break
every bone in your body.
So now, Rose,
you know as well as I
we're not gonna hurt ya.
Now, Rose,
you take it easy.
You ain't got a chance, sister.
You're done milked
and you don't know it.
[ sighs ]
I know what !
Here, Yeller.
Son, you bring that dog in here
and Rose will go crazy.
All right, Yeller,
hold her there.
Well, if that don't beat all.
I never saw such a dog.
And you won't never see
another one like him.
Hello, the house !
I thought maybe
it was Papa.
Mornin', ma'am.
I'm burn Sanderson
from down near San 'tone.
Runnin' me a few head
of cattle over
on devil's creek.
- Yes, Mr. Sanderson ?
- Bud Searcy told me about
an old, stray dog you had.
Sounded like it might
be the one I lost.
You mean a...
Big Yeller dog ?
That's him.  The worst
egg-sucker and camp-robber
you ever laid eyes on.
Steal you blind
while you're watchin'.
But there never was
a better cow dog born,
or a hog dog either.
Travis, go call Old Yeller
to the house.
- But, Mama--
- Travis !
Yes, Mama.
Won't you get down,
Mr. Sanderson ?
Thank you, ma'am.
[ Travis ]
Arliss.
What do you want ?
Bring Old Yeller
to the house.
What's the matter ?
You'll find out.
Ma'am, you and the boys
don't have much protection
out here.
Bad as I need that old dog,
I could give you a loan of him
till your man comes home.
[ sighs ]
no, Mr. Sanderson.
If he's your dog,
better take him now.
Well, maybe you're right, ma'am.
Come on, boy.
[ whining, panting ]
why, you prowlin'
old rascal.
[ laughs ]
come on, boy.
[ barking ]
Well, good-bye, ma'am.
I'm sure much obliged.
[ whimpering ]
Come on, Yeller.
That's my dog !
You can't take my dog !
- [ whinnying ]
- you can't take my dog !
You can't take my dog !
Whoa, boy !
[ grunts,
disgusted sigh ]
Arliss, aren't you ashamed,
throwin' rocks at that man ?
I'll bust him with another
if he takes my dog off !
Arliss !
[ laughing ]
Maybe he's right, ma'am.
Man comes to take my dog off,
I'd throw a fit too.
Let me talk to this boy
a minute.
Well, boy ?
Go on, Arliss.
Go on.
Whatcha got
in that pocket ?
Come on.
Let's take a look.
Why, ain't he
a Jim-dandy.
Finest lookin'
horned toad I ever seen.
What about my dog ?
You mean you really want
that thievin', Old Yeller dog ?
- I sure do.
- Well, then maybe we can
do some swappin'.
I've been wantin' mighty bad
to get me a big horned toad
like you got there.
You mean you'd swap me
Old Yeller for this here
horny toad ?
Well, now,
that's a fine horny toad,
and I want him bad.
But on the other hand,
he ain't hardly as big
as a dog.
Seems like I oughta get
a little to boot.
Like what ?
Well, I'll tell you
how it is.
I've been in that cow camp
starvin' on my own cookin'
so long,
I don't hardly throw
a shadow no more.
Now, if you could talk
your Mama...
Into feedin' me one,
big woman-cooked meal,
Why, I figure it and
that horned toad
would be worth...
At least a lop-eared
Yeller dog, don't you ?
Well, I guess so.
Will you feed him, Mama ?
Of course I will.
All right, I'll swap ya.
Here, boy !
He's all yours, boy.
Come on, Yeller.
Come on, boy.
Hey.  What about
my toad ?
Come on, boy.
Come on.
[ barking ]
[ laughs ]
I haven't ate
like this...
Since the time I splurged
on a big feed at the
Menger Hotel in San 'tone.
Well, I'm happy
you enjoyed it,
Mr. Sanderson.
Well, ma'am, I guess
I better be gettin' back
to camp.
Come with me, boy, while
I get my horse settled.
Yes, sir.
When Mr. Coates gets back,
I want you to come and see us.
I want him to meet ya.
That's mighty nice
of ya, ma'am.
Thank you.
Good-bye, boy.
Take good care
of that Old Yeller dog.
Yes, sir.
And you take care
of my horny toad.
I will.  Bye, ma'am.
Good-bye.
Didn't tell your Mama this.
Didn't want to fret her.
But there's a plague
of hydrophobia in these parts.
Hydrophobia ?  You sure ?
I've done shot two wolves,
a fox and a skunk
that had it.
I wanted to warn you
not to take any chances.
Well, I don't know if
I could tell if a critter's
got the sickness.
You can't hardly
tell at first.
Not until they get
to the point of slobberin'
and staggerin' around.
You see a critter in that fix,
you know for sure.
But you wanna watch
for others that ain't
that far along.
Now you take a bobcat
and a fox--
You know they'll run
if they get the chance.
But when one don't run
or maybe makes fight at you,
why, you shoot him and quick.
After he's bitten you,
it's too late.
You done with your
hog markin' for this year ?
No.  I'm aimin' to start
tomorrow.
You watch them hogs
same as everything.
I know your Papa left
you in charge of things
while he's gone.
And I figure
you're man enough
to handle the job.
Don't scare you,
does it, boy ?
No, sir.
[ chuckles ]
well, yes, sir.
It scares me a little bit,
but I'll sure do
like you told me.
That's a way
a man talks, son.
Hog tracks, Yeller !
Get 'em, boy !
[ snorting ]
[ barking ]
[ hog snorting ]
[ barking continues ]
- [ barking continues ]
- hold 'em, boy !
[ hogs squealing ]
[ Old Yeller snarling ]
All right, Yeller.
Fetch 'em right under here.
[ hogs squealing ]
[ snarling ]
[ squealing ]
Over bit the right ear.
Under slope the left.
All right, pig,
now you're wearin'
the Coates' Mark.
Easy.
[ squeals ]
Whoa-ooo !
[ wild squealing ]
Yeller !  Yeller !
[ Yeller snarling ]
[ squealing ]
[ snarling stops ]
Yeller.
Yeller !
Oh, Yeller.
You're all cut
to pieces.
[ crying ]
you're gonna be all right,
ya hear ?
I'll get Mama.
Mama'll fix you up for sure.
Come on, boy.
Gonna put you in here.
Come on, Yeller.
Want them hogs
to come back and get ya ?
[ whimpering ]
[ grunting ]
You're gonna stay here
till I get back.
[ whimpering ]
[ whimpering continues ]
I mean it, boy.
I'm comin' back.
I promise.
[ whimpering ]
[ groaning ]
Come on now.
I'll help you to bed.
Mama, we gotta go back
after Old Yeller.
You're not goin' any place
until that leg gets well.
I've doctored hog cuts before.
This one of yours
could be as dangerous
as a rattlesnake bite.
Mama, you don't understand.
I promised Old Yeller,
and I'm goin' !
Travis !
I aim to go after Old Yeller.
He'll die without help !
All right, then.
We'll all go.
Mama, them buzzards
ain't got him !
[ whimpering ]
What's the matter with Yeller,
Mama ?  Who stopped him up
in this hole ?
We've come to get him out.
But first, I wonder
if you'd do somethin' for me.
What ?
Go catch me
a green-striped lizard.
We passed one back
there a piece.
Prettiest I ever saw.
Sure, Mama.
I'll catch him.
We're gonna have to hurry
if we wanna get him patched up
before Arliss gets back.
[ whimpering ]
Oh, Travis.
I didn't know it
was gonna be this bad.
Them hogs would've
never touched him.
He was keepin' 'em
off of me.
We'll have to sew him up.
Go jerk me a hair out
of Old Jumper's tail.
[ whimpering ]
Yes, Yeller.
Take your ax and
go cut two long poles
for a litter.
The sooner we get him home,
the better.
Mama, I got your lizard.
Ain't he pretty ?
Ooh, yes.
He really is.
Now if you'll just keep him
for me until we get home.
We're gonna play a game.
What kind of a game ?
We're playin' Old Yeller
is sick.
You're gonna take care of him.
Is that why
he's all wrapped up ?
That's right.  Now,
you're gonna ride here
and hold him.
Like we was
two sick injuns ?
And you make sure
he don't fall off.
On account of he's
a sicker injun than me ?
That's right.
Now remember.
Don't lean on him.
And don't play with him.
He's a very, very
sick Indian.
[ grunting ]
Come on,
Jumper.
Mama ?
Hmm ?
Them prickly pear roots
gonna make Travis well ?
I hope so, son.
Mama ?
Hmm ?
When you're done,
will you play with me ?
I'm sorry, Arliss.
I'm too busy now.
You go out
in the backyard
and play.
But I tell you, there ain't
nothin' to do out in
that old backyard.
[ squealing ]
now, Arliss, you stop it,
and go outside this minute.
[ Mr. Searcy ]
hello, the house !
It's Mr. Searcy !
[ Arliss ]
ain't he pretty ?
Is he for me ?
Partly.  Mostly
he's for Travis.
But Travis can't
play with no puppy.
He's sick.
Sick ?
Him and Old Yeller.
Hog cut.
Good mornin', Mr. Searcy.
Hello, Elizabeth.
What's this about
that boy of yours
gettin' hog cut ?
Whatcha doctorin' with ?
Prickly pear root.
Miss Coates, I brung
somethin' for Travis.
Can I take it to him ?
Go right in there, honey.
Now if you'll excuse me,
Mr. Searcy, I'm makin' up
some new poultice.
You know,
it's right providence
I come along when I did.
'tain't nothin' better than a
prickly pear poultice, providin'
a body knows how to fix it.
[ Elizabeth ]
you hurt pretty bad ?
I'm all right.
Take more than them
old hogs to kill me.
Well, I--
I brung you
a surprise.
One of Miss Priss' pups.
They was born
in a badger hole.
Seven of 'em.
This 'uns the best
of the bunch.
See ?  He don't holler
when you hold him up
by the neck hide.
Papa says that means
he's a good dog.
That don't mean nothin'.
If his mouth's black inside,
that's what counts.
[ puppy whining ]
W-well, anyhow, I--
I-I brung him to ya.
Well, I got me a dog.
Old Yeller.
Well, why don't you
give him to Arliss ?
He'll like him.
[ door closes ]
[ sighs ]
[ crying ]
here, you can have him.
Golly !
That's the secret, Miss Coates:
A-beatin' them roots till
they're all soft and squishy--
Mama, look at the little,
bitty puppy Elizabeth give me.
Sure cut up,
ain't ya, boy ?
Clean to the bone,
looks like.
That there poultice
is sure the stuff
to suck out the poison,
Provided, of course,
he ain't got "hydrophoby."
"hydrophoby" ?
Could be.  It's all over
the countryside.
Stuff dyin' like flies: Foxes,
wolves, polecats, hogs--
hogs ?
Hogs can get it.
Same as that there boy or
that Old Yeller dog there.
Seen them foamin'
at the mouth,
shown any signs of fits ?
Fits of temper ?
Of course not !
Well, you better keep
a close watch on them.
Liable to show up at any time.
Recollect had me an uncle
once down in east Texas
got mad dog bit, he did.
Knowed he was bound to die.
Chained himself to
a sweet gum tree.
- Stayed right there
till sickness took ahold.
- Mr. Searcy, please.
But it's the gospel truth !
He went to snarlin' and snappin'
at everything in sight.
He run at his woman
and young 'uns,
tryin' to bite 'em.
He'd have done it
if that chain
hadn't held him back.
Stayed right there
till he died of
the slobberin' fits.
They buried him under
that sweet gum tree--
Mr. Searcy, that's enough !
Not another word !
Biggest, nicest funeral
you ever did--
What do you mean tellin'
an ugly story like that to
a boy who's just been hog cut ?
Now, Miss Coates,
I was just tryin' to give
a word of warnin'.
Reckon if I can't be
of no more help around here,
I'll be makin' tracks for home.
Help.  There are plenty of ways
a man could help around here.
Huh ?  By doin' what ?
Like hitchin' up the mule and
gatherin' in the corn crop...
Before the deer eat it up,
or the blowin' rain
rot it in the field !
Now, don't you fret yourself at
all about that corn crop.  I'll
be glad to take care of that.
Elizabeth ?
Yes, Papa ?
Miss Coates here, she's
in kind of a bind.  Ain't got
her corn in the crib yet.
Figured I'll leave you behind
to help her with the job.
Mr. Searcy, Elizabeth's
nothin' but a little girl.
Yeah, well,
she ain't much for size,
But she's just like her
old pappy-- stout and willin' !
[ disgusted sigh ]
Now, don't you forget,
Miss Coates.  If there's any
other thing I can do for you,
Don't you be bashful
about tellin' me.
I'm on call
day or night.
Bye !  Bye.
Oh !
I do believe
you are cooler.
Mama, don't let what
Mr. Searcy said bother you.
I'm gonna be
all right !
I'm sure
you will be.
I know, Mama.
Mama, I know.
I got a good look
at them hogs.
Now, them hogs was mean,
but they weren't mad.
[ sighing ]
[ cow mooing ]
Travis,
we got lots of corn.
Me, Mama and Elizabeth.
[ cow mooing ]
Ain't that old Rose
I hear bawlin' ?
She's been actin'
flighty lately, like she
was scared of her own shadow.
And this mornin'
she wouldn't
let her calf suck.
I think, maybe, she's got
a bit of pea vine.
No, Mama, it can't be pea vine.
Not this late in the year.
[ mooing ]
Oh.
The poor thing.
She's
blind sick.
[ mooing ]
Mama, that cow's
got "hydrophoby."
"hydrophoby" ?
Oh, no, Travis.
Mr. Sanderson said when they
stagger and slobber around,
you know for sure.
I'll go
get my gun.
[ mooing ]
[ gunshot ]
Let's get finished
and go burn the carcass.
If the varmints get at it,
could be that might
spread the disease.
I'm hungry.
Well, I'll go rustle you up
some bread and milk.
How come you shot
old Rose ?
She was sick.
Well, you were sick too.
How come they
didn't shoot you ?
Well, that's
somethin' different.
Where'll Rose go
now she's dead ?
Nowhere, I reckon.
She's just dead.
Will she
go to Heaven ?
I don't much reckon.
Ain't there
no cows in Heaven
for the angels to milk ?
Well, how do I know ?
Here's your supper.
How fer off
is Heaven ?
Oh, I don't know.
A fer piece, I guess.
Is Heaven as far off
as Papa went ?
[ exhales ]
a heap further than that.
Where'd Papa go to ?
Kansas.
Arliss, quit eatin'
with that nasty old pup !
Well, he's hungry too !
[ Katie ]
Travis !
Bring your gun !
That's Mama !
What's the matter with her ?
You stay in this house,
Arliss, you hear ?
Travis !  Travis !
Travis !
Bring your gun !
Travis !  Travis !
A wolf !
[ Arliss ]
Mama !
Don't let Arliss
come down here.
I'm comin', Arliss !
- What happened ?
- It was so sudden,
I don't hardly know.
- The wolf came
leapin' out at us.
- Lucky you had Old Yeller.
It was lucky for us, son,
But it weren't lucky
for Old Yeller.
He's chewed up some,
but he ain't bad hurt.
No wolf in his right mind
would've jumped us at the fire,
Not even a loafer wolf.
That wolf was mad.
I'll... Shoot him...
If you can't.
But either way,
we've got it to do.
Mama, listen.
Old Yeller just
saved your life,
and Elizabeth's too !
And he saved mine
and Arliss' !
We can't !
We don't know
for certain.
I'll pen him up
where he can't get out.
A-and then we'll wait.
We can't just shoot him
like he was nothin'.
Don't you understand ?
All right, son.
If you think
there's a chance.
[ barking ]
hear that ?
Well, now, that sounds
like a healthy dog to me.
Take a look at him, Mama.
See for yourself.
He sure looks fine,
all right.
Two whole weeks,
and nary a sign of a thing.
Think we could let him out ?
No, son, not yet.
They say sometimes
it takes a month to tell.
Now, I told you:
If everything's all right,
We'll let Old Yeller
out come Saturday.
But, Mama,
why not now ?
No, we've waited this long.
I guess we can stand it
another couple of days.
Aw, Mama.
Here we are, boy.
More grub.
[ Yeller growling ]
Yeller ?
[ growling continues ]
What's the matter, boy ?
Come on.
It's time to eat.
[ growling, snarling ]
How is he tonight ?
All right,
I reckon.
- Are you sure ?
- I said he was all right,
didn't I ?
I guess you wouldn't like it,
either, if you had to stay
shut up in a corn crib !
You ain't gonna keep my dog
locked up in that crib no more !
You stay away from that dog.
You understand ?
It's time for you
to go to bed, Arliss.
Aw, Mama.
Do as I say.
Yes'm.
Don't you worry, boy.
I'll get you outta here.
[ snarling, barking ]
Where's Arliss ?
I don't know.
Arliss !
[ Katie ]
Don't open that door !
Arliss !  Keep away
from that door !
Arliss !
[ snarling ]
[ snarling continues ]
No, Mama.
There's no hope
for him now, Travis.
He's sufferin'.
You know we've got to do it.
I know, Mama.
[ snarling continues ]
But he was my dog.
I'll do it.
[ sobs ]
[ gunshot ]
Hello, the house !
Papa !  Ya done
came home !
[ yapping ]
Hiya, boy.
Ain't them injuns
scalped you yet ?
Papa, what'd you bring me ?
I brought you somethin',
all right.
Just hold your potatoes
while I go kiss your Mama.
Jim !
Oh, Jim !
What'd you
bring me home, Papa ?
Where is it ?
[ jingling ]
hear this, Katie ?
Money.  Cash money.
First we've had
since the war.
That ain't all.
What ?
I got that dress.
Prettiest thing
you ever seen.
Oh !
And a fancy pair of shoes
to go with it.
Gee-whiz !
Put it on, son.
[ laughing ]
There you are.
All right, chief.
Let's hit the warpath.
[ whooping ]
come on, boy !
Oh, Jim !
It's lovely.
I been achin'
to see it on you.
Where's Travis ?
I wanna get a look
at his face when he sees
the horse I brung him.
Him and Elizabeth Searcy
are over at north hill...
Burying Old Yeller.
Old Yeller ?
Come in the house
and I'll tell you about it.
Travis ?
If you could just
come to like the pup--
He-he's part
Old Yeller.
He may be
part Old Yeller,
But he ain't
Old Yeller.
Your Mama told me
about the dog.
Come sit down, son.
That was rough,
son.
As rough a thing
as I ever heard tell of.
But I'm mighty proud
of how my boy
stood up to it.
Couldn't ask no more
of a grown man.
Thing to do now is...
Try and forget it.
Go on bein' a man.
How, pa ?  How you gonna
forget somethin' like that ?
I guess I don't
quite mean that.
Reckon it's not a thing
you can forget.
Maybe not even a thing
you wanna forget.
What I'm
tryin' to say is...
Life's like that
sometimes.
Like what ?
Well,
Now and then, for no good
reason a man can figure out,
Life will just haul off
and knock him flat.
Slam him again' the ground
so hard it seems like
all his insides is busted.
But it's not all
like that.
A lot of it's
mighty fine.
And you can't afford
to waste the good part
frettin' about the bad.
That makes it
all bad.
You understand what
I'm trying to get at ?
Yes, sir.
It's just that--
Yeah, sure,
I know.
Sayin' it's one thing
and feelin' it's another.
But I'll tell you a trick
that's sometimes a big help.
You start lookin' around
for somethin' good...
To take the place
of the bad.
As a general rule,
you can find it.
Brought you that horse
I promised.
Yes, sir.
I reckon you
ain't in no shape
to take pleasure in him yet.
No, sir.
We'll just keep him
a while.
Maybe you'll come to
feel different later on.
Your Mama was fixin' supper
when I left the house.
Might hurt her feelings
if we're not there
on time to eat it.
[ puppy barking,
growling ]
[ Katie ]
leave that alone !
You get outta here !
Put it down !
Why, you thievin',
little wretch !
[ yapping ]
Who's that beatin' my dog ?
You can't beat my dog !
You can't beat
my dog !
Hold it, chief.
I think you're fixin'
to raise the wrong hair.
Mama was tryin'
to kill my dog.
I never even touched him.
Of course, she didn't.
Ooh, whee !
Supper ready ?
Ready and waitin'.
Good.
Looks like
it's about time I...
Started learnin'
this old pup
to earn his keep.
Don't look like to me
he's hardly big enough
to learn nothin' yet.
He's big enough to learn...
If he's big enough
to act like Old Yeller.
(music) young Yeller is a puppy (music)
[ barking ]
(music) a little
ol' lop-eared puppy (music)
(music) it's plain to see
he's got a family tree (music)
(music) the image of his pappy (music)
(music) he's frisky
and he's happy (music)
(music) and that's how
a good pup should be (music)
(music) frisky and happy (music)
(music) here, Yeller
come back, Yeller (music)
[ whistling ]
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) in the west (music)
(music) here, Yeller (music)
[ whistling ]
(music) come back, Yeller (music)
(music) best doggone dog
in the west (music)
(music) best doggone dog (music)
(music) in the west (music)
}}