[Horn playing "Taps"]
[Horses whinnying]
Hey! Come out! Come out!
[Indistinct shouting]
[Man] What's the excitement,
soldier?
Fire in the horse corral.
- [man] Mind if I take a look?
- Stay where you are, prisoner.
[Man] More of your
southern hospitality.
- Hello.
Your name Whitney Randolph?
Ol' Wiley Whit himself,
The boys in the Harvard
Glee Club used to call me.
You lose something?
[Man] Speaking to me?
No. No, just still
grumbling to myself.
- What do you want?
- Come with me.
Why should I?
The governor of Texas said so.
Does that mean anything?
- It most certainly does.
- Then shut up and come on.
- [man] Come on, hurry up.
- [Whitney] I can't
find my shoes.
[Man] Never mind
your shoes, come on.
Halt!
[Dogs barking in distance]
- Hello, Peter.
- Why, hello, Mr. Todd.
Would you wake Governor Lubbock
and tell him I'm here, please?
Yes sir, he's up and
expecting you. Come right in.
Good evening.
Don't get up, Governor.
When I can't get up
to greet a friend of mine,
It'll be time to bury me.
How are you, Todd?
- Fine, sir, and you?
- Oh, as well as a man
has a right to be
In these trying times.
Glad to see you again,
Mr. Randolph.
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you, sir.
And, uh, thanks
for rescuing me.
You can thank Captain Croyden
of the Rangers.
I did.
He isn't having any.
I, uh... I don't think
he likes my Yankee accent.
Why should I? I'm joining
Hood's Army tomorrow.
[Chuckles] Don't tell me
I was rescued by a Johnny Reb.
Uh, gentlemen, perhaps
it'd be well for all
If we clarify
the atmosphere somewhat.
Thank you, Peter.
Help yourselves, gentlemen.
I take it you haven't told
Captain Croyden why you're here.
He didn't ask. He's the most
uncurious man I've ever met.
Governor told me
to get you and I did.
See what I mean?
Just like sending him
To the store
for a bucket of lard.
I think it's time you knew
that Mr. Randolph is from
The Department of Army
Intelligence in Washington.
Why be so tactful, Governor?
Come right out with it.
Captain Croyden, sir,
I am a Yankee spy.
Governor,
I never thought...
Oh, don't get
excited, Captain.
Governor Lubbock is a Texan
first, last and always.
- And a great one.
- Thank you, Mr. Randolph.
So, before you reach
for that gun, Todd,
Let me add that Mr. Randolph
is not spying on Texas
Or any part
of the Confederacy.
Todd, a week ago,
Mr. Randolph,
By some magic of his own,
Got through our lines
and came to see me.
He told me a story.
I agreed to help him.
I furnished him an escort,
they became separated
And Mr. Randolph
was picked up by a patrol
of the Confederate cavalry.
When I learned of it,
I sent for you,
And as usual,
you carried out your orders
With characteristic
speed and dispatch.
Speed. He didn't even
give me time to find my boots.
Mr. Randolph needs a man
to guide him into Mexico.
You're that man, Todd.
To, uh...
See that I don't fall
in the wrong hands again.
Maybe. Maybe not.
You mind laying your cards
on the table, mister?
Oh, not at all.
Not at all.
Everything above board,
nothing up either sleeve.
Did you ever hear of Juarez?
- Heard of him.
- He's a great man. A patriot.
- Nobody's disputin' it.
- The French are.
With an army
and by trying to put a ruler
over the Mexican people.
Your government...
Oh, I beg your pardon,
my government,
Has been shipping guns
and ammunition to Juarez.
The last three months,
we've lost two big shipments.
We've traced them to a town in
northern Mexico called Corrales.
A short time ago, a friend
of mine named Brooks went
down there to have a look.
He, um, hasn't come back.
Go on.
Brooks got one message through
before he disappeared.
Someone's raising an army
in Corrales.
So?
So it's my job to take up
where he left off.
You'd get me as far
as the border at least.
Governor, I don't like the idea
of playing nurse to a Yank.
Sorry to hear you
say that, Captain.
It seems a shame to break up
such a beautiful friendship.
- I got a war to fight.
- That's right, Todd, you have.
But you've also got
a duty to Texas.
Well, Texas
comes first, Governor.
That's why I'm appealing
to you, Todd.
And why I helped
Mr. Randolph here.
This army is so close
to our border,
It poses a threat
to our safety.
If there is danger there,
we must know it and take steps
to meet it.
Will you go?
What size boots
do you wear?
[Playing harmonica]
* Carry me back
to old Virginny *
* If you do, I'll fight you
every gosh-darn step
along the way *
[Stops playing]
Mind if I run my gums over it?
Thanks.
[Starts playing]
Very superior instrument.
Wouldn't mind
owning this myself.
Give you a dollar for it.
Wager for it.
With this, uh,
very fine piece of cutlery.
If you were a stranger,
I'd say no, but, uh...
Hey, just a minute.
[Whitney gasps]
Well, a man
would be a poor sport
If he didn't give a friend
a chance to get even.
Now, if you'd match
these two objects
With something of equal value,
like, say, um...
Say like that, uh,
little silver doo-dad
you're wearing there.
[Whitney gasps]
[Chuckles]
I've been doing some thinking,
Mr. Randolph.
Where I come from,
a man wouldn't think of
bringing up a matter like this,
But, uh...
would your feelings be hurt
If I kinda took a look
at those dice of yours?
I take it you're suspicious,
Mr. Croyden.
Just curious, Mr. Randolph.
Oh, and curious
you should be, sir,
Losing all your worldly goods
to a northerner.
[Plays tune]
I apologize, Mr. Randolph.
Oh, your apology accepted,
Mr. Croyden.
I'm still curious, though.
You must pack
a rabbit's foot
or something.
Just a streak of luck,
it'll run out one of these days.
Oh, Mr. Croyden.
Please be very careful
with that animal.
Remember, I'm just
loaning him to you.
[Shakes dice]
[Sighs] Thanks, nurse.
- What for?
- For stopping.
I was about to choke
to death on your dust.
Well, you better take
a quick breather,
We're gonna kick up a lot more
before we cross the border.
There's some people
I don't want to meet up with.
- [Whitney] Such as?
- [Todd] Comanche Indians.
Confederate cavalry
rounding up deserters.
You mean to tell me, sir,
that there's Texans
Who refuse to fight
for their glorious state?
Not Texans...
Yanks who came to Texas.
I don't mind the Indians,
but Confederate cavalry,
I'd have a hard time
explaining what I'm doing
with a Yankee spy.
That's Confederate cavalry.
Let's get out of here.
Don't shoot,
they're friends!
You call that friendly?
[Whitney] Phew! Whoa!
They're turning back.
They had to.
That's the Rio Grande.
Ah. That was a close one.
I'd hate to be stopped
by a Texas bullet.
Come on.
Whoa.
[Woman speaking Spanish]
[Man speaking Spanish]
Look at all
that nice, wet water.
And look what's sitting in it,
a damsel in distress.
- Shall we, uh...
- [shakes dice]
To see who
rescues her, Mr. Croyden?
You can have her, Mr. Randolph,
I'll take the water.
[Man speaking Spanish]
On second thought,
I don't think I'll gamble.
I might win.
[Woman] Drop your gun belts.
Drop your gun belts, I said.
Now you may go.
Thanks.
[Speaking Spanish]
Just what did she say?
In English.
She thinks we're bandits.
Well, that's
understandable.
But I assure you, senorita,
we are quite harmless.
You are now.
Take yourselves away.
Quick.
You're making a mistake.
You see...
Don't argue with her.
She waits for that army
to fix that carriage,
She'll be in the middle of the
stream for the rest of her life.
Wait.
Perhaps I misjudged you.
You did.
This is wild country.
A woman can't take chances.
No, ma'am, she can't.
Neither can a man
without his gun.
Very well, then,
I'll make a bargain.
Help us and you can
have your guns back.
Oh, I, uh... I don't know
if we could do that or not.
You see, you hurt our feelings
when you didn't trust us.
'Course, uh, I can't say
that I blame you when I look
at my partner here.
He's really not as ornery
as he looks, though.
He kinda grows on ya,
if you give him time.
I haven't that much time.
Is it a bargain?
It's a bargain.
Well, there she is,
good as new.
Thank you.
And there's your guns.
- Thanks.
- [Whitney] Come on,
give me a hand.
Coming.
- Wait.
- Yes, ma'am?
I'm on the wrong side
of the stream.
Why, so you are.
My mother told me not to
pick up ladies I wasn't
properly introduced to.
My name's Madeline Danzeeger.
Madeline.
That's a pretty name.
- Almost as pretty as you.
- You say that very gallantly.
Perhaps you'll be
equally gallant
And let me ride your horse
across the stream?
I'll share him with you.
Put your arms around my neck.
Put your foot
in the stirrup.
- Please, they're waiting.
- For what?
- For us.
- Oh.
I'd like to pay you
for your trouble.
That's not necessary.
It's a pleasure.
- That's nice perfume.
- It came from France.
If you told me your name,
I'd see that you were rewarded
for your kindness.
- Todd.
- Just Todd?
My turn, Mr. Croyden.
Thanks again.
I don't know
as I cared for that.
I do all the heavy work
and he gets all the thanks.
[Todd] Grab on.
What's in there, rocks?
[Whitney] It's light,
compared to the other ones.
Allow me.
Gracias.
Thank you.
I shall cherish this little
token of our meeting
Until my dying day.
Or at least until I reach
the nearest saloon.
You won't have it long,
Corrales is just ahead.
[Speaking Spanish]
I guess it's
the Texan in you.
She gives you a smile,
she gives me a peso.
That you can spend.
Ah, but I'd trade it
for a smile any day.
A woman's smile
is a thing of...
Would you stop gabbing?
I'm trying to
figure something out.
Yeah, I'm trying to figure
something out, too.
How do I get
my horse and guns?
Well, you might try wading.
[Long sigh]
Well, there she is.
Uh-huh. Not the sort of place
I'd choose to live in.
[Sniffs] Or die in either,
for that matter.
This spying business,
it, uh...
Wouldn't be dangerous,
would it?
Not a bit. The worst thing
that could happen to you
Is... get killed.
Doesn't look like much
is going on here.
Kinda empty.
Hey, where is everybody?
[Speaking Spanish]
She says everybody's
joined the army.
Oh.
You two figurin'
settling down here?
Any reason why we shouldn't?
Nope, if there's
a reason you should.
We could probably
think of a few,
But we'd kind of like to
keep them to ourself.
Got any objections?
Nope.
[Sighs]
- [speaks Spanish]
- Beer.
Well, nurse,
Now that you've delivered me
safely to Corrales,
Sound of wind and limb,
you can scamper back to Texas
And pick up your musket.
That's just what
I'm aiming to do.
Soon as I wet my whistle
and pick up some grub.
I figure it won't take too long
to lick you fellas,
And I...
I don't wanna miss the fun.
Well, if you feel that you
can spare an hour or two,
I might have a message
for you to take back
to Governor Lubbock.
Brooks?
Punching cattle pays good.
Or is that too peaceful?
That depends.
- Punching for you?
- Nah.
Basil Danzeeger.
- Never heard of him.
- You will.
Stick around long enough.
Can't speak for my friend here,
but I might stick around,
after I look your town over.
You know where I can
get a boot repaired?
And a busted holster fixed?
There's a boot shop,
zapateria, down the street.
Much obliged.
You don't suppose
he hangs around
Just to pick up
saddle stiffs
For this man,
Danzeeger, do you?
He may be hiring, but he
ain't looking for cowhands.
You know, nurse, you got the
makings of a first-rate spy.
[Speaking Spanish]
The heel to the boot,
she's unstuck.
- The... [speaks Spanish]
- Oh. [Speaks Spanish]
The heel,
she's unstuck, senor.
[Speaking Spanish]
Speak Spanish or English.
What do you want?
I've lost a heel and my friend
would like to get
a holster fixed.
I am busy.
Too busy to talk to a friend
of theirs, Roberto?
President Juarez has
a great admiration for
your Abraham Lincoln.
What has that to do with me?
Take off your boot.
[Speaks Spanish]
What do you want of me,
Senor Randolph?
I'm looking for
a Captain Brooks.
Have you seen or heard
anything of him?
Captain Brooks is dead.
He was dead
when we found him.
I put up a cross.
I could do no more.
Thanks.
I do not care to
put up any more crosses,
Or have one put over me.
Nor do I.
Then you must work
with extreme caution.
There's a man named Danzeeger
behind what is going on here.
He has spies everywhere,
mostly renegade Americans.
You mean like that fella
at the cantina?
Yes. He watches
the newcomers in town.
What do you know
of this man, Danzeeger?
It is rumored that he is
a cashiered German army officer.
But we know
nothing for certain.
Except that he
has plenty of money
With which to pay El Gavilan
and his soldiers.
- Who?
- El Gavilan. The Hawk.
That is what
General Liguras,
Who leads the army,
calls himself.
- And, uh, what of him?
- A poor, misguided fool, senor.
In these troublesome times,
any man who can
gather a thousand men
Will call himself a general.
He is, at heart,
a loyal Mexican.
Of that I am sure.
But he's not
an educated man
- and could easily be misled.
- [Whitney] By Danzeeger?
- Who else?
- [hoofbeats approaching]
[Speaking Spanish]
There, you see for yourself.
The Hawk returns with
the payroll for his army.
There will be dancing
in the streets tonight,
As there always is
when the soldiers are paid.
Sit down, please.
They are coming here.
Pick up boots for El Gavilan.
- They are ready, muchacho?
- They are ready, General.
Pedro, my boots.
[sighs]
[Grunts]
[Loud grunt]
Oh! These are the best of all.
You have done well, muchacho.
Pedro.
[Liguras groaning]
[Speaks Spanish, laughs]
Ah! [Speaks Spanish]
You make another pair for
Liguras right away, eh?
[Speaks Spanish]
The boots.
- You take these.
- [speaks Spanish]
Adios, Roberto.
Now that General Liguras
is a man of wealth,
He buys a new pair of boots
each month.
Well, at least
we know his weakness.
You never can tell when a thing
like that will pay off.
Agreed. What are your plans?
I'd like to start with
a visit to Brooks' grave.
Meet me a mile south
of town in an hour
And I will take you there.
If you need any lodgings,
See the good Senora Alvarez
and tell her I sent you.
Thank you, Roberto.
We saw the buzzards circling
even before he was dead.
That's how we found him.
He spoke more like an
Englishman than an American.
A transplanted Englishman,
Roberto.
What had they done to him?
They tied him
between wild horses.
An old Indian custom.
But this was not
the work of Indians.
The thongs that tied him
were not deer hide,
They were rope.
American rope.
There is no worse torture.
The headlong fight
of wild and broken Mustangs,
Pulling at the arms and legs
of the man tied between them,
Is more than human courage
can endure.
When the arms are pulled
from their sockets...
Who did it?
One dares not ask.
One can only grope in the dark
for the answer.
I see an army gathering
in the mountains.
I see the pockets of honest
field workers turned soldiers
lined with silver.
And I hear a general boast that
he will lead an army into Tejas,
When guns and ammunitions
come from Presidente Juarez.
The governor was right.
Do they speak of
this plan openly?
[Roberto] Oh, yes.
Oh...
No, there's more to this
than meets the eye.
Brooks was not killed
for finding that out.
Juarez has hardly enough
guns and ammunition
to defend himself.
Why should he send them
to this... this Liguras?
Besides, Juarez is
building for the future,
He's not concerned
with the past.
No. No, my friend,
Brooks was not killed
for that.
He was killed
for something else.
Agreed, amigo, but no word
comes from Juarez himself.
He is bottled up
by the French,
Yet Danzeeger says
he's an agent from Juarez.
I do not believe him.
I don't think Brooks
believed him either.
That's why they killed him.
[Todd] Odd that an
Englishman should be
fighting for your cause.
Not so odd.
"To count the life
of battle good"
And dear the land
that gave you birth.
And dearer yet
the brotherhood
"That binds the brave
of all the earth."
Well, you've got
your message, nurse,
you can leave anytime now.
Who said anything
about leaving?
[Mexican music playing]
- Tequila.
- [man speaks Spanish]
[Bartender] Gracias.
Decide to stick around?
How about your friend?
We hit the same trail,
We don't ask each other where
we've been or where we're going.
Or why.
A fellow lives longer
that way.
He sure does
in this town.
Wrap yourself in your
own tarp, I always say.
We've, uh...
met before someplace.
I've been there.
- Laredo, maybe?
- Could be.
A man who makes his living with
a rope and a saddle gets around.
It's been quite a bunch
of years since I saw ya.
What were you saying about
wrapping yourself
in your own tarp?
We were talking.
That's very good,
you're fast.
Now put it back to bed.
In the last couple of years,
My shoulders got itchy
around strangers.
Best thing is to stop
being strangers, then.
This is Red Hyatt,
Does the hiring and firing
for Mr. Danzeeger.
Whatever he's been drinking
for Mr. Hyatt.
I might want him
to hire me sometime.
Did you, uh,
think of a name maybe?
- How about Jones?
- I'm usin' it.
- Smith?
- [Red] We got three of 'em.
And I'm Brown.
How about Todd?
Anybody here named Todd?
- Todd what?
- Just Todd.
My mother was
closed-mouthed, too.
Well...
Well, you gentlemen got more
out of him in your first meeting
Than I did eating out of
the same frying pan with him
for two weeks.
- Nice to know you, Mr. Todd.
- Hello.
Since curiosity seems to be
a disease around these parts,
I shall cure it forthwith.
- Mm. I'll have one of these.
- [man speaks Spanish]
My name is Whitney Randolph.
I am not seeking occupation
of an outdoor nature
And I frown on the
indiscriminate use of firearms.
Gracias. The latter being
the chief reason
for my presence here.
Have you a dice cup, muchacho?
Now, anything else, gentlemen,
Before I lure someone
into a game of chance?
Is that how
you make your living?
Know a better way, friend?
Yeah, poker.
You can play it
sitting down.
Ah, a man after my own heart,
Hating even the slightest
suggestion of exercise.
Dice...
While a
fascinating pastime...
How do you do?
Does overdevelop the muscles
of the throwing arm
And put calluses on the knees.
Now, it, uh, just so happens...
No hard feelings, but I
like the cards here better.
The backs got prettier
pictures on them.
An art lover appears
in the wilderness.
Shall we?
I'll peg you yet.
Keep working on it.
- Hello.
- Hi.
[Hoofbeats approaching]
[Woman laughing]
Hello. Remember me?
Without the whiskers, I mean.
Yes, of course.
Uh... This is Mr...
- Todd's the name.
- Mr. Danzeeger.
I found your daughter sitting
in the middle of a creak
With a broken wheel
on her carriage.
Oh?
My daughter didn't
mention the incident.
Oh, it was nothing, really.
Not worth mentioning.
Nevertheless, I'm very happy
to be able to thank Mr., uh...
Todd, you said the name was?
[Todd] That's as good as any.
Isn't it?
It's as good
or better than most.
You know, there aren't
very many men around here
That I'd care to trust
with my daughter, Mr. Todd.
[Todd] I can understand that.
[Danzeeger] You plan to
stay long in Corrales?
If the climate agrees with me.
My health wasn't
too good up north.
- How far north?
- Texas.
There's a war on up there.
Or... hadn't you heard?
Oh, yes. Yes, I've heard.
You, being a peace-loving man,
came to Corrales
In preference to, uh,
fighting, is that it?
- That's about it.
- I have a number of men
in my employ who, uh,
Feel the same way about it.
Perhaps our Mr. Hyatt here can
talk you into working for me?
I think I could be argued
into that without...
- too much trouble.
- [Danzeeger] Good.
- [speaking Spanish]
- [shouting, cheering]
You will honor me
with a dance?
I'm very sorry,
General, but...
Well, I'm rather tired after
my long trip from Monterrey.
Excuse me, won't you?
We were just leaving.
[Danzeeger] You understand,
I'm sure, General.
Si, I understand.
The lady is tired.
- Buenas noches.
- Buenas noches, General.
Guillermo.
* Oh, I come from Alabama
with a banjo on my knee *
* I come from Alabama
My true love for to see *
* Oh, Susanna...
* Oh, Susanna
Don't you cry for...*
[Door opening]
Oh, good night,
Senora Alvera.
- And, uh, gracias.
- [woman speaks Spanish]
I'd have been here sooner,
only my companions
were careful players.
They were as reluctant
to part with their words
as they were with their wages.
I guess I'd never make
a first-rate spy.
Not good enough
at gambling.
I'll give you another lesson
one of these days.
If we're both still
alive and kicking.
Somebody...
Somebody's playing an
awful rough game up here.
Somebody named Danzeeger?
Danzeeger, Liguras,
perhaps both.
At any rate, it's Liguras
who winds up with the chips.
Did you find out
anything else?
Uh-huh. Liguras' force
numbers about 1,500 men,
Most of 'em unarmed.
Give these a gentle rinsing,
will you, nursey?
And get blood poisoning?
Anything else?
Several interesting things.
It, uh, took me a little longer
than I expected,
But I finally found out
what I wanted to know.
[Sniffs] Roberto was right,
Liguras is waiting for guns
and ammunition from Juarez.
- Hm. Heliotrope.
- Wait a minute.
Didn't you just lose
two big shipments of arms?
Didn't you trace them here?
Well...
Every once in a while,
you meet a bright Texan.
You're right again.
Somebody is double-crossing
somebody.
The question is
who's doing it to who?
Hm... [tsks] "To whom,"
my uncouth friend, "to whom."
Well, I know that I'll lay my
hard-earned pesos on Danzeeger.
What's he doing with
a private army of thugs?
And where does he get the money
to pay Liguras and his soldiers?
- Just what is he up to?
- When you find that out,
You'll find out who killed
your friend Brooks. And why.
That's exactly what
I mean, Mr. Croyden.
Eh? What do you say?
Shall, uh, we have a look?
I'll cover Danzeeger.
He offered me a job.
Good. I'll take Liguras.
Oh, by the way, have you
recalled where Hyatt met you?
Yeah. [Chuckles]
I got a better memory
than he's got.
El Paso bank hold-up.
I threw a slug at him.
He should be packing a piece
of lead in him somewhere.
He was, uh,
running away at the time.
Oh.
Seems to me you're taking
quite a chance, son.
Didn't you say the worst thing
that could happen to you
In the spy business
is getting killed?
Ooh. [Groans]
Water. Where's water?
Oh, here. I'll get it.
Well, give it to me.
Keep a straight line.
Keep in formation!
At least they make
a frightening noise.
They're supposed
to be cavalry men.
[Guns firing]
Mr. Todd,
men come to Corrales
For two reasons.
Sometimes they're chased
across the border,
These men I can use.
Sometimes they're sent
across the border,
These men I can't use.
[Chuckles] You should have seen
the chunk of border I crossed.
Mm, yes,
perhaps I should have.
Listen, mister.
I came here looking for work.
All I ask is...
what's the pay?
Pay's good.
A man can become rich.
That's what this man
would like to become.
No curiosity about
my little army?
You want a private army of
your own, that's your business.
You want to hire me, fine.
You don't want to hire me,
- that's fine, too.
- [laughs]
I like incurious men.
But there are some things
you'll find out.
I'm an agent
of the Mexican government.
You don't object to that?
Just as long as
your money's good.
Perhaps you'll
change your mind
When you find
the regular picture.
My orders are to wait until
Texas is left unguarded,
Then move in and take over.
For who?
Mexico, of course.
With, uh, that bunch
I saw out there?
They'll serve as scouts
for General Liguras,
- he has 1,500 men.
- You'll need more than that.
Believe me,
when the time comes,
There'll be many more
than 1,500.
Does that set well with you?
I still say...
what's the pay?
There's more than money in it.
There's land.
You have no objections to owning
a piece of Texas, have you?
Not if it's a big piece.
There are very many acres,
there are very few of us.
If I were a curious man,
which I'm not,
I'd wonder what the people
of Texas will be thinking
When you move an army
into their state.
They're quite busy at the
moment, fighting a civil war.
Too busy to give
the matter much thought.
I see what you mean.
Well, I'll, uh...
put my horse away
And stash my gear.
You do that.
[Door closes]
Fancy bunkhouse you got here.
We like to make our men
feel at home.
[Men shouting in Spanish]
[Speaks Spanish]
I have here a
very fine selection
of merchandise for you.
[Speaks Spanish]
I may enter, yes?
No, senor.
[Speaks Spanish]
[Speaking Spanish]
Gracias, gracias.
[Soft guitar playing]
Pretty music, isn't it?
Yeah.
Woke me up.
I wasn't sleeping too good.
Too closed-in up there,
I thought maybe I'd
find me a haystack.
That so?
I don't like
walls and fences.
Too many of 'em in Texas,
that's why I came south.
Maybe I should've
kept going.
Oh, we wouldn't want that.
- "We?"
- Yeah.
Me and Danzeeger.
Him for one reason,
me for another.
You know, there's something
been worrying me
Like a burr in a saddle blanket
worries a horse.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Where have I seen you before?
I'd like to have you stick
around till I figure it out.
And, uh... Danzeeger?
Oh, maybe he just wouldn't
like to lose a good man.
Why don't you ask him?
I will.
I know, touchy shoulder.
But don't try to saddle up.
The boys have got orders.
Much obliged.
Forgive me for
coming here, I had to.
Did you?
I wanted to speak
to you alone.
I... I see you're
angry with me.
I... I shouldn't have come.
All right, you're here.
What do you want?
That's what I came to ask you.
What are you here for?
- Hyatt put me here.
- No, in Corrales.
Why does anyone
come to Corrales?
But you're not like the rest.
They're thieves and worse.
They would have robbed a woman
at the stream, a lone woman.
With a rifle in her hand?
They would not have
allowed a woman to
go unmolested, Mr. Todd.
Maybe I didn't see
anything I wanted.
No.
I saw the look in your eyes
when you lifted me
on your horse.
They seemed to like
what they saw.
Why is everybody
watching me?
Because they're
afraid of you.
Just as they were afraid
of a man named Brooks.
They put him in this room.
What about Brooks?
I only know they
were afraid of him,
So he was killed.
Why are you telling me this?
Why should you?
Yes, why should I?
You're nothing to me.
A man I've known only a moment.
There's been too much killing
of innocent people already.
I don't want anything
to happen to you.
To me or to your father?
Look, I took great risk
in coming here, Mr. Todd,
- you must believe me.
- Why should I?
I don't know
anything about you.
Except you can tie
a man's stomach in knots
And make his tongue feel
as thick as a saddle blanket.
- I must go.
- Maybe that's all right,
Providing you feel
the same way.
You must let me go, Hyatt
is watching you every moment.
He has good reason to, he's
trying to remember something.
Like the name
Croyden perhaps?
I heard your friend
mention it at the stream.
You've got a good memory.
Go away and I'll forget.
Maybe I can make you forget.
Would you please...
Help me down?
Thank you.
Stay close,
I'm going into town.
The shoemaker brought word
that Jones is having trouble
With some of our men.
I should be back by morning.
[Danzeeger shouts]
Senor, would you mind
tightening my saddle girth?
Your friend went to
Liguras' camp two days ago
And he hasn't been seen
or heard of since.
Thanks.
- All right?
- Gracias, senor.
Hey, put that fire out!
Stay away from this building,
you know the orders!
Hey Mack, Brownie,
get some water up here!
[Men shouting]
[Window creaking]
[Clattering]
"Poudre."
Powder.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Creaking]
There's somebody in here
and he better come out
with his hands high.
Croyden, Texas Rangers,
El Paso,
I remember every time
my back hurts.
[Piano playing, woman singing]
* All of your charms
overwhelm me *
* Here in my arms
You're divine *
* The light is in your eyes
* That seems to tell me
* This lovely night
* Will be the night
* I made you mine *
You shouldn't have come here.
Keep playing.
[Continues playing]
That's a pretty song.
It's an old French love song.
- French?
- I learned it at school
in Paris.
It will always
remind me of... someone.
A girl in Texas, perhaps?
Young and sweet?
Like this song?
* I dream of Jeannie
* With the light brown hair
There is a girl somewhere,
isn't there, Todd?
Maybe.
Maybe there are
a lot of girls.
[Distant knocking]
- Keep playing.
- [man] Someone's
in the powder house!
- [continues playing]
- Someone special, I mean.
Waiting?
If there was,
You could make
a man forget her.
[Man] Hey, Mack, Brownie...
You could make a man
forget a lot of things
Like sentries
outside his window
Or guards sleeping
on his saddle blankets.
- Yes?
- I could use some help,
Something with
a saddle on it.
- [man] Open the gate!
- [man 2] Spread out!
[Indistinct shouting continues]
Come with me.
What happened?
I just remembered who I am,
And word is getting around
quick out there.
What are you going to do?
I've gotta get out of here.
- But I'll be back, I promise.
- No, don't promise.
You'd be foolish
enough to try,
And they'd only kill you
as they did Brooks.
- Why did they kill Brooks?
- Don't try to find out.
Promise you'll go away
and not come back.
I want you to live, Todd.
[Knocking]
Give me ten minutes,
then drop over the wall
into the storehouse.
I'll manage
your horse somehow.
[Men continue shouting]
[Door opens, closes]
[Shouting in Spanish]
[Speaking Spanish]
You say Senor Danzeeger
send this to me?
That's right.
You're a very big liar,
he knows I cannot read.
- You're pretty smart, General.
- Ah, very smart.
That's why they call me
El Gavilan, The Hawk.
Why you come here?
What do you want?
I'm looking for...
Looking for a friend
of mine named Randolph.
He came up here
a couple of days ago.
Oh, yes, that fella.
You look for him, eh?
Come with me.
[Sighs] Hello, nurse.
You run along now, Melinda,
see if the beer's cold.
I was afraid
your luck had changed.
I'm glad to see
it hasn't.
Oh, but it has, it has.
The general won my boots.
So I see.
Liguras cannot read writing
but he can read the cards.
Why you lie? Why you
say Danzeeger sent you?
So I wasn't very smart, General.
I wanted to get in
so I thought up the letter.
I am a little new
at the spy business.
What is that you mean,
"spy business?"
You just let
a rabbit out, son.
- Better catch it.
- Doesn't make any difference.
I just remembered who I am.
If you had hound's ears,
you could probably hear
Him and Danzeeger
riding this way now.
[Speaks Spanish] Why you say
Danzeeger come for you?
[Whitney sighs]
Because, General,
he's found out who we are.
And he thinks
that you oughta know, too.
- I hope he's right.
- You're wasting time. Tell him.
[Sighs] Well, I have a distinct
feeling that the water's going
to be awfully cold,
But, uh, here goes.
General, I'm an agent of
the United States government,
And, uh, this...
this brash, young
fellow here is a...
- He's a Texas Ranger.
- Ranger, eh?
You come to spy on El Gavilan?
Well, now, let's not
put it that way, General,
it's just that...
Well, when one country
sees a friendly neighbor
Raising an army
on her borders, she...
Well, naturally, she...
You can't blame her
for being... curious.
So we were sent down here
to see what's going on.
I will tell you
what is going on.
But afterward, you must die.
For then you will know
El Gavilan's plans.
You still wish to know, senores?
Ah, I see you
do not want to die,
But it is no matter,
I tell you all the same.
El Gavilan will sweep down
on the Tejanos
And take the land, so!
Then he will give it
back to Mexico.
Or maybe he will
keep it for Liguras.
Now you know.
And, while the Hawk
is sweeping down on Texas,
Just what do you think
an old bird called the Eagle
Is going to be doing?
Sleeping?
Your people are too busy
fighting each other,
They will have
no time for Liguras.
He will fight
and he will win.
Or maybe he will die.
It makes no difference.
They will celebrate
in the villages.
The people will build
big statues to Juarez.
And perhaps they will build
little one for Liguras.
Who knows?
They don't build statues
to traitors, General,
- they hang 'em.
- I, Liguras, a traitor?
[Todd] You will be
if you fight for Danzeeger.
He's an agent
of the French government.
Well, so you finally
figured it out, too.
It wasn't too hard.
This is some sort of trick,
I do not believe you.
[Whitney] No, General,
it's no trick, it's the truth.
Where do you think Danzeeger
gets the money
That he pays you
and your soldiers?
- From Juarez, senor!
- No, General.
That money comes from
the French agent in Monterrey.
And it's brought
into Corrales by the
beautiful Madeline Danzeeger.
Yes. In trunks so heavy
That it takes two full-grown
nitwits to help lift them
- into a carriage.
- You sure?
Just as sure as I am that the
perfume she wears is French.
No! Danzeeger is
a friend to Mexico.
When the guns and ammunition
arrive from Juarez, we march!
He has given his word!
The guns are already here,
General.
But they're not from Juarez,
They're French guns
and stolen American guns
- intended for Juarez.
- You saw them?
- Enough to outfit a regiment.
- You're a very big liar, senor.
If Danzeeger has guns,
why he don't tell Liguras?
Because he's working
for the French!
I don't know what, but he's
got some kind of a trap.
When he's ready to spring it,
you'll get your guns,
And you'll be in the trap.
You can prove this, senores?
General, you'll have
to take our word.
No, no, it's not enough.
I must see proof.
I go to Danzeeger.
If what you tell me is true,
I kill him.
If what you tell me
is not true, I kill you.
[Liguras speaking Spanish]
We can't let Liguras
go with us.
If he gets his hands on those
guns, he'll march right now.
And then it's,
"Look out, Texas."
Get one thing straight,
If it wasn't for the girl,
I wouldn't be here.
If there's any rough stuff...
I have ordered the horses.
But first,
senores, we drink.
To Presidente Juarez.
You love him very much,
don't you, General?
I lay down my life for him.
You know, General,
If you love him, stay alive.
He needs brave men
like you to, uh...
To help fight his enemies.
You do not say
what you mean, Yankee.
You're very smart, General.
But Danzeeger is smart, too.
He doesn't want you to know
that he's working
for the French.
That's why he had
the man Brooks killed.
If you face him now,
he would lie.
He'd even destroy
the proof of his guilt.
- What do you want me to do?
- Stay here.
Let us bring
the proof to you.
Then he can't
lie his way out.
It is agreed. I stay here.
And now, senores...
To Juarez.
And no tricks, Tejano,
my men are everywhere.
Senor...
My boots.
Little big, perhaps,
but better than the bare foot.
I'm flattered.
[Speaks Spanish]
[Chattering in Spanish]
Here's the powder,
it's all I could get.
It'll be enough.
Meet us at Danzeeger's place
tomorrow at 12:00 sharp.
And bring Liguras
and his men.
I will be there.
Be careful.
Danzeeger's men are everywhere
like angry hornets.
[Explosions]
- [chattering, shouting]
- [man] What is it?
[Chatter continues]
Margarita, what is it?
What happened?
[Speaks Spanish]
Go quickly and find out
what it means.
- [shouting continues]
- [explosions continue]
[Knocking]
[Madeline]
Is that you, Margarita?
[Gasps] Todd?
Why did you come back?
For you.
You're coming with me.
I can't, it's impossible.
You'll have to,
it isn't safe here.
I'm used to danger,
I can't leave.
Don't ask me why, Todd,
just go, please,
Before it's too late.
If you love me,
you'll come with me.
I do, Todd, I do.
Oh, darling,
Please believe me, I tried
not to fall in love with you.
I didn't want to.
[Man] Guards!
Open the gate! Open it!
[Explosions, shouting continues]
In four days, we'll be across
the border, you'll be safe.
Now, hurry, no arguments.
- Todd...
- Say it later,
there isn't time.
I've got to say it now, Todd.
Crossing the border
Won't free me from Danzeeger.
We're married, Todd.
He's my husband.
Don't look at me like that.
It was you who called me
his daughter, remember?
Yeah, I remember.
You didn't bother
to put me straight.
Well, how was I to know
it would go this far?
When I realized what was
happening, I wanted to tell you,
but he wouldn't let me.
Look, darling, he doesn't
mean anything to me.
Someday, when this
is all over...
It's all over now, Madeline.
When Liguras sees this letter,
He'll stand you and your husband
up in front of a firing squad.
Knowing who I am
and what I am,
Do you still want me
to go with you?
It's the only way
to save your neck.
No. No, there's one other.
Give me the letter.
Well, what are
you waiting for?
A moment ago,
you said you loved me.
Either you were lying then
or you're bluffing now.
Todd, listen, I have a duty
to perform to my country,
The same as you.
If I have to shoot, I will.
Give me the letter.
[Gun fires]
[Shouts]
Thank you, my dear.
You've reestablished
my faith in you somewhat.
There was a moment or two in
the past few days, I must admit,
I thought I'd lost your
affections to this
charming Texas spy.
Captain Croyden, my wife.
- We've met.
- Oh?
She told you. In that case,
there's nothing more to be said.
- Will you take over, Mr. Hyatt?
- With pleasure.
All right, Captain Croyden.
What will they do with him?
I, uh, imagine Mr. Hyatt
has ideas on the subject.
- Thank you.
- Oh, let him go.
Send him to Mexico City
and hold him a prisoner.
You're scarcely in a bargaining
position, my dear.
Please?
Losing one's head in this
business is dangerous enough.
Losing one's heart is worse.
I'll see that he's not harmed.
[Todd grunting, straining]
Tie him off good.
I don't want him to drag
and get his brains beaten out.
I want to make sure you know
what's happening to you
When they pull you to pieces.
You all right down there?
All ready, Red.
[Red] Stand clear
when I say go.
Comfortable, Captain?
I'm surprised an old
campaigner like yourself
Should fall for
a woman's smile.
An old sod. [Tsks]
Well, there seems nothing
left to say but goodbye.
- [men shouting]
- [gunshots]
[Men hooting, cheering]
Whoa!
Whoa, boy!
Ho!
Come on!
Hang on, nurse!
If I cut you loose on this
side, can you swing up?
I'll try.
Take the knife!
Whoa.
Whoa! Steady, boy.
Whoa, boy.
Whoa, boy. Steady.
Hurry, Whit!
[Gunshot]
[Breathing heavily]
Hello, nurse.
Shut up and lie still.
Reminds me of the...
Guy who missed the top step.
Would you mind...
Straightening out
my legs for me, Mr. Croyden?
Not at all, Mr. Randolph.
- Better?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
Wait a minute.
If I wanted my legs
straightened out,
Wouldn't I move 'em myself?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
I'll try and get
your horse for you.
I don't need a horse.
I understand...
We use an entirely
different kind of...
Transportation
where I'm going.
If my luck holds out.
Sun's getting kind of high.
Don't forget, you got a...
Luncheon date with Liguras.
I know.
Can I have your guns, Whit?
Sure, Todd.
You know something, mister?
I've changed my mind
about a short war.
It'll take us quite a while
to lick you Yanks.
- I'll be back as soon as I can.
- Sure.
You know something funny?
Everything happens to me
with my boots off.
[Danzeeger] The shadow
grows longer, General.
It's well past noon.
Where are these Americans
who will bring proof
of my disloyalty to Mexico?
Si, muchacho,
Where are the men who tell
Liguras this wild story
Of hidden guns and ammunition?
Perhaps they were burned
in the storehouse, General.
[Chuckles] I would destroy
valuable powder and weapons?
[Liguras] You have listened
to the Yankee, Roberto.
If there are guns
I must have proof.
Where is the proof?
[Danzeeger] There'll be no
proof. The Americans won't come.
[Liguras] I believe this.
I ask my friend to forgive me.
No need
of forgiveness, General.
Just take your men
back to camp.
Si, si.
- [speaking Spanish]
- [speaks Spanish] He comes!
[People chattering]
Did I not tell you that he
would keep his word, General?
He comes alone, like a man
who is sick or drunk.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting,
General, but...
I was unavoidably detained.
Your friend,
he of the good luck?
His luck ran out today.
He's dead.
Thanks to him, I'm not.
You overlooked him, Danzeeger.
Regrettable oversight on the
part of Mr. Hyatt, I assure you.
Come, Tejano, where's
the proof you promised?
Last night, I had a paper
in my hands signed by the
French Minister of War.
It said that Danzeeger
was his agent.
[Liguras] Well,
the paper, where is it?
Go on, Captain.
Show it to him!
- You have it, Tejano?
- No, but I saw it.
That's why I was tied
to wild horses like Brooks.
He wanted to make sure
I didn't tell you.
- He's lying.
- The paper said that the money
that pays your troops
- comes from France.
- It comes from Juarez.
[Todd] Maybe you'll believe
your own countrymen.
Tell him, Roberto.
Si, what say you, muchacho?
He tells the truth.
These are with the French
Who sent an Austrian
to be our emperor,
And his wife, a Belgian,
to be our empress.
Why did you not
tell me this before?
You were afraid because you
could not prove what you say?
Would you believe me, General,
if I told you?
- [Danzeeger] Madeline!
- Yes, I take the lady's word.
The American speaks the truth.
- Stay out of this.
- No, I won't.
You promised to let him go.
You and your troops will be
used to stop the Americans
- if they come to help Juarez.
- Don't listen to her!
You've got to listen to me.
My husband and I
are agents of the French.
If you seize Texas, you will
take it for France, not Mexico.
Hurry, Captain!
- Todd!
- [gunshot]
Smith, Brown, cover us.
- [Madeline groans]
- [gunfire continues]
- Take care of her, Roberto.
- I will.
[Shouts in Spanish]
- Stay with your men!
- [shouts in Spanish]
Why you stop?
It's almost dark,
he'll get away.
Get up!
Come on, get up!
- There he is!
- Wait.
Danzeeger!
Can you hear me?
- I hear you!
- You've got one chance!
Give up!
Will Liguras treat me
as a prisoner of war?
Guarantee safe conduct
to Mexico City?
- How about it, General?
- No, senor, he must die.
I make no promise!
In that case, gentlemen,
Come and get me!
You stay here,
amigo, I get him.
You wouldn't get 50 feet
up that hill, General.
- He'll slip away.
- We'll smoke him out.
I'll set fire
on the base of the peak
and set the draw here.
You cover from there
and get him when he comes out.
He must not escape.
You'll get him, General.
Stay down here.
[Gunshot]
Keep your eye on that draw,
General, he'll come out like
a scared jackrabbit.
That's the only way out.
The horses, senor, they'll
be frightened by the fire.
You will take
them away, please.
Liguras? Liguras!
Where are you?
- Here I am!
- Come back! Come back!
No! No!
[Gunfire continues]
[Gunfire]
Poor Liguras,
he could have been a great man.
He was a patriot.
Are there any greater?