Looks like we're getting
close to civilization.
I wouldn't give half an acre
of Texas for the whole Montana Territory.
[ Honky-tonk Piano ]
- Howdy.
- Evening.
We need some feed and a couple stalls.
That'll be $16 overnight, gold or silver.
We ain't aiming to buy you out, mister.
Ain't aiming to sell. It's still $16.
- In advance.
- That's Yankee talk.
Never mind.
My brother don't know the war's over.
You got $16?
Uh, we're a little short of funds.
Then you boys better be on your way.
I figured you might be in a trading mood.
For instance?
Well, uh, one genuine Yankee saber.
Oh, and this fancy timepiece.
Solid gold.
Used to belong to a live general.
And a fine pair of field glasses.
You with the reb army?
In a left-handed sort of way.
- Quantrill's Raiders.
- Mighty tough outfit.
So I've heard.
How, uh, far do these things reach?
Four or five miles.
I'll trade you the whole kit and kaboodle
for $50 over your 16.
- Might give you 20.
- Thirty.
Twenty-five. That's my limit.
Mister, you just bought your self
a parcel of Yankee souvenirs.
Well, gents, help your selves...
to the feed and stall space.
You want your horses before sun up,
just come and take 'em.
Door's always open.
- Never mind the saddles.
- Reckon this'll be a quick one, huh?
Could be.
- [ Honky-tonk Piano ]
- [ Patrons Chattering ]
Take a look around the back.
- [ Continues ]
- [ Chattering Continues ]
- Come on, damn you!
- Eight! Eight!
- Aw, come on!
- Pay off!. Pay off!.
Come on, seven.! Pay off.
No way in or out back there.
A lot of action inside.
- Craps again.
- [ Chattering, Muttering ]
Never saw such a herd
of hard-rock gophers in my life.
Gold's what they grow here, not beef.
- Clint. You need remindin'?
- No.
We're here on business.
lots of looking, very little drinking.
- And the war's over.
- Yep. The war's over.
- What'll it be?
- What do you drink in Montana, friend?
Too blamed much.
Fractured, or all of a piece?
A couple of snorts.
That'll be eight dollars in greenbacks,
five in silver or a pinch of dust.
Mmm. Expensive, living hereabouts, huh?
If you call it living.
Sure ain't slept in a barrel long.
Nothing gets a chance to age in a boomtown,
mister. Not even the people.
Mild as milk juice.
How's about another snort?
Easy, boy. let's not foul this up.
You're calling the turns in this deal, Ben.
Make way, gents.
Take a look. The fancy Jasper.
looks real prime.
Fat as a June grouse.
- Howdy, Nathan.
- How are ya?
- Evening, Mr. Stark. Buy you a drink?
- My pleasure. Gus.
Hear you're riding to Butte tonight.
Yes. After I leave,
set 'em up for the boys.
[ Stark ]
Long as it lasts.
[ Gus ] Sure thing.
Hope you'll be heading back here soon.
I will, one of these days.
Hank.
Hank!
Get your hands up,Jasper.
Keep 'em up.
Now peel off that money belt.
Freeze it.
Thought I raised you neater than that.
Now you can unfasten that money belt
and pass it over real slow.
Is that all?
- Or do you want my watch too?
- Keep it.
We're traveling now.
We're real taken
with your company, Mr. Stark.
I'm afraid I can't say the same.
Fact is, we're so taken
that we can't leave you.
Can't have you rousing out those vigilantes
on a cold night like this.
If you're gonna kill me,
get it over with now.
Move over a shade, Ben.
Allow me to accommodate the gentleman.
All I said was, we didn't want
to leave you here.
I'm hoping we don't have to.
You coming, mister, or staying?
You're dealing.
- I guess I'm riding.
- Saddle your horse.
[ Ben ]
We bunked here night before last.
[ Clint ]
Quiet as a graveyard, ain't it, Mr. Stark?
Sit down, Mr. Stark.
Hate to lose a man who talks
like a college professor...
but we've brought you far enough.
Tomorrow Clint'll
pick up some supplies.
You can take your share
and hightail it back.
- Minus my money?
- Yeah, minus.
Would you, uh, care for a cigar?
Thank you.
How about you?
If you open that belt, you'll find nothing
but mint-fresh hundred-dollar bills.
The kind that crackle?
[ Chuckles ] That's what I like.
Spending them won't be easy.
You'll leave a trail so wide...
the Pinkertons'll be on you
like buzzards on a dead mule.
And who's to tell the Pinkertons?
You?
You're making it tough
on yourself, Mr. Stark.
I'm not trying to make it tough.
Only tempting.
Never could resist temptation.
Will you answer just one question?
- [ Hammer Cocks ]
- Ask it.
What were steers selling at
when you left Texas?
We haven't been home in four years.
Three and four dollars a head,
and no takers.
- Of all the stupid, stalling-
- What are you driving at?
What we buy in Texas,
we sell for $50 a head in Montana.
You mean you'd drive a herd 1 ,500 miles,
all the way from Texas to Mineral City?
- I had meant to.
- He's loco, Ben.
I was planning to go to Texas,
but I'm no cattleman.
I knew I'd need a trail boss.
Now, ain't that too bad.
But it's not too late.
My offer still goes. We split 50-50
on every cow we bring into Montana alive.
- Ha!
- Can't you see how big this is?
I'm offering you half the chips...
in the biggest game you ever
had the chance to sit in.
A chance for big money-
honest money.
More than you could ever make
in a lifetime.
And against that, what have you? Spending
a few thousand, and then prison. Or hanging.
It's dealer's choice, hermano.
A chance to make something
for ourselves.
With him holding the joker.
I don't like the game, Ben,
but you call it.
Do you realize there hasn't been a mouthful of
beefsteak in Montana since before the war?
We'll gamble.
Give him back his money belt.
You carry the bankroll, Mr. Stark.
We'll carry the guns.
A man couldn't ask
for better protection.
- What do we do now?
- We short-cut it straight across.
Pretty rugged. Only an Indian
could get through that.
We ain't mentioned it afore, Mr. Stark,
but me and Ben is quarter-blood Comanche.
[ Rifle Cocks ]
Well, get down. Don't just sit there.
Get yourselves some shelter.
Henry, put the horses up.
Make yourselves to home.
I reckon we got a little coffee left.
Thanks, Grandma.
Grandma?
Here, drink some of this.
It'll warm you up.
Well, go ahead.
I ain't gonna bite you.
I don't know.
Those teeth look pretty sharp to me.
Well, they oughta be. They haven't
had anything to eat in three days.
- What?
- Well, take a look for yourself.
Them folks are starving.
From the looks of you,
you ain't doing any better.
No. We lost our packhorse.
[ Ben ] Maybe you're not
as empty-handed as you think.
You ain't thinking
of butchering one of our mules.
That's no mule, Grandma.
That's a Missouri elk.
You just start setting the table.
How we gonna get our wagons
out of here without mules?
You starve to death,
you won't need any wagons.
Mister, you're talking my language.
Oh,just so you won't have to keep
confusing me with your grandma...
my name's Nella- Nella Turner.
I'm Ben Allison.
Mr. Allison, we're mighty pleased
to have you stay for supper.
- We're having Missouri elk.
- Yes, ma'am. Coming right up.
Well, how you two human icicles
standing the thaw?
Now that we got some real, live heat,
things are perking up again.
Ben's my brother. I'm Clint.
Clinton Allison, ma'am. Free and single
as a skunk at a Sunday school picnic.
Probably for the same reason.
Now, don't go honey-fussing me, ma'am,
just 'cause I'm rich and handsome.
look,junior, why don't you run along
and help Papa cut up the nice mule.
Mama's hungry.
Anything to please a lady.
- You don't talk much, do ya?
- No.
These others are not your people.
You asking or telling me?
Merely an observation.
It figures.
You know, for a fella who doesn't do
much talking, you got real busy eyes.
It's not that I mind being stared at.
That's part of being a female.
But I don't like being
weighed, measured and counted.
I'd call it 1 30 pounds.
Pure gold in the rough.
Just needs a little refining.
Don't shortchange me. It's 1 3 5.
And just to show you
how unrefined I am...
why don't you get off your dead end
and get us some firewood.
Your servant, ma'am.
We oughta make
Bent's Trading Post by noon...
and have a rescue party
back here by sundown.
You ever find your way to Montana,
miss,just ask for me.
I'll remember.
Nathan Stark, Montana.
- You own the whole territory?
- I mean to someday.
You know something?
When a woman looks pretty at sunup,
then she's really pretty.
Didn't think you could spout so elegant.
I got words I ain't ever used.
You come to Prairie Dog Creek
and hear 'em.
Prairie Dog Creek? Where's that?
The only country in the world-
Texas, ma'am.
So long, folks.
What does it mean?
Well, the hand,
fingers pointing down...
busted gun pointing down-
that's just plain bad news.
Them markings, Ben.
They ain't Comanche or Cheyenne.
No. Sioux. The Oglala tribe.
They're the throat-cutters.
That lower marking there
means a knife slash.
- I'm going back.
- look, Allison.
Will you make sense?
We're halfway to the post.
Besides, look at those tracks.
Due north.
No reason to suppose they'll get
within 1 0 miles of that camp.
There's one reason
you haven't been watching.
The Sioux are no different than you and me
when it comes to talking shelter out of a storm.
And that could be Timpas Grove.
What if it is? It's not our concern.
You got a short memory.
There's an army detachment at Bent's.
Fighting Indians is their business.
We'll never get anywhere if you stop
and help every bunch of cripples we meet.
Our business is getting to San Antone,
and every day counts.
- Nobody asked you to turn back.
- let's get moving, Ben.
Clint!
You stick with Stark.
- Me? With him?
- Him and the bankroll.
What for? I could cut him loose from his hair
and his bankroll. look like an Injun job.
Now you listen to me. I'm gonna
tell you this once, and just once.
When we meet again,
at the post or in San Antone...
I want the 20,000 and him alive.
- Savvy?
- All right.
Just don't rawhide me, will ya, Ben.
- I'll play it your way.
- Good.
Be seeing you, hermano.
Thought that brother of yours
had more sense...
than to risk everything
chasing after a woman.
It ain't 'cause of her.
There's others there too.
He'd do no different
if you was back there.
- I have grave doubts about that.
- Stop pushing, Stark.
If I had my way,
I'd be riding back there with Ben...
and you'd be as dead
as last night's Missouri elk.
Now git.
[ Screams ]
[ Rifle Fire ]
[ Rifle Cocks ]
[ Rifle Shot ]
You the only one left?
Yeah. I was in the wagon when they hit us.
So was this.
If only them folks hadn't run.
[ Rifle Fire ]
Get your trappings and some of that meat.
We're getting out.
Anybody to home?
We'll wait here till this storm
blows itself out.
Build yourself a fire. There are matches
right there in the saddlebag.
I'll putJeb up.
Best I can do for you tonight,Jeb.
Try and dig you up something
in the morning.
Oh! My feet are half froze.
Huh? Here, get those boots off.
Here.
Push. Give me the other one.
- And the socks.
- Ooh.
Hey, don't get 'em
that close right away.
Oh.
[ Moans ]
- Can you feel that?
- Uh-huh.
- [ Huffs ] Feel good?
- Mm-hmm.
Hey! No sleeping.
You gotta get out
of these wet clothes.
Just a minute. In a minute.
Can't afford to have
a frozen woman on my hands.
Come on. Up now.
- [ Mumbling ]
- Pick yourself a corner and get out of'em.
Yeah.
I'll get some wood.
Ben.
I'm mighty grateful to you
for coming back after me.
I'm just mighty grateful.
- Ben?
- Hmm?
[ Sighs ]
What are you doing?
Here. Want some?
No.
After a long ride,
I get hungry as a bear.
[ Groans ]
I wish you'd warm my feet some more.
Here.
Put 'em on my back.
Ohh.
[ Clicking Tongue ]
Hey, you ever been in love before?
- Me?
- Mm-hmm.
I'm kinda bashful.
[ Wind Gusting ]
[Jeb Whinnying ]
Here, boy. I dug this up for you.
I wish I was a peach tree
A-growing in the ground
And every time
My sweetie passed by
I'd shake some peaches down
But he's an ornery cowpoke
And bashful as can be
And if he wants
them peaches of mine
He'll have to climb the tree
- I want a tall man
-  [ Whistling Along ]
Don't want a small man
Long as he is all man
That's good enough
For me
[ Yawns ]
Hey, cowboy!
You better come and get it!
[ Whistling ]
Was that you or a coyote howling?
- You didn't like it?
- Scared me.
I was about to go off
and leave you, only I, uh...
haven't had my breakfast.
Whoa! Short rations.
- Is that rabbit cooking?
- Yeah.
Met up with him at daybreak.
- And it's still storming.
- Yeah.
looks like it's gonna blow up some more
coming in from the north now.
But I got nothing to complain about.
Roof over my head...
fire going strong...
solid home cooking.
What else could a man want?
[ Muffled ]
Mmm, mmm!
listen, you go over there
and sit down...
and I'll sample
some of this home cooking.
You know, my hands are freezing.
Help me off with these chaps,
will you, Grandma?
All right.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- This way.
You know something?
You do remind me of my grandma.
Yeah.
The way she must've looked when Grandpa
Allison bought her from old Stone Bear.
Cost him six horses, a musket, uh...
and his fancy gold snuffbox.
You know, that's a heap
to pay for a woman.
But the old boy
never seemed to regret it...
although I do think
he missed his snuffbox.
Now, me- I don't use it.
No snuffbox, no deal.
I could shop around some.
You know, a funny thing-
two months ago, the only future I had
was the wrong end of a rope.
- Hmm?
- Yeah.
Clint and me turned bad men,
held up that Nathan Stark fella.
- I thought you were partners.
- We are now, in a cattle deal.
I got a hunch, Nella, that something
great's gonna come out of it.
Not ''big'' great,
the way Stark sees things...
but ''little'' great.
- And that's good enough for me.
- ''Big'' great pays off better.
All I want is a little ranch
in my home country...
along Prairie Dog Creek.
Ain't anything like it in the world.
The world's bigger than that, Ben.
You just haven't looked.
I looked plenty.
Four years of war,
watching men scrabble over life...
like coyotes over a kill.
And for what?
Did they eat better, sleep better?
A corner's all I want...
with the right kind of woman.
You ever been
in my part ofTexas, Nella?
No. But there's
something better someplace.
There's just gotta be.
Maybe so. Maybe right here.
You sure give a honey and molasses
flavor to this rabbit.
That's not honey and molasses.
That's just girl.
- Ben.
- Yeah?
How much you figure your share
of the cattle drive?
Mmm, it depends on luck.
High as 50,000, low as plain nothing.
Nobody ever got through
on this kind of drive.
You will.
[ Chuckles ]
I sure got a double reason for trying.
You know, with $50,000-
even half of that-
you could buy a big business...
maybe out in California.
Honey, when you see
that prairie dog country...
you wouldn't swap it
for anything else.
The house will sit square
on top of the hill...
looking down at the river.
Yeah, I know.
Two rooms to start,
but it'll grow, gradual-like...
and maybe three, four rooms.
Yeah. Slow and easy.
You tied to that dream, Ben?
Tighter than a cinch strap.
Even if I feel different?
Well, I guess I was wrong
in not asking.
I kinda took it for granted
that we feel the same about things.
Not about ranch living.
I had all of that I could stand
when I was a kid.
It couldn't have been that bad.
I wish I could show you a picture
of my ma on her wedding day.
She was beautiful-
all alive with hopes and plans
for the future.
I was only 1 2 when she died.
She wasn't beautiful anymore...
just old.
An old, old woman.
No more hopes, no plans.
That's just one side of the picture, Nella-
the hard-luck side.
Don't it depend a little
on who you're with...
and how you feel about each other?
My pop loved Mom.
There wasn't any man could've
loved a woman more than he did.
No, it was ranch livin'-
dirty, mangy, sod-busting living
that killed her.
And him a year later.
As bad as it seems to you,
they probably were happy.
Happy?
Years of going without...
washing greasy plates
and chipped enamel cups...
sleeping on flour sacks...
digging for water holes
where there ain't none to be found...
and praying the winter will be over
before your cows are all frozen dead?
Is that the kind of a dream
you want to be tied to, Ben?
It won't be like that.
I won't let it be.
Pop must've told Mom that
a thousand times.
It never turned out the way he wanted.
I'm sorry, Ben...
but your ideas and mine
just don't seem to fit.
I want more out of life than that.
[ Sighs ]
I didn't mean to insult you
with my measly offer.
Don't say that, Ben.
It's only my right to dream
I'm arguing for.
Yeah. Great big dreams.
Yes, great big dreams...
with a man who's going places
and has room for a passenger.
like Nathan Stark maybe.
It could be you!
I'm sorry. I dream small.
I just wanted to see if you're
the same girl I've been kissing.
You ain't.
Here. This'll keep you warm.
It's you who needs warming!
- Whoa.
- [ Whinnies ]
- You still tight as a cinch strap, Ben?
- Tighter.
Well, I guess it's better we found out
right now how we both feel.
It sure is.
[ Horse Nickering ]
- Allison?
- Yeah.
Hoped it was you when we cut
across your trail way back there.
Sorry about the others.
You all right, ma'am?
- My brother at the post?
- Took the stage to San Antone.
Sure got a boot out of him.
He said he'd chased us Yanks,
and we'd been chasing him...
but blamed if he'd ride alongside of us.
Said to meet him if you were still alive.
Otherwise, he would
personally make arrangements
for the other gentleman to meet you...
wherever you were.
Great sense ofhumor.
Soldier, when does the next stage
leave the post for California?
California? I'm afraid nothing
for at least two months.
The only stage trail open
this time of year is San Antone.
I'm sure you can
make connections out of there.
There's a horse over there
for you, ma'am.
You wouldn't think pretty country
like this could get so cold.
It'll warm up some the closer
we get to Prairie Dog Creek.
And you know what? That's one of
the real garden spots in all Texas.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Bah!
- I beg your pardon, ma'am?
- What for?
- Well, I thought you said something.
- I said ''bah!''
Yes. Of course. Certainly.
It's warmer downstairs.
Yeah.
likely looking female we got with us.
- Yeah.
- Dance hall woman?
No. Prospector.
Get out!
Ain't no such. Not a female.
- What kind?
- What kind of what?
Prospecting.
Gold digging.
Hyah! Brownie! Chuck!
Whoa! Whoa.
Come on.
- Did you have a good trip, ma'am?
- Yeah, fine.
My feet feel like they walked all the way.
- Well, I hope you find what you're looking for.
- Thanks.
Here. You might be needing this when you
get around to staking out a new claim.
- Swamper, you getting my trappin's?
- Yes'm.
Don't get lost, bashful boy.
Remember, you're in the big city now.
- Howdy.
- Howdy, ma'am.
[ Sighs ]
I gotta get these off.
I think my feet are asleep.
Well, mister, what's your problem?
Oh, n-nothing. Nothing.
Whoo. Whoo.
There.
Hello. Remember me?
Well, now, I'm not about to forget the man
who's gonna own the whole of Montana.
Thanks.
Where's, uh, Ben Allison?
- I wouldn't know.
- Didn't he get to San Antone?
Oh, yeah. He's around.
Don't tell me you've lost track
of each other so soon.
Now, what's that supposed to mean?
Only that people often
get attached on a long trip.
Why the sudden interest, Mr. Stark?
I didn't notice you riding back
to Timpas Grove when those Sioux hit us.
No. I was heading this way,
and I never detour.
[ Chuckles ]
How much is your cheapest room?
- How long do you intend staying?
- That depends on the price.
Well, uh, dollar and a half a night,
nine dollars for the week.
- One night, for a starter.
- Never mind, Clerk.
let Miss Turner have my suite.
Find me the next best.
- [ Bell Dings ]
- At least you'll have a bathtub.
like I asked before,
''What's that supposed to mean?''
Only that hot water and a tub
go well together...
especially when they surround
a beautiful woman.
You may waste the words,
but you sure don't waste much time.
I try not to waste anything.
Boy, you want to pick up my trappin's?
I don't know. I'm so stove up,
I don't think I can get up these stairs.
Oh, uh...
I guess we better get something straight.
When I take a bath, I surround myself
with water and the tub-
nothing and nobody else.
I was about to leave.
But first I wanted to ask you
to have dinner with me tonight.
- In these things?
- No.
But there are some shops in town,
if you'll gamble on my judgment.
Well, I don't see how I can lose.
I'll see you later.
Oh, uh, I wear
a size seven and a half boot.
You can guess about the rest.
Benjamin Dabney Allison.!
Chicksaw Charlie! Well, you haven't
changed a bit, you old polecat!
Thought you got lynched
or something, Colonel.
- Yanks shoot your horse from under you?
- Nope. Came in on the stage.
Hey, Ben.!
Glad you made it, hermano,
and all in one piece.
- How's our bankroll, old boy?
- Stark?
Safe and elegant
and wearing all his hairs.
Senor Ben!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ laughing ]
This is the happiest moment in my life!
Hello, luis. Been a long time.
- It was like forever, Senor Ben! like forever!
- Four years.
- How 'bout some small celebrating?
- We got something to celebrate?
More than 4,000 head,
all bought and paid for.
What about herders? You sign any?
They don't cotton to driving 1 ,500 miles
through Injun country.
But you being here, won't be hard to round up
the boys that rode with you and Quantrill.
I have some very tough caballeros too!
With you, Senor Ben,
they'll ride clear to hell!
Well, thanks, luis, but I figure on stopping
somewhere on the Texas side of it.
Is a long time till for dying!
- Tonight we get drunk!
-Jump in, men!
And I cook a special dinner
for you tonight!
Tortillas, enchiladas, senoritas, music...
and everything!
Never put a hat on a bed.
It's bad luck.
Oh! Ahh.
[ laughing ]
- looks like a plucked chicken.
- Mire.
- What's that?
- Ah, the finest in my shop.
Mmm. Please to lean down
the neck, senorita.
There. Ay, que encanto.!
How you like it, eh?
- Smells like a friendly skunk.
- Oh, no, no!
From delicate French roses,
direct from my shop.
- Eh. Skunk.
- [ laugh ]
When Senor Stark smells you-
Ooh, la, la, senorita. He go wild!
Well, then take it away because
I'm not much in the mood for running.
Ah, you run a little,
and then you stop a little.
And when you want
Senor Stark to catch you...
then you sit down in the big chair.
Hey, do you happen to know
a big galoot named Ben Allison?
Oh, do I know him!
Oh, who does not?
When he was here,
every woman knows Senor Ben...
from both sides of the Rio Grande.
Que hombre, mujer. Que hombre.
Always loving and fighting.
No time for anything else.
Just loving and fighting.
Did he have any special girl?
Senor Ben? Oh, with him,
all the senoritas are special.
But I think one time
maybe Conchita and Francesca...
a little extra special.
Oh, for two or three weeks.
Oh, please, no breathing, senorita.
Oh, I remember when they
fight and pull the hair.
But Senor Ben,
he just laugh and ride away...
to fight the Yankee gringo.
- [ Gasps ]
- Hey! Please to stop the breathing, senorita!
Nothing is worth this.
Take it back to your shop. I can't stand this!
- Oh, no. Stop, please. [ Speaking Spanish ]
- It's too-
There you are! It is all finished.
Now you can breathe.
There's nothing left to breathe with.
Ah, no corset, no caboose.
Now, you watch Maria.
look. The swish to the right
and the swish to the left.
You see? The right and the left.
See? No swishing in the middle.
Only the right and the left.
like this, you see?
Now, senorita, it's up to you.
Make with the caboose.
Mmm. Hmm.
A little more swish, swish.
Eso es.!
[ Spanish ]
- Two more of the same, and keep them well-iced.
- Si, senor.
- Everything is ready.
- You can bring the food anytime.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Is everything satisfactory?
Perfection, senor. In a few moments
you will see for yourself.
She's like a beautiful red rose...
and, oh, the finest figure
I have ever seen.
In all, the total comes to $1 60.
- That's quite a figure too.
- Oh, for such a woman, it is most reasonable.
Gracias.
Uh, senor, I wish you the most beautiful
evening of your entire life.
[ laughs, Sighs ]
Well, quite a change
from Timpas Grove, huh?
Quite a change in you too.
You better like it. You bought it,
and it's not going back.
How come we're eating up here?
Why don't we eat downstairs?
After your long trip, I just thought
dining in private would be more restful.
You sure think of everything, don't you?
Tomorrow night we'll dine downstairs.
Give San Antone a chance
to gape and envy me.
That's important to you, isn't it?
Being envied.
Frankly, very.
People only envy a successful man.
They envy a failure nothing.
- [ Knocking ]
- Come in.
Well, looks like a real fancy barbecue.
I wanted it to be an occasion.
- Excuse me, sir. Shall I serve the wine?
- No, we'll serve ourselves.
This, uh, is getting to be
more private all the time.
I guess I dislike sharing your company
even with waiters.
Shall we sit down?
I don't know whether this rig is made
for sitting, but I'm hungry enough to try.
You'll grow into clothes like these, Nella.
Eventually you'll wonder how you
could have been satisfied with less.
You sure make it easy to buy.
Well, if I'm that persuasive...
maybe I can talk you out of going west.
No. No detours for me either.
Is there any, uh, particular attraction
in California?
No, nothing special.
Just like everybody else,
I'm looking for the end of the rainbow.
[ Chuckles ]
Rainbows aren't a matter of geography.
You can find them anywhere.
even in a snowstorm in Timpas Grove.
Well, I didn't.
You might have better luck in Montana.
With you owning the whole territory?
And all its rainbows.
You dream big, Mr. Stark.
- I have no interest in being a small man.
- [ loud Pop ]
- What is that?
- Champagne.
The wine of a connoisseur.
You're gonna have to bend down a little with
them words if you want me to understand.
Why don't you try reaching up instead?
That's what you want out of life, isn't it?
Yeah, I guess I do.
- How do you say that word again?
- Connoisseur.
Connoisseur.
It means a person of taste.
Should we drink a toast?
Might as well go whole hog.
To you and me, Nella...
and a mutual monopoly
on the best things in life.
You sure talk like
one of them connoisseurs...
but I like it first class.
This is first class too.
I just gotta take my shoes off.
My feet are killing me.
[ Chuckling ]
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Mariachi ]
[ Exhales ]
That's the fastest bit of prospecting
I ever saw.
I came down here
for just one reason, Mr. Allison.
Peekaboo clothes and everything.
And I got no more use
for you or your insults!
It'll make a nice remembrance.
Senor Ben! Senor Ben!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
- What do you want?
- [ Spanish Continues ]
You tell her to quit sounding off about me,
or she's gonna get in trouble.
Oh, cool off.
She's not talking about you.
- She's looking for Clint.
- Don't lie to me!
I know all about you.
The great Mr. Allison...
fighting and loving everything in sight
on both sides of the Rio Grande.
- [ Spanish ]
All right, sister, I warned you.
Now you git!
Git! Pronto.!
Bueno.! Bueno.!
You no kill me. [ Spanish ]
All right.
You gonna start apologizing?
You're talking upside-down.
I got nothing to apologize about.
Just you keep coming,
and you'll see what happens.
That's better.
- Now, are you gonna apologize?
- No.
Go on, lady. Shoot him.
Go on! Shoot him.
Won't work good without these.
Oh, you dirty, sod-busting...
woman-chasing connoisseur!
That's all, prospector.
looks like she's in love with you,
hermano.
[ Exhales ]
Out cold.
Ain't never been cold in her life.
Mmm. Trouble is,
she can't breathe good.
She's cinched too tight.
[ Grunts ]
Mighty fancy outfit.
That cost someJasper a piece of change.
I wonder who the moneybags is.
- Ah, who cares?
- Senor Ben! Senor Ben!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Ben ]
Manana, manana.
Ay.!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Breathing Deeply ]
Breathing like an old swamp frog.
I'll take her back to her gold mine.
Come on. Give me a hand.
Get her in the saddle.
- [ Grunting ]
- You got her?
Whoa! Hold it!
Her back door's open.
- [ Continues ]
- [ Shouting, Laughing Continues ]
Well, boys, I'll lay
the whole proposition on the line...
with no guarantee that anybody's coming
out of this rich or smelling of roses...
or even that you're gonna
come out of it at all.
'Cause we're gonna drive this herd
of cattle all the way to Montana.
If we make it...
you'll have full bellies and a bonus of $4.00
for every head you bring into Mineral City.
That's high as $ 1 6,000
divided among you.
- What do you say?
- We're with you, Colonel!
let's go, Ben!
[ Shouting, Cheering ]
All right, luis, fire 'em up!
[ luis Shouts In Spanish ]
Boys! Boys!
Put Miss Turner's belongings
in one of the wagons.
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
- You bringing her along?
- Any objections?
''Any''? I'm full of'em.
Personal or otherwise?
Personal. Nothing but.
We figure on having enough trouble
without dragging along some more.
All of the sudden, when it comes
to traveling I'm supposed to be trouble.
Nella will be my responsibility.
That's for sure, partner.
Get her junk switched!
You reckon she can get
into that tub, Ben?
Maybe she should've
brought two of'em.
Why don't you two muleheads
join the cattle?
You save her hide,
and theJasper gets her.
[ Whistling ]
I got no brand on her.
But it's the principle of the thing, Ben.
Just 'cause he's partners with us
don't give him the privilege of staying alive.
lay off.
[ Man Speaking Spanish ]
[ Spanish Continues ]
En el nombre de padre, del hijo,
de Espiritu Santo. Amen.
All right! Point 'em north!
[ Whooping, Shouting ]
Hah!
[ Whistles ]
Roll the wagons under those trees.
Where you been?
Hide and seek, hermano.
But middling sober.
You got me working with short rations.
Bet I dig out your whiskey
before we get halfway through Kansas.
- That's what worries me.
- [ Nella Humming ]
[ Sighs ]
Well, there's nothing around here
but, uh, coyotes.
If you're not too sleepy,
we could talk a bit.
[ Nella ]
No, I oughta be fine.
This countryside's
getting prettier all the time.
Yeah. Especially ever since
we left that Prairie Dog Creek.
Man, that was the ugliest country
I ever did see.
Nothin'but millions ofbullfrogs
croakin'all night...
and mangy cattle
everywhere you looked.
It'll be different, more beautiful
as we continue north.
Montana really must be something, huh?
It is.
It's the last word.
Tell me about it, Nathan,
how it's all gonna be when we get there.
[ Stark ]
I already did.
[ Nella ] I know, but I just love
to hear it over and over.
Oh, and, Nathan, would you
help me off with my boot, please?
[ Stark ]
It's a pleasure.
Thank you.
[ Exhales ]
Well, I guess I'll be turning in.
- Good night.
- Pleasant dreams.
Think I'll check the herd.
- They been acting kinda restless.
- Yeah.
You and the herd, hermano.
That cowpoke, he ain't human
He says that he prefers
To go to bed with his six-gun on
And never take off his spurs
That cowpoke's had no learnin'
There's bone between his ears
And he ain't much of a Romeo
'Cause he sleeps with a herd of steers
I want a tall man
Don't want a small man
Long as he is all man
That's good enough for me
I want a tall man
Don't want a small man
Long as he is all man
That's good enough for me
We got visitors, Colonel.
Wagon all shot-up.
Whoa.
Howdy. We're hoping you got
a bit of grub to spare.
Yeah, sure thing.
Clint, have luis fix 'em up with
a sack of flour and a couple slabs of bacon.
You been hit by theJayhawkers?
Jayhawking buzzards.
Running in bloody packs
all up and down the Kansas line.
We didn't have a prayer.
Killed four of us.
Even Sarah, my missus.
Best swing your herd
and turn back, mister.
How manyJayhawkers were there?
Pack of 50 or 60.
Offered to let us through for a tax
of a dollar a head.
We had 500 cows, but no money.
Now we got nothing.
Your grub's ready at the chuck wagon.
If there's anything else you need-
No, thanks. Real obliged to ya.
Vamonos, muchachos.!
We can just about make
that dollar-a-head tax.
- We're not paying any tax.
- Not to any Kansas blue-bellies.
I don't like paying
any better than you do...
but if it's a case of percentages-
eventual profits against loss-
I prefer paying.
You're outvoted, Mr. Stark. Two-thirds
of this partnership says we're going through.
- And we're not paying any tax.
- There's another consideration.
If we run into gunplay, there's Nella.
Hey! leave me out of this!
If there's any trouble,
I'll handle my share.
Nevertheless,
we have to consider her safety.
''We''? Ain't it kinda late to start
splitting up your responsibility?
[ Shouting ]
Get your wagons moving, hermano.!
luis, get your wagons around.
- Then do just like I told ya.
- Si, Senor Ben.
Stark, you'd better get
your responsibility under cover.
Put her in the bathtub.
Tell her to lay low.
TheseJayhawkers
might get a little ornery.
Hyah!
looks like we might have trouble
with thoseJayhawkers.
Allison refuses to pay off.
You'd better keep under cover.
[ Whistles ]
Hyah! Hyah!
Ay.!
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
We still have time to be practical, Ben.
The odds are way out of line.
Then we'll change the odds.
I thought our idea was to get to Montana.
Pay off, if we have to, but get there.
People build monuments to men
who make good.
Fools wind up in unmarked graves.
Don't worry, Mr. Stark.
I'll protect ya.
Tie it off, Clint.
Howdy, neighbors.
There's a small matter of some ferry charges
before you cross the state line.
You Kansas fellas
are great for jokes, I guess.
Now,just wipe that smile off, neighbor.
Wipe!
Us Kansas fellas aim to collect
damages from you rebs...
for what you did in these parts in the war.
How much?
You must be driving close to 5,000 head.
The going price is one dollar.
Calves half-price.
But I like round numbers.
How round?
Five thousand dollars.
Gold or greenback. I ain't particular.
Well, guess there ain't nothing to do
'cept pay you off.
[ Shouting, Hooting ]
Alto, muchachos.!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
It was magnifico.! But too short!
No more we call you a colonel.
Now you are a general!
- Any of our boys hurt?
- Nope. Only the blue bellies.
And we got a mess of'em!
Came out of that pretty lucky, Allison.
But I still say it was a bad gamble.
Got any more mottos,
hang 'em on your saddle.
luis, get a burial detail going.
We're moving on.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Spanish Continues ]
[ Chuckling ]
You shot theJasper right 'tween
the horns. It's yours.
''Death before dishonor.
Alvah Jenkins.''
I'll shoot you for it.
- luis, get a target.
- Si, senor.
- Were any of our boys hurt?
- No. We were lucky.
[ Grunts ]
[ Clanking ]
- [ Gunshots Continue ]
- [ Clanking Continues ]
[ Can Lands On Ground ]
No good, Senor Ben.
Is no good. Imitation!
So was theJasper who owned it.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Cattle lowing ]
We'll take 'em up the river and cross 'em
in one lick. We'll raft the wagons.
Stark. You'd better get
your responsibility on a horse.
This isn't gonna be
like bathing in that tub.
Never mind about me, mulehead.
If you can make it,
so can I, tub and all!
We'll split the herd to cross over.
I'll go up and hold this bunch
until you put some across.
- All right, luis, move 'em out.
- [ Speaking Spanish ]
- Pedro, let the horses across after we get over.
- Si, senor.
Clint!
When you're ready,
find a good spot and take 'em over!
- [ Shouts, Whistles ]
- [ lowing Continues ]
All right!
[ Whistles ]
There's a shorter crossing down below.
Why don't you go that way?
- Why don't you?
- All right, I will.
[ Vaqueros Shouting, Whistling ]
All right, amigos! let's get goin'!
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Whistling Continues ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
Keep 'em movin'! Keep 'em movin'!
Keep pouring 'em across!
Easy with 'em! Easy with 'em!
[ Ben ] Get those that are
bogged down on their feet.!
Pedro! Send over the horses!
[ Whinnying ]
Keep 'em headed straight across!
[ Shouting In Spanish ]
[ laughing ]
Stark.
Your responsibility's in trouble.
- Your boots, Senor Ben.
- Ah, gracias.
You all right, Nella?
You miserable groundhog.
Why didn't you give me a hand?
You saw me stuck in the mud.
Mud? I thought that was quicksand.
Ah, you dirty son of a coyote.
[ laughs ]
[ Nella ]
There's one place down in Texas
One place I've never been
They call that mud hole
Prairie Dog Creek
I'll bet it's hot as sin
The cattle all go loco
The bullfrogs die of thirst
Before I'd go to Prairie Dog Creek
I'd roast in gravy first
Tall men are no good
Small men are no good
All men are no good
But he's the worst
Of all
Well, there's nothin'
like a good launderin'job...
to make ol' Moneybags
feel like a man.
[ laughing ]
Unless your brother grows up, Ben,
there's gonna be trouble...
because I've had a bellyful.
- I'm sorry about it, Stark. I'll straighten him out.
- I hope so.
Otherwise I'll have to.
look, mister, you're talking about my brother.
He's a pretty tough hombre.
That's your problem.
Well, remember what you said this afternoon
about fools winding up in unmarked graves.
The big difference is, I'm no fool.
No, maybe so,
but you tangle with Clint...
and you won't live long enough
to have one of those monuments built.
Hmph.
luis, could I have a couple of buckets
to wash the soap off with?
Coming right away, senorita.
Howdy.
[ Frog Croaking ]
little to left. More. More.
The other one.
[ Grunts ]
Aah!
There. That'll give you a chance
to dry off behind the ears,junior.
[ Chuckling ]
Nothing like a cold bath
to make a boy feel like a man.
- [ Cattle lowing ]
- [ Vaqueros Shouting, Whistling ]
[ Whinnying ]
Morning, gentlemen.
- I'm Colonel Norris,
commandant here at Fort Bozeman.
- Morning
What's the chances of resting our herd
up here for a couple of days?
You'll be here much longer than that.
Several months, as a matter of fact.
The Bozeman Trail is closed.
looks open enough to me.
You go out there,
you'll find out how closed it is.
Chief Red Cloud
and half the Sioux nation are waiting...
daring us to ride out there
and commit suicide.
You can start building your cabins
and corrals along the river.
- Winter sets in pretty early in these parts.
- Thanks.
But we didn't come this far to get closed out.
We'll just rest up for two days.
Perhaps I didn't make myself clear.
The Bozeman Trail is closed.
No law against opening it, is there?
We'll bed down over there
under the trees!
luis, where's my little ditty bag?
- The little bag.
- In that wagon, senorita.
Ah. Gracias.
Hey, luis! Where are my boots?
- You have them on, Senor Ben!
- Oh! Oh, yeah. Thank you.
You weren't serious about
tackling Red Cloud, were you?
I'm serious about going through.
You're being somewhat less conservative
than the United States Army.
If Red Cloud's building up
to a full-sized war...
this fort's not gonna be any healthier
than out there in the open.
That's theory, Ben, not fact.
As things stand now,
our choice is limited, but safe.
We can stay here, or turn back
to Abilene and sell the cattle.
Mmm. For what we paid for 'em.
No. We didn't bargain to winter here.
We agreed to take the herd through to
Mineral City, and that's where we're going.
Dead or alive, huh?
Why argue, Nathan?
Mr. Allison's a man who never
changes his mind about anything.
Sometimes I do about people.
Put that out a little further,
I'll cut it off.
Nah, I'm not dictating to you, Stark.
You're free to cut out your share
of the herd and stay here...
or head back to Abilene.
- Without a single wrangler?
They wouldn't leave you.
- You can talk to 'em.
Anybody who wants to is free to go.
That includes you
and your responsibility.
Hey, luis!
What are we having for supper?
Well, I got huevos rancheros,
enchiladas, tamales...
carne asada, tortillas,
frijoles refritos and frijole aguados...
garlic...
and plenty chili pepper!
On your way,junior.!
This place is occupied.!
[ Chuckling ]
- [ Frog Croaking ]
- Sidney, what do you figure this is all about?
- [ Croaking Continues ]
- Huh? You think so?
Beat it, you crowing rooster!
I'm coming out of here!
It sounds like one of them
female frogs, don't it, Sidney?
[ Croaking Continues ] Yeah, well,
why don't you go in and take a look-see.
I'll hang you to the nearest tree,
you chuckle-headed ape!
[ Chuckling ] Come on out, Sidney.
It's time to do the laundering.
You're rotten, Clint.!
I'll cut your heart out
and feed it to the buzzards!
[ laughing ]
I'll chase you all the way back
to your Prairie Dog Creek!
Never mind, Nella.
Time junior learned his lesson.
You gonna play teacher?
As they say in your part
of the country, I aim to.
[ Gunshot ]
Don't make me kill you,junior.
Stark! If you're spoiling to use that gun
some more, you got your wish.
It was all fair and square, Ben.
He beat me to the draw.
Clint, get back to camp.
He called the turn,
so I had to nick him.
But you didn't go all the way.
Only because I need you
to take us through to Montana.
By the time you two stop bowing
to each other, I'll be drowned.
- I'll get you some clothes.
- Nah, never mind.
If that isn't big enough,
I'll cut you that one.
[ Singing In Spanish ]
- [ Continues ]
- [ Nella Laughing ]
When I was waltzing with that young lieutenant,
he was stepping all over my feet...
and blushing like a June bride.
He said he was engaged to some
little girl from Philadelphia.
Nathan, where in tarnation
is Philadelphia?
Colonel North was a little put out
that you didn't pay your respects.
I'll catch up with him before we leave.
Nathan, it was a lovely evening...
and you're a wonderful dancer.
I found this in the bushes.
- Where is he now?
- Drunk. But I don't know where.
How are you on praying, Jasper?
I'm gonna kill you, Stark.
Reach for it...
so I can start killing
Go on. Reach!
- I'll let you get real close.
- [ Hammer Cocks ]
Get clear, Ben.
You ain't gonna stop me.
- Sober up, hermano.
- Ain't nobody gonna stop me.
You got no use for that gun tonight.
Don't make me do it, Ben.
Don't make me shoot.
If there has to be a shooting,
we'd better keep it in the family.
Hermano.! Clint!
Clint!
luis! Get me a horse!
You ready, Nella?
Nathan, I don't feel much like going.
But I told the commandant
we'd be there.
His wife arranged this tea party
in your honor.
I know, but I never was one
for teas and gossip.
I don't understand you, Nella.
If Clint Allison is big enough to draw a gun,
he's big enough to take care of himself.
His disappearance isn't our problem.
It's his brother's.
Anyway, he'll turn up,
like a bad penny.
Maybe. But meanwhile we've
been stuck here for three days.
You didn't find him?
No. Not a sign.
Don't you worry. Tomorrow we get
all the vaqueros and find him!
Nope. We're moving out.
Si, senor.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Spanish Continues ]
Yoo-hoo.! Yoo-hoo.!
If I'd have been a Sioux,
you'd have been a dead Comanche.
That's what you think. I been trailing you
since early this morning.
I'm real glad to see you, hermano.
You all right?
like when Grandma used to whup me-
more shamed than hurt.
[ laughs ]
Well, people been drunk before.
Me, Pa. Even Grandma
was pretty good with the jug.
Yeah, but not loco drunk.
Well, get on back to the herd
and take up your job.
- [ Cattle lowing ]
- [ Vaqueros Shouting, Whistling ]
I don't feel much
like seeing anybody right now.
So how's about riding with you?
Yeah, sure.
luis's been off his pepper and beans lately.
Could be he's worried about you.
- Only you wasn't.
- Well, a touch.
- Ben.
- Yeah?
How often you get sick
of trying to bring me up?
- Oh, quit jabbering. You ain't the worst.
-Just the dumbest.
I know what store you set in gettin'
the herd through, getting your ranch.
And about Nella and Stark,
I reckon we just see it different.
So I ain't messing in no more.
That'll sit real good with me.
There are some things a man can't change.
The trouble is, I get fired up
and make a dumb try.
Keeping out of the way
is the only medicine.
let me take over riding point.
You can't keep dodging people, boy.
- Everybody'll be glad
to see you back- even Nella.
- Naw, it wouldn't work.
At least riding point
will keep Stark out of my gun sights.
I ain't quick enough for him,
but I'm loco enough to try.
All right, Clinton.
But when you get out there-
I know, I know.
Walk your horse slow and easy.
- Don't move out less'n it's clear as Texas water.
- Well,just remember that.
You'll be getting close enough
to those Siouxs to smell the war paint.
Here. You'll need that.
Gracias, hermano.
This is gonna be like old times again.
'Cepting I'll be doing the leading.
Don't worry. I'll leave trail signs
plain enough so's even you can read 'em.
[ laughs ]
Oh. Almost forgot.
Wanna show you how reformed I am.
The rest of my whiskey-
the stuff you couldn't find-
is in Nella's wagon under that bathtub.
Yeah, I know.
I found it two days ago.
Hasta la vista, hermano.
Adios.
Clint's edging us north again.
Says the Sioux are coming in
from the east and the west...
making some kind of a rendezvous.
Road back to the fort's still open,
if there are any takers.
If the herd's going through, I am.
I believe in staying close
to my investments.
[ Ben ]
That's Clint's horse.!
luis, hold the herd here.
Double your picket line.
Get more men around
these here wagons.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
- luis.
-Si, senorita. That's Senor Clint's horse.
Mire, senor.
Cut the rope, boys.
[ Luis Praying In Spanish ]
In el nombre de padre, del hijo,
del Espiritu Santo. Amen.
Senor Ben, the friends of your brother
are full of sorrow.
Thanks, Carlos.
Gracias, muchachos. Gracias.
Carlos, get my horse.
I'll be riding point.
May be gone for a couple days.
Watch for my signs.
- But, Senor Ben, if you do not-
- Then you take 'em through.
Have you seen anything of him, luis?
Don't worry, senorita.
I'm not worried.
[ Praying In Spanish ]
Is that a prayer, luis?
A little one, for Senor Ben.
You like him, don't you?
like him? I love him, senorita.
Why?
That's a question
not very easy to answer.
Why a man love his home?
Why do I love my Mexico?
Because love is something in here...
and here.
That's the way it's supposed to be
with friends, senorita.
Today, tomorrow, you say to me...
''luis, you must die for Senor Ben.''
Then I will ask you, ''What time?''
I owe Senor Ben my life...
two or three times from long ago.
It is not right to love a man
for saving your life?
Si.
[ Vaqueros Speaking Spanish ]
[ Spanish Continues ]
[ Spanish ]
Red Cloud's got us boxed-
point, drag and both sides.
Cut off from the river ahead.
That would be
the Yellowstone and Montana.
Yeah, the canyon's just this side.
Narrow, and a mile long-
perfect for ambush.
Do you think the Sioux
are waiting there?
They could have jumped us any time
they wanted in the last five days.
They waited for this spot.
It's a perfect trap.
They know that if we get through
that canyon, we're safe.
It's their last chance, and ours too.
Any ideas?
Don't you think it's a bit late
for advice and suggestions?
We're sitting in the middle of a hangman's
noose awaiting the inevitable.
I'm not sitting or waiting.
I'm driving my split of the cows right up the mouth
of the canyon and then we're going through.
Whoever wants to come along
is welcome.
Anyone wants to
look after his own hair can do it.
Senor Ben speaks
for luis Estrella and his vaqueros.
Nathan, a man can't get to own Montana
by just sitting here with a lot of cows.
Sure.
Probably hasn't been a rainbow in years
this side of the Yellowstone.
As long as you're gonna feed
the Sioux some beefsteak, count my cows in.
luis...
I don't want the cattle to get
any water this side of the canyon.
Keep 'em cob dry,
drinking nothing but dust all the way.
Yes, yes! No water, and they run wild!
I give the orders!
luis.
- Have Nella ride on the chuck wagon. Watch her.
-Si, senor.
More Sioux out there
than there are fleas on a dog.
That big cat won't move
until us mice try and go through.
luis, have the men break out
their blankets and old shirts.
Everything they can wave at the herd.
Tell 'em to check their guns
and ammunition.
Stark, you can help. Move those last
two wagons to the other side of the herd.
I wanted a chance to tell you
I'm sorry you're caught up in this.
Oh, it ain't your fault.
You didn't exactly give me an invite
to come along this trip.
Well, either way,
it's too late for wishing.
It always is. For dreaming too.
Yeah. Especially that.
You remember the thing
we once argued about?
You dreaming of ownin'
some acres of dirt...
in Prairie Dog Creek...
and me dreaming of owning the world.
A little dream and a big dream...
both gonna be smashed
into the same nothing up that canyon.
Maybe not, Nella.
I got a hunch you
and your dream will make it.
And owning half of Montana
one of these days won't be bad at all.
I guess not.
Be sure you got plenty of cartridges,
and stay down low in the wagon.
Sure. Me and the bathtub.
Yeah.
Good luck.
- Everything's ready, senor.
- Good.
Watch for my signal. Then pile 'em
into the canyon so fast they can't stop.
Si, senor. Vamonos.!
Allison change your mind
about anything?
- What makes you think he'd bother to try?
- You.
Pure gold in the rough
that still needs a bit more refining.
- That doesn't mean a thing to him.
- Well, it does to me.
You're gonna look very beautiful walking up
the stairs to the governor's mansion, Nella.
Up the back stairs or the front, Nathan?
I'd say that was up to you.
Right now I'd say it was up
to a fella named Red Cloud.
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Vaqueros Shouting, Whistling ]
- [ Gunshots ]
- [ Whooping, Shouting ]
- [ Whistling Continues ]
- Hyah!
[ Gunshots ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
Take cover, and start using that rifle.
[ Sioux Continue Shouting, Whooping ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Vaqueros Continue Shouting, Whistling ]
luis, how many head did we lose?
Oh, about 1 00, 1 50.
- Oh. Well, those belong to Stark.
- [ All laughing ]
- You can water 'em again.
-Si, senor.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Vamonos, muchachos.!
- Ready, Nella?
- Yep.
I'll hold the herd outside Mineral City
until you arrange for pasture.
I'll do better than that.
By the time you arrive
in town tomorrow...
I'll have the cattle sold and paid for
and I'll be fixed to pay you off.
- Will we be seeing you in town, Ben?
- If you look real quick.
Nella, let's start looking
for that rainbow, huh?
Oh.
[ Hoofbeats ]
- Is Nathan Stark here?
- In the office.
I expected you this afternoon.
I came as soon as I got through turning the
herd over to your buyers and their wranglers.
It's all right. Only I didn't want
to be late getting to the hotel.
Nella and I are celebrating.
Total comes to $1 7 0,000.
Eighty-five each.
That's what I agreed to do, isn't it?
That's what we agreed to do.
Just a play on words.
The point is, I always keep my word
to the exact penny.
But there's another point
more important to me than money...
and I've been looking forward to it
for many months.
No man ever stuck a gun in my belly...
and lived to make a profit out of it.
I think you missed meeting these gentlemen
on your last visit to Mineral City.
I want you to meet
the vigilante committee.
Gentlemen, this is that very competent
highwayman, Benjamin Allison.
Take his gun.
Si, senor?
I, uh,just wanted our friend Stark
to get a look at the view.
[ Shouts In Spanish ]
Now, if you're still interested
in a hanging, Stark...
I'd like to hear more of the details.
No, I've lost interest.
Put up your gun.
You know how I feel about gambling
when the odds are wrong.
- And they couldn't be more wrong.
- That's obvious.
As much as the fact that I made
the mistake of thinking you trusted me.
That mistake
is going to cost me $1 7 0,000.
I never trust any man who figures
percentages as close as you do.
I'll keep that in mind for the future,
if there's going to be a future.
Don't worry. You and Nella will get
your chance at owning Montana.
That's a very pleasant surprise.
lots of surprises, Stark.
Give me 1 6,000.
That's the bonus I promised my men.
Ten thousand for me.
That's what I figure I earned.
And a hundred-dollar bill
for party drinking.
The rest is yours.
Big dreamers need big money.
Nella can tell you about me.
I dream small.
- You handle champagne water?
- Y-Y-Y-Yes, sir.
Then use this hundred to buy a bottle
for Nathan Stark's wedding.
And tell the lady
that Ben Allison said good-bye.
Yes, sir. Good-bye. I will.
Thank you, sir.
luis.
- Tell the hombres to have one on the house.
- Si, senor.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Now I'll never find out.
What's that, Mr. Stark?
Whether I would have been able
to let you go through with hanging him.
There goes the only man I ever respected.
He's what every boy thinks
he's going to be when he grows up...
and wishes he had been
when he's an old man.
[ Vaqueros Singing In Spanish ]
Now for a good celebration
and a big drunk!
No. Skip me, luis. Here, split this bonus money
among the boys, share for share.
- Senor Ben, this is a night for drinking.
- Some other time.
[ Continues ]
What's the matter with the general?
He always have drink with the boys.
His heart is sad for the woman he loves.
I think, after I have two or three drinks,
I'll go back to town...
and make her a widow, but quick.
It won't be manana.
[ Ends ]
[ Guitar ]
[ Nella ]
I wish I was a peach tree
A-growin'in the ground
And every time my sweetie passed by
I'd shake some peaches down
And ifhe wants more peaches
Here's all he has to know
Just plant my tree
In Prairie Dog Creek
And watch them peaches
Grow
Howdy.
I love
My tall man
He ain't
A small man
My man
Is all man
And the only one
For me
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Salud.!
[ Vaqueros ]
Salud!
Ben, it was a long walk out here
and my feet are killing me.
Will you take my boots off?