[CROWD CHEERING]
[MARCH PLAYING]
[TOWER BELLS RINGING]
The passenger list, sir.
Oh, very good.
[DISTANT MARCH PLAYING]
[SEAGULLS CAWING]
Who are the Edmunds boys,
private Brooke?
Three brothers, sir,
All posted to south Africa
on the same day...
My birthday in fact, sir.
Is that so, Brooke?
I don't believe it.
Is that...?
What on earth is he doing down here?
Get down to the waterfront, Brooke.
Get customs to pull
this chap to one side...
Van Diemen, south African Boer.
- Escort him here, please.
- Yes, sir.
Tell him...
tell him
Major Carlysle would
very much like to see him.
Yes, sir.
This one's short.
Get me another.
Man:
Yes, sir.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
Brooke,
Where are you off to in such a hurry?
I've been asked to escort
one of them Boers.
The major wants to see him.
Let me have a look at that.
We should have hung
them all, shouldn't we,
Instead of giving them
a king's pardon?
What's his name?
Bloody hell.
With me, Brooke.
[CHILDREN CHATTERING, LAUGHING]
Woman:
Come on, girls.
Next, please.
Oi.
Uh, Mr. Van Dimon.
Diemen...
Van Diemen.
So, Mr. Van Dimon,
what brings you
All the way to our remote
little corner of the world?
Well, I'm curious.
Curious?
You'd have to be very curious
to travel thousands of Miles.
Bloody right, I'm curious.
I'm very curious to find out
Why you boys crossed two oceans
To help the British burn down my farm.
Well...
Arjan Van Diemen.
[CROWD MURMURING]
And I thought the war was finished.
Not for you, you murdering bastard.
You're under arrest.
Give it over.
Go on.
Give him his rifle back.
Now, you bloody fool!
Put your weapon away.
Do you know who this is?
That'll be all.
Thank you, Saunders.
Jesus.
Don't make me write you up.
Get back to the docks, Brooke.
Give some real soldiers
a hero's welcome.
Yes, sir.
[DISTANT BOAT HORN BLARING]
Apologies for the undignified welcome, Mr.
Van Diemen.
Saunders there was
with me in south Africa.
He seems to have forgotten
the war's over.
I'm sure you understand.
Mm.
So you do exist.
I led a detachment of cavalry
For nearly two years
trying to catch up with you.
We chased you clean
across the Transvaal
Whilst you caused havoc.
And you, major...
You couldn't even catch
a simple farmer.
What's your plan here, Van Diemen?
You're a long way from home.
You too.
On the contrary,
this is home for me now.
Home?
Huh.
Home these days seems to be most
of the globe to you British.
So are you planning
on buying some land here,
Perhaps take up farming again?
No, I guess we didn't
leave you with much, did we?
Well, for what it's worth,
Mr. Van Diemen,
I hope you do find your new home here.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
[HORSE SNORTING]
Come here.
What is this?
It's a piece of home.
- Home?
- Mm-hmm.
What do you mean, home?
It belonged to my grandfather.
Sometimes he would cry over this.
Looks like sand to me...
Red sand.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
You're very pretty.
There's a lot prettier in this town.
Some of them officers' wives, they...
No no no no, I've seen
lots of women...
Wahine on Tahiti.
You could be a Princess there.
Take your hands off me.
I'm quite capable
Of walking by myself.
Come on, sergeant.
You've had a bit too much.
Goes with the rank, corporal Drake,
- With the rank.
- Yes, your highness.
"goes with the rank."
Oh, watch yourself there, Teddy.
Don't you "Teddy" me.
Oh, hey. Oi.
There's a lantern on
In the stables.
[DOOR RATTLING]
I'll have his guts for garters.
Well well well,
What have we here?
If it isn't young Lucy
And a bloody savage.
What are you two doing in here,
Besides the obvious?
I don't think I know you.
Do you know him?
Never seen him.
Wonder where he gets his money from.
Weren't interested
in our horses, were you?
He's talking to you.
You think he understands English?
[CHUCKLES]
Anyway,
You're trespassing on army property.
I think a thrashing might be in order,
Gentlemen, eh?
Now come and take your punishment
Like a good little savage.
- Hold him up.
- Get up.
Eh?
I'll teach you to mess with our women.
[GRUNTS]
Get up.
[HORSES WHINNY]
[SPEAKS MAORI]
- What did you say?
- Leave him alone, you bastards.
You should have taken
your thrashing, boy.
Savage!
Christ, you bloody...
[SAUNDERS SHOUTS]
[LUCY SCREAMS]
Jesus Christ.
Jesus.
You bloody killed him.
We need a doctor.
Get a bloody doctor!
[PANTING, MOANS]
[MEN CHATTERING]
[SIGHS]
[SAUNDERS MOANS]
Sir...
[LUCY CRYING]
You walked into the stables
And he simply attacked you?
Yes, sir.
Unprovoked?
Well, we did ask him
what he was doing in there.
We thought he was after the horses.
- That was all?
- Yes, sir.
Levin.
That was about the way of it.
And this was the way of it?
[CRYING]
Yes, sir.
That were the way of it.
He was off that whaler
that came in yesterday.
Sergeant Leybourne.
I don't think our man
will be getting far, sir.
Let's make sure he doesn't.
He's been seen heading
off up the coast.
I'll need half a dozen men.
That should be enough.
And horses.
He's on foot, so we'll
soon catch up with him.
What about dogs?
No, no dogs.
This isn't a blood sport.
I won't have it turned into one.
Now that local scout...
Mr. Bryce, sir.
Yes, Bryce.
I want him here,
Fully provisioned within the hour.
We'll leave at first light. See to it.
Van Diemen.
I don't suppose you saw anything?
You know, we could use
another good tracker.
The reward is 100 sovereigns...
100 sovereigns alive, 25 if dead.
That's a lot of money.
You see that man?
He butchered British officers.
I don't want that scum
anywhere near me.
That needn't trouble you,
sergeant major.
You shan't be accompanying us.
You and Corporal Levin are in no
fit state to be chasing anybody.
The pair of you
will return to barracks.
I trust I make myself clear.
Yes, sir.
- Well?
- Yes, sir.
Look, when I arrived
yesterday at the harbor,
I didn't see any whaler.
They left without him
on the afternoon tide.
The skipper was angry as hell,
Charging around, shouting at
everybody if they'd seen him.
I tell you, I was near
to locking him up.
Why so angry?
Well, he'd lost his
harpoonist, didn't he?
A good harpoon man's
worth gold these days.
These all his belongings?
Yeah, these and his
kit bag over there.
- That too?
- Yeah.
[SEAGULLS CAWING]
[HORSES WHINNY]
[GROANING]
[HORSES WHINNYING]
[PANTING, COUGHS]
Carlysle:
All right, dismount.
Sergeant Leybourne,
these horses need a rest,
- Just a few minutes.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Bryce, what is it?
Maori.
See?  The weight's
all on the toes.
No heel print.
The weight's right.
By the spacing...
his height.
It's him.
If he keeps heading up this coast,
He'll reach Dunney's Point,
Find a boat... whew,
Away at sea 'fore you know it.
Very well.
Private barker!
Sir.
Get up on those rocks, man, see if
we can't get around the headland
Before the tide comes in. Yes, sir.
Mr. Van Diemen,
is there a problem?
It's not him.
No disrespect
to Mr. Bryce here,
But our man was used to wearing shoes.
This man,
Whoever he was...
he never wore shoes.
[SPITS]
With respect, major,
I don't think our man
is just another sailor.
I think he's coming home.
[MAN PANTING]
Sir, if we go right away,
We should be able to get around
before the tide cuts us off.
Thank you, barker.
All right, mount up!
Van Diemen!
Blast the man.
Barker, get his horse.
Yes, sir.
[GROANS]
Mr. Bryce.
Your man left
empty-handed, didn't he?
That's right.
Your Mr. Van Diemen
was right.
Raupo bread.
Maori pollen bread.
Where would he get that?
Look at the size of this fire.
[CHUCKLES]
Whoever this fellow was,
he was in no hurry.
Mr. Bryce, are you
seriously telling me
That we've been following
the wrong man all day?
Same build, same height,
Wrong Maori.
[LAUGHS]
I knew we should have
gotten bloody dogs.
We'll double back, pick up the trail
Where our Mr. Van Diemen
disappeared on us.
And you're quite certain
you can do that?
I'll have two trails to
follow instead of just one.
Well, we'd better get on
with it then, haven't we?
[FLIES BUZZING]
Mm, been fishing, eh?
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[WINCES]
[WATCH TICKING]
[RUSTLING]
Head, feet.
So you knew I was watching you, eh?
Good.
Mm.
[SNIFFS]
So you've made yourself some shoes?
Mm, clever boy.
Horses won't be much use to
us from here on, major.
Al right.
Thank you, Mr. Bryce.
- Private barker.
- Yes, sir?
You'll take these horses
back to base in the morning.
Yes, sir.
- Crowther.
- Yes, major?
- We'll keep yours as a packhorse.
- Sir.
[BIRDS CALLING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[INSECT BUZZING]
[EXHALES]
[RUSTLING]
[WINGS FLUTTERING]
Do not move
Unless I tell you to.
[SPEAKING MAORI]
I said do not move.
Stand still.
Stop.
Shut up.
[GUNSHOT]
Argh! Bloody hell.
That's better, eh?
How much are they paying you for me?
How much?
100 sovereigns alive, 25 dead.
25?
Mm.
A lot of people
would be happy with 25.
Lucky I got you.
If I have to kill you, I will.
Mind you, anybody
who'd be happy with 25
Would probably be
too stupid to find me.
Yeah, they would.
That's 75 sovereigns'
difference alive or dead.
I'll tell you what:
What will you give me if I promise
- Not to choke myself to death?
- Just walk.
What are you reading?
Hey, I asked you a question.
That "the wicked will perish.
The enemies of the Lord
Shall be as the fat
of lambs."
Mm.
"but the righteous
showeth mercy, and giveth."
The 37th psalm.
I spent a lot of time
in a missionary school.
That's where I learned to read.
You're an educated man.
Does that make a difference?
Perhaps.
Why?
Because education distinguishes
The civilized man from the savage.
Ah, there are no savages here then.
The missionaries taught
us all to read...
All of us.
My father could quote your
bible from cover to cover.
"you cannot know your enemy," he said,
"until you know
his God."
And did he find their God?
Oh yes, he met him
At the end of a rope.
So what's my life worth now?
125 sovereigns?
I am not a killer.
You'll have an honest trial.
I'll get an honest hanging.
What is that?
Let me see.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
You can trust me.
Wife? Daughters?
Pretty.
Van Diemen:
Yeah.
How old are they... your daughters?
Eight, and the twins are six.
And where do they live?
Back in town?
They don't live.
They're buried
in south Africa somewhere.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
They say when children die, they...
They stay children forever.
You can't start a story
and not finish.
It's not good.
[SPEAKING MAORI]
It's not good for your soul.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Stop here.
Two hours.
All right, let's keep moving.
Kereama:
It's just mouku.
You can eat it.
You didn't know that, did you?
Mind you, you weren't brought up here.
You see this?
Meke-meke.
Just a little nibble on that
and you'll be
Spewing your guts out for days.
I shouldn't have
told you that, should I?
"and his blessing covered
the dry land as a River
And watered it
as a flood."
I could build us a raft.
"as he hath turned
the waters into saltiness,
So shall the heathen
inherit his wrath."
[BIRDS CALLING]
Stop.
Sit. Sit.
[GROANS]
[SNORES]
[GUN CLICKS]
Don't move.
I'm not moving.
Turn around slowly.
Drop the pistol.
Drop the pistol!
No.
What?
Drop it.
No.
I'll shoot you.
You know, when I travel
I always keep an empty chamber
In case of accidents.
Before you cock it,
I'll have a bullet between your eyes.
You're lying.
Truth is I'm not really sure.
I've been careless
these past two days.
Of course,
We won't know until
you pull that trigger.
I don't believe you.
Fine.
And I will pull the trigger.
Well, if you're right, I'm dead.
If I'm right, you're dead.
But until you pull that
trigger, we won't know.
Drop the gun.
No.
- Drop the gun.
- You drop your gun.
- I'm not dropping my gun.
Fine.
Let's just walk to shore.
And keep your hands
where I can see them.
No. No.
I will pull the trigger.
I'll take my chances.
My legs are getting cold.
You should have stayed
over there where it's dry.
You are the most annoying man
I have ever met.
I should kill you
for just being annoying.
I thought you weren't a killer.
I'm not, or I would have
shot you right away.
In which case you'd be dead.
Well, we don't know that yet, do we?
I'd like a smoke.
No.
[TWEETS]
[GUNSHOT]
[WHISPERS] Damn you.
Damn you.
Come on, come on.
[GRUNTING]
They meet here separately.
Hold there.
There's two now.
- Both of them? Two men, both of them?
- There's two.
- All right, which way?
- This way.
Sa-bine.
Sabine.
Is that your wife?
What language is this?
I told you
I'm from south Africa.
You're one of them Boers.
Sounds like a bushpig.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
"Boer"...
It means "farmer."
You're the strangest
farmer I've ever met.
You fought the British, didn't you?
My grandfather led our people
against the British.
He was a great leader, a warrior.
But he lost.
He lost like you.
And this brought great
shame on our people.
And we were labeled tangata hara...
Men of sin, rebels.
I never lost.
Well, why are you here
then, in my land?
Where is your farm, farmer man?
You fought the British and
you lost too, didn't you?
You lost.
And that's not all you lost, is it?
Where'd you learn to track a man?
Hey.
Dabe.
What do you mean, dabe?
Dabe... my father's
houseboy,
Old hottentot.
Hottentot.
[CHUCKLES]
What's a hottentot?
A south African bushman.
A bushman? I've never seen one.
You never will.
All gone, good as.
Like me.
As dumb as they are,
They will catch you
And probably shoot you.
If I were in your shoes,
Which I am,
I'd just worry about them finding me.
You can't run forever.
One of us will find you.
You best pray it isn't me.
But I'm not the one who's running.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
I think you're the one
who's running away.
And I think...
I think you left your soul behind.
Now untie these
Before I break your bloody neck.
[COUGHING, GASPING]
[PANTING]
Kereama: You know, when
you sail for a long time,
You've got to get on
with all the blokes.
If someone doesn't get on,
We just throw them overboard
at the next port.
With you, I don't think
We would have waited
till the next port.
Your wife...
how did she die?
Did she get sick?
Did she get sick of you?
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said that.
Thanks.
Walk.
- What is this?
- Biltong.
I'd rather die of starvation.
Right here.
Something here.
Blood.
Fighting or...
Which way?
Van Diemen:
Come.
Kereama:
Wouldn't it be easier
If we just wait for the River to calm down?
No, I'm not taking chances
with the rain,
Not in this bloody country.
It's not going to rain.
I'm a sailor.
I can tell you the weather
From the color of the water.
I lied, okay?
I lied.
Come.
You're taking me back to be hanged
For something I didn't even do.
Huh?
What would you do, huh?
What?
Oh, Mr. Silence now, huh?
Mr. Silence?
You say another word...
I'll hang you myself
From that bloody tree
over there. You follow?
Oh, you lie as well.
Huh?
Jezus christus allemachtig!
You lie just by saying nothing.
In fact,
Everything you don't say
is one big lie.
What in God's name
are you talking about?
Well, that's the second
question you've ever asked me.
You going to answer it?
Well, you just said you'll hang
me if I said another word.
Argh!
Come, you, come.
Walk.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Your wife...
She died in that war, didn't she?
It's none of your concern.
- She did, didn't she?
- It's none of your concern.
I was just asking.
Why do you...?
No.
I just...
She never died in no bloody war.
But I thought you said...
I don't know how she died, all right?
All right.
When the sporting British
couldn't beat us,
Lord Kitchener sent his troops down
To burn our farms.
He drove our women and children off
Like cattle.
He penned them
In these
barbed-wire camps.
I don't know how they died...
Sickness, starvation.
There's no one left to tell.
Listen, we both hate the British.
I don't hate the British.
Yes, you do.
I hated my God for a time.
I stood naked in front of him.
I reviled him.
I was so angry.
I thought
I knew him.
Then I remembered
That God did not create
the savage in me.
"though he slay me,
Yet will I trust
in him."
"but I will maintain
my own ways before him."
Mm.
I still think you hate the British.
You think you can get me
to set you free?
Well, I don't know.
You think
That if you could make you and me the same,
That would make me set you free?
I fought for something.
You're just a bloody criminal.
I'm not a criminal.
You're walking on my land.
My tupunas named the
mountains and the rivers.
It's my lineage.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
And I saved your life, bushpig.
It's about respect.
Let me tell you about respect.
During the war me and my men...
We would cut off the trigger fingers
Of the bravest British
officers we captured...
Only the bravest officers, mind,
The ones most worthy of respect.
You understand that?
That's what I did
to people I respected.
Doesn't leave much hope
for me then, does it?
Hope kills fools like you every day.
Sergeant, let's send Corporal Crowther
Back to base for fresh provisions.
This is taking a damn sight
longer than I'd hoped.
Yes, sir.
You'd better show Crowther where
you think we'll be this evening,
'cause I don't bloody know.
It'll just be a rough guess, major.
Yes, I'm sure it will,
Mr. Bryce.
Do you think he's got him, sir...
That Van Diemen?
Without a doubt.
Are the stories they
tell about him true...
You know, butchering our men?
Well, let me put it
this way, private...
If it weren't for the reward,
We'd probably be spared the
trouble of executing him.
I reckon that'd serve him right, sir.
Drake was a good man.
Drake was a trousered ape, private,
A disgrace to his uniform and his rank.
Begging your pardon, sir,
But he didn't deserve
to die the way he did.
No, you're quite right.
Indeed he didn't.
You haven't seen action
yet, have you, private?
No, sir, not as such.
Not yet.
I hope to, sir.
A word of caution:
Just be sure
That when your children
ask you what you did...
What you did in defense of the realm,
That you're able to give
them a worthy answer.
I beg your pardon, sir?
If he's still alive, he'll
be given a fair trial.
If he's guilty, he'll be hanged.
An example will be made.
Te ara ruamano.
The path of ruamano.
He's like our spiritual guardian.
And he's known to save those
of his people in danger.
What?
This... you pakeha
call it Elson's Gorge.
Let me look.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
Look, you can draw your gun
and shoot me.
Don't doubt it.
I will shoot you.
That bullet will cost you
75 sovereigns.
Nice.
North, south,
East.
Oops.
Damn you.
Come.
Come come come.
No no, I don't care much
for that idea.
- I will let you go.
- Let go.
I'll let you go.
Go ahead, let go.
I swear I'll shoot you.
Well, you can try.
But to get your gun,
You're gonna have to let go
of this rope with one hand.
I'll break your bloody neck
if you jump.
Or you could fall in with me.
And with that pack, the rifle
And your fat puku,
you could sink and drown.
I'll shoot you as you fall.
You might miss.
And I might drown.
Ruamano might save me.
But we won't know, will we,
Until you let go?
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
[COUGHS]
[GUNSHOT]
[SPEAKS MAORI]
You wish to fight me?
Come. Come.
Get up.
I'm innocent.
[SCREAMS]
[GROANS]
What's the matter with you, eh?
I'm just trying to uphold the law.
You're a liar.
It's got nothing to do with the law.
It's for money. You've sold your soul.
You know they're going to hang me
For something I didn't even do.
There were witnesses.
Yes, soldiers.
And a woman.
She's a pakeha woman and I'm a Maori.
It was soldiers who did it.
And it was soldiers
who hung my father.
They made me watch.
Then they forced my head around
And made me watch them
hang my grandfather.
If you kill me,
You will condemn yourself.
They will find you,
No matter how long, how many years...
What's a few years
worth, eh? Eh?
What's it worth to a condemned man?
Eh? Argh!
Do it. Do it.
Do it!
You can't kill me.
You can't do it.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
[SPEAKING MAORI]
[BOTH SHOUTING IN MAORI]
Are you all right?
I'm quite well,
Mr. Bryce.
Thank you.
[SPEAKING MAORI]
You bloody little Maori.
- Carlysle: That's enough.
- Van Diemen: No.
That's enough, Mr. Bryce,
Unless you plan to carry
him back to town.
Sergeant, tie him up.
Renwick, get the rope
And tie him up.
Well, Mr. Van Diemen,
you've obviously endured
- A tough couple of days.
- Yeah, major.
You needn't fret, sir.
100 sovereigns are yours.
Admirable, most admirable.
[KEREAMA GRUNTING]
Come on, get up.
Get up, you bloody savage.
Renwick, give us a hand.
Get up, your murdering bastard, you.
Major, with your permission, if you
tie his hands in front of him,
It'd help him walk easier and quicker.
All right. Sergeant, do as Mr.
Van Diemen suggested.
Sir.
Renwick.
I didn't expect to see you until
our return, sergeant major,
Well, sir, corporal Crowther said
Your orders were for me to bring
supplies with due haste, sir.
I'm sure the corporal
said no such thing.
Well, now you're here, you'd
better get about it, I supposed.
Just remember, sergeant major,
This is not a vendetta.
[MEN CONVERSING]
Carlysle:
Yes, thank you, Saunders.
All right, sergeant major.
Tough bastards, aren't they?
My family fought against them
In the land wars 30 years ago.
Good fighters,
Clever as the weasels.
You face them doing
one of those godless
War-jigs of theirs,
Their haka,
Screaming like a pack of wild dogs,
Mate, you know you're in trouble then.
Fierce.
And the women are worse.
Excuse me.
I should know.
I married one.
[LAUGHING]
Some meat.
Thank you.
Where's he going?
Feeding our meat to a murderer.
What, is he comforting him?
Feeding the savage.
- Thanks.
- Mm?
For this.
You must have been quite a soldier.
I was never a soldier.
[SIGHS]
More like...
We were a small rabble.
We stopped the British,
But only for a short while.
You were fighting for your land,
Fighting for your freedom.
That'll make a soldier out of a man.
Fighting for my freedom?
Well, you were, weren't you?
[CHUCKLES]
I'll tell you about the freedom
I was fighting for.
Late one morning
The day after new year's,
I was riding home to my farm.
I saw dabe for the last time.
He was hanging
from my neighbor's tree.
What, the British hung your dabe?
No.
Not the British.
My neighbor...
he hung him
For stealing a duck.
82 years old.
No old bushman was going
to steal from a white man.
My friend...
He hung him from a tree,
Left him there for six months
As an example.
Did you avenge him?
No.
I went to war
And fought for that bastard's right
To do it again.
That's the freedom I fought for.
Without freedom we're nothing.
When they hung my grandfather,
He called to me...
"it's you now, Kereama.
You must rid us all
of this hara."
The shame?
But I ran away.
That's different.
You were only a boy.
That's why they never hung me.
I wasn't big enough.
Soldiers just threw
the bodies into a hole.
I couldn't even bury them properly.
So I ran away.
But I always knew in my heart
That I had to come back
And set them free.
So that's why you've come home...
To restore your family honor
and your own?
I almost made it.
It's just beyond that Ridge.
But you denied me that.
You denied me that...
You and your dabe.
Carlysle: Saunders, I think
the prisoner will be fine
Without your attention.
Come on, mate.
Come on, get up.
You'll be all right. Come on.
These ropes were cut, see?
Mm-hmm.
He has a way with rope.
- He has a way with rope?
- Mm-hmm.
What, you knew?
You let him go.
It was tough enough catching him.
In God's name, man, do you
really think I'd let him go?
Well, I'll tell you
one thing for sure:
Somebody let him go,
And in a hurry.
He cut through his wristband as well.
We'll get him.
How is he, sergeant?
The savage beat him pretty
bad, sir, but he'll be okay.
Mr. Bryce.
How long?
Two, three hours perhaps.
But he's in bad condition.
He'll leave an easy trail.
He won't get far.
Van Diemen?
Mr. Bryce knows
his business.
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen,
But I have a score to settle.
[PANTING]
Right, we'll leave camp here.
Major Carlysle, sir.
This had better be
important, Saunders.
I just wanted to ask, sir,
Now that the prisoner
is armed, what your...
Armed?
How armed?
Did Sergeant Leybourne not bring
it to your attention, sir?
The prisoner made off
with Renwick's rifle.
[PANTING]
Carlysle: Unfortunately, it would appear
That the niceties of Justice
are fast becoming
A luxury we can no longer afford.
You have my permission
to shoot him on sight.
However, this is not to be a game.
There's no place here for sport.
I'll see court-martialed any man
Who doesn't kill him cleanly
with the first shot.
Do you understand?
Mr. Bryce.
[PANTING]
He could have gone one of two ways.
Take the wrong one...
- Mr. Bryce, please don't tell me...
- I'll find him.
Well, do so, and quickly.
[LAUGHS]
[PANTING]
[SPITS]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[PANTING]
[CHANTING IN MAORI]
This is a sacred place...
The home of ruamano.
I would come here with my grandfather
When I was a little boy.
I'd have to wait outside
While he entered into the cave
To talk to our spiritual guardians.
Now it is my time...
Time to redeem the mana
Of my fathers.
[WHISPERING IN MAORI]
[CHANTING]
[CHANTING ECHOING]
[CRYING]
[SPEAKING MAORI]
There's only one way out of here.
You know this camp.
Bryce has lost the track,
But only for a while.
That won't last.
We have to get you out of here.
Believe me, they will shoot you down.
I'm still curious to know
Why you cut the trigger fingers
Off the British soldiers.
God tells us it is a sin
to kill other men
Unless you are protecting your home
And your loved ones.
It stopped good men
from sinning again.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[SCREAMS]
Get up.
Come.
Bryce was better than...
than you thought.
There's plenty of cover.
If we split up,
We can get around them.
But they'll just keep on following us.
They haven't got us yet.
Look, I can't run. I can't climb.
There's no way around them.
- You have to.
- I can't run.
We may not have to.
It's your life.
No, it's your life too.
And I'm not a killer.
We can fight.
Ja?
[SNIFFS]
I need you to do one thing...
One great thing.
No.
You must.
I won't do it.
You must help me on my
Journey to Hawaiki.
What?
It's the final resting place
for our people.
Don't let them hang me.
I don't want to die like my fathers,
Hung from some post without mana,
Without dignity.
[SPEAKING MAORI]
[SHOUTING IN MAORI]
I'll take it from you.
[SPEAKS MAORI]
[CHANTING IN MAORI]
[GUNSHOT]
Saunders, Bryce, round to the right.
Sergeant, with me.
Damn.
Van Diemen.
Another trophy
for his majesty's Justice.
He had courage.
He needs respect.
Not your soundest economic
decision, Van Diemen.
I have a little saved.
Bugger that.
I'd rather have his head.
The price will be on your own.
Yeah.
[GRUNTS]
We have to take the body back.
At least have your men bury him, Carlysle.
We cannot leave him here.
I'm sorry,
Mr. Van Diemen.
Enough time has been spent on this.
- There you go.
- Thank you, Murray.
You think Bridget will like it here?
Without a doubt, sir.
I've ordered the linen
you requested, sir.
It'll be here in plenty of time
for your wife's arrival.
[MAN COUGHING]
He's alive.
Sergeant!
Sergeant Leybourne.
I want a man in every
port, every harbor
On the lookout for a Maori with
his right index finger missing.
Now, damn it. I want him arrested
and brought here alive.
Van Diemen.
Major.
I heard you were leaving us.
This country has no interest for me.
Australia?
There's a place they've named
Van Diemen's land there.
Mm, I like the sound of it.
Leaving without your reward?
Woman:
Thank you.
Man:
There we go.
25 sovereigns.
It could have been four times that.
Mm.
He's alive, isn't he?
It must have been
like old times for you.
He didn't even scream
when you cut his finger off.
I suppose you have your reasons.
I suppose I'll never quite
understand what they are.
It's quite the sum.
But why so generous?
You were there, weren't you?
Did you give the order?
Did you give the order
to burn down my farm?
No, I did not.
Oh.
Tell me one thing:
Was anybody in the house
When you watched it burn to ash?
No.
I can assure you of that.
Man: Sir. Sir, we're ready.
The captain's gonna be
wanting to weigh anchor.
Yeah.
Major.
Van Diemen.
[GRUNTING]
You know, I've sent
messengers to every port,
Every whaling station.
Seen one of these before?
At most you've bought him a few weeks,
Perhaps a few days.
I sincerely hope it was worth it.
Do you know what a few days of life
Means to a condemned man?
Right about there.
[INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
...The end...