[Gunshots]
I THOUGHT I TOLD YOU
TO STAY PUT.
I GOT TIRED WAITING.
SOMETHING CAME UP.
WHAT?
I'LL TELL YOU LATER.
I'LL WAIT HERE.
I WANT YOU TO GO BACK
TO THE HOTEL!
WHY?
BECAUSE A MAN'S GOING
TO GET HIMSELF KILLED HERE.
YOU WANT TO WATCH THAT?
TAKE THE LADY
BACK TO THE HOTEL.
[Gunshots]
MR. MALSON?
MR. BEAUDRY.
BOB.
THIS IS MR. TANNER
FROM MIMBRENO.
I'M BOB VALDEZ.
BOB'S TOWN CONSTABLE
IN LANORIA.
WORKS 2 OR 3
NIGHTS A WEEK,
MEXICAN PART
OF TOWN.
THE NIGHTS I'M IN TOWN.
I RIDE SHOTGUN...
I WORK WITH THE--
LET'S GET SOME SHADE.
BOB.
YES, SIR?
THERE'S AN ARMY DESERTER
HOLED UP DOWN THERE.
KILLED JAMES C. ERIN
UP AT FORT HUACHUCA.
MR. TANNER SPOTTED HIM
DRIVING THROUGH LANORIA.
UH, WHERE'S THE, UH,
THE SHERIFF?
UP IN ST. DAVID.
HE WON'T BE BACK
TILL TONIGHT.
[Gunshots]
MR. TANNER IS SURE
THAT IS THE MAN?
J.C. ERIN
WAS A GOOD FRIEND
OF MR. TANNER'S.
HE FEELS VERY STRONGLY
ABOUT THIS.
WE HAVE TO BE SURE,
MR. MALSON.
IT'S A SERIOUS THING.
THIS IS MR. TANNER'S
SHOW, BOB.
BETTER LET HIM
RUN IT.
APACHE.
THE MAN'S WIFE
OR HIS WOMAN, MAYBE.
SENOR  TANNER,
HE YELL FOR HER
TO COME OUT,
BUT SHE NEVER COME,
TILL NOW.
I THINK SHE'S SAYING
SHE DON'T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT YOU
OR YOUR RIFLE.
SHOOT HER?
COULD MAKE HER
JUMP SOME.
UH-HUH.
I COULD USE A LITTLE
SOMETHING TO DRINK.
[Whistles]
DIEGO!
[Gunshot]
WHERE'S HE GOING?
HEY, HE'S DUMBER THAN
HE LOOKS. HA HA HA.
IF HE FLUSHES THAT NIGGER,
YOU COULD REALLY SHOW US
SOME FANCY SHOOTING.
[Man]
THAT'S CLOSE ENOUGH.
I'LL KILL YOU
IF YOU RAISE IT.
I BELIEVE IT.
CAN WE TALK?
YOU'RE TALKING.
THE MAN UP THERE,
MR. TANNER,
HE SAYS YOU KILLED
SOMEBODY.
I NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
HE SAYS YOUR
NAME IS JOHNSON.
IT AIN'T.
HE SAYS YOU KILLED THIS MAN
AT FORT HUACHUCA.
I WAS IN THE 10th
A LONG TIME AGO.
YOU DESERTED?
I SERVED IT OUT.
MAYBE YOU GOT SOMETHING
TO PROVE IT?
IN THE WAGON,
THERE'S A LEATHER
BAG WITH MY PAPERS.
WOULD YOU COME WITH ME
AND TALK TO MR. TANNER?
I DON'T KNOW HIM.
THEN HE WON'T KNOW YOU.
HE DIDN'T KNOW ME
THIS MORNING
WHEN HE
CHASED ME HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL GET THE PAPER
THAT SAYS YOU WERE
DISCHARGED,
AND THEN WE'LL SHOW IT
TO MR. TANNER, HUH?
HE COMES DOWN HERE.
SURE, SURE.
PLEASE, CAN YOU POINT THE GUN
SOME OTHER WAY?
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
NO!
IT LOOKED LIKE HIM,
IT SURE LOOKED LIKE HIM.
HE AIN'T THE ONE
YOU SAID?
NO.
I'VE SEEN THIS ONE
BEFORE, THOUGH.
I KNOW I'VE
SEEN HIM BEFORE.
CONSTABLE,
YOU WENT AND KILLED
THE WRONG COON.
[Chuckles]
HEH HEH HEH.
[Breathing heavy]
[Digging]
LISTEN...
I'LL TAKE YOU
BACK TO TOWN.
I KNOW A PLACE
YOU CAN STAY TONIGHT,
ALL RIGHT?
WE?
NOW, WHO IS "WE"?
WELL,
EVERYBODY WAS THERE.
YOU MEAN TAKE UP
A COLLECTION,
PASS THE HAT.
SI.
YES, MR. MALSON.
MIGHTY FINE THOUGHT,
BOB, MIGHTY FINE.
DON'T YOU AGREE, EARL?
SURE.
GIVE HER A FEW DOLLARS,
ENOUGH TO GET HOME.
ANY IDEA WHERE
SHE WANTS TO GO?
I DON'T KNOW.
BACK TO HER PEOPLE,
I THINK.
GOOD IDEA.
YOU'VE GOT ABOUT
$3 OR $4 THERE.
IT'S NOT MUCH.
CHRIST, SHE'LL BE
THE RICHEST SQUAW
ON THE RESERVATION!
HOW MUCH DID YOU HAVE
IN MIND, BOB?
I WAS THINKING
MAYBE $200?
[Dog barking]
[Laughing]
I WOULD LIKE
TO KNOW SOMETHING.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW
WHY WE'RE LISTENING
TO THIS GREASER.
[Malson]
R. L., KEEP YOUR MOUTH CLOSED.
HE KILLED HIM, NOT US.
WHAT'S HE COMING
TO US FOR?
SHUT UP
OR GET OUT OF HERE.
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY,
BOB, $200.
ALMOST AS MUCH
AS I MAKE IN A YEAR.
GIVING HER
A SUM LIKE THAT
IS LIKE ADMITTING
WE OWE IT TO HER,
LIKE WE'RE TO BLAME.
WELL, WHO ELSE?
WAIT A MINUTE, BOB.
WHEN IT COMES
TO FIXING THE BLAME,
I AGREE WITH R.L.
YOU TOOK IT ON YOURSELF
TO GO DOWN AND TALK
TO THAT MAN.
YOU KILLED HIM.
I KNOW THAT, MR. MALSON,
I KNOW THAT.
DON'T TAKE IT
SO HARD, BOB.
WHAT THE HELL, IF FRANK TANNER
HADN'T MADE THAT MISTAKE,
THE WHOLE THING
WOULD NEVER HAVE HAPPENED.
SURE, IT'S ALL
TANNER'S FAULT.
GO TELL HIM THAT.
MAYBE WE SHOULD...
TELL HIM.
I TELL YOU WHAT, BOB.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL HIM?
IF HE PUTS UP $100,
WE'LL PUT UP $100.
HE'S DRIVING THAT STOCK
HE BOUGHT FROM MR. MALSON
BACK TO MIMBRENO.
YOU CAN CATCH HIM
AT THE SWING STATION.
[Coins clink]
YOU MEAN IT,
MR. MALSON?
YOU HAVE MY WORD, BOB.
I KNOW EVERYBODY
WHO DOES BUSINESS
WITH  SENOR  TANNER.
I DON'T KNOW, UH,
BOB...VALDEZ.
IT IS A PRIVATE MATTER.
SENOR  TANNER
DON'T KNOW YOU EITHER.
I MEET HIM TODAY.
I KILLED A MAN FOR HIM.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
TO TALK WITH YOU...
ABOUT THE MAN TODAY.
WHAT MAN?
THE ONE WHO WAS--
HE HAD THE WOMAN
WITH HIM.
SAY WHAT YOU WANT.
WE WERE TALKING.
MR. MALSON, MR. BEAUDRY,
YOU KNOW WHO I MEAN--
AND WE WERE SAYING THAT--
THAT MAYBE WE SHOULD GIVE
SOMETHING TO THE WOMAN.
NOW SHE
DON'T HAVE A MAN.
THEY SEND YOU OUT HERE?
I THOUGHT OF IT,
BUT THEY WILL GIVE $100...
IF YOU WILL GIVE THE SAME.
GET RID OF HIM.
I'M NOT FINISHED YET.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I WANT TO EXPLAIN--
[Gunshot]
HE DON'T HEAR YOU
SO GOOD.
IT'S TOO LOUD
OUT HERE.
[Laughter]
WHO IS THAT MAN?
WHAT HAPPENED TODAY?
IT HAD SOMETHING TO DO
WITH JIM'S MURDER,
DIDN'T IT?
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE!
I WISH YOU'D STOP LOOKING
FOR WHOEVER DID IT.
I DON'T CARE.
I DO.
BECAUSE THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO THINK YOU DID IT.
YES.
YOU KILL MEN WITHOUT CARING
WHAT PEOPLE THINK?
I DON'T LIKE THEM THINKING
I HAD TO KILL ONE
TO GET HIS WIFE.
THEY'RE GOING TO KNOW
THAT YOU CAME TO ME
BECAUSE YOU WANTED TO.
THAT'S TRUE, ISN'T IT?
EASY...EASY, CARLOS.
HELLO, VALDEZ.
[Speaking Spanish]
OH, IS HONOR TO MY HOUSE
TO HAVE AS GUEST
THE BRAVE SHOTGUN RIDER
OF THE STAGE--
HIS EXCELLENCY
THE CONSTABLE
OF LANORIA.
IN THE MEXICAN PART
OF TOWN.
I NEED SOME WATER
FOR THE HORSES.
ANITA!
HOW IS SHE?
I TAKE HER BACK
TO THE RESERVATION.
A LITTLE GIFT
FOR YOUR HOUSE
FROM MY HOUSE.
OH, THAT HOUSE.
COME OUT OF THE SUN,
AND WE'LL HAVE
A GLASS TOGETHER.
[Sighs]
WHOO.
[Horse whinnies]
HE'S PRETTY GOOD.
CERTAINLY BE AS GOOD
AS HIS FATHER.
BETTER.
LAST WEEK,
SENOR  MALSON SEE HIM.
PROMISE HIM A JOB.
SENOR  MALSON.
"MIGHTY FINE BOY
YOU GOT THERE, DIEGO.
"CHIP OFF
THE OLD BLOCK.
"I RECKON HE'LL BE
BREAKING IN HORSES
FOR ME SOON,
"SAME AS HIS PA."
OH,  SENOR  MALSON,
YOU ARE TOO KIND
TO THIS POOR  PEON.
WHAT AN HONOR THAT
THIS WORTHLESS SON OF MINE
SHOULD WORK HIS ASS OFF
TO MAKE YOU RICH.
"WELL, YOU'RE A GOOD
GREASER, DIEGO.
"AS LONG AS YOU ARE
A GOOD GREASER,
"I TREAT YOU
FAIR AND SQUARE.
"YESSIREE, DIEGO.
"YOU PEOPLE SURE
KNOW HOW TO LIVE--
"SINGING,
DANCING, SCREWING.
"DON'T WORRY
ABOUT NOTHING."
I COME BACK FOR HER
LATER.
[Gunshot]
BUENO, SENOR  TANNER.
IT'S A DEAL.
YOU WILL HAVE THE GUNS
IN NOGALES BY FRIDAY?
WE'LL BE THERE.
[Dog barks]
I'LL BE
A SON OF A BITCH.
SENOR  TANNER.
THE CIRCUIT JUDGE
COMES DOWN TO
LANORIA TOMORROW
FROM ST. DAVID.
I...I HAVE TO REPORT
WHAT HAPPENED.
THE INDIAN WOMAN
CAN MAKE TROUBLE FOR US...
WITH THE LAW.
NOW, $100 IS NOT MUCH
TO GIVE.
LOOK, YOU...
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU
HORSESHIT THEM PEOPLE
INTO GIVING A GREASER
A TIN STAR,
BUT YOU DON'T
HORSESHIT FRANK TANNER.
SENOR  TANNER!
WHY YOU DON'T HELP
THIS WOMAN?
HE DON'T LEARN,
DOES HE?
[Grunts]
[Grunting]
REMEMBER TUCSON?
THAT PREACHER?
FIX HIM THE SAME.
[Grunting]
NOW LET'S SEE HIM WALK.
[Grunts]
[Groans]
HEY, WHERE YOU GO?
IT'S THAT WAY...
THE WAY YOU CAME.
I CAME ON A HORSE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THE HORSE.
WE TAKE CARE OF IT.
[Laughing]
HEY, DON'T FALL
ON YOUR BACK.
YOU'LL BE
LIKE A TURTLE.
[Laughter]
I DON'T REMEMBER
ASKING YOU HERE.
I GOT TIRED
RIDING FENCE
FOR MR. MALSON.
I FIGURED YOU COULD
ALWAYS USE ANOTHER GUN.
YOU COULDN'T EVEN HIT
A SITTING-DUCK NIGGER.
SHE NEVER SMILES.
IF SHE WAS MY WOMAN...
I WOULD MAKE HER SMILE.
[Speaking Spanish]
GOING RIDING?
YOU BASTARD.
WHY DON'T YOU
CUT HIM LOOSE?
FOR GOD'S SAKE, FRANK,
HE'S ONLY TRYING
TO HELP A POOR WOMAN
WHO'S
LOST HER HUSBAND.
SO AM I.
I'M HELPING ONE ALREADY.
1 POOR WIDOW WOMAN'S
ENOUGH.
JIM WOULD HAVE
USED THIS ON YOU.
YOU'RE
THINKING OF IT?
I'M THINKING
YOU'RE A DAMN FOOL
TO WORRY ABOUT ANYTHING
EXCEPT THE WAY I TREAT YOU.
I TREAT YOU ALL RIGHT,
DON'T I?
SOMETIMES YOU'RE HUMAN...
SOMETIMES.
WE DELIVER THE GUNS TO
NOGALES IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
HOW WOULD YOU
LIKE TO COME ALONG?
AREN'T THERE ANY WHORES
IN NOGALES?
SURE, LOTS OF THEM.
LOTS OF PRIESTS, TOO.
WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
PRIESTS MARRY PEOPLE,
DON'T THEY?
I'LL HOLD YOU
TO THAT, FRANK.
I RECKON YOU WILL.
AH!
[Groans]
UNH!
[Panting]
[Gasps]
AAH!
[Screaming]
I SWEAR, YOU SURE ARE
ONE DUMB SON OF A BITCH.
WHEN THAT POLE BUSTED,
WHERE DID YOU THINK
IT WAS GONNA GO?
YEAH, IT'S YOUR OLD  AMIGO
YOU TRIED TO BASH
WITH YOUR SHOTGUN BUTT.
YOU REMEMBER THAT,
DON'T YOU?
YOU WENT AND
KILLED THE WRONG COON
AND WAS GOING
TO TAKE IT OUT ON ME.
CUT ME LOOSE...
PLEASE.
YOU MUST ACHE SOME
FROM THAT STOOPING OVER.
YOU KNOW,
I DIDN'T LIKE YOU
TRYING TO HIT ME
WITH THAT SCATTER GUN.
YOU MADE ME SORE,
I'LL TELL YOU.
CUT ME LOOSE...
PLEASE.
[Snickers]
AAH!
HOW DID I GET HERE?
YOU CRAWLED.
I HEARD THE DOGS.
OH.
THEY NAILED ME
TO A CROSS.
WHAT CROSS?
SOMEBODY
CUT ME LOOSE.
SOMEBODY STABBED YOU
IN THE BACK.
NO.
NO, A TREE DID THAT.
WHAT KIND OF A TREE
DOES THAT?
WHERE'S
THE INDIAN WOMAN?
SHE TAKE HER WAGON
AND GO.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU TAKE ME HOME.
[Giggling]
[Horses approaching]
WHOA.
GRA CIAS, D IEGO.
[Dog barking]
THAT'S FAR ENOUGH!
IS NOT TRUE.
THE CONSTABLE
FROM LANORIA?
LAST TIME I SAW YOU,
YOU HAD A CROSS
ON YOUR BACK.
I GET TIRED OF IT.
SOMEBODY FOUND
YOU, HUH?
SOMEBODY.
YOU HAD LUCK WITH YOU
THAT TIME.
FRIENDS?
SURE.
LIKE YOU AND ME.
WE TALK A WHILE,
WE HAVE A DRINK
OF WHISKEY.
WHAT YOU THINK ABOUT
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
I THINK I SEE
MANY GUNS.
YOU COME UP HERE TO TALK
AND YOU BRING ALL THOSE GUNS.
TSK TSK TSK.
THIS LITTLE THING?
IT'S FOR RABBITS.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU COME HERE FOR?
TO HUNT RABBITS?
NO, I COME TO ASK YOU
TO DO SOMETHING FOR ME.
BECAUSE
WE'RE FRIENDS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I WANT YOU TO GO
SEE  SENOR  TANNER
AND TELL HIM
VALDEZ IS COMING.
I THINK
SOMEBODY ELSE GO.
LISTEN.
I'VE BEEN HERE
ALL DAY.
THERE'S NO
SOMEBODY ELSE.
THERE IS JUST YOU
IN FRONT OF ME.
THAT'S ALL.
YOU SURE OF THAT?
YOU BET YOUR LIFE
ON IT?
ON YOURS.
NO, NO.
WHAT KIND OF TALK IS THAT
WITH 2 FRIENDS?
YOU WANT ME TO TELL
SOMETHING TO MR. TANNER?
ALL RIGHT, I'LL GO.
PUT THE RABBIT GUN DOWN.
YOU WAIT HERE.
I'LL GO TELL MR. TANNER
WHAT YOU SAY,
THEN I COME BACK,
THEN I TELL YOU
WHAT HE SAY.
HOW'S THAT?
I BE HERE.
AH.
DON'T MOVE.
WHAT YOU...
WHAT YOU PUT
IN THAT THING?
I TOLD YOU.
SOMETHING FOR RABBITS.
LISTEN, I'M GOING
TO GET YOUR HORSE
AND PUT YOU ON IT.
I CAN'T...
I CAN'T RIDE.
SURE, YOU CAN.
RIDE TO  SENOR  TANNER
AND TELL HIM
VALDEZ IS COMING.
YOU HEAR WHAT I SAY?
BUT LISTEN, MY FRIEND,
I THINK YOU
BETTER GO QUICK.
WHAT ELSE
DID HE SAY?
THAT'S ALL.
JUST "VALDEZ IS COMING."
GO OUT AND GET HIM.
WHERE?
HE COULD BE ANYWHERE.
WELL, GOD DAMN IT,
YOU GOT PEOPLE
WHO READ SIGN.
SI.
WELL, SEND THEM!
WE GO TO NOGALES
TOMORROW.
WHEN I SAY WE GO.
[Dog barking]
NOTHING.
HOW MANY MEN
YOU GOT OUT?
A SNAKE
COULDN'T CRAWL THROUGH.
I SUPPOSE
NOGALES IS OFF.
DELAYED.
SENOR  VALDEZ SEEMS
TO BE MAKING A FOOL OF YOU
WITHOUT MY HELP.
UH-HUH.
YOU SOUND
LIKE A WIFE.
THAT'S RIGHT...
SO LET'S WAIT
TILL IT'S OFFICIAL.
GOOD NIGHT, FRANK.
YOU ARE A BITCH.
WHAT IS
BOTHERING YOU?
VALDEZ IS COMING.
THAT'S WHAT
BOTHERS ME.
QUE?
VALDEZ IS A
FOOLISH MAN,
BUT WHY HE WARN US
HE'S COMING?
COME TO BED,
CARINO.
MAYBE NOT SO FOOLISH.
VALDEZ SAYS HE'S COMING.
WE GO OUT TO MEET HIM.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT
VALDEZ WANTS.
QUE?
OH!
AH!
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
$100.
OH!
IT'S IN THE SAFE.
GET IT.
[Gasps]
THE CANDLE.
PUT THE GUN
ON THE FLOOR.
SLOWLY, PLEASE.
GOD DAMN IT,
DON'T SHOOT!
[Valdez]
YOU LOOK FOR SOMEBODY?
FIRST YOU DROP
THE GUNS.
THEN
YOU TURN AROUND.
WE FOUND HIM,
MR. TANNER.
WAS SHE WITH HIM?
NO, SIR.
HE SAID TO GIVE YOU
A MESSAGE.
TELL YOU HE'S GOT SOMETHING
TO TRADE NOW.
FOR YOU TO COME
WITH $100.
COME WHERE?
[Gasps]
THEY WERE 3
OF YOUR BEST, YOU SAID?
MY VERY BEST.
YOU STILL WANT
TO GO TO NOGALES?
YOU WANT VALDEZ?
I GET HIM NOW.
[Gasps]
YOU SHOULD HAVE STAYED
WHERE I LEAVE YOU.
AAH!
[Breathing heavy]
WHERE ARE YOU
TAKING ME?
UP.
YOU WILL BE HOME
SOON ENOUGH.
FRANK TANNER KNOWS
WHERE TO FIND ME NOW.
HE'LL COME.
SI.
HE WON'T COME ALONE.
I THINK SO, TOO.
YOU'RE A FOOL.
I ALREADY SAID NO
TO YOU ONCE, BOY.
BUT I GOT MORE
TO OFFER THIS TIME.
LIKE WHAT?
I HEARD
YOU WERE LOOKING
FOR BOB VALDEZ?
I'M LISTENING.
THERE'S A MAN
WHO'D KNOW
WHERE HE IS.
WHO?
THE GREASER WHO
BROUGHT HIM INTO TOWN
AFTER YOU
RUN HIM OUT OF HERE.
DIEGO LUZ.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
GAY ERIN.
MRS. JAMES C. ERIN.
FORT HUACHUCA?
YES.
THE BLACK MAN I KILL,
HE DON'T
KILL YOUR HUSBAND.
I KNOW.
YOU GOING TO MARRY
FRANK TANNER?
WHAT DOES IT MATTER
TO YOU?
I WANT TO KNOW IF HE
WILL PAY FOR YOU.
LET ME GO,
AND I'LL GET THE MONEY.
NO.
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES IT MAKE WHERE
IT COMES FROM?
IT MAKES A DIFFERENCE.
WHERE'S VALDEZ?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHERE DOES HE HIDE
IN THE MOUNTAINS?
I DON'T KNOW.
NOBODY HERE KNOWS.
YOU TOUCH HER,
YOU BETTER KILL ME.
WE CAN DO THAT.
[Whimpers]
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE IS VALDEZ.
MAN, WHO YOU THINK
I PUT FIRST, HIM?
THAT'S
A NICE LOOKING GIRL.
I LIKE A LITTLE MORE
UP THERE,
BUT MAYBE THE FIRST ONE
OF THE DAY WILL BE
ALL RIGHT.
SHOOT HER FIRST.
YOU HOLD ON TO YOURSELF
IF YOU CAN AND YOU SAY...
WHAT VALDEZ IS DOING
IN THE MOUNTAINS.
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU'RE HIS FRIEND.
YOU HELPED HIM!
YOU TOOK HIM TO LANORIA
TO GET HIS GUNS.
I HOPE HE PUTS
1 ROUND INTO YOU,
YOU ROTTEN
SON OF A PIG.
[Laughing]
HA HA HA HA!
HE DON'T KNOW.
WE WASTED
ENOUGH TIME HERE.
FIX HIS HANDS SO
HE WON'T BE SO
HELPFUL NEXT TIME.
BURN THE PLACE DOWN.
VALDEZ COULD SEE
THE SMOKE A LONG WAY.
BURN THE PLACE DOWN!
THEY'RE FRIENDS,
AIN'T THEY?
HE'LL COME.
JUST LEAVE ME HERE
WITH A COUPLE MEN.
WOULD YOU COME
IF YOU SAW
YOUR FRIEND'S HOUSE
BURNING?
SURE.
HEH HEH HEH.
YOU WOULDN'T...
BUT VALDEZ...
MIGHT.
[Coyote howling]
FOR THE COLD.
MR. FRANK TANNER...
HE KNOW YOUR HUSBAND?
YOU THINK FRANK TANNER
KILLED MY HUSBAND?
HE COULD.
HE COULD,
BUT HE DIDN'T.
OH!
[Horses whinny]
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO FEED THE HORSES.
SENOR  MALSON'S HORSES.
I SAW YOU COME
ACROSS THE PASTURE LOW.
NOT LOW ENOUGH,
IF YOU SAW ME.
LOW ENOUGH.
THE ONE BY THE HOUSE
DID NOT SEE YOU.
WHAT'D THEY DO TO YOU?
WHAT YOU SEE.
I'M SORRY.
IS NOT YOUR FAULT.
MR. R.L. DAVIS
BRING THEM.
LISTEN, IF YOU
SEE THAT ONE,
GIVE HIM SOMETHING
FOR ME, HUH?
YOU'RE A GOOD FRIEND.
THE BEST.
I TELL YOU SOMETHING,
FRIEND.
WHEN THEY
START IN ON MY GIRL,
IF I KNOW WHERE YOU ARE,
I TELL THEM.
[Neighs]
WHERE'S VALDEZ?
[Mumbling]
OH.
MAYBE I'LL TAKE HIM
ALIVE, HUH?
MR. TANNER'D LIKE THAT,
ESPECIALLY IF HE'D
DONE ANYTHING TO YOU.
HUH?
HE DIDN'T DONE
ANYTHING TO YOU?
[Mumbling]
ALL RIGHT, NOW,
YOU JUST
STAY PUT, MA'AM.
DON'T LET ON NOTHING.
UNH!
[Gunshot]
JESUS CHRIST,
I'M HIT!
HEY, DON'T SHOOT!
I'M COMING OUT!
DON'T...
NO!
NO, PLEASE.
THEY'RE
GOING TO SHOOT.
NO!
THIS ONE FOR DIEGO.
NO, I--I SAVED YOU!
I CUT YOU LOOSE.
YES, I DID.
I CUT YOU LOOSE
FROM THEM POLES.
HOW IN THE HELL DO YOU
THINK YOU GOT LOOSE?
LOOK AT YOUR WRIST--
THAT ONE.
THE SCAR, WHERE
MY KNIFE SLIPPED
CUTTING THE ROPES.
LOOK AT IT!
GET ON YOUR HORSE!
[Gunshot]
[Gunshots]
[Distant gunshots]
DID YOU FIRE AT THEM?
YES, SIR.
HIT ANYBODY?
I DON'T THINK SO.
BUT YOU MIGHT HAVE.
YES, SIR.
YOU COULD HAVE
KILLED MY WOMAN.
WE LOST 5.
YOU SHOOT HIM,
THAT'S 6,
THE SAME AS
VALDEZ KILL HIM.
HOW MANY
YOU WANT TO KILL
FOR THAT MAN?
AS MANY AS IT TAKES.
INSTEAD OF SHOOT HIM,
MAKE HIM RIDE POINT.
THAT WAY HE'S THE FIRST
ONE VALDEZ WILL SEE.
I GOT TO GET
LOOSE SOMEHOW.
CRAZY BASTARD'S
GOING TO KILL ME.
WHY?
YOU CUT HIM LOOSE.
HE'S A KILLER,
LADY.
YOU KNOW HOW
MANY MEN HE KILLED
THE LAST 2 DAYS?
YOU DON'T KNOW
HIM, LADY.
MR. R.L. DAVIS.
HUH?
COME HERE.
I WANT YOU TO GO DOWN
THERE, BY THE BIG ROCK.
UH, WHAT DO YOU WANT
ME DOWN THERE FOR?
I WANT TO SEE YOU
IN FRONT OF ME.
HMM.
WHAT IF THEY COME?
THEY ALREADY COMING.
I DON'T SEE NOTHING.
TAKE MY WORD.
HEY, YOU'RE CRAZY,
YOU THINK YOU CAN
MAKE A STAND HERE--
BY THE ROCK!
PLEASE.
THEY WILL SEE THIS.
GO BEHIND THE ROCK.
ARE YOU GOING
TO MAKE A STAND HERE?
I'M JUST GOING
TO SLOW THEM DOWN.
[Gunshots]
[Horses whinnying]
[Gunshot]
SHARPS...
OR SOME KIND
OF BUFFALO GUN...
OR A CANNON.
HE CAN SHOOT,
AND HE KNOW
WHEN TO MOVE...
AND WE HAVE
LOST 5 MORE.
YOU AIN'T GOING
TO FIND YOUR WAY IN THIS.
IT WILL BE THE SAME
FOR FRANK TANNER.
YOU KNOW HOW
MANY MEN YOU GOT
TO WORK THROUGH HERE?
NOT SO MANY NOW.
YOU DON'T CARE
HOW MANY MEN YOU KILL.
YOU KILL HER.
TELL HIM.
TELL WHO WHAT?
FRANK TANNER--
HE COMES ALONE
WITH $100,
OR I KILL HER!
YOU AIN'T GOING
TO SHOOT ME IN THE BACK?
WE CAMP HERE.
HEY!
MR. TANNER!
YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO KILL ME.
THAT WAS A BLUFF,
WASN'T IT?
BUT THEY'LL KILL YOU.
SEND ME BACK.
YOU DIDN'T KILL
THAT BLACK MAN. I DID.
I LET FRANK SEND ME
BACK TO THE HOTEL
THAT DAY.
I COULD HAVE STAYED
AND STOPPED IT.
YOU TELL ME FRANK TANNER
DON'T KILL YOUR HUSBAND?
AND WHEN I SAY
THE BLACK MAN DON'T.
YOU SAY, "I KNOW."
YOU KNOW WHO KILL HIM?
YOU KNOW WHO KILLED HIM?
WHO KILL YOUR HUSBAND?
TELL ME.
WHO KILL HIM?
I DID.
[Crying]
[Sobbing]
NO!
WHAT?
NOTHING. I JUST
GOT DONE TELLING YOU
EVERYTHING HE TOLD ME.
HOW'S MRS. ERIN?
SHE LOOKED JUST FINE.
I MEAN, HE
AIN'T HURT HER ANY.
HE KEEP HER TIED?
YES, SIR.
OR SHE'D RUN OFF?
YEAH, YOU BET
SHE WOULD.
YOU THINK
HE'D KILL HER?
WITH THIS ONE,
YOU CAN NEVER TELL.
GOD DAMN IT!
YOU GOT
ANY IDEAS?
I COULD
RIDE ALL NIGHT,
AROUND THE FOG,
MAYBE I GET UP ABOVE
HIM BY MORNING.
YOU AND THE REST
COMING UP BEHIND.
IF HE HOLDS PUT
TILL THEN.
HE'S GOT TO
WAIT FOR THIS FOG
TO BURN OFF,
SAME AS ANY MAN.
[R.L.]
HE DON'T DO
LIKE ANY MAN.
SOME THINGS.
HE TOOK A WOMAN
ALONG, HUH?
MIGUEL, TOMAS,
VAMOS!
IS HE COMING?
HE'S COMING.
BUT NOT ALONE.
NO, NOT ALONE.
WHAT'S OUT THERE?
THE PASS.
IF I COULD REACH THERE,
AN ARMY DON'T FIND ME.
YOU'VE BEEN
THERE BEFORE?
MANY YEARS AGO,
CHASING APACHE.
BUT NOW I THINK
THERE IS SOMEBODY ELSE
OUT THERE.
EL SEGUNDO.
I CAN SMELL HIM.
I SHOULD HAVE KEEP
MOVING LAST NIGHT,
FOG OR NO FOG.
YOU CAN GO.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
I WOULD LIKED
TO HAVE GOTTEN THE $100
FOR THE INDIAN WOMAN.
I'D LIKE TO SEE
FRANK PAY IT.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
CAN YOU STAND?
UH-HUH.
YOU LIKE TOBACCO?
NO.
AHEM.
TELL ME SOMETHING.
WHO ARE YOU?
I TOLD YOU ONCE BEFORE--
BOB VALDEZ.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
BOB VALDEZ,
YOU HIT ONE, I THINK,
700, 800 YARDS.
CLOSER TO 1,000.
WHAT WAS IT?
SHARPS?
MY OWN LOAD.
YOU EVER HUNT BUFFALO?
APACHE.
I KNEW IT.
WHEN?
BEFORE I KNOW BETTER.
YOU KNOW
HOW MANY DEAD WE GOT?
11.
YOU COUNT, HUH?
YOU BET.
YOU HURT BAD?
NO.
YOU BETTER
COME OVER HERE.
WE CAN TALK ABOUT IT
WHEN WE GET HOME.
I'M NOT GOING HOME.
SHE BETTER THAN
YOUR INDIAN SQUAW?
TELL YOUR WHORE
TO MOVE OVER.
MOVE OVER, PLEASE.
LITTLE BIT MORE.
ANY LAST WORDS?
$100.
HEE HEE HEE.
CRAZY BASTARD.
KILL HIM!
EL SEGUNDO.
SHE'S NOT MY WOMAN.
I AIN'T GOT NO GUN.
TOMAS!
[Speaking Spanish]
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
I TELL THEM
TO GO HOME.
I HIRE THEM,
I FIRE THEM.
GOD DAMN IT!
I'M TALKING
TO ALL OF YOU!
I'M ORDERING YOU
TO KILL HIM!
SENOR  TANNER...
I HAVE AN IDEA.
YOU HAVE A GUN
IN YOUR HOLSTER.
YOU SHOOT ME.
NEXT TIME.
NO.
I SHOULD HAVE KILLED YOU
3 DAYS AGO.
OR GONE TO NOGALES.
OR PAID THE $100.