(school bell ringing)
Okay, Holly,
Will Schuester, Mr. Figgins,
Brad the piano player?
Oh, that's easy.
I'd bang Will Schuester,
marry Figgins,
and push Brad the piano player
off a cliff.
What? No way.
Holly, I'd marry Will and
have sex with Figgins.
See, I've gotten real
good at getting my soul
to float above my body
when I'm doing the nasty.
So I'd cringe my way
through a sweaty hump
session with Figgins,
and bone Will Schuester
well into my 60s.
Oh, fantastic.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't April Rhodes,
America's favorite
alcoholic dwarf whore.
Oh, thank you, Sue.
Holly and I were just playing
Kill, Marry, or Bone.
Well, April,
as you have absolutely
no business whatsoever
on this campus, normally,
I would have you
physically removed.
However, since you seem
to be hanging out
with the willowy
and winning Holly Holliday,
(laughs) I am willing
to make an exception.
Hey, girl.
Thanks, Coach.
Wait a second. You
guys know each other?
Oh, you bet
your sweet ass we do.
Yup, the minute
I met Miss Holliday,
we immediately hit it off,
and we've been best of friends
ever since.
Mm-hmm. We're auditioning
for The Amazing Race.
I'm Principal Sue Sylvester.
And I'm Substitute
Holly Holliday.
And together we are...
BOTH:
Team Gorgeous!
SUE:  As a seven-time
national championship
cheerleading coach, I know what
it's like to work as a team.
(sputtering)
And I'm looking forward
to the physical challenges.
HOLLY:  And I'm looking
forward to eating
those half-formed
fetal duck eggs!
(both yelling)
So, Sue, um, April and
I were just talking...
No. I'm sorry, Holly.
The glee club's over.
Okay, I know. I just, um...
I was just thinking,
you know, just 'cause
Glee Club is over
doesn't mean that there can't be
any music at the school, right?
What you getting at, Holly?
HOLLY: I mean, you
know, there are plenty
of other clubs in this school.
Maybe we could
work a little music into some of them.
That's right, Holly.
You know, it's a proven fact,
when you put music
in the classroom,
test scores go up.
Oh, please, dear God, shut up.
Sue, we're just
asking for one week.
Fine. You have one week
to somehow shoehorn
music into McKinley's
extracurricular clubs.
But, please, see if you can't
involve William in this somehow.
It'll soften the blow
of the glee club's cancellation.
(school bell ringing)
(laughter)
Ooh!
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(school bell ringing)
TINA:  This time in a
person's life is supposed
to feel fresh
and full of possibility.
But unlike every other senior
at this school,
I seem to be the only one
still waiting by the phone
to be invited to the dance.
I got rejected by
my backup school, Ohio State,
and Brown still hasn't told me
if I got in yet.
And at this point,
I'm taking desperate measures.
I get it. I was adopted,
and I've never been to temple.
But all of my friends
are going to be in New York,
and Mitzvah is the only school
that is still accepting
for fall semester.
I wrote an essay about why
the reason I'm applying so late
was because I was on a kibbutz,
whatever that is.
So, here we go.
Fingers crossed.
I just got to get
to New York somehow.
Well, what are you guys doing?
Well, Mr. Shue wanted us
to pack away the trophies
before Sue came in and
had the Cheerios! do it.
No, don't get upset. Oh.
I'm upset.
Guys, you might want to sit down
for this. I have some huge news.
You guys got married and adopted
Russian twin babies. Yes!
Blaine got into NYADA!
I got into NYADA!
Oh, my God!
Congratulations!
(overlapping chatter)
Congratulations.
Wow! Oh, my God! You guys,
do you know what this means?
All of us... we're all going
to New York together!
(whoops) Oh!
You guys, we're gonna
miss our shift!
Ew!
Oh.
Hey! Hey!
If I wanted to watch men
in capri pants
slobbering all over each other,
I'd watch Monday Night Football.
(canned laughter)
(theme music playing)
(applause and cheering)
Whoa! Man, those ten flights
of stairs are a bitch.
I wish this apartment
had an elevator.
It does.
Now you tell me!
(laughter)
(audience member whistling)
Sam, where are your clothes?
Oh. I think I left 'em
at the Laundromat.
(laughter) Again?
Aah! Rachel, quit
hogging the bathroom!
RACHEL: I'm never
coming out of here!
That's what I said
sophomore year of high school.
(applause and cheering)
I'm serious!
Open the G-dang door!
I'm never getting
spray-tanned again
at a Vietnamese doughnut shop.
Where do we keep the ketchup?
ALL:
Mike Chang!
What are you doing here?
I'm here to win Tina back.
Did I say that out loud?
Also, I'm here to teach
dance to the homeless,
and I brought a few
chums to help me out.
(noise-makers sounding)
(applause and cheering)
Sam, where's your clothes?
Oh. I knew I forgot something.
(canned laughter)
(sitcom musical sting)
Oh, my gosh, Tina,
I-I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm great.
You guys, New York,
it's gonna be amazing.
MERCEDES: You know, being here
with everyone has brought
so many good feelings
and memories,
and... I mean, look
at Puck and Quinn.
I mean, I have no idea
what's going on there,
nor do I know
where her boyfriend
ran off to, but it looks
like we can be expecting
another "accidental"
pregnancy sometime soon.
(whoops) Yeah, yeah.
Yeah! KURT: But, alas,
with the old good feelings
come the old bad ones, too.
Why, just today, Mercedes and I
were in the lunch line
when a battle from
way back in the day
came out,
a-and we found ourselves
at each other's throats again.
They have zero
nutritional value.
Listen,
potatoes are vegetables, okay?
And Tots are made from potatoes.
Ergo, Tots are vegetables.
Well, I'd like some kind of proof of
how much potato is actually in there.
And ruin the mystery?
What in the hell is wrong
with you? Move it.
Yes, I know. It's really
hard to see friends fighting,
but I'm just glad that none of
you guys were there to see it.
I was right behind you in line.
Because the most upsetting thing
is watching two people you love
fight about
something ridiculous
and there not being anything
you can do to stop it.
But, thankfully, we made up
and we have never been closer.
- Mmm. - And we've decided
to heal our hearts
with a song.
♪ I am ♪
♪ Changing ♪
♪ Trying every way I can ♪
♪ I am changing ♪
♪ I'll be better than I am ♪
♪ I'm trying ♪
♪ To find a way ♪
♪ To understand ♪
♪ But I need you ♪
♪ I need you ♪
♪ I need ♪
♪ A ♪
♪ Hand ♪
♪ I am changing ♪
♪ Seeing everything so clear ♪
BOTH:
♪ I am changing ♪
♪ I'm gonna start right now,
right here ♪
♪ But I need a friend ♪
♪ To help me start
all over again ♪
♪ Oh, that would be just ♪
♪ Fine ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ I know it's gonna work out ♪
BOTH:
♪ This time ♪
MERCEDES:
♪ Hey ♪
BOTH:
♪ 'Cause this time I am ♪
♪ This time I am... ♪
♪ I am ♪
♪ Changing ♪
♪ I'll get my life
together now ♪
♪ Oh ♪
BOTH:
♪ I am changing ♪
MERCEDES:
♪ Yes, I know how ♪
BOTH:
♪ I'm gonna start again ♪
♪ I'm gonna
leave my past behind ♪
BOTH: ♪ I'll change my life ♪
♪ I'll make a vow ♪
BOTH:
♪ And nothing's gonna stop ♪
♪ Me ♪
♪ Now... ♪
(cheering and applause)
(school bell rings)
You remember when we first met?
I was in here doing my hair...
Are you trying to make peace with
me by getting all nostalgic?
Because, if so, you are
forgetting the one thing
that you should have learned
from all of our magical time
together, and it's
that I have no heart.
Look, I've been unkind
to you, okay?
And-and I won't get
into the whole thing
about how watching Kurt and Mercedes
sing got me all sentimental
because I know you'll just
make fun of me for it.
No, you know what?
Go ahead, please.
Because if I don't express
my venom at least once a day,
I get constipated.
I want to give you ten shows.
Any ten shows after
the first three months,
all right?
And you can pick. They can be
ten in a row or one at a time.
It's a peace offering.
That way, your mom can come
or your abuela.
I just... I don't want
to do this anymore.
It's exhausting
and it's depressing.
(chuckles) No.
I want them all.
The only reason
why you're doing this
for me is because you know
that I'm gonna go
all Showgirls on you and win.
No more scraps, Rachel.
I will be happy
and kiss and be friends
once you give me the part.
God, what is it about anymore
with you, Santana?
I just... I don't get it.
Yeah.
I'm just not sold
on the whole idea.
Will, this is going
to work. I swear.
You just have to trust me.
Okay...
(Southern accent): Hey there,
Animal Husbandry Club!
I'm animal rights activist
Temple Grandin!
Overcoming autism
gave me insight into how
to slaughter livestock
in a more humane way.
I think in pictures, not words,
and I'm hypersensitive
to loud noise!
But that don't mean I don't know
how to party. Hit it!
(Eddie Murphy's
"Party All the Time" begins)
♪ Girl, I can't understand it ♪
♪ Why you want to hurt me ♪
♪ After all of the things
I've done for you ♪
♪ I buy you champagne and roses,
put diamonds ♪
♪ On your finger,
diamonds on your finger ♪
♪ Still you hang out all night,
what am I to do? ♪
♪ My girl wants
to party all the time ♪
♪ Party all the time,
party all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants
to party all the time ♪
♪ Party all the time ♪
♪ She parties all the time ♪
♪ Girl, I've seen you in clubs ♪
♪ Just hanging out and dancing ♪
♪ You give your number
to every man you see ♪
♪ You never come home at night ♪
♪ Because you're out romancing ♪
♪ I wish you'd bring some
of your love home to me ♪
♪ My girl wants
to party all the time ♪
♪ Party all the time,
party all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants to ♪
♪ Party all the time,
party all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants
to party all the time ♪
♪ Party all the time,
party all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants to party
all the time, party all ♪
♪ The time... ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ She likes
to party all the time ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Parties all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants to ♪ (cheering)
♪ Party all the time, party
all the time ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Party all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants
to party all the time ♪
♪ Party all the time ♪
♪ My girl wants to, yeah ♪
♪ My
girl wants to party all the time ♪
♪ Party all the time, party
all the time ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ My girl wants
to party all the time, party ♪
♪ All the time... ♪
(cheering)
How's that for a field trip?!
(school bell rings)
Oh, my God.
Are these all lilies?
They're the lesbian of flowers.
I also...
got you this.
Two tickets to Lesbos Island?
But these are
both one-way.
Yeah, I figured once we arrived
at the girl-on-girl paradise
that is Lesbos
that we'd never want to leave.
Okay, listen.
Brittany, I love you, but
running away with me and
living on a lesbian island
is not what you want to do.
You just don't want
to go back to MIT.
And you shouldn't.
Just because your amazing
mathematical mind can solve
all the world's problems
doesn't mean that it has to.
It's not your dream, and
neither is being with me.
You're one to talk.
Since when is becoming a
Broadway star your goal in life?
A star is a star. It doesn't
matter where in the sky I shine.
I don't want to run away with
you because I want to run away.
I want to run away
with you because
you and I are the only truly
awesome people I've ever met,
and I'm tired of doing stuff
that only matters
to people less awesome than us.
Okay, but this isn't
like your math stuff.
I'm going to be
rich and famous.
This is a great
first step for me.
And, besides, I'm not gonna
let that dwarf Berry win.
(clicks tongue)
Listen...
you have spent most
of your life in the closet
because you cared about
what people thought about you.
Walking away from a dream
that you don't actually
care about is you winning,
because it's you saying,
"This is not who I am,
and I don't care who knows it."
(laughs quietly)
You know, it's funny.
I spend months
tangled up in knots,
and in five minutes,
you straighten me out.
Mm.
You really are a genius.
I'm just the world's
foremost expert
in the field of Santana Lopez.
(laughs)
So... what do you want to do?
(school bell ringing)
(sighs)
My life is literally over.
Where the hell did all
these flowers come from?
BLAINE:
What's wrong, Tina?
Nothing. Just the fact
that I'm going
to spend the rest
of my life in Lima
because I'm not Jewish enough.
MAN:
Dear Tina, Mitzvah University
was delighted
to receive your application,
albeit five weeks late.
However, we know the truth.
Your name is not Tina Cohen.
You are Tina Cohen-Chang.
You are a big, fat liar.
I didn't get into Mitzvah,
so I guess
I'm the only one in this room
who's not going to New York.
Why? You don't need a college
acceptance letter to get over
that bridge. I can't just go
there without some kind of plan.
Well, uh, Kurt did, and I think
he's doing pretty great.
It's an adventure. Not for me.
You don't understand.
Without some kind of
direction, I just feel
like a giant,
free-floating loser.
Yeah, like me.
And me.
(piano plays slow,
gentle melody)
("Loser Like Me" begins)
♪ You may think
that I'm a zero ♪
♪ And everyone you want to be ♪
♪ Probably started off like me ♪
♪ You may say
that I'm a freak show ♪
♪ But give it
just a little time ♪
♪ I bet you're gonna
change your mind ♪
♪ All of the dirt
you've been throwin' my way ♪
(in harmony):
♪ It ain't so hard to take ♪
♪ 'Cause I know one day ♪
♪ You'll be screamin' my name ♪
♪ And I'll just look away ♪
♪ Yeah, I'll just look away ♪
ARTIE AND TINA:
♪ Just go ahead and hate on me ♪
♪ Run your mouth
so everyone can hear ♪
♪ Hit me with the worst
you got ♪
♪ Knock me down ♪
♪ Baby, I don't care ♪
♪ Keep it up, and soon enough ♪
♪ You'll figure out ♪
♪ You wanna be ♪
♪ A loser like me ♪
♪ Push me up
against the locker ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
ARTIE AND TINA:
♪ All I do is shake it off ♪
♪ I'll get you back
when I'm your boss ♪
♪ I'm not thinkin'
'bout you haters ♪
♪ No ♪
ARTIE AND TINA:
♪ And I could be a superstar ♪
♪ I'll see you
when you wash my car ♪
♪ And all of the dirt
you've been throwin' my way ♪
♪ It ain't so hard to take ♪
♪ Oh, and, and ♪
♪ I know one day
you'll be screamin' my name ♪
♪ And I'll just look away ♪
♪ Just go ahead
and hate on me ♪
♪ And run your mouth ♪
♪ Run your mouth ♪
♪ So everyone can hear ♪
♪ Hit me with the worst you got
and knock me down ♪
♪ And knock me down ♪
♪ Baby, I don't care ♪
♪ Keep it up, and soon enough
you'll figure out ♪
♪ You wanna be ♪
♪ A loser like me ♪
♪ Loo-oo-oo-oo ♪
♪ A loser like me. ♪
(song ends)
Ooh, that was nice.
(laughs)
Hey, please, please, please,
please come to New York.
You don't need a plan.
You'll figure something out
once you get there.
We can get an apartment.
You guys are the best.
Let's do this.
ALL:
Yeah.
(cheering) (whoops)
Nick, I'm a good friend
of yours,
and in a dumb way,
I'm kind of smart.
So I'm gonna tell you
what you ought to do.
You ought to marry me.
So I'm gonna tell you
what you ought to do.
- You ought to ma...
- Well...
you certainly are dedicated.
Well, under normal
circumstances I would be,
but considering the fact
that I have to worry
about you pushing me
off the stage at any moment,
I can't slip, even for a second.
Well, I don't like that.
You have been
dreaming about this role
since you were in gay-utero.
And you have actually worked
your tiny butt off to get it,
and I'm coming and sucking
all the celebration out of it.
Why?
Honestly, like,
what have I ever done to you?
Nothing.
I'm just not a
particularly nice person.
And sometimes I make choices
that seem like the right thing
at the time, but then,
looking back,
they're actually kind of mean.
Listen, I don't want
to be a Broadway star.
I'm too lazy
to do eight shows a week.
Wait. So, does... does that mean
that you're quitting the show?
I texted gay-face director
ten minutes ago,
and said, "I hereby
resign as U.S.
of this production of F.G."
- Pithy.
- Listen,
don't get all sentimental
on me or anything like that.
I'm really happy for you,
but I didn't do this for you.
I did this entirely for myself.
I know,
and that was very brave of you.
But do you think
that we could maybe at least
sing a song together
in the glee club?
Fine. But I'm not gonna sing
some tired old song
that we've already done.
'Cause Santana Lopez
is way too badass for that.
(Oh Honey's "Be Okay" begins)
♪ Fresh cut grass ♪
♪ One cold beer ♪
BOTH:
♪ Thank the Lord ♪
♪ I am here and now ♪
♪ Here and now ♪
♪ Summer dress ♪
♪ Favorite park ♪
BOTH:
♪ Bless your soul ♪
♪ We are here and now ♪
♪ Here and now ♪
♪ I'm wide awake ♪
♪ So what's the point
of dreaming ♪
♪ When your life is great ♪
♪ Celebrate the feeling ♪
♪ Oh, can't complain
about much these days ♪
♪ I believe we'll be okay,
oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Can't complain
about much these days ♪
♪ I believe we'll be okay,
oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ We'll scream it out ♪
BOTH:
♪ I believe we'll be okay ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ We'll be okay ♪
♪ Can't complain
about much these days ♪
♪ I believe we'll be okay ♪
BOTH:
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
♪ Yeah... ♪
♪ Can't complain
about much these days ♪
♪ I believe we'll be okay ♪
BOTH:
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Can't complain
about much these days ♪
♪ I believe we'll be okay ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ We'll scream it out ♪
BOTH:
♪ I believe we'll be okay ♪
♪ We'll be okay. ♪
(cheering and applause)
Oh, thank God.
(laughs)
I have before me a buttload
of angry letters
from members
of the Animal Husbandry Club,
their parents, state
and local politicians,
the National Autism Association,
as well as One Million Moms.
Although in actuality, there
aren't a million of them.
There's really only 100,000,
but each and every one of 'em
is an uptight bitch.
I hardly need to tell you
that this
will mark the end
of your extracurricular
musical experiment.
I understand.
I'm sorry about this, Sue.
It won't happen again.
Will.
Will, Will.
Wait one second, please.
This isn't over yet.
We can go to the hockey team,
and we can do Glee on Ice.
Please. Stop.
Look, it's finished.
The glee club is over.
All I want to do is just get
through this week
and-and try to enjoy graduation.
I've accepted it.
It's done.
Artie Pants, I need you.
Oh, finally.
I'm in love with you, too.
Just give me a second.
I'm gonna send Kitty
- a breakup text.
- What?
No, this is about Will.
Oh. Y-You're in love with Will?
No. I'm not in love with anyone.
Get your camera equipment,
meet me in the Spanish room.
(clears throat)
(Pink's "Just Give Me a Reason"
begins)
♪ Right from the start ♪
♪ You were a thief,
you stole my heart ♪
♪ And I, your willing victim ♪
♪ I let you see
the parts of me ♪
♪ That weren't
all that pretty ♪
♪ And with every touch,
you fixed them ♪
♪ Now you've been talking
in your sleep ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Things you never say to me ♪
♪ Tell me
that you've had enough ♪
♪ Of our love ♪
♪ Our love ♪
♪ Just give me a reason,
just a little bit's enough ♪
♪ Just a second,
we're not broken, just bent,
♪ And we can learn
to love again ♪
♪ It's in the stars ♪
♪ It's been written in the scars
on our hearts ♪
♪ We're not broken, just bent ♪
♪ And we can learn
to love again ♪
♪ I'm sorry,
I don't understand ♪
♪ Where all this
is coming from ♪
♪ I thought ♪
♪ That we were fine ♪
♪ Yeah, but this is happenin' ♪
♪ You've been having
real bad dreams ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ You used to lie
so close to me ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
BOTH: ♪ There's nothing
more than empty sheets ♪
♪ Between our love ♪
♪ Our love ♪
♪ Love ♪
BOTH:
♪ Just give me a reason ♪
♪ Just a little bit's enough,
just a second ♪
♪ We're not broken, just bent ♪
♪ And we can learn
to love again ♪
♪ It's in the stars ♪
♪ It's still written
in the scars ♪
♪ On our hearts that we're not
broken, just bent ♪
♪ And we can learn
to love again ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ah. ♪
(applause)
I'd like to make
an announcement.
Puck has asked me to
go out with him
as boyfriend and girlfriend.
'Cause, you know,
we've never actually dated.
So, um, I decided to throw
caution to the wind and say yes.
Wait, what?
Yeah, I-I can't make
any promises,
but, you know,
you're the only guy
who's actually been okay
with me just being myself.
Well, once you've seen a baby come
out of a girl's magic garden,
everything else is
easily acceptable.
QUINN: I think I love you, Puck.
And I know
it's not gonna be easy, what
with me in New Haven and you...
who knows where.
But I'd rather do hard with you
than easy with somebody else.
Wanky.
Santana, for once,
I'd appreciate it
if you'd keep your
inevitable snark to yourself.
No, no. Look,
I got to be honest,
I really like this pairing.
(chuckles) Come here.
(cheering)
Well, in many ways,
that brings us full circle,
which is perfect because
that was officially...
the last song that will ever
be sung in Glee Club.
We all have more songs to sing.
We just can't sing them
in here anymore.
(sighs) Glee Club...
is officially over.
Thank you, guys.
It's been an honor.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
RACHEL:
Hey.
So, we don't actually
know your name
because this video was
made before you were born,
but you are the son or
daughter of our teacher.
KURT:
Will Schuester.
You know, many of us don't get
to know our dads as men
until they're older,
past middle age, maybe
a little beaten down by life.
But we want to tell you
about what your dad was like
when he was young.
When he could dance
like Fred Astaire.
MARLEY:
And sing like Michael Bublé.
He was an amazing teacher.
Your dad and I almost hooked up,
which means
I could have been your mom.
Hit me up when you want
your first tattoo.
I know a guy.
If it wasn't for your dad,
I would've never been
Prom Queen,
though that was kind of
a bad experience for me
when I think about it.
But I still would've been living
my life with a fake stutter.
You had to be there.
Okay, it may seem
a little weird to you,
but back here in the Dark Ages,
it was still crazy
for girls to love girls
and guys to love guys,
but your dad made sure
that we felt safe
loving whoever we chose.
BRITTANY: He does this magic trick
where he pulls a duck out of a hat.
You should have him
show you sometime.
SAM:  Your dad had a
passion for teaching.
He really loved that moment
when he connected with a kid.
And he was prone to
overemotional (laughs)
yet often inspiring pep talks.
To put it simply, I was not
a particularly nice person.
(book thumps)
That sweater's legit.
And then your dad came along,
and I became a man who was kind
a relatively large portion
of the time.
I can say without a doubt
that your dad saved my life.
Little Hepburn and Tracy
wouldn't have a daddy
if it wasn't for your dad.
Those are the names of my kids
who aren't born yet either.
We used a surrogate.
I donated the egg.
UNIQUE:
In the whole wide world,
you'll never meet a man
more accepting
and open to nature in all
its wonders than your father.
He's a gem.
SUE:
The best thing about your dad
and that horrible perm of his
is that no matter
how talentless, misshapen, ugly,
miserable
or sexually ambiguous you are,
he will still love you
unconditionally.
ARTIE: Your dad made sure
that everyone in this school
understood what it was like
to see the world
from this chair,
and he helped me see
all that I could be
even though I was in it.
He is the most genuine...
honest...
...kind...
generous...
...sand dollar...
amazing man any of us
have ever met.
He loved and looked
after every one of us
with as much care and concern
as he does for you.
We love your dad.
We love him very, very much,
and no matter where we are
or what we're doing,
he's with us.
Because we have his name
tattooed in our hearts.
(Journey's "Don't Stop
Believin'" begins)
♪ Da, da, da, da,
da, da, da, da ♪
♪ Da, da, da, da, da, da,
da, da ♪
♪ Da, da, da, da... ♪
♪ Just a small town girl ♪
♪ Livin' in a lonely world ♪
♪ She took the midnight train
going anywhere ♪
♪ Just a city boy ♪
♪ Born and raised
in South Detroit ♪
♪ He took the midnight train ♪
♪ Going anywhere ♪
♪ Da, da, da, da,
da, da, da, da ♪
♪ Da, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ A singer in a smoky room ♪
♪ A smell of wine
and cheap perfume ♪
♪ For a smile they can
share the night ♪
♪ It goes on and on
and on and on ♪
♪ Strangers waiting ♪
♪ Up and down the boulevard ♪
♪ Their shadows ♪
♪ Searching in the night ♪
♪ Da, da ♪
♪ Streetlight people ♪
♪ Livin' just to find emotion ♪
♪ Hiding ♪
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ In the night ♪
♪ Working hard to get my fill ♪
♪ Everybody wants a thrill ♪
♪ Paying anything
to roll the dice ♪
♪ Just one more time ♪
♪ Some will win ♪
♪ Some will lose ♪
♪ Some were born
to sing the blues ♪
♪ Oh, the movie never ends ♪
♪ It goes on and
on and on and on ♪
♪ Strangers ♪
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Up and down the boulevard ♪
♪ Their shadows searching ♪
♪ In the night ♪
♪ In the night! ♪
♪ Streetlight ♪
♪ People ♪
♪ People! ♪
♪ Livin' just to find emotion ♪
♪ Hiding ♪
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ In the night ♪
♪ Don't stop ♪
♪ Believin' ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Hold on to that feeling ♪
♪ Streetlight ♪
♪ People, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Don't stop ♪
♪ Believin' ♪
♪ Hold on to that feeling ♪
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ Streetlight ♪
♪ People ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Don't stop! ♪
(whooping, applause)
(indistinct cheering, laughing)
You done good, Holly Holliday.
You, too, babe.
Our work is done here.
We did it flawlessly and
looked flawless while doing it.
Amen.
Hey, do you want
to go get drunk,
rob a bank and sail
around the world
on one of those
gayboy cruise ships?
We'd be the only women there
and get all the attention.
(slow gasp)
I thought you'd never ask.
(both giggle)
Kitty, when you
see me in the hall,
will you say hello?
Of course. Someone's
got to tell you your shoes
don't match your purse.
Cheerio, please.
My shoes always match.
I cannot believe that Sue
Sylvester finally shut us down.
She won.
She actually won.
You guys, you're gonna
miss my big moment.
Get your butts
to the auditorium.
Hang on a second.
Sue Sylvester didn't win.
Maybe she took away Glee Club,
but she'll never
take away what we had.
We were part
of something incredible.
It was more than that.
You know, we helped
each other become
better people in this room.
No one can ever
take that away from us.
(sighs)
Come here. Bring it in, guys.
Come here.
You remember Superman?
I do, that was good.
That was good. This broom is
poking me in places I don't...
Arthur Abrams.
(applause)
(whooping, cheering)
Blaine Anderson.
Tina Cohen-Chang.
Sam Evans.
Rebecca Jackson.
(whooping, cheering)
Blaine, you guys, I can't
go to New York with you.
Tina Cohen-Crazy. You can't
get cold feet on us now.
No, it's not that.
I was gonna tell you later, but
the Dean of Admissions from
Brown called me this morning...
And you got in? I got in.
I'm going to Brown!
Oh! Tina. Congratulations.
Wow, that is great.
(laughing): Thank you.
And, finally...
Brittany S. Pierce.
(cheering, applause)
I called in some
favors with Sue.
I figure that everybody deserves
a high school graduation,
even if it's a year late.
(kiss) (exclaims)
You guys, I'm graduating.
(whooping)
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present to you
the William McKinley High
graduating class of 2013.
(whooping)
Brittany, I have
to tell you something.
I think I've made
a huge mistake.
You don't want to run away
with me, do you. What?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Of course I do.
(groans) I was doing some
research on Lesbos island,
and it turns out that it's not
chock-full of lesbians.
It's full of German
tourists, so,
I bought us our return tickets.
I think that we should
go to Lesbos first,
and then Hawaii
for a couple of weeks,
and then come home.
Well, I don't want
to go back to MIT
and I can't return to Lima.
I want you to come
to New York with me.
Is that a yes?
Yes.
(soft laugh)
(sighs)
Here for one last
verbal beatdown?
These are my last two
Razzle Dazzle Fruit
Punch wine coolers
from my cellar.
Company went out of
business back in the '80s,
and I've been saving them
for a special occasion.
Well, what could be more special
than the glee club's funeral?
Mm.
Well... (exhales)
You finally won.
Honestly, I-I don't get the
way you see the world, William,
but I got to give you this:
whatever it is you
did in this room,
you changed a lot of kids'
lives for the better.
And your own.
As you know,
I find both of your
spouses intolerable
and bony, but at least
this one is kind to you.
Yeah, I'm not gonna miss this.
Oh, I am.
Nobody ever went the
distance with Sue Sylvester
the way you did, Will.
My whole life
I've been searching for
a worthy adversary.
(sighs)
I'm gonna miss the fight.
I could have done more.
There's still so many
more kids out there.
Well, who says you can't?
Listen, William, you were
a horrible history teacher
and you were a worse
Spanish teacher.
If you're going to be
of any good to anybody,
you need to be
coaching a glee club.
Which is why I got
you an interview
for the open slot
at Carmel High.
Vocal Adrenaline?
Think of what you could
accomplish with a real budget.
And without somebody like me
constantly trying
to take you down?
Wow.
I mean, tha-that's
really amazing, Sue,
but they're our mortal enemies.
There is no "our"
anymore, William.
We're in the middle of
the new computer lab.
You did what you could do here.
And that was much more
than I will ever care to admit.
But it's really over.
It's only an interview.
You could always blow it.
Oh, God, that's awful.
Yeah, that's why they
went out of business.
I'll give you a minute.
(door closes)
(sighs)
RACHEL (echoes):  Being great at
something's going to change it.
Being a part of something
special makes you
- special, right? - PUCK: I was
tossing kids into Dumpsters.
ARTIE:  I had never
kissed a girl before.
KURT:  I wasn't honest
about who I was.
Five...
MERCEDES:  And Glee Club will
never end, Mr. Shue, because
you are Glee Club.
KURT:
'Cause in this room
it doesn't matter
if you're gay or straight.
What matters is that
we're friends.
SANTANA:
The struggle continues, but...
at least I know I'm not alone.
RACHEL:  If I'd let you down
when you needed me the most,
I'd never forgive myself.
FINN:  We went around the
room and everybody said
what they wanted
to win this thing for,
and we all said the same thing.
We want to win this for you.
(echoing chatter, laughing)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com