So here's what you missed
on Glee...
Consider this the opening salvo
of World War Sue.
I'm asking you for your help
to destroy the Glee Club.
I will not stop
until your little Glee Club
is annihilated into oblivion.
I swear to sweet holy Satan
I will end you.
And that's what you missed
on Glee.
All right, let's see what
you guys have been working on.
(Clean Bandit's "Rather Be"
begins)
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, whoa ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ We're a thousand miles
from comfort ♪
♪ We have traveled
land and sea ♪
♪ But as long
as you are with me ♪
♪ There's no place
I'd rather be ♪
♪ I will wait forever ♪
♪ Exalted in the scene ♪
♪ As long as I am with you ♪
♪ My heart continues to beat ♪
♪ With every step I take ♪
♪ Kyoto to the Bay,
strolling so casually ♪
♪ Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum ♪
♪ We're different and the same ♪
♪ Gave you another name ♪
♪ Switch up the batteries ♪
♪ If you gave me a chance,
I would take it ♪
♪ It's a shot in the dark,
but I'll make it ♪
♪ Know with all of your heart
you can't shake me ♪
♪ When I am with you,
there's no place I'd rather be ♪
♪ No, no, no,
no place I'd rather be ♪
♪ When I am with you,
there's no place ♪
♪ I'd rather be ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Be ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ If you gave me a chance,
I would take it ♪
♪ It's a shot in the dark,
but I'll make it ♪
♪ Know with all of your heart
you can't shake me ♪
♪ When I am with you,
there's no place I'd rather be ♪
♪ Be... ♪
♪ No place I'd rather be ♪
♪ No, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ When I am with you ♪
♪ There's no place
I'd rather be. ♪
All right!
Great job, guys.
That was really impressive.
Thank you so much.
Okay, now I know you guys
probably still have
vacation brain, but any pointers
would really help us out.
Guys, thoughts?
What is going on with you, guys?
There was a fire at Dalton.
It burned to the ground.
There's nothing left.
Academy's gone.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(school bell ringing)
Thank you, everyone, for coming
to this emergency
Glee Club meeting.
Now, as I'm sure everyone
in this room is aware of by now,
Dalton Academy has burned
to the ground.
Now, I've gathered you all
here today because Blaine, Kurt
and myself have
been talking and...
although just a moment ago,
we could only see
the Warblers as our competition,
now it's time for us to see them
as a friend and ally.
We have made the decision
to make some lemonade
out of these lemons
and join together
as a show choir super group.
This is an opportunity
for all of us.
We need them just as much
as they need us.
Where's Rachel?
Shouldn't she be here for this?
Uh, she is in New York
on some business,
but she'll be back soon.
But she is totally on board
with this plan.
Well, okay.
(cheering)
Thank you so much, Mr.
Schuester, for your generosity.
It is in times like these that
we can find comfort in the
kindness of our friends.
It's gonna be a challenge
for all of us to move forward,
but I know that we can do this.
And I think it's so awesome
that the Warblers' passion
for show choir is
stronger than ever,
'cause we're really
gonna need that strength
and commitment to not only
win sectionals,
but to take it all the way
to nationals this year!
Come on, guys!
(cheering)
(whoops) Yeah!
I'm sorry,
but the aroma of overly
dry-cleaned polyester uniforms
just wafted into my office
and up my extremely
sensitive nose.
And I can see why now.
The Glee Club is hosting
the Lima Gay Men's Chorus.
Oh, no, she didn't!
BLAINE: Sue...
you know very well that
these are the Warblers.
They're at McKinley now.
They're part
of the New Directions!
Oh, they most certainly are not.
And they're going to take their
freshly scrubbed cherubic faces
and get the hell
out of my school.
They're staying, Sue.
I've already cleared it
with the superintendent.
How dare you go over my head!
Well, I will just have
to get it un-cleared
with Senate Majority
Leader Mitch McConnell,
who I met recently
on the Cayman Islands
at a leadership retreat
and turtle hunt.
He's also a priority contact
on my brand-new
cutting-edge Apple Watch.
Now, fly away, Warblers.
Don't listen to her. Stay.
Leave!
Stay!
There's a good chance
we won't be rehearsing today.
Make no mistake, William.
When the final bell tolls,
I will have plucked
every Warbler feather
out of this school.
Doomsday has arrived.
Bring it, Suzy Q.
Don't call me that.
- Suzy Q.
- Stop it.
Suzy Q.
What's the Q stand for?
You monster, Coach!
Why wouldn't you let
the Warblers
join the New Directions!?
It's so unfair!
Honey, Becky, I cannot
understand a word you're saying.
I think she's saying it's unfair
that you won't let the Warblers
- join the Glee Club?
- For crying out loud.
The superintendent
said it was okay!
And "The superintendent
said it was okay."
Well, the superintendent
may have said it was okay,
but the president pro tem
of the United States Senate,
Orrin G. Hatch,
begs to differ.
Oh, save the drama
for your mama!
The Utah Republican
agrees with me
that the Glee Club is stupid
and that the notion that
two rival show choirs
would suddenly just join
forces out of nowhere
is both morally repugnant
and convenient.
I'm not gonna let you
get away with this!
Becky Jackson,
do not stand in my way,
lest I brand you a traitor.
I've performed unspeakable acts
of loyalty for you.
She said she's performed
unspeakable acts of loyalty.
Really? Like what?
BECKY:
I shoplifted for you!
I perjured myself
before a grand jury.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth so help you God?
I swear.
I don't even know why,
but hurting kids
with a burned-down school
is my moral limit!
You're evil, Sue Sylvester!
And you're not
my friend anymore.
Becky Jackson, don't you
trundle away from me.
You toddle out of this office,
and you will never come back!
(Becky crying)
You.
You did this.
You turned her against me.
No, she turned on you
all by herself.
Okay.
RACHEL: It's hard to believe
it's only been a year
since I walked the halls
of NYADA, but I feel like
a completely different person.
I used to be just like them...
Naive and eager...
And I used to see this place
as just another stepping stone
on the way to bigger things.
But I'm not that girl anymore.
I've been through the fire
and clawed my way back,
and now I'm here to ask
for a second chance
from the one woman
who can do it.
And you know what?
She might laugh in my face,
and I don't even care, 'cause
I know one thing for sure.
I can do this.
- Rachel Berry?
- Mm-hmm.
Madame Tibideaux is ready
to see you now, briefly.
Okay.
But I wouldn't get my hopes up.
She's been looking
forward to this.
(phone rings)
You can go in now.
Thank you.
Butt Chin?
I... mean, William.
What are you doing here?
What a wonderful surprise.
I'm just as surprised
as you are, Sue.
HARRIS:
Actually,
Principal Sylvester, I...
hope you'll, uh...
take the formality
of this meeting seriously.
I need to make sure
you understand
what I am telling you today.
And Mr. Schuester
is a witness,
as well as an aggrieved party.
Well, I'm happy to
clear up any confusion.
Something has come
to my attention,
something grave and...
almost beyond...
I saw your hurt locker, Sue.
I can't believe my eyes.
Sue Sylvester keeps
the keys to this place?
Now, in executive coaching,
they train us to be
ready for the most
extreme circumstances.
But what I saw next
chilled me to my marrow.
Myron?
My own nephew?
He's just an innocent bystander,
a tween genius who...
loves sequins too much.
(bell gongs)
What?
I am all for young love,
but, uh...
but this is wrong, right?
I could've overlooked,
oh, so many things,
but what I saw next
left me no other choice.
What's this?
(gasps)
Sweet...
Sue Sylvester?
I don't see how my...
personal forms of
recreation, uh,
have negatively impacted
my job performance.
I inspire people
by stoking my own
embers, if you will.
And I stand by,
and am very proud,
of what good I have
done for this school.
And if I think if you were
to ask any McKinley parent
or student or any reader
of the U.S. News
and World Report...
I take my responsibilities
seriously, Principal Sylvester.
And clearly...
a part of you does as well.
(clears throat) But after I saw
your locker of vendetta
and your...
pornographic spread,
I cannot
allow you near
the students of McKinley.
Or... any other young people,
anywhere, ever.
It is with profound regret
that I terminate
your employment.
I'm sorry, wha...?
I'm sorry, what
did... you say?
You're fired.
Hello, America,
I'm Geraldo Rivera.
Washington, Jefferson,
Madison, Sylvester.
My guest tonight
is an American treasure...
Or at least, she was.
Champion cheerleading coach.
Sue Sylvester has led a life
chock-full of winning.
Lately, Sue, it seems like
you've been smacked around
by the loser stick.
Is that right?
Well, Geraldo, uh,
despite being one of the scions
of American education,
I have recently
lost my position,
my financial security
and my legacy
has been tarnished.
And today, I intend
to set the record straight.
But, Sue, reading your record
of accomplishments,
they seem almost
too good to be true.
And when our fact-checkers
pored through them, Sue,
they found out that
most of them are made up.
I beg your pardon?
Well, for instance, we learned
that you were not born
in the Panama Canal Zone,
you did not fight
in the Falklands War,
you did not play any role in
extracting the dictator Noriega,
nor is there any evidence
whatsoever
that you were ever waterboarded.
Now, Geraldo, I'm gonna
stop you right there.
I waterboarded myself.
You did not direct the TV movie.
The Dallas Cowboys Cheerleaders,
you don't have
Trinidadian roots,
nor were you ever,
even for the shortest time,
the tambourine player
for Wilson Phillips.
I played tambourine
Geraldo, I-I'd
like to respond
to some of these allegations.
You've claimed to have
romantic involvements
with Dan Quayle,
Stephen Baldwin, Matt Lauer,
Johnny Cochran, David Boreanaz
and the drummer
from Jimmy Eat World.
All of these men have
categorically denied this.
I dated all of the members
of Jimmy Eat World.
It just begs the question, Sue:
are you a compulsive liar?
I mean, you've publically
and repeatedly claimed,
for example,
that the singer Michael Bolton
is the father of your child.
Well, that is absolutely true.
Sue Sylvester, our producers
have found out otherwise.
Take a look.
I've never met Sue Sylvester
or heard of this
"ThunderBolton69."
I only heard about her
when my lawyers
informed me that she had been
going around saying
I had bought her an island
where we had a years-long
torrid affair,
and that I was
the father of her child.
I honestly think the woman has
some sort of mental illness.
Sue, do you want
to respond to this?
Fine.
I will admit I can't prove
that Michael Bolton
is the father of my child.
Let's hear from another
of Sue's alleged lovers
to find out what he has to say.
Look, I don't blame Sue for
falling head over heels for me.
I mean, she's got eyes.
But she mistook a little
grab-ass in a condo
for true love.
That bitch is crazy.
She had me kidnapped!
And then she signed me up
for these dating sites:
Farmers Only,
BlackPeopleMeet.com.
And the only thing
that she put in my profile
was that my boobs were like
elephant ears.
Sue, it just makes me wonder:
are you okay?
Do you have a history
of profound mental illness?
What I have a
history of, Geraldo,
is devoting my entire life
to the students
of McKinley High.
You know, when I graduated
from the Sorbonne,
I was recruited
by every single one of Wall
Street's top investment banks.
Halliburton wanted
me for their COO.
One time, a very drunk
Boris Yeltsin called to tell me
that if I wanted Russia,
he would just give it to me.
I could've had wealth
and power beyond
my wildest dreams!
But instead, I chose a career
filled with service
and sacrifice
in order to nurture and
enrich the delicate minds
of America's children.
Since day one, they have been
and will continue to be
my number one priority.
Sue, a lot of these things
that you have just mentioned
seem like lies to me.
I visited McKinley
High School to talk
to some of these students,
and they tell
a much different story.
She slashed the tires
on my wheelchair 17 times.
She swapped out my weave glue
with mayonnaise.
She made a fake elevator
which she trapped us in
and then pumped airborne
drugs through the vents
and built a small robot
that forced us to kiss
while it watched
and made noises.
She put a live bear in my house.
Sue Sylvester came
all the way to New York City
to see me in my opening night
on Broadway...  Funny Girl...
Just so that she could
walk out halfway through
and have sex
all over my apartment.
She cut my dreads off.
GERALDO: Why does she hate
the Glee Club so much?
Do you have any explanation?
She's had it out
for the Glee Club
from the very beginning.
Before we were around,
the Cheerios! Were the stars
of this school,
and then we showed up,
and she's never forgiven us
for stealing her thunder.
Geraldo Rivera,
this is an outrage!
This is slander!
These are all lies orchestrated
by one Will Schuester!
Judas!
This may come as
a surprise to you, Sue,
but it was not Will Schuester
who tipped us off.
It was someone else.
It was Becky Jackson.
BECKY:
Who is Becky Jackson?
America's dying to know.
Well, I could tell you
who she is.
She's a poet, a lover
and a dreamer.
I know, because
Becky Jackson is me.
Becky always told me stories
about Coach Sylvester,
but that's what I thought
they were: just stories.
I was like, wait, her
secretary's an actual convict?
She pushes kids down the stairs?
And she was my best friend,
and I supported
anything she did.
And when Dalton Academy
burned down,
she refused to let gay Blaine
and the Warblers
join in the Glee Club.
And I knew it was time
to blow the whistle.
I am so much happier
now that I am free from Sue,
and I got a hot boyfriend.
He takes me there every time.
And all of those
Cheerios! Out there,
quit being such basic bitches.
Don't let Sue Sylvester
control you.
You deserve better.
(newscast music playing)
We'll be right back.
Get out of my face!
I'm sorry this isn't going
- the way you intended.
- Not really.
Are we rolling?
We're not rolling, are we?
No, no, we're in commercial
right now.
Geraldo, the foundations
of my entire life
have been destroyed.
All I ever wanted
was to be a champion,
and to inspire others
to be champions.
That's why I chose a career
in cheerleading.
Just wanted to succeed
by watching my girls succeed.
Tough world out there, Geraldo.
I wanted them to be tougher.
Smarter.
I wish you had interviewed some
of my more successful Cheerios!,
like Quinn Fabray,
currently enrolled at Yale;
Brittany S. Pierce,
math prodigy, M.I.T.
Santana Lopez was
a Broadway understudy
and now could have
a very promising career
as a high-class prostitute.
We did actually
reach out to them.
All three declined to comment.
Wait.
Are the cameras rolling?
Yeah, I lied. I lied.
We didn't go to commercial.
The camera's been rolling
the whole time.
Classy, Rivera;
that's very classy.
You know what this is?
This is
a character assassination.
This interview is a hack job
unworthy of the name Fox News,
a global brand known worldwide
for being fair and balanced.
And it's unworthy of you,
my friend.
I agreed to sit down with you
because you're a titan
of American television,
known for weird,
shirtless selfies,
getting chaired in the face
by a white supremacist,
and not finding anything
whatsoever in Al Capone's vault.
When I took the reins
at McKinley High,
it was a cesspool of hate.
And it was my vigilance
and tough love
that turned that place
into a no-bully zone
where the most vulnerable
were protected.
Well, Sue, we have an interview
with, uh, someone who does agree
with your assessment,
your position.
We are choosing to protect
their identity though...
The voice has been altered.
Take a look.
(deep distorted voice): I'll say
it till the cows come home:
Sue Sylvester saved my life.
I was in an abusive marriage
to a man they call Cooter
the football recruiter,
and Sue supported me
leaving him.
Also, when I chose
to transition,
Sue supported that, too.
Hey, wait,
why are the lights off?
(deep distorted voice): I'm not
trying to hide my identity.
I'm proud to stand up
for Sue Sylvester.
I am as I am, Geraldo Rivera.
And I refuse to apologize to you
or anybody else.
Am I a tough customer?
You bet your bottom dollar I am.
But that's the way I was raised.
As you may or may not know,
my parents were Nazi hunters.
And the lies continue.
No, we weren't Nazi hunters.
Her father and I
just told her that
so it would give us a good
excuse not to be around her.
Little Susan was a biter.
She was nasty
from the day she was born.
She even bit my lip
on her way out.
It was weird.
What kind of a newborn
has a full set of teeth?
What can I say?
From the minute
I laid eyes on her,
I knew that Susan
would always be
the daughter that
I just couldn't love.
"The daughter that I
just couldn't love."
That must be hard to hear.
"The daughter that
I just couldn't love."
♪ ♪
So who is Sue Sylvester?
Really?
Is she a lying,
vindictive psychopath?
Is she a career criminal
who has endangered the lives
of countless children
and actually deserves
to be behind bars?
For the final word, let's go
to one of Sue's coworkers
and show choir director
William Schuester.
Until next time,
I'm Geraldo Rivera reporting.
Have I had my problems with Sue?
(laughs)
You bet.
She has made my life miserable
for as long as I can remember.
(sighs)
But that's because
she's a fighter
and someone who refuses
to betray her own values.
And I'd be lying if I said
her cutthroat spirit
didn't keep everyone around here
on their toes,
striving to work harder
and be better.
Oh, don't get me wrong.
She is not a nice person.
But the fact is
she's an outstanding teacher
and a born leader...
and McKinley High is
a worse place without her.
She deserves a second chance,
and that's exactly what
I told the superintendent.
(laughs softly)
I'm going to bat for you, Sue.
(dark, dramatic music playing)
Okay, that's enough, thank you.
Thank you for being the
soundtrack for my melancholia.
Hello, "Mother."
Hello, Susan.
Thank you for
agreeing to meet me.
I know this must be
difficult for you.
"Difficult" doesn't begin
to describe it, Mother.
You've been lying
to me for years.
Susan, does it really matter
that your father
and I were working
in the accounts receivable
department at Ma Bell
while you thought we were
out chasing Nazis? (Laughs)
That's not the lie
I'm talking about.
You never loved me.
No, technically,
that's not a lie,
because I never really told you
that I did love you.
You know, it would be very
easy to be angry at you.
But I've just spent
the last few days
at the Greater Columbus
Convention Center
attending Oprah's "The Life
You Want Weekend" weekend.
And there I learned
that relationships
are a two-way street.
I realize I wasn't
the easiest kid.
My earliest memories are of
trying to light you on fire.
I want to apologize for
all the booby traps.
And the biting.
Oh, Susan, your father
and I really did love you.
We just had an odd way of
showing it, that's all.
We never did get the hang
of that parenting thing.
I always wanted you to
do what I wanted to do,
but you wouldn't have
anything to do with it.
Oh, I remember how much I loved
those old movie musicals,
and you couldn't stand them.
Every time I took
you to a matinee,
you'd start crying and
screaming and biting
and trying to set me on fire.
Five minutes in, I realized
I had to take you home.
Mother, I'm sorry,
but sitting through a musical
is torture for me.
How do people
just burst into song?
How does everybody
just magically know the lyrics?
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
I'm the one who should
be saying I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I never was the
mother I should have been.
I'm sorry I lied to you.
I'm sorry I missed
out on your life.
It's okay to be
angry, sweetheart.
You're going to be angry
for quite a while.
I just hope that someday
you and I can sit down,
have a cup of coffee
or something,
if not as mother
and daughter, then...
just as friends.
I would like that.
Hold on.
I have a question for you.
What?
Were you and Dad ever in love?
Well, of course we were.
We fell in love
when we first met,
on a trolley.
And you would like to sing
about it, wouldn't you?
Yes.
Then I will sing with you.
Well, you hate musicals.
But I love the sound
of my own voice.
Okay, band nerds.
"Trolley Song," A flat.
(trolley bell dings)
("The Trolley Song" from
Meet Me in St. Louis begins)
♪ With my high-starched collar
and my high-topped shoes ♪
♪ And my hair piled
high upon my head ♪
♪ I went to lose a jolly
hour on the trolley ♪
♪ And lost my
heart instead ♪
♪ With his light brown derby
and his bright green tie ♪
♪ He was quite
the handsomest of men ♪
♪ I started to yen ♪
♪ So I counted to ten ♪
♪ Then I counted to ten again ♪
♪ Clang, clang, clang
went the trolley ♪
♪ Ding, ding, ding
went the bell ♪
♪ Zing, zing, zing
went my heartstrings ♪
♪ From the moment I saw him,
I fell ♪
♪ Chug, chug, chug
went the motor ♪
♪ Bump, bump, bump
went the brakes ♪
♪ Thump, thump, thump
went my heartstrings ♪
♪ When he smiled,
I could feel the car shake ♪
♪ He tipped his hat
and took a seat ♪
♪ He said he hoped he hadn't
stepped upon my feet ♪
♪ He asked my name,
I held my breath ♪
♪ I couldn't speak because
he scared me half to death ♪
♪ Buzz, buzz, buzz
went the buzzer ♪
♪ Plop, plop, plop
went the wheels ♪
♪ Stop, stop, stop
went my heartstrings ♪
♪ As he started to leave ♪
♪ I took hold of his sleeve
with my hand ♪
♪ And as if it were planned ♪
♪ He stayed on with me ♪
♪ And it was grand ♪
♪ Just to stand with his hand
holding mine ♪
♪ To the end of the line... ♪
♪ Zing, zing, zing, zing ♪
♪ Went my heart.... ♪
(music ends)
(laughs):
Oh, oh!
Thank you, Susan.
Okay, let's just make
sure nothing like this
ever happens again.
I promise.
So Carmen Tibideaux
actually told you
to get out of her office?
Look, you're missing
the point, okay?
She said that she could see that
I was humble, that I was sorry,
which means that
I can't give up.
There's still a chance.
Rachel, I think
that you may be reading
- a little too much into this.
- I don't think so.
Yeah, I mean, anyone named Madam
Tibideaux doesn't really seem
like a woman who
changes her mind
or stays in human
form for too long.
I always thought NYADA
was a school for witches.
What I think Sam
is trying to say is
that you're just reaching
a little bit.
If you remember, I got
kicked out of NYADA, too.
Carmen cut me herself.
Like, with a knife
because she wanted your blood
for potions?
No, because she's not a witch.
Look, you guys,
I could see it in her eyes.
She was moved momentarily.
And for that moment,
I saw myself back in NYADA,
back on track before my life
got completely derailed.
Which is why I'm writing
her this letter.
And I'm putting all of
my humiliation out there,
all of the bad reviews
and the good reviews,
a-and the good Glee Club
reviews, and she's gonna see it,
she's gonna give me
another chance,
and I'm gonna get back in.
Look, we're all
behind you 100 percent
getting your life back on track,
but I think
that you clinging on to NYADA,
(phone vibrates)
I don't think...
Wait a minute.
This-this is
a-a New York number.
I think this could be her.
I have to go t-take this.
Hello, this is Rachel.
Okay, I don't think
this is healthy.
Yeah, I don't think
these are even
actual press clippings
about the Glee Club.
These are just from
Jacob Ben Israel's blog.
Guys, I think we should
just be good friends
and support her
about going back to college.
Shh, she's coming.
What is it?
Was it NYADA?
That was the producer
for the Russell Simmons musical
of the audition
that you put me up for.
I-I don't know,
I totally forgot about it,
but... I got it.
A-And they-they want me
to start in, like, a few weeks.
Oh, my God!
Rachel, see,
your life is already
back on track.
I totally forgot about it...
Oh, congratulations.
Thank you.
What about going back to school?
You know what,
maybe you guys are right.
I don't need to be just forcing
this to happen with school.
You know, I don't have
to go to NYADA.
This is really exciting.
I'm gonna go tell Kurt.
And a-five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
(slowing):
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven...
Come on!
This choreography is about
as rudimentary as it gets.
And you guys aren't even close.
Okay, that-that is enough, guys.
We're a team, and a team is
comprised of people
with individual strengths
and weaknesses.
Are we a team?
Because look at us.
Half of us are wearing uniforms
from a different school.
KURT:
She's right.
There is a major disconnect.
We've got to make some changes.
Teams wear uniforms...
Better grab a blazer.
You guys would look
great in blazers.
This is McKinley, dude.
Yeah, your sexist empire
doesn't even exist.
Our look is iconic.
Synonymous with
tradition and excellence.
Not to mention,
it elevates anyone who wears it
to sex-symbol status.
Wait, I'll take one.
Women love these.
Do they?
Come on, guys,
we've welcomed you
to our school with open arms.
Semi-open.
You can't expect us
to adopt your uniforms, too.
But, you know,
it would save us the effort
of having to try
and find a new look.
Okay, look, you guys,
we've had a lot of success
with this in the past,
so we'll just give you
our uniforms
to wear during the competition.
Red T-shirts and Converse
are not uniforms.
You have costumes.
WILL:
Guys, enough!
We need to have some
unity here, okay?
Look, you attend McKinley now.
I'm really sorry, guys,
but the blazers need to go.
We are grateful that you've
welcomed us to your school,
and to be performing
with you guys,
but we didn't choose
to come here.
You always talk about
how important Glee Club
and-and McKinley is to you;
well, we felt the same way
about Dalton.
And then we watched it
burn to the ground.
These jackets
aren't just uniforms.
They're a tribute.
A last surviving artifact of a
place that meant so much to us.
It's all that we have left.
You pumpkins got bigger problems
than your costumes.
I just got word that Sue is the
new coach of Vocal Adrenaline.
(piano plays dramatic melody)
So you get fired
from your old job,
and despite hating show choir
and never having
coached it before,
you're our new coach.
Correction.
I may be your new coach.
If I deem you worthy
of crushing the New Directions!
With a national championship
you will be guaranteed
under my tutelage.
And how exactly do we
prove we're worthy?
By surviving the
Barf-tron 200.
- The what?
- The Barf-tron 200...
is a single consecutive
five-hour workout routine
designed to invoke
maximum nausea.
200 box jumps, 200 pull-ups,
200 burpies, 200 wall balls,
200 double-unders,
and 200 consecutive run-throughs
of Frank Stallone's
"Far From Over,"
made famous by John Travolta's
triumphant performance
in Staying Alive,
the best sequel of all time.
(Frank Stallone's "Far From
Over" begins) ♪ Da, da-da ♪
♪ Da, da ♪
♪ Da-da, da, da, da,
da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ This is the end ♪
♪ You made your choice,
and now my chance is over... ♪
Come on!
♪ I thought I was in ♪
♪ You put me down and say ♪
♪ I'm going nowhere... ♪
I am pushing you harder
than you've ever
been pushed before.
♪ Save me, darling ♪
♪ I am down,
but I am far from over ♪
♪ Give me something ♪
♪ I need it all,
'cause I am running over... ♪
SUE:
You think this is hard?
Try taking down a gazelle
with your bare hands!
That's hard!
(rhythmic humming)
We're only halfway there!
♪ Da, da-da ♪
♪ Da, da ♪
♪ Da, da, da, da, da... ♪
I am now pushing you harder
than the level at which
I was previously pushing you!
(rhythmic humming)
That doesn't look hard at all!
Just passing the ball
back and forth?
Sit up straight
and engage those abs!
♪ Save me, darling ♪
♪ I am down,
but I am far from over ♪
♪ Give me something ♪
♪ I need it all
'cause I am running over... ♪
Hey, ladies,
good luck with menopause
if this is how fit you are
at the peak of your physicality!
You should be ashamed
of yourselves!
(rhythmic humming)
(music builds)
(music ends)
All right, everyone, take five.
And then we're doing it
all over again.
Sue Sylvester,
I think I speak
for all of Vocal Adrenaline
when I say we'd be honored
to have you as our coach.
Sam, good, I need your help;
we have to figure out
what to do with this
whole Warbler crisis,
especially now that Sue
is on the attack.
So here, will you
put this jacket on?
Um, I think you're making
a mistake.
With the jacket?
It's just a jacket.
Look, we have to commit to this
and just tell our kids
that this is
what we're doing, okay?
The Warbler's school
burned down.
If this is gonna give them
a little bit of comfort,
then it's the least we could do.
I mean about taking
that part in New York.
What about NYADA?
Look,
Mercedes was right.
It's pathetic,
and worse than that,
it's desperate
to cling to the idea
of going back there.
(phone vibrating)
It's not pathetic to go back.
Hello, this is Rachel.
I...
That was Carmen Tibideaux.
I'm back in NYADA
if I want to be.
That's amazing! Oh, my gosh,
I knew, I knew that you could
just do it, I told you.
That's what I said.
Did I not say that?
I'm not going back there.
What?
Sam, I just want to go back
to New York a winner,
not with my tail
between my legs.
And Mercedes is happy for me,
Kurt is happy for me,
Blaine's happy for me.
Why can't you be?
You're the person
who matters the most;
just be happy for me.
I'm telling you the truth, okay,
not just what you want to hear.
Yet you said that I was destined
to be back in New York.
Yeah, but not like this.
Like what?
What's wrong with this?
This is what I wanted!
No, what you wanted was
a second chance to get it right,
and Carmen
just gave that to you, okay?
If you throw all that away,
you're gonna be making the same
mistakes all over again.
Look, Rachel, come on, stop.
It's not a mistake.
Me going back to my life
and who I was
is not a mistake.
I just think that
in this day and age,
it's insane not to get
a college education, you know?
But, Sam, you're not in college.
Well, I know,
but I don't want Rachel
to make my mistakes that I...
Rachel is a big girl.
She's gonna take care of
herself, okay? We just have...
(organ playing Europe's
"The Final Countdown")
Oh, my Lord, this is serious.
Sue, what are you doing?
I'm making a statement.
You've crossed me
for the last time,
William Schuester.
Do you have any idea
how many times you've said that?
And it still feels good.
You betrayed me,
and I am taking it upon myself
to destroy the Glee Club
and you once and for all.
And I know I've said
that before, too!
Betray you?
Okay, everyone else
betrayed you, Sue.
There were two people
Geraldo interviewed
that stood up for you,
and I was one of them.
Silence!
Brad?
("The Final Countdown" resumes)
Oh, don't even think
that you can out-Europe me, Sue.
I saw them play live at the
Franklin County Fair in 1993.
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ We're leaving together ♪
♪ But still it's farewell ♪
♪ And maybe we'll come back ♪
♪ To Earth, who can tell? ♪
♪ I guess there is
no one to blame ♪
♪ We're leaving ground ♪
♪ Will things ever be
the same again? ♪
♪ It's the final countdown ♪
♪ The final countdown ♪
♪ Oh... oh! ♪
(guitars playing rapidly)
Oh, my God, they've gone crazy.
We can't let this happen to us.
♪ The final countdown ♪
♪ Oh! ♪
♪ It's the final countdown ♪
♪ We're leaving together ♪
♪ Final countdown ♪
♪ We'll all miss her so ♪
♪ It's the final countdown ♪
♪ Countdown ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ It's the final countdown! ♪
(music ends, crowd cheering)
(cheering stops abruptly)
I mean, it was so weird
to see you and Sue
do a fantasy air guitar battle.
Weird and
borderline psychopathic.
I feel so awful
you guys had to see that.
But I'm done.
I...
We are gonna beat Sue
at sectionals.
Well, looks like Sue is
the least of our worries.
I just got cornered by Myron.
Rachel Berry, Uncle Bob just
told me devastating news!
The bottom line is
if New Directions doesn't win,
not only will the Glee Club
get the ax,
but all arts and music programs
will be wiped from the school.
But what am I supposed to do
with all my sequin jackets?!
That's impossible;
I'm paying for the Glee Club
out of my own pocket.
That's what I said!
But that's impossible.
Rachel Berry is paying
for the Glee Club
out of her own pocket.
But this goes beyond
what she can afford,
and this is also
about allocation
of facilities and resources.
I mean, that choir room has to
go back to being a computer lab
or at least another classroom.
(shrieks)
I just can't believe it
after everything that
we've been through.
This could be worse.
We've survived
far more difficult things,
not just in Glee Club,
but in life.
You know, screw it.
We've had to fight
for everything
we've earned in our lives,
and this is just the beginning
of a new fight.
I am so proud of you all.
And as badly as I want
to save the arts,
my greatest accomplishment
are the people sitting
in front of me right now.
We never give up,
and we never will.
Well, if only we could just
agree on costumes to wear
for the most important
competition of our lives.
That might actually be
one problem
that we may have fixed.
("Rise" begins)
(rhythmic humming)
♪ Have you ever felt
like you woke up ♪
♪ On the wrong side
of your heart? ♪
♪ Has it ever felt
like it's broken ♪
♪ Like the world
tore it apart? ♪
♪ Have you felt so weak ♪
♪ You could hardly stand? ♪
♪ Like if you ever fell,
you could never tell ♪
♪ If you'd ever
get back up again ♪
♪ I know it's hard to do ♪
♪ But I think you can make it ♪
♪ 'Cause I know we can take it ♪
♪ Baby, we will ♪
♪ Rise ♪
♪ We are young,
we are the dreamers ♪
♪ We will fly ♪
♪ When the world
will not believe us ♪
♪ We will rise above the ashes ♪
♪ Before this whole life
passes us by ♪
♪ You and I ♪
♪ We will rise ♪
(rhythmic humming)
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ Oh, we will ♪
♪ We will rise ♪
♪ We are young,
we are the dreamers ♪
♪ We will fly ♪
♪ When the world
will not believe us ♪
♪ We will rise above the ashes ♪
♪ Before this whole life
passes us by ♪
♪ You and I ♪
♪ We will rise ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We will rise ♪
♪ We will rise above the ashes ♪
♪ Before this whole life
passes us by ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ You and I, we will rise! ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com