(bell rings)
I thought you weren't
allowed here.
I'm permitted
on school grounds
as long as I'm
getting my work.
Oh, I wanted to tell you
I'm available
for vocal coaching
if you need any help.
We need to bring our "A" game
if we have any chance
of beating the Trouble Tones.
Oh, we're not gonna have any
trouble with them.
Not as soon as I have
Shelby Corcoran fired.
(whispers):
She's sleeping with Puck.
Look, that's a really, really
dangerous rumor
to make up, okay?
You're gonna ruin
her entire reputation.
That's the plan.
And it's not a lie.
I heard it from Puck.
First of all, Puck is 18, so
what he and Shelby are doing,
even though it's just wrong
and so gross, it's not illegal.
So all you're doing
is you're just,
you're getting her fired,
which is gonna take away
her income
to provide food and clothes
and put a roof over her
child's tiny little blonde head.
Sounds like an unfit mother.
And I'll be waiting in the wings
when they take Beth away
from her.
Beth loves her mom.
Shelby is her real mom.
Look, you've done a lot
of really bad things, Quinn,
but if you tell people about
this Puck-and-Shelby thing,
you'll be ruining this little
girl's life,
and then you'll have really
hit rock bottom.
(bell ringing)
Sectionals is in our auditorium
for the first time since 1963,
Too much talking,
not enough looking
for songs for Sectionals.
We need to do something upbeat.
Mr. Shue, maybe we need
to concentrate
on our performer problem
before we set a set list.
I mean, at least
the Cheerios! can dance.
We need star power.
We need Sam Evans.
Sam transferred.
His whole family moved.
We don't even know where he is.
He's in Kentucky.
It's just across the
border from Cincinnati.
It's about a four hours
from here.
Even homeless people
have Facebook.
Rachel and I might
as well get used
to a life of barista work
and summer stock.
There's no way we're
getting into NYADA now.
If we don't win at Sectionals,
I pretty much have nothing
to live for.
New Directions! is a mess,
and we're gonna lose, Kurt,
and I can't do a thing about it.
Every time I open my mouth,
Finn gives me these looks like,
"What does he think he's doing?"
I know what I'm doing.
Hey, guys!
It's so crazy.
I'm sitting
over there
checking out this guy
and all of a sudden I'm, like,
"Wait a second
I know that hair."
What's up, buddy?
Haven't seen you online.
Hi, Kurt.
We've been really busy
with Glee Club.
Practicing for Sectionals...
together.
Mmm, congrats on the Warbler win
at your sectionals.
We're up this week.
Yeah. Well, hey, if there's one
guy that can whip New Directions
into a legitimate threat,
it's Blaine Anderson, right?
Right.
I need another coffee.
I don't like you.
Fun.
I don't like you either.
I don't like the way
you talk to my boyfriend,
I don't like your smirky
little meerkat face,
I don't like your
obnoxious CW hair. I'm onto you.
Let's get a few things straight.
Blaine's too good for you.
New Directions! is a joke.
And one of us has
a hard luck case
of the gay-face,
and it ain't me.
Odds are by the end of the
school year, I'll have Blaine
and a nationals trophy,
and you'll have khakis
and a Lima Bean apron
and that gay face.
You smell like Craig's List.
What are you guys
talking about?
Duh, the next time we're all
going out drinking, killer!
Uh-oh.
Well, I gotta run.
But you take care of that
Warbler, Kurt. (clicks tongue)
Wait. This can't be
the right place.
Sam works in a bar?
Well, there just aren't
a lot of theaters in
Northern Kentucky,
so theatre groups
just have
to perform in whatever
space they can find.
There's a lot of ladies here--
like, older ladies.
Finn, it's no secret
that dinner theater appeals
to elderly women.
ANNOUNCER (over P.A.):
Good afternoon, ladies!
Are you ready to meet
the men of Stallionz?
Then please welcome
to the stage-- Cobra!
I didn't know Backdraft was
a musical.
ANNOUNCER: Someone get the door,
'cause here comes Mr. Package.
(women screaming)
Oh, God, no.
ANNOUNCER:
And ladies, let's give
a warm
welcome to White Chocolate!
♪ ♪
That's not an image I can
ever get out of my mind.
Give me a dollar.
What?
Just give me a dollar.
Rach-Rachel...
I tried getting a real job.
DQ was great and I got
two free Blizzards a day,
but it paid just over
minimum wage. Thanks.
You know how much
I made this afternoon?
60 bucks.
$61... in 15 minutes.
Am I ashamed I work here?
Yeah, I'm ashamed.
My dad got a job working
construction to pay the rent,
but when my brother needs
a new pair of shoes
or the TV busts,
these abs pay for it.
Your parents don't know
that you work here?
No, they just think
the DQ pays really well.
I'm good at this.
You're good at it
because you have
that a boy-next-door
innocence
that makes you
approachable, okay?
You're good at it for all
the reasons that you
shouldn't be doing it.
Come back to McKinley, Sam.
We need you for Sectionals.
Tell me you don't want it.
Dude, you're young,
you got so much potential.
Working re is, like,
throwing your life away.
Okay, I want it... but
my dad will never let me.
Don't know till you ask.
Here we go.
Dad, Mom, what
I'm trying to say
is I want to go back
to Ohio with them.
They need me to compete at
Sectionals this weekend.
And he could stay at one
of our houses,
so it wouldn't be
like he was homeless.
Not that there isn't
a quiet dignity in that
or anything.
You think you two could
go in the other room,
make yourselves
busy, please?
Yeah, totally-- I'm really
good at looking busy.
Son...
we've had a really tough year,
but now we've back
on our feet.
You had to become
a man much sooner
than other kids your age.
I'm-I'm proud of
what we've all done.
It's just that...
I miss being a teenager.
(Mom sniffles)
Hey-hey-hey-hey...
Mom, please don't...
Look, if you cry, I won't go.
I'm just crying because...
(sniffles, sighs)
it just makes me so sad
to think of not seeing
your face every day.
Though I don't
understand why
the Dairy Queen makes you put
that glitter all over it.
This gonna make you happy?
You have no idea.
Come on.
Are we sure yet which band
members are joining us?
Well, it looks like
"Floppy Hair Bass Dude,"
"Chapped Lips McGee,"
and "Johnny Tromboner."
God, we're screwed.
No, we're not.
I know for a fact
that we're winning.
Hey, great news,
everybody.
Sectionals is going to be
a challenge, but we have a--
Mr. Shue, we all appreciate
your endless supply
of affirmations, but all
the sparkling cider in the world
can't deny the fact
that the Titanic has hit
the iceberg and now
we're on a sinking ship.
Not if I can help it.
(all cheer)
Hey.
Hi!
Come here!
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't
for Finn and Rachel.
I sort of lost my way, but...
true friends help you
find your way back.
Let's hear it
for Sam Evans!
(all cheer)
All right, enough
of the sentimental stuff.
It's time y'all get
a little country
back in this joint! Oh!
(all exclaim)
Cheers!
Two, one, two, three.
(Toby Keith's "Red Solo Cup"
begins)
♪ Now a red Solo cup is the best
receptacle for barbecues ♪
♪ Tailgates,
fairs and festivals ♪
♪ And you, sir, do not have
a pair of testicles ♪
♪ If you prefer drinking
from glass ♪
♪ Hey, a red Solo cup is
cheap and disposable ♪
♪ And in 14 years,
they are decomposable ♪
♪ And unlike my home,
they are not foreclosable ♪
♪ Freddie Mac can
kiss my ass! Ooh! ♪
♪ Red Solo cup, uh-huh,
I fill you up ♪
♪ Let's have a party ♪
♪ I love you, red Solo cup ♪
♪ I lift you up,
proceed to party ♪
♪ Proceed to party ♪
♪ Now, I seen you in blue
and I've seen you in yellow ♪
♪ But only you, Red,
will do for this fellow ♪
♪ 'Cause you are the Abbot
unto my Costello ♪
♪ And you are the fruit
to my loom ♪
♪ Red Solo cup, you're more
than just plastic ♪
♪ You're more than amazing,
you're more than fantastic ♪
♪ Believe me when I'm not
the least bit sarcastic ♪
♪ When I look at you
and say... ♪
Red solo cup,
you're not just a cup.
God, no!
You're my...
Friend?
You're my friend.
Thank you for being my friend,
red Solo cup.
QUINN:
Aw...
♪ Red Solo cup, I fill you up ♪
♪ Let's have a party ♪
♪ Have a party ♪
♪ Let's have
a party ♪
♪ I love you, red Solo cup ♪
♪ Red Solo ♪
♪ I fill you up ♪
♪ Let's have a party ♪
♪ Let's have a party,
yeah-eah! ♪
♪ Solo cup ♪
♪ Do-do ♪
♪ Oh, do-do ♪
♪ Solo cup ♪
♪ Doo-dee-da-ba ♪
♪ Hmm-hmm-mm. ♪
(all cheer)
(plays flourish)
Corn dogs!
I just heard the news that
Trouty Mouth is back in town.
I've been keeping
a notebook, just in case
this day ever came.
"Welcome back, Lisa Rinna.
"I've missed you so much since
your family packed their bags,
"loaded them in your mouth,
and skipped town.
"I can't tell you how
many times I've wanted
"to enjoy a crisp pickle,
but couldn't find anyone
"to suck the lid off the jar.
"I assume you've been
working as a baby-polisher,
"where young mothers place their
infants' heads in your mouth to
"get back that newborn shine.
"So glad you're back.
"I haven't seen
a smile that big
"since a Claymation
Abominable Snowman got
"his teeth pulled by
that little gay elf dentist.
Love, Santana."
I missed you, too, Santana.
Oh, my God.
(bell rings)
Hey, Sam, wait up.
I'm sure you've heard
that Mercedes has
a new boyfriend.
He's got a full scholarship
to Ohio State.
Nice to see you,
too, Quinn.
No, no, it's a good thing.
See, I'm free,
you're free.
And I'm sure that you've noticed
that I'm supermodel thin
now that my thyroid is
under control.
What do you want, Quinn?
Look, last year
I didn't appreciate you.
But we're
perfect together.
Quinn...
I'm gonna get Beth back.
And-And you'd be perfect
to help raise her.
You're so good with kids.
What is so funny?
Quinn, you've got
what I call "rich
white girl problems."
It's a tough world
out there, I know.
I've been through it.
You only get one senior year.
Enjoy it.
You know that song "Jack and
Diane" by John Mellencamp?
Please don't sing.
My favorite lyric
is this one:
"Hold on to 16 as
long as you can."
+
with the applications?
Deadlines are this week.
Tina, I already applied
to Stanford.
Pre-med.
But you don't want to be a
doctor, you want to be a dancer.
Not if it means ripping
my family apart.
My dad hasn't said
one word to me
or my mom since
West Side Story.
I'll dance in my free time.
Everyone's happy.
Except for you.
Mike, your dad needs to
understand that dancing
is your passion,
not some extracurricular.
I miss him, Tina.
I know.
But you have one life, Mike.
One chance to get it right.
Don't be a coward.
Don't call me that.
You won't make it as a dancer
if you're not 100% committed.
So maybe your dad's right.
Maybe you should be a doctor.
Or maybe he's right,
and we shouldn't be together.
(bell ringing)
WILL:
...six, seven, eight.
Bum-bum-bum.
Step and hit.
Come on!
To the beat!
What does it even
matter, anyway?
It's not like we have
a chance of winning.
Not without the girls.
Sir, girls smell
better than ham
and when they're dancing
and bouncing around,
you can't help but watch them.
Well, that's it then.
We'll take what's most appealing
about us as a group,
and we'll use it
to our advantage.
Yeah, how about, you know,
something like, um...
something like that?
Cute!
I like the spin,
I like the spin.
Try it again.
Yeah.
God, okay, stop, stop.
Look, Blaine,
this... is totally boy band.
What we need
to sell here is sex.
What the hell is that?
That's a, it's a body roll.
It's not a body roll.
That is sex.
Man's not wrong.
I got light tingles where
it's only 50/50 for tingling.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sam, that's awesome.
That's exactly what we need.
No, that's not,
that's not what we need.
We don't have to
resort to... that.
It's cheap.
You know, it's selling out.
I came back here to win.
When you're desperate,
sometimes you got to,
you know, use your assets
and do what you got to do
to get back that advantage.
This is the advantage.
Of course that's what you think;
you have to
think that
in order to sleep at night.
What the hell does that mean?
It means that
I'm not for sale.
WILL:
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey.
Forget it.
(bell ringing)
Is that Sam's face?
Yep. Yours, too.
Don't act so surprised.
After getting bullied so much,
I took up boxing.
I also started the Dalton
branch of Fight Club,
which I obviously
can't talk about!
What is your problem
with me, anyway?!
Ever since I got here, you've
given me nothing but crap.
Honestly, dude,
I was kind of jealous.
I felt threatened.
Your talent kind of
freaked me out,
made me question whether or not
I was good enough.
Look, Blaine, I'm sorry.
Uh, I've been acting
like a jackass to you.
With Rachel gone,
you're the most
talented, well-rounded member
of this team.
And now more than ever,
we need to be on the same page.
United.
Tell me what you need me to do.
We have an opportunity.
An opportunity to be remembered
at this school
for the rest of our lives
for doing the impossible.
But it all starts right here,
with you and me.
I just want to be able to look
across that stage at you
and know that we did
everything we could.
No regrets.
Let's get back to work.
(chuckles)
All right.
(bell ringing)
What are you doing?
Holding your hand.
Don't.
Sam, look, I...
I heard about your boyfriend.
Then you heard he's
built like a bulldozer.
We had a summer fling.
It was more than that.
I'll always have a special place
in my heart for you,
but... I've moved on.
And you need to do the same.
I don't care how big
or bad your boyfriend is.
I'm gonna fight
to get you back.
+
What's this?
A bootleg of
West Side Story.
Starring your son.
You missed
the performance,
but I thought you should see how
truly incredible Mike was in it.
Go. Take that with you.
Are you sure?
'Cause if you saw it,
then maybe you'd realize
that Mike's throwing
everything he loves away
just to please you.
And if you don't make it right,
he's going to spend
the rest of his life
doing something he hates,
dying inside.
Tina...
sit.
Please.
You want to be a performer, too?
And your parents support this?
They love me.
They love you,
but they're not honest with you.
And you children,
you think you know everything,
but this path
you've chosen, Tina,
the one you want
Mike to choose, too,
there'll be such heartache.
So few opportunities for you.
I know. I've heard the jokes.
I better hope they do
a musical of The Joy Luck Club
or Memoirs of a Geisha.
I don't care.
Performing is
what I need to do--
same as your son.
And it may be hard,
but it's what we were
born to do.
You know, you're always
talking about honor,
Mr. Chang.
Help your son honor his gift.
(warming up):
♪ La, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la ♪
Okay, guys,
you're going to want to sing
from your diaphragm
as much as you can.
And if you forget the words,
just keep your lips moving.
Hopefully, nobody
will notice.
Let's take a few moments
to gather our thoughts.
Trouble Tones
are on in five.
Good luck out there.
What?
Why would you try
and talk to my dad?
You're making things worse.
He almost didn't
let me come today.
I'm really disappointed
in you, Tina.
Well, that makes
two of us,
'cause I'm really
disappointed in you.
Hello, Will.
Looking good, ladies!
We just came to say,
may the best glee club win.
Yes, and just in case
that glee club is us,
I have convinced Miss Corcoran
to consider a contingency plan.
SHELBY: Yes, in the event
of a New Directions! loss,
Trouble Tones has voted
to allow any of you
to join us at Regionals.
You're welcome.
Excuse me?
That's incredibly
rude, Santana.
We're being nice.
It would be rude if I
followed you around
and every time you took a step,
I played a note on a tuba.
Thank you for the offer,
Miss Corcoran, but right now,
we're gonna concentrate
on winning this thing.
And we will be winning, Shelby.
We've got it in the bag.
Puck here is going to
come through for us.
He's such a shining star,
in every conceivable way.
Don't you think?
Good luck, everybody.
See you on the ice.
Sad?
Devastated.
ANNOUNCER:
And now, the judges
for this year's
Show Choir Sectional
Come on.
here at McKinley High.
Department of Motor Vehicles
Employee of the Month,
Brandy Englebert!
(cheering)
From the 11th District
Court of Appeals,
the Honorable
Judge Dorothy Saunders!
(cheering)
And Western Ohio's
Birthday Clown of the Year
three years running-- Tickles!
(cheering)
(horn honks)
And now, let's welcome
our first performers.
All the way from Defiance, Ohio,
the Unitards!
(applause)
(train whistle blows)
(rhythmic clapping)
("Buenos Aires" playing)
♪ What's new, Buenos Aires? ♪
Oh, my God, it's
the Gerber baby.
♪ I'm new, I want to say
I'm just a little stuck on you ♪
♪ You'll be on me, too ♪
Oh, my God,
she's good.
Oh, this is torture.
I should be singing that song.
♪ Stand back ♪
♪ You ought to know
what you're gonna get in me ♪
♪ Just a little touch
of star quality ♪
♪ Fill me up with your heat,
with your noise ♪
♪ With your dirt, overdo me ♪
♪ Let me dance to your beat,
make it loud, let it hurt ♪
♪ Run it through me ♪
♪ All I want is a whole lot
of excess ♪
♪ Tell the singer
this is where I'm playing ♪
♪ And... if ever I go too far ♪
♪ It's because of
the things you are ♪
♪ Beautiful town ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ You're a tramp,
you're a treat ♪
♪ You will shine to the death,
you are shoddy ♪
♪ But you're flesh,
you are meat ♪
♪ You shall have every breath
in my body ♪
♪ Put me down for a lifetime
of success ♪
♪ Give me credit,
I'll find ways of paying ♪
♪ Stand back, Buenos Aires ♪
♪ Because you ought to know
what you're gonna get in me ♪
♪ Just a little touch of,
just a little touch of ♪
♪ Just a little touch
of star quality. ♪
(cheering)
Wow.
(chuckles)
I didn't count on that one.
Where are you going?
Aren't you supposed to be
in the auditorium?
I saw you leave the auditorium.
I know what you're gonna go do.
You're gonna go tell Figgins
about Shelby and Puck.
I'm an adult.
I can do
whatever I want.
If you want to be
a destructive force
in the universe,
that's your business, okay,
but can you just please
at least wait until after
the Trouble Tones perform?
Why?
Because we don't want
to wreck all the hard work
that our friends in that group
put into their performance.
So we win.
No, not like that.
Look, just... if you're going
to go through with this,
you owe it to Shelby
to tell her first.
It's the adult thing to do.
(sighs)
I got a taste of what it's like
to do the wrong thing.
Okay? And it feels awful.
+
Does she have a temperature?
Okay, forget it.
I'll be home in an hour.
Looks like I'm going
to be missing
my own victory party.
Puck told me about you two.
I'm going to tell Figgins
and get you fired.
I'm ending it.
Not that there's
that much "it" to end.
You shouldn't have
come here with her.
I would have been fine.
What you did was wrong.
What you're doing with Puck
is wrong.
You're so young... pretty...
Don't talk down to me.
It goes away, you know.
Not the pretty--
you'll always be pretty--
but the young.
It happens really slow,
and you don't even notice it,
and then, one day...
everything just feels different.
I can't wait to feel different.
Don't wish away your life.
You're exactly
where you're supposed to be.
I think I thought
that being with an 18-year-old
would make me feel 18 again,
but mostly, it just
made me feel even older.
(sighs)
All right.
I'm going to enjoy my last
few hours of being a teacher.
I recommend that you enjoy
being up on that stage.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
from McKinley High,
competing for
the first time ever,
the Trouble Tones!
I am sorry, Quinn.
(Gloria Gaynor's
"I Will Survive" begins)
♪ At first I was afraid,
I was petrified ♪
♪ Kept thinking I could never
live without you by my side ♪
♪ But then I spent
so many nights ♪
♪ Thinking how you
did me wrong ♪
♪ And I grew strong ♪
♪ And I learned
how to get along ♪
♪ And so you're back ♪
♪ From outer space,
I just walked in ♪
♪ To find you here with that
sad look upon your face ♪
♪ I should have changed
the stupid lock ♪
♪ I should have
made you leave your key ♪
♪ If I'd have known
for just one second ♪
♪ You'd be back to bother me ♪
♪ Oh, now, go ♪
♪ Walk out the door ♪
♪ Just turn around now ♪
♪ 'Cause you're not
welcome anymore... ♪
We got this.
Yeah, we do.
♪ You think I'd crumble ♪
♪ You think I'd lay down
and die ♪
♪ I'm a survivor ♪
♪ What? ♪
♪ I'm not gonna give up ♪
♪ I'm not gonna stop ♪
♪ What? ♪
♪ I'm gonna work harder ♪
♪ I'm a survivor,
I'm gonna make it ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I will survive,
keep on survivin' ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ Thought I couldn't breathe
without you, I'm inhaling ♪
♪ You thought I couldn't see
without you, perfect vision ♪
♪ You thought I couldn't last
without you, but I'm lastin' ♪
♪ You thought that I would die
without you, but I'm livin' ♪
♪ That I would fail without you,
but I'm on top ♪
♪ Thought it would be over
by now, but it won't stop ♪
♪ Thought that I
would self-destruct ♪
♪ But I'm still here ♪
♪ Even in my years to come
I'm still gonna be here ♪
♪ I'm a survivor,
I'm not gonna give up ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I'm not gonna stop,
I'm gonna work harder ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I'm a survivor,
I'm gonna make it ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I will survive,
keep on survivin' ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ Oh, no, not I,
I will survive ♪
♪ Oh, as long as I
know how to love ♪
♪ I know I'll stay alive ♪
♪ I've got all my life to live ♪
♪ And I've got
all my love to give ♪
♪ And I'll survive,
I will survive, hey, hey ♪
♪ I'm a survivor,
I'm not gonna give up ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I'm not gonna stop,
I'm gonna work harder ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I'm a survivor,
I'm gonna make it ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I will survive,
keep on survivin' ♪
♪ What? What? ♪
♪ I will survive. ♪
(cheering and applause)
+
ANNOUNCER:
Also from McKinley High,
let's give it up
for the New Directions!
(cheering and applause)
♪ A-boo, boo, boo, boo, boo ♪
♪ A-boo, boo, boo,
boo, boo ♪
♪ You went to school
to learn, girl ♪
♪ Things you never,
never knew before ♪
♪ Like "I" before "E"
except after "C" ♪
♪ And why two plus two
makes four ♪
♪ Now, now, now,
I'm gonna teach you ♪
♪ Teach you, teach you ♪
♪ All about love, dear ♪
♪ All about love ♪
♪ Sit yourself down
and take a seat ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is repeat after me ♪
♪ ABC, easy as one, two, three ♪
♪ Or simple as do re mi ♪
♪ ABC, one, two, three,
baby, you and me, girl ♪
♪ ABC ♪
♪ Easy as one, two, three ♪
♪ Or simple as do re mi ♪
♪ ABC, one, two three ♪
♪ Baby, you and me, girl ♪
♪ Just a, a little bit ♪
♪ Come on, let me love you ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Just a little bit ♪
♪ Little bit ♪
♪ Teach, teach, sing it out ♪
♪ Come on, come on ♪
♪ Come on, let me show you
what it's all about ♪
♪ Reading, writing, arithmetic ♪
♪ Are the branches
on the learning tree ♪
♪ Well, listen,
without the roots of love ♪
♪ Let me tell you, girl ♪
♪ Your education
ain't complete ♪
♪ T-t-t-teacher's
gonna show you ♪
♪ Show you, show you ♪
♪ How to get an "A" ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ Spell me, you, add the two ♪
♪ Listen to me, baby,
that's all you gotta do ♪
♪ Oh, ABC,
it's easy as one, two, three ♪
♪ Or simple as do re mi ♪
♪ ABC, one, two, three,
baby, you and me, girl ♪
♪ ABC ♪
♪ It's easy ♪
♪ It's like counting
up to three ♪
♪ Sing a simple melody ♪
♪ Do re mi, ABC ♪
♪ That's how easy love can be,
sing a simple melody ♪
♪ One, two, three, you and me ♪
♪ Ah, yeah! ♪
Sit down, girl!
I think I love you!
No! Get up, girl!
Show me what you can do!
♪ Shake it, shake it, baby ♪
♪ Come on now ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ One, two, three, baby ♪
♪ That's how easy love can be ♪
♪ ABC, it's easy ♪
♪ It's like counting
up to three ♪
♪ One, two, three ♪
♪ Sing a simple melody ♪
♪ Do re mi, ABC ♪
♪ That's how easy love can be ♪
♪ I'm-a gonna teach you how to
sing it out, sing it out ♪
♪ Sing it out, sing it out,
sing it ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Baby, ABC, it's easy ♪
♪ It's like counting
up to three ♪
♪ One, two, three ♪
♪ Sing a simple melody ♪
♪ Do re mi, ABC ♪
♪ That's how easy love can be ♪
♪ I'm-a gonna teach you how to
sing it out, sing it out ♪
♪ Easy as one, two, three. ♪
(cheering and applause)
(Janet Jackson's
"Control" begins)
This is a story about control.
My control.
Control of what I say,
control of what I do.
And this time,
I'm gonna do it my way.
(dance beat starts)
♪ When I was 17,
I did what people told me ♪
♪ Uh ♪
♪ I did what my father said
and let my mother mold me ♪
♪ But that was long ago ♪
♪ I'm in ♪
♪ Control ♪
♪ And now I've got a lot ♪
♪ Ow! ♪
♪ Control ♪
♪ To get what I want ♪
♪ Never gonna stop ♪
♪ Control ♪
♪ And now I'm all grown up ♪
♪ Jam ♪
♪ Whoo, whoo ♪
♪ Rebel ♪
♪ That's right ♪
♪ Got my own mind ♪
♪ I want to make
my own decisions ♪
♪ When it has to do
with my life, my life ♪
♪ I want to be
the one in control ♪
♪ So let me take you by the hand
and lead you on this dance ♪
♪ 'Cause what I've got
is because I took a chance ♪
♪ I don't want
to rule the world ♪
♪ Just want to run my life ♪
♪ So make your life
a little easier ♪
♪ When you get the chance,
just take control ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Now I've got a lot ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Control ♪
♪ Now I'm all grown up ♪
♪ Ooh! ♪
♪ Free at last ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Free ♪
♪ Now control this ♪
♪ Uh ♪
♪ 'Cause I've got my own mind ♪
♪ Gonna make my own decisions ♪
♪ When it has to do
with my life ♪
♪ I want to be
the one in control ♪
♪ I'm in control ♪
♪ Uh ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ I'm in control ♪
♪ Uh ♪
♪ Ah. ♪
(cheering and applause)
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ I'm gonna make a change ♪
♪ For once in my life ♪
♪ It's gonna feel real good ♪
♪ Gonna make a difference ♪
♪ Gonna make it right ♪
♪ As I turn up
the collar ♪
♪ On my favorite winter coat ♪
♪ This wind is blowin' my mind ♪
♪ I see the kids
in the street ♪
♪ Without enough to eat ♪
♪ Who am I to be blind ♪
♪ Pretending not
to see their needs? ♪
♪ A summer's disregard ♪
♪ A broken bottle top ♪
♪ And one man's soul ♪
♪ They follow each other
on the wind, you know ♪
♪ 'Cause they got
nowhere to go ♪
♪ That's why I want you
to know ♪
♪ I'm starting with the man
in the mirror ♪
♪ I'm asking him
to change his ways ♪
♪ And no message could
have been any clearer ♪
♪ If you wanna make
the world a better place ♪
♪ Take a look at yourself
and then make a change ♪
♪ I'm starting with the man
in the mirror ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ I'm asking him
to change his ways ♪
♪ Change his ways ♪
♪ And no message could
have been any clearer ♪
♪ If you wanna make the
world a better place ♪
♪ Take a look at yourself
and then make a change ♪
♪ You gotta get it right,
while you got the time ♪
♪ 'Cause when you close your
heart then you close your mind ♪
♪ I'm starting with
the man in the mirror ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ I'm asking him
to change his ways ♪
♪ And no message could
have been any clearer ♪
♪ If you wanna make the
world a better place ♪
♪ Take a look at yourself
and then make that change ♪
♪ Stand up ♪
♪ Make that change ♪
♪ Stand up and let
yourself now ♪
♪ Man in the mirror ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Make that change ♪
♪ Stand up, stand up
in love ♪
♪ You know it, you know it,
you know it, you know ♪
♪ Change... ♪
♪ Make that change. ♪
(cheering and applause)
+
(cheering, whooping)
Get over here!
Gave it our all.
Yeah, we did.
Top dogs! Yes!
This is what I was missing!
I just...
I can't believe it.
I can't believe
he actually came.
He stood and...
Michael.
May I speak
with you?
Both of you?
Dancing is your talent,
your dream.
That's what
you tried to tell me.
That's what you
tried to tell me.
And that's what
I saw tonight.
This is your path, son,
so you must follow it,
and make us proud.
And your mother
and I, we will
help you follow it
however we can.
Apply to dance schools--
the best ones.
Dad...
Dad, I... I missed
the deadlines, I think.
No, you didn't.
I sent in your applications,
just in case.
I kind of had to forge
your signature, though.
I love you so much.
(honks horn)
As an award-winning clown,
I'd like to say
that it's nice, for once,
to be working with kids
that are just sick with talent.
Third place-- The Unitards!
(cheering)
Harmony...
Hi. I just wanted
to tell you
that I thought you
were really amazing.
And just think,
I'm only a sophomore
and I'm already this good.
Next year's going
to be a bloodbath.
In second place...
...we have the Trouble Tones!
In first place
is New Directions!
(cheering)
♪ ♪
(light switches clanking,
echoing through auditorium)
Well, my suspension
is officially over.
It'll still be on
my transcript, though.
I'm just hoping that
the admissions department
at NYADA sees it
as a sign of my artistic,
rebellious, attitude.
Good luck with that.
Are you going to go tell
Figgins about Shelby?
'Cause I just...
I still think
that it's a really
terrible idea.
I came here to talk
to you, actually.
To tell you I'm not
going to tell.
Why?
Because I love Beth, and I don't
want to ruin her life.
I wanted to thank you actually.
For what?
For keeping me from
doing something stupid.
Something I would have regretted
my entire life.
We're kind of friends, huh?
Kind of.
What do you
think about Yale?
Oh, no, I have my
sights set on NYADA.
No, for me.
I'm not the singer
that you and Kurt are,
but Yale has an amazing
drama program.
And I really do
like to perform.
Yeah.
Certainly would nail all the
parts where the girl has to cry.
No, I think it's a great idea.
I mean, especially since you
won't have me to compete with.
You're a lot better
than you know.
Well, I'll see you
at Glee Club.
Where are you going?
I have a couple people
I need to talk to.
Okay, well, I don't know
if you need help with
your Yale application...
Not with the Yale application,
but, um, there is something
you could do for me.
We were better.
I don't know, I think it
could have gone either way.
It was that damn Trouty Mouth.
Even I felt a little
something in my lady loins
when he did that
magic sex dance.
All right, ladies,
girl talk.
No. Uh-uh. Don't you dare try
and give us a pep talk.
Or ask us to come back to New
Directions-- not interested.
Wait, is it even possible?
Do you think they would
really take us back?
Of course they would
take us back.
But I'm telling you,
I'm not going.
Do you know what growing up
is about?
Losing things.
In six months, we'll
all be gone, scattered.
We'll keep in touch.
Yeah, but it
won't be the same.
When we see each other,
it'll be a special occasion.
It'll be different.
I don't want to grow up yet.
I'm not ready
to lose you girls.
What are we supposed to do?
Come back to Glee Club and sing
background for Blaine and Berry
until we graduate?
I'm not doing that again.
We know what it feels like
to be out front now.
What if Mr. Shue agreed
to let the Trouble Tones
sing at least one number
per competition?
Well, even if Mr. Shue did agree
to that, Rachel never would.
What if I told you that
they both already did?
I'm listening.
Look, I know I went
a little crazy.
But I'm here now.
I'm 17-- I have the rest
of my life in front of me.
I love Glee Club.
I love you girls.
And when we're 27, or 87,
I want us to be able to look
back on these next couple months
and talk about how it was
the best times of our lives.
Can't do that if we're
not all together.
We're doing a big number
in the auditorium
to celebrate our victory
and to prepare for Regionals.
We could use a couple
more girl voices.
Let me know if you hear about
anybody who might want to join.
♪ Give me a second ♪
♪ I need to get my
story straight ♪
♪ My friends are in
the bathroom ♪
♪ Getting higher than
the Empire State ♪
♪ My lover he's waiting for
me just across the bar ♪
♪ My seat's been taken
by some sunglasses ♪
♪ Asking 'bout a scar and ♪
♪ I know I gave it
to you months ago ♪
♪ I know
you're trying to forget ♪
♪ But between the drinks
and subtle things ♪
♪ The holes in my apologies ♪
♪ You know I'm trying hard
to take it back ♪
♪ So if by the time
the bar closes ♪
♪ And you feel like
falling down ♪
♪ I'll carry you home ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ We are young ♪
♪ So let's set the world
on fire ♪
♪ We can burn brighter
than the sun ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ We are young ♪
♪ So let's set the world
on fire ♪
♪ Fire ♪
♪ We can burn brighter
than the sun ♪
♪ Carry me home tonight ♪
♪ Just carry me home tonight ♪
♪ The angels never arrived ♪
♪ But I can hear the choir ♪
♪ So someone come and
carry me home... ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ We are young ♪
♪ So let's set the world
on fire ♪
♪ We can burn brighter
than the sun ♪
♪ We are young ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ So let's set the world
on fire ♪
♪ We can burn brighter
than the sun ♪
♪ So if by the time
the bar closes ♪
♪ And you feel like
falling down ♪
♪ I'll carry you home tonight. ♪
Synced By YesCool
www.addic7ed.com