All right, kids;
Show me what you got.
Ready? Five, six,
seven, eight.
Welcome to NYADA.
This is Dance 101,
my name's Cassandra July,
and if you are not suffering
from severe body dysmorphia,
then you don't want it enough.
Let's get this straight,
freshmen:
There's maybe two
of you in this room
that are good enough
to make it in this business.
As for the rest of you,
thank you for paying my rent
on my loft in SoHo.
Hey. What's your name?
Uh, Lydia.
No, no, your name's Muffin Top,
and from now on,
it's rice cakes and ipecac.
Or cut off a butt cheek,
'cause you need to drop a few.
Hold it.
I'm sorry.
Did my conversation with
Muffin Top offend you?
- No.
- Hmm?
What's your name?
- Rachel.
- Little Miss...
- David Schwimmer?
- Little Miss David Schwimmer.
I bet you were
a big star back in Iowa.
- I'm actually from Ohio.
- Ohio.
That's even worse.
You ever look at a map?
Ohio is like a giant turd
that Michigan just
can't pinch off.
So did you come all the way
to New York City
to show me how to run my class?
- No, I... I came to learn.
- Okay.
Lesson number one:
Your piqué turns are pathetic,
and your stuck-up
little attitude's
really pissing me off.
Music!
All right, let's go!
Energy in your fingers.
Higher. Higher.
Into the ground.
Higher!
Higher, higher!
- Come on!
- I don't need any help.
No, no, sweetie, I'm not
coming down here to help you.
I'm coming down here to give you
a big New York City welcome.
You suck.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
What's up, blogosphere?
Jacob Ben Israel here,
back on the street
with an exclusive look at
McKinley's newest celebrities,
the New Directions!
Artie Abrams,
lunch room sources tell me
you've been seen
sitting with Cheerios!
Well, I'm usually sitting.
But, yes, and I can tell you it
is great to finally be popular.
National champs, baby!
Whoo!
Sam Evans: from hobo stripper
to glee club celebrity.
- How does it feel?
- Awesome, and about time.
I never thought
I'd have a freshman
for a personal assistant.
This isn't organic.
Wow. "C You Next Tina."
Do Taylor Lautner again.
Bella, I love you.
And I am a werewolf.
Is it true you broke up
with Mike Chang
a week after tattooing
"Mike Chang 4ever" on your hip
because the long-distance
thing was too hard?
Um... okay.
I still love him,
and we're still friends,
and I changed the tattoo
to "Make Change 4ever."
Change is good.
They said Rachel Berry was
the group's undisputed star,
so, really,
the only question is:
Which one of you
is the new Rachel?
- I am. - I am.
- I am.
It's nice to know I'm missed.
New York can make
a girl feel lonely.
I miss my dads.
I miss Finn.
I haven't heard
from him in two months.
Maybe he's just trying to
give me the space I need
to make it on my own.
Surrender, right?
I'm sure that's it.
My roommate seems nice.
Well, I haven't
officially met her.
She's usually busy with
company, but she sounds nice.
I just wish Kurt had
gotten into NYADA with me.
The co-ed bathrooms take
some getting used to.
I got tired of
everyone's opinion
of my extensive
nighttime ritual,
so I started showering
at 3:00 in the morning
when no one else is around.
♪ Sister Christian, oh,
the time has come ♪
♪ And you know that
you're the only one ♪
♪ To say okay ♪
♪ Where you goin'? ♪
♪ What you lookin' for? ♪
♪ Oh, those boys
don't want to play ♪
♪ No more with you... ♪
♪ You're motoring ♪
♪ What's your price
for flight? ♪
Hey.
You're a freshman, right?
Yeah, I'm Rachel Berry.
I'm majoring in
musical theater.
Me, too.
Brody Weston.
- I'm a junior.
- Hi.
Well, you survived
your first class with Cassie,
so you must be good.
- Is she, uh, always that awful?
- Yeah, she's tough.
But I wouldn't have gotten that
chorus gig in the revival of
Working last summer if
she didn't push me so hard.
You were on Broadway?
Steel Worker Number Three.
Show lasted for, like,
three performances,
but still...
I like to come in here
at night, too.
People give me a hard time
about my moisturizing ritual.
- Me, too.
- We're actors, right?
Our skin is like our
paintbrush and our canvas.
Actually, I'm not really
sleeping much, lately.
Not a lot of city noise
in Lima, Ohio.
I just think everything takes
a little getting used to, but...
yeah.
You'll be fine.
Just remember, you're here
because you're the best
of the best.
Start believing that.
Oh, and, in case
you were wondering...
which you were...
I'm straight.
So he was wearing a towel
that was barely covering
his tinkletube,
and he's straight? Hot.
Do you like him?
No, you know I'll
always love Finn.
Oh, and I love you,
I miss you like crazy,
Oh, is that why you're
calling me every three hours?
Well, I just want to make
sure that you're okay.
I'm great, I love it here.
My dance teacher worships me.
But how are you?
Are you okay?
- I'm keeping busy.
- Where are you right now?
I just passed Mrs. Hagberg's
old classroom.
Figured I'd stop by McKinley
and meet their newest addition.
Porcelain, this is
my daughter Robin.
I've loved the name ever since
I was a little girl.
It recalls hope, and springtime,
and my favorite dead Bee Gee.
Oh, she's the love of my life.
And I'm so...
so devoted to her.
Kitty! Get in here.
Yes, Coach Sylvester?
I need you to
change Robin's diaper,
and then sing her a lullaby.
Preferably something not yet
butchered by the glee club.
Good luck finding one.
Porcelain, this is Kitty.
Kitty is my new head bitch.
She's like a young Quinn Fabray,
except she's not pregnant,
manic-depressive,
or in and out of a wheelchair.
Shouldn't you be
in college or something?
I thought gay people were
all successful overachievers.
- I am a successful...
- Oh, don't pay attention to what Kitty thinks,
Even if it's exactly what
the rest of the world thinks.
I'm actually very proud
of you, Twinkletush.
You're a real trailblazer.
You know, it used to be
that just straight
ex-football players
would lurk the halls
of high schools
after graduation,
but you've proven that
gay ex-show choir champs
can also be
depressive sad sacks desperately
clinging to the past.
I'm not a sad sack, okay?
My classes at Allen County
Community College
start next week...
I'm sorry, I tuned out the
moment you opened your mouth.
Keep living the dream,
Porcelain.
Glee!
We are coming off of
a National Championship,
but it's time to look forward,
And thanks to Glee now being
the coolest club in the school,
- Whoo!
- Right on.
This shouldn't be a problem.
All right.
Yes, we've lost some big voices.
But we still have
some huge ones in here.
And I promise to do
everything I can
to replace the ones
that we lost.
And on that note,
I'd like to introduce you
to our newest member: The MVP
of last year's nationals,
Wade "Unique" Adams.
That's a great haircut,
Mercedes.
I thought you graduated.
I wanted to be somewhere where
different was celebrated.
We are so excited to have you.
Guys... where's the love?
I think Wade is great,
but the competition
to be the new Rachel
is already so intense,
- the last thing that we need is one more contender.
- "The New Rachel"?
Every glee club needs
a star performer.
Rachel was that,
and now that she's gone,
many of us want the job.
Okay, we don't win with stars.
We win as a team.
One that supports new members.
Now, I don't want to hear
any more of this...
this "New Rachel" stuff, okay?
Have a seat, Wade.
Make no mistake:
Unique will be the new Rachel.
We decide this
on our own, then...
Thunderdome style.
5:00, in the auditorium.
So, here are the rules:
We perform the song for Artie,
he makes his choice,
we go to Mr. Shue as a group,
and we tell him who
the new lead soloist is.
Hopefully, it'll be me, 'cause
that's what Rachel wanted.
Though I am uncomfortable doing
this behind Mr. Shue's back,
I am a director.
Therefore, I never pass up on
an opportunity to judge people.
What song are we singing?
What Rachel would sing,
if she were here.
The song of the summer,
"Call Me Maybe."
- Yes.
- Do you need time to prepare?
I can sing any song, any time.
Just press play, and get back.
♪ I threw a wish in a well ♪
♪ Don't ask me,
I'll never tell ♪
♪ I looked to you as it fell ♪
♪ And now you're in my way ♪
♪ I'd trade my soul for a wish ♪
♪ Pennies and dimes for a kiss ♪
♪ I wasn't looking for this ♪
♪ But now you're in my way ♪
♪ Your stare was holding ♪
♪ Ripped jeans,
skin was showing ♪
♪ Hot night, wind was blowing ♪
♪ Where you think
you're going, baby? ♪
♪ Hey, I just met you ♪
♪ And this is crazy ♪
♪ But here's my number ♪
♪ So call me, maybe ♪
♪ It's hard to look right ♪
♪ At you baby ♪
♪ But here's my number ♪
♪ So call me, maybe ♪
♪ Hey, I just met you ♪
♪ And this is crazy ♪
♪ But here's my number ♪
♪ So call me, maybe ♪
♪ And all the other boys ♪
♪ Try to chase me ♪
♪ Well, here's my number ♪
♪ So call me, maybe ♪
♪ Before you came into my life ♪
♪ I missed you so bad ♪
♪ I missed you so, so bad ♪
♪ Before you came into my life ♪
♪ I missed you so bad ♪
♪ And you should know that ♪
♪ I missed you so, so bad ♪
- ♪ It's hard to look right ♪
- ♪ Hard to look right ♪
- ♪ At you baby ♪
♪ But here's my number ♪
♪ So call me, maybe ♪
♪ Hey, I just met you ♪
♪ And this is crazy ♪
♪ But here's my number ♪
- ♪ So call me, maybe ♪
- ♪ Call me ♪
- ♪ Before you came into my life ♪
- ♪ I missed you so bad ♪
- ♪ So bad ♪
- ♪ I missed you so, so bad ♪
♪ So call me, maybe? ♪
So, Artie...
who's the new Rachel?
So, how's Santana?
She's good; she's just really
busy with cheerleading practice
and it's hard making out
over Skype.
You can't really scissor
a Webcam.
Here's an extra hot soy latte
for him
and a no-chocolate for her.
Yes.
I can't wait till Friday.
Why?
Glee Club auditions.
That sounds like fun.
Pretty nice.
Is it depressing
that I'm more excited about it
than either of you?
- Yeah.
- No, not at all.
Just a little bit.
- No, it's...
- Excuse me. Garcon?
My ice latte's too cold.
It's an iced latte.
It's an iced latte
that's too cold.
I'm gonna need you
to make me a new one.
- Hello?
- Hey, Kurt, you got to refill the biscotti
Barrel every 15 minutes.
Coming.
I'll be right back
with your latte.
- Uh, Miss July?
- Yeah?
I, uh, I don't know how to tell
you this, but I can't be
your TA this year.
I start Wicked
rehearsals tomorrow.
I'm just playing
a flying monkey, but still...
Oh, stop it. Does it matter?
It's your first Broadway show.
You'll never forget it.
I was 17, I was a dancing spoon.
Well, the casting director
said it's the recommendation
you gave me that really
put me over the top,
so thank you for
everything. Oh!
I'm so proud of you, Benjie.
Thank you. I should go.
I have to get fitted
for my monkey legs.
You had enough time,
so who is it?
You can't rush
the casting process.
My genius needs
it's dream time.
You guys
are the Glee Club, right?
Hi. I'm gonna try out.
I'm a sophomore.
My name is Marley.
Okay, well, lots of competition,
so good luck to you.
Unique offers her greetings
and salutations.
Wade, you can't wear
that makeup and stuff in here.
You have to understand
how this stuff works.
It's like Game of Thrones.
Yeah, the peace between us
and the truly popular kids
is weak... winter is coming.
It's not gonna take much
for us to get smacked down
to the bottom again.
Maybe you should just save
Unique for performances
and be Wade
the rest of the time, hmm?
All right...
I'll go take off my face.
- Hey, glee people.
- Hey, Kitty.
Hey, you guys see
the new lunch lady?
She's so fat, they took a
picture of her last Christmas.
Still printing.
Hey, she has to wear a watch
on both wrists
because she covers
two time zones.
Maybe she has,
like, a medical condition
or she swallowed somebody
with a medical condition.
Right, Artie?
When she sits around the house,
she really sits around
the house.
Attaboy.
Attaboy!
Hey, you ready to go?
Hey. I thought that
you could wear this
to your glee audition.
Well, even if they think
it's secondhand,
the tag will say
high-class secondhand.
It's high school;
It's all about being special.
But... the right kind
of special,
not Goodwill clothes,
daughter-of-the-lunch-
lady special.
You really think
I have a chance
of getting into Glee Club?
You have magic
in your throat, Marley.
It's time to share it
with the world.
I'm going to drive the car
a couple blocks away,
and I will wait for you there.
I don't want
to risk anyone seeing you
get in the car with me.
Mm-wah!
God almighty, Schwimmer,
possible you're getting worse?
I've been practicing a lot.
I've just had a little bit
of a rough week.
Aw, you tired? You lonely?
You homesick?
Well, you better decide how
badly you want it
'cause this school is filled
with people
who will do whatever necessary
to make it in this business.
Why are you picking on me?
I'm not! I'm motivating you!
What's your problem now?
There's just alcohol
on your breath.
It's Listerine.
Let me tell you something.
I may not be
a wide-eyed ingenue anymore,
but I can still dance
circles around any of you.
Music.
♪ I met a girl in East L.A. ♪
♪ In floral shorts
as sweet as May ♪
♪ She sang in eights
in two barrio chords ♪
♪ We fell in love,
but not in court ♪
♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah, America ♪
♪ Mis canciones
son de la revolución ♪
♪ Mi corazón
me duele por mi generación ♪
♪ If you love me,
we can marry on the West Coast ♪
♪ On a Wednesday
en el verano en agosto ♪
♪ I want to dance and love ♪
♪ And dance again ♪
♪ And dance again, ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ America, Americano ♪
♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ America ♪
♪ Americano ♪
♪ If this would be
a perfect world ♪
♪ We'd be together then ♪
♪ Let's do it, do it, do it ♪
♪ Only got just one life,
this I've learned ♪
- ♪ Who cares what they're gonna say? ♪
- ♪ Let's do it, do it, do it ♪
♪ I want to dance and love ♪
♪ And dance again ♪
♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ America ♪
♪ Americano ♪
- ♪ I want to dance
- ♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ America, Americano ♪
♪ I want to dance ♪
- ♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ America, Americano ♪
- ♪ I want to dance ♪
- ♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ America, Americano ♪
♪ I want to dance! ♪
You're not just on my list,
Schwimmer,
you are my list.
Class dismissed.
Okay, let's get started.
Remember, guys,
we're looking for superstars.
I'm Stoner Brett.
This is Buster's "Gettin' Hot."
♪ This is gettin' hot,
this is gettin' hot ♪
♪ Got my mind on my money
and my money on my mind ♪
♪ Sipping on a 40
while I'm pushing on the dime ♪
♪ Feel the pain, the game ♪
♪ Yeah, Lil' Wayne,
Lil' Wayne. ♪
De'wanda Umber.
Are there words to this?
She gotta go.
Hello, sir.
What's your name?
Jake.
Got a last name, Jake?
Uh, just Jake.
Okay, well, show us what
you got "Just Jake."
♪ Some things
we don't talk about ♪
♪ Rather do without ♪
♪ Just hold the smile... ♪
He's so sexy.
No, he's not.
Yes, he is.
♪ Ashamed and proud of ♪
♪ Together all the while ♪
♪ You can never say never ♪
♪ While we don't know when ♪
♪ Time and time again ♪
♪ Younger now
than we were before ♪
♪ Don't let me go... ♪
♪ Don't let me go ♪
♪ Don't... ♪
I don't get to finish?
We got a lot of people to see.
But I've been practicing.
We've seen enough. Thank you.
That's rude and unacceptable.
Kurt, I'll handle this.
Jake, come on, man,
why don't you pick up
the music stand?
Next!
Returning students,
welcome back.
New students, welcome
to the round room.
The acoustics are perfect
and there are no corners.
Which means there is nowhere
to hide in here.
First-year students will
have the opportunity
to sing publicly twice.
The first time today, the Debut.
Also known as the
"Freshman reaping."
The second, the Winter Showcase
at the end of the semester...
if you are invited.
Shall we begin?
Beatrice McClaine.
My name is Beatrice McClaine
and I'll be singing "Ave Maria"
written by Franz Schubert.
♪ Ave Maria... ♪
I'm gonna stop you there.
When I accepted you at NYADA,
what did I tell you
you needed to do?
You needed to practice
all summer long.
- I did.
- You did not.
I think you need
to practice a little bit more
and reapply in December.
Did she just get cut?
It happens.
Rachel Berry.
Impress me.
Hi. I'm Rachel Berry, and I'll be
singing "New York State of Mind,"
written by Billy Joel.
Popularized by one Miss...
Barbra Streisand.
♪ Some folks like to get away ♪
♪ For a holiday
from the neighborhood ♪
♪ Hop a flight to Miami Beach ♪
♪ Or to Hollywood ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ But I'm taking a Greyhound ♪
♪ On the Hudson River line ♪
♪ I'm in a New York
state of mind ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ It was so easy ♪
♪ Living day by day ♪
♪ Out of touch ♪
♪ With the rhythm
and the blues ♪
♪ But now I need ♪
♪ A little give-and-take ♪
♪ The New York Times ♪
♪ The Daily News ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ It comes down to reality ♪
♪ And it's fine with me ♪
♪ 'Cause I let it slide ♪
♪ Don't care if it's Chinatown ♪
♪ Or on Riverside ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ I don't have any reasons ♪
♪ I left them all behind ♪
♪ I'm in a New York state of ♪
♪ Mind ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm just taking a Greyhound ♪
♪ On the Hudson River line... ♪
♪ Line... ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm in... ♪
♪ I'm in a New York... ♪
♪ State... ♪
♪ Of... ♪
♪ Mind ♪
- ♪ Ooh ♪
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ State of mind. ♪
Nice.
Thank you. Thank you.
Wow.
Now, that's what I call
star quality.
What do you guys think?
- Ten.
- It was good.
What's this?
I'm organizing
all the sheet music.
Artie, go around it,
not over it.
Thanks, Dottie.
You're dismissed for the day.
This is for you...
and no, it's not a bribe,
because we all know
Rachel told me herself
that I'm the new Rachel.
MVP in the house.
Bro, I thought we agreed you'd
only wear that stuff onstage.
What's wrong with you guys?
This club is about diversity
and acceptance.
Or at least it used to be.
And another thing...
since when did everyone
become so obsessed with
who's the biggest star?
Since day one... you and Rachel
fought over solos
for three years.
No more stalling, Artie.
Who's the new Rachel?
Tell us.
After meticulous deliberation
and an online poll,
the new Rachel
is... Blaine.
- How?
- Brittany, you were a close second.
- I came in third?
- Let's not worry about third or fourth place.
And we don't need
to talk about this, either.
Why do you hate
strong black women for?
Guys, this young lady
gave hands-down
one of the best auditions
I have ever seen.
Let's give it up for our
newest member, Marley Rose.
Marley, on behalf of all
of New Directions!, welcome.
Thank you.
I'm really excited to be here.
I really like your sweater.
Where'd you get it?
Oh. Thanks.
Um, J.Crew.
Really?
The only new member
out of all those people?
It wasn't that many.
Okay, it was awesome!
Hearing them cheer for me,
accept me.
And that Rachel Berry
everybody talks about
rode that glee club train
right to Broadway.
Well, I don't want to be
on Broadway, though.
I want to be a singer
on the radio.
Well, then let the glee club
help you get there.
For now, the important thing
is you found someplace
you belong.
There's one problem.
They were making fun of you.
Well, they're teenagers.
Just feels so weird
lying about you.
You're my mom.
You remember what happened
at the last school?
You didn't have any friends.
I won't let that happen again.
This is your shot to sit
at the popular kids' table.
Don't blow it.
Of course, I think you
should be the lead soloist.
But can I give you some advice?
Even when Rachel was
her most controlling,
she still made sure
everyone felt included.
Okay. You have a point.
Can I give you some advice?
You can't be here
anymore, Kurt.
I get it. I know.
I'm pathetic.
No, no, you're...
you're not pathetic.
It's just that you're...
you're stuck.
You don't belong here anymore.
You belong in New York.
And I'm reapplying for NYADA.
But I can't just
go to New York.
You don't need NYADA.
And believe me,
I don't want to see you go,
but I just can't stand
to see you stay here.
It's killing you.
And that's killing me.
What about us?
In a year,
I'll be there, too, but...
right now is your time.
You're ready.
♪ So this is what you meant ♪
♪ When you said
that you were spent ♪
♪ And now it's time to build
from the bottom of the pit ♪
♪ Right to the top ♪
♪ Don't look back ♪
♪ Packing my bags ♪
♪ And giving the academy
a rain check ♪
♪ I don't ever want
to let you down ♪
♪ I don't ever
want to leave this town ♪
♪ 'Cause after all ♪
♪ This city never
sleeps at night ♪
♪ It's time to begin,
isn't it? ♪
♪ I get a little bit bigger ♪
♪ But then I'll admit ♪
♪ I'm just the same as I was ♪
♪ Oh, don't you understand ♪
♪ I'm never changing who I am ♪
♪ This road never
looked so lonely ♪
♪ This house doesn't
burn down slowly ♪
♪ To ashes, to ashes ♪
♪ It's time to begin,
isn't it? ♪
♪ I get a little bit bigger ♪
♪ But then I'll admit ♪
♪ I'm just the same as I was ♪
♪ Now don't you understand ♪
♪ I'm never changing who I am ♪
♪ It's time to begin,
isn't it? ♪
♪ I get a little bit bigger ♪
♪ But then I'll admit ♪
♪ I'm just the same as I was ♪
♪ Don't you understand ♪
♪ I'm never changing who I am. ♪
I'll miss you so much.
Brittany, I'm sorry, but I won
fair and square. You can't
- just decide not to sing anymore. We all need your voice.
- I had a song
In my heart, Blaine Warbler,
and you killed it.
Now I have a dead
song in my heart,
and pretty soon, the corpse
of my dead heart song
- is going to start to smell.
- Okay, guys.
Since we can't do
a popularity homecoming float
with all white people, I say
I think we should do one
- with all white chrysanthemums.
- That's a good idea.
We need a float,
why don't we all just ride her?
Look at her boobs.
It's like two grocery bags
full of soup.
- That's really mean.
- Excuse me?
You don't know her.
You don't know
what her life is like.
So? Why do you care?
Because she's my mom.
I thought you guys
were different.
That your boyfriend?
Hey.
Yeah, this is Finn.
He's in the Army, so we really
haven't been
talking much lately.
I had a girlfriend back home
when I first started NYADA.
Yeah, we lasted six weeks.
No, that's not
gonna happen to us.
I'm not gonna turn
my back on him.
Oh, nobody said you should.
Anyway, I came to tell you
that you killed it
in Tibideaux's class.
Nice job.
Thank you.
You know, it's just,
other than when I was
singing that song,
I've just really never felt as
amazingly wrong as I do here.
Just all alone.
Kind of feel like I'm just
gonna throw up all the time.
Well, it's just because
you're becoming
a different person.
That's why you came
to New York.
To be that new
and improved girl.
Here, let me see your phone.
We're gonna take a picture.
Let me see.
You look good.
Don't fight the new you.
Because from what I've seen,
she is gonna kick
some serious tail.
And start adding
new memories to the old ones.
Walk you to class?
What's the problem, people?
You've been here a week.
You should be dancing at, like,
Black Swan levels
of psychosis right now.
You, Miss Schwimmer.
Show me your piqué.
Okay, give me another one.
Center yourself this time.
Better, slightly.
You gonna roll your
eyes at me now?
No.
And I'm gonna
keep getting better
till I'm the best
you've ever seen.
Oh, you're mouthy.
And you got guts.
Good, I like it.
I like that spirit
in my students.
'Cause it'll make
it more fun for me
when I'm making your every
waking moment a hell on earth.
So boring.
All right.
As soon as you find
a place to live,
I'll ship you the
rest of your stuff.
And you'll get enough cash
from selling your car
to get you through at least
two weeks in a motel.
And the emergency credit
card, which is only for what?
Emergencies.
Dad, this is silly.
I don't have to be in New York
to reapply for NYADA.
So I can find a job
that pays me the same amount
as Lima Bean, but pay
ten times more in rent?
Yeah, because it's
an adventure.
Look, all great artists need a
little struggle in their lives.
Didn't you tell me
that Julia Roberts
sold shoes in New York
before she made it?
Good enough for Pretty Woman,
good enough for Kurt Hummel.
Scared?
Terrified.
New York is gonna be a
breeze compared to Lima.
Think about all the crap
you've been putting up with
the last couple years.
You know the difference between
this place and New York?
Decent bagels?
New York is filled
with people like you.
People who aren't
afraid to be different.
You're gonna feel
at home there.
If you're not scared,
just means you're not
sticking out your
neck far enough.
You truly are
the world's greatest dad.
I know. It's written
on the coffee mug
you got me for Father's Day.
Now, get out of here.
You're gonna miss your flight.
I'm gonna miss you, Dad.
You can always come back.
But you won't.
I love you.
I love you, too, Kurt.
Hey, Marley, um, just wanted
to apologize for all of us
and beg you not to quit.
Look, I get you.
Like, for instance, I know that
that sweater is from Walmart
- and your mom sewed the J.Crew label into it.
- How do you know that?
Because my mom used to do
the same thing for me.
The best thing about Glee Club
is it's not about labels.
If you can sing,
if you can dance,
you belong.
And, dude, you can sing.
I don't know.
You say that,
but the way you were
making fun of my mom,
something doesn't feel right.
We came to apologize.
I think being popular
felt a little too good,
and we forgot ourselves.
Well, I didn't.
I was always popular,
but I do forget to wear
underwear sometimes, though.
The best part about
Glee Club is that
everyone gets to be a star.
Which is why we're all
hoping that you could
come to rehearsal with us
this afternoon
and maybe sing lead vocal on
one of the songs
we're working on.
And if words
don't convince you,
let the majesty and mystery
of Unique's fabulousness
be enough!
I mean it.
Glee Club's a special place.
I mean, where else could I
dress like this and be
welcomed with open arms?
Okay, one last thing.
I don't think I'm comfortable
sitting with
that cheerleader
and those guys at lunch.
That won't be a problem.
We could handle Gimpy
and the Tarantula Head
and Richie Poor, because
you guys were national champs
like us, but our invitation
was not extended
to pre-op Precious
based on the novel Barf
by Sapphire
and Mike and Molly's daughter
as part of our crew.
Well, I guess we're not
in your crew anymore.
You know, I was kind of hoping
you'd say that.
And with that,
order is restored.
Well, looks like
you guys have been
officially welcomed
to the Glee Club.
Unique's eyes...
they are on fire!
Let's get you guys cleaned up
and go to rehearsal.
You wanted to see me?
Yes, I wanted
to talk to you
about your audition.
Do you have any idea
how hard I worked on that song?
I was up for three nights
getting it right,
and you didn't even
let me finish.
Glee Club performs
in front of hundreds of people.
Some of them might boo you.
You gonna throw
a mic stand at them?
So I'm angry.
I got a right to be.
You don't know me.
You don't know my life.
I know your brother, Jake.
Puckerman.
Half-brother.
Our dad's like an NBA player.
There could be
50 other Puckermans
running around Ohio.
No one ever mentioned
anything about having a brother.
He doesn't know.
I get it.
Now that you know
I'm related to your boy,
I'm good enough
for your stupid club?
No. When I saw you
were related to him,
I realized how much good
Glee Club did him.
Made me want to take
a chance on you.
But you've got to get
that chip off your shoulder.
And I interrupted
your audition because I knew
after the first verse
that I wanted you in this club.
You're really good, Jake.
You think I'm good?
Yeah.
No.
I'm not changing.
I like this chip on my shoulder
and I'm not losing it
to sing for you.
I'm not my brother.
♪ I've made up my mind ♪
♪ Don't need to think it over ♪
♪ If I'm wrong, I am right ♪
♪ Don't need to look
no further ♪
♪ This ain't lust ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ This is love ♪
♪ But if I tell the world ♪
♪ I'll never say enough ♪
♪ 'Cause it was not
said to you ♪
♪ And that's exactly
what I need to do ♪
♪ If I end up with you ♪
♪ Should I give up ♪
♪ Or should I just keep
chasing pavements? ♪
♪ Even if it leads nowhere ♪
♪ Nowhere ♪
♪ Or would it be a waste ♪
♪ Even if I knew my place ♪
♪ Should I leave it there? ♪
♪ Should I give up ♪
♪ Or should I just keep
chasing pavements? ♪
♪ Even if it leads nowhere ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Should I give up ♪
♪ Or should I just keep
chasing pavements? ♪
♪ Even if it leads nowhere ♪
- ♪ Or would it be a waste ♪
- ♪ Would it be a waste ♪
- ♪ Even if I knew my place ♪
- ♪ If I knew my place ♪
- ♪ Should I leave it there? ♪
What's wrong?
You sound sad.
I lied. I'm not okay.
- ♪ Should I just keep on ♪
- ♪ Chasing ♪
♪ Chasing... ♪
I miss you,
and I miss everything.
- ♪ Should I just ♪
- ♪ Keep on ♪
- ♪ Chasing pavements? ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Should I give up ♪
♪ Or should I just keep
chasing pavements? ♪
♪ Pavements... ♪
My dance teacher's a monster,
and I can't even
go to my dorm room,
because my roommate is
sleeping with the entire school.
Why don't you move out
and find a new roommate?
Yeah.
Turn around.
♪ Should I give up ♪
♪ Or should I just keep
chasing pavements? ♪
♪ Even if it leads nowhere. ♪
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.