[Rooster crows]
[Dog barks]
[Horses whinny]
[Engine starts]
[Bell tolls]
- You got all your stuff?
- Oh, yeah.
[Crow caws]
When you get there,
be sure and give us a call.
- We want to know where you are.
- All right.
[Bus horn blows]
- How are you fixed for money?
- Oh, I'm OK.
[Laughs]
You better take...
Take this 50 in case you run
into a mite of trouble.
You never know what's gonna happen
between here and there.
Thank you.
Well, boy...
Don't worry too much.
It's just the smart people
that have to worry.
The Lord will take care
of the ignorant ones.
- [Laughs]
- Huh? You paying attention?
Right.
I love you.
See you.
##
[man] Any person who alters,
forges, knowingly destroys,
knowingly mutilates,
or in any manner
changes this certificate,
may be fined not to exceed $10,000,
or imprisoned
for not more than five years...
...or both.
[Woman] # When the moon
# Is in the seventh house
# And Jupiter
# Aligns with Mars
# Then peace
# Will guide the planets
# And love
# Will steer the stars
# This is the dawning
of the Age of Aquarius
# Age of Aquarius
# Aquarius
# Harmony and understanding
# Sympathy and trust abounding
# No more falsehoods or derisions
# Golden livin'
dreams of visions
# Mystic crystal revelation
# And the mind's true liberation
# Aquarius
# When the moon
# Is in the seventh house
# And Jupiter
# Aligns with Mars
# Then peace
# Will guide the planets
# And love
# Will steer the stars
# This is the dawning
of the Age of Aquarius
# Age of Aquarius
# Aquarius
# [vocalizing]
# Harmony and understanding
# Sympathy and trust abounding
# No more falsehoods or derisions
# Golden livin'
dreams of visions
# Mystic crystal revelation
# And the mind's true liberation
# Aquarius
# Aquarius #
- [cymbals crash]
- Yeah!
Excuse me, ma'am.
Could you spare some change?
That's a great hat you've got.
Can you spare
a couple nickels or dimes?
- Beautiful horse.
- Ma'am, could you spare some change?
I've never ridden a horse.
Is it difficult?
Well, would it be possible if
I could ride it, just a little ways?
Just once, for a minute?
Hey, lady, could I ride...
Come on. Please?
[Man] Woof, forget it.
I'll get you one for Christmas.
- [Laughing]
- Spare some change?
Spare some change?
Change. You know,
like nickels, dimes, quarters?
- You want me to give you some money?
- Right.
- Why?
No reason, except she's pregnant
and we haven't eaten for two days.
I don't believe you.
- Where you from?
- Oklahoma.
Listen, man, I know how it feels.
I used to come from Kansas myself.
Hey!
[Organ playing]
[Choir humming gospel]
[Indistinct chattering]
[Woman] Bring him. Bring him!
[Humming continues]
[Man] Watch out for that hill.
[Continues, indistinct]
- [Woman] Watch it here.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Indistinct chattering, laughing]
Hold on, hang on.
Whoo!
[Whinnies]
# Sodomy
# Fellatio
# Cunnilingus
# Pederasty
# Father, why do these words sound
# So nasty?
# Masturbation
# Can be fun
# Join the holy orgy
# Kama Sutra
# Everyone #
[horse whinnies]
- [Woman] Get the horse!
- [Man] Stop the horse!
Hey, stop that horse!
- Whoo!
- Woo-hoo!
[All shouting]
Go, go! Go get them! Go! Go get them!
Come on, go! Get them!
# Once upon a looking-for-Donna time
# There was a 16-year-old virgin
# Oh, Donna
Oh, oh, Donna
# Oh, oh, oh
Looking for my Donna
# I just got back
from looking for Donna
# San Francisco
psychedelic urchin
# Oh, Donna
Oh, oh, Donna
# Oh, oh, oh
Looking for my Donna
# Have you seen
- # My 16-year-old tattooed woman?
- [Chorus] # Oh, Donna
- # Heard a story
- [chorus] # Oh, Donna
# She got busted for her beauty,
oh, oh, oh
# I just got back
from looking for Donna
# San Francisco's
psychedelic urchin
# Oh, Donna
Oh, oh, Donna
# Oh, oh, oh
Looking for my Donna
# And I'm gonna show her
life on Earth can be sweet
# Gonna lay my mutated head
at her feet
# I'm gonna love
to make love to her
# Till the sky turns brown
# I'm evolving, I'm evolving
# Through the drugs
# That you put down
# Once upon a looking-for-Donna time
# There was a 16-year-old virgin
# Oh, Donna
Oh, oh, Donna
# Oh, oh, oh
Looking for my Donna
# Looking for my Donna
# Donna
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
[blues guitar]
Hey, man, you're a real cowboy.
No, no, don't get off. We still got
15 minutes left. Take off.
- No, I got some things I gotta do.
- Yeah? Like what?
I want to see
the Empire State Building.
I can do that today. Tomorrow, I wanna
go on that boat ride around Manhattan
- where you see the Statue of Liberty.
- Sounds real good.
If you have any ideas
about things to do while I'm here...
I don't have too much time.
I'm going in the army
in a couple days.
I think we can help you.
[Women] # Hashish
# Cocaine
# Marijuana
# Opium
# LSD
# DMT
- # STP
- # BMT
- # A&P
- # IRT
# SPC
- # Alcohol, cigarettes
- Claude.
Here, man.
Hey, Claude.
Claude, hey, speak to me. Claude!
Hey.
- # Equinol, Dexamil, Compazine
- # Dexedrine
- # S-E-X Y-O-U
- Is she really pregnant?
# Wow #
Really pregnant? Yeah, I am.
That's what she says.
"That's what she says."
That's what she knows.
- I am.
- Jeannie, you don't know anything.
- I know who the father is.
- Yeah?
You know that, you know a lot.
If the baby comes out white
and squishy, crying his ass off,
then we know Woof
is definitely the daddy.
But if he comes out all beautiful
and chocolate brown,
that's mine.
- [Woof] "White and squishy"?
- Yeah, man. White and squishy.
[All laughing]
Listen, he come out and see
your crazy black ass standing there,
he's gonna be spitting
watermelon seeds in your face.
You always open up your mouth
before you even think.
Look, when this baby
comes out and sees me,
he's gonna be so happy
and so proud.
Do you know what he's gonna say?
# I'm
# A colored spade, a nigra
# A black nigger
# A jungle bunny, jigaboo
# Coon, pickaninny, mau-mau
# Uncle Tom, Aunt Jemima
# Little black Sambo
# Cotton-pickin' swamp guinea
# Junk man, shoe shine boy
# Elevator operator
# Table cleaner
at Horn and Hardart
# Slave, voodoo zombie
# Ubangi-lipped, flat nose
# Tap dancer, resident of Harlem
# And President
of the United States of Love
# President of the United States of Love
# Bad shit
If you invite this man to dinner
You're gonna have to feed him
# Watermelon, hominy grits
and shortening bread
# Alligator ribs and pig tails
# With some black-eyed peas
# Lord, chitlins
# Some watermelon, hominy grits
and shortening bread
# Alligator ribs, pig tails
# Black-eyed peas
# Collard greens
# And if you don't watch out
the boogie man will get you
# Boo
Yeah, I'm talkin' about y'all
- # Ooh
- # Oh, yeah
# So you say
Ha-ha! Whoo!
Say something to boogie man.
Go on.
Say something to the boogie man.
Boogie man.
It's his first day in America.
He just got off the boat.
Did you have a nice trip?
# Manchester, England
England
# Across the Atlantic sea
# And he's a genius
Genius
# He believes in God
# And he believes that God
believes in Claude
# That's him
# Claude Hooper Bukowski
# Finds that it's groovy
to hide in a movie
# Pretends he's Fellini
and Antonioni
# And also his countryman
Roman Polanski
# All rolled into one
# Claude Hooper Bukowski
# Manchester, England
England
# Across the Atlantic sea
# And he's a genius
Genius
- # He believes in God
- # I believe in God
- # And I believe that God
- Yeah!
# Believes in Claude
That's me
# That's me
# Claude Hooper Bukowski
# Finds that it's groovy
to hide in a movie
# Pretends he's Fellini
and Antonioni
# And also his countryman
Roman Polanski
# All rolled into one
# Claude Hooper Bukowski
# Manchester, England
England
# Across the Atlantic sea
# And I'm a genius
Genius
# I believe in God
# And I believe that God
believes in Claude
- # That's me
- # That's him
# That's me #
# I'm black
I'm black
# I'm pink
I'm pink
# I'm Rinso white
# I'm invisible
# Ain't got no home
Ain't got no shoes
# Ain't got no money
Ain't got no class
# Ain't got no scarf
Ain't got no gloves
# Ain't got no bed
Ain't got no pot
- # Ain't got no faith
- Look here, man.
# Ain't got no mother
Ain't got no culture
# Ain't got no friends
Ain't got no schoolin'
# Ain't got no shine
Ain't got no underwear
# Ain't got no soap
Ain't got no A-train, Ain't got no mind
# Ain't got no smokes
Ain't got no job, Ain't got no work
# Ain't got no coins
Ain't got no pennies
# Ain't got no girl
Ain't got no ticket
# Ain't got no token
Ain't got no God
Yeah!
# Ain't got no grass
Ain't got no acid
# Ain't got no clothes
Ain't got no pad
# Ain't got no apples
Ain't got no knives
# Ain't got no guns
Ain't got no garbage
- # Ain't got no draft card
- # Burn it
# Ain't got no Earth, Ain't got no fun
Ain't got no bike, Ain't got no pimples
# Ain't got no trees
Ain't got no air, Ain't got no water
# City, banjo, toothpicks, shoelaces
teachers, football, telephone
# Records, doctor
brother, sister, uniforms
# Machine guns, airplanes, germs, M-1s
Bang, bang, bang
# M-2, bang, bang, bang
# Ain't got no home
Ain't got no shoes
# Ain't got no money
Ain't got no class
# Ain't got no scarf
Ain't got no gloves
# Ain't got no bed
Ain't got no pot
# Ain't got no faith
# Ain't got no God #
Hey!
Where you going?
I got a lot of things to do today.
Thank you.
Hey!
Claude!
What?
Come here!
I want to show you something.
What is it?
Just come here, please.
- What?
- Look at that.
What?
- That's the chick on the horse.
- Oh, that's not her.
What do you mean?
Look at it.
Short Hills.
It's real close.
- That's today?
- That's right.
You want to go?
Why?
Why? Don't you want to meet her?
Don't you have
to be invited to those?
Would you like to come
to a party with me?
## [dance]
## [continues]
[Whining]
[Indistinct chattering]
Come on, will you guys spread out?
Mingle.
Sit, my dear.
[Man] Steve? Steve?
- Great party, huh?
- Yeah.
Steve...
There's an odd-looking
character over there.
And here to the right,
that chap over there.
That colored gentleman over there
with the girl.
See those two girls there?
- Do you know them?
- No.
Why don't you just unobtrusively...
...see if you can find out
who they are, how they got here,
who invited them,
and come back and let me know, will ya?
- Sure thing.
- OK.
Hi, I'm Steve Wright.
- What's your name?
- Hud.
Hud.
Are you supposed to be here?
- I mean, who brought you guys?
- Mr. Berger.
Well, enjoy the party.
[Laughing]
They're with Mr. Berger.
- Mr. Berger?
- Yeah.
Who's Mr. Berger?
I don't know.
Don't even suck on it
if you don't want to burn your lips.
- Now?
- Now start puffing on it.
- Now, now, now.
- [All chuckling]
- [Knocking]
- There. See?
- [Man] Sheila?
- Just a minute.
- [Knocking continues]
- Just a minute!
[Man] What's taking so long, love?
- [Whispering] We're smoking grass.
- I'm getting dressed.
Sweetheart, come on. You have a lot
of people waiting to see you.
Will you relax, Daddy?
Well, hurry up.
[Rattles doorknob]
- What's going on here?
- They're getting dressed.
Open the door this minute!
- I'm taking care of it.
- I can see you are.
[Knocking]
[Father] Sheila?
- Yes?
- [Giggling]
There's no excuse
for this performance.
Hello.
[Indistinct chattering]
Ted, Ted...
Excuse me. Mr. Berger?
- You can call me George.
- I think that it's a private party.
I think you and your friends
better leave, please.
- You do?
- Yes, I think that's the thing to do.
OK.
- [Hitting glass]
- Mr. Berger...
[Berger] Excuse me, everybody.
- Everybody, please quiet down.
- Mr. Berger...
I think that you and your...
I just wanted to say a few words,
then we'll go.
- I don't care what you have to say.
- I know. Everybody, listen.
- We weren't invited to this party...
- Mr. Berger.
Just a second.
I just want to talk for a second, OK?
- I don't care about that.
- I know you don't care.
- I think you better leave.
- Please, just give me two minutes.
Just wanna talk to
the people for a second.
- All right?
- No.
- Please.
- No, I think you better go.
Please.
I'm losing my patience.
This is a private party.
You were not invited.
You'd better leave.
- You don't understand.
- I have nothing to understand.
You got something to understand.
You don't understand what this man
will be doing for you.
- I don't want to hear about it.
- You should hear about it!
- You know what he's gonna do for you?
- I don't care!
You should care because
he's gonna be fighting for you.
He's going to Vietnam to fight for you,
to save your life!
- I don't care what he's gonna do.
- To save your life!
Or what you're gonna do.
- I want you out!
- You should care!
If you want me out of here,
you'll have to throw me out.
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna get the police. I'm not gonna
muss myself up fussing with you.
- I'll get the police if I have to.
- OK.
- That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
Penguin.
Now, my friend, Claude, here,
is in love.
He saw this chick on a horse...
- Excuse me.
- Jesus.
[Man] Now, let's deal
with this as gentlemen.
- OK. OK. Good.
- Quietly. As gentlemen.
- Now may I give you a word of advice?
- Yeah.
Get your ass out of here, now.
Is that it?
- That's it, yes.
- Thank you.
Now, listen.
Claude here is in love.
The girl he's in love with
is sitting in this room.
He just wants to sit here
and look at her for five minutes.
He just wants to look at her
and have this picture in his head
when he's off there fighting
in the jungles.
Is that so much to ask?
Hey! This is for you, man.
Wait a minute.
This is what you want.
Sheila, is that OK if Claude
just sits here and looks at you
for a few minutes before we go?
You've got a hell of a nerve,
young man.
# I got life, mother
# I got laughs, sister
# I got freedom, brother
# And I got good times, man
# I got crazy ways, daughter
# I got million-dollar charm, cousin
# I got headaches and toothaches
# And bad times too
# Like you
[woman screams]
# I got my hair, I got my head
I got my brains, I got my ears
# I got my eyes
I got my nose
# I got my mouth
I got my teeth
# I got my tongue, I got my chin
I got my neck, I got my tits
# I got my heart, I got my soul
I got my back
# I got my ass
# I got my arms, I got my hands
I got my fingers, Got my legs
# I got my feet, I got my toes
I got my liver, Got my blood
# I got life, mother
# I got laughs, sister
# I got freedom, brother
# I got good times, man
# I got crazy ways, daughter
# I got million-dollar charm, cousin
# I got headaches and toothaches
- Watch out!
- # And bad times too
- # Like you
- Oh, my God!
# Got my hair, Got my head
Got my brains, Got my ears
# Got my eyes
Got my nose
# My mouth
I got my teeth
# I got my tongue, Got my chin
Got my neck, Got my tits
# Got my heart, Got my soul
My back
# I got my ass
# I got my arms, I got my hands
I got my fingers, Got my legs
# I got my feet, I got my toes
I got my liver, Got my blood
# Got my guts
Got my muscles
# I got life, life, life
# Life, life, life
# Life #
Claude Bukowski,
George Berger,
Lafayette Johnson,
Jeannie Ryan, Woof Daschund.
The court is about to pronounce
sentence upon each of you.
The sentence of the court:
You be confined to the workhouse
for 30 days
or pay a fine of $50.
Your Honor,
I don't think you understand.
We haven't got any bread.
I'm awfully sorry.
There isn't anything I can do.
- [Claude] Your Honor?
- Yes, sir?
What if one of us has the money?
- Which one?
- I do.
[Mouthing words]
You may proceed to pay your fine.
Proceed to the clerk's office.
- Excuse me, Your Honor.
- [Man] What's your name?
- Bukowski.
- Wait a second. Put down George Berger.
- No!
- Berger...
- Bukowski.
- Just one second. Claude, listen.
Let me get out of here.
I'll go and get the money.
- Then I'll get everybody out.
- This is my money.
I'm sorry, but my dad gave me
this money in case of trouble.
- This is trouble.
- Don't be stupid, man.
This is your last chance
to get us out of here.
Just stop it. This is mine.
I'm getting out of here.
- Don't you trust me?
- Of course not.
Look, man, don't be stupid.
How will you get the bread?
You don't know anybody on the streets.
How you gonna get the bread?
He's not, man. He's just gonna leave us
in here to rot, that's all.
- No, I can make some calls.
- Yeah, call my mama.
You better know what you're doing.
You sure better, George.
[Horn honking]
What's that?
Uh, excuse me.
You're in our way.
What?
You're blocking our way.
Would you move, please?
Sure.
- Hi.
Remember me?
Yeah.
Come on in.
We have to get to school.
Great.
Just get in, will you?
What do you want?
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Jesus H. Christ!
What do you think you're doing?
You can't drive this car! We're only
covered for Dad and me, OK? Sheila...
Listen, man, I got a little problem.
I need some bread right away.
It's $250.
I need it now.
- This is all about money?
- Yeah. You got any?
No.
Look, we really don't have any time now.
We've got to be at school.
So will you just stop the car? OK?
Just let me drive.
Sheila!
- What do you want me to do?
- Tell him to stop.
Stop.
Listen, my friends are still in jail.
So what I figured was
you could ask your old man
for the bread to get them out.
- Ask my father for the money?
- Yeah.
[Laughing] Right.
He got us into this.
At least he could get us out of it.
- He got you into this?
- Yeah.
He told you to dance on the table
and break all the dishes?
He didn't tell me to dance on the table.
There's a left here
at the bottom of the hill.
- I think you're really crazy.
- What are you talking about?
The man got the kids in jail.
We want the money to get them out.
- Coming up is a left.
- It's impossible.
- Why is it impossible?
- He won't even give me a credit card.
- With that house you live in?
- It's coming up here!
- Two hundred and fifty dollars.
- Right here!
Turn left! Right here!
Jesus! You missed it!
What did I miss, Steve?
The school. It's back there.
- Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- [Laughs] Mmm.
OK. Look, we'll help you, OK?
We'll try to get you some money. OK?
So you can stop the car now,
and I'll drive. OK?
- When?
- I don't know. Right after school.
OK, how's that? About 4:00, OK?
We'll have it for you at 4:00.
See, that's my other problem, man.
- What?
- You're full of shit.
[Snickering]
[Berger] You won't ask your old man for
the bread, and Junior is full of shit.
What am I doing here?
[Stammering]
[Car horn honking]
[Clicking]
No, no, no, no...
- And men?
- Men? What do you mean?
Do you have any sexual attraction
towards men?
- Am I a homosexual or something?
- Yeah.
Well, I wouldn't kick Mick Jagger
out of my bed,
but I'm not a homosexual. No.
Can you tell me why you're so uptight
about having your hair cut?
# She asked me why
# I'm just a hairy guy
# I'm hairy, noon and night
# Hair that's a fright
# I'm hairy, high and low
# Don't ask me why
# Don't know
# It's not for lack of bread
# Like the Grateful Dead
# Darling
# Give me a head with hair
Long, beautiful hair
# Shining, gleaming
steamin', flaxen, waxen
# Give me it down to there
Hair
# Shoulder-length or longer
# Here, baby, There, Mama
Everywhere, Daddy, Daddy
# Hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Let it fly in the breeze
# And get caught in the trees
# Give a home to the fleas
in my hair
# A home for fleas
# A hive for the buzzin' bees
# A nest for birds
There ain't no words
# For the beauty, the splendor
the wonder of my hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# I want it long, straight, curly, fuzzy
# Snaggy, shaggy, ratty, matty
oily, greasy, fleecy
# Shining, gleaming, steaming
# Flaxen, waxen
knotted, polka-dotted
# Twisted, beaded, braided
- # Powdered, flowered
- # And confettied
- # Bangled
- # Tangled, spangled
# And spaghettied
# Oh, say can you see my eyes?
- # If you can
- # Then my hair's too short
- # Down to here
- # Down to there
- # Down to where it stops by itself
# Do-do-do-do-do
Do-do-do-do-do
[howling]
# They'll be ga-ga at the go-go
When they see me in my toga
# My toga made of blond
brilliantined, biblical hair
# My hair like Jesus wore it
# Hallelujah, I adore it
# Hallelujah, Mary loved her son
# Why don't my mother love me?
# Hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair #
You know, Danny's mother said
Danny said to say hello.
He's in second year
of dental school
and the girl he's dating
is beautiful, nice.
It's got a lot of mayonnaise,
the way you like, both sides.
- Eat it.
- Thanks, Mom.
- It's good. Eat it.
- I will.
Give me your pants.
I'll wash them.
- Why?
- They're dirty.
No, they're fine.
They're not dirty.
Yeah, they are. It'll take a minute.
The pants are fine, Ma.
What do you say, Pop?
What do you say, what?
Nothing, Ma. Nothing.
Pop?
- If you need money, get a job.
- Money? You talking about money?
- What do you need money for?
- Nothing, I just need it.
- Who is she?
- Who is who?
- The girl?
- What girl?
- Who is the girl?
- There's no girl.
You can tell us everything.
We understand everything.
What are you talking about?
I need some money.
If you need the money,
tell us the truth.
What are you talking about?
Goddamn it. Every time
you come home, there's trouble.
Why don't you clean yourself up?
Why don't you get a haircut?
Get a haircut,
and I'll give you the money.
You'll give me the money
if I get a haircut?
For Christ's sake,
do something to make us happy!
You'll give me the money
if I cut my hair?
- What?
- Will you give me $500?
- Give me your pants!
- My pants are clean!
Why? They're clean, for Christ's sake!
How much you need?
## [drumbeat]
- # Hair
- [whooping]
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair #
[chattering]
[Man] The draft is white people
sending black people
to make war on the yellow people
to defend land they stole
from the red people!
[All cheering]
# LBJ took the IRT
# Down to Fourth Street, USA
# When he got there
# What did he see?
# Tricky Dick on LSD
- # LBJ
- # IRT
# USA
# LSD
# LBJ
# FBI
# CIA
# LSD
- # LBJ #
- Hey. Come on.
[Sheila] Hey, Berger! Berger!
Berger!
- How you doing?
- Hi. How are you?
- All right.
- Listen, first...
I want to apologize for Steven.
He's very young,
and he really doesn't understand.
- [Drumbeat]
- [People cheering]
# Tell me who do you love
# Man
# Tell me what, man
# Tell me
# What did you love, man
# An old-fashioned melody
# Dy-dy-dy
Dy-dy-dy #
Listen, I was thinking...
...would you like to get married?
What?
Would you like to get married?
- To whom?
- Me.
Because I was thinking I'm having
this baby, and, if you were married,
the Army couldn't take you.
They wouldn't take you because they
don't take people who are married
and are having babies.
## [continues]
# We're all encased in sonic armor
# Beltin' it out
through chrome grenades
# Miles and miles of Medusan chord
The electronic sonic boom
# It's what's happening, baby
It's where it's at, Daddy
# They chain you and brainwash you
when you least expect it
# They feed you mass media
The age is electric
# I got the electric blues
I got the electric blues
# Dum clackety clack, boom rock
Folk rock, rhythm and blues
- # An old-fashioned melody
- # Dum clackety clack boom rock
# An old-fashioned melody
# We're all encased in sonic armor
beltin' it out through chrome grenades
# Miles and miles of Medusan chord
# It's what's happening, baby
It's where it's at, Daddy
# I got the electric blues
I got the electric blues
- # I got the electric blues...
- [organ]
[Organ continues]
# Do you, Sheila Franklin
# Take this man to be
# Your lawful wedded husband?
I do.
- # Do you, Claude Hooper Bukowski
- [hoof beats]
- # Take this woman to be
- [nickers]
# Your lawful wedded wife?
I do.
# I now pronounce you
man and wife
# [chorus] Hare Krishna
Hare Krishna
# Krishna Krishna
# Hare Hare
# Hare Rama
Rama Rama
# Hare Hare
# Hare Krishna
Hare Krishna
# Krishna Krishna
# Hare Hare
# Hare Rama
Hare Rama
# Rama Rama
# Hare Hare
# Hare Krishna
Hare Krishna
# Krishna Krishna
# Hare Hare
# Hare Rama
Hare Rama
# Rama Rama
# Hare Hare
# Love, Love, Love, Love
# Drop out, Drop out
Drop out, Drop out
# Be in, Be in, Be in, Be in
# Take trips, get high
Laugh, joke and good-bye
# Beat drum and old tin pot
# I am high on you-know-what
# Marijuana
# Marijuana, Marijuana
# Juana Juana
# Hare Hare
# Marijuana, Marijuana
# Juana Juana
# Hare Hare
# Beads, flowers
freedom, happiness
[screams]
# Beads, flowers
freedom, happiness
freedom, happiness...
[East Indian language]
[Jeannie] Claude!
[Crowd whooping]
Claude!
[Berger] Claude!
Claude Bukowski!
Hey, Berger.
Right there.
Are you all right?
Hey, you OK?
Where you been?
Where have we been?
Where have you been, man?
Watching the water.
Watching the water? Let me
see your eyes. Let me see those.
Oh, my God, black basketballs.
Look at my face.
Look at the sky.
Look at the stars.
- See the stars?
- Look at that.
Everybody,
a shooting star right over there.
Quick, everybody, make a wish.
Berger?
Will you take me home now, please?
Why do you want to go home?
It's Claude's last night.
Right?
Are we going to do something?
- Yeah, we'll do something.
- Yeah.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
It's Claude's night.
What do you want to do?
Take Sheila home.
[Berger] Hey, she's all yours.
Have a good time.
- I'm just taking her home.
- I know.
- Have a good time anyway.
- [Both chuckling]
Come on, Jeannie.
Come on.
- Whoa!
[Jeannie laughs]
Get your pants off and come on in!
You want to go home?
- You're just taking me home, right?
- Yeah.
- No, you know what I mean.
- I'm just taking you home.
Because nothing's gonna happen.
No, I'm just gonna take you home.
No. No, no. I think
I'll go home by myself.
No, I'll take you home.
- I don't feel like it.
- Why not?
I don't have to
explain everything to you...
...do I?
Come on! Come on, will ya?
The water is filthy, you know.
Listen, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be so...
I'm really sorry.
I wasn't trying to upset you.
That's all right.
It's just sometimes I get so...
I understand.
- You're upset, right?
- Oh, no.
No, you are.
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
I just... But I just thought...
- You're going away tomorrow, right?
- Yeah.
So, what's the point?
You mean, if I wasn't going away,
it would be different?
Maybe.
Well...
- I might not go.
- Right.
- You expect me to believe that?
- I'm serious.
Forget it.
I don't believe you.
Hey... Where did everybody else go?
They're around somewhere.
Jeannie's still up there.
Hey, where are our clothes?
- Where did they take them?
- [Snickering]
[Laughing]
Funny, funny, funny!
You guys are so mature.
Don't look at me.
I didn't have anything to do with it.
Don't worry about it.
They're around.
Berger!
Sheila...
- Taxi! Taxi!
- [Taxi tires screeching]
[Chuckling]
[Berger] Don't go!
I've got your purse! Sheila, wait!
I don't believe it, man.
What happened?
What the hell did you do that for?
- It was fun, man.
- Fun?
I'm really sorry.
I didn't think she'd ever
pull a stunt like that.
We know where she lives. We'll give
her clothes back tomorrow. It's cool.
I won't be here tomorrow.
You're not still serious
about that shit, are you?
That's none of your goddamn business.
It is my goddamn business, man.
What do you want?
You want to be a hero with a gun,
a big macho dude in a uniform?
- Is that what you want?
- I can't talk to you.
I'm standing right here.
Talk to me.
I'm right here. Talk to me.
I think you're ridiculous.
I am ridiculous.
I'm totally ridiculous.
I'm ludicrous.
I don't want to go over there
and murder women and babies.
Go ahead and be ridiculous,
and I'll do what I have to do.
Who are you doing it for?
I'm doing it for you, man.
Look, don't hand me that.
If you're doing it for me, don't.
Because if the shoe was on the
other foot, I wouldn't do it for you.
Give me my clothes.
How will she get home? She doesn't
have her stuff. She has no bread.
You better get that stuff to her.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Wasn't that what you wanted?
You're telling me I'm ridiculous?
##
[Claude] # Where do I go?
# Follow the river
# Where do I go?
# Follow the gulls
# Where is the something?
# Where is the someone
# That tells me
why I live and die?
# Where do I go?
# Follow the children
# Follow their smiles
# Is there an answer
# In their sweet faces
# That tells me why
I live and die?
# Follow the wind song
# Follow the thunder
# Follow the neon
# In young lovers' eyes
# Down to the gutter
# Up to the glitter
# Into the city
# Where the truth lies
# Where do I go?
# Follow my heartbeat
# Follow my hand
# Where do they lead me?
# And will I ever
# Discover why I live and die?
# I live and die
# Why do I live?
# Why do I die?
# Where do I go?
# Tell me why
# Tell me where
# Tell me why #
Next.
- [Man] Woodrow, Sheldon?
- Yes, sir.
Everything off, please.
Woodrow, your socks.
Woodrow...
Have you got some problem
with your socks?
No, sir.
Then take them off.
Sergeant.
Next.
# Black boys are delicious
# Chocolate-flavored love
# Licorice lips like candy
# Keep my cocoa handy
# I have such a sweet tooth
# When it comes to love
# Once I tried a diet
# Of quiet rest
# No sweets
# But I went nearly crazy
# And I went clearly crazy
# Because I really craved for
# Chocolate-flavored treats
# Black boys are nutritious
# Nutritious
- # Black boys fill me up
- # Up
# Black boys are so damn yummy
# They satisfy my tummy
# I have such a sweet tooth
# When it comes to love
- # Black, black
# Black boys
Next!
# White boys are so pretty
# Skin as smooth as milk
# Hair like Chinese silk
# White boys give me goose bumps
# White boys give me chills
# When they touch my shoulder
# That's the touch that kills
- # My mother calls them lily
- # Mama says lilies
- # I call them picadillies
- # Picadillies
- # My daddy wants me to stay away
- # Daddy
# But I say come and play
# Hey, hey, hey
# White boys are so groovy
- # White boys are so
- # Tough
# Every time they're near me
# Just can't get enough
# White boys are so sexy
# Sexy, sexy, sexy
# They're so long and lean
# Love those sprayed-on trousers
# I love the love machine
# My brother calls them rubble
- # They're my kind of trouble
- # Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo
# My daddy warns me no, no, no
# But I say white boys go, go, go
# White boys are so lovely
# Beautiful as girls
# Love to run my fingers
# And toes
through all their curls
# Give me a tall
- # A lean
- # A sexy
- # A pretty
- # A groovy
- # A juicy
- # White boy
# Yeah, give me a white boy
- # White boys
- # Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
- # Come on and lie down beside me
# White boys
# Yeah, give me a white boy
- # White boys
- # Ooh-ooh-ooh
# White boys #
[woman] # Doors locked
# Doors locked
# Blinds pulled
- # Lights low
- Move it!
[All yelling]
- # Lights low
- [soldiers shouting]
# Flames high
- # Flames high
- [men grunting]
# My body
- # My body
- [gun fire]
# My body
# My body is walking
# In space
# My soul is in orbit
# With God face-to-face
# Floating, flipping
# Flying, tripping
# Tripping from Pottsville
# To starlight
# Tripping from starlight
# To Moonville
[male chorus]
# Red black, Blue brown
- # Yellow crimson, Green orange
- Trainee.
- # Purple pink
- Hyah!
- # Violet white
- [grunting]
- # White white
- [yelling]
# White white
[female chorus]
# All the clouds are cumulus
# Walking in space
- # Oh, my God, your skin is soft
- [indistinct]
# I love your face
# How dare they try
# To end this beauty?
[Male chorus]
# They keep us underfoot
# They bury us in soot
# Pretending it's a chore
# To ship us off to war
[mixed chorus] # In this dive
we rediscover sensation
# In this dive
# Walking in space
we find the purpose of peace
# The beauty of life
You can no longer hide
- [leaders shouting]
- # Our eyes are open
# Our eyes are open
- [explosions]
- # Our eyes are open
# Wide
# Wide #
Hey, Berger! Berger!
Hey. How you doing?
- I'm all right.
- Yeah?
Look, I've got something.
Where is he?
Nevada!
So, I was thinking of writing him.
- What do you think I should say?
- I want to say something.
Tell him that... I want to say
that Jeannie says hi.
You're gonna write him?
Why don't you come with us?
- Where are you going?
- Nevada.
We are?
Aren't you serious about anything?
I'm always serious.
When are we going?
As soon as Sheila's ready.
I can't just take off and go to Nevada.
No, I guess not.
- We'll see you.
- Wait a minute.
- How will you get there?
- Car.
[Woman] Lafayette!
- You don't have a car.
- I'm gonna get a car.
- Lafayette?
- How? How can you get a car?
What are you staring at?
And who's that?
What are you doing here?
Come on.
- I said come with me.
- I heard you.
I'm asking you, who is that woman?
- Are you a friend of my Lafayette?
- I ain't no Lafayette no more.
- Don't bother her, all right?
- What have you done to your head?
Never mind.
Just go on back home.
Is that his child?
- Look, don't be talking to her.
- Is that your child?
You wouldn't understand.
What do you mean?
Is that your child or isn't it?
What kind of question is that?
Maybe it is and maybe it isn't.
What?
I knew you wouldn't understand.
You don't understand anything.
I understand just fine.
You explain it to me.
Do you understand about cosmic
consciousness and all kind of that shit?
That's what I'm talking about, baby.
All I'm talking about
is Lafayette Junior here is your child.
I just want to know
if that's your child too.
Never mind that. Come on.
Come on!
- Where are we going?
- I'm taking you to the bus.
- You're going back home. Come on!
- I don't want to go home!
You're going back home.
Understand me?
- I want to stay with you.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- Because you can't. I said so.
Look, we've got a friend in trouble,
and we have to help him.
Baby, that's all you need to know.
Why don't you just go home?
I never said you couldn't
help your friends, Lafayette.
Goddamn it, woman!
I ain't no Lafayette!
Shit! Don't you understand nothing?
# How can people
# Be so heartless?
# Be so cruel?
# Easy to be hard
# Easy to be cold
# How can people
# Have no feelings?
# You know I'm hung up on you
# Easy to be proud
# Easy to say no
# Especially people
# Who care about strangers
# Who care about evil
# And social injustice
# Do you only
# Care about the bleeding crowd?
# How about a needing friend?
# I need a friend
# How can people
# Be so heartless?
# How can they ignore their friends?
# Easy to give in
# Easy to help out
# Especially people
# Who care about strangers
# Who say they care about
# Social injustice
# Do you only
# Care about the bleeding crowd?
# Oh-whoa-oh-oh
# How about a needing friend?
# I need a friend
# How can people
# Have no feelings?
# How can they ignore their friends?
# Easy to be hard
# Easy to help out
# Easy to be proud
# Easy to say no #
- Hi, Steve.
- Hi.
Wanna come out of the car
for a minute?
No.
- I just want to talk to you.
- You want to talk? Talk.
I'd like to talk to you outside.
I don't want to talk to you.
Don't worry about a thing.
I'll handle this.
- OK. What do you want?
- The keys.
No. Hey, come on...
Cool out, baby.
- No, you're taking the car?
- Just for a few days.
- Coming with us?
- No, I'm not going with you!
- All right.
- Sheila, come on.
Out of the car. Sheila! What...
Sheila!
I'm not into any heavy preference trip,
you know, like who the father is.
I don't care.
I think they're both beautiful.
Don't you?
But how can you not care about that?
If a woman carries a child, don't you
think she should know who the father is?
Well, I admit that I have this dilemma.
But it will be resolved real soon.
It's not like a big crisis or anything.
It's not like a world war.
I don't know
what you're so uptight about.
I fell in love with someone.
We had a child,
and we were gonna get married.
That's why I'm uptight.
- Yeah?
- And you're holding it up!
No, I'm not holding it up.
You don't see the way it is.
This is really a great thing
that's happened to all of us.
Everybody's really happy about it.
The guys are really happy.
I think it would be great
if you could be happy about it, too.
- You're crazy.
- Yeah, I'm crazy.
We're all crazy.
Let's shake on it.
Let's not.
[Car horn honking]
[Sheila] Come on.
[Officers shouting orders]
[Shouting continues]
If all you men could be standing
where I'm standing
and seeing what I'm seeing,
you'd know how it feels
to be truly proud of our country.
The United States Army is the greatest
fighting force in the world.
And now, you men...
...are going to be thousands of miles
away from home in a few days.
And you'd better take some
of that greatness with you.
And this afternoon,
while you're on leave,
you'd better take some of it
with you, too.
- [Feedback]
- [Rock and roll music over P.A.]
## [continues]
[Cheering]
[Whistling]
Sergeant!
Shut the damn thing off!
# Ripped open
# By metal explosion
# Caught in barbed wire fireball
# Bullet shock
# Bayonet
- # Electricity
- What do I turn off?
Move out!
- # Electronic
- Attention!
- # Data
- [soldiers booing]
# Processing
# Black uniforms
- Company!
- Attention!
Company!
# Mail order
# Rifles
Get some results!
[Booing]
# Two hundred
# And fifty-six
# Vietcong
# Captured
# Two hundred
# And fifty-six
# Vietcong
# Captured
Prisoners in Niggertown
It's a dirty little war
Three, five, zero, zero
Take weapons up
And begin to kill
Watch the long, long armies
drifting home
[vocalizing]
# Prisoners in Niggertown
# It's a dirty little war
# Three, five, zero, zero
# Take weapons up
# And begin to kill
# Watch the long, long armies
drifting home
# Prisoners in Niggertown
# It's a dirty little war
# Three, five, zero, zero
- # Take weapons up
- # And begin to kill
# Watch the long, long armies
drifting home...
Everybody out!
[Music stops]
[Gunshots continues]
- Company!
- Attention!
Now can all you men hear me?
##
# Good morning, starshine
# The Earth says hello
# You twinkle above us
# We twinkle below
# Good morning, starshine
# You lead us along
# My love and me
as we sing
# Our early morning singing song
# Gliddy glup gloopy
Nibby nabby nooby
# La-la-la lo-lo
# Sabba sibby sabba
Nooby abba nabba
# Le-le lo-lo
# Tooby ooby walla
Nooby abba nabba
# Early morning singing song
# Good morning, starshine
# The Earth says hello
# You twinkle above us
# We twinkle below
# Good morning, starshine
# You lead us along
# My love and me
as we sing
# Our early morning singing song
# Gliddy glup gloopy
Nibby nabby nooby
- # La-la-la lo-lo
- # Gliddy glup gloopy
# Sabba sibby sabba
Nooby abba nabba
- # Le-le lo-lo
- # Nibby nabby nooby
# Tooby ooby walla
Nooby abba nabba
# Early morning singing song
# Singing a song
Humming a song
- # Singing a song
- # Whoa
# Loving a song
- # Laughing a song
- # Laughing...
- # Singing a song
# Sing a song
Song a sing
# Song, song, song
Sing, sing, sing, sing, song
Sing, sing, sing, sing, song #
Hi.
- How you doing? What can I do for you?
- We're going in.
I'm sorry, but there's no civilian
contact allowed on the base right now.
- We're on alert. You can't come in.
- We're not civilians.
We're friends of a guy on the base.
His name's Claude Bukowski.
- You probably know him. He's a private.
- I don't know him.
Really nice guy with blonde hair.
He's short.
I don't know him. You'll have to turn
your vehicle around and go off post.
All right? If you need some help,
I'll be glad to assist you.
Otherwise, back your vehicle up
and turn it around.
Listen, we don't want
to make any trouble.
- Turn around and you won't, OK?
- Just let me make a phone call.
No, you don't make it here.
You make it where I tell you to go.
You just said you wanted
to give me some assistance...
I'll help you turn around.
That's all.
- You don't understand...
- Chief, this is it.
Turn around and go.
We clear?
- You get my drift, right?
- You don't understand, man.
- You don't understand.
- We've driven five days straight!
- Listen, my man...
- I just want to see my friend.
I'm telling you
to get the hell off my post.
Turn around and go that way.
That's what I'm telling you.
You listen to me.
I'm not listening to you. Got that?
[Sighs]
[Starts engine]
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
## [country]
[Sheila] Uh, what's your name?
- What's your name?
- George.
- What's yours?
- Sheila.
Yeah?
- Is your husband on base?
- I'm not married.
I'm visiting my brother.
No, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
OK, this time I'll do it.
Hey, that was a really good one.
Let me do that again.
OK, I'll blow one,
and then you blow one,
and see if they can, you know...
You blow one through one of mine, OK?
Ooh! There, they did it.
- [George] Toot, toot!
- [Sheila giggling]
Where is it? Where is your car?
Right over there.
Hi.
[Giggling]
[Laughing]
God Almighty.
- [Laughing]
[Giggling and laughing]
Hey... Hey, let's pull over there.
[Clears throat]
Stop, stop. Let's stop here.
Company, halt.
- Dismissed.
- "Dismissed?"
Hey!
You cutie-pie!
Come here, my cutie!
Watch my hat!
[Honking car horn]
Hey! What are you doing?
Hey!
Hey, baby!
- [Car honking]
- [Laughing]
Hey! That's my car!
[All cheering]
Hey!
[Harmonica playing]
[Scissors snipping]
[Harmonica stops]
How do I look?
Very authentic.
[Chuckling]
[Laughing]
Your left. Your left, right, left.
Your left. Your left.
Your left, right, left.
- # I want to go to Vietnam
One, two, three, four...
[indistinct chattering]
[Soldier] At ease!
Bukowski!
- Yes, Sergeant.
- Let's move it out.
- Double-time, soldier.
Yes, Sergeant.
- "Double-time, soldier."
- [Chattering]
- Sir?
- In the car, soldier!
- Yes, Sergeant.
- Are you an asshole, soldier?
- No, Sergeant.
- That's too bad, because I am.
Blah, blah, blah...
[laughing]
How you doing, man?
[Both laughing]
# I want to be an Airborne Ranger
# I want to live a life of danger
- Stay in the car. Stay in the car.
- What are you doing?
# I want to go to Vietnam...
[chanting continues in the distance]
What are you doing?
- Get in the trunk.
- What?
- Come on. Get in the trunk quick.
- Why?
Everybody's waiting. We have a big
picnic planned for you in the desert.
- Come on, get in.
- The base is on alert.
They're taking head counts all the time.
If I'm not here, I've had it.
Listen, it's just for a couple of hours.
I'll have you back in time for dinner.
- I can't.
- What do you mean?
We just drove 2,000 miles to see you.
Everybody is waiting.
Just trust me, will ya?
I have it all figured out.
You're making it sound
like I don't want to come.
Then come.
Get in the trunk.
I mean...
I can't believe you're here.
I just can't believe it.
Traveling all that way?
I can't believe it.
I appreciate your coming here.
I can't tell you.
Don't tell me, just come with us.
Just get in the trunk.
You don't understand.
This isn't a game.
What will I tell everybody?
- Did Sheila come?
- Yeah.
- And Jeannie?
- Everybody's there, man.
How is Sheila?
How is she?
What are you doing?
Give me your clothes.
[Chattering]
- Claude!
- Hey!
- Hey Claudey!
- Claudio!
Hey, man! You made it!
[All laughing]
Hey!
- Whoo!
[Laughing]
Attention!
At ease!
Sound off when your name is called.
- Compost!
- Here, sir.
- Head.
- Sumner.
- Here, sir.
- Brook.
- Bukowski.
- Here, sir.
- Hart.
- Tileman.
- Here, sir.
- Scanlin.
- Noonan.
- Here, sir.
[Engine starts]
Now give me your attention, men.
I just received word we've been
alerted for overseas movement.
I want you to secure your web gear,
get your duffle bags packed,
and get on this red line.
Sergeant, you have three minutes
to have these men ready.
- Yes, sir.
- Let's go, men. Move with a purpose.
[Chattering]
Let's go! Let's get it all quickly.
Let's move with a purpose!
Let's snap to it
like you got a pair.
Let's go. Move it, quickly.
Get on the red line.
Get your duffle bag packed.
Let's go over there.
Move like you got a purpose.
What the hell's wrong with you, soldier?
Didn't you hear
what the captain said?
Get your cell pod!
Get your helmet liner!
Get your pistol belt!
Get it right now!
Let's move like you got a purpose!
Get the doggone coat on!
Quickly! Let's go! Move it!
I don't know what's the matter with you.
You act like you don't want to go.
I don't want to go, but if you gotta go,
I gotta go. We all gotta go.
So let's move it right now!
Let's get on the red line.
Let's go.
[Indistinct barking of orders]
What in the hell are you waiting on?
Get that web gear on!
I want that brain bucket on your head!
I want that duffle bag on the red line!
Soldier, there's a war on!
Huh...
[breathing heavily]
[Man] All right, men, move!
Hurry up!
Now, listen up!
When I call your name,
sound off smartly and move out!
- Compost!
- Yes, sir!
- Sumner!
- Peterson!
- Yes, sir!
- Brook!
- Bukowski!
- [Drum roll]
Bukowski!
You better get your head
out of your ass! Let's go!
This way, soldier!
Let's go! Move out!
You better move, soldier!
Hey! Where are you going!
What's the matter with you? I said
put your duffle bag on that truck!
The vehicle right there!
Let's go! Get it on there now!
# We starve, look
# At one another
# Short of breath
# Walking proudly
in our winter coats
# Wearing smells from laboratories
# Facing a dying nation
# Of moving paper fantasies
# Listening for the new-told lies
# With supreme visions
# Of lonely tunes
# Somewhere
# Inside something there is
# A rush of
# Greatness
Who knows what stands in front of
# Our lives
I fashion my future
# On films in space
# Silence tells me secretly
# Everything
# Manchester, England
England
# Across the Atlantic sea
# And I'm a genius
Genius
# I believe in God
# And I believe that God
believes in Claude
# That's me
# We starve, look
# At one another
- # Short of breath
- Berger!
# Walking proudly
in our winter coats
# Wearing smells from laboratories
- # Facing a dying nation
- Berger.
# Of moving paper fantasy
Listening for the new-told lies
# With supreme visions
Of lonely tunes
# Singing our space songs
# On a spider web sitar
# Life is around you and in you
# Answer for Timothy Leary
Dearie
# Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
# Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
- # Why don't you let
- # Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
# Let the sunshine
- # You wanna let
- # Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
- # Why don't you let
- # Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
- # Why don't you let
- # Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
# Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# the sunshine in
# Let the sunshine
# Let the sunshine in
# The sun...
#... shine in #
# Darling
# Give me a head with hair
Long, beautiful hair
# Shining, gleaming
steamin', flaxen, waxen
# Give me it down to there
Hair
# Shoulder-length or longer
# Here, baby, There, Mama
Everywhere, Daddy, Daddy
# Hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# I'll let it fly in the breeze
# And get caught in the trees
# Give a home to the fleas
in my hair
# A home for fleas
# A hive for the buzzin' bees
# A nest for birds
There ain't no words
# For the beauty, the splendor
the wonder of my hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# I want it long, straight
curly, fuzzy
# Snaggy, shaggy, ratty, matty
oily, greasy, fleecy
# Shining, gleaming, steaming
# Flaxen, waxen
knotted, polka-dotted
# Twisted, beaded, braided
- # Powdered, flowered
- # And confettied
- # Bangled
- # Tangled, spangled
# And spaghettied
# Oh, say can you see my eyes?
- # If you can
- # Then my hair's too short
# Down to here
Down to there
# Down to there
Down to where it stops by itself
# They'll be ga-ga at the go-go
When they see me in my toga
# My toga made of blond
brilliantined, biblical hair
# My hair like Jesus wore it
# Hallelujah, I adore it
# Hallelujah, Mary loved her son
# Why don't my mother love me?
# Hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# They'll be ga-ga at the go-go
When they see me in my toga
# My toga made of blond
brilliantined, biblical hair
# My hair like Jesus wore it
# Hallelujah, I adore it
# Hallelujah, Mary loved her son
# Why don't my mother love me?
# Hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair
# Flow it, Show it
# Long as God can grow it
My hair #