What about me, my lovely wife?
- Stop it! - Yes, my friend.
I still don't understand
why you're going to London
Why would the scion of one of the
richest families of Shimla...?
He isn't going after the money.
- Then...?
Man! Have you seen British babes?
- Forget babes
Not money, this is about dotcom
Someday, computer technology will
turn into a huge industry
And my ideas can best be put to use
out there. Why else would I leave home?
Will you forget us once you're there?
- How can you say that Mr Khanna?
Can we ever forget this friendship?
Did you hear that Tina? If our parents'
friendship isn't going to end...
how will our friendship end?
- Our friendship will never end Raj!
Tina, you will write to me, won't you?
- Yeah... yeah, I'll write...
I'll email you regularly.
- But I don't have a computer...
Of course!
You don't even have a computer!
But I have...
- Excellent!
I'll email you on Pooja's computer
Pooja, you always help me out,
you're such a good friend
Come on son, its time
for the train to leave...
Dear Tina,
London is such a huge city
Such tall buildings and Big Ben is so
much bigger than the Shimla clock tower
We live in Hampstead. We're the only
lndian family over here
Everyone else is British
The best part about schools here is,
you don't have to wear uniforms...
everything's straight out of an
Archie comic... London is...
Such a big and beautiful city!
But I miss home. India. And you!
I'm waiting to hear from you.
Do write. Love, Raj
Raj has really turned into
a big bore!
God! Do I have to sit
and email him now? No way...
Tina! You promised him you'd write!
- Sure...I must have...
You're always making Raj so miserable
- So now I should sit and email him?
If you're so keen,
why don't you write?
Dear Raj, London sounds so exciting.
Shimla is all the same
I remembered you at lunch today.
I ate your favourite "gobi parathas"
Do you get "gobi parathas" in London?
Bye for now. Got to do homework
Dear Tina, I'm so happy you replied.
Now we'll always be friends
Yes I do get "gobi parathas" here
Our ltalian chef makes them
under mummy's supervision
But they don't taste like lndia
Guess what... I stood first in class
I didn't know you're
as sharp as Pooja in studies
You know, I've been selected
for the class cricket team
Someday even I might become
a big cricketer
I've a new friend, Ronnie Mendonca.
I go to church every Sunday with Ronnie
Something strange happened
when I went to church today
Suddenly I started humming a tune.
I'm e-mailing you the tune
Your tune is as much of a habit with me
as you are. Whenever I'm in church.
I hum your tune.
- For me, you're like a habit
Unless I've written to you
all about everything...
I can't even go to sleep.
- Then start reading
Love Story
You know something, I only have
a 15-year old photo of you and Pooja
I've asked you so many times,
at least send me a photo
Well...considering what you say
... that you know me so well...
I want to see if you even recognise me
when we're face to face
Oh come on, who needs a picture!
I'll recognise you the instant I see you
Your image is in my heart.
- Liar
We'll soon know who the liar is.
I have some good news, I'm coming home
I'm coming back to lndia.
I'm going to see you once again
After so many years... in a way
I'll be seeing you for the first time
You must be so beautiful!
I'm sure...
you're still the prettiest...
still the most beautiful
That's not me Raj,
that's someone else...someone else...
y
He's coming back!
- Who?
Raj!
- Who's Raj?
What have you done Pooja? Why did you
write all those letters in my name?
Ok so I was stupid! But now you have
to help me. He's here just for 2 weeks
Just for 2 weeks you have to pretend
you wrote those letters...that's all
Its as simple as that!
- I can't do something so stupid!
Tina, after all I've done for you?
Ever since we were kids...
I've always done your homework.
Because of me, you've passed every year
But you? You can't even do
this much for me?
Ok, ok stop trying to get my sympathy
like always and just leave it to Tina!
So tell me,
what does this Raj look like?
Six foot tall, blue eyes, and...
- Enough...Iet him come
Let's see what this Raj is all about
y
The one who comes in my dreams
I wonder how she'll be
The one who keeps me awake all night
Hiding in my heart since long
I wonder how she'll be
The one who comes in my dreams
I wonder how he'll be
Hiding in my heart since long
I've seen him in such different ways
Seems like I know him for days
Heavens are deciding the
fates of 2 hearts
Without even seeing him
I'm so restless
Oh my God! what will happen to
you if you meet him?
Taking my dreams away always
coming in my way how she'll be?
In my eyes he has a place
in my heart since days
For the first time when I meet
the one, the only of my dreams
Nervous I am I don't know why
seems like hiding the moon in the sky
I will not say a word to her,
Just keep staring at her face
Oh this restless this eagerness!
I wonder how he'll be
Hoping she is want I have seen
All these years in my dreams
I will be meeting her soon
In a day, or two I wonder how she'll be
The one who comes in my dreams
I wonder how he'll be
The one who keeps me awake all night
I wonder how she'll be
I wonder how he'll be
That's Raj! Not bad.
So how long does the act last?
2 weeks? Leave it to Tina.
I'll do as much for you
How're you son?
Our Raj has become so handsome
Here comes my friend from London!
Play it up for my friend!
Eat, drink, make merry!
Come on...
- Give me a hug
Dear sister-in-law...
- What are you upto?
Just taking a chance
You must be Tina, right?
I'll recognise you the instant
I see you, your image is in my heart
You're even more beautiful than
I had imagined you to be
That I am...but you're not
too bad yourself Mr America
America? But... I'm from London
- London, America.... who cares?
And anyway, once I've said it,
I've said it, understand Mr America?
Pooja?
Even you're all grown up too.
But I never thought...
Tina would grow up like this!
- And what did you think about me?
How do I tell you
what I've thought about you?
Those who think, don't do
and those who do, don't think...
Kids! What are you doing here?
Come on, let's hurry home
I'm celebrating your return
with a kirtan at home
Not another prayer session!
- Oh yes. One more
Say hail to the Mother Goddess
I had heard that people forget
their culture when they go abroad
I may have gone abroad
but my heart was right here
Wow, that's culture for you!
Mr America's actually winking!
You're amazing... you look beautiful
even in a churidaar
I wish I could say the same for you
Well son, won't you join in the prayer?
I wonder how he'll be
It's not that I don't like him...
he's quite good looking...
But these good looking guys have
their noses up in the air...
they have to be brought down to earth.
- No Tina! Raj is not like that!
Really? You seem to be quite into Raj?
While writing all those letters...
I hope you haven't fallen
in love with him
I'm so stupid! You're not going
to fall in love.
You've only time for your books & computer.
And you're a good daughter.
You'll marry the person your parents
choose for you, right?
And you? What sort of a marriage
are you going to have?
Me? I'm definitely going to have
a love marriage!
Are you in love with Raj...?
- Tina doesn't fall in love with boys
Boys fall in love with Tina...
- If you're talking about love...
then you must've mentioned my name?
- You wish!
Tina, you remember when we were kids?
We'd bunk school and come skiing here?
And Pooja used to bring our homework!
Pooja what have you brought today?
Raj.
- Me? How's that?
Hey Mr America... bet? I'll win today
just like I used to when we were kids.
Lets see who wins...
I never accept defeat, Raj.
- But I really enjoy losing
You enjoy losing in a race?
- Who's talking about the race?
What then?
- I'm talking about losing my heart
Why are you in such a rush to lose?
- I'm in no rush... I've already lost
I don't shake hands with losers
Let me congratulate the winner
This is how you turn defeat
into a victory!
Who won?
- I lost a long time back... now...
Now...?
Now? Now its in His hands
For the first time I've looked
at a guy and felt something...
but this can't be love.
Love can't happen like this
I thought when I fell in love
I'd be on cloud nine
I thought I'd feel shy to look at him.
But this is nothing like that
Still I like him. It's easy
to be friendly with anyone...
but love is something
I know nothing about.
This is where You come in
I'm sleepy
Oh, I'm sorry, did I disturb you?
- Not at all. Come in
This is the same room isn't it?
This is the same room where
Tina used to write to me from?
This is the same room, this is the
same computer and this is the same me
Fifteen years!
It's exactly how I imagined it
You're still working?
- I'm applying to some universities.In London.
London? You're coming to London?
And I don't know?
I wanted to surprise you
What will you be studying?
- Art
Art? Tina also likes art.
Which university are you applying to?
London University.
- Hey that's my university!
I know.
- Why didn't you ever email me?
If I did would you reply to me
like you replied to Tina?
And what's that supposed to mean?
- That's the point. Anyway, forget it
You really like Tina don't you?
- You're her friend, I can tell you
You know, without meeting each other,
without having seen each other...
We...
- We know everything about each other
Not just that
Perhaps we started falling in love.
- Without meeting...
Without having seen each other.
- This is such a beautiful bond
And what makes it so perfect
is that Tina is so beautiful
Yes, that she is!
Pooja, looks like we're going
to be good friends
You'll be my first girl-friend!
Will you be my friend?
y
Would you be that special friend?
That special friend till the end
whether it's worth
being friends with you
Let me tell you
in a day or two...
That way we are friends
since days...
then why behave
in such different ways
You never know when
you fall in love...
That is so true
there is no clue
Who takes that heart
and just goes through
So! Would you be
that special friend?
Whether it's worth
being friends with you
That special friend till the end.
Let me tell you in a day or two
You too are a friend of mine,
so help me with your sunshine
Go ask your friend the reason why
she is so clue less, she is so shy
There is no reason why!
She is so clue less and so shy
All I know that she wants to be...
Is a friend, friend till eternity?
So! Would you be that special friend?
That special friend till the end
whether it's worth
being friends with you
Let me tell you
in a day or two...
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Walking into a girl's bedroom uninvited
Aren't you ashamed to sleep with the
door open with young men in the house?
Never expected a shameless young man
Well, that's me!
Anyway, what are you doing today?
Why?
You have to have lunch with
Tina and me today
No Raj, not today. I have to go
to the library and then...
This is such a romantic place.
There must be a special reason...
to bring me to such a romantic place?
Yes there is. What?
- I'm hungry!
Tina! Look there!
Raj, why are you looking at young boys?
- Didn't you see what he's reading?
Love Story
Love stories are so boring aren't they?
- You don't remember "Love Story"?
If you hang on to your old memories,
how will you ever create new ones Raj?
What will you have?
- You know what I like
Gobi parathas
Raj, I have to go. The youth festival
is coming up and like every year...
my dance performance will be the best!
Watch me! Everyone's waiting for me
Thanks you saved us today!
Youth Festival
I can't figure out why Tina seems
different in person from her letters
Look Raj, you guys are meeting for
the first time. Give her some time
You know Tina.
She's a bit forgetful
And then again writing to someone and
meeting face to face is so different
When I'm not with her, I imagine what
it will like when we're together...
but when we are together,
everything is very different...
Have you heard that song?
You're in that state of mind...
Which song?
If you don't meet me I worry...
But when you do meet me I feel shy
What's wrong with you?
Hey, "paratha"! Who ordered?
You're such a little kid!
Dip hot "parathas" into cool yogurt.
- And then straight into your mouth!
It's more fun to have
someone feed you
When do Tina's rehearsals get over?
- By the evening
Did you go for your rehearsals
or to a wholesale market?
I got to wear the perfect look.
- And all this shopping just for that?
I couldn't make up my mind...
- So you bought the entire store!
Pooja-Tina, we're home
Tina... don't you have something
to say to me?
What?
- Do I have to tell you...?
Not so fast
- Fifteen years is not fast...
Hey Pooja do you think
fifteen years is fast?
Even fifteen years weren't enough...
Why can't girls ever give a simple
answer to a simple question?
That's not how we say good
night in London
Hey Mr America, so tell me how
do you say good-night in London?
You can't be so far away...
Your eyes can't be open...
Eat. It's Sunday.
You won't put on weight
Back from his jogging.
He needs his cereal
Cereal-eater! You're missing "parathas"
- That's one "paratha"- paunch
No! That's my wife's love!
- Here's some more. With love
There's this really good proposal...
- Have you gone mad?
How can I get married a second time
when you're still alive?
Oh be quiet! Do you have to joke
all day long?
How can there be a proposal for you?
It's for Pooja
Nice people, the Vermas from London.
They own 3 restaurants. The boy is nice
What...?
- Really
Hear? Proposals for Pooja from London!
After all, whose daughter is she?
Pooja wait.
- What's it Mamma? I'm in a hurry
I have to meet Raj at 9:.30.
- Listen... here's a proposal for you
How many times do I have to say it?
I'm not ready to get married
Alright.
Hear me out. A proposal from London!
- From London?
Yes, they are very close friends.
Rohan Verma is their son
Mamma, I'm not interested. Tell him.
What was the name...? Tell Rohan Verma
Well, she's turned down the proposal
without even seeing the boy!
After all whose daughter?
- Eat
Raj, what's going on?
How will this look on Tina?
This will look beautiful on anyone
This is no ordinary pendant. Look
You really know how to break hearts!
Not breaking hearts.
I'm reuniting hearts.
One half stays with me and
the other with Tina
Isn't it amazing?
I wanted to show you before buying
Give me one more
One more?
- For you
For me?
When you find someone special,
give him one half
Finding someone special isn't so easy
I thought you wanted to wait a while?
You...? What are you doing here?
What if Daddy sees you?
What if Daddy doesn't see me?
- You're not as stupid as you look
Hey, Miss Universe, you're not
as beautiful as you look
You're much more beautiful than that
Look at this... one half of this
heart will be with me
And the other half... with you
- Hey Mr America...
anyone can steal in here in the middle of
the night and declare their love
I'll believe it when you say it
in front of everyone
Then I will make you wear this pendant
Where do you think you're going?
What if Daddy sees you?
Anyone can steal in here in the middle
of the night through the window
y
Today's guys I tell you,
such morons! What to do
Some ask me, how are you?
Some ask me, how do you do
Never! Ever! Has any one said?
Oh! My darling I love you
Hey! Today's girl, listen you,
what I have to say you hear that too
I won't say how are you!
I won't say how do you do!
Right here right now all I'll say is,
Oh! My darling I love you
Today's guys I tell you,
such morons! What to do
They want to meet up, hiding from all
They want to go out, hiding from all
Where am I scared of any one?
I just want you to be the only one
How am I supposed to know that?
Hold my hand to prove that
Holding your hand
you know what I will do
Then let's cross the seven seas
Together we shall always be
Where will you do such a thing!
Then let's cross the seven seas
Together we shall always be
With you I would never go,
risking life to do so
Only if you drown in love,
will you not fear God above
If that's the matter I'll tell you
Oh! My darling I love you
Hey! Today's girls I tell you...
Hey! Today's boys I tell you...
I won't say how are you
I won't say how do you do
Right here, right now
I'm going to say it...
Oh! My darling I love you!
Like every year, this year too!
The winner is Tina Kapoor
Don't move... I'm coming in
Look ahead. Smile
Excellent! Hold that
Tell me once more that you love me.
- Once more?
Hey Mr America, that was just a song.
Did you really believe it?
Hey Miss Universe... I was declaring
my love for you in the song
Say it... you love me
Pooja where are you... come on
Hey come on Pooja
Say it. You love me
It's late, good night
I'm going to change
Apart from this trophy, my son seems
to have won another trophy
Really, and what's that?
Should I say it?
Here's my son's real victory.
- Really...?
Yes
My daughter is naive
But we're sensible right?
I like Tina! What do you say lady?
I've been longing for a daughter-in-law
and Tina is like our own daughter
I can't believe this! Even after
becoming such a successful man...
you want Tina as your daughter-in-law?
Hey, save these filmi dialogues
for someone else
Money doesn't make a successful man.
Can you ever put a value on friendship?
Look this is my promise to you.
Tina will marry Raj
Wonderful! Wonderful!
We must have a picture
What's happening to me?
Nothing ever embarrassed me before
I've never felt anything in my heart
for anyone before... but now...
whenever Raj...
You know what I'm trying to say
But I don't know.
What are you trying to say?
I didn't know you pray to Radha Kishen.
I thought I knew everything about you
You've hidden quite a lot from me...
- Raj! You shouldn't eavesdrop!
But you were talking about me...
- Hey Mr America, what do you think?
I only think about you all the time?
Not all the time... maybe only all day?
Only while you're awake?
Why? I could even dream of you
when I'm sleeping?
Looks like that's where we'll meet next.
- Why?
I have to go back Tina. Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow? So soon?
I did write to you that
I was coming only for two weeks
Wrote...? Oh your letters! Raj, can't
you stay back a few more days?
Not possible, we're launching a website
for a British company and then...
Hey what's the matter?
- You're the one that's leaving...
and you're asking me what's the matter?
- Hey, I'm going away...
but I will return. But I still
haven't heard...
what I've been waiting to hear.
Won't you say it once before I leave?
Fine... I too won't say it
till you return
Now I'll have to return
You got to bring him back. Fast
You're still awake?
- You too are still awake
I was saying bye to Tina
- Bye...? Oh yes of course...
Its been two weeks and you have
to launch that website...
See, you remember everything! Tina
doesn't even remember I'm leaving
Maybe she didn't want to remember.
- She still hasn't told me she loves me
Have you told her?
- Do I need to?
Not something you say.
It's something to be understood.
Then maybe you don't understand...
matters of the heart.
How do you do it Pooja?
How do you understand me so well?
- What to do? I take you for a friend
I have to live up to it right?
- Right...
What's up?
Beautiful song! Isn't it?
- One of your favourites right?
This is the problem with
these old cassettes
I've fallen in love
Then why is my heart
so afraid of love?
My heart says the road ahead
is difficult
And the destination is unknown
I've fallen in love
I'm in love
yet I am so afraid of love?
I'll miss you pal
You'll have to come to London for your
art course interview at some point
So why not come along with me?
How can I go until I hear from them?
- lt'll be nice if you're there
I won't feel so far away from Tina.
- Oh so that's why you want me there?
No Pooja, just joking... you've become
such a good friend in these few days
What if I need my friend?
- Close your eyes, think of me...
and I'll be there!
- Promise?
I swear
You're lucky that she turned out
the way she did...
if she was fat or dark,
you'd be in trouble!
Ronnie, you only go by
physical appearances?
Isn't that what you're doing? You're
not looking at the other one at all
Who... Pooja?
- Pooja? Who's Pooja?
Pooja is our childhood friend
- You really had some childhood
Tina on one side
and Pooja on the other!
So tell me how was she,
this childhood friend?
She knows me so well...
she knows what I like to eat...
she loves Hindi songs
just like me
Pooja? I thought
you were talking about Tina
Papa, even though I really want to,
I can't express what's in my heart
Some things are better left unsaid
And what if they're not heard
because they're left unsaid?
If you say them with a true heart,
they'll always be heard
That's a big risk... what if
Mr America turns out to be Mr Stupid?
You're really opening up your heart!
You were so shy in front of the others
Watch me! The next time I'll say it
in front of everyone...
Close your eyes, think of me
and I'll be there
Gobi parathas
Ronnie, home-made lunch today?
- No. Mummy is away. I'm eating burgers
You..? What are you doing here?
- "Gobi parathas"
And I was just thinking about you!
- Didn't I tell you?
When you miss me, just close your eyes
and think of me and I'll be there!
So here I am!
Gobi parathas
What's with Mummy and Daddy?
They don't seem to want to return
Are they planning to settle down
in Shimla again?
You know what Papa is like... he keeps
postponing their tickets every week
And you? When is your interview?
- Tomorrow
And then?
- Since I've come all the way...
I'm thinking of staying on for a week
I'll go shopping for everyone
Shopping later... you're in my town,
I'm going to show you around
No work for a week...
I'll show you London City!
What a lovely church this is!
- lsn't it? I come here every Sunday
Oh this is the church!
What will you be studying?
- "Art
Art? Tina fancies Art too
Love stories are so boring
Oh your letters...?
Writing to someone and
meeting face to face is so different
I thought I knew everything about you.
You've hidden quite a lot from me.
Finding someone special
isn't so easy
Pooja what have you brought today?
- Raj
Me...?
But you never emailed me
You don't understand
matters of the heart
Maybe, you don't understand
Tina doesn't even know this tune
Cricket posters in your room
The crucifix on your wall
Every Sunday, you go to church
On your bookshelf, "Love Story"
Gobi parathas
None of these...
Tina knows nothing about these
Tina is not different
from her letters
Tina is different from your letters
It was you!
It was you...?
You have to answer me! Why did you
lie to me? Why this deception?
Why did you play this cruel joke on me?
Why did you play with my heart?
Why Pooja? Why?
I'll recognise you the instant
I see you... your image is in my heart
Isn't that what you wrote?
I was waiting for you Raj
But at the station you didn't even
look at me
You just walked past me
You never thought Tina could be Pooja
because Tina is so beautiful!
Didn't we decide Raj that we would
recognise each other's hearts?
But you fell for Tina's beauty...
You immediately tell for her
Raj the truth is that we always want
the one we love to be most exotic
But that's not me Raj,
that's not me
Tina doesn't admit it but I know she's
in love with you and you know it too
This love is not right! This love
was never Tina's to begin with
Tina will have to understand...
that I've always loved the person who
wrote me the letters...
and Tina... wasn't the one.
She's completely different
If we turn this lie into the truth,
then we'll suffer for it, Pooja...
you, Tina and l. There's only
one truth in this lie Pooja...
only one truth...
the truth...
that I love
I've always... Ioved only you
Only you
No Raj
Nothing else... nothing else, Pooja.
We had to come together Pooja
Your coming for the interview,
humming that tune in this church...
all this has happened for a reason
He's the one who decided
we should be together Pooja
He brought us together
And He will make sure
we stay together forever...
together forever
No Raj, it's too late Raj
It's too late, Raj.
Too late
y
God knows since when
you're in my heart
Since I'm there
you've been with me
I promise...
you're the only one
in my heart till eternity
God knows since when
you're in my heart
Since I'm there
you've been with me
I promise...
you're the only one
in my heart till eternity
Life is like a long path
Where people just keep walking by
Whom are you waiting for then
Walk along till the end
I've been waiting all this while...
since, I've met you in my life
God knows since
when you're in my heart
Since I'm there
you've been with me
I promise...
you're the only one
in my heart till eternity
For an eternity
Love is like a sacrifice
Which people always have to bare
Let us take this sacrifice
To show that we really care
I'll do anything for you...
to show that I love you too
God knows since when
you're in my heart
Since I'm there
you've been with me
I promise...
you're the only one
in my heart till eternity
Come, let's go back to Shimla
and tell everyone the truth
These bangles have been
in our family for years...
every daughter-in-law wears them.
When Ma sees you wearing them...
she'll understand everything
Now I've given you
all my gold and my diamonds
And now... for once...?
- Not now. After the wedding
That's the problem with lndian girls!
Everything's after-we're-married
If you're in such a rush, why not
find yourself an English girl?
After-we're-married