(LAVA BUBBLING)
(ROARING)
I'll be honest, Ferb.
I'm having a hard time
putting a positive spin
on this.
But I guess
that's life, huh?
One minute,
you're having
the best day ever,
the next, you're being fed
to a monster the size of
a two-car garage.
Yeah? Well,
welcome to my life.
Huh. And everything
started out so well
this morning.
(CHATTERING)
Good morning, Perry.
Now that's the way
to wake up.
This is gonna be
the best day ever.
♪ We consider
every day a plus
♪ To spend it
with a platypus
♪ We're always so
ecstatic
'Cause he's semi-aquatic
♪ Our Ornithorhynchus
anatinus
♪ Brings smiles
to the both of us
♪ Life's never
fuddy-duddy
With our web-footed buddy
♪ When we're
brushing our teeth
It's better
♪ Tying our shoes
♪ Combing our hair
It's better
♪ Like we're a cheese
sandwich
And he's the cheddar
♪ Blinking our eyes
It's better
♪ Breathing in and out
So much better
♪ Sitting in a chair
It's better
♪ And taking a bath
Just a little bit wetter
♪ Every day is such a
dream
When it's started with
a monotreme
♪ He's duck-billed
and he's beaver-tailed
and hairy
♪ You know that he's
hairy
♪ Everything's better
with Perry
♪ Everything's
better with Perry
Everything's better with
Perry
♪ It's better
And we just want
to tell you, Perry
♪ Everything's better
with you
♪ Better with you ♪
(CHATTERING)
Good morning, boys.
Happy anniversary, Perry.
Oh, that's right!
Gosh. I can't believe
it's been five years.
I remember the day
we first got you.
Come on, kids.
Pick out any pet you want.
Look, Phineas,
this one's
looking at you!
And this one's
looking at you, Ferb.
Why won't anything
look at me?
Ferb! This one's looking
at
both of us at the same
time.
(CHATTERING)
That thing?
You're kidding, right?
Is there something
I can do for you?
Yes. We'd like
that one, please.
You'd like to adopt
a platypus?
Is that what it is?
Well, yes.
May we have him, please?
Okay.
What would you even
name a platypus?
PHINEAS:  Of course,
Ferb and I knew exactly
what to call you.
BOTH: Bartholemew!
(CHATTERING)
And then when
we got you home,
we renamed you Perry
and gave you this locket.
Look how young
we all were.
Hey, Jeremy.
You wanna go
to the mall?
You know, I'd love to,
but my dad's taking me
to check out his old
college today.
Booyah! Go Polecats!
Booyah!
He's already set up
an interview with
an academic advisor.
Can you believe that?
Gee, Jeremy, I forgot
you're a whole year
older than me.
A trip to college?
That's...
That's really great.
Okay, well,
I'll talk to
you later. Bye.
Oh, Jeremy!
In the blink of an eye,
you'll be moving on
to the next phase
of your life.
You'll be
going to college
and wearing tweed jackets
with patches on the
elbows.
You'll be so mature.
And look at me.
I'm a child!
Jeremy, you'll see.
I can mature.
Starting with taking
this silly photo off.
(GASPS) Mr. Miggins!
Have you been there
the whole time?
All right, looks like
the pitcher's ready.
And batter up!
Batter, batter,
batter, swing!
Yes, sports fans,
that may be the best hit
ever in the history of
platypult baseball.
And the crowd exhales
loudly
through their mouths.
(MIMICS CROWD ROARING)
And Fletcher
snags the pop fly.
He's out!
Hi, Phineas!
What you doing?
Turning Perry's
involuntary reflex
into a sporting event.
Hi, Perry, can I try?
Whoa, momma!
Nice shot, Isabella.
Did someone
lose a ball?
Yeah, we were just
playing platypult.
I love
platypus-themed sports.
You know,
if we had two Perrys,
we could put a net
between them
and play
platypult badminton.
Who's Annette?
Ferb, that's it!
I know what we're
gonna do today.
No, seriously.
Who's Annette?
Okay, everyone,
I think the tail
is all set.
I'll just go check
with the foreman.
He's gone!
Hey, where's Perry?
Did he really slip away?
On his anniversary?
Sometimes it seems
like Perry's missed
every single cool thing
we've done all summer
long.
I guess he can do
whatever he wants.
After all,
it's his day, right?
(STONE CLATTERS)
Hey, what was
that small noise?
Let's all go
walk over to it.
Good morning, Agent P.
A quick word.
Recently you've been
having some close calls
and your host family has
almost caught you
sneaking into your
lair several times.
No need to remind you,
but I'll do it anyway,
that if your
cover's blown,
you'll have to be
transferred to another
city
with another host family.
And we both know
you wouldn't like that.
I remember the day
you were first assigned.
Enjoy your platypus!
Thank you, cheerio!
Agent assignment
complete, sir.
Good job, Karl.
If you keep up the great
work,
you'll make unpaid intern
in no time.
KARL:  And I did.
Don't get cocky, Karl.
Agent P, as you know,
every operative is
equipped
with an autoscan
replication device
just like the one
in your hat.
We've been using
the information
you've gathered
to replicate
each and every one of
Dr. Doofenshmirtz's
Inators.
Our top men have been
analyzing them to
determine
if they've been
getting smarter
or dumber.
And to be honest,
the jury's still out.
Now we find out that
he's in the process
of building
an
alternate-dimension-related
Inator.
Your assignment
is to stop him before
he finishes building it.
Behind you,
rising dramatically
from the floor,
is Karl,
with some high-tech
gadgets
that you might find
KARL: Uh, sir? Hello?
I didn't step on in time.
Would you mind
lowering the
platform again?
Great. Let me
cue the music again.
Well, obviously,
this first item is our
new wrist
communicationizer.
It has many applications
that will help you
in the field.
For example, a powerful
directional electromagnet.
It will draw
any metal object to you.
See?
And these are aluminum!
Quit goofing around,
Karl,
and show him the
hologram.
Yes, sir.
(MONOGRAM CHUCKLES)
Pretty nifty, huh?
With this device
you'll be able to
contact me
from anywhere
at any time.
But don't call
between 3:30 and 4:00
because that's when
I take a shower.
(EXCLAIMING)
Wait a minute.
Is that me?
Oh, no!
His holographic projection
has become mesmerized
by his video image.
I better shut it off.
And if you
push this button,
it gives your adversary
an incredible ice cream
headache.
(SHOUTING IN PAIN)
It's gone.
You better watch
where you point that!
Hey, girl!
What are you doing?
Stacy, Jeremy's
going to college soon,
and here I am,
concerned with busting
my brothers to my mommy
and living
in this nursery.
A unicorn!
A unicorn, Stacy!
(IN CHILDISH VOICE)
"Hi, I'm six!"
You've gotta help me
get rid of all this junk.
Wow! Bold move!
Yep. Goodbye,
childhood folly,
hello, carefree
undemanding adult life.
Yeah, good luck with that.
Candace, your father and I
are off to the movies.
While we're gone,
you're in charge, okay?
Okay, Mom!
And you know, I'm even
thinking about giving up
on busting my brothers.
The irony is, that as
a grown-up, you don't
need to tell your mom.
You can just
bust them yourself.
(GASPS) That's it!
Stacy, I'm old enough
to bust them myself!
That's what
I just said.
CHORUS:
♪ Doofenshmirtz
Evil Incorporated! ♪
Now, Perry the Platypus,
quake in terror
as I punch a hole through
to another dimension.
Behold,
the Other-Dimensionator...
NORM:  Sir!
What? What?
I finished
setting up the buffet.
For crying out loud, Norm.
I was in the zone!
I just thought
you were playing
with your doll.
It's not a doll,
it's a stand-in!
Pretendy the Practicepus,
see?
I wonder
if Perry the Platypus
practices with a fake me.
It would be nice to know
he cares enough.
PHINEAS:
All systems are green.
Prepare to launch
on my mark.
T minus 30 and counting.
29, 28, 27, 26...
Of course,
you'll only need this
if you're attacked
by one of the royals
or a member of Parliament.
So it's probably okay
to leave the safety on.
And here's your
brand new rocket car.
Sweet, huh?
Good luck, Agent P.
Karl? Did you tell him
the accelerator's
a little touchy?
I think he knows, sir.
PHINEAS: Three, two, one.
Service!
(EXCLAIMING)
Phineas and Ferb,
you are so busted...
Oh, my gosh! Where'd it
go?
You there, small children!
Where's the big
contraption?
I don't know.
It was here
just a moment ago.
It disappeared?
Stacy, do you realize
what this means?
We're done?
No, some kind of
mysterious force
always takes away
Phineas and Ferb's
inventions
before Mom shows up.
This time it took
away their invention
before I showed up!
The mysterious force
recognizes that
I'm now a grown-up.
A mysterious force?
I'm not buying it.
I am a woman of science,
at least that's what
my horoscope said.
Well, I'm going to
prove it to you
and bust my brothers
at the same time!
Where are my brothers?
We just launched them
towards the park.
Buford is there with
the other platypult.
Okay, as the adult,
I decree we are
going to the park.
Does anyone need
to go potty first?
Fine, make it quick.
Ferb, it looks like
we're gonna hit
that building
that looks vaguely
like your head.
Time to give it
a little test.
(MACHINE POWERING DOWN)
Hmm.
Well, I just finished it.
It can't be broken
already.
(SIGHS)
I stand corrected.
All right, what's with
the giant shuttlecock?
We're really sorry, sir.
I don't know what
happened.
One minute,
we were innocently
launching ourselves
across the city in
a badminton platypult.
The next thing we know,
we're bouncing on
up to the eastside
to your deluxe apartment
in the sky.
Well, it looks like
you've totaled my
Other-Dimensionator.
An Other-Dimensionator?
What does it do?
Well, at the moment,
it just stops giant
shuttlecocks, apparently.
But it's supposed
to let me go into
other dimensions.
That's cool!
We can help you fix it.
I'm Phineas,
and this is my
brother Ferb.
I'm Dr. Heinz
Doofenshmirtz,
but my friends call me...
(SIGHS)
I just got in such a funk.
Ferb is naturally
handy with tools.
I bet we could
put this thing back
together in no time.
What the heck.
Before we start,
there's a whole
buffet set up here,
please partake.
I was expecting someone
who seems to be running
late.
You're lucky I got
a rocket car winch.
Lots of guys
don't have that.
PHINEAS: Almost there.
Okay,
field compressor attaches
to the auxiliary
generator.
Was this working before?
Well, if by "working"
you mean "functioning
properly," then no.
Well, I think
I see your problem.
Everything's wired through
this self-destruct button.
Do you even need that?
Well, of course I...
Wait a minute.
No, I do not need that.
You are absolutely right.
So Ferb has rigged up
this remote control
so that if we get
separated from the portal,
we can open another one.
Nice touch, kid.
I guess this is
the last piece.
Okay, Ferb,
boost me up.
Ooh, I cannot wait!
(CHATTERING)
PHINEAS:
There you are, Perry.
Perry?
Yeah. He's our
pet platypus.
Is every platypus
named Perry?
In a perfect world, yes.
Well, he's a cute
little fellow.
Hi, there.
Coochee, coochee...
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Perry, no!
We do not bite
the elderly.
Again, ow!
It's okay.
Platypuses don't
typically like me.
Well, Perry, you're just
in time to see us open
a window
into another dimension.
Perry, no!
What are you doing?
No, no!
Perry, this is not
tug of war!
This is not
Silly boy,
what's gotten into him?
All right,
let's get this show
on the road, huh?
Remember,
if your cover is blown,
you'll never see
the boys again.
Hey, does anyone hear
someone talking?
Never see them again.
Okay, here we go.
Right in...
Perry! No!
Not on the sofa!
I'm sorry, Dr. D.
We should take him out.
No, no. Wait.
It'll be all right.
I was planning on
replacing this
old couch anyway.
Now come on.
Let's light
this pop stand,
or however it goes.
Gosh, this is...
It's kind of
weird, actually.
I'm usually thwarted
by this point.
Well, I guess
he's not coming.
And now, behold!
The mind-blowing
first images from beyond
our dimensional reality!
Hmm.
It's a...
It's a couch.
That's a bit
anticlimactic.
I guess it's a nice couch,
though...
Hey! I got an idea!
Let's swap my couch
for that one!
Um...
I got it. I got...
Or maybe I...
Come on, you want to
give me a hand here?
Whoa! Awesome,
check it out.
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
(STUTTERS) Hello.
Say, aren't you...
PHINEAS: Hey, Dr. D!
Look at this.
Hold that thought.
You're famous here.
DOOFENSHMIRTZ'S VOICE:
Get off!
(IN DISBELIEF)
"Heinz Doofenshmirtz,
your leader"?
A whole tri-state area
where I am already in
charge!
Yeah! Hold on,
I gotta go check
something out.
Uh, yoo-hoo!
Hello, again.
Is this some kind of test?
Is that really you, sir?
(LAUGHS) Holy boy!
Even the great
Francis Monogram's
my slave in this
dimension!
I prefer the term
"indentured
executive assistant."
Well, I want to meet
this other dimension me.
Where can I find him?
Oh. You're from
another dimension?
Well, he'll probably
wanna see you then.
He's into that
freaky sort of stuff.
Have a seat
and I'll let him know
you're on your way up.
Okay. So I just
gotta sit here and...
CHORUS:
♪ He's Doof Doof
Doof Doof Doof Doof Doof
♪ Bask in his glory
Kneel at his feet
♪ You're in for such a
treat
He's Doofenshmirtz ♪
That was awesome!
All right, who's
interrupting my...
Hmm.
Do I know you?
Yeah! I'm you from
another dimension!
Well, that would explain
the handsomeness.
Right back at you,
big guy.
Does that mean
you and I are
exactly alike?
I suppose so.
♪ Do you want
some rice pudding?
♪ Ick, no, that's gross
♪ It was a test
Almond brittle?
♪ Oh, I love it the most
♪ Me, too
♪ Do you collect coins?
♪ Yeah, just in case
♪ Vending machines become
the dominant race
♪ I've been alone
all these years
♪ With my irrational
fears
But not the
vending machine thing.
That's gonna happen.
♪ But now before me, I
see
♪ Someone with whom I
agree
♪ I've found
a brand new best friend
And it's me
♪ I've found
a brand new best friend
And it's me
♪ I thought I'd be taller
♪ I've been told I slouch
♪ I thought
I'd have both my eyes
You know
♪ It's in this pouch
Ouch! You know,
I can't help but notice
that your scar goes
over your eye patch.
Yeah?
Nothing.
♪ Do llamas weird you
out?
♪ Yeah, are they camels
or sheep?
♪ No, no, I meant Lorenzo
♪ That's right
He played Meap
♪ Now I know all about
you
♪ And you know
all about me
♪ Oh-wee-ooh!
♪ And now before me I see
♪ Someone with whom I
agree
♪ I've found
a brand new best friend
And it's me
♪ I've found
a brand new best friend
And it's me
♪ Now that I found you
♪ We can be a duo
♪ That's right
♪ Twice the evil
Double Doofenshmirtz
♪ Coming at you Fridays ♪
What's that?
I mean, are we doing
a TV show together?
No. It just sort of
sounded like...
I mean, we could.
We should!
Hmm. Maybe we're
not so much alike.
That can be
our catch phrase.
You're the grumpy one.
Wow, he's done
really well for himself.
What do you think, Perry?
(CHATTERING)
Hey, where is Dr. D?
So what you're telling me
is you're still not ruler
of your tri-state area?
Well, obviously you
did not have to deal
with my nemesis,
Perry the Platypus.
Oh, didn't I? Observe.
What is it?
DOOFENSHMIRTZ 2D:
This is Perry the
Platyborg!
He was once my nemesis,
but now, he's general
of my army!
Wow! You are good!
DOOFENSHMIRTZ 2D:
Dismissed.
That was awesome!
Now who's
interrupting me?
Remind me to berate
my indentured
executive assistant.
No, man, it's cool.
They're with me.
Hey, Dr. D.
We thought we'd lost you.
Hi, fellas!
You dare to bring
a secret agent in here?
This boy's
a secret agent?
No, not him!
The quiet one?
DOOFENSHMIRTZ 2D:
No! Not... No. Him!
This plant?
The platypus!
That's Secret Agent
Perry the Platypus!
Oh, hey.
He's just a platypus.
He doesn't do much.
This is rich.
I see what's
going on here.
You really think
that he's your pet,
don't you?
Wrong! He's using you!
You're just his cover.
He's a secret agent!
Here, here,
let me prove it.
General Platyborg,
come down here at once.
He'll be here
in just a second.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
All right, Platyborg,
you see that platypus?
You know what to do.
Perry!
What was that for?
Perry, are you okay?
Told you.
How are his vitals?
Wait, let me
try something.
Platyborg!
Do the same thing
to those two boys.
What?
CHORUS:
♪ Perry ♪
Perry?
Yes! I knew it!
Wait a minute.
I'm confused.
Why does their platypus
fight so good?
Perry the Platypus!
Really?
What?
Perry?
Get them!
You're a secret agent?
Whoa! Whoa!
Hey, be careful with that.
So this is where
you disappear to
every day?
You come here
and fight this guy?
No, he fights me.
He doesn't really
know this guy.
You fight a pharmacist?
Why would you even do
that?
Actually,
I'm an evil scientist.
A lot of people
are confused by
the lab coat.
You're evil?
He's evil?
(GLASS CRACKING)
So, not only have you
been leading a double
life this whole time,
but you sat there
and let us help
an evil scientist
open an evil portal
into an evil dimension!
And you did nothing
to stop us?
Well, he did pee
on the couch.
Wait a second,
I just realized.
That was a conscious
choice.
You peed on my couch!
No, no.
That wasn't enough.
That's when you should
have
put on your little hat.
Not now, after we've
gone through it into
this mess!
For badness sake,
you can hash all
this out in prison.
Guards!
Ow! Brain freeze!
(YELLING)
I'm sorry.
I'm just having trouble
processing this right now.
"So you've discovered
your pet is a secret
agent."
I don't want
your pamphlet!
Uh-oh.
He's coming
back around!
(GRUNTING)
You have got
to be kidding me.
For crying out loud.
What, they didn't teach
you
how to get out of this
in spy school?
Oh, snap.
Look! There's a logo
on this parachute!
He's got his own logo?
All this time we're like,
"He's a platypus.
He doesn't do much."
Well, apparently you do!
You do... You're...
You're tangled up in
the...
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Wow! Saved by
unconventional
architecture.
May I please
see your papers?
Show me your papers
or be destroyed.
Curse you,
Perry the Platypus!
Jinx! You owe me a soda.
Get me! I'm a Georgia
O'Keeffe painting!
Fourth and Main.
What? No tip?
Never mind. I'm good.
Looks like
they're gone.
You're a secret agent?
And you've been
living with us
this whole time?
Was that evil guy right?
Were we just
a cover story to you?
I mean, were you ever
really our pet
or part of our family?
Well, apparently not,
'cause you didn't trust us
enough to tell us.
Anyone else
around here leading
a bizarre double life?
Put your hand down, Ferb.
You're a secret agent!
He's a secret agent!
You're right, Ferb.
We've got to concentrate
on the task at hand.
We've got to get back
to our dimension,
and I don't even know
where to start!
That's right!
The remote!
I knew that would
come in handy.
All right,
let's go home.
Wait, that's not
our dimension.
Nope. Uh-uh.
Now this thing's broken.
We're gonna need some
help.
I know!
Let's go find us!
Wait, I just realized,
you could have been
cleaning your own
litter box this whole
time!
We are not done
with this conversation.
So tell me,
other dimension me,
what do you see here?
An ordinary platypus.
And now
what do you see?
Perry the Platypus!
You know,
I'm starting to see
why you haven't
become ruler
in your dimension.
All right,
Mr. Eviler-Than-Thou,
just how did you
manage to take over
the tri-state area anyway?
Simple, I used
an army of big,
scary robots.
NORMBOTS:  We should
do lunch sometime.
Wow, that is scary.
I tried that
robot thing once, too.
I hid the self-destruct
button
on the bottoms of their
feet
so no one
could reach them.
And march!
I think I've said enough.
I still don't get it.
If we're the same person,
why are you so much better
at being evil than me?
True evil is born
through pain and loss.
You see,
when I was a small boy
back in Gimelschtump,
I had a toy train.
Then, one day I lost it.
Choo-Choo?
That's... That's it?
What do you mean?
That's your emotionally
scarring back-story?
That's your
great tragedy?
Dude! I was
raised by ocelots.
I mean, literally.
Disowned by my parents
and raised by
Central American wildcats,
and you're telling me
you lost a toy train?
That's all?
That's all you got,
really?
I had to work
as a lawn gnome!
I was forced to wear
hand-me-up girl's
clothing!
Neither of my parents
showed up for my birth!
Well, how did you
feel when you lost
that toy train?
I never lost
that toy train...
Well, maybe if you had,
you'd have done better.
Since you have neglected
to take over your
tri-state area,
I think I'll go over there
and give it a shot myself!
Great!
We can be a team!
Yeah, right. A team.
Wait, was that sarcasm?
No!
Yeah! Right there!
I'm pretty sure
that's my voice
when I'm being sarcastic.
Okay, Buford,
where are
Phineas and Ferb?
How should I know?
They never showed up
for me to return serve!
That's considered a
forfeit
in catapult badminton.
So I went to get
some Victory Gum.
CHORUS:
♪ Victory Gum! ♪
A tradition as old
as the game itself.
Don't play with me,
young man.
Where is the giant
platypult they built?
I don't know.
Seems to have vanished.
Really? Did you
hear that, Stacy?
The mysterious force
took the platypult away
before I, the grown-up,
could see it.
Yeah, yeah. I'm sure
there's a perfectly
logical
explanation for all of
And they laughed at me
for installing
a platypult tow rig!
Who's laughing now, Wayne?
The logical explanation
is the mysterious force.
The real question is,
why does it care so much
about my little brothers?
Why doesn't it want
them to get busted?
Well, why don't you
ask it, Kierkegaard?
What? Existentialist
trading cards.
They came with the gum.
Wait, he's right!
I should just ask it!
I'll bet I can
reason with it.
Reason with it?
Candace, it's a force
that you made up.
No, I know what I'm
talking about, Stacy!
Come on!
STACY: Where are you
going?
To my back yard!
The heart of the
mysterious force!
Would you like to
trade two Sartre
for a Nietzsche?
All right.
Sucker!
Well, this should be
our street.
But it sure
looks different.
Dad?
Boys, what are you
doing here?
You'd better get inside
before the Doofbot
catches you.
I'm off to the factory.
See you next week.
Wow! Well, I guess
we'd better get inside.
You might want to...
I mean, these guys
might not know that
you're not really a...
You know.
(CHATTERING)
Boys! I thought you
were in your room.
Get inside!
And get your dooferalls
back on before someone
sees you.
If you need me,
I'll be hiding
in the basement.
That was weird.
Let's find
the other us's.
And... Hey, I got a one!
Pick a Doofopoly
instruction card!
"Conform."
I can do that.
Hi, guys.
No! They're
replacing us!
I must not have conformed
quick enough.
No, no,
it's not like that.
We're you guys
from another dimension.
Different dimension?
Is that allowed?
Apparently.
Oh, look!
Perry's back!
Where have you been?
We've missed you so much.
Phineas,
he's not your Perry.
He came with us.
Oh. Sorry.
Wait, can I hold him
a little longer?
It's just that,
well, he left one day
and never came back.
He's been gone
for a long time,
and I'm really worried.
All right,
you know the only time
we're allowed to
make noise is
on Doofens Day.
So keep it...
Are there four of
you in this room?
Five, counting Perry.
I see nothing.
I have plausible
deniability.
Boy, your Candace
is much less curious
about what you're up to.
What do you mean?
Well, it seems like
our Candace has spent
her entire summer
focused on
what we're doing.
Summer? I think
that was outlawed
a long time ago.
You guys don't
have summer?
Well, that's...
That's terrible.
Summer. It sounds
dangerous
yet oddly compelling.
What is it?
What is summer?
Man, where do I begin?
♪ The days are longer
The nights are shorter
♪ The sun is shining
♪ It's noticeably warmer
♪ Summer
♪ Every single moment is
Worth its weight in gold
♪ Summer
♪ It's like
the world's best story
And it's waiting to be
told
♪ It's ice cream cones
and cherry soda
Dripping down your chin
♪ It's summer!
Man, where do we begin
♪ Summer
♪ It's ponds and
pools and garden hoses
Trying to beat the heat
♪ Summer
♪ Bicycles and roller
skates
And even just bare feet
♪ It's also
surfing tidal waves
Creating nano-bots
♪ Or locating
Frankenstein's brain
♪ Finding a dodo bird
Painting a continent
♪ Or driving
our sister in...
Wait, maybe
we're going too fast.
♪ Summer
♪ It's crickets and
cicadas
And a glass of lemonade
♪ Summer
It's sitting
with your brother
♪ In the back yard
Under the shade of
a big tree
♪ That's what
it means to me
♪ The days are longer
The nights are shorter
♪ The sun is shining
♪ It's noticeably warmer
♪ Summer
♪ Every single moment is
Worth its weight in gold
♪ Summer
♪ It's like
the world's best story
And it's waiting to be
told
♪ It's ice cream cones
and cherry soda
dripping down your chin
♪ It's summer
Man, where do we begin
Man, where do we begin ♪
Wow. Summer sounds
like a blast.
That's just the tip
of the iceberg.
Like this summer
for instance.
We built a rollercoaster,
we became one-hit wonders,
we traveled through
time...
(MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
This is a message
for other dimension
Perry the Platypus.
If you turn yourself in,
I promise not to hurt
your little friends.
If you don't,
all bets are off.
And then we launched
ourselves from a giant
Perry the Platypult and...
You are kidding me.
You're actually
sneaking away again?
So nothing's changed.
Did it ever occur to you
that we could help you?
That we could have
made a great team?
But I guess you can't have
teamwork without trust.
You don't have to
sneak away anymore.
We know your secret.
You can just go.
WOMAN:
♪ I walk away
from you, my friend
♪ I hope that
this is not the end
♪ Of all the times
we figured out
♪ How to seize the day
♪ As I walk away ♪
You know,
I used to think you
couldn't
spell "platypus" without
Well, you can.
But it would
just be "platyp."
Well, I guess if you
guys can't help us
fix the remote,
we could check
with Isabella.
Who is Isabella?
The girl who lives
across the street.
Mom says that
talking to neighbors
can be dangerous.
MOM 2D: It's true!
Well, it's time you met
her.
Come on,
you'll like her.
What about
the Normbots?
Relax! We've been
avoiding them all day.
If you're really careful,
you can...
Okay, we've got to be
more careful than that.
May I please see
your identification?
Uh...
Display your
travel papers
or be destroyed.
Display your travel...
I can't stand
these things.
Hey! It's Buford.
Who are you guys?
We're Candace's brothers.
We're going to Isabella's.
Are you part of
the Resistance?
I used to be
in the Resistance,
but I got so good
at it that I started
resisting them.
DOOFENSHMIRTZ: Behold,
the Other-Dimensionator!
Actually, this is the
other
Other-Dimensionator.
The Other-Dimensionator is
back in the other
dimension.
Okay, step one is,
push this button.
Step two,
stand back in awe!
(MACHINE POWERING DOWN)
(GROANS)
That's it?
Now that
I think about it,
those two boys made some
modifications to my design
which may have
allowed it to...
You know...
To work.
Great, now I need
those two boys?
Ah! Perry the Platypus!
Jinx!
You owe me two sodas!
Listen, Perry the
Platypus,
I know I told you
if you turned yourself in
I wouldn't hurt your
friends,
but change of plans!
Now I need to hunt
them down which might
involve a little hurting.
I know that makes me
a liar, but hello! Evil!
Come on,
Isabella's house
is right through...
What you doing?
Isabella?
Do I know you?
Hey, Isabella!
Him I know.
Buford, what do you want?
I thought you were
resisting us?
I was helping
Candace's brothers
cross the street.
Candace has two sets
of twin brothers?
No, he and I are
from another dimension.
We're trying
to get back.
All right, girls,
release them.
Why would you want to come
to this dimension, anyway?
Well, we didn't mean
to come here.
Now we can't get back
unless we can fix
this device.
Well, we may have
someone who can
help you. Dr. Baljeet.
Baljeet!
That's Dr. Baljeet to you!
Were you not listening?
Here is the crux
of your problem.
Think of the universe
and all of the many
dimensions as circular.
The energy flows
between the dimensions
like this, clockwise.
Say this is your dimension
and this is our dimension.
You traveled with
the flow of energy.
So going clockwise
would be easy!
Going counter clockwise
would take 8 million
gigawatts of energy,
overloading
the local power grid.
I have prepared
a little song to help
illustrate my point.
♪ If you travel
through dimensions
♪ Going clockwise
makes it easy
♪ Going counter clockwise
would take 8 million
gigawatts of energy
♪ overloading
the local power grid ♪
I know,
it needs a chorus.
Anyway, without the
8 million gigawatts,
you would have
to go clockwise,
the long way around.
Theoretically,
you would get home
but there is no telling
how many dimensions
you would have to
go through.
Well, do you think
you can help us
get enough power
to open the window
backwards
so we can get home?
Well, we should probably
ask our leader.
(IN DEEP VOICE)
Ask your leader what?
(COUGHING)
Who made the topiary
out of wild parsnips?
I'm allergic,
and it's messing up
my voice.
Candace, you're the leader
of the resistance?
What are you two
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
doing here?
Never mind,
I'll deal with you later.
You two,
I've been spending
all these years trying
to keep my brothers safe
and suddenly their faces
are
all over the Doofen
Channel.
We're just trying
to get home.
Well, what's stopping you?
Right now?
Quantum physics.
Baljeet.
We need to generate
8 million gigawatts
for inter-dimensional
travel.
Then we've got
work to do.
Isabella, start
redirecting the power.
Aye aye!
Gretchen! Monitor
the Doofen Channel.
Make sure we're not
raising any alarms.
I'm on it.
Buford, keep resisting.
No!
Excellent.
(IN DEEP VOICE)
And will somebody
get rid of that topiary!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Thank you.
Oh, great and powerful
mysterious force!
I know you are
just trying to
protect my brothers
but I am simply trying
to protect them, too,
from their
dangerous inventions.
Show yourself so that
I may reason with you!
Maybe we should
build a shrine to it?
Candace, that's...
(BOTH GASP)
(BOTH SCREAM)
BOTH:
It's a mysterious force!
Ferb! I think we got it!
It looks like home!
What do we do now?
I don't know.
I can't believe
it actually worked.
Well, thanks, everyone.
Hey, where's...
Oh. That's right.
CHORUS ON TV:
♪ Doofenshmirtz
Evil news update ♪
This just in.
Our supreme leader
has announced the capture
of public enemy number
one,
Perry the
Alternate-Dimension
Platypus.
I guess we won't be
seeing him any more
except as a platyborg.
It's 3:30.
We now conclude
our broadcast day.
Now go to bed!
We've got to save him!
Oh, no.
Too risky.
You've got to get back
to your dimension.
We're not going anywhere
without our platypus.
I thought you told us
he was just using you
as a cover.
I know what I said.
I was hurt.
But even if
it was all an act,
he's still
a part of the family,
and we're not
leaving him behind.
I may never be able
to open this again.
It doesn't matter.
We're going back for him.
Well, then
you're on your own.
Fine.
Just tell us where
Doofenshmirtz keeps
his prisoners.
We have to help them!
No, we don't.
Yes, we do. Remember
how we felt when our
Perry disappeared?
Oh, criminy,
I must be crazy.
All right,
we can get there
through the tunnels.
Yes!
Let's suit up, people!
You know what, Stacy?
I'm tired of
the mysterious force
pushing me around.
I'm going to show it
who's boss.
Candace, wait!
I will try to keep it open
for as long as possible
but the window
is very unstable.
Even the slightest
disturbance will
cause it to collapse.
Like that, for instance.
Hey, Candace.
You guys are so...
Wait, why are there
four of you?
Oh, these guys are
from this dimension.
Are we inside
the mysterious force?
I'm not sure
I understand
the question.
And why is Isabella
suddenly fashionable?
What do you mean,
"suddenly"?
Seriously,
where are we?
Candace, I'm sure you have
a million questions,
but right now we have
to save Perry from being
turned into a cyborg.
What?
We'll explain on the way.
So, how do I dress
in your dimension?
Hey, is that me?
I look good!
Oh, no.
You two stay here.
But we want to help.
That's an order!
CANDACE: Wait,
so in this dimension,
Perry is a secret agent?
No, in this dimension
he's a cyborg.
So, where is he an agent?
That would be
in our dimension.
But we're not in
our dimension now.
Okay, I'm having trouble
processing this.
Now I wish
I hadn't thrown away
that pamphlet.
And why are we
in mine cars?
This'll take us as far
as the underground
entrance
to Doof's headquarters.
From there we go up
the ventilation shaft.
The detainment center
is on level four.
And the snack bar's
on level five!
If there's time.
Buford.
I'm just gonna
get some nachos.
So, if there's another me
and another them,
then there must also be
a Jeremy Johnson here,
too, right?
Huh? Oh, yeah,
Johnson, Jeremy.
Leads a three-man strike
team on the north side.
Good soldier.
Good soldier?
That's all you
think of him?
Don't you think
he's dreamy or cool
or even cute?
Tell me at least
you think he's cute.
Cute doesn't win
the war, kid.
Oh. Well, I guess.
But what do you guys
do around here for,
you know, fun?
Look, "Candace" is it?
No offense, but fun
isn't really on my agenda.
You know, since
Doofenshmirtz
took over the tri-state
area,
even though
I was a little girl,
I've been focused
on one thing
and one thing only.
He's going down,
down, down.
Down, down, down, I know.
But what about BFF's?
Or slumber parties?
Or busting your
little brothers?
Busting my brothers?
I spent every day
of my life trying to
protect my little
brothers.
I had to grow up
pretty quick around here
to make sure
they didn't have to.
Gee, you make growing up
sound like it's a bad
thing.
It is what it is.
I'll do whatever it takes
to protect the ones I
love.
Aw! Thanks, sis!
What are you guys
doing here?
We're here to help.
Sir, we're nearing
the target!
Don't move!
Okay, people,
change of plans.
This is as far as we go.
We're not going
to help them?
No, we're gonna
get you two home
where it's safe.
But we wanna...
Look, this isn't our
fight.
It's their fight,
and you two shouldn't
have gotten involved.
Maybe none of us should
have.
Now we're out of here.
I don't remember it being
so dark down here.
Dark?
That's because it's a
trap!
And if it was light,
you would have
seen us and run away,
hence ruining the trap!
I think they get that.
PHINEAS: Perry!
We, uh... We, well,
came to rescue you.
So far it's not going
as well as we'd hoped.
We didn't have
a lot of time to,
you know, plan
something elaborate,
but I guess
we could have created
some sort of diversion
just in case...
(SIGHS)
Yeah, we could have
thought this out more.
(LAUGHS) I got you
and I got your
little friends, too!
Game over! You lose!
I win!
Mark this the hour
of your doom,
Perry the Platypus.
Three forty...
I got one of these
watches with just
the little hash marks.
It doesn't even have
the numbers on it.
Let's just say
it's between
3:30 and 4:00,
Eastern Standard Time.
Whoa!
(SCREAMS)
I told you,
not between
3:30 and 4:00!
They're getting away!
(ALARM BLARING)
I knew this was
a bad idea. All right,
everyone in the cars!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Isabella, start the motor!
Yes, sir.
I got it.
You two,
keep your heads down
and remember your
training!
We never had
any training!
Well, keep your
heads down!
Consider yourself trained.
This is going to be close.
All right,
you rust buckets.
Let's dance.
Um, can you do that?
Well, apparently.
I am so in love
with her right now.
What?
Nothing.
If we can get
to the north tunnel
before they get to us,
I can trip
the security door.
Isabella, can you
give us more throttle?
It's all the way in, sir!
All right, hang tough.
This is going to get
hairy.
Can we make those turns
at this speed?
Well, we're about
to find out.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
There it is.
We should be okay
if we can hold off
these...
Can we do that?
No. Keep your head down.
We're slowing down, sir!
Keep it on the floor!
It's on the floor.
There's too much track,
sir.
I don't think we're going
to make it!
Everyone,
to the front now!
We're going to have
to cut loose these...
The motor's overheating!
Sorry, guys.
You're on your own.
PHINEAS 2D:
What are you doing?
My job.
Protecting you two.
We've got to go back
and help them.
That's not our fight.
But you just
abandoned them!
We could have made it!
We could have all made it!
Or we could have
all been captured,
and I wasn't going
to take that chance.
These are
the tough choices, people.
Somebody's got to
be the adult here.
You two are safe,
and that's what's
important.
But... But... But...
End of discussion.
Man, I had my heart set
on those nachos.
Look, mysterious force,
I feel a little awkward
talking to you
since I didn't believe
in you at first because,
you know, it's crazy.
But then I saw you
eat my friend,
so I've made
a little shrine here.
It's nice.
There's a banana and...
Oh! Mr. Miggins.
So I hope
this makes up for the
whole disbelief thing.
Are we, uh...
Are we good?
Now you have no choice
but to fix my machine.
No.
That's not one
of your choices.
Fix the machine!
No.
Can I...
Can I say something?
So, I think I'm up-to-date
on
the whole Perry Agent
thing.
Strangely, that's the
most normal thing that's
happened this afternoon,
but who exactly
is this guy?
Fix it!
No.
Look, I would make myself
do it but apparently
he's an idiot.
Hey!
Fix the machine!
No.
All right, then,
you've forced my hand.
Fix the machine!
No.
Really?
When I was your age,
I did anything
a puppet told me to do.
How old do you think
we are?
I don't know.
One, two?
You know,
it's hard to tell
with the one eye.
Anyway, I don't know
why you're being
so uncooperative.
All I'm asking you to do
is make my machine work
so I can invade
and conquer your world
and enslave your loved
ones.
See, that's just it.
Why would we do something
that would lead to our
own self-destruction?
Self-destruction?
Self-destruct...
Wait a...
Wait, that's it.
I remember now.
They took out my
self-destruct button.
I don't know why
I put it back in,
but here.
I'll just rewire this,
like so, and there.
It's working! It's
working!
It's functioning properly!
Well, look who just
became redundant.
Send them
to their doom!
Yes, her, too.
Yes, yes, everyone.
Doom, doom,
doom and doom.
Doom!
Jinx!
You owe me three sodas.
Okay, doom for him, too.
What? But I'm you!
Doom!
Wow, if I had
a nickel for every time
I was doomed by a puppet,
I'd have two nickels.
Which isn't a lot.
But it's weird that
it happened twice, right?
Welcome, doomed guests.
Come on, keep trudging.
Doom is thataway.
I would say, so far,
adulthood gets about
a three.
You know,
this may be as
good as it gets.
And now for my all-time
favorite game.
Poke the Goozim
with a stick.
Surrounded by lava.
My second favorite game
is backgammon. Love it!
Whoa! Whoa!
Hold the phone.
I could be useful.
What if you need a kidney
or a stand-in
for boring functions
you have to attend?
Or another kidney?
Doom!
Pooh.
(ROARING)
Cranky, cranky, cranky.
Oh, I love the crank!
I'll be honest, Ferb.
I'm having a hard time
putting a positive spin
on this.
Blah, blah, blah,
two-car garage, etcetera.
Yeah? Well,
welcome to my life!
Whoa, deja vu-ish.
Perry, check out
that guard!
Keys!
Cool! Look out!
Ow! Is this the plan?
Tell me
this isn't the plan!
NORMBOT:  You are
tampering
with the property of...
Let's make omelets!
DOOFENSHMIRTZ: Can you
get a little more lift
out of this thing?
I think I just
bruised a kidney.
NORM 2D:
My bicycle is missing!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL SIGH)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Yes! Go, Goozim!
It's muffin time, sir.
Already?
Okay, I see where
you're going with this...
I officially prefer
our dimension!
(SCREAMS)
DOOFENSHMIRTZ:
This may not be the
best time to tell you,
but I actually flunked
jungle gym in grade
school.
I just couldn't get the
hang
of all the climbing...
(SCREAMS)
Oh, great,
you caught it!
Unlock me!
Are you even
paying attention?
That's right.
It can wait. Later!
More guards!
It's muffin time, sir!
You're broken!
(THUMPING)
(GRUNTING)
Yay, other dimension
Candace!
Phineas!
Catch!
(GASPS) The remote!
(ROARING)
Perry, let go!
What?
No, no, don't let go.
Perry! Trust me!
CANDACE:
Two words! La-va!
Trust me!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ROARS)
(WHIMPERING)
They opened another
portal!
Go after them!
And her!
That banshee
screaming girl.
Get her, too!
Thanks,
Perry the Platypus.
NORMBOT:
Stop where you are.
You cannot leave.
I use aggression
to mask my insecurities!
The portal!
Boy, I could go
for a lemonade.
(GRUNTING)
NORMBOT:
The portal closed, sir.
Oh, pooh.
Oh, well. Time to
start the invasion!
And somebody
get me a muffin!
But it's not
muffin time, sir!
All right, follow me.
We're going around
clockwise.
MAN:
♪ If there's no
hospitality
Just get out of town
♪ You can't be
lying on formality
And saying...
♪ I guess
I'll see you around
♪ You've got no
obligations
Nothing holding you down
♪ Find a new situation
And say
♪ I guess
I'll see you around
♪ You've got no time to
waste on sentimentality
♪ Get out and find
yourself
a brand-new reality
♪ You've got to find
yourself
a brand-new reality
♪ A particle duality
A new dimensionality
♪ Yeah, yeah!
♪ I guess I'll see you
around
♪ Sometimes it's
appropriate
To stop for a snack
♪ If you do then
I hope you get back
♪ I guess
I'll see you around
♪ Hopping clockwise
through dimensions
Is a dangerous thing
♪ But it seems to
help a lot if we sing
♪ And we can sing about
♪ A brand new reality
A brand new reality
♪ I guess
I'll see you around
♪ A brand new reality
A brand new reality
♪ A
brand-brand-brand-brand
♪ I guess
I'll see you around ♪
All right, how about
two Kafkas for your
Dostoyevsky?
Stop wasting
my time, Buford.
Wait, I think this is it.
Where have you guys been?
This is it!
(DOOFENSHMIRTZ 2D
LAUGHING EVILLY)
I spy with my
one little eye
a new tri-state area
that's one dictator
short of a dictatorship.
Well, that's all
about to change.
Pretty soon I'll be ruling
over two tri-state areas,
a virtual six-state area!
Fly, fly, my Normbots!
We've got some
oppressing to do!
(DOOFENSHMIRTZ 2D
LAUGHS EVILLY)
Why is Perry
wearing a hat?
We don't have
time to explain.
We've got to try
and stop an evil...
Uh-oh. It's too late!
They're never going
to fire her and...
Hey, did you see that?
No, I...
What's going on?
Oh, my!
What is it?
It's a comb over!
I know, I should
really just shave it.
Not happening.
My watermelon!
NORMBOT:
All vehicles must stop.
It's okay!
It's a rental!
(HONKING)
Oh, great!
Albuquerque '93
all over again.
I wish other-dimension
Candace was here.
She took out, like,
30 of them
with a giant
stone lawn gnome.
Agent P! Our agents are
being
overwhelmed by the sheer
number of robots coming
into our dimension.
You must get to
Doof's headquarters
and stop him.
Aye, aye, sir.
We're ready to serve.
Oh, no. You kids
need to go home
where it's safe.
With all due respect, sir,
we've been through
quite a lot together.
We're a team now.
Nope, far too dangerous.
And besides,
our insurance
won't cover it.
Tell them, Agent P.
Come on, Perry.
Let's go kick
some robot chassis!
Perry?
Wow, I guess
we're going home then.
Hey, where's Dr. D?
MRS. THOMPSON:  Hello?
Hello, Mrs. Thompson?
It's me, Heinz.
I think I left my keys
in the other dimension.
Can you buzz me in?
Who is this?
Heinz Doofenshmirtz!
Your neighbor.
For, like, 12 years.
Who?
I live in the penthouse.
I wear lab coats a lot.
I speak with the accent
I am currently speaking
to you with.
Just like my
neighbor upstairs.
Yes, exactly!
He's not home.
You'll have to
come back later.
No, no, wait.
This is just beautiful.
I decide to do
the right thing,
and I end up in a cell.
Well, at least my
brothers are safe.
What lesson am I supposed
to be learning here?
(HISSING)
I'm Jeremy Johnson.
I'm here to rescue you.
Johnson, Jeremy?
Yes, sir.
And I picked up
a couple new recruits.
We found a way to bypass
the entire security grid.
It was cool.
What? You brought
my little brothers?
Are you out of
your mind, soldier?
I didn't know
they were your brothers,
but I should have known.
They're smart
and courageous,
just like you.
You think I'm smart
and courageous?
Well, yeah, uh, sir.
Uh, good work, soldier.
We should really
get out of here
while we can.
Most of the Normbots
are away in the other
dimension.
We can slip away
pretty easily.
The Normbots are
in the other dimension?
This isn't the time
to escape.
This is the time
to make our move.
Let's go!
ALL: Yes, sir!
Boys, wait.
Thanks for rescuing me.
I'm really proud
of you both.
And we're proud
of you, too, sir.
I got nachos!
Who wants some?
Nobody?
Oh, Mysterious force,
you can see I'm
really trying here.
Please bring back Candace!
Oh, hi, Stacy.
And I also want a car.
I still can't believe
Perry wanted us to go
home.
I mean, look at this.
There's robots all
over the tri-state area.
And now for the weather.
There's robots, Phil!
Robots! (SCREAMING)
You'd think he'd need
all the help he could
get...
(BEEPING)
Hey, what's that?
Ferb, do you hear that?
It's Perry's locket.
It's like a homing device.
(BEEPING FASTER)
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Shall we?
This must be
Perry's lair.
Welcome, Phineas and
Ferb.
Please insert the key.
Do you have a key?
(NOTE SOUNDS)
Please insert the key.
Good try.
That's odd.
It's a shaped keyhole.
It kind of looks like...
Wait a minute.
Phineas and Ferb,
this message is top
secret,
for your ears only.
If you are hearing this,
the tri-state area
is at emergency
alert level Alpha Red.
Agent P needs your help.
How does he know
we'll know what to do?
He knows
you will know
what to do.
He also knows you two
are the only ones
capable of helping him
because you two are
the only ones capable
of creating these.
Auto-scan
replication initiated.
Ferb, I think I know
what we're gonna do today.
NORMBOT:
You have a new leader.
Put on your dooferalls.
36-inch waist.
No way! I'm a 34!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
So, I guess you
trusted us after all.
I was wrong.
It was not for me!
Heads up!
Platyposterior
coming through!
Now this is what
I call busting.
All right, everyone!
Let's kick some
robot chassis!
ALL: Yeah!
All right,
that is very good.
Phineas!
Anything we can do?
Yeah!
Musical accompaniment!
(PLAYING  ROBOT RIOT)
♪ We're gonna kick
some robot chassis
♪ So you better
tell your robot nation
♪ To say a robot prayer
'Cause you better prepare
♪ For an automaton
annihilation
♪ You think you're
gonna take us down
♪ Well, mechanical man,
you just try it
♪ You're gonna ride
that rail out of town
♪ This is a robot riot
♪ I think you know
what I mean
♪ This is a robot riot
I'm gonna break you down
♪ And sell you
for scrap metal
But I'll keep enough
♪ To build myself
a trampoline
♪ 'Cause your momma
was a blender
♪ And your dad was just
a washing machine
♪ This is a robot riot
♪ I'm gonna break you up
I'm gonna break you down
♪ I'm gonna take you
to a chop shop downtown
♪ You know that
you'll be dreading
This android Armageddon
♪ I think you
better check your fluids
'Cause I know you're
sweating
♪ You know you're gonna
lose
And sing the robot blues
♪ You'll blow a fuse
And take a robot snooze
♪ I will deactivate you
Because I kind of hate
you
♪ Don't want to
beat around the bush
♪ We're gonna decimate
you
♪ This is a robot riot
♪ Oh, man, it's on
♪ I'm gonna rip you up
And put you back together
♪ In a new configuration
Just to mow my lawn
♪ 'Cause your sister
is a fridge
♪ And you know her
light is always on
♪ This is a robot riot
♪ Robot riot...
We've got to do
something about
that portal.
Ferb! We're gonna go
try to close the portal!
♪ This is a robot riot
♪ I'm gonna rip you up
I'm gonna break you down
♪ I'm gonna take you
to the chop shop downtown
♪ I'm gonna rip you up
I'm gonna break you down
♪ I'm gonna take you
to the chop shop downtown
♪
What? Oh!
I've had just about
enough of you, you...
Ow! What is on this!
I was wrong, Stacy,
about everything.
I'm not a grown-up.
I can't control
mysterious forces.
I can't even get my mom
to see what my brothers
are doing!
Stacy, that's it!
I can't get my mom
to see what my brothers
are doing!
Candace,
where are you going?
I'm gonna bust my
brothers to my mom!
And I'm gonna fail!
No, it's Heinz
Doofenshmirtz.
You borrowed sugar from me
this morning.
MRS. THOMPSON:
I don't have any sugar.
I had to borrow some
from my neighbor
this morning.
Yeah. That's me!
He's a nice man,
but I hear he's divorced.
Oh, that she remembers.
Mom!
Candace, what are you
doing here?
You got to come outside
and bust the boys!
I'm not leaving now.
The girl is about to
forgive the guy for the
cliche misunderstanding.
Well, after she battles
these robots.
Whoa! This 3-D is amazing!
Ferb, we'll handle it
down here.
Go help Phineas!
Come on, you stupid thing.
Work!
So that dish must be
what's controlling
the robots.
Maybe I don't need
to close the portal
if I could just
take out that...
Oh, yeah!
Oh, no, you don't.
Now the baseball
is on the other foot.
Or however that
saying goes, I'm not...
I'm not really sure.
Hey, hey, hey,
where are you going?
You know, all that's
going to happen from
you guys coming up here
is that I'm going to have
a brand-new platyborg.
(LAUGHS)
And maybe even a boyborg!
Try saying that
five times fast.
Boyborg, boyborg, boyborg,
boyborg, boyborg...
I guess it's not that
hard,
never mind.
(CHATTERING)
You know something, kid?
You've been
a thorn in my side
all day long.
(WHISTLES)
But that's about
to change right now!
No!
(DOOFENSHMIRTZ YELLING)
My babies!
No, what have you done?
It's weird that Perry's
a secret agent, huh?
Yeah, but it was obvious
in retrospect.
Has anyone
seen my pants?
Yeah, they're
over there.
Wolverines!
Mom, if you care
one iota about me,
your family, and your
city,
you'll come outside
with me right now!
Well, I guess I could
use some more popcorn.
Great! Come on,
come on, come on,
come on!
Ferb! Bro, I just hit
the best home run ever!
Now, tremble before me!
No, I'm down here.
See, one last trick
up my sleeve.
It's me! I'm the trick
up my own sleeves,
'cause I'm in the sleeve,
get it?
(SIGHS)
Pearls before swine.
Hope you got your 3-D
glasses
'cause I'm coming at you!
Yeah!
Hey!
What? I'm kind of
in the middle of
something here.
I got a little something
just for you.
Here.
Choo-Choo!
Yeah, it's mine.
See, I told you
I never lost it.
It was in a box
in my pantry labeled
"VHS tapes."
Go figure.
Anyway, you can have it.
I can't believe it!
Choo-Choo, it is you!
Heart melting,
back-story resolving,
evilness diminishing.
It's the least I can do.
You know,
I don't even know
what I was thinking
with the whole
evil robots thing.
Actually,
when I look around,
I'm really embarrassed.
Let me clean this up.
Look! Self-destruct
button.
Ah, you.
Yeah. Here we go!
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, hurry, hurry!
Do I even need to say
"there's nothing there"
anymore?
Mom, you can say it
all you want.
There's nothing there!
Whoo-hoo! I did it,
I saved the world!
You can go back
to your movie now.
Yeah, you know what?
We're totally cool now.
I'm just gonna go
return to my home
and live out
the rest of my days
with my Choo-Choo.
Okay then, ciao!
Home. It's good
to be... Uh-oh.
Book him, ladies.
You know, my crimes
against humanity had just
completely slipped my
mind.
Hey! Did you guys
just see that?
I saved Danville!
Good job, soldier.
So what'll you do now?
Wow, I haven't thought
of anything but busting
Doofenshmirtz for years.
I don't know.
Well, I know what
interests I'd pursue.
Hey! Here you all are.
I'll take that
under consideration.
What about you, Candace?
You know,
after all of this,
I'm gonna give myself
a little more time
to be young.
It's not such
a bad place to be.
You know what?
Me, too.
Hey, I just wanted to
say thanks for telling us
all about summer,
you know,
opening our horizons,
and teaching Ferb
classical guitar.
(NOTES PLAYING)
(CHATTERING)
Hey! It's our Perry!
Perry!
Looks like
the evil was fried
right out of him.
Sorry he's mostly
made of metal now.
Are you kidding?
That makes him
extra cool!
Thanks so much, guys.
I'm glad
we could help.
Man, this has been
the greatest day ever.
Imagine how much fun
we can have together
now that we know
you're a secret agent.
Yes, yes,
the next 15 minutes
should be a real hoot.
Well, then, of course,
Agent P will be
sent away forever.
What?
You didn't know?
Didn't he give you
a pamphlet?
We threw it away.
Does anyone
read those things?
I tried to warn you, sir.
Kids, I'm sorry
but now that Agent P's
cover has been blown,
you won't be allowed
to see him anymore.
That's why
you didn't want us
to know your secret.
So we'll never see
Perry again?
There has to be
another way.
Sorry, Phineas.
It isn't safe.
You know too much.
Now I never wished
so much that I could
unknow something.
Sir, maybe
there is a way.
What about
Dr. Doofenshmirtz's
Amnesianator?
I never built
an Amnesianator.
I think I'd remember
building something
like that.
Well, that might work.
But you'd all have to
agree.
So our choice is to either
forget the best day ever,
forget the biggest
adventure
we've ever had,
and forget
meeting Agent P,
or remember today,
but never see Perry again?
Well, we've had
a lot of great days.
But we only have
one Perry.
Agreed.
ALL: Yeah!
MONOGRAM:
All right, everybody.
Tall kids in the back.
Just need to do
a little more
programming here
and we'll be
ready to roll.
Hey, buddy, Ferb and I
just wanted to say
our goodbyes.
You know, we thought
we'd finally met
the real you
when we found out
you were Agent P,
but the fact is,
pet, secret agent,
they're both the real you.
You are now and
always have been
a great pet
and a great friend.
We're gonna
miss you, Agent P.
I love you, pal.
Sir, are you crying?
No, I'm sweating
through my eyes.
Okay, sir.
We're ready.
Okay, Karl.
We're set.
Um, Major Monogram?
Yes?
So none of us
will remember
any of today?
That's right.
Good!
(GASPS) Isabella!
Hit it, Karl!
Wait! Wait, wait!
(ME AND MY BRO PLAYING)
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Now me and my bro
We're takin' care of
things
♪ We're from a pair of
jokers
to a couple of kings
♪ It goes to show
you never know just
what a shuffle brings
♪ Me and my bro
We're takin' care of
things ♪
(KICK IT UP A NOTCH
PLAYING)
♪ Oh, yeah!
♪ If you're lookin' for
fun,
baby, we're a shoo-in
♪ But we're a little
young
to be doin' what
we're doin', yeah
♪ We got heads full of
dreams
and sneakers full of feet
♪ The world is our oyster
and life is tastin' sweet
♪ We're takin' off like
we're in a supersonic jet
♪ But if you think we've
gone
about as high as we can
get,
♪ We're gonna
kick it up a notch
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ Oh, man,
you know it's true
♪ Gonna kick it up a
notch
♪ We're gonna
push on through
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ We're not content
to go with the flow
♪ 'Cause everybody knows
summer rocks
♪ But now
we're ready to roll
All right, Slash,
let's roll!
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ Yeah, crankin' up the
evil
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ I'll cause
political upheaval
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ Yeah, I'm gonna get
medieval on you
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ Oh, man,
you know that's true
♪ Gonna kick it up a
notch
♪ We're gonna push on
through
♪ Kick it up a notch
♪ Not gonna go
with the flow
♪ 'Cause everybody knows
summer rocks
♪ But now we're
ready to roll! ♪