Subtitles & Sync By
FridayToker
(PANTING)
(GIRL LAUGHS)
Hurry up, Kay!
SONG: ♪ Whoa, thought it was a nightmare
♪ Lo, it's all so true... ♪
Slow down, cuz!
♪ They told me don't go walking slow
♪ The devil's on the loose... ♪
Come on, Kay!
I'm coming!
♪ Better run through the jungle
♪ Whoa, don't look back to see... ♪
WOMAN: Stop.
Me, me, me!
BOY: Ladies and gentlemen,
it gives me great pleasure
to welcome to the stage this afternoon
four of Australia's
deadliest entertainers.
The one, the only, the very talented
Cummeragunja Songbirds!
(ALL SING 'NGARRA BURRA FERRA')
(GIRLS CONTINUE SINGING)
MUHAMMAD ALI: They never call me
nigger, never put no dog on me.
I'm fighting to free him,
and my mama ain't free in Louisville!
(MOANS)
Oh, kiss me...
Oi! You having one of them
dirty dreams again?
Nick off, will you'?
I said get up, you lazy mongrel!
We've got a talent contest to win.
Jeez, I was having the best
dream of my life,
and you had to ruin
the whole blasted thing.
Julie! What's wrong with you'?
She's mad, like you.
Doesn't mean she has to
suck my flaming face off.
I don't see how you're going to win
any contest if I'm not there.
I told you, you can't come.
You're not old enough.
They won't let you in.
They wouldn't know how old I was
unless you told them!
Julie, you're not going!
That's the end of it.
Hurry up, Dad.
I need some hot water for the shower.
Well, you should have got up
half an hour earlier, then.
We haven't got half an hour.
We're gonna miss the flamin' bus.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Glorious day, Julie.
Oh, rack off, goat-face.
(SCREAMS)
Good job.
How could Jimmy not love that'?
You're not the first girl
that's ever been left at the altar.
What do you expect from a Middleton,
anyway?
(SINGS) ♪ Yellow bird
♪ Up high in banana tree
♪ Did your lady friend
leave the nest again?
- I That is very bad.
- ♪ Ooh
- ♪ Makes me feel so sad.
♪ You can fly away
♪ In the sky away
♪ You more lucky than me
♪ Yellow bird... ♪
What'? If I'm not coming with you,
I'm not singing with you.
♪ Up high in banana tree
♪ Yellow bird
♪ You sit all alone like me
- ♪ Better fly away.
- ♪ Ooh
- ♪ In the sky away.
♪ Picker coming soon
♪ Pick from night to noon
♪ Black and yellow you
♪ Like banana too
♪ They may pick you someday. ♪
Still not going.
See ya.
SONG: ♪ There's a land
that is fairer than day
♪ And by faith we can see it afar
- ♪ For the Father... ♪
- Cooee! Hey, hey, hey!
- What's his problem?
- It's 'cause we're black, stupid.
No. It's 'cause you're ugly.
Taxis always stop for me.
Now, now, girls.
♪ In the sweet by and by
♪ We shall meet... ♪
Going into town'?
Oh, here's trouble.
BOY: Wake up!
Get up, you drongo!
(BOYS LAUGH)
- SONG: ♪ I'm a soul man... ♪
- (IRISH ACCENT) Hey!
Get out of my life,
you horrible little gobshites!
♪ I'm a soul man
♪ Daddy-o
♪ Got what I got the hard way
♪ And I'll make it better
each and every day
♪ 80, honey... ♪
- (DOG BARKS)
- Bite me, dog.
♪ Don't you fret... ♪
- WOMAN: Come on, Buster, come on.
- Morning.
Well, thank you for turning up.
Oh, you are welcome, sweet tits.
You're on your last warning, boyo.
Oh, blow it out your flabby arse.
(COUGHS)
Uh, hello.
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls, welcome.
My name is Dave Lovelace,
and as you can probably tell from
my accent, I am from Melbourne.
Pause for laughter.
You're getting the idea.
I kind of start off slow,
and then I slowly peter out.
Alright, let's get going here.
First up, we've got Noelene.
Where are you, Noelene,
you skinny-arsed... (MUTTERS)
Oh, too kind.
That's your music, is it, love'?
Oh.
Noelene is going to play
one of my personal favourites,
a song made famous by the Seekers.
It's called 'Morning-town Ride'.
She's got her own guitar,
so I'm just going to leave her to it.
And I'll be over here...
(QUIETLY) ..opening a vein.
(SINGS) ♪ Train whistle blowing
makes a sleepy noise
♪ Underneath their blankets
go all the girls and boys
♪ Rocking, rolling, riding
out along the bay
♪ All bound for Morningtown
many miles away... ♪
Put that away, you halfwit!
You're going to get us kicked out.
Yeah, look at 'em! This could be
the last drink I ever get.
♪ Fireman rings the bell
♪ Sandman swings the lantern
to show that all is well
(SINGS OFF-KEY) ♪ Can't afford
to get bored, dear old Sadie
♪ Looks as though
you'll always be a cleaning lady. ♪
(APPLAUSE)
Well done, Tommy.
I have to say, I think you've
got a long career ahead of you.
Ironically, in cleaning.
OK, last up.
Hello - we've got a couple of sisters
who tell me that
they're from down the road a bit,
in a place called Crommer-er-unge.
Crommer-arra-runge.
Commer-ah-range-er-ah.
ELDER SISTER: G'day, folks.
- Thanks for the heartfelt applause.
- (DAVE LAUGHS)
You can find something else to do,
we don't need you.
I'm Gail. This is Cynthia.
And, uh... just so as you know,
you're all standing
on blackfella country.
CYNTHIA:
We're the Cummeragunja Songbirds.
Here's a Merle Haggard tune.
Hope to God you like it.
(COUNTRY AND WESTERN TUNE)
♪ Today, I started loving you again
♪ And I'm right back
♪ Where I've really always been
♪ I got over you just long enough
♪ To let my heartache mend
♪ And then today
I started loving you again
♪ What a fool I was
to think I could get by
♪ With only these few million tears
I've cried
♪ I should have known
♪ The worst was yet to come
♪ And that crying time for me
♪ Had just begun
♪ Well, today, I started
loving you again
♪ And I'm right back
where I've really always been
♪ I got over you just long enough
♪ To let my heartache mend
♪ And today,
I started loving you again
♪ Yes, and today, I
♪ I started loving you
♪ Again. ♪
GAIL: I thought I told you to
stay home.
Who are you to tell me what to do,
you hard-headed drongo?
I'm the one who's going to drag your
big lip over your fat head in a minute!
Stop it!
- Um...
- Excuse me, mate!
- We're in the middle of something.
- I just wanted... That wasn't terrible.
Do you sing anything other than that
kind of country and western shite?
Sorry, what's wrong with
country and western, mate'?
OK.
Alright, folks.
We got a winner for youse.
Taking home the 10 bucks -
you won it, bud...
it's Noelene, with 'Morningtown
Ride'.
- But I was great!
- We were the best.
That's bullshit, Merle.
That's a sack of dick.
You're giving it to Noelene'?
She's allergic to music.
That's a fix.
(CHANTS) Fix, fix, fix, fix, fix...
Show's over, girls. Pack your swags
and get back to the humpy.
You were marvellous.
Hey, hey, Tammy Wynette.
Did you forget something'?
Thanks.
And we can get ourselves thrown out
of a pub. Don't need your help.
Thought I told you Abos
to get off my premises.
Oh, you were happy enough to have us
sing in your crappy contest.
- Who said I was happy?
- What's the story anyhow?
- She your relative or something?
- She's ugly enough.
- (LAUGHS)
- And you can piss off out of it too.
You were a shithouse MC anyhow!
Better than you deserve.
And a lot better than you pay.
Oh, I can find somebody else.
Alright, let's not do anything hasty.
Come on. Remember'?
I'm the man who made you feel
like a girl of 50 again.
Are you gonna make me fetch my rifle'?
Hey, where are you going?
I've got something to show you.
Oi! Read this, will you'?
Will you just leave me alone? I think
you've caused me enough trouble today.
- I don't know how to read.
- GAIL: Julie, what are you doing'?
(READS) "Singers and dancers wanted"
"to perform for the American troops
in Vietnam.“."
And it says
there's good conditions too.
I thought you didn't know how to
read. - Where'd you get this?
Of course I know
how to read, goat-face.
- Then why are you showing me that?
- You need a job, don't you?
We're offering you one.
- Playing for us in Vietnam.
- (LAUGHS)
Yeah, OK. Where's Vietnam'?
Hey, Julie, the only place
you're going is home on the bus.
You want to go perform in Vietnam'?
What are you going to do'?
A corroboree'?
Why not? We're the best girl group
you'll ever see.
You're the best Aboriginal
girl group I've ever...
you're the only
Aboriginal girl group I've ever seen.
But trust me, girls, singing in
Vietnam? It's not for you.
Who are you to say
what we can and can't do'?
You're right, I'm sorry.
The years have been unkind.
I'm sure you'll do much better.
Good luck.
Comora... comoral...
Good luck, ladies.
(ENGINE SPUTTERS, FAILS)
No petrol, eh'?
CYNTHIA: Hey, this is alright!
30 bucks a week.
OK.
Let's... Just for fun,
let's say that you do go to Vietnam.
What would you sing?
Because this may have escaped
your notice, but you're black.
And you're singing
country and western music.
It's just wrong.
Well, what do you think
we should sing?
90% of all recorded music is shite.
The other 10% is soul.
Soul music.
Otis Redding, Sam Cooke,
that kind of stuff.
- We don't sing that type of stuff.
- We like Charley Pride.
No, not country. Soul!
Not... (IMITATES BANJO)
Just... boom, boom, boom!
(AMERICAN ACCENT) ♪ Give me
some of that sweet soul music! ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me introduce you to
the Godfather of Soul, Mr James Brown!
Ow!
That kind of thing.
If you want to perform
for the brothers in Vietnam,
you've got to give them soul.
(SNORTS) What would this duppy
white fella know about soul music?
Hey!
I might be a little pale on the outside,
but my blood runs Negro, woman.
What, the bits
that don't have whisky in them'?
I'm not the one up there
playing songs about cowboys.
I like cowboys.
From what I saw,
you could barely play at all.
Ooh.
Give me the number.
You'd better hold your ears,
because you're about
to see this Black Panther roar.
SONG: ♪ I was brought up
on a side street
♪ I learned how to love... ♪
He's a bit silly in the head,
I reckon, eh'?
♪ I was educated from good stock
- ♪ When I start loving... ♪
- Yeah, no, that sounds good.
♪ Oh, I can't stop
♪ I'm a soul man
When Dave Lovelace calls,
people listen.
And this 'duppy' just got us
an audition next week in Melbourne.
Us?
Without me, there's no you.
You're gonna to have
to talk to Mum, now, eh'?
Happy to talk to Mum.
Alright. Let's go steal some petrol.
♪ I'm talking about
♪ A soul man
♪ I'm a soul man
♪ Soul man
♪ Soul man... ♪
Don't you fellas
ever read the newspapers?
Vietnam? There's a war in Vietnam!
It's true.
They're having some problems
over there at the minute,
but I'd imagine that the girls would
be miles away from any of the fighting.
And there'd be armed guards, of course.
Marines whose sole task
it would be to watch over the girls.
And who's watching over the
Marines? - Mum, just listen to him.
He's got us an audition in
Melbourne.
- Well, who is he? I don't know him!
- He works at the pub in town.
- Not any more.
- Julie's right.
I have managed to secure the girls
an audition in Melbourne.
When someone
with my musical pedigree calls
and says, "Hey, Lovelace here.“".
"Hey, Dave, how's it going?" "Good.“
You know, we small talk 'cause
we're comfortable with each other.
But then I say,
"Hey, I've got a group."
"Bring them down, Dave.
We want to see 'em."
You're gonna manage them, are ya'?
And mould them.
And shape them.
What about our jobs?
Our jobs are gammin.
OK, Gail,
the two things to remember here...
there's the money...
and there's the Soul Man.
Nah. No way.
If you think I'm gonna let you girls
gallivant around Melbourne,
up to no good...
Mum.
Maybe he's right.
Maybe this is the chance of a lifetime.
What's wrong with your life now'?
Being treated like dogs by the gubs
in town every single day.
That's not the life I was born for.
- I'm destined for fame.
- We can stay at Uncle Ed's.
Move over, Aretha.
Stand back, Wilson Pickett.
Pack your bags, Supremes,
because there are some new cats in town.
And those cats go by the name
of the Crunjuaberry Currants.
The Cunner... Cummarendens.
(LAUGHS)
The... We're going to have to
think about your name.
Get up, you moron.
Mum.
I suppose Gail and Cynthia can go.
But Julie stays here. She's too young.
JULIE: That's stupid!
Everyone knows
they're nothing without me.
- Julie, that's enough now.
- You've got a child.
And you're no more
than a child yourself.
I know I've got a child. That's why
I want to make something of myself.
- Get out of my face, four eyes.
- DAVE: Hold on, hold on.
Julie's the key.
Julie's the one with the voice.
- Yeah, I am.
- You are not.
You should ask Kay.
Who's Kay?
MAN: Kay's their cousin.
She lives down in Melbourne somewhere,
but I wouldn't know where.
I do.
What? Since when?
Long enough.
Kay and them girls used to sing
together once upon a time.
Time that girl came back to us,
anyway.
Dave?
Step into my office, will you'?
Go on, then.
Yep.
So, Mr Soul Man...
you reckon you're the real thing,
do you?
Probably not.
Your daughters are the real thing, though.
You a murderer'?
No, sir.
I was an entertainments officer
on a cruise ship.
Not any more, though.
No.
I had some problems.
You know, you can always tell where
a fish has been by cutting open its guts.
But you've gotta have
the right knife for it.
Always like to keep my blade
really sharp.
I will lay down my life before
I let any harm befall those girls.
You'd better.
Don't worry about Julie.
She's a prize catch, eh'?
- Isn't she, though'?
- Mmm.
And, ladies, this design fits... stacks
beautifully in the fridge or the pantry.
- Coffee, anyone'?
- WOMAN: Yes, please.
It makes great lunch-boxes
and things like that.
Come on.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
GAIL: Kay? Are you in there'?
(KNOCKING RESUMES)
Howdy!
Gail.
Cynthia.
You should have let me know.
What do you want'?
If it's money, I can't.
WOMAN: Kay'? Are you alright?
Uh, won't be a moment.
Are we coming in, or what'?
It's not really convenient
at the moment.
I've guests.
Yeah. We make you shame, do we?
Jeez, you haven't changed one bit,
have you?
Still talking like some upper-class
gub and we're your personal slaves.
I don't know what you mean.
Gubba.
It means 'white person'.
- I think you'd better go.
- Kay?
Can I help you?
No.
- Kay, do you know these people?
- I'll handle this.
Kay, we're going to Haysia.
- What?
- Where?
Haysia!
- Thailand.
- Vietnam, you twit.
Oh, Vietnam, then.
Well, don't get lost.
We need you, cuz.
We're going to be doing shows
for the soldiers in Thai...
Vietnam.
Singing...
But it's gotta be all three of us.
You're wasting your breath.
She's lost, that one.
Act your age, not your colour.
Oh, jeez! I don't know you two!
Youse mob better punch on or something,
but sort it out, whatever it is,
'cause this is my big break!
Cynthia!
Your friend's screeching for you.
CYNTHIA: (KNOCKS) Kay?
We're staying at uncle Ed's, Kay.
WOMAN: Is everything alright?
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYS INSIDE)
Welcome, welcome all.
- Uncle!
- Come on, then.
Here you are. Have some of that.
SONG: ♪ You're sweeter
than the honey that the bees make
- ♪ Soul sister... ♪
- Dance, my beautiful nieces!
Shake those hips, use those legs.
Look at these boys!
♪ Sweeter than the icing
on the best cake
♪ Soul sister
♪ You're brown sugar
♪ I was in the dark
but now I see... ♪
We need whisky! Whisky!
♪ I was always proud
But now I'm sayin' it loud
♪ Keep on givin' it to me
♪ Love and affection to the bone...
f
- Lovely place you've got here.
- Isn't it great?
Yeah, love it.
♪ You're brown sugar
♪ Keep on sockin' it to me
all night long
♪ Soul sister... ♪
- Oh!
- Oh! I've done it again!
- Drink!
- Oh.
Drink, go on.
Oh, the mice are moving the dice!
I bet you can't do it again, snake
eyes. Come on.
For when you're trying to get all your
different bits of food together,
for a dinner party
or something like that,
'cause you can just take the lid
off, you pop some warm...
or probably boiling water is better.
Just in the bottom there,
and then you've got
little ventilating holes.
Gail!
Gail, it's your mum!
I'm... oh, I'm quite...
Oh, here she is. Here she is.
Mum?
GAIL: What's wrong'?
That flamin' Julie's run off
somewhere.
What? Mum!
What? What's up'?
- Don't you "What up" me.
- GAIL: Mum? What did you say'?
You've let Julie run off to
Melbourne, haven't you?
Oh, stop your rot.
NAN: I taught her well.
Mum? Will someone talk to me!?
Your dad and Nan
helped Julie escape.
Where's that James Brown fella?
- Gail?
- Hey.
Where is he? Gail?
You never told me
that your uncle was Irish.
- Gail!
- We try to hide that.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
- Hello?
- I'll get it.
Julie!
Hey, sis!
What's she doing here'?
I'm here to sing.
Dad and Nan said I could come.
Did they, now'?
They didn't tell me.
What do you want'?
I'm coming to Vietnam.
Who says we want you'?
Right - if you say no Julie
and you say no Kay,
then there's no Cynthia.
And if there's no Cynthia,
there's no show.
Bust you, then.
(SINGS) ♪ Love and affection
to the bone... ♪
ALL: (SING) ♪ Soul sister
♪ Brown sugar
♪ Keep on sockin' it to me
all night long
(SINGS) ♪ Soul sister
♪ Brown sugar
♪ Love and affection to the bone
♪ To the bone
ALL: I Soul sister.
♪ Brown sugar... ♪
Well, that was interesting, wasn't it'?
Where do we rehearse?
I thought those biscuits
were for patients only, Bruce.
GAIL: One, two, three.
GIRLS: (SING) ♪ I bet you're
wondering how I knew
♪ About your plans to make me blue... ♪
MAN: You've got this
for the next three nights, OK'?
♪ With some other girl
that you knew before
♪ Between the two of us girls,
you know I love you more
♪ It took me by surprise, I must say
♪ When I found out yesterday
♪ Don't you know
I heard it through the grapevine? ♪
Alright. Uh... good.
It was good. Yes, very good.
But, um... how do I say this'?
OK - next time you do it,
can you make it sound blacker'?
Manage that, Kay'?
DAVE: Alright. Let's go again.
'Grapevine'. This time, uh, Julie,
can you sing the lead, please?
What?
No, no, no.
I'm Gail.
- That's right.
- Yeah, my name's Gail.
I sing lead.
Julie and the girls do back-ups.
How do you feel about not singing lead?
How do you feel about
getting knocked out by a woman'?
Pretty embarrassed, I would imagine.
The thing is, Gail, I pick the songs
and I pick who sings them.
Nobody tells me or my sisters
what to sing or who sings lead.
Your voice isn't good enough
to sing lead.
You want to say that again?
Not really. No.
Gail, you are a commanding presence,
on stage as you are in life.
But you also have the weakest voice
out of the four of you.
He's right, Gail.
You can hold a tune but
you can't hold your own in a solo.
Sometimes.
More than sometimes.
Anyone else'? Cynthia?
Maybe you should just let
those of us who can do it, do it.
Yeah, OK, then.
- DAVE: Gail, that's very...
- Shut up. I'm not finished.
I'm finished.
Alright.
Before we go again...
girls, when I met you,
you were doing your whole
country and western thing
and that's fine - we all make
mistakes.
But here's where we learn
from that mistake.
Country and western music is
about loss.
Soul music is also about loss.
But the difference is,
in country and western music,
they've lost, they've given up and they're
just at home whining about it.
In soul music,
they're struggling to get it back
and they haven't given up,
so every note
that passes through your lips
should have the tone of a woman
who's grasping and fighting
and desperate to retrieve
what's been taken from her.
You understand?
Now, what it is that you're
searching for, that's up to you.
I'm just here to get you there,
you know?
(PLAYS MELLOW SOUL TUNE)
(SINGS) ♪ I'll take you there... ♪
There's a place
called the Apollo Theatre.
It's where dreams are made,
where legends are born.
♪ I'll take you there... ♪
I can see you girls singing
in places like that.
There and in the Rainbow,
in the Olympia,
the best rooms in the world.
GIRLS: (SING) I I'll take you
there... ♪
Because you've got it within you -
you just need to let it out.
♪ I'll take you there... ♪
That's it! Let it out of you like
a geyser coming out of the ground!
Like a volcano
springing from the earth,
and you just can't stop it.
♪ I'll take you there... ♪
Like a volcano pushing through
the earth beneath you.
♪ I'll take you there... ♪
Until finally, it's easy enough,
like breathing in and breathing out.
- I I'll take you there... ♪
- And breathing in and breathing out.
(SINGS) ♪ And breathin' in
and breathin' out
♪ And breathing in
♪ Oh, mercy!
♪ Oh, oh
♪ Can I have some mercy now? ♪
Any questions'?
One, two, three.
SONG: I Now, don't you ever.
- ♪ Be sad... ♪
- One, two, three.
- ♪ Lean on me... ♪
- OK. Wrong arms, girls.
Wrong arms. Gail.
- Thank you.
- Hey!
Alright. Are we ready?
Let's get our dancing shoes on,
ladies.
- ♪ Hold on... ♪
- Mmm!
One, two, three.
- ♪ I'm coming.
- One, two, three
♪ On my way... ♪
That's it, that's it. Nailed it.
Keep going! That's it, girls.
Come on, feel it.
Feel it.
Mmm! Yeah, check them! Look at that!
- Here you go, brother.
- Alright.
That's what we're aiming for, girls.
Look at them sashay.
- Yeah, yeah.
- That's gonna be you, ladies.
That's it.
♪ I'm coming
♪ Hold on
♪ I'm coming... ♪
Alright, move it now.
♪ Hold on... ♪
And put your hands on those hips.
♪ Hold on, I'm coming... ♪
Come on, back it up, back it up.
♪ Reach out to me
- ♪ For satisfaction, yeah... ♪
- You see how it's working?
OK.
♪ Look
♪ Call my name now
♪ For quick reaction, yeah
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah... ♪
You, especially, I have my eye on.
There was some shit going down over there.
Nice, Julie, nice.
OK, let's go again.
♪ Hold on
- I I'm coming... I.
- Whenever you're ready, girls.
♪ Hold on
♪ I'm coming
♪ Hold on... ♪
Women.
Oh, sorry, Cyn.
I was supposed to give you this
as soon as I got to Melbourne.
Hey. Oh, you look lovely.
- How's everything?
- Did Jimmy give you this?
- Did he?
- Who's Jimmy?
None of my business.
- I've been thinking, Cyn.
- No, don't. You'll hurt yourself.
- You want to get married'?
- Who to?
To me.
What'?!
Sorry. It was just a thought.
Hey! Cyn! Come back! I'm sorry!
You mob! You mob!
I'm getting married!
(CHEERING)
Oh, my God! I'm getting married!
CYNTHIA: (SCREAMS) Why?!
He's already broken my heart once!
I was going to wear Nan's wedding dress!
I was just getting over it!
Hey, hey, hey!
You're always just getting over him.
Now snap out of it, blast ya.
- Will she be able to sing?
- JULIE: Cyn!
Don't let Jimmy Middleton
ruin things for ya.
We're going to be famous.
He should be the one crying over you.
DAVE: Give her some of this.
I don't need that.
(PLAYS SOUL TUNE)
JULIE: (SINGS) ♪ When
♪ When I
- I Had you.
- I Had you
♪ I treated you
♪ Bad
♪ And wrong, my dear
- I And since.
- ♪ Ooh
♪ Since you went away
♪ Don't you know I sit around
♪ With my head hanging down
- ♪ And I wonder.
- ♪ Ooh
♪ Who's loving you'?
♪ I, I, I, I
♪ Oh, I:
♪ Should have never
♪ Ever
♪ Ever made you cry
♪ And, boy, since
♪ Yeah
♪ Since you've been gone
♪ Oh, don't you know I sit around
♪ With my head hanging down
- ♪ And I wonder.
- ♪ Ooh
♪ Who's
♪ Loving
♪ You
♪ Who's loving you? ♪
And your name again?
Cummeragunja Songbirds.
Say what now'?
We're the Sapphires.
Sapphires?
We'll see you in Saigon.
SONG: ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na,
na, na, na, na
♪ Got a certain little girl
She's on my mind
- ♪ No doubt about it... ♪
- Bonjour, Saigon!
♪ Sometimes she's gonna
make me feel so bad
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na
♪ Na, na, na, na
♪ Feel so bad... ♪
(HORN BEEPS)
Myron Ritchie. Your promoter.
Welcome, Sapphires.
Welcome to Saigon.
I'm trusting you'll regard the La Parisian
as your home away from home
all the while you're here in Vietnam.
Is this where we're staying?
Nothing but the best for our stars,
baby.
OK, uh, Myron, um,
are you the man we talk to about money
because, um, if we don't get
the bucks, these stars don't shine.
- Gail.
- Hey!
Myron. Dave Lovelace.
Great to meet you.
I'm the manager of the Sapphires.
These girls are ball-busting good.
Man, this is going to be great.
Food and accommodation
have all been taken care of, ma'am.
And I think you'll find you gals
won't need much cash on the road.
But in the meantime, why don't you
girls check in - have a look around
while I talk turkey with Ringo Starr
and big sister here.
Plenty to see.
- Ladies.
- Plenty.
It goes without saying,
reports on the Sapphires
have been excellent.
And I've got to tell you,
I'm really looking forward
to seeing you sweethearts showcase
your talent on stage tonight.
Tonight?
Well, listen up, honey.
I got 32 acts.
Five of them are soul sisters.
If you can't shake your money maker
for the brothers tonight,
you're all on the first plane
back to Austria tomorrow.
Australia.
The first plane.
Fear not, brother Myron.
I know my girls can lay it down.
And, sister, the singing -
it ain't the half of it.
The show - it better be right on.
If the pool's gonna be on the roof,
it's gonna be up this way.
Are you sure we're allowed up here?
Isn't it just for the soldiers?
Yes, Julie.
I can smell where the good-looking
men are from a mile away.
You're over Jimmy Middleton now'?
Don't mention his name.
He's had his go.
He's not getting a second serve
of this coffee-coloured Koori.
He's in Cummeragunja, I'm in Saigon.
I can do what I like.
GAIL: Kay!
Need ya!
Kay!
Oh!
Sorry.
We're looking for the pool.
You'll find the pool thataways.
OK.
I work in a hospital.
GAIL: Kay!
Gail?
Can I have a word?
Ah, yeah,
we're going to need to smarten up.
I've never seen
so many black men in the one place.
Stand back, Jack.
This little black duck
gonna go quack, quack, quack.
- Hello'?
- WOMAN: Hello.
Hello? Hello? Something like this.
You know, shiny?
Um... class. We want class.
Class, yeah.
But with cleavage.
- Yes?
- You want striptease?
Very sexy.
Yes, very sexy.
Yes?
Yes.
That's it.
What are you gawking at?
Chicken breasts.
Chicken... have breasts.
Tasty breasts.
MYRON: Now, we've got four real-life
Aborigines from Australia
and they're gonna be putting it down
out there for you tonight.
So I want you to be polite.
Grab a drink off my beautiful ladies
because we've got a big line-up
for y'all tonight.
And remember,
you're at the Cave, baby.
The best black bar in Saigon.
Yeah.
- Let's do it. Yeah?
- Yeah. Alright.
- Alrighty.
- Yeah!
- ♪ I get lovin'
- ♪ Lovin'
♪ By the hundred
- I And I get lovin'
- ♪ Lovin'
♪ By the pint
♪ Got me doin' the camel walk
♪ In my sleep
♪ Make me do the James Brown
♪ Every time I get on my feet
♪ Listen to me
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
♪ What a mighty good man
♪ Say it again now
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
What a mighty, mighty good man
♪ Yes, he is
♪ A mighty, mighty good man
♪ Let me put it on your mind
Let me put it on your mind
♪ He thrills me Kills me
♪ He's a lovin' kind
♪ Another ounce of his love
♪ And I think I'm-a gonna slip
♪ Lose my grip
And do back-over flips
♪ Listen now
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
- I What a mighty good man.
- I Say it again now.
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
♪ What a mighty, mighty good man
Oh! Oh!
♪ What a man
♪ And deep inside I know it
♪ And I'm not ashamed to show it
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
♪ What a mighty good man
♪ Say it again now
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
♪ What a mighty good man
What a mighty, mighty good man
♪ What a man, what a man, what a man
♪ What a mighty, mighty good man
♪ Oh! ♪
(SQUEALS) Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh!
We did it! We did it!
We've just got to remember to keep
in step in the choruses, that's all.
Oh, my lord, girl.
That was out of sight!
Wow, thank you. You're too kind.
- Oi, he means me, cuz.
- I was joking, alright?
Hey, hey, hey.
Baby girl.
Ain't no fool around here
buying you a drink'?
Uh-uh, beautiful.
You offering'?
You looking at your man.
(BOTH LAUGH)
6:00 in the morning,
front of the hotel there.
The Sapphires hit the road and
you tighten up the act out of town.
We're gonna tour the Sapphires
for three headline-busting weeks.
That's 27 shows in 23 days.
And then we play the big venues -
Nha Trang and back here in Saigon.
- You dig?
- Right on.
Hey, back up the truck, brother.
There are things we need to discuss,
like a military escort.
You're four black women in
a war zone, honey.
Now, all you need to do is sing.
Myron, we don't pass wind
without a military escort.
Come on, Dave.
Do you think I'd be sending my stars
out on the road
without the might of the US military
to protect them?
What about a band?
You've been singing with them
right there, sister.
Look, I'm leaving this up to you,
white boy.
Don't screw this up on me.
I don't screw up, Myron.
(MYRON CHUCKLES)
Hmm.
Just go get the dresses.
You've got to look me in the eyes.
It's bad luck.
Hey, sister. Remember me?
On the rooftop?
- It's Kay, right?
- Oh!
Ooh! Chill out, chill out.
(KAY GIGGLES)
Oh, shame. He's yours.
So, you got plans for tonight?
Are you always this clumsy?
No, ma'am. Only around beauty.
Oh.
Better watch your step, then.
Hmm. Alright.
Name's Robby.
Goodnight, Robby.
Hey, it's all groovy, baby.
You've work to do.
We'll save the pleasure of meeting
for another time.
But, hey, don't you forget now.
Whoo!
(CRASH!)
Ooh. Chill out, chill out.
Chill out. Chill out.
It's all groovy, baby.
They still working.
(LAUGHS)
Seriously, now, honey'?
Never relax. Never assume.
That party girl there in the
miniskirt could be Vietcong.
She could lob a hand grenade
across the bar at any time.
Boom! (CHUCKLES)
If you've got to do that,
can you do that somewhere else
where we don't have to watch you?
Hey, sis, if you want something,
you've got to go get it.
Yeah, well, can you get it
somewhere else? I can hear you.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Where's Julie?
She went that way.
(WOMAN CRIES)
There you are.
What are you doing out here'?
I need to know where you are
at all times.
I didn't know
it was going to be like this.
Anyone could lob a hand grenade
and start shooting at us.
There you are.
What did I tell you?
You shouldn't even be here.
Shouting at me isn't gonna help.
Yeah, well, it's your stupid idea
in the first place, isn't it?
DAVE: Julie, darling.
Don't worry.
Everything's going to be fine.
Can you not stick your nose in it'?
Jesus Christ.
Look, Gail, if I could think of a
way to insult a black woman
without coming across as racist...
Well, if you can't,
it probably means you are.
Will you just shut up'?
Look, you know what? That's it.
We're going to have this out,
you and me.
Come on, bud. Let's go.
Fine. Here and now.
This shit - this has to stop.
You're going to have to start giving
me the respect that I deserve.
Respect?
What are you,
the flaming mission manager?
Yes! I'm the manager.
I am the man who's going to manage you
better than you've ever been managed!
It would take a special man
to manage me properly.
Well, you're looking at him!
Excuse me! Crying. Scared.
OK, Vietnam. I'm here!
(LAUGHS)
JULIE: ♪ Yeah!
♪ Ooh, I bet you're wondering
how I knew
♪ Baby, baby, baby,
about your plans to make me blue
♪ Mmm, with some other girls
you knew before
♪ Between the two of us girls... ♪
DAVE: Please welcome to the stage...
Good morning! Lieutenant John Jenson
at your service, ma'am.
How are you'?
♪ When I found out yesterday
♪ Don't you know that
I heard it through the grapevine
♪ Oh, I heard it through the grapevine
♪ Not much longer would you be mine
♪ Don't you know that I heard it
through the grapevine
♪ Oh, I heard it through
the grapevine
♪ And I'm just about, just about,
just about to lose my mind... ♪
Ma'am?
Incoming radio message for you.
- For me?
- Yeah.
ROBBY: Whoo!
Say it again, now! Hey!
(LAUGHS)
Thank you.
(BOTH SQUEAL)
♪ ..half of what you see
♪ And none of what you hear
♪ Baby, I just can't help... ♪
DAVE: These ladies have come a very,
very long way to entertain you
so please, give a very, very
warm welcome to the Sapphires!
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
(SCREAMS) Oh, my God!
Leeches! Get it off me!
♪ Don't you know that I heard it
through the grapevine
♪ Oh, I heard it through
the grapevine
♪ Not much longer would you be mine
♪ Don't you know that I heard it
through the grapevine
♪ Heard it through the grapevine
♪ And I'm about, just about,
just about to lose my mind
♪ Oh, yes, I am
♪ Oh, yeah! ♪
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
MAN: Move it! Let's go!
DAVE: (LAUGHS)
Hey, Duggie, that looks burnt to shit.
Hell no. This is what you call
cooking, Cajun-style.
Ah!
This here's my famed
blackened catfish.
It's the speciality of the house.
Hot!
- And spicy.
- Mmm.
Dave, I'm telling you,
ain't nothing surer with the ladies
than a man packing a home-baked
spread of catfish and a side order of soul.
You know, you can tell where a catfish
has been just by cutting open its guts.
Is that right?
Something like that.
First question.
Are you attracted to the man or not'?
A little.
I wouldn't say he's my one and only.
(GIGGLES)
That's what Stevie Kayne said to me
and I ended up with Hartley.
Stevie Kayne's the father of your
child'?
Stevie with the glasses'?
Well, if you ask me, this isn't
the place to be encouraging romance.
We're here to work.
Speak for yourself, sister.
Mm-hm.
(CHUCKLES)
(WHISPERS)
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
- G'day-
- Hey.
- What's that'?
- Catfish.
It's, uh, blackened catfish.
It's supposed to look like that.
- You want to try it'?
- No.
No? Alright.
- More for me.
- Mm-hm.
(WHISTLES)
Those Hollywood folks there,
they know how to pull a crowd.
That's what I'm gonna do too.
Yeah?
♪ You better shout my love
♪ Ooh
♪ Thank you, baby... ♪
(LAUGHS)
Now, what do we have here'?
Oh, that's, um, that's Jimmy's ring.
The boy's a damn fool.
(WHISPERS) God, you're beautiful.
♪ I want to tell the world, baby
♪ You better shout my love... ♪
Sir?
Delivery for you.
From Saigon.
I love you, man. I love you.
Yeah.
You're my favourite soldier.
- Yeah, thank you.
- You're my favourite.
Thank... thank you, sir.
DAVE: Shut up!
(ALL SHOUT, LAUGH)
(ALL SING DRUNKENLY)
♪ In Asia, once again
♪ Once again!
♪ In Asia, once again!
♪ Once again
(SINGS INDISTINCTLY)
Hang on, hang on.
Hey, Irish.
Hey, telephone man.
Oh, shit.
Dave, it's Myron. Hey, listen up, man.
- Oh, hey, Myron!
- Word's out about the Sapphires.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, man. I'm good.
I got a gig headlining in Nha Trang.
What?
But here's the thing, Dave.
Yeah, the line's pretty bad.
No escort.
You're gonna have to get there
under your own steam.
- That's cool, Myron.
- Do you hear what I'm saying?
- Good to hear from you, bro!
- Dave? Dave? You hearing me'?
Dave?
(MEN CHUCKLE)
Shh.
- No.
- (LAUGHTER)
Stop it, stop it, stop it.
Dave Lovelace.
Get out here.
(LAUGHTER)
MAN: (WHISPERS)
Take it for protection!
Hey, tell her... tell her she's
sweet.
- Shut up.
- Looks like you're in trouble, man.
Hey, Gail.
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
How you doing?
You know we have
an early start tomorrow.
Who are you, my wife'?
You're on your last warning.
How about that?
I came here to apologise
for giving you a hard time
but now I'm not gonna bother.
Your apology is rejected!
(LAUGHTER)
♪ If you need me
♪ I want you to call me
♪ Said if you need me
♪ All you gotta do is call
♪ If you want me
♪ Send for me
♪ I said if you want me, want me
♪ All you gotta do is send for me
♪ But don't wait too long
♪ Just to pick up your phone
♪ And I'll be home
♪ Where I belong. ♪
- He's taking me out!
- (SQUEALS)
(LAUGHS)
Taking you out?
Is that what you flash ones call it'?
You have no shame!
She has no shame, eh'?
Oh, honestly, Gail.
Don't stress
about what you're gonna wear.
You're not gonna be wearing it long.
(LAUGHTER)
Going out with a black fella's
not gonna make you any blacker, Kay.
Oh, well. You never know.
You think you can walk away
from your mob'?
Live in the city for 10 years
making out you're a gubba
and then get up on stage and say
you're a black fella and that's alright?
Nah. It's not alright, not with me.
Don't start me, Gail.
I'm not going to do this now.
Oh, this poor little mission gin
is making the coconut shame, eh'?
What did you call me?
Coconut?
Oh, sorry. Have I offended ya'?
Don't go telling me what I am
and what I'm not.
I didn't get a say
in how things worked out for me.
So you're black now, or you're
white?
You're black
now you think there's money in it.
I know what I am.
Yeah, but does Robby?
DAVE: Gail?
Gail?
What was that about?
Kay's mum.
It's her birthday.
So we're doing a show for her...
and we're on top of a truck.
Two black cars pull in.
Government fellas.
- Run!
- ( SCREAMING)
GO, go!
- Come on! Now!
- Get the kids away!
Mum and Dad screaming at us.
"Kids, get across the river!“"
I don't get it. What did they want'?
The children.
It's my responsibility, Dave,
to look after the little ones
because I'm the oldest.
Hurry UP!
I'm not to let them out of my sight,
especially not Kay.
Why Kay'?
If you're fair like Kay,
them fellas reckon
she could pass for white.
- Get out of the way!
- Leave them kids alone!
Take her from her family,
put her in an institution,
teach her white ways.
Pretty soon, there'll be no
black fellas left to worry about.
- (COUGHS)
- Kay.
And then, um, Kay got sick.
I mean real sick.
We're scared it's pneumonia
so we take her to town, to hospital...
and... and that's when we find out
them government fellas have been back.
Where's Kay'?
They've taken Kay from the hospital bed.
You've got to speak to me!
Say something to me!
Where's my baby little girl?
Where's Kay gone? Kay!
Where are you, baby girl?
- Speak to me!
- GAIL: "Kay."
Say something to me!
GAIL: "Where are you, Kay?"
No, I won't stop!
GAIL: "Where's my girl?"
Where's Kay gone?!
You know, we didn't see Kay
till her mum died.
They let her come home for the
funeral.
And all she could say
in all that time...
If you people worked
as much as you fished,
you'd be really rich, you know?
And I've never been able to forgive
her, or myself.
We should dance.
What?
It's a good time to dance.
Uh, nuh.
Come on.
I'll show you how to
shake your moom.
Yeah-no, I've seen you shake your
moom. It's not pretty.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm gonna teach you
the Lovelace Lanky Leg Shuffle.
No.
If I start dancing like you,
the brothers there
might think I'm a gubba.
Oh, I see. You're saying because
I'm white, I can't dance. Is that it'?
- Yep.
- Well, that's just racist.
You're a racist.
You should know better.
Come on.
Just watch and learn.
Don't be afraid.
It's all about the shoulders.
They don't belong to me,
they belong to the music in my head.
(BOTH LAUGH)
- Nuh.
- Deadly.
When we use that word, 'deadly',
it usually means something's good.
Ooh.
You know, Gail,
there's a funny thing about you.
Everybody thinks
that you're just this...
this mouth on legs...
this defensive,
argumentative old witch.
Stick with me.
There's a reason
that you're this... terrible mouth,
and it's very simple.
You're mama bear...
and they're your little baby cubs.
- You been drinking?
- (LAUGHS)
No.
Oh.
Come on, then,
you silver-tongued wannabe.
I'll dance with ya.
Let me lead.
For once.
DUGGIE: (SINGS) I These arms of mine.
♪ They are lonely
♪ Lonely and feeling blue
♪ These arms of mine
♪ They are yearning
♪ Yearning from wanting you... ♪
ROBBY: You know,
anyone can walk into a door.
Just as long as you ain't on the run
or anything.
Haven't broken the law, have you'?
Maybe.
I ain't gonna tell nobody.
I'm pleased.
Man, I like you a whole lot, Kay.
Just so we're clear, Robby, I'm
black.
I'm just... pale black.
Me too.
Know how I feel?
I feel good.
Ow.
You OK?
No, it hurts.
Do it again, just on this side.
♪ Ohhh, mmm
♪ I know a place, mmm
♪ Ain't nobody cryin'
♪ Ain't nobody worried
♪ Uh
♪ Ain't no smilin' faces
♪ Ohhh
♪ Lyin' to the races
♪ Help me
♪ Come on
♪ Come on, somebody, help me now
♪ Oh, help me, y'all
♪ I'll take you there
♪ lvlmm
♪ Help me now
♪ I'll take you there
P Oh!
♪ Oh, mercy... ♪
Come on, sweet tits. We gotta move.
So, this is goodbye.
Huh?
Me and the guys
will be leaving you folks today.
I just have to say
it's been a real pleasure.
What? You're leaving us here'?
On our own'?
- Not if I had my way, ma'am.
- How do we get to our next gig'?
I...
Sorry, ma'am. I thought you knew.
The military's approved the use
of a vehicle for you.
In that?
What about the band?
Ma'am, I understand your band
is being pulled out also.
Dave?
Myron, hi. Listen, it's Dave.
What's happening, bro?
They've taken away our military
escort and our backing band.
I can't accept that.
Dave, we've already talked about this.
Wait. When?
Last week on the phone.
Don't screw this up on me!
Do you hear me?
Now, a colleague of mine,
Lou McGary,
is touring from the States.
Some big names.
He wants to hear Julie sing.
Man, I think we got us a star
in the making here.
- What's so special about Julie?
- Shh!
You need to get yourselves
to Nha Trang.
I'm gonna get Lou on a military
flight.
We got to get Julie
in front of this guy.
Myron, explain to me how we're gonna
gig without Hendo and the band.
- Where's Hendo and the band'?
- Shh!
Man, forget about them, man.
They're out of the picture.
We got a 10-piece in Nha Trang
that's nothing but class, baby.
No, wait, wait... Myron, wait.
If you want the breaks,
you gotta make 'em, man.
And then you gotta take 'em, baby!
Julie could put us on the map,
stateside.
You dig what I'm saying?
Now, you want to stand
in the way of success?
Then you go right ahead.
No, Myron...
Myron?
My...'?
- You don't remember, do ya'?
- I do. I...
Um...
It's coming back to me.
He said, uh...
something about,
you know, Nha Trang and, um...
What?
How smashed were you
when you let Myron talk you into this?
I'm sorry.
Yeah. Sure.
Sir, you might find a use for this.
You'd better give that to me.
Bye, ladies.
Good luck!
(HORN BEEPS)
(SNIFFLES)
Oh, truly, Cyn.
I can't see how he's a great loss.
All Hendo did was feed you booze
and drugs and take advantage of ya.
Gail, there isn't a soldier
in Vietnam
who isn't stoned out of
his brain all the time.
Yeah, well, don't forget he had a wife.
- How do you know?
- Cyn, there's always a wife.
Not always.
Dave, you're not married, are you'?
What?
- Are you married'?
- What?
"What?" Are you married'?
(SCOFFS) No.
Yes.
Oh, holy mother of God.
- Shit.
- Alright.
(SPEAKS VIETNAMESE)
They want us to get out.
- Do you want the gun'?
- Shit, no. No.
- (SPEAKS VIETNAMESE)
- DAVE: OK, nice and easy.
Alright. We're not soldiers.
Entertainers. Come on.
Uh, singers, you know?
Girls, sing something.
Anything.
(SINGS NERVOUSLY)
♪ Sadie, the cleaning I... ♪
(GASPS)
Go.
Girls. Come on, girls.
(SPEAKS VIETNAMESE)
Where do I go'?
Just drive.
Hey, Julie. Can you come here for a sec'?
This is the guy I want you to meet.
His name is Lou McGary, OK'?
Hey, Lou. This is Julie McCrae.
Lou-Lou, miss.
I have heard so much about you.
She's got some pipes on her, Lou.
- Wait till you hear this girl.
- I bet she does.
Looks like I found me a star.
♪ One, two, three!
♪ One, two, three
♪ You got to know how to pony
♪ Like Bony Maronie
♪ Mashed Potato
♪ Do the Alligator
♪ Put your hands on your hips
♪ And let your backbone slip
♪ Do the Watusi
♪ Like my little girl Lucy
P Oh!
♪ Na, na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na,
na-na-na, na-na-na
♪ Na-na-na-na
♪ Na, na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na,
na-na-na, na-na-na
♪ Na-na-na-na
♪ Yeow!
♪ I feel it
P Oh!
(LAUGHS)
(SQUEALS)
♪ Na, na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na,
na-na-na, na-na-na
♪ Na-na-na-na
♪ Na, na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na,
na-na-na, na-na-na
♪ Na-na-na-na... ♪
That's it, Cyn. No more.
What the heck was that all about?
She's right.
You're making us look like crap.
What's your problem?
They love me out there.
Maybe you should just
pull it back a bit.
Now let's get back on stage.
Nuh. Not with her.
You've been drinking, Cyn,
and there's too much at stake tonight.
What are you doing? Sacking me?
- Dave?
- I'll decide.
I think we should all decide.
Cyn, we're doing it without ya.
Right? Decision made.
Gail.
I'll make you proud of me, bub.
Gail? Gail? Hold on one sec.
I just wanted to say I, uh...
I thought you dealt with that
really well.
No, I mean it -
you know, it was a tough call
and you're obviously
getting really good at this.
Gail, the whole marriage thing,
it's probably not as bad as it sounds.
- (SCOFFS)
- I mean it.
Listen, there's me with,
like, a house and a wife
and me not yet 21 and her no lover of
the rock'n'roll and I'm out on the rip.
It was an unholy alliance but I
probably should have mentioned it.
- Yeah, you should have.
- Wait, wait, Gail, before you go.
I wanted to talk to you about
something
so I wrote it down.
No, uh, the thing is, Gail...
I was never good enough.
I was never good enough
at music and certainly not at life
and that's a...
that's a hard thing to take...
because I didn't have a place
and then I met
these crazy Aboriginal girls
and one amazing woman
and I had a place and I liked it.
So if I've ruined all of that,
then I'm an idiot.
But you knew that already.
No, don't look at it now.
For the love of God.
Just read it when I'm not around.
I'm sorry.
(FLARE GUN FIRES)
- (GUNFIRE)
- Get down!
- What's happening?!
- We're under attack!
We're calling in the sharpers.
- What?
- We're gonna get you out of here.
Let's go.
You three, with me. Get over there.
Go, go! Get to the chopper!
Keep moving! Keep moving!
(SCREAMS) Gail!
(GUNFIRE)
Go! Move it, move it, move it!
Inside. Get in. Go!
Where's Julie and Kay'?
OK, I gotta go get the girls.
Julie!
Kay!
Dave!
(SCREAMS)
- I need your help.
- Shit!
Didn't you say you had
medical experience'?
Here, hold this.
I clean a hospital.
I don't think it counts.
Then you can clean up here.
Get your nigger hands off me.
Keep that black dog away from me.
- Shhh.
- (SOBS)
DAVE: Now, I know it might seem
a little odd that I write a letter
but certain things
are best said from a distance,
especially when you're addressing
a woman who thinks she's Cassius Clay.
Gail, from the moment we got
kicked out of that pub together,
I knew you were someone
I wanted in my life.
Someone to fight the good fight
with, and often against.
You just had something and
I knew it.
Don't ask me how or why
because I couldn't tell you.
All I know is,
like the first time I heard Otis
Redding sing 'These Arms of Mine'...
I knew life would never
be the same again.
And this is the effect
that you've had on me, Gail.
So, that being said...
it would be a great honour
if you would allow me
to become part of your family.
I would be proud to call
your sisters my sisters
and your mother my mother
and your family my family.
Get to the point, blast it.
DAVE: I guess what I'm saying is,
will you marry me?
Once I've sorted my other little
situation out, will you marry me then?
(SOBS)
DAVE: There, I've said it.
Well, I've written it.
You don't have to answer
straight-away.
I don't mind waiting
until we get back home.
Anyway, I love you.
(SOBS)
ROBERT F. KENNEDY: I have some
very sad news for all of you
and I think sad news
for all of our fellow citizens
and people who love peace
all over the world,
and that is that Martin Luther King was
shot and was killed tonight in Memphis.
(AUDIENCE SCREAMS AND CRIES)
NEWSREADER: A single shot
took the life of Dr King
as he stood on the balcony
of the Lorraine Motel in Memphis.
NEWSREADER 2: Martin Luther King...
Let me tell you how it is for
a black Marine in Saigon tonight.
His home is burning
and here he sits in hell
while his brothers and sisters
are dying in the streets.
It's reasonable to assume
that he might begin to question
what the hell he's fighting for.
These Marines, they need something.
They need what you can provide,
and they need it tonight.
I know you're hurting
but I need you to sing.
Gail, are we gonna do this?
Excuse me, you want something?
Excuse me, sir,
I have phone call for her.
Hello?
It's Mum.
Mum, how did you know where
to find us'?
That Dave fella fixed it
all last week.
He's a deadly fella, that one.
You give him a big kiss for me.
Yeah.
Auntie Gerry?
It's me, Kay.
You're a good girl, bub.
Your mum would be so proud of ya.
(SNIFFS) Cyn.
I made the biggest mistake of
my life, Cyn.
- Jimmy'?
- I want to fix it.
Well, you should've
thought about that before, eh'?
I've got fellas lining up
to suck my ring off
so put Mum back on the phone
and leave me alone, blast ya.
You know what I want to hear.
(ALL SING 'NGARRA BURRA FERRA')
MARTIN LUTHER KING: And I've looked
over and I've seen the promised land.
I may not get there with you but I want you
to know tonight that we as a people
will get to the promised land.
So I'm happy tonight.
I'm not worried about anything.
I'm not fearing any man.
Mine eyes have seen the glory
of the coming of the Lord.
♪ Oh, oh
♪ I wonder why
♪ Why do we live in hate?
♪ Stepping on our own without
a warning
♪ And then turn and walk away
♪ When people make the world
a better place for us to live in, yeah
♪ When people make this world
a better place to live in
♪ Oooh
♪ lvlmm
♪ Whoa, whoa, oh
♪ Times left might bring you down
♪ To a shadow on this cold, black earth
♪ Cold black earth
♪ Even though, even though it hurts
♪ You must give yourself the right
to go through another day
♪ Instead of worrying yourself sick
♪ Over things people say and do
♪ You should try to understand
♪ Life as you see fit
♪ And the world would be
a better place
♪ Oooh
♪ Don't you know
♪ People make this world
a better place. ♪
Alright?
Alright.
I suppose we'll have to find
a new piano player.
I don't much reckon you're gonna find
anyone with such good dance moves.
What else you got?
I'm very reliable.
Yeah, well, we're
a long way from home.
You better look after us.
All I want to do is look after you.
Come here a minute, then.
That's from Mum.
That's from me.
I liked your one the best.
MAN: Mum! Mum! They're here!
GAIL: Dad! Mum!
CYNTHIA: Mum!
GERALDINE: Come here.
Oh, my girls!
GAIL: Dad!
CYNTHIA: Dad!
How you going, girls?
(SPEAKS YORTA YORTA)
(SNIFFS)
Welcome home, my daughter.
(LAUGHS)
- Robby be here next week, eh?
- Ah!
Marriage, eh'?
That's fine, I suppose.
But you're gonna have
to learn about ceremony and law.
You're gonna have to learn how to
dodge spears and duck under boondies
and then we're gonna take you
over there.
Not there, there - way over there.
And you're gonna be naked too,
right? - Dad, cut it out!
Nah, gammin! (CHUCKLES)
Wanna come shooting?
(CHUCKLES)
- (WHISPERS) I am pretty deadly.
- You are.
- We don't have to live here, right?
- No, we don't. We'll go into the city.
Sweet.
('I CAN'T HELP MYSELF' PLAYS)
(LIP-SYNCS) : Oooh.
- ♪ Sugar pie, honey bunch.
- ♪ Sugar pie, honey bunch
♪ You know that I love you
♪ I love you
♪ I can't help myself
♪ I love you and nobody else
- ♪ In and out my life.
- ♪ In and out my life
- ♪ You come and you go.
- ♪ You come and you go
♪ Leaving just your picture behind
♪ And I kissed it a thousand times. ♪
Ladies and gentlemen, the Sapphires!
(SINGS) ♪ When you snap your fingers
or wink your eye
♪ I come a-running to you
- I I'm tied to your apron strings.
- I I can't help myself.
♪ And there's nothing that I can do
♪ Ooh...
♪ Oh, I can't help myself
♪ I love you and nobody else
♪ When I call your name
Boy, it starts the flame
♪ Burning in my heart
Tearin' it all apart
♪ No matter how I try
♪ My love I cannot hide
- ♪ Sugar pie, honey bunch.
- ♪ Sugar pie
- ♪ You know that I'm weak for you.
- ♪ Weak for you
♪ I can't help myself
♪ I love you and nobody else
Ooh
- ♪ Sugar pie, honey bunch.
- ♪ Sugar pie
- I I'll do anything you ask me to.
- ♪ Ask me to
♪ I can't help myself
I want you and nobody else
- ♪ Sugar pie, honey bunch.
- ♪ Sugar pie
- ♪ You know that I love you.
- ♪ Love you
J“ I can't help myself
I love you and nobody else. ♪
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
('IN THE SWEET BY AND BY' PLAYS)
♪ There's a land that is fairer than day
♪ And by faith, we can see it afar
♪ For the Father waits over the way
♪ To prepare us a dwelling place there
♪ In the sweet by and by
♪ We shall meet on that beautiful shore
♪ We shall meet
on that beautiful shore. ♪
('GOTCHA' BY JESSICA MAUBOY PLAYS)
♪ Bang bang, heat it up
Feel my cup filling up
♪ Double denim, zip it up
Oh, oh, oh
♪ I'm feeling, I'm feeling your love
♪ Oooh
♪ OK, bring my girls
Time for pussycats to purr
♪ You'll just have to wait your turn
Oh, oh, oh
♪ Because we're running,
we're running the world
P Uh!
♪ Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
♪ Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha by the
collar and you're coming with me
♪ Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
♪ Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha in my
pocket where I want you to be
♪ So you got all the cash
and a big kick stash
♪ And your car's all waxed, oh, oh
♪ But it's all just an act
♪ Here we go
♪ High beams turned on
We do the impossible
♪ Oh, can you feel it in your soul?
I Are you feeling, feeling my
love? - ♪ Oh, yeah!
♪ Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
♪ Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha by the
collar and you're coming with me
♪ Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
♪ Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha in my
pocket where I want you to be
♪ Come, you're being drawn to
my door
♪ Come, you're banging feet to
the floor
♪ Oh, the room is turning to gold
♪ Gold, gold, gold, gold
♪ Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
♪ Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha by the
collar and you're coming with me
♪ Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
Oh, oh, oh! Whoa
♪ Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha in my
pocket where I want you to be
♪ Where I want you to be, yeah. ♪
('NGARRA BURRA FERRA' PLAYS)
('IN THE SWEET BY AND BY' PLAYS)
♪ There's a land that is fairer than day
♪ And by faith, we can see it afar
♪ For the Father waits over the way
♪ To prepare us a dwelling place there
♪ In the sweet by and by
♪ We shall meet on that beautiful shore
♪ We shall sing on that beautiful shore
♪ The melodious songs of the blessed
♪ And our spirits shall sorrow no more
♪ Not a sigh for the blessing of rest
♪ In the sweet by and by
♪ We shall meet on that beautiful shore
♪ We shall meet
on that beautiful shore. ♪