A new school year, Blanche.
A new era.
If the Russians
can put a man in space,
just imagine what our young
American minds can do at Rydell.
(THEY CHORTLE)
- This is going to be a wonderful year.
- Wonderful.
(SCREECHING TYRES - CRASH)
- Miss McGee!
- Blanche!
# Spendin' my vacation
in the summer sun
# Gettin' lots of action and lots of fun
# Scorin' like a bandit
'til the bubble burst
# Suddenly it got to be September 1 st
# Woe is me
# All summer long
I was happy and free
# Save my soul
# The board of education
took away my parole
# I gotta go back, back
Back to school again
# You won't find me
'til the clock strikes three
# I'm gonna be there 'til then
# I gotta go back, back
Back to school again
# Whoa, whoa, I gotta go
Back to school again #
She's late again.
I think being late demonstrates
terrible leadership qualities.
- I'm not waiting.
- Here she is.
We're gonna be late. Let's go.
# Geometry and History is just a pain
# Biology and Chemistry
destroys my brain
# Don't they know
that I deserve a better fate?
# I'm really much too young
to matriculate
# Well, Mama, please
# Your child's come down
with a fatal disease
# Mama said, "Come on, you lazy bum
and get your butt out of bed
# "You gotta go back, back
Back to school again
# "It's bye-bye, fun
Get your homework done
# "It better be in by ten"
# I gotta go back, back
Back to school again
# Whoa, whoa
I gotta go
# Back to school again #
Senior year, the home stretch.
My dad wants me
to go to junior college after grad.
- Nerd junior college.
- What are you gonna do?
Sleep.
What are you gonna be
when you grow up?
A burden on society.
- Hello, Miss Mason.
- Hello.
- Ready for a great new year?
- I love your hair.
- Oh, thanks.
- (BOTH) All 300 pounds of it!
- Hello, boys.
- Good morning, Miss Mason.
I'd love to see all of you
in Music Appreciation.
I'd like to see all of you
- You just might.
- I think I'm in love.
Oh, my hair!
- Excuse me. Let me through.
- What are you doing?
- Watch it!
- Nerd!
- Michael?
- Frenchy?
(ENGLISH ACCENT)
Hello. Hi. Thanks for meeting me.
When your cousin Sandy
said you were coming to America,
I said, "Any cousin of yours
is a cousin of mine."
- She said you'd know the ropes.
- Ropes are my specialty.
I dropped out of Rydell
to go to beauty school,
but flunked Tinting
when my hair turned pink.
Pink?
# The Pink Ladies pledge to act cool
# To look cool and to be cool
# 'Til death do us part
Think Pink! #
Hi, guys.
Your mother!
But now the most important thing
in my life is skin care.
- So tinting's out and skin care's in.
- That's why I'm back at Rydell.
To get my Chemistry
so I can mix my own cosmetics.
Makes sense.
# I got my books together
and I dragged my feet
# And then I saw this angel
Boppin' down the street
# I said, "Hey, pretty baby,
how's about a date?"
# She said, "I'm goin' to school
and I can't be late..." #
Hey, basketball. You caught it!
How tall are you? Never mind.
We'll put high heels on
your sneakers and make you centre.
Go catch that! Oh, boy!
Basketball, basketball!
(CHEERS AND WHISTLES)
# Whoa, whoa, I gotta go
Back to school... #
- Thank you.
- Give it back!
Hey, have a nice trip.
(LAUGHTER AND CHEERS)
(RAUCOUS CHATTER)
Yeah.
Hold it, Birds.
Comb.
Door.
- Make way.
- Pardonne-moi!
Gentlemen, start your engines.
# I gotta go back, back
Back to school again
# Whoa, whoa, I gotta go
# Back to school... #
(FRENCHY) You're going to love Rydell.
# ... again! #
(BELL RINGS)
From the front, it's a perfect nose. From
the side, it doesn't belong on this face.
So dump the face and keep the nose.
- What's the new look, Sharon?
- Jackie Kennedy.
It only landed her a president.
The magazines say that JFK
secretly prefers the Marilyn Monroe look.
Hi, Johnny. I really like your hair
in the back. It's really cool.
- Thanks.
- Still giving lube jobs.
- Stuff it, Goose.
- What's the story, Stephanie?
Yeah, what's the story?
Sorry!
- You know the story, Johnny. It's over.
- Yeah? Yeah? That's not good enough.
- Don't make a scene.
- There's no scene.
- Johnny!
- What's the scene?
- There's no scene, all right?
- Sorry!
- Hi, Louis.
- Hello to you.
What's this?
The Vince Fontaine National Library?
Quiet, please!
Laugh, you jerks, but wait till
I turn up on "National Bandstand".
You may turn up on the bandstand,
but your beak will still be turning down.
- You're mean.
- I gotta do it.
The nose goes.
"Bandstand", here I come.
I wouldn't fool around
with Mother Nature.
- You did with everyone else.
- Shut up!
- Meet me at the homeroom.
- Pants!
- Hi, Paulette.
- Hi, Willie.
Hey.
Excuse me.
(TALKS SLOWLY)
How long have you been in America?
A week.
I'm staying with my aunt and uncle.
Oh. These are the lockers.
Take a locker and lock it.
Because these guys will steal every...
...thing.
- Thanks.
What do you think you're doing?
- Just putting things in my locker.
- His locker!
- Excuse us.
- No one touches these lockers, OK?
- You can't read? That spells T-Bird.
- Which spells us.
- This is a protected landmark.
- A slice of American history.
(HUM IN UNISON)
- Dig?
- I think I understand.
Good. A real Einstein.
My name's Michael Carrington.
I'm the Duke of Earl.
This is your new locker, Shakespeare.
- A perfect fit.
- We're being invaded by foreigners.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, fine, thanks.
- Don't let these guys bug you.
- I won't, don't worry. Ah...
- When are you going to grow up?
- The nerd invaded our sacred turf.
I want to talk.
Meet me for a smoke after class.
I quit. It's bad for your health.
- Standing me up is, too.
- Says who?
The Sturgeon General
of the United States.
(WHISTLES AND CAT CALLS)
All right, everyone take a seat.
I got mine. You loved it.
God, watch the nose!
(PLAYS: "SWANEE RIVER")
Good morning, Rydell, and welcome
one and all to a new school year.
I know this is going to be an exciting
and stimulating year for all of us.
First, I'd like to welcome back
our own Mr Spears,
who made such a miraculous recovery
from the mental exhaustion
which sent him to the hospital
last spring. Welcome back, Mr Spears.
We're all rooting for you.
(SCREAMS - LAUGHTER)
Now, Rydell is very proud
of her extra-curricular activities,
so please come out for band try-outs.
If you play an instrument, it's better
to play with a group than with yourself.
Auditions for the June Moon Talent
Show will be held next month.
Come out one and all.
You could win 100 long-playing records.
Last but not least, we are fortunate
to have a straight-'A' student
all the way from England,
by the name of Michael Carrington.
(MASON) Stand up, Michael.
All right, now, all say hello
to Michael Carrington.
Hello, Michael Carrington.
Let's have a wonderful year.
Rydell High, beat the Cavaliers!
(ALL CHANT) Rydell High,
beat the Cavaliers!
- What's the story with Johnny?
- I outgrew him over the summer.
He hasn't lost the hots for you.
He hasn't learnt when you're dead,
lie down.
- There's more to life than making out.
- I never thought of that.
(BAND PRAC TISES: "MOON RIVER")
Michael.
Michael!
- I heard you play piano.
- Where did you hear that? I can a bit.
Then you must play for the talent show
audition. I won't take no for an answer.
- (FRENCHY) Michael!
- Well?
- OK, I'll do it. Why not?
- I think he's kinda cute.
- Virgin alert! Virgin alert!
- All male periscopes down.
- How's your first week been?
- Great. Yours?
There's a fascinating world
of chemistry out there.
Yeah, I know. How well do you know
that Stephanie Zinone?
Stephanie Zinone
is one of my very best...
Uh-oh. Michael, there's
something you don't understand.
Stephanie Zinone is a Pink Lady.
If you're not a T-Bird, which you are not,
you can look, but don't touch.
Michael, I wouldn't even look.
Well, then,
how do you become a T-Bird, then, eh?
Well...
Football is like life, you gotta push.
You gotta push and elbow. Come on!
Push those men out of the way.
Elbow 'em, then bite 'em,
then rip 'em, then chew 'em up.
Come on, push!
Push, push!
Attaboy! Chew 'em up.
Come on! Don't you have any...
Come on. You're a bunch
of old turkeys. Can't you push?
Ah... ah... ah...!
You said push.
- Look.
- What are they doing here?
(JEERING)
- Nogerelli.
- Balmudo.
These cockroaches
will invade our turf once too often.
We should take care of them tonight.
- (VOICE CRACKS) Tonight, we bowl.
- You're lucky. We're bowling tonight.
I like that.
(LAUGHS MOCKINGLY)
You'd better write your will, boys.
- Hey, baby, check your oil?
- Hi, hot stuff.
- Hey, are we bowling tonight?
- That's right.
- And Paulette...
- Yeah, Johnny.
- I want you to look special, dig?
- No problem.
(BAND: "WHEN THE SAINTS GO
MARCHING IN")
Whoo! Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- Hey, Johnny!
- Yeah, Johnny!
- Way to go, Johnny!
- Hey, do not mess the hair.
- I'm sorry.
- Hey, Paulette. Whose side are you on?
- Our side.
- Then don't fraternise with the enemy.
- Mark that a strike.
- You hit two pins!
It's a technical strike because
these chicks were late. Read the rules!
- Read 'em and weep.
- That's not fair.
- This bra's killing me.
- You wish.
You gotta put your fingers
in the holes.
I'm not breaking my nails.
You got something going with Paulette?
I'm giving her therapy for her disease.
- What disease?
- Nymphoidmania.
(GIRLS CHEER)
- What's the final score?
- That happens later tonight.
Last game, winner take all. Agreed?
Just shoot the ball!
Shoot the ball!
# Come on, everybody
Gather round
# I'm gonna show you
how to knock 'em down
# When I'm on the ball
I'm the number one
# And I'm gonna show you
how it's done
# Let's bowl, let's bowl
Let's rock 'n' roll
# Hey, come on
Let's get the show on the road
# Let's bowl, let's bowl
Let's rock 'n' roll
# You're sittin' on a bomb
That's about to explode
# We're gonna score tonight
# If you're lookin' for a fight
# Then the time is right
# We're gonna wipe the floor
# With you tonight
# We're gonna score tonight
# We're gonna rock, we're gonna roll
We're gonna bop, we're gonna bowl
# We're gonna score, score,
score, score, score... tonight!
# Waa-aah...
# Hey, Paulette, take a look over here
# I'm your kingpin, honey
And I'm gettin' in gear
# Hey, Johnny, Johnny
Go for that strike
# And I just might be your baby tonight
# Let's bowl, let's bowl
Let's rock 'n' roll
# Hey, come on
Let's get the show on the road
# Let's bowl, let's bowl
Let's rock 'n' roll
# 'Cause the stakes are high
And the winner takes all
# We're gonna score tonight
# Don't get sore when you lose tonight
# We're gonna show you how
to do it right
# We're gonna score tonight
# We're gonna rock, we're gonna roll
We're gonna bop, we're gonna bowl
# We're gonna score, score,
score, score, score... tonight!
# You bowl me over
# Bowl me over
# She's hot tonight
# You bowl me over
# Take a hike
# Get a strike
# Ten, nine, eight, seven
# Six, five, four, three, two, one!
# We're gonna score tonight
# We're gonna score
# Tonight
# Tonight #
"Always be courteous
when asking for a game.
"Hi, want a game?
Howdy, fellas, let's bowl some balls.
"Bowling, anyone?"
- Another well-deserved victory.
- Yeah, but where's the trophy?
Right here, Johnny.
Oh, kissies.
That's for best average.
Now what about for best score?
- God!
- Touchy!
- What about the trophy for best score?
- I ain't no one's trophy.
Oooh!
She ain't no one's trophy! So that's how
it's gonna be now, Miss Independent?
Yeah, independent.
I kiss who I want, when I want.
I could kiss the next guy
who walks through that door.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Be my guest.
Let's eat.
- I vote for pizza.
- You vote for bed. It's past ten.
- Go home and leave me alone.
- Bed stinks.
- Is it too late to join the game?
- You want something?
- Food!
- Life stinks.
- Are you talking to me?
- Yeah, you'll do.
- Great.
The name's Michael Carrington.
The name's Dolores.
Dolores Rebchuck.
Some call me Woodchuck
or Upchuck, but I prefer Dolores.
- Got it?
- Got it.
They think they're cool
'cause they got wheels.
- (PAULETTE) Dolores, go home.
- Looks like we don't make the grade.
With them it's all these weird codes
and rules and pledges about cycles.
You gotta be a biker or a biker's old lady.
Without a cycle, forget it.
- Pisses me off.
- We're in the same boat.
I sure can't afford a cycle without a job.
I'm willing to negotiate.
I offered to be a Pink Lady mascot.
It ain't the coolest job, but it's a start.
Think they'd listen?
Forget it. Pisses me off.
It's late. I'd better walk you home.
I don't need a babysitter, OK?
Why not think of it as a date, OK?
Why didn't you say so in the first place?
Come on. When I'm in 12th grade,
I'll be head of the Pink Ladies.
They'll rule the school.
They'll be the best.
We'll have the best-looking jackets.
I once tried to put letters on this jacket.
They fell right off.
It was really embarrassing 'cause
it happened in front of my sister Paulette.
- (SCREECHING TYRES)
- (HORN BLARES)
- Morning, Mr...
- Stuart.
- You could've killed us, Rhonda.
- Good move.
- Imagine dying a virgin!
- Oh, God.
- Nosebleed.
- Nurse, room 11.
- Good morning, I'm a substitute for...
- Good morning, Miss McGee.
- Good morning, Miss...
- (GASPS)
Mason.
- This is Mr...
- Mr Stuart.
I love your hair, Miss Mason.
Thank you, Mr Stuart.
Miss Mason will help you
while you're learning the ropes.
- My pleasure, I'm sure.
- I'm sure you're sure.
- I'm a substitute for Mr...
- Spears.
Follow me.
That's why we're gonna win this talent
show. 100 long-playing albumens.
- But we got zero talent.
- There must be ten Roy Orbisons there.
The greatest hits of Beeth-oven?
Good morning. My name is Mr Stuart
and I'm your substitute teacher.
(LAUGHTER AND CHATTER)
- Let's have a cigarette.
- Yeah.
- Uh-um.
- Mr Nogerelli. I've been looking for you.
Hello, Miss McGee.
You're looking lovely today.
There has been a rumour,
Mr Nogerelli,
that motorcycles have been driven
across our school lawn.
I know that couldn't have been you,
Mr Nogerelli.
I'm sure you have more respect
for grass than that. Right?
- Hear this. No more! Understood?
- Mm-mm.
Good. Do you smell something burning?
Mr Nogerelli...
I guess you sure told her, huh, Johnny?
- Water!
- Sorry, I'm sorry, Johnny!
I'll kill you!
- OK, we're ready.
- Good luck, girls.
The try-outs and we're the first.
I hope I don't blank out. Now!
# His loafers were Weejuns
# His chinos were black
# With a cute little buckle
# That fastened in back #
These are my girls.
There's some good breeding up there.
And that is so important.
- Hey, what's happening?
- Hey, Woodchuck.
Dolores, all right? What's happening?
"Brad".
Does this song stink, or what?
# Don't know what possessed me
# But I gave him my address
- # And my heart shook with fear
- (BACKSTAGE CHATTER)
# As I prayed that I'd hear
# From Brad
# Hear from Brad #
(SHARON) I won't let a little hard work
come between me and 100 LPs.
We're calendar girls. You have to
get into your seasons, become them.
Rhonda, you're fall.
Give me maturity, give me ageing...
- Give me a break.
- Lunchtime.
# Then at yesterday's tea dance
# My day turned to night
# Muffy Rogers was wearing Brad's pin
# I could just die #
Thank you, but we haven't got all day.
- But these are my girls.
- I know, dear. Next!
OK, OK, we're almost ready.
I want everybody to sing
their ah, ah, ahs.
Take your music.
Do I have to do everything myself?
Are you ready?
# Ah-ha-ha...
# I'll be your girl for all seasons
# All the year through #
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Are you free after school today?
- I'm free every day.
It's in the Constitution.
- OK, we're ready.
- Sharon Cooper and the Seasons.
- (DAVEY) Ouch!
- # If you fall in the fall you'll see
# September can be heavenly #
- Eugene, ready with the leaves?
- Ready.
# When autumn leaves
are falling from the tree #
(RHONDA) I'm sick of being a tree.
- That's enough. Thank you.
- We still have three more seasons!
- I need the stage for my Drama class.
- Oh!
Sharon, what about tonight?
- How about a hamburger later?
- I'm busy.
- How about tomorrow?
- Busy.
So maybe you can explain
about the bowling alley.
- You just don't kiss a guy and...
- It was just a joke. Forget it.
- Let me give you a hand.
- I can manage.
- I think he's in love.
- I think he's cute.
I think you should shut your yaps.
You forgot this one.
- Thanks.
- The day after tomorrow?
(SIGHS)
Stephanie...
Look, when are you
gonna get the picture?
# If you really want to know
# What I want in a guy
# Well, I'm lookin' for a dream
on a mean machine
# With hell in his eyes
# I want a devil in skin-tight leather
# He's gonna be wild as the wind
# And one fine night
# I'll be holdin' on tight
# To a cool rider
# A cool rider
# If he's cool enough he can burn me
through and through
# Whoa, whoa
# If it takes forever
# Then I'll wait forever
# No ordinary boy,
no ordinary boy is gonna do
# I want a rider that's cool
# That's the way it's gonna be
# That's the way that I feel
# I want a whole lot more
than the boy next door
# I want hell on wheels
# Just give me a black motorcycle
# With a man growin' out of the seat
# Then move aside
# 'Cause I'm gonna ride
# With a cool rider
# A cool rider
# If he's cool enough
he can burn me through and through
# Whoa, whoa
# If it takes forever
# Then I'll wait forever
# No ordinary boy,
no ordinary boy is gonna do
# I want a rider that's cool
# I don't want no ordinary guys
# Comin' on strong with me
# They don't know what I'm lookin' for
They don't know what I need
# You're gonna know it
when he gets here
# 'Cause the ground will be shakin'
# I'll do anything
to let him know that I'm his
# His for the takin'
# I want a cool rider
# A cool, cool, cool, cool rider
# I want a C-O-O-L R-l-D-E-R #
English, I got something scholastic
to discuss with you.
What I'm saying is
you're Mr History, right?
I got this essay on the fall of Rome.
I didn't even know they were in trouble.
- What are you driving at?
- Papers for paper.
Essays for cash?
- So that's it.
- What's what?
- It'll have to be a motorcycle.
- Good idea. Invest in a cycle. So?
- You've got a deal.
- All right.
When we make the drop,
not out in the open like this.
I got a rep to protect.
It's open.
Your uncle said you was back out here.
What is this joint?
- It's his nuclear fallout shelter.
- Yeah?
- You got that essay?
- You got the cash?
This is a neat joint.
A nucleoid shelter.
It's private, good for homework
and other activities
involving student bodies.
Mm-hm.
Can you handle a couple
of History assignments also?
- I'll try.
- OK, and remember, this is between us.
- I got a rep to protect here, OK?
- Yeah.
William the Conqueror, by the Goose.
Oh, God.
Nobody, but nobody,
knows this happened, dig?
Whatever you say.
That's very nice. Nice penmanship.
Remember. I got a rep to protect.
OK, Shakespeare?
(TAPPING)
Reproduction.
It's very simple, but yet very important.
Now, what is the best time of the month
for a woman to conceive?
Mr...
...Jaworski.
- What's "conceive"?
- You know, to be fertile.
- What's the best time?
- Ask Nogerelli.
- Mr Nogerelli?
- Ask Goose.
- Mr Goose?
- Ask Dimucci.
- Mr Dimucci?
- What?
Conceive. What is the best time?
At night?
I can see that we're not getting very far.
I got the same problem.
- Morning, everybody.
- Good morning.
Good morning, Mr Stuart.
- Let's start at the beginning. Page one.
- Open your book.
- "Where do babies come from?"
- If you need me, I'll be right over here.
Do we need this for the exam?
# The parts of a flower
are so constructed that
# Very, very often
the wind will cause pollination
# If not, then a bee or any other
nectar-gathering creature
# Can create the same situation
# Yes, anything that gets the pollen
to the pistil's right on the list
# I'll try to make it crystal clear
# A flower's insatiable passion
turns its life into a circus of debauchery
# Now you see just how the stamen
gets its lusty dust on to the stigma
# And why this frenzied chlorophyllous
orgy starts each spring is no enigma
# We call this quest for satisfaction
a what, class?
# A photoperiodic reaction
# Oh, that's good
That's very good
# Hey, I'm lost. Where are we?
# Chapter two
# Page five
# Reproduction
# Put your pollen tube to work
# Make my stamen go berserk
# Reproduction
# I don't think they even know
what a pistil is
# I got your pistil right here
# Where does the pollen go? #
Get back here. Get into your seats.
Next chapter.
Now, in an abstract way,
the same thing applies
to the reproductive organs
of the more complex life-forms.
But we are now dealing
with sexual response.
Are there any questions
before we begin reading?
# Is it possible the female member
of some sex on a couch
# Could, like, get this guy all hot
and she never even knew it?
# Negative
# When a warm-blooded mammal
in a tight little sweater
# Starts pulling that stuff
she's saying that she wants to do it
# Can't prove it by me
# 'Cause they change their tune
when you got 'em in the back seat
# With his heart beatin' fast
# They make it sound like a track meet
# Gross!
# Yeah...
# ... Then all they can do is say,
"No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!"
# Reproduction
# Baby, give it to me now
# Is that all you think about?
# Reproduction, come on, baby,
show me that you really love me so
# I think I'm gonna throw up
# Where does the pollen go? #
Mr Goose, please be seated.
The human is the only being capable
of consciously controlling
his number of offspring.
Are there any comments on that?
I was wondering
if you could tell me where she lives.
- What is this?
- # Mr Stuart
# Is it true that guys like you,
you know, mature and all
# Carry some protection with them
for sexual occasions? #
Oh, God!
# Can a girl just do that thing in a book
# Where she adds up the days of her,
what do you call it, mentalstration?
# Oh, that's really neat!
# Yeah, and what if a guy says
the numbers don't add up right, huh?
# Yeah, yeah, yeah!
# Reproduction
# Hope he's proud of what he's done
# He was only pokin' fun
# Reproduction
# See what happens when a boy
and girl don't know how to play it safe
# Reproduction
# Where does the pollen go? #
(LAUGHTER)
Learn anything, Steph?
What's the rush? Gotta take a pill?
Try to remember that their bodies
are more developed than their minds.
- I understand.
- They have drives.
- Lustful drives.
- I understand.
Good.
- Hi, Mr Stuart.
- May I speak to you, Miss McGee?
- What about?
I've missed my last two periods.
That's all right.
You can make them up after school.
# Where does the pollen go? #
Nice one, Davey. That does it.
Yep. Follow me.
Quite a selection here. All very,
very serviceable machines, young man.
One or two were my personal
transportation a few spare parts ago.
A little elbow grease and any one
of these beauties is a fixer-upper.
- You got yourself a bike.
- Great.
- And you're gonna need these.
- Thanks.
Good luck.
(S TEPHANIE) # Cool rider
# A cool rider
# If he's cool enough he can burn me
through and through
# Whoa, whoa
# If it takes forever
# Then I'll wait forever
# No ordinary boy,
no ordinary boy is gonna do #
Bollocks!
# I want a rider that's cool #
Oh, Michael! Michael!
- Good to see you, French.
- What were you trying to do?
I'm trying to ride that motorcycle
without bloody well killing myself.
Wait a second. Michael!
Michael, this isn't for... Stephanie?
# I'll be yours in winter
# When the snow is on the ground
I'll warm you through December
# And I'll always be around
# Ah-ha-ha... #
- That will be all for today.
- Blanche!
Wait, we still have some more seasons.
We have to start with winter
because Paulette's late and...
...she was late again today, but she's
here now and we'd like to do summer.
Sharon, will you stop yelling?
You're in the show.
- (SQUEALS)
- Next.
The Preptones.
# Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum-bum-bum
# Mr Sandman, bring me a dream #
These are my boys. Look.
Good, clean-cut American boys.
I know.
# Then tell her
that her lonesome nights are over
# Sandman, I'm so alone
# Don't have nobody to call my own
# Please turn on your magic beam
# Mr Sandman, bring me a dream #
- That was wonderful!
- Yes.
The T-Bones.
Birds. T-Birds.
# Hum hum hum
# We're goin' prowlin'
# Walk, talk like a T-Bird #
These are my boys.
# Walk, talk like a T-Bird tonight
# Oww!
- # Prowlin' #
- Thank you.
- That was just wonderful.
- It was very nice.
We could work a little bit
on the harn-omies. Catch you later.
Thank you.
My mom wants you to come over
for a psaghetti at your convience.
Thank you.
- Practise over mid-term break.
- Practise?!
# I'll be yours in springtime
When the flowers are in bloom
# We'll wander through the meadows
In all their sweet perfume
# Aa-ha-ha
# I'll be your girl for all seasons #
- Disaster!
- What? We blew it?
No, we made it. But we're the worst.
- We'll get unworst.
- Liverwurst.
- How did we get in?
- They recognised natural talent.
Everybody made it.
They didn't have enough acts.
Get him!
# Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum-bum-bum
Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum
# Mr Sandman, bring me a dream
# Make her the cutest
that I've ever seen
# Give her two lips
like roses in clover #
If we are gonna win that grand prize,
we've got to get it together like that.
But with class.
- I want the Roy Orbisons.
- You'll get 'em.
# Please turn on your magic beam
Mr Sandman, bring me a dream #
- I'm talkin' only weeks before the show.
- I'm talkin' winnin' albumens.
- I'm talkin' progress.
- I'm not talkin'.
Scum!
Balmudo's out front and he's all alone.
Tilt! My turn.
Your turn after we tilt that crater face,
Balmudo. Come on.
- Comb.
- Louis, be careful!
Smoke.
Light.
Comb again.
(MOCKING LAUGH)
Come on, action out front.
Balmudo's gonna get his face mangled.
- All right.
- Oh, my gosh!
Hey, where is that rat-face, Bal?
You lookin' for a rat-face,
mouse-brain?
Get that mutha!
# Who, who, who's that guy?
# He came out of the darkness
in the middle of the night
# Blazin' like a mutha
with a fist of dynamite
# He ain't foolin' no one
on that pile of chrome and steel
# Burnin' up the pavement
like he was some kind of wheel
# He's lookin' for a rumble
and some heads are gonna bust
# He's gonna take a tumble
with one solitary thrust
# The only thing you guys are gonna
do is eat his dust
# Who's that guy?
Where did he come from?
# Hey, tell me someone
# I never knew anyone could be so cool
# Who's that guy?
# What's so amazin'?
# From headlight to tailpipe
His burners are blazin'
# Looks to me like he could really fly
# Who's that guy?
# Who, who, who's that guy?
# He wears a pair of goggles
like a man from outer space
# It really doesn't matter
that I haven't seen his face
# We're gonna wrap those handlebars
around that neck of his
# The punk is gonna get it
# When we find out who he is
# Everybody wants you
when they don't know who you are
# If you're a man of mystery
it really takes you far
# Everyone around you
thinks that you're a star
# Who's that guy?
# Where did he come from?
# Where can I get one?
# They never knew
that I could be so cool
# Who's that guy?
# On that motorcycle?
# What would they say
if they knew it was Michael?
# Looks to me like he could really fly
# Won't somebody tell me?
# Who's that guy?
# Who's that guy? #
Pretty cool stuff.
(POLICE SIREN)
Everyone inside... We bowl!
- All right!
- Yeah, we bowl!
- Hey, Dimucci, did you see that?
- Yeah, I saw it.
- Come on, Steph.
- I'll catch you up.
- Hey, what's eatin' you?
- Nothin'.
You know, Steph. There's been talk.
We haven't been talkin',
but there has been talk
questioning your loyalty to the Birds.
Doesn't mean you gotta go steady with
Johnny. I think it's better that it's over.
Yeah, but the code does say
we're T-Bird chicks, at least till grad.
Let's go, Louis.
Maybe I'm tired
of being someone's chick.
Tired of being someone's chick?
Are you feeling OK?
- Yo, Ritter!
- Yo, Goose!
- I don't know what I'm feeling.
- Have a ciggy. It'll make you feel better.
(GOOSE) Those guys are show-offs.
I hate those matches
from the liquor store.
Oh, thanks.
# Looks like he could really fly
# Won't somebody tell me
# Who's that guy?
# Who's that guy? #
Want a ride?
(POLICE SIREN)
Some other time.
# Who's that guy?
# Who? Who? Who?
# Whoa, whoa, whoa
Who's that guy? #
I heard there was this motorcycle chase
outside the Bowl-a-Rama,
and according to Paulette Rebchuck,
this very mysterious and gorgeous guy
knocked Stephanie Zinone
right out of her bobby socks.
- How do you plead?
- I am guilty.
- Great. But now what?
- We've got a problem.
On that motorcycle, in that gear,
I knocked that girl out of her socks.
- But like this...
- You'll knock her into her socks.
Simple, I have to tell her.
Next time I see her... Come here.
Next time I see her,
I'm going to walk up to her and say,
- "Steph..."
- Uh-oh.
Hiya, girls.
- Your boyfriend's here.
- (GIGGLING)
- Having a facial?
- Yeah.
Delish!
- Steph.
- What?
- Do you?
Have you... ever read
a Superman comic?
- Not in the last few hours.
- I was just checking. Right?
Just checking.
- He needs the guidance counsellor.
- Rhonda, you got a nose job.
- I walked into a door.
- So she says.
- (SIREN)
- Attention, attention, please.
This is a test. I repeat, this is a test.
Please do not panic.
Nuclear war is like football:
If the Russians throw the bomb,
you intercept it
and ram it down their end zone.
It's like life. Somebody throws
something, you throw it back.
Please proceed to your nearest shelter.
Boys to one side, girls to the other.
Run, run, run!
- Blanche, please do not panic!
- Miss McGee, it's so loud.
Please do not panic.
(CREAKING HINGES)
How did you talk me into this?
- You trust President Kennedy?
- Of course.
All right. Kennedy says we gotta be
prepared for a nucleoid war.
- It's nuclear, Louis.
- Yeah. Nuclelar, nucular...
...a bomb's a bomb.
- (CLANKS AND LOCKS)
- (SHE GASPS)
This is an official fallout shelter bed.
Hey, you gotta be prepared, 'cause
some day, when you least expect it...
Ka-blam! Nucleoid war!
(SIREN)
- What's that?
- It's started.
# America is calling
# Let's care enough
to give our very best #
What's happening?
The Russians are attacking. Get down.
# For if we give our very best
# I know that
we will more than pass the test #
- Get off me!
- Think about it.
What if we died here tonight
without ever doing it?
"Lt"? Oh, my God! Let me out of here!
Are you crazy? They're dropping bombs.
# Yeah, let's do it for our country
The red, white and the blue
# It's Uncle Sam who's asking
So your mother will approve
# Tomorrow I'll be fighting
And I'll win this war for you
# Let's do it for our country
Our country wants us to
- Oh, Louis!
- # Bullets are exploding
# They'll soon be at the door
# Give something to America
you never gave before
# Yeah, let's do it for our country
# The red, white and the blue #
Are you sure my mother would approve?
Your mother don't even have to know.
And you think we're old enough to go?
- All the way.
- But, Louis, you might get hurt.
- Oh, God.
- Think about it.
It would be like doing it
for the Statue of Liberty.
- Or the Grand Canyon.
- The New York Yankees.
For... Disneyland!
# Let's do it for our country
# The red, white and the blue
# It's not a lot to ask of us
Our parents will approve
# You'll be a mighty soldier
# Before this night is through
# Let's do it for our country
# We owe it to our country
Our country wants us to #
- I'm ready.
- Me, too.
- Hurry, let's sign up.
- No, don't!
Oops! Guess you didn't get any,
huh, Babooch?
Louis Dimucci! Oh, God!
Oh, how could you do this?
- That'll be about $1.60.
- Will you get my windshield?
Yeah. Hold on. Just a second.
- Hi.
Can I pay so I can get out of here?
Yeah, look, hold on just one minute,
OK?
- Sorry.
- It's all right.
OK, that's two, three, four, five.
- (MAN) Where are the maps?
- What kind?
- (LAD Y) Street maps.
- Yeah?
Hey, miss. What do I owe you?
Eh... 50 cents.
- How about that ride?
- My windshield!
- You forgot our green stamps.
- We're in a hurry. The maps?
Are you going to get
this windshield or not? Come on.
- Honk it where the sun don't shine!
- Where are you going?
Oh, I can't stop shivering.
Then hold on.
That's what's making me shiver.
- Great ride.
- We're home.
Shoot.
- I can't stop shivering now.
- Why?
Because...
- There's something I should tell you.
- What?
- (RUMBLE OF ENGINES)
- Oh, no. We've got company.
- Check this out!
- I can handle these guys.
- He popped Balmudo.
- Look who he's poppin' now.
When am I gonna see you again?
Friday night. The Talent Show.
Let's go!
Out front, you hear?
Talent Show?
(S TEPHANIE) How'd he know?
Hi. What are you guys doin'?
What's the story
with the creep on the bike?
- What?
- The creep?
- Yeah, the creep, the story.
- (RHONDA) Shut up, Goose.
- (PAULETTE) Leave her alone.
- Shut up.
- Let's have it.
- What?
- The story.
- I think...
We don't care, Sharon!
No chick of mine messes
with no other creep except this...
...except me.
- No chick of yours?
- Someone's jealous.
- You never get jealous over me!
- I ain't jealous.
- Stay out of my life, then.
I'm out! I catch you with that punk again,
I'll rearrange his face.
He's a dead man. D-E-D!
You better decide
who belongs to who around here.
- You're making a scene.
- Because I'm getting mixed up.
You're embarrassing me.
Aah!
I think you owe Paulette an apology.
- Jerk!
- Where are you goin'?
Forget about it.
- Weirdos.
- Who needs broads?
Me. I get to second base with Sharon
and get called out when I try third.
He bombed out in the bomb shelter.
Yeah. I think we could all use
a little guaranteed... (WHISTLES)
...all-the-way action.
- And I know just the place.
- Yeah?
# Well, come on and tell us, Johnny
# What's the secret of success?
# You gotta take a tip
from the King of Hip
# 'Cause you know that he's the best
# We're goin' prowlin'
# Tonight
# You say you're hungry for a lover
# Gotta find a chick
who'll give you more
# Well, there's a spot
that I've discovered
# Where a guy's guaranteed to score
# I'm gonna show you cats some action
# Like you've never seen before
# We're gonna get some satisfaction
# Down at the grocery store
# We're goin' prowlin'
# Walk, talk like a T-Bird tonight
# There's a female butcher
# At the luncheon meat display
# Got the best tongue in town
# She delivers both night and day
# You'll see the apple of your eye
# Stacking peaches in a five-foot pile
# Just waitin' for some guy to come
# And take her rollin' down the aisle
# I like a debutante that comes across
# Now, that's what I call class
# I like a tall girl with long legs
that come right up to her...
# You know what I like?
I like a girl who's really smart
# Provided that she's really stacked
# Yeah? Well, I love 'em all
And they love me
# 'Cause I'm the leader
of this here pack
# We're gonna find ourselves
some cuties
# Who are sad and all alone
# We're gonna show
them little beauties
# That we're T-Birds to the bone
# We're goin' prowlin'
# Walk, talk like a T-Bird tonight #
How about some sales tax?
(SCREAMS THEN GIGGLES)
Very nice.
We could win those albumens yet.
- We can win those albumens.
- We gotta get rid of the competition.
There is some very good work here
and some very sloppy work.
Miss Zinone, I would like to see you
about your Shakespeare essay.
(BELL)
(TANNO Y) Attention, please. A few
reminders of graduation activities.
The final dress rehearsal for the
Talent Show is Thursday afternoon.
All students on the decoration
committee for the Lani Kai Lani Luau
report to Coach Calhoun
after school today.
- I guess she didn't like your paper.
- I gotta write the whole thing again.
- Do you want some help?
- I don't know.
Think it over. It's not a difficult decision.
- (PAULETTE) Steph, you comin'?
- Yeah. I'll think about it.
I don't usually do this bad in English.
I got other stuff on my mind these days.
- Can I help?
- No, it's not school.
- Let's get this over with.
- All right.
Where do you want to start?
- It's this guy.
- What guy?
- Forget it.
- I'm trying. You're not making it easy.
I had this idea of Mr Right.
A stupid idea, right?
- Right.
- Out of nowhere he shows up.
- Like some dream or something.
- Who?
- Mr Right.
- Oh, right.
I've seen him twice and both times
he's wearing these goggles.
- I don't even know who he is.
- Mr Right?
Isn't that kind of weird?
Not weird weird but, like, exciting weird.
So, what's the problem?
Maybe he's just not
everything I imagined.
What if he's just some ordinary guy?
What if he is, eh?
What if we get back
to the Shakespeare essay?
- Stephanie.
- I figured out Hamlet's problem.
No ketchup.
- He got along OK without it.
- They never put ketchup on.
How can you eat a hamburger
with no ketchup? Shoot that over here.
Where were we?
You figured out the problem
with their hamburgers.
You know what his big problem is?
No laughs.
The guy's gotta lighten up, right?
- Bite?
- No, thanks.
- Who are we talking about now?
- Hamlet.
Oh, right.
"Hamlet went nuts when he caught
his mother doing it with his uncle."
- Not so great?
- You have the right idea.
But you could've said,
Hamlet was tormented by his mother's
incestuous relationship with his uncle.
"Incestuous relationship"! Mason's
gonna flip when she reads this.
"Incestuous." You're a really
smart guy, you know that?
You must think I'm a dummy.
- Actually, I think you're kind of terrific.
- Get outta here.
You're the terrific one.
You know all this deep junk.
I don't understand it any better than you.
I just know a few big words
that impress English teachers.
You impressed me.
And I give credit to who I want, OK?
- To whom.
- To who, to whom, to you, that's whom.
- So learn how to take a compliment.
- All right.
- A hamburger for my friend. Loaded.
- With ketchup.
Double ketchup.
There are some very cool,
very scoreable broads at this joint.
Cool. Scoreable. What-not.
- Very nice.
Lots of Rydell girls
would go out with you.
- What about you?
- Me? Are you kidding? That's all I need.
- No, I wasn't.
- God, look, I didn't mean anything...
- We're just different types, that's all.
- Different types?
- What do you mean?
- Look, there's a Pink Lady code, OK?
Well, to quote Dolores,
"The code stinks."
- Hi.
- What's this? Nerds' night out?
- What are you, a cop?
- Sure picked up a lot of new friends.
I guess the T-Birds
ain't the class act no more.
Goose. Wait for me inside.
- I don't want to eat alone.
- Go on!
What do you want?
Yeah, well,
I just wanted to let you know that...
...l'm officially declaring us
as an item officially over.
- You're declaring?
- That's correct.
OK, fine. You've declared it.
It's over. Can I go now?
Just like that, huh?
I got one more thing to say to you.
That jacket you're wearing
is T-Bird property.
You want to leave the party?
Leave the jacket. I got a rep to protect.
So don't damage the rep,
we don't damage new friends, dig?
What happened? Did she take
the nerd's brains over your brawns?
- I dumped her, not versa-vice, got it?
- Sure, Johnny.
Don't worry about it.
(ALL TALK AT ONCE)
- All right, cherry pie!
- Davey!
# I'm all dressed up
# In my finest attitude
# Pretending I don't care
# Guess I really messed up
# By trying to be two
# When only one heart can be there
# Why can't I be just what I am
# And speak my love
without any shame?
# Why can't she see what I am
# Is a costumed fool
# Trapped in a tragic game?
# Charades and pretty lies
# They hide what's deep inside me
# Charades conceal me
# But can't you feel
# The real me
# Behind my charades?
# Oh, please don't mind me
# Performing at my hardest
# As I paint upon the air
# You won't find me
# 'Cause it's a portrait of the artist
# As the man who isn't there
# Charades and pretty lies
# They hide what's deep inside me
# Charades conceal me
# But can't you feel the real me?
# The real me
# Behind my charades?
# Can't you feel the real me
# Have I lost the real me
# Behind my charades? #
(CHATTERING)
(LIZ) Girls, girls, I'm so nervous.
How do I look?
Perfect. Just remember,
have lots of fun tonight.
- And good luck!
- He's meeting her out front.
How can she get so hot and bothered
over someone she doesn't know?
Sharon!
- What?
- She's got a crush.
(MOTORC YCLE)
I'll be back.
- It's that guy.
- This time we get him.
Johnny, no!
Johnny!
Rhonda, go. They're going to kill him.
- Who's killing who?
- Open the door. Move over.
- Where are we going?
- I don't know, just go!
(GIRLS SQUEAL)
Oh, God! We're gonna die and
I'm wearing my mother's underwear!
- Where are we going?
- Just follow 'em!
I figured the guy to slow up.
Right?
Yeah, it ain't our fault
the guy don't slow up, huh, Johnny?
It's gotta be at least 100 feet
to the other side.
- Johnny?
- Yeah, yeah, what can I say?
If he didn't make it,
he ain't gonna look too pretty.
Where is he?
- He ain't down there.
- Where'd he go? Biker heaven?
- (STEPHANIE) I know he's dead.
- He made the jump. I could do that.
- Yeah, you could jump that, Johnny.
- Let's go.
- And I'll never see him again.
- Come on!
- What have I done?
- Nothing.
- He'll be OK.
- Nobody rides like him.
- There's nothing down there.
- You can't stay here.
We'll be late.
He jumped over a cop car.
That was a big jump.
(RHONDA) He'll show up, I know it.
I just know it.
(WHISTLES AND CHEERS)
# If your sweetheart
- # Sends a letter of goodbye #
- (GIRLS SCREAM)
- (BO Y) If I stand...
- (STAGEHAND) Don't worry, looks fine.
- Hi, Johnny.
- Hi... Hold it!
What are you, crazy?
I told you before,
you are not going out there like that.
I know, I gotta put
a little something on my face.
You gotta put something on your body.
I gotta dress like this. I'm summer.
Get yourself a pair of galoshes,
a snowsuit, a scarf and be winter.
And that is Johnny Nogerelli's final word.
Well, you want to hear my final word,
Mr Push-Everyone-Around Nogerelli?
Maybe you can bully
some chicks in this school,
but this chick
has been bullied for the last time.
I may not be the classiest chick,
but I'm the best you're gonna get,
so take it or leave it!
- # So let your hair down
- (AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
# And go on and cry #
Let go of me!
Stop that!
Shut up! Quiet!
And now, Martin Miesner
and his red-hot accordion.
Let's go practise up in the can.
- Don't worry.
- The albumens are ours.
# Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum-bum
Bum-bum-bum-bum-bum-bum #
- Hey, he's taking our jackets.
- Hey, come on, guys.
Hey, Nogerelli!
Don't do it. OK, guys.
Turn it off! Hey, Nogerelli!
(AUDIENCE LAUGHTER)
Thank you, Martin Miesner.
And now, I have the great pleasure
to introduce the T-Bones.
(MUSIC INTRO, GIRLS SCREAM)
# We're goin' prowlin', prowlin'
# Tonight
# Tonight #
(RAPTUROUS APPLAUSE)
- The T-Bones.
- Birds! Birds.
And now, the Calendar Girls
in "A Girl For All Seasons".
(APPLAUSE)
# I'll be yours in springtime
When the flowers are in bloom
# We'll wander through the meadows
In all their sweet perfume
# And every night I'll hold you tight
Beneath that April moon
# Ah-ha-ha...
# I'll be your girl for all seasons
All the year through
# Your girl for all seasons
'cause I'd love
# Yes, I'd love to be everything to you
# Just you
# I'll be yours in summer
When we're playing in the sand
# We'll spend the day together
Making love and getting tanned
# And on the beach at sunset
When we're walking hand in hand
# Ah-ha-ha...
# I'll be your girl for all seasons
# All the year through
# Your girl for all seasons
# 'Cause I'd love
# I'd love to be everything to you
# Just you
# If you fall in the fall you'll see
# September can be heavenly
# If you fall, say you'll fall for me
# When autumn leaves
are falling from the tree
# I'll be yours in winter
When the snow is on the ground
# I'll warm you through December
And I'll always be around #
(SHARON) What's wrong with
Stephanie? She forgot the words.
Somebody help her with the words.
(GOOSE) It's that guy.
(JOHNN Y) This time we get him.
(S TEPHANIE) Johnny! Where is he?
(DIMUCCl) He ain't down there.
(JOHNN Y) Where'd he go?
(S TEPHANIE) I know he's dead.
Louis, pull the curtain.
I'll be back.
What's the matter?
- # No more secret rendezvous
- Stephanie, what's wrong?
# I'm gonna miss
all the things we'll never do
# I just can't believe
# You left me here alone
# How in this world
# Can I make it on my own?
(MICHAEL) # Remember, I love you
# I won't be far away
# Baby, close your eyes
# And think of yesterday
# And we'll be there together
(TOGETHER) # Love will
turn back the hands of time
# Turn back
# The hands of time
(STEPHANIE) # Baby, don't you know?
# It's hard to let you go
# Save all your dreams
# And keep me in your heart
# It hurts to say goodbye
# No matter how I try
# Love will survive
# Even though we have to part #
Stephanie, please don't cry.
Oh, it all seems so unfair.
Just when I found you, I lost you.
That doesn't matter now.
The only thing that matters
is that I love you.
And you're the only one
who can keep our love alive.
So, Stephanie, don't forget me.
I promise.
# Remember
# I love you
# You won't be far away
# I just close my eyes
# And bring back yesterday
# And we'll be there together
# Love will turn back the hands of time
# Turn back
# Turn back the hands of time
# We'll turn back
# Turn back
# Turn back the hands of time
# We'll turn back #
(CHEERING)
And now,
the winners of the Talent Contest,
and the King and Queen
of the Lani Kai Lani Luau, Mr Nogerelli
and Miss Zinone.
Please, Miss Zinone,
remember you're a queen.
- Smile, Stephanie.
- You won the whole talent show.
- The girls' division.
- That's not so bad.
Everyone bow and we'll see you all
at the Luau tomorrow.
I can't believe we won half the records.
All the Tichokski and Choppin.
What are you talkin'?
No Roy Orbisons?
(APPLAUSE
AND CHEERING CONTINUE)
# A well-a bop a bop a hula
Rock-a-hula rock-a-hula
# Luau, luau, luau, luau
# A wham-a bama lama
Shanga langa langa langa
# Luau, luau, luau, luau
# Rah rah Rydell
Well-a well-a well-a well-a
# Rock-a-hula luau wow
# Come-a come-a come-a
To the rock-a-hula luau
# Everybody's here
And we're waitin' for you now
# We're gonna stick together
And we won't let go
# We're lettin' everybody know
# It's a luau
# A rock-a-hula luau #
You know, it's girls like that
who give summer fun a bad name.
# Come-a come-a come-a come-a
We're gettin' it on now
# Summer, summer, summer
Is a-comin' along now
# I wish it was forever
'Cause it feels so right
# Don't you worry, honey
We'll be rockin' all night at the luau
# A rock-a-hula luau
# Summer is coming
We're all here together
# If only this feeling
Could go on forever
# Summer is coming
We'll always remember
# Summer is coming right now
# Rock-a-hula luau
# It's a rock, rock-a-hula luau
Rock-a-hula luau
# Hula, hula, hula, hula... #
(TANNO Y) As the sun sets
on the Lani Kai Lani Luau,
a reminder to our seniors:
In the words of our very own
President Kennedy,
"Think not what your country
can do for you,
"but what you can do for your country."
Now, will the King and Queen
of the Luau
take their appointed positions
on the Pool of Enchantment.
(CHEERING)
(CROWD CHANT: HULA! HULA!)
Come on, we're havin' a good time!
- Stop it! What are you doing?
- I'm burnin' myself.
You'll burn us up! Can't you put it out?
You'll knock us over.
- I'm tryin' to be cool here.
- Get me out of here.
Your doctor's right, Mr Spears.
School is better for you than hospital.
But I am encouraged at the way
you've been looking lately.
You look so... Mr Spears!
Oh, good heavens!
- Ya-hoo!
- (SCREAMS)
Sit down, Stephanie. Quit foolin'!
- Will you help me row!
- Stop yelling!
Get out of the way!
You punk!
Haul ass, shrimp!
- Get off of me!
- Will you help me row!
Get out of here!
Stuck in a pool with a chick!
Birds, get 'em!
- I got one! I got one!
- Sorry!
Get off! I didn't mean it.
- Balmudo!
- That's the guy who decked me.
- It's him.
- It's him!
(ENGINE REVS)
He's alive!
Ah-ah-ah!
- What's wrong with you, man?!
- You've ruined our luau!
Michael! It's Michael!
Michael.
- You?
- You made that jump?
Shakespeare?
I thought you were dead.
- You?
- Move! I'll rearrange his...
- Hey!
- What?
Nothing.
- No.
- Yeah. Yeah, Johnny.
Yeah, well, you got one more jump,
Mr Cool Rider, Shakespeare, Carrington.
- Haven't we had enough of this?
- She's got a point.
- Lou's got a point.
- Shut up! I've got a point, too.
- Jacket.
- One T-Bird jacket.
For starters, let's see how it looks.
(MURMURS FROM CROWD)
Very nice.
OK.
- All right.
Listen, I gotta talk to you.
We can't see each other any more.
I've got another man on my hands.
Oh, right.
(INAUDIBLE)
That's the breaks.
(JOHNNY) What's everybody lookin' at?
Disperse!
(WHISPERS) Stephanie.
I never thought you'd kiss me
if you knew who I was.
Are you crazy?
I got two for the price of one.
- Are you certain?
- I've never been certainer.
- More certain.
- The certainest.
The certainest. Yeah, I like that.
I'd love to kiss you again.
# You were the one
The one in my dreams
# But I never knew it
# I wanted to tell you time and again
# But I couldn't do it
# All that you are is all that I need
# No more pretending
# Now I can be me
You can be you
# And we're never ending
# We'll be together
# Always together
# Like birds of a feather
# Forever and ever
# We'll be together
# I like what you got
I guess it's OK
# If you want to show it
# I am what I am and I'm all for you
# Just want you to know it
# Will I ever score?
# There's nothin' wrong
with just likin' each other
# We all had our doubts
But it's workin' out with one another
# We'll be together
# Always together
# Like birds of a feather
# Forever and ever
We'll be together
# We'll be together
# Always together
# Like birds of a feather
# Forever and ever
# We'll be together
# Always together
# Always together #
# I gotta go back, back
Back to school again
# You won't find me
'til the clock strikes three
# I'm gonna be there 'til then
# I gotta go back, back,
Back to school again
# Whoa, whoa, I gotta go
# Back to school... again
# Geometry and History
it's just a pain
# Biology and Chemistry
destroys my brain
# But don't they know that I deserve
a better fate?
# I'm really much too young
to matriculate
# Mama, please
# Your child's come down
with a fatal disease
# Mama said,
# "Come on, you lazy bum
and get your butt outta bed
# "You gotta go back, back,
Back to school again
# "It's bye-bye, fun
Get your homework done
# "It better be in by ten"
# I gotta go back, back,
Back to school again
# Whoa, whoa, I gotta go
# I got my books together
and I dragged my feet
# And then I saw this angel
boppin' down the street
# I said, "Hey, pretty baby,
how's about a date?"
# She said, "I'm going to school
and I can't be late"
# Well, I could see
# The look in her eyes
was sayin', "Follow me"
# I was caught
# I thought of playin' hooky
But on second thought
# I gotta go back, back,
Back to school again
# You won't find me
'til the clock strikes three
# I'm gonna be there 'til then
# I gotta go back, back,
Back to school again
# Whoa, whoa, I gotta go
Back to school...
# ... Again! #