(sailor's hornpipe playing)
( Popeye's theme playing )
( whistle blows )
( staccato laugh )
Hey, what's this,
one of Bluto's tricks?
I'm in the wrong movie.
Captioning sponsored by
PARAMOUNT PICTURES
( thunder crashing )
( bell ringing )
♪ Sweet Sweethaven ♪
♪ God must love us ♪
♪ We the people ♪
♪ Love Sweethaven ♪
♪ Hooray, hooray, Sweethaven ♪
♪ Flags are wavin' ♪
♪ We're people from the sea ♪
♪ Safe from democracy ♪
♪ Sweeter than a melon tree ♪
♪ Put here for you and me ♪
♪ Sweethaven ♪
♪ Sweet Sweethaven ♪
♪ God must love us ♪
♪ We the people ♪
♪ Of Sweethaven ♪
♪ God must have landed here ♪
♪ Why else
would he strand us here? ♪
♪ Where the air
is nice and clear ♪
♪ Sweethaven
even sounds so near ♪
♪ To Heaven ♪
♪ God will always bless
Sweethaven ♪
♪ God will always
bless Sweethaven ♪
♪ God will always bless
Sweethaven. ♪
( honking horn )
You just dock?
I have.
Uh-huh.
There'll be 25 cents
docking tax.
What for?
Where's your seacraft?
It ain't no seacraft.
It's me dinghy,
and it's under the wharf.
Aha. Ah, huh.
This your goods?
They is.
Yeah?
You're new in town,
right?
( sotto voce ):
You call this a town?
Yeah.
Well, first of all,
there's 17 cents
new-in-town tax.
Then there's 45 cents
rowboat-under-the-wharf tax,
and one dollar leaving-your-
junk-lying-around-the-wharf tax.
So, all together,
you owe the Commodore
$1.87.
Ah, who's this Commodore?
That the nature of a question?
There's a nickel question tax.
Oh, forget it.
I see what you're up to here.
Here we go.
Exact change, please.
I'm an exact-change
taxman.
Oh. Mmm. Here's a dollar.
Here's a red cent.
( excited chatter )
Here's a franc.
A peso.
Here's a guilder.
Oh, sorry I'm taking
your time.
There's a dime;
there we go.
There's one quarter.
Curiosity tax.
Hey, I paid me tax.
( chattering )
Oh, tax this, tax that.
Ooh, my nightmare don't...
Mmm, I gets disgustipated.
"Have you paid your tax?"
( muttering )
MAN 1:
I got it, I got it.
MAN 2:
No, I-I got it.
MAN 3:
I got it, I got it.
MAN 4:
Don't worry, I got it.
POPEYE:
Holy cow.
Looks like me old pipe.
Wonder what it's doing here?
What a coinkydink.
Hey! What is this?
This ain't
the orchestra pit.
( grunting )
( chuckling )
Oh, lookit there.
♪ Nobody seems to care... ♪
You've got so much
to bear, ma'am.
Can I...?
Blow me down!
That's it, that...!
♪ Oh, it's the wind
and air... ♪
Just try to double dare
to... blow me down.
PARROT:
Awk! Wait for me!
Hello, there, mate.
Maybe, uh...
Ah, blow me down.
♪ It's no bother, but... ♪
Look over there--
stranger's coming.
You'd rather not, huh?
Well, that's easy to see.
♪ Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm ♪
♪ Wherever I go... ♪
Ooh, nice-looking knees,
it does it for me.
Bad news!
Bad, bad, bad news.
POPEYE:
Hmm, I don't believe that.
♪ What a lovely day... ♪
Well, it's still
a perfect day, but...
Oh, maybe ma'am,
you would like to...
Blow me down
again, there.
♪ It's a lovely place ♪
♪ Think I'd like
to stay, but... ♪
Stranger in town.
Blow me down.
Somebody roll into town?
♪ Trouble, trouble,
trouble, trouble... ♪
Blow me down--
local glum club.
♪ It's friendly here... ♪
A little scary, too.
I think I'll spend a year,
♪ Or two, maybe thr... ♪
Whoa, tut-tut-tut.
♪ I yam what I yam,
wherever I go ♪
♪ I came from the sea... ♪
Should've got me number,
but no one's looking it up,
ain't it?
Oh...
Good day.
I hate you to pieces!
Kind of a greasy good day,
but that's all right.
Bunch of carrotsk?
No, no.
You ain't got no carrotsk?
What are those, prunes?
Phooey on carrots!
Take broccoli.
I am in the mood
for carrotsk.
I need me vitamins.
Phooey on carrots!
Take spinach!
If I wants spinach,
I'll axk you for spinach.
So, why
you didn't say so?
For you, each a dollar.
How much is
the broccoli?
Nickel, maybe dime.
And the spinach?
Dime, maybe quarter.
Then how come
carrotsk is a dollar?
Dollar fifty.
You buy what I don't feel
like selling,
it'll cost you $2.
( muttering )
All right, here you go.
Uh-uh-uh-uh!
Hey, deadbeat,
this is a nickel.
I pays what I
feels like paying.
( chuckling )
You're not up to
no good, are you?
'Cause if you are,
there's a 50-cent up-to-no-good tax.
( clamoring )
Come here! Come back!
♪ Seems like everywhere ♪
♪ Lots of people here ♪
♪ Try to blow me down... ♪
( laughs )
♪ Unlike the clothes I wear ♪
♪ I haven't... ♪
Careful, there.
What blew him into town?
Oh, the short arm of the law,
huh?
♪ Blow me down ♪
♪ Blow me down... ♪
Ow!
Hey, come ba... hey, hey-- ah!
( sputtering )
( men grumbling )
Uh, are you the piano tuner
or the man with the party favor?
You got a room for renk?
What for what?
Renk, renk-- your
sign says you got a room for renk.
Oh, my stars
and gardens!
My mind
was a million miles away.
Come in before you catch
your death of mud.
"Mud."
"Oyls." That explains it.
She's down a quart.
Scums-- I'll find you.
Come on, come on!
Mmm. Don't make them
like they used to.
Oh, come on.
Oh!
I'm sorry, Mother,
but it's ugly.
I ask you, have you ever
seen anything so ugly?
I won't be engaged
in this hat.
I heard that.
Don't think I didn't hear that.
Oh...
She owes me an apology.
Oh... ugly.
There's nothing
left to say.
What do you think?
I think
it's up to you, dear.
Well, what do
you think? Ugly.
I think it's a conspiracy.
Oh...
Why would they manufacture
deliberate ugliness
unless they wanted me
to look ugly?
If we find that out,
we find out everything.
There's a stranger
in t... um... ooh...
Oh...
I can't get engaged.
You'll have to tell
Bluto; I can't.
We'll have to
cancel the party
tomorrow night.
It's not my fault
that it's so ugly.
( gasping )
What are you doing
listening in on
a private conversation
between me
and my mother?
I have a good mind to have
my father call a policeman.
Olive, will you show
Mister... Mister...?
Oh. Popeye, ma'am.
...Mr. Eye
the spare room?
Just Popeye, ma'am.
Go upstairs, Mr. Eye.
Olive will show you the room.
( chuckling ):
Thanks.
( groans softly )
( sotto voce ):
Some kind of asylum here.
Show me a room.
Show me some
courtesy
might be nice.
I don't see why
I have to do anything
on the day
before my engagement party
when nothing's ready,
especially me.
And what kind of name is that,
anyway-- Popeye?
Pretty strange.
What kind of name is Olive Oyl?
Sounds like
some kind of lubricants.
Thank you very
much, ma'am.
( gasps )
Don't look in that room;
that's my room.
Meant no
disrespect there.
Ugly, huh?
You owe me an apology.
What?
Wonder who shoved
a feather in his ear?
What'd you say?
Sure is nice weather
you have here.
( chuckles )
Your name really Olives?
So what?
Olives Oyl?
( chuckles )
You don't look
Greek to me.
So, you're short.
Or are you just passing
yourself off as short?
Can I see me room now?
Ooh, as if I cared.
Let me give you
a hand there.
Maybe it needs
a little oil.
Oh!
( shrieks )
Oh, oh...
( glass shattering )
Nice-looking room.
Never seen a room done
in early demolish-kin before,
but this'll do for me.
Careful how you treat that bed.
Nothing goes
on this bed.
Sorry, ma'am, it's just some...
Watch that lamp!
( chuckles ):
Let me give you some assistance.
Here, give me your hand.
There, that's it.
Yeah, here we go.
Oh, you're in first.
Is that... oh...
Boy, is it hot in here.
I still respect you.
Ooh!
( chuckles )
Me bad eye, didn't see that.
Hmph!
( shattering )
( door slams )
Thanks for your help.
Uh, Miss Oyl, maybe...
( bell dinging )
WOMAN:
Don't forget to put the cat out, dear.
MAN:
We don't have a cat.
Eau de toilette.
Yeah, eau de toilette.
( chuckles )
( sniffs ):
Yeah.
COLE:
How do you like that?
Gold is up 20 cents,
two dollars an ounce.
Out of my kitchen,
Mr. Wimpy.
CASTOR:
I knew it, I knew it, see...
You wait for
the supper gong.
I could've made
a fortune on Billings
if Bluto would've let me go
directly to the Commodore.
He's so jealous
of me, that Bluto.
Well, who
wouldn't be?
COLE:
Me, I'm not jealous of Castor.
He's my son.
Man jealous
of his own son.
You owe me an apology.
I didn't mean you.
CASTOR:
Never lets me go to the Commodore.
Commodore is a paragon
of sagacity.
If ever I could
put in a good word...
"Shut up" is the word.
"Pass" is another word
that Wimpy...
You don't pass.
He should be
killed to death.
COLE:
It says here the Commodore's taxing salt again.
Don't look as good as I smell,
but too late now.
( chuckles ):
Got to go.
Oh, Mr. Eye,
have you met-- uh, Pop?
Mr. Wimpy,
my son Castor,
Mr. Geezil,
my husband Cole.
We're all one big
happy family here.
Hmph!
Although not really.
I mean, well, Mr. Geezil
and Mr. Wimpy are, um...
Me, I'm family.
Well, you're
my husband.
You owe me an apology.
OLIVE:
Well, I can't find anything.
What are you
looking for, Olive?
A glass.
Oh, uh, here's a glass.
That's a short, fat, ugly glass.
I want a tall, pretty,
slender glass.
They're all broken.
I could've made
a fortune in fish futures...
Fish?
but I'd have to dip into capital.
Fish futures smell.
( laughter )
What kind of glass
do you want, Olive?
A wine glass
or a brandy glass,
or a water glass?
Oh, not a thing--
I don't want a thing.
Real appetizing.
I want a fork.
Right beside
your plate.
If it was a knife,
it would cut you.
And a knife.
Will you sit down?
Why don't I have a knife?
And a nice dress?
You owe me
an apology.
( Geezil muttering )
Passing fish,
please.
Fish, excellent idea, Miss Oyl.
I would suggest before
matrimony, fish.
Fish before
matrimony.
Ooh, that does look good, there.
Wish I had a plate though.
...because four times
engaged is three times much.
Oh, he can't talk me
out of anything; I'm not a child.
I'll say you're
not a child.
Who says I'm not a child?
You said you're not a child
and I agreed with you,
that's who.
Who asked you
to agree with me?
Well, no one can stop me
from agreeing with you
if I want to.
I can.
Quarreling at
my table.
You both owe me
an apology.
Sorry, Pop.
What?
Please pass the shrimp,
chicken and meatballs.
Well, I don't know.
Captain Bluto has
the patience of Job.
Or is it job?
Certainly got
a very good job, Job.
And he needs a lot of patience.
Why, he runs this town
for the Commodore
while he's away.
And the Commodore's always away.
As a matter of fact,
I've never seen him.
Have you, Cole?
What?
I'd never let a girl
break my engagement.
I'd break her nose before
she broke my engagement.
And you better not try on me
what you pulled on Bluto,
because I'm no pushover.
You owe your
sister an apology.
Will you stop fidgeting?
Finishing touch here.
OLIVE:
Oh, this knife won't cut.
Here, take mine.
Not since I was child
have we had a sharp knife
in this house.
COLE:
You owe me an apology.
You don't like
our knives.
Bluto's rich, he can buy you
plenty of knives.
Ooh, I hate this table,
it's ugly.
I'm the only one with
nerve enough to tell the truth about it.
( nasally ):
Well, then, why don't you let Bluto the pushover
buy you a new table?
Am I right, Pop?
Right.
I'm right, right?
You're right.
Right.
WIMPY:
Nothing left?
Oh... Bluto, Bluto, Bluto.
Everyone takes advantage
of my poor Bluto.
Get a new... glass,
a new knife.
Now they want a table.
Well, hmph!
That's why I always
have to break off
our engagement--
to stop you all
from taking advantage
of the sweetest,
most humble man
on the face of this Earth!
Hmph.
Mmm.
You make me sick.
( sighs )
Never good to be too full,
I guess.
( music plays in distance )
( people chanting indistinctly )
( buoy dinging in distance )
( sighs )
( music continues playing )
( people chatting )
( creaking )
( growling )
( foghorn sounds in distance )
( echoing ):
It's 9:00!
Curfew!
Lights... out!
( silence )
WOMAN ( whispers ):
You can have a kiss now.
( kissing )
Oh!
Poppa.
Pretty soon you and me are going
to be together again, huh?
Yeah.
30 years ain't that long.
Besides, next Wednesday's
our annual-versity.
Yeah? Yeah.
( sighs )
Stay alive.
That's all I'm axskin you.
( sighs )
Good night, Poppa.
( kiss )
Aw...
( grunts )
( sighs )
There.
( bell ringing )
( rooster crows )
Sweep, sweep,
sweep, sweep.
Sweep, sweep...
Hey-up!
Ah... whoop!
( grunts )
Eee-oh!
♪ Everything
is food, food, food ♪
♪ Everything is food to go ♪
♪ Everything is food
for thought ♪
♪ Everything you knead
is dough ♪
♪ It is food ♪
♪ Everything is food ♪
♪ Everything
is meat, meat, meat ♪
♪ Careful what
you put on your feet ♪
♪ Once it lived
on an ani-mule ♪
♪ Now it walks along with you ♪
♪ It could be food ♪
( screams )
♪ Everything is food ♪
♪ I would gladly pay you Tuesday
♪
♪ For a hamburger today ♪
♪ He would gladly pay you
Tuesday ♪
♪ For a hamburger today ♪
♪ Everything
is chow, chow, chow ♪
♪ Everything is food to go now ♪
♪ Everything
is fast-food chains ♪
♪ From your lemon
to your sugarcane ♪
♪ It is food ♪
♪ Everything is food ♪
Did you order a hamburger?
Yeah, I ordered
a hamburger.
That's what I got,
No, I beg to disagree.
Rough House,
a genuine hamburger
for the gentleman.
I'm buying.
Hey, thanks.
ROUGH HOUSE:
Who's paying?
I'm buying, he's paying.
TAXMAN:
A nickel hamburger tax?
I'd refuse to pay
if I were you.
A shocking abuse of power.
TAXMAN:
Rough House!
♪ Food, food, food ♪
♪ Everything is food ♪
One hamburger-chiseler's tax.
♪ I would gladly
pay you Tuesday ♪
What kind mooch is this?
♪ For a hamburger today ♪
♪ He would gladly
pay you Tuesday ♪
♪ For a hamburger today ♪
( growling )
♪ Everything is upside-down ♪
( laughs )
♪ Everything is sunny-side up ♪
♪ Did you pay for this ♪
♪ In American? ♪
♪ They can't trick us
with no hot dog ♪
♪ Everything is food,
food, food ♪
♪ Everything is food. ♪
( yelps )
( sighs )
MEN:
Hey, hey, hey, Laverne!
( all shouting )
Give us a smooch!
( laughter )
I really need someone
to kind of talk to,
'cause I thought everybody
in this town might be deef.
Huh, what's that?
Huh? Oh.
( boisterous laughter )
You know, jusk why
I'm here is...
I'm looking for me pap.
Yeah, oh...
I've searched
the seven seas for him,
and I haven't
found him yet.
I was only two years old,
me own pap left me.
I was just a mere infink.
Me own pap...
( boisterous laughter )
Pipe down, will ya?
Me own pap ditches me.
I'm a very tolerant man,
except when it comes
to holding a grudge.
I never thought
I'd forgive me paps,
but about
seven years ago,
I ships out on this boat,
The Gloomy Gus.
( chuckles ):
That's a boat. Yeah. ( boisterous laughter )
Just off the coast
of Guam.
It breaks up
on this typhoon,
and I'm stuck on
this raft for 45 days
without food or waters.
But after all
this time on this raft,
this visiktation
comes to me.
Looks just like me mother,
rest her soul.
( boisterous laughter )
And it says,
"Your pap is still alive."
Excuse me.
( boisterous laughter )
So, when I was
finally rescued,
I figured out that I got
to forgive me paps, you know?
Uh, you see,
I'm only afeared
that he might be dead,
and never realize what a
fine figure of an orphink
I turned out to be.
You sure got
a nice-looking face there,
One-Eye.
( laughter )
One-Eye?
I've seen better arms
on a baboon.
You're a slimy...
Yeah, you want to
know why you're so "lonescome,"
go take a look
at that mirror.
( laughter )
( table rattling )
( chuckles )
( cracking knuckles )
You know, if there's
one thing I ain't got,
it's a sense ka humor.
Where did you get that,
uh, pronunskiation?
( laughter )
Yeah? Got an olive
caught in your throat?
( laughter )
Well, yeah, well,
I'll get back to you.
( laughs )
Pappy.
His Dada.
No. I want
my Dada.
Hey, if I were
your daddy,
I'd ship
out, too.
( laughter )
Yeah. You're
too dumb-looking
to leave on
a doorstep.
( laughter )
Hey, runt...
I'll bet your
pappy...
is as ugly
as you are.
Another thing I got...
is a sensk
of humiligration.
Now, uh, maybe you swabs can,
uh, pool your intelligence
and sees that I'm asking you
for an apologiky.
( laughs )
Hey, Butch,
why don't you
give daddy's boy
an apology?
With pleasure,
Spike.
( laughs )
The little one-eyed rat
wants an apology.
Well, I would like
to offer my most sincere
and hum-felt apologies.
You got it.
( laughter )
( groans )
That's so low...
picking on innocents.
( laughter )
You apologize?
( groans )
( laughter )
Do you apologize?
I-I apologize.
Rosie, get my hat.
I think
it's time we leave. I...
back to the dairy...
( laughter )
( whimpering )
( screams )
( growls )
Apologize.
For what?
( laughter )
All these innocents.
This is a smorgasbord
of violence.
Well, that's everybody.
Everybody's apologized.
Yeah,
everybody's really sorry.
Oh, everybody's
really,
really sorry.
Now it's your turn
to be sorry.
MAN:
Oh, yeah.
( glass shattering )
I'm sorry to have to do this,
but enough is enough.
( men grunting )
Hey.
Come on.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey.
Sorry.
( mumbling )
( groans )
Thanks.
Anybody else want
to apologygy?
( growling )
( clears throat )
All in a day's fun, ain't it?
( soft grunt )
I dare you.
Nobody home?
There you go.
Sorry about that.
No. Keep the change.
( chuckles )
( cash register dings )
( spits )
( Pelican squawks )
Remember, my dear,
tonight it's my
turn to be tall.
Oh.
MAN:
Very nice party.
I can't help
but feel sad, though.
Chico?
This is a sad day
for me.
Chico, hand these things out.
It's one of the saddest days
of my life.
( growling )
Flowers.
I forgot the flowers.
( growling )
Yup.
Oh, disillusionkand.
( laughter )
Oh, look at that.
Oh, me dress blues.
This is Castor's
favorite color.
Oh, you
and Castor.
Oh, phooey.
( chatting indistinctly )
WOMAN:
Oh, hello there, Cousin.
We're just waiting
for Captain Bluto.
Oh, I can't tell you
how happy this makes me
to attend Miss Oyl's parties.
( chuckles )
( silence )
( clock ticking )
Uh, nice-looking furs there.
( growls )
Hmm?
Oh.
( chuckles )
( clock ticking )
Boy, uh, I don't know
when I've had this much fun
and still been conskious.
Well... I better be on me way.
Oh, reservoir.
( chuckles )
Not really as nice as ours.
But he's so big.
( cuckoo clock sounding )
( woman laughing )
WOMAN:
I really...
MAN:
Typical smutty sailor comment.
WOMAN:
Sailor....
Oh, I don't want
to go to no party.
Well, that's good,
'cause you ain't invited.
Who says I ain't invited?
I says.
Who are you?
You know who I am.
I'm you.
( squawks )
Don't drain your sense
of dignity... is that it?
Nah.
( shattering )
WOMAN:
Ugly.
WOMEN:
Bluto's ugly all right.
( women giggling )
OLIVE:
Bluto's distinguished.
( fly buzzing)
WOMEN:
He's distinguished, all right.
Distinguishingly
ugly.
( laughter )
Bluto's special.
ALL:
Oh, he's special, all right.
Especially ugly.
( laughter )
♪ He's tall ♪
♪ Good-looking ♪
♪ And he's large ♪
( laughter )
♪ He's large ♪
♪ Large ♪
( giggling )
♪ Tall ♪
♪ Large... ♪
( woman giggling )
( fly buzzing )
( growling )
Good morning,
Captain Bluto.
( stammering ):
I... I mean...
Good evening,
Captain Bluto.
I mean...
♪ And he's mine ♪
♪ Not a mandolin ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ He's an accordion ♪
( accordion plays )
♪ I have to squeeze him
each night to keep him warm ♪
♪ Warm ♪
♪ Oh, boy ♪
♪ He's virile ♪
♪ And he's strong ♪
♪ Strong ♪         ♪ Strong ♪
♪ Strong ♪
♪ He's strong ♪
♪ Strong... ♪
Uh...
Sounds like Fluto.
Bluto.
At your
services, sir.
There's a good picture
in the paper this week.
A lovely
present for you
down at the pawn
shop, Captain Bluto.
I would have
brought it, but it was too late.
Anytime you want
me to come by
and stain up the boat,
Captain Bluto.
Mother!
♪ He's got money and respect ♪
♪ That's true ♪
♪ He's better than the rest ♪
♪ He may not be the best ♪
♪ But he's large ♪
( laughter )
♪ And he's mine... ♪
ALL:
She can have him.
Yeah.
She loves me.
( applause )
MAN:
Of course she does.
She don't
love me.
Oh, no.
( all murmuring )
( fly buzzing )
She'll marry me.
( applause and cheering )
♪ Large ♪
♪ Mine ♪
♪ Mine... ♪
She won't marry me.
( murmuring )
Oh.
( stammering )
( fly buzzing )
She will.
( applause and cheering )
She won't.
( stammering )
( groaning )
♪ It may seem funny,
but it's not ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ I'm thankful ♪
♪ For what I've got ♪
♪ Me, too ♪
♪ It may not be a lot ♪
♪ But he's large. ♪
She will.
( applause and cheering )
Yes, yes.
She...
( growls )
Faulty flower...
C-Captain Bluto.
( growling )
WOMEN:
Mrs. Oyl, Olive's...
Olive's what?
WOMEN:
Olive's...
( growling )
...getting ready.
Good.
Now, where were we?
Uh, she won't
marry you, she...
She will!
( applause and cheering )
Oh, my word!
Son-in-law.
( fly buzzing )
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Ah! Ooh.
( groans )
( mumbling )
( sighs )
( fly buzzing )
( growling )
NANA:
Olive!
( grunts )
( fly buzzing )
( growling )
( growling continues )
( applause and cheering )
MAN:
Marvelous, marvelous.
No place to go.
Can't go to no party
without an invite.
Whoo!
( muttering )
( squawking )
Ho, ho, ho, whoa.
Whoo! Ooh.
Miss Oyl.
Oh...
You scared the
wits out of me.
Yeah, I almost knocked 'em
out of you, too.
Sorry I did that
to you. What right do you have
to lurk here in the dark
in the middle of the night
and scare the wits
out of a person?
I wasn't.
I was just, uh, kind of, uh...
Oh, oh.
How's your party going,
Miss Oyl?
Oh, that's a
dumb question. Yeah.
Where do you think I'm headed
right this minute?
Um... well, uh,
mmm, that way, I think.
Out of town.
I am not headed
out of town. Oh.
Don't you see which
direction I'm facing?
You're going,
now you're facing... Oh, ooh, whoa.
Now you're facing east.
Oh.
Maybe a little southwest.
Place your bets. Oh. Oh!
You need some help
with your bags there, Miss Oyl?
Ooh, oh, no.
I didn't touch ya.
I didn't mean
to hurt ya.
Thank you.
Oh, you do.
Oh.
( muttering )
No, that's
the wrong way.
Oh.
No, that's
the wrong way.
I want to go...
Oh...
Oh, oh...
( muttering )
Whoo! Oh. Oh, oh.
Oh!
( muttering )
Oh, oh...
( horn honking )
Oh...
That way.
That'll be 50 cents
impersonating-a-
traffic-cop tax.
What?
Oh.
I'm sorry, Miss Oyl.
Didn't recognize you
from the back.
It won't happen again.
How come Miss Oyl
don't have to pay no taxes?
TAXMAN:
That's ten cents question tax.
( mutters )
But... I'll let you off this time
since you're
with Miss Oyl.
Good night, Miss Oyl.
Well, how come being
with Miss Oyl
means I don't have
to pay no... ( horn honking )
...taxes?
Well, I don't know
what you're talking about.
( growling )
Here's a nice cup of tea
for you, Captain Bluto,
while you're waiting.
( gulping loudly )
Where's Olive?
Olive?
You think everyone pays taxes
but me and my family,
don't you? Mm-hmm.
Well, you couldn't be
more wrong.
If I'm wrong, why
am I in the right?
You think it's because
I'm engaged to Bluto
and Bluto runs the town
for the Commodore
so we get special favors.
Well, it's a lie. Hmm.
Olive!
( growling )
Bluto is kind and generous
and likes to do things
for his loved ones.
( Pelican squawking )
And you want me to
hurt his feelings.
Well, phooey on you.
( mutters )
Hmm. You don't even care
enough about me or my family
to be at my engagement party.
And what are you doing here
in Sweethaven anyway, hmm?
Well, I'm-I'm looking
for me pap.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Oh, well, if that's
true, then where is he?
Well, yeah, um, got me there.
I don't really know.
I... I got this sense
that he's here though,
you know?
Oh, well, all right,
I'll wait. Hmm.
Anyway, there are too
many guests as it is.
Half of them I hate.
( Bluto growling )
( glass crunching )
( growling and crunching
continues )
One thing I remember
about me pap
was that he always used
to throw me up in the air.
But he'd never be there
when I come down, you know.
Heh, heh, heh.
Mmm.
Boy, he had a sense
ka humor, didn't he?
Yeah, that was me pap.
I remember that
time he gave me
an electric eel as a toy.
( laughs ):
Eep!
Yeah, that was fun.
Or he'd rock me
in my cradle
real, real, real hard
and I'd lose me formula.
And then he'd say, "One
day, you'll be a sailor."
That... ( laughs )
that's what I am today.
Yeah. Sometimes, he'd
bounce me on his knee.
Most of the time
he'd miss, though
'cause he couldn't see
too well with one eye.
( laughs )
Oh, me pap, yeah.
Well, I'm not waiting
any longer. Hmm.
Oh, sorry, Miss Oyl.
( laughs )
I was philoscofying.
Mm-hmm.
...between us, got kind of
derailed and... ( laughs )
Oh, yeah, long time waiting.
( laughs )
Wait a while..
What are you doing
with that basket?
Well, I-I'm carrying it.
It's your basket, ain't it?
It is not my basket.
Somebody has deliberately
painted that basket
to look like my basket.
My basket was clean
and beautiful
and this basket is ugly.
( rattling )
Rattlesnake!
Miss Oyl, we should at least
have dinner first,
or something.
Rattlesnake!
Oh, rattlesnake!
Ooh! Oh, oh, oh!
Rattlesnakes?
Where is it, Miss Oyl?
Where is it?
( rattling )
Oh, oh,
rattlesnake, oh!
Don't worry, Miss Oyl,
I've handled
vermins before.
I'll rattle that snakes
so it's a pair of shoes.
Rattlesnake!
( rattling )
I'll rattle that...
I'll rattle him
upside-down. Rattlesnake!
I'll take
his little mariachis.
Rattlesnake!
Uh, no, I'll get to him.
Hey, hey, hey!
OLIVE:
Oh!
( coos )
Aw...
Oh...
( laughs )
Blow me down.
Oh.
Here you go.
Here's your snake.
( rattling )
There you go.
What have you got here?
"To the one-eyed sailor."
Oh, that must be me.
Wait a minute.
Hold on there.
Watch out, I don't
want to hurt you.
Hi.
( laughs )
I'll read this.
I'll bring it
right back to you.
There we go.
( baby crying )
Oh, I ain't that ugly.
( crying )
It's all right.
Oh, it's okay.
I am, I am, I am.
I'm all right.
Hey...
It's okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, we're
together in this.
Mmm, mmm.
Mm-hmm.
All right. "I must
trust someone..."
Mmm... bah-bah-bah.
You're a baby.
It's says here.
Right there, right.
"I must trust someone
with me baby
"until I frees meself of
certain financhkal obligations.
Yeah. "Which will
take 25 years or so
"at which time I
shall reclaims him.
"In the meantime,
"love him as only
a mudder could.
Signed, a mudder."
Ho, ho, ho.
You want the note?
Okay, take it back.
How are ya?
I loves you more
than you'll ever know.
Olive...!
( rumbling, glass shattering )
( yelling fades )
( growling )
( band playing upbeat tune )
It's Olive's fault, oh, oh.
( gulping )
Oh, oh!
I-I... I...
♪ I'm mean, I'm mean, I'm mean ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ He's mean, he's mean ♪
♪ You know what I say ♪
♪ He's says he's mean ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ He's mean, he's mean ♪
♪ Mean! ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ He's mean, he's mean ♪
♪ I'm meaner than... ♪
Aah...
♪ That's it, that's it ♪
♪ I mean what I say ♪
♪ He do, he do ♪
♪ I'm so mean I had a dream ♪
♪ Of beatin' myself up ♪
♪ I broke my nose ♪
♪ I broke my hand ♪
♪ I wrestled myself
to the ground ♪
♪ And then I choked myself
to death ♪
♪ And broke the choke
and woke up ♪
( growls )
♪ I'm mean ♪
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ He's mean, he's mean ♪
♪ If you know what I mean ♪
( yelling )
♪ You'll know what I mean ♪
♪ Dood, dood, dood, dood ♪
♪ I'm mean ♪
♪ He's mean, he's mean ♪
♪ Meaner than... ♪
Aah...
♪ I sure am mean ♪
♪ Yeah, mean ♪
♪ He's mean, he's mean ♪
♪ I'm meaner than that ♪
Out of my way!
♪ You know what I mean ♪
♪ I'm so damn mean ♪
♪ I'm mean! ♪
( people talking excitedly )
( talking stops )
Look at this.
I came looking for me pap
and now I'm
a mudder.
( talking resumes )
He's so cute.
( singsongy ):
Little baby.
Olive, I, uh, certainly
engaged your enjoyment party.
And I...
I mean, I...
Theres you go.
Got another two
to go there.
Mmm, I'm not going to drop him.
( singsongy ):
Little baby.
Oh, when you
throw a party,
you throw a party,
don't you?
BLUTO:
For the last time, where's Olive?!
Oh...
( growling )
POPEYE:
Oh, yeah...
Uh-oh.
Uh-ooh.
Oh...
( Bluto growling )
Oh.
What...?
( inhales sharply )
( grunting, sizzling )
Uh-ooh.
( sizzling )
( grunts )
( growling )
Oh...
( baby fussing )
Oh, oh.
( growling )
The women
and infinks first.
Here you go.
Oh...
I'll get back to you,
I will.
Oh, oh...
Oh...
POPEYE:
Little-little something
to remember me by.
Oh!
Good luck.
( fussing )
Oh...
Huh.
There's a logical
explanaskin for thisk.
OLIVE:
Oh... Oh...
Uh, I'd make the same mistake
meself.
( Bluto growling )
Yeah, and I knows
what you thinkins.
( Bluto grunting )
Oh!
( Popeye muttering )
( sputtering )
Oh, look at the birdies.
All right, I'll fight
all eight of ya.
( grunts )
Oh...
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow...
OLIVE:
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh!
Oh...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
Oh, oh, oh, oh...
Whoa...
( grunting )
BLUTO:
Okay, shorty,
the Oyls are going
to be double taxed.
( muttering )
Hey, hey, what the...?
Hey, hey!
Triple taxed.
( muttering )
Quadruple taxed.
Oh, look at that,
uh, oh, oh.
Going down.
Ooh, ow!
( growls )
( groans )
Surtaxed.
( Pelican squawking )
( Popeye muttering )
What a lovely
shade of blue.
Exercise taxed.
Overtaxed.
( muttering )
And...
thumb taxed!
( drill grinding )
( yelling )
( choking )
( blowing pipe )
( spitting )
Heh! Don't thinks I blames ya,
'cause I don't.
Nope.
TAXMAN:
"Whereas you are in arrears on your bathtub tax
"and whereas there is no bathtub
in extant.
"And whereas you are in arrears
on your refrigerator tax
"and whereas there
is no refrigerator in extant.
"And whereas you are in arrears
on your Victrola tax
"and where as there is no
Victrola in extant.
"And whereas you are in arrears
on your household
"and impertinences
maintenance tax
"and whereas there
is no house...
"or household or impertinences
or maintenance,
"by the order invested in me
by Captain Bluto
"on behalf of his honor,
the Commodore...
Aah, phooey,
the Commodore.
Next to Wimpy,
I hate him best.
"You owe..."
This is extremely grave news.
Please, pay attention.
"...the sum of twelve thousand,
twelve hundred,
twelve dollars
and twelve cents."
Cole, stop reading!
Plus one sunflower-
embarrassing-the-taxman tax.
Phooey!
And double phooey!
Avast there. Avast.
Watch it,
you'll hurt her.
Oh, yeah?
A lot you know.
Her is a him.
See, it likes to smoke.
So... you're
just a landlubber, ain't ya?
Oh, yeah,
well, I'm a woman.
well, I am a mudder.
Oh, yeah?
Come here.
Papa.
Oh, yeah?
He wants me,
he wants me there.
You must have an IQ
about half a million, don't ya?
Oh, yeah,
coochie-coo.
None of that baby talk
around me son.
Me son's gonna be a man
and not a baby, I'm thinking.
Ain't that right?
Oh, come to Papa,
me little Swee'pea.
♪ You're my little Swee'pea,
you're my little Swee'pea. ♪
Swee'pea?
Mm-hmm.
You're bats.
Oh, yeah?
I found him in Sweethaven.
That is why he's me Swee'pea.
I am calling him Swee'pea,
and that is his name.
Ain't that the truth?
Yeah?
Mm-hmm, yeah.
Well, Swee'pea is
about the worst name I ever heard on a baby.
Well, what do you want me
to call him? Baby Oyl?
( squeals )
( crowd murmuring )
CASTOR:
Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
A bit of boxing
tonight.
( all chatting excitedly )
( horn sounding )
CASTOR:
What could happen to me?
Well, I could get killed.
It'd be worth getting killed
to help Mom and Pop.
What if I won?
I'm fast, I'm foxy.
He could have a heart attack.
( band playing
Sweethaven anthem, off-key )
ALL:
♪ Sweet Sweethaven ♪
♪ God must love us... ♪
OLIVE:
Ooh, and I disapprove of you
taking me to a fight
and my parents to a fight
and my baby to a fight.
♪ Ah, Sweethaven... ♪
POPEYE:
Fights is fun.
OLIVE:
Oh, fights are not fun.
NANA:
Know the words for this song, Cole?
COLE:
Of course I know the words.
It's our national anthem,
isn't it?
POPEYE:
Pardon us...
Ah-ah-ah.
That'll be 62 cents--
going-to-an-illegal-
sporting-event tax.
If it's illegal,
how come it's going on?
( bell dinging )
WIMPY:
Ladies and gentlemen!
Citizens of Sweethaven...
Popcorn!
Be careful...
( muttering )
Ooh, watch that step.
Wait a minute.
They're having a lover's quarrel
in front of us.
( bell dinging )
WIMPY:
That unworthiest of worthies...
the pejorator of...
Fight stuff.
Fight stuff!
Now, look at that.
Isn't that...?
Wait a minute.
Yeah... right there,
right there is Castor.
OLIVE:
Castor!
Oh, my son! Castor!
POPEYE:
Make a man outta yourself.
Mom, Pop,
I'm gonna fight him.
Whoops.
NANA:
Don't go!
Oh, it's my baby.
Get out--
Get my baby outta there!
Don't touch his feet!
He's gotta dance
with those feet.
( cheering )
GEEZIL:
Castor, we go home now.
Olive, do something about this.
What are you,
a nut?
What good are you, Olive?
You get in there and get your
brother out of this!
I can't stand much more of this.
( bell dinging )
Where are my pills?
GEEZIL:
Don't do this!
Mr. Geezil,
get him outta there, Geezil!
WIMPY:
Gentlemen, you know the rules:
There are no rules.
This is a fight to the finish.
First man who is dead, loses.
Good luck to both of you.
Did you see what he was doing?!
You didn't see?!
Good luck to you.
GEEZIL:
I hate you to pieces!
All right, come over here.
Now don't,
don't kill him.
Just fluff him up a bit.
( Nana shouts indistinctly )
GEEZIL:
You'll be leading with the left hand.
Castor! Castor, get outta there!
( kiss )
Go for him,
right away, son. ( bell dings )
Come on, Castor.
( taunting indistinctly )
Give him Oyl, Castor!
Give him Oyl!
( woman shouting
encouragement )
( Castor yelling )
NANA:
Come on, hit him, hit him, hit him...!
POPEYE:
Hang him!
Come on, Castor.
Come on, knock him.
( thud )
Oh!
( shouting )
( taunting indistinctly )
WIMPY:
...three, four, five, six...
POPEYE:
Get up!
Your name's Castor,
not Custer.
Come on,
sting that whale!
GEEZIL:
Don't make him mad, Castor.
( yells )
( chuckles nervously )
GEEZIL:
He's not a person!
Hi. I'm, uh... Cas...
( groans )
That's it! Come on, that's it.
Kick him!
Didn't you see that?
Hey, ya bum!
You're a bum.
I'll teaches ya
how to fight fair.
GEEZIL:
He's not a person!
One, two, three...
Oh, hello. Very good.
Very good fight.
...five...
Up, up, up!
POPEYE:
Ya outta get taught how to fight.
( crowd jeering )
I got your numbers!
Ya beached whale.
I'm gonna teach ya...
No, no, no!
No!
( thudding )
( Nana shrieking )
( crowd booing )
( bell dinging )
( gasping, cheering )
Oh. Popeye!
COLE:
Watch out now, Mr. Oxmeat!
You, you, you!
You're gonna be
kissing canvas real soon.
( laughing )
OLIVE:
Oh! Oh!
Poor little fatherless baby.
Oh, you'll be murdered.
WIMPY:
All right, gentlemen, you both know the rules.
This is to be a fight
to the finish.
Touch gloves
and come out fighting.
What are you afraid of?
I got a magnet in
there or something?
( chuckles )
( angry staccato laugh ):
Come on!
You scums.
I know who you...
OLIVE:
That was dirty.
Little birdies-- I think
you're gonna be seeing
real soon.
Be right back, Mom.
I know you will, sonny.
( dinging )
GEEZIL:
All right, here we go.
Now, what were
we thinking
what was before
half thing
on winning ahead
with your mind?
OLIVE:
Give him a karate chop!
GEEZIL:
Very good.
Fist...
that's fighting.
OLIVE:
You can take him!
( Olive laughing )
Don't you dare!
Hey, your mudder's here?
So what?
You bet
I'm his mother. Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
I'm a mudder meself.
That's his mudder;
I can't bust him...
You see?
You're letting his
mother's be distracting you.
Not be doing that.
That kid...
( muttering )
You don't bust him,
he kill you, right?
Yeah, I got it.
Now listen.
Dancing, dancing, dancing.
( Popeye humming )
Dancing, dancing.
Dancing legs.
Be careful.
WOMAN:
Come on, sailor, fight!
OLIVE:
Oh, yeah. Watch it!
To the left. To the right.
Look out.
Easy! Easy!
Watch what you're doing.
OLIVE:
Popeye!
Oh, be careful.
Be careful.
POPEYE:
There.
I gotta ask you...
get your mudders...
outta the ring.
Oh, oh.
The bucket.
Watch it! Watch it!
She's got a bucket!
( yells )
( bucket clattering )
Oh, Mommy!
I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Where do I send the flowers?
( Popeye grunts )
( grunts )
That's it. Come on!
WOMAN:
Give him the old one-two!
POPEYE:
That's one.
That's two...
and three for me.
Timber.
( cheering )
( bell dinging )
POPEYE:
Oh, can't see nuttins.
Oh, there it is.
POPEYE:
Hey, Cap'n Pea.
( chuckles softly )
Look it there, Olives.
He's got my eye.
He does not
have your eyes.
He's got my eyes.
He's got your mouth.
Dizzy dame.
( chuckles softly )
One day, Swee'pea's,
he's gonna go to school
and bust bigger kids
in the mush.
Yeah, you like that,
don't yous? Yeah.
And we'll move
into a vine-covered cottage
on a shady lane.
And we'll garden together,
and we'll play house.
♪ I've been sailin'
'bout the seven seas ♪
♪ Lookin' for somebodys
who would sail with me ♪
♪ Sail with me ♪
♪ And I've been waiting
for someone like you ♪
♪ A man who could love me
and will promise to ♪
♪ Stay with me ♪
♪ Sailing ♪
♪ Sail... ♪
♪ Nothin' feels better
than a rows on the sea ♪
♪ And I can't think of anyone
but you to stay with me ♪
( giggling )
♪ Stay with me ♪
♪ Sail with me ♪
♪ Stay... ♪
♪ With me ♪
♪ Sail... ♪
♪ With... me ♪
♪ Me. ♪
Oh, Popeye.             Shh.
GEEZIL:
What is that glop you're eating?
WIMPY:
It's a soup burger.
These are difficult times.
Burgers can't
be choosers.
Phooey.
Work is what is making
the heart grow stronger. Come.
Open wide.
Bye, Mom.
Ow!
Worry, worry, worry.
( Popeye muttering )
Now... there!
Well, hope the taxes
don't come to too much.
Oh, the main thing is
that you're all right.
Yeah.
Well, were you worried
that I might have gotten killed
or something, maybe, yeah?
Oh, Popeye,
don't be silly.
I knew.
POPEYE:
Oh, you... you didn't have no confidenkce.
OLIVE:
Oh, I did, too.
Mm-hmm, yeah.
I did, too.
After I asked Swee'pea.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
( chuckling )
That's rich.
Oh, you're gone now.
You're really a dizzy dame.
Oh, I asked Swee'pea,
and he told me.
Isn't that so?
( whistling )
What's this here?
See, I asked Swee'pea,
"Swee'pea, will
Popeye be killed?"
Uh-uh.
No?
So then I asked,
"Swee'pea, will Popeye
be seriously maimed?"
( gurgling )
No?
( chuckling )
That's two for two.
That could happen
to anybody, ya know.
So then I queried,
"Swee'pea,
will Popeye
actually survive?"
( whistles )
POPEYE:
Yeah, I survived. Yeah, yeah.
OLIVE:
"What? You mean he'll win?"
( whistles )
Oh!
( Popeye chuckles )
That's-that's a neat trick.
Oh-ho, me infant
is a psychic of profiks.
POPEYE:
If I didn't see it with me own eye,
I wouldn't believe it.
COLE:
That kid's a regular forecaster.
Remind me to ask him
about gold futures.
More interested in talking
to him about immediate futures.
Uh, Popeye?
POPEYE:
Yeah?
WIMPY:
He's an adorable little fellow.
And he's a psychic, too.
Ain't that the truth.
WIMPY:
But he looks a little peaked to me.
He needs some air.
Air? That's all
we have here is air.
WIMPY:
With your permission, Popeye,
I'll... take him
for a little walk.
Well, Wimpy, why not?
I mean, you're
like his uncle.
You're his Uncle Wimp.
( chuckling )
Yeah, that's it.
Come along.
Hey, don't forget
his little hat here.
Don't forget his hat.
He's going out in uniform.
Oh, of course.
There you go.
Thank you.
Ain't that something?
He's taking him
for a walk.
Hey!
Hey, wait a minute there.
You trying to pull a fask one?
He can't walks yet.
Oh, I'll carry him.
Oh, in that case,
it's all right then.
As long as you take him
for a drags or something.
Hey, I want to carry him
for a walk.
Oh, leave
him be there, Olive.
It's Uncle Wimps
going with the Swee'pea.
Oh, yeah, Wimpy can take
him but I can't? Hmm.
Well, um...
wh-who says you can't?
You said I can't. Hmm.
Oh. Well, um...
that was before.
Before what?
Well, um...
before I... I knew
you was worried about me.
Oh!
Oh.
You mean, now
I can carry him
just because I was
worried about you?
Yes. Yes, mm-hmm.
Phooey.
Phooey?
Mm.
Y-You said "phooey"
to me?
I said "phooey"
and I mean "phooey."
Phooey.
She said "phooey" to me.
( laughs )
She said...
"phooey" to me.
( racing trumpet sounding )
WIMPY:
We have Lickety Split, number one.
Number three, Sandcrab.
How 'bout six?
( whistling )
Everything's going
to be all right.
Now, he's with
his Uncle Wimps,
and they've only been gone
for a couple of hours.
Yeah, couple of hours.
Ooh, wait a minute.
This town could have been built
in a couple of hours. Whoo!
Oh, got to be trustworthy.
Wimps is trustworthy.
Wait a minute,
I don't trust him as far as I can throw him.
Throw him?
I can't even lift him.
I don't see them anywhere.
Well, maybe they went
to the Rough House.
No, Wimpy's barred
from the Rough House.
Bad credit.     Right.
Oh, my stars
and horses!
( gasps ):
Derby day?
That rat Wimpy.
What's this got to do
with me Swee'pea?
They've gone
to the races.
A baby at the
horse races.
Where is these races?
Come on. Let's go.
( shouting )
( neighing )
Come on! Come on!
( dinging )
Oh!
( all shouting encouragement )
And the winner is...
Cat's Pajamas.
Yippee!
We've done it.
POPEYE:
Oh, that Wimps.
Abducticating me Swee'pea there.
Oh, a race track
ain't no nurskery.
Oh, patience, patience.
Got to remain calm.
That's it.
Straight ahead.
( lusty whistles )
( door closes )
WOMAN:
Lonesome, chubby?
We've got it. Look.
The Wax Doors and Gardeners?
No.
Number two, Ed.
Ed?
That's a horse.
All right...
number six, Holy Moly.
( whistles )
You like Holy Moly?
( race starting trumpet plays )
Holy Moly?
( giggles )
Holy Moly.
That's it, Holy Moly.
We can't lose.
Everything on Holy Moly.
( starting bell dings )
( shouting )
( horses neighing,
pounding hoofbeats )
( all shouting encouragement )
( neighing )
WIMPY:
Come on, Holy Moly.
Come on,
Holy Moly.
( neighing )
Come on!
Come on... oh,
we're going to win.
Ooh, look.
Hooray!
We've done it!
POPEYE:
Oh, what is this?
A house
of ill repukes?
Ooh, who'd bring me infant
to this den of immoraliky?
Don't touch nothin'. You might
get a venerable disease.
OLIVE:
Oh. Ooh. Ooh!
Is that a bed pole
you got in your pocket, handsome?
Hello. Better grab me loins up
for this one.
Read your paper, Cole.
Will you...?
You know, if Mom caught me
in here she'd kill me.
( gasps ):
There's Mom.
Where is
that Wimpy?
( cash register rings )
Oh!
Pardon me.
Oh! Oh!
Oh, Castor, what
are you doing here?
I've been behind you
all the time.
$110, $120.
POPEYE: There he is.
Wimpy, I'm
disgustapated.
May I borrow the infant
for just a moment here?
Oh, well, yes,
for just a moment.
I don't want your
little sweet peepers
to see what's
about to happen.
SWEE'PEA:
Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
I ought to bust you
right in the mush.
Yeah, what is this?
It's 120 simoleons.
OLIVE:
You won 120 simoleons?
You know how many
hamburgers that is?
Put your eye
where your ear is.
Disgraceful.
How many races?
Two races.
Hmm, let me see
that racing form.
Oh, maybe we can...
Oh, Swee'pea?
We, oh... oh, now...
Wait, no.
No child of mine
is growing up to be
a raceking kout.
Come on, me little...
OLIVE:
Now, wait a minute.
( race starting trumpet plays )
Ooh... oh.
What are you
doing there?
No childs of mine
will be exploiticated
for ill-gotten gains.
Yeah, that's true.
You're going to be a president one day.
It is not ill-gotten,
it's good-gotten gains.
These gains with cloth us
and feed us and save us.
Wrong is wrong even
when it helps you.
The horses are
at the gate.
Oh, family is more important
than dumb morality, hmm.
Oh, look, he's got
something in his eye.
Let me see.
Oh, I know how that feels.
There you go.
OLIVE:
Steven's Wish?
Keep It Going?
Lady Lucy?
Sucking Lemons?
( whistles )
Sucking Lemons!
Oh, what am I?
Some kind of barnacle
on the dinghy of life?
OLIVE:
Oh, make it snappy.
Oh, I ain't no doctors,
but I knows
that I'm losing me patience.
120 simoleons
on Sucking Lemons, please.
What am I?
Some kind of judge or lawyers?
( growling )
Maybe not, but I knows
what law suitks me.
Careful there,
don't ruffle me feathers.
What am I?
I ain't no physcikisk,
but I knows what matters.
What am I?
I'm Popeye, the sailor.
♪ And I yam what I yam what
I yam and I yam what I yam ♪
♪ And that's all that I yam ♪
♪ 'Cause I yam what I yam ♪
( horse whinnies )
You've got it?
I think so, yes.
( hoofbeats pounding )
♪ And I got a lot of muskle,
and I only gots one eye ♪
♪ And I never hurts nobodys,
and I'll never tell a lie ♪
♪ Top to me bottoms
from the bottoms to me top ♪
♪ That's the way it is
till the day that I drop ♪
♪ What am I? ♪
♪ I yam what I yam ♪
( Popeye murmurs,
horse neighs )
♪ I yam what I yam
what I yam what I yam... ♪
Here he comes.
Come on, Sucking Lemon. ♪ What I yam, what I yam ♪
Oh, come on, get up there. Ooh!
POPEYE:
Wondered about meself.
To be or not to be--
who's axskin'?
♪ I can open up an ockean,
I can take a lot of sail ♪
♪ I can lose a lot of waters,
and I'll never have to bail ♪
♪ On the coast of Madagascar,
grab a whale by the tail ♪ Boy, let's go get it.
♪ What am I? ♪
I yam what I yam!
♪ I'm Popeye, the sailor ♪
♪ I'm Popeye,
the sailor ♪
♪ I'm Popeye, the sailor ♪
♪ I yam what I yam,
and that's all that I yam ♪
♪ I yam what I yam
what I yam what I yam ♪
♪ I'm Popeye, the sailor man. ♪
Ha-ha!
Whoo, hoo-hoo!
( singing jibberish )
( laughs )
Arms, don't fail me now.
( instrumental break )
♪ I am what I am
and that's all that I am ♪
♪ I'm Popeye, the sailor man. ♪
( laughs )
Whoo, hoo-hoo!
( shouting and arguing )
( gong clangs, reverberates )
Whoo, hoo-hoo!
( cheering fades )
( Olive weeping )
Oh, I hate to do this,
Swee'pea, but it's neskessary.
Sometimes you got to do things
you don't want to do
when you got to do 'em, but...
NANA:
Oh, it's cruel, Mr. Eye...
It may not make sense now
but maybe later.
...uh, Mr. Pop...
um, Mr. Popeye.
POPEYE:
I'm sorry, Mrs. Oyl,
but it's parenk's duty
to protect me adopticated son
from child abusk.
Oh, oh, but think
of Olive.
You can't take
the poor baby
away from poor Olive.
Me moraliky ain't bilge,
Mrs. Oyl.
Me mind is set,
and when me mind is set,
I don't think
from nothin'.
You sure about that?
Yeah, I think so, yes.
( Swee'pea crying,
Popeye muttering )
COLE:
Maybe we owe him an apology.
We'll find
another place
to plant
ourselves. Yeah.
( Popeye grunts )
Me, I'll check you, okay?
Yeah, you all right there?
This ain't bad, is it?
It ain't the Ritz,
but at least you get
a little womb service here, huh?
( Swee'pea giggles )
POPEYE:
It ain't no palatkial mansion either,
but we got something.
Best I ever saw.
It's got your
blankets here.
Yeah, there we goes.
Got your blankets.
Here we go.
You moved out
of the Oyl's?
None of your business.
$4.25, moving out tax.
Nuts to you,
and nuts to your taxes.
You moved in here?
What's it look like?
$5.25, moving-in tax.
Oh, don't forget
double nuts.
And where's this
baby come from?
Oh, this pelican's
brought him.
89 cents--
unlicensed baby tax.
Oh, get out of here!
Don't take me personal.
Hey, oh-oh, oh, no!
( yelling )
( all cheering )
Hoop... hoop... hoopla!
Did ya see that,
what he did?
A whole lot of peoples.
( Popeye chuckling )
( crowd heckling )
Oh, thank you.
( raucous cheering )
MAN:
Go tax the fishes!
( laughing )
( Swee'pea whimpering )
Swee'pea? Swee'pea? Swee'pea?
Where's Swee'pea?
( stammering ):
Swee'pea!
( Swee'pea crying )
POPEYE ( yelling ):
Where's Swee'pea?!
Swee'pea!
( echoing ):
( wind blowing )
( thunder rumbling softly )
( blowing and rumbling stop )
( wood creaking )
( gentle rattling )
( sighs )
It's me own fault
Swee'pea's been kidnapped.
Olives was right.
Even an orphan needs
a mudder and a fadder.
Oh..
If I was going to
be Swee'pea's mudder,
I should have at least
let her be his fadder.
Ovisk ovisk.
Oh...
I ain't man enough
to be a mudder.
♪ And all at once I knew,
I knew at once ♪
♪ I knew he needed me ♪
♪ Until the day I die, I won't
know why I knew he needed me ♪
♪ It could be fantasy ♪
♪ Oh-oh ♪
♪ Or maybe it's because ♪
♪ He needs me, he needs me,
he needs me, he needs me ♪
♪ He needs me, he needs me ♪
♪ Da-da, da, da, da, da,
da-da, da-da, da ♪
♪ It's like a dime a dance,
I'll take a chance ♪
♪ I will because he needs me ♪
♪ No one ever asked before,
before ♪
♪ Because
they never needed me... ♪
But I do.
But he does!
♪ Maybe it's because
he's so alone ♪
he's never had a home ♪
♪ He needs me, he needs me,
he needs me, he needs me ♪
♪ He needs me, he needs me ♪
♪ For once, for once in life ♪
♪ I finally felt
that someone needed me ♪
♪ And if it turns out real ♪
♪ Then love can turn the wheel ♪
♪ Because he needs me,
he needs me ♪
♪ He needs me, he needs me,
he needs me, he needs me ♪
♪ Da-da, da, da, da, da,
da-da, da-da, dum ♪
da-da, da-da, da. ♪
( horn blowing )
( wood creaking )
( water lapping softly )
( snoring )
( slurping )
( loud belch )
( whimpering )
Bye-bye.
Dear...
Swee'peas.
♪ Everybody's gotta have
somebodys ♪
♪ Even if it's only mes ♪
♪ Stops yer cryin', Swee'peas ♪
♪ And try to go to sleeps ♪
♪ I don't know
hows you got here ♪
♪ I don't knows if you cares ♪
♪ You could've come
from Heavens ♪
♪ Or a typhoon anywhere ♪
♪ Well, me, I came from Heaven
of Cuddly Na-La Lagoon ♪
♪ And I was told me mammy
gave me up in a typhoon ♪
♪ Well, don't you cry,
little Swee'pea ♪
♪ You and me,
we's both the same ♪
♪ And the biggest tear
I ever seen ♪
♪ Came in the eye
of a hurricane ♪
♪ Go to sleep, sleep, sleepy,
now tell me what you sees ♪
♪ And someday when you's older
I'll tell you's all about me. ♪
"Love...
From Popeye."
Oh, oh...
( loud pop )
( clattering )
( Popeye scatting melody )
WIMPY:
Let me see, now...
"Keep out."
Hmm... "Tax shelter."
Uh...
Oh, the Commodore's boat,
but no Commodore, of course.
( gulls cawing )
Aha!
Swee'pea's still
in Sweethaven. Wimpy!
Who are you talking to?
Uh, uh...
What did you say
about Swee'pea?
I said nothing!
Oh!
Oh... but what about... Bluto?
Oh, help, help, oh.
Oh, my, oh!
Oh, oh. Oh dear, oh.
Miss Olive, please help me.
So help me, help me.
G-Get me out.
Phooey!
Not until you tell me
everything you know
about Swee'pea.
I know nothing!
Come clean!
Oh! No!
Oh, no! I confess, I confess!
Yeah, infinks.
Ew! I hates infinks.
The kid's worth a fortune,
Commodore!
Uh, I got all
the fortune
I cares about,
you idiot.
I got me
buried treasure...
and don't you wishes
you knows where it's hid.
( laughs )
Eat your spinach,
you no good infink.
Eat it.
Eat it!
Oh, I can't see anything.
There's no one
home. Let's go.
Wimpy, you come back here
this very minute.
Uh...
Open this door.
It's probably locked.
Open this door!
BLUTO:
Commodore.
PAPPY:
Shh.
( cries )
Don't keep calling me
Commodore...
inside this here harbor.
I got millions o' emenies.
And you is ten or 12 of 'em.
BLUTO:
I call you an old fool.
We could break the bank
at the betting parlor.
This kid can
predict the future.
PAPPY:
I don't want to break the bank in the betting parlora,
you noninticky.
I owns the betting parlora,
and I owns you.
( grunts )
So don't talk to me
about no future.
I hates the future.
And I hates the past.
And I hates the present.
Especially you, yeah.
BLUTO:
All these years I've been loyal mean,
and all these years,
you've been dropping hints
about buried treasure.
You think
that's fair, hmm?
Don't darest say I ain't fair.
True I hates,
but I come by me hating fair...
and square.
Hating's me call.
I will live and die by hating.
( chuckles )
Hate's done me more good
than anything in the world.
( grumbling )
♪ It's not easy bein' me ♪
♪ Masker of me own deskiny ♪
♪ And I hates responsibiliky ♪
♪ Oh, it's not easy bein' me ♪
Shut your lip,
and open your mouth.
♪ Oh, it's hard
to be in charge ♪
♪ Even harder bein' large ♪
♪ But you're charged
when you're in charge ♪
♪ No, it's not easy bein' me ♪
Oh, I hate
you so much! What's as much as a mutiny?
Mutiny!
♪ Oh, it's not easy bein' me ♪
♪ Admiral of me own ship
at sea ♪
I've been scuppered.
Oh, we better
tell Popeye
we found him.
Who?
♪ It's not easy being me ♪
Shh! Everyone.
Come on.
Torpedoed.
I've been torpedoed.
♪ It's not easy
bein' me ♪
♪ The problems
of the large ♪
♪ If ya know
what I mean ♪
♪ He's large,
he's large! ♪
♪ I got me
own destiny ♪
♪ Yo ho, yo ho! ♪
♪ It's not easy
bein' mean! ♪
♪ Sometimes
some things happen ♪
♪ I don't know why anymore ♪
♪ Sometime one time
something happened ♪
♪ I don't know what anymore ♪
( laughs )
♪ It's not easy bein' me ♪
♪ Masker of me own indignity ♪
♪ And it's not the all
or end of me ♪
♪ Still, it's not easy
bein' me ♪
♪ It's not easy bein' me ♪
Me own rope, too.
♪ It's not easy... ♪
( Bluto laughs )
♪ Bein' me... ♪
Hey, you harming Swee'peas?
What?
OLIVE: Oh.
Oh. Shh. No.
You'll break his heart.
Your father.
You found me fadder?
No!
Yes.
Oh.
Oh, you tell him.
Uh...
No, I'll tell him.
Oh, no.
Don't tell him.
Let's don't tell him.
Well, what
did you find?
Me Swee'pea
and me fadder?
Uh, more than that.
You found me
fadder and me Swee'pea. Oh.
Commodore.
Oh, no.
Well, you-you found me fadder,
me Swee'pea and the Commodore.
OLIVE:
Oh. And Captain Bluto.
Oh! Oh, I get it.
No, that's a real cool
joke there.
OLIVE:
Your father is a rat!
Oh.
A crook
and a kidnapper.
And he's on the Commodore's boat
right now
with Bluto and Swee'pea.
That's what I can't tell you.
No, he ain't.
Oh, he is, he is!
No, he ain't,
he ain't. Oh.
And me fadder ain't
no kidnappers.
Oh, he is, too.
He's a rat, a crook,
a kidnapper
and a bad father and more!
No, no, no, no.
More?
Yeah.
Well, it appears that...
your father is the Commodore.
Lies. Lies.
There ain't no
dadblasted treasure.
Kid?
This is a crucial question.
Listen close.
Can you lead me
to the old goat's buried treasure?
PAPPY:
Don't tell him!
You little rat fink...
( annoyed whimper )
He ain't no
Commodores.
A hoity-toity
Commodore.
He would
never be that.
Oh, a rat.
Oh.
A crook.
A kidnapper,
and a Commodore.
I don't listen
to the advice
of some dizzy
gaming broad.
Oh!
No. They ain't there.
And I'm going
to prove it.
Now where
ain't they?
Uh, they ain't
on the Commodore's boat.
That's where
they ain't? Mm-hmm.
Well, if that's
where they ain't,
that's where I'm
going to prove that they ain't.
Oh, come on.
Let's do this.
Oh, Popeye, wait a minute.
ALL:
Go get 'em, Popeye!
My husband has
delegated me
to inform you
that he's behind you.
I'd go with you, Popeye,
but I've a shave
and shampoo awaiting.
KIDS:
Give 'em hell, Popeye!
Kick 'em
in the butt.
You can count
on me, Mr. Popeye,
uh, tomorrow.
See I'd go with you,
but I got to lock up.
WOMAN:
I just hope he doesn't get hurt.
MAN:
I'd go with you, Popeye, but I got us a cold.
You know I'd go with you...
MAN:
I'd go, Popeye,
but the piano man's...
He's coming.
Revolution is waiting.
Oh, are you going?
MAN:
Heard it's impartial.
( whistle blows )
MAN:
I ain't going. Are you going?
Not me.
I ain't going.
MAN #3:
If I wasn't afraid of the water, I'd go.
WOMAN:
Make 'em dance, Popeye.
WOMAN #2:
Almost brought you a bottle of Pepsi.
MAN:
Clean up on 'em, Popeye.
Nauseating.
Don't worry,
I'm going with you,
but good luck.
POPEYE:
Is this where he ain't?
( muttering )
( metal rattling )
Hey, hey.
Come on, you...
Come on. Hey.
Hey.
( frog croaking )
I... I know
you ain't down there.
Truth is, you ain't here...
Now...
where ain't yous?
Where ain't me Swee'peas?
What's that? What? Who?
Pappy?
Pap?
Poppa?
Pa...
Poppa.
I ain't nobody's poppa,
you one-eyed, fish-faced,
sissy-fated, sniffle snaffle.
( chuckles ):
Oh.
I knew it.
( laughs )
Oh, I knew it.
I found yous.
Oh. I hate sentiment.
I am disgustifated.
Ooh. Ooh, nuts to you.
Phooey, phooey, phooey!
Oh, yes, yes.
Oh, Poppa.
Poppa, Poppa, Poppa.
Oh, Pap... fadder.
It's me. It's me.
Your oxspring son.
Stand to, you swab.
Yes, sir.
You're casking shadows
on Poopdeck Pappy.
Pride of the Pacifiric.
And father to the shark.
Brother to the piranhaca.
Cousin to the killer whale.
And uncle to the octopussy.
( nasal whine )
I'm your one and only exspring.
See, we got the same bulgy arms.
No resemblance.
We-we got the same
squinky eye.
What squinky eye?
That's going to be hard
for you to see. Oh.
We got the same pipe, Pap.
You idiot, you can't
inherit a pipe!
Ooh.
I am poppa to no male.
Nor no female child.
That no court could prove
otherwise.
Oh.
Oh, yes.
( laughs )
There's one way to prove
I ain't your fadder.
Pick up that can of spinach.
Pick it up!
Yeah.
Now bring it
over here.
Yeah. Yeah.
Now eat it.
Eat it?
Eat it.
Raw?
Eat it raw.
( muttering )
Eat that spinach.
I don't want to eat...
Eat the spinach,
you brat.
I don't want to eat
that spinach.
Oh!
I don't want to eat that spinach.
I don't want to eat...
( crying like baby )
Eat that spinach!
Oh, you
disobedient brat.
( crying like baby )
You was disobedient
when you was two,
and you're still
disobedient now!
You wouldn't eat
your spinach.
Spinach what kept
our family strong
for thousands of years.
And what does me only
oxspring do with it?
BOTH:
He spits it up.
His mother
ups and dies,
and he wouldn't
eat his spinach.
She choked on it, Pop.
His poppa
out of work,
and he wouldn't
eat his spinach.
It wasn't my fault.
The whole country
in a depressigan.
( nasal whine )
And he wouldn't
eat his spinach.
That was Coolidge, Poppa.
His poppa going hungry.
Going off to steal.
Stealing what?
BOTH:
Spinach.
So his ungrate
son could grow up big and strong.
You know what I done?
You know what I done
when the G man catched me
and thrung me in jail?
No.
Hmm?
I laughed.
Yeah. You laughed?
I laughed a whole year.
( nasal laugh )
( groans )
Cut me down
from this yardarm.
Getting away with that rotten
little insect of a stool pigeon.
Cut you down?
Cut me down!
Cut me down.
Cut you down, cut you down.
Cut me down!
( loud thudding crash )
( nasal groan
and birdies singing )
I, uh, cut you down.
Are you serious?
Well, you said
cut you down.
I didn't say
cut me down.
I said get me down,
get me down.
Oh, oh, unhand me, you brute!
Oh, what are you doing?
What?! Oh!
( shouting )
Come down here,
Bluto!
And don't you ever
pick up another knife.
If you do,
I'll make you eat it.
You'll be known as
the sword-swallowing sailor.
( groaning )
That's me pap.
That's me pap, I know he is.
Oh, what is all this brightness?
I can't see. I-I...
WIMPY:
Oh, Popeye!
All hands on deck.
( shouting over one another )
Come on,
haul ass, haul ass.
They're on the vile body.
Miss Oyl,
that's me fadder.
NANA:
No!
COLE:
Your pappy's a Commodore?!
( bell dings, engine chugging )
( laughing )
Follow me,
get out of here.
He's got him! Bluto's
got Olive and Swee'pea!
Olive? Olive?
Help! Popeye!
Olive! Olive!
Who got me Olive?
I got to get him before
he gets me treasure.
All of you
can commandeer it.
OLIVE:
Help, Popeye!
CASTOR:
The wharf, the wharf is moving.
PAPPY:
Shut up, stupid.
This ain't no wharf.
This is me getaway boat.
I'll punch your head.
( laughing )
PAPPY:
Hoist the main mast.
( shouting )
OLIVE:
Hurry up, Popeye!
You're falling behind!
And Bluto's getting away!
Yeah, with us!
( shrieking ):
Help!
COLE:
What is it?
GEEZIL:
It's a rock.
It's a hard place.
CASTOR:
Oh, no. It's Scab Island.
Mom...
NANA:
Don't worry, Castor.
Your father's with us.
CASTOR:
S-S-S... Scab Island!
PAPPY:
Haul ass!
Haul ass, haul ass.
Get to your stations.
Get to your battle stations.
Oh... oh, phooey!
( bell ringing )
PAPPY:
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Who do you think you
are, Captain Arab?
I'm trying to save
me Olive Oyl and me Swee'peas.
PAPPY:
Olive Oyl? Swee'pea?
What are you doing,
making a salad?
I want me treasure,
do you hear me?
I want me treasure!
I am the Commodore
of this ship,
and don't you
give orders on it!
Oh, yeah? Well,
I'm the Commodore, me friend.
You command this privy,
and I'll commands
me friends.
Is that any way to
talk to your fadder?
You ain't me fadder.
Me fadder was tall
and kind
and looks like
Abraham Lincoln.
Yeah, don't tell
me what I am.
Eh? Where'd he go,
where'd he go?
I says I am your fadder.
I ought to know
whose fadder I is
and whose fadder I ain't.
POPEYE:
Who says?
I said. I said.
I says avast, you bilge rat,
before I use you as an anchor.
Bilge rat, bilge rat,
bilge rat?!
Mutiny, mutiny!
I am your one and only fadder.
Look it, look it--
Eh...
the same bulgy arms.
No resemblance.
Eh, the same squinky eye, eh?
What squinky eye?
The squinky eye.
Help, Popeye! Oh!
We even got, we even
got the same pipe. Look!
( spitting )
This ain't me pipe.
( groaning )
He took the bait.
Eh, I've never seen anything
like this before in me life.
Talking to your
poor old fadder like that.
You disobedient brat.
You're spoiled--
that's what you are-- spoiled.
Children. Children. Kids.
Eh, phooey!
Phooey!
Give them everything they want,
and what'd you get in return?
Nothing, nothing.
Nothing but heartache,
heartache, sadness, and miserky.
And a bad time, once in a while,
when you try to give them a
bath, and they don't want it.
And another bad time
when you want to do something
that you really want to do,
but all they want to do
is not what you want to do.
Bless their little hearts.
If they were
really made out of gold,
I'd like to sell them
on the open marketplace.
I could make me a fortune.
I could've
made us a fortune. Kids!
Eh, they don't
know what they're doing.
Kids, dadblast 'em!
They're gonna lead you to ruin.
That's what they gonna do.
Lead you to ruin.
They cry at you
when they're young,
they yell at you
when they're older,
they borrow from yous
when they're middle-aged,
and they leave you
alone to die...
without even paying you back!
Children. Phooey!
( horn sounding )
You give them
everything they want,
and what do you
get back in return?
You gets nothing!
Catch him like
a big, fat lobster.
Why, they're just smaller
versions of us, you know.
Well, I'm not
so crazy about me in the first place.
So why do I want
one of them?
I'm asking you.
Children.
Ah, children.
Little children.
You'll pour
your heart out to them,
you give them
everything they want,
give them candy,
and a lot of toys,
and what do you get back?
You get a lot of noise.
( singsongy ):
Nah-nah-nah-nah, nah, nah.
My poppa's a mean old man!
( horn sounding )
I'm through with children.
I'm through with kids.
There ain't nothing
I'm never gonna do about it.
POPEYE:
There it is, Pap, we's got 'em cornered.
( cheering )
Dad blast
that dirty bilge rat!
You! You, with
that crazy beard,
get that fat guy up here.
Come up here.
Get up here, get up here.
OLIVE:
Help! Oh! Help me!
POPEYE:
There she is!
PAPPY:
Haul ass, haul ass.
Get the cannon and move it here.
Come on, haul ass,
haul ass, haul ass.
Get the cannon
and move it here.
In a good position, that's it.
POPEYE:
What are you doing?
You can't fire that thing.
There's women and infants
on that boat.
PAPPY:
You stop worrying.
All I'm gonna do
is fire a warning shot
right across
the bow.
Don't you thinks
I knows what I'm doing?
Ah, short, short.
I was a little short.
A little short?
Reload it, reload it.
Reload it.
No, you don't.
Dadblast it! I missed!
( laughing and cheering )
Full speed ahead.
Slow down, Pap,
so we can board her.
We're not
gonna board her.
I'm gonna ram him.
He's not going to get away
with my treasure.
POPEYE:
Me Olive and me Swee'pea is on that boat!
( horn tooting )
( gurgling )
( Swee'pea whimpering )
Ha, ha. Pirate's Cove.
I should've known it.
All right, Mr. Mean.
Oh, 'cause that's gonna be your
name from this day forward!
Yeah, well, you've
broken your bail of straws
on this camel's back,
and just to think
that I was ever gonna get
engaged to you again!
Oh, nevermore, I say.
Nevermore!
GEEZIL:
Get the water out of the boat!
PAPPY:
Lower the lifeboats. All women first.
Get the water out of the boat!
CASTOR:
Portly men first!
( shouting )
( screaming )
Oh, shit!
( babbling )
Now, listen, kid,
this is the most important.
Is the treasure underwater?
OLIVE:
Oh!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You'd better let me
out of here.
Okay, kid,
you watch the boat.
I'm going in.
Oh! Phooey. Oh!
Oh... oh...
Wait a minute!
Where do you think
you're going? ( loud splash )
( groaning )
CASTOR:
We're almost there!
COLE:
We're almost where?
Get me out of here.
Oh, I'm all wet.
Oh!
Oh, there's fish in here.
( low, rumbling growl )
Oh.
Popeye, help!
Olives!
Oh, that's it.
Help!
Uh-oh.
GEEZIL:
Land ho!
Go get him, son.
CASTOR:
Oh, he's a submarine.
He thinks he's a submarine.
Popeye!
Nana?
( gurgling )
GEEZIL:
Pirates. There's pirates.
NANA:
Oh!
( sinister laughter )
Bluto!
Hey, that's my treasure,
you runt.
What goes down...
must come up.
Bluto!
OLIVE:
Ah, you're in trouble now!
( Bluto growling )
Even though you're
larger than me,
you can't wins,
'cause you're bad,
and the good always
wins over the bad.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah!
ALL:
One... two... three!
OLIVE:
Oh, help.
Help! Popeye!
Hey! Who, what, where, why,
when? What is this?
Hey, where...?
I think we owe him an apology.
Your intentions
were good, yeah.
Oh!
Good night, Irene.
Haul ass, haul ass!
I got to get that treasure.
Now, where is it, where is it?
It must be down there some...
oh!
There it is, there it
is! You, Undertaker,
Undertaker,
get over here.
That's me. I'll
undertake that.
Get over here, get over here.
Come on, get
on this rope. Get on this rope.
Ah, that rotten
little infink's looking at me treasure.
Look at it.
Come on, pull it up.
Come on--
pirate's booties.
Ha-ha! He ain't
gonna get it.
He ain't
Heave! Heave!
I think I'm going to!
( panting )
( growling )
( shuddering grunt )
Look out! Popeye, no, oh!
Open it!
Get away,
get away, get away!
( growling )
OLIVE:
Help!
Oh, I can't see a thing!
( crashing )
( groaning )
OLIVE:
Help! Help!
Popeye!
Oh, oh, thanks!
Whoops!
So, it's a
sword you need,
is it, you
little runt?
Yeah.
( growling )
You won't be needing that,
will yous?
Watch him, Popeye. Yeah?
Allez-hut, hut, hut, hut!
Hey!
Popeye!
Oh!
( low, rumbling growl )
Bubble.
( whimpering )
Whoa!
( cries out )
OLIVE:
Oh, oh, octopus, octopus!
Help! Help!
Oh, Popeye!
Uh... it is an octopussy.
Help! Help!
Oh, I'm going
to save that kid.
I'm going to save him.
( crying )
PAPPY:
Hands off!
Hands off
that kid, you!
Help! Popeye!
Help! Help! Oh!
Help, oh, help!
Hook him, hook him.
( crying )
Oh, oh...
Oh, oh!
Oh, Swee'pea! Oh!
( Wimpy laughing )
Hoopla, hoopla.
OLIVE:
Oh! Oh, ooh! Oh...
Oh, who is that down there?
Whoa, oh, don't get fresh.
Oh. Oh...
( Bluto grunting and growling )
( laughing ):
I'm going to show you
the treasure chest now,
little one.
Here we gonna...
Oh, boy,
look, whoa!
( chuckling )
Here.
Oh, yes, yes.
Oh, he's got a little...
( laughing )
Isn't that cute?
OLIVE:
Popeye!
( alarmed exclamations )
Dancing, dancing, outside.
Keep your head!
WIMPY:
Look out!
( both chuckling )
( low, rumbling growl )
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Oh, help! Oh...
( gargling )
( groaning )
Help! Help!
Popeye! Popeye!
Oh...!
PAPPY:
Ah, you sissy faded sniffle snaffle!
If you'd eaten your spinach
like I told you,
you wouldn't be losing
this fight.
I ain't gonna eat no spinach.
I ain't losing.
Oh! Help!
You disobedient brat.
Here, eat this spinach.
( Swee'pea laughing )
Bull's-eye!
Help!
( screaming )
I-I-I...
Oh, yeah?
Oh, yeah.
You don't like spinach?
I hates it.
Yeah.
( laughing )
Eat this spinach.
Eat, eat.
( choking )
( laughing )
( grunting )
See you in Davy
Jones' locker.
( laughing )
Now, my treasure!
Sound the charge, kid.
( Swee'pea blowing horn )
( rumbling )
( Popeye's theme playing )
Help!
Help! Oh!
Oh!
( laughing )
Look at Bluto!
Look at that!
Bluto's
turned yellow!
♪ 'Fraidy cat,
'fraidy cat! ♪
Good riddance to bad garbage.
Oh, Popeye!
-♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
-Oh, my hero!
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ He's strong to the finish
'cause he eats his spinach ♪
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ Oh, I'm Popeye,
the sailor man ♪
♪ I'm Popeye, the sailor man, ♪
♪ I'm strong to the finish
'cause I eats me spinach ♪
♪ I'm Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man,
he's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ He's strong to the finish
'cause he eats his spinach ♪
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ I'm one tough gazookas
that hates all palookas ♪
♪ That ain't
on the up and square ♪
♪ I biffs 'em and buffs 'em,
and always outroughs 'em ♪
♪ And none of 'em gets nowhere ♪
♪ If anyone guesses
to risk his fisk ♪
♪ It's buff and it's wham,
understands? ♪
♪ So keep good behavior,
that's your one lifesaver ♪
♪ With Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man,
he's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
POPEYE:
Chicken of the seas, yeah.
♪ He's strong to the finish
'cause he eats his spinach ♪
♪ He's Popeye, the sailor man ♪
♪ Popeye ♪
♪ Popeye, the sailor man. ♪
SWEE'PEA:
Popeye. Choo-choo!
Captioning sponsored by
PARAMOUNT PICTURES
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org