SIMBA: Everything the light
touches is part of our kingdom.
The Pride Lands.
Ruling it is a big responsibility, Kiara.
And someday, when you're Queen...
KION: Heads up! Incoming!
- (GRUNTS)
- Kion!
Oh! (CHUCKLES) Sorry, Dad.
Me and Bunga were playing Baobab Ball...
And Kion couldn't handle the pass!
What? A giraffe couldn't handle it.
You kicked it over my head!
- Kion!
- And you couldn't handle it!
- Bunga...
- Yeah? Try to handle this!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
Boys!
Whoa!
Kion, I need to talk to your sister.
She'll be tracking gazelles
with her friends today.
(CHUCKLES) Because I'm training to be...
Queen of the Pride Lands. Yeah, yeah.
I know all about it, Kiara.
(SCOFFS) Least I have my life figured out.
What are you gonna grow
up to be, little brother?
Happy?
All right, you two, that's enough.
Kion, why don't you
and Bunga go play somewhere else?
BUNGA: Yeah! I know the perfect place!
Hey, Kion!
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
You'll never get the baobab fruit, no.
- (CONTINUES SINGING)
- Ha! You got nowhere to go, Bunga!
Says you! Zuka Zama!
(LAUGHS)
Catch me if you can, Kion!
Game on, Bunga!
Later, Dad.
Have fun tracking those gazelle, Kiara.
I gotta get Bunga!
(SIGHS) I can't believe we're related.
Kion will grow up someday. I hope.
(SINGING) It's a good day
to have some fun to run and play
CHORUS: Whoa-ay-oh
(BUNGA LAUGHING)
Sun's so hot, it melts my worries all away
CHORUS: Whoa-ay-oh
I'm gonna take it easy,
Got no reason to work all day
CHORUS: Whoa-ay-oh
Oh, yeah!
I'm gonna keep on smiling,
Keep on riding all the way
CHORUS: Whoa-ay-oh
Come on, I'll tell ya
(CHORUS SINGING)
(GASPS)
Everyone! Scatter!
Whoa
Come play with me and we'll run free
Through the Pride Lands
up to the highest tree
- Whoa
- (LAUGHING)
Gotta live for fun
It's the only way
It's a beautiful
It's a beautiful day
Bunga. Kion.
It's a beautiful
It's a beautiful day
- (GROWLS)
- Yow!
(GROANS)
Whoa
Come play with me and we'll run free
Through the Pride Lands
up to the highest tree
Whoa
Gotta live for fun
It's the only way
It's a beautiful
It's a beautiful day
Gotcha now, Bunga!
Not yet! Cheka, cheka, cheka!
(CHUCKLES) Stop it! Bunga!
Got it! Whoa!
Aww. It rolled into the Outlands.
Game over.
Says who? I'm not afraid of the Outlands.
Neither am I! It's just... My dad!
- He says we shouldn't...
- Oh! Please!
Simba's a big old scaredy cat
when it comes to the Outlands.
You know what my uncles always say!
Hakuna matata.
Whoa! Huh?
Bunga? (SCOFFS) You look a little stuck.
You kidding? It's just a tree branch.
Uh...
Zuka Zama!
(GRUNTS)
Now where did that baobab fruit go?
(GROWLING)
Oh! Afraid there's no meat
left for you boys.
(WHINING)
Janja, Janja! A baobab fruit!
Let's eat it! I'm starvelated!
What do you take me for, a vegetarian?
I want something nice and meaty for lunch!
Something...
Huh? Where'd it go?
(LAUGHING)
What? What's so funny?
What are you laughing at? Tell me!
Stuff it, fur brains! Look...
A honey badger.
(SLURPS)
Now that's my idea of a delightful lunch.
(GROWLING)
Chungu! Cheezi! Bring him to me!
Yeah, boss!
Here we go!
Heyvi kabisa.
Bunga! Heads up!
Relax, Kion. Remember?
- Hakuna...
- (SNARLING)
Matata.
Get outta there, Bunga!
Okay, hyena.
You wanna see what this
honey badger's made of?
I'll show you what I'm made of!
(HYENAS LAUGHING)
Hey! Lemme go so I can show that
other guy what I'm made of!
Hyenas! Put Bunga down!
Pick on somebody your own size!
Kion! You want the honey badger?
Come and get him!
Let him go!
You hyenas don't want
any trouble with my dad.
Ooh. Like how you'd get into trouble
if you came into the Outlands?
(LAUGHS)
Uh, Kion?
He's too afraid to come down here.
Yeah! 'Fraidy cat!
BOTH:
'Fraidy cat! 'Fraidy cat! 'Fraidy cat!
All right, yeah. Fun's over.
Janja needs his lunch.
Lunch?
No!
Let him...
(ROARS)
See ya, hyena! Wouldn't wanna be ya!
Heyvi kabisa!
What was that?
Zuka Zama!
Kion, how'd you roar like that?
I don't know, Bunga.
Wish I did, though.
Well however you did it,
it was un-Bunga-Iievable!
That was Kion's roar?
(LAUGHS)
Yes, Nala, yes!
He is ready! It is time!
Eh, no, Rafiki. He can't possibly be
ready. He's still a cub.
Simba, Simba. You heard the roar!
I heard it. It's just...
It's a big responsibility.
I need more time to prepare him.
I think you've just run out of time Simba.
You need to tell him.
But, Nala...
Listen to Rafiki, Simba.
Kion is ready. It is time.
KION: Time for what?
Dad? Rafiki? What's going on?
Son, we need to talk.
Oh, no. Dad, we already had that talk.
(SINGING) Can you feel the love tonight...
I know all about that mushy stuff!
(LAUGHS) I... Well... (CLEARS THROAT)
It's not that, Kion.
No, no. Most definitely not that.
We have heard your roar! Yes, yes!
Yeah. It was, uh, kind of different today.
Different? Different, you say?
(CHUCKLES)
It is more than different.
It is the Roar of the Elders!
When you use it,
the great lions
of the Pride Lands' past roar with you.
What? You mean that's what
happened to my roar?
Yeah, lions in the sky! I saw that!
The Roar of the Elders
is a great gift, Kion.
It will make you the fiercest
animal in the Pride Lands.
- But...
- But what?
No, no, Simba.
It is you who must tell Kion
about the Lion Guard.
The Lion Guard? What's that?
This way, Kion.
Uh, okay.
Oh, come on, Rafiki.
You already know what it is, don'cha?
Come on, tell me.
Huh?
It's a bunch of vines?
Rafiki?
Whoa!
Look at that!
How did I not know this was here?
Dad, what is this place?
This is the Lion Guard Lair.
It's the secret meeting place for
the members of the Lion Guard.
Ugh! Maybe they should think
about fixin' the place up.
(COUGHS) Or at least doing some dusting.
Hmm. Yes.
(CHUCKLES)
Ah! That's more like it.
Can you show that trick
to my Uncle Timon and Uncle Pumbaa?
(CHUCKLES)
Dad, enough with all the secrecy stuff!
You gotta tell me.
What is the Lion Guard?
The Lion Guard is the team
that protects the Pride Lands
and defends the Circle of Life.
According to tradition, the Lion Guard is
made of the Pride Lands'
fiercest, bravest,
fastest, strongest, and keenest of sight.
So what happened to them?
It looks like
they haven't been in here since forever!
I'm afraid it's a story
without a happy ending.
- Whoa!
SIMBA: When your grandfather
Mufasa was about your age,
his younger brother, Scar,
was leader of the Lion Guard.
Scaralso had the gift of the Roar.
The Roar made Scar feel powerful.
But that power went to Scar's head.
He began to think that he should be king,
instead of his older brother, Mufasa.
So Scar ordered the Lion Guard to help
him take down Mufasa.
When the Guard refused,
Scar was furious.
And then, Scar used the Roar
to destroy the Lion Guard.
What Scar didn't realise
was that by using the Roar for evil,
he would lose the power
of the Roar completely.
Heyvi kabisa.
Yeah.
The Roar is a very powerful gift.
It can be used for great good.
But it can also lead to terrible evil.
Well, I'd never be like Scar. Ever!
I'm glad to hear that, son.
Because starting today,
you are the leader of the new Lion Guard.
I'm the what?
You heard Simba! Ha-ha!
The leader of the new Lion Guard?
It is you!
Yes! It. Is. You!
Dad?
It's true, Kion.
Wow. Amazing!
It is. And now,
as the leader of the Guard,
I need you to assemble
the Pride Lands' bravest,
fastest, strongest, and keenest of sight.
Okay, Dad. Got it!
Don't worry. I'm gonna make you proud!
Yes, Bunga?
This is un-Bunga-Iievable!
You see, Simba?
And now, Kion will choose the best lions
in the Pride for the Guard.
I hope so, Rafiki.
I'm still not sure he's ready.
(BIRDS CAWING)
Wow! Me. Leader of the Lion Guard...
Protectors of the Pride Lands!
It's kinda scary.
- BUNGA: Hey, Kion.
- Huh?
Kion!
Ergh! Bunga!
Ready to start assembling the Lion Guard?
Huh? Now? Yeah? Huh?
Yes! Argh!
Just stop splashing me!
Splashing?
Oh. (CHUCKLES) Sorry, Kion.
Hakuna matata, Bunga. Now, come on!
Time to assemble the Lion Guard!
Lion Guard?
Hmm.
Dad said the Lion Guard needs
the Pride Lands' bravest,
strongest, fastest, and keenest of sight.
So I think I'll go ask the bravest
animal in the Pride Lands first.
Kion, wait!
Before you go asking
whoever you think is the bravest,
think about this...
I might not be the biggest honey badger.
But I know what's in my heart.
And I'm not afraid of anything or anyone!
I know, Bunga. That's why...
I'll help the Lion Guard fight hyenas.
Or jackals, or crocodiles, or vultures!
Vultures?
Or great big rock slides
or wild fires or floods!
I will stand with
the Lion Guard! I'll never give up!
I'll, I'll...
Why don't you stop talking
so I can ask you to join the Lion Guard?
Say what?
Come on, Bunga!
You're the bravest animal I know!
I want you to be
the first to join the new Lion Guard.
Zuka Zama!
Zuka Zama, indeed.
I wonder if Janja knows
about the Lion Guard.
You couldn't have made a better choice.
We're gonna make a great team!
I can't wait
to tell Uncle Timon and Uncle Pumbaa.
(PANICKED SCREAM IN DISTANCE)
Kion! Do you hear that?
ZURI: (STRAINING) A little help?
Sounds like Kiara's friend, Zuri.
And she needs help.
Our help!
It's our first adventure!
Lion Guard to the rescue!
Lion Guard to the rescue?
Hey! Bunga, wait up!
Hold still, Zuri. Timon and Pumbaa
said they know how to help.
(WHINING) Where am I gonna go, Tiifu?
I'm stuck.
(SIGHS) You wouldn't be stuck
if you didn't keep stopping to sharpen
your claws on every other tree.
But Kiara, if I don't
keep them sharp, they don't stay shiny!
TIMON: Don't worry, ladies.
Me and Pumbaa have
everything under control.
Timon's right.
We used to help Simba
get his claws out of logs all the time.
And you're sure about this?
Sure, I'm sure.
If it weren't for us, your dad would still
be stuck to a tree somewhere.
- Ready, Pumbaa?
- Ready!
Okay, on three.
One... Two...
BUNGA: Stand back, Pride Landers!
Bunga of the Lion Guard is here!
What!
- Bunga!
- (ZURI GASPS)
Ow! My claw!
- Whoa!
- (LOUD CRASH)
(ZURI SCREAMING)
Creepy crawly bugs!
- (BUZZING)
- Ew!
Zuri, you hit the jackpot!
It's a smorgasbord!
(MUNCHING)
Hang on, Zuri! I'll save you!
Okay, Bunga.
You've done enough saving for one day.
Bunga, I... Whoa.
What's going on?
Oh! I broke a claw!
It hurts!
There, there, Zuri.
You're gonna be just fine.
Oh, hey, Kiara.
How'd the gazelle tracking go?
(SIGHS) We never got to the gazelles.
Zuri got her claws stuck in a tree.
(LAUGHS) And then she fell face first
into a log full of bugs!
Mmm!
Bugs are so gross.
Mmm.
And so delicious.
Ooh, look.
- Another one.
- (SCREAMS)
Get it, get it away!
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Ow, my paw!
(SOBBING)
Hey, everyone. Everyone. Listen to this!
Simba just put Kion
in charge of the new Lion Guard!
Lion Guard?
What's a Lion Guard?
Dad just told me about it.
The Lion Guard is the team
that protects the Pride Lands
and defends the Circle of Life.
And I'm its new leader.
I'm gonna be on the Lion Guard, too.
It's un-Bunga-Iievable!
(CHUCKLES) You and Bunga?
Protecting the Pride Lands?
Does Dad know about this?
Dad told me to assemble
the Pride Lands' best.
And I'm the best. Just ask me.
Well, if you ask me,
it sounds like it might be dangerous.
It's worse than that, Pumbaa.
It sounds like work.
Yeah! It's both!
Eek... Work!
Gee, Bunga. I don't know...
Uncle Pumbaa, Uncle Timon, please?
Work? Danger? Definitely not.
Have you forgotten our
problem-free philosophy?
It means no worries...
I know it's not
Hakuna matata, Uncle Timon.
It's... It's Zuka Zama!
Zuka Zama?
Don't ask!
What's Zuka Zama?
What's Zuka Zama? What's Zuka Zama?
I'll tell you all about Zuka Zama!
You had to ask.
(SINGING) Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Zuka Zama
Life's exciting, life is fun
Zom zom zom
A big adventure for everyone
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Life's a party
and it's filled with thrills
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Don't worry about the scrapes and spills
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
- Pop up, pop up...
- Zuka Zuka
- Dive in, dive in
- Zama Zama
- Go, go, go
- Zom zom zom
Flyin' through the trees
like a busy, busy bee going
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Now you know my little motto for life
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Enjoy the chaos
Ignore the strife
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
When life throws you a crazy curve
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Go Zuka Zama
Don't lose your nerve
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
- Pop up, pop up
- Zuka Zuka
- Dive in, dive in
- Zama Zama
- Go, go, go
- Zom zom zom
Flyin' through the trees
like a busy, busy bee going
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
- Pop up, pop up
- Zuka Zuka
- Dive in, dive in
- Zama Zama
- Go, go, go
- Zom zom zom
Like a bee, like a bee
Like a busy, busy bee going
Zuka Zama
Zom zom zom
Ah! Zuka palooka.
I still don't think Bunga should be
signing up for some jungle patrol.
- Lion Guard!
- Whatever you call it.
Timon, Pumbaa, please.
I really do need Bunga on the Lion Guard.
He's the bravest animal I know.
Bravest animal you know?
He's brave, all right.
Brave bordering on stupid.
Thanks, Kiara!
Well, when you put it that way...
Congratulations, Bunga!
We always knew you had it in you!
Oh, brother!
Kion's gonna wreck the Pride Lands
before I even get to be Queen.
Oh, Bunga. I'm so proud, I could...
(BREAKS WIND)
Oops.
Sorry.
Zuri, let's get you back to Pride Rock.
We're outta here!
I better go assemble the rest of my team.
Wait, Kion! The Lion Guard
needs to stick together!
Was it something I said?
Janja, I'm hungry!
Me, too!
You two only have yourselves to blame.
To think that you were scared
by the roar of a lion cub!
Janja, see, Kion's roar...
It wasn't like, like a normal roar.
It was, uh... (NERVOUS LAUGH)
Super loud!
And the clouds!
They turned into roaring lions!
Oh! So you're scared of clouds, too?
(LAUGHING)
Stuff it, fur brains!
Seems we have a visitor
to our humble, humid den.
Janja. Hyenas.
Mzingo! What are you doing
this far into the Outlands?
Looking for leftovers?
No, but I'd be happy to eat...
Forget it. We don't have any.
Simba's cub, Kion,
managed to cancel our lunch plans.
(LAUGHING)
Then you already know about Kion.
Know what?
Simba has told Kion
to assemble a new Lion Guard.
Lion Guard? That's impossible.
The Lion Guard died out after Scar...
Unless...
(STAMMERS) Janja?
The Roar. Of course!
Of course, what?
Don't you know the stories?
The Lion Guard was legendary.
The most powerful team
of lions in the Pride Lands.
At least they were... (SNICKERING)
Until Scar destroyed them!
(LAUGHING)
What? A lion destroyed the Lion Guard?
Or so the story goes.
Ha-ha-ha! Hilarious!
Yeah! Them lions ain't too bright!
Stuff it, fur brains!
A new Lion Guard
could be very bad news for us hyenas.
And all the other Outlanders.
I gathered as much
from what I overheard from Kion.
Yes. The old Lion Guard
protected the so-called
Circle of Life.
If Kion's new Lion Guard wins
the trust of the Pride Lands,
we Outlanders will...
(GROWLS)
(HYENAS LAUGHING)
Now, Janja. What were you saying
about the Lion Guard and the Outlanders?
I was saying,
with a Lion Guard
patrolling the Pride Lands,
it will be next to impossible
for us Outlanders
to take whatever animals we want for food.
Then what are we gonna do?
Ooh, we could eat each other.
No, we'll strike now,
before the Lion Guard is ready.
And we'll take down
all the animals we can.
Mmm. I like the sound of that.
Whole herds of animals!
- Yeah, right!
- Tasty!
Tonight, we Outlanders will feast.
Hyenas and vultures alike!
Tonight, we strike!
(LAUGHING)
(SINGING) When you live in the Outlands
It's better to make your own rules
Ask anyone outside the Pride Lands
The Circle of Life is for fools
(VOCALISING)
We go where we want when we want to
And we eat
Yes, we eat as we please
That Kion can't give us a curfew
Or tell us to stay in the trees
Tonight, we strike
No one's safe
So the time is right
The Circle of Life's gonna feel our bite
Tonight, we strike
(VOCALISING)
So before this new Guard is ready
To defend the Pride Lands from harm
We'll make them all feel unsteady
We'll give them cause for alarm
Tonight, we strike
No one's safe
So the time is right
The Circle of Life's gonna feel our bite
Tonight, we strike
(LAUGHING)
All right, fellas, bring it in.
Here's the plan.
While the animals are in their slumber
We'll be creeping beneath
And just like a roaring thunder
We will wake them up with our teeth
Tonight, we strike
No one's safe
So the time is right
The Circle of Life's gonna feel our bite
Tonight, we strike
- Tonight, we strike
- Tonight, we strike!
No one's safe
So the time is right
Nobody is safe!
The Circle of Life's gonna feel our bite
Tonight, we strike
Outlanders, arise and follow me!
The Pride Lands will never
know what bit them!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
Target in sight.
Dive!
Hey, Ono!
(GRUNTS) Whoa!
Oh. Hi, Kion.
Good to see you.
You see just about everything, Ono.
That's why I want to talk.
ALL: (CHANTING) Beshte! Beshte! Beshte!
Hey, everybody! Who wants a water slide?
- Ooh, yeah!
- Me, me!
Do it, Beshte!
Poa. One water slide, coming up!
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
(GRUNTS)
ALL: Yay!
Yeah!
(LAUGHS)
Strongest?
(BLOWS RASPBERRIES) Strongest.
Also wettest.
- Aah!
- Ono!
Fuli, wait! Kion wants to talk!
Not now, Bunga. I gotta run.
What? Why?
(PANTING) That's why.
(SCREECHING)
Oh.
I see Fuli's a bit occupied.
Even I can see that, Ono.
But I have an idea.
Whoo!
Huwezi!
You can't catch me!
Fuli! This way!
Fuli! Jump!
Beshte! Now!
Nice save, Beshte.
(PANTING) Totally. Thanks.
And as for you guys, I said I'm sorry!
I wasn't trying to be mean when I said
you look funny when
you scratch your heads.
Apology accepted.
(ALL GROAN)
Hey, guys. Thanks for meeting with me.
I wanted to talk to you because...
Well, I need your help.
What's the kerbubble, Kion?
The five of us are
the Pride Lands' fiercest,
bravest, strongest, fastest
and keenest of sight.
And that's why I want you all to join
the new Lion Guard.
Together, we'll protect the Pride Lands
and defend the Circle of Life.
(WHISTLES)
Well, lick my tail and call me a meerkat!
Hey! My uncle's a meerkat!
No offence, Bunga.
Wait! Aren't you a honey badger?
A Lion Guard?
Figures.
Always the lions lording
over the Pride Lands.
I suppose Simba put you in charge
of this little team, Kion?
You bet your spots he did!
Fuli, the Lion Guard needs you.
You're the Pride Lands' fastest.
You got that right.
And you're supposed to be the fiercest?
Well, he is a lion.
And lions are fierce.
It's kinda common knowledge, really.
Show 'em the Roar, Kion.
Show 'em the Roar!
What's Bunga talking about? The Roar?
You think you're somethin' special
just 'cause you can roar?
Wait 'till you hear it. C'mon, Kion.
Show 'em the Roar!
So what is the deal with your roar?
Oh, you totally have to show us, Kion.
Seeing is believing!
Though with a roar,
it's more about hearing.
Okay, fine. I'll show you the Roar.
Just, uh, stay behind me.
I don't want anybody to get hurt.
- Excuse me.
- Watch it!
Pfft. Groundlings.
Ready?
Okay. This is the Roar...
(TINY SQUEAK)
What in the Pride Lands...
That was... Different.
(LAUGHS) Kion!
You call that a roar? (CHUCKLES)
Didn't sound like a roar.
That wasn't the Roar! That was a squeak!
I've found him, Your Highness!
Kion is over here!
See, Dad? What did I tell you?
Thank you, Kiara.
You and Tiifu go ahead
and track the gazelle.
I need to talk with Kion. Alone.
Yes, Dad.
Thank you, princess.
Dad! Am I glad to see you!
I'm not sure why, but when I tried to...
Kion, Kiara tells me you've asked
Bunga to join the Lion Guard.
Hey.
Is this true?
Well, yeah.
I was just talking to
all my friends about it.
Your friends?
Kion, I asked you to assemble
the new Lion Guard.
Instead you're just
playing with your friends?
I'm not playing, Dad.
My friends are the new Lion Guard.
Fuli is the fastest.
Beshte is the strongest.
Ono is the keenest of sight.
And the bravest, it's Bunga.
Kion, the Lion Guard
has always been made of lions.
Do you really
think a Lion Guard with only one lion
can protect the Pride Lands?
Well, actually...
Son, listen.
The Lion Guard isn't
a game you play with your friends.
It's real.
The Circle of Life, and your life,
will depend on who's on your team.
Please, Kion.
There are plenty of
good lions for the Guard.
I need you to take your
new responsibility seriously.
Just as seriously as Kiara takes hers.
But I do take it seriously.
Kion...
Little B, I think Kion needs
some time to himself.
KIARA: Be sure to stay low
while we're tracking the herd.
And we need stay downwind,
so they don't catch our scent.
That's why it's important
to watch how the grass moves.
Are we going to attack them?
No. My dad says we should only
take what the pride needs,
to keep the Circle of Life in balance.
If we took down gazelles
just to learn how to do it,
pretty soon there wouldn't be any left.
Then we'd be as bad as the hyenas.
(GASPS)
What's Mzingo doing up there?
Vultures only circle like that
when they're expecting to eat.
Kiara, look!
KIARA: Hyenas. And Janja's leading them.
TIIFU: There's so many of them!
Yeah. And with Mzingo
circling over the gazelles,
I have a feeling they're up to no good.
What are we going to do?
Go find my dad
and tell him Janja and his clan are here.
I'll stay here and keep watch.
Okay, Kiara. Be careful!
Dad wanted the best for the Lion Guard.
And I found them.
But now, maybe the best isn't good enough?
I just don't understand.
(SINGING) Why?
Why even trust me at all?
They say the Guard is my call
But then come tell me I'm wrong
Now what
What should I do?
And who
Who do I turn to?
Now everything feels so upside down
Deep down, maybe I knew
It was way too good to be true
With all my friends looking up to me
Some leader I turned out to be
Kion!
Heyvi kabisa. Are you...
Yes, Kion. I am your grandfather.
Mufasa.
I've heard a lot about you.
And I've been watching you.
You are about to embark
on a great journey, Kion,
leader of the Lion Guard!
I'm not sure Dad's
gonna let me lead the Lion Guard.
He's worried that I can't handle it.
Kion.
Simba is worried.
But he's worried because he loves you.
Being leader of the Lion Guard
will not always be easy.
Then maybe Dad's right.
Maybe I'm not ready to lead.
Or use the Roar.
I'm not even sure I can control it!
First, it's super loud.
Then it's just a squeak.
And I...
I don't want to end up like Scar.
Don't be afraid, Kion.
Trust your instincts.
The Roar will be there
for you when you need it.
And so will I.
Until the Pride Lands' end.
Grandfather Mufasa. Don't go yet.
Trust my instincts.
The Roar will be there when I need it.
Maybe my journey is far from done
They need a leader and I'm the one
So now it's time for them all to see
The Lion I was born to be
It is time
To take the lead on my own
It is time for
something bigger than I've ever known
No need to wonder
The choice is done
Now I believe I'm truly am the one
So is it time?
Is it time?
Yes.
It is time
Kion! Kion! Janja! The hyenas!
They're attacking the gazelles!
What? Oh, no!
Mzingo's telling the hyenas
which one to target next.
Smart, in a devious sort of way.
I don't get it.
They've already scored a couple gazelles.
That should be plenty for all of them.
Yeah. Why are they still attacking?
Janja and his clan will keep going
until the whole herd is dead.
- What?
- No.
Don't they understand the Circle of Life?
They don't care about the Circle of Life.
They're not hunting for food.
They want to throw
the Pride Lands into chaos.
And it's up to the Lion Guard
to stop them!
The Lion Guard?
You mean us?
What about what Simba said?
So what if we're not all lions?
I know we're the Pride Lands'
fiercest, bravest,
fastest, strongest, and keenest of sight!
- That's true.
- Of course we are.
I guess?
Yeah! Let's go get those stinkin' hyenas!
Hold it, Bunga. This isn't a game.
We need a plan to take on the hyenas.
And I think I have one.
That is, if the rest
of you are ready to join the Lion Guard.
I'm in.
Ditto.
Lay it on us, Kion.
Bunga...
(ROAR)
You are the bravest!
Fuli.
(ROAR)
You are the fastest.
Ono.
(ROAR)
You are the keenest of sight.
Beshte.
(ROAR)
You are the strongest.
We are the Lion Guard.
And here's what we're going to do.
(SIGHS) What's taking Tiifu so long?
Dad needs to stop this!
What?
Till the Pride Lands' end,
Lion Guard defend!
(ROAR)
Zuka Zama!
(HYENA EXCLAIMS)
Aagh!
Looking for something, feather neck?
Ooh.
Huwezi! Nowhere to run
that I can't run faster!
(SURPRISED SHOUTS)
(GROWLING)
See what I mean?
(EXCLAIMING)
(FULI CHUCKLING)
That's right! Keep going!
Comin' thru!
And, Beshte! Now!
Outta the way!
Twende Kiboko!
(LOUD CRASH)
Simba, Nala, look!
(HYENAS YELPING)
RAFIKI: Kion's Lion Guard! (LAUGHS)
They have Janja and the hyenas on the run!
That's our boy!
(GASPS) But the herd!
It's charging right towards Kiara!
- Oh, no!
- Kiara!
Agh! Help!
Kion! Kiara's hurt!
Okay. We need to get to her fast.
I'm the fastest there is.
But what do I do once I'm there?
Just get me close!
I'll take it from there.
- Bunga?
- Don't worry, Kion.
This time, yours truly has a plan!
Okay. Hurry.
This way!
Zuka Zama!
Kiara's trapped behind that rock.
Uhh, I can't get any closer.
Then this is where I get off!
Hang on, Kiara!
Whoo! Ha ha!
Ahhh!
Zuka Zama!
Bunga? Have you lost your mind?
Never had one, Kiara!
Now, if you don't mind...
Scram ya, goofy gazelles!
Take this!
(HISSING)
Uncle Pumbaa taught me that one.
(COUGHS) Thanks, Bunga.
You might be stinky,
but you sure are brave.
Kion! Bunga and Fuli did it!
Kiara's safe!
Great! Have them
regroup with us at the edge of the field.
It's time to give Janja and his hyenas
something to remember.
- Mom! Dad!
- Kiara!
You're safe.
I might not be if it weren't
for Kion and his friends.
I guess he knew what he was
doing when he picked them.
He did, didn't he?
Look! Look!
Well, if it isn't Kion the lion cub.
You and your friends better leave now,
before you get hurt.
We're the Lion Guard, Janja.
We defend the Circle of Life.
You and your kind are not
welcome in the Pride Lands.
Ever!
(ROARS LOUDLY)
(HYENAS SHOUTING)
Zuka Zama! Now that's the Roar!
Oh!
Did you hear that?
Kion.
Whoa.
(YELPING)
You win today, Kion.
Next time won't be so easy.
See, Simba? You see?
Huh?
He is ready! It is time!
- Simba?
- Yes.
Kion is ready.
It is time.
SIMBA: Time for the Lion Guard.
(SINGING) There's a time in life
when you may get a great calling
And it seems so big at times
you feel like you may be falling
If you believe in who you are
there's no need to go running
You found a place with your friends
The adventures keep on coming
(CHORUS VOCALISING)
For the Pride Lands
They're united
The Roaris on guard
Last time it was Simba
Looking after the Pride Lands
Staying strong and united
And no matter where we stand
We'll never be divided
Roar of the lions in the sky
Always keeping a watchful eye
Fierce, fast and brave and strong
Look out
Here comes the Lion Guard
(CHORUS VOCALISING)
Look out
Here comes the Lion Guard