(Upbeat, jazzy rock music)
Knock it off, Tina.
I'd lay off the booze, Tina.
You've had enough.
Today, Tina and alcohol are
gonna have a great cocktail.
Look, you booze it all you want
But you better lay off me.
You better stand on your feet
Because if you fall on your face,
I'm not gonna pick you up.
You understand?
When did you ever have to carry me home?
I've always been able to
stand on my own two feet.
I never needed you,
And I never will.
Say, whatever happened to campus big-shot
That'd do anything for kicks?
Campus big-shot's grown up.
Times have changed, Tina.
We're not a buch of kids anymore.
I've got plans.
You can do all the partying you want.
You better stay out of my way.
Stop preaching.
I know about your plans.
Your experiments in that laboratory.
Well, let me tell you something,
I have a few experiments of my own
I'm just itching to try,
And they don't have one thing to do
With test tubes and bunsen burners.
Okay, Tina if that's what you want.
(Gasps)
Oh, Hank, what's happening to us?
So when are you gonna
get it through your head
That life isn't just all fun and games?
Okay, okay, no more lectures.
We're not even talking
the same language anymore.
All right if that's the way you want it,
Then you just go on your way,
And I'll go mine.
We'll see who gets the most out of life.
Oh, brother, you ain't seen livin'
'Til you've seen Tina swing.
(Steamboat horn blowing)
(Water rushing)
We're coming to the spot now.
When we get about there, gimme a yell.
Okay, now.
Okay, Boss.
(Water splashes)
(Water gurgles)
(Barrel thuds)
(Foreboding music)
(High-pitched tones)
(Intense, chaotic music)
(Foreboding music)
(Water bubbling)
(Intense, chaotic music)
(Upbeat music)
♫ Ring-da-da-da-ding, doo-de, bop bop
♫ Turn on the ignition
♫ For this expedition
♫ Ring-da-da-ding, doo-de, bop bop
♫ Find me a baby
♫ Oh my, oh why
♫ I sure think ♫
Hey that reminds me, did
I bring my hotdog buns?
♫ Gonna get some wheels see how it feels
♫ To fly on down the road
♫ Gonna get some wheel see how it feels
♫ Make a left, make a
right, down the cotton side
♫ We'll fly on down the road
♫ Let's fly ♫
(Crowd cheering)
♫ Fasten up your seatbelt
♫ Ring-da-da-da-ding, doo-de, bop bop
♫ It'll do your treat melt
♫ 20, 40, 60, 80
♫ How fast can we go ♫
(Music drown out by motorbikes)
♫ Make a left, make a
right, down the cotton side
♫ We'll fly on down the road
♫ Signal for a right turn
♫ Ring-da-da-da-ding, doo-de, bop bop
♫ Signal for a left turn
♫ Oh my, here's a traffic circle
♫ How far can we go?
♫ Gonna get some wheels, see how it feels
♫ To fly on down the road
♫ Make a left, make a
right, down the cotton side
♫ And fly on down the road.
♫ Let us celebrate some
♫ Ring-da-da-da-ding, doo-de, bop bop
♫ 'Fore this little crate's gone.
♫ 80, 90, gosh-all-mighty
♫ How fast can we go
♫ Gonna get some wheels,
♫ See how it feels
♫ To fly, fly, fly, fly
♫ Gonna get some wheels
♫ See how it feels
♫ To fly, fly, fly
♫ Hang on tight, baby
♫ It's all right, baby
♫ Here we go, go, go, go, go, go
♫ Go baby, go baby, go baby, Go!
♫ Do you hear a siren
♫ Ring-da-da-da-ding, doo-de, bop bop
♫ Funny little siren
♫ Joyride's over, no more clover
♫ Off to jail we go
♫ Bye-bye bunny
♫ Joyride's ending
♫ Bye-bye license
♫ Your suspended
♫ Bye, bye, bye, bye ♫
(Children playing)
Johnny, I never let anyone
kiss me like this before.
My name's not Johnny.
What is it?
Irving!
Irving? (Laughs)
What's in a name?
(People chattering)
(seagulls squawking)
(Water splashing)
(Monster groaning)
Hank.
Elaine, kinda shook me up there.
You always go around
sneaking up on people?
Well I saw you just
staring out at the ocean,
So I thought I'd come
down and talk to you.
♫ Everybody get
♫ to the dance floor now
♫ Oh, yeah
♫ We gonna cut loose now
♫ Well, yeah, everybody's
♫ Doin' it, doin' it,
♫ Doin' it, doin' it
♫ Do now ♫
Daddy thinks quite a
bit of you, you know,
Thinks you have a great future.
Working with Dr. Gavin has been
Just about the greatest thing
That's ever happened to me, Elaine.
But I still have this problem with Tina.
She's always on my mind.
Oh, I'm sure Tina will come around
To your way of thinking.
She's bound to realize
what she has in you, Hank.
Well, we'll see.
♫ Just a wigglin' and wobblin'
♫ Well, come on, come on, come on, come on
♫ Shake it, shake it, shake it, shake it,
♫ Shake it, shake it now
♫ Just a wiggle and a wobbilin'
♫ Yeah, Whoa
♫ Isn't anything like
shoutin', little Jimmy
♫ Oh no, no, no, no, no, no, no
♫ Isn't anything like doin' the holy goin'
♫ Isn't anything like mashed potato
♫ I said no, no, no, no, no, no, no
♫ What's, hey, stoppin', hey
♫ I know, hey, I'm not
♫ Wiggle wobble
♫ Oh, yeah
♫ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
♫ Wiggle, wiggle
♫ Wobble, wobble
♫ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
♫ Wiggle, wiggle
♫ Wobble, wobble
♫ Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle
and a wigglin' and wobblin'
♫ Yeah, come on, do
it, do it, do it, do it
♫ Do it now ♫
Hey, what's going on up there?
I don't know, let's go see.
♫ Shake it, baby, shake it now
♫ Just a wigglin' and wobblin'
♫ And a what's, hey, stoppin', hey
♫ I know, hey, I'm not
♫ Wiggle wobble
♫ Oh, yeah
♫ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
♫ Wiggle, wiggle
♫ Wobble, wobble
♫ Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
♫ Wiggle, wiggle
♫ Wobble, wobble
♫ Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle
and a wigglin' and wobblin'
♫ Do it, do it, do it, do it ♫
What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
♫ Just a wigglin' and a wobblin'
♫ Yeah, come on, come on, come on, come on
♫ Shake it, shake it, shake it, shake it ♫
(Foreboding music)
She doesn't want to go with you.
Look, I don't think
that's any of your business.
(Fists thudding)
(Body pounding into ground)
(Crowd yelling)
(Anxious music)
(Fists thudding)
[Hank] Ow!
(Crowd shouting)
Hank, I, I, think that we should
[Man in Hat] Come on Mike.
Come on Mike, let's get out.
(Children playing)
(Water splashing)
(Upbeat, beachy rock music)
♫ Ahhhhhhh
♫ Woooooo
♫ Oh, everybody do the zombie stomp
♫ Just slam your foot
down with awful thump
♫ You reach out further and further
♫ Get me closer, get me closer
♫ Baby, baby don't be scared
♫ 'Cause I'm standin'
here lookin' kinda weird ♫
(Water splashing)
♫ Well, everybody do the zombie stomp
♫ Just slam your foot
down with an awful thump
♫ You reach out further, further
♫ Get me closer, get me closer
♫ Honey, I'm no Frankenstein
♫ Oh, yeah baby, we'll be awfully fine ♫
(Foreboding music drowning out beach band)
♫ Oh, everybody do the zombie stomp
♫ Just slam your foot
down with an awful thump
♫ You reach out further, further
♫ Get me closer, get me closer ♫
(Foreboding music drowning out beach band)
♫ Spook it up the whole night through
♫ Oh, everybody do the zombie stomp
♫ Just slam your foot
down with an awful thump
♫ You reach out further, further
♫ Get me closer, get me closer
♫ Oh everybody do the zombie stomp
♫ Just slam your foot
down with an awful thump ♫
(Foreboding music drowning out beach band)
(Monster growling)
(Frightened shrieking)
(Intense, chaotic music)
♫ The zombie stomp is fun to do
♫ Come along and do the zombie, too.
♫ Spook it up the whole night through ♫
Do you believe that
kissing is unhealthy?
I don't know I've never been...
You've never been kissed?
No, I've never been sick.
♫ You reach out further, further
♫ Get me closer, get me ♫
(Water splashing)
♫ If I don't have you
♫ Elaine
♫ Well, that's my baby's name
♫ I don't know if she loves me
♫ But I love her just the same
♫ What good is a man
♫ Without a woman
♫ And what good am I ♫
Hiya, Charlie.
Do you like bathing beauties?
I don't know, I never bathed one?
(Laughter)
(Woman screaming)
(Crowd murmuring)
(Gasps)
(Reel clicking)
Well, what happened to her?
Hit and run or something?
That's, uhm, why we called you, sir.
It was no accident.
She was found that way at Painter's Point.
Some kids were having a party,
She wondered off,
10 minutes later she was dead.
Uh-huh, the papers have it?
The Daily Herald has wind of it.
There's a reporter out there now,
Muttering about sea
monsters, that sort of thing.
Any statements?
My men questioned everyone at the party.
They all gave the same story.
They think something came out of the sea.
Ridiculous.
That's what I thought, Lieutenant.
Whoever did this couldn't
have come over by land,
Musta come from the sea.
Maybe a while shark or something?
Any blood smears?
We're running the standard tests
Uh, Gavin, Doctor Gavin.
Get him to work on this.
(Siren wailing)
Morning.
Morning
Nice morning.
Looks like a clear day.
I was just looking at that little cloud
Up there by the sun and
thinking it might rain.
I guess everybody interprets the world
According to his own mood. (Laughs)
Well, no weather's good for a funeral.
In my business I try to avoid them.
Elaine, it's 9:30.
I guess she'd be abnormal,
if she were on time.
How's she taking it?
It's not easy for any of us.
A lot of families have
been affected by this.
Helps her to know she's not alone.
Here's the sample that you asked for.
I'm gonna run some carbon-14
tests on this tissue.
There have been some recent discoveries
In the field of genetics,
That may give us a clue to its structure.
Good luck, Doctor.
Thanks, Bye.
(Sirens wailing)
Oh, you're ready.
You do understand why I'm not going,
Don't you, dear?
Of course, Daddy.
Everybody knows how hard
you've been working.
You gonna pick up Hank on the way?
Yes.
Oh, Daddy, I'm so upset about Hank.
Here I am, going to Tina's funeral,
And I have such feelings about him.
What kind of feelings?
I don't know!
Is it because he's free now?
Yes, I suppose so.
You go ahead, dear.
I'll get to work.
(Engine revving)
It's a human thing, Dr. Gavin.
It's a human, evil thing,
lurking and creeping
Crawling around out there, in the night.
I know it, I feel it.
You mustn't talk like that.
A great deal of the ocean
is still a mystery to us.
There are undoubtedly forms of life
That we know nothing about.
It's that voodoo, that's what it is.
Now that's ridiculous, Eulabelle.
I want you to get this idea
of voodoo out of your head.
I have no doubt we'll find
a perfectly reasonable
Explanation for the girl's death.
Maybe you right,
But the police have been looking
And they haven't found anything.
They been running around
here like head-less chickens.
And you been looking and
reading, and what have you found?
Nothing is solved in a few hours.
This'll require a lot of research.
And while you're researching,
There's something creeping
and crawling and lurking
Around out there.
That's enough!
It's the voodoo, that's what it is.
You better go to bed, Eulabelle.
Did you lock up?
Locked, double locked,
and triple locked.
Ain't no monsters gonna
get in here tonight.
It's the voodoo, all right.
[Elaine] Hi, Daddy.
Hello, dear.
I thought you were going out tonight?
Oh, I was, but it's just
another slumber party.
They're all the same so I'm
not really missing anything.
Did you let 'em know you weren't coming?
No.
Don't you think you should?
Oh, Daddy, I just don't
see how you can even think
Of such a thing after
what happened to Tina.
Tina's death has affected
a great many people,
But it doesn't give you or anyone else
The right to be discourteous.
Oh, all right, I'll go telephone.
(Laughter)
Okay
(Telephone ringing)
[Voiceover] Shhhh!
Hello.
It's for Livvie
Livvy, it's for you.
[All] Livvy (giggling)
Hi.
Hi, Elaine.
Where are you?
Why?
Oh, Elaine, you're gonna miss all the fun.
Oh, Elaine, we've got secret information
That the boys from the Kya
Psi House are gonna crash.
We've gotta big bucket
rigged up over the door.
I can't wait to see Ricky Oeder's
As he comes through the door
and gets it spilled on him.
Oh, Elaine, please come.
It'll be so much fun.
Well, okay.
All right.
I understand.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Livvie.
I'm glad I called, Daddy.
It was the right thing to do.
♫ Oh, that is the fortune
♫ Of all woman-kind
♫ They're always controlled ♫
(Foreboding music drowns out singing)
♫ Controlled by their parents
♫ Until they are wives
♫ Then slaves to their husbands ♫
(Foreboding music drowns out singing)
♫ Always been courted
♫ By the Wagoner's lad
♫ He courted me daily
♫ By night and by day ♫
(Foreboding music drowns out singing)
♫ And going away ♫
(Foreboding music)
(Laughter)
Shhh, what was that!
Come on.
[Voiceover] What are they doing?
[Voiceover] I smell something awful.
Smells like dead fish.
[Voiceover] Ew, I hope
they don't throw fish again.
Like they did last year.
[Voiceover] Shhh, quiet girls.
Everybody keep quiet,
I'll turn off the lights.
Okay, boys, the door's open!
(Giggling)
(Anxious, chaotic music)
(Girls screaming)
(monsters groaning)
(Monsters growling)
Rumors from an invasion from the sea
Took on a new dimension last night,
When over 20 teenage girls
were brutally attacked
And murdered during a slumber party.
A survivor described
these monsters differently
From those which terrorized the beach
Only a few days ago.
But Dr. Gavin, special
consultant for the Police,
Suggested that these beings
probably have different forms,
In the same way that human
beings vary in size and shape.
Meanwhile, specialists from
all over the United States
Converged on our city in an attempt
To piece together the
scattered reports of attacks
In a massive effort to
find out the identity
Of these strange creatures from the sea.
[Paperboy] Extra,
extra, read all about it!
Extra, extra, read all about it!
[Voiceover] Thank you.
Listen, we better skip this town.
This is place where they're
having all the trouble.
Cops?
No, murders, by the hundreds.
Some kind of monsters, killing people,
And drinking their blood.
Ewww, it give me the creeps.
Imagine being that thirsty.
Oh, very funny, Miss Ghoul.
I read all about it in the papers.
This town's too hot for my blood.
Well you know what I mean.
Listen girls, I need some gas.
We better stop and we'll
get some directions, too.
(Brakes squeaking)
Yes, ma'am.
Can I help ya?
He's cute, isn't he?
Fill me up, huh.
[Man] Sure.
(Gas pump humming and dinging)
Say, what's this I hear
about all these murders
You've been having around here?
Oh yeah, it's a big deal.
They gotta big investigation going on now.
They got guys coming up here
from Washington and everything.
Hey, we better get outta here, girls.
You aren't kidding.
Hey, handsome,
What's the fastest way to get to New York?
Well I guess the best
way is to go down here
To Wiremill Road, and you turn left,
And go two blocks over, and uh,
Then you turn right and
you go past the quarry,
And uh, you'll see the throughway
right on the other side,
You can't miss it.
Thanks, how much do I owe ya?
That's four dollars, please.
Thanks, honey.
[Man] You're welcome.
Turn left, turn left.
Look at this route.
I can't look, stupid.
I'm driving.
You wanna crack us up?
(Engine humming)
[Driver] Here we go, New York or bust.
[Voiceover] (laughs) Oh, yeah.
This is a road?
(Tire hissing)
Oh great, a flat tire.
[Voiceover] Now what'll we do?
Hey, where you been?
Paul needs help with the wheel.
Down by that quarry.
Somethin' musta died in there.
It smells like the food n' fish market
In the middle of July.
(Foreboding music)
How's it goin', hun?
Well I got it off,
but I can't see nothin'.
How 'bout some help.
Okay.
Hey, hold it, you two.
What's with you?
I heard something.
(Foreboding music)
Oh, if it ain't money
rustlin', it ain't worth hearing.
Shhh, hold it, I hear something, too.
Sounds like somebody,
Somebody big, walking in mud.
You two flipped your wigs or somethin'?
There's that fishy smell again.
I think I'll go take a look around, girls.
(Growling and screaming)
(Music box chiming)
(vacuum humming)
I've had my share of the
misery, too, Miss Elaine,
And I know what it is.
Three brothers and two sisters,
All dead and gone.
But you don't see me goin' around
Moanin' and groanin' all day.
I have my work, and the Lord has his,
And he takes care of us, wherever we are.
Why what's this, Eulabelle?
Oh, that's mine.
Give it to me.
It's a voodoo doll, isn't it?
You really believe in it.
Now, don't you go teasing, Miss Elaine.
I know a lot more things than I say.
Eulabelle, there's no
such thing as voodoo.
Who is it anyway?
One of them zombies.
Dr. Gavin was so worried,
I thought I could help.
Well, somebody's got to do something.
(Doorbell chimes)
Hello, Mr. Hank, come in.
[Hank] Hello, Eulabelle.
Here's that nice young boy,
Just pining to take you out.
Now, quit your moanin' and groanin'
And go out and have some fun.
Probably didn't need me
this afternoon, Elaine.
Well, I thought, maybe you'd
like to go for a drive,
Or something.
Oh, I don't know, Hank.
Now, go on upstairs and change.
He'll wait.
[Hank] Look, I don't mind waiting.
You go ahead and change.
All right.
(Engine humming)
Why did you come back
to the beach, Hank?
I don't know, Elaine.
I had a funny feeling about this place.
Come on, let's go.
(People chattering)
Hey man, what's happenin'?
How ya doing, gang?
Pretty dead tonight, huh Ron?
Yeah, ever since Tina got killed
Like, no action around here.
Yeah, well, it'll pick up.
[Both] Take it easy.
Ron, what are you gonna play?
What'd you like to hear, Elaine?
How 'bout, mmmm,
You're not a Summer Love?
Mmm, just for you, baby.
Hi.
Excuse me, Hank.
Sure, go ahead.
♫ Summer love, summer love
♫ You are not a summer love
♫ To be mine, to be mine
♫ To be mine, forever.
♫ You are not a summer love
♫ Oh, my darling, darling, darling
♫ Promise to love me ever
♫ I say, forever
♫ That you will be, endlessly
♫ Close to me
♫ Like the sand and the sea
♫ Summer love, summer love
♫ Not a summer love
♫ I'll be true, I'll be true
♫ To you, forever
♫ Darling, I'm no summer love.
♫ Oh, my darling
♫ Tell me, tell me
♫ You'll be mine forever
♫ Summer love, summer love
♫ Love me forever
♫ I say, forever
♫ That you will be
♫ Endlessly, close to me
♫ Like the sand and the sea
♫ Summer love, summer love
♫ I'm not a summer love
♫ I'll be true, I'll be true
♫ To you, forever.
♫ Darling, I'm no summer love
♫ Oh my darling
♫ Tell me, tell me
♫ You'll be mine forever
♫ Summer love, summer love
♫ Leave me, never.
♫ Leave me, never ♫
(Crickets chirping)
Goodnight, girls.
Now you go straight home.
My brother's coming to pick us up.
Good night, now.
[Girls] Goodnight, Johnny.
(Foreboding music)
He's not coming, let's walk.
[Voiceover] No I think the...
[Voiceover] Where'd you get that?
[Voiceover] No I think that
pink would be well for her,
But it's not always the best color.
Not which I love it, to think about,
But what can you do?
[Voiceover] No I like him
But he's not the greatest
thing in the world.
[Voiceover] Cold
[Voiceover] No, well, he's not.
[Voiceover] Yeah, but my mother took it,
Well I knew a guy who did that
But it didn't do any good at all
[Voiceover] You got a cat?
[Voiceover] And it was much easier.
(Horn honking)
Come on, girls.
(Monster growling)
(Foreboding music)
(Static hissing)
(Intense, chaotic music)
(Glass shattering)
(Monster groaning)
[Elaine] It's still alive.
I wanna make some notes.
Yes, sir.
April 10th, 7pm.
Notes on possible malignant organism.
Overall configuration,
that of a human arm,
Severed just below the elbow joint.
Muscle tissue seems to be a sea anemone,
Species of protozoa.
These organs are exactly
like human organs,
Except for they have been
replaced by the protozoans.
Of course, this creature
needs the ordinary necessities
Of human life.
Proteins, fats, sugars, and so forth.
But since his organs are so decomposed
That they can neither produce nor retain
The oxygen necessary for its survival,
It needs the only food
which can keep it alive.
Blood?
Human blood.
If a human body, a drowned person,
Were attacked by tiny sea plants,
Which became parasites and completely...
Dead?
No, he's still alive.
But it's changed into a...
Well, is it a plant or an animal?
It's both?
It's a giant protozoa.
Dr. Gavin, can they be killed?
I don't know, Lieutenant.
They are the living dead.
They're zombies
Nothing so dramatic as that, Elaine.
They're more like a jelly fish.
You can't kill 'em by shooting
them or cutting them up.
Well, then how can you kill them?
Shhh.
(Foreboding music)
I hear something.
There's something out there.
I know there is.
All right now everybody
just keep calm and be quiet.
The gun won't help you.
Here, take these knives.
They're all we have.
Elaine, over there in that corner.
Lieutenant when I say,
"lights," turn them on.
I'll take care of this one.
Lights!
Eulabelle!
Oh, (laughs)
What are all of you doin'
Sneakin' and peakin' in the dark.
I'm afraid you gave us quite a scare.
Oh, I'm sorry Dr. Gavin.
But it so quiet up there in the house.
And I get scared by myself,
all alone, at night.
And them zombies they
coming at me tonight.
I just know they will.
(Screaming)
(Specimen popping and hissing)
Look it's burning up.
Eulabelle you've killed it.
Oh, Dr. Gavin, I'm
sorry, I didn't mean...
Don't be sorry, this is wonderful.
You've discovered a way to
destroy these creatures.
Oh, Lord, Lord.
Look, completely dehydrated.
Protozoans are almost all water.
This is all we have left.
But what makes all the
smoke and steam, Daddy?
Sodium.
Plain old sodium.
Hank, you remember your chemistry.
Sodium is a very unstable metal
That reacts violently with water.
That's right.
Then they can be killed, with sodium.
They can, if we can find them.
(Muffled upbeat music)
Same to you, fella!
What about that guy, huh?
We are unwanted.
Outcasts.
Orphan of the storm.
What storm?
The storm of my soul.
Right.
Where do we go now?
We'll drive
Are you cape-ab-able of driving?
Of course I'm cape-ab-able.
Are you cape-ab-able.
Of course, I am.
Where's the car.
That a way.
(Men drunkenly whooping)
I'll get my car.
Yeah, you wait here, I'll get my car.
(Engine revving)
(Metal crunching)
Hey, buddy.
I guess weren't cape-ab-ab-able.
(Hysterical laughing)
Let's walk.
Hey, lead the way.
(Hysterical laughing)
Woowee!
Hey.
Yeah.
What's that sound?
(Laughter) It's you.
No, it's you.
(Foreboding music)
Let's hear you walk.
No, it's not you.
Now you walk.
It's not you either.
Hey.
What's it sound like?
It sounds like somebody in rubbers,
Filled with water.
You wearin' rubbers?
No.
Me neither.
It's probably, probably somebody
Came from the swimming pool,
And came from swimming with their,
With their shoes and socks on.
(Laughing)
That's not so funny.
It's probably some old drunk.
God, I hate drunks.
Hey Stan, look.
Truck.
They left their lights on.
Yeah.
Well, we better go turn 'em off.
Yeah, save his battery,
for heaven's sake.
Hey, Stan, there's a guy in here.
(Laughing)
Hey buddy.
(Laughs) What are you doing, sleeping?
Oh, buddy.
(Laughing)
Hey, hey, hey, buddy, buddy.
(Intense, chaotic music)
Stan.
Hey Stan, this guy ain't got no face.
Hey, Stan!
Hey Stan, where are ya?
Hey Stan!
Stan, don't play these
games on me like this.
Stan!
Hey, don't eat me!
(Crying)
(Monsters growling)
(Man gurgling)
Because of this recent discovery,
The police now feel certain
that in a very short time,
A method will be found
to locate and destroy
These frightful monsters.
Extra, extra read all about it!
(Woman screaming)
(monster growling)
(Siren wailing)
[Hank] Dr. Gavin, look.
(Static crackling)
Scale 15
The water from that arm is radioactive.
That means the cells
themselves are radiated.
But how?
Floating pig.
The what?
Oh, the floating pig,
That's what we call the garbage scow
That leaves the harbor every week.
You see it's been dumping,
Waste material from the
reactor at the University.
Do you know where they dump?
See a friend of mine
says he saw them once out
At Western Island, I believe.
Western Island, Western Island.
There it is.
Look at these currents, Hank.
If one of those containers sprung a leak,
The waste would be drawn
right by our shore,
And that's where Tina was
killed that first night.
Western Island is also where
that fishing boat went down
Just a few weeks ago.
These creatures are human bodies,
Kept alive by radioactive decay.
So, wherever they go they
leave radioactive water.
So all we have to do is to test the water
To know where they've been.
Right, then we can tell where they are.
At this minute, wherever they are,
They're building up a small, and harmless,
Radioactive residue in
the surrounding water.
Our geiger counters will
give a scale 15 reaction
To that water, so...
So, what we have to do
is just test all the water
In the immediate area,
And if they're in one of those lakes,
Well, we'll get a scale reading
from the counter, right?
Right!
I'll call the police.
We'll organize and get all the people
In the countryside to help us.
Then all we have to do is find them,
And sodium will kill them.
All right, Dr. Gavin.
Say, Dr. Gavin we don't
know how many there are.
We might need tons of it.
You get on the phone
And call every chemical
supply company in the area.
Someone must carry sodium
in large quantities.
I'll call Lieutenant Wells
and get this thing started.
If we're quick, we may stop these monsters
Before another night of killing.
Right, Dr. Gavin.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Now these are instructions
and map coordinates.
Break up into separate teams.
Each team is to organize a
search in that specific area.
There are a limited
number of geiger counters,
But more are being
brought up from New York,
So don't worry about it,
You'll have them by the
end of the afternoon.
I want you to find every single
body of water in your area.
And be sure it's tested.
You've got to be sure that
those things haven't been there.
Let's get going.
(Exciting, lively music)
(Water trickling)
[Eulabelle] How's it going, Mr. Hank?
Oh, it's no use, Eulabelle.
Nobody has any sodium.
They all get their
supply from special order
From New York City.
Did you try everybody
in the telephone book?
Yeah, almost, all but a couple.
Well you try that couple.
You've got to try, Mr. Hank.
Well, go on!
All right, Eulabelle.
I'll call New York City.
Hello Operator, would
you please get the uh,
Manhattan Chemical Supply
Company in New York City.
That's right.
Hello.
Listen, do you carry any sodium?
That's right, the metal.
You do?
Well, listen, do you have a lot of it?
Well, will you hang onto it for me?
Hank Green.
Yeah, that's right
All right, I'll be there in about an hour.
(Jazzy rock music)
[Eulabelle] Oh, afternoon, Dr. Gavin.
Afternoon.
I saw ya coming so I
brought ya some coffee.
Oh, good, thank you.
Any luck with your
water testing, Dr. Gavin?
Absolutely no luck.
I must've tested at least 10
places and didn't find a thing.
Well, Mr. Hank found that
chemical, whatchya call it.
[Dr. Gavin] Oh, good.
And he's gone on to New York to get it,
But he won't get back before dark.
And Elaine, where's Elaine?
Well, she's gone on too, Dr. Gavin.
I think she mentioned Fingle's Quarry.
Fingle's quarry?
Yes, sir.
Good God, why didn't I this before.
That's the deepest body
of water around here.
And it's right where those
three girls were killed.
Oh.
When Hank gets here,
Tell him I've gone to Fingle's quarry.
Yes, sir.
And call the police, and
tell them to meet me there.
Yes, sir.
(Engine humming)
(Breaks squeaking)
(Leaves crunching underfoot)
(Engine revving)
(Engine humming)
[Voiceover] Calling car 28,
Pick up Hank Green.
He is coming east on route 104
In gray MG and proceed
to Fingle's quarry, over.
Will do, immediately.
(Engine humming)
(Birds cawing)
(Static hissing)
(Foreboding music)
(Elaine screaming)
(Intense, chaotic music)
(Engine humming)
[Policeman] Are you Hank Green?
That's right.
Just follow me.
(Siren wailing)
(engines revving)
(Intense, chaotic music)
(Elaine screaming)
(Sirens wailing)
(Engine humming)
(Monsters growling)
(Elaine moaning)
(monsters growling)
[Dr. Gavin] Elaine!
[Elaine] Daddy, hurry
up, you gotta help me!
Oh my God!
(Sodium popping and hissing)
(Monsters groaning)
(Sirens wailing)
(Thunderous roaring)
(Explosions popping, hissing)
(monsters growling)
(Low tones)
(Elaine moaning)
[Voiceover] Please relay
the following information
Please relay the following
information to territorial
(Speaker downed out by moaning)
At this time,
However, these streets are not blocked.
These streets are not blocked.
(Birds chirping)
(Soft, melodic music)
[Eulabelle] Oh, Mr. Hank, come in.
Hello Eulabelle.
Say is Miss Elaine receiving today?
I think she's asleep.
Let's check.
All right.
[Voiceover] We interrupt this
program of morning melodies
To bring you a special bulletin.
Late last night our police force,
With the assistance of Dr. Richard Gavin,
Located the hiding place of
the monsters from the sea.
Local officials assured all citizens
That the invasion of
the sea zombies is over.
We return you now to morning melodies.
Hank.
Hello, darling.
How's the leg?
Oh, it's much better.
I just saw your father,
And he's been burned badly,
But he'll be fine.
And he'll be back from the
hospital within a week.
Oh, thank God.
♫ Elaine
♫ Well, that's my baby's name
♫ Elaine ♫
Oh, Hank.
♫ But I love her just the same
♫ What good is a man
♫ Without a woman
♫ And what good am I
♫ If I don't have you
♫ Love me, too
♫ Who-hoo-ho-ho-Who-hoo-ho-ho
♫ I don't want to be lonely
♫ I don't want to be blue
♫ But I can't help it
♫ If I don't have you
♫ Elaine
♫ That's my baby's name
♫ I don't know if she loves me
♫ But I love her just the same
♫ What good are the stars
♫ Without a heaven
♫ And what good am I
♫ If I don't have you
♫ Love me, too
♫ Who-hoo-ho-ho-Who-hoo-ho-ho
♫ Elaine
♫ That's my baby's la-la-la-la-la-la-la
♫ La-la-la-la-la
♫ Elaine, Elaine, Elaine,
Elaine, Elaine, Elaine ♫