(ANNOUNCER) Previously on
AMC's "Hell on Wheels..."
(CULLEN BOHANNON) You gonna
pay out that man's wages
to his son.
That's the least I can do.
Land bought today will be...
(MAGGIE) Ten times the price tomorrow.
Here to buy some of that
property you sellin'.
We want profit astronomically.
I should have known that family life
wasn't for you.
All the death and destruction,
everything I done,
all that is for naught.
Doubt I'll finish this route.
We're better off here,
me and William.
Interesting you would rather be here
instead of with your wife and child.
♪♪
(GRUNTING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
ISAAC: William.
Didn't 'spect we'd be seeing you again.
Well...
here I be.
Hello, William.
- Is Naomi within?
- (WILLIAM CRYING)
ISAAC: I got you.
You came back.
The Swede's dead.
Well, I hope you'd stay for supper.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
I can't live out here forever.
It's too much work alone.
Dangerous.
Besides, it ain't what the
Heavenly Father wants for us.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on now. Have some more of
that chicken. Looks real good.
Father disagreed with the
Prophet on Thor Gundersen.
Got him cast out. And us with him.
I know.
So, where'd you say you're headed?
I didn't.
That ain't settled.
I got an apple pie in the oven.
ISAAC: Good plates...
Apple pie...
You got the royal
treatment, Mr. Bohannon.
Would you like that last biscuit?
- No, thank you.
- You sure?
Naomi's a fine cook.
- Isaac?
- ISAAC: What?
- You are.
- Thank you for dinner.
I've had enough.
Please. Stay the night.
Of course.
You're welcome to.
I'll sleep in the barn.
William.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
- (GROANS)
- ISAAC: Mr. Bohannon...
(PANTING)
I'm sorry about supper.
Should've seen it'd be hard on
you, but it's been so long...
She's my wife.
William's my son.
Sickness and health is what
it means to be a husband.
We swore an oath.
You left her to smallpox.
Isaac.
Naomi and I share a faith, Mr. Bohannon.
You see, we also swore an oath.
After you were long gone.
But the difference is...
I will never ride away from her.
NAOMI: All right. Let's
just get some rest.
We'll talk everything over
in the morning. All right?
All right. Go on.
It's all right. I'll be right in.
Thank you for saving them.
For dispatching that monster.
The Swede cast a long shadow
over all our lives, Mr. Vinson.
We'll be moving on in the
morning, Mr. Bohannon.
I suggest you do the same.
(INDISTINCT ARGUING)
Welcome home, Mr. Durant.
Home? Laramie? Hardly.
With any luck,
the railroad will be through the
entire godforsaken territory
of Wyoming before long.
Surely you won't miss Laramie.
Nah, that ain't it.
I just...
I don't know, Mr. Durant.
I'm warm, I'm safe. Got a full belly.
- I ought to feel grateful, but...
- Ennui.
On what?
There's a certain
dissatisfaction sets in
when we get what we think we want.
Yeah. Ennui.
I guess that's it.
- How long have they been there?
- Since this morning.
This came in on the train.
Something about Cheyenne
being the new railroad hub?
DURANT: Mmm-hmm.
I am sorry, Mr. Nobles, but there
is nothing I can do for any of you.
You can give us back our money.
I am sure the railroad'd be willing to
buy back your land at the current value.
NOBLES: Current value's jack shit
now that Cheyenne's the hub.
The only reason we bought in so high
is 'cause you told us Laramie
was gonna be the hub.
Because that's what I told her.
It's what I believed at the time.
Unfortunately, we are subject to the
whims of the executives in New York.
Now, Mrs. Palmer was taken
in, as we all were.
She's come out a lot nicer.
That fancy Cheyenne hotel of
hers has tripled in value
while the dirt she sold me
ain't fit to raise hogs.
I will personally buy back
all Laramie land deeds
at 10 cents an acre
above the going rate.
Come on, boys. Smells
like horseshit in here.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I never knew you was looking for me.
Started at the fort.
Then Salt Lake City,
where I heard about the smallpox.
Naomi, if I would've known...
That wasn't your fault.
I never sent word.
It only ever felt like I caught
a tiny piece of your heart...
This one dark night
in a lonesome barn...
One night of sin...
Don't say that.
It's why I went with
you to the railroad.
'Cause I'd already asked
so much of you, I...
I couldn't ask you to stay in that fort.
And Cheyenne seemed
exciting at the time.
Just wasn't the right thing.
Not for William.
I know.
I'm sorry.
No. You don't owe me that.
You never owed me a thing.
That's, that's why I could watch
you ride away from us so easy.
I wished I hadn't.
I quit the Union Pacific...
to look for you and William.
I spent months in the wilderness,
just searching.
I ain't ever stopped thinking about you.
Naomi. Please.
I was planning a house.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I'm here.
You know...
There was a time those words from you
was the only thing on God's
earth I wanted to hear.
But that time has passed.
We have Isaac now.
I love him.
You're right to take
them to Salt Lake City.
Prairie ain't safe.
Naomi's worried that Brother
Brigham will turn us away.
I could help stoke that engine.
You know the Prophet?
Yeah.
We ain't exactly fond.
But Thor Gundersen
twisted his son all up.
Figure news of his hangin'
ought to get me a sit-down, at least.
Ute braves are on the move. Saw
'em myself on the way over.
We'll take our chances alone.
I ride to Truckee straight
after, Mr. Vinson,
but I aim to see them safe.
And I ain't asking.
I suppose a second gun couldn't hurt.
Back in town, I see.
And thirsty from the trip.
I'll take a bourbon
and a thousand more Irish workers.
Christ, that's half of County Cork.
$20 a man.
Keep your money.
It's the hard paper I want.
Stock in the Union Pacific Railroad.
You're a labor contractor.
Aye. And I'd say I'm undervalued.
No one holds you in higher
esteem than I do, Mickey.
Oh, Jesus, I'm touched.
The thing is, though,
I know that you're short
900 Mormon graders.
Brigham Young is a stubborn man.
I don't want it all to be
liquor and whores, Doc.
I'm tired of the Dead Rabbits
and this whole dirty business.
I will make you a partner
in the railroad's construction
company. Credit Mobilier.
Credit Mobilier is a worthless shell.
I want the real thing. I
want legitimacy. I...
(SIGHS)
Or you can race Cullen
Bohannon with no graders.
Bohannon.
Hardly the adversary I expected.
Well,
it seems like you don't need
my services after all, then.
The bourbon's on the house.
Hey. (SNAPS FINGER)
It's not Sunday or a holiday, Psalms.
Why aren't you in the cut,
building my railroad?
Four long years I been
toiling on your railroad.
Today, I'm busted as
the day I was freed.
I come to sell back my deed
for whatever I can get.
I did caution you not to tangle
in the complicated world
of real estate investment.
You chose...
to disregard my warnings.
However, you... You have
been loyal to the railroad
and I would like you to have this.
Thirty pieces of silver don't
buy back what you took.
I hope you're not
looking for an apology.
It would be beneath your dignity
to ask, and mine to offer.
I guess I better get
back to the cut, then.
(EXHALES)
NAOMI: There's pieces in there still.
Yeah. Doctor couldn't get it all.
It won't ever heal then.
Some things don't.
You should get some sleep.
Yeah. I'll go check on William.
- Good night.
- Yeah.
I met her about a year ago.
Aaron Hatch and his family
stumbled into Salt Lake,
most of them boiling with pox.
My father took in the survivors.
And Naomi...
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
She was so darn pretty...
I could hardly look at her.
She is a beautiful girl.
There's a sadness in her.
You can see it.
There is a strength there, and grace.
We been through drought, Injuns,
plague of grasshoppers... (CHUCKLES)
There was also William's first steps.
Christmas.
All the apple pie.
And all of it melts from her eyes...
whenever she looks at you.
I have a right to know your intentions.
(CLANKING)
See to Naomi.
(COCKS GUN)
(SIGHS)
You. John. Listen up.
Prepare to translate. And make
haste, for Christ's sake.
I hate it down here.
Attention all Jakes.
Bossy man Huntington back from Utah.
He say: Picky uppy pac.
Doleime, ching-chong.
(SPEAKS CANTONESE)
Longer shifts. No more breaks.
And bonuses for every
man at tunnel's end.
(MEI SPEAKS CANTONESE)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(IN ENGLISH) Bohannon?
He back? From Utah?
Word is he found his family.
Nope. Don't count on seeing him
down here again, stupid ass.
CULLEN: Too close. We can't run.
- Well, we'll fight.
- Ain't a fight they want.
They're all busted up,
and they're on foot.
- They want the horses.
- That's right.
- The horses are too valuable.
- Night is in their favor.
Lose the ridin' horses
or lose your scalps.
Do it.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
CULLEN: Go!
(MEN HOLLERING)
(SINGING IN CANTONESE)
Cullen Bohannon to see the Prophet.
(GRUNTS)
The Bible describes an apostate
as a sow that was washed,
then leaves to wallow in the mire.
The Word commands they
be stoned to death.
Ain't no apostates here.
Just good Mormons.
And me.
Sometime Mormons.
Those who have heard the truth,
turned their backs on it
to follow Aaron Hatch.
Aaron Hatch was a good man.
He's dead.
And Thor Gundersen is hanged.
Thor Gundersen spat poison
in my beloved son's ear.
It's good the snake is dead.
Come in, gentile.
For now, these Hatchites
may feed and water their
horses in our stable.
We will discuss what
shall become of them.
CULLEN: They ain't Hatchites.
Just stray sheep in need of their flock.
You've betrayed their
shepherd with lies.
The flock will suffer for it. I
no longer bargain with gentiles.
I ain't here to bargain.
Just to speak for a good,
devout Mormon family.
Your family.
Naomi is your wife. William is your son.
That's why I want what's best.
Family is a cherished gift
from Heavenly Father.
Marriage is a sacred vow.
You would return his gifts?
Some might say that
makes you an apostate.
So long as Naomi and William
ain't the ones who got to pay.
Ambition resides in your
heart, Mr. Bohannon,
fed by the sin of pride.
It's why you choose the
railroad over your own family.
The Bible warns us,
Heavenly Father saves not by money,
power or vanity.
He saves by love.
I pray you learn this.
For without love...
you will die a lonely, wretched thing.
(SNIFFLES)
And the stray sheep?
Would you deny them the
love of their shepherd?
(HORSE BRAYING)
(BANGING CANE)
Isaac's gone to water the horses.
Brigham Young hopes you're
in church on Sunday morning,
front row, so he can
bless your marriage.
My father would have wanted
me to keep my vow to you.
This ain't your head talking.
William is your son.
It ain't right for me
to keep him from you.
Pray on it.
I will.
Throw your backs into it.
Listen here. This is slack work.
Pick it up, else we miss a meal.
Why?
Why we gotta work like
mule for the fat man?
'Cause it's your job, that's why.
And he break our backs,
steals our money.
This ain't slavery time. We
ain't got to go along now.
You're right.
To hell with the fat man.
We don't work for him.
We work for ourselves.
I was tricked by the devil, that's true.
Was tempted by easy money.
But freedom ain't easy.
So next time, we wait. We wait and see.
- We ain't got no money left for next time.
- (MEN AGREEING)
PSALMS: That's why we
need our jobs, fool.
So we can save up. Can't
let the devil beat us.
We'll just see what the
Lord got in store.
I'm done waiting on the Lord.
What else you got, huh?
No bread. Nowhere to go.
No 40 acres and no mule.
All you got is this job. Huh?
It's all you got.
Now you pick up them damn shovels.
And you work.
McGinnes is our only connection to
the labor market in the northeast.
More Freedmen, then. Buy out the
bonds from the southern prisons.
We haven't kept up payment on
the Freedmen's bonds we have.
The prisons have refused
further business with us.
Thank you, Mr. Delaney.
This is what comes of nepism.
The useless son-in-law
of my bloated former partner.
Well, what does he do all day?
Tap a ball of string around...
You need McGinnes if you want
the coal fields in Ogden.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Our schemes have left us with no
friends, New York, no allies.
You need Mickey.
I'm right and you know it.
DURANT: Four hundred shares
in Union Pacific Railroad.
Enough to buy you out
of the vice business
and set you on the road to legitimacy.
Me mother'd be proud. (CHUCKLES)
It's not all steaks and French wine.
Ownership comes with responsibilities.
And what kinds of responsibilities?
Responsibilities suited to
a man of your background.
A man unafraid of back alleys.
This is supposed to keep me from
them kinds of responsibilities.
It's not just the Dead Rabbits.
Every business is dirty.
Give me the stock.
I'll have your thousand workers out
to you by the end of the week.
Hmm.
You kept your word.
- Thank you.
- I ain't done it for you.
I know who you done it for.
You're leaving.
(CULLEN SNIFFLES)
Isaac...
is a good man.
Is this is the right thing?
It's the only thing.
(SNIFFLES)
William.
I was going to say this to
you when you got older,
but I best tell it to
you now. (SNIFFLES)
I hope you strive...
(GASPING)
your whole life...
(VOICE BREAKING) to be humble.
You respect women.
You take your hat off at the table.
Don't... Don't never start a fight
nor run from one neither.
Forgive. Forget.
Speak true.
Listen to your mama and your daddy.
(SNIFFS) I hope you find
love, Cullen Bohannon.
You deserve that.
(CULLEN GROANS)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(HORN BLOWING)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
(GRUNTS)
I thought you no come back.
Yeah, I thought so myself for a second.
But that's all done now.
(MOANS)
(GASPS)
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com