Previously on AMC’s Hell on Wheels…
All the skilled men are locked up,
thanks to your friend Sidney Snow.
Never figured you for a lawman.
Campbell's not just gonna
hand over these workers.
We're gonna break 'em out.
I'ma need those prisoners back.
Can't win this one.
You may go forward with me
and begin life again.
[music]
Allow me.
I gather this isn't the first time
you've helped a woman into her clothing?
Nor is it the first you've
been helped into yours.
What if I told you that it was?
Why, I'd say you've kept poor company.
Company has a way of
damaging a girl's reputation.
That was not the passion of a woman overly
concerned with her reputation.
That was the triumph of
curiosity over experience.
Several triumphs.
At least three.
Two.
Maybe.
Well, two so far.
- I love my work, Mr. Campbell.
- Mm-hmm.
I would hate to think that
I'd allow my curiosity
to jeopardize that.
And I love women, Miss Ellison.
You may rest assured,
I am discreet.
[Train whistling]
Is something wrong?
Move it. Come on.
Ain't got to be this way.
You boys could just step aside.
Let us pass.
How 'bout that?
Go on.
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com
Hey!
Uh-uh.
That ain't no plaything.
You wait until I teach ya. All right?
Guess you're 'bout old enough.
Go on.
Ezra!
What did I tell you?
Don't throw me a sassy look.
There's plenty of wash to be hung.
Plenty of fish in the creek, too.
Go on.
That man.
Sidney Snow. Did you get him?
Not yet, no.
You will?
The men are refusing to go back to work.
They won't set foot outside the church,
and I can't say I blame them.
Those wanted posters are
sitting on Campbell's desk.
I'm sure me own is right there on top.
Sidney Snow turned tail
and we just stood down
the last of the deputies.
Ain't nobody to enforce them posters.
Except Campbell.
I say we kill him.
People got killed already.
The men need assurances.
As do I.
Let's go get 'em, then.
You stay here.
You'd have no drinking with
my crew of saints, Mr. Huntington.
No gambling or carousing.
No. Those are Union Pacific
problems, Mr. Young.
Found amongst an Irish labor force.
I have none of that with my Chinese.
Mr. Huntington,
I came into this world with nothing.
No land, no money, no education,
no prospects.
As a young man, I often went without food,
and learned to savor the
taste of wild sparrow.
Through the grace of God,
I have built a small empire
here on the edge of the great salt lake,
where I am paving the way to zion.
I have not accomplished these
things by doing business
with men who would take for
granted the hard-won bounty
of my table or endeavor
to waste my precious time.
I admire your tenacious will, sir,
and I wouldn't dream of wasting your time.
Now, the celestials suit my
needs in almost every way.
They are Hardy, healthy,
and they work for pennies on the dollars.
But they are prone to work stoppages,
the worst of the which I am in midst of now.
What do they eat?
- Excuse me?
- Gundersen?
Their food.
What do you feed them?
You'll have to excuse my ward clerk.
He's new to Lion House.
Doesn't yet understand our manners.
Forgive me.
I am but a poor sinner.
Unworthy. Ignorant.
A fool. Please.
As I was about to say,
sloth is a sin common to sons of ham
but rare indeed among mormons.
I could easily provide
you with over 800 workers.
♪ I hates the yankee nation
and everything they do ♪
♪ I hates the declaration ♪
♪ of independence, too ♪
♪ I hates the glorious union
that's driven with our blood ♪
♪ I hates the strife of battle... ♪
♪ That hurted all my kin ♪
[Humming]
Gentlemen...
How did we get here?
We got here, John,
by way of your pernicious attacks
on my railroad and my person.
Railroad is mired in
corruption and incompetence.
- Incompetence?
- Gentlemen.
Don't matter how we got here.
Got to find out way somewheres new.
Now, Governor,
my men are goin' back to work.
I want your guarantee they'll be left alone.
That request is an excellent starting place
for this negotiation.
It is not a request.
You are outmanned and outgunned,
so now you will tear up
those ridiculous bond notices
and wanted posters and you
will stop harassing the men.
I remain provisional governor
no matter your number of guns.
You can call yourself provisional king
of the world for all I care.
As such, I will not abandon
the enforcement of law.
My mistake was tryin'
to keep the matter parochial.
My mistake, as I see it now,
was not establishing martial law earlier.
And I could have stayed in
Mississippi for martial law.
No one likes martial law,
but lacking any credible
local law enforcement...
All right.
I'll do it.
But I ain't gonna wear marshal's badge
and I sure as hell won't work for you.
I work for the railroad and that's
the only kind of badge I'll wear.
That's good enough for me, Mr. Bohannon.
'Course, should you prove
yourself unable or unwilling
to perform your duties at any time,
I will not hesitate to telegraph the fort.
Not necessary.
You have my word.
[Gunshot]
Hey! Hey! We're locked in.
Hey! Hey!
Sweet baby Jesus.
It's a fire! Fire!
It's a fire!
Check the lock!
Get that fire!
Get it!
Fire!
[Screams]
Hey, open the door!
Open them. Jesus.
Somebody grab them guns before they go off!
It was him. It was Sidney Snow.
Mickey!
Organize a bucket brigade before
the whole damn town goes up.
Aye. Right, lads!
Every Irish, negro, cowboy and kraut!
You grab yourselves a bucket!
Let's save this town!
Mr. Bohannon, I'm over here!
If you value me service at all,
get a message to me
sweetheart in Lisdoonvarna.
[Coughing]
Tell her go on and marry
that bollocks Doherty.
Far be it from me to make her an old maid.
Shut up, Paddy.
You can write her yourself tomorrow.
I can't read, sir.
Can't help you there.
Watch it!
[Screams]
[Both coughing]
- Get it out!
- Water!
Keep 'em coming.
Pass the bucket. Come on.
Quickly lads!
Come on, get this fire out!
Keep 'em coming!
Come on, faster, faster.
Come on, move it out.
All right, boys, pick it up!
It's always good doin' business
with a fellow pioneer, Mr. Young.
Please, thank all of your wives
for the heartiest hospitality
I have felt on either
side of the Mississippi.
We'll make a Saint of you yet,
Mr. Huntington.
I will pray for your safe
return to Sacramento.
And I will hope for your continued
health and prosperity.
Oh, uh... mister, uh...
Gundersen, was it?
That name is Norwegian if I'm not mistaken.
You are not mistaken.
Why did you want to know what
kind of feed I give my chinamen?
Our guest asked you a question,
brother Gundersen.
I learned during the war
that an army runs on its stomach,
and what is a labor force
if not a small army?
I see.
Thank you.
I spent years on the Union Pacific Railroad
under Thomas Durant.
Oh, that old son of a gun?
He ever give you that damn speech of his
- about the lion and the zebra?
- Oh, many times, yes.
Oh! 'Bout turned me into rip van winkle.
Because you found it boring?
[Laughs]
Tell me, did you ever have the opportunity
to work with Cullen Bohannon?
That man impresses the hell out of me.
Everything I know,
I learned by careful
study of Cullen Bohannon.
How about that?
And I suppose I'll see him
on the downslope soon enough.
Perhaps you could use a
former Union Pacific man
to accompany your fresh mormon workers.
That is,
if brother Brigham can spare me.
We will discuss it.
Hmm.
Leave us, Gundersen.
Good day.
You. Remember me?
You no good trash.
Help... me...
Look at me.
Look at me!
My name is Eva.
I'm a mother, daughter, injun,
wife, and whore.
But all my time on this earth,
I ain't ever met a bigger
piece of shit than you.
He couldn't be saved.
Have you seen Ezra?
I-I'm sorry, I haven't.
Ezra hasn't come back.
I'll be over after a while.
He's never stayed out all night.
All right. Hey, listen.
H... h...
he run off before all this started.
- He's all right.
- But... but where is he?
Probably just tryin' to stay out of the way.
We'll find him.
- Ezra!
- Come on out, now!
Have you not seen him, Ruth?
Oh, you know how boys are.
- He's just hidin' somewheres.
- Ezra!
Ezra!
- I won't be cross!
- Ezra!
Please! Come out!
What is it?
The back room.
No, church was clear.
Under the floor.
Ruth...
No.
Please.
- No!
- No, no.
No! Let me... let me go!
[Screams]
[Sobbing and wailing]
Sidney Snow. Where is he?
I don't know.
He's your marshal.
[Grunts]
I haven't had eyes on him
since he left on that prison train!
He takes his orders from you.
Hey, that man's incapable of takin'
orders from anyone.
Whoa! A child is dead!
I swear to you before God.
I had nothin' to do with the
heinous crimes at the church.
You hired that son of bitch
when you should have hung him.
You're right.
The blame for last night's tragedy is mine.
I never should have empowered Sidney Snow.
I've killed far better men than you
for doin' a lot less than that.
I have no shred of doubt.
I'd like to offer every
resource at my disposal
to help you find him and see him hang.
You're all out of resources,
far as I can tell.
Campbell didn't know.
We searched the casino,
the whorehouse, the laundry.
Every bleedin' rat hole in Cheyenne.
- Search again.
- I've searched it already!
He's got to be somewheres.
I oversaw the search myself.
Bohannon.
- You seen him?
- Mm-mm.
There are a lot of rotten,
mangy dogs in this town,
but none who'd shelter a child-killer.
All he had to was hop on a horse.
He's halfway to Mexico by now,
or some other arsehole town in this world!
He ain't in Mexico.
Cullen!
He's gone.
It's over.
I had him, Mickey.
In the general store.
Had my gun to his head.
Well, why didn't you shoot him?
Ruth...
We searched everywheres...
And I was too slow.
Stupid.
I let Sidney get away.
When you first brought him to the church,
I wanted to send him to the orphanage.
I had no business being anyone's mother.
You was just scared.
I never learned his full name.
Never knew where he came from.
Whether he had brothers or sisters
or what became of his family.
I don't know if he was a
colicky baby or a happy one
or if his eyes were like his father's.
He'll never go to school.
Never have a sweetheart.
Never get married.
He hated doing chores.
He brought live toads into the church.
He was wild and headstrong...
And I could never get him to take a bath.
But he was a good boy.
And the last time I saw him,
I spoke to him in anger.
No. No.
You was just tryin' to protect him.
The good it did.
- You didn't know.
- I should've known!
I was supposed to take care of him.
I never deserved to be a mother.
[Sobs]
[Sobbing]
Ah, brother Brigham.
Good day.
You made a favorable impression
on Collis Huntington.
We discussed your
accompanying the saints to
work on the Central Pacific.
He'd like you along.
Truly a man of vision, like yourself.
The holy spirit compelled me to...
to reach out to him.
Oh!
I am God's prophet on Earth.
Not you.
Forgive me, brother Brigham.
I was bested by my pride.
Heavenly Father has plans for you here.
In the future, it would behoove
you to remember your place.
Of course.
Oh, thank you,
♪ oh Lion of the Lord ♪
Finish dressing and pray.
There's a ward meeting in half an hour.
[door closes]
[Speaks foreign language]
♪ That I should know your face my love ♪
♪ like sorrow knows the morning dove ♪
♪ that I should hold you to my breast ♪
♪ come back to me is my request ♪
♪ my own true love remember me ♪
♪ when once again my eyes you see ♪
♪ my heart lays in a darkened place ♪
♪ that you should know my weary face ♪
♪ I'll search for you on Jordan shore ♪
♪ to hold you in my arms once more ♪
♪ I've travelled down
this long hard road ♪
♪ and I'll not ever let you go ♪
♪ that I should know your face my love ♪
♪ come back to me is my request ♪
[Knocking on door]
Eva, I saw what you did.
What'd I do?
You killed that man.
After the fire.
I know he was monstrous.
You don't know nothin' but words.
Eva.
I know.
He done you, too.
You murdered him.
Weren't exactly murder.
How could you do it?
I notice you didn't try to stop me.
No.
I mean I...
I...Couldn't have done it.
It's all right, Miss Ellison.
You ain't done nothin' wrong.
Enough things happen to
you long enough out here,
you can do anything.
You'll see.
Don't.
You was always there for him, Ruth.
That means a lot.
You lost your own son to violence.
Yeah, Joshua.
He's about Ezra's age.
How do you endure it?
Ain't nothin' brings peace.
When you find the devil
who did this to my child,
I hope you return him to hell with my wish
that his suffering be deep,
and eternal.
[Sobs]
Good morning.
Rats?
It's ghosts, more like.
Hmm.
Yes, well...
When Hannah left me, I...
I actually preferred the
solitude of my prison cell
to the empty rooms of the family house.
Oh.
Don't let your new duties
keep you from conquering Sherman Peak.
I'm writing an article
about the administration
of justice in Cheyenne.
I don't think you're going to like it.
Ah, damn it!
Not a delicate lady, Mr. Bohannon.
What we have here
is a strong-backed, thick-thighed whore.
I'd recommend a plumbing wrench.
Plumbing wrench it is, Mr. Delaney.
Mr. Delaney?
Thank you.
Supposin' now we, um...
Get this contraption of
your'n on up and runnin'.
Won't find it friend to the workin' man.
Anything that keeps me droppin'
dead chuckin' rock
is a friend of mine.
This steam shovel of
your'n chew up Sherman Peak
like you say,
what use is old Psalms?
Or you, while we at it?
Tomorrow's problem.
Hand me that wrench right there.
Cullen Bohannon!
Get your blue coat killin'
ass out here, now!
I'm right here, Sid!
You best come and talk to me 'fore
I shoot the piss out of this pig shit town!
All right.
Let's talk.
Well, look at you.
You're jealous of my badge.
You had to go out and get one for yourself.
You should have kept ridin'.
Yeah, I thought so too.
You know, I was half way to Denver
after I set that cute Lil'
yankee twist's church on fire.
You know what it was made me come back?
It was you.
Bohannon.
You and me got unfinished business.
Suppose that's right.
What do you say we settle things right now?
I'm all done with killin'.
Well, maybe you gonna get killed.
I'm gonna arrest you.
Well, why don't you come
on over here and try.
Drop that gun.
Yeah, come on and take it.
[Gunshot]
Ahh!
[Coughs]
Well, dip me in dog shit.
[Coughs and laughs]
The church lady?
sync and corrections by dreaMaker7
www.addic7ed.com