ANNOUNCER: Previously, on AMC's
"Hell on Wheels"...
(CHEERING)
When those government inspectors
order you to rebuild,
it'll cost you a hell of
a lot more than Ogden.
Take Ogden, if that'll
put an end to this!
Did you have a hand in Chang's murder?
CULLEN: You don't leave
this room till I get back.
I love you, Cullen.
Grant made you Secretary of the Interior
to make judgment calls, not to...
You'll get your judgment, Mr. Durant...
but not today.
(GROANS)
Tell me you haven't melted
it down and sold it already.
(SCOFFS)
The Union Pacific
provides the final spike,
the Central Pacific nails
it down, like we agreed.
I agreed to hold a ceremony at
the location of your choosing.
Collis, the heaviest thing you've
lifted to date is a dessert spoon.
You think my masculine capabilities
are insufficient, sir?
I think you'd rather not
answer that question
in front of 200 of Washington's finest.
(DURANT CHUCKLES)
(EXHALES)
(GROANS)
(BOTTLE ROLLS)
(SNORING)
Mr. Lee?
Wake up. Translate that.
(SIGHS) Need sleep, bossman.
(GROANS)
Translate.
Address.
In Ningpo.
An address?
China?
Ribbed with iron,
clad in silver, and crowned with gold,
this spike will wed the oceans.
Telegraphs
in every major city will buzz
to life with the knowledge
America's transcontinental
railroad is now complete.
At the fall of my hammer, the operator
will tap out a three dot transmission.
The message?
One word...
Done.
Whiskey.
MICKEY: You don't need
another drink, mate.
(GROANS) Hair of the dog.
- Give the man a drink!
- Pipe down, ya traitor.
What'd you say?
For the love of Josephine,
can't a man sleep?
- Whiskey damn it.
- I called you a traitor.
And we don't serve C.P. here.
Call me traitor again.
It's over, there ain't no sides.
All right?
Except the side of whiskey.
Just give him a drink,
for God's sake, Mick.
Ah, shut up, Patrick.
I told you all, there ain't no U.P.
and there ain't no C.P., God damn it.
Oi, the hell there ain't.
Job or no job, I'm a Union Pacific man.
Your pasty Mic ass'd still be down
a mine shaft if it weren't for me.
PSALMS: Call me traitor again.
Keep your voices down.
I don't work for you, Bohannon.
You mean the winning side?
Hand to God,
the next man who asks me for a drink,
I swear I'll throttle him.
Whiskey.
(GRUNTS)
(CLAMORING)
(BRASS BAND PLAYING)
(APPLAUSE)
(GRUNTING)
(SILENCE)
(MUSIC RESUMES)
(APPLAUSE)
Thank you, thank you.
(GUNSHOT)
What the hell is this all about?
Mr. Bohannon?
Mick?
I...
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hell if we know.
Congress requests your
presence in Washington
to testify against Thomas Durant on
charges of bribery, fraud and corruption.
Well, shit.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
I ain't going to Washington.
You've been summoned by Congress.
You tell Congress I've
a railroad to see to.
- Supplies to send West...
- The railroad is finished.
President Grant is determined
to see all those guilty of corruption
over its building punished
to the full extent of the law.
Uh-huh.
You're not yet an old man, Mr. Bohannon,
but you are no longer young.
I advise you to reflect
on what it is you decide to do next,
whose company you choose to keep.
Your subsequent venture will likely
determine the shape of your life.
A subpoena is not a request.
A cavalry escort can be
arranged if need be.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm buying out your
stake in the railroad.
But I'm not selling.
I've been indicted.
News will hit the papers tomorrow.
I want no record of your
involvement in the Union Pacific.
I helped build the Union Pacific.
You're associated with the Dead Rabbits.
I'm compelled to cut ties.
(SCOFFS)
Your stock value by
tomorrow will plummet.
Stick around, then you'll be
broke or in jail or both.
I've buried bodies for you.
(SIGHS)
I hope you don't want a
kiss goodbye, McGinnes.
I'm not your father.
I hope you hang.
(SNICKERS)
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Eva, here you are.
Sheets don't wash themselves,
Ms. Ellison.
Need all the girls on their backs.
Tricks'll dry up soon
as the workers leave.
Hey!
You want a roll, go round
the front, wait your turn.
Oh, Eva, that's not a John.
That's my editor from the Chicago
Tribune. He's very interested in you.
- I ain't on the menu.
- No, he's interested in your story.
He wants me to help you
write it, in a book.
Folks don't wanna read about a whore.
It would be a story about a survivor
and folks will love it.
Folks will love you.
- That ain't been my experience.
- This could be a way in for you.
- Into what?
- Society.
If that's what you want.
Or anything, reall
A best-selling authoress
can write her own ticket.
Slow down, Mr. Bohannon, pack light.
I need you back in San Francisco
as soon as you're finished
with this Washington business.
That well's deeper than you think.
Careful you don't fall in.
They're interested in Durant, not me.
No, they're a hound with a scent.
Once they've chewed through Durant,
they'll come sniffing after us.
I'm ahead of that problem.
It was you, lit that little bonfire
in the C.P. Depot last night, huh?
I gosomething for you.
To commemorate the Golden Spike.
Only four like it in the world.
Go ahead, put it on, Mr.
Bohannon, you've earned it.
Once you're back in San Francisco, we'll
get started on the Southern Pacific.
- Shortline?
- Uh-uh.
She doesn't have the romance of the
transcontinental,
but don't write her off.
She's just beginning.
Plenty of roads to build yet.
Oh, see that?
Railroad man, through and through!
- CONDUCTOR: All aboard!
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(CONDUCTOR SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(BELL DINGING)
(TRAIN RATTLING)
(BELL TOLLING)
Thank you, sir.
_
MAN: Mr. Bohannon?
Archibald Romans,
Senior White House Staff.
I'm here to invite you to President
Grant's gala this evening.
I ain't much for galas.
In celebration of the
completion of the railroad.
I come to testify, Mr.
Romans, not socialize.
The President has asked for
you personally, Mr. Bohannon.
Grant knows I'm in town?
Your stay at the Willard
Hotel has been compensated.
Might I suggest you get
yourself checked in
and cleaned up before the soiree?
- (CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CHATTERING)
I assume you've been
corralled into testifying
at this circus tomorrow.
I'm not at liberty to discuss
the hearing, Thomas.
Congratulations on driving
the golden spike.
I stand accused of bribing
government officials.
That's officials like you.
Now, I would advise you to say nothing,
we're all in this together, Stephen.
You've been away, so,
allow me to fill you in.
You're poison in this town.
And very much in this alone.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Now these hands...
Have built things.
Ma'am.
You're Cullen Bohannon, aren't you?
The man of the hour.
Quite an accomplishment,
this railroad of yours.
Thank you ma'am.
You're more handsome
than I ever imagined.
You must tell me everything
about the Wild West.
They say it isn't safe
for a respectable woman.
I'm sorry.
I'm not in the right place.
Margaret, your husband
is asking for you.
Oh, George, he's a bore.
And he's hopeless without you, my dear.
Can't begrudge poor
Margaret for flirtations.
That's her husband.
Colonel George Armstrong Custer.
Damn impressed with your accomplishment
on the railroad, Mr. Bohannon.
Ten miles in a single day, was it?
Well, had me one hell of a crew.
You've the guts and countenance
of a good soldier, sir.
Who did you serve?
I rode under General
Nathan Bedford Forrest.
Confederate.
That's right.
Shit, I led the charge against
you boys at Bull Run.
Had you outnumbered and outgunned,
but God damn if you didn't give
us one hell of a steeplechase.
Where I come from, an
ass-whooping amounts
to more than a steeplechase, Colonel.
Come over here, boys.
I want you to meet the
Grayback son-of-a-bitch
who built ten miles of
iron road in a single day.
To Mr. Cullen Bohannon...
Toughest whoop-ass on the
transcontinental railroad.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Thank you.
He looks at me and he
says, "What's a poodle?"
- Oh, now.
- Oh, at ease, gentlemen.
Mr. Bohannon.
You've met the Colonel, I see.
Bohannon here was just
explaining the difference
between a blood hound and a poodle.
I got that right, Captain?
Good enough for a Yankee.
Have you boys heard how to tell
a good Yankee from a bad one?
Mr. Bohannon?
Why, that's simple, Mr. President.
All the good Yankees go home.
Let's go get some real food.
Yes, sir. Nice to meet y'all.
Ah.
Oh, yes.
Go ahead, eat it.
Those frilled dainties they're serving
up there aren't fit to feed men.
Mmm.
'Coffee'?
(LAUGHS)
Mmm-mmm.
Now,
if you brought me down here to
talk about Thomas Durant...
Oh, I have a Senator who will testify
to taking bribes from Doc Durant.
Bad fruit left over from the
previous administration.
I don't need your help cleaning house.
-We just here for the coffee then? -Mmm.
(INHALES SHARPLY AND EXHALES)
I'd like to make you a Colonel
in the Fourth Cavalry.
You'd be the Undersecretary of the Western
Territories for the United States Army.
Your job would be to protect
the railroad you've built
from all present threats.
- You mean Indians.
- All threats, Mr. Bohannon.
Cutthroats and train robbers.
Cattle rustlers along the Texas border.
And, yes, renegade Indians.
I ain't no Indian killer.
You're smart enough to prevent
bloodshed where possible,
and not afraid to get your
hands dirty when necessary.
You'd report to the
Secretary of the Interior.
Sounds like you're asking
me to wear Union Blue.
I'm asking you to wear
an American uniform.
Your country needs you, Mr. Bohannon.
Don't deny who you are.
I'm a railroad man.
Bullshit.
You're a soldier.
Lost without a war to fight.
Ah, damn.
I've got to go make a speech.
Think it over.
Yes, sir.
(SIGHS)
(SCOFFS AND CHUCKLES)
A backwards rebel right at
home in the nation's capital,
I never thought I'd see the day.
Ain't nobody more
surprised than me, Doc.
Never thought I'd see the day you'd be
itching for a train back to Hell on Wheels.
They've turned a Senator.
Several, probably.
I don't know who, but
whatever hog they've got tied
will squeal loud and clear.
Mmm.
You've gotten outta
tighter spots than this.
Grant needs a scapegoat.
I'm out of allies.
Maggie Palmer was right.
She was a good woman.
I loved her.
They brought me here to testify.
Say whatever you want.
Enjoy your newfound favor
because it will be over in an instant.
Those men you were
laughing with in there,
they're not your friends.
They'll bleed you dry,
toss you out with
yesterday's newspapers.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
I came to cash out my 10%.
I've got a big labor contract
at the docks in San Francisco.
I thought you'd come along.
I ain't a labor contractor.
Well, we'll keep the whores, then.
Hell, we'll import new ones from France.
I've big plans, Eva.
We're only expanding.
We ran a good enterprise.
I'll always be thankful for that.
But we're bad for each other, Mickey.
Josie...
- Shea...
- That was business.
Come to San Francisco.
We stick together, it's a matter of time
before one of us devours the other one,
and you know it.
Here you go then.
Good luck to you.
Me leaving's the closest thing
we got to a happy ending.
Sounds like you've got it all sorted.
Don't go sour on me.
See yourself away.
(DOOR OPENS)
The President will see you now.
...property, and free
political opinion...
You've reached a decision.
Perfect fit.
Anything else, sir?
No. No, thank you.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
Your name and title for the record.
Cullen Bohannon.
Stake-holder and Chief Engineer,
Central Pacific Railroad.
Your current title, sir.
Colonel, 4th Cavalry, U.S. Army.
I'll cut right to it, sir.
Have you ever witnessed Thomas Durant
offer an elected official a bribe,
in form of stock or cash in
exchange for favorable legislation?
The transcontinental railroad
could not have been built
without Thomas Durant.
That wasn't an answer.
I'll ask again.
As a former employee
of the Union Pacific,
did Thomas Durant ever
voice his intention to
or offer any bribes to
an elected official?
The transcontinental railroad could not
have been built without Thomas Durant.
Mr. Bohannon, you have sworn an oath
before this committee
under penalty of perjury.
We have a dozen Senators on record saying
Thomas Durant attempted to bribe them,
are you disputing their
account of the facts?
The fact I know to be true
is that the transcontinental railroad
could not have been built
without Thomas Durant.
This committee has the authority
to hold you in contempt, Colonel.
You have the right to
detain me, Governor,
but that won't change the fact
that the transcontinental railroad
could not have been built
- without...
- BOTH: Thomas Durant.
Thank you, Colonel. That'll be all.
ED: The lecture circuit
won't know what hit them.
First stop, Council Bluffs,
day after tomorrow.
But the book isn't written yet.
The book will come,
don't worry about that.
In the meantime, your face tells
the story better than any book.
LOUISE: Maybe we should
go over the details.
Yes. Walk us through it, Mrs. Toole.
You were headed West with your family
when you were attacked by Wild Mojave...
- Yavapai.
- Sorry?
It was...
(SIGHS)
We was attacked by Yavapai.
Apache.
Then they traded me to the Mojave
for three blankets and a horse.
Three blankets and a horse.
The price of a human soul.
Great detail. Possible title.
- Remember that, Ms. Ellison.
- Mmm.
So, the Mojave marked your
face and made you their slave.
No. Not exactly.
(CHUCKLING) How would you describe it?
They...
Everyone had marks but...
The point is to let Mrs. Toole
tell her story in her own words.
Go ahead, Eva.
We won't interrupt.
It was hard at first
because I missed my momma.
But then I had me a Mojave...
Had me a Mojave sister and...
I'm sorry, this dress just
don't seem to fit right.
(STUTTERS) But, the dress
is part of the story,
it indicates you... You've been saved.
Saved from what?
(SCOFFS)
From a life of savagery, of course.
The marked face and the dress, we
can't have one without the other.
Not now, Ed.
I can't do this.
Eva, we'll get a different dress.
No, it ain't the dress.
The railroad is finished, Eva.
What else will you do?
This is the best that you can hope for.
(SCOFFS)
Oh, God, I...
I'm sorry. I...
I love you, Louise.
But I promised myself
I'm done whoring.
Good luck in Chicago.
(GUNSHOT)
You're one hell of a shot.
Plenty of practice.
Too bad for the Apache.
That's where you're heading, right?
Arizona territory?
Ship out tomorrow.
Apache women are turned on by gore.
Fornicate like rabbits
once the killing's done,
you barely have to force them.
Got myself a few trap
trophies from Arizona,
had 'em stitched into coin purses.
No.
It ain't that kind of assignment.
Just bringin' a couple
of renegades is all.
Grant tell you that?
He's a politician, I suppose he has to.
You're a killer.
You know what happens in the fog of war.
Got to go see to the wife before I go.
Keep up with my conjugal duties,
lest she turn to the postman.
You got yourself a girl?
That's for the best. Kes you focused.
Don't worry about Grant's bullshit.
You'll ship out, kill some Injuns,
blam, blam, blam, then ride
back to Washington a hero.
Nothing better.
(DOOR OPENS)
PRIEST: Bless you, my son.
How long has it been since
your last confession?
Are you a soldier?
It's all right, my son.
No man is without sin,
but you can be forgiven.
Do you seek salvation?
Do you wish to be saved?
(SNIFFLING)
(LAUGHING)
Thank you.
Thomas Durant will invoke
his fifth amendment right
as secured by the constitution
of the United States.
Mr. Durant, we have sworn testimony
corroborating the charges against you,
am I clear you are choosing to let these
charges go unanswered by you here today?
Mmm-hmm.
As is your constitutional right,
so long as you're aware
the record of history
will remember Thomas
Durant as a criminal.
The record of history?
That's right, Mr. Durant.
My client will invoke his right...
The record of history
will read, however,
the handful of overfed
Senators in this room
who choose to write it.
I'm not interested in the
record of history...
Mr. Durant, please.
I am interested in reality.
Not the one bandied inside
the halls of Congress,
but the one I witnessed
with my own eyes out West.
Five years ago,
the American people, torn apart by war,
cried out into the darkness
and turned a hopeful ear
to the void for an answer.
Americans needed a dream
and I gave them one.
A transcontinental
railroad that would unite
Dreams don't come pretty,
they don't come clean
and they sure as hell
don't come simple...
They come true.
Truth delivered by lies is no less true,
and dreams made reality by f.
1,776 miles of iron track,
that is what I delivered!
Track upon which thousands
of wheels will now revolve
carrying on their axles the
wealth of half the world.
Final Destination, San Francisco!
DURANT: Drawn by the Iron Horse,
announcing to the world
with its piercing scream
that we are a great people who
can accomplish great things.
Yet the American people,
driven by their cowardly
representatives in Washington,
are in need of a villain.
And so here I sit,
elected by you,
to play my part...
The part of the scapegoat.
The patsy. Sent into the wilderness
so that men sitting in this room
can lay their sins upon my back,
and claim they themselves are clean.
Men enjoying immunity while
enriching themselves on the backs
of those who sacrificed everything
to make manifest America's destiny.
Lives have been lost.
Men have been ruined.
I saw it, and I survived.
I will not return from the wild
having made America's dream a reality
only to have six bureaucrats
in starched collars judge
the manner in which I
realized that dream.
Put me on trial, lock me in prison,
erase me from the record.
For history is written in pencil...
And the truth is carved in
steel across this nation.
And one truth above
all others is this...
Without me and men like me,
your glorious railroad
could never have been built.
♪
(WATER SPLASH)
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
♪
- sync and corrections by Caio -
- www.addic7ed.com -
To everyone who made Hell on Wheels...
And to everyone who loves it,
AMC says thank you for a hell of a ride.