"Wives, submit yourselves
to your husbands
"as is fitting in the Lord.
"Husbands, love your wives
and do not be harsh with them.
"Children, obey your
parents in everything
"for this pleases the Lord.
"Slaves, obey your earthly
masters in everything,
"not only when their eye is on you
and to curry the favor,
but when sin... sin..."
Sincerity.
"Sincerity of the heart
in referring to the Lord."
Well, I don't believe it.
How old are you, boy?
I ain't but 9 years, sir.
Pay up, gentlemen.
It's dangerous, you know,
teaching them to read.
That's true.
Nat Turner was taught to read.
Nonsense.
Let me show you.
Boy, can you explain
to me the meaning
of what you just read?
No, master.
See?
It's like a parrot
reciting Shakespeare.
Well done, Elam.
Well done.
"Now, I have heard the
groaning of the Israelites
"whom the Egyptians hold in slavery,
"and I have remembered my promise.
"Say unto the children of Israel,
I am the Lord."
"And I will bring you out from
under the burdens of the Egyptians,
and I will rid you out
from under their bondage."
"And I will redeem you
with a stretched out arm,
and ye shall know that
I am the Lord."
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
[Train whistle blowing]
Behold Robert Bell's legacy,
gentlemen.
We follow the North Platte
clear into Wyoming,
and we skirt the black hills
to the South,
and strike the Rockies here.
He found the way through.
Now we have payroll, we have
manpower, we have material.
I expect no further delays
in making the 40 miles by
the government deadline.
Am I understood?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, Mr. Durant.
Good. [Sighs]
And we will finish on schedule?
We won't finish anything if I don't
dig myself out of this hole we're in.
How long will you be gone, sir?
A few days.
I'm escorting Mrs. Bell to Chicago.
Ohh.
You can wipe that lascivious
look off your face.
It's not what you think.
I'm seeing senator crane.
I have seen how she look at you.
Nonsense.
No, it's true.
Cullen:
I guess you're leaving.
I'm going to Chicago to see
my late husband's family.
Then it's on to England.
You don't sound too
excited about going home.
I don't have a home anymore.
I had hoped to stay here
with Robert forever,
settle down on a ranch or a farm.
Raise a family.
Grow old and die together.
The world don't care much
for our plans, Mrs. Bell.
Indeed it don't, Mr. Bohannon.
[Train whistle blowing]
Do try and stay out of trouble.
I'll try, ma'am.
[Train whistle blowing]
Eva: Mr. Bohannon!
Mr. Bohannon!
Mr. Bohannon,
you've got to stop them.
- What the hell happened?
- Elam. They're gonna hang him.
[Train whistle blowing]
How the hell is that my problem?
You've gotta do somethin'.
Talk to the Swede.
He's the head of security.
He's the one gave them the go ahead.
Said his men are gonna
let off some steam.
[Men yelling]
Move them tables aside!
Move that table!
[Men yelling]
[Grunts]
[Indistinct grunting and yelling]
[Grunts and groaning]
Anybody squeamish about a hangin'
had best move along right now!
Let him loose!
Let him loose or there's going to be
a river of Mick blood flowing in here!
There'll be an ocean of nigger blood.
I guarantee that. Boys.
[Cocking guns]
Looks like you've brung
shovels to a gunfight.
Well, no matter.
We'll use them to dig your graves.
We'll take our chances.
Put your weapons down.
This is between him and me.
Ain't no use in none of y'all
getting shot dead for it.
I can't do that.
We can't just walk away.
You've got to walk away...
Because the rest of y'all
gonna get killed, too.
I say we finish him now.
Elam: Mr. Toole.
Mr. Toole...
Give me your word they ain't going
to come to no harm if they walk away.
You have my word.
Tell your men to put their guns down.
Lower your guns, boys.
Go on now.
Elam.
You all git.
Go on! You hear me?
Get out of here.
Go on.
[Indistinct chatter]
Tuck your tails!
Ain't nothing we can do.
I don't know whether
you're aware of it,
but we Irish are the niggers
of the British Empire.
That what this is about?
You showin' the world you ain't at
the bottom of the barrel no more?
You're damn right it is.
Any last words?
I'm going to kill
your lily white ass.
When we meet in hell, perhaps.
Go on, now!
Go to it, boys!
[Men talking indistinctly throughout]
[Elam grunting throughout]
[Grunting
[horse whinnies]
[Grunting]
Drop him.
Shoot him!
[Grunts]
[Men shouting]
Will somebody please
shoot the bastard?!
[Men yelling]
Well, you shoot him.
Cut his ties.
[Grunts]
Let's go!
Got a horse outside waiting for you.
[Panting]
[Coughs]
Any of y'all thinking
about coming after me
best get fitted
for a shroud and a box.
[Horse whinnies]
Just climb on the
sumbitch and hang on.
[Men yelling]
[Chuckles]
Sure is a stupid-looking
spud muncher, ain't he?
Some respect for the dead, Mr. Bolan.
In the end, when
all is said and done,
all we really own is our death.
It is given us the moment we is born,
and we carry that burden
the best we can.
I've seen men die screaming.
I've seen men die with nary a peep.
Mmm. Well, this one here died
trying to draw down
on Cullen Bohannon.
Well, then perhaps
he was stupid after all.
Now...
This... hanging of yours
went not so well.
He was as good as dead
till Johnny Reb came busting in here.
What do you propose to do about it?
What do you mean?
Well, this brigand...
This rebel... has upset
the balance once again.
And he must be dealt with.
I still don't follow.
Why does that not surprise me?
You... must pursue... Bohannon.
Hmm?
Me?
Yeah.
I don't know nothing
about warfare as such.
You created this mess,
and you'll clean it up or die trying.
I'll not do it.
Aah! Jesus!
Now, all of you that was
involved in this hanging
will accompany Mr. Toole
on his noble quest.
How the hell do you expect these
Bogtrotters to track down Bohannon?
Well, that's their problem.
Ah, let me and Dix take 'em.
Hmm?
I'll track him down like a rabid dog.
Cullen: Hold. Slow up,
slow up. Slow up.
Why we stopping here?
Good a place as any.
Bohannon...
What you did for me
back at that saloon...
What the hell was you thinkin'?
You carrying on with a white woman?
I'm a free man.
You ain't that free.
Why you get to decide that?
I ain't decide nothing.
That's the way of the world.
What's it like to own
somebody, Mr. Cullen?
Any different than owning
a dog or a pig or a plow?
I treated my people well,
if that's what you're asking.
Your people?
You make it sound like
they was family to you.
Well, one of them practically
raised me after my mother died.
Yeah, but...
You be owning her.
Even if she changed
your dirty drawers,
you still be owning her.
I wouldn't mind owning me
a white woman.
Yes, sir.
That might be nice.
Maybe I'd bring her in
from the fields
of an evening and have me some fun.
[Chuckles]
Watch yourself.
And what if she give me a baby boy?
Would I own that, too?
Or would half of him be free?
And what if I bring that boy
into my house from time to time?
And teach him to read and write?
And I give that boy
just enough hope...
To think that maybe...
Just maybe he different.
Different than all
the other white folk I owned?
Nah.
He ain't no different.
He just a mule.
Everybody know a mule ain't no horse.
Ain't that right, Mr. Cullen?
[Wheels clacking]
[Groans]
[Train whistle blows]
[Sighs]
Damn it all.
[Footsteps]
I'm sorry, I...
No! Ma'am, please, stay.
You weren't at dinner.
I... supped on Brandy.
Five course meal.
Do you know what this is?
[Sighs]
It's a penny.
I wish it were just a penny...
Rather than the seed
of my own destruction.
I don't understand.
I was raised in a shanty
town in hell's kitchen.
Only difference between
us and the rats
were the rats were
better fed and cleaner.
Sorry to hear that.
I don't want your sympathy.
One day, while I was rummaging
through the trash for a meal...
Some gentlemen passed me by.
One of them told me
he would give me a penny
if I ate a putrid apple
that even the rats had passed over.
I... will never forget that taste.
It was all I could do
to keep it down.
Ohh. They had a good laugh, and...
One of them tossed me the coin.
And on that day, my bark
was set on a course
that neither tempest nor
leviathan could alter.
I would have it all...
And I would have it on my terms.
[Sighs]
I know no other way, Lily.
I faced ruin many times...
And I always found a way out.
But...
This time... I fear I may not recover.
Is this Thomas Durant...
Or some blubbering schoolboy
I see before me?
I gave you those maps
so you could finish the railroad...
For Robert's sake.
I won't let you quit.
Get your head out of that bottle
and figure out a way.
[Train whistle blows]
[Crickets]
I gave my slaves their freedom
before the war started.
Damn near went broke
paying their wages.
I'm supposed to thank you for that?
No.
I only did it for my wife.
I sure as hell didn't understand it.
[Sighs]
It pissed me off, tell you the truth.
So why'd you do it, then?
Well...
Mary had a way of
talking me into things.
Hmm.
It wasn't until
I come home from the war...
Right then, actually...
That I understood that she was right.
I found Mary where she was hanged,
you know.
But... I couldn't find my boy.
We'd always play hide and go seek,
and he'd always hide
up in the hayloft.
Every damned time... every time...
He'd... and I'd just...
I'd pretend like I couldn't find him.
See, the Yankees, they...
They burned the barn,
but it was still standing.
And...
There he was...
Up in the hayloft.
His body was curled up,
and his arms was...
Hugging his knees to his chest.
But he wasn't alone.
Bethel... the woman who raised me...
She was with him.
She had her arms
wrapped around him...
Like she was protecting
him from the flame.
Both their bodies, they were...
Scorched black...
Fused together, you know?
Couldn't really tell where one of
them ended and the other one began.
And I just remember standing there
and thinking to myself...
God's got a funny way
of teaching you things.
Huh?
Yeah.
I wouldn't give a s if I was you,
either.
13, 14, 15, 16.
Ahem. You ever shoot a gun?
Oh, yeah.
Massah let us shoot guns on
the plantation all the time.
You try.
You got to cock it.
Again.
Keep firing.
Damn.
And you're ready.
What do you mean, I'm ready?
I can't even hit the dang tree.
Well, you're just going to
have to get in close, then.
How am I going to get up
close without getting shot?
Whoever you're shooting at is going
to be just as scared as you are.
You take your time.
Don't lose your head.
Count your rounds as you fire.
If you're calm, you'll
count their rounds, too.
The trick is making sure the other
man has to reload before you do.
And if I don't?
You're dead.
End of lesson.
[Train whistle blowing]
[Door opens]
Good morning.
Good morning, Thomas.
I think I may have found
a way out of my mess.
Now, this is a map of
all the other railroads...
An intricate web of iron
connecting all the eastern cities.
But something is missing.
Can you see it?
There is no direct route connecting
the Union Pacific to New York... yet.
Well done.
Why not?
Well, I have two choices.
I can build a beltline to the R&R
or to the M&M line, further south.
I own substantial stock in the R&R.
But I don't understand how this
helps you out of your mess.
A stock tip like that could have the
president himself eating out of my hand.
And I know senator crane,
that's exactly what he's after.
[Indistinct chatter]
I didn't know
they had something planned.
I don't know them well.
I've only met them once.
I'm sure they'll be
very happy to see you.
I'm not so sure.
Can't you stay a while?
I have to meet with senator crane,
but I'll be back later to
take you to your hotel.
Lily.
Mrs. Bell.
I am so sorry to see you
under such circumstances.
Thank you, my dear.
Emily.
Lily.
Charlotte.
I see by your dress you're
already out of mourning.
I didn't know.
Let's go meet the guests, shall we?
Jordan, I'm afraid you
have me by the short hairs.
I came here today hat
in hand to beseech you.
Show some mercy.
I'm almost tempted
to see this through
and let you rot in jail.
Almost?
So there's hope?
There's hope.
But it's going to cost you.
Name your price, sir.
I want to know if you're
connecting to the R&R or the M&M.
Prison it is then.
Ahem. I shall contact
the authorities now.
You'll be ruined, doc.
Your railroad snatched from you.
It's the R&R.
[Sighs]
When will you announce?
Friday.
You still have plenty of time.
Put everything you have into it.
You'll be a millionaire
by the end of the week.
Oh, but...
Don't tell a soul.
[Indistinct chatter]
Robert brought
this painting to London.
It was on display when
I went to see him lecture.
I'm sure you're sorry you ever left
the comfort of London after
what you've been through.
Soon, you will be returning
to your old life,
and your dreadful experiences out
there will seem like a bad dream.
The nerve of her.
Showing up with that Durant.
And look at her peacocking
around in that garish dress.
I'd like to give her a good drubbing.
[Gasping and giggling]
If she hadn't been there,
Robert may have been
able to save himself.
He killed that savage with his
dying breath so she could live.
I begged Robert not
to marry the woman...
Spoiled, pampered aristocrat.
Fair-haired maiden of the west.
Indeed.
Robert didn't kill
the savage, Charlotte.
I did.
You lying little brat.
Lily.
Hold your tongue, madam.
Robert did give his life saving me.
He is the reason I still draw breath,
but I didn't just stand
back and watch it happen.
We fought together,
side by side, just as we lived.
I wouldn't expect you to
understand that, Charlotte.
Robert fought hard,
but the Indian prevailed.
I watched him murder my husband,
and he would have killed me next.
But I tore an arrow from my shoulder
and thrust it through his throat,
and I pushed.
And I didn't stop pushing
until he was dead.
So that's your fair-haired
maiden of the west.
Lily...
I think it's time to go.
[Indistinct talking]
[Horse nickers]
Man: Right here.
Yeah, they've been gone for hours.
This is madness.
We're never going to catch 'em.
Shut the hell up.
We ain't done nothin' wrong.
If you guys had been
better at trackin',
we would have found 'em already.
Still warm.
Ambush!
[Gunshot]
[Horses neighing]
Ambush!
Where are they shooting from?
[Horse whinnies]
Uh!
[Horses neighing and men shouting]
[Gasps]
[Groaning]
[Gasps and gulps]
Am I dying?
Yeah.
Uh...
Will I... will I find
peace where I'm bound?
[Bubbling]
I don't know if men like us
ever find peace, Mr. Bolan...
In this world or the next.
[Groans]
But I hope so.
I really do.
[Birds calling]
[Footsteps]
What are you smiling at?
You empty.
[Clicks]
Any last words?
Go to hell, you black...
[Gurgling]
My name is Elam Ferguson.
You be sure to tell the Devil
that when he asks who killed you.
Why so glum, Jordan?
The stock could always recover.
I lost everything.
You still have your senator's salary.
This isn't over.
There's still the matter
of the missing $147,000.
Already back in the company's till.
Some strange sort
of accounting mistake.
People have already lost
their jobs over it.
Ahem.
And just to be sure,
I've applied grease to
all the proper machinery.
Rumor has it you made
3 million off the deal.
5.
I managed to buy the M&M
stock at quite a discount.
But don't tell a soul.
Thomas... please...
I have a family.
Don't worry, Jordan.
You're still of some use to me.
Well, in the meantime,
here's a shiny new penny for you.
[Chuckles]
Are you sure about this?
Yes.
But what will you do?
Where will you live?
I haven't figured it out yet.
I do know that I cannot
go back to London.
I cannot go back to
a life I now despise.
Then it's decided.
I knew you would understand.
Lily, there's something
I must tell you.
Thomas.
No, no, I must say this.
I am a man, and what I
have with my wife is...
It is not...
What a man needs.
Ours was always a practical marriage.
I mean, there was a time when...
Mmm.
But that time is past.
What I'm saying is if...
If I had a woman like you by my side,
then... no.
If I had you by my side, Lily,
there is nothing I...
We couldn't do together.
This isn't fair on you.
I know. I know that.
Don't say anything.
If there is a chance...
If there is the glimmer
of the faintest chance,
then you will make me
a very happy man.
[Train whistle blowing]
What about Toole?
He out in them woods
with a bullet in him.
They all dead?
Yep.
Found this in one of his saddlebags.
Ahem. You reckon I
should say something?
Suit yourself.
I don't really know my Bible verses.
23rd psalm.
"The Lord is my Shepherd.
"I shall not want.
"He maketh me to lie down
in the green pastures.
"He leadeth me beside
the still waters.
Both:
"He restoreth my soul.
"He leadeth me in paths of
righteousness for his name's sake.
"Yea, though I walk through
the valley of the shadow of death,
"I will fear no evil,
for thou art with me.
"Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
"Surely, goodness
and mercy shall follow me
"all the days of my life,
and I will dwell in
the house of the Lord forever."
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com