Previously on AMC's Hell on Wheels...
He raped and murdered my wife.
This is a pardon.
Get this railroad under control.
And the race is on, gentlemen.
***
You do not make exceptions to the law.
We must teach you the gospel principles.
Moving this town is more important
than finding the baby?
- Where's my baby?
- Can't tell you if he's dead, now, can he?
***
What do you know about him that I don't?
[Soft music]
♪ ♪
♪ I like to look for rainbows ♪
♪ whenever there is rain ♪
♪ and ponder on the beauty ♪
♪ of an earth made clean again ♪
♪ I want my life to ♪
♪ be as clean as earth ♪
♪ right after rain ♪
♪ I want to be ♪
♪ the best I can ♪
♪ and live with God again ♪
Here, you comb your hair,
- and I'll hold this for you.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
[Chuckles]
Nice.
And this one right here, eh?
Get the--that's nice.
Then you can put it
down like that, yeah?
Good boy.
[Laughs]
Yeah.
♪ I know when I am baptized ♪
♪ my wrongs are washed away ♪
♪ and I can be forgiven ♪
♪ and improve myself each day ♪
♪ I want my life ♪
Lord, pour out thy spirit
on thy servant.
♪ To be as clean ♪
That he may do this work
with holiness of heart.
♪ As earth right after rain ♪
I baptize thee...
♪ I want to be ♪
having authority
from the almighty God...
♪ The best I can ♪
as a testimony that ye have
entered into a covenant
to serve him until
you are dead.
- Mm.
- ♪ And live with God again ♪
And he will grant unto you
eternal life...
Ah!
Through the redemption
of Christ.
- [Laughs]
- I baptize thee--
- hold your nose.
- Yeah.
Papa?
[Gasps]
Oh!
Joseph!
[Crack]
Ah! Help!
Mr. Anderson?
Help!
[Grunting]
[Both panting]
Oh!
Run, Ez--
[crack]
Ezra!
I'll find you, Ezra!
Huh!
I always do.
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
[Crowd shouting]
What in the hell is going on?
[Blows landing, men grunting]
Ah!
[Grunts]
Come on, get off him.
Hold on!
Get off him!
What in the hell is going on?
Huh?
This cranky bastard
won't budge his animal!
[Mule brays]
He's holding up me wagons!
He won't move, Mr. Bohannon!
I tried.
[Mule brays]
[Grunts]
[Mule braying]
Ugh.
Son of a bitch!
What the hell?
Had a broke leg.
See that swole up ankle?
That's why it wouldn't move.
That mule cost me $50.
[Laughter]
Well, I'm sorry for your loss.
Help me get this animal
off the tracks.
Here. Unhitch this.
Unhitch that.
All right,
we're all gonna lift him.
And we're gonna swing him around
this way, okay?
- And...
- Well...
One...
I see nothing has changed
around here.
One less mule.
One more jackass.
Yes, well--
Is there something
you want to tell me?
No.
Mr. Bohannon.
I told you not
to come back here.
And I told you if I ever did,
it would signal a reversal
of fortune for you...
and here I am.
You Bohannon?
Grant, Ulysses.
For God's sakes, this man is
the next president
of the United States!
If you come looking
for my vote,
you've come a long way
for nothing.
And I was sure
that I'd carry Mississippi.
[Laughs]
[Laughter]
Well, uh, by order
of the court, this injunction.
It requires you to cease
and desist
all railroad operations
immediately,
pending the outcome
of our investigation.
You're shutting down
my railroad?
For starters, yes.
Can we at least move
the mule first?
Yes. Yes.
General.
All right.
Huh, yeah, it is.
Thank you.
Mr. Bohannon.
- [Laughs]
- The board of directors
for Credit Mobilier
is troubled by news
coming out of Hell on Wheels.
- What news is that?
- Allegations.
Unseemly to our cause,
and souring public opinion
of the railroad.
As a publicly held company,
dependent upon the government
for our operating capital,
it is incumbent upon this board
to restore public trust.
Best way to restore
public trust is to let me
- get on with the work.
- And we will,
just as soon as we determine
your fitness
to continue as chief engineer.
Mm-hmm.
And you bring
Ulysses S. Grant here,
to help you do that?
As you know, the general
serves as secretary of war,
and as such, is Washington's
representative.
You mean to grandstand
for them photographers outside?
I'll leave the grandstanding
to the former head
of the U.P., Mr. Bohannon.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, a criminal.
There's a good idea.
Five weeks ago,
an appeals court in New York
overturned the ruling
against Mr. Durant
for embezzling railroad funds,
so not only
is he not a criminal,
he has rejoined the board
of Credit Mobilier,
and remains
its chief stockholder.
Well...
I got me a town to move
and a railroad to build.
Ain't got no time
for a kangaroo court.
You should make time.
[Gavel bangs]
Mr. Durant,
you have the floor.
Thank you.
This is a competency hearing,
Mr. Bohannon,
not a court of law, and as such,
the board has instructed me
not to dwell on the murders
you committed,
but I shall, for the record,
enumerate them.
Uh...
November, 1865.
Four months after
the end of hostilities,
Captain Ebert Nelson,
formerly of the 13th Ohio,
gunned down in Dayton, Ohio.
Private Buckton Prescott
was killed
in a church in Washington, D.C.
Captain Daniel Johnson,
Union Pacific foreman,
murdered in Hell on Wheels.
I think we get the point, doc.
Nearly done, general.
Lieutenant Wuster,
Lieutenant Tanner,
sergeant Frank Harper,
all murdered,
and all attributed
to Cullen Bohannon,
as enumerated
in Miss Ellison's article.
Told you when I took this job
there's a lot of graves
- along this railroad, Mr. Ames.
- Yes.
But you didn't tell us
that you had murdered these men.
Ain't nobody misses 'em.
[Chuckles]
Well, be that as it may,
the board is here to ascertain
your character, Mr. Bohannon.
Your impropriety,
your penchant for violence,
your innate lack of judgment
is what's on trial here,
as the secretary will attest.
For the record, it's his men
done the murdering of my family.
General Grant is not
the subject of this inquiry.
- Maybe he ought to be.
- [Slams desk]
- You're out of order, sir!
- Calm down, senator.
I suggest a ten-minute break
before we call
our first witness, Mr. Chairman.
Ten-minute break.
[Gavel bangs]
[Applause]
Mr. Bohannon.
What did you mean when
you said General Grant's men
murdered your family?
Look, look, if I'm gonna write
the truth, I'm gonna need your--
What truth?
Yours, mine, or theirs?
The truth.
There's no such thing.
Hand off that pistol.
Nod if you understand me.
You promised that if
I provided you with information,
you'd protect me.
I came from nothing.
Did you know that?
[Sighs]
There is nothing
in my heritage, my people,
where they came from,
their place in the world,
to give me even
the slightest leg up
on what is to be my destiny.
The school of hard knocks
was my teacher.
And do you know what I learned?
If Mr. Bohannon finds out that
- I've been feeding you infor--
- That a man who is encumbered
by what's right and what's wrong
will never achieve anything.
Are you listening to me?
I am not encumbered
by what encumbers most men
because I am not most men.
I thought I saw
the same potential in you.
If I was mistaken...
you'll have no one
to blame but yourself.
I will remind you, Miss Ellison,
that you are under
a moral obligation
to tell the truth,
as you know it, for the benefit
of these proceedings.
I understand.
You have written numerous
articles about Mr. Bohannon
for the New-York Tribune
since your assignment
- in Hell on Wheels, haven't you?
- Yes.
You know him well?
I-I don't think anybody
knows him well.
Ah, well, keeps to himself,
does he?
- That's not what I meant.
- What did you mean?
Well, he's not
the chattiest person, and he's--
- A bully.
- No, I was going to say--
Didn't you write a story
about Mr. Bohannon's decision
to hang the hatch boy?
Yes.
You described Hell on Wheels
as a Sodom and Gomorrah
of the Nebraska plains,
with Mr. Bohannon as its lot.
Hmm.
Well, surely you don't condemn
the chief engineer
of the Union Pacific
for performing his duty
and punishing the murderer
of his chief of police?
You can, and you must,
if you're not certain
that the man
he lynched committed the crimes
for which he was hung.
Are you suggesting
that Mr. Bohannon,
in the name of
the Union Pacific,
hanged an innocent man?
The boy in question was
suspected of the transgression,
but no one was able to say,
definitively,
that he had done it.
I myself thoroughly examined
his skull in the aftermath,
and found nothing to suggest
criminal tendencies.
And the boy was, what, 17?
And quite devout, I understand.
Mr. Bohannon asked me
if I'd had occasion
to know what the Mormons
are like, as a people.
How they might react
to being forced off their land.
He asked me if I thought
they would fight.
Hmm, sounds like
he wanted to fight.
Not a fight.
It was a baby.
Along with Mr. Ferguson, sir.
And yet, it was Mr. Bohannon
who gave those young people,
your employee and her hapless
suitor, a pistol,
and bullets, and left them
to die in the wilderness.
He handed them a gun, yeah.
Did you witness
this inhumanity?
No, sir, um, but Mr. Bohannon
told me about it, yeah.
Ah.
- Bragging, no doubt.
- Bullshit.
Again, sir,
you're out of order.
Am I the only one who sees
what's going on here?
What, Mr. Bohannon?
A total mis-retelling
of events.
Decisions had to be made,
it fell to me to make them,
the railroad
had to move forward.
You're two weeks behind,
are you not?
Over the decision you made
not to move camp while you
searched for a whore's baby.
Or am I mis-retelling that?
These are complicated issues,
Mr. Bohannon,
with serious public
and fiduciary ramifications.
And as stockholders
of this company,
we have every right
to explore them,
whether you like it or not.
Hmm.
So you was a soldier, huh?
Where'd you fight?
I marched with Sherman.
In Mississippi?
What the hell you doing
out here?
Looking for railroad work.
[Gasps]
You ain't never did
no railroad work.
Was you with them boys
that killed Bohannon family?
You come here for revenge?
My brother was murdered,
in a church,
in Washington, D.C.?
- There needs to be a reckoning.
- Ain't gonna be none!
'Cause you gonna be gone.
[Locomotive chugging]
[Train whistle blows]
Mr. Ferguson...
is Mr. Bohannon,
formerly a killer--
uh, pardoned, by law,
for those sins--
still, in your opinion,
capable of killing a man?
I suppose he would kill
if another man tried
to kill him.
That was not the question.
Have you seen him kill a man?
Yes, or no?
Yes.
How recently, Mr. Ferguson?
Recent.
Eh, no more questions.
Thank you, Mr. Ferguson.
I move we clear the room,
go into executive session,
and vote on whether to retain
or relieve Mr. Bohannon
of his position.
All in favor of the motion?
Both: Aye.
Aye.
Here.
What is that?
A contract, binding you
to the railroad,
whether I'm here or not.
Bohannon.
[Train whistle blows]
[Sighs]
We're always the first to go.
The saloon and the...whorehouse,
the last.
Why do you suppose that is,
Mr. Bohannon?
Sin takes longer to pack.
Anything else you need?
I'm sorry for my part
in what happened today.
- No, you spoke honest.
- No, but I failed to tell--
I am who they say I am, Ruth.
I done every damn thing
they say I done.
My father once told me...
to put the past behind you,
you must accept that
you've moved beyond it.
I don't think you have,
Mr. Bohannon.
The truth is, until you do...
I'm not sure the railroad
can save you.
The point of this was
to get Bohannon out
and my son-in-law in.
You said Ames would go along
once he heard the evidence.
He didn't.
So how are you gonna fix this?
I am fixing it now!
If Delaney isn't running
this road
by the time Grant is elected,
we'll both end up
in Hudson prison.
I swear to God, if your family
did not own half
the Boston waterfront,
you would be working
in a fish shop!
Here!
What is this?
A backup plan.
And, if I may say,
a brilliant one.
Your son-in-law will be chief
engineer by the end of the day,
because Bohannon will resign.
Are you sure Bohannon
won't sign this?
[Chuckles]
So sure that I guarantee that
by this time tomorrow afternoon,
you and I will once again be
suckling on the railroad's teat!
We'd better be.
[Sighs]
So, you want me to sign
this piece of paper,
denying the things I done,
which you pardoned me of,
so you can tell people
I ain't done 'em.
And if I sign it,
I get to keep my job?
Killing ain't that easy
to put behind.
I don't expect men like these,
who bought themselves
out of the draft,
to understand what
I'm talking about, general,
but I reckon you do.
Killing ain't something
anyone is born to.
It's something we learn.
And you're the one who has
to live with it when it's done.
Hmm.
I done a lot of killing,
both during and after the war.
Mr. Durant
and Senator Metcalf here,
they'll call me a murderer
as it suits them.
But no matter
what they call it,
it won't bring back those men,
or my family.
Damn sure won't change
who I am.
You're refusing
to sign the statement?
I won't sign it
because it ain't true.
I'm a killer
and a railroad man.
You can't pick one without
choosing the other.
Like I said, I make no apologies
for my temperament.
- Mickey.
- Everything okay, Mr. Bohannon?
I have never been better.
The good stuff.
No, from underneath the bar.
Yes, sir, boss man, sir.
Ain't nobody's boss no more,
Mickey.
- Durant is.
- They fired you?
I quit.
What about the railroad?
Durant will finish it.
Shit, he started it.
Did you know when you fed me
the story about Mr. Bohannon's
involvement in those killings
that it would lead to this?
Justice?
You getting your railroad back.
History is never kind
to men like Bohannon.
Though that has nothing
to do with men like me.
So what's left
for a man like you?
The only and only thing
I ever truly wanted.
[Chuckles]
To be known as the man who built
the Union Pacific Railroad.
[Chuckles]
That's all?
[Laughs] Well...
that's quite enough, thank you.
Hmm.
Tell me something,
Miss Ellison.
Why aren't you further ahead?
You are the most
widely read journalist,
male or female, in the country.
What are you doing out here?
I go where the story takes me,
Mr. Durant.
No.
You did something
to get yourself excommunicated.
What was it?
Involved with the wrong man?
[Scoffs]
I'm here, as you already seem
to know,
because of one small,
unrequited indiscretion,
the sort of thing that wouldn't
have warranted an afterthought
were I a man.
Hmm, well...
I believe that, my dear,
is the crux of your problem.
I have met Miss Ida Greeley.
She's very fetching.
Were you a man,
I am sure that Mr. Greeley
would welcome whatever affection
you felt toward his daughter.
I wrote a story,
Mr. Durant.
As a result,
you got what you wanted.
Perhaps you could tell
a story for me now,
that would hasten my return
back to New York.
Take advantage
of my relationship
with Mr. Greeley, you mean?
Oh.
Would that I could,
Miss Ellison.
Would that I could.
[Western folk music]
♪ ♪
Whiskey, please.
We're closed.
- Closed?
- Mm.
Whatever she wants, Mickey,
on me.
No, no, no, no, no,
that's fine.
No, no, no, no,
you did your job.
She told the truth, Mickey.
I admire that.
If more people did that,
the world would be
a better place.
- Give us a second, will you?
- [Laughs]
To the truth.
And consequences.
You know how to two-step?
- Uh, yeah.
- All right, let's do it.
♪ ♪
[Laughs]
- All right.
- [Laughs]
- Ah! [Laughs]
- Whoa. [Laughs]
Oh--what was that?
- I don't know, but I liked it.
- [Laughs]
I ruin you, and you kiss me?
- I'm drunk.
- [Chuckles]
[Door opens]
Elam, I'm tired.
I got something
I wanted to tell you.
What?
Lookie here.
What is it?
Durant kicked Bohannon
off the railroad,
but this piece of paper mean
I still got a job,
- whether Bohannon here or not.
- Elam, I--
Hey, hey.
I ain't never expect
to have all this.
You, the baby,
the chief of police job.
I got a future.
But I want more than that.
I want a house, with steps...
and glass windows.
[Chuckles]
A little garden.
We got a girl.
I want a boy, too.
[Chuckles]
I want you to be mine, woman.
I want you to be my wife.
I want to marry you, Eva.
Proper like.
Elam.
You gonna marry me, then?
Elam...
yes.
[Grunts, groans]
[Gun clicks]
Turn around.
Slow.
Who are you?
Jasper Prescott.
Prescott?
You killed my brother.
Shot him dead in that church.
You come here to kill me?
Yes.
Anything I can say
to talk you out of it?
No.
[Gunshot]
I am sorry for your loss.
Recent advances
in cranioscopy have
proved that the human brain
is the seat of character,
general.
Phineas Gage proved that.
You may remember
that he was the--
Shouldn't you be getting back
to the fort, major?
Let me quote just one item
from the most recent
American Phrenological Journal.
I believe you will see the value
of craniometry in the building--
You may not.
Barkeep!
This beer or horse piss?
Actually, sir, we ran out
of our better dark lager
sometime last week.
[Groans]
- Mickey.
- Huh?
After what you've been
through today,
you've earned this.
I'll meet you back
at the train.
Mm.
[Exhales sharply]
- Yeah?
- Damn, I miss that.
You know the problem
with being me?
Can't be no worse
than being me.
Everyone knows I'm a drunk,
and I've been told you can't
make it to the white house
on the back of a pink elephant.
You mean you can't drink
in public?
Shit.
Well, may be best
you don't run for president.
[Sighs]
It's too late for that.
Well, general...
I think maybe you're in need
of a good snipe hunt.
I've been known to enjoy
a good snipe hunt now and again.
♪ I know when I am baptized ♪
♪ my wrongs are washed away ♪
♪ and I can be forgiven ♪
♪ and improve myself each day ♪
♪ I want my life
to be as clean ♪
♪ as earth right after rain ♪
♪ I want to... ♪
♪ look for rainbows
whenever there is rain ♪
♪ ponder on the beauty
of a land made clean again ♪
♪ I want my life
to be as clean ♪
♪ as earth after rain ♪
♪ I want to be the best I can ♪
♪ and live ♪
♪ with God again ♪
They call me, "The Butcher."
Did you know that, Bohannon?
Mm-hmm.
On account of the men
who died by my orders.
300,000 in all.
Men, fathers, sons, brothers.
All dead.
Thanks to me.
Of course, those who gave me
that moniker also thanked me,
publicly and privately,
for winning their ugly war,
and keeping them out of it.
Yeah.
[Chuckles]
- What?
- [Laughs]
What I wouldn't give to be this
close to you three years ago
- with a griswold in my hand.
- [Laughs]
That pistol was one damn
unreliable piece.
Mm.
Always worked when I needed it.
I consider myself lucky, then,
that your killing days
are behind you.
Yeah.
I need you to finish
this railroad,
not that shifty
sack of shit Durant.
I need a soldier
to win this battle.
I will pull whatever strings
I need to in Washington.
You reach Cheyenne in 20 days,
on time, on budget,
and I will convince congress
to reinstate you permanently
till you can join up with
Huntington and
the Central Pacific.
General, I--
[Sighs]
- What about Durant?
- You let me worry about Durant.
A northern general,
southern soldier,
working together to unify
these United States.
It's what the country needs.
[Laughs]
Well, where the hell
is Cheyenne?
I had the Bureau
of Land Management
rename the town of Durant
to Cheyenne.
- You renamed Durant's town?
- Yes, sir, I did.
[Laughs]
Oh!
Does he know yet?
- Nope.
- Can I tell him?
Only if you agree to my terms.
You're damn good.
That's why I won, son.
And that is why I will be
the next president
of the United States.
I'm smarter than I look.
Are you?
I don't know.
[Train whistle blows]
This train is for railroad
employees only.
You're fired.
[Locomotive chugging]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com