[ Horse whinnies ]
[ Music ]
Hey!
Hello?!
You need something?!
Sweet dreams, Sheriff!
It's a beautiful night
to be born!
[ Bird squawking ]
[ Static ] Ruby, it's me.
I think we have a dead body.
Ruby: Where?
I have no idea.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
[ door opens ]
Ruby: Morning, Sheriff.
Morning.
Reports of any deaths last night?
[ Door closes ]
Uh, no.
How about this morning?
No. Why?
You want there to be one?
Think I just got a tip.
You think? From who?
[ Sighs ] A Heyoka.
[ Chuckles ]
You mean the drunk guy
who walks backwards
around the square? That one?
Excuse me?
Cheyenne man
that lives in the area.
He's, uh, something of a, uh...
A head case.
Sacred clown.
Cheyenne call him
contrary warrior.
He, uh, does the opposite
of what you'd expect.
Why?
Tradition, mostly.
Seems the whole idea
is to get people
out of their comfort zones,
force them to examine
their beliefs.
That's annoying.
If I just heard him right,
we got a dead body somewhere.
Ruby: Walt.
I know you hate politics,
but pretending
there's a murder...
it's a strange way
of procrastinating
before the debate.
I'm not procrastinating.
Well, have you been preparing?
For the last decade.
Just got a call.
I guess your Heyoka was right.
Or would that be wrong?
We got a body.
That's not a body.
It's a skull.
Looks like some pottery, too.
Better call in the university
and the culture committee.
Could be a Cheyenne
burial site.
My first question is
who am I not going to
fire for this?!
Barlow, there are regulations
about these things.
Let's be reasonable.
I'm always reasonable,
which is why I am not
gonna stand around
funding an arrowhead Hunt!
I don't need you to be
doing this right now.
You want to be Sheriff?
Start acting like a Sheriff.
Make the problem go away.
[ Cellphone ringing ]
[ Beep ]
Vic, what's up?
Vic: Give me Walt.
No.
Damn it, branch,
just hand Walt the phone.
[ Sighs ] It's Vic.
Is that what my son
has grown up to be?
Walt Longmire's
personal assistant?
What are you gonna do
at the debate...
fetch him his coffee?
Branch, stay here.
Watch the site, and your father.
Where are you going?
Murder scene.
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Door creaks, Bell clangs ]
[ Footsteps approaching ]
Death card.
[ Sighs ]
You know, it's not
as sinister as it looks.
All it means is that
something's coming to an end.
Sometimes, it's a good sign.
Tell her that.
Bruises on her windpipe.
Busted capillaries
under her eyelids.
Looks like she was strangled.
Could be a robbery.
Could be.
No sign of forced entry,
though.
Yeah, of course,
nobody around here
ever locks their doors anyway.
Looks like Cassandra
had an open-do policy.
Anyone could have
walked in here.
It also looks like Cassandra
wasn't actually named Cassandra.
Cynthia Two Rivers.
I need to find
her brother, Aaron.
Vic: Why?
He rode past my cabin
this morning.
Seems strange to have
your tribe's contrary warrior
living in
an abandoned building.
It would be strange,
especially since the last
actual contrary warrior
died in 1974.
What does that make Aaron?
A pest... With pretensions.
[ Rattling ]
[ Aaron chanting indistinctly ]
Walt: Aaron,
your sister's dead.
That why you rode past
my cabin this morning...
to tell me?
No.
Your cabin rode past me.
[ Laughing ]
Aaron...
Walt is looking for
your sister's killer,
so cut the crazy-Indian act
for a minute and help.
Maybe...
I should follow your example...
And pretend
not to be Indian at all.
Red on the outside,
white on the inside.
Here, a shining apple
for your teacher!
Aaron, where were you
last night?
Home.
You are homeless.
Shining apple, so are you!
Aaron, if you can't give me
a straight answer,
I have no choice
but to arrest you.
How did you know
your sister was dead?
I-I walked to her place.
I looked inside, and...
Her body was there,
but she was not.
Did you kill her?
No! Did you?!
Stop it.
I need... I need to stand.
[ Grunts, groans ]
[ Clattering ]
Sheriff, I loved her.
[ Sighs ]
She was the only one
who believed in me.
[ Whimpers ]
You have to find who did this
and make them pay.
I'll do everything I can.
I believe you.
[ Pop ] Ahh!
You can never tell
when he is telling the truth.
He's just like
everybody else, then.
At least he's up front
about it.
Before I banned him
from The Red Pony,
Aaron Two Rivers
used to drink his fill
and walk out the door
backwards...
without paying.
His contrary act is less
charming than you think.
Sheriff!
Sheriff.
[ Breathing heavily ]
I was questioning...
The clients...
Who kept coming
into Cassandra's.
This one guy took off
as soon as he saw me.
Get his license-plate number?
No, just a good read
on his face.
Find him.
[ Pats back ]
Hey. Check this out.
So, there are five hidden mikes
in this room alone.
And if you follow the wires...
Cassandra taped her sessions.
And I can't find any tapes,
and I have searched everywhere.
Maybe that's what
the killer was after.
Calvin: No, I want...
I want to know what's going on!
I'm not...
Where's Cassandra? Cassandra?!
- Gretchen: Calvin!
- Ferg: Sir...
Cassandra, are you...
you can't go in there!
I just want to know...
where's Cassandra?!
That's all I want to know!
She's dead.
No!
She's only one
who knows where Emma is.
Gretchen: It's okay, baby.
[ Crying ] She's... she's the
only one who knows! I know.
This is Emma, our daughter.
What happened?
Two years ago, we went, uh...
Camping on the Blackwater river,
near Pensacola.
Gretchen was cooking,
and I was, uh,
reading some stupid article.
Calvin... so, I let her go...
To the river by herself.
She said, "bye,"
went out the camper forever.
The police ruled Emma's death
an accidental drowning.
We left Florida and moved here
a year ago to start over.
We started hearing stories
about Cassandra,
that she could
locate Cheyenne graves
by contacting the dead.
At... at first,
a-all I wanted was Cassandra
to tell Emma that I was sorry,
but on our first session,
she told me that she...
[ Sniffles ]
Did she tell you your daughter
was still alive?
Yes.
[ Breathing heavily ]
I mean, no one saw her
go into the river.
A-a body was never recovered.
I mean, it's possible,
you know?
Walt: How often have you
come back to Cassandra
since she told you this?
Gretchen: Once or twice a week.
She asked us to bring in
objects connected to Emma,
so we've been bringing in
clothes, jewelry...
Diaries.
To help her locate
your daughter.
Cassandra said
that Emma was somewhere
[sniffles] In the woods
in the northeast.
I mean, we're so close,
Sheriff.
That's what makes this so hard.
Gretchen: Cassandra
called us last night.
She had another vision.
Yeah, we thought today
might be the day.
Did you...
You know,
see anything written down
about Emma
or anything like that?
Not yet.
[ Sighs ]
It's okay, yeah. Okay.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Sighs ]
Ferg said none of the neighbors
saw or heard anything,
but no one answered over here.
[ Knock on door ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
[ Sighing ] What now?
There's a killer on the loose,
and no one's answering, so...
better make
a public-safety check.
[ Scraping ]
[ Coughs ]
Vic: Holy shit.
Who would want to
live like this?
Apparently, our murder victim.
This is Cassandra's place, too?
So she's a psychic
and a hoarder?
I don't think Cassandra's
simply a hoarder.
Medical, legal records,
uh, background checks.
This looks like research.
We research our subjects.
Maybe psychics
do the same thing.
Maybe our victim simply
investigated her clients
and passed it off as psychic.
Well, if she did,
then she could have
learned something
that she shouldn't have.
Like maybe a husband...
Cheating on a wife?
There's a lot of secrets here.
Which means a lot of suspects.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
Well, will you look at this?
Now, this is why they say
it can take months
to properly assess
a burial site.
Jacob Nighthorse,
what in the hell
are you doing on my land?
Well, I'm representing
the tribal council, Barlow,
and the Cheyenne
culture committee.
And, of course,
you know if this turns out
to be a significant finding,
the remains
will have to stay put,
and you'll need to build
around them.
This is the 15th hole,
and I can't have a teepee
in the middle of the damn fairway.
Dad.
Let me ask you something.
When you're building
your casino,
do you stop digging
every time you run across
some of my people's garbage?
You were directly warned
about this land, were you not?
Well, if I paid attention
to every kook came my way,
I'd be out in the desert
right now
with tinfoil on my head.
Wait... what's this
about a warning?
Oh, this Cheyenne gal
came into a planning meeting,
said she had a vision
of Indian remains on my land.
[ Scoffs ]
Her name wasn't Cassandra,
was it?
I think so. Why?
Looks like someone
strangled her last night.
[ Sighs ]
So, I'm g-guessing
we aren't just thoughtfully
giving people
their things back.
When a client comes in, we'll
ask them their name, address,
when was their last appointment,
and what about.
That should give us
a timeline and suspect pool.
Ruby: Walt, could I talk to you
in your office?
Just for a minute.
Oh, dad, I found
your dress khakis
in the back
of the cabin closet.
They look brand-new.
That's 'cause
I've never worn them.
And if you show up at
the town hall looking like that,
you might never
get a chance to, either.
That mean you're gonna
vote for me?
That depends on how you do
in the debate.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
These are some of the questions
you'll be fielding
at the debate.
I thought the questions were
supposed to be impromptu.
Nothing is impromptu.
The voters will be asking
both candidates hard questions.
It would be better
if you were prepared.
Think of it as leveling
the playing field.
I can win this thing
fair and square.
Fair and square like Walt...
sticking you out here
babysitting your father
while he preps?
[ Cellphone ringing ]
You better answer that.
I'm sure Walt wants to
keep you distracted.
[ Sighs ]
Hey, Ruby.
Where?
I'm on my way.
So, where is
he sending you now?
Just give me
the damn questions.
[ Engine turns over ]
This is Walt's plan, huh?
Having me deal with
one tedious task after another
while he gets ready
for the debate?
This tedious task
is called police work,
and Walt didn't tell Ruby
to send you here.
I did, because I'm drowning
in this shit.
So, what are you doing?
Looking.
For what?
Something worth killing for.
Failing that,
an appointment book
would be great.
All right. Can I help you?
Do you have your I.D.?
Yes.
Walt.
That's the guy who ran.
Baseball helmet.
Name and address, please.
Phil Capps...
1909 packard place.
Okay. When did you last
see Cassandra?
Four days ago. Good.
Why'd you run off today when
you saw my deputy? What?
People flee a murder scene,
there's usually a reason.
I didn't flee.
I was embarrassed.
Riggs passed away
six months ago.
He was the only
real family I had.
[ Sighs ] Every week,
I made an appointment
to talk to him.
I guess that's over.
You can always go
to another psychic.
I've tried.
They're a bunch of frauds.
But Cassandra was different.
She was the real deal.
When she contacted
my grandpa Joe,
he told her when he died,
when he married grandma,
everything.
How else could she know?
There's no appointment book,
but...
I did find
the financial ledger.
Should give us a client list,
a larger suspect pool.
[ Chuckles ]
What's so funny?
You just never know
who's gonna get fleeced
by a drunken con artist.
Prejudiced much?
About what?
Psychics get paid
to take wild guesses.
People are so needy,
they read into it
like it's some kind of gift.
Check Cassandra's finances.
She had a gift, all right...
gift for leveraging mortgages
on both her houses
and running up huge bills
at bars and liquor stores.
Maybe she was self-medicating.
What, you... you actually
believe in this stuff?
Like you've never
had your cards read?
Vic, I'm a guy... in Wyoming.
The only cards I have read
are at the poker table.
[ Scraping ]
Paneling's not nailed down
all the way.
[ Sighs ] Hey, Kenny Rogers,
give me a hand.
[ Grunting ]
What the hell?
[ Sighs ]
This is, like,
the entire county.
Asha Little Wolf...
Kishori Crowfoot... those are
Cheyenne names, aren't they?
Sound like it.
Look... there's a birth
and a death date.
Could be maps
of Cheyenne graves.
Why go to this much trouble
just to hide this?
It's always dangerous to know
where the bodies are buried.
[ Sighs ] [ Knock on door ]
What do you make of those...
Wow. Don't.
No, wouldn't dream of it.
We need to figure out
who Drew up these maps and why.
Maybe it was Cassandra.
Spirits could have guided her.
I mean, that's what her clients
would think, right?
Some more than others.
According to this ledger,
Gretchen and Calvin Cowley
spent a small fortune
looking for their daughter.
There's no one more desperate
than the parent
of a missing child.
You think Cassandra took advantage
of that and the Cowleys snapped?
You know, I haven't found
their file yet.
That could have been
what was taken.
You searched the whole house?
Yes.
No. Keep searching.
Have Ferg dig deeper
into the Cowleys' finances.
Jacob: You wanted to see me.
How are things progressing
at the burial site?
Could be an important finding.
Construction will have to hold
while we expand the dig.
Let me know if Barlow
gives you any trouble.
I appreciate
the unexpected support.
Jacob, uh...
I actually called you in
to discuss something else.
A murder.
I understand you visited
a psychic recently...
Cassandra.
I did. I did, indeed.
Like many people,
I have a desire
to stay in touch
with my ancestors.
Yeah. How many times
you visit her?
Two or three times.
Imagine it's quite
an experience
speaking to the dead.
So, which is it...
two or three?
Three. Why does it matter?
That way, I can tell
if she was charging you
$6,000 or $9,000 an hour.
There's a line item here
said you paid her 18 grand.
So what were you really
paying her for?
[ Sighs ]
Psychic geological surveys.
Cassandra walked my casino land,
searching for remains.
She found none, so I built.
That was money well spent?
It was, and I bet you
Barlow Connally
wishes he'd done the same.
If I were you, I'd speak to him
about the murder.
You don't need second sight
to see the anger in that man.
And, by the way,
I like the uniform.
It makes you look like someone
worth voting for.
Man: Deputy Connally,
do you feel your family's
business in the area
will create
a conflict of interest
for you as Sheriff?
Branch: Good business
is good news for our county.
Now, I'm sure
many of you remember
my Uncle was once Sheriff.
And like lucien,
I am my own man.
And I were pushed to choose
between our county's
best interests
and my father's profit margins,
trust me, I'll choose
Absaroka every time.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
My question
is for Sheriff Longmire.
Sure.
[ Clears throat ]
Sheriff, is it true that
you're afraid of technology
and you don't even
own a cellphone?
I wouldn't call it fear.
[ Feedback ]
I'm s... [ Feedback ]
As I just, uh,
ably demonstrated,
sometimes technology
is more of a distraction
than a help, so...
[ Crowd chuckling ]
Well, I will vote for you
early and often,
but I was pulled over
by this foul-mouthed
blonde lady last month,
and it turns out
she's not even from here.
Why are you taking jobs away
from Wyoming residents?
Sheriff, I'm very sorry
about the passing of your wife.
Thank you.
But didn't she lead a movement
to stop the building
of the casino?
Yes. She did.
My wife, Martha, was concerned
about the influence
of the casino
on local culture and crime.
So, does that mean you're
gonna play "I told you so"
every time there's a crime
connected to the casino?
Not at all...
my department will provide
the same protection
after the casino opens
as it did before.
With just four people?
[ Crowd murmuring ]
The new casino will bring
tens of thousands of newcomers
to Absaroka County.
This will bring
new opportunities
but also new challenges.
Now, I've discussed
a security action plan
with Jacob Nighthorse.
And in this plan,
the casino would hire
a private security firm
that would coordinate
with my department,
keeping our area safe
while creating good local jobs.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
My question's
for the challenger.
I look forward to it.
Deputy Connally, uh,
you've been a deputy
for a short time.
What experience
has prepared you
to better serve
and protect our county
over your opponent?
Yee-yee-yee-ooh! Whee-hoo!
[ Crowd screaming ]
Whoo-whoo!
Whoo-whoo! Whoo-whoo!
I'm the real Sheriff
of this county,
and you are all
under arrest for murder!
[ Cackling ]
You may be wondering
why this drunken clown
interrupted my brilliant
debate performance.
Aaron, why did you
interrupt the debate?
Indians hate
watching massacres.
[ Laughs ]
A-and you seem
more interested in politics
than catching
my sister's killer.
We may have uncovered
what your sister's killer
was looking for.
Cassandra told me
these were lost,
but you can never get
a straight story out of her.
How did Cassandra
put these maps together?
She have a vision?
My sister had a talent
for reading people,
but the thunder spirit
did not reside in her.
She did not have vision.
Then how were these maps made?
When I was a boy...
Grandma go go drove
all over the place,
taking down every Cheyenne
grave marker she could find.
For every grave,
she Drew a map.
Why?
I believe that was
when Cheyenne graves
were being ransacked
for artifacts.
You can't rob graves
you can't find.
Who knew your sister
had these maps?
Nobody among the living.
Is that the truth, Aaron,
or another one of your riddles?
You tell me, shiny apple.
Or maybe you can't
tell the difference between
a shiny lie
and the plain truth.
Shiny lie!
Hey! Hey!
[ Cackles ] Shiny lie!
Shiny lie! Aah! Aah!
Henry! Aah!
Perhaps he will fall upward.
[ Sighs ]
You gonna arrest
Cassandra's brother?
Walt: I have him in a cell.
I'll let him go
once he sobers up.
Hey, Vic, it's Ferg.
Checking out
the Cowleys' finances.
Their search for Emma looks like
it's about to bankrupt them.
Could be motive. Have you found
the Cowleys' box or file?
Not yet. They never came by the
station to claim anything.
Cassandra had her clients
bring in their
most prized possessions.
Maybe we should start looking
at people who aren't coming in.
Call if we have something.
Yeah, me too.
[ Beep ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Doorknob rattling ]
[ Wood creaks ]
Hey! Don't move!
[ Gasps, breathing heavily ]
Walt: Why did you break
into Cassandra's house?
Curiosity.
We know you and Calvin
have paid a lot of money
hoping to find your daughter.
I also have some evidence
that Cassandra
might be a fraud.
And if she lied to you
about Emma being alive,
nobody would blame you
for being angry.
I caught on to Cassandra's con
pretty early.
One time, she tried
describing Emma to us.
I recognized the language...
it was from a news article,
nearly word for word.
Why not call her on it?
I couldn't do that to Calvin.
Before we met Cassandra,
he was suicidal.
But with her, he had hope,
something to live for.
So you paid Cassandra
to lie to your husband?
I had to decide
what I loved more...
Calvin or the truth.
It wasn't that hard.
Where's Calvin right now?
Fiddler's tap room
out on highway 12.
Drinking.
So, why were you
in Cassandra's house, really?
I was hoping to get rid of any
research connected to Emma.
What do you think
Calvin would do
if he knew Cassandra
was a fraud?
He wouldn't kill her,
if that's what you're asking.
Calvin doesn't own a gun.
He's never even fired one.
Cassandra wasn't shot.
She was strangled, silenced.
I just called the tap room.
They haven't seen Calvin
all day.
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts ]
Mrs. Cowley,
where's your husband?
I don't know.
[ Inhales sharply ]
He took off
after we talked to you.
If your husband figured out
the truth about Cassandra...
He needs our help.
Hi.
So, I found another box for you
to add to your collection.
What's inside?
I don't know.
I didn't think it was
my place to look.
[ Car door closes ]
Jacob: Tell me something.
Why did I find myself
in Walt's office this morning,
being questioned
about a murder?
I knew you could talk your way
out of that ledger,
but I found something else
you couldn't
talk your way out of.
What is that?
Maps of Cheyenne graves,
which are now
in Walt's possession...
all except two.
My father's
golf course development
and this casino property.
According to these,
there weren't actually
any remains on my father's land.
But there were bodies buried
right here on yours.
Well, that's interesting.
Did you pay off Cassandra
to move those remains
from your property
place them on my father's?
I was right about you.
You will make
one hell of a Sheriff.
I know, but that wasn't
the question.
A few months ago,
Cassandra warned me
about bodies on this land.
If I didn't pay her, she said,
she'd start having visions
in public.
So it was a shakedown.
For about five minutes.
Then I offered her
10 times what she was asking.
All she had to do
was make those remains
and I got to say, that's some
impressive Detective work.
Actually...
I'll hold onto these for now.
Level the playing field.
There's no chance
that Cassandra got greedy...
Tried to blackmail you?
Do you have an alibi
for the night of her murder?
I am my alibi.
If I had killed Cassandra,
you wouldn't have found
a ledger with my name on it
inside her house.
In fact,
if I were to kill someone,
I suspect
no one would ever find
trace or trail of the crime.
[ Sighs ]
Enjoy the rest
of your night, deputy.
And do watch your step.
Vic: I found
our missing husband.
[ Sighs ]
Calvin Cowley. Where is he?
Sheridan... he just put
a charge on his credit card
for Mama Tia's
psychic readings.
Looks like
he's still a believer.
Which makes it unlikely
he killed Cassandra
out of, uh, disillusioned rage.
Just like everybody, he loved
Cassandra, the drunken grifter.
Show some respect.
What did I say?
[ Sighs ] I'm just getting
a little tired of everybody
piling on the victim.
People found comfort in her,
and I seriously doubt
that she was an alcoholic.
Branch told you about
her credit-card charges.
Yeah... bars and liquor stores.
But I have spent the last
I don't know how many hours
in Cassandra's house.
How many alcoholic hoarders
do you know
that have exactly zero bottles
in their house?
[ Sighs ]
Cassandra's clients...
they love her.
Maybe it wasn't a client.
Maybe she told someone something
they didn't want to hear.
You here to arrest me?
You didn't answer my question.
You gonna place me
under arrest?
Depends.
Where were you two nights ago
when that psychic was murdered?
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
After everything
I've given to him,
my son still has the gall
to come into my house
and accuse me of murder.
Now, if you think I did it,
just come out and say so.
Dad, just tell me
where you were.
Well, let's see.
Uh, I was just about where
you are right now, actually.
Doing what?
A 26-year-old stewardess
with daddy issues.
Eh.
[ Clear throat ]
That's a little
too much information,
but that's all
I needed to know.
No. No, no, no.
You do not get away that easy.
Now, tell me, son,
where are you getting
all the cash
for these campaign ads?
It's not my money.
I know it's not your money.
But then, it's never been
your money, has it?
I have allies and supporters.
You mean you have investors,
who will be impatient
for their returns.
Is that why my golf course
is indefinitely delayed?
Jacob Nighthorse pays
for a few commercials,
and you throw the old man
under the bus?
Actually,
I now have the leverage
that would force Nighthorse
to remove those remains
so construction can
start back up again.
Good. Use it.
I need something
from you first.
And what would that be?
My coffee.
[ Car door closes ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
[ Aaron chanting ]
Hello, Aaron.
Your sister, uh,
made a living selling lies.
You were ostracized
for serving the truth.
You must have appreciated
the irony.
Ironically enough, I didn't.
Aaron, tell me what happened.
I need you to drop
the contrary act.
I can't.
I had the thunder dream.
I have to obey
the thunder spirit.
I used to think
it was my calling.
It's my curse.
I think I understand.
What are you doing?
[ Metal scrapes ]
[ Grunts ]
Sheriff...
I'm here to turn myself in
for the murder of my sister,
Cassandra.
But why...
Would you kill your own
flesh and blood, Aaron?
My sister was paying bar tabs,
liquor-store bills
all over the county,
including at The Red Pony.
Wasn't her drinking
she was paying for.
It was mine.
Two nights ago, she found me
ransacking her house...
Looking for money.
She told me
she was cutting me off.
Actually...
First, she told you
she was cutting you off,
then you started throwing
and breaking things.
Yes, because it meant
no more alcohol.
And she knew
that was the only thing
that quieted the voices
in my head.
But it was never
about the booze, was it?
Your sister told you
that you never
had the thunder dream,
that you are not
a contrary warrior,
that you're nothing more than
a paranoid schizophrenic
who needs clinical help.
You heard the one person
you thought actually
believed in you say, "no."
She said she was gonna
have you institutionalized,
and you snapped, didn't you?
I would do anything
to take it back.
But I can't.
And now I must face
what I have done.
It is my sacred duty
to serve the truth.
Aaron Two Rivers...
You're under arrest.
[ Handcuff clicks ]
[ Crying ]
I need to talk to Gretchen
and Calvin Cowley
about their daughter.
Walt: How do you know
about the Cowleys?
[ Tires screech ]
[ Door creaks ]
Sheriff, what are you
doing here?
Who is this?
Cassandra's brother.
He asked to speak to you
about your daughter.
Is that okay?
Yes, please.
I talked to my sister...
About Emma.
She told me she was in Vermont,
outside Burlington...
In a blue house.
Was that the truth?
Would you believe it if it was?
[ Car door opens ]
Hey, dad.
Hi.
You said you had
something to show me.
What is it?
I don't know yet.
Vic, uh, found this
among the possessions
of a dead psychic.
Well, I have
a hard time believing
that you ever visited
a psychic.
[ Sighs ] I didn't.
But it appears
that your mom did.
[ Click ]
Do you want to hear this?
Martha: To be honest,
I normally would
never come here.
But things
have changed in my life.
Cassandra: The spirits say,
if you're asking
whether or not
the cancer will kill you,
their answer is...
No, it will not.
I just got my diagnosis
two days ago.
They say it's terminal.
How could you even know?
Is there anything else
you would like the spirits
to tell you?
Yes. My husband, Walt...
what will happen to him?
You truly want to know?
Yes.
The spirits say...
[ gasps ] [ Click ]
I guess we'll find out
soon enough.
[ Crickets chirping ]
Sync and corrections by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com