Previously on Longmire...
- How'd you find me anyway?
- I used to be a cop.
Seems like you're
just asking for trouble.
Well, you'd know a lot about that
wouldn't you Moretti?
I didn't donate $100,000 to your campaign
because I like your smile.
I promised Henry I'd get out the vote.
A lot of people on the Res don't have cars.
[Siren wails]
Your ex girlfriend is in critical
condition after getting hit by a car.
You didn't have anything to do
with Cady's accident, did you?
Don't look back. It's better to keep
your eyes down the road.
Man: The cowboy has always been
a dying breed.
But he takes his dying slowly,
perched upon his steed.
The prairie is his prison,
his church, his wife.
And if you take away his sky,
you take away his life.
Yet, where does he go
when the ranges all have closed?
Does he retire to his bunkhouse
in depressed repose?
No, he climbs
back in that saddle,
if just to bide his time.
The cowboy knows
a good death...
Is hard to find.
Longmire 02x12
A Good Death is Hard to Find
Originally Aired August 19, 2013
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com
Thanks.
[ Bells jingle ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Clears throat ]
Ed.
Branch: All the bank manager
could tell me
was that the safety deposit box
was rented to a man
named James Notley.
And Notley's will said
that when he died,
they had to deliver this box
to the Absaroka County Sheriff.
Ruby?
Ruby: Check our records
for James Notley. Already on it.
James Notley sent this here
for a reason.
Ferg, you got any salt?
Uh... I think so.
[ Sighs ]
You want the pepper, too, or...
Nope.
Just the salt.
Branch, hand me your water.
You making a saline solution?
Let the finger soak
for a few hours,
we'll be able to hydrate it
and get a print off it.
Ruby: James Notley's been
in the state penitentiary
since 1989.
Lucian arrested him
for armed robbery.
I guess I better
go talk to Lucian.
Come on, Branch.
Let's go shake your family tree.
The ideal woman
is like a good cowboy stew...
Meaty and saucy
and easy to chew.
Her spuds should be yummy
without being gummy,
and her scent should never
turn your face blue.
Lucian...
[ Applause ] We need to talk.
Good, 'cause this here boy's
a few iambs short
of a full pentameter anyway.
Can we use your office?
And miss all this?
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Man: Now for the pivotal
middle portion
of my love-struck cowboy
limerick triptych.
[ Applause ]
I want to know
about James Notley.
[ Sighs ]
Who?
James Notley.
You arrested him, 1989.
Along with plenty other men.
- You need to be more specific, Walt.
- Armed robbery.
Nope.
Still can't place him.
Too many French fries.
- What?
- Trans fats.
Causes brain shrinkage,
therefore memory loss.
I read about that
in an issue of neurology.
James Notley sent me
a severed finger today.
That trigger any memories?
You know, Walt, folks weren't
so chatty back in my day.
I may have had to shorten
many a man's finger.
You chopped off fingers?
Seriously?
Hell, boy, it was the '70s...
Watergate, women's lib.
All bets were off.
This arrest was made in 1989.
James Notley.
Armed robbery.
Missing finger.
Oh!
Yes.
Notley.
Right.
Synapses are firing now.
Yep.
I arrested that man
for stealing dinosaur bones.
Excuse me.
[ Dialing ]
[ Keyboard clacking ]
Ed: Hello?
Ed!
It's Vic Moretti.
How are you?
Deputy Moretti,
I was just thinking about you.
You and your wife aren't still
in Durant, are you?
'Cause Sean
just got back to town.
We could go to dinner
at the Red Pony.
Oh, thanks for the invite.
We headed back to Philly
a few weeks ago.
[ Chuckles ]
That's too bad.
Well...
we'll have to take
a rain check, huh?
Yes, we will.
Take good care of yourself.
You, too, Ed.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
[ Keyboard clacking ]
Distance from caller...
8 1/2 Miles.
[ Buzzer ]
Hank: A lot of these prisoners
will hold it in until rec time,
so they can... unload
with a little privacy.
That's what James did,
and he was stabbed 13 times
mid-delivery
and just two weeks away
from his release.
- You find out who did it?
- No.
I don't think we will, either.
Someone covered the lens
of that security camera,
and this place is packed
with killers, literally.
James have any enemies?
Not that I know of.
But if he made eye contact
with the wrong maniac,
that's all it would take.
Hell, if one of these lifers
knew James
was gonna be released,
he may have gone all stabby
out of spite.
The D.O.C. usually handles
prison deaths, sheriff.
And you're from the other side
of the state.
Why are you so interested
in James Notley?
Actually, James seemed to take
an interest in me.
He had a package, uh,
sent to my office.
I'm trying to figure out why.
He have any recent visitors?
Let me take a look.
According to our records,
his only recent visitors
are this Connie Mallery,
who I assume
to be his girlfriend,
and... you.
Me?
Log-in says you were here
exactly one week ago.
Can I take a look at that?
You are the sheriff
of Absaroka County, right?
Lucian.
You said you didn't remember
James Notley.
Prison records say you visited
him just a week ago.
Well, I guess my memory's
worse off than I thought.
I doubt that.
You know,
you and I have been playing
this here match
for nigh on to six weeks now.
Right now I need you
to answer my questions.
Only if you play this game.
Get up.
Okay.
[ Clears throat ]
Tell me about James Notley.
That man was a pain in my ass.
He smuggled dinosaur bones
out of the state of Wyoming
and sold them overseas.
Ergo, he was a rank opportunist
and a speed bump on the road
to scientific progress.
So, how does a speed bump
manage to smuggle dinosaur bones
out from under your nose?
Well, in the summer of 1989,
the university dug up
a complete skeleton
of a Triceratops.
It was valued at $800,000.
And Notley waited
until they crate the thing up.
Shows up at the university,
forced some grad student
at gunpoint
to load the crates into a van.
About a week later,
I get him to confess.
By cutting that off?
By busting
the bastard's alibi, nephew!
Anyway, he had all his fingers
when I saw him last week.
As I recall,
the two middle ones
seemed particularly healthy
and robust.
Why the visit?
Nostalgia?
Money.
By the time
I'd arrested Notley,
he had already unloaded
them fossils,
but there was no sign
of the cash he made off of 'em.
And I knew
he'd stash it someplace.
I just offered to go 50/50.
The 800 grand?
No.
On the finder's fee.
And as I told Notley,
a finder can command up to,
I don't know,
50% of any missing money
he finds.
Why would James
want to give you half of 50%?
Because he knew
I'd either find the money
or find him with the money.
And either way, he'd be screwed
as a cat in a dog pound.
Some people
would call that blackmail.
And some people can kiss
my once-magnificent rump.
So, why'd he send the finger?
I don't know.
As a souvenir?
From what?
Night of the robbery.
Vic: There you are.
[ Siren wails ]
[ Honking ]
[ Tires squeal ]
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
I thought I was doing
the speed limit, deputy.
You told me
you were in Philadelphia.
Yes, I did.
Careful.
I said I was in Philly
because I was afraid
something like this might happen
if you knew I was here.
Honestly, Moretti,
the last time we met,
you creeped me out.
It's not like
I broke into your car.
You okay?
You seem a little paranoid.
What are you doing
in Durant, Ed?
Ahh [Sighs]
Something about this place.
A lot to live for here.
Besides,
I'm pretty sure I can go
absolutely anywhere I want to.
Are you sure you're okay?
You seem a little tightly wound.
That is a natural reaction
to being stalked!
Wow.
That's funny,
because it feels like
you're stalking me.
I mean, how did you, uh,
know where to find me, huh?
Triangulate my cellphone?
[ Chuckles ] You did.
Okay.
There's no easy way
to say this,
but I don't want you
to contact me again.
You're making me feel
uncomfortable.
And, quite frankly,
pretty violated.
[ Grunts ]
Have a nice day.
[ Breathing heavily ]
Nope, sorry. No.
Conference hours are over.
Professor Tony Moten?
I'd like to talk to you
about James Notley.
It was after 2:00 A.M.,
and we had brought
the Triceratops in
earlier that afternoon.
And as a doctoral candidate,
it was my job to sort
and catalogue the vertebrae.
How did James Notley get in?
I opened the door.
Why?
He knocked.
What happened then?
Look, this was 24 years ago,
and it's taken me just about
as long to get over it.
Why are you asking me
to do this all over again?
James Notley is due to be released
from the state prison in about a week.
You think he still blames me
for his arrest?
That's hard to tell.
I opened the door.
A guy in a ski mask comes out.
He's got his gun in my face.
He tells me that he's gonna take
bones with him,
whether they're mine
or the dinosaur's.
It's up to me to decide.
I tried to stall him.
The next thing I know,
he's got my arm pinned
to this table here.
He pulls out a pocketknife,
and he cuts off my finger.
It took him three times
to get it all the way off!
Did he have anyone else
with him?
Not that I saw, no.
[ Smacks lips ]
You asked if James Notley
still blamed you
for his arrest.
Why?
I described the pocketknife
that he had to the sheriff,
and I think
that's what got him convicted.
So, what'd he do
with your finger?
I don't know.
I was just focused
on trying to survive.
It's pretty convenient
that James robbed them
on the same day
they brought in the skeleton.
Dr. Moten might have been
James' inside man.
If he was,
means he had his own finger
cut off for cover.
Might've been worth it.
My Uncle said that skeleton
was worth 800 grand.
Split that two ways,
I'd say it's still worth
a finger.
And if your partner
gets murdered in prison,
you wouldn't have to share
the money at all.
Well, maybe that's why
James had the finger sent in...
To point the finger
at his partner.
"Point the finger."
That was a joke.
[ Smacks lips ] I know it was.
So, what do we have?
A smudge or a partial print.
Are Dr. Moten's,
uh, prints on file?
Yeah.
He was booked on a D.U.I.
five years ago, so, yeah.
But just nine prints.
So, that could be
Moten's finger.
Walt: Yeah,
or someone else's entirely.
I know my Uncle said
James Notley had all his fingers
when he saw him,
but Lucian and the truth...
They have sort of an
on-and-off-again relationship.
All right, then, Ferg...
Uh, find out which funeral home
James Notley's body
was sent to.
See if the mortician
noticed any missing fingers.
[ Insects chirping ]
[ Dog barks in distance ]
[ Lock clicks ]
[ Water running ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Door opens ]
Hey.
Trouble at home?
Ferg: Hey, Walt,
the mortician said
that James Notley
had multiple stab wounds,
but he still had all...
of his fingers.
Mortician say anything else?
Yeah, that, uh,
Notley's funeral...
Is in about an hour.
Want to come to a funeral
with me?
Might cheer you up.
I'll take you up
on the next one.
God entrusts us
with the miracle of life.
Thus, we must trust
God's wisdom.
We live in an imperfect world.
We're tested.
What are you doing here?
Sheriffing.
What are you doing?
Well, just burying
one more S.O.B.
I'm happy to have outlived.
Sometimes you've got to take
a moment to smell the roses.
Is that James' girlfriend,
Connie Mallery?
Yep.
You planning on talking to her?
Well...
I need to find out
what she knows
about James Notley
and a possible partner of his.
Walt, if Notley had a partner,
I'd have smoked him out by now.
Let's talk to Connie anyway.
If you want her to talk,
don't take me.
- Why?
- Notley claimed
he was with Connie
the night of the robbery.
When I... tricked her
into admitting otherwise,
it busted his alibi,
put him in prison.
All these long years later,
she still ain't talking to me.
So, did Sheriff Connally
send you here?
I've told that man for 20 years
I don't know where James
hid the money, okay?
I'm just trying to figure out
what James
was trying to tell me.
He, uh...
He sent a safe deposit box
to my office,
delivered after he died.
What was in it?
A finger.
I don't know whose it is
or why James sent it to me.
Do you?
Oh, good Lord, no.
Do you know
if James had a partner?
If he did, he never told me.
Did he ever mention
the name Tony Moten?
Well, he was the guy
who was involved in the robbery,
but James and I really never
talked about him.
We only talked
about the future.
[ Voice breaking ]
But the last time,
we barely talked at all.
We got in this fight,
and I walked out.
It was just so stupid.
[ Sniffles ]
What did you fight about?
You know, he was...
He was this close
to getting released,
and... he was miserable.
He just kept getting
more and more paranoid
and saying that he was never
gonna get of there alive
that someone was
gonna screw him over.
Did he say who?
No.
[ Sniffles ]
I, of course, thought
he was imagining things.
This has always been
his favorite dress of mine.
Been waiting 24 years to wear it again.
I thought it'd be a happy day.
[ Sighs ]
Everything okay?
Not really.
You want to tell me
what's going on?
I used to be a brunette.
I dyed it blond
when we first moved here.
And we didn't just move here
for Sean's work.
We also moved here
for, uh, my protection.
Why?
Back in Philly,
at my old precinct,
there was a cop
named Bobby Donolato.
And he was caught up
in some, uh...
some really dark stuff.
So, I uh...
reported him.
There was an investigation,
and then Bobby blew his brains
out in his bathtub.
Why didn't you tell me this
when you applied for the job?
'Cause I didn't think
you'd hire me.
Because you'd done
the right thing
at your last job?
[ Scoffs ]
Bobby's friends didn't think
it was the right thing.
They blamed me for everything,
especially Bobby's partner...
Ed Gorski.
You mean the ex-cop
who turned up a few weeks back?
I could never prove it,
but Ed started leaving
bullet casings in my locker,
on my car.
So, Sean...
Started talking to his company
about a transfer.
And we moved.
Why are you
telling me this now?
Because Ed's stalking me.
He's broken into my car,
my house.
Can you prove that?
No.
Has he threatened you?
As you know,
unless Ed
makes a direct threat,
there's not much
legally can be done.
Is Sean in town right now?
No.
Then don't go home tonight.
You stay at my cabin
till we can figure this out.
Okay.
[ Knock on door ]
[ Door opens ]
Walt... oh!
Um, Hank Thompson
from the state prison
is on the phone.
What you got, Hank?
One of our guys on the cleaning
crew found this letter.
In James' cell?
Yeah, penthouse suite.
It was sticking out
of James' old mattress.
Officially,
that's D.O.C. evidence,
but they won't do squat
with it.
I thought you'd want a copy
before I gave it to them
to file away.
- Appreciate it.
- You bet.
Walt: James Notley had a partner
named Riley Manning.
James' letter says
that if Riley
denies being his partner,
just show him the finger.
It's his.
Letter also says
that if Notley
is killed in prison,
it's because, uh,
Riley found the money
and had him killed.
What do you want me to do?
Letter says
that the money's hidden
in an abandoned car
past mile marker 24.
Go see if it's there.
On my way.
What about you?
I'm going to the home
of Riley Manning.
Walt: Well, it look like
we both we struck out...
no Riley, no cash.
The most likely explanation
is that Riley Manning
has taken off with the money.
One of his neighbors saw him
loading his pickup in a hurry.
We'll speak to Connie Mallery
tomorrow,
see if she knows anything
about Riley
- or where he might have gone.
- Okay. Sounds good.
You sure you don't want to,
uh, switch spots?
Um, I've spent many a night
on that couch.
- It wouldn't put me out.
- No, that's okay. Thanks.
Extra blankets are in the pantry
if you need them.
Okay.
[ Door closes ]
[ Water running ]
[ Knock on door ]
Lizzie: Hello? Walt?
I'm returning
that book I borrowed!
I know it's late.
I guess...
[Chuckles]
I was just in the neighborhood.
Of course.
It's the co-workers
you have to look out for.
I guess my ex
was right after all.
You spend
that much time together,
something's bound to happen.
Lizzie, this isn't
what it looks like.
Don't pretend
to be embarrassed.
Here, read it.
You can't count on just being
young and willing forever.
[ Door slams ] I'm married!
[ Chuckles ]
When has that stopped anyone?
[ Knock on door ]
I knew this was gonna happen eventually!
I just thought you'd be man
enough to tell me when it did!
[ Door opens ]
What are you doing here?
Making a fool of myself again.
Pretending to return your book.
- Lizzie, this...
- She already told me
how it isn't
exactly what it looks like.
What a strange love rectangle
you've got going.
- Excuse me?
- Well, as I'm sure you have not noticed,
I really like you.
But you're still in love
with your dead wife!
And I was willing
to live with that,
because I thought there was
a part of you set aside for me!
But there's not, because
you're saving it for her!
Lizzie, there's nothing going on
between me and Vic.
Nothing.
Oh, Walt.
Of course there is.
You're just too afraid
to admit it.
[ Door slams ]
Branch: Still no word
on Riley Manning's whereabouts?
Vic and Ferg are coordinating
a search for Manning's truck,
a silver pickup,
either no plates
or stolen plates.
Ruby sent an A.P.B.
to the highway patrol.
You mean Riley Manning
was James' partner?
I mean,
they were friends, but...
Riley?
What gives you that idea?
Is Riley missing a finger
on either hand?
Actually, yeah.
On his right hand.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe
I didn't think of that before.
Wait. So, was it Riley's finger
in that box you received?
We think so.
James left a letter
in his cell.
That's why we think
Riley was his partner.
Wow.
When's the last time
you saw Riley?
I used to see him every month.
He'd come by and get a haircut.
He was always between jobs,
and he was James' friend,
so I wouldn't charge him.
But then he just stopped
coming over.
Walt: When?
Um, this last winter.
I think the last time
I saw Riley
was about three months ago.
I was hiking
out by Lake Desmet,
and he nearly caused me
to jump out of my sneakers.
[ Chuckles ]
Why?
Well, he shouted at me
from the lake.
He was piloting this,
like, 30-foot sailboat.
[ Chuckles ]
So, how does a guy
who can't afford a haircut
end up with a sailboat?
I don't know.
Some guys are just lucky,
I guess.
Thanks for your time.
Of course.
[ Siren wails ]
- Man, I was going the speed limit.
- I know.
I got an A.P.B. out
on a silver pickup,
so I need to see
your driver's license
and your registration.
Is your father
named Riley Manning?
I don't know.
I never met my daddy.
Look, I really can't afford
to pay for a ticket right now.
So, is there anything
I can do to get out of it?
[ Chuckles ]
Well, this is actually
my neighbor's truck.
And, uh...
I don't think
it's registered, so...
Wait right here.
I'll be right back.
[ Keyboard clacking ]
[ Computer beeps ]
Those plates are stolen.
Riley Manning!
Raise up your arms
and step slowly out of the car!
Branch:
So, you didn't even follow him?
[ All talking at once ]
Ferg, what happened?
Look, I knew I couldn't
stall the suspect long enough
for backup to arrive.
I figured
he was armed and dangerous.
So, I approached the truck.
I addressed him by his name,
and he sped off.
Yeah, of course he did.
But not until after
I dropped my watch
into the bed of his pickup.
It's a digital watch...
With built-in GPS...
Which means we can track
Riley Manning wherever he goes.
Walt: Riley Manning?
We have something of yours.
So, aren't you curious
how I got hold of your finger?
What makes you think it's mine?
Your partner told me.
Before he was murdered,
James Notley
took it upon himself
to bequeath that finger
to my department.
It seems to have something to do
with a Triceratops skeleton
the two of you stole
and sold off back in 1989.
Some dinosaur bones?
You've got the wrong guy.
Tell James that.
"My confession in 1989
was incomplete.
"I never named my partner,
Riley Manning,
"who helped me plan the heist,
drove the van,
and kept watch
as the bones were loaded."
That's damning testimony...
armed robbery and murder.
Nobody died during that heist.
I'm not talking
about Tony Moten.
I'm talking about James.
"I have reason to believe
Riley has recently found out
"where I hid the 840 grand.
"If this is true,
I fully expect to be killed
before I am released."
Whoa. Whoa.
Wait now. I...
I might have been involved
in a few robberies
a long time ago,
but I never killed anyone.
And I sure as hell
wouldn't turn on James.
He was my partner.
Most guys would've sold out
their partner,
plea-bargained
for a lesser sentence.
Not James.
He did the time. And when
he got out, he got the money.
That was the deal.
So, why'd he have your finger?
I got 10% of the money
up front.
James got the rest.
But he was going away
for a long time.
I wanted to prove to him
he could trust me.
So I pulled out a knife,
and I gave him 10%
of the fingers on my hand.
Where's what money right now?
Wherever James put it.
This letter says he hid it
in the trunk
of an abandoned car.
We checked that car.
It's gone.
Well, that sucks.
But I don't know where it's at.
I might be tempted
to believe that
if you didn't split
from your house
and speed away from my deputy.
If you had nothing to do
with James' murder, why run?
James' girl warned me.
Connie called,
said I should probably
lay low for a while,
that the sheriff
was on my trail.
She's never forgiven herself
for getting James arrested.
I guess she doesn't
want to feel responsible
for my arrest, as well.
[ Slams jukebox ]
Me and James
were like brothers.
So, why'd he write this letter?
He didn't.
I'll bet you
old Sheriff Connally
blackmailed James into giving up
the location of the money
and then pulled strings
to have him killed behind bars
and then planted that letter
to set me up.
What makes you think
Lucian would do that?
His nature.
I mean, he stole James' girl
20 years ago.
Why not steal his money, too?
Lucian had a relationship
with Connie Mallery?
That's a polite way
of putting it.
Sheriff Connally pounced on her
the second he put James
behind bars.
You owe me a beer.
The heart is like a horse that
you can break, but never ride.
The heart is like a horse...
[ Knock on door ]
That you can break...
We need to talk.
About what?!
I'm practicing art here!
About your relationship
with Connie Mallery.
You can lead the horse
to jagged cliffs
and force it to peer
into the great divide.
- Stick to prose.
- Oh, come on, Walt.
You can't take poor Connie
at her word.
The girl is grieving still.
She's gonna come
a little unwound.
I didn't hear it from Connie.
I heard it from Riley Manning.
Riley Manning.
Now, who in the hell
would that be?
That'd be
James Notley's partner.
Ever since I looked into
James Notley's murder,
you've been lying to me.
There are now accusations
that you're the one
- behind the murder.
- Okay, Walt.
Okay! You win!
I'm not like you!
I'm not perfect!
I've actually made
a few damn mistakes in my life!
Well, what are we
talking about...
Chopping off fingers,
sleeping with a witness,
or having a man killed?
Look, every one of those
fingerless pissants
had it coming.
But that don't make me
a murderer, just a man.
So, you did have a relationship
with Connie.
[ Sighs ]
Oh. Well...
For a while, I did.
She was scared and needed
somebody to protect her.
And if you think
she's pretty now,
you should've seen her
20 years ago.
Looking back,
you might say I...
took advantage
of the situation.
But I don't regret it.
We brought Riley Manning in.
He was on the run.
He said Connie tipped him off.
Did you give her any details
about this investigation?
No. Now, why the hell
would you think that, Walt?
Because Connie
warned Riley Manning
before I even told her
we were looking for him.
[ Door closes ]
Connie, it's Sheriff Longmire.
We need to talk.
[ Music ]
Connie: [ Laughs ]
Connie?!
I need you to come down
to the station!
[ Music stops ]
And, Hank, since you're off duty
from the prison,
why don't you come with us?
Connie:
So, why am I here?
I thought you said
that James' letter
named Riley as his killer.
Aren't you arresting him
for James' murder?
Riley's four months behind
on his pickup payment.
His mortgage is upside down.
He certainly
doesn't own a sailboat.
In fact, Riley's never had
much money at all.
Which means he's never really
had a reason to kill James.
Oh, my God.
Ohh.
[ Breathes deeply ]
I'm...
I'm afraid to say it,
but...
What if...
What if it was Hank?
I mean, you know that he works
at the prison.
That's how we met
in the first place.
What if Hank was afraid
that I'd go back to James
once he was released?
How long have you and Hank
been seeing each other?
Well, I mean, not long.
You know?
[ Sighs ]
I mean, for years
I was faithful, but...
You think Hank
is capable of murder?
You know, he told me
that he wouldn't want to live
without me.
I just...
you know, I just thought that
he was just being sweet, but...
Hank's got this jealous streak.
And his temper...
if he was angry...
yeah, I think
he could've killed James.
Would you be willing
to say that in court?
I don't know.
When Hank gets angry,
it can get...
pretty scary.
[ Door opens ]
I just talked to Connie.
What'd she say?
This.
Connie: Hank's got
this jealous streak.
And his temper...
If he was angry...
Yeah, I think
he could've killed James.
[ Recorder clicks off ]
I can't believe it.
Believe what?
That she would talk about me
like that.
I never laid a hand on her.
James was the abuser, not me.
Connie said she was afraid
that James would go crazy on her
when he got out.
You were
supposed to protect her?
Yeah.
What'd you do about that?
I told psycho Carl
that James was going around
calling him his bitch.
Next thing you know,
James was getting shanked
on the crapper.
You did this
at Connie's request?
Damn right I did,
and on her dime.
She paid me 15 grand.
Where do you think Connie got
that kind of money from?
Who knows?
I mean, her job?
She's an occasional hairdresser,
works out of her house.
So unless she got
a pretty big tip...
Oh, shit.
You mean Connie
has James' 800 grand?
Did you forge that letter
you found in James' cell?
I didn't have to.
James wrote it himself
and gave it to me.
Connie was telling him
about some friend
that had been buying sailboats
and taking vacations
in the Caribbean.
All of a sudden, James starts
getting all paranoid
- about this friend.
- Riley Manning.
She was playing us
the whole time, wasn't she?
She found James' money
and spent it.
Come on.
She had you kill James
before he was released
and could figure it out.
[ Doorknob turns ]
Connie, you can come out now.
Connie, is there anything
you want to say to Hank?
He's gonna be going away
for quite a while.
I believe in mercy, sheriff.
But anybody who did
what he did to James
deserves whatever's coming.
I couldn't agree more.
Actually...
it's this way.
What...
What are you doing?
Arresting you...
for conspiracy and murder.
Wait.
Hank told me the whole story.
And, Connie,
for your own protection...
I'd stay on that side
of the cell.
Sheriff, I don't understand.
Wait. What...
[ Recorder clicks on ]
Connie: When Hank gets angry,
it can get...
Pretty scary.
It's your move, Walt.
Walt:
You've been exposing your queen,
hoping I'll rush in
and get myself trapped.
[ Chuckles ]
The queen's gambit.
I guess not everyone's
gonna fall for it.
Like the horse has its rider,
like the moon has its sky...
So a man has his loneliness
mistaken as pride.
The sheriff is not here.
[ Clears throat ]
I'm not looking for Walt.
I'm looking for you.
[ Clears throat ]
Can you keep a secret, Henry?
I have been known
to keep one or two.
That ex-boxer
from the res
who knocks
people's teeth out...
what's his name?
His name is Hector,
and he's a mercenary for hire,
for the Cheyenne.
Do you think
he'd ever do something
for someone
who wasn't Cheyenne?
What did you have in mind?
[ Telephone rings ]
Yeah?
Walt, do you know
one of your deputies
came to me to hire Hector?
What did Vic want?
For Hector to scare off
a man named Ed Gorski.
Can I help you?
"We men are wretched things."
We are?
[ Laughs ]
Says who?
Achilles.
About 3,000 years ago.
Read "The Iliad"?
I'm familiar with the classics.
But have you read it, Ed?
Interpretations vary.
I think it's a poem
about a man's destructive rage.
Achilles was a warrior.
He had a partner,
a fellow warrior.
A friend.
There's no greater enemy
than the mortal enemy
of a friend.
I would not disagree with that.
So Achilles confronted
his friend's great enemy.
Achilles gave the man
one warning...
There is no weapon...
No army that could protect
this enemy
from the sheer hell
that is Achilles' rage.
And what happened
to this enemy?
Achilles ran his sword
through the man's guts
and dragged his dead body
around the town.
So...
could this enemy have done
anything otherwise?
He could have got out of town
while he still had the chance.
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com