Previously on Longmire.
Good evening Sheriff.
Not sheriff quite yet.
Maybe you could use
some help with that.
How do you feel about term limits?
Why are you taking jobs away
from Wyoming...
Is it true that you are afraid
of technology?
My mind hasn't changed.
I came to Denver to find out
about about my mother.
Why don't you ask your dad?
He spent the last year lying to me.
Beautiful flowers for a beautiful sunrise.
Where's the card?
Looks like you have a secret admirer.
What is it?
They found me.
[ Beeping ]
[ Cash register beeping ]
[ Music ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
I think I'm really
getting the hang of this.
I can always use the help.
Well, I need a towel
and another vodka Martini
and whiskey sour
for table number nine.
Oh! Got to go.
The best part is,
then the bitch hired a lawyer.
Vodka Martini and whiskey sour.
Wrong table.
Okay. Sorry to bother you.
So, what exactly
are you suggesting?
I'm suggesting
that you make some easy money.
My wife's always the last
to leave her office.
You can just do it
in the parking lot.
You want me to kill your wife?
Unh-unh.
[ Engine turns over ]
[ Engine shuts off ]
Look... I tip
what I think is fair.
If you don't like it...
I am not looking for a tip.
Well, then what do you want?
I heard what you were saying...
About your wife.
Well, you heard wrong.
I was just blowing off steam.
Relax.
You do not have to explain.
I hear problems all the time.
I just wanted to tell you
that I know someone
who can help you
make your problem go away.
Oh, really?
Who?
Me.
Sync and correction by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com
I would like
to report a murder.
Okay.
Who's the victim?
A woman. I believe
she works in an office.
- What happened?
- Nothing yet.
Okay, then. Who's the killer?
If all goes according
to plan, I am.
A man at The Red Pony tonight
was trying to hire someone
to kill his wife.
I volunteered.
Of course you did.
It's what anybody would do.
What's the guy's name?
This is where things
get a little fuzzy.
Vic: So, then,
you don't know his name?
He did not offer.
And he paid in cash,
so no credit-card receipt.
That is why
I followed him outside
and offered to do the job.
He said he would
call me tomorrow.
So, the guy said,
"I want you to kill my wife"?
Not in those words exactly.
So, then,
you can't be 100% sure.
I know what I heard.
And I know what I saw.
A white man,
six foot-ish, dark hair.
With a medium build?
I'll call the sketch artist.
He was talking to a biker.
Yeah. Whose name
you also don't know.
Regardless, we need to set up
surveillance on Henry's phone.
Ferg, you take care of that.
The rest of us need to do
everything we can to identify
this man and his wife.
Henry, you know anyone else
might be able to identify
either of these two men?
I was going to tell you.
I told him not to.
You know, I-I didn't
want you to worry.
[ Chuckles ] After my little
leave of absence,
they'd already replaced me
at the law firm.
I have bills to pay.
So, I offered her a job.
It is only part-time.
Stop.
Right now, I'm just interested
in preventing a murder.
Table nine... do you remember
who was sitting there?
Um...
Table nine is the one
by the fireplace? Yes.
[ Chuckling ] Hell, yeah,
I remember the guy
that was sitting there.
There were two of them.
There were?
I only remember the hot one...
the handsome one.
Huh.
So, which was the hot one...
the husband or the hit man?
I am not
a good judge of hotness.
Wait, a hit man? Walt: Yeah.
These are the kind of people
you come across
when you work in a bar.
Dad. We can talk
about this later.
Right now, we need to know
anything else you remember
about this guy.
He was wearing a vest
with The Brown Hawk
construction logo on it.
[ Car door opens ]
Vic: So, which one do you think
is the hot one?
[ Chuckles ]
Him.
We're looking for a bad boy.
How do you know?
Trust me. I know.
Yeah, I was at The Red Pony
last night. So what?
You were sitting with someone.
Who was he?
Just some guy named Bill.
I didn't bother
asking his last name.
So you never met him
before last night?
Nope. Got a call two days ago
about building a deck.
Said he got my name
from a friend.
You agree to build his deck?
Budget was too small.
What about
murdering Bill's wife?
You agree to do that?
Speak up, Richard.
If Bill's wife dies,
you're gonna go
from building decks
to stamping out license plates.
What did you and bill
talk about?
He told me he was into bikes,
so we talked about
my new Harley,
then he started dumping
about his wife,
said that she didn't have
a problem spending his money,
but, uh, hadn't gone down on him
since the honeymoon.
Then, all of a sudden,
he's like, "you know what, man?"
"Forget about the deck. You
want to make some real money,
you help me deal with her."
So he asked you to kill her?
Yeah, pretty much.
And how did you respond?
[ Chuckles ] I said "no,"
and I walked out of there.
He say how or when
he wanted you to, uh,
take care of her?
He said she worked at a bank,
figured I could pop her
in the parking lot,
make it look like
a robbery after work.
So, why does
this guy Bill think that
you're the man to talk to
about killing his wife?
Told you I don't know
how he got my name.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah. You know what?
Yeah, I do.
My psycho ex...
I broke up with her last week.
I bet you the bitch
put Bill up to this
and then called the cops on me.
What makes you think
the bitch would do something
like that?
'Cause that's the kind of
crazy-ass shit you women do.
Bet you Richard Montero's got
at least one assault
against a woman.
At least we know something
about the wife now.
You and Branch need to get to
every single bank in the county.
Find every employee
married to someone named
Bill, Billy, William, or Will.
[ Car door opens ]
He will call.
I believe you.
Anything?
[ Door closes ] Give it time.
[ Sighs ]
Maybe I should
stay out in the bar.
This guy knows I work here,
and he seems to prefer
doing business face-to-face.
Just relax, Henry.
[ Telephone ringing ]
It is a beautiful day
at The Red Pony
and continual soiree.
This is Henry.
Hello?
I'm here, standing bear.
Guess what I'm not wearing.
[ Chuckles ] [ Clears throat ]
Deena,
I cannot do this right now.
The police
are recording this call.
Of course they are,
because what I want you
to do to me is against the law.
Deena, seriously,
I will call you back later.
[ Clears throat ]
Well, at least we know
the equipment works.
Yeah.
Hey, Branch.
I got nothing. You?
Uh, I talked to three banks
that our potential victim
supposedly might work at.
I got nothing either.
For such a small town,
they sure got
a lot of banks here.
No kidding.
Let me know if you, uh,
find anything.
Moretti.
Ed Gorski.
Wow. I almost didn't recognize
you with the blond hair.
What are you doing here?
My wife and I
are on a little road trip.
Vacation?
Self-imposed. I retired.
[ Chuckles ]
You seem young for that.
Well, you dodge bullets
long enough,
you're entitled to
a pretty decent pension.
Wow. Wow.
You are a sight for sore eyes.
Look at you all deputized
in the wild west.
This must be fate.
I should buy a lottery ticket.
You do that.
I got to get to work.
How are you and your husband doing?
Good.
We're good.
Listen. I'm in the middle
of something, so...
I get it, but we should
get together tonight.
I don't think so.
Come on. I'll bring my wife
as a chaperone.
Okay. Sure.
A drink.
Where are you guys staying?
Well, we've got the rv,
so we're staying at, uh,
two moons rv park,
but I'll give you my cell.
And even though
I am on a fixed income...
I'll buy.
Okay.
Sean.
I-I couldn't remember
your husband's name.
But it's Sean.
I knew I'd remember it.
Go eagles!
[ Telephone ringing ]
It is a beautiful day
at The Red Pony
and continuous...
Bill: I'm looking for Henry.
You got him.
Remember that job
we talked about?
I do, and I am still...
well, forget it.
I found someone else.
[ Click ]
Vic: So, Ferg traced the call
to a guy named Bill Norquist.
They have him in custody,
but Ferg says
that he won't tell Walt
what his wife's first name is.
No Norquists on any of
these banks' employee lists.
[ Police radio chatter ]
Maybe the wife
never took his last name.
I'll call the courthouse.
Should be a marriage certificate
on file with her name on it.
[ Engine turns over ]
Oh, come on! This is absolute
and utter insanity.
Not only did I not do that,
I can't even imagine
doing something like that.
So, two men,
independently of each other,
both misunderstood that you
wanted to have your wife killed?
Sheriff, if you locked up
every guy in a bar
who runs his mouth about wanting
to make his wife go away,
all the jails would be full
and all the bars would be empty.
We have a recording
of you calling Mr. standing bear
this afternoon
to tell him
you hired someone else, though.
I was a little freaked out. I thought
maybe he was gonna come after me.
I thought maybe he was
gonna come after my wife,
so I called him today
and made up that business
about hiring someone else
just hoping that
he would leave me alone.
Obviously, I misunderestimated
this psychopath.
You are lying.
Oh, really?
Well, I guess
it's your word against mine.
Look, Mr. Norquist.
Just tell us your wife's name.
Really? Why?
So you can go ahead
and tell her
that you think that
I tried to have her killed?
I think not.
Bill, don't say another word.
Sheriff, I'm Clay dunbar.
I represent Mr. Norquist,
and we are leaving.
Clay, thank God.
This native American here
is trying to say
that I tried to hire him
to kill my wife.
Branch just called.
Bill's wife goes by
her maiden name...
Diane Highsmith. Oh, great.
Now they're gonna
poison Diane against me.
Not another word. Hey, listen,
sheriff... next time you see me,
I might be dead, because my wife
might kill me. Bill! Come on.
Listen to the good one, all right?
Come on.
What a load of crap!
You follow Bill Norquist
wherever he goes.
You both seem so delighted
that I'm alive.
What's going on?
We believe that somebody may
have put out a contract on you.
To kill me? Like in the movies?
I don't think so.
We have multiple witnesses
who say otherwise.
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry. What are you doing?
[ Dialing ]
I'm calling my husband.
I'm sure he'd like to know.
Ma'am, I don't think
that's such a good idea.
You think he's behind this?
Have you two
been having problems?
Yeah. We're married.
Look... I'm sure that someone
just heard him
talking trash about me.
"I'm going to kill her."
It's nothing
I haven't heard before.
When push comes to shove,
he's all talk.
Maybe that's why
he hired someone else to do it.
So, if this is true,
who did Bill hire?
He's not saying.
But until we can sort this out,
you should find
a different place to stay
other than your house.
I can stay at a friend's place.
She's away for the week.
I know where the keys are.
I'll follow you.
[ Inhales sharply ]
Well, all right, then.
[ Truck beeping ]
Okay, Walt? The lawyer brought
Bill right back to his office.
He works at some kind
of shipping company.
Why don't you get back on
the horn with the phone company?
Get a trace
put on Norquist's cell.
See if he makes any more calls.
Got.
Bill's going inside.
Should I follow him?
We don't want him
siccing his lawyer on us.
Just stay put out there.
Let me know when he leaves.
Roger that, sheriff.
You think your husband
will look for you here?
I doubt it.
He's never taken an interest
in any of my friends.
Come to think of it,
this is actually
the first time in months
he's actually
taken an interest in me.
I'll be fine from here.
I'll be out front
watching your place.
I like knowing that.
[ Music ]
So, where's your wife?
She's not feeling too good.
Think it's the altitude.
So, ed... [ Clears throat ]
Durant, Wyoming, isn't really
on the way to anywhere.
This wasn't fate, was it?
Not entirely. No.
Look... I was tough on you
during the whole I.A. Thing
with Bobby.
Putting it mildly.
I was out of line.
I've moved on.
But I haven't.
I'm an alcoholic, Vic.
And it got worse
after Bobby's suicide,
and I kind of
blamed you for that.
One part of my recovery
is to make amends
with the people that I hurt.
That's why I made my wife
take this detour,
because I wanted to come here
to say that I'm sorry.
Why did you order a beer?
It's something I do.
I order a drink and leave it be
to test myself.
Seems like you're just
asking for trouble.
Well, you'd know a lot about
that, wouldn't you, Moretti?
I better get back to my wife.
How did you find me, anyway?
Come on. I used to be a cop.
[ Cellphone rings ]
This is Branch.
Cady: Oh. Hey. I, um...
Cady?
Yeah. Hi. I'm sorry.
I-I didn't mean
to dial your number.
Did you ass dial me?
I guess I did.
[ Chuckles ] Sorry.
So, what are you doing?
[ Cellphone beeps ]
[ Grunts ] Hey, Branch.
Did I startle you?
Nope.
I thought I'd see
if you wanted me
to take your shift
watching Diane.
Seriously?
Well, you're always telling me
I'm giving you the
unglamorous assignments, so...
[ Cellphone ringing ]
Hello.
Ruby: I have a call for Walt
from a Detective
in South Dakota.
Huber: Hey, sheriff.
Detective Huber.
We just found a body
on the outside of town.
His I.D. Says he's from Durant.
Walt: What's his name?
His name? Let's see.
William Norquist. You know him?
Yeah.
Yeah, I know him.
Huber: His body temperature
indicates
he's been dead 6 to 8 hours.
Looks like he bled out
from his femoral artery.
Guy took two shots
to his thighs.
Walt:
Not much blood in the car.
Nah, seems like
he was dumped in the car
after he got shot.
Who found him?
Some gutter punk.
They're like these kids
that would rather
ride the rails than shower.
One of them hopped this boxcar
and found the dead guy.
I'd like to talk to him.
Her.
[ Polaroid whirs ]
Vic, I'm telling you.
I had eyes on that door
all night.
There's no way
he came out the front.
Well, his bike is still here
and the company said
his key card never swiped out.
So how does he end up dead
200 Miles away from here
if he never even
left the office?
[ Train whistle blows ]
He hopped a train.
Jesse: So, I was waiting
to hitch a ride to Chicago.
And when this one pulled up,
one of the doors were open,
which is a sign
that one of us is riding.
But when I pulled myself on,
he was just lying there.
I-I took a picture.
It's really hard
to find film anymore.
Did you see anyone else?
No, you kind of
want to avoid people
when you're looking to hop on.
Mind if I keep this?
[ Chuckles ] Yeah, I mind.
Evidence.
Fine.
Vic: You sure? He never
registered? Ed Gorski.
This is the
two moons rv park, right?
Okay, well, check again.
I'll wait.
Hey, Ferg!
We should get a sample of this,
run the blood type.
If there was a train car here,
nobody would be able to
see this spot
from the shipping yard.
The killer either
knew this train yard
or he's a real pro.
[ Knock on door ]
[ Sighs ]
I was just getting in the bath.
I'm sorry, but I kind of
need to talk to you.
Well, come on in then.
I, uh, have to go
turn off the running water.
[ Water running ]
[ Water stops ]
Listen, Diane. I've got
some news about your husband.
I'm sorry.
Bill is dead.
What happened?
We don't know much,
but it looks like
he was shot two times.
They found his body
in a boxcar.
So it's all over?
I can go home now?
Well, not exactly.
It's still possible that
Bill hired someone to kill you,
so I'll stay on patrol outside
until we can get to
the bottom of this case.
You know,
when Bill and I first met,
we were totally in love.
And then, bit by bit,
it all fades.
And here I am, years later,
hearing he's dead,
and all I feel is nothing.
Life's funny.
These swabs
are from Norquist's body.
Can we have them checked
against the blood you found
at the rail yard?
Sure. Walt. It's Branch for you.
What's up, Branch? Branch: Hey, Walt.
So, I notified Diane.
How did she take it?
She took a bath.
There's something off about
that condo she's staying at.
Kind of feels like
a model apartment.
I was curious
about that out-of-town friend,
so I called
the condo leasing office.
And? The friend's name...
Is Diane Highsmith.
Clay: Sheriff,
I just found out about Bill.
Can I have a moment? You bet.
I think Diane is behind this.
Why do you say that?
Last week,
Bill called me in a rage.
He was going through
some of Diane's e-mails
and he found a file
with a bunch of stuff
to and from a divorce attorney
at Pierce-Strahan.
She's had divorce plans
in the works for six months.
She was waiting
to pull the trigger.
Why was she waiting?
Well, she was waiting
for Bill's rich mother to die,
which she did 10 days ago.
So Diane's half
of the divorce settlement
just went up $1.2 million.
That's a reason
for him to want to kill her,
not the other way around.
She could just pull the trigger
on the divorce,
she'd get what she wanted.
Unless if what she wanted
was everything.
So, what's going on?
Did someone kill him again?
Diane, were you planning
to divorce your husband?
No.
So, you're not working with
an attorney at Pierce-Strahan?
Did you go through my e-mail?
No. But your husband did.
[ Sighs ]
Okay.
Yeah, we've gone through
a couple of bad months,
and I was taking steps
to protect myself.
You were doing this in secret?
In case you've forgotten,
my husband is the kind of man
who hires hit men.
You weren't just waiting
for his sick mother to die
so you could get
a larger settlement?
I was waiting
for his mother to die
because that is
the decent thing to do.
I wasn't just gonna
walk out on him
during something like that.
But you're okay with
secretly leasing an apartment
across town?
That's a lot of secrets
for one person.
Husbands and wives
keep secrets from each other.
Have you ever been married,
sheriff?
Yep.
Then you know
how stifling it can be.
No. I don't.
One more question.
Branch confirmed
you haven't left this condo.
Have you made contact
with anybody
about killing your husband?
Why would I start
a divorce process
if I was going to hire someone
to kill my husband?
Maybe so you could say
exactly what you just did.
[ Sighs ]
[ Harmonica playing ]
Hey, baby. I'm back.
So you are.
Mm.
When you left, you told me
you were going to Bismarck.
The phone records indicate
that you were actually
in Chicago.
You can't be serious. You're
checking my phone records?
I had other reasons
to check the phone records.
[ Harmonica continues ] I don't
like it when you're like this.
Why were you in Chicago, deena?
[ Telephone ringing ]
It is a beautiful day
at The Red Pony
and continual soiree.
This is Henry.
Man: Just the guy
I'm looking for.
Who is this?
Your worst nightmare.
I know what you did, Henry.
You went to the police
about Bill Norquist.
That was a real pain in my ass.
I never meant to upset you.
Bill and I had a deal.
And when you tattled on us,
he reneged.
So I told Bill that,
"if you're not gonna pay me
to kill your wife,
you better pay me
not to kill her."
Pretty smart, right?
But Bill wouldn't do it, so
do you know what I did, Henry?
You shot him. That's right.
Bill died over $2,000.
[ Harmonica playing ]
That's what his life was worth.
Such a waste.
And I still don't have my money.
Which brings me
to my next question, Henry.
How much is your life worth?
[ Harmonica continues ]
[ Gun cocks ]
[ Engine revs ]
[ Horn honks ]
Man: Which brings me
to my next question, Henry.
How much is your life worth?
You have to do something, Walt.
Ferg's tracing the phone
that made that call.
I pulled Branch off another job
to stay here full-time
till we find this guy.
Somebody's threatening
to kill Henry.
You're gonna put one deputy
in the bar?
I appreciate this sudden show
of care and concern, deena.
[ Sighs ]
Hey, Walt. This guy...
somebody stole my motorcycle!
He said he's been here
for a few hours,
but when he went out
to the parking lot,
his bike was gone.
We'll do all we can
to find your bike, sir.
My deputy will take down
your information.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
So, the mystery caller knows me
and knows
how to hot-wire bikes.
Richard Montero has a couple
auto thefts on his record.
Maybe he's still
involved in this.
Ferg, I'm gonna
need you to check
Richard Montero's alibi
for the last few hours.
Okay. I-I just got off
with the phone company.
The guy called
from a disposable phone.
It's the only call
it's ever made.
And it's not being picked up
by any of the towers around here
so maybe
he took out the battery.
What about incoming calls?
I got two calls
from that pay phone
outside the cargo company.
Figured that was probably Bill.
And, uh,
one call from another number.
Did you get her?
Get who? Diane, Bill's wife.
I'm assuming
that's why you called me here.
Did you find some evidence
to connect her to Bill's death?
[ Sighs ]
We found evidence.
But it actually only
connects you to Bill's death.
What? Th-that's ridiculous.
We have
the killer's phone number.
You called him. Why?
Okay, okay.
Th-this can't be right.
This is... okay, look.
Right here.
Here is my recent call list.
I have never dialed that...
you were saying?
I...Now I remember.
When we left here yesterday,
Bill borrowed my phone
to make a call.
You know, I've been thinking
about hit men.
So have I.
Most of them
fit a certain profile.
They're unknown
in the community,
lot of them
have substance problems
and need money,
and most of them...
most of them
have some kind of background
that prepares them
for taking lives.
Sounds about right.
So, I think
I got a possible candidate.
[ Sighs ] I ran into
this guy I used to work with.
From Philly. Ed Gorski.
At first,
I didn't think anything of it,
but he shows up
in Durant of all places
right in the middle
of this whole thing.
You think Bill hired your friend
to kill his wife?
It's possible.
He's an ex-cop, so he's
certainly got the training.
So, Bill uses his lawyer's phone
to call the killer,
maybe arranging a meeting
to call off the hit.
So, they meet here,
something goes wrong,
hit man kills him,
puts his body on the train.
Doc bloomfield confirmed
that Bill's blood type
matches the blood that
Ferg and I found right here.
Walt: I've seen
that graffiti before.
That's the same tag
was in the train car
where we found Bill's body.
Well, it's obviously
a popular place for homeless.
Actually, gutter punks.
[ Gasps ]
[ Southern accent ] Okay.
Okay. It's okay.
I'll... I'll just get moving.
What's your name, son? Huh?
Oh, uh, Scott.
How long you been here, Scott?
Oh, I just, uh... I just
got off the train yesterday,
but, you know, I been
through here a bunch of times.
I like the Mountain air,
you know?
But, hey, listen, I don't... I
don't want to cause any trouble.
I just... I got my things now.
I'll get going.
You recognize this guy?
Oh, yeah.
He's the manager here
or something.
[ Chuckles ]
You ever speak to him?
Well, he...
he yells at us
to get off the property, yeah.
He call you?
Whose tag is that?
With the zipper.
Um... That's zip.
Yeah. I don't know, man.
I stay away from that dude.
He scares me.
Why's that?
Zip's like mensa smart, okay?
And all the girls like him,
but I don't know, man.
You get to riding around
like I do
and you just
get a feeling for people.
And I'm telling you,
that guy's got dead eyes,
shark eyes, almost like
he ain't even human, you know?
Do you know where zip is now?
You know,
I... I saw him this morning,
but I don't know where he went to.
[ Cellphone rings ]
You know, he's kind of appears and
disappears like a phantom. Moretti.
I don't know. Yeah. Hang on.
It's Branch.
While I was at The Red Pony,
I was checking in with Diane
every hour.
Last time I tried her,
she didn't pick up.
Henry said he'd be fine, so...
better get back over
to her condo,
see what's going on.
Already did. She wasn't there.
I'm almost at her house.
Hey, Walt.
There's a motorcycle here.
Same plates as the one that
got stolen from The Red Pony.
Stay put. Wait for backup.
[ Whimpers ] Shh.
It's okay. You're okay.
[ Crying ]
You're okay. You're okay.
[ Sobs ]
I was already inside
before it occurred to me
that the motorcycle outside
wasn't Bill's.
Before I could do anything,
he grabbed my neck.
He had a gun.
Did he say anything?
He said that
nobody would come to help me.
You all were at The Red Pony.
So the call to Henry
was a decoy.
And then he asked me how much
I thought my life was worth.
I told him
I'd give him whatever he wanted.
How much money did he take?
$500.
But I don't think
that he cared about the money.
He was enjoying himself.
What did he look like?
Was he a middle-aged guy,
short blond hair?
[ Sighs ]
He was a kid, maybe 25, 26.
He smelled like
he hadn't showered in days.
And he had
a tattoo on his face.
I want every train
that's passed through Durant
in the last two hours stopped.
[ Train horn blows ]
Well, the good news is
your friend from Philly
wasn't here
to kill Bill or Diane.
Yeah, but the bad news is,
I have no idea
what he was doing here.
Got your phone? Vic: Yeah.
That's the number of
that disposable cellphone.
You don't think
he's gonna answer, do you?
Nope.
[ Dialing ]
[ Cellphone ringing ]
Hey! Zip!
Stop!
Hey!
Zip!
[ Grunts ]
[ All panting ]
Who the hell are you?
Where did you get that phone?
Some guy named zip. He said
he didn't need it anymore.
Where is he? He left.
Said he needed
to get out of town,
knew where he could Jack a car.
[ Sighs ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Normal voice ]
Lock the door, Henry.
Life is tale told by an idiot.
Do you know who said that?
Shakespeare.
"MacBeth," to be more specific.
Yes. Well done.
You know, Henry, I've, uh...
I've been riding trains
all across this country
for about the past three years,
looking for
the meaning of life.
It was a total waste of time.
[ Gun cocks ] Hey!
Life... Is meaningless...
Full of sound and fury
but signifying nothing.
Bill Shakespeare
understood that,
but it was Bill Norquist
who really opened my eyes.
I mean, this guy shows up to me
out of nowhere
with a gun
and a simple proposition...
kill my wife for $2,000.
He showed me that,
while life may not have
any meaning,
it certainly has value.
Deena: Henry. [ Knock on door ]
I know you're in there.
Henry, open up.
No sound, Henry.
And no fury.
I can shoot her
just as easily as you.
Deena: Fine, Henry!
If you are going to kill me,
get it over with.
You don't seem to understand,
Henry.
I can't kill you
because I figured out
what your life is worth.
What is that?
A ride out of town.
[ Telephone rings ]
It's a beautiful day
at The Red Pony.
Deena, it's me. Where's Henry?
Oh, hey, Walt.
Henry's pissed at me.
So he's locked himself
in his office.
Are you sure?
You know the difference
between a sociopath
and a psychopath, Henry?
I believe sociopaths
completely lack
the capacity for remorse.
You see, psychopaths
are smarter, better planners.
Which one do you think I am?
Don't get too clever.
Just keep your foot
on the gas pedal, Henry.
Very well.
[ Engine revs ]
[ Tires screech ]
[ Both grunting ]
[ Gun cocks ]
Get back, sheriff!
Walt: Drop the gun!
Get back. Drop the gun.
No, I don't think so.
I see your Southern accent
disappeared.
[ Southern accent ] Shoot...
y'all think I didn't know
you was recording
them phone calls?
I ain't stupid.
You let him go,
I'll let you go.
[ Normal voice ] No, no, no.
You're not
making the deals here.
So, let me ask you, sheriff...
how much is Henry's life
here worth to you, huh?
It's tough
to put a number on it.
I've known this man
since I was a boy.
That's a long time.
It's a lot to add up.
How much?!
I got $20 in my pocket.
His friendship's
worth more than that.
Looking at Henry's truck,
I'd say the axle's broken.
[ Metal creaks ]
So my vehicle
is your only chance to escape.
You sell it whenever
you get where you're going,
that's something.
What about your cellphone?
It's in the truck.
Part of the deal.
It's a simple trade, zip.
Nobody's gonna stop you
in a sheriff's vehicle.
All right. Hey, look...
you toss the keys.
You do it nice and easy.
Walt, do not.
I got no choice, Henry.
[ Groans ]
Good shot.
Well, not gonna let him
take my truck.
Sync and corrections by GeirDM
www.addic7ed.com