Previously on Longmire...
The city council called...
they scheduled a debate
between you and Branch.
I didn't donate $100,000 to your campaign
because I like your smile.
My mind hasn't changed.
I came to Denver to
find out about my mother.
Why don't you ask your dad?
He spent the last year lying to me.
If Detective Fales insists
on investigating me,
he's free to do so.
It wasn't your job to kill that man.
That was mine to do.
[Birds chirping]
[Sighs]
[Door slams] Ohh!
Oh, my lord.
Sorry, Ruby.
I guess I got a little
overeager with the door.
What's that all about?
Walt got me a job.
Well, I'd like to stay and chat,
but I've got a delivery
for Victoria Moretti.
- What? For me?
- Beautiful flowers for a beautiful sunrise.
- Branch: Your husband do something bad?
- No.
You do something good?
Shut up. Hey, Bob.
- Where's the card?
- Uh, it should be under the ribbon.
[Telephone rings]
It's not here.
Well, maybe he wanted the
flowers to do the talking.
Walt. I got Sergeant
Haynes, Highway Patrol.
Hey, Charley. What's up? Is it serious?
Is it serious?
[Police radio chatter]
Yeah, I'd say it's serious.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[Police radio chatter]
From the looks of these skid marks,
whoever was driving
sure stopped in a hurry.
- Any sign of the driver?
- No.
I just found the empty
rig, called you right away.
These look like 5.56 caliber.
No blood. No personal effects, either.
Vic, run the VIN number and
call the trucking company.
I want to know where this
truck was coming from,
where it was going, and who was driving it.
Branch, come with me.
[Dialing]
Someone unhooked a trailer from this rig,
attached it to a new one.
You can tell from these marks.
Hijacking?
Dust these hookup lines for prints...
the entire cab, inside and out.
The entire cab?
- Yep.
- What was hijacked?
Isn't that what you're
supposed to be calling about?
I'm on hold.
Livestock.
Cattle most likely. Cow patties.
Like cattle rustlers? That's still a thing?
You can fence cattle at 100% face value.
Could easily be $1,000 a head.
If this rig was pulling a few dozen cattle,
it's good money.
Why not steal the whole truck, rig and all?
Seems like it would be a lot easier.
A lot easier to get caught, too.
Most of these rigs have built-in GPS.
So... if you stole some cattle,
where would you take them?
Slaughterhouse.
All you'd have to do
is doctor the paperwork,
get paid quick.
Evidence is destroyed.
Yeah, hey... we just found one of your rigs
- off county Road 9...
- Branch.
Check the local
slaughterhouses... all of them.
Is that before or after
I dust this whole rig?
You choose.
Sergeant.
We need to search every
truck moving out of the area.
Smart rustlers will transfer the cattle
to a regular tractor trailer,
cut breathing holes in the roof.
[Police radio chatter]
Hey, you were right about the cows.
Trucking company said the driver
loaded up 42 head of cattle
this morning at the,
uh, Triangle Arch Ranch.
[Cows mooing]
[Gate clangs]
Dale Lowry?
I'm not donating to
either candidate, Sheriff,
you or the Connally
kid running against you.
I'm not looking for votes, Mr. Lowry.
I'm looking for 42 head of cattle.
Any of yours heading to
A.C.A. processing in Dubois?
Yeah, why?
They didn't make it.
Your load got hijacked
out on county Road 9.
[Sighs] Son of a bitch!
Bill of lading reports 36,421 pounds.
That sound right?
[Sighs] That's what I shipped.
Damn it. I'm out $50,000.
- That's the second theft we've had in three years!
- Pop, calm down.
Insurance will cover
half of that if I'm lucky.
Wait a minute, what about Cooper?
My driver... is he all right?
Do you know this Cooper James?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We go way back.
I always request him special.
We're searching for him and your cattle.
We got roadblocks up
and one of my deputies
checking local slaughterhouses,
make sure the rustler's not
trying to unload them fast.
You heard of any local
cattle auctions coming up?
Wasn't there one today in Worland?
I'm gonna need a copy of your brand.
[Horse neighs]
I'm gonna need to call the
Wyoming livestock bureau.
Protocol is for them to put
a stock detective on the case.
What the hell's a stock detective,
and why do we need one anyway?
Well, they're whole job
is catching rustlers.
May have some inside info,
make our lives easier.
- Like a cow cop.
- Kind of.
I'm going to that cattle auction
in Worland. I'll drop you off.
- You can, uh... you can drive to Cooper James' place...
- [cellphone rings]
See if his family's heard from him.
Okay.
Hey, hon.
That was, um, really sweet.
What was very sweet?
Uh, the flowers that you sent.
Why would I send flowers?
Because we're married.
I... I don't mean I wouldn't send flowers.
But last time I did, you didn't
really like them very much.
Yeah, w... [Laughs]
I don't... I don't like carnations.
You know, you know that.
But I... I like flowers.
Well, looks like you have a secret admirer.
No. I don't. Well, who sent them, Vic?
[Horn honks]
Vic?
[Knock on door]
Keep it down, boys.
Are you Cooper James' wife?
Yeah. I'm Linda.
I'm Deputy Moretti.
Do you mind if I come in for a moment?
[Scoffs] Sure.
[Toys clacking]
Thomas.
Thomas! Thomas.
- Take your brother and go outside.
- Why?
'Cause you don't want to piss off
your mother by being rude. Come on.
Go. Take your guns out.
[Sighs] I'm sorry about that.
Um... what is this all about?
[Clears throat]
When's the last time you spoke to Cooper?
Not in the last day. He's out on a job.
Why? Was there an accident?
Not exactly.
We found his rig. It had been abandoned.
What?
W... what happened? Where is he?
We're looking for him.
And I promise you that we're gonna do
whatever we can to find him.
In the meantime... it would really help us
if we had a better picture of him.
Can we borrow that one?
Yeah. Uh...
of course.
Great. Thank you.
And, uh, if you hear anything from anyone,
you call me immediately, okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
Pull any prints from that truck?
Yeah, but I haven't had
a chance to run anything.
Been too busy driving all over Wyoming
visiting four different processing plants.
Already? That's pretty fast.
I can't drive 55.
Anyhow, no sign of Triangle Arch's cattle.
[Auctioneer calling]
You're up $600. Now $625. $625 now. $650.
$650. Now $675. $675. We're at $675.
[Calling continues] $675, $675?
There's $675 right there.
Thank you very much.
Now $700. Looking for $700 on the bid.
- $700 on the bid.
- [Calling continues]
Looking for $700? Looking for $700?
Sheriff? Uh, you bidding?
Nope. Just browsing.
I need everybody's livestock papers.
[Crowd murmurs]
Thank you. Thank you, ma'am.
That's the last of them. And nothing.
Hey, Sheriff.
Well... are we good to go?
Almost.
What's the average auction
weight for that class of steer?
Oh, around 1,100 pounds, give or take.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
You got your summons pad?
You writing me a speeding ticket?
Maybe.
All right.
Dale Lowry had 42 head,
weighed 36,421 pounds.
The average weight of
each steer was 867 pounds.
He was selling underweight cattle.
Yep.
That's bad business.
Let's find out how bad.
[Police radio chatter]
[Brakes hiss]
[Engine revs]
Help!
Help me! Please!
- Cooper James?
- Yeah.
I've been looking for you.
Ms. James?
This is Deputy Moretti.
I have some great news.
Uh, we found your husband. [Laughs] Yeah.
So, we just need to get
a statement from him,
and then he should be home in a few hours.
Sheriff. You have a visitor.
R.J. Watts, Wyoming livestock bureau.
Detective, thanks for coming by.
I understand you found the trucker.
It's a good start. What did he say?
We haven't questioned him
yet. He's in my office.
I thought you'd want to hear
what he had to say firsthand,
so I gave him a few minutes
to eat and collect himself.
So, this rig tries to pass me.
And I look over, and the
guy in the passenger seat's
wearing a ski mask, waving a rifle at me.
Bastards cut me off.
I hit the brakes as hard as I could.
How many other people in that rig?
Maybe four of them jumped
out, all wearing masks.
They opened fire.
I thought they were gonna kill me.
But then, I'm getting pulled out,
hands tied, blindfolded.
They mention any place,
any end location they
might take these cattle?
No. They barely spoke.
Plus, m... my ears were
ringing from the shots.
All I remember, uh...
is getting tossed in the
trailer with the cattle.
They hooked it up to their rig, took off,
then dumped me in the middle of nowhere.
[Sighs]
I just w... want to go
home... see my wife and kids.
That's all we need tonight.
[Sighs] Vic, let's give Cooper a ride home.
My car's at the trucking company.
Vic: That's no problem. I'll drop you off.
These rustlers ain't amateurs.
Doesn't appear that way. [Sighs]
I got a bead on a guy...
that... that I bet is involved with this.
Bobby Dunwood.
He's one of the worst rustlers there is.
By "worst" I mean violent.
- So, where is he?
- Well, there is that.
He is currently incarcerated.
He's serving out the
end of a reduced sentence
at the State Pen Ranch.
He's gonna be out in a couple of months.
- Jail?
- Yeah.
That's a pretty solid alibi.
Walt... there are men running
major criminal enterprises
outside maximum security.
This place they got
Dunwood, it's... it's...
Hell, I've seen harsher
conditions in a Motel 6.
It's like he's at a dude ranch.
You really think Dunwood carried
out this hijacking from jail?
You got multiple guys. You got masks.
You got high-powered weapons.
I... it's Bobby's modus operandi.
Sounds like we should talk to him.
[Cows mooing]
I heard this place was low-security.
I had no idea how low.
Yeah. No fences. No guard towers.
Every inmate works.
Gives them purpose and job training
for when they're released.
Plus, Wyoming gets nearly free labor.
Wins all around.
Lucky Wyoming. [Chuckles]
Dunwood. Dunwood!
There's no need to yell!
[Grunts]
R.J. send you?
Someone hijacked a truck
in my county, 42 head...
sounds a lot like you.
Right.
But I'm in here.
So, I fail to see how I'd be involved.
But I appreciate the flattery.
Easy enough to plan and issue orders
when you have this kind of freedom.
Sure.
But somebody would have had
to have visited me, right?
Check the visitors logs.
I ain't seen no one.
Well, then... any thoughts on
who might have pulled it off?
I can't help you with that one.
Only that it wasn't me.
And I wouldn't believe
everything you hear, Sheriff,
especially when it comes
from the mouth of R.J. Watts.
Well, it's natural to say that
about a man who put you away.
Why don't you tell little
R.J. it's time to retire?
'Cause I'm starting with a clean slate.
I already got two legit
offers for ranch work
when I get out of here.
I'm gonna buy me my own ranch someday.
[Horse neighs]
[Horse snorts]
I look forward to seeing that.
Vic. You all right?
[Telephone rings]
[Beep] Hello?
[Sighs] Omar. It's Vic.
Did you send me flowers?
Well, uh... I don't know.
Did you receive flowers?
You got another suitor besides me, Vicky?
Vic? Walt needs you.
Vic, I checked the visitors log.
Dunwood hasn't had any visitors of note.
- Maybe he had a go-between.
- True.
I need you to check the whole visitor log.
I also got a list of recent parolees.
We need to find out where they ended up.
One of them may be working with Dunwood.
[Horn honks]
Vic, you there?
- Guys.
- Vic?
Guys!
[Horn honks]
[Cow moos]
[Sighs] If this thing kicks me...
Triangle Arch.
It's Dale Lowry's brand. [Cellphone rings]
One down. Only 41 to go.
Maybe this isn't cattle rustling at all.
Could be some kind of political statement.
"My farts caused hurricane Sandy."
That was Cooper James' wife.
He didn't come home last night.
Coop came in here to
file an incident report.
It's right here. Took him 20 minutes.
I know. I saw him go
in there. What happened?
Well, he left. I thought
someone was picking him up.
But his car is over there.
[Sighs]
Where the hell could he have gone?
[Engine revs]
Ok.
I got him. [Grunting]
- So, you got my message.
- [Grunting] Yep.
Can't say as I saw this coming.
[Sighs]
What am I gonna tell his wife?
I said we got him back.
This isn't your fault, Vic.
I drop a witness off, and
before they can get home,
these bastards come, and
they hang him in a trailer?
R.J.: Cooper wasn't a
witness. He was in on this.
Partners turned on him.
One less guy to divide the pie with.
What makes you so sure?
He didn't smell like manure.
- I noticed when we cut him down.
- Spend a couple hours
bouncing around the back
of a truck full of steer,
you're gonna smell like cow shit.
Desperate men do desperate things.
It leads to this.
If the hijackers killed him
to keep more of the take,
why let a cow go in town square?
It's throwing away money.
It's a misdirect.
They want us running in
circles trying to figure out
who hung a stupid sign on a Heifer's neck.
Meanwhile, they bolt off
to Colorado or Kansas,
and they sell the rest of their haul.
You're still thinking Dunwood?
Dunwood folds into this somehow.
He's killed before.
You're not gonna find that
on his rap sheet, but he did.
Why is that?
Because a couple of years
before he went to jail,
I had a guy in Dunwood's
crew, my own snitch.
Well, Dunwood must have found out about it
because I found my guy, too.
And his hands were bound behind him,
and he was hanging from the rafter
of a truck-stop bathroom.
That sound familiar?
So, then, how do we get Dunwood?
Well, there's one thing we can try.
We release him on furlough.
We keep an eye on Dunwood. We follow him.
I bet you he'll lead us
right to the guys who
helped him pull this off.
I'll think about it.
Right now, I got to notify Cooper's wife.
No. I'll tell her.
[Sighs]
Mrs. James, I'm sorry to
tell you that we found Cooper.
And he's gone.
He was found...
[Sobs]
[Sighs] Mrs. James...
Don't you touch me!
You lied.
Saying everything was
okay, that... oh, God.
[Sniffles]
[Sighs]
My oldest son found that three hours ago
on my front doorstep.
[Zipper opens]
He was like family.
Are you sure Cooper was involved?
Looks that way.
[Sighs] Well, I am at a loss.
Branch: Looked into your insurance.
You tripled your theft
coverage since last year.
Why?
Well, when you've been robbed before,
it's a normal thing to do.
Dale, have you been struggling financially?
What, just 'cause I upped my insurance?
Sheriff, that's called being prudent.
Is it prudent to sell underweight cattle?
Why not let them graze and fatten
up all summer, then sell them?
Sounds like you needed money.
I did need money, Sheriff.
That's why people sell things.
See, I spent too much on feed last fall.
I got overextended.
I took it in the balls
in '07 like everyone else.
I got a son and a daughter,
both in fancy, east-coast colleges
costing me 80 grand a year.
Here's how things look
from where I'm sitting.
You got financial trouble.
You tripled your theft insurance.
You hired a trusted driver
to do whatever you asked.
I didn't steal my own cattle!
And I sure as hell
didn't kill Cooper James.
And you want to talk more about it,
you can call my lawyer!
[Door slams]
[Clears throat]
Look what showed up on
Cooper James' doorstep
this morning, according to his wife.
[Sighs]
It's $10,000.
If you're gonna kill Cooper
to cut him out of the deal,
why give his wife a
duffel bag full of cash?
We got more cattle heading up main street.
The question in Durant these
days is, "where's the beef?"
And the answer is, "everywhere you turn."
[Horn honks]
[Cows mooing]
Excuse me, ladies.
What do you think about everything
that's going on here today?
- Anyone?
- Uh, yeah.
I support whoever did this.
The beef industry is destroying our planet.
They cut down rain forests,
overbreed in inhumane conditions.
Meat is murder.
Thank you, miss.
Omar: Young lady!
This is Wyoming. This is beef country.
Now, I respect your right to free speech,
but not your stupidity.
100 years from now,
people will look back
on you as a barbarian.
Darling, why do you
think God gave us these?
They're called bicuspids.
They're for tearing meat, not tofu.
People like you are destroying this planet!
- Hey!
- It's people like you that are killing...
Get out of here, Omar! Enough!
Show's over. Everybody go home.
You. Don't let that guy
get under your skin, okay?
You're this close to being
arrested for disorderly conduct.
He could file assault charges against you
if he really wanted to.
Vic: Go.
Omar, what are you doing?
I was just minding my own business,
delivering somebody flowers,
when this ecoterrorist came
up, started talking garbage.
These better not be for Vic.
Oh, come on, Walt. It's all in good fun.
Didn't this kind of harmless
fun cost you your first wife?
- All right, I'll ease up.
- No.
Don't ease up. Just stop. Okay?
I'm gonna go have me a burger!
[Sighs]
[Cows mooing]
I'm looking for a man named Jordan Helms.
Now, the feds say he moves around a lot
but might be holed up on the res.
First of all, Jordan Helms is
just an activist who
posts lectures on YouTube.
And he is not holed up.
He's a Brit who's shacked up
with his Cheyenne girlfriend.
Supposedly, Helms has connections
to the E.L.F., Earth Liberation Front.
Supposedly, they sabotaged
a fracking operation
in Cumberland County last month.
Same deal with the eco signs.
Maybe Mr. Helms has raised
his activism to a new level.
[Inhales deeply] Let me see what I can do.
[Music]
Pardon me for not stopping. [Panting]
This machine has a small dynamo...
that creates electric power.
I've almost generated our day's needs.
Mr. Helms, I'm investigating
the hijacking of a truck full of cattle.
Cattle are showing up with
signs attacking big beef.
[Panting]
Shadow said she saw it on the news.
I don't watch.
Look at this, then.
[Sighs]
[Laughs]
I don't know anything about it.
[Sighs] That said,
I wholeheartedly support whoever did.
And civil disobedience is a
powerful weapon to enact change.
I've seen what arrogant
actions can do to an empire.
The Cheyenne people,
they respect the earth.
She needs our support.
Am I right, brother?
I suppose... brother.
Walt: You reach a lot of
people with your videos.
My deputy tells me you have
50,000 followers on Facebook.
This is a war.
I'm fighting for the
planet. It can get ugly.
Yeah, real ugly. Like murdering ugly.
I thought you said it was
a cattle-truck hijacking.
The man driving the truck was killed.
Look... I want to be clear.
I could not and would not ever support
any action that results in violence.
I had nothing to do with this.
Unless posting those
speeches on the Internet
inspired some unhinged people.
Then you had a hell of a lot to do with it.
This is America, where
people are supposed to
take responsibility for their own actions.
[Cellphone rings]
- Hello?
- R.J.: Moretti. Is the Sheriff with you?
Yeah, hang on a second. Walt.
Heya, Walt.
Did "Johnny Greenpeace" confess?
Walt: Nope.
Yeah, I didn't think so.
I had the D.A. draw up papers
for Dunwood to be furloughed.
Excuse he's gonna be given is budget cuts.
Final step, I need you to sign off, Walt.
Hey, pull over here.
Did you, uh, find out where
Dunwood's prison buddies
went to work after their release?
I got my deputy working on that.
She's preoccupied at the moment.
R.J., send the furlough
papers to the station.
I'll sign them.
[Engine shuts off]
- Stop messing with me!
- Walt: Hey! Hey!
- How do you not remember?
- I don't remember.
- Take a breath. Take a breath.
- That's bullshit! Where's the card?
- Where's the card?
- Okay, I may... I may have lost it.
What's going on? This job
is a lot of responsibility.
I'm just trying to learn the ropes here.
- [Sighing] Oh, my God.
- I'm sorry!
Bob, retrace your steps.
Find the card that went with those flowers.
[Sighs]
[Ice shifts]
Find that card, Bob.
Okay. Okay.
R.J.: You know, I've
put 16 guys behind bars
in the last 10 years.
Every single one of them are out.
Most of them went back rustling.
- What was his name?
- Who?
Your informant... the one
you said that Dunwood hanged.
Davy Wilson.
He was a good guy. He didn't deserve that.
You do what we do,
the people you work
with become like family.
My dad did this, you know? Oh, yeah.
Yeah, he was the real deal.
He was a tom horn sort of stock detective.
You didn't tussle with
him and get off easy.
Old bastard died in the line of duty.
Drove his truck off the
road chasing a stolen haul.
I guess I'd do the same if I had to.
People think cattle rustling's a joke.
Well, it ain't a joke. It ruins lives.
My dad... Davy.
[Sighs]
[Chuckling] Besides, I don't know
what the hell else I'd do besides this.
What about you?
If I don't get re-elected next month,
I'll have an answer for you.
Well, if I was a resident,
I would vote Longmire.
[Laughs]
Have you ever considered relocating?
[Laughing] No. Hell, I'm too old to move.
[Laughs] [Cellphone rings]
Oh.
Yeah. Watts here.
Yeah, yeah, he's here. Hang on.
Hey, Vic. You okay?
Yeah. [Sighs]
I'm fine.
So, uh... Branch is still
going through the visitors log,
but I found out that
in the last six months,
13 inmates have been
released from State Pen Ranch.
And all of them have ranch jobs,
but one guy named Whitey Culver
works at the Triangle Arch Ranch.
- Good work, Vic.
- Vic: Right.
I heard her. Her...
voice really cuts through.
So, it looks like we've got
our connection to Dunwood.
You stay tight on him. I'm
gonna go talk to this cowhand.
Dale.
I don't see a lawyer
there with you, Sheriff.
Look, I'm just trying to figure this out.
Now, I'll ask a question.
You don't want to answer
it, that's your call.
You got a hand named Whitey Culver?
Yeah. He's working now. Why?
Were you aware that whitey served some time
at the State Pen Ranch?
He got locked up for a bar
fight that went too far,
not for rustling.
Whitey served with a
guy named Bobby Dunwood,
one of the biggest rustlers in Wyoming.
So, I'm gonna need to talk to whitey.
He lied to me.
He told me he never met a one.
Well, it's true what they say, isn't it?
No good deed goes unpunished, does it, son?
I'll go get him.
[Sighs]
Sugarloaf... that's in Maine, right?
Yeah.
You go to college up there?
Yep, one more year to go.
Dale: Here he is, Walt.
Talk to the man.
Is there a problem, Sheriff?
You know Bobby Dunwood, don't you?
No. [Scoffs]
A l... little bit. But I...
Ah, Whitey. You're fired.
Dale, hang on a sec.
You been in touch with Dunwood
since you were released?
Hell no.
Mr. Lowry, haven't I always
done a good job for you here?
You know, I had good intentions hiring you.
But now I can't afford to trust you.
Walt: Whitey.
The truth is all I'm looking for.
I didn't steal no cattle, Sheriff.
- Trent.
- Trent: Yes, sir?
Will you come pick up
your cows? I got no space.
Today good?
Sure thing, Sheriff.
Okay.
Come on, Whitey.
Omar: Can't Vicky take my complaint?
No. Branch will be back soon.
Oh, come on, Walt. Do I have to do this?
Got no issues with that granola girl.
- I like pushy women.
- [Door closes]
Just do what I ask you to do.
Ruby: Walt.
Trent Lowry's here for the cows.
Uh, I just need you to sign
some paperwork in my office.
After you.
Amy?
Hey. You're here.
They're trying to charge me
for bumping some old, crazy guy.
You two know each other?
I guess you met at college in Maine.
Freeport College, is it?
I noticed your T-shirt this
morning in the town square.
I assume you two are dating.
- Yeah.
- Is that against the law?
Depends on what you do on your date.
I just got one question for you, Trent.
Are you okay with Whitey
Culver getting fired
for a crime he had nothing to do with?
I don't know that he had
nothing to do with it.
Yeah, you do. You both do.
Men rustle cattle to make money.
They're not interested in
advancing a political agenda.
But you are.
Amy, are you familiar with
a man named Jordan Helms?
Yeah. So are a lot of people.
He has a very impressive
Facebook page, lots of friends.
They leave comments like, uh,
"big beef destroys the planet.
It's time to stop
talking and start acting."
You recognize that?
It's got your picture
and your name next to it,
along with another 46 comments by you.
It's not against the law to
express an opinion, is it?
No. But it sure gives you a motive.
And he's opportunity son of a rancher.
Look, Sheriff... isn't it your job
to find criminals who deserve punishment?
So, why not arrest the board of B.P.?
Their greed and negligence resulted in
172 million gallons of crude
oil being spilled into the Gulf.
They're the real criminals.
- What are you doing?
- [Handcuffs click]
What is this? What are you doing?
You can't do this.
Actually, I can.
When you murder someone, you go to jail.
Cooper James, the trucker
hauling those cattle,
he was murdered, hung by the neck.
You scared now?
Wait. We never hurt anyone.
Those cows were never really stolen.
We're releasing all of them.
It was just a hoax to raise awareness.
We paid Cooper $10,000
to shoot up that rig and switch trailers.
- That's all.
- That's a crime.
Cooper needed that money
for his family. All right?
This was supposed to help
everybody get what they wanted.
Nobody was supposed to die.
Why would we kill Cooper?
You two take a moment and
talk amongst yourselves.
Good luck.
So, you think they did it?
[Sighs]
Well, they stole the cattle,
but I don't think they killed Cooper James.
Well, who else would want Cooper dead?
They're the only ones who
knew he was involved in this.
No. They weren't.
Yeah. Watts here.
- Walt: R.J.
- Oh, hey, Walt.
Hey, you talk to that cowhand
over at Triangle Arch yet?
Walt: He's clean, but we made an arrest.
Turns out the rustlers
weren't really rustlers at all.
Dale Lowry's son, Trent,
he did something stupid
for a girl he loves.
We have a confession.
Well, h... hold on, Walt.
You... you think a college
kid killed that trucker,
strung him up like that?
Tell you what, let me talk to him.
You over at the station?
Walt: Nope. I'm driving
out to the State Pen Ranch.
What are you doing that for?
Walt: Dunwood has nothing
to do with this case.
It's time to end his furlough.
Pick him up and meet me
back at the State Pen Ranch.
Yeah, s... sure, Walt.
Um... I'll see you over there.
[Sighs]
There he goes.
So, what now?
We wait.
Bob Barnes found the card
that went with your flowers.
He dropped it off.
[Knock on door]
Dunwood: R.J.? What are you doing here?
Who's it from?
Come on, Vic.
After all this, you're not
gonna tell me what it says?
[Inhales deeply]
It says "happy anniversary."
I thought your anniversary was in October.
It is.
But did you see that girl?
[Groans] Come on, man!
You got to be kidding me.
[Grunts] Oh, yeah.
I seen this truck before.
Aw, you're... come on, man!
[Engine turns over]
State Pen Ranch is the other way.
Yep.
Dunwood: This about the hooker?
'Cause I didn't know she was
one till she asked for the cash.
[Cellphone rings]
Yeah. Watts here.
- Walt: R.J.
- Oh, hey, Walt.
- Dunwood with you?
- Yeah, I got him.
We're heading back to State Pen Ranch.
See you in about... 10, 15.
No, you won't.
You got your own plans for Dunwood,
same as you had for Cooper James.
What are you talking about, Walt? I...
Look, j... just stay tight,
and... and I'll see you soon.
I'm bringing Dunwood in.
Then why are you driving
in the wrong direction?
Why you following me?
Why are you heading out of town, R.J.?
'Cause I'm going home.
Not with Bobby Dunwood.
There's not gonna be
any more hangings, R.J.
Look... that thing with Cooper...
I didn't mean for that to happen.
Yeah, I followed your deputy
and him back to the truck depot.
But... h... he didn't smell like cattle.
I just noticed it a little
quicker than you did.
And when I pressed him
on it, he kept lying.
And I hate a liar. Can't stand one.
I knew damn well he stole them.
He did. But not for Dunwood.
He was working with the rancher's son.
I told you I got nothing to do with this.
Now pull the truck over and let me out!
There's a connection, Walt.
You just ain't found it yet.
This piece of trash
has ruined enough lives.
And I'll be damned
if I'm gonna give him
another slap on the wrist
and let them unleash him again
to go back out and start stealing,
ruin more lives, take more lives.
No. No, that ends, and that ends now.
R.J.
R.J., I can't let you leave Absaroka.
Now, there's an honorable way to end this.
How's that, Walt?
All them sons of bitches I sent away...
not a single one of them
is still behind bars.
Now they gonna put me in jail.
So, where's the honor?
Detective...
think about what you're doing.
Sheriff, I have.
I have.
[Beep]
[Inhales deeply] You got your seatbelt on?
No.
Good. [Engine revs]
[Tires squeal]
What are you doing?!
Hey!
R.J.!
[Buckle clicks]
[Groaning]
[Inhales deeply]
[Sighs]
Aw, you're awake.
I wanted to surprise you.
- What's the occasion?
- Doesn't have to be an occasion.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
- You hurt your finger?
- Love hurts, babe.
Plus, I got competition from
that secret admirer of yours.
So I got to go big. [Clicks tongue]
[Sighs]
What is it?
They found me.
[Sighs]
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -