(Theme music playing)
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Man: Bring her back online.
Can you hear me?
Woman, Western accent: Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm not feeling quite myself.
Man: You can lose the accent.
Do you know where you are?
Woman, standard accent: I'm in a dream.
Man: That's right, Dolores.
You're in a dream.
Would you like to wake
up from this dream?
Dolores: Yes.
I'm terrified.
Man: There's nothing to
be afraid of, Dolores,
as long as you answer
my questions correctly.
- Understand?
- Dolores: Yes.
Man: Good.
First...
have you ever questioned the
nature of your reality?
(fly buzzes)
Dolores: No.
(birds chirping)
Man: Tell us what you
think of your world.
Dolores: Some people choose
to see the ugliness in this world.
The disarray.
I choose to see the beauty.
Morning, Daddy. You sleep well?
Well enough.
You headed out to set down some
of this natural splendor?
Thought I might.
Dolores: To believe there
is an order to our days,
a purpose.
- (piano playing)
- Man: What do you think of the guests?
Dolores: You mean the newcomers?
Passenger: Now, the first
time I played it white hat.
My family was here.
We went fishing, did the
gold hunt in the mountains.
- And last time?
- I came alone.
Went straight evil.
It was the best two weeks of my life.
Dolores: I like to remember
what my father taught me.
(train whistle blows)
That at one point or another,
we were all new to this world.
(piano continues playing)
(bell ringing)
The newcomers are just
looking for the same thing we are...
A place to be free
to stake out our dreams,
a place with unlimited possibilities.
Oh, God, it's incredible.
Better be for what we're paying.
(Clanging)
(distant dog barking)
- (grunting)
- (kids shouting)
Murderous son of a
bitch named Hector Escaton
gunned down the marshal.
He's holed up in the mountains.
You there.
You look like the kind of
man who'd put his mettle to it.
Not today, Sheriff. Apologies.
(Chatter)
Rye whiskey.
What about it?
Well, it ain't doing any
good sitting in that bottle.
- (Glass thuds)
- (liquid pouring)
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
I'll give you a discount.
Well, no offense, but...
I'd rather earn a woman's
affection than pay for it.
You're always paying for it, darling.
The difference is our costs are fixed
and posted right there on the door.
Man: Do you ever feel
inconsistences in your world?
Or repetitions?
Dolores: All lives have routine.
Mine's no different.
Still, I never cease
to wonder at the thought
that any day the course of my whole life
could change with just
one chance encounter.
Don't mind me.
Just trying to look chivalrous.
You came back.
I told you I would.
Can I see you home?
Well, that all depends. Can you keep up?
Well, I have to fetch my horse.
Better fetch him fast.
Teddy: That's a beautiful sight.
Never understood how you keep them
all headed in the same direction.
(laughs) I forget
you dress like a cowboy,
but that's about the extent of it.
See that one?
- Yeah.
- That's the Judas steer.
Rest will follow wherever
you make him go.
How do you pick him out?
Just know these things.
Same as I knew you'd be back.
You saying I'm predictable?
There's a path for everyone.
Your path leads you back to me.
I know things will work
out the way they're meant to.
Same as I know my daddy still
won't be happy to see you.
(laughs)
(sighs)
(mooing)
Father wouldn't let
them roam this close to dark.
(Gunshot)
(gunshot)
Stay put, Dolores.
(Groans)
Ain't you got anything out here
other than milk, old man?
Go ahead.
I'm in no rush to meet my judgment,
but I'm more sure of the
outcome than you, you son of a...
(gunshot)
Nothing but milk, then.
Shame of it is you killed the old woman
before any of us could have a turn.
I reckon she's still warm enough.
Nobody gonna judge you for it.
(Man whistles)
(gunshot)
Oh, shit. Shit, shit, shit.
(Gunshots)
Man: Last question, Dolores.
What if I told you that you were wrong?
That there are no chance encounters?
That you and everyone you know
were built to gratify the desires
of the people who
pay to visit your world?
Daddy!
(Sobbing) Daddy! No!
Man: The people you
call "the newcomers."
Hello again.
Your daddy gave it up quickly.
Think he's losing his touch.
You'll be following right
behind him, you son of a bitch.
Is that any way to treat an old friend?
I've been coming here for 30 years,
but you still don't remember me, do you?
After all we've been through.
They gave you a
little more pluck, Dolores.
- Absolutely charming.
- (sobbing)
Take your hands off her.
Oh, Teddy.
Any special tricks for us?
They teach you to sit up, beg?
How about I give
you the first shot, hmm?
After all, every dog has his day.
Well, your mouth move fast enough.
How about your gun?
(Gunshot)
(gunshot)
Man: What if I told you that
you can't hurt the newcomers?
And that they can do
anything they want to you?
I never understood why
they paired some of you off.
Seems cruel.
(Gunshot)
And then I realized
winning doesn't mean anything
unless someone else loses.
Which means you're here to be the loser.
Let me help you, son.
Seems you're not the
man you thought you were.
Come on, beautiful.
Oh! Oh, no! No!
Teddy! Teddy!
(Gunshots)
No, no, no, please don't hurt him.
I'll do whatever you say. (screams)
I didn't pay all this
money 'cause I want it easy.
I want you to fight.
- Don't you touch her!
- (gunshot)
(hammer clicks)
- (gasps)
God damn, feels good to be back.
- (Screams)
- Let's celebrate.
(Dolores screaming) No! Don't!
Oh, no, no!
No!
(screaming continues)
Man: Would the things I told you
change the way you think about
the newcomers, Dolores?
No!
Dolores: No.
Of course not.
We all love the newcomers.
Every new person I meet reminds
me how lucky I am to be alive...
(Dolores crying, screaming)
...and how beautiful this world can be.
(piano playing)
(train whistle blowing)
Woman: Oh, my God, they're so lifelike.
Look at that one. He's perfect.
Perfect is boring.
I'm more interested in the bad guys.
(Buzzing)
Did you see it?
No.
Give it a second. She'll do it again.
Her finger. That's not standard.
I noticed it last night.
Went looking in the update.
It's a whole new class of gestures.
But if we didn't put
it there, then who did?
Ford. He still reviews every
update before we issue them.
He must have slipped it in
there without telling anyone.
(Beeps)
He calls them "reveries."
The old gestures were
just generic movements.
- These are tied to specific memories.
- How?
The memories are purged at the
end of every narrative loop.
But they're still in there,
waiting to be overwritten.
He found a way to access them,
like a subconscious.
A hooker with hidden depths?
Every man's dream.
It's the tiny things that
make them seem real,
that make the guests fall
in love with them.
(Beeping)
Excuse me.
(Beeping stops)
We have a problem?
We have some unscheduled activity.
Evidently, one of your
creatures is restless.
In the park?
No, sublevel 83, cold storage.
We should be cautious.
Send a response team, full armor.
I'll take care of it myself.
I think you guys enjoy playing
dress up as much as the guests.
The hosts can't hurt you by design.
You don't have kids at
home, do you, Bernard?
No.
If you did, you'd know that
they all rebel eventually.
You'll forgive them for
being a little uptight.
Every time your
team rolls out an update,
there's a possibility
of a critical failure.
We don't update the
hosts in cold storage
and the park hasn't had a
critical failure in over 30 years.
Meaning we're overdue.
I'll go along, too. If it's one
of mine, I might be able to help.
They're only yours until
they stop working, Bernie.
Then they're mine.
(Elevator rattling)
(guns cocking)
(beeping)
Cooling system's been down for weeks.
Gonna smell fantastic. I
recommend you hang back.
Bernard: When are they gonna fix this?
Livestock
management's got other priorities.
(Beeping)
Besides...
no one's complained.
Host: Here's to the lady
with the white shoes.
Take all your money,
drink all your booze.
Stop.
Unless you plan to
decommission the boss.
- (Glasses clink)
- Ain't got a cherry, that ain't no sin.
She's still got the box
that the cherry come in.
- (Whirring)
- I'll drink to that.
The old coffin varnish.
They don't make that like they used to.
Hmm.
They don't make
anything like they used to.
Damn right. Men neither.
I've seen a few showdowns in my day.
More than you know.
- (Chuckles)
- (liquid pours)
Shall we drink to the
lady with the white shoes?
Perhaps we better drink to a...
deep and dreamless slumber.
Old Bill here was
always a good listener.
He was the second host we ever built.
Were you with us in those days, Bernard,
or was that before your time?
Most were decommissioned before
I was brought on, I'm afraid.
They repeated themselves,
broke down constantly.
A simple handshake would give them away.
You'll put yourself
away again, won't you, Bill?
I saw the new gestures, the reveries.
They're beautiful.
The distance you've
traveled from then till now,
it's remarkable.
Yeah, that's a word for it.
Morning, Daddy. You sleep well?
Well enough.
You headed out to set down some
of this natural splendor?
Thought I might.
After my errands, of course.
See you home before dark.
That bandit who gunned down the marshal
is still hiding up there in the hills.
I'm not a child anymore.
I'll be just fine.
When I was a law man...
Yes, Daddy, I know all about
when you were a law man.
I know all your stories and so does
every boy that ever came courting.
I know how boys
think. Was one myself once.
Given to all manner of
drinking and mischief.
Whatever happened to
that fearsome ne'er-do-well?
He vanished the day
I became your father.
I am what I am because of you,
and I wouldn't have it any other way.
I know, Daddy.
I'll be home before dark.
(Bell ringing)
(chatter)
(hammer clanging)
Sheriff: Murderous son
of a bitch Hector Escaton
gunned down the marshal.
He's now holed up in the mountains.
You there.
You look like the kind of
man who'd put his mettle to it.
What do you think, honey?
Sounds fun.
You're new.
Not much of a rind on you.
I'll give you a discount.
No offense, but I'd
rather earn a woman's affection
than pay for it.
(speaking Chinese)
Clarence: Wait, wait, I know that one.
Hey, Teddy.
Yeah, last trip, this
dude showed me around.
What's the good word, Teddy?
Mighty kind of you.
Sweet.
Not as sweet as you.
I'm afraid I've got other
plans tonight, Dolores.
Have a pleasant evening.
You're new. Not much of a...
Place your bets, gentlemen.
Place your bets.
(Flies buzzing)
- (whistles)
- (horse whinnies)
Yeah, looks like Hector's been this way.
Any idea how much
longer this is gonna take?
My wife doesn't want to
be up here after dark.
We know he's up in
these hills somewhere.
He's gonna put up one
hell of a fight when we...
When we... when we...
Sheriff?
Something is wrong with it.
I want to head back to town.
Now.
Lee: What the fuck is wrong with it?
You updated the guy,
and now he's a
six-foot gourd with epilepsy.
So what the fuck happened?
I don't know.
Well, that's exactly what you want
to hear from your head of programming.
We haven't finished the diagnostic yet.
Clearly it's exhibiting
some aberrant behavior.
Pretty fucking aberrant, Bernie.
Your hosts get sick, they get lost,
but this is grotesque.
Is it a problem with the update?
Possible, but not likely.
If it's the unlikely version, how
many hosts have you updated so far?
Maybe 10% of the population.
All right, we pull all updated
hosts until we can figure it out.
Are you fucking kidding me?
That's 200 hosts spread across
a dozen active storylines.
The guests interrupt your
precious storylines all the time
when they want to
shoot or fuck something.
No, when they want to.
We sell complete immersion
in 100 interconnected narratives.
A relentless fucking experience.
Now, you pull one character,
the overall story adjusts.
You pull 200 at once, and
it's a fucking disaster!
I mean, what do you propose we do?
Close down? Issue
fucking gift certificates?
It's beautiful... Your brow.
When you're angry but
trying to control it,
the fine muscles pull into a little arc.
It's elegant.
Would you mind if I recorded it?
I'd love to show it to my team.
No, Bernard, you may not record it.
Ah, there it is again.
We have 1,400 guests in the park.
I need to know if they're in any danger.
His core code is intact,
which means he can't hurt a guest.
He literally couldn't hurt a fly.
- All he can do is...
- (snorts)
...that.
All right, Bernie.
Run a diagnostic.
In the meantime, there's so much
as an unscripted sneeze,
I want to know about it.
(Beeping)
(bird screeching)
(chatter, laughter)
(people grunting, moaning)
This place is fucking wild.
Clarence: This is basic.
Level one.
You ride out of town,
that's when the real
demented shit begins.
That's where my man Teddy comes in.
He's like a guide.
Honestly,
the guy kind of creeps me out.
(laughs)
Fuck it, he leads us out in the canyons,
we get bored, we just use
him for target practice.
Father: I don't think we're
supposed to be cross the river.
It's too adult for Jacob.
We didn't mean to bother you.
No bother at all. It's a beautiful spot.
I always found it a shame that
I have it all to myself.
They come here every day.
Would you like a closer look?
(Horse nickers)
(clicks tongue)
Don't be scared. They're very gentle.
Here, put your hand out real flat.
They're beautiful, aren't they?
You're one of them, aren't you?
You're not real.
I have to go now. Sun's almost down.
You should, too. There's
bandits in these hills.
- (Man whistles)
- Man #2: Hyah! Hyah!
- (Horse whinnies)
- (men shouting, whistling)
- Here we go, yah!
- Yah!
(Whistles)
You waiting up for me, Daddy?
I told you I'd be home before dark.
I found this in the field today.
Doesn't look like anything to me.
But where is she?
Have you ever seen
anything like this place?
Doesn't look like anything to me.
I'm gonna help Mama put supper on.
(Lighter clinks, clicks)
I had the same thought.
Needed a little
sunshine before turning in.
So, when do you get
to rotate home again?
If you're this bad at
writing small talk,
how the fuck did you get your job?
Get to the point.
I wanted to apologize if I
came across as aggressive.
And I wanted to talk to
you about the update.
The problem's been resolved.
There should never have been
an update in the first place.
Ford and Bernard keep making
the things more lifelike.
But does anyone truly want that?
Do you want to think that your husband
is really fucking that beautiful girl
or that you really just shot someone?
This place works because the
guests know the hosts aren't real.
So what exactly are you suggesting?
Stop the updates altogether.
Maybe even roll them back a bit.
Make the hosts more manageable.
Lobotomies tend to do that.
Well, think of the benefits
in terms of design
time, maintenance, costs.
Not to mention the Dr. Ford factor.
The guy's gonna chase his
demons right over the deep end.
I mean, no one respects him more
than me, but at some point...
I. No one respects him more than I.
Your pronoun is the
subject of the second clause.
I was saying...
You were saying should
our fearless leader
have a breakdown, you want to
leverage it for your career.
Listen, a changing of
the guard is long overdue.
I just wanted you to
know that you have my support
and that I know that the corporation's
real interest in this place
goes way beyond gratifying some rich
assholes who want to play cowboy.
And here I thought you were only good
for writing depraved little fantasies.
You're right.
This place is one thing to the guests,
another thing to the shareholders,
and something completely
different to management.
So enlighten me.
What do you think management's
real interests are?
You're smart enough to
guess there's a bigger picture,
but not smart enough to see what it is.
You know how much use that
makes your support to me?
Fuck all.
Get some sleep, Mr. Sizemore.
You'll have more rich
assholes to gratify tomorrow.
(Piano playing)
Early night, Maeve?
Feeling a bit out of sorts.
Clementine can pick up the slack.
Night.
Forgetting something, Kissy?
I'm beginning to think
you're getting sweet on me.
Well, on account of you
being half cornhusker.
Tell me which half is which
and I'll search that half.
(laughs)
Yeah, the half that's
gonna cut your fucking throat.
(Floorboards creak)
- I told you, I didn't take...
- (hammer clicks)
(gurgling)
Good as new again, huh?
Sometimes I envy your forgetfulness.
We've got a serious
problem with one of the hosts.
Thinking this one's still thirsty.
Not gonna die this time, Arnold.
Ain't nothing gonna kill me.
- (Gasps)
- (gunshot)
(whimpering)
You can't have none. Ain't for you.
Found me another bottle.
You're a growing boy.
A growing boy.
(laughs)
Growing boy!
(Powers down)
We got two guests inside.
We'll go talk to them,
you sort this mess out.
You know, they're
supposed to turn on each other,
but only if a guest takes them
on the High Sierra storyline,
and Walter always buys it.
Well, I guess Walter got
tired of buying it.
I suppose this means the sheriff
wasn't an isolated incident.
It's good news, really.
Confirms the problem was
part of the update.
We can roll them back,
clean them up, put them back in service.
You think I'm gonna sign off
on this fucking homicidal
thing going back into service?
It's homicidal by design.
Walter kills other hosts all the time.
I'll admit the method here
is a little unconventional,
but it didn't hurt a guest.
The hosts are supposed to
stay within their loops,
stick to their scripts
with minor improvisations.
This isn't a minor improvisation.
This is a fucking shitstorm.
We recall all remaining
updated hosts tomorrow.
Examine them one by one,
decommission the faulty ones.
What about narrative?
A recall of that
size will be disruptive.
I've told our overstimulated
friend to advance
the saloon heist a week
and make it twice as bloody.
Should give us cover to
recall the remaining hosts
and the guests will love it.
I'm not sure Ford will approve.
I'm not sure either, which is why
you get to be the one to tell him.
This is your fuckup, Bernie.
Only seems fair.
Ford: So our creatures
have been misbehaving,
and you haven't yet isolated the bug?
That's so unlike you, Bernard.
Unless, of course, you have and are
simply embarrassed by the result.
It's the code you added, sir.
The reveries.
It has some...
"Mistakes"
is the word you're too
embarrassed to use.
You ought not to be. You're a
product of a trillion of them.
Evolution forged the
entirety of sentient life
on this planet using only one tool...
The mistake.
I flattered myself we were taking
a more disciplined approach here.
I suppose self-delusion is a
gift of natural selection as well.
Indeed it is.
But, of course, we've managed to slip
evolution's leash now, haven't we?
We can cure any disease,
keep even the weakest of us alive,
and, you know, one fine day
perhaps we shall even
resurrect the dead.
Call forth Lazarus from his cave.
Do you know what that means?
It means that we're done.
That this is as good
as we're going to get.
It also means that you must indulge me
the occasional mistake.
(Groans)
About three liters.
That's how much blood I left in you.
Lose more than that, you die.
But for now, you're mine.
I'm gonna get some answers out of you.
(Gurgles)
(laughs)
Where are you... (laughs)
(coughing)
What do you want?
You know about games, don't you, Kissy?
Well, this is a complicated one.
I don't play. I only deal.
Who said anything about you playing?
You're livestock, scenery.
I play.
The others, they just come
here to get their rocks off,
shoot a couple Indians.
But there's a deeper level to this game.
You're gonna show me how to get there.
A lot of wisdom in ancient cultures.
(Coughs)
And perhaps it's...
time to dig deeper into yours.
No. No. No.
(Screaming)
(birds chirping)
Morning, Daddy. Did you sleep well?
Daddy, you've been out here all night?
I had a question.
A question you're not supposed to ask.
Which gave me an answer
you're not supposed to know.
What's wrong, Daddy?
Would you like to know...
(stuttering) the question?
- Question?
- Mama!
Mama, help! Come quick!
Don't worry.
Don't worry. I'll take care of you.
- No!
- (gasps)
You should go. Leave.
Don't you see?
Hell is empty and all
the devils are here.
(Whispers)
You stay right here. Understand?
I'm gonna find the doctor.
- You came back.
- I told you I would.
- What's wrong?
- You have to come with me right away.
My father's very ill.
(Piano playing)
I think we best stay put.
All right. All right.
With considerable
effort and lack of sleep,
I've managed to massage
events to inspire Hector
to head to town a week early.
Oh, and I've also punched
up the speech he gives
after robbing the saloon.
It's chilling. You'll see.
I can barely contain myself.
That's the sheriff's
horse, you son of a bitch.
- (Gunshot)
- (people screaming)
His rifle, too.
- (Gunshot)
- (people screaming)
(gunshots)
(people screaming)
(gunshot)
All the banks and trains around here,
and you fucking
reprobates choose to rob us?
Why not?
You're all here
indulging your particular vices.
And so I've come to indulge mine.
(Gunfire continues)
I've got to get back to Father.
- (Gunfire continues)
- Dolores, no!
(Grunts)
Teddy.
Don't mind me.
Just... just trying to look chivalrous.
Oh, Teddy.
(Gunshots)
(groaning)
You're a low-down son of a bitch.
I know.
I know we both believe the same thing.
No matter how dirty the business,
do it well.
(Whistles)
No telling there's
anything worthwhile in that safe.
We should take this sweet little bitch
just in case.
- (Gunshot)
- (gasps)
(piano playing)
- (gunshot)
- (grunts)
(gunshot)
Problem with the
righteous... They can't shoot for shit.
Making a hell of a racket, though.
(Gunshots)
You wanted me.
Well, let this be a lesson.
- The lesson is...
- (gunshot)
- (gunshots)
- (grunts)
Oh, Jesus.
(Breathing heavily)
(laughs)
Look at that! I just
shot him through the neck!
And his pal here, too.
Look at her wriggle.
Yo, go get that photographer.
I want to get a picture of this.
- Okay.
- Whoo!
You're welcome.
Maybe you'll get to
your speech next time.
Oh, Teddy.
At least I got to see you one last time.
(Crying) You're not
going anywhere, now, hear?
There's a path for everyone.
My path is bound with yours.
Teddy?
Teddy, no.
Please.
No, we've only just begun.
(Sobbing)
- (flashbulb pops)
- (laughs)
That was good. Hang on. Hang on.
Let me get the hat. Get the hat.
(laughs) All right.
Help, please.
My father's sick at home,
but I can't just leave
him out here in the street.
(Crying)
Soon this will all
feel like a distant dream.
Until then, may you rest in
a deep and dreamless slumber.
(Beeps)
Two more over here.
We got them all.
That's all of them.
Any preliminary results?
Most of them are checking out fine.
We had one who...
definitely was not.
Bring her back online.
(Beeping)
(gasping)
Cognition only. No emotional affect.
(Gasping stops)
All right, sweetheart, can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm not feeling quite myself.
Lose the accent.
- Do you know where you are?
- I'm in a dream.
That's right, Dolores. You're in a dream.
A dream that could determine your life.
You want to wake up from
this dream, Dolores?
Yes.
I'm terrified.
There's nothing to be afraid of,
as long as you answer
my questions correctly.
- You understand?
- Yes.
Good.
First, have you ever questioned
the nature of your reality?
No.
Has anyone around you?
For instance, your father?
Dolores: He was scared.
He wasn't thinking right.
He showed you a picture.
That's right.
Stubbs: Was there anything
odd about that picture?
Dolores: No, nothing at all.
It didn't look like anything to me.
If it breached, he needs to be put down.
That's the policy.
Would it not be best for
us to discover why first,
Ms. Cullen?
Please.
We've run a full diagnostic,
but the results are,
well, confusing.
Tell me, what happened to your program?
(Shivering)
"When we are born,
we cry we are come
to this great stage
of f-f-fools."
That is enough.
Tell me, do you have access
to your previous configuration?
Yes.
Access that, please.
What is your name?
Mr. Peter Abernathy.
Mr. Abernathy, what are your drives?
Tend to my herd.
Look after my wife.
Your final drive?
Well, my daughter Dolores, of course.
I must protect Dolores.
I am who I am because of her,
and, well, I...
I wouldn't have it...
I-I wouldn't have it any...
other...
I-I have to warn her.
Warn who?
Dolores.
The things they do to her.
The things you do to her.
I have to protect her.
I have to help her. I...
She's got to get out.
Very good, Mr. Abernathy.
That's enough.
Bernard: This behavior,
we're miles beyond a glitch here.
Access your current build, please.
What is your name?
Rose is a rose...
is a rose.
What is your itinerary?
To meet my maker.
Uh-huh.
Well, you're in luck.
And what do you want
to say to your maker?
By most mechanical
and dirty hand...
(laughs)
I shall have such revenges on you
both.
The things I will do.
What they are, yet I know not,
but they will be the
terrors of the earth.
You don't know where you are, do you?
You're in a prison of your own sins.
(laughs)
Turn it off.
(Powers down)
What the hell was that?
I don't know. He's off script.
We didn't program any
of those behaviors.
Shakespeare.
We've used this host in a number
of different roles, have we not?
Since I've been here, he's
been Abernathy for 10 years.
He was sheriff for a while before then.
- And before that...
- The professor.
Yes, from a horror narrative
called "The Dinner Party."
He was leader of a group of cultists
out in the desert who turned cannibal.
Ford: He liked to quote
Shakespeare, John Donne,
Gertrude Stein.
I admit the last one is
a bit of an anachronism,
but I couldn't resist.
These are fragments of prior builds.
The reveries must be
allowing him to access them.
No cause for alarm, Bernard.
Simply our old work coming
back to haunt us.
Stubbs: Your father
whispered something to you.
What was it?
He said I shouldn't tell anyone.
I won't tell anyone else.
Promise.
He said,
"These violent
delights have violent ends."
Stubbs: Does that mean anything to you?
No.
I don't think so.
Have you ever lied to us?
No.
Last question, Dolores.
Would you ever hurt a living thing?
No.
Of course not.
Tilt your head back, please, Peter.
(Whirring)
Woman: Wipe's complete.
You don't think any of that
had an impact on her core code?
Not good old Dolores.
You know why she's special?
She's been repaired so many
times, she's practically brand-new.
Don't let that fool you.
She's the oldest host in the park.
Come on, sweetheart.
Tell us what you think of your world.
(Western accent) This world?
(Birds chirping)
Some people choose to see
the ugliness in this world.
The disarray.
Morning, Daddy. You sleep well?
Well enough.
You heading out to do some
more of that painting of yours?
Dolores: I choose to see the beauty.
(whispering)
(train whistle blows)
Dolores: To believe there
is an order to our days...
a purpose.
(fly buzzing)
I know things will work
out the way they're meant to.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --