- Previously on Wynonna Earp...
- Willa!
Who have you hurt the most?
- [gunshot]
- [screaming]
I forgive her!
- Just one crazy girl.
- You're saying
Bobo's hiding
Revenants in the trailer park?
You wanna win this war, we do it my way.
Are you gonna tell me you're kicking
it with the ghost of Doc Holliday?
Demons walk among us, and
they mean to end my line.
You don't wanna do this!
You have no idea what I want.
- Revenge.
- Seems like you're just my type.
What makes you think that you are mine?
Willa!?
Willa!
[screaming]
- Willa?
- It's Wynonna.
Your sister, the bag of
chaos you live with?
[gasping]
But this is...
but Willa's gone. Dead.
I'm alive. Right?
Get them.
Dude, I did! I have! Look!
I killed them so hard.
Sent their creepy
asses back where they belong.
Not all of them. [echoing]
Willa?!
Willa, you can't be here...
Daddy couldn't save us.
How the hell will
you? They'll eat you alive.
[screaming]
Oh! Here.
OK. OK.
Nan always said the
Prairie winds bring in bad dreams.
- Those're some brutal winds.
- Here,
- drink some water.
- Is it beer o'clock?
Mix it with tomato
juice and it's breakfast.
Only if you throw a raw egg
and some
horseradish in there too, Daddy.
[gun falling to ground]
Whoops-a-daisy.
You can't keep doing this.
Killing people and
pretending like it doesn't affect you.
I'm more than halfway through The Seven.
Yeah, but there are, like,
seventy-seven in the curse, OK?
You're barely five
percent of the way in.
You and your math both suck.
You called out Willa's name.
I miss her.
I can't quite remember...
Did she have pierced ears?
Yeah.
One piece at a time.
That's how people slip away.
Daddy said revenge
was a balm for the soul.
If I kill the evil that
took him and our sister,
then we can dream, and
remember, and it won't have to be sad.
Try to get some sleep, OK?
Tracking down
Revenants can wait 'til morning.
[grunting]
[screaming]
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -
♪ 'Cause I gave you all
I've got to give ♪
♪ And no, that
ain't no way to live ♪
♪ I told that devil ♪
♪ To take you back ♪
I brought you a shirt, so
put your coffee back on.
You know what I mean.
The thermostat is broken.
Whole building. Furnace won't quit.
Good.
I thought I was suffering some
kind of pec-induced fever.
What's on the agenda today?
The City Manager's
requested a meeting, so I need you
to put on your grown-up face.
I have one of those?
This is the chief
executive officer of Purgatory.
- And a judge.
- It's not like he's the law.
He decides who is the law.
And...
he could shut us down,
so we need to be on his good side.
So get yourself chest already.
Dressed. Already.
Don't wanna keep
Judgey Manager Dude waiting.
Cryderman. Let's not
keep Judge Cryderman waiting.
Record scratch.
Judge who?
I've been meaning
to call you in,
but we've had some unfortunate issues
with the Town Planner.
Is that the man that lost his
arm in the biking accident?
Some things just work out.
Of course. Judge, you
have a terrific town here
and my partner and I
want to help make sure
- it stays that way.
- Exactly.
That's why I wanna know what
the hell you're doing here, Dolls?
- As you know, the U.S. Marshals...
- Joint Task Force,
Special Assignment, etcetera.
I know this.
The Crydermans have been in Purgatory
for over 140 years. And
we like to keep tabs.
It's a small town thing.
Are criminals, drug dealers and
gangbangers a small town thing too?
As a Judge,
you always wonder where
the bad seeds end up.
Turns out, right back here in my office.
Where d'ya think Bobo Del Rey
will end up? Or do you
not keep tabs on him?
Mr. Del Rey may not be an Ivy Leaguer,
but he's no moron.
To be honest, Judge, I'm less concerned
about Bobo's IQ, and more concerned
about his potential criminal activity.
What criminal activity?
This crate was delivered to
his trailer. I took the photo
- this morning.
- Could be anything.
Then why are his
colleagues guarding it with guns?
He has connections. Do
you know what that means?
It means trouble. But only if my
partner and I overstep our bounds.
I don't like extra work
cluttering things up. Especially
during duck season.
You know what I've heard? There's a
bumper crop of mallards this year.
You a duck-huntin' man?
Maybe I'll give you a
call on migration day.
You give us a chance to prove
that Bobo's heading
up a criminal conspiracy?
[snapping fingers]
And I'll have a thermos
of bourbon at the ready.
[laughing]
Can we get back to business here?
I'll have a warrant sent
over within the hour.
Thank you very much, Judge.
It's a shame, what went south
with this girl.
Born bad, I think.
Her daddy was a real legend.
I'm just glad the dead rest easy.
Gum?
Might take the taste of
judge anus out of your mouth.
Look, I know you got a
history with the judge,
but we hit jackpot. A search warrant.
I'm a 27-year-old
woman cursed with shooting
demon-adjacent revenants who
bleed frothing brown goo,
and now I have to
worry about search warrants?!
This is all the warrant I
need. And Bobo's an easy target.
You know what happens if
you shoot Bobo in a trailer park
filled with humans,
women and children, right?
One more checkmark on my to-do list?
Someone records him
being sucked into the
ground. Puts it online.
It goes viral. The government bombs
the Ghost River Triangle,
conspiracy theorists go mad
and you spend the remainder
of your days in a psych ward.
Oh, if you're not dead already.
- So we do it by the stupid book.
- You, me,
and a collection of local finest.
We get to use legit cops?
Dolls, you coulda led with that.
Waverly will stake the
place out during the raid
and photograph anyone she
sees. Doc will come down,
see if he recognizes anyone
- from the old days.
- Cryderman know about this?
Shh.
- Nope.
- Aw, there's a little rebel in there.
Not that little.
What is there? A sale on lawn chairs?
Park's looking mighty empty.
Hey, you find any clippers in
there? I got this hangnail
that's just driving me nuts.
While you're down there, Deputy
Whatever-The-Hell Earp,
my knobs need some polishing.
Actually, there's a lot around here
that could use a woman's touch.
Officer, could you take
him outside, please?
Now.
All right.
He's clearly a criminal, so where's
the stuff to prove it?!
Time to regroup.
Something's wrong, Dolls. I feel it.
[grunting]
Back...
Doc...
die!
Wooden crate.
Five feet by two by one.
Not ringin' any bells.
I saw you receive it.
Where's it at? What's in it?
Oh, yeah. Um...
- No, still not ringing.
- I think it's time
that I talk to some of your 'friends'.
- Where can I find them?
- Big sale on yoga mats
down at Lululemon.
He's just gonna keep
jerking us around. This won't work.
You in the mood to take a trip downtown,
Bobo?
Easy, boys.
I'm think I'm comfy right here.
But maybe Deputy Earp over there
might want to give
me a little underdoggy,
get the breeze going?
Uh-oh...
All I want
are the scumbags who came for Ward Earp.
Two of them are still alive.
Tell me who they are,
and we leave you alone.
- Get down.
- Wynonna's
going all Wynonna again.
Two choices. You can help me...
- Deputy Earp!
- Or you can not help me, and die.
Really?
You can't arrest me, Mr. Dolls.
Once it's done, it's done.
There will be no mercy for you.
Thanks for the tip.
[gasping]
Oh shit.
Find, Distance to Puerto Vallarta.
Total distance - 2,696 miles
or one day and 19 hours.
Begin guidance?
This shit would just follow
me to the beach anyway.
Hey, look.
Evidence Bobo can't
get his porn off the 'net.
Resisting arrest. Resisting arrest.
Possession for half an ounce.
Pot brownie. And don't think
I wasn't tempted to
eat it on the way back.
You know none of these charges are gonna
stick, right? This is what happens
when you go cowboy. We got nothing.
We blew it. And now I
gotta cover for you.
- You don't have to do anything.
- I have to do my job.
When are you gonna get it, Wynonna?
I'm not a cop, Dolls.
OK? So let me just do things my way.
Your way isn't working.
You think I don't get worked up over
these bastards, the same as you?
- Who knows what you feel, Dolls.
- I have to deal with Cryderman.
- Well, I'll come with you.
- No.
You've done enough damage for one day.
Waverly said the
trailer park was so empty
it looked like
Sharknado had ripped through it.
Sounds like Bobo was tipped off.
[door opening]
It's about time.
I'm starved. Just leave it on the table.
I'm not your lunch.
- Least I hope not.
- Well, come in, come in.
- To what do I owe...
- Who told you
I was watching you?
Huh? Nobody else knew where I was.
Nobody.
You're shorter than I remember.
And you're taller than I remember.
Sit.
Why,
when I was little,
did you choose me
to manipulate? Huh?
Because I was gullible?
- Weak?
- Weak...
is something you've never been.
I...
chose you...
because you were angry.
I wasn't angry.
You sure?
- I'm not, OK?
- You've got depths
that neither of us
know the bottom of yet. Trust me.
You don't know anything about me.
Oh?
Except maybe what happened to Willa.
Nothing good.
Get out.
Goodbye.
Well now there then,
isn't my dance card full.
Privacy,
finally.
But something tells me you're not
here to give me a lap dance, are you?
It's a shame to waste
those beautiful tits of yours.
Thank you, Bobo,
for making this so damn easy.
And what would that be, sweetheart?
Blowing a giant hole in your head.
OK, Wynonna, you don't wanna do this.
And I don't want to die.
I can't die.
At least, I'd rather not.
You're a hot mess in tight jeans.
You want to pump bullets into my head?
I got some bullets I'd
like to pump into you too.
- Yeah, eat shit.
- Or maybe your
pretty little sister of yours.
Watch your mouth.
You watch your mouth.
You think those shoulders are heavy now?
You wait
until everyone you love is in agony.
[outside door buzzing]
[heels clicking]
Don't say another word, Robert.
Ms. Stone.
Hey!
You're releasing
him? On whose authority?
You have a lawyer?
Don't you start.
Bad time to ask you for a lift?
I guess so.
Dick.
No sudden moves.
You're gonna give me your cell phone.
- [grunting]
- OK.
Here.
I saw how you handled Bobo's guys.
Now we're gonna pay him another visit.
I was just thinking
I need another man to
tell me what to do today,
and here you are!
Awesome!
Not to be rude, but
can we cut the chitchat?
I get car sick real bad.
Absolutely. Anything else?
Drive-thru fro-yo? Slurpee run?
Just drive.
[tires screeching]
That girl could use a cigarillo.
Del Rey and his
lawyers are considering suing
for unreasonable search and seizure.
- Know what that means?
- Insufficient cause for action.
And my name
gets dragged through the
mud by some overpaid battle-axe.
- What can I do, sir?
- I'll get the lawyer back
before five. You draft an apology,
and personally deliver
it. Bring your protégée.
Protégée?
You hire somebody for
their ass, you're responsible
- for covering it.
- That's out of line, sir.
I disagree.
And don't ask me for another warrant
unless there's something
there worth finding.
Something was there.
And for some reason, Bobo
was a step ahead of us.
If I need to move up
the chain of command...
Please. Your
superiors have been calling me,
Deputy Marshal. Asking if,
given your lack of results,
I think you should continue
in your position.
Really?
Who you been talking to?
What should I tell them?
Put your hands on your
stupid little head.
I think I'm gonna be sick. Nope.
It passed. Don't shoot.
- I know who attacked your family.
- Oh! Did you see us?
That was awesome! Hey, we
saw you leaving the cop shop
driving like a maniac so... Oh shit.
- Names. Now.
- OK, thing is,
I don't exactly have their names.
But I have a picture of all seven.
Standing by your dad's dead body.
If you wanna know
who's been killing the heirs,
- who'll eventually come for you...
- Fish?!
That is you!
[laughing]
- You old sonofagun.
- Well, dang my melt.
It's Doc Holliday!
[laughing]
Dang, boy!
You do not call me
to deal with your petty affairs.
Next time,
I expect it to be
for my reasons.
I hear them.
They call and they call,
they cry and they cry.
They won't stop.
Why won't they stop?
My head...
We're getting close, Constance.
Or should I call you
by your alias, Miz Stone?
[gasping]
It's Mrs. Clootie.
[cracking]
Now.
Tell me, what is it with you
and those damn Earp girls?
- You're ridiculous.
- [screaming]
Always chasing one of
them with your tongue out.
Suck it up, revenant.
All of it.
You wanna know power?
Suck.
It. Up.
OK, boy.
You look good.
What happened? Yatt
were thick as thieves.
- How come he turned you revenant?
- He didn't.
I'm still me. Except not.
Not to mention a sight for sore eyes!
Trout, Pickerel, whatever
your name is. Can we focus?
Doc, don't you feel a tad thirsty?
Well, if you're
buyin, I am always thirsty.
So, about this picture.
I saw you at the trailer park,
standing up to Bobo?
And I knew you could help me.
- With?
- Got caught up in a scheme.
Somebody I love. I was weak.
Some chick turn you to a life of crime?
Haven't heard that song before.
It wasn't a chick.
Oh! OK. Yep.
Life could be pretty
lonely for a fella like me.
Back in those days. You can imagine.
And then, the most beautiful man
I'd ever seen.
A photographer. Daguerreotypes,
- you know what those are?
- Old-timey pictures, right?
Mm-hmm.
He walked right up to me on the street.
He was so bold that way.
Sold me on getting my photo done.
You had to sit completely still.
My stomach was
fluttering something awful.
We just stared at each other.
And stared.
By the time the photo was finished...
How blarfably romantic.
We promised
that if we were ever struck
down by Peacemaker,
next time we regenerated,
we'd meet at the same day,
time and place.
So, what? He didn't show?
I went to the trailer
park. All folk knew
was that he'd struck some deal
with Bobo. A deal that went bad.
Which finally brings us
around to you in my truck
- and a knife at my throat.
- I need to know if he's OK.
Or not.
And if we could find out?
I'd die a happy man.
Shoot me ten times if you want.
You really have a photo of the Seven?
My fella took all their hunting photos.
Them with their "trophies". The heirs.
So I help you...
I help you back.
You're gonna want to talk to Vinnie.
He's alone at a crab shack.
Whoa.
So?
I'm paying a visit to
a guy named Vinnie.
Vinnie the Vulture?
Wynonna, he don't give
up information so easy.
I'll get it out of
him any way I need to.
Have you ever tortured anybody before?
Does six-year-old Waverly
count? 'Cause...
Hurtin' and killin', Wynonna, they are
two very different things.
Yeah. I got this.
- Alone?
- [sighing]
Look, you stay here,
keep an eye on your little friend.
If this is a trap and I die, gut him.
So you weren't expecting guests?
Why you wanna find
some brokeback Nancy's boyfriend anyway?
- Why is he your problem?
- I made a promise.
A deal.
I'm trying to become the
type of woman who keeps her word.
Oh, you have a 'code'? That's cute.
Don't make me hurt you.
Where's the photographer?
Earps.
Always trying to cut filthy little deals
whenever it suits them. [smacking lips]
This is the good part.
- Dad?
- You enjoy yourself, baby girl.
Vengeance is fun.
It's what we live for.
Nice party trick,
but Ward didn't sound like that.
I just need information.
Mm-hmm. You keep telling yourself that.
As long as you're having fun...
No!
- Where is the photographer?
- Come on now,
don't wuss out, honey! Why
don't you go for the wrist
- or the neck?
- I'm not trying to kill him.
It'll make you feel better. For a while.
Then you'll have to kill another,
but that's OK. It kept
me busy. I loved it.
You're not my dad!
Now tell me what I need to know!
Tell me.
- Tell me!
- Hell's Gate!
Bobo had Doc take Levi over Hell's Gate.
Across the line, so he'd fry.
To torture him, teach him a lesson.
Doc Holliday?
Levi begged and begged him to stop.
You would have loved it.
Go on, don't stop now.
'Cause we won't. Not
until you're in pieces,
like your big sister, Willa.
OK.
- [gunshot]
- You OK?
I know where he is.
Vinnie told me where Bobo put him.
I can take you there,
but I get my photo of the Seven first.
Sure.
Thing is, we might need to commit
a little tiny break-and-enter
- to get our hands on it.
- Where, Fish?
The basement
- of the civic building.
- That's the police station.
You want me to break
into the place I work?
Yeah, OK. I'm
surprised it took me this long.
Now, if we can get our hands on some
dynamite, and scale the North wall...
- I got something better.
- What is better than dynamite?
Boobs.
Ugh! How do you boys work in this heat?
Ladies. Even better!
I wonder if you might
be able to help me out?
No? Nothing?
OK. Yeah.
Pardon me, ladies,
but I seem to have gotten myself
the tiniest bit lost.
In short, ma'am, my
partner and I sincerely apologize
for the embarrassment on Mr. Del Rey
for our unnecessary and
unprofessional conduct.
Where is his partner? Surely you know
I cannot consider this a full
- and plenary quittance.
- Now now, Cece.
Surely you know
our whole municipal
system can't be held accountable
for every halfwit who
goes off half-cocked.
Dolls?
We do our best to
maintain discipline in the ranks.
Ma'am.
Miss Earp is a lowlife,
but we can't be responsible.
Deputy Marshal Dolls
knows he's made a mistake.
Wynonna
is an unconventional vital
asset to my team.
She is a survivor that never gives up.
And we could do with fewer child abusers
behind the bench.
Warning. The building is now under
a carbon monoxide evacuation.
Please exit in a
calm and orderly manner.
If you are dizzy or
weak, inform a co-worker now.
I've got some phone calls to make.
To your bosses.
Do whatever you like.
And your bourbon's for shit.
Uh, alarm! You need to evacuate.
Uh, this just doesn't make sense to me.
'Sense'?
Carbon monoxide!
- Colourless, odourless, lethal?
- Not to be hurtful,
but I know better than to take anything
at face value when
there's an Earp in the vicinity.
Especially if they're
claiming to look out for you.
- Nice. Good instincts, Dickenson.
- We better shake a leg.
Hello?
So this is the Black Badge Division.
My, my.
Dolls has been busy.
- You looking for something?
- Goddamn. It's you.
How was it down there?
Chilly, I bet.
One burnin' thought kept me warm.
Încá tu sunt piatrâ,
John Henry
Holliday.
Înca tu sunt piatrâ,
mort fârâ
emu
mângâia,
tu somn somn somn...
Yo, Fish.
The problem with this
whole criminal thing
is that it's kinda fun.
That is one of the
problems, Fish. But there are other...
Bigger problems.
Run. Thank you!
- You get your precious photos?
- It's just a box of negatives.
We have to find someplace to develop...
No. No, you take me to him now.
- Gear down, bro. We have a deal.
- I can't live like this,
not anymore,
not knowing...
Please, God, Wynonna!
You had your way with the Vulture!
Are you going to torture me too?
The dates on the negatives match up.
Yeah, fine, OK. We'll take you to Levi.
Well, to where Vinnie
said he was, at least.
Levi?
Oh, thank you. Thank you, thank you.
So Vinnie wasn't lying.
And don't try to tell me
you just know Levi
from the good old days.
Oh, I wouldn't dare.
But the name should ring
a bell with you too,
'cause the last time you saw him,
he'd gotten himself mixed
up with a Shadow Assassin.
That guy?
He's here? You're sure?
Don't get your hopes up. We don't
know what we're gonna find.
Fish, you cross that line,
and you will live a
thousand lifetimes of agony.
But you can cross, though. Right?
Whatever we happen upon,
I think we should tell
Fish we didn't find anything.
I don't give a rat's ass
if he's a pile of carrion.
- We made a deal.
- Have you
seen what happens to revenants
that cross the Ghost River boundary?
Not up close.
But you have.
Well, it ain't gonna be pretty.
[flies buzzing]
Clearly.
I should've gone for Puerto Vallarta
when I had the chance.
The revenat steps over the line for a
second and it's pure torture for them.
So what the hell happens if you
leave 'em staked out here for days?
It wasn't my idea to do this.
Oh, well, the fact that you were duped
into doing Bobo's dirty
work makes it all better.
Bobo wanted to make an example
of Levi so people
wouldn't cross him. I don't have
a Black Badge Division backing
me up, so I was not
in a position to be refusin'.
He chewed off his foot like an animal.
Where's the rest of him?
Well, looks like he
crawled back to safety.
Hey, you guys? What's happening?
This is the only way to sanctuary.
[man sobbing]
Fish?
[sobbing]
Just thought you'd want to say goodbye.
Levi?
It's me. Ambrose.
Your Ambrose.
What'd you do to Bobo?
What'd you do this time, bad boy?
You just could never help yourself.
No matter what I said,
you were gonna do wrong.
Are you gonna tell him, Doc?
Well, I reckon he knows.
- Fish...
- Vengeance is hollow, Doc.
Isn't worth a thing.
I think it's time. You
sure you're OK with this?
It was always gonna end this way.
I don't want to live, waiting
for either of us to be
shot down by the heir.
That's no life.
So you've made your peace?
You're gonna be the one to
break this curse, Wynonna.
For all of us.
And I thank you.
I'm gonna count to three. OK?
One.
♪ Don't you cry ♪
♪ Go to sleepy ♪
♪ Little babies ♪
It's almost time, lovies.
Uncle Bobo is finding you. All of you.
And then it will be
just like we planned.
All right, that's enough, Constance.
Let's not get hysterical.
Let me take them. They'll
be happier with me.
Won't you let me?
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
What I would like,
Connie...
is for the lead to get
out of this goddamned prison.
My lead that you've
been promising me for years.
Tit for tat.
Like we've always said.
I put your boys back together,
you give me that lead.
By the by.
When were you gonna tell me Doc Holliday
was back amongst the living?
When were you gonna tell me
he scares the living shit out of you?
You had no right!
I did what was right!
Right woulda been shooting that
thing and us running for it!
He wasn't always a thing, Doc.
And if I'm gonna keep killing them
and not go crazy, then
I need more than revenge!
Goddamnit, Wynonna!
- They're bad people!
- So I just
ignore they're people at all?
I spent over a hundred
years in the dark, at the bottom
of a dried up old well.
Do you know what thought I turned over
and over in my head? What I lived on?
The sheer knowledge
that I would pay back the bitch
that made me what I am.
This monster.
- You're not a monster.
- But a lesser man than Fish.
I saw her today.
At least I think I did.
And she...
Her power... I couldn't.
That's why you stayed. Not to help us.
I staked that man out there.
I knew what would happen to
him and I staked him still.
Even worse, I would stake every
Revenant in this world,
and most of the humans too,
if that's what it takes to
destroy Constance Clootie.
I need rules, Doc. A code.
Otherwise I'll end up just like you.
Oh, stop kidding yourself, Wynonna.
You are exactly like me.
We can't.
Shh. Say that after.
♪ Looking by the window ♪
♪ I can see ♪
♪ The raging crowd come ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
♪ Hear the whistle ♪
♪ Of revenge, my dear ♪
♪ ♪
- Is it of the Seven? Is it done?
- Not yet.
Please hurry. If Fish screwed me, I'm...
Going to realize you shouldn't
have trusted him? Stop hovering.
Or do you want to do this yourself?
'Cause this isn't my
vendetta. It's my job.
And I appreciate it.
Are we good?
Look, I killed three in a day.
Including the one who
helped us get these pictures,
and you know what? He wasn't terrible.
He looked into my eyes,
and I offered him a
chance to make peace.
And I felt... better.
Great plan.
Only thing is, Revenants
don't understand what 'peace' means.
Well, maybe only a few take
a shot at coming clean,
but I gotta offer it. I
can't fill up on revenge.
I need some peace. For me,
for my sister.
You do it your way, I'll do it mine.
As long as we are
pulling in the same direction.
Roughly.
Take a look.
- Can I take this?
- Mm-hmm.
As soon as you find a
picture of The Seven...
Yeah, I'll call. Go.
I feel like I've seen this before.
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -