(DRUM ROLLS)
*
(SOFTLY)
Bring it out, boys.
(WHISPERING)
Be really quiet while
I go get your father.
Hey.
How's it comin'?
Well, it's coming.
Thank you.
(GASPS, GROANS)
Your back still
bothering you?
Yeah, a bit.
Can give it a good
rubbin' this evening.
Yeah, that'd be nice.
You mind coming inside
with me for a minute?
What for? I gotta hang that
window before nightfall.
Well, I can't lift the
crock pot all by myself.
Uh... alright.
Hey... you know,
what're you doin'?
I don't have
time for this.
You'll see!
(LAUGHING)
Ahh.
SURPRISE!
(LAUGHS)
Happy birthday,
my love.
We love you, Pa!
I love you guys, too.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Alright, Davey,
how many cards
do you want, huh?
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
See, not your turn.
We go this way.
No-no-no-no.
Remember?
Sorry.
It's this way. We go
this way. Remember?
This way.
We go this way.
S'alright. Davey,
how many cards do
you need?
One.
Oh. Alright,
gunslinger. One card.
How many cards do
you need?
Three, please.
Three. Okay...
and I'll take two.
Okay. No, not your
turn again. Remember,
it's your brother's turn.
Alright, let's see what
you got here. Oh!
You got a pair.
That's pretty good.
What do ya got?
A flush?
A flush.
What kind of gunslinger has
his mom help him cheat? Hmm?
(PLAYFULLY)
Where's that poker face?
Eh.
(ALL LAUGH)
We're gonna
have to watch him.
(LAUGHING)
Let's do it again, alright.
Put your cards in.
Here we go.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(MOANING) Ahh... yes.
(CHUCKLING)
You've got hands
of gold, Mrs. Stevens.
(GROANS)
Why thank you,
Mr. Stevens.
(GROANING)
Ahh... oh, man.
How much work do you still have?
Uh... I gotta replace all
the shutters and windows
Due to the winds
that're comin' in.
And then I'll probably
have to start workin'
on the roof.
It's not raining
for a while, though.
I know.
You know, it's gonna
take a while to fix
that right.
You got me and the boys to help
you.
(CHUCKLING)
Yes, I do.
Happy birthday.
Mmm.
PUFF.
(WIND BLOWING)
(HORSES GALLOPING)
(THUNDEROUS GALLOPING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Pew, pew, pew.
WILL... BOYS!
Breakfast!
(THUNDEROUS GALLOPING)
You done
with that window?
Yeah, I finished that one.
I'll make my way
around the back
of the house.
And, hopefully, I'll
get started on the roof
by week's end.
You know you have
all summer.
You don't have to do
it all by yourself.
You got me and
and the boys.
We'll help you, Pa.
(GALLOPING)
What's that?
It's horses.
Uhp, uhp... stay put!
You expectin' anyone?
No... unless it's
Sheriff Barr.
He said he might
drop by to help out...
come by today, but
But I don't know who else
he'd be bringin' with him.
(DRUM BEATS,
GALLOPING)
(LOUD CLANKING,
DRUM BEATS)
(THUNDEROUS DRUM ROLL)
Boys, go to
your room now!
Will, do you know
those men?
Never seen 'em
before.
(CLANKING,
DRUM BEATS)
Maybe they're just
here to get some water.
I'll just make sure
they keep movin' along.
You get the boys,
and you go get hid.
(DRUM BEATS,
CROW CAWING)
Who is it?
I'm looking
for Mr. William Stevens.
Who's askin'?
CRASH!
THUD!
(DRUM ROLL,
CLANGING MUSIC)
(MUSIC,
NO SOUND)
*
(GUN CLATTERS)
GANG LEADER:
Hello, Will.
(BOOT STEPS)
Who the hell are you?
I asked who you are,
mister!
Oof!
Best be watching
your tongue, Sheriff!
Okay... what is this?
Okay, what do you want?
Revenge.
Sorry. I don't
recognize you.
Did I do something
to wrong you, son?
Huh?
BANG!
AH!
The only person to have
the right to call me "son"
was my father
Who you shot in the back
and killed in cold blood.
(MUFFLED CRY)
(GUN COCK)
Now who was that,
Will?
Just me here!
I'm all by myself.
Will, are you
lying to me?
GANG LEADER: Sit him
up in that chair.
(BOOT STEPS,
SPURS JINGLING)
Is this somebody's
birthday, Will?
Come out!
(SING-SONG)
Come out wherever you are!
Must be somewhere else
in the house.
Who's your father?
John Horn.
Ahh... not
THE John Horn?
Indeed.
That'd make you
his son Lee.
Boy, the apple
didn't fall far
from that tree.
THUMP!
BOOH!
(SCREAMING)
GET OUT HERE!
COME ON!
(SCREAMING)
Bitch!
GET IN THERE!
You hurt my family,
I will kill you!
I didn't tell you
to get up.
BANG!
(SCREAMS)
Well, who do
we have here?
JUST STOP!
Now tell me, which one
of you handsome boys'
birthday is it today?
Beg my pardon. Is it
the birthday girl?
Are you alright, honey?
I didn't tell you
to speak, Will.
What's your name,
young lady?
Don't answer him.
Will, you're being
very rude!
SMACK!
My name's Lee Horn.
What's your name?
When someone sticks out
their hand, it's polite to
oblige and shake their hand.
My name is Lee Horn!
What is YOURS?!
Selina!
Nice to meet ya, Selina.
I'm sure you already met
my good friends.
This is one of the famous Bell
brothers, Chris... that's his
big brother, Joe.
Russian Pete... and
Tommy Clyburn,
the El Paso Kid.
Didn't know you had such
a beautiful daughter, Will.
I'm not his daughter...
I'm his wife.
(LAUGHING)
Well, you are quite
the stud for a broken down
old cowboy. I mean...
Happy birthday, darlin'.
Will's birthday!
It's your birthday today.
Had I'd known,
I'd brought you a present.
What is it you want?
Okay. I'll get it
for you.
I told you. Revenge.
I've got like $30.
Alright. And I've got a couple
horses, and I've got some guns
that are still workin'.
You're placing the value of
human life on guns, horses,
and 30 mangy dollars?
You have nothing to offer,
Will. If I want something,
I'll just take it.
Keep my wife out of it!
Shut up!
Keep your mouth shut.
What are you doing with a broken
down, cowardly old law man like
this one, anyway?
MY PA AIN'T NO COWARD!
(LAUGHING)
Indeed he is,
my boy.
Get...!
Shooting a helpless man
in the back, killing him
in cold blood.
My father said
you were tough,
tougher than nails.
That you weren't
afraid of anything.
You may not be afraid
of what happens to you,
but what about your boys?
NO! NO! NOOO!
KEEP MY KIDS
OUT OF THIS!
(SCREAMING)
What about
this little boy here?
(WHIMPERING)
You stop
your hollerin'.
You leave my kids
out of it!
Ohh!
SLAP!
Davey: AHH-AH-AHHH!
(URINATING)
DID YOU JUST PEE
ON ME?! DID YOU PEE
ON MY BOOTS?!
(LAUGHING)
What you laughin' at?
You think that's funny?
(BOY SCREAMS)
Let's see what's funny.
NO, PLEASE.
PLEASE, DON'T!
HEY! DON'T SHOOT!
(BOY CRYING)
WHIRR
CLICK
HEY!
YOU WANT FUNNY?
THIS IS FUNNY!
How 'bout this? Huh?
Let's have some FUN!
LET'S DO IT!
Let's have some fun,
Will!
Lee, what're you doin'?
NO, PLEASE! PLEASE
DON'T TOUCH MY KIDS!
(CRYING)
BANG!
AHHHH!
(CRYING)
Come here, you
little brat.
LEE! STOP IT, LEE!
You shoulda killed me
when you had the chance.
When you killed my dad.
I'll make sure
he doesn't come after me.
SELINA: NO!
BANG!
(CRYING)
SON OF A BITCH!
BANG, BANG!
Planned this day
for a long time, Will.
Grew up hearing
stories about you.
How fast you were...
you never missed...
always got your man.
I been waitin'
a long time for this.
(LAUGHING)
And it's turned out
way better than I expected.
Let's have some fun,
darlin'!
Get on!
LEE: Make him watch!
(PANTS UNZIP)
HUH?! TAKE
A GOOD LOOK NOW!
YEAH!
HUH?!
GO, LEE!
You been a lucky man,
Will.
Huh?!
Who's next?
I'm next, boss!
GET IN THERE!
(SPURS JINGLING)
Take my hat off
for this one, eh.
You like that, eh?
I think we're just
about even. What do
you think, Will?
Look at me, Will. I know
you got some life in you,
old man. Look at me.
LOOK AT ME!
Get in there, Chris!
Now, you just about
the sweetest thing
I ever seen!
YOU GONNA LIKE THIS!
(GRUNTING)
*
You finish her up.
You boys meet us
back in town.
LET'S GO!
RUSSIAN PETE: What
the hell you doin'?
Give me your pistol.
What in the hell
you doin'?!
I said,
gimme your pistol!
CLICK
BANG!
(HORSE HOOVES)
What is going on?
GO!
Get away!
Get away from me!
Aw, what's the matter,
you drunkard? You drop
your hooch?
Aw, all that stink.
You ever hear of soap,
you son of a bitch?
Come on... can't you
get up, you drunk?
Hey.
UGH!
Easy, Mister!
She's just
the town drunk!
Help her up.
Pick up them
groceries.
Now apologize.
Sorry, ma'am.
Sorry.
Get.
Howdy do, Frank.
I haven't seen you
in a coon's age.
Been out on
the trail, have you?
Runnin' down those,
uh, cattle rustlers
and murderers?
I guess you'll be
gettin' a room over
at the Billards?
Uh, we had some
trouble yonder,
a few months back.
Huh. Bad bunch of boys come
through here and raped a woman,
killed her whole family.
Husband and kids, Frank.
It was an awful mess.
I, I wish you woulda been here.
So, how long you planning
on staying this time?
How much?
Let's see...
that'd be, uh, 26¢.
Always feel safer when
you're in town, Frank.
Well, I'll be. If it
ain't Frank Allison.
How are you, Frank?
Suppose you'll be
needing a room?
Same as usual?
Corner room upstairs,
around the back?
Yeah.
Your money's
always good here,
Frank.
You stay as long
as you like!
Town always feels
safer when you're
here, Frank.
Good talkin' to ya,
Frank!
*
(HORSE TROTTING,
JINGLING)
I can't help you none,
Frank.
I haven't seen half
of these men before.
Haven't even heard of 'em.
You'd think they'd know better
than to come lookin' to trouble
this town, though, huh?
Whoa... hold on a second.
I know this son of a bitch.
That's Lee Horn.
He come through here
a couple months ago
with his gang.
Killed a whole family
on the outside of town.
Raped the wife,
left her for dead.
She's still alive?
Yeah. She's in a real
bad way now, though.
Got drunk all the time.
Understandably so.
What she look like?
She looks like a drunk,
I reckon.
She still lives
on the outskirts of town.
She comes into town
maybe twice a week,
Pick up her hooch,
mind her own business.
She don't bother nobody.
I was to help her husband
that day on the house.
And, uh... my wife was sick,
on account of being pregnant
and all. So I didn't go.
When I went the next day...
I found her.
Lord, what a mess.
She said Lee Horn come and
murdered her whole family.
Frank!
You're welcome to stay
as long as you like.
Always feel safer
when you're here.
(DRUM BEATS,
CLANGING MUSIC)
What is it?
Saw a movement
in these rocks.
I don't see nothin'.
What you all
lookin' at?
Lee saw movement,
over near the rocks.
(SPITS)
(GUN COCKS)
CLICK
Hold it right there, Lee.
You and your boys are
under arrest.
Let's take this
nice and easy.
What seems to be
the problem, Deputy?
Plenty.
Your latest transgressions
were robbing those banks
down in Benson and Douglas.
But worst of all was the murder
of Will Stevens and his boys.
"Most recent transgressions".
Those are big words, boys.
Means this man's educated.
Makes him even more dangerous.
Let's not have no shootin'
there, Lee. Enough people
been killed.
Indeed, why would there be
more shooting? We don't want
any trouble, sir.
BANG!
No!
You want us
to grab
their ammo?
Interesting what
he said.
What?
He mentioned Will Stevens
and the boys. Didn't say
anything about the wife.
You did do
what I told you to?
I told him to, Lee!
He wouldn't do it.
CLICK,
BANG!
Hell, he didn't even
have his time with her,
like the rest of us.
Is that so?
Wasn't no need to kill her.
We were there for the Sheriff.
You never said nothing about
him having no wife and kids!
And what difference
does that make?
THEY WERE CHILDREN, LEE.
Well now, come on now, boss.
It don't matter none if we,
if we didn't kill her. Right?
Yeah, it does, you idiot.
She's a witness!
How the hell do you think
that deputy knew about it
in the first place?
We go to Mexico. What
difference does it make?
Yeah, we best
get going, boss.
Do anything like that again,
and I'll kill you.
Boss, that's not
the way to Mexico.
We're not going
to Mexico. We're
going back to Bisbee.
Shit!
Who's that?
That there is
Frank Allison.
Best bounty hunter
in the West.
Hey.
Can I get you
anything, Frank?
Samuel got any
of that stew?
Sure does. I'll tell him
to get you a bowl.
Anything else you want?
Excuse me, ma'am.
I didn't see you there.
Howdy, Selina. Suppose
you'll be wanting
your usual?
Her "usual" being
the whiskey?
Frank, she's hurtin'.
Well, keeping her
liquored up all the time
isn't gonna help her.
It's what she wants, Frank!
Bring her some soup.
Sit.
You should get
yourself cleaned up.
You're the lady whose
family was murdered.
I may be looking
for these men.
That's what I
was gonna talk
to you about.
But here you are
talkin' to me.
I have some pictures.
You can look at 'em
if you want.
Tell me if it's
the same men.
Can you tell me
how many there were?
Five. There was
five of them.
SAMUEL: Everything
okay here?
There's your soup,
Selina.
Gonna get cold.
You're not a lawman.
You're a bounty hunter.
I want you to teach
me how to shoot.
Pardon?
Teach me how
to shoot.
No.
Why? Why not?
You wanna protect yourself,
wear one of them garters on
your leg under your skirt.
Keep a small blade in it.
For me and the lady.
Wait! Why won't you
teach me to shoot?!
Wait!
Selina, don't bother the man.
Why won't you teach
me to shoot?!
You leave him be!
Go back and sit.
Get something
to eat besides whiskey.
Like Mr. Allison said.
*
(PIANO MUSIC.
LAUGHING)
(SLAPPING
THE TABLE)
How many you want?
I'll take two,
Sheriff.
I'll take two, also.
And weep.
Henry, how many you want?
I'll take two.
SHERIFF BARR: Frank?
Oh yeah. Guess what,
Frank. I don't want
any either.
Here. Check.
Check.
Uh... how's that look?
Looks good to me, 40¢.
Frank's probably gonna
bump it up.
Just callin', huh?
Alright, I'll call.
I got nothin'.
SHERIFF BAR: (LAUGHING)
He's got nothin'. Henry?
Three jacks.
(LAUGHING)
Well, I got you beat.
I gotta straight.
What do you got, Frank?
Flush.
Again? Come on.
Jeez!
That Frank is a poker ace,
that is for sure.
Hey... you, ah, you
hungry, Selina?
No.
That's it for me,
fellas. I'm out.
Take care. Good
playin' with you.
Alright.
Not much fun,
just the four of us.
I can play.
SHERIFF BARR:
You know how?
Well enough.
You got money?
(COINS JINGLE)
Looks good to me.
Frank, you alright
with the lady playin'?
FRANK: Queens.
SHERIFF BARR: Well, I got
you beat, Frank,
'cause I got three jacks.
Two tens for me.
Got you all beat
with a straight.
That's it for me,
fellas. The lady
has broken me.
It's gettin' late.
Better be headin'
home.
Alright. Back
to work for me.
Fellas... ma'am.
See ya later, Frank.
So long, Selina.
I cleaned up.
What'd you say?
Good.
You gonna teach
me to shoot?
I can pay you.
Give you back
all this money
you lost today.
I don't need
your money.
Besides, what do
you wanna learn how
to shoot for?
Please... Frank,
please teach me
how to shoot.
Well, I'm supposed
to ride out in the
morning, but...
Suppose I could
stop by for a bit.
Sheriff says you live
on the outskirts
of town?
Yes. About a mile west.
Stevens place.
You can't miss it.
Thank you, Frank.
*
You came.
Said I would.
I did what you
told me.
That's good.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Am I gonna teach
you or not?
Come in. Please.
Haven't kept the place
as clean as I should've
past few months.
That's your husband?
Yes.
Will Stevens, right?
You knew him?
Knew of him.
Lawman out of Texas.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
That'd be nice.
Thank you.
All those years married
to a lawman, he never
taught you how to shoot?
Wasn't no need to.
But now there is?
Why's that?
I ain't got no one
protectin' me anymore.
Fair enough.
First things first.
Your grip.
Gotta be tight.
Can't have a lose hand.
You got a lose hand,
you ain't gonna hit
anything.
I said tight.
Alright?
And hold it out there.
Don't lock your elbow,
But don't bend it
too much, either.
It'll kick right
back and hit you
in the face.
Knew a feller broke
his nose like that
once in a gunfight.
Made a mess.
Look right down
your arm.
Down the sight there.
Down it.
Pull the trigger?
No. Not yet.
Let's start over.
Why?
Pullin' the trigger's
the easy part.
Learnin' how to draw and aim,
that's the rough part.
So we're gonna do it over, and...
I don't need to learn that.
I need to learn how to shoot,
Frank.
Won't make any difference. You
don't learn how to draw properly
you'll be dead already.
I don't need to learn how to
draw. I need to learn how to
kill a man!
Alright then.
If you can draw quicker,
shoot before me, then you're
ready to practice shooting.
What're you waitin' for?
Holster that weapon!
When you're ready, draw.
If you beat me,
shoot me dead.
(GUN SLIDING
INTO HOLSTER)
I'm not gonna
tell you again.
Look. I've never shot
a woman before. I'm not
plannin' on doin' it now.
But if you're gonna
be stubborn, you best
beat me to the draw
If you want me to keep
practicing with you.
BANG!
Where are you going?
We're done.
What do you mean
"we're done?"
Just that.
Wait! Wait, where
do you think you're
going?!
Wait!
Wait, Mr. Allison,
will you just wait for
one moment?
Where are you going?!
Mr. Allison, where are...?
I said I was sorry!
I'm sorry, okay?
I will listen to you!
Just wait! MR. ALLISON!
PLEASE DON'T LEAVE ME!
KNOCK, KNOCK,
KNOCK, KNOCK!
Frank, you in there?!
Frank?!
KNOCK, KNOCK, KNOCK!
(PANTING)
Frank. They're comin' back.
They killed Deputy Thompson.
They killed him
and his whole posse
on the Old Spanish Trail.
They're killin' everybody,
Frank. Everybody in their path.
Who's that, Sheriff?
Lee Horn!
(PANTING)
What're we gonna do?
What're we gonna do, Frank?
How many men can
you round up?
Oh, I don't know.
Folks are scared to death
After what Lee
Horn's gang done
to Selina and her family.
How many?
I think none, Frank.
Reckon it'll just
have to be you
and me, then.
Ah, now, hold
on now.
Why don't I get on
the wire to Tucson?
See if I can get
us some help.
Get on the wire, then.
But if Horn gets here
before help arrives,
We better be ready
for 'em.
Gonna go wire.
*
(FOOTSTEPS)
(CLICK)
It's a good way
to get yourself killed.
Thought you
were leaving.
What are you
doin' here?
I want you to finish
teachin' me
how to shoot.
Well?
I'll be back
by tomorrow.
Now, this holster,
you're gonna have to pull
straight up and out.
Or else it's
gonna hang up
every time. Try it.
Alright, well,
let's try shooting,
alright?
Remember, arm out in
front, both eyes open.
Don't cross in front
of your body, or you
won't shoot straight.
Now, we're gonna
squeeze the trigger.
Don't yank it.
But make it
one fluid motion.
Don't pull it halfway.
Commit to it.
BANG!
You yanked.
No, I didn't.
I squeezed!
You yanked!
Okay. Okay.
Can I try again?
BANG!
Give you somethin'
to shoot at.
Maybe that'll help.
Try and remember
everything I told you.
(CLICK)
BANG!
You expected to hit it?
Yes.
Take you a hundred tries.
And that's if you're lucky.
What are you waitin' for?
You got three more shots
in that gun. Shoot.
CLICK
BANG!
Alright. You're reloaded.
CLICK
BANG!
You know, you're
holdin' your breath.
No.
I told you it would
take a while.
Yeah. You said that
already.
How many men
have you killed?
Twelve. I've killed
twelve men.
Is it hard?
To shoot someone?
Shootin' them
is not hard. Killing 'em
is something else entirely.
But you only kill a man
when he tries to kill you.
Or if maybe he
deserves to die?
Wouldn't be my right
to judge that.
But what if they'd done
something... so horrible
that...
Like what Lee Horn
did to you?
Yes.
Be my duty
to turn 'em over
to the law.
But what if it
was YOUR family,
YOUR life?
You'd kill 'em,
Mr. Allison.
You know you would.
Yeah. Yeah,
I'd kill 'em.
CLICK
BANG!
Damn it!
See you tomorrow morning?
I ain't learned to shoot yet.
All day, and I didn't
hit a damn bottle.
Said you'd teach me to shoot.
Tomorrow, then.
BANG!
Whoa.
Nice shooting.
Frank!
Selina, how are you?
Frank, can I, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Why don't you reload
and keep practicin'?
BANG!
Tucson dispatched
a couple of U.S. Marshalls
And a couple of deputies
to come out here,
after they got my wire.
Well, got word
that they found Lee Horn.
So they set up a whole ambush
in this place called "Dog Creek"
On the Gila Trail,
about two days ago.
Yeah. I know
the place.
Well... a mail messenger
found 'em, dead.
Who?
The two U.S. Marshalls
and the deputies!
The Gila Trail, that
hits the main road
into town?
Yeah, well, any idea how
soon they'd be here if they
was to come from Dog Creek?
About two days,
I reckon.
What about Tucson?
They sending anyone?
Oh, nah. They got... they got
half a regiment
Chasing some Apaches
up the side of a mountain.
They said they can't
spare anyone for week.
Anyone else you
can call on?
Well, that would be
Deputy Thompson,
but Lee killed him.
They're all dead, Frank.
There ain't nobody left!
Lee Horn done
killed 'em all!
So what're we gonna do?
BANG!
Why don't you
stay here tonight?
Pardon?
You're just gonna be back
here in the morning.
Put down your things.
I'll make us some supper.
Don't reckon I've ever had
a roast this good before.
Pot roast was
Will's favorite.
He'd eat it every day.
Breakfast, lunch and supper.
Stick his nose in the kitchen,
say, "Cookin' a roast?"
Yeah, well... vegetables,
chicken, bread.
He always thought
he smelled a pot roast.
You have everything
you need, Mr. Allison?
Hey, you can call
me "Frank".
Good night, Frank.
(PIANO MUSIC)
(PIANO RESTARTS)
Howdy, cowboys. Welcome
to the Bisbee Saloon.
Samuel, we got customers.
What's your name,
good lookin'?
John.
Well, I'm Scarlet. It's
a pleasure to meet you.
And who are
your friends?
Their names
aren't important.
Samuel, you got
customers!
Huh?
(GIGGLING)
Bye, honey.
Howdy, gentlemen.
What can I get you?
Get my boys a room.
And there's more
where that came from.
Right away. Vilma!
Raquel! Girls, get
over here.
VILMA: Raquel,
honey, come on.
And where's your
room, darlin'?
See you boys later.
SCARLET: Let's find out.
Alright, now I want you
to try and MOVE and shoot.
Those bottles
are too far away.
You can't pick your
distance in a gunfight.
That's the idea.
I want you to try
and find a spot.
Fire two shots from cover.
Just to keep their heads down
and then try and get closer.
Go on.
BANG, BANG!
From behind cover!
You fire from behind
cover only.
Otherwise, you're
gonna get shot.
You understand?
Alright. Go on.
BANG!
DAMN IT!
It takes time.
What am I doing
wrong?!
It's flat different.
You're moving now.
It takes a lot of practice.
Look, when you get
to cover, take a second.
Don't rush your shot.
Know where you're gonna
shoot before you do. See it
without looking. Then shoot.
That make sense?
This what it's like
in a real gunfight?
(SIGHS)
Go.
CLICK
You gonna shoot?
You gonna answer
my question?
About what?
This what it's like
in a real gunfight?
Can't answer that.
Why not?
'Cause each one's
different. That's why.
BANG!
Bottles don't
shoot back.
Hey, Tommy!
Hey!
Can't walk very well
right now.
(LAUGHTER)
Sheriff Barr. Why
don't you come on in
and have a drink?
That's alright, Samuel.
Maybe later.
Wait here.
Sheriff Barr's a good man.
He don't mind strangers
stoppin' over
every now and again.
Sheriff!
How do? Name's "Joe".
Hey. How are you?
Nice to meet ya.
Hey. Sheriff Barr.
How are ya?
I hope you don't mind us
stoppin' in for a rest.
We been on the trail
a few days, so...
Is that right?
Where y'all from?
We're on a cattle drive,
up near Douglas. Just on
our way back to Naco, so...
Welcome to stay
as long as you need.
Okay.
Samuel, here, he's got
some of the finest rooms
in town.
So make
yourself comfortable.
Alright.
Thank you.
You sure do like
reading, don't ya?
Mm-hmm.
Why?
Trying to educate myself.
And it helps me relax.
Hmm.
We should get back
to shootin'.
(HORSE NEIGHING,
TROTTING)
Frank.
Sheriff.
Selina.
Sheriff Barr.
It's good to
see you again.
Frank, I need
to speak to you
for a minute.
Selina, would you
excuse us for a minute,
please?
How do you know it's
Horn and his gang?
They got that look, Frank.
They're murderers. I could
see it in their eyes.
You actually see Horn?
Frank, I'm tellin' ya.
Did you SEE Lee Horn?
No, I did not see
Lee Horn, but I know
he's here.
I know it's them, Frank.
I know it!
I'm sorry, but...
I know it's them.
You're not thinkin'
of taking them on
all by yourself, are you?
Not here in Bisbee.
I reckon I am.
You're not gonna
help me.
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
Selina...
Lee's here?!
LEE'S HERE?!
That's why you stayed?
That's why you stayed?!
We don't know that
for sure.
Selina... I know
how you must be feelin'
right now.
Don't you DARE tell
me how I'm feeling!
If it is Horn
and his men,
I will handle it.
I'm going to
help you.
You wanna what?
I'M GOING TO HELP YOU!
I don't need your help.
Well, you're
gonna get it!
Selina... this is
what Frank does.
Let him handle this.
These men
killed my husband
and my little boys
In front of my eyes.
And they've raped me
and left me for dead.
Selina, there ain't nothin'
you can do to help.
Well then, I
can die trying!
You don't know
what you're
talking about.
PLEASE! These men,
they took my life
away from me!
Well, look. I'm gonna,
I'm gonna head on
back to town
And keep an eye
on these fellas...
in case it is Lee Horn.
Selina.
You're not a gunfighter,
Please, I can
help you.
No.
But you been
teaching me
to shoot!
Teaching you to shoot
whiskey bottles
Is not the same as taking on
Lee Horn and his gang!
They're murderers.
They'll kill you.
Like I said, I
can die trying.
No.
But I can shoot
as good as...
NO!
What are you doing?!
Where are you going?!
FRANK! DAMN IT,
ANSWER ME!
WHERE...
They killed my babies,
Frank.
THEY KILLED
MY BABIES!
They killed
my babies!
*
(LAUGHING,
TALKING)
Hey, we need to talk.
Darlin', give me a moment
with my friends.
Alright. Just
a moment.
Lee, we need to get outta
here, right now.
The Sheriff was in here.
I'm tellin' you,
he knows who we are.
Let's go visit
the Sheriff, then.
Boys!
CRASH!
Howdy, Sheriff.
Howdy. (LAUGHS)
Good afternoon
to ya.
You gave me
a fright there.
I understand you met
one of my boys.
But I wanted to
personally assure you
They're not here
to cause any trouble in this
sleepy little town of yours.
We'll take a night off
the trail and be gone
tomorrow morning.
Well... that'd
be fine, then.
You okay, Sheriff?
Yep. Yeah, I'm
fine. Just a...
You don't look it.
Well, I been a little
under the weather lately.
(ALL LAUGH)
(DRAWERS OPEN)
There's nothin'
over there.
Hey, Lee!
Come take a look
at this.
(LAUGHS)
Look like anyone
you know?
Nope.
(ALL LAUGH)
You're sure?
I'm positive.
(LOUD LAUGHTER)
I like this guy.
I really do.
Anything else
I can do for you?
(LAUGHTER)
Ain't you boys missin'
one of your men?
Scarlet!
Send one of your girls down
to see the Kid.
Where's he at?
He's keepin' the Sheriff
company.
Be a good little girl
and send one of them down.
Just do what he
says, Scarlet.
Go.
Last round, boys.
Move the horses 'round back
and get to bed.
We got
a long day tomorrow.
Thank you,
mister bartender man.
(CRACKLING FIRE)
*
(VILMA MOANING)
(GUN COCKS)
I wouldn't do that.
Better cover
yourself, miss.
Who the hell are you?
Where are the rest
of your boys?
Well, why don't you tell
me... who you are first?
You killed Will Stevens
and his boys.
Raped his wife and
left her for dead.
Now, the Sheriff.
(LAUGHS)
BANG!
(VILMA SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
He and that whore
of his wife,
He and that
whore of his wife
deserved it!
(GROANS)
(TOMMY SCREAMS)
I...it wasn't me. I swear
to God. It wasn't me.
I didn't touch her.
I didn't rape her. I didn't
rape her, it was Joe.
It was five of you.
Where are the others?
Where are they?
Saloon?
Yeah!
(GROANS)
Why did you come back
to Bisbee?!
Because we wanted
to finish, we
wanted to finish...
Finish what?
(LAUGHING)
That's it...
gonna kill her...
VILMA: Oh, my God.
Is he dead?
Not yet.
Y'know, I don't much like
whores. So you're gonna be
quiet. You understand?
Else you'll end up
just like him.
What're you doing?
Back in a while.
Unless you make a racket.
Then I'll be back sooner.
Just leave me
in here?!
Hey, Pete. You awake?
Wake up,
you drunk bastard!
(MUMBLING)
Wait. Wait.
What the hell did you do?
Sleep down here
all night?
Nah. No sleep.
Well, hurry up and get ready.
We're riding out soon.
Gotta go to
the crapper.
Well, then do it!
CLICK
That's a mighty
nasty trick, missy.
Pointin' that gun at me.
I got no truck
with you.
You raped me and you
murdered my family.
I had to.
Lee Horn,
he woulda killed me.
Killing me... won't bring
your husband back.
Put the gun down.
I will give you something
your husband couldn't.
BANG!
What's goin' on
out there?
Shut up and get back
in that bed.
People are...
SHHH!
Hear that, Lee?
Where's Pete?
He went to the crapper.
Ah, hell.
Where's the Kid?
Last I seen him,
he's still bangin'
away on Vilma.
Go get him.
Please let me out
of here. Can you just
open the door?
I've been
stuck here for hours!
Who done this?
WHO?!
He had a hat on and
big, long coat and...
You give me a name!
I don't know his name!
You give me
somethin' else, or I'll
shoot you where you lie.
All he said was about
some man, killin' some
man and rapin' his wife.
That's all I remember!
That's all I know.
I swear it!
Let me outta here!
PLEASE!
Killed him, Lee! They
shot Tommy! Was talkin'
about Will Stevens.
Think it's that
bounty hunter?
The one the Sheriff's talkin'
about, that Frank Allison?
Lee!
I need you to go
find Pete.
If he's still alive,
we're gonna need him.
What?!
I'll go.
I told Chris to.
And I'm tellin'
you, I'll go!
I need you on the balcony
with that rifle.
You can pick of anybody on the
roof tops or the street.
Chris is twice as fast.
He'll be down there
in half the time.
You do this for me?
I can do this, Lee.
Get goin'.
I'm goin'.
CLICK
BANG!
BANG! BANG!
CLICK
BANG!
(GURGLING)
(SPITS)
(SPITS BACK)
BANG!
*
(MUSIC)
CLICK
BANG!
What the hell are
you doing?
I killed 'em. I killed
two of those bastards,
Frank!
Well, I got Tommy Kleiber.
That just leaves Horn.
We gonna go
get him?
I'll handle him.
You've done enough.
But, Frank!
NO!
Horn's a cold killer.
He's not like the others.
He'll hit what he aims at.
So stay here, and
stay down.
When this is over,
I'll come back for you.
Frank?!
Be careful.
CLICK
OHH!
Hello, darlin'.
You're not gonna
be needin' this anymore.
Now, who's your friend
out there?
Go to hell, you
murdering son of a bitch.
That's the way
you wanna play it.
Hello, out there!
I got somethin' I think
you're gonna want!
You know, it's a pity
it's come to this.
If my friends had done
what they were
supposed to,
We wouldn't be in
this predicament.
Surely there's a peaceful
resolution we can come to.
I got a lot of money,
nobody to share it with.
So let's work something out,
shall we?
The only peaceful resolution
is for you
to throw down your guns
And come out
with your hands up, Lee Horn.
You pompous idiot.
I got a better idea.
I'm gonna count to five, and
you're gonna put YOUR guns down.
Or I'll put a bullet
in her head.
One... two... THREE!
Here I am, Horn. No need
to shoot her. Let her go.
The famous Frank Allison.
Well indeed, sir, it
has been an honor.
BANG!
NOOO!
Nooo!
BANG!
(HORN LAUGHS)
Nooo!
Get in there!
Alright, darlin'...
Now I'm gonna finish what
shoulda been finished
a long time ago.
Get off me!
Just like
the last time.
Go to hell!
BANG!
Frank!
FRANK!
Frank.
(WEEPS)
We got 'em, Will.
We killed every last
one of 'em.
May they rot in hell
for what they did to
you and to my boys.
We got 'em.
(HORSE HOOVES)
How you feelin'?
Well... this is for you.
What is it?
It's the reward money
for Lee Horn and his gang.
Lee alone was worth
over $500.
The big one... he never
raped me. Supposed to
kill me, but he didn't.
I reckon' it's better
I killed him then.
Take this.
I can't take it.
It's a lot of money. You can
rebuild your life. Live easy
for a long time.
Where you headed?
Up to Naco. After a man
for robbin' a bank in Douglas.
And back to Tombstone.
Is that where you're from?
You got family there?
Yeah.
You take care of yourself,
Mrs. Selena Stevens.
Hey, Frank.
You need any help
catching those fellows in Naco?
No. But if I do,
I know where to find you.