[BIRD SCREECHES]
YOU KNOW I GOTTA BRING YOU IN.
YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO KILL ME FIRST.
YEAH, I KNOW.
DO IT.
I CAN'T.
[SHOUTS]
♪ CAREFUL HOW YOU
LOOK AT ME, NOW ♪
♪ STRANGER
♪ YOU AIN'T ROLLED THE TRAIL ♪
♪ THAT I'VE BEEN ON
♪ UNTIL YOU TASTE THE DIRT ♪
♪ AND SMELL THE DANGER
♪ YOU DON'T KNOW THE HELL
♪ THAT'S MADE ME STRONG
♪ THE DEVIL STOLE MY WOMAN ♪
♪ DOWN IN TUCSON
♪ AND A BISCUIT
DOWN IN JUAREZ BECAME ♪
♪ MY ONLY FRIEND
♪ SPURRED MY HORSE BEFORE
♪ MOST BEEN AROUND...
CUT THE NOOSE OFF ♪
♪ AND RODE OFF IN THE SUNSET ♪
♪ ONCE AGAIN
♪ AND I RIDE HIGH
♪ IN THE SADDLE
♪ BUT MY HEART HAS HIT ME
♪ LIKE THE SETTING SUN
♪ I NEVER HAD TO RUN AND HIDE ♪
♪ WITH MY OLD FRIEND
♪ HERE BY MY SIDE
♪ BUT YOU CAN'T KILL
♪ A MEMORY WITH A GUN
OH, CRAP!
♪ OH, WAKE UP, LITTLE DARLING ♪
♪ OPEN THEM EYES
♪ ALL THOSE BIRDS OUT SINGIN' ♪
♪ OUTSIDE
♪ MM, GET UP, LITTLE DARLING ♪
♪ THROW ON THEM SHOES
HOW ARE YOU, EDWARD?
TWO S'S IN MISSISSIPPI, AMOS.
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS.
I'M JUST TRYING TO HELP.
YOU'RE LATE. OH, YEAH.
YOU'RE LOOKING FINE
AS CREAM GRAVY, ELEANOR.
YOU'RE LOOKING SPIFFY
YOURSELF, JESSE.
HAD A LONG NIGHT. OVERSLEPT.
YOU DIDN'T.
HADDIE RANDOLPH.
SHE'S A REAL BEAR-CAT.
HADDIE RANDOLPH?
JESSE, HOW IN THE HELL
DO YOU DO THIS?
YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES
I WONDER MYSELF.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A LOT MORE TIME
TO WONDER ABOUT THAT,
BECAUSE CHIEF...
HE'S IN A REAL MOOD TODAY.
AND WHEN HE FINDS YOU?
[LAUGHS] WOW.
HELMS!
AMOS.
JESSE.
CLOSE THE DOOR BEHIND YOU.
PLEASE.
HAVE A SEAT.
SURE.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WELL, YOU...
CALLED ME IN, REMEMBER?
I'M NOT IN THE MOOD FOR THIS.
SO I WAS A LITTLE LATE.
WORK STARTS AT 7:00 A.M. SHARP.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHAT TIME IT IS?
I UNDERSTAND, SIR.
THIS IS A BUSINESS, SON.
A WELL-OILED MACHINE.
IF ONE COG IN THE WHEEL
IS NOT WORKING,
THEN IT ALL FALLS APART.
DO YOU SEE WHAT
I'M TRYING TO SAY TO YOU?
THAT I'M A COG, SIR?
I SHOULD'VE FIRED YOUR ASS
LONG AGO,
WHEN I HAD THE CHANCE.
TROUBLE IS,
YOU DO A BANG-UP JOB.
WHEN YOU'RE HERE.
HENCE MY DILEMMA.
HOW TO LET YOU GO
WITHOUT BEING THE BAD GUY.
OR HOW TO LET YOU STAY
WITHOUT APPEARING WEAK.
COME AGAIN, SIR?
I HAVE THIS LITTLE
PET PROJECT OF MINE.
MORE OF A PASSION, REALLY.
I STUMBLED ON THIS
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO
WHEN I TOOK OVER
THE CHIEF'S JOB.
ARIZONA, 1892.
BANK ROBBERY GONE WRONG.
SIX PEOPLE DEAD.
THEY CALLED IT
THE MID-DAY MASSACRE.
SEPTEMBER 23RD, 1892.
FOUR MEN, LED BY
AN ILL-TEMPERED OUTLAW
NAMED LEVI HARDEN,
WALKED INTO A BANK.
IN THE SMALL BOOM-TOWN
OF YOUNG COUNTRY, ARIZONA.
WHEN THE SMOKE CLEARED,
SIX PEOPLE WERE DEAD,
INCLUDING A FIVE-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
TRAVELING PHOTOGRAPHER
HAPPENED TO BE PASSING
THROUGH TOWN THAT DAY.
SHELDON, THE ONE THAT
STARTED THE GAZETTE.
THAT'S RIGHT, AND WHAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
A SERIES OF RUDIMENTARY SHOTS
TO TEST A CAMERA HE'D INVENTED
ENDED UP CAPTURING
ONE OF THE ONLY
LIVE BANK ROBBERIES
EVER CAUGHT ON FILM.
[GUNSHOTS] RUN!
NO, MEN, STAND DOWN!
STAND DOWN!
DON'T SHOOT! DON'T SHOOT!
DON'T YOU...
I'LL FUCKING KILL HER!
HEY, I'LL KILL HER, DUKE!
HARDIN, DON'T YOU HURT HER!
I KNOW YOU DON'T WANT THAT.
[HAMMER CLICKS]
DON'T!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
NO!
[MAN GRUNTS]
COME ON!
HEE-YAH! HYAH!
IT GAINED NATIONAL ATTENTION,
WHAT WITH THE VICIOUS
NATURE OF THE CRIME
AND THE HIGH-PROFILED
INDMDUALS INVOLVED.
ONE IN PARTICULAR,
A WELL-RESPECTED U.S. MARSHAL
NAMED DUKE DONOVAN.
THAT HIM?
MM-HMM.
SOME SAY HE WAS THE RINGLEADER.
SO THE MAN PEOPLE
WERE SUPPOSED TO TRUST
ENDED UP BETRAYING THEM.
DOESN'T END THERE.
DONOVAN AND HARDIN
ESCAPED FREE
AND CLEAR THAT DAY.
BUT A POSSE
CAUGHT UP TO THEM LATER.
THIS ONE'S ALIVE.
SO HARDIN DOUBLE-CROSSED
DONOVAN AND TOOK THE MONEY.
ON THE CONTRARY, IT'S ALL
RIGHT THERE WITH DONOVAN.
DONOVAN CLAIMED THAT
HE WAS TRYING TO STOP THEM,
BUT HARDIN WAS
HOLDING A WOMAN HOSTAGE
OUTSIDE OF TOWN.
HE SAID HE WAS GONNA KILL HER
IF DONOVAN DIDN'T
AID IN THE ROBBERY.
SO DONOVAN SAID
HE WENT ALONG WITH IT,
UNTIL THE LAST SECOND.
THERE WAS NO SIGN
OF A MYSTERIOUS WOMAN.
AND HARDIN? DONOVAN CLAIMED
HE SHOT HIM IN THE HEAD
BEFORE HE BLACKED OUT.
NEVER FOUND THE BODY.
WELL, WHAT HAPPENED NEXT?
I DON'T KNOW
IF IT WAS HIS 20 YEARS
OF SERVICE TO THE LAW,
OR THE FACT
THAT DONOVAN CLAIMED
HE NEVER FIRED A SHOT
DURING THE ROBBERY,
BUT SOMETHING PUT DOUBTS
IN THE MINDS OF THE JURY.
THAT'S A HANGIN' OFFENSE,
BUT THEY SENTENCED HIM
TO LIFE IN THE YUMA
TERRITORIAL PRISON.
HE LASTED THERE SIX WEEKS
BEFORE ESCAPING.
HE WAS KILLED TWO DAYS LATER
BY A YOUNG DEPUTY.
SOUNDS LIKE QUITE A STORY.
OH, IT IS. I HAD TO UNCOVER
A LOT OF ROCKS
TO FIND THIS MUCH.
BUT WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I'M NOT SURE.
BUT I'M GONNA LET YOU
HELP ME FORM THAT OPINION.
HOW'S THAT?
BY GETTING AN INTERVIEW
WITH THE LAST MAN ALIVE
WHO KNOWS WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
HIS NAME IS SEYMOUR REDFIELD.
SOME PEOPLE THINK HIS REAL NAME
IS TOM SULLIVAN.
THE YOUNG DEPUTY THAT
KILLED DONOVAN THAT DAY.
WHEN SULLIVAN BROUGHT
DONOVAN'S BODY BACK TO TOWN,
HE DISAPPEARED.
WAS NEVER HEARD FROM AGAIN.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
TALK TO THIS MAN?
WELL...
LET'S JUST SAY
WE DON'T SEE EYE TO EYE
AND LEAVE IT AT THAT.
ONLY INTERVIEW I NEVER GOT.
WELL, WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
HE'LL WANNA TALK TO ME?
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
MORE MOTIVATION THAN I DO.
YOUR JOB'S ON THE LINE.
GET THE STORY.
OR...
HELLO?
HELLO? MR. REDFIELD?
JEEZ.
THAT'S A .45 LONG COLT.
ITS MANY ADMIRERS
REFERRED TO IT
AS THE PEACEMAKER.
MR. REDFIELD?
DEPENDS ON WHO'S ASKING.
I'M JESSE HELMS,
FROM THE GAZETTE.
[GROANS]
I WAS HOPING
I COULD TALK TO YOU.
I'D'VE THOUGHT YOU PEOPLE'D
TAKE THE HINT BY NOW.
UM, I DIDN'T MEAN
TO INTRUDE, SIR.
KNOCKED ON THE DOOR,
AND IT FELL OPEN.
YOU KNOW, I COULD'VE BLOWN
YOUR GODDAMN HEAD OFF.
AND I'D'VE BEEN
WELL WITHIN MY RIGHTS.
BUT, SINCE I JUST
SAVED YOUR LIFE,
WHY DON'T YOU HAVE
A DRINK WITH ME?
UH, NO... NO THANK YOU, SIR.
I'M ON THE CLOCK.
WHOSE CLOCK?
NOT MY CLOCK.
WELL, IN THAT CASE,
A SMALL ONE, SIR.
WHY DON'T YOU REST YOUR BUTT?
MAKE YOURSELF COMFORTABLE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
YOU KNOW, MY, UH...
[REDFIELD SIGHS]
CHIEF SAID THAT YOU DIDN'T
LIKE TO TALK TOO MUCH.
YOUR CHIEF?
YOU MEAN MORGAN HEINZ?
WELL, PAY NO ATTENTION
TO MORGAN HEINZ.
HE'S NOTHING BUT
A DAMNED OLD BLOWHARD.
ONLY THING HE'S INTERESTED IN
IS A GOOD SCANDAL
SO AS HE CAN SELL
MORE SHEETS OF THAT
RAG HE PUTS OUT.
HEINZ SAID THAT
IF I DIDN'T TALK TO YOU,
THEN I'D BE OUT OF A JOB.
OH, WELL, THAT'S TOO BAD.
HOWEVER, I HEAR THE PIG FARM
DOWN THE ROAD IS HIRING.
YOU KNOW, SIR,
I DON'T WANNA WASTE
ANY MORE OF YOUR TIME.
I'LL SEE MYSELF OUT.
[HAMMER CLICKS]
I INHERITED THIS GUN
FROM DUKE DONOVAN.
THE DAY HE DIED.
MARSHAL DUKE DONOVAN?
THE VERY ONE.
WAS THAT THE GUN
HE USED IN THE ROBBERY?
IS THAT WHY HEINZ
SENT YOU HERE?
TALK ABOUT DUKE DONOVAN?
WELL, YES, SIR. IT IS.
WELL...
I SUPPOSE IF YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR THE TRUTH,
THAT'S WHERE IT ALL BEGAN.
WITH DONOVAN.
BY 1892,
SOME SAY THE LEGEND
OF DUKE DONOVAN
HAD BEGUN TO ECLIPSE THE MAN.
HE NEVER HAD ANY CHILDREN.
ON ACCOUNT OF THEIR
GETTING MARRIED
LATER IN LIFE.
JUST A WIFE HE LOVED FIERCELY.
♪ THEY SAY THAT
EVERY NAME IS WRITTEN DOWN ♪
BUT THEIR PASSION
FOR EACH OTHER
MORE THAN MADE UP FOR IT.
♪ ONE DAY OUR TIME WILL COME ♪
THEIR LOVE WAS CONSTANT.
♪ AND EVERY ONE OF US
♪ WILL STAND ALONE
♪ TO ACCOUNT FOR
WHAT WE'VE DONE ♪
THROUGH THICK AND THIN,
SHE STOOD BY HIM.
HAS THE JURY REACHED
THEIR VERDICT?
WE HAVE, YOUR HONOR.
WE, THE ABOVE ENTITLED JURY
DO HEREBY FIND DUKE DONOVAN
GUILTY ON ALL COUNTS.
[PEOPLE CLAMOR] [GAVEL POUNDS]
ORDER!
ORDER IN THE COURT! ORDER!
NOW, THE PUNISHMENT
FOR SUCH A CRIME
IS TO HANG
BY THE NECK UNTIL DEAD.
IN LIGHT OF YOUR MANY YEARS
OF COMMUNITY SERVICE,
AND YOUR IMPECCABLE
SERVICE RECORD,
THE COURT HAS
DECIDED TO GRANT YOU
A REPRIEVE. [PEOPLE CLAMOR]
THEREFORE, YOU ARE
HEREBY SENTENCED
TO LIFE IMPRISONMENT
AT YUMA TERRITORIAL PRISON.
WHERE YOU SHALL DO HARD LABOR
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE,
WITHOUT THE POSSIBILITY
OF PAROLE.
THIS COURT'S ADJOURNED.
TAKE HIM AWAY.
[PEOPLE CLAMOR]
[REDFIELD]
DUKE CAME TO YUMA PRISON
IN THE SPRING OF 1893.
HIS ARRIVAL WAS
THE TALK OF THE PLACE.
HE HAD AS MANY ENEMIES IN YUMA
AS HE DID ADMIRERS.
[LAUGHS] HE'D PUT
HALF OF THEM IN THERE.
HE WAS A QUIET, DELIBERATE MAN.
AND THOSE EYES...
NO ONE EVER FORGOT THOSE EYES.
ALL HANDS AT ATTENTION!
WARDEN'S ON THE FLOOR!
I'D LIKE TO TAKE A MOMENT TO...
PERSONALLY WELCOME
YOU ALL TO YUMA.
[LAUGHS]
I BELIEVE... [PRISONER COUGHS]
YOU'LL FIND YOUR STAY HERE
TO BE A TOUGH, BUT A FAIR ONE.
WE WORK A SIX-DAY WEEK
AND REST ON SUNDAYS.
THAT'S RESERVED
FOR THE GOOD LORD.
I DON'T CARE WHO YOU ARE
OR WHAT YOU DID.
BUT IN HERE, YOU'RE MINE.
THE GOVERNMENT
OF THIS GREAT TERRITORY
HAS ASKED US TO ASSIST
IN THE CONSTRUCTION OF
A NEW SECTION OF PRISON.
YOU'LL GET TWO SQUARES A DAY.
BUT YOU'LL HAVE TO WORK
DAMN HARD FOR THEM.
HOWEVER, IN THE END,
YOU'LL MANAGE TO DO SOMETHING
YOU FAILED TO DO
IN YOUR PREVIOUS LIVES.
MAKE A POSITIVE
CONTRIBUTION TO SOCIETY.
I CONSIDER MYSELF A FAIR MAN.
SHOULD YOU HAVE A NEED
THAT HAS NOT BEEN ADDRESSED,
MY DOOR IS ALWAYS OPEN.
ACE HIGH.
GODSPEED IN YOUR WORK.
YOU LADIES HEARD THE WARDEN.
BACK TO WORK.
NOT YOU, DONOVAN.
COME WITH ME.
COME ON!
YOU'LL BE STAYIN' IN HERE.
WARDEN LOGAN THOUGHT
IT MIGHT BE A GOOD IDEA
TO KEEP YOU AWAY FROM
THE REST OF THE POPULACE.
GET CHANGED.
WE'LL COME BY
TO COLLECT YOUR CLOTHES.
REMEMBER, LADIES.
THERE IS NO TALKIN'
ON THE LINE.
UNLESS YOU WANNA
BE EATING YOUR DINNER
THROUGH A STRAW.
KEEP IT DOWN! STAY QUIET!
PUT YOUR BACKS INTO IT!
HEY!
ARE YOU TALKIN' TO ME?
YEAH.
I LIKE THAT PICKAXE
YOU GOT RIGHT THERE.
SAY...
AIN'T YOU THAT LAW DOG
EVERYBODY'S BEEN TALKING ABOUT?
YEAH.
THAT'S ME.
THAT'S RIGHT!
THESE ROCKS AIN'T
GONNA BREAK THEMSELVES!
[REDFIELD]
DONOVAN BEGAN TO SETTLE IN
TO HIS NEWFOUND LOT
AT LIFE IN PRISON.
WORKING BY DAY.
SEPARATED FROM THE OTHER
PRISONERS AT NIGHT.
MANY BEGAN
TO FORGET HE WAS THERE.
AS DAYS TURNED TO WEEKS,
THE FIRST MONTH PASSED.
IT LOOKED LIKE DONOVAN
WAS GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
THAT IS,
UNTIL THE DAY WILL PENNY
AND CAGE DALTON ARRIVED.
DALTON'S ORNERY DISPOSITION
GOT HIM THROWN
IN THE HOLE IMMEDIATELY.
[DALTON MUTTERS]
STRAIGHT TO THE HOLE.
[REDFIELD] AS FOR WILL PENNY?
WELL...
HE WOULD HAVE MORE TO DO WITH
THE FATE OF DUKE DONOVAN
THAN ANYONE COULD HAVE
EVER REALIZED.
THAT'S RIGHT!
KEEP DIGGIN'!
YOU WANT SOME?
NO MESSIN' AROUND!
IS IT TRUE?
THAT IF THE WARDEN'S
IN A BAD MOOD,
HE MAKES US PRISONERS DIG
WITH JUST THE HANDLES?
NO?
[SOBS]
WHAT'RE YOU DOING, KID?
[SOBBING LOUDLY]
KEEP WORKIN'!
HEY!
GET A HOLD OF YOURSELF,
GODDAMN IT.
BUNCH OF CRIMINALS.
KID, KID, LOOK AT ME.
YOU WANT CANE TO HEAR YOU?
SON OF A BITCH.
SORRY ABOUT THIS, KID.
NO-NO-NO-NO-NO!
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK HE'S SCORPION-BIT.
THAT TRUE?
YES. IT'S JUST LIKE HE SAID.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
GET HIM UP ON HIS FEET.
GET HIM UP ON HIS FEET,
TAKE HIM TO THE WAGON.
GET HIM A DRINK OF WATER.
WHOLE THING'S GONNA
SET US BACK TODAY.
WARDEN'S GONNA BLOW UP!
TAKE A LITTLE SIP OF WATER.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, MR. DONOVAN.
WARDEN'S ON THE BLOCK!
WHAT HAPPENED HERE?
HE GOT SCORPION-BIT, SIR.
SHOW ME.
OH...
WHAT'S THAT, SIR?
SHOW ME YOUR BITE.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
I DON'T KNOW...
YOU KNOW, I...
SHOW THE BITE NOW,
OR I'LL SHOOT YOU DEAD.
OKAY! PLEASE.
[SOBS] THERE IS NO BITE.
I DON'T GOT NO BITE, SIR.
I THOUGHT SO.
THERE, NOW. THERE, NOW.
IT FEELS GOOD TO TELL
THE TRUTH, DOESN'T IT, BOY?
YES, IT DOES, SIR.
HMM.
WELL, THAT'S STILL NO EXCUSE.
OH NO! PLEASE! PLEASE!
THROW HIM IN THE HOLE.
I WILL NOT TOLERATE LIARS.
GET UP! COME ON!
YOU GOT A PROBLEM WITH THAT?
HE'S JUST A KID.
THAT KID CUT
A COUPLE IN EL PASO
FROM EAR TO EAR WITH
A BUTCHER'S KNIFE.
BUT THEN, YOU KNOW ALL ABOUT
MURDERING WOMEN AND CHILDREN,
DON'T YOU?
DEPUTY SULLIVAN?
YES, SIR?
THROW HIM IN THE HOLE AS WELL.
SEEIN' AS YOU'RE
THE SYMPATHETIC TYPE,
YOU CAN SPEND SOME TIME THERE
WITH YOUR NEW FRIEND.
LET'S GO, DONOVAN.
COME ON.
NEXT TIME, IT WON'T BE EMPTY.
I'M SORRY ABOUT THIS, DONOVAN.
[MICE SQUEAK]
ALL RIGHT.
♪ THEY SAY THAT EVERY NAME ♪
♪ IS WRITTEN DOWN
♪ ONE DAY OUR TIME WILL COME ♪
CHECKING THE LOCKS.
♪ AND EVERY ONE OF US
♪ WILL STAND ALONE
♪ TO ACCOUNT FOR
WHAT WE'VE DONE ♪
STOP.
...CUT YOUR GODDAMN TONGUE OUT.
♪ WHAT I HAVE
♪ AND HAVEN'T BEEN
GET SOME SLEEP.
♪ VENGEANCE IS MINE
♪ SAYS THE HOLY WORD
♪ BUT I CAN'T WAIT TILL THEN ♪
♪ NO, I CAN'T WAIT TILL THEN ♪
♪ EACH TIME YOUR NAME
♪ FALLS ACROSS MY LIPS
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
♪ IT'S LIKE A PRAYER INSIDE ♪
♪ NO CHAINS OR WALLS
♪ ARE STRONG ENOUGH
♪ TO KEEP ME FROM
♪ YOUR...
STILL ONE MORE WEEK TO GO.
♪ I'LL HOLD YOU CLOSE
♪ AGAIN
COCKSUCKER.
♪ MY FAITH REMAINS
♪ TILL THE END OF TIME
♪ BUT I CAN'T WAIT TILL THEN ♪
♪ NO, I CAN'T WAIT TILL THEN ♪
♪ THE SUN BURNS CROSS THE SKY ♪
♪ EVERY DAY I DIE
♪ ONE MEMORY AT A TIME
LADIES. LOCKDOWN.
♪... THE BONE
♪ SILENCE WEARS ME DOWN
♪ LIKE WATER ON A STONE
LISTEN, DONOVAN.
YEAH, KID?
THAT, UH, THAT THING IN, UH,
YOUNG COUNTRY?
DID IT REALLY GO DOWN
THE WAY THEY SAY IT DID?
YOU KNOW, IN ALL MY YEARS
OF WORKING WITH THE LAW,
THERE'S ONE THING I LEARN.
AND WHAT'S THAT?
NOTHING EVER WENT DOWN
THE WAY THEY SAY IT DID.
YEAH.
UH, I GUESS SO.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, KID?
GUESSING THEY GOT YOUR
STORY WRONG, TOO, HUH?
NO, SIR.
I...
I KILLED THOSE PEOPLE
DEADER THAN HELL.
AFTER MY PARENTS DIED,
THE STATE TOOK
MY SISTER AND ME.
PUT US IN AN INSTITUTION.
THEN ONE DAY, THIS...
THIS COUPLE COME, AND...
THEY SAY I WAS GONNA
GO LIVE WITH THEM.
IT WAS ALL RIGHT AT FIRST.
MADE SOME NEW FRIENDS
AND HAD A ROOF OVER OUR HEAD.
THEN, UH...
THEN, ONE NIGHT, UH,
THE WIFE CAME INTO MY ROOM.
SHE WASN'T WEARIN' NOTHING.
AND SHE SAID, IF I TOLD ANYONE,
SHE WAS GONNA
SEND MY SISTER AWAY.
SO, UH...
I WENT ALONG
WITH IT FOR A WHILE.
TO PROTECT HER.
THEN I...
I CAUGHT THE OLD MAN WITH HER.
AND I...
I KNEW I HAD TO DO SOMETHING.
SHE WAS JUST...
JUST A LITTLE GIRL, YOU KNOW?
INNOCENT.
THAT'S A HELL OF A THING, KID.
THAT'S A HELL OF A THING.
IT'S A REAL TOUCHING TALE,
AIN'T IT?
WHAT ABOUT YOU, DALTON?
WHAT'S YOUR STORY?
ME?
OH, I'VE DONE...
TRAIN-JUMPING
AND GRAVE-ROBBING.
CARD-PLAYING.
LYING, CHEATING, STEALING
PRETTY MUCH MY WHOLE LIFE.
SEE, I WAS IN, UH,
CLEMENTINA, NEW MEXICO.
A FEW WEEKS AGO, IN A JAIL,
WAITING ON MY TRIAL DATE,
AND THERE WAS A MAN
IN THIS...
IN THE JAIL CELL WITH ME.
HE'S LIMEY,
THROUGH AND THROUGH.
HAD A REAL NASTY SCAR
ON THE LEFT SIDE OF HIS FACE,
WHAT WAS HIS NAME?
WE AIN'T IN NO HURRY, IS WE?
I SAID, WE AIN'T IN NO HURRY.
[CHUCKLES]
WHERE WAS I?
OH, YEAH.
THIS FELLOW CLAIMED THAT, UH,
THE GUNSHOT TO THE HEAD
ALMOST KILLED HIM.
BANK ROBBERY
GONE WRONG, SAYS HE.
CONVINCED THIS LAWMAN
TO GO ALONG WITH HIM
ON ACCOUNT OF
HE HAD A FINE PIECE OF ASS
HELD HOSTAGE,
AND HE WAS GONNA KILL HER.
IF THE LAWMAN DIDN'T
GO ALONG WITH HIM.
I NEED YOUR HELP, DUKE.
PUT YOUR GUN DOWN, OR I'M
BLOWING HER HEAD RIGHT OFF!
HE'S GONNA KILL ME!
PUT YOUR GUN DOWN!
GOOD. I NEED YOUR HELP.
KEEP TALKING. WELL...
ANYHOW, THEY
PULLED OFF THE ROBBERY
AND GOT BACK TO THE HIDEOUT.
AND THEY THOUGHT THIS LAWMAN
WAS GONNA BE EASY PICKINGS,
ON ACCOUNT OF HE WAS
OUTNUMBERED AND ALL,
BUT...
THEY WAS WRONG.
COME ON! LET'S GO! HAH!
AAH!
WHOA!
DARK IRONY, IT WAS.
SEEMS THAT THIS LAWMAN
AND THE WOMAN
HE WAS TRYING TO HELP
WAS ACTUALLY THE VERY WOMAN
WHO BETRAYED HIM.
SHE WAS A PAINTED LADY.
LOVER OF LEVI HARDIN.
NURSED HIM BACK TO HEALTH.
WAS IN ON IT ALL ALONG.
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM?
WHERE IS HE?
THAT'S, UH...
THAT'S THE BEST PART, SEE?
HARDIN WAS CAUGHT
STEALING CATTLE
IN THAT PART OF COUNTRY.
THAT'S A HANGABLE OFFENSE.
[CROWD] ♪ HALLELUJAH
♪ HALLELUJAH
SHERIFF?
LEVI PERRY HARDIN,
YOU HAVE BEEN
SENTENCED BY A JURY
TO HANG FOR YOUR CRIMES
UNTIL DEAD.
DO YOU HAVE ANY LAST WORDS?
YEAH.
Y'ALL CAN KISS MY ASS!
[CROWD GASPS]
[MAN GRUNTS] [CROWD SCREAMS]
YEAH! HYAH!
IT'S JUST FUNNY HOW
A MAN CAN KILL INNOCENT
WOMEN AND CHILDREN
AND GET LIFE IN PRISON.
BUT YOU TAKE A MAN'S COW?
[LAUGHS]
THAT'S A WHOLE 'NOTHER
GODDAMN DEAL, AIN'T IT?
GUARD!
YOU TELL THE WARDEN
I'M READY TO SEE HIM.
WELL, PRISONER DONOVAN.
THIS IS A PLEASANT SURPRISE.
LEAVE US.
I MUST COMMEND YOU.
YOU AND YOUR FRIEND
LASTED A GOOD WHILE.
NOT AS LONG AS SOME, MIND YOU,
BUT THEN, THEY DIDN'T
HAVE THE CHOICE YOU DID.
I CAME HERE TO TELL YOU
THAT LEVI HARDIN
IS STILL ALIVE.
AND I THINK I KNOW
WHERE HE'S HEADED NEXT.
EXCUSE ME?
THAT'S WHAT YOU
CAME TO SAY TO ME?
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I SAID?
HARDIN'S STILL ALIVE.
I THINK MY WIFE'S IN DANGER.
WELL, THAT IS A PREDICAMENT.
BUT I FAIL TO SEE
WHAT THAT HAS TO DO
WITH OUR MEETING HERE TODAY.
LISTEN, YOU SON OF A BITCH!
I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU THINK OF ME.
MY WIFE'S IN DANGER.
HARDIN'S NOT GONNA STOP TILL
HE GETS TO ME
ANY WAY HE KNOWS HOW!
NOW, YOU GOTTA DO SOMETHING!
I SUGGEST YOU TAKE YOUR HANDS
OFF MY COLLAR.
ONE CALL FROM ME,
AND YOU WON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT YOUR PRECIOUS WIFE.
BECAUSE YOU'LL BE DEAD.
EXCELLENT.
GUARD!
TAKE HIM AWAY.
NO, PUT HIM IN WITH
THE MAIN POPULATION.
I'M SURE THEY'LL
MAKE ROOM FOR HIM.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU THINK OF ME.
THERE'S AN INNOCENT WOMAN
IN DANGER.
IT'S YOUR DUTY TO HELP HER!
IT'S YOUR DUTY!
I HAVE A WITNESS!
ASK DALTON!
THEY WILL CRUCIFY HIM, SIR.
DO IT.
[MOANS] CY,
YOU DO MAKE THE BEST RIBS
THIS SIDE OF THE MISSISSIPPI.
HMM.
LOOK, SULLIVAN,
AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
YOU'RE THE ONLY GUY
IN HERE THAT HAS
SOME SENSE OF RIGHT AND WRONG.
NOW, IF YOU WON'T
HELP ME, HELP HER.
UNHOOK HIM.
SHE'S ALL ALONE
OUT THERE, SULLIVAN.
YOU GOTTA HELP HER...
YOU GOTTA DO SOMETHING!
THERE AIN'T NOTHING
I CAN DO, GODDAMN IT!
WHAT THE HELL
AM I SUPPOSED TO DO, HUH?
GO ON.
GO!
GO, PLEASE.
SON OF A BITCH.
MR. DONOVAN.
I GOT ME A NICE PLACE
RIGHT OVER HERE FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, FIRST THING
I DID WHEN I GOT OUT
WAS MAKE A TRADE FOR THIS.
HEY, DONOVAN.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
YOU NEED TO GET
OUT OF HERE, KID.
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
YOU STAY AWAY.
NO, SIR, I NEED TO STAY
RIGHT HERE WITH YOU.
BEAT IT.
BEAT IT!
WHAT YOU GONNA DO?
I'M NOT SURE.
YOU REMEMBER ME?
OH YEAH, I REMEMBER YOU.
JARVISON.
YOU AND YOUR RAPIST BROTHER.
IT AIN'T PROPER
TO INSULT THE DEAD
SINCE YOU DONE THE KILLIN'.
KID, I WANT YOU
TO PROMISE ME SOMETHING.
YES, SIR.
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS TO ME,
YOU HANG IN THERE.
YOU STICK WITH THE OLD-TIMERS.
THEY KNOW HOW TO SURVIVE.
YEAH. YOU HEAR ME?
UH-HUH. BUT YOU GONNA BE OKAY?
JUST PROMISE ME.
YES, SIR.
LET IT BE.
[PRISONERS CHEER, YELL]
YEAH! GO!
COME ON, MR. DONOVAN!
WATCH OUT!
COME ON. COME ON.
YEAH. COME ON.
TAKE IT... TAKE IT EASY.
COME ON.
COME ON, COME ON.
HANG IN WITH ME, NOW.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, KID.
YOU GIVE HIM A DECENT BURIAL.
LADIES!
LOCKDOWN.
NIGHT-NIGHT TIME.
[CYRUS] CHECKIN' THE LOCKS.
CHECKING LOCKS.
DONOVAN.
YOU DON'T BELONG HERE.
MEET ME AT
THE NEW YARD IN ONE HOUR.
YOU GET CAUGHT,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
[COYOTE HOWLS]
CHECKIN' LOCKS.
HEY! HEY!
COME ON.
GET DOWN! GET DOWN.
NOW, LOOK.
THIS, THIS TUNNEL WILL
TAKE YOU INTO THE CEMETERY,
UNDER THE WALL, AND COME OUT
BY THE WARDEN'S STABLES.
THERE'S A SET OF REINS
THERE WAITING FOR YOU.
THE WARDEN HAD THIS DUG
IN CASE THERE WAS EVER A MUTINY.
WHAT ABOUT YOU? OH, NO.
MY RUNNIN' DAYS...
THEY BEHIND ME.
YOU JUST GET ON.
RESCUE YOUR LADY.
HEY, DONOVAN.
I'M REAL SORRY ABOUT THAT KID.
NOW, GO ON,
GET TO GETTING, CAUSE...
THEM GUARDS'LL BE STARTING
A NEW SET OF ROUNDS SOON.
CYRUS, YOU COULD
GET HUNG FOR THIS.
NO, DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[HAMMER CLICKS] [MAN GRUNTS]
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOUR RUNNING DAYS WERE OVER.
I CHANGED MY MIND.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
♪ WELL, I WAS
SHAKEN FROM MY SLEEP ♪
♪ AS THEY DRAGGED ME
♪ TO MY FEET
♪ I WAS MISTAKEN
♪ BY THE LONG ARM OF THE LAW ♪
♪ AND THE LESSON
♪ I HAVE LEARNED
♪ IS THE INNOCENT GET BURNED ♪
♪ AND THE GUILTY SET YOU UP ♪
♪ TO TAKE THE FALL
♪ NOBODY'S GUILTY IN HERE
♪ AND THE TRUTH AIN'T ALWAYS ♪
♪ HOW IT APPEARS
♪ OUR STORY'S ALL THE SAME ♪
♪ LORD KNOWS
WE'VE ALL BEEN FRAMED ♪
♪ AND THE EVIDENCE
♪ IS PERFECTLY CLEAR
♪ NOBODY'S GUILTY IN HERE
SORRY TO TROUBLE YOU, MA'AM.
GOT A MAN HURT.
CAN WE USE YOUR WELL?
PLEASE?
BRING HIM INSIDE.
WHOA, YOU KNOW.
WE'D BETTER WATER THESE HORSES.
THERE'S AIN'T NO TIME.
WELL, IF WE DON'T WATER THEM,
WE'RE GONNA BE WALKING.
ALL RIGHT.
WHO WAS IT? DONOVAN.
AND CY, TOO.
CY?
GODDAMN NIGGER.
BRING THEM BACK.
DEAD.
PUT HIM OVER THERE.
GET ME SOME TOWELS.
WELL...
IT'S A REAL PRETTY PLACE.
YEP.
WHOA. [GROANS]
AHH. THANK YOU.
NOT MUCH FURTHER, FRIEND.
I'LL TELL YOU ONE THING, CYRUS.
YOU SURE DON'T
RIDE LIKE A COOK.
THAT'S 'CAUSE I AIN'T ONE.
WELL, THE WARDEN
SURE LIKED YOUR COOKING.
YEAH, WELL, THAT'S 'CAUSE
OF MY SPECIAL SAUCE.
OH, SPECIAL SAUCE, HUH?
YOU DON'T WANNA KNOW.
[BOTH LAUGH]
SO WHAT HAPPENED, ANYWAY?
WHAT HAPPENED TO WHAT?
TO GET YOU THROWN
IN THAT RAT-HOLE PRISON?
OH, WELL.
I WAS IN THE NINTH.
YOU'RE A SURE-ENOUGH
BUFFALO SOLDIER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S COLONEL HATCH,
WASN'T IT? YES, SIR.
YOU KNOW, WE HAD US
THIS OLD BUCK SERGEANT.
I MEAN, HE WANTED TO RIDE ME
ALL THE WAY TO KANSAS CITY.
BUSTING ME DOWN TO A DOG...
MADE YOU A COOK, DID HE?
YEAH, I DON'T
LIKE BEING A COOK.
LET ME ASK YOU
SOMETHING, DONNY.
NOW, REALLY, DO...
NOW, DO I LOOK LIKE
A DAMN COOK?
COOK.
HOW'S IT LOOK?
HE'S GOT A BULLET
IN HIS STOMACH.
GUT-SHOT.
HOW LONG AGO WAS HE SHOT?
A FEW DAYS AGO.
WHERE DID IT HAPPEN?
JUST ACROSS THE BORDER,
IN NEW MEXICO.
YOU KNOW, YOU ASK
A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
DON'T MEAN TO.
MY HUSBAND WAS ALSO A MARSHAL.
DONOVAN. YOU KNOW HIM?
UH, WE'RE GONNA NEED
TO GET HIM INTO TOWN.
I'LL GET THE T...
YEAH, I KNOW HIM.
I KNOW HIM REAL WELL.
AAH!
YAH! YAH!
WHOA, WHOA.
WHAT'S WRONG?
SOMETHING AIN'T RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHERE ARE THE HORSES?
WELL, THEY COULD BE TURNED OUT.
MADDY!
[DONOVAN SOBS]
OH, MADDY! MADDY.
MADDY, MADDY, MADELEINE.
TALK TO ME.
I'M GONNA GET HELP.
OH GOD...
OH, NO.
CYRUS, GET THE HORSES.
WE GOTTA GET TO TOWN.
SHE'S HURT! SHE'S HURT BAD.
DON'T DIE ON ME.
YOU HEAR ME? DON'T DIE.
I LOVE...
GET THE HORSES! DON.
DON, SHE'S GONE.
[DONOVAN SOBS] I'M REAL SORRY,
BUT SHE'S GONE.
ANOTHER DRINK?
NO.
I LOST MY THIRST.
WELL, YOU WANTED THE TRUTH,
DIDN'T YOU?
I JUST GAVE YOU
WHAT YOU ASKED FOR.
YEAH, I DID, DIDN'T I?
YOU SURE AS HELL DID.
I DIDN'T ASK YOU TO COME
SNOOPING AROUND HERE,
YOU KNOW?
WHY ARE YOU
TELLING ME ALL OF THIS?
WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST
LET ME WALK OUT OF HERE?
MAYBE I FELT SORRY FOR YOU.
BEING IN TROUBLE WITH
YOUR CHIEFY AND ALL.
OR MAYBE
IT'S JUST BECAUSE
YOU REMIND ME OF MYSELF
WHEN I WAS YOUR AGE.
I DON'T KNOW.
I DO KNOW...
YOU DIDN'T COME HERE
TO TALK ABOUT ME.
YOU CAME HERE
TO TALK ABOUT DONOVAN.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, THEN LET'S SEE.
WHERE WAS I?
OH YEAH.
HARDIN AND HIS MEN
CONTINUED WEST.
TO THEM, THE EVENTS
THAT HAD TRANSPIRED
JUST A FEW HOURS EARLIER
WERE NOTHING MORE THAN
A PASSING AMUSEMENT
TO BE BOASTED ABOUT.
♪ OH MY DARLIN' MADELEINE
GO ON, CHARLIE,
HAVE FUN WITH IT.
COME ON.
WAKE UP.
I KNOW YOU'RE NOT DOING WELL,
BUT YOU'RE SLOWING US
ALL UP HERE.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
[DONOVAN GRUNTS]
YEAH, THEY'VE BEEN HERE,
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S THEIR HOOFPRINTS
IN THE WATERING HOLE.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
WE'LL SET UP CAMP
HERE FOR THE NIGHT.
YOU KNOW I'M REAL
SORRY, DONOVAN.
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, I...
I JUST DON'T GOT NO WORDS.
THIS AIN'T YOUR FIGHT, CYRUS.
YEAH, WELL.
IT SEEMS TO ME,
I'VE BEEN FIGHTING OTHER
PEOPLE'S WARS MY WHOLE LIFE.
AND I EXPECT THIS
AIN'T NO DIFFERENT.
SOMETIMES THERE'S WARS
A MAN JUST GOT TO FIGHT.
MIND TELLING ME
WHAT THE PLAN IS?
I'M GONNA TRACK HIM DOWN.
ALL THE WAY
TO THE GATES OF HELL,
IF I HAVE TO.
ALL RIGHT.
WHOO, YEAH.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
THAT IS A FINE FIRE
RIGHT THERE.
THINK WE GONNA
CATCH 'EM TOMORROW?
IF THEY'RE HEADED WHERE
I EXPECT THEY'RE HEADED.
WHERE'S THAT?
BACKSIDE OF THE WHETSTONES.
DONOVAN'S RANCH.
HOW FAR?
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
ANOTHER DAY,
OR MOST OF IT, AT LEAST.
DAMN.
YOU THINK HE DID IT?
DID WHAT?
ROBBED THAT BANK?
KILLED THOSE PEOPLE?
HELL YEAH, HE DONE IT.
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST DON'T KNOW.
YOU'D BETTER GET TO KNOWIN'.
SHE DONE THIS FOR YOU,
DIDN'T SHE?
SHE DID A LOT OF THINGS FOR ME.
♪ THUNDER ROLLS
♪ UP FROM THE GROUND
♪ BIRDS FLY AWAY
♪ FROM THE SOUND
♪ A LONE HERO
♪ STANDS IN THE EYE
♪ OF THE STORM
♪ AND DEMONS
♪ DANCE IN THE FIRE
♪ CHASING DESIRE
♪ LIKE DEVIL'S COMPANIONS
♪ BUT ONE WILL STAND
♪ WHEN THERE'S NONE
♪ WHEN BLACK HORSES RUN
♪ THROUGH THE DARK CANYON
THAT'S NOT GONNA
DO ANY GOOD NOW.
I DON'T RECKON IT'S GONNA
DO NO HARM, NEITHER.
READY?
GO AHEAD,
I'LL CATCH UP WITH YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
♪ ...WHERE I'VE
NEVER BEEN BEFORE ♪
♪ IF YOU WILL HOLD THE DOOR ♪
♪ I WILL RUN
THROUGH THE VALLEY ♪
♪ WHERE THE SUN
WILL NEVER SHINE ♪
♪ IF YOU WILL BE MY LIGHT ♪
♪ AND HARD AS I TRY
♪ THERE'S JUST
NO PLACE TO HIDE ♪
♪ UNTIL THIS JOURNEY ENDS
♪ AND THERE'S
NO TEARS LEFT TO CRY ♪
♪ AND I'LL KEEP YOU WITH ME ♪
♪ SAFE IN MY MEMORY
♪ AND I WILL SEE YOU
♪ ON THE OTHER SIDE
♪ OF THE RIDE
YAH! YAH!
♪ AND I AM BOUND
TO FIND THE MAN ♪
♪ THAT I USED TO BE BACK THEN ♪
♪ AND BEFORE WE MEET AGAIN ♪
♪ WHEN I PUT THIS ANGER DOWN ♪
♪ SIX FEET IN THE GROUND
♪ I WILL NEVER KILL AGAIN
♪ AND HARD AS I TRY
♪ THERE'S JUST
NO PLACE TO HIDE ♪
♪ UNTIL THIS JOURNEY ENDS
♪ AND THERE'S
NO TEARS LEFT TO CRY ♪
♪ AND I'LL KEEP YOU WITH ME ♪
♪ SAFE IN MY MEMORY
♪ AND I WILL SEE YOU
♪ ON THE OTHER SIDE
♪ OF THE RIDE
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
TAKE THE REINS.
WHAT IN THE HELL IS THIS?
THAT'S SAGE.
THAT'S AN INDIAN SIGN.
INDIAN SIGN?
THE HELL YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
CY MUST STILL BE WITH HIM.
LET'S GET DOWN TO THE BARN,
SEE IF WE CAN'T
FIND SOME GRAIN.
FIGURE IF THEY'RE
GOING AFTER HARDIN
THEY'LL BE IN RIO VERDES.
INDIAN SIGN, MY ASS.
HEY. HEY!
SHOW SOME GODDAMN RESPECT!
I DON'T CARE WHO YOU ARE.
IF I CATCH YOU DOING
SOMETHING LIKE THAT AGAIN,
SO HELP ME GOD,
WHEN WE LEAVE HERE,
I'LL BURY YOU HERE.
THAT GOES FOR BOTH OF YOU.
BITCH.
YEAH, YOU THINK THE WORD'S OUT
ON OUR ESCAPE YET?
THERE AIN'T NO RAILROAD.
PROBABLY NO TELEGRAPH.
SHOULDN'T BE NO PROBLEM, THEN.
YEAH, UNLESS HURLEY'S
STILL THE MARSHAL HERE.
HE KNOWS YOU?
HE'S AN OLD ACQUAINTANCE.
HELL, DONOVAN, EVERYBODY
IN THIS COUNTRY KNOWS YOU.
LET'S GO. YAH! COME ON!
♪ OUTLAW
♪ WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE? ♪
GET ME A BLOODY
BOTTLE OF WHISKEY!
♪ SHOOTING UP THIS TOWN
♪ AND BREAKING HEARTS
♪ OUTLAW
♪ SON, WHO DO YOU
THINK YOU ARE? ♪
MAYBE. MAYBE.
♪ SITTING AT THIS TABLE ♪
♪ PLAYING THE DEVIL'S CARD ♪
♪ WE GOT LAW IN THIS TOWN ♪
IT'S A LITTLE EARLY
IN THE MORNING, AIN'T IT, BOYS?
♪ AND WE GONNA
WIND UP HOLDING ♪
♪ A DEAD MAN'S HAND
♪ YEAH
[BARTENDER GROANS]
♪ OUTLAW
DRINK IT UP, BOYS!
♪ BEST YOU GET ON BACK THERE ♪
♪ WHILE THERE'S TIME TO RUN ♪
♪ THERE'S AN OLD GRAVEDIGGER ♪
♪ OUT ON THE EDGE
OF THIS TOWN ♪
♪ HE'D SURE BE HAPPY SON
♪ TO LAY YOU DOWN
♪ WE GOT LAW IN THIS TOWN ♪
♪ MAN, AND HE'S GOT...
♪ YOU GONNA WIND UP HOLDING ♪
♪ A DEAD MAN'S HAND
UH, WE DON'T SEE TOO MANY...
UH...
WE DON'T SEE...
TOO MANY... WHAT?
STRANGERS.
AROUND THESE PARTS.
SO, WHAT'LL IT BE?
WHISKEY. TWO GLASSES.
LEAVE THE BOTTLE.
WHAT'RE YOU LOOKING AT?
I SAID, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU LOOKING AT?
YOU GOT ANY COFFEE?
COFFEE?
OH, YEAH.
SURE. OF COURSE, I'LL...
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THAT'D BE A GOOD IDEA.
I KNOW YOU...
I KNOW YOU HEARD ME.
WHAT'RE YOU LOOKING AT?
[CLICKS HAMMER]
OH, AND YOU, TOO?
WHAT'RE YOU LOOKING AT?
THAT IS A MIGHTY NICE
BANDANNA YOU GOT THERE.
HUH?
OH. YOU LIKE THIS? THANK YOU.
I KNOW YOU, DON'T I?
MAYBE.
BEEN AROUND HERE BEFORE?
NO.
I'M FROM SONORA.
THEY CALL ME CHALE.
WELL, THAT IS QUITE A NAME.
YOU'RE MY FRIEND, RIGHT?
BUT YOU GOTTA
TELL ME SOMETHING,
FRIEND.
WHY THE HELL
DO YOU COME IN HERE
WITH YOUR MULO SLAVE
WHO STARES AT PEOPLE?
IT'S RUDE, NO?
NO, HE'S NOT RUDE.
HE JUST DOESN'T LIKE SCUMBAGS.
NO, THAT AIN'T IT.
I JUST DON'T LIKE YOU.
[CHALE SCREAMS]
COME ON, LET'S GO.
AAH!
I'LL BE NEEDING
THAT HORSE, GOVERNOR.
[CLICKS HAMMER]
I DO KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
WAS HE HERE? WAS HE HERE?
WHO?
TELL ME WHAT HE LOOKED LIKE.
TELL ME WHAT HE LOOKED LIKE!
HE WAS A ROUGH-LOOKIN' MAN.
HE HAD A BAD SCAR THAT
RUN ACROSS HIS FACE.
WE DIDN'T MEAN NO TROUBLE.
WE'RE JUST TRYING
TO MAKE A LMNG IS ALL.
YOU DIDN'T MEAN ANY TROUBLE?
YOU DIDN'T MEAN NO TROUBLE?
[CLICKS HAMMER]
IF YOU'RE GONNA KILL ME,
START SHOOTING.
EASY, DUKE.
JUST NEED TO TALK.
THERE AIN'T NO TIME.
THEY TOOK OFF THAT WAY.
BEST I CAN TELL, ON ONE HORSE.
[DONOVAN MURMURS]
WE CAN CATCH THEM THEN.
CAN'T LIE,
IF THEY COME LOOKING FOR YOU.
I WOULDN'T EXPECT YOU TO.
LET'S GO.
WHOA-WHOA-WHOA.
GREETINGS.
I'M DEPUTY TOM SULLIVAN.
YUMA.
MARSHAL HURLEY.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A COUPLE OF MEN.
ONE OF THEM'S A NIGGER...
DUKE DONOVAN.
THE OTHER ONE'S NAME
IS CYRUS PARKER,
AND HE IS A BUFFALO SOLDIER.
THEY BROKE OUT OF YUMA.
YEAH, THEY CAME THROUGH TOWN
A COUPLE OF HOURS AGO.
KILLED TWO MEN.
I AIN'T SURPRISED.
ME EITHER.
THOSE WERE A COUPLE MEN
WHO NEEDED KILLING.
ROLLED WITH LEVI HARDIN'S GANG.
WE CAUGHT WIND
THAT HARDIN'S MEN
KILLED DONOVAN'S WIFE.
THAT THEY DID.
SON OF A BITCH.
ANY IDEA WHERE THEY'RE HEADED?
OH, MY GUESS
WOULD BE THE BORDER.
THE BORDER?
YEAH. THEY'RE HOT ON HIS TRAIL.
WHOSE?
HARDIN'S.
OBLIGED. LET'S GO.
THANKS FOR THE WHISKEY.
♪ FREEDOM IS YOUR PRISON
♪ AND YOUR CURSE
TO KEEP ON RUNNING ♪
♪ HARD TO TELL THE DIFFERENCE ♪
♪ FROM THE HUNTER
AND THE HUNTED ♪
♪ LOOKING FOR REDEMPTION
♪ DOWN THE BARREL OF A GUN ♪
♪ YOUR FINGER ON THE TRIGGER ♪
♪ AND YOUR BACK
AGAINST THE SUN ♪
♪ GOING DOWN
♪ GOING DOWN TO THE PLACE
♪ WHERE NO MERCY CAN BE FOUND ♪
♪ AND YOU PAY FOR
WHAT YOU'VE DONE ♪
♪ WITH YOUR SOUL
♪ GOING DOWN
WHERE THE DARKEST ♪
♪ OF THE ANGELS CIRCLE ROUND ♪
♪ HE'S JUST WAITING
'CAUSE HE KNOWS ♪
♪ YES HE KNOWS
♪ IT'S GOING DOWN
♪ GOING DOWN
[HORSE PANTS]
COME ON, WALKER! GO!
WHOA-WHOA-WHOA.
EASY.
HE AIN'T BEEN DEAD LONG.
YEAH.
OH GOD!
COME ON. COME ON. GET UP, CY.
[CYRUS GROANS]
HOW BAD IS IT?
WELP, DIDN'T CATCH ANY BONE,
BUT IT'S A GOOD ONE.
WHAT'S GOING ON OVER THERE?
WHOA, WHOA.
THAT'S THREE
OF THE WARDEN'S DEPUTIES.
THEY'RE GONNA BE
SITTING DUCKS FOR HARDIN.
FOSTER. CHECK IT OUT.
WHAT'RE YOU DOING?
I CAN'T LET
INNOCENT MEN GET KILLED.
EVEN IF THEY ARE
TRYING TO KILL ME.
THINK THEY LOST US?
LISTEN.
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S TOO QUIET.
SULLIVAN, GET DOWN!
AAH! [HORSE NEIGHS]
AAH!
GODDAMN IT! JESUS!
DO SOMETHING!
DO SOMETHING! GODDAMN IT!
SON OF A BITCH!
[HARDIN GRUNTS]
HE'S ALREADY DEAD!
ALREADY DEAD!
WE GOT ONE!
WE GOTTA GET BACK TO CYRUS.
READY? LET'S GO.
AAH!
DAMN, MY LEG!
HOW'RE YOU DOING, CY?
HOW THE HELL'S
IT LOOK LIKE I'M DOING?
DONOVAN, TRYING
TO GET YOURSELF SHOT?
YEAH, IT APPEARS SO.
COME ON.
WE ARE DEAD MEN DOWN HERE.
SULLIVAN, WE GOTTA
GET TO HIGHER GROUND.
NOW YOU'RE MAKING SENSE.
CY, I'M GONNA NEED
THAT MARE'S LEG.
YEP.
WHEN I GIVE THE SIGNAL,
YOU GIVE IT ALL YOU GOT,
ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT, TOM.
YOU BREAK WHEN I DO.
LET'S GO!
AAH! SHIT!
COME ON, WALKER, LET'S GO!
FUCK!
HOW MANY BULLETS YOU GOT LEFT?
FOUR. FIVE, MAYBE.
SO I GUESS WE'RE
FINALLY GONNA GET
TO FINISH WHAT WE STARTED.
FINISH WHAT YOU STARTED.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THE WAY I SEE IT, WE BOTH LOSE.
YOU TOOK MY MONEY.
AND I TOOK YOUR LIFE.
YOU KNOW WHAT, I'M GONNA
LET GOD SORT THAT OUT.
FUCK YOU!
SO THIS IS IT.
THIS IS THE BEST YOU CAN DO.
THE GREAT
DUKE DONOVAN!
HUH?
GET UP.
GET UP, DUKE.
GET UP...
FUCKING... [SCREAMS]
AAH!
DUKE!
SHE CRIED OUT
FOR YOU, YOU KNOW!
FOR YOU TO SAVE HER.
OH, SHE WAS A LIVE ONE!
SHE WIGGLED LIKE
A LITTLE FISH, SHE DID!
SHE WAS ALL WET AND SLIMY.
I SLID RIGHT UP, RIGHT IN.
[HARDIN LAUGHS]
YOU KNOW I GOTTA BRING YOU IN.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO KILL ME FIRST.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I AIN'T GOT NO CHOICE.
WE ALL GOT CHOICES.
I MADE MINE A LONG TIME AGO.
DO IT.
I CAN'T.
[SCREAMS]
[HARMONICA PLAYS]
YOU'RE GETTING PRETTY GOOD
ON THAT THING, CY.
HEY DONOVAN.
YOU EVER WONDER WHY
I HELPED YOU ESCAPE
OUT THAT PRISON?
IT'S 'CAUSE YOU
HELP ME REMEMBER
HOW I USED TO WALK.
AND I'M MIGHTY BEHOLDEN TO YOU.
HERE.
THIS'LL KEEP YOU COMPANY
ON YOUR TRAVELS.
YOU KNOW, YOU MIGHT EVEN LEARN
HOW TO PLAY THE DAMN THING.
THANKS.
[REDFIELD]
DONOVAN NEVER TOLD SULLIVAN
WHERE HE WAS GOING.
BOTH MEN WANDERED...
SO AS NOT TO PUT
THE OTHER AT RISK.
CYRUS RODE EAST.
SOME SAY TO LOUISIANA.
WHERE IT WAS RUMORED
HE'D PROSPERED
IN DRY GOODS.
SULLIVAN RETURNED
TO YUMA WITH A BOUNTY.
OF COURSE, IT WAS SO CHARRED,
NO ONE COULD REALLY
TELL WHO IT WAS.
SO THE WARDEN HAD
TO TAKE SULLIVAN'S WORD
THAT IT WAS DONOVAN.
THAT DAY, SULLIVAN
LEFT YUMA FOR GOOD.
CHANGED HIS NAME TO DUNCAN,
AND A MONTH LATER BECAME
THE SHERIFF OF WICKENBURG.
WHERE HE LIVES TO THIS DAY.
SO SULLIVAN NEVER
UP AND DISAPPEARED
LIKE EVERYONE THOUGHT.
HE JUST CHANGED HIS NAME.
NOW YOU'RE CATCHING ON.
[REDFIELD LAUGHS]
WAIT, IF...
IF YOU AREN'T SULLIVAN...
AND ONLY THOSE THREE
SURVIVED THAT DAY,
THEN YOU'RE...
THAT MAKES YOU...
82 YEARS OLD.
[HARMONICA NOTE]
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU GOT THAT GUN
THE DAY DUKE DONOVAN DIED.
I DID.
I INHERITED THIS GUN
FROM DUKE DONOVAN
THE DAY HE BECAME
SEYMOUR REDFIELD.
HE DIDN'T NEED IT ANYMORE.
HE WAS A DEAD MAN.
THERE'S NO STATUTE
OF LIMITATIONS ON MURDER.
IS THERE?
NO, SON, I'M AFRAID NOT.
JUST GOT ONE MORE QUESTION.
WHAT IS IT?
THE ROBBERY.
WERE YOU TRICKED INTO IT?
OR BEHIND IT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK I NEED ANOTHER DRINK.
CAN I ASK YOU ONE MORE THING?
WHY'D YOU TELL ME EVERYTHING?
WELL, I FIGURE
THE SAND IN MY HOURGLASS
IS RUNNING A LITTLE LOW,
AND SOMEBODY
OUGHT TO KNOW THE TRUTH
ABOUT WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
JUST KEEP IT UNDER
YOUR SOMBRERO, WILL YOU?
UNTIL AFTER I'M GONE?
THANK YOU.
♪ THUNDER ROLLS
♪ UP FROM THE GROUND
♪ BIRDS FLY AWAY
♪ FROM THE SOUND
♪ A LONE HERO
♪ STANDS IN THE EYE
♪ OF THE STORM
♪ LIGHTNING CRACKS
♪ OPEN THE SKY
♪ MOTHERS TAKE THEIR CHILDREN ♪
♪ AND HIDE
♪ EVIL RIDES
♪ AND THE DAY OF DARKNESS
♪ IS BORN
♪ WHEN FEAR
BLOCKS OUT THE LIGHT ♪
♪ AND THE DAY TURNS TO NIGHT ♪
♪ AND HOPE IS ABANDONED
♪ AND DEMONS
♪ DANCE IN THE FIRE
♪ CHASING DESIRE
♪ LIKE DEVIL'S COMPANIONS
♪ BUT ONE WILL STAND
♪ WHEN THERE'S NONE
♪ WHEN BLACK HORSES RUN
♪ THROUGH THE DARK CANYON
♪ GUNSHOTS
♪ TEAR OPEN THE AIR
♪ TREMBLING HEARTS
♪ SEND UP A PRAYER
♪ HOPING SOMEONE WILL COME ♪
♪ TO EARN THEIR SALVATION
♪ WHEN ROCKS OF FAITH
♪ CRUMBLE TO DUST
♪ YOU SEARCH YOUR HEART
♪ FOR SOMEONE TO TRUST
♪ SOMETIMES IT'S YOU
♪ YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN CHASING ♪
♪ WHEN FEAR
♪ BLOCKS OUT THE LIGHT
♪ AND DAY TURNS TO NIGHT
♪ AND HOPE IS ABANDONED
♪ AND DEMONS
DANCE IN THE FIRE ♪
♪ CHASING DESIRE
♪ LIKE DEVIL'S COMPANIONS
♪ BUT ONE WILL STAND
♪ WHEN THERE'S NONE
♪ WHEN BLACK HORSES RUN
♪ THROUGH THE DARK CANYON