[Slashing]
[Hooves clomping]
[Gun fires]
[Horse neighs]
Get down, damn it!
[Speaking Apache]
I'm no Apache.
[Groans]
Leave me be.
[Gun fires]
Where are you from?
Creel.
That's where I'm headed.
I'll get you home.
[Whispers] No.
I've got to go to him.
He needs me.
There's nothing but Apaches for 60
miles between here and ft. Creel.
The Apaches won't hurt me.
[Gun fires]
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy!
Look.
There.
Good afternoon. What
can I do for you?
Oh.
Did you find her?
Where's the horse
she was riding?
Dead.
That's too bad.
You take care of my horse?
Where did you find Mrs. Grange?
Give him plenty of
feed and water.
He needs it.
And rub him down, too.
# [bugle playing]
Hello, Harrington.
Jess Remsberg.
I see they've busted you
back to corporal again.
Yeah, twice.
Say, it's been a
long time since...
yeah, yeah, it's
been a long time.
Is Scotty McAllister
out at the fort?
Yeah. Did you hear
he made lieutenant?
Tell him I'm in here, will you?
Sure.
Well, look at them out there.
Watching, waiting to see
how I'm gonna take it.
Laughing behind my back.
When they brought you
back the first time,
I tried to treat you decent.
This time, the Apaches didn't
take you away, you ran away.
My horse is dead
and you're back.
Should've been the
other way around.
[Sobbing]
Oh, stop it, Ellen.
[Sobbing loudly]
Stop that!
Please, Ellen, please.
Please, I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
I didn't.
[Crying]
I'm sorry, will.
I'm sorry I was brought
back to shame you.
I don't like the way I feel.
I hate myself for it.
You know how I loved you.
You were always good to me.
When Chata's band took you,
I just near went out of my head.
I hunted for you
for a whole year,
until I figured
they'd killed you.
Will, there's something
I didn't tell you...
and suddenly, you were back.
I was afraid to tell you...
I wanted for us...
there's something that
happened to me...
I don't want to
hear what happened!
I don't want to know
anything about it.
It's bad enough just
thinking about you
with them Apaches all the time,
trying to stop from
thinking about it...
I had to go back to them.
I had to!
That's what I'm
trying to tell you.
You mean, you liked living
with a bunch of savages?
You don't understand.
Well, no, I don't understand.
Lots of white women have been
grabbed off by the Indians.
Any decent one of them
would've killed herself
before she'd let them turn
her into an Indian squaw!
I'm not that decent, I guess!
Well, don't shout.
They'll hear you!
You don't care what
happens to me...
only what people
think about you.
I do business with them people.
The same people that treat
your wife like dirt.
I was better off
with the Indians.
Maybe that's where you
figured you belong.
I don't belong here anymore.
Maybe you don't.
At a trot!
Ho!
Keep them in line there.
At a gallop!
Ho!
# [bugle playing]
Back into line.
Left about!
Ho!
[Horse neighing]
No!
[Man] Get into one line, damn it!
Get into one line there!
Get on right of that flag!
Sgt. Ferguson!
Yes, sir!
That was the worst exhibition!
Well, I know, sir, but
most of these new horses
are a long way from
being saddle broke...
half your men don't know one
end of a horse from the other.
Yes, sir! Come on now.
Pull it into line there!
Let's get this right!
Dress on that flag!
Lieutenant...
move those mounts! Look alive!
What is it, corporal?
Jess Remsberg's in town, sir.
Jess?
How does he look?
Well, he still ain't over
it, that's for sure.
Where is he?
The saloon, sir.
Harrington, you lend Sgt.
Ferguson a hand.
Yes, sir.
Sgt. Ferguson. Yes, sir?
You keep those men polishing the seats
of their pants on saddle leather
until they can do that turn.
Yes, sir!
We leave for Concho in 2 days!
All right, now, we're gonna
try this maneuver once more.
The dress is right,
down on that flag.
Forward, at a gallop!
Ho!
# [bugle playing]
[Ferguson] Left about! Ho!
[Ferguson] Left turn, left turn!
Come on, move those
horses in line!
Move into line!
[Ferguson shouting orders]
# [piano playing]
Whiskey.
Lieutenant...
I've got a wagon load of goods for ft.
Concho.
I'd, uh, sure appreciate it if I
can tag along with your troop.
No.
What do you mean, no? I've got
a right to army protection.
If I take you along, you do.
But I'm not.
My, you sure do look pretty
in that new uniform.
Lieutenant, I'm sure...
Grange, this trip's going
to be rough enough
without dragging
along extra freight.
Sorry.
[Laughs]
I hear you found Ellen
Grange on the way.
Her husband didn't seem too
anxious to get her back.
Tom van scouting for you?
Aye.
I sent him down to Mexico
to check how many more warriors
have joined Chata's force.
I found him about
60 miles south,
where I picked up Mrs. Grange.
I'd say he was 2 days
dying, Apache style.
Then Chata's already come
north across the border
slaughtering anyone
they've run across.
Not without reason, Scotty.
The Apaches have been holed up
on that hellhole
reservation at San Carlos,
tricked, lied to, murdered...
it cuts both ways, Jess.
Bad enough when a man like
tom van ends the way he did.
When you find women and
children dead like that...
I've got to tell Maj.
Novac about van.
Wait a minute.
You sent me a message.
I'm here.
Aye.
[Bells tinkling]
That's a pretty nice scalp
you got there, mister.
I know where an Indian
scalp like that
would bring a pretty good price.
How much you want for it?
What was that, McAllister?
He was going to
kill you, Toller.
All I did was ask what he
wanted for the Indian scalp.
This Indian was his wife.
[Gasping]
What happened?
I hit you.
It's a good thing you did.
Where is it, Scotty?
Where'd you get it?
Ft. Concho, from
the town marshal.
New man. Clay Dean.
Clay Dean?
Aye. Killer for hire, wearing a badge.
You know the type.
[Sighs]
Thanks, Scotty.
Dean may not be the man.
If he's not, he'll tell me.
The man who caught my wife alone is
gonna pay, and not just by dying.
He'll be praying...
stop it, Jess!
Apaches take revenge that way.
No civilized...
that was no Apache that
killed and scalped my wife.
That was one of
your civilized men.
We're heading for ft. Concho
in a couple of days, Jess.
I want you to come along.
You just wanna be with me
when I catch this man Dean.
You figure I'll let him die
quick and easy if you're there.
With tom van gone,
I need a scout.
No.
Jess. I've 2 wagon-loads of
ammunition and 25 green troopers.
Col. Foster needs them in ft.
Concho.
What are you bucking for?
I can't afford any
mistakes on my record.
I'm going to be a
general some day.
I don't remember you being
so damned ambitious.
I'm getting married
when I get to Concho.
Sgt. Neabamer's daughter.
She'll give you hell
if I don't get there.
I guess a week or so won't
make any difference.
We ought to bury that, Jess.
After I find the man
that took it off her.
Tell the major he'll
have to wait.
I've got some unfinished
business to take care of.
McAllister said you
wanted to kill me.
I don't much like that idea.
I'd rather get it over with now,
if the thought's
still in your mind.
It's not.
Are you quite sure?
I said so.
Then I apologize.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I know you didn't.
[Girl screaming]
[Men laughing]
Let her go.
Like hell. She tried
to steal our horses!
She ought to be put in jail,
like any horse thief.
No, we won't let her go
till she's nice to us, like
she was to those Apaches.
[Man] She shouldn't mind
us, after all that time
she took pleasuring Chata's son.
I said, let her go.
Sure.
[Grunting]
[Horse neighs]
[Men grunting]
[Screaming]
[Grunting]
[Groaning]
Ugh.
[Groans]
Ow!
[Horses neighing]
I didn't lay a finger on you.
I wasn't gonna do
anything to her,
just tell her
husband, that's all.
You won't tell her husband anything.
You just forget it!
All right, I won't, I swear!
[Panting]
I like changing odds. 2-to-1
seemed more of an even bet.
So you saved me again, Mr.
Remsberg.
This time you saved my honor.
Only, now you know there's
none left to save.
You sound like I ought to
apologize for butting in.
I didn't ask you to
bring me back here.
Look, if the Apaches had
taken you captive...
at least the Apaches didn't
spit when I walked past.
People here treat me like I'm...
I know.
I had a Comanche wife.
Well, that's different.
No one thinks it's
wrong for a man
to take himself an Indian girl,
as long as he leaves her
behind when he goes.
I said she was my wife.
I know how they look at you.
I know how they treat you.
One of them finally
killed my wife.
Come on, better get you home.
I can understand why you'd
want to run away, Mrs. Grange,
but there's something you
ought to think about.
If you go back to Chata's band,
his son, Nachee,
will most likely kill you
for running away from him.
I didn't run away.
I was taken away, unconscious.
Our brave soldiers
hit the Apache camp
while the men were out hunting.
The trooper who gave me this
almost killed me before
he saw my blond hair.
But if I were your husband, Mrs.
Grange...
you are not my husband.
They all think any decent
woman would prefer to die
than live as an Apache squaw.
Maybe they're right.
Death comes soon enough.
Anybody that hurries
it is a damned fool.
What I was trying to say is...
what's over is done.
You and your husband
could go someplace
where nobody knows
what happened to you.
My husband would know.
# [bugle playing]
[Grange] Thanks, major.
I appreciate your cooperation.
It's my pleasure, Mr. Grange.
Have a seat, sergeant.
If that was a hint you want me
back in the army, no thanks.
Toller, Chata may have already
started north across the border.
You know what that means.
But as far as my
re-enlisting is concerned,
no chance, major.
The army owes me for 40 horses
I spent the last 4 months
hunting and breaking.
I'm planning on
investing my stakes
in a nice, profitable
gambling saloon.
No more army for me, major.
Sir, Grange claims you've
given him permission
to accompany me to ft. Concho.
The army has to cooperate
with traders like Grange...
yes, sir, I understand.
He's been most helpful
to us many times.
Yes, sir. It's just that
with all green troopers,
and only 2 days
before we head out...
you don't have those
2 days, McAllister.
You'll be starting for ft.
Concho at dawn.
Sir, I need time to whip those raw
recruits into some kind of shape.
And half those horses Toller
delivered still aren't saddlebroke!
Then he will just have to finish
breaking them on the way to ft. Concho.
There's no time left... hold on!
My contract with the army calls for
delivery of fresh mounts to McAllister.
And I've delivered them.
Your contract reads that you'll be paid
for delivering saddlebroke horses.
It ain't my fault that he's got
to move out before I'm finished!
Sir, if I could have
just one more day.
You have your
orders, lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
Not with me, he don't!
Sir.
You can have your money for the 20
mustangs you've already broken.
If you want to get
paid for the rest,
you'll have to tag
along with McAllister.
He'll give you a receipt for every
horse you break in on the way,
and col. Foster will pay
you for them in Concho.
The men I hired to help catch those
mustangs are paid off and gone.
The clothes I lived in
for 4 months, I burned.
I didn't buy this new outfit
to eat no trail dust.
You're dealing me this off the bottom
of the deck. This is a swindle...
be careful, Toller!
You shut up, McAllister!
You don't scare me none.
And you sure can't
pull no rank on me.
Toller, I'm sorry.
But that's the way
it will have to be.
Hurry it up, Toller.
You might manage to break
another horse or 2 before dawn.
You enjoy seeing me on the
horn, don't you, McAllister?
You were a pretty good
sergeant once, Toller,
but to me, you're just another
money-hungry civilian.
You used to be a pretty good
sergeant yourself, McAllister,
but now you're just...
a rank officer.
I'll be back, major.
[Ferguson shouting orders]
Get in there!
Move it out!
Company, attention!
Line up in columns of 2,
dress right on the flag.
Fall in over there!
Form up in columns of 2, and
dress right on that flag.
Get that horse up off his back!
Go get those reins!
Bring that horse back in here!
[Horse neighing]
[Toller shouting]
[Horses neighing]
[Shouting]
Open her up.
# [bugle playing]
Whoa!
Grange?
Yeah?
You might not be able to
get any kind of an escort
back here for weeks,
maybe longer.
So?
Might not be too good an idea,
leaving your wife here
alone, all that time.
What makes it your business?
Hmm?
Well, it doesn't make
any difference anyway.
She stole 2 horses, and
disappeared again last night.
Did you report it?
No, why should I?
They could have sent
somebody after her.
Now, maybe she's got
too much of a start.
If she wants to go, she can go.
Straight to hell,
for all I care.
Sergeant,
mount up!
[Ferguson] Prepare to mount!
Mount!
# [bugle playing]
Scotty, I'll be
riding out on my own.
I'll, uh, I'll pick you
up in a couple of days.
Remember, you're no use to
me hung up like tom van.
Yes, mother.
Oh, I'll, uh, I'll need a spare horse,
in case I have to make some time.
Toller!
I want a receipt.
[Ferguson] Bring
that horse forward!
[Scotty] Drop that
guard there, trooper.
Pull yourself up, lad.
Look proud, all of you.
Move them out, sergeant.
Yes, sir!
Lead off to the left
in a column of twos.
Forward! Ho!
# [bugle playing]
# [drums beating]
Sergeant, present arms.
Company, present arms!
# [marching tune playing]
[Man] It is your doing
Nachee is dead.
White-eyed trappers
took him alive.
They beat him to
death with a whip.
I didn't want him dead.
You white-eyes want us all dead.
But when I die, it will not be
as tame reservation Indian.
I will die Apache!
Killing my enemies!
Alchise!
[Speaking Apache]
Kayeta.
Where is Kayeta?
[Speaking Apache]
Kayeta.
[Baby cries softly]
The boy is your son.
You can care for
him, while you live.
Nachee's body lies in
Mogollon mountains.
You will live until
we come there.
You're going to kill me?
No.
You will be alive
when I bury you in
the grave of my son.
[Toller shouting]
[Horses neighing]
[Toller] Hold there! Hold on!
Come on!
Yah!
[Horse neighing]
Sir, there's a rider
coming in from the south.
Here, rub him down
while he's feeding.
You've been pushing hard.
I didn't want to
come in after dark
and have one of your rookies
mistaking me for an Apache.
Thank you.
Got anything for me?
I got a good look at Chata.
You stretch your
luck pretty thin.
He's got about 45 armed men.
He's on the move.
His whole camp,
women and kids...
including your wife, Grange.
[Scotty] Where's Chata headed?
[Jess] The Mogollon range
would be my hunch.
With his families along, he's
got to set up a permanent camp
before he can put
on any war-paint.
If we could cut in ahead of
him, catch him by surprise...
Scotty, he's got almost
50 fighting men.
You've got 29, including
me, Toller, and Grange.
All I'm figuring is to hold Chata in
place long enough for reinforcements
to reach us from Concho.
Just hold on a
minute, lieutenant.
You ain't aiming to
tangle with Chata?
If you're going to eavesdrop,
at least keep your mouth shut.
I put out a lot of money
for what's in that wagon.
I want to get it to Concho!
I didn't invite you
along, Grange!
If you're so anxious
to get to Concho,
just hoist your butt on
that wagon of yours and go!
You think I'm crazy?
Cpl. Harrington!
You busting with things
to say, too, Toller?
I don't like it any
more than Grange,
but you're the
cock-a-doodle-doo here,
so I'm stuck.
Then?
I just finished busting you
another gut-twister. Mark it.
Yes, sir?
Corporal, you'll
carry a dispatch
to col. Foster at ft. Concho,
and don't stop on the way.
Not to eat, not to sleep.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Pick him out the 2 fastest
mounts we've got.
In future, Grange,
when I'm having a
private conversation,
you keep the hell away from me.
Like right now.
Jess, get a solid
meal under your belt.
I want you to ride out
to keep track of Chata.
That'll leave you
without a scout.
Chata could find you
before I find him.
I'll take care of myself.
You take care of yourself.
There's a man in Concho I've
got to see before I die.
[Men chattering]
Grange.
Yeah?
If we should tangle
with Chata...
he'll have to leave his
families unguarded.
There's a chance we
could get to your wife,
get her out.
[Scoffs]
Well, she's where
she wants to be...
so let her be.
[People chattering]
[People laughing]
[Speaking Apache]
[Jess] Mrs. Grange!
Ellen Grange!
[Gun firing]
[Man shouting]
[Neighing]
Mrs. Grange!
What the...
get your pencil ready.
Them horses all you worry about?
Yeah. I got 10 more to bust.
Then my worries are over.
You can still lose your
skin out here, too.
Not if I can help it.
Sir,
there's fresh pony tracks
leading across our trail
into that canyon.
Well, soldier boy, you
found your Apaches.
We proceed, sir?
Tell the men we'll
advance at the ready.
Yes, sir.
Toller...
do you remember the
Ojo Caliente fight?
You got an arrow in your backside
and I pulled you to cover.
I remember.
I have to lead the column.
Somebody's got to find
out if Chata's up there.
And if I get killed,
you'll know.
That's right.
I see.
[Guns firing]
[Men shouting]
[Apaches hollering]
Hold your fire! Re-form in twos!
Hold your fire!
[Toller] Come on, you
ain't paid for yet!
Get those wagons to the rocks!
[Hollering]
[Gunfire continues]
[Grunting]
Form a company front behind
the wagons, sergeant,
and do that about turn!
[Ferguson] Yes, sir.
Let's get you mounted.
Leave me be!
Don't give me no
orders, McAllister!
[Ferguson] O'Brien!
Form company front
behind the wagons.
# [bugle playing]
[Hollering]
[Ferguson] About turn!
Fire!
About turn!
[Gun fires]
[Shouting]
[Man yelling]
[Horse neighing]
Your leg's broke.
I know.
Sir, there's 16 dead,
and there's some more
men that's hurt so bad
they can't be of much use.
And, uh, the cook wagon's lost.
I know, sergeant.
All our grub, sir.
And all the water.
I know, sergeant!
Chata's got us pinned down here.
As long as he keeps
us pinned down...
until col. Foster shows up,
it'll have been worth it.
Won't it, sergeant?
Yes, sir.
Tell the men that the water
they've got in their canteen
will have to last them until
the reinforcements arrive.
Any man who uses his up...
will just have to
drink his own sweat.
Yes, sir.
And, sergeant...
fine job for your
first Apache fight.
Thank you, sir.
Well?
Find shade for the
wounded and see
that everything's done
that can be done.
Yes, sir.
I think the worst casualty
is that cook wagon.
That Chata, he dealt the cards,
played us, and took
the first hand cold.
I've still got an ace
card up my sleeve.
Harrington?
Aye.
Don't look!
Look the other way.
It's Cpl. Harrington.
Come on, let's go.
That's where Scotty is holed up.
We gotta get to those rocks
before Chata can cut us off.
When I give you the word,
you get going full out!
Here, I'll take the boy.
You've both got a better chance
of making it if I take him.
Give him here.
[Baby crying]
[Speaks Apache]
What are you doing?
Chata won't take a chance on his
men shooting his own grandson.
[Speaking Apache]
Now!
Lieutenant, lieutenant, look!
[Speaking Apache]
[Hollering]
Prepare to fire!
Fire!
[Baby crying]
Gimme, gimme, you're
scaring the kid.
Ah!
[Sighs]
Ah! Choo-choo, now.
[Murmuring soothingly]
Whee!
[Murmuring]
Whoo!
[Ellen laughs]
Oh, you're standing up now!
Yeah, you're standing up!
Choo-choo!
What'd you bring that here for?
That's her son.
Sorry, ma'am...
I didn't mean to...
Scotty, Harrington
didn't make it.
He was tortured before he died.
Probably told Chata
everything he knew.
So Chata knows.
I'm waiting here for reinforcements
that aren't going to arrive?
He also knows what you
got in those wagons.
He wants that ammunition
and the glory.
And he gets both
by wiping us out.
Which makes him bigger than
ever with the Apaches.
Jess.
We've got to break
out and find water.
Where?
There's only 2 places
between here and Concho.
One of them's where Chata
left his families,
20 miles inside those hills.
With those wagons,
you'll never outrun him.
And the other place?
Diablo canyon.
Just a half a mile from
where Chata's sitting.
But Diablo is a box canyon.
There's only one way in.
I spotted 4 or 5 Apaches
just inside the rocks.
That's all he'll need
to hold you out.
Weli... what's next... general?
How old is he, ma'am?
4 months.
He don't favor his
mother, that's for sure.
[Man chuckles]
That's yours?
Yes.
You didn't tell me that...
why?
After the way you acted?
So you ran off the first chance
you got to get back to this...
half-breed bastard!
Ah, come off it, Grange.
You stay out of this, Toller!
That's just a little
baby that's Ali...
you keep your mouth
shut or I'll...
you were saying?
Pick it up.
Be careful, Grange.
I told you to pick it up.
You got another one in your holster,
use that one or back water.
[Gun fires]
You two can play games
some other time.
Right now, we can't spare
either one of you.
You ought to play poker, Grange.
You got natural luck.
It. McAllister would
like to see you two.
[Scotty] Look, we
set out at dark
with the wagons for Concho.
Chata's not likely to follow us
till he's sure we're
not just trying
to feint him out of the canyon.
He'll just scout us,
knowing he can catch us easy
enough when he's ready.
After a couple of hours
I'll shift direction...
strike straight for where
he's left his families.
His scouts will race
back to report it.
Chata will have to
come out to stop us.
Only by then, I'll have
changed direction again.
Circling back to
Diablo canyon...
getting there
before Chata realizes
what's happened.
You might make general one day.
Except he'll probably
leave some men
in the entrance to that canyon,
just in case.
That's something you'll
have to take care of
before you set out for Concho.
You and the 4 best
men I've got left.
Toller?
He's not under my orders.
But I'm thirsty, too
and I'm getting thirstier.
[Ferguson] Troopers, mount up!
We're moving out!
Dress on the wagons!
# [bugle playing]
Let's move it!
[Ferguson] Flank the
first armor wagon!
White, Hopkins, flank
the second armor wagon.
It's time now, Mrs. Grange.
[Ferguson] Avery, miller,
flank the freighter's wagon.
Bugler, drive point
behind the lieutenant!
Help me mount, sergeant.
Sir, are you sure you're able?
Sergeant, I give the orders.
Yes, sir.
Here.
Jess.
As far as I'm concerned,
your job's done when
you report to Concho.
If Clay Dean's there...
I'll not take it bad if you
don't return with col. Foster.
Oh, Scotty.
Aye?
Keep an eye on Ellen Grange
and her boy, will you?
You've got no luck, Jess.
She's already married.
"Welcome to your gory bed..."
"or to victory."
[Wagons clattering]
[Toller] Been over 2 hours.
McAllister must've made
his first move by now.
[Scotty] Now, we start
straight for the hills
and Chata's families.
# [bugle playing]
[Men yelling]
[Horse galloping]
It's a scout, reporting
back to Chata.
[Man yelling]
How many?
I couldn't count.
They couldn't have
left too many behind.
Turn back to the canyon!
We've got to get there by dawn!
Now!
# [bugle playing]
It's almost dawn.
We keep on like this all the
way, these animals will die!
We'll all be dead if we don't.
[Men chattering]
[Hollering]
Move those wagons faster!
Advance forward!
# [bugle playing]
Bugler, start the charge!
[Guns firing]
Make way for the wagons!
Ah!
Bugler, sound the charge!
# [bugle playing]
[Gun clicks]
[Hooting]
Swenson! Sound the charge!
# [bugle playing]
[Gasping]
Welcome to the water
hole, general.
[Horse snorts]
Where's Jess? Is he all right?
He's on his way to Concho.
Get the survivors back
to the water hole.
Start with Mrs. Grange.
Mrs. Grange!
You stay there.
Did Jess get away?
[Groans]
Yes, except 2 of
Chata's outriders
followed him all the way out
and got some shots at him.
Sgt. Ferguson.
Yes, sir?
Get them lined up
ready for inspection.
Tell Maj. Novac we're
heading out for Concho.
Sir, we only got
just 11 men left.
You.
Get the lieutenant...
sergeant, guard the entrance
to the canyon with...
help him.
[Groans]
And position the 2 best marksmen
we've got left on
top of the mesa.
Try and get snipers up there.
Mr. Toller...
I understand you fought through
a few of these Indian campaigns.
A few.
Look, I'm a damned
good sergeant, see...
but I never fought
no Indians before.
I never even been west of St.
Louis
till I brought out this
bunch of recruits.
[Sighs]
Get those horses back to the water.
They earned it.
And get one of those ammo wagons
all the way back to the water
so we can use it
for a last stand.
The question now is whether we can
hold out until col. Foster gets here.
Suppose Remsberg gets caught?
Remsberg ain't Harrington.
I don't much like the idea of
blowing up all this ammunition.
Let's hope we don't have to.
Casey! Nyles!
Let's get you inside, so you can
watch this whole rim up here.
If I was Chata, I'd
call it quits.
Anybody see where
that come from?
Scatter! We're too exposed.
They're using arrows.
They're out of ammunition.
Chata is taking no
chances a stray bullet
will hit that ammunition wagon.
[Snorting]
The lieutenant, uh,
seems to be resting easier.
Fever's down, he'll
be all right.
You must love that kid an awful
lot, to do what you did.
He's my child.
I wish, uh...
that I'd taken it different.
I want you to know that, Ellen,
because we're not gonna
get out of here.
Maybe if...
maybe if we'd had a kid...
things would have
been different.
You were a good husband, will,
before the Apaches took me.
But you never would
have been again.
Weli...
you'll need this when
they get in here at us.
There's 2 cartridges in it.
[Inaudible]
Toller.
Sergeant.
Sir, they're getting ready
for something out there.
Let's have a look.
My wagon.
They're using it for cover!
Sergeant!
Ah!
Hold your fire till you see
something to shoot at.
Fire!
[Guns firing]
Hold your fire until you can
see the legs of those ponies.
[Toller] Get ready to fire.
Now!
[Horses neighing]
Casey, Nyles, cover us!
We're coming back!
One got back inside here.
[Grunts]
Get going.
Grange, get going!
Get down.
[Crackling fuse]
# [bugle playing]
Did you finish that
big meal already?
Colonel, is Clay Dean in town?
The marshal? I suppose so.
Unless he's off
celebrating some place.
He killed a man last night.
We'll be ready to pull
out in 5 minutes.
I'll catch up with you, colonel.
[Colonel] Sergeant, mount up.
[Man] Company, mount!
# [bugle playing]
[Man yelling]
[Animal howling]
[Horse neighing]
We have to move back further.
Yeah, they'll all be slipping
back in here now it's dark.
We're pulling back, get moving.
Hold it.
Anybody seen Grange?
Grange?
Grange!
[Woman laughing]
[Man] Who's that?
Jess Remsberg.
Who the hell is Jess Remsberg?
Scout for col.
Foster at the fort.
All right.
What do you want?
You Clay Dean?
Yeah.
I need some information.
It's important.
Better be important to me.
Well?
Where did you get that?
I won it in a poker game.
Who did you win it from?
Why?
Who?
First, you tell me why
you want to know.
She was my wife.
Oh.
So that's it.
No, you're not gonna find
out about him from me.
I might tell him about you,
though, when I see him.
He did you a favor, mister.
I ain't got nothing against
a man bedding down
with a pretty, young
Indian girl...
but when you call one
of them your wife...
tell me who you won it from.
You can leave here
now, squaw man.
Leave your gun belt.
Take off that gun.
Or use it.
Ah!
[Grunting]
[Whimpering]
Now, tell me who you
won her hair from.
If I do?
If you do, marshal,
you go on living.
You've got yourself quite a
name as a bad man with a gun.
Maybe you think you can
tell me any name at all,
then later come gunning for me.
Is that what you're
thinking, marshal?
No, I... [screaming]
Well, now you know.
You're not fast anymore.
You give me the wrong name and
I'll come back and finish the job.
Now who?
He needed $10 to see my hand.
Grange put up the scalp for it.
He was drunk and he...
did you say...
Grange. A freighter.
Will Grange.
He was telling how
he'd revenged his wife
on this Comanche
girl he'd caught.
[Groaning]
Ugh!
Ah.
Get inside the perimeter.
Get against the wall!
[Groaning]
Get back!
But he's alive!
[Animal howling]
[Horse neighing]
[Grange screaming]
Will!
[Baby crying]
They're killing him.
Not yet.
It's an old trick.
They saved him for this,
to work on our nerves.
[Screaming continues]
[Sobs] Oh, god.
[Grange wailing]
[Grange screaming]
"Holy Mary, mother of god,
"pray for our sins..."
"now and in the
hour of our death."
Ferguson!
It's time to collect
that dry brush
and get it under
that ammo wagon.
If they rush us,
that wagon better burn fast.
[Grunting]
[Grange screaming]
Mrs. Grange!
Somebody's got to kill him.
Put an end to what
they're doing.
Ugh!
Mrs. Grange.
Give me the gun and get down.
No.
Oh.
[Moaning]
It's all up to you now, Toller.
Don't let them get
the ammunition.
Chata won't get that ammunition
even if he wipes us out.
And he's lost too many men
against a force half his size.
And you did it.
No.
I killed most of my men.
Chata had to be stopped
and you stopped him.
That's what the army's out
here to do, ain't it?
Is it?
Yes.
[Groaning]
Toller.
You...
you tell them that...
[Grange screams]
You sure this is what you
want to do, Mrs. Grange?
I don't want him to die.
Chata will take care of him.
And raise him as an Apache.
My people would never raise
him as one of their own.
They're getting
ready for the kill.
We better get back to the wagon.
Now, Mrs. Grange.
Mrs. Grange, let go now.
[Sobbing]
They're coming, all of them.
If they get me, you
fire this wagon.
[Thudding]
[Guns firing]
[Gunfire stops]
Company, halt!
Ellen!
Ellen. Let me go to will!
Where is he?
Let me go to him, please!
Ellen! You stay here.
I'll find him.
[Grange whispering] K-kill me.
Have pity.
Please, kill me.
Kili... please.
Kili...
[Gun fires]
I wonder if they'll stay on
the reservation this time.
Why should they?
Company, forward turn!
Ho!
Forward!
General.
[Shredding]
synced and corrected by: coolsuren