Marshal Duckett?
I'm Sheriff Parker.
My deputy, Tuck.
Welcome to Ghost Town.
Come a long way, Sheriff.
What's goin' on here?
We appreciate that,
Marshal, we truly do.
Looks like this town's
already cleaned itself up.
Yeah? How's that?
Well, sir,
Harmon Teaster came to town.
- Harmon Teaster?
- Yes, sir.
[Narrator] American settlers
fought over land and gold.
They pushed far
to the western sea,
leaving a trail of blood
in their wake.
In the east,
pioneer settlers
from the distant Celtic
and Scottish lands
settled in
the rugged Appalachians.
Life was hard
for these proud, rugged people.
Blood was thicker
than water,
and their conflicts were often
settled in pounds of flesh--
where an eye for an eye
was an unspoken duty toward
preserving family honor.
Rightin' the wrongs
done to family was common.
Feelings toward
the neighboring Cherokee
ran both hot and cold.
Some called them "brother,"
and some called them "savages."
The Appalachian folklore legend
of Harmon Teaster,
who lived and walked
these mountains,
was a man driven
by honor for his family
who brought his own
brand of justice.
This would haunt him
deep into his winter years.
These mountains
will teach something
to anyone who will truly listen
to what they have to say.
So listen as they speak now.
[coughing]
It'll help.
Now sip that down.
You tryin'
to poison me?
Stop teasin'
and drink up.
That tonic will
make you feel better.
Susie! [gasps]
[speaks in Cherokee]
Violet, I saw your ma,
Susie, behind that tree!
- Pa...
- Plain as day.
- You're burning up with fever.
- I saw your ma.
You get on up inside.
Come on. Come on, Pa.
[breathing heavily]
I saw her.
You thought you saw her.
- I did.
- It's the fever.
I did see her.
Just lie a spell and rest.
I'm making some broth
to keep your strength up.
I love you.
You're my little angel.
I love you, too.
I'm gonna go to the garden
and pick a few things.
Just rest yourself here
quietly.
[breathing heavily]
Pa! John Burnett's
riding in with his boys.
They're coming this way.
I told you Pa
would come for me.
Your pa can come say
anything he wants, boy,
but you're still gonna stand
trial for killin' that Injun.
Injun! Boy.
Ain't no sense
about them Cherokee.
Pa...I don't think
he's coming here to talk.
Why don't you
just let him go?
Do you think that's right,
Harmon? Just turn him loose?
Boy makes a lot
of sense there, Sheriff.
Shut your mouth,
Victor!
- You ought to listen.
- I said shut up!
I ask you again, do you think
that's the right thing to do?
Just set him free?
Ransom,
you got my son.
Your son killed an
Injun boy in cold blood.
I saw him with my own two eyes.
[John] That wasn't no boy.
That was a savage.
Doesn't matter.
He's standing trial for what he did.
My son got some
growin' up to do,
but I can't have him gettin' in all
this trouble over some thievin' redskin.
Now you tell me how
we can work this out.
Mr. Burnett,
just back yourself out of here.
I'm sending for the judge
tomorrow morning.
- You ignorant ass!
- Pa!
I tried to be civil, and you
went and got all righteous on me.
Boys!
Open that cell.
Now!
[Ransom groans]
I ain't got no key!
Find the key.
Hurry up!
Open that cell.
Get in there.
[laughing]
Watch him, Pa.
[horse neighing]
[Ransom groans]
Just let him go.
Please!
You come from bad seed, boy.
[gun cocks]
Ain't your doin',
but that don't matter none.
[groans]
[Ransom]
Help, please, God!
[henchmen grunting]
Digger, where you at?
Digger!
- Right here.
- Get one of them pine boxes.
We got
a dead man walkin'.
[laughing]
Dead man walkin'!
Come on.
Get it up.
Put him in it, boys.
No, no, no! No!
- No! No! No!
- [Victor laughs]
No! No!
Make yourself comfortable.
[laughing]
Close it up.
[Ransom groans]
Digger!
- [Ransom groans]
- Never did like you nohow.
[groans]
No! No!
Get a hammer and nails.
[horse neighing]
[spits]
[Ransom]
No!
Get the hell out here!
Digger,
nail her shut.
- I'm gonna kill you all.
- [hammering]
[Victor laughs]
That's one.
Two.
[laughing]
Three.
And that's four--
Hey, hey, hey! Hold it.
- Knock knock.
- [Ransom] Help!
I don't think
he's dead yet, Pa.
- [Victor laughing]
- Let's shut him up, boys.
- [Ransom] No! No! No! No!
[Victor laughing]
[humming]
[Victor cackles]
- What do you think, Pa?
- Light him up.
[laughing]
Hey.
You Ransom's boy?
Yes. Ye--
Who are you?
I'm Jim Jumper.
We gotta help him.
No, we gotta
get you outta here.
Now, come on.
Let it be known
that from now on,
the Burnetts
run Maggie Valley...
and all of Haywood County.
Anybody got a problem,
you come see me.
[Young Violet]
Wake up, Pa.
Susie!
[speaks in Cherokee]
Come home to me.
Ma!
Not yet, Pa.
[Victor laughing]
Time to die, Harmon.
- Pa!
- [grunts, gasps]
Y-You dream.
[groans]
Who are you?
The white man...
who I once called husband...
named me Susie.
Husband was also
an angry and abusive man.
He's no longer alive.
Get some of that
into him.
Those men.
Did they follow us?
They didn't follow us.
You must eat
to have strength.
I can't.
[Violet]
Please? Just try a little.
No. [whimpers] No.
I don't want to.
- You're gettin' worse.
- I'm not hungry.
You're gettin' worse,
and I think you need medicine.
I've tried all of Ma's cures,
but the fever won't break.
Maybe...
I could go to town.
No. You don't go to town.
I know.
Papa was killed in town.
You don't go to town.
Whatever happened there
happened a long time ago.
Things have changed.
You don't know if
your uncle will get that--
He could be gone
for weeks, Pa!
- We don't know how long.
- No.
- Please.
- No, you don't go.
I know the memories
are hard on you.
You don't go.
And I know how you
feel about what you did.
[sobbing] Susie.
Susie...
[Ransom's voice]
Do you think that's right, Harmon?
[echoes]
...that's right, Harmon?
[shouts]
Thought we were
gonna lose you.
No.
You been down
nearly a week.
Susie been by your side
the whole time.
She's taken
a shine to you.
She's down by the river,
bathin' in the moonlight.
Women things,
I reckon. [chuckles]
I know what you're thinking.
You think if you can get
far enough away from here
and if you've taken fond
of Susie, well, then--
I have taken a...
shine to her.
But a man's got to do...
what he's got to do.
I understand about righting
wrongs done to family.
I could help you.
This ain't your fight.
Well, you'd best go
'fore she comes back.
Take the horse.
We'll wait for you here.
I'm sorry. I can't
let you die like Ma.
[Young Violet's voice]
I can't let you die.
[man screaming, shouting]
[screaming continues]
What the hell's
going on here?
My leg! My leg!
Leave him alone!
Marion!
[screaming]
[groaning]
[John groaning]
How much wood
you think she'll take?
You're gonna have to replace all of this.
I can tell that already.
- And...
- What?
Cole, how much
did you pay for this?
Pete gave me
a good deal on it.
- He said it was slightly used.
- "Slightly"?
Look at this thing.
It looks like it's been up and down
the Oregon Trail a half dozen times.
Damn it all to hell!
Damn!
She still
wants to leave?
You know...
This town is full
of whores and sinners.
Good morning, madame,
and how are you today?
Morning.
Is this it?
Yeah. I know it
don't look like much,
but with a few improvements,
it'll work.
How long?
Couple days.
Maybe a week.
A week? I want out
of this godforsaken town now!
And you...
your father...
[Bobcat]
Happy birthday, Willy.
He's the animal
that killed my brother.
And you do nothing!
Looks like you got
a problem with your missy.
[laughing]
You got somethin'
you wanna say to me?
I don't believe
in guns.
If I did...
You'd be dead.
It's lucky for you I don't
believe in shooting an unarmed man.
It's downright
unsporting.
But I'd be happy to loan you one.
Bang! [laughing]
That's enough, Jim.
Put it away.
So, Willy, your pa's having a birthday party
for you tonight down at the Silver Dollar.
Is that right?
Just tell him
that I'm not interested.
Hey, uh, you know
how your daddy gets.
Think it'd be best
if you just came, you know.
He ain't gonna take it
too kindly if you don't come,
bein' that you're
the guest of honor and all!
Well, lookee here.
Look like another whore's
come to town. [cackling]
At 30, I was involved
in so much.
Mining, owning saloons,
land, more.
Will has no interest
in any of that.
That boy is meek
and worthless to me.
- But he's your blood, Victor.
- Yeah.
Maybe he'll come around.
Hopefully. Ah.
[Victor]
Mmm...
Coffee?
Shot of poison, sir?
Not this early.
Here. Buy yourself
something nice for tonight.
Thank you.
You know... I think I have
an idea how to loosen Will up.
[laughing]
Dear Almighty Father,
it's me, Violet.
I've never been
in a church before,
so forgive me
if I do something wrong.
I ask that you send your
healing hand down to touch my pa,
Harmon Teaster.
Have mercy
and don't call him home yet.
He's an honest man
and always a good
husband and father.
Don't ask
to save others.
You might put me
out of business.
Elmer Inlow's the name.
Folks round here
call me Digger.
I do all the burying
when duty calls.
All up through Haywood
and Buncombe County.
So, uh...
did you say
your pa was sick?
Yes, sir.
You say his name
was Harmon Teaster?
Is it?
Could you direct me
to the doctor's office?
I'm sure I passed it.
Morning.
Morning, Will.
I'm Violet.
Will Burnett.
Good to meet you.
I'll leave you two
to yourselves.
I got business
to take care of.
[sighs] That man
is a little strange.
Strange. I know.
This is
a beautiful church.
Thank you.
Is it yours, or...
No. I'm just the caretaker,
I guess you could say.
Caretaker?
See, our preacher,
he kind of left town,
and some of the folks still like
to get together on Sundays.
So I'm trying
to keep it open and...
do a little reading from
the Good Book here and there.
You preach.
I wouldn't go so far
as to call it preaching.
Just...good folks
getting together
for a little bit
of reading, praying.
I think that's wonderful.
- Well...
I'm sorry.
What were you saying?
No, say what you
were gonna say.
I really wasn't saying
anything, so please.
I was gonna ask if you could
direct me to the doctor's office.
You do have
a doctor in town?
Oh, yeah.
Dr. Hugh Morrison.
He's a wonderful man,
and, uh, I'd be happy
to take you to see him.
Thank you.
Is it all right if I leave
my horse tied up here?
- Yeah, that'd be fine.
- I shouldn't be too long.
Are you... sick
or something?
No, my pa is.
Sorry.
Well, right this way.
You should come to church
on Sunday with me.
Might be a nice change.
Might be. It gets harder and harder
to do this thing all the time.
- You remember my friend Ally?
- Sure.
From Richmond?
I had a letter from her.
And she's getting along
just fine.
She's married now, and she's
looking to have a family.
You help some
to help themselves,
and you watch over
the others until then.
You do a good thing here,
Birdie.
Why, General James Martin.
How you doin'?
Listen,
you wouldn't know the...
whereabouts of Victor Burnett now,
would you?
[spits]
Buzzard.
[sighs]
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Could I have one?
I don't want that.
Give me the good stuff.
Anybody know where, uh,
Mr. Burnett is, or what
kind of mood he's in?
He's in a foul mood
this morning.
He is a little more
on edge than normal.
To hell with you, Digger!
You ain't never gonna get me
in one of your boxes.
Yeah, we'll see.
Another drink.
- What's he so edgy about?
- Hard to say.
Well...
Well, I think they're trying to plan
a birthday party for Will tonight.
- A party?
- Yeah, he is...
planning a birthday party
this evening.
But he can't
find Will.
I just saw him coming down the
street a while ago with Sorrells.
And, you know, he had
that biddy old wife with him.
[Judd, Digger laughing]
Give me another drink.
This is gonna be a good
celebration tonight.
Madame Birdie,
if I was you, I'd move!
- Digger...
- [Digger] Now, Jackknife...
I'm gonna make
old Digger dance!
- You better put that gun away.
- [Judd] Put that gun away!
I'll put you
in a pine box.
To hell with you, too,
Mr. Judd!
- [laughing]
- [gunshot]
Runnin' out
like some crippled bird.
[Little Jack]
Pa.
It's all right.
Pa, I thought I told you
you can't be firing in here.
I was just having a little fun.
I was gonna make old Digger dance.
- Yeah, I know.
- Victor used to make him dance.
Victor shot him
one time.
Mr. Burnett doesn't like to be woken up.
Gotta get you outta here.
Hey! What's all
the ruckus down here?
I'm sorry, Mr. Burnett.
My pa, he just--
Listen, Little Jack.
I can talk for my own self.
Well, Mr. Mayor,
I see you brought
your pet dog with you.
[chuckles]
You may dress like
a white man, Injun,
but that don't make you one.
And I'll tell you
something else.
I've killed a-many
of your kind in my day.
Yeah. Chief!
- Come on, Pa.
- I told you.
- [Victor shouts]
- [Jackknife shouts]
Old Knife here
worked for my pa.
He's a good man.
Just a bit too much shine.
- Take him home to sleep it off.
- Yes, sir, I will. Come on.
Huh. Well,
I don't know, Victor.
I'm just pleased
to help you any way I can.
You know I appreciate your
support for my railroad project.
Well then, of course, I'm gonna
expect your support come election time.
- Right?
- You know you'll have that.
Okay.
Copperhead, let's go.
- Mr. Burnett, sir...
- Very busy today, Digger.
Oh, Mr. Burnett.
I got some information
you might find
very interesting.
What?
It's about
your pa's murderer.
- [grunts] Mr. Burnett--
- Never mention my pa again!
You're not fit
to lick his boots!
Keep your mouth shut!
I'm sor--
I'm sorry, Mr. Burnett.
Ah, hell.
Come on to my office later on.
We'll talk about it.
Okay, Mr. Burnett.
Well, here you go.
Thank you.
Thank you so much, Doctor.
It's a pleasure, Gladys,
and, Caleb, remember,
when you're climbing
those trees,
grab separate branches
with each hand.
- Okay? You'll fall less often.
- Will do.
Are you gonna be staying
in town for a little while?
No, I'll be heading home
soon as I get the medicine.
Yeah.
I was hoping that maybe
one of these Sundays
you could come down
and sit in church.
I would like that.
All right. I'll let you tend
to your duties directly here.
I don't mean to
hold you up or nothin'.
It was a pleasure.
No, listen, the...
the pleasure...
was all mine.
Hope to see you soon.
Take care.
Pardon me.
Are you Dr. Morrison?
I am.
How can I help you?
I have a father
with a persistent fever,
and I really
need your help.
- You are?
- I'm sorry. My manners.
Uh, I'm Violet...
Teaster.
- Teaster, you said?
- Yes, sir.
Where's your father at?
Back over
towards Cold...
Just a few
mountains over.
He was too sick
to travel, so I thought
maybe you can give me a tonic
that I could take to him.
We can try something.
But if I can't see him, it's
hard to know what will help him.
Anything you can do
will be much appreciated.
I can pay.
Not much, but some.
We'll work that out.
I'm sure I have something.
I haven't seen you
around here before, have I?
No.
I don't blame you.
This used to be a family town.
Now, it's gotten
worse and worse.
I used to see
more kids like that
with fractured arms,
climbing trees.
Now I'm doing
mostly gunshot wounds.
I didn't see too many women and
children when I came into town.
They're hiding.
The sheriff has no control
over what goes on here.
Drunks are running around on
the street all day and all night.
If you're traveling by yourself,
you better be careful.
I will.
Um... I'm gonna
wrap this up.
Do you want some...
Freshen up?
Or, uh, can I make you
something to eat? Or...
I'll take you up
on the freshen.
Thank you.
Are you damn sure
she said Harmon Teaster?
I'm sure as day,
Mr. Burnett.
- Leave.
- Now, Mr. Burnett...
Take off!
[laughing]
Yeah.
[yelling]
[Young Victor yelling]
Captain! Captain!
[shouting]
[grunting]
[spits]
[gasps] Oh... Pete...
[breathing heavily]
Ain't right, Captain!
It just ain't right!
- It ain't right, Sheriff.
- We ought to do something.
Oh, Betsy...
Stay here.
Both of you.
Let's get inside.
You got something
to say to me, Sheriff?
I reckon not.
[Whiskey]
Captain.
Sir, Mr. Burnett's
looking all over for you.
I was just up with him
a short time ago.
Yes, sir. Well,
he says it's important.
[sighs]
Here, I'll take that.
This should keep it
safe for the journey.
Take one spoonful
every hour. Okay?
That fever
just might break.
Thank you so very much.
How much do I owe you?
How's a dollar sound?
Thank you, Doctor.
Bye.
Sorry I'm late.
I put my pa
down to bed.
What are we having
this little meeting for?
Maybe we're all
getting a raise.
- [laughing]
- Yeah, a raise.
[Victor]
Silence!
Some of you know that
my parents were murdered.
As well as many of the citizens
of this town some years back.
That's right.
It was by that one Harmon Teaster fella.
Quiet!
- [giggling]
- [Victor] Get out of here.
It has just been
brought to my attention
that this man who was never
brought to justice is still alive.
And his daughter walks
these very streets as we speak.
[Moose] I done seen
a strange girl in town.
Ain't that right, Joe?
Saw her head
into Doc's office.
Well, I want that girl
brought to me.
A hundred dollars to anyone
who brings her here immediately.
[Whiskey]
Let's do it.
- You want the girl unharmed?
- For now.
Run, girl. Run fast.
You say something
to me, General?
Hell with you, Yankee.
Not my fault you fought
on the wrong side.
Confederate forever.
The last shot of the war rang
out right over in Waynesville.
Confederacy's dead.
I still be hearing
the echo.
- Good day, General.
- Captain.
- Howdy, Will.
- Hey, Tom. How you doin'?
All right.
What you working on?
Just tinkering with a few
things here and there.
Mm. Place is looking
mighty fine.
Yeah? Thank you.
It's coming along.
So what brings you
down here?
Oh, I, uh--
I just, uh...
come in to, uh...
reflect a little.
You need to talk
about something?
Well...I feel peculiar
talking to you about this.
That's on account
of my pa, ain't it?
Will, how can you be
such a decent, honest man
when your pa's
the way he is?
I always account it
to the fact
that his parents
were all murdered.
Hmm...
But, uh, that don't
account for
the way he was
before they were killed.
You were there?
Uh! I saw enough.
I know...the truth
about what happened
with Harmon Teaster.
His pa was the law
around here.
And your pa...
had done gotten himself
into some bad trouble.
What kind
of trouble?
[exhales]
Well, Will...
He got drunk on shine
and killed some Indian boy.
And, uh,
Harmon Teaster's pa, Ransom,
he was dead set
on having your pa stand trial
for what he'd done.
Then your granddaddy,
Big John Burnett,
wickedly set his men
upon Ransom Teaster.
The whole town
saw what happened.
No man should have
suffered that way.
And Harmon Teaster witnessed
that merciless killing
from a jail cell window.
Somehow he escaped,
and when he came back
a few nights later...
he brought down
a vengeance on your family
and all the men
responsible
that is legendary
in its violence.
I mean, he made this town
into a ghost town.
I never heard the part
about the lawman before.
Well, I reckon... they left
some of the facts out.
Reckon so.
Now, your pa was hell-bent
on striking back.
But all the Burnett
gun hands were dead.
So he went around to other towns and
raised a small army of cutthroats.
They started out
looking for Harmon Teaster.
Never found him.
Now, legend says
that he hid himself out
in some mountain den
for years.
Others say he took in
with the Cherokee.
Don't you think that
he'd be dead by now?
May be.
But secrets
don't always stay buried.
Will...
this town is as bad now
as it ever was.
Maybe worse.
Now, I know
I should do something.
But I saw what they did
to that other lawman...
Ransom Teaster...
I'm afraid.
Tom, if you're afraid,
why don't you just leave?
Oh, I can run
from different places,
but I can't run
from myself.
Your pa and his boys
are getting way out of hand.
The people of this town
are looking for help.
What are you gonna do?
I have no clear path
in sight.
So... I come to pray.
I know it's been
a long time, but...
maybe He'll still listen
to an old man with a badge
seeking to do
the right thing.
Well, Tom, I'm gonna
let you sit here and reflect.
- Thanks, Will.
- No. Thank you.
Almighty God...
hear my prayer.
Do you have
an appointment?
No.
We're looking for a little lady
that was seen coming in here.
She still here, Doc?
Excuse me. I have
sensitive materials here.
Sensitive?
Sensitive materials...
for a sensitive man.
I'm getting real sensitive
about finding this girl, Doc.
Hell, Bobcat,
that ain't the right word.
[Dr. Morrison chuckles]
She's not here.
[Whiskey] She was here.
She ain't here now.
Doc, you wouldn't be keeping that
woman to yourself now, would you?
We need to go check
your living quarters?
We'll see how you all like it the
next time I have to sew you up.
You're always
getting out-drawn.
How you gonna like it when
I have a needle and thread,
when I gotta take
some lead out of your ass?
What are you saying, Doc?
[Jim Dandy]
Doc's right, Bobcat.
We haven't seen you hit anything
you was aiming at in a long time.
[laughing]
Doc's sewn you up
at least a half dozen times.
[laughing]
See what I mean?
You'd be having Doc pick lead from
you if Digger didn't get to you first.
Hell, he's just telling
some truth.
Doc's kept you from bleeding
to death on many occasion.
All right, boys.
Just tell us where
the lady is, Doc.
I honestly
don't know.
Hell, she's got to be
in town somewhere.
Let's go, boys.
- You, too, Little Jack.
- [blows a kiss]
I ain't
been shot yet.
No hard feelings.
This is unreasonable.
How can we run a business
when people don't pay?
[Pete]
I'll talk to Victor.
- Victor?
- He's harsh, I know.
But he's also
a businessman.
He'll listen to reason.
That Yankee mercenary
working for him
shows no respect.
For anybody
or anything!
Pa, are we
gonna be okay?
You mind your chores, boy.
Shh. We have customers.
[Betsy Mae] I'm terribly sorry.
Can I help you find anything?
[Violet] I'm picking up
a few little things.
This is amazing that you
have all this in one place.
You've never been
to a general store?
No.
My uncle and pa took me
to a trappers' gathering once,
but it was nothing
like this.
Pa? I think we got trouble.
So this is where
you've been hiding.
This horse is a nag.
You ought to let me
pick you a good horse.
I just wanted to wish you
a happy birthday, son.
Thank you.
I've had a half dozen people
out trying to find you
so I could have
a word with you today.
I don't know why
you defy me so.
Isn't there something in that Good
Book about respecting thy father?
You trying to tell me now
that you've read the Good Book?
I've read a line
or two here and there.
I know we don't always
see eye to eye
and I may not be
the ideal parent,
but I've always tried to provide
and help make you into a man.
Yeah. You've helped me decide what
kind of man I never want to be.
[laughing]
Will!
These people don't respond to
all that religious guilt bullshit.
They need authority from
someone who can give punishment.
Direct punishment
and reward.
You sound like you're
trying to fill in for God.
- Is that what you're trying to do?
- Enough!
I'm having a gathering
tonight at the Silver Dollar,
in your honor.
And I have a surprise
or two for you.
That church bell you've been
wanting is one of them.
I'm not demanding.
I'm asking my son
to please come tonight.
Let's have just one night
where we could put our differences
aside and be father and son.
Let's do it for your mother.
I know she would
have wanted that.
Agreed?
All right. Agreed.
- I'll be there.
- Great! Great.
Six o'clock to whenever.
We'll have a grand old time.
- Need new clothes or anything?
- No, I'm good. Thank you.
I'll see you
in a few hours, then.
- You best get cleaned up.
- I will.
Sure is pretty.
[cackling]
Like an unplucked flair.
- I need to be going now.
- She ain't goin' no-damn-where.
- [Jim Dandy] Nope.
- What's going on here?
- Let the girl go on her way!
- Shush, Betsy.
[Captain] I can see
this is gonna be difficult.
- Whiskey. Moose.
- [Moose] Let's go.
- [laughing]
- [Violet shrieking]
- [Violet whimpering]
- [Bobcat cackling]
Take her to my office
and watch her.
She gets away, I'm holding you
all personally responsible.
She ain't goin' nowhere,
Mr. Burnett.
[Victor, Jim Dandy laughing]
Makes you feel like
a little kid again.
[Mayor] Victor!
Hold on, fellas.
You mind telling me
what's going on out here?
A bit of family business.
Victor. Now you
got to understand.
It does not look good for people to
be dragged off the streets of this town
in the middle
of broad daylight like that.
[spitting] And it's bad for politicians
to be messin' with other folks' business.
There are still laws
in this town, Mr. Burnett.
Let's all
just take it easy.
Mr. Burnett, sir, what right
do you have to take that girl?
- What right?
- [grunting]
- [blows landing]
- [Deputy Tuck grunting]
You're trying to create
a job vacancy real fast.
Digger would be happy to box you and
your amigo up, if that's what you want.
That girl's pa
murdered my family.
In my book,
that gives me every right.
And if any of you
even question my actions again,
or get between me and
my business, I'll bury you!
- You understand?
- All right, now, Victor--
- Get the hell out of here.
- Victor...
W-We're stepping away.
[Mayor]
Stepping away right now.
Copperhead!
Copperhead, come on!
Come on!
Harmon.
Wake up.
Susie?
I do not have long, my love.
[whimpers]
You will be faced
with a serious choice
that has serious consequences
attached to it.
How will I know what to do?
I shot those men dead,
chopped 'em in the head
with a ax.
And then I shot
that poor old woman dead.
Huh.
- How can I do anything any worse?
- Shh!
I know what you did
and why you did it.
- Hold on, old friend.
- [groaning]
Everything will be okay.
[groaning continues]
[thunderclap]
Violet?
Where the hell are you?
Very strong.
You put in his drink,
and he will be...
How you say?
More relaxed.
Much more relaxed.
Influence will be
much more easy.
Hmm.
Thank you.
Who's she?
That, my dear...
is the daughter of the man
who murdered my family.
[thunderclap]
- [whimpering]
- And he's still alive, isn't he?
After all these years,
he's alive.
He's sent himself away like
a coward after what he did.
- [whimpering]
- Well, I intend to find him.
And you, my dear,
are going to tell me where.
Now...
I must go downstairs
to greet our guests.
And, honestly,
I don't trust anyone else
to watch over you,
save the good captain here,
because I pay him very well.
Captain,
please help yourself
to any of the brandy.
I'll be back shortly.
Birthday. Oh, it's sure
a good reason for a drink.
[laughs]
Dandy with all diamonds.
That's twice, Mr. Walters.
[laughs]