[ Horse Whinnies ]
OH!
OH, YOU, RIO GRANDE!
GET IN THERE!
COME ON, SPEED!
i¡¡VIVA MEXICO!
AH HA HA HA HA!
OH! OH!
YAH! HAH!
EE-HA HA HA!
i¡¡VIVA MEXICO!
THIS HERE'S MEXICAN DIRT!
YOU CAN'T TOUCH ME!
HA HA! HEE HEE HEE!
OH! OOH HOO HOO!
YOU THOUGHT YOU'D GET
THE OLD MAN IN THE MOON.
YOU TEXAS CLOWN BUZZARDS IS
A DISGRACE TO THE CONFEDERACY.
SPEED,
THIS AIN'T NO TIME
TO LET ME DOWN.
GET UP!
COME ON, SPEED!
[ Yelling ]
GODDAMN IT, SPEED!
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
THIS IS
MEXICAN TERRITORY!
[ Yelling ]
I DON'T BELIEVE IT!
HE GOT ACROSS THE RIVER,
AND HIS HORSE
FAINTS ON HIM!
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT!
IT'S A GODDAMN
FOREIGN COUNTRY
HERE!
THIS AIN'T FAIR,
GODDAMN IT!
THIS AIN'T FAIR!
THEY'RE STRINGING UP
OLD SPEED.
I HAVE HERE
A VERY FINE ANIMAL
ONCE OWNED
BY THEHOMBRE
WE'RE ABOUT TO HANG.
WHAT AM I OFFERED?
HEY! I STILL OWN
THAT HORSE.
WHEN WE WANT TO HEAR
FROM YOU, AMIGO,
WE'LL RATTLE
YOUR CAGE.
HA HA HA!
IS THAT THE HORSE
THAT FAINTED?
YEAH, HE FAINTED,
BUT HE GOT UP,
DIDN'T HE?
HA HA HA!
WHAT?
OH!
TOWFIELD, I TOLD YOU
TO KEEP THESE BUZZARDS
OUT OF HERE!
TAKE IT EASY, MOON.
YOU'RE LUCKY
YOU'RE GETTING
A DECENT HANGING.
I'D HAVE DONE IT
OUT THERE
ON A SCRUB OAK.
GODDAMN VULTURES
HANGING AROUND HERE
ALL MORNING.
THEY JUST WANTED
TO TAKE A GANDER
AT THE MAN
OF THE HOUR.
YEAH. WELL,
I'M FLATTERED AS HELL.
YOU'RE A REAL CARD,
MOON.
I'M GOING
TO MISS YOU.
YOUR FAMILY'S
HERE.
MAKE IT SHORT.
BOYS!
BROTHER ABE,
JIMMY, GUSSIE,
AND EVERYBODY.
DUMB-ASS DEPUTY.
HE THOUGHT
YOU WAS REALLY MY FAMILY.
THAT'S HOW I FIGURED.
YOU LOOK PRETTY
AS A PAINTING, HONEY.
HOW YOU DOING,
HENRY?
WELL...
ROLL IT OUT.
NOTHING LIKE THAT,
HENRY.
WE JUST COME
TO SEE YOU OFF.
SEE ME OFF?
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
YOU DID TOO GODDAMN GOOD
ON YOUR OWN, HENRY,
DID YOU?
NOW, YOU SHOULD HAVE
STUCK WITH US
BECAUSE WE WAS
GOING PLACES,
GODDAMN IT!
WHAT DO YOU MEAN "WAS"?
ALL YOU GOT TO DO
IS SPRING ME.
IF WE TRIED ANYTHING,
WE'D ONLY GET OURSELVES--
YEAH, BUT THAT'S
WITHOUT MY PLANS.
AH, CUT THAT OUT.
BIG ABE, THEY'RE
GOING TO SEND ME
TO THE BONE ORCHARD.
[ Big Abe Spits ]
IF YOU GOT ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO GIVE AWAY, HENRY,
NOW'S THE TIME.
SAY YOUR
GOOD-BYES, BOYS.
NICE KNOWING YOU.
YEAH, COOGAN, SURE.
YOU KNOW,
IT JUST AIN'T RIGHT.
JUST FOR CUTTING
A FEW HORSES
AND ROBBING A FEW BANKS.
THE LAW'S GOT TO
BE CHANGED, HENRY.
COME ON NOW, CLYDE.
SO LONG, MOON.
ADIOS.
OH...
WELL, HONEY,
LEAST WE HAD
SOME GOOD OLD
TIMES TOGETHER.
YOU WAS THE BEST
I EVER HAD...
EXCEPT FOR MAYBE
THAT CIRCUS FELLER.
WHY DOES THAT
ALWAYS UPSET YOU SO?
WHAT THE HELL
DID YOU BRING
A THING LIKE THAT UP
AT A TIME
LIKE THIS FOR,
HERMINE? SHIT!
HENRY!
[ Sobbing ]
DON'T YOU WORRY
NONE, MOON.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF THIS GIRL
LIKE SHE'S
MY VERY OWN.
COME ON, NOW.
OH, HENRY!
HENRY!
MR. MOON?
IT'S ABOUT
THAT TIME.
WHAT ABOUT
MY LAST MEAL?
YOU'RE SMOKING
IT.
HA HA HA!
HANDS BEHIND
YOUR BACK, MR. MOON.
HE AIN'T FOR YOU,
SERENE.
I WOULDN'T TAKE YOU
TO A DOGFIGHT
IF YOU WAS
THE DEFENDING CHAMP.
[ Hector Laughs ]
YOU OUGHTN'T
HAVE DONE THAT,
MR. MOON.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU
KEEP ME IN JAIL
FOR IT?
YOU TELL HIM
ABOUT THE ORDINANCE?
NO.
WHY NOT?
I DON'T
LIKE HIM,
AND PEOPLE
I DON'T LIKE
I DON'T
TELL NOTHING.
GODDAMN IT, TOWFIELD.
WHAT ORDINANCE?
SHERIFF PILE?
KYLE.
WE GOT THIS
ORDINANCE HERE.
IT WAS
PASSED AFTER
THE CIVIL WAR
ON ACCOUNT OF
A LOT OF OUR BOYS
DIDN'T COME HOME,
AND THE WOMEN
WAS BEGINNING
TO CHEW UP
THE GRASS.
I FEEL SORRY
FOR THE GRASS.
I'M FEELING SORRY
FOR THE WOMEN.
ANYHOW, THIS
ORDINANCE STATES
THAT ANY MAN SHORT
OF BEING A MURDERER
CAN BE SAVED
FROM THE GALLOWS
BY ANY
PROPERTY-HOLDING
FEMALE,
PROVIDING SHE DECIDES
TO MARRY HIM.
THEY DONE THAT
IN ROMAN TIMES, TOO,
AS I RECOLLECT.
SWEET JESUS
H. CHRIST ALMIGHTY!
MA'AM! MA'AM!
I THINK THERE'S
A COUPLE OF THINGS
ABOUT ME THAT I'D LIKE
FOR YOU TO CONSIDER.
I DON'T NEED
YOUR INSULTS.
OH, I AGREE
WITH YOU COMPLETELY,
BUT YOU GOT TO TAKE
INTO CONSIDERATION
A MAN CAN GET
A LITTLE IRRITATED,
AND HE CAN ACT
LIKE THE DICKENS
WHEN HE'S ABOUT
TO PULL HEMP.
BUZZARDS, HUH?
WELL, BUZZARDS
CAN FLY,
AND THEY KEEP
THE DESERT CLEAN.
I COOK!
I COOK LIKE
THE SON-OF-A-BITCH!
I MEAN,
LIKE THE DICKENS!
OH!
HELLO, SON.
GO TO HELL.
I UNDERSTAND.
[ Cow Moos ]
BE QUIET!
SHH!
HENRY LLOYD MOON,
YOU'VE BEEN FOUND GUILTY
OF HORSE THIEVERY
AND SENTENCED
TO BE HANGED.
DO YOU HAVE ANY
FINAL LAST WORDS?
JUST THIS.
I WANT TO TELL
YOU GOOD PEOPLE
OF LONGHORN...
ESPECIALLY YOU
LOVELY LADIES,
THAT THE OLD SAYING--
"YOU CAN'T JUDGE A BOOK
BY ITS COVER"--
IT'S TRUE.
SOME BOOKS IS ALL
SCRUFFED UP ON THE OUTSIDE,
BUT WHEN YOU TURN AROUND
AND LOOK INSIDE,
WHY, THE WORDS IS...
JUST...WONDERFUL.
IS THAT IT,
MOON?
WELL, ISN'T THERE ANYBODY ELSE
GOT ANYTHING TO SAY?
"THE LORD
IS MY SHEPHERD.
"I SHALL NOT WANT.
AW...
"HE MAKETH ME
TO LIE DOWN
"IN GREEN PASTURES.
"HE LEADETH ME
"BESIDE
THE STILL WATERS.
HE RESTORETH
MY SOUL."
THAT'S NOT RIGHT.
"THE LORD
IS MY SHEPHERD.
"I SHALL NOT WANT.
"HE MAKETH ME
TO LIE DOWN
[ Groaning, Sobbing ]
"IN GREEN PASTURES.
"HE RESTORETH
MY SOUL.
"HE LEADETH ME
"BESIDE
THE STILL WATERS.
YEA, THOUGH I
WALK THROUGH
THE VALLEY--"
OH!
I'M A VETERAN OF
THE GREAT CIVIL WAR!
THE ONLY REASON WHY
I TURNED TO CRIME
IS THERE WASN'T
NO JOBS--
NOT ONE SINGLE JOB
FOR A MAN
THAT RISKED HIS LIFE
FOR THE COUNTRY...
"THOU ANOINTEST
MY HEAD--"
AND THE CONFEDERACY!
THIS ONE'S DUMB.
HE'LL SWING
FOR SURE.
HE'S BETTER OFF.
"AND I WILL DWELL
IN THE HOUSE
OF THE LORD FOREVER."
BULLSHIT!
[ Rapping On Window ]
HE'S READY TO GO!
STOP!
I'LL TAKE HIM.
FLORENCE.
NOW--
AH!
DON'T YOU THINK
THAT YOU'RE
A MITE
TOO ELDERLY
TO BE TAKING ON
A RESPONSIBILITY
LIKE THIS?
I'VE GOT A GOOD
FEELING ABOUT HIM, ANDREW.
THE BOY'S A VETERAN.
HE DESERVES
A SECOND CHANCE.
SOMEBODY TAKE
THIS SON-BITCHING
BLINDFOLD OFF ME
AND LET ME SEE
MY BRIDE!
WHERE IS SHE?
FLORENCE!
AAH!
AH HA HA! AH!
MRS. HENRY MOON,
LET ME LOOK AT YOU.
[ Sheriff Kyle ]
STAND BACK, FOLKS.
FLORENCE.
STAND BACK, PLEASE.
JUST AIN'T YOUR DAY.
MAYBE SHE JUST FAINTED.
I THINK
I MADE HER DIZZY.
DOWN SHE GO,
UP YOU GO!
IS SHE DEAD?
[ Man ]
AT LEAST SHE DIED HAPPY.
THEN I'LL TAKE HIM.
[ Crowd Gasping ]
JULIA, WHAT
ARE YOU SAYING?
HE'S AN OUTLAW.
I ASSUMED THAT'S WHY
YOU WERE HANGING HIM.
ARE YOU DRUNK?
SHERIFF KYLE,
YOU KNOW I DON'T DRINK.
'COURSE
SHE DON'T DRINK!
YOU WANT HIM?
ACCORDING TO THE LAW
I CAN CLAIM HIM, RIGHT?
I ASKED YOU
OUT 10 TIMES.
WHAT DO I GET?
A FLAP OF YOUR
UMBRELLA.
SHIT!
ALL RIGHT.
OK, JULIA.
MR. MOON,
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
WELL, I AIN'T
NO SIDE OF BEEF
TO BE AUCTIONED OFF,
BUT...WHAT THE HELL.
FINE BY ME.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
WELL, I THINK
I'LL SKIP
THE WEDDING.
I AIN'T TAKIN'
FRANK TOKIN'S
BUSINESS TONIGHT.
[ Gunfire ]
SOMEBODY'S TAKING
HIS BUSINESS,
OR WE AIN'T
GOT NO BUSINESS.
???? [ "Wedding March" ]
???? [ Ranchera ]
WONDERFUL!
AHA!
NOW, MR. MOON,
NO DRINKING.
NO GAMBLING.
NO WIFE-BEATING.
NO ALLEY-CATTING,
WHATNOT, AND WHAT HAVE YOU.
YOU'VE GOT
TO MINDHER.
IF YOU TRY RUNNING,
THERE WILL BE $500
ON YOUR HEAD.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
MUCH OBLIGED
TO YOU.
MUCH OBLIGED.
SHALL I TAKE
THE REINS, DEAR?
ADIOS!
i¡¡BIENVENIDOS!
SEE? I TOLD YOU
HE HAD A PLAN.
YOU'LL DANCE IN THE AIR,
YOU SON-OF-A-BITCH...
FOR STEALIN' MY GIRL!
MISS, AH...
IN CASE YOU
WANT TO KNOW
WHO YOU'RE
DEALING WITH...
I USED TO RIDE
WITH QUANTRELL'S
RAIDERS.
YOU ALWAYS
THIS QUIET?
WHEN I HAVE SOMETHING
TO SAY, YOU'LL HEAR IT.
WELL LOOK, I CAN
GET OFF RIGHT HERE
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED.
'COURSE A GOOD HUSBAND'S
HARD TO FIND.
YOU WEREN'T
YOU WERE STANDIN'
IN FRONT OF THE WHOLE TOWN
WITH A ROPE
AROUND YOUR NECK.
YEAH.
YOU SURE ARE
A SMART WOMAN.
I LIKE
SMART WOMEN.
I'M SURE YOU DO.
WHO'S THAT?
ONE OF THE REASONS
WE GOT MARRIED.
HEY, ROVER.
THAT'S GROVER.
GROVER.
[ Rooster Crows ]
THIS IS
WHERE I LIVE.
WELL, JULIA,
IT AIN'T MUCH,
BUT IT'S
A START.
WELL, I GUESS I DON'T
GET TO CARRY YOU
ACROSS THE THRESHOLD.
WIPE YOUR FEET,
PLEASE.
ALWAYS DO.
WELL THEN,
IT, UH...
LOOKS LIKE
AN OPERA HOUSE.
PLEASE TAKE
YOUR CLOTHES OFF,
MR. MOON.
[ Laughing ]
DON'T SIT THERE.
HERE.
PUT THESE ON.
THESE IS, UH...
THESE ARE
WORK CLOTHES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL, I JUST
GOT MARRIED.
DON'T COUNT
ON THAT TOO MUCH.
THIS IS
A GOLD MINE?
IN TEXAS?
IT'S GOING TO BE.
LOOKS LIKE MICE
BEEN INTO IT.
FIRST YOU'LL
BEGIN CREVASSING,
THEN CROSSCUT
USING THE SINGULAR
JACKING METHOD.
I AIN'T, UH,
FAMILIAR WITH
THAT PARTICULAR METHOD.
YOU PRY AWAY
ANY LOOSE ROCKS.
ARE YOU WATCHING?
HUH?
THEN YOU
INSERT THE DRILL
LIKE THIS.
THEN YOU USE
THE SLEDGEHAMMER.
SIMPLE.
YEAH.
WHERE'S THE GLOVES?
MY HANDS
BLISTERS EASY.
BETTER BLISTERS
THAN NECK BURNS.
UH...
MR. MOON--
PRETEND WE'RE FRIENDS
AND CALL ME HENRY.
THE RAILROAD
IS BREATHING
DOWN MY NECK,
SO LET'S NOT
WASTE ANY MORE TIME.
WELL,
I'LL DO
ALL I CAN DO,
BUT THAT'S ALL
I CAN DO.
I'LL BE OUTSIDE
RUNNING AURIFEROUS TESTS.
WHY DON'T YOU
RUN ONE ON YOUR SKULL
WHILE YOU'RE AT IT?
SUPPER'S READY.
I DON'T BELIEVE
IN WASTING TIME
AT THE TABLE.
HOW DID YOU COME
INTO THIS PLACE?
IT WAS MY FATHER'S.
DID HE BELIEVE
IN THIS GOLD MINE?
HE BELIEVED,
BUT NOT ENOUGH.
SOUNDS LIKE
HE WAS THE BRAINS
IN THE FAMILY.
BOILED CHICKEN?
BOILED IS BETTER
FOR YOU.
[ Sniffs ]
HOW'S ABOUT
A LITTLE DESSERT?
SAID, UH...
HOW'S ABOUT
A LITTLE DESSERT?
I HEARD YOU
THE FIRST TIME.
YOU DIDN'T ANSWER ME
UM...
CAN I ASK YOU
A PERSONAL QUESTION?
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
THAT YOU HAD A MAN?
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND
WORKING IN CONFINED SPACES
BECAUSE TOMORROW
WE START TUNNELING.
GODDAMN! I SHOULD
HAVE KNOWN.
YOU CAN ALWAYS
TELL A VIRGIN
ON ACCOUNT OF THE
WHITES OF THE EYES
AIN'T CLEAR.
HA HA HA!
SEE, I GOT THIS THEORY
ON VIRGINS--
THAT THEY ALWAYS LOOK
PEAKED AND GROUCHY
ON ACCOUNT OF THEY'RE
GOING AGAINST NATURE.
I DON'T WANT TO GET
CALLUSES PATTING MYSELF
ON THE BACK,
BUT IN MY TIME,
I HAVE PUT A GAL OR TWO
IN TUNE WITH NATURE.
I'M SURE NATURE
IS VERY GRATEFUL.
OH, LISTEN.
DON'T, UH,
LET STARTING LATE
BOTHER YOU NONE.
SOME OF THEM
LATE BLOOMERS IS, UH...
[ Whistles ]
HEE HEE HA HEE!
I'LL BE OUTSIDE
IN THE BARN
IF YOU FEEL LIKE
GETTING ACQUAINTED,
OR, UH, TALKING
ABOUT TUNNELING.
[ Door Closes ]
AND REMEMBER,
NATUREIS
THE GREAT PROVIDER.
HA HA HA HA!
[ Crowing ]
[ Grunting ]
OH, GODDAMN.
WELL, GOOD MORNING,
SPOT.
GET YOU SOME BACON?
GOOD MORNING, MISS!
WHAT'S FOR BREAKFAST?
[ Clucking ]
CONSERVE YOUR ENERGY.
THERE'S A LOT
OF WORK TO DO.
DON'T YOU WORRY
ABOUT ME.
I KNOW HOW
TO PACE MYSELF.
IF I WANT TO...
I CAN DO THIS
ALL DAY LONG.
I'M TALKING ABOUT...
WHERE ARE YOU
SUPPOSED TO SET?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
[ Panting ]
WELL...
I WANT TO...
TAKE A LITTLE
SPANISH PAUSE.
THAT'S ONE
OF THE KEYS
TO PACIN'
YOURSELF.
YOU JUST GO ON
TRIMMIN' YOUR
WICKS.
I CAN DO THIS
ALL DAY LONG.
I'M TALKING ABOUT
ALLDAY LONG!
ALL DAY LONG!
HA HA HA HA!
HEY, LADY!
NO CABEZA, NO TRABAJO.
UNDERSTAND?
SHE SURE IS FULL OF PISS
AND VINEGAR TODAY, AIN'T SHE?
AN AWFUL LOT OF LITERATURE
ON PHILADELPHIA.
WHAT'S THE FASCINATION
WITH THE CITY OF MOTHERLY LOVE?
BROTHERLY.
I'M MOVING THERE.
TO PHILADELPHIA?
JUST AS SOON
AS I STRIKE GOLD.
I LIKE IT DOWN THERE
IN MEXICO.
THE PACE SUITS ME BETTER--
SLOW DAYS AND FAST NIGHTS.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Knock On Door ]
WHAT A PLEASANT
SURPRISE.
WE SAW THE LIGHTS
AND FELT WE WOULDN'T
BE INTRUDING.
OH, LORETTE, YOU'RE
NEVER INTRUDING.
UH, Y'ALL REMEMBER
MY HUSBAND HENRY.
WELCOME
TO OUR HUMBLE ABODE.
WE BROUGHT ALONG
A LITTLE WEDDING
SOMETHING.
OH, YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE.
HOW PRETTY.
WE WAS JUST SAYING
HOW MUCH WE NEEDED
A FIGURINE.
I'LL GET US
SOME TEA.
SHALL I HELP?
WE'LL HELP.
DON'T BE LONG,
NOW.
[ Lorette ]
WE FELT YOU'D BE NEEDING
SOMEONE
TO TALK TO,
ESPECIALLY NOW.
LOOK, HONEY, WHAT
LORETTE'S TRYING TO SAY
IS THAT WE ALL HAVE
SO MUCH IN COMMON THESE DAYS.
WE DO?
WE'RE ALL
ORDINANCE BRIDES.
OH.
SINCE YOU'VE NEVER
BEEN MARRIED BEFORE,
WE ALL THOUGHT WE SHOULD
HAVE A LITTLE CHAT.
DO YOU PREFER ORANGE PEKOE
OR LAPSANG OOLONG?
YOU SEE, A HUSBAND
HAS CERTAIN RIGHTS.
AND A WIFE HAS
CERTAIN DUTIES.
AND THAT'S WHERE
THE TROUBLE STARTS.
SPEAK
FOR YOURSELF,
LORETTE.
HA HA HA!
[ Laughter Continues ]
YOU KNOW,
I RODE WITH QUANTRELL--
FINEST REVOLVER GANG
IN HISTORY
TILL HE DIED.
QUANTRELL DIED?
LAST YEAR.
MMM.
THAT SHORTY...
HE DON'T EVEN ASK.
HE JUST GOES
RIGHT TO IT.
THOSE OUTLAWS
JUST DON'T KNOW
HOW TO TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER.
WHITEY IS SO FUNNY.
WHY, LAST NIGHT,
HE GOT ALL PAINTED UP
LIKE AN INDIAN,
AND DID HE GO
ON THE WARPATH!
WOO WOO WOO!
[ Fly Buzzing ]
[ Swat ]
SAY, WANT TO HAVE YOURSELF
A REALLY WILD TIME?
WHY DON'T YOU DRESS UP
LIKE AN INDIAN?
HA! WELL, THAT SOUNDS
LIKE IT OUGHT TO BE
JULIA'S CUP OF TEA.
HA HA HA!
I GUESS I'LL,
UH, GO ON OUT
AND SEE HOW
THE SQUAWS ARE DOING.
I SUPPOSE WHAT WE'RE
TRYING TO SAY, JULIA,
IS IT'S NOT AS MUCH
OF A CHORE
AS YOU MAY HAVE HEARD.
UH-HUH.
BUT IF IT SHOULD
BECOME ONE,
I HAVE FOUND
THAT THE BEST
THING TO DO
IS JUST THINK ABOUT
CANNING APRICOTS.
APRICOTS?
WELL, FOR SOME REASON,
APRICOTS JUST SEEM
TO WORK BEST.
[ Teakettle Whistling ]
HOW WE DOIN', LADIES?
BYE!
THANK YOU
FOR THE LOVELY GIFT.
[ Henry ]
LET'S DO IT AGAIN
REAL SOON.
NICE FOLKS.
THEY SEEM CONTENT.
WELL...
YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY SAY--
LADY LOVE AN OUTLAW
LIKE A LITTLE BOY
LOVE A STRAY DOG.
WE STILL HAVEN'T
CLEANED UP THAT TABLE.
YOU KNOW,
I WAS THINKING ABOUT
THEM CHAIRS OF YOURS.
PICKING THEM UP,
SETTING THEM DOWN
THROUGH THE AIR.
WHY, IT'S POETRY.
I THINK I'M GETTING
A HEADACHE.
PRETTY SOON--
ALL OVER AMERICA,
PEOPLE'S GOING TO BE
PICKING UP CHAIRS
AND SETTING
THEM DOWN.
IT'S GOING TO BE
ALL YOUR DOING.
JULIA...
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE TRY CANNING
SOME OF THEM
APRICOTS?
[ Door Slams Shut ]
"IT WOULD BE LIKE A MAN
HAULING WITH ONE OX
"““AND LOOKING
FOR TWO,
"HOPING FOR THE HELP
OF THE LORD.
"WHY NOT GET RID
OF ALL THE OXEN
AND COUNT ON THE
MAKER ALL THE WAY?"
VERY GOOD.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO HEARING IT
ON SUNDAY.
THANK YOU.
[ Henry ]
MORNING, LADIES.
I SURE DID ENJOY
THEM CANNED APRICOTS LAST NIGHT.
[ Julia ]
YAH!
JULIA!
[ Braying ]
WHAT IN THE HELL WAS
THAT SUPPOSED TO BE?
A JOKE.
NO. YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
A JOKE IS WHEN YOU
MAKE SOMEBODY LAUGH.
HA HA HA!
[ Sneezes ]
MISS TATE,
PLEASE STEP
INTO THE OFFICE.
IT'S, UH,
MRS. MOON.
EXCUSE ME.
MISS TATE--
WHY, YOU--
HENRY.
I BELIEVE THIS IS BETWEEN
MR. POLTY AND MYSELF.
HEY, MOON!
IT LOOKS LIKE
THE HONEYMOON IS OVER!
HA HA HA!
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
MOON?
YOU'RE LOOKING LIKE
A DOG WITHOUT A BONE.
HA HA HA!
HEY, HECTOR.
YEAH?
WHY DON'T YOU
GO DOWN
TO THE MEXICAN
SIDE OF TOWN
AND SEE WHAT THE BEANS
IS JUMPING ON.
BEANS?
BEANS.
[ Neighs ]
YOU KNOW...POLTY'S JUST
ANOTHER WORD FOR CHICKEN.
GOOD ONE, TOWFIELD.
WHO THOUGHT IT UP
FOR YOU?
COME ON!
LET'S GO CHEW THE FAT.
WHAT FOR?
BECAUSE
I'M IN A GOOD MOOD.
WELL...THEN, UH,
HOW'S ABOUT
A LITTLE SNORT?
???? [ Honky-Tonk ]
HEY, PEACHY.
BOTTLE OF MASH
AND TWO GLASSES,
NORVELL.
NOT FOR HIM.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
NOT FOR ME?
SHERIFF'S ORDERS.
THE SHERIFF
DIDN'T TELL ME.
YOU DON'T TELL HIM
NOTHING,
SO HE DON'T
TELL YOU NOTHING.
THEM'S THE BREAKS.
AH!
YOU KNOW, I OWE YOU
A SPECIAL THANKS.
WHAT FOR?
HELL! IF YOU HADN'T
JERKED ME BACK
ACROSS THE BORDER
TO MY JUST DESERTS,
SO TO SPEAK,
WHY, I'D NEVER
HAVE BEEN MARRIED
TO JULIA.
THINKING ON IT
THAT WAY, WHY...
YOU SORT OF...
INTRODUCED US.
YEAH, TOWFIELD...
THINGS IS GOOD.
YOU HEARD ABOUT
THEM MATCHES
MADE IN HEAVEN,
DIDN'T YOU?
WELL, I'M IN ONE
OF THEM.
GODDAMN IT, MOON!
YOU STOLE MY GIRL!
TAKE IT EASY,
TOWFIELD.
YOU'RE WRINKLING
MY GOOD-LUCK
BANDANNA.
HOW'S THIS--
YOU GIVE ME
THE BOTTLE,
AND I'LL, UH,
I'LL TELL YOU
THE TRUTH.
YOU MEAN YOU WAS
JUST JAPIN' ME?
[ Sighs ]
SHE PUTS CHAIRS
UP ON THE WALL
SO'S PEOPLE
CAN'T SIT ON THEM.
WHAT?
I CAN'T GO INTO IT,
TOWFIELD.
IT'S OVER YOUR HEAD.
BUT IT'S BAD, HUH?
LIKE EGGS
ROLLED IN SAND.
TSK, TSK, TSK.
DUCK OUT BACK
FOR A SNORT.
[ Man ]
THE TROUBLE
WITH ANDREW JOHNSON
IS HE'S A DAMN MUGWUMP.
OH, DON'T MENTION THAT
SON-OF-A-BITCH'S NAME.
[ Horse Urinating ]
UGH!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Neighs ]
LISTEN,AMIGO.
I DON'T EVER WANT YOU
TO CALL ME A BEAN AGAIN.
[ Glass Shattering ]
[ Blows Landing ]
WHAT THE HELL
WAS THAT?
THIS IS AS DIFFICULT FOR ME
AS IT IS FOR YOU, JULIA.
HA!
YOU KNOW, A YEAR AGO
LAST CHRISTMAS EVE,
I HAD TO MOVE
150 COMANCHE SOULS
OFF THEIR SACRED
BURIAL GROUND.
I KNOW EXACTLY
HOW THEY FELT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
HONEY?
YOU LOOK WHITER
THAN AN ALBINO.
YOU BEEN BOTHERING
MY WIFE?
WE HAVE 30 DAYS
TO VACATE.
[ Gunfire ]
[ Yelling, Shouting ]
[ Henry ]
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THIS DOESN'T
CONCERN YOU.
IF IT CONCERNS HER,
IT CONCERNS ME.
THE RAILROAD'S
TAKING OVER MY LAND
UNDER
EMINENT DOMAIN.
[ Woman ]
CHESTER, COME ON!
EMINENT DOMAIN.
AIN'T THAT WHERE SOMEBODY BRIBES
THE STATE LEGISLATURE
TO TAKE AWAY
SOME POOR FOLKS' LAND?
I WON'T DIGNIFY THAT
WITH AN ANSWER.
I AIN'T ASKIN'
FOR NO DIGNIFICATION.
BUT I DO FIND IT
INTERESTING
THAT YOU, UH,
PREFER DOING BUSINESS
WITH THE LADY
OF THE HOUSE.
COME ON, MOON.
I'M SORRY, JULIA,
BUT UNLESS I AM
ADVISED OTHERWISE,
I'LL BE OUT TO SURVEY.
YOU KNOW...
POLTY'S JUST ANOTHER WAY
OF SAYING CHICKEN.
????  [ Julia Singing,
Indistinct ]
?? THEY WORSHIP
GOLD AND DROSS ??
?? THEY MAY BE OLD MAIDS ??
?? TILL THEY DIE ??
?? AND WILL NEVER
FEEL THEIR LOSS ??
?? MOTHER SAYS
I MUSTN'T ??
?? OH, GEORGE,
PLEASE, GEORGE ??
?? NOT JUST YET ??
OH, YES.
?? OH, MOTHER SAYS
I MUSTN'T ??
?? MOTHER SAYS I MUSTN'T ???
?
[ Muttering, Indistinct ]
OH, YES.
OH, OH.
I LOVE YOU!
[ Sneezes ]
WHO'S THERE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OH, JULIA!
I WAS JUST OUT HERE
SURVEYING.
YOU LIAR! YOU WERE
SPYING ON ME!
ME? I NEVER WOULD
DO SUCH A THING.
HELP!
JULIA, I SWEAR
ON MY HONOR
I DIDN'T SEE A THING!
IT'S NOT WHAT YOU THINK!
YOU OLD--
WHAT'S GOING ON
HERE?
NOTHING.
YOU BOTHERING
MY WIFE AGAIN?
I WAS OUT SURVEYING.
THERE'S
MY EQUIPMENT--
MY TRIPOD, MY MAPS,
ET CETERA.
I CAUGHT YOU,
DIDN'T I?
I SWEAR, NO.
I WASN'T DOING
ANYTHING.
THEN APOLOGIZE.
I APOLOGIZE.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW EMINENT DOMAIN
YOUR ASS OUT OF HERE.
HA HA HA!
WOO, NASTY.
OOH!
OH!
HA HA HA!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
NOTHING.
WHY'D YOU STOP
LAUGHING?
I DON'T KNOW.
GET TO WORK.
I'D RATHER LAUGH.
THAT'S ALL YOU
LIKE TO DO.
NO, THAT AIN'T ALL
I LIKE TO DO.
UH-UH, MOON.
UH-HUH.
UH-UH.
UH-HUH. UH-HUH.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
HA HA HA!
OOH! NASTY!
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
DAMN.
A NORTHER.
IT'S A NORTHER.
YEAH.
DID YOU GET STUNG?
YES.
DID YOU?
WHERE?
JULIA...
[ Henry's Voice Echoing ]
AN OUTLAW DOESN'T KNOW HOW
TO TAKE NO FOR AN ANSWER.
[ Thunderclap ]
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING DOWN THERE?
HUH?
WHAT AM I DOING?
OH, I GUESS
I WAS DREAMING
ABOUT A TUNNEL
OR SOMETHING.
GET UP!
YOU GOT ME DRUNK.
I DON'T REMEMBER
A THING!
I DIDN'T GET YOU DRUNK!
AAH! I WILL NOT HAVE
THAT KIND OF TALK
IN MY HOUSE!
HEY!
YOU TRICKED ME!
[ Panting ]
I DIDN'T TRICK YOU.
YOU GET YOUR CLOTHES
AND GET OUT!
THERE'S WORK TO DO!
OH.
I GET IT.
YOU'RE SO AFRAID THAT YOU'RE
GOING TO LIKETHAT...
THAT YOU'RE GOING TO
FORGET ABOUT THE GOLD
AND PHILADELPHIA!
YOU GET
YOUR CLOTHES,
AND YOU GET
OUT OF HERE!
SON-OF-A-BITCH!
I WAS RIGHT
ALL THESE YEARS!
THERE AIN'T A LADY
THAT KNOWS HOW TO
APPRECIATE A MAN.
NO GODDAMN...
UNNATURAL QUESTIONS!
"HOW DID IT FEEL?"
DAMN IT!
I FEEL SORRY
FOR THE POOR
SON-OF-A-BITCH THAT,
SON-OF-A-BITCH THAT
WINDS UP WITH YOU!
NICE BEING
MARRIED TO YOU!
[ Thunder Continues ]
UGH!
UH! OH!
YOU HAVEN'T GOT
A PLUGGED NICKEL!
YOU HAVEN'T
EVEN GOT A GUN!
YEAH!
UH! YOU WON'T GET
20 MILES
BEFORE A POSSE WILL
COME AND GET YOU
AND STRING YOU UP!
THE ONLY REASON
WHY I SLEPT WITH YOU
WAS SO YOU'D
KEEP ON WORKING!
I HOPE
THEY HANG YOU!
YOU...
OH!
[ Clucking ]
NOT THE CURTAIN!
YOU WOULDN'T DARE!
WELL...
I HADN'T THOUGHT OF IT,
BUT NOW
THAT YOU MENTION IT,
UP IN SAN FRANCISCO,
I SEEN SOME CHINESE
THAT DONE IT THIS WAY.
THE CHINESE
IS AN OLD CIVILIZATION.
THEY UNDERSTAND THINGS
ABOUT PLEASURE THAT,
I'VE NEVER
EVEN THOUGHT OF.
ONE THING FOR SURE...
WE AIN'T HAD
A BORING MARRIAGE.
???? [ Men Singing,
Indistinct ]
[ Man ]
DEPUTY, HOW CAN YOU
DO A THING LIKE THIS?
BUT 15 DAYS?
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
TELL IT
TO THE RAILROAD.
WE'VE BEEN HERE
SINCE '43.
WELL,
THEM'S THE BREAKS.
[ Hector ]
COME ON!
[ Spits ]
DAMN BLACK GOO!
GIDDY-UP!
HYAH! HYAH!
HUH!
WELL...
I WAS JUST GOING
INTO TOWN TO...
BUY AN ANVIL.
[ Knocking ]
JULIA?
NOW, GENTLEMEN,
LET'S NOT HAVE NO
MISUNDERSTANDINGS.
UH, ME
AND THE LITTLE WOMAN
HAVEN'T BEEN
GETTING ALONG OF LATE.
DON'T GO IN THERE! OH!
JULIA?
[ Julia ]
WHERE'S THE DOCTOR?
WHAT'S THE MATTER, DEAR?
DOCTOR...
OH, YEAH.
UH, I NEVER DID
GET OVER THERE.
THIS PEA BRAIN
GRABBED ME
AND STUCK ME
IN AN ANIMAL WAGON.
IT WOULD HAVE
BROKE YOUR HEART
TO SEE IT, HONEY.
YOU NEVER
TOLD ME ABOUT
NO DOCTOR.
YOU NEVER ASKED ME
ABOUT NO DOCTOR.
IS SOMETHING WRONG,
JULIA?
FEMALE TROUBLE.
OH...
THE VAPORS.
[ Henry ]
I BETTER PUT YOU
TO BED, DARLING.
I JUST GOT
OUT OF BED, DARLING.
WHAT THE HELL
DID YOU PICK HIM UP
FOR, TOWFIELD?
HE WAS DRESSED UP
LIKE A MEXICAN.
YOU CAN'T ARREST
A MAN FOR THAT.
I TOLD HIM.
WELL...
LET'S LEAVE THESE TWO
LOVEBIRDS ALONE.
JULIA.
I TOLD HIM.
I TOLD YOU,
BUT, NO, YOU WOULD--
[ Hoofbeats Departing ]
[ Door Closes ]
YOU MISSED ME,
DIDN'T YOU?
I DID NOT.
YEAH. I CAN SEE IT.
THEM EYES AIN'T
ANGRY.
THEY'RE RELIEVED,
AND THEY AIN'T
BLOODSHOT NO MORE.
I WANTED YOU BACK
FOR ONE REASON--
TO WORK THE MINE.
NAW.
YOU MISSED
THE OLD MAN
IN THE MOON.
HA HA HA!
HELL, I GOT
MY FAULTS.
I ADMIT IT, BUT...
AW, HELL, I GOT
MY WAYS, TOO.
YEAH, I...
I MISSED YOU
A LITTLE BIT, TOO.
I DID.
WHEN I WAS HEADING
FOR THE BORDER,
I COULDN'T STOP
BUT THINKING
NOBODY'S EVER SAVED
MY LIFE BEFORE.
AND I JUST COULDN'T
LEAVE YOU
IN YOUR TIME
OF NEED
OF ME.
[ Laughing ]
IT'S BEEN
QUITE A DAY.
I'M A BIT
TUCKERED OUT.
I THINK I'LL TAKE
A POCA SIESTA.
OH, YOU DON'T HAVE
TO SLEEP IN THE BARN.
YOU CAN SLEEP
ON THE COUCH.
SAY WHEN.
WHEN.
[ Bats Screeching ]
BATS.
[ Groaning ]
[ Rumbling ]
[ Boards Creaking ]
[ Coughing ]
THAT'S IT FOR ME.
I'M TOO YOUNG
TO DIE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND
ABOUT DREAMS.
I UNDERSTAND ABOUT
WAKING UP, TOO.
DIDN'T I WANT
TO RIDE
WITH THE YOUNGER
GANG,
AND THEY WOULDN'T
HAVE ME?
CLAIMED I WASN'T
CUT OUT TO BE
A YOUNGER.
MY FEELINGS
WAS HURT,
BUT I ACCEPTED IT.
YOU KNOW,
FOR AN OUTLAW,
YOU'VE BEEN
A PRETTY GOOD FRIEND.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
GOLD!
GOOD LORD ALMIGHTY,
I'VE FOUND GOLD!
GOLD!
[ Creaking ]
WATCH OUT.
DON'T KNOCK
INTO NONE OF THESE BEAMS.
I BEEN HERE.
I KNOW IT'S AROUND
HERE SOMEWHERES.
I CAN FEEL IT!
I DON'T SEE NOTHING.
IT'S HERE.
BELIEVE ME.
WHERE?
[ Creaking ]
GODDAMN!
HA HA HA!
GOLD.
LOOK AT THAT! GOLD!
OH!
GOLD! GODDAMN,
IT'S ALL OVER
EVERYTHING.
I TOLD YOU.
DIDN'T I TELL YOU?
OH, HONEY, KISS ME.
I'M RICH.
GODDAMN, I AM RICH.
I KNEW IT.
YOU WAIT LONG ENOUGH,
AND PRETTY SOON,
DOWN IT'S GOING TO COME
RIGHT ON YOU.
LIKE A WALL FULL
OF MEXICAN TEETH.
YOU KNOW,
I'M GOING TO
GET MY INITIALS
PUT ON MY SADDLE,
IN GOLD.
THEY LIKE IT THAT
WAY IN MEXICO.
ALLS WE GOT
TO DO NOW IS...
DEPOSIT THIS FIRST BUNCH
IN THE BANK AND THEN--
"WE"?
WHAT DO YOU
MEAN, "WE"?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
WELL, JUST THAT,
IN ALL FAIRNESS,
I PLAYED A PART
IN STRIKING THE GOLD.
YOU NEVER BELIEVED
IT EXISTED.
BUT YOU'D HAVE
NEVER STRUCK IT
IF IT WASN'T FOR ME.
CORRECTO?
SO?
SO...HA HA!
WHERE'S MY--
WHERE'S MY SHARE
IN THE STAKE? HA HA!
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'LL GIVE YOU 10%.
HA HA HA!
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU SEE, SHARING IS
GIVINGTO EACH OTHER.
50%.
WE'LL TALK
ABOUT IT LATER.
OH, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
UH, 25%,
AND WE CAN...
STOP THIS CONVERSATION
RIGHT HERE.
MUST BE FUNNY
ACTUALLY DEPOSITING
SOMETHING
IN A BANK,
HUH, MOON?
YEAH!
IT'S A WHOLE NEW
EXPERIENCE FOR ME.
THAT'S IT.
SURE ARE SORRY
TO HAVE YOU
AND MIRIAM
LEAVING US.
THANK YOU,
MRS. HABER,
BUT WITH THE RAILROAD
AND THIS BLACK STUFF
SPRINGING UP EVERYWHERES,
A MAN JUST CAN'T GROW
A DECENT EAR OF CORN.
OHHH!
AWFUL HEAVY
FOR FIGURINES.
IT'S MY WHOLE
COLLECTION.
WELL, I'LL GUARD IT
WITH MY LIFE.
AW, YOU CAN DO BETTER
THAN THAT, WHITEY.
[ Laughing ]
HENRY LLOYD MOON
AT THE BANK.
HMM.
WANT ONE OF THESE?
SURE.
[ Indistinct ]
GODDAMN IT.
I LIKE BEING RICH.
MAYBE NOW YOU CAN
BUY YOUR WAY
INTO THE YOUNGER GANG.
DOLL,
I THINK I'LL BUY ME
A LITTLE CANTINA
SOUTH OF THE BORDER.
TIME TO START LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
GODDAMN IT, HONEY,
I'M GOING TO BE
APATRON.
TEQUILA...
CARDS...
SENORITAS...
HEY.
WAIT TILL
THE DOMINGI SISTERS
GET A LOAD OF ME!
HA HA HA!
"BUENAS NOCHES,
SENOR MOON.
COMO ESTA USTED,
SENOR MOON?"
"MUY BIEN, GRACIAS.
Y USTED?"
HA HA HA!
WOO!
DON'T DO THAT.
YOU'RE ACTING FOOLISH.
[ Owl Hooting ]
MAYBE YOU OUGHT
TO TRY IT.
YOU WANT TO SEE
SOMETHING FOOLISH?
THAT'S FOOLISH.
50%?
YOU'RE GOING TO GIVE ME...
WE'RE PARTNERS,
AREN'T WE?
WELL, IF YOU'RE GOING TO
PUT IT THAT WAY.
YEAH.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO...
SAY THIS, HENRY...
BUT...
I THINK I GOT...
GREEDY AND SELFISH
LIVING ALONE
SO LONG.
WELL...
THAT'S HOW YOU GET.
ONCE YOU GET STARTED...
YOU DON'T HARDLY
EVER GET OUT OF IT.
FOR CALLING ME HENRY.
[ Bell Ringing ]
???? [ Fiddle ]
[ Shouting ]
i¡¡DIOS MIO!
FRIENDS OF YOURS?
USED TO BE.
WHAT ARE THEY
DOING HERE?
GOOD QUESTION.
[ Pounding On Door ]
[ Henry ]
WELL, HA HA!
SORRY TO KEEP
YOU ALL WAITING,
BUT, UH...
ME AND THE MISSIS
WAS JUST PLAYING
A LITTLE GAME
OF FISH.
THOUGHT WE'D STOP BY
AND BRING YOU
A LITTLE SHIVAREE,
MOON.
OH, DID YOU?
SINCE WE AIN'T BEEN
FORMALLYINVITED.
WELL, ME AND JULIA
WAS JUST SAYING
THE OTHER DAY
HOW WE WAS, UH,
GOING TO
HAVE YOU ALL OUT.
WELL, YOU DAMN SURE
GOT YOUR WISH,
DIDN'T YOU?
HA HA HA!
I DAMN SURE DID.
AIN'T YOU GOING TO
ASK US IN, HENRY?
WHY, SURE,
HONEY PIE.
MI CASA ES SU CASA.
DON'T YOU BOYS KNOW
HOW TO WIPE YOUR FEET?
[ Big Abe ]
HEY, HOG COOGAN!
WIPE YOUR FEET
OFF.
[ Stomping Feet ]
HOPE YOU LIKE TAFFY.
IT WAS MY IDEA.
THANK YOU.
THEY CALL ME
BIG ABE.
OLD HENRY STILL SNORE
IN HIS SLEEP?
???? [ Tapping Piano Keys ]
I WANT THEM
OUT OF HERE!
NOT AS MUCH AS I DO.
MOON!
YOU WANT THEM
TO FIND OUT
ABOUT THE DUST?
HA HA HA HA!
WELL!
ANYBODY HUNGRY?
HUNGRY? SHIT, I COULD
EAT A FROZEN DOG.
HA HA HA!
WELL, WE'LL GO ON
OUT TO THE KITCHEN,
AND SEE
IF WE GOT ONE
ALREADY FROZE.
HA HA HA!
[ Hog ]
I WOULDN'T EAT
NO FROZEN DOG.
HA HA HA!
???? [ Tapping On Piano ]
i¡¡ESTUFADO DEL DIABLO!
A FEAST FIT FOR A KING.
THAT'S HIS
SPECIALITY.
THEM FEMALE
BULLFEATHERS
MAKE IT TASTY.
DID YOU KNOW
THAT OLD HENRY USED TO
COOK FOR THE RAIDERS?
HE COOKED FOR
QUANTRELL'S RAIDERS?
NO. HE NEVER
TOLD ME THAT.
I BET THERE'S A LOT
OF THINGS HE NEVER
TOLD YOU.
[ Laughs, Spits ]
SHIT!
ABE!
GODDAMN, ABE.
JESUS CHRIST!
YOU'LL LOOSEN
MY MOLAR UP!
???? [ Fiddle ]
[ Laughing, Shouting ]
?? GRAB YOUR GIRL,
NOW PULL ON HER MANE ????
YAHOO!
JUST PLAY ALONG
A LITTLE WHILE LONGER.
WELL,
YOU GO ON AHEAD.
I DON'T WANT
TO SPOIL YOUR FUN.
WELL, I AIN'T HAVING
A GOOD TIME.
I SWEAR I AIN'T.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO THROW THEM
OFF THE TRACK.
THEY WOULDN'T KNOW
IT WAS ME
IF I WASN'T
ACTING WILD AND...
AW...
FORGET ABOUT ALL THIS.
GET IN THERE
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME.
[ Slaps Bottom ]
ACT FOOLISH!
WOO!
?? BEAUTIFUL DREAMER ??
?? AWAKEN TO ME ??
?? WAKEN TO ME ??
?? STARLIGHT AND DEWDROPS
ARE WAITIN' FOR THEE ??
[ Hog ]
?? THEE ??
AH, SHIT.
???? [ Continues ]
THIS AIN'T NO
REAL MARRIAGE.
COME ON.
MEET ME TONIGHT, HUH?
I'LL GIVE YOU
MY OLD COYOTE CALL.
?? BEAUTIFUL DREAMER ??
REMEMBER?
A-WOO--
NOT NOW.
?? TO ME ????
WOO HOO!
ANYBODY SEEN
MY GODDAMN MOLAR?
NOPE.
BUT IF I DO,
CAN I PUT IT
UNDER MY PILLOW
FOR THE TOOTH FAIRY?
HA HA HA!
TOOTH FAIRY!
YOU WON'T
GET NOTHING
FOR HIS MOLAR.
[ Julia ]
WELL, COME ON, BOYS.
LET'S HELP BIG ABE
FIND HIS GODDAMN MOLAR.
NO! WAIT!
I HAVE A BETTER IDEA.
MOON, LET'S YOU AND ME
GO BUY BIG ABE
A WHOLE DAMN SET
OF GOLD TEETH! HA HA!
[ Whispering ]
YOU'LL RUIN EVERYTHING
ACTING LIKE A GODDAMN FOOL.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
WHAT ANYBODY SAYS!
I'M A GENTLEMAN!
[ Blows Raspberry ]
AND I'M NOT
GOING TO THROW UP
IN THIS HERE HOUSE.
I'M GOING OUTSIDE
TO THROW UP
'CAUSE I--I RESPECT
YOUR HOUSE.
UM...
BIG ABE,
YOU CAN THROW UP
IN THIS HOUSE
ANY OLD TIME.
HA HA HA!
GODDAMN GOLD! GOLD!
THAT SON-OF-A-BITCH
IS KEEPING GOLD FROM US.
GOD ALMIGHTY.
SON-OF-A-BITCH.
[ Hoofbeats Departing ]
[ Footsteps ]
YOU ALMOST SPILLED
THE BEANS.
COME ON AND HELP ME
FIND BIG ABE'S MOLAR.
DIDN'T I TELL YOU
TO WATCH WHAT
YOU WAS DOING?
YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND OUTLAWS!
I UNDERSTOODYOU
WHEN YOU TOLD ME
TO ACT FOOLISH.
I DIDN'T TELL YOU
TO GET DRUNK
AND START SINGING
YOUR DAMN FOOL HEAD
OFF!
HOG LIKED MY SINGING.
THAT'S WHY
THEY CALL HIM HOG!
[ Door Slams Shut ]
[ Hermine ]
A-WOO!
[ Henry Howling ]
[ Coyotes Howling ]
AAH!
DAMN, HERMINE.
QUIT YOUR GODDAMN
COYOTE CALLING.
I'M HERE.
YOUR WIFE'S
ACTING TERRIBLE,
AIN'T SHE?
SHE JUST HAD
A LITTLE TOO MUCH
BUG-JUICE.
HA HA HA!
I FIGURE
YOU AIN'T HAD
MUCH OF ANYTHING
OF ANYTHING
IN A LONG TIME.
HOW'S COME
YOU AND THE BOYS
DECIDED TO
STOP BY TONIGHT?
I WANT TO
MAKE IT GOOD
FOR YOU, HENRY.
HONEY, YOU AIN'T HEARING
WHAT I'M ASKING.
WHAT WAS
THE QUESTION?
I DON'T WANT TO
HURT YOUR FEELINGS.
I APPRECIATE
THE COYOTE CALLING,
BUT I TOLD YOU
THINGS HAS CHANGED.
CRAWL IN, HENRY.
SEE WHAT I GOT.
HERMINE, YOU AIN'T
HEARING ME.
I SEEN WHAT YOU GOT.
IT WAS SWELL.
WE HAD SOME
TIMES TOGETHER
THAT I'LL
NEVER FORGET.
BUT, HERMINE,
NOW I'M TOOK.
HENRY.
AAH!
[ Coyote Howling ]
[ Julia ]
HOLD IT.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
UH...DON'T SHOOT.
VAMOOSE.
WELL...
IF I WAS MONKEYING AROUND,
WOULD I STILL HAVE
MY CLOTHES ON?
THEN WHY DID YOU
GO OUT THERE?
DON'T MAKE
NO DIFFERENCE.
NO MATTER WHAT I SAY,
YOU AIN'T GOING TO
BELIEVE ME.
GO AHEAD.
WELL, I WAS JUST
TRYING TO GET
INFORMATION
OFF OF HERMINE.
THAT WASN'T ALL
YOU WERE TRYING
TO GET OFF OF HER.
ALL I WANTED TO KNOW
WAS IF THEY
KNEW ANYTHING
ABOUT THE GOLD.
YOU CARE MORE
ABOUT THAT DAMN GOLD
THAN ABOUT ME.
THAT AIN'T TRUE.
I COULD HAVE DONE
WHAT YOU THINK,
BUT I DIDN'T.
I DON'T BELIEVE
YOU DIDN'T.
I WAS THERE STRICTLY
ON BUSINESS.
YOU WANT THAT WOMAN!
YOU TAKE HER,
BUT YOU FORGET
ALL ABOUT THE GOLD.
PEOPLE CAN'T AFFORD
BUSINESS PARTNERS
THAT CHEAT ON THEM.
WE MADE
AN AGREEMENT.
AND I'M BREAKING IT.
YOU CAN'T
DO THAT TO ME.
I JUST DID.
THAT TEARS IT.
GOING TO PUT THE OLD
DOUBLE "X" TO HENRY MOON, HUH?
WELL, WE'LL SEE.
YOU WANT YOUR GUN
BACK, MOON?
WHERE'S THE GODDAMN GOLD?
WHAT GOLD?
THAT GOLD THERE.
THAT'S REAL GOLD!
WHERE IS IT?
YOU AIN'T AS IGNORANT
AS YOU LOOK, ARE YOU?
COME ON IN.
HOW MUCH
WE GOT HERE?
ENOUGH. IN FACT,
I WAS JUST COMING LOOKING
FOR YOU BOYS.
SURE, YOU WAS.
WE'RE GOING TO HIT
THE LONGHORN BANK.
THERE AIN'T NOTHING
IN THAT CHICKEN-FEED BANK
BUT SUN-FILLED WINDOWS.
AND ALL THE LITTLE
LADY'S GOLD.
LET'S HIT HER
IN THE MORNING.
NOT YET.
GOT A PLAN?
I'M GOING TO
MAKE THAT WOMAN
SORRY SHE EVER SAID,
"I DO."
I TELL YOU,
HE'S HIDING
SOMETHING FROM US.
[ Coogan ]
I DON'T THINK SO.
I KNOW SO.
[ Hog ]
I WAS CERTAIN
HE HAD A PLAN.
ME, TOO, BUT I DON'T KNOW
IF WE'RE GOING TO BE IN IT.
LET'S KEEP A WATCH
ON THE SON-OF-A-BITCH.
[ Abe ]
COME ON, GANG!
YOU...
YOU BETTER TAKE
A REST BEFORE
YOUR ARM FALLS OFF.
YOU WANT SOME WATER?
ARE YOU ALWAYS
THIS QUIET?
I'VE GOT
NOTHING TO SAY.
[ Creaking ]
I KEEP MY WORD.
[ Explosion ]
[ Henry ]
JULIA!
[ Rocks Falling ]
HONEY!
MOON!
HONEY, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
GODDAMN!
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES. OH!
ALL RIGHT.
[ Creaking ]
CAN YOU STAND THERE?
YES.
O.K. ALL RIGHT.
[ Rumbling ]
[ Julia Screaming ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WELL, I'VE
BEEN BETTER.
[ Creaking ]
EASY. EASY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
NOTHING'S GOING TO
HAPPEN TO YOU.
HERE, HOLD THIS.
YOU STAY RIGHT HERE.
WHEN I GET BACK,
WE'LL TAKE US A LITTLE
SPANISH PAUSE.
[ Creaking ]
HENRY LLOYD?
[ Henry ]
WHAT?
NOTHING.
I'M SORRY ABOUT
LAST NIGHT.
I KNOW IT DOESN'T MATTER,
BUT IF WE'RE GOING TO DIE,
I--I WANT IT TO BE
AS PARTNERS.
50/50.
WE WAS A GOOD TEAM.
GOOD? SHIT.
WE WERE THE BEST.
HONEY PIE...
MOON, I'VE BEEN THINKING.
SINCE WE'RE GOING
TO GO ANYWAY,
WHY DON'T WE GO OUT
IN A BLAZE OF GLORY?
MOON, TIE ME UP.
JULIA...
WE'RE ALIVE.
I'VE BEEN
WATCHING YOU, HENRY.
FIGURED.
AIN'T YOU UP EARLY?
WE DON'T HIT THE BANK
TILL 10:00.
WELL, THERE'S BEEN
A LITTLE CHANGE
IN PLANS.
WELL, I GOT TO
TELL BIG ABE.
YOU GOT TO DO
WHAT YOU GOT TO DO.
I'LL NEVER
FORGET YOU, HERMINE.
YOU WAS
THE FIRST WOMAN
I DIDN'T HAVE TO
PAY FOR.
ADIOS.
[ Knocks On Door ]
YOU'RE A MITE EARLY,
COMPADRE.
I WANT TO MAKE
A WITHDRAWAL.
YOUR BETTER HALF
HAS TO DO THAT.
ORDINANCE HUSBANDS
AREN'T ALLOWED TO MAKE
WITHDRAWALS.
BESIDES, WE'RE CLOSED.
YOU'RE OPEN NOW.
OPEN IT UP.
OVER THERE
IN THE BIN.
HURRY UP,
WHITEY.
I NEVER FIGURED
YOU'D DO THIS TO JULIA.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO SAVE MY MARRIAGE,
WHITEY.
HYAH!
JULIA!
JULIA?
GROVER,
WHERE IS JULIA AT?
JULIA!
GODDAMN.
ROCKS.
GODDAMN,
HONEY PIE.
FREEZE, MOON!
MR. MOON,
YOU'RE STILL HERE.
WHERE'S JULIA?
I GUESS HE AIN'T
HEARD THE NEWS.
HA HA HA!
WHAT NEWS?
YOUR WIFE SOLD HER PROPERTY
TO THE RAILROAD.
GENTLEMEN, START
TAGGING THE FURNITURE.
WHEN?
DOES THAT
CONCERN YOU NOW?
WHERE IS SHE?
I BELIEVE ON HER WAY
TO PHILADELPHIA.
AND YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY
TO MEET SAINT PETER.
THAT'S RIGHT, MOON.
YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY
TO MEET SENOR PETER.
[ Gunfire ]
COME OUT, MOON.
WE KNOW YOU GOT IT!
I AIN'T GOT NOTHING!
WE DON'T
BELIEVE YOU!
HENRY, WHO THE HELL
IS THAT?
THE EX-MOON GANG.
i¡¡CHINGA LA LUNA!
IF THEY WANT A GUNFIGHT,
THEY PICKED THE WRONG
HOMBRES TO MESS WITH!
GODDAMN YOU!
WATCH IT, BIG ABE!
OK. 1, 2, 3!
WHEN DID SHE LEAVE?
WHY SHOULD I
TELL YOU?
ABOUT
A HALF-HOUR AGO.
NOW!
MOON.
SHOOT BACK.
YES, SIR, THIS IS
MIGHTY STRANGE
STUFF.
MURIEL DROPPED
A LANTERN
IN A PUDDLE OF IT
THE OTHER NIGHT,
AND THE WHOLE FARM
'BOUT NEAR WENT UP
IN FLAME!
BURNED HALF
THE HAIR OFF
OF MY HEAD.
STUNK FOR TWO WEEKS.
THE RAILROAD SAID
THEY'VE GOT
NO USE FOR IT,
SO I THOUGHT
I'D TAKE SAMPLES
BACK EAST
AND MAYBE SELL IT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
MISS JULIA?
OH, I'M SORRY,
MR. STANDARD.
I DIDN'T HEAR
WHAT YOU SAID.
[ Gunshot ]
HYAH!
AAH!
WHOA IN THERE!
WHOA! WHOA.
HOLD UP
IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
STAY CALM.
WHOA. WHOA.
ALL RIGHT.
STEP DOWN, JULIA.
WHOA.
COTTON, THAT SON-OF-
A-BITCH CAN SHOOT.
HE RODE WITH
QUANTRELL.
COME ON,
YOU'VE RUN FAR ENOUGH.
COME ON, NOW.
I'M LOSING MY PATIENCE.
YOU AIN'T
TAKING MY GOLD!
THEY DISCOVERED
GOLD!
NAH. THEY HAD
A LITTLE TOO MUCH
BUG-JUICE.
YOU DIDN'T EVEN
WRITE A NOTE
WHEN YOU LEFT.
WHAT WAS I
SUPPOSED TO WRITE?
"GOOD LUCK,
HENRY AND HERMINE"?
I WAS GOING TO
EXPLAIN EVERYTHING.
SEE, I--
[ Sheriff Kyle ]
MR. MOON.
ARE YOU ROBBING
THIS STAGE OR NOT?
BURN THE BREEZE,
KYLE,
OR I'LL
BLOW EVERYBODY
INTO FEATHERS.
WE DON'T DESERT OUR WOMEN
OUT HERE, MR. MOON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
SHERIFF.
YOU GO ON AHEAD.
HE'S JUST TRYING
TO IMPRESS ME.
[ Sheriff Kyle ]
ARE YOU SURE, JULIA?
OH. WELL...
YOU TWO OUGHT TO TRY
AND GET ALONG, THEN.
WE ALL HAD TO.
HYAH!
MY HEART FROZE
WHEN I CAME HOME
AND YOU WAS GONE,
HONEY.
LET ME HELP YOU UP.
OH!
THANK YOU, MOON.
I'M NOT SURE I'LL EVER
GET USED TO MEXICO.
WHY, SURE, YOU WILL,
HONEY PIE.
YOU GOT USED TO ME,
DIDN'T YOU?
ANYWAYS...
FIRST, LET'S GET USED
TO BEING RICH.