[Bugler playing]
[Bell clanging]
Yay! They're coming!
They're coming!
QUINCANNON: Sick call!
[Bugler playing]
DOC: Corpsman!
KIRBY: "A" troop.
Fores right. Yo!
OFFICER: Fores right. Yo!
KIRBY: Troop, halt!
OFFICER: Halt!
KIRBY:
Gentlemen, congratulations.
OFFICERS: Thank you, sir.
KIRBY: Indian scouts...
yuh-te.
SCOUTS: Yuh-te!
When you're dismissed...
you will walk your horses
for half an hour...
then water and picket them.
The sutler's store
will remain open until 12:00.
Let them have some beer.
TROOPS: We thank the colonel.
QUINCANNON: That's a fine idea.
KIRBY: Officers post. Gallop.
OFFICER: Prepare to dismount!
[Echo]
Dismount!
To the left!
[Horse whinnies]
[Bugler playing]
KIRBY: Good evening.
TROOPER: Good evening, sir.
KIRBY: Good evening, sir.
SHERIDAN:
Have a cup of your own coffee?
KIRBY: I've been thinking
of nothing else...
for the last two hours.
SHERIDAN: Tough, huh?
KIRBY: Tough, sir.
I haven't had
a cup of duty coffee with you...
since we rode
down the Shenandoah together.
Fifteen years ago, wasn't it?
KIRBY: Fifteen years,
two months...
seven days.
How did you fare on patrol?
Had a running fight
for 30-odd miles.
We captured Natchez,
their chief...
eight others before the Apaches
reached the Rio Grande...
and crossed into Mexico.
Pursuant to orders...
I halted on our side
of the river.
Men didn't like it very much.
Neither did you.
Neither do I,
but that's the policy...
and soldiers don't make policy.
They merely carry it out.
The State Department
could do something.
Yes. They'll write
a sharp note of protest...
if you care to read
sharp notes of protest.
I'll declaim them over
the graves of the troopers...
who were guarding
the water holes.
Three of them staked face down
on anthills.
You've got the dirtiest job
in the army.
No doubt of that.
I'm not complaining, sir.
I get paid for it.
SHERIDAN:
Maybe you should complain.
I'll listen.
This coffee isn't as good
as it used to be.
I'll make a note of that.
Maybe someday it'll get better
and stronger.
KIRBY: I'll drink to that, sir.
Stronger.
Too bad about your son.
I hadn't heard.
Oh, I'm sorry, Kirby.
I thought you knew.
He failed mathematics
at West Point...
and they've dropped him
from the military academy.
Indeed.
Oh, it's no disgrace
failing mathematics.
I missed it myself
by the skin of my teeth.
I haven't seen my son
in 15 years.
Yes, I know.
Kirby, this coffee's weak,
but it's all we have.
More?
If it's all we have.
[Bugler playing]
[Troopers singing]:
You're in the army now.
You're not behind a plow.
You'll never get rich
by digging a ditch.
You're in the army now.
SERGEANT: Hup left. Hut.
[Troopers singing]:
You're not behind a plow.
You son of a gun,
You're on the bum.
You're in the army now.
SERGEANT: Knock it off!
Knock it off!
SERGEANT: Left face!
Aye, you're a fine body of men.
Put your bags down.
This is your home,
so make yourselves comfortable.
Aye...
I bid you all welcome
to Fort Starke...
recruits that you are.
But in no time at all,
you'll be soldiers.
Sure.
Why, in less than six months...
with good behavior
and hard work...
you'll be wearing yellow stripes
on your britches.
Would you mind putting your cap
back on your head, son?
BOONE: No, not at all, doc.
[Men laughing]
Did any of youse
ever ride a horse?
TYREE: Yeah, some.
QUINCANNON:
Answer the roll call.
- Adams.
- Present.
- Baker.
- Yo!
- Boone.
- Yes, sir?
- Yeah?
QUINCANNON: Just say yo.
BOONE: Yo.
- Carroll.
- Yo!
- Dirks.
- Eaton.
- Yo!
- Franklin.
- Hackenschmidt.
- Yo!
- Ives.
- Murphy.
- Here!
- Perkins.
- Yo!
- Selby.
- Present.
- Tyree.
- Yo!
- Yorke.
- Present, sir.
QUINCANNON: All right.
Pick up your bags.
QUINCANNON: Left face!
KIRBY: As you were, sergeant.
I don't want you to be fooled
about what's coming up for you...
torture.
At least that.
The war department
promised me 180 men.
They sent me 18, all told.
You are the 18.
So each of you will have to do
the work of 10 men.
If you fail, I'll...
have you spread-eagled
on a wagon wheel.
If you desert,
you'll be found...
tracked down
and broken into bits.
That is all.
SERGEANT: Forward. Hey!
Hut, two, three, four.
QUINCANNON: Trooper Yorke, sir.
KIRBY:
I haven't seen you for 15 years.
JEFF: So I've been told, sir.
I have no clear memory.
You proved that
when you failed at West Point.
Yes, sir.
KIRBY: Where did you enlist?
At Highland Falls, sir.
Next day.
Lied about your age.
Recruit training?
Jefferson Barracks, sir.
KIRBY: Hmm.
On the official records,
you're my son.
But on this post,
you're just another trooper.
You heard me tell the recruits
what I need from them.
Twice that
I will expect from you.
At Chapultepec...
my father, your grandfather...
shot for cowardice the son
of a United States senator.
That was his duty.
I will do mine.
You've chosen my way of life.
I hope you have the guts
to endure it.
But put out of your mind...
any romantic ideas
that it's a way of glory.
It's a life of suffering
and of hardship...
an uncompromising devotion
to your oath and your duty.
JEFF: Have I the colonel's
permission to speak?
KIRBY: Within proper limits,
yes.
I didn't ask
to come to this regiment, sir...
but I wouldn't have it otherwise
now that I'm here.
May I also
put something straight?
Proceed.
I'm not in this post
to call you father.
I was ordered here
as Trooper Jefferson Yorke...
of the United States Cavalry.
That's all I wish to be, sir.
KIRBY:
Then we understand each other.
JEFF: We do, sir.
KIRBY: Sergeant Major?
The recruits are for field duty
as of now.
Dismissed.
QUINCANNON: Trooper Yorke.
KIRBY:
What are you waiting for?
Trooper Yorke expects his salute
to be returned.
Military regulations, sir.
[Quincannon laughs]
KIRBY: Quincannon.
TROOPERS:
Can't you go around faster?
Keep your heads down!
That's it!
Hey, hey!
Keep it coming now!
You got it made!
There we go!
Once again and faster!
SERGEANT:
Put it up another notch.
Give 'em a good jump.
See how easy it is?
When I was a young man
like yourselves...
I could jump nine feet tall...
with an Indian under each arm.
What tribe?
QUINCANNON:
Once again and faster!
Horsemen. Ha ha!
TROOPER: Yaah!
TYREE: Appears to me
they make a lot of fuss...
jumping a horse
over some sticks.
BOONE: Yo.
JEFF:
That's a six-foot jump, Travis.
QUINCANNON:
Give them their heads.
Now over!
There, you see?
That gives you an idea
what horsemanship is like...
in the United States Cavalry.
Now after that
comes the Roman teams.
That's easy.
It's the way the Romans
used to ride.
The ancient Romans.
Standing up.
BOONE: Yo.
QUINCANNON: Slim!
Upsy-daisy!
TYREE: Mister, what time do you
blow the horn around here...
for folks to eat?
QUINCANNON: Do you think you'd
like to try that before you eat?
TYREE: You mean ride
like them ancient Romans?
QUINCANNON: Yes.
BOONE: Yo!
TYREE: Let's go, Sandy!
Hyah! Hyah!
[Whip cracks]
Come on, Sandy!
Easy, now! Easy!
RECRUITS: Yay!
RECRUITS: Yay! Thatta boy!
Horsemen.
Oh, boy-o, horsemen.
TYREE: Nice team, Corporal.
BOONE:
That the general idea, doc?
QUINCANNON:
That's the general idea...
but before I'm through
with youse...
you'll be taking them jumps
backwards.
Is there another man...
PRESCOTT: The marshal
wants to make a routine check.
He thinks perhaps this man
might be among our new recruits.
MARSHAL: Got anybody name of
Tyree among your horse thieves?
QUINCANNON:
Horse thieves is it now?
MARSHAL: That's what I said.
QUINCANNON: They're all men
wearing the uniform...
of the United States Cavalry.
MARSHAL: Fella I'm lookng for
is from Texas...
wanted for questioning
about a killing.
QUINCANNON: Is there a man
from Texas among youse?
BOONE: Yes, sir.
I'm from Texas.
Name of Boone. Daniel Boone.
MARSHAL: Daniel Boone?
That name's kind of familiar,
ain't it, Mink?
Name's Tyree.
A $50 reward.
BOONE: Right tidy sum.
QUINCANNON: Tyree.
Nobody here by that name.
Sergeant, be taking the marshals
to sutlers.
Give them a wee drop of comfort.
MARSHAL:
Who's buying the liquor?
QUINCANNON:
The sergeant will pay for it.
Heh.
Horse thieves
we don't have here...
but horsemen
I'll make of youse yet.
BOONE: Yo.
QUINCANNON: Anyone else
want to try the jumps...
after the manner
of the ancient Romans?
JEFF: Yes, sir, I would.
TYREE: Get it done, Johnny Reb.
TYREE: Get up on 'em!
TROOPER: You'll get busted
for this, Quincannon.
TYREE: Get your hat.
You all right, boy?
JEFF: Yeah, I'm all right.
[Bugler playing]
QUINCANNON: Curry them well
and cool them off, men!
In six months, we'll have the
finest drill team in the world.
[Smack]
TROOPER: Come here, Jim.
Get in there.
SECOND TROOPER: Let them fight!
QUINCANNON: Cool it off there!
QUINCANNON: Break it up!
SERGEANT:
What are you guys doing?
Break it up!
QUINCANNON: Break it up!
Break it up, I tell you!
TROOPER: Let them fight.
QUINCANNON:
What started this fight?
JEFF: I refuse to answer, sir.
TYREE: Go ahead.
Tell him, reb.
This fella here spoke derogatory
about the boy's pappy.
BOONE: He also said
he was the teacher's pet...
of a chowderheaded
mick sergeant.
What's that mean, doc?
QUINCANNON: Did you say that?
HEINZE: Yes, I did.
You did, did you?
Yes, I did.
Did you mean it?
QUINCANNON:
We'll settle this tonight...
behind the picket line,
soldier-fashion.
Marquis of Queensberry rules.
QUINCANNON: Shouted face chow...
What was it he said?
BOONE:
Chowderheaded mick sergeant.
QUINCANNON:
Chowderheaded mick...
And you meant it?
HEINZE: Yes, I did.
QUINCANNON:
Nine o'clock tonight, boys!
TYREE: Get it done, Johnny Reb.
[Bystanders shouting
and cheering]
BOONE:
That a boy! Keep your left up!
QUINCANNON: Put him up.
Put some water on him.
TYREE: You're winning, boy,
just like a mountain lion.
BOONE: You're doing good,
but don't forget that left.
Twist it.
Keep your left in his face.
You're doing good.
Doc: You'll get busted
for this, Quincannon.
DOC: You're doing all right,
but use that right.
Keep throwing that right in.
Like that.
Hit him with the right.
QUINCANNON: Lovely fight,
but watch them fouls.
None of that, see?
And when you come out,
none of that.
TROOPER: Attention!
KIRBY:
Well, Quincannon, talk fast.
QUINCANNON:
Soldiers' fight, sir.
KIRBY: What caused it?
QUINCANNON: I refuse to answer.
Respectfully, sir.
Heinze?
I refuse to answer, sir.
Yorke?
No, sir.
Soldiers' fight, eh?
Carry on.
QUINCANNON:
You heard what the colonel said.
Carry on with the fight.
JEFF: Thanks, Heinze.
HEINZE: I'm sorry, soldier.
JEFF: I apologize.
DOC:
Let me have a look at that eye.
You're going to be all right.
Just sit right down.
QUINCANNON: You little rascal.
It's the left you should have
been watching.
The left.
The left like that.
[Bugler plays Reveille]
DOC: Good morning, sonny.
JEFF: Why, that's castor oil.
[Reveille ends]
KIRBY: Supply train
two hours and 20 minutes late.
TRUNKETT: Whoa.
TRUNKETT: That's the colonel's
quarters there, ma'am.
PRESCOTT: Trunkett, when did
you take unto yourself a wife?
TRUNKETT: I ain't yet.
PRESCOTT:
Begging your pardon, ma'am...
but unauthorized ladies
are not permitted on this post.
I am not unauthorized.
L... I'm afraid
we have no accommodations...
no quarters for mothers
of the enlisted men.
KATHLEEN: I have a pass
signed by General Sheridan.
PRESCOTT:
May I help you, ma'am?
KIRBY: I'll handle this,
Captain.
PRESCOTT: Thank you, sir.
Good evening, Kathleen.
Good evening, Kirby.
Sergeant.
SERGEANT: Yes, sir?
KIRBY: See that Mrs. Yorke's
bags are unloaded...
and taken to my quarters.
SERGEANT: Yes, sir.
QUINCANNON:
Welcome home, darlin'.
KATHLEEN: I see you still
have that arsonist with you.
KIRBY: You mean Quincannon?
He is a sergeant major
in the United States Army.
Anything he may have done
long ago in the line of duty...
he did in obedience
to my orders.
Reluctantly, I may add.
KATHLEEN:
Oh. The reluctant arsonist.
KATHLEEN: The safest way for
us to start our conversation...
would be for you to just say...
"To what do I owe the honor
of your visit?"
KIRBY: I saw the reason
for your visit this morning.
KATHLEEN: How is he?
KIRBY: He's grown considerably,
I thought.
Right now he's bruised up
a little.
Had a fight. Not much.
KATHLEEN: A fight?
With another soldier.
KIRBY: Hardly an officer.
KATHLEEN:
Hardly with an officer?
He's not gentleman enough
for that.
KIRBY: You said it... soldier.
That's enough for me.
Not for me.
Jeff was boyishly ashamed when
he was expelled from West Point.
He shouldn't have enlisted.
I could have sent him
to Lexington.
He could have tutored
in mathematics...
and then got his commission.
But he did enlist,
and he's here.
KIRBY: And here he'll stay,
and here he'll serve.
Ramrod, wreckage, and ruin.
Still the same Kirby.
Special privilege
to special born.
Still the same Kathleen.
Kirby, I've come
to take Jeff home.
He signed enlistment papers.
He took an oath.
KATHLEEN: Oath.
Jeff can be released
from the army...
bought off honorably
for the sum of $100.
I brought that amount with me
in Yankee gold.
You forget
one very important detail.
A release requires my signature
as commanding officer.
You've overlooked several other
important details.
Number one...
you're a fine figure of a woman.
Number two...
you probably haven't eaten.
There's a box of flat silver
in that chest.
I'll send someone over
to set the table.
You will dine with me?
KATHLEEN: Of course.
[Bugler playing]
[Music box plays]
[Men singing]: Yellow stripes
on britches blue...
ridin' along before us.
KIRBY: The regimental singers.
[Men singing]:
...and gaily sing this chorus.
KIRBY: Probably to serenade us.
That is very gracious of them.
[Men singing]:
And hope she's gonna stay.
Hope she's gonna stay.
Yellow stripes
on britches blue...
ridin' along before us...
just so we can ride behind...
and gaily sing this chorus.
Brand and burn
and mark his hide...
and ride him every day.
Kiss your gal
and leave her there...
and hope she's gonna stay.
Hope she's gonna stay.
JONES:
With Mrs. Yorke's permission.
KATHLEEN: Thank you.
[Guitar music playing]
[Soloist singing]:
I'll take you home again...
Kathleen...
across the ocean wild
and wide...
to where your heart
has ever been...
since first
you were my blushing bride.
[Men singing]: The roses
all have left your cheeks.
I watched them fade away
and die.
KIRBY: This music
is not of my choosing.
[Singing continues]
KATHLEEN: I'm sorry, Kirby.
I wish it had been.
[Soloist singing]:
When ere you speak...
[Men singing]: And tears bedim
your loving eyes...
[Soloist singing]:
Oh, I will take you back...
Kathleen...
to where your heart
will feel no pain.
[Men singing]: When the fields
are fresh and green...
I'll take you to your home...
again.
KIRBY: Good night, Kathleen.
Sleep well.
KATHLEEN:
I'm sorry to dispossess you.
KIRBY: I dispossessed you
more forcibly 15 years ago.
KATHLEEN:
You've grown more thoughtful.
KATHLEEN: Pleasant dreams.
KIRBY: Good night, Kathleen.
[Stomping]
Ahem!
KATHLEEN: Who's that?
It's Sergeant Major Quincannon,
ma'am.
[Man singing]:
When the cattle are prowlin'...
and the coyotes are howlin'...
under the western sky...
a cowboy is singin'...
his spurs are a-jinglin'...
as down the trail he rides.
[Chanting]
[Lndians chanting loudly]
QUINCANNON:
Johnny horse blanket!
QUINCANNON: Tell them Indians
to stop that yowling!
[Sergeant shouting
in native language]
[Chanting stops]
QUINCANNON: And make them
put them fires out!
[Sergeant shouting
in native language]
QUINCANNON: Like to have me
carry you across the bridge?
KATHLEEN: I would not.
[Sergeant shouting
in native language]
[Men singing]:
I want some black-eyed peas.
I want some mustard greens.
I want some corn pone
on the side.
I want my chicken fried...
with a golden hide.
Aha!
San Antone.
When I was a kid,
I had a locket...
and inside was a picture...
of Davy Crockett.
I know a gal named Ann...
that lives in Texarkan...
that loves a boy in Arkansas.
But when they take a ride...
it's on the Texas side.
Aha!
San Antone.
TYREE:
Say, what was that verse...
you used to sing
about the Alamo?
[Men singing]:
Oh, now I wanna go...
down to the Alamo...
down where my grandpa lived...
QUINCANNON: Trooper Yorke!
JEFF:
Fellas, this is my mother.
TYREE:
I'm deeply honored, ma'am.
BOONE: I'm glad to make
your acquaintance, ma'am.
KEN: Howdy, ma'am.
You don't have to hide
your bruises, Jeff.
Your father
told me all about them.
What kind of man is he, mother?
He's a lonely man.
He's a very lonely man.
They say he's a great soldier.
I suppose he is, but...
what makes soldiers great
is hateful to me.
I've come
to take you home, Jeff.
I can't leave, mother.
It'd be quitting.
You're stubborn and proud,
Jeff...
just like he is.
Just like you are, mother.
I'll buy you out.
No!
I failed at West Point.
I'm gonna work this out
my own way.
I'll take you home...
as soon as your father signs
your papers.
Maybe they didn't tell you,
mother...
but the application requires
my signature, too.
I refuse to sign it.
[Howling in distance]
QUINCANNON: I'd like to...
Ah, them blasted coyotes.
BOONE: What coyotes, sir?
TYREE: Them ain't coyotes, sir.
QUINCANNON: And how long
have you been out west?
TYREE: Long enough to know
a coyote when I hear it, sir.
[Lndians chanting]
QUINCANNON: Watch it!
[Lndians chanting loudly]
QUINCANNON: Quayne!
KEN: Coyotes?
BOONE: Jeff!
Jeff, put out that light!
[Bugler playing]
[Whinnies]
DOC: Hey, you!
Blow Call to Arms!
Call to Arms. Y-Yes, sir.
[Bugler sounds Call to Arms]
KIRBY: This is an attack,
Preston.
For'd as skirmishers.
PRESCOTT: For'd as skirmishers!
Follow me!
[Whinnies]
[Screaming war cries]
MARY MARGARET: Uncle Timmy!
Uncle Timmy!
[Bullet richocets]
KIRBY: Ladies all right?
TROOPER: Fine, Colonel.
KIRBY: How's Mrs. Yorke?
DOC: Mrs. Yorke
is not in her quarters.
KIRBY: Trooper Yorke...
take your mother
back to her quarters.
JEFF: Yes, sir.
KIRBY: I will see you later,
Captain.
SERGEANT: Chiracahua.
Mescalero.
Chiracahua.
White Mountain.
KIRBY: They've concentrated
three tribes.
This means real trouble,
gentlemen...
unless we can stop them before
they cross the Rio Grande.
KIRBY: Captain St. Jacques,
you will form troop "A".
Two bandoleers of ammunition
per trooper.
Four days' rations.
Is that clear?
ST. JACQUES: Yes, sir.
- Sergeant!
- Yes, sir.
KIRBY: Ready to move out
in 30 minutes.
[Bugler playing]
KATHLEEN:
I suppose I'm under arrest...
for being out of bounds,
as you call it.
KIRBY: No, but we can't have
the colonel's lady fainting...
every time
there's a little shooting.
Kirby.
I'll take them.
Thank you.
OFFICER: Attention!
KIRBY: Column of twos, Captain.
CAPTAIN: Right by twos.
Fall out!
Yo!
KIRBY: Singers, give us a tune!
[Soloist singing]: We better
get along on our way, old gal.
[Men singing]:
15 miles on the Erie Canal.
[Soloist singing]:
'Cause you bet your life...
I'd never part with Sal.
[Men singing]:
15 miles on the Erie Canal.
Low bridge, everybody down.
Low bridge...
for we're comin' to a town...
and you'll always know
your neighbor...
your pal...
if you've ever navigated...
on the Erie Canal.
KATHLEEN: Water, Sandy.
KATHLEEN:
Hang these up by the feet.
BOONE: Yo.
DOC: Good morning, Mrs. Yorke.
KATHLEEN: Good morning.
- Busy woman.
- Yes, indeed.
KATHLEEN:
Anything I can wash?
DOC: I generally
let another lady do my things...
but I'm sure
the sergeant here...
would like to give you
his trade.
DOC: As a doctor...
I would diagnose those
as saddle sores.
PRESCOTT: Trooper Tyree.
TYREE: Here, sir.
PRESCOTT: I have a demand
from the Deputy U.S. Marshal...
to seize you under warrant...
issued by due and legal process
by the district court...
Fernando X. Hernandez,
judge...
on charges of manslaughter.
TYREE: The way that sounds,
I must be arrested.
PRESCOTT: As Colonel Yorke
is not present...
you will await his signature
before taking him.
MARSHAL: Any place I can lock
this soldier boy up...
till the paperwork's signed?
DOC: With a fella like this,
I mean a desperado...
why not leave him
at the hospital?
MARSHAL: That's a good idea.
Get my feet checked.
They've been bothering me.
You want to come along
peaceful-like...
or want me
to use these cuffs on you?
TYREE: I'm always peaceful,
marshal.
Ain't no use doing nothing else.
TYREE: Excuse me, ma'am.
KATHLEEN: You're arresting
that nice man for manslaughter?
PRESCOTT: Not me, Mrs. Yorke.
The United States
Deputy Marshal.
KATHLEEN: Manslaughter.
KATHLEEN: What are you going
to do about it?
A gentle soul who'd walk
10 miles out of his way...
before he'd step on an ant.
[Spits]
KATHLEEN:
You go to the hospital.
Get him some tobacco,
anything he wants.
And we'll get him a lawyer
to defend him.
JEFF: He's partial
to molasses candy.
KATHLEEN: Get some.
KATHLEEN: Yankee justice.
Arresting a nice young man
like that for manslaughter...
and promoting arsonists
to be sergeant majors!