[GUITAR PLAYING]
[TRAIN HORN BLARING]
Come on, corporal, pick up your feet.
This here box is pretty heavy,
lieutenant.
Gold usually is.
Come on, get a move on.
Get ahold of it in there.
Now you get in there with it,
and stay there.
Yes, sir.
You tell Colonel McNally
the train's ready.
- Awaiting instructions.
- Yes, sir.
"Tell Colonel McNally
the train is ready.
Awaiting instructions."
Thanks.
- Sorry, sir.
McNALLY: Hmm?
Sorry to disturb you, colonel.
- You were told to, weren't you, lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
Well, then,
you'd have been sorrier if you hadn't.
- Yes, sir.
- What do you want?
Message from Plainsburg.
What does Lieutenant Forsythe want?
Further instructions, sir.
Well, you tell the lieutenant
to get in that car,
close up and stay there
until I knock on the door.
Yes, sir.
I can tell by the way they're talking.
The gold's on the train.
You hear that?
The colonel says for you
to get in that car and stay there
until he knocks on the door.
Good luck, lieutenant.
Let's go.
[HORN BLARES]
Hey, sergeant,
the train has left Plainsburg.
- You all hear that?
MAN: Sure did.
Keep on listening.
Captain, message coming through.
Train is on its way.
Better get ready.
MAN 1: Don't worry, captain.
MAN 2: We're awaiting.
What time is that train due
at River Junction?
About 15 minutes, sir.
She will take on wood and water
for the Blue Mountain grade.
- Who's in command?
- Captain Barrett, sir.
Hmm.
Well, you give Captain Barrett
my compliments
and tell him if anything goes wrong
at River Junction,
I will personally see
that he rues the day.
Yes, sir.
I can't see how a man can hear a train
just by listening to the rail.
- Them rails is all put together--
- Pendergrass, can't you shut up?
Keep it quiet.
Here she comes, sarge.
MAN:
All right, get back.
Don't let nobody see you
and don't come out until I tell you.
Hard to let that much gold go by.
It sure is,
but when it gets as far as the captain,
we'll get it back.
All right, boys, let's go.
Move it, come on.
Let's get those ropes across the track.
[MEN CHATTERING]
Bigfoot, be telling the captain
the train passed here.
BIGFOOT:
Sure enough, sergeant.
Bide,
get them to tie those ropes well.
BIDE:
Tie those ropes hard and fast.
Hank, you move faster
or the train will be here and gone.
Captain.
They left River Junction.
- James?
JAMES: Yes, sir.
You got enough grease?
We got enough so when that train hits,
it won't go nowhere.
- Better put it on extra heavy.
- Yes, sir.
- Francis.
PIERRE: Are you ready?
- I guess so.
[BEES BUZZING]
These here hornets are getting madder
and madder.
Just listen to them.
They're mad all right.
How does it look, lieutenant?
Well, looks just fine.
Just fine.
She's coming, captain.
PIERRE: All right,
everybody get completely out of sight,
and don't come out until you see me.
Hey, Beaufort, get down from that tree.
- Train's left River Junction, sir.
- Good.
Once it gets here,
there's not much to worry about.
Well, it isn't here yet, lieutenant.
- No, sir, but what l--
- So do you mind if I worry?
No, sir.
May I say something, colonel?
Go ahead.
Well, is it because you think
the ten miles from River Junction to here
is the worst part of the trip
that you gave the gold detail
to Lieutenant Forsythe?
That's one of the reasons.
He's been with you quite a while,
hasn't he, sir?
Since the war began.
Yes, sir.
MAN: That engine's sure pulling hard
up that hill.
We're slowing down, lieutenant.
Watch it when she hits the grease.
Wheels are slipping,
and we have no traction.
MAN:
Hornets, hornets! Thousands of them.
We got to get out of here.
- We're all set, captain.
- Good work.
Billy Joe, get that wire down.
MAN:
Over here, help. Let me out of here.
PIERRE:
Blow off her steam, Wilbur.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
All right, everybody on.
Cut loose.
Come on, get on.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
- You can make it.
MAN 1: Jed, come on.
Come on, Jed. Get up, Jed.
MAN 2:
Well, you damn near didn't make it.
The wire's dead.
Could be the lines are down.
Colonel, the wires are dead
between here and River Junction.
- Damn, call in your outpost.
- Yes, sir.
Sound assembly.
[TRUMPET PLAYING]
MAN:
Mount up, men, mount up.
Come on, everyone. Get up.
Open the door.
[MAN GRUNTS]
[GRUNTS]
[BOTH GRUNT]
- Captain, them hornets is sure busy.
- Yeah, I see them.
MAN:
For God's sakes, Henry, jump.
[GRUNTS]
MAN: Let's go, let's go out.
Come on, gang, let's move out of here.
Jump, jump. Let's get off the train.
MAN: I can't see.
- Jump.
Johnson, is that all of them?
I'll find out, captain.
I can't see nary a soul.
Give those hornets some smoke
and get them out of there.
I don't want them there when I go in.
It's all yours, captain.
Jed.
Yes, sir.
We're going faster than we figured.
Do you think
you could slow it down any?
Brakes don't do no good, captain.
We're gonna hit hard.
You better find yourselves a place
with a good hold.
[MEN WHOOPING
THEN CHATTERING]
- Good work, sergeant.
- Good to see you, sir. Have any trouble?
- Not much.
- Bide is handling the gold.
Got the horses down here.
MAN:
Come on. Let's get it.
You'll be all right, Jeb.
[JEB GRUNTS]
What happened here?
They greased the track, colonel.
And then they jumped us
and knocked us out
and when I come to
the rest of the train was gone.
- Can you have this thing going?
- No, sir.
- All the steam's gone.
- Lieutenant.
[MEN WHOOPING]
MAN 1: Sure looks pretty.
MAN 2: It's what we come for, ain't it?
MAN 3:
Hand me some.
MAN 4: Pass it back, men.
We got plenty for everybody.
- We got the gold all right, sir.
- Get it loaded as quick as you can.
Hurry up, Bart.
I sure have a heavy load, sarge.
PIERRE:
Let's go, boys, keep it moving.
Corporal, get that wagon started.
Let's not take all day, men.
All right, move out.
[MEN WHOOPING]
How bad is he, corporal?
It's Thompson.
He's got a bad cut in his shoulder.
- I'll be all right, sir.
- What's the matter with your face?
Oh, they threw a hornet's nest in the car,
sir.
- That's why we had to jump, sir.
- Hmm.
- Where's Lieutenant Forsythe?
- Down the track a way.
Sir, they say he's hurt pretty bad.
- Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
Danford, Van Tiet.
Fall out and give them a hand here.
Group, forward, yo.
Colonel McNally, over here.
[HORSE WHINNIES]
Ned.
I'm sorry, sir,
but we just couldn't stay in that car
with all those hornets.
I know.
- You feel this?
- Colonel.
Colonel, those rebs had to know
beforehand about that gold.
They sure as hell did.
They sure got the jump on us.
Can you feel this, Ned?
No, it just feels numb, sir.
Can you move your head?
No, but it doesn't hurt, sir.
I know I'll be all right.
Lieutenant, your neck's broken.
Well, that's-- That's--
I'm sorry I can't wait here with you, Ned,
but--
No, I know, sir.
Colonel?
Catch them, will you?
I will.
Forward, yo.
McNALLY: Corporal,
get up in that car and take a look-see.
MAN:
Yes, sir.
- Wyler.
- Yes, sir.
Get on out ahead of us,
see which way they took off.
Probably south.
- Colonel.
McNALLY: Yeah.
The gold's gone. They've got it, sir.
I thought so.
Over here, colonel.
They had a wagon, sir.
You can see the tracks. They split up.
Part of them went out that way
with the wagon,
and the rest of them out there.
The wagon was heavy coming in
and heavy when it left.
Load could have come
from this pile of stones, sir.
Maybe that's what they wanted us
to think.
You mean the gold's on the wagon?
Well, I'm going after the wagon.
You take half the troop
and follow those that went to the east.
- Yes, sir. Bartell.
BARTELL: Yes, sir.
You and your squad follow me.
- And, lieutenant.
- Sir?
If you catch them,
I want you to bring a couple back.
- And I want them to be able to talk.
- Yes, sir.
Squad, fall out, ho.
Hyah, hyah!
McNALLY:
Follow me.
Jenkins, check that trail.
- Colonel.
- What is it?
There's a button from a reb uniform.
Could have come this way.
A wagon couldn't have got up there,
could it?
Not a chance.
Well,
then, you and Miller come with me,
and the rest of you, follow that trail.
Well, if the gold was in the wagon,
they're packing it now.
They came into the water here, sir.
And they went upstream
or downstream?
Who can say, sir?
Well, all right, you two go downstream
and I'll go upstream.
Hey, Johnny Reb.
Stay right where you are.
Yank, I'm unarmed.
That's what bothers me.
Turn around anyway.
[TUSCARORA GRUNTS]
Don't drown him.
I won't.
[McNALLY GRUNTS]
He hit his head, captain.
Give us a hand here.
[TUSCARORA GRUNTS]
He's heavier than a baby whale.
MAN:
It's all quiet out there, sergeant.
PIERRE:
Let's hope it stays that way, captain.
[GRUNTS]
PIERRE:
You'd better leave that bandage alone,
unless you want
to start bleeding again.
How do you feel?
McNALLY:
I hurt.
You hit your head on a rock.
I feel like a damn fool
letting you take me.
I would too.
You haven't got a bad leg.
Bandage fooled me.
PIERRE:
Bide over there loaned it to me.
Real blood too, colonel.
Made by a Yankee bullet.
Who knocked me off my horse?
Tuscarora here.
I hurt a little too, colonel.
You're a big man.
You're the outfit
that's been taking our gold shipments.
That's the fourth lot you've grabbed.
The South needs money, colonel.
- I know you from someplace, don't l?
PIERRE: You do.
- What's your name?
- Pierre Cordona.
McNALLY:
What?
French mother, Mexican father,
from New Orleans.
- Four or five years ago in Abilene.
PIERRE: That's right.
Something about a horse, wasn't it?
A big bay horse.
Heh, you stole it.
The hell I did, I won it.
You won a sorrel.
McNALLY:
The sorrel turned up lame.
When you play poker,
you should know what you're playing for.
I remember now.
We were both on that big bay.
PIERRE:
Yeah.
And I was in front and you were behind
with a gun in my back.
Well,
some of your friends wanted to shoot me.
PIERRE:
And I wasn't very happy about it.
Colonel, I'd feel a little better
if you'd stay away from those rifles.
Well, neither one of us got hurt.
Now, tell me,
what am I doing in this rig?
Well, colonel, you used me,
and now I'm gonna use you.
This time, you're gonna be in front
and you're gonna get us out of here.
And if we run into any Yanks,
you're gonna be between us and them
and you're gonna be the first man shot.
I don't know where all our units are.
If you don't know,
you better guess pretty good.
If I were you, I would start doing
a little thinking before we leave.
- When are we leaving?
PIERRE: As soon as it's dark.
Do you have to tie my hands?
Captain's orders.
Oh, and, colonel,
I'll be riding right behind you.
I can throw this knife pretty good
and it don't make no noise.
I hear you, sergeant.
Douse that light.
Them in the back too.
Get ready to move out.
Captain.
PIERRE:
What is it, corporal?
Which direction
do you think that Yank's taking us?
South.
I can't see the stars,
but we should be heading south.
Well, you're wrong. Which side of a tree
do you think moss grows on?
PIERRE: The north side.
BIDE: The moss is on this side.
And right now we're going north.
Sure, we're going north.
Half of Sheridan's army
is south of here.
Only way we can go is around them.
I don't know
whether I can get you through,
but it's your idea, captain,
and you're stuck with it.
You better not be trying something,
colonel.
You might be sorry for it.
Lead on.
TUSCARORA:
Hold it, colonel.
- Captain.
- Yeah?
We're getting near water
and I smell smoke.
Take a look, sergeant.
Better keep an eye on the Yank.
What do you think, colonel?
I told you I can't keep track
of every outfit.
Might even be some
of your Johnny Rebs.
[HARMONICA PLAYING]
They're Yanks, all right. A cavalry outfit.
That would be the 10th Ohio.
They were 20 miles
from here yesterday.
You keep pretty good track
of where you are, colonel.
I try to, sergeant.
- Can we go by them?
- Better ask the Yank here.
Well, colonel?
Well, the best way to go
is right by them, east.
Pass the word.
We're right near a Yankee camp.
Keep your horses quiet.
- Use your hands if you have to.
BIDE: Going past a Yankee--
And how am I supposed
to do that with mine tied?
Cut him loose, sergeant.
You be mighty careful, colonel.
I will, sergeant.
Go ahead. Slow.
See anything, colonel?
McNALLY:
Rebs on your flank. Look alive.
Get over here.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
- Every man for himself.
- Come on.
[TRUMPET BLOWING]
MAN 1: Let's get out of here.
MAN 2: Let's go.
PIERRE:
You men separate and ride south.
We'll meet back by the bridge.
Ride fast, but don't lose that gold.
O'Brien, you and Morgan flank--
MAN 1: Go.
MAN 2: Let's go.
[MAN WHISTLING]
Don't get nervous, sergeant.
Just drop that horse pistol.
Keep moving.
Your captain's over by that log.
- What happened to him, colonel?
- He hit his head.
He's all right. Wake him up.
[McNALLY SNIFFS]
What's in that canteen, sergeant?
Corn liquor.
I could use a little of that myself.
[HORSES APPROACHING]
Better be quiet.
Your captain's
in the wrong uniform, remember.
Well, captain, how do you feel?
Back in the cave,
you said you felt like a fool.
Now I do.
I thought you gave in
a little too easy, colonel.
When we was going north to get away,
we was just going into trouble.
You wanted that gold bad,
didn't you, colonel?
Not as bad as I wanted you two.
Somebody in my outfit
had to be giving you information.
- I want him.
- And you want us to tell you.
Tell me and I'll cut you loose
and turn my back.
The two of you will have
a good chance of getting away.
Otherwise, you're a prisoner
in the wrong uniform.
- You know what that can get you.
- Yeah, I know.
And our boys lose all chance
of getting more gold? Uh-uh.
The war isn't over yet, colonel.
All right.
- Over here.
MAN: Captain.
- Hold up.
McNALLY: Over here.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
Captain.
Just got this.
Damn, all this for nothing.
MAN 1: Can you use a blanket?
MAN 2: Sure can, sir.
- Give him a blanket, corporal. Next man.
MAN 3: You got boots or shoes?
- Chills and fever?
MAN 4: No, sir.
MAN 3: Feeling bloated, cramps?
You will when you tangle
with that salt pork they're giving.
Here, drink this. Next man.
MAN 5:
Name, rank, unit.
McCord, Bide, lance corporal,
Tupelo fusiliers.
- Tupelo fusiliers?
- Kind of a small outfit.
Kept on getting smaller.
Last time I heard, I was all of it.
- Captain.
- Length of internment, eight months.
Here, give that to the paymaster. Next?
You want a blanket?
- You were right.
- I thought he'd be here.
MAN 1: Cordona, Pierre, captain,
First Louisiana Cavalry.
MAN 2: You've got $2 coming to you,
captain. Sign here.
MAN 1:
You're entitled to your sword, captain.
- Could I have a pistol, sir?
MAN 1: No firearms.
- Never mind about the sword.
MAN 2: Here's your $2.
Phillips, Tuscarora, sergeant,
First Louisiana Cavalry.
- Sign here, sergeant.
MAN 1: McCord, Bide.
- Lance corporal, First Louisiana Cavalry.
MAN 2: Sign here.
Pierre and Tuscarora.
Got a good memory, colonel.
Glad you fellows weathered the storm.
Well, it's a simple life, colonel.
No wine, no woman, no song.
- And no whiskey.
- Well, I can remedy that.
You two don't mind drinking
with a blue belly.
Colonel, sir,
I'd drink with the devil himself.
I feel just like he does.
We're headed in the right direction.
[CHATTERING]
PETEY:
Hi, colonel.
Hello, Petey. Whiskey for three.
None of that cow purge.
Give us some whiskey.
But, colonel, this is planter's stock.
Jamaica rum.
- I paid dear for this.
- And you charge dear for it.
Give us some of that stuff
on the bottom shelf.
Give me the bottle.
Colonel, I think I know
why you want to see us.
I take it you haven't found the fellow
who gave us the information
about your gold shipments.
Who sold you the information
about our gold shipments.
No, I haven't. But I will.
You make it sound
like it's something personal, colonel.
Well, a boy that I watched grow up
was in that car
that you threw the hornets into.
PIERRE:
Was he hurt bad?
- We buried him the next day.
PIERRE: I'm sorry.
Colonel, we killed your friend,
but you don't seem to hold that against us.
Well, what you did was an act of war.
But selling information, that's treason.
Rotten treachery for money.
I want the name of that man.
There were two men.
I don't know their names.
We gave them the money and they
gave us the papers with information.
Well, can you describe them?
One was a big man,
almost as big as you.
The other one--
Well, you were closer.
The other fellow,
even in the dark he stood out.
He's like an albino,
white hair, white skin, smaller man.
That's all.
Well, that's more than I had.
You fellows can do me a favor.
If you run into either one of them,
let me know.
PIERRE:
You can be sure of that.
- Another drink?
- How about letting us buy you a drink?
Ho, ho, what did they give you
when you signed off?
Two dollars.
- Where are you heading?
PIERRE: Oh, just look around.
I'm going back to Texas.
Man who brought me up
has a ranch in Rio Lobo.
Well, $2 won't get you very far.
Since you two have been locked up,
our payrolls have been
coming through pretty regularly.
That'll get you to Texas.
You can owe me.
Colonel, I never thought
I'd wanna kiss a Yank.
Colonel, if we run
into one of those fellows you're after,
where can we reach you?
Blackthorne, Texas.
That's near your Rio Lobo country.
The sheriff there
can always get in touch with me.
I see the sheriff of Blackthorne County
has earned himself some bounty money.
Heh, one of these little hides
can buy a man a lot of drinks.
- Good to see you, Cord.
- Thanks.
I was wondering when you'd show up.
Well, I got your message, Pat,
that Pierre Cordona wanted to see me.
Yeah, you got here just in time.
He got in last night.
He's up at the hotel.
Come on in. I'll give you a drink.
What's it all about, Cord?
- Will you tell me why you're here?
- Well...
Didn't, uh... Didn't Cordona grab
a couple of Army payrolls from the Yanks?
That's right.
And I heard that, uh, you captured him
and put him in a prison camp.
You heard right.
Cord.
You're not fixing on causing
any trouble, are you?
- I wouldn't like that.
- Don't worry, Pat.
And besides, you're too good
for that young fellow.
There's no hard feelings between us.
- The war is over.
- Oh, that's good.
Then why do you want to see him?
The only reason Cordona could get away
with those payrolls
was because some people on our side
were selling him information.
I'm after them.
Are you working for the Army,
or is this something personal?
Both.
Sheriff, I'd say
you were gonna have company.
- Which one of you is the sheriff?
- I am, miss, I'm Pat Cronin.
- If there's anything--
- I want to report a murder.
PAT: A murder?
- And I want the man who did it arrested.
- Where'd this happen?
- In Rio Lobo.
PAT: Oh, I'm sorry.
- What do you mean, you're sorry?
PAT:
That's out of my jurisdiction.
Does that mean you're not
gonna do anything?
- Well, it means that--
- Excuse me, miss, you said Rio Lobo.
- Did you--? Huh?
- You connected with the sheriff's office?
Are you connected
with the sheriff's office?
- Well, no, l--
- Will you please stay out of this?
Sheriff, I asked you a question.
Does that mean
you're not gonna do anything?
It means I can't do anything.
I have no authority there.
Look, a man was shot and killed.
Miss, unless a U.S. Marshal
or the sheriff of Rio Lobo asks me--
- You know the sheriff, don't you?
- Yes, ma'am, I do.
- And you know he's not gonna ask you.
- I know that too.
Especially since the man who committed
the murder was one of his deputies.
I'm sorry, miss.
Well, so am l.
I just thought--
So am l.
Who is the sheriff of Rio Lobo?
Tom Hendricks.
- Blue Tom?
- That's right.
Ever run into him?
Well, I chased him enough,
but I never got lucky.
Well, how about that drink?
- I'm out.
- As usual.
I'll buy you one.
Town's growing up, Pat.
- Good morning, Hank.
- Morning, sheriff, can I help you?
I'd like you to meet a good friend
of mine, Cord McNally.
- Glad to meet you.
- Thank you.
I'm looking for a Pierre Cordona.
He's staying here.
- Room 19.
HANK: He's gone.
He's up there, all right.
Just a minute.
He left a message about something.
Um, let's see, now--
He said he'd shoot anybody who woke
him up unless the building was on fire.
He gave me $2.
Oh, it was to see
that nobody started a fire.
Oh, $2 will buy a lot of sleep
around here.
- I guess we can wait for a while.
- How about that drink?
And remember, you're buying.
- Hello, Jane.
- Hi, sheriff.
Sit down. Give us a bottle, Jim.
Little Miss Busybody.
She'll either be in the jail or the hotel.
Chuck, take a look in the jail.
Nobody in the jail, Whitey.
All right.
George, you go around back.
- Come in that way.
- Right.
You two come with me.
Pat.
Well, young lady,
you gave us quite a chase.
Sheriff, this is the man
that I wanted you to arrest.
He's the murderer.
Well, that may give the sheriff
the wrong idea about me.
It was self-defense, sheriff.
Old man tried to knife--
- That's a lie, he didn't have--
- Hold on, miss, I can handle this.
Who are you, mister?
And what exactly is your business here?
Name's Carter, Whitey Carter.
I'm a deputy from Rio Lobo.
As to my business,
I came looking for her.
- She's wanted.
- Wanted?
What for?
She and the old man she lived with
ran one of them medicine shows.
You know, snake oil,
crooked shell games.
Pick a few pockets on the side.
- That's another lie, I didn't do anything.
WHITEY: She was the come-on.
Sheriff in Rio Lobo
just wants to talk to her.
- So I'll take her along with me.
- Just a minute, Mr. Carter.
I'm the sheriff of Blackthorne,
and I wanna see a warrant.
- A warrant?
- For the young lady's arrest.
Well, heh, I never thought about that.
PAT: Without a warrant,
you're not taking anybody.
I got a warrant right here, sheriff.
Satisfied, sheriff?
Now drop your gun and go sit down.
All right, everyone stand still,
no one gets hurt.
Come on, you.
[GRUNTS]
Look out, Cord.
- Did they hit you, Pat?
- No, I did it myself when I hit the floor.
You're getting too old
for these dive-downs.
- Well, captain.
- Hello, colonel.
Glad you joined us when you did.
I heard the racket
and somehow I knew it was you.
How did it start?
Well, this young lady here
shot that white-haired man.
She really didn't wanna go
with him, did she?
- Can you blame her?
- Well, I'll be damned. Look here, colonel.
This was one of the fellows
you were hunting.
Well, I never--
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
Is he dead?
McNALLY:
Unfortunately, yes.
Did I kill him?
Not entirely, but you sure helped.
Well, I couldn't let him take me.
I'd rather be dead.
But you damn near got us all killed.
Well, I'm sorry, I--
- I just--
- Are you gonna faint?
I... Unh.
- What'll I do with her?
- Bring her up to my room.
McNALLY: Where is it?
PIERRE: Up there on the left side.
The door is open.
There's somebody in there.
Oh, I forgot. Come on, Maribel, get up.
MARIBEL:
What are you waking me up for?
PIERRE:
Here's your robe. Come on, move on.
MARIBEL: Why can't I sleep?
PIERRE: I'll explain later.
Come on.
- Is that what I'm leaving for?
- Yes.
I thought you were a gentleman.
You've been busy.
PIERRE:
Uh, just keeping out of trouble.
- Hank, go get the undertaker.
- Yes, sir.
Never mind, here he comes.
I heard some shooting, sheriff.
Do you need me?
Yes, Ruf, we got a lot of work for you.
One over there, two over here
and one over in the corner.
Well, I'll get right at it.
What did you find out?
I talked to the stage driver
that brought the girl from Rio Lobo.
Said he picked her up
a couple of miles out of town.
She was telling the truth, all right.
He was after her, and he shot the old man
with the medicine wagon.
Now, what did Tuscarora say
in that letter?
Only that he saw
one of the men you were after.
- A man with white hair.
- Well, that'd be Whitey from downstairs.
He said that, uh, Whitey worked
for a rich Yankee.
Tuscarora said
he has never seen this Yank yet.
Well, you didn't come all the way
to Blackthorne to tell me that.
No. Tuscarora's in trouble.
They're trying
to take his old man's land.
And you thought I'd join in?
Two guns are better than one.
Maybe we're after the same thing.
Maybe I can help you.
Well, I reckon I'm in.
I'll go as far as Rio Lobo
and we'll find out.
What did you just say?
Well, how do you feel?
Ugh, oh, I don't know.
Aren't you the man
that came downstairs?
Joined in and helped us
when we needed it.
Pierre Cordona, Miss--
- What is your name?
- It's Shasta, Shasta Delaney.
You don't have any pants on,
Mr. Cordona.
I didn't have much time
after the shooting.
- Well, you have time now, don't you?
PIERRE: Yes, I--
- Well, why don't you put them on?
- Because, uh, you're lying on them.
Oh.
You don't have
many clothes on yourself.
Who unbuttoned--?
Who took my clothes off?
PIERRE: I did.
- Why?
- We flipped a coin and I won.
- Oh, I've never heard of anything--
Haven't you ever heard of loosening
a person's clothes when they faint?
[SIGHS]
Oh, yes. Unh.
I guess I'm acting like an idiot, aren't I?
I'd say almost.
- Yeah, I would say so too.
- I'm sorry.
Suppose I could have a drink?
McNALLY:
You're not gonna faint again, are you?
No, Mr. McNally.
Do you only take a drink
when you're about to faint?
I'd hardly say that, miss.
Thank you.
[COUGHS]
-You all right?
-Mm-hm.
Oh, when I was waking up,
didn't I hear you say something
about going to Rio Lobo?
- You did.
- Good.
- Well, I'm going with you.
- You--
- Oh, no, you're not.
- Don't be silly.
How much do you know
about Rio Lobo?
You've never been there, have you?
Either of you.
You don't know where to go
or who to talk to.
You don't even know
who's a friend or an enemy.
- Well, I can help.
- Why do you wanna go?
Well, I wanna get my wagon.
Heh, old Charlie wanted me to have it.
Oh. Every time I think about him, I--
[SNIFFLES]
Anyway, it's all I own.
You can't ride in that outfit.
Well, if you get me a horse and my valise,
I'll be ready in ten minutes.
Oh, captain.
When you get the troop paraded,
let me know.
I'll be in the bar.
There she is.
I'll take that.
How far is it to Rio Lobo?
Oh, 70 or 80 miles.
Took three days on the stage.
Well, it'll take us longer than that.
All ready.
Oh, we forgot something.
Can she ride?
Can you?
Oh, which side of the horse
do you get on?
Left side.
I knew it.
Ah, you're a pretty good teacher,
Frenchy.
Yeah, heh.
Well, this looks like a good place
to bed down.
Cold, but it'll get colder.
I'll see what I can find to make a fire.
Shasta, you don't happen to have a bottle
of that doctor's snake oil with you, do you?
- Just happen to have some.
- Good.
[McNALLY WHISTLING]
What are you so happy about, colonel?
Well, I've had
about the right number of drinks,
and I am warm and I'm relaxed.
Well, if you gentle people
can manage without me,
I shall go to sleep.
- Good night.
- Night.
McNALLY: Ugh.
I'm freezing.
This will help.
Don't do that.
- I don't like it.
- Well, I'm sorry.
- I was going--
- I'm tired of being pawed.
I've had enough.
What happened?
What made you say that?
Oh, why go into it?
Because I would like to know.
All right.
I was married.
It wasn't a good marriage.
He couldn't drink, but he did anyway.
And when he did, he wasn't good.
Like when he drank,
he used to gamble.
And when he lost,
he thought he was being cheated.
I don't know if he was or not,
but the other guy
was faster and a good shot.
So I had to get a job.
Do you know what it's like to work
in a saloon?
- No.
They never leave you alone.
Never.
And good old Charlie Simms
came along.
The only man who was ever nice to me.
And they killed him.
Do you have any more questions?
Yeah. What are you gonna do now?
- I'm going to bed.
- I mean, after this is all over.
[SIGHS]
Well, I'm gonna get Charlie's wagon,
and then I'm going to, uh...
I don't know.
You can't run a medicine show
by yourself.
Oh, I don't know,
I'm pretty good at getting people
to buy that Apache herb tonic.
Something will turn up. It always does.
You know, I like you.
- Why?
- Because you don't cry.
Oh, but I do.
You saw me.
You cried for your friend,
not for yourself.
There's a lot of difference.
Don't be nice to me. Please.
Wait.
- Heh, I didn't figure--
- Didn't you want me to do that?
Of course I did. Sure, I did.
But I'm generally the one who starts it.
Well, that's why I started it.
Because now I know when it'll stop.
Well, I would...
Um, good night.
SHASTA: Pierre?
PIERRE: Yeah?
- See these poles above me?
- Mm-hm.
SHASTA:
I can't figure out what they're for.
They're all burnt.
Well, I would say those poles were used
by the Indians to bury their dead.
They put the bodies on the poles
- and burned them up.
- What?
Probably, you're sleeping on a skull
of some brave--
I'm what? Hey.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey.
How about waking up?
How did she get here?
Why don't you ask her?
Hey, you, how'd you get here?
What? Oh, when you were asleep.
It was cold.
Well, why me?
Why didn't you pick on him?
Well, he's young and I thought that--
Well, you're older, you're comfortable.
- Comfortable?
- That's all I could think of.
I've been called a lot of things,
but "comfortable"?
I'll say this.
You're a lot better than a hot brick
to keep a man warm.
Heh. It's nice to be appreciated.
- Is that coffee I smell?
PIERRE: It is.
If you get up, you can have some.
Rise and shine.
Come on.
Well, this is Rio Lobo. Take a look.
McNALLY:
Looks quiet enough.
Too late to start anything now.
Where does Tuscarora's girlfriend live?
You said we could hole up there.
Yes, she's on the edge of town.
There's a corral nearby
we can put the horses.
Can we get there without being seen?
Yes, if you can get across the street.
- Take a look, Frenchy.
- Right.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
It's me, Shasta.
SHASTA:
Hurry, Maria.
Oh, Shasta.
Listen, we don't have much time.
These are friends of Tuscarora's.
They're here to help Mr. Phillips.
This is Captain Cordona.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
And this is Colonel McNally.
Maria, can we come in?
We have to have a place to stay tonight.
S, but the horses,
it's not good to have them here.
Where's a good place?
Over there, you will find an empty house.
You see that?
- And you will find a corral on your right.
- All right. I'll take them.
MARIA:
But be careful, they are watching.
You went away.
Why did you come back here?
Oh, Maria, it's a long story. But first,
tell me what's been happening here?
What has Ketcham
and the sheriff been doing?
They have been after Phillips
to sell his ranch.
Has he sold it?
I don't know. I haven't seen Tuscarora
since you went away.
I am afraid, Shasta.
And everybody's afraid here.
The sheriff's men are watching
everywhere.
- They're watching this house?
- Everywhere.
It's not going to be safe
for you to stay here.
-We have to stay here tonight.
MARIA: S, s.
And we haven't eaten.
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't think.
But I'll just prepare something for you.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
I'm sorry, miss.
There's someone's chasing me
and I don't have any other place to go.
- You don't have to go.
- What?
You can stay here.
Would you mind putting that light out?
As you wish.
Thanks.
Don't stand in the middle of the room.
Get away from there.
- Can you see anyone?
- I don't see a soul.
- Would you like me to have a look?
- I'm looking.
Yes, but I could go outside.
You'd better put some clothes on first.
As you wish.
No, I didn't mean that exactly, ma'am.
I don't think you should go out there.
Well, then we, uh, we could stay here.
I have plenty of tortillas and beans
and chili and even some wine.
Sounds good. I wish I could stay.
- Why not?
- Because I think they're gone now.
- I must get back to my friends.
- I'm sorry.
- I don't know how to thank you.
- You don't have to.
- My name is Pierre. What's yours?
- Amelita.
Thank you, Amelita.
Wait a minute.
It's all right.
That smells good.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
PIERRE:
Cordona.
Come in.
McNALLY:
Where you been?
I put the horses away and I was hiding.
Hiding? From whom?
From the people that watch the town.
I told you. Where were you?
In the house of a girl.
A girl? Pretty fast worker.
- Where'd you meet her?
- I crashed the door and there she was.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, she's pretty. Dark hair.
- I think her name's Amelita.
- Oh, I know her. She's a friend of mine.
- Well, she helped me.
- Well, I hope you had fun.
Stop it, Shasta.
What are we gonna do now?
Well, we're gonna stay here tonight.
In the morning, I'll go into town,
see what I can find out.
Why don't we go into, uh, Phillip's ranch
and--?
If they're watching this town,
they're certainly watching the ranch.
- And the sheriff knows you, doesn't he?
- He does.
McNALLY: Well, he'll sure as hell wanna
know what you're doing here.
He always wants to know
all about any stranger.
Well--
Wrap up your wrist
and say you hurt yourself,
and say you're looking for a doctor.
Better the dentist. He's a friend
of Tuscarora and Mr. Phillips.
He can tell you much.
Well, I feel a toothache coming on.
I hope you have plenty of this wine, Maria.
[HORSES NEIGHING]
- Come on, boys. Bring them in here.
MAN: There you go.
Thanks, boys.
See they get some water, will you?
- I'll be back in a little while.
- You be careful.
[WHISTLES]
- Been a long time, Maria.
- All right, boys, come on.
Tuscarora. Come here.
You wanna see me?
DEPUTY: You just brought some horses
into town, didn't you?
- That's right.
DEPUTY: They yours?
- They're ours.
- I think some of those horses were stolen.
That's a lie.
[GRUNTING]
MARIA:
No! No! Leave him alone!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop this wicked thing!
[GRUNTING]
[CRYING]
All right, that's enough.
[GROANING]
What's going on?
Just teaching him some manners,
sheriff.
He's been stealing horses.
We gotta save enough of him to hang.
Take him over to the jail.
MAN:
Come on, on your feet.
[CRYING]
Bring the girl along too.
Why?
[MARIA CRYING]
McNALLY:
Are you all right, lady?
Are you?
You'd better go on home.
[CHUCKLES]
McNALLY:
Go on.
MAN: You're kind of new around here,
aren't you?
- Just got in this morning.
- Figure on staying long?
Bum tooth.
Hey, doc. Got a customer for you.
TOM:
Oh, mister.
After you get that tooth fixed,
just amble on out of town.
Sounds like good advice.
Doctor.
Come on in, sir.
Keep an eye on that big fella.
See if he really has a bad tooth.
- So you got a bad tooth?
- No, I haven't.
- Get in the chair.
- I told you, my tooth's all right.
Get in the chair.
Well, can't we just talk?
See that fella over there by the jail?
He's checking out your story
on your tooth.
- All right, open real wide.
- Well, I can't talk with my mouth open.
Well, I'll ask the questions,
you just nod or shake your head.
Now, that girl Maria,
the one that got knocked around,
- she send you?
- Yeah.
I thought so, the way you bolted in here.
- Ow! That hurts.
- Well, then yell.
- Most of my patients yell a lot.
- Ow!
Take a look out there.
[McNALLY SCREAMS]
[McNALLY SCREAMING]
McNALLY:
He's getting-- He's gone.
Is that my tooth?
No, no. No, yours are fine.
Tell me what's going on around here.
Well, the man really running things
and putting up all the money
is a man named Ketcham.
Came in here right after the war.
Hendricks killed the sheriff we had
and Ketcham made Hendricks
the new sheriff.
Take a look out there.
- Wish I could hear what they're saying.
- Don't have to.
Blackmail.
If they do things
the way they've been doing it,
Hendricks will send his bullyboys
out to Old Man Phillips' ranch.
They'll run off all his stock
so he's on foot,
then they'll tell him that the way
to keep his boy from being hanged
is to sign over his ranch to them
for a quarter of what it's worth.
Now, I know that old man,
he's stubborn as hell,
but he dearly loves that boy.
So they'll keep him there till he cracks
and signs over his land.
Well, Ketcham's
been picking up a lot of land.
All of it that's any good, Mr...
- Mr--
- Doesn't matter.
Well, Mr. Doesn't Matter,
I hope you can do something.
You got plenty of help?
Well, no. No, I haven't.
Well, God be with you.
I still wish you luck.
We ought to give them
one more good yell.
They usually yell a lot
when I give them a shot of this.
Hey. Ow!
That's the real stuff.
Well, if you'd have been a good enough
actor, I wouldn't have used it.
That'll be a dollar, 6 bits.
Would 4 bits be just as good?
Just as good.
Thank you, Mr. Doesn't Matter.
McNally. I'll be seeing you.
You must hide.
Maria told me to tell you that
the sheriff is sending some men here.
- Where can we hide in here?
- I don't know.
SHASTA:
Under the bed. Hurry.
AMELITA:
Oh, wait a minute.
First, pour some water over my head.
PIERRE: All of it?
- Yes, go ahead.
[DOOR KNOB RATTLING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
AMELITA: Who is it?
MAN: Open up.
- Just a minute.
MAN: Hurry it up.
AMELITA:
Just a minute.
- Anybody else in here?
AMELITA: Well, you're here.
I can't see, who are you?
Sheriff's office.
Nobody in here.
They're gone now.
[SHASTA LAUGHING]
- What are you laughing at?
- You wouldn't believe what he said.
You don't have to say those things,
they're private.
- No, but do you really get away with that?
- Yes.
- Do you know what he said?
- No, what did he say?
He said, "One more kiss before we die."
Can you imagine?
- That's stupid.
- It is not.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Who is it?
McNALLY: Me.
- What did you find out?
- Plenty.
They slapped Maria around
this morning,
put Tuscarora in jail
for stealing his own horses,
and they've sent men out
to Old Man Phillips' ranch
to force him to give in.
- Are we gonna let them?
- Not if we can help it.
- How do you get--?
- I'm sorry.
I couldn't get here before,
there were men.
We had visitors.
Well, I was just asking the way
to Phillips' ranch.
- I'll take you.
- Oh, no, not a chance.
Well, she can't stay here.
You know that, don't you?
I'll take the wagon.
- Why?
- Because it's the only thing I've got left.
And I might not get a chance
to come back and get it.
You must have a lot of faith in us.
Well, you're good,
but you're taking on a lot.
Can you get out of town
without being seen?
With a little bit of luck.
Come help me, Amelita.
I'll meet you both east of town,
about a half mile from the little church.
- The little church?
- I can show you.
Is there anything else I can do for you?
Well, pray a little.
We'll be back if things work out right.
It's very much for just two men.
I hope there'll be three
when we see Mr. Phillips.
- Will you show us the way?
- Yes, I know a better way. Follow me.
SHASTA: There are two of them
out front by the gate.
I don't see the third one.
Wait a minute.
See that shack behind the house?
- Doesn't that look like cigarette smoke?
- You've got good eyes.
I see him.
- Think you can handle him?
- Sure.
- I can get in behind him.
- All right.
PIERRE:
How about you?
We can leave Shasta at the wagon
and when we get through--
SHASTA:
Through? You'll be through, all right.
How are you gonna get close enough
to those two men?
Well, this comfortable old man figured
he'd ride right down there and shoot them.
How are you gonna get into the house?
Old Man Phillips will probably
blow your head off
before he even knows
what side you're on.
- Madam, did you happen--?
- Don't be sarcastic.
- Do you happen to have any suggestions?
SHASTA: Yes, I do.
- I'll drive the wagon in, you'll be in back.
- Wanna get yourself killed?
Look, they're part of the bunch
that killed Charlie Simms,
- I just wanna them to pay for it.
- No, no, no. I'm against it.
This is your first step, isn't it?
If you fall down,
you won't get another chance.
- I will not permit it.
- You won't permit it?
- Oh, he's in love with me.
- I didn't say I was in love with you.
- You said you thought you were.
- I don't wanna get in trouble--
Are we gonna rescue an old man
or stand around here and argue?
Just give me two minutes
before you start. And I still don't like it.
This thing between you two,
kind of sudden, isn't it?
Oh, it's not me, it's him.
Are all Mexicans as sudden as he is?
One little kiss and the balloon goes up.
Let's get in the wagon.
Well, he's had his two minutes.
About two minutes more and we'll know
whether your idea was any good.
When the shooting starts,
don't forget to duck.
Yes, colonel.
- Let's go.
- Hyah!
MAN 1:
Got a visitor.
What in tarnation is that thing?
MAN 1:
Hold it right there, miss.
Where do you think you're going?
Well, my horses need water.
I thought I could get some here.
- Well, it ain't very safe to go that way.
- Hey,
ain't that the girl
Whitey Carter went looking for?
- You the girl?
- Yeah, I'm the girl.
You got any more of that snake oil?
Yeah, there's plenty
in the back of the wagon.
Think I'll get some.
Where you been?
They've been looking all over for you.
Oh, I don't know, I've been--
Oh, I guess I can tell you.
I don't like Whitey.
I didn't want him to find me.
Well, everybody's got different tastes.
You can't--
[WAGON SQUEAKING]
What was that?
Probably your friend
getting some snake oil.
Hey, tell me, what's a girl suppose to do
when a man keeps following her around?
I'm tired. You know, I haven't slept.
Except for the other night,
over a place where an Indian was buried.
- It was awful.
- Indian?
Where was the Indian buried?
I don't know. I can't remember.
It was just before somebody hit me.
They hit you? Who?
I didn't see him, but he hit me.
- Where?
- There.
Well, you certainly took long enough.
I was running out of things to say.
That I can't believe.
SHASTA: Hurry it up.
McNALLY: Just a minute.
What's going on out there?
Who's out there?
You better speak up or I'll shoot!
McNALLY:
Hold on a bit. We're trying to help you.
Hyah!
[GUNSHOT]
McNALLY:
Hold your fire, you fool!
Don't you come no closer!
I'll go. He won't shoot a woman.
McNALLY:
Don't count on it.
Mr. Phillips, let me in.
You just stay where you are out there.
What's going on over there?
Look out, he'll shoot you.
Stay away from that window.
- Where's Shasta?
- Inside.
PHILLIPS: Who's out there?
- It's me.
PHILLIPS: Who's me?
- Pierre Cordona.
Cordona? You Tuscarora's captain?
PIERRE: Used to be.
- Well, don't you try nothing.
You, big fella,
get down off that contraption.
Now get your hands up high
and walk up here nice and easy.
You too, Cordona. And keep them high.
Just keep them up there.
Just keep your hands up
and say something. Go ahead.
- Well, what'll I say?
- Just talk to me. I wanna hear you talk.
- If you'd quit prodding me with that--
- I knew it.
I knew it. I can tell by your talking,
you're a Yank.
Didn't you tell him?
Well, he's a rather difficult man
to convince.
Well, you'd be too, if you had a flock
of no-goods like that hanging on you.
Mr. Phillips--
You said you was my boy's captain,
how do I know that?
Um-- Did he write to you
about the first battle we were in?
PHILLIPS:
Mm-hm.
Did he get shot in the arm?
Well, I guess
you're who you say you are.
Now, what's this damn big Yank
doing here?
Well, this damn big Yank's
after another damn big Yank
and helping you in the process.
Sound like you mean that.
What's your name?
Cord McNally.
Didn't Tuscarora tell you about me?
Ha, ha. Cord McNally. Yeah, he sure did,
and I ain't gonna repeat what he said.
Tell me about her. You know, I'd have
shot her when she come running up here,
but she's got the best looking legs
I ever seen.
McNALLY: I didn't have the view you did,
Mr. Phillips.
What's she doing here?
Whitey Carter
murdered one of her friends.
Oh, old Charlie Simms.
Yeah, I heard about that.
Now I know who she is.
- Whitey's dead.
- That's the best news I heard all year.
- Who killed him?
- She did.
Well, I'll be a suckered mule.
Legs like that and can shoot too.
I sure am obliged to you folks
for getting me out of the fix I was in.
- This calls for a drink.
McNALLY: Well, I could sure use one.
You know, they got my boy, don't you?
What do you plan on doing about that?
Just gonna ride into town
and bust open the jail?
Ugh! That stuff is not for the young.
What'd you brew that with?
I asked you,
are you just gonna bust open the jail?
The answer is no,
unless you want your boy killed.
- Think I'm a fool?
- That's not the question.
We've gotta have something
to bargain with.
- Like what?
- Like Ketcham.
Ketcham?
Are you serious or are you crazy?
A little bit of both, but it's the only way
I know to get your boy back.
Well, how do you get Ketcham?
You know his ranch pretty well,
don't you?
I was there before he had it.
How far is it?
- Two, three hours.
- You coming with us?
Heh, heh. Reckon I'm crazy too.
Is there a safe place here where we can
leave this young lady while we're gone?
PHILLIPS:
Hank Prior's place is on the way.
Reckon we could get there before dark,
if we're to leave right away.
No, I'm going with you. I can help.
- You're not going.
- Yes, I am.
You're not going. You've been trying
to run this show since we met.
Now, listen to me and keep still.
You are not going.
- Oh, come--
- You tell them, Frenchy.
Yeah.
PHILLIPS:
Much obliged.
I'd give every damn horse I own
to get a chance at that fella.
Mr. Prior, if we don't come back,
you said--
I'm not gonna disappoint you.
I told you I'd get the girl to Blackthorne.
Thank you.
[PIERRE SPEAKING SPANISH]
No, no, no.
What the--? Frenchy.
You figuring on coming with us,
or you got something better to do?
[PHILLIPS CHUCKLES]
PHILLIPS:
That's a silly question, colonel.
Like to be doing that yourself,
wouldn't you?
No, Mr. Phillips, not a chance.
I'm just comfortable.
PIERRE: You keep calling me Frenchy.
I'm half-Mexican, you know?
Yeah. Well, which half was kneeling
and which half was kissing her hand?
- Where's Ketcham apt to be?
PHILLIPS: The big house.
McNALLY:
What does he look like?
- Big man, black hair and moustache.
- That could be anybody.
Could also be the man that was
with Whitey when we paid the money.
Could be.
How many men has he got?
Fifteen, 20 hands.
They'd be in the bunkhouse.
There's one over there to the left,
and another one farther off to the right.
Then there's these men
he's got guarding the place,
which you soldier boys
would call sentries.
Ketcham doesn't take many chances.
I can see three of them.
No, four.
There's one over here by the gate.
We'll have to get them first,
and then get into that house
and grab Ketcham.
- Use him to hold the rest off.
- We'd better not kill him, then.
No, we'd better not kill him.
Well, Frenchy?
I think I can take the one
in front of the house.
I'll take the one off to the left
and the one in front of the bunkhouse.
Leave one for me.
You think you could you sneak up
on that fella at the gate?
I can sneak up on a coyote
if I have a mind to.
Better give me a little start.
No sense in letting this go to waste.
Remind me to ask Tuscarora a question.
[PHILLIPS BURPS]
About what?
He said you were a saintly old man
that didn't hold with all the vices.
I don't. I don't hold with them at all.
That don't stop me from taking a saintly
pleasure in them whenever I get a chance.
Why don't you blow a bugle?
You ready? If you ain't, I'll go by myself.
[SIGHS]
[CHICKENS CLUCKING]
[GRUNTING]
[BELL RINGS]
- Where's the old man?
- Over there.
You get the fella at the gate?
He's at another gate now
looking for St. Peter.
The big man at the desk,
he's the one I gave the money to.
Sergeant Ike Gorman.
MAN:
What the--?
KETCHAM:
Guards! Tom! Reg! What are you--?
[KETCHAM GRUNTING]
McNALLY:
I've waited a long time for this.
Sergeant Major Gorman,
how does it feel?
Remember Lieutenant Forsythe?
Well, here's one for him.
[LAUGHS]
McNALLY: Get up.
- Hold them for a while.
McNALLY:
Here's another.
[KETCHAM GRUNTS]
[MAN GRUNTS]
PHILLIPS: That's a dandy, McNally.
Give him one for Tuscarora.
[KETCHAM GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
All right, sergeant.
Let's talk to your people.
You tell them they move a finger
and I blow your head off. Yell out.
Can you hear me? This is Ketcham.
Don't move. Don't do anything.
- You hear me?
MAN: Yeah, we hear you.
Now tell them to get our horses
and one for you.
Bring their horses around
and one for me.
MAN:
All right, Mr. Ketchum.
When you got him softened up,
find out where he hides them water rights
and deeds and all that stuff
he's been stealing.
You don't think I'd be fool enough
to keep them here, do you?
McNALLY:
Where do you keep them?
Where are they?
- It's all in the bank.
McNALLY: Where?
- In the bank.
[KETCHAM GRUNTING]
They're here.
Behind that cabinet. In a safe.
Take a look.
PIERRE:
This way.
PHILLIPS:
It's locked.
PIERRE:
There.
[CHUCKLES]
Here they are, McNally.
All the stuff we was looking for.
PIERRE:
Look out!
Colonel McNally, I'm on fire! Help me!
- Phillips, help me, please!
- Let him burn.
No, McNally, don't let him burn
till he signs these papers.
McNALLY: Are you ready to sign?
- Please. I'll sign anything! I'll do anything!
- Somebody help me!
- All right, Frenchy.
Oh! Help me! Oh!
[GROANING]
Ketcham, take a look at this.
Them triggers is wired back.
Now, you can see what happens
if my thumb slips off.
Heh, heh. And my thumbs ain't as strong
as they used to be.
We got your horses.
What do you want us to do with them?
Bring them up to the house!
Come on, let's go.
[PHILLIPS CHUCKLES]
McNALLY: One man hold the horses.
The rest of you clear out.
KETCHAM:
I'm coming outside.
Do what he says. Don't try anything.
PHILLIPS:
You take the sorrel. That one's mine.
- Can you cover him while I get up?
- Get up.
PHILLIPS: All that fighting we done
in there wore me out.
[McNALLY LAUGHS]
All right, Ketcham, move out.
Let's hold it up here.
I can't keep riding like this.
Would you rather walk?
- Anybody following us?
- I didn't see anyone.
Let's talk a bit.
You want your boy out of jail,
don't you, Mr. Phillips?
Damn right I do.
McNALLY: Well, how do we get him out?
- We use Ketcham.
We give them Ketcham
and how long do you think
before Hendricks will have him back
and the rest of us too?
You and your dad-blamed
military mind.
You gotta know the answer
to everything.
- What'll we do?
- All right.
Us civilians ain't the fools
you Yanks think.
There's a fort at Longhorn Springs,
ain't there?
- That's right.
PHILLIPS: All right, you take him there.
And what'll Hendricks be doing
all this time?
He'd rather see Ketcham dead
than the Army get him.
You got something in mind, colonel?
Yeah. We don't take Tuscarora
out of jail,
we join him there, fort up.
You, Frenchy--
And I go into Longhorn Springs
and bring in the cavalry.
- That's smart for a captain, Frenchy.
- Thank you, sir.
You ought to be back
by late tomorrow afternoon.
If we run into any trouble,
we can hold out till then.
Stay on this trail till you hit the stage road,
then you take the west fork.
Good luck, colonel. Sir.
Uh, don't forget, colonel,
my thumb's getting kind of tired.
Let's don't go where there's no rocks.
My horse might stumble
and we have us an accident.
Let's go.
[DOOR OPENS]
TOM:
What are you doing here?
DEPUTY:
Thought you'd like to know
that we went out to Phillips
where I should take over.
We found Barter dead,
Mitten had a broken shoulder
and Chester had been coldcocked
pretty bad.
He said a girl drove in
that medicine show wagon.
He was looking it over
and that's about all he could remember.
So it could've been two or three of them.
The wagon was gone
and so was Phillips.
Anybody see
which way the wagon went?
DEPUTY:
No, couldn't find any tracks. Too dark.
Spence, you take five men,
go out and guard the north road.
Warden, you take a few more.
Leave some on the south road, close in.
The rest of you, go on out to the west fork.
Stop everybody going out and in.
Shoot anybody that tries to get by.
Now move.
What are we stopping here for?
McNALLY: Tuscarora's girlfriend.
Maybe I can find out how things stand.
Can you handle Ketcham?
If you hear a loud noise,
it'll be Mr. Ketcham dying.
[MARIA SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
McNally.
Mr. McNally.
- Oh, you got him.
McNALLY: We got him.
I'm glad.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
In case you don't know,
that's Spanish for "pig," Ketcham.
Much has happened tonight.
The men came from the Phillips' ranch
and told what you had done.
And the sheriff was very angry.
Would you like to see what he does
when he's angry?
Come in, then.
Amelita.
Show him. Show him.
Amelita?
Take a look.
Go on, take a good look.
- The sheriff did it.
- Why?
AMELITA:
To make me talk. To punish me.
He did it and then he laughed.
He laughed.
Someday I'm gonna kill him.
You'll have to beat me to it.
I'm gonna kill him someday.
Be careful. The sheriff has many men
outside hunting for you.
And others waiting for you in the jail.
Well, we've got the edge on him.
We got their boss.
- I will pray for you.
McNALLY: Good night.
Well, they don't know
we've got Ketcham yet,
but they know we've been out
to your place and got you.
So they'll probably be waiting for us.
Still wanna try?
With or without you, colonel.
McNALLY:
Well, that's good enough for me.
Move.
We're getting near the jail,
Mr. Ketcham.
My rheumatism's kind of bad, so don't
do nothing to put a strain on my fingers.
[LAUGHING]
McNALLY:
You in the jail!
Tell Hendricks to step out.
Blue Tom,
we got your friend Ketcham here.
And there's a sawed-off shotgun with
the triggers tied back right behind him.
He wants to tell you something.
Sergeant major, you louse this up
and you won't live to know it.
Talk.
Hold your fire, Tom.
Do anything he says. Don't try anything.
McNALLY: You hear him?
- I heard.
Get all your men out of the jail.
You heard him. Come on out.
Now everybody drop their guns.
What do you say, Mr. Ketcham?
Do it, Tom. For God's sake, do it!
All right, drop them.
Everybody ease over and keep going
till you're in front of that hotel.
Hendricks, you hold it.
There's still somebody in that jail,
Ketcham.
Tom, don't try it.
Get whoever's in there out.
All right, Barney, come on out.
Drop your gun
and get over with the rest of them.
You wanna step down, Mr. Phillips?
[PHILLIPS GRUNTS]
Hope this thing don't go off
while I'm climbing down.
Step off, sergeant major. Let's go to jail.
Don't worry, Mr. Ketcham,
we'll get you out of there.
Now, that's a good idea, sheriff.
Why don't you try it? Please try it!
No, don't try it, Tom. Whatever
you got in your head, you forget it.
He wants you to try something.
He's crazy.
He's right. Ha!
Got another barrel left. Get in there.
We'll be here a day, maybe two.
Then the United States Cavalry
will be here.
I should have taken you this morning.
You should have tried.
McNALLY: Tuscarora.
- Colonel.
Couldn't say hello this morning,
but I'm sure glad to see you.
How do you feel?
- Fine, except for some sore ribs.
McNALLY: Give me a hand.
I'll stay back here with Ketcham
in case his friends try something.
[LAUGHS]
Hey, don't you worry none, Ketcham.
You're gonna be the first to die.
Where's Captain Cordona?
He's gone for help.
How long are we gonna be here?
Till he comes back with the cavalry.
Douse that light.
[PLAYING UPBEAT TUNE BADLY]
Mr. Phillips,
is that the only tune you know?
I don't know this one,
that's why I keep practicing it.
[CONTINUES PLAYING TUNE]
Colonel, you have any trouble
getting back into town?
Well, they had men out,
but we had Ketcham.
You suppose they have men
watching the roads too?
Hendricks is not stupid.
What if they catch the captain
before he gets to help?
Well, then I'd say we're in more trouble
than we've been in
since we started this thing.
Mr. Phillips, is there any way
of getting you to stop that?
Yeah, I'd stop for a drink.
Well, if there's one, I'll get it for you.
[CONTINUES PLAYING TUNE]
Where do you think you're going?
[GUNSHOTS]
[HORSE NEIGHING]
In the jail.
This is Doc Jones, the dentist.
Can I come in?
Let him in.
You're taking a chance coming here.
No, I don't think so.
They're not even watching the place.
Don't bet on it.
Well, anyway,
I brought you some food and some beer.
Better see Ketcham gets a bite.
He don't get no beer, does he?
Neither do you,
unless you promise not to play that harp.
I'll stop.
[PHILLIPS CHUCKLES]
[KNOCKS ON DOOR]
McNALLY: Who's there?
SHASTA: Shasta.
[SHASTA PANTING]
What are you doing here?
I couldn't stand waiting, not knowing.
I took one of Mr. Prior's horses.
Nobody saw me.
MAN:
Hey, you in the jail.
- What do you want?
- I got a message for you.
But I don't wanna get shot
delivering it to you.
- What is it?
- Here it is.
McNALLY:
See what it is.
- Well, they got Frenchy.
TUSCARORA: Is he all right?
Evidently.
They wanna trade him for Ketcham.
If they got him,
there ain't gonna be no soldiers.
Where do they wanna make the trade?
They say there's a cantina and a barn
down by a creek
at the other end of town.
I know where that is.
Well, they say they'll be at the barn
with Frenchy an hour after sunup.
We're to start Ketcham
from the cantina.
- Is that all it says?
- That's all.
They don't say what they'll do
after we make the trade?
We'll there's four times as many of them
as there are us.
What do you think they'll do?
What's it gonna be, colonel?
Doesn't look to me
like we got much of a choice.
You that delivered the message,
you out there?
I'm here.
McNALLY: Well, tell Hendricks
we'll be there after sunup.
And tell him if we see anybody
on the way over there,
he's gonna lose his boss.
I'll tell him.
Anybody got the time?
Two hours to sunup.
Is there anything at all I can do?
Hadn't he ought to take
them water rights and deeds
and that stuff Ketcham signed?
He could get them back to the owners.
Yeah, doc.
They won't know Ketcham signed these
till after the trade.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot, all of you.
And I wish you luck.
Luck, he says.
We need more than luck.
We need a miracle.
How about it, sergeant?
Think you can pass one?
Colonel?
Don't seem like you wanna be the one
to say it, so supposing I say it?
It's time.
All right, bring him out.
Shasta, you'd better wait
four or five minutes after we're gone,
- then beat it over to your friends.
- All right.
And if we lose, get out of town quick.
Colonel.
I just wanted to tell you that--
I'll be safe.
Sergeant major,
you'd better wipe that smile off your face
or I'll do it for you.
Hold it a minute.
TUSCARORA: You folks better stay
at this end of town and you won't get hurt.
Look out.
It's all right, Colonel McNally.
They're friends.
What are you doing here?
They came to help.
They won't be much help
unless they're real good.
You got your land back.
Doc gave you the deeds, didn't he?
Sure we got our deeds back.
But what are they worth if you lose?
You men better know
what you're getting into--
Ketchum, we promised you in the trade,
but we didn't say anything
about what condition you'd be in.
[PHILLIPS LAUGHS]
Now, can any of you shoot?
As far as shooting goes,
Bide is a good shot.
You remember him. His bandage on
the captain's leg got you that headache.
Remember, colonel?
- I remember.
- We all fought in the war, colonel.
All right, you're in.
Somebody watch that back door.
You got more help than you think,
colonel.
There's men over there behind that wall.
Could take those fellas by surprise
and outflank them.
Bide, how deep is that creek?
Oh, it changes. Three, four, six feet.
- Deep near the bridge?
BIDE: Ought to be.
Colonel, I got an idea.
Can you hold up this trade,
give me a little time?
- Well, not for long, they know we're here.
- Bide, give me your gun.
McNALLY: What do you plan to do?
TUSCARORA: Ain't got time to explain.
Well, I can't hold up any longer.
Hendricks.
What do you want?
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
You start Ketcham, we'll send Cordona.
I'd like to take a look at Cordona.
Okay, bring him out.
Satisfied?
Whenever you're ready.
Hey, colonel,
he got where he wants to be.
All right, Ketcham.
Now, you're gonna walk across there
slow and easy.
Unloosen your belt.
What for?
To keep your hands busy. Walk.
That's far enough.
Hendricks!
Here's your man.
Move.
All right, take it nice and easy.
[BIDE WHISTLING LIKE A BIRD]
McNALLY:
Ketchum, hold it right where you are.
There's about six guns on you,
don't move.
Well, sheriff, what'll it be?
I want Ketcham.
McNALLY:
I want him too.
He's no use to you.
He's signed all those deeds
back to their rightful owners.
You're broke, both of you.
Is that right, Ketcham?
No, no, no, wait a minute.
Wait a minute, Tom.
- Is that right?
KETCHAM: He's lying, Tom. Don't shoot.
[GRUNTING]
You yellow--
[GUNSHOT]
McNALLY:
Ow!
[GUNSHOT]
Get back in here, you dang fool.
Ow! Take it easy.
Drop your squawking. You ain't hurt.
That gun's useless.
Don't mind if I shoot, do you?
Makes me feel better.
There's a lot more than three of them
out there, sheriff.
They're gonna be tough to run out.
Pete, you got the dynamite?
Not here. I got it where I can get it.
Can you use it on the cantina?
Throw it right through the window.
- Take Red to back you up.
- Come on, Red.
See those fellas?
They're trying to get around us.
Watch them.
- Colonel, the capt--
- I saw him.
Get a match.
[GRUNTS]
Holy! Look out!
We could have had that dynamite
in our laps.
Sure lucky I brought you along.
Ought to set them back.
Look out behind you!
Let's get out of here!
- Where you think you're going?
- We're licked, sheriff.
Come back here, you lousy--
Come on back here!
[GUNFIRE]
[TOM SCREAMING]
- Where you going?
- After Hendricks.
They're running, colonel.
Well, Hendricks can't run far.
Look out.
Glad you brung me, huh?
Spread out. This thing isn't over yet.
AMELITA:
Turn around, sheriff.
I want you to see who's gonna kill you.
[GUNSHOT]
[CRYING]
You got your town back.
I told you I'd kill him.
I told you, didn't l?
You told me.
I had a right to.
I'm gonna always wear this mark.
And every time I look at it,
I wanna know I had the right to kill him.
If you hadn't done it,
somebody else would have.
Now, you wanna give me a lift?
Mr. McNally, you...
- You make a person feel awfully--
-Please, don't say "comfortable."