[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC - "LAUGH YOUR TROUBLES
AWAY"]
Say that was swell.
How about another song?
Buck, if you've got all that
chirping out of your system,
Maybe you can get
back to the ranch.
Sure Dad.
I'm riding back right away.
I want you to go up
to North Fork Range,
See what's wrong up there.
What do you think is wrong?
I don't know.
I was up through
there the other day,
And there ain't hardly
a calf on the range.
And I don't think cows
have quit having families.
Maybe mountain lion's
been getting them.
I didn't see any lion tracks.
Well I'll scout around and
see what I can find out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Slow that critter,
don't waltz with him!
I got him.
Bring him in.
Hurry up.
We got to make tracks out of
here before we have visitors.
Here comes Buck Lawson.
Hit leather.
Leave that iron.
I want Buck Lawson to find it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Dad, it ain't
mountain lions that's
Been getting away
with our calves.
I jumped a bunch of
rustlers at work.
Rustlers?
And they left in
such a hurry they
Forgot their branding iron.
Keep RP, Tex Preston.
That's the way I read it.
Why that lowdown coyote.
I fought Tex Preston to a
standstill 15 years ago,
And it looks like he
ain't learned his lesson.
That branding iron fixed
things with the Lawson outfit.
Now let's go scare Tex Preston.
You boys know what to do.
Stay here and watch
for my signal.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Howdy, Bat.
Hello, Tex.
How's everything?
Things are not so good.
Seems like I'm
losing stock lately.
When I was riding
over this way,
I found a cow of yours
laying in the brush.
She'd been shot.
What?
Someone killing my stock?
It looks that way.
There was a calf hanging around.
Looked like he was
related to her,
But he carried Pop
Lawson's brand.
Well the lowdown
coyote, killing
My cow so he can
steal my calves.
Why I fought Pop Lawson to
a standstill 15 years ago.
You think he's know better
than to monkey with a buzz saw.
Mr. Preston I think to myself,
you're tired of eating beef,
So I cook you a nice duck.
Boy she looks beautiful
in the frying pan.
This comes from our prize stock.
Looks to me like somebody
ain't very friendly.
I got a pretty good
idea who did it.
No one ever asked me for
a fight without finding
Me willing to oblige.
Mr. Preston, I think for myself
again you have to eat beef.
Ducky, ducky.
Fritz, come here.
Fritz, come here ducky.
Nice duck.
Go away.
I don't want you.
Come here.
I won't hurt you.
Perfectly safe.
Can we not sit down somewhere
and talk things over?
Come here, Fritz.
Look at the nice corn.
I can eat myself.
Come here.
I won't hurt you.
Fritz, come here.
Ducky, ducky.
Come here, ducky.
Come here.
I just want to make
friend with you.
Look Fritz, it's getting
late for the boss's dinner,
And I'm getting tired.
Fritz, I only need
you for one minute.
Fritzy, come out.
I got something for you.
I got something nice for you.
[SCREAM]
Fritzy, you're around
here someplace.
You boys enjoy yourself while
we're waiting for the stage.
As I was saying,
I never thought
That Mrs. Clancy
could be so small.
You're absolutely right.
Well good bye.
Good bye.
Good morning, Mrs. Johnson.
Good morning.
Howdy, Tex.
Hello, Sheriff.
I'm warning you, Tex.
Don't start no trouble in town.
I won't hunt no trouble, and I
won't run away from it either.
Buck, there's no sense in
all you boys riding to town.
You scout around, keep
an eye out of rustlers.
But you might end up
with that Preston outfit.
If I do, I reckon I
can take care or myself.
I don't need someone
to ride hurt on me.
All right, Dad.
We'll head back.
Now don't forget
what I told you.
Come on.
Let's get those supplies.
Hello, Tex.
What are you doing in town?
My niece comes in
the stage today.
Your niece, huh?
Coming out for a visit?
No, she's going to
make a home with me.
Her folks died, and I'm
all the kin she's got.
She's not coming to
a very peaceful spot.
Oh it will be
peaceful all right,
When I do some
exterminating that
Needs to be done around here.
And you're just the
man that can do it.
Don't worry.
We will do it.
Come on.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC - "HEY, LOOK OUT"]
I want to talk to you.
What's on your mind?
You keep your nose
out of that fight
Between the Lawson
and Preston outfits.
Let nature take its course.
It's my duty to keep peace.
Your duty, if you're smart,
is to do as I tell you.
I'm grabbing myself a nice
bunch of cattle from both sides,
And each one blames the other.
I'll finally end up
owning both outfits.
[MUSIC - "HEY, LOOK OUT"]
What about that
money for the bank?
Is it coming in on the stage?
I stood for rustling
and a lot of dirty work,
But holding up the
stage might mean murder.
That's going too far.
If you don't like
my game, just say so.
The warden at the
penitentiary would just
Love to see you come back
and finish your time.
When a man wants
to go straight,
Why won't you give him a chance?
Cry about that some other time.
What about that money?
It's due to arrive
on the stage.
Now you're talking sense.
Beat it.
Well Bat, how's
everything working out?
Great, Nita.
I'll sure keep my promise and
load you down with diamonds.
I can carry the weight.
Bartender, my private bottle.
Yes, sir.
Coming up.
Will you be in
town for a while?
No, I got a little job to do.
The one I told you about?
Yeah, I just got some
information about it.
I'll see when I get back.
Be careful, will you?
Don't worry about me.
Come on.
Why you big ox!
What are your trying to do?
I can't help it, boss.
I schlitzed.
Well schlitz that
stuff into the wagon.
I'm going over to the barbershop
and get all cleaned up.
Good.
[MUMBLING]
[MUSIC - "SHE'S THE DAUGHTER OF
SWEET CAROLINE"]
That was mighty fine, boys.
Give her another whirl.
Sure will.
Curry me down, Sammy.
I don't want to scare my niece
by looking like an outlaw.
I'll make you
look Beau Brummell.
Oh you needed go
as far as that.
Don't strain yourself.
[MUSIC - "SHE'S THE DAUGHTER OF
SWEET CAROLINE"]
Pop Lawson and Preston
are both in town.
Pop Lawson just got in town.
Reckon I got to head
to the cyclone cellar.
If anybody in town's
got any calves,
They'd better watch them today.
I thought the county paid
a bounty on coyotes instead
Of letting them
run around loose.
Seems to me, I smell something
that should be buried.
Smells mighty like a polecat.
Why you...
I won't get shaved here today.
I might catch smallpox.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Here it comes.
I wonder who those hombres are.
Let's pick up their trail
and see what they're up to.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Stop that trouble.
Come on, men.
Beat it, boys.
Here comes trouble.
After them, men.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Are you all right, Miss?
I'm nearly frightened to
death, but otherwise all right,
Thanks to you.
You had a right to be scared.
Nobody would have found
that ride a pleasure trip.
Why it's outrageous that
a respectable citizen
Should be endangered like that.
I'll see that something is
done to put a stop to it.
That's a way for a man to talk.
I'll have the Sheriff
take you along
When he goes after
those outlaws.
He needs more men like you.
Lend me hand with
those fellows on top,
And we'll take the stage on in.
Someone will hang for this job.
Pete in there was a good man
and a good friend of mine.
Maybe you'd rather
ride on top with me.
Yes, I would if you don't mind.
I'm proud to have your company.
Hey cowboy, climb aboard
or we're going to leave you.
Hurry up!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
We missed a rich haul on
account of Buck Lawson.
Do we stand for that?
What do you think?
I think we send
Baby Face after them.
Sure boss, I'll make
smoked beef out of him.
Shut up.
Take it easy, Baby Face.
He'll get his.
Only we'll do it the smart way.
We'll have those two
outfits killing each other.
It's about time we run off
another bunch of stock.
Don't you see the dynamite,
you local maverick?
I hear the stage was
held up today, Sheriff.
They didn't get
anything, but they
Killed Pete and the
Wells Fargo messenger.
Hm that's too bad.
Sheriff, outlaws
have been mighty busy
Around here of late.
And I can't see where
you've done much about it.
You better not prod
the Sheriff, Buck.
He might take an interest in
all that gun smoke out your way.
That ain't just
according to law.
What a minute, Buck.
You're wrong, Bat.
Any man's got a right
to protect himself.
What's the matter, Nancy?
Forget something?
Oh no, I was just
looking around.
Well there ain't much
to see in this town.
We better get going.
All right, Uncle Jim.
But it seems I
should say something
To the man that
stopped the runaway.
The least you have to say
to him, why the better.
All right, boys.
We'll get started.
Buck, how about
riding with the posse?
I got an idea it would
be wasting my time.
Meaning anything in particular?
No, it just seems
that you don't
Have any luck when you
go hunting outlaws.
Dad, don't you think we
better get back to the ranch?
All right.
I don't admire that
remark Buck Lawson made.
He's too smart
for his own good.
I'm taking him out of
circulation before long.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Boss, we ain't been able to
round up enough prime beef
To make it worthwhile
sending a trail
Real herd to the railroad.
I bet I can thank
Pop Lawson for that.
And the Sheriff
must be on his side.
Why I'm being rustled poor and
can get no help from the law.
You better do something
about it pretty pronto.
I'll do plenty.
Put on more hands, but get
men that can sling guns.
I'll stop it.
I'll ride into town and see
what gunfighters I can locate.
All right.
[SINGING]
What's the matter?
Worried about something?
I was just thinking what
a fine world this would
Be if there wasn't
any Lawsons in it.
I think it's a pretty
nice place just as it is.
And I'm sure you're the
nicest uncle in the world.
Going for a ride again today?
You don't mind, do you?
Why bless your heart, no.
Go on and enjoy yourself.
Otto, I'm going for a ride.
Would you put up a lunch for me?
What would you like to eat?
Oh a half a dozen sandwiches,
some boiled eggs, and pickles.
Where are you going
to put all that?
In my saddlebag.
In your saddlebag.
And then where are
you going to put it?
In my tummy.
In your tummy, a
little girl like you.
Every day she gets
more appetite.
Oh I get terribly
hungry when I ride.
Yeah, I know.
It's the exercise.
You want two pieces of
cake like yesterday?
Yes, two pieces.
You make such wonderful cake.
I know.
[MUSIC - "DOWN ON THE SUNSET
TRAIL"]
[MUSIC - MISTER JACK AND MISSUS
JILL"]
Say that was mighty pretty.
Why didn't you
tell me before this
That you could really sing?
Can I?
The best I've ever heard.
Liar.
Honest.
Was that song for me?
Well there's
nobody else around.
Did you really like it?
Why certainly.
That is all but the finish,
the part about the wedding.
Oh I see, a woman hater.
Don't you ever think
of settling down?
Not until I stop this
feud between our families.
I hope you can, Buck, soon.
Oh let's forget
all this trouble
And just go on with our picnic.
Wait a minute, Buck.
I'm trespassing on
the Lawson range.
Aren't you going
to throw me off?
Well not until after
we've had this lunch.
Oh is that the
only reason why I'm
Welcome, just
because I feed you?
I'm not saying it is, and
I'm not saying it isn't.
In other words, you don't
believe in taking chances.
Well come on, I'll
feed you anyway.
A range war's like rolling
a rock down a mountain.
Easy to start, but
might hard to stop.
But you don't hate me,
and I don't hate you.
Why can't we be allowed
to live in peace?
We have the right to be happy.
We could have all that if
only we could make folks
Use common sense
instead of gun smoke.
Oh I better get
back to the ranch.
I tried to reason
with Uncle Jim,
But it only makes him angry.
He just won't listen to me.
We still can be friends
in spite of everything.
Just friends?
But there's a very serious
matter I want to talk to you
About just as soon as I get
this trouble ironed out.
I'll be waiting.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Is this the way
you ride the line,
Lollygagging with one
of the Preston breed?
Dad, she has nothing
to do with the quarrel
Between you and Tex Preston.
She's of the same breed.
And man or woman, I won't
have one of them on my range.
Dad, I don't take to that
kind of talk about my friends.
Please Buck, don't quarrel
with your father on my account.
If there's any quarrel,
it's of his makings.
Dad, if you're calling for a
show down, I'm standing pat.
If you favor my enemies,
you're not my son.
Go back Buck, and make
up with your father.
I can't come between you.
We'll work this out somehow.
I'll make those
two old warhorses
Understand some common sense.
If you don't mind, I'll
ride a ways with you.
All right.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Tex, your niece has been
riding out to meet Buck Lawson.
I think they're headed for town.
What?
I'll put a stop to that.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
You get home just
as fast as you can.
I don't allow no
Lawsons on my ranch.
Get before I make
a shiv out of you.
Uncle Jim, please.
Do as he says.
There won't be any trouble.
You promise?
I promise.
Now you make tracks
and make them pronto.
You're not afraid to shoot
it out with me, are you?
No, I'm not.
I dare you to talk to
me for five minutes.
Why I never took
a dare in my life.
Come on.
Start talking, and make it fast.
Tex, you think our
outfit rustled your stock.
I know you're wrong.
Well I've lost plenty of stock.
So have we.
Are you rustling from us?
I am not!
Hold on, Preston.
You agreed to talk
for five minutes.
Well all right.
We're both losing stock.
You blame us, and we blame you.
That don't make sense.
Doesn't it strike you as being
reasonable that someone is
Playing us against each other
and rustling from us both?
If you and Dad would stop this
fool war and work together,
We might find out who it is.
Even if I was willing, it
takes two men to stop a war.
If you'd only meet Dad halfway,
I know he'd be reasonable.
Buck, you sound
honest to me, and I
Believe you're
talking horse sense.
I'm glad you see
it my way, Tex.
I'll make Dad wash
off the war paint
And meet you in
town for a powwow.
Will you be there?
Sure.
So long, Tex.
So long, Buck.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Royce, Nancy!
Buck Lawson just killed Tex
Preston over on the south pass.
Shot him in the back.
Hit leather men,
and shoot on sight.
I'm sorry, Nancy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
How could he do
a thing like that?
You can't tell what a man
might do in the heat of anger.
You can count on me to
do all I can for you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC - "MISTER JACK AND MISSUS
JILL"]
[APPLAUSE]
Hello, sweetie.
I haven't seen you for so long.
Don't bother me.
I'm busy.
Sheriff, I got a job for you.
Yeah?
I reckon it won't be
anything I can be proud of.
What is it?
I want you to
arrest Buck Lawson
For the murder of Tex Preston.
Hey, hey hey!
I hear you've
been showing a lot
Of interest in
that Preston girl.
What I do is my own business.
Oh like this, eh?
Yeah, just like that.
That's where you're wrong.
You owe me plenty.
And don't get the idea you can
kick me off like an old shoe.
What will you do about it?
Stick around.
You'll find out.
I'm so sorry, Nancy.
Nan...
Stay where you are!
Get out of this house.
What do you mean?
What have I done?
Don't pretend.
Bat Haines said
you shot my uncle.
He lied.
Nancy, you can't believe that.
Oh I don't know
what to believe.
I left you talking to Uncle
Jim, and now he's dead.
That's what I came to tell you.
Only two people knew that
Jim Preston was killed,
Myself and the man who shot him.
Bat Haines and I
are due for a talk.
I want to talk to you.
Hold on, Buck.
I'm arresting you for murder.
On whose say so?
Bay Haines.
Hold on, Bat.
This man is in the
custody of the law.
I'll take those shooting irons.
We both know who
killed Tex Preston.
Yeah, but I know who's
going to hang for it.
Don't bank on that too heavy.
Get going.
If we could stop this rustling,
we'd pull out of the hole
All right.
But there's no chance to
raise any money right now.
Thank you.
That's all I wanted to know.
Your uncle was
talking about taking
On some more gunfighters.
I've located three or four.
No!
I'll have no more bloodshed.
Yes'm.
I think Bat Haines is
a snake in the grass.
Snake or no snake, he'll be
boss around here pretty pronto.
Oh yeah, boss around here.
Don't forget I'm the cook.
I'll fix him.
Why try to run a cow ranch?
That's no job for a woman.
Now as my wife...
No, that's out of the question.
What's the matter
with me as a husband?
Why some day I'll be the
biggest man in this county.
That has nothing to do with it.
Oh still hankering
for that half pint
That murdered your uncle, eh?
I don't believe he did it.
You mean I lied?
When two men tell a different
story, one of them lies.
All right.
I tried to be friends,
and for thanks
I get slapped in the face.
Your uncle owed
me a lot of money.
You better be
ready to pay it up.
You know I can't right now.
That's your worry.
Thanks, Otto.
I hope you get stomach trouble.
Otto, how many
times have I told
You not to eat so much pie.
Do you want to get sick?
I feel all right.
Hurry up and get ready.
I want you to ride
to town with me.
What's the matter, Bat?
You look worried.
What makes you think so?
Just the way
you've been acting.
Don't pay so much
attention to me.
Maybe the Sheriff
takes orders from you,
But no jury will come with
him if she's on his side.
Maybe we won't have a jury.
Men, we've got to take
things in our own hands
And take care of Buck
Lawson in our own way.
[MURMURING]
Nancy, it was
mighty nice of you
To drop in and see if they're
taking good care of me.
I'm sorry.
Is there anything I
can do to help you?
There's nothing to worry about.
They can't convict me of
something I never did.
Bat Haines is buying the drink.
Everybody chin up to the bar!
Nancy, Nancy!
They coming to take Buck
over to the gambling house
And hang him.
Who is?
The whole town, I guess.
Let him go and give him
a chance to save himself.
I can't turn a prisoner loose.
Would you keep him
here to be murdered?
They won't try
anything like that.
If I had a couple of the
boys from Dad's ranch,
I'd give them a run
for their money.
You'll have them.
What about the Sheriff?
He might object.
Oh he'll be reasonable.
Come on.
Let's get going.
What if I told this crowd
what I know about you?
[SLAP]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Wait a minute, Haines.
Don't forget, there's
a law in this town.
That's all right, Sheriff.
We figured to save
you some bother.
Come on, men.
Hurry, or you'll be too late.
Get the boys.
We're riding to town.
You're back of this, Haines.
You're not man enough
to fight it out with me.
Why bother?
This suits me all right.
Sentences you to be strung
up until you are dead.
Hold on, men.
Buck Lawson is innocent.
It was Bat Haines who...
[SCREAM]
Stay where you are!
From now on, I'm
playing a lone hand.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Stay where you are.
Turn around.
Take care of them, Dad.
I got a job to do.
Buck, wait!
I'll be right back.
Drop those gun belts, and
be careful how you do it.
Are you hurt bad, Sheriff?
It looks like I'm at
the end of my trail.
Haines did all the rustling
and caused all the trouble
Between you and Tex Preston.
And Nita was in with him.
You'll find him in a
cabin at Big Rock Canyon.
Round up all the boys.
We're heading for
Big Rock Canyon.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Go ahead.
You got it all your own way.
I'll give you an even break.
That's more than you did for me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Are you looking for Bat Haines?
Yes.
[LAUGH]
In about one minute, he'll be
scattered all over these hills.
Buck, Buck!
Some of you boys
take her to town.
Lock her up.
The rest come with me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
NANCY: Buck, Buck!
Are you hurt?
I don't think so.
But what happened?
You just missed being an
angel by about three seconds.
I think he's somewhat
of an angel right now.
What is this important matter
you wanted to talk to me about?
That's right.
I forgot.
Wait a minute.
Now.
[MUSIC - "MISTER JACK AND MISSUS
JILL"]