NARRATOR.: In all the world,
they were the greatest outlaws.
They were the greatest revolver fighters.
The greatest train, stagecoach
and bank robbers that ever lived.
Frank James was there,
armed with his Navy Colt and Bible,
and there was "Fancy Kid" Chadwell,
wearing his ten guns easy.
And Charley Pitts, the Ozarks Medicine Man.
And the wild Younger brothers.
Bob Younger, the youngest Younger, and
his brother, "Silent Jim," who had been
shot in the mouth by a bushwhacker.
Silent Jim only spoke with his guns.
Then there was big Clell Miller, the
mountain man, and of course, Jesse James.
Jesse James, riding side by side
with the great Cole Younger.
And they rode like the wind.
Even before the wounds
of the Civil War
had healed in Missouri, the railroads
came swarming in to steal the land.
Everywhere, men from
the railroads were driving
poor, defenseless families
from their homes.
(WIND HOWLING)
And that's when a fresh wind
suddenly began to blow.
It was other Clay County farmers,
the James and Younger boys,
coming to the rescue.
They tarred and feathered the
railroad men and drove them from the land.
From that moment onward,
they were outlaws.
But the people of Missouri would never
forget what the boys had done for them.
And that's why in 1876
the Missouri State Legislature
met in an extraordinary session.
These James and Younger boys
are called outlaws by some.
But to many more
they are heroes.
Now. I propose that a full and
complete pardon and amnesty
be granted to them.
(ALL CHEERING)
Let them go scot-free.
And let those who have pursued
them cease and desist immediately.
(ALL CHEERING)
And let these James and Younger
boys return to their homes
and their families
to lead fruitful lives,
so that we may have
peace once again
in Missouri.
(HORN BLOWING)
NARRATOR.: But the railroads had hired the
greatest detective of them all, Allan Pinkerton.
And here's where the true story
of the Northfield raid began.
Legislators are here to make laws.
We are here to make examples.
They're foolish to think that
fifteen years of criminal behavior
can be legislated away.
But in the event this amnesty
does come into being,
we'll already have done our duty.
They'll enjoy their amnesty
in the hereafter.
(ALL LAUGHING)
PINKERTON: Time is running out for
Cole Younger and Jesse James.
We're gonna infiltrate Clay County
and find them in their hideout.
We're gonna kill those
murdering James boys.
I can't think of one,
can you?
I've searched back through the
crannies of my mind and I cannot
think of one single honest man
we ever robbed.
Because we rob the robbers,
is why.
Just the railroads,
the banks,
all of them plug hats.
Talk about giving us amnesty.
Hell!
It's up to us to give
amnesty to them.
Could you hand me
some of that there, Jesse?
Surely.
What's this?
Chicago, Illinois.
North Platte, Nebraska.
The Athens of America.
What are these here for?
Cole put them in here.
He said now that
amnesty's coming,
his plans would be better served
by putting them in here.
Plans? This here's
ain't nothing but shuck.
They is raids, Jesse.
What do we want to go
behind enemy lines for?
Cole says they ain't
enemy lines anymore.
"Cole says." Cole?
That big rooster turned out to be
nothing but a little bitty chicken.
No enemy lines. There's enemy
lines and always will be, Frank.
Getting a little crooked
down there, aren't you?
"Calling all true-blooded
Americans. Come one, come all.
"Buckle on a wheat belt." Corn...
Wheat... Holstein cattle...
Dollar sign, dollar sign, dollar sign.
Got dollar signs clear across the pages.
Biggest bank west of the Mississippi.
Northfield, Minnesota.
What's this?
Cole put some writing on the back of here.
Four hundred and eighty miles.
"Disguise, cattle buyers."
Wear dusters.
Looks like Cole was planning
this raid before the amnesty.
That's a dumb-ass plan
if I ever heard one.
(MEN LAUGHING)
What's going on out there?
Even then, it took half a hundred
Yankees to do it. Well, sir?
When they cut Big John's head off,
they stuck it on a pole and paraded it
around town, waving it like Old Glory.
And that man, and this is
no Haziyappi, that man was so mean,
that his eyes gazing
down that pole
petrified three grown men
that looked too close.
Yes, sir, that was a day of wonderments.
That was a wonderment.
Come on, Cole, take off your shirt
so's we can see your bullet holes.
Oh, hell, ain't no different
than any other man's bullet holes.
Only difference is, some of them are
peeking through my lucky brace.
Show it to us.
All right.
Come on, Cole. Quit yapping
and let's get out of here.
I've been shot in it 14 times.
BOY: Look at that!
That old Cole, chasing birds.
Where'd you get it?
I got it in Kansas City
a few years ago.
Harnessmaker name of
J. Dudley Dobbs made it for me.
Made it out of quarter-inch leather,
sun-dried and brine-soaked.
Fourteen times
in fifteen years.
Makes a fella wonder if he
chose the right line of work.
Any damn fool can get himself
shot full of holes.
It ain't hard getting shot,
it's the getting back up.
BOY: How long you have to wear
your lucky vest, Cole?
Oh, all my life, I guess, son.
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh, that ain't bad.
Helps you sit up straight.
Still, there are worse things in life
than having something permanent.
Cole! You gonna wag
your tongue all day? Come on.
Yeah. See you later, boys.
This is a day that's been
ten years coming for me.
Ten long years.
From here on in,
you men are farmers.
Your job is to plough them
under like manure.
Now, get those
sons of bitches.
This is war, to the knife.
And the knife to the hilt.
You know, Bob, I believe I'm
gonna have to whip your ass.
Oh, yeah?
Yep.
You been wise-assing with
old Jesse and Chadwell
a bit much lately,
haven't you?
Well, at least Jesse James
ain't no chicken.
Yeah.
COLE: A fella wants to be careful who
he calls chicken. It's a little risky.
Even if it is his brother.
Especially if he ain't never shot a man.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
You ain't never shot a man,
have you, Bob?
No, I ain't.
Good. That's the best time to stop: Before you start.
Like old Comanche Tony.
Remember he used to ride with us?
Yeah.
Now, he was a good robber
and a good shooter.
Only one thing
he wasn't good at.
Yeah? What weren't
he good at, Cole?
MAYBELLE: Hold it, Cole.
What weren't he
good at, Cole?
Damn.
Hello there, Cousin Maybelle.
Boy, you look a treat.
Where you going?
I got no plans that
can't be altered.
Why?
I know how you love
to fix things, Cole.
And...
Yeah, well...
(STAMMERING) Well, you know the outlaws
always try to help a body.
See, the first thing an outlaw's
got to do is lend a helping hand.
Bob, you think that
I could fix that?
I guess you better, Cole.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah, that was the thing about
old Comanche Tony,
he never learned to laugh.
Had no sense of humor.
You know, a fella's got to look at
the sunny side of things all the...
(GUN FIRING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
BOB: Cole.
Cole.
WOMAN: One little Indian.
Two little Indians!
One named East,
and one named West.
The Son,
and the Father,
and the Holy Ghost.
In goes frost,
and out comes fire!
(SPITTING)
(WOMAN CHANTING)
Silk draws good
through bullet wounds.
Chimney soot.
That superstitious palaver ain't
going to do any good, Charley Pitts.
You got something better,
Frank James?
From the look of him, I'd say
a prayer would be better.
I got the Granny Woman working on it. She's
the best yarb lady in these here hills.
If she and Ezekiel can't do it, maybe
your prayer might come in handy.
WOMAN: In my own blood.
Live!
Yea, I say unto thee, live!
Come down here
and stole the land.
Come down here and they
blowed off my mother's arm.
And they killed John Younger.
And now Cole Younger.
They call this peace. Well, we're
gonna share that peace with them.
MAN: Amen.
I had me a vision.
I seen a Yankee city,
far to the north,
with the biggest bank I ever seen.
And I seen us all dressed up in
cattle dusters come riding
fine Kentucky blue-bloods,
riding into this
smug Yankee city,
this city of the plains,
built on the spoils of war.
And we're guerrillas again,
behind enemy lines.
And we make that Yankee town
weep! That Yankee town weep!
I seen a place called North.
A place called North.
A place called
Northfield.
Give me an "Amen," boys.
Amen!
Amen.
(WHOOPING)
Where's Jesse?
The boys are riding again,
Cole.
But we got an amnesty coming.
I told Jesse he was gonna have to
settle with me if he started things up.
Don't get up, Cole.
Got to, Charley Pitts.
Got to keep getting up,
cause if you don't, some son of a
bitch'll start shoveling dirt on you.
Wait for the return of some zeal.
I got zeal.
I got enough zeal to ride
in town and keep the peace.
They ain't in town, Cole.
Yeah? Where are they?
A place called Northfield.
Minnesota.
It come to Jesse in a vision.
That blinkey-eyed bastard.
Even his visions ain't his own.
I am gonna need some cures
and provisions from you.
For sprains, bunions,
ague and saddle rump.
I'll put some bugs inside
there, and dried cat's blood,
and mole pee
in your assifidity bag.
Charley Pitts,
you put this silver ring
in your ear.
A silver ring
to ward off the fear.
You got anything for me,
Granny Woman?
Winter wind is gonna blow.
Child's cry across the slough.
Don't go.
NARRATOR.: It was late summer
in 1876 when Cole
and Jim Younger and Charley Pitts
left Clay County and headed north.
Their first stop was Clell Miller's
mule farm in northern Missouri.
Hey, Clell.
Cole.
That damn Jesse told me you was dead
when they come by here yesterday.
He say anything about
where he was going?
No. Didn't say much.
Just said they was gonna buy
some cattle and settle down,
now that we're
getting amnesty.
Jesse's gone on a raid, Clell.
What?
Yeah. Going on a raid.
Now that we got amnesty coming?
That's right.
Going on a raid up
to Yankee land.
Just gonna rile up folks.
We're gonna try
to stop Jesse.
I'm going with you.
You got more than your mules
to think about, Clell Miller.
You're married folks.
Damn it.
I'm doing this 'cause of you.
So's you can rest easy, honey.
You told me you was through
riding with this gang of scum.
You'd best stay, Clell.
Hey Jim, let's take
a look at something here.
I want you to be able to travel
without being recognized.
You gonna put that mule tail
on him, Cole?
You got anything
to make this stick?
Yeah. I got some pitch
in my assifidity bag.
You handsome devil.
Looks good, doesn't it?
Miss Miller, ain't that handsome?
I ain't interested in handsome.
I'm only interested in decent. Doing
right's better than looking right.
Do you hear that,
Clell Miller?
All right. Let's go, boys.
(GUNS FIRING)
(WHOOPING)
COLE: Hey, Clell!
I snuck off.
I despaired of trying to make
that woman understand that
riding on a raid is one thing, while
riding to stop a raid is a whole 'nother
kind of thing entirely.
Kind of like a knightly crusade,
or a noble quest, huh?
Yeah. Besides that,
I got tired of
shoveling all that mule shit.
Well, let's ride, then.
Right! Kind of like
old times, ain't it?
I don't believe it!
Cole Younger,
alive!
This time I'll deal with him
personally.
What happened?
Indians. Probably Sioux.
When did it happen?
Early this morning.
COLE:
Blinkey-eyed little bastard.
CHARLEY: Jesse?
Yeah. Those soldiers were
pistoled close in.
No Sioux in the world would have left
that long blonde hair on that soldier.
He had a prettier mop than
George Armstrong Custer.
CLELL: Why would Jesse want to kill a
half a dozen soldiers like that for?
COLE: Guns. You know about Jesse.
He's got a thing about guns.
He never has quite enough
to satisfy him.
If we don't start hurrying,
he's gonna be using them again.
CLELL: How far away is this place
we're going to?
COLE: A couple hundred miles.
CLELL: Damn! My assbone's
gone to sleep already.
(EXCLAIMS)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
COLE: Hey, Clell, how'd you like to
ride your assbone on an iron horse?
(PLAYING HARMONICA)
"The fly wheel is connected
to the working beam..."
Horses all right?
Riding easy.
The stock ramp's this side of town.
The engineer knows to stop.
I can't wait to see old
Jesse's look when he sees us.
I can't get used to being on a
train that I'm not fixing to rob.
It's a bad omen using what you
fought against, you know.
I see you are a man who is interested
in the marvels of mechanics.
Here is something which I
would never forgive myself
if I failed to show you.
Watch the champions
fight it out.
There they go! Look at that.
Ain't that a wonderment?
Boy, look at that.
Got a bird there, too?
See him wag his tail?
Damn. Look at that.
Where are you boys from?
Oh, here and there.
Oh, nice place.
Yeah. We hated to leave.
(LAUGHING)
Now, I like a man who'll josh.
I tell you,
I've seen enough sour faces
and heard enough angry words
where I just came from
to last me a lifetime.
Where'd you come from?
Where you been?
Well, Missouri. Just got back.
What do you figure
makes them Missouri folks
so sour and angry?
Why, it's that amnesty vote
they just took in the Legislature.
I never believed I would
see so many elected officials
voting on the side
of cut-throats.
MAN: I vote yes!
(INAUDIBLE)
(MEN CLAMORING)
Mr. Beale from Jackson County.
I vote yes. Give them amnesty.
(MEN CHEERING)
DRUMMER.: It was at that moment
that the Speaker of the House
went into an emergency session.
Afterwards, some people tried to say
there'd been a shady deal made.
But if you ask me, it took great
courage for the Speaker of the House
to rule that entire
amnesty vote out of order.
Oh, a lot of those
Missourians were upset.
But they got to realize that
whoever breaks the law has got to pay.
Damned thieves.
Right.
Those outlaws
don't deserve amnesty.
I ain't talking about
the outlaws,
I'm talking about them
bribing railroad dicks.
Well, I don't mean to get into
an argument, gentlemen. I...
Gentlemen.
Looks like there ain't
gonna be no amnesty.
Looks like.
What're we gonna do, Cole?
CLELL: Yeah. What are we
gonna do, Cole?
CHARLEY: Ain't no need to
head off Jesse now, Cole.
What're you thinking on, Cole?
The biggest bank
west of the Mississippi.
CHARLEY: I don't like it here.
This place bodes ill.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Good day, Sheriff.
Passable.
You're cattle buyers?
That is correct, sir.
I could tell by your coats.
And what have you
got there, Sheriff?
Prisoners.
We're taking them up to
Stillwater Penitentiary.
What'd they do?
All sorts of things.
Riffraff.
Tramps come looking for work.
Got some rabble-rousers here,
too.
They look none too happy.
My hope is that I've helped put
them on the straight and narrow.
It would appear you have, Sheriff.
They have a straight and narrow look.
Examples must be made.
There's been a rash of disrespect, ever
since Jesse James invented train robbery.
Hell, Jesse James didn't
invent the train robberies.
Who did?
Why, I did, Sheriff.
(LAUGHS)
And I've got a bigger one
than Paul Bunyan.
I hope you enjoy your stay
in Northfield.
Thank you, Sheriff.
(SHERIFF SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
CLELL: Who in the hell
is Paul Bunyan?
CHARLEY: Goddamn Jesse James,
told people he invented
robbing banks in broad daylight.
Hell, you invented that,
too, Cole.
COLE: This world ain't fair
to thinkers, Charley Pitts.
Ain't that a wonderment.
That is a wonderment.
CHARLEY: "American Centennial.
One hundred years of Union."
Who they trying to shuck? Seems to
me they left out a whole civil war.
Union, hell.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
These people are celebrating
the American Centennial,
they ain't even Americans.
(WOMAN CHATTERING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Bunch of foreigners.
I think I'll play
first base today.
Bunch of pansies, too.
Ain't that a wonderment.
That damn train's
done jumped the track.
CHARLEY: There's the bank, Cole.
I brought it just to show you all
it's a pleasure to be doing business
with you here in Northfield.
I'd like to dedicate this first song
to all the folks of Northfield
who've done business with us.
And to those who will do
business with us in the future.
(SPUTTERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
We'll have it working soon,
folks. Come back later.
Just a few minor adjustments.
You said it would work.
It will. It will.
It better. You're making me
a laughingstock.
I'm not paying you
until it works.
Oh, hello there.
Good day, sir.
You're a stranger in town.
Yeah.
WILCOX:
Here on business, no doubt.
COLE: Yeah.
If there's anything we can do for
you at the bank, let us know.
Much obliged.
Your pressure gauge is stuck.
There's a spiral spring
in there...
Hey, get away from there.
Go on.
Well,
your pressure gauge is stuck.
That's got nothing
to do with it.
Now, don't touch anything.
It's dangerous.
Don't you want to shut it off?
Don't touch anything.
What will he think of next?
Mr. Wilcox will stop at nothing
to get money in his bank.
I read it was the biggest bank
west of the Mississippi.
Must be doing pretty well.
If you think that being on the verge
of closing down is doing very well.
Are you the president
of this here bank?
I happen to be the bookkeeper.
What'd you say your name was?
King.
Well, Mr. King, ever since the Panic of
'73, getting the public to trust in banks
has been the problem.
People see that banks close,
then they see depression
and inflation.
These people are hoarders,
because they don't trust in banks.
There. You see that man over there?
That's the landlord.
Richest man in Minnesota.
Does he trust in banks?
Carries it right around with him.
Mr. Wilcox has stopped at nothing
to get depositors for his bank.
And do you know why?
So that he can get the money, so that he can
enter into every wildcat scheme in this area.
First, he brings in a new
vault, with a time clock.
A time clock! Then he starts giving
away gifts, throwing lavish parties.
That didn't do any good.
And now this. Calliope.
That's the latest scheme.
I just don't like to see
people taken advantage of.
Wouldn't surprise me a bit
to see him skip town.
Widows' money! Poor people!
Poor farmers!
This man will stoop to anything
to get money in his bank.
And I have to stand there
and watch it all...
It's an interesting scheme,
Mr. King.
But where do you
take your profits?
Your bank wouldn't have a farm we
might use, would it, Mr. Wilcox?
You mean a recent foreclosure?
(LAUGHS)
Done and done, Mr. King.
I like the cut of your jib. You drive
a shrewd bargain, but why not?
Everybody's doing it.
From Jay Gould and Jim Fisk
right on up to
President U.S. Grant himself.
After all, it's a game of wits.
Survival of the fittest.
But... But do you think
they'll fall for it?
Give it a try.
What can you lose?
I can lose a bag of gold.
That's why I'm sending along
Mr. Bunker here, as protection.
Just in case your friends
prove to be untrustworthy.
You understand, of course.
Oh, I understand, Mr. Wilcox.
Well, partner,
we better get moving if we're gonna
put that money in your bank.
Right, partner.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Cole Younger. In Minnesota.
Turn this train around.
We're going to Minnesota.
So they're heading north, trying to get
away, now that amnesty is cut off.
This time luck won't be
on his side.
This time there won't be
a next time.
No, sir.
Don't need any help
from anybody.
No, sir.
I can manage myself.
NARRATOR.: On September 5, 1876,
after traveling
more than 400 miles,
Jesse James
had come to Minnesota.
In the Panic of '73,
we lost everything.
In '74, the locusts
come swarming in.
Then the damn politicians come
swarming in and then the railroads.
The next year,
influenza took my Harvey.
Last thing he said to me was,
"Lottie,
don't sell the children."
Children's all I got left. And I ain't gonna
sell them, not even for the mortgage.
It took us years
to get the children.
Would you like to see them?
I was just packing them when you boys rode up.
They're in the trunk.
FRANK: No, that's all right.
They come from
all over the world.
My Harvey called him Samuel.
People come from all over here to
Hanska Slough to see the children.
That darn landlord give you till
noon today to be on your merry way
if you don't pay the mortgage.
Yankee bastard.
And all because
you owe him how much?
Eighty dollars. But I
ain't selling the children.
Darn right you ain't gonna
sell the children.
Frank, you give her
a hundred dollars.
No, young man, I ain't come to
that, I ain't taking your money.
Well, ma'am, maybe you'd let
us adopt little Sammy Boy.
He'll have a good home. And
you'll be able to stay here.
God bless you.
I ain't taking
a cent more than eighty.
I know you boys are trying
to do me a good deed.
I want to tell you something.
Watch yourselves.
Crooks and robbers
are everywhere.
I want to repay you.
Where do I write you?
Let's go, boys.
BOB: Thieving landlord bastard!
That sure was nice of you,
Jesse.
One of the first things
an outlaw's got to learn is to
lend a helping hand.
I heard Cole say that.
He must've learned it
from Jesse.
My brother Jesse's
near to a saint.
Only robs the robbers, huh?
JESSE: Landlord!
Landlord, you're driving women
and children from their homes.
I don't want to do that.
I'm just doing
what has to be done.
If I allow one person
not to pay, well...
Landlord,
I'm selling this doll to you.
I'll pay.
How much do you want for it?
I want everything you've got.
He was going for his gun,
Jesse.
I'm Jesse James. My brother
Frank, Bob Younger, Chadwell.
There's a lesson for you, Bob.
No one should be able to identify
a guerrilla in enemy country.
Besides, he's a Yankee.
Best pick up that doll.
Else they'll think the old woman
bushwhacked him for the rent.
Hell, she's a Yankee, too,
Bob.
There's another lesson
for you.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Gentlemen, I'd like you to meet
Mr. King, cattle buyer from Missouri.
Mr. Allen, Mr. Manning,
Henry Wheeler.
Henry's gonna be a doctor.
(ALL CHEERING)
You mean you've never seen
baseball before?
That is correct, sir.
It's all everybody's doing, nowadays.
It's our national sport.
That's true.
It is our national sport.
Our national sport, gentlemen,
is shooting, and always will be.
You don't have to carry
a rifle around here, Mr. King.
You're in Minnesota now,
not your outlaw state.
Well, that is irony, sir.
For only yesterday,
I was waylaid by rogues
just outside of town.
What? Outside Northfield?
That is correct, sir.
Ruffians tried to rob me
of my gold.
And that is why
I'm carrying this rifle.
Is that so?
I've heard there's
a gang of thieves around here.
A number of people
have had their life savings
stolen right out
from under them.
I haven't heard a word about that. Have
you heard anything about that, Manning?
No! Robbers around Northfield?
This man is saying there are
robbers in the area.
I tried to contact
your sheriff.
He's taking a bunch of tramps
up to Stillwater Penitentiary.
At any rate, I'm putting
my gold in the bank.
Safest place in town.
Well, may be safe
against bank robbery,
it's not safe against
bankruptcy.
You don't know what you're
talking about, Manning.
No? You got no gold in your bank, Wilcox.
Money's got no security there.
Mr. Manning, I think you're
in for a little surprise.
(EXCLAIMING)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
I got it, I got it.
MAN: Throw it in, man!
Throw it in!
MAN: Safe!
I got it, I got it!
I got it!
I got it. I got it.
I got it! I got it!
Out. He's out.
Come on,
get back here and fight!
ALLEN: Out!
Throw the ball away.
Get rid of that.
Don't let him get the ball!
We'll lose the game!
Stupid!
(GUN FIRES)
(MAN WHOOPS)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
We win. We win.
Crybaby!
Bunch of sore losers!
Go on home!
You come back to Northfield, we'll
really show you a thing or two!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Look at them run.
That's a nice shot.
I guess we showed
those Saint Paul boys.
I'd sure like to see
some more of that.
So would I.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Faster, damn it. Nothing
can go wrong this time.
Their fate is sealed.
They're doomed.
Doomed.
(GUN FIRING)
All right.
Now, Henry,
I want you to nestle her up
into your shoulder like she was
the sweetheart of your dreams.
Now, tickle her trigger
and say,
"President U.S. Grant's mother."
HENRY: President U.S. Grant's
(MOUTHING)
Mother.
(MEN LAUGHING)
She's pulling to the right,
Henry.
Now,
remember,
relax your eyes
before you pull it.
(MAN WHOOPING)
Mr. Wilcox, will you come
and open the bank?
I've got the gold shipment
here.
ALLEN:
What gold shipment is that?
What's going on here, Wilcox?
I'm glad you got through,
Bunker.
There's been a rash of
robberies around here of late.
Let's get that money into
the vault where it will be safe.
You mean all of that is gold?
(PEOPLE GASPING)
Dog drag a mule!
I don't believe it!
Just don't anybody touch that.
It's going in the vault
of the First National Bank.
And we're seeing to it.
As a special gesture
to the people of Northfield,
the bank will be open today,
Sunday, to receive your deposits.
With due respect to the Lord,
sir, I'm putting mine in today.
Very wise, sir.
So am I.
Me, too.
(ALL CLAMORING)
(GRUNTS)
Well, your housing's loose.
I think I can fix that.
I can make a little wooden shim.
Hey, hey get...
I can stick it right in there.
Don't touch anything.
I'm an expert.
I know what I'm doing.
All right, sir.
Well, guard,
is that the final deposit?
Hey, you don't mind my asking, do you?
How come you got that earring on your ear?
Allen, you got a way of embarrassing more
strangers that come to Northfield...
I'm just asking because it looked funny
to see a man with an earring in his ear.
Especially a bank guard.
A silver ring
to ward off fear.
What? What'd he say?
He says he wears it
to ward off fear.
What the hell language is he talking?
I can't understand a word he says.
That wards off fear, huh?
That might be a selling point.
Say, I'd be interested
in about a gross of those.
How do they go? In pairs, or you
always just wear one like that?
Listen, there could be
a market for a thing like that.
Are you selling those?
Don't mind him.
That's just Crazy Gustavson.
His boy went marching off to
war and never come back again.
It's been ten years now,
and Crazy thinks that every stranger
in town might be his boy, Willie.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
No, it ain't Willie,
Gustavson.
No Willie. No.
Willie?
Just ignore him. He doesn't
understand a word we're saying.
He's harmless. He's crazy.
"Ja," crazy.
The stare of a crazy man's
bad luck.
Make him stop it.
Oh, here, wait. Look.
Get out of here! Scram!
You crazy squarehead!
You see that? You throw
a stone at him and he goes away.
One thing we like to do around here
is make strangers feel at home.
You just let us know
if he bothers you any more.
All right, folks.
You can come in now.
Better learn to keep a few stones in
your pocket while Crazy's around.
What did that man say
about stones?
Nothing. They don't know nothing. Just
having their fun with a crazy man.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Hey, don't touch that.
It's steam. What are you...
Creep! Get out of here.
Go on. Git! Go on! Git!
Folks. Folks, I'm sorry.
We're closing for lunch.
ALL: No! No!
Please!
We'll be back in an hour.
That's right.
We'll take all your deposits in an hour.
Just be patient, please be patient.
Okay, folks. See you later. Thank you.
Thank you, guards. Thank you.
Closing for lunch, now.
You must let us in.
All of this gold coming in
so suddenly?
Don't you think
we ought to count it, Bunker?
Don't worry about it, Heywood.
Mr. Wilcox and I will take care of that.
But I...
After we've taken all the deposits.
Now, you have a nice lunch,
Heywood. All right?
COLE: Now, she's been pulling
to the right on you, son.
But with this new attachment,
she ought to pull to the left.
Now, you got yourself a real
one-eyed scribe.
All right, come on over here
and I'll show you again.
Remember, get your feet set,
haul her up to your shoulder,
bunker your head down,
and you got yourself a proper
man-stopper.
Here she is, Frank.
City of the plains.
Yankee Gomorrah,
built on the spoils of war.
Reminds me of the time
we rode into Lawrence, Kansas
during the war with old Charley
Quantrell, flying the black flag.
Lord, we done ourselves proud.
Greatest guerrilla raid of all time.
Must have killed a thousand
jayhawkers that day.
Later on, they tried to say we
killed some women and children,
to try to make us look bad.
I didn't see no damn women
and children.
You, Frank?
I didn't see any.
None that was white, anyway.
What's that there?
It's called a calliope.
Cole?
What the hell you doing here?
You boys hear about my vision?
What kind of vision?
I had a vision about robbing the
biggest bank west of the Mississippi.
I ain't heard that one, Cole.
That's 'cause
it ain't happened.
Yet.
Howdy, there, Jesse.
(LAUGHING)
You boys look like
you could use a bath.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Hey, now, boy!
You know, I think we're Northfield's
most prominent citizens
now we got that bank
filled up.
CLELL: That's true.
And we're the guards.
BOB: My, oh, my.
The whole country's gonna talk
about this forever and ever.
FRANK: I'm gonna write it up and
send the story into the paper.
COLE: Oh, this is good in here.
Oh, this is warm. Nice. Good.
Them rocks get that water
all that hot?
(CHARLEY SCREAMS)
Old Frank getting wet!
(MEN LAUGHING)
Look at him.
Come on, Jesse.
Come on.
Tomorrow, we're gonna make
this smug, Yankee town weep.
We're gonna blow it
to kingdom come.
No, we ain't either, Jesse.
Only a fool smokes up a town
when it ain't necessary.
We're gonna
walk into that bank,
make a withdrawal from
my partner, Mr. Wilcox,
and walk out without
a shot or a shout.
It's not like this here's
a business transaction, Cole.
This is a guerrilla raid.
We ain't in it for the money.
Well, you're wrong,
Cousin Jesse.
We're in it 'cause of pride, 'cause
it's right, to show the world.
You know what
this here's all about?
It's about amnesty, and
amnesty's about our freedom.
Amnesty? I thought you said
the amnesty got voted down.
That's right. They bought it away
from us, we're gonna buy it back.
That means raising the ante,
and that means one thing:
Robbing one more bank so we won't
have to rob no more banks.
Gotta work on that one for a while, Cole.
Don't bother, Charley.
Been working on it last couple of days, and
that's the way it comes out every time.
Well, no matter. We'll be
around a campfire tonight,
planning and telling stories
like old times.
Hell, Jesse, we're gonna celebrate.
We're gonna celebrate before the raid,
we're gonna celebrate after the raid,
and we're gonna celebrate the raid.
And tonight, I'm gonna treat
you boys to something special.
There's a little place of
light love called Mankaty Kates.
(ALL WHOOPING)
That ain't the way to do it. We ain't going.
Yeah, no need for girls.
Girls, all kinds of girls.
Come on, boys. Come on.
I'm ready.
On my way.
Get your ass back here,
Chadwell.
Oh, boy.
Home sweet home.
The place I wanna be.
(MEN LAUGHING)
No more deposits today.
I guess the whole town's
put their money in.
(CLATTERING)
HEYWOOD: Stones!
Stones!
Stones.
You! You... You tricked the whole town
into putting their money into the bank.
I knew this had to be
some lousy scheme.
Heywood, you keep your mouth
shut about this, you hear?
Bunker, you were in on this.
Heywood, if the bank closes,
we're out of a job.
Heywood, I did it for you...
You keep your mouth shut!
...and the people's money...
Don't say another word...
Heywood, listen to reason!
(SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
MAN: Rustoff,
let the whores go now.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Hello, Clell.
I shouldn't have done that.
(LAUGHING)
She's pretty, but I'm married folks.
It ain't right.
Yeah.
You feel that way, Clell, maybe you
should've thought of that before.
Well, I did.
Before, during and after.
Damn near
spoiled the whole thing.
Rather gone frog gigging.
Jesse was right.
On a guerrilla raid
you gotta live clean.
Jesse always had a kind of a
sickness borne within his soul,
he always kind of had
something against womenkind,
particularly young ones.
I don't know why.
Yeah, it is a funny thing,
you know, how Jesse never did seem to
have too much to do with the ladies.
Ain't you forgetting
Zerelda Mimms?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, Zerelda.
Yeah.
That's right, Bob,
that's right.
Yeah. Even a blind chicken
will pick up some corn.
(LAUGHS)
(HUMMING)
Damn. Look at that Jim.
He's a good dancer.
You know, Jim used to be
a hell of a storyteller.
Ain't that a wonderment.
What is a wonderment?
A wonderment?
A wonderment's
a thing of wonder.
Something to behold.
Something rare and good.
Could be a beautiful picture
or a pretty song or...
Or a feeling.
(LAUGHS)
Sounds a mite precious.
It is.
You know there's a revolution
going on right now with machines?
Machines?
Machines.
Run by steam
and oil and electric.
Here last March, a fella named A.G. Bell
registered in the United States Patent Office
a contraption where a man's voice
can be heard over a mile away.
That is a wonderment, Kate.
Hey, honey, what's the matter?
No more, okay? I'm tired.
MAN: Rustoff,
let the whores go now.
Hey, Cole, come here.
I got something for you.
I know, but I... Come on.
What?
I got you something.
It'll give you real zeal.
(SCREAMS)
I'm dying of rupture.
(GROANING)
Damn, I hope that gives me some
zeal, because that is terrible.
Cole, you was
supposed to rub it on!
What's the matter?
I'm trying to decide
whether to kill you or not.
Do you feel anything?
(SIGHS)
No, I don't feel anything.
Here she comes, Cole!
CHARLEY: I've got the world's greatest
whore-lugging man right here now, folks.
Now, give him room. Give him room.
Get your money out.
Take your bets right here.
How much you got?
Ten?
MAN: Let's start with one!
Stay on your feet, Cole!
Two! Three!
Lug them whores, Cole.
CLELL: Six. Seven. Stay on your
feet and we got the money.
Look at them whores go.
Ten!
(ALL CLAMORING)
KATE: One at a time, girls.
One at a time.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It looks like rain.
We better get these sheets in.
(CACKLING)
See you later, Kate.
I doubt it.
Looks like you're taking
your business elsewhere.
That ain't business, Kate.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I'll take a king now.
Hold it a minute, boys.
(BELL TOLLING)
No.
Hold it.
We're just
making a withdrawal.
Mr. King. Mr. King.
What's going on here?
This isn't part of our deal.
Tell these men...
Mr. King, tell these men
to put their guns down.
Tell them we're partners,
Mr. King.
Look, don't you see...
You don't understand. I...
Tell him to open it.
Open it.
These men mean business,
you fool!
You can't call me a fool, Mr. Wilcox!
You're all a bunch of crooks.
This is your scheme,
this is your business deal.
Now that everybody's
put their money in the vault,
you want to stage
a false holdup.
Heywood, open it.
Open it or you're fired.
Fired? I quit.
Besides, the time lock is set.
Tell him to open it.
Open it now.
COLE: Hold it.
I trusted you, Mr. King.
Don't hit me anymore, please.
Hit him.
Willie?
He's just a crazy old man.
Get out of here!
Nice try, fella.
Hell, the damn thing
ain't even locked.
Get in there, Chadwell. Get in there.
Get your ass in there, Chadwell.
(GIBBERING)
Go on, you old fool.
Get out of the rain.
(CALLIOPE BLARES)
(GUN FIRES)
(CALLIOPE BLARING)
No, damn it,
the time lock is set!
Open that damn door!
Get out of here, all of you.
This is one scheme
that isn't gonna work.
Chadwell.
I'm gonna get you out.
What are you doing, Jesse?
Chadwell!
Jesse James!
I'll get you out, bud!
Oh, Christ, no.
(BLARING CONTINUES)
It works.
The damn thing works!
It looks like Crazy Gustavson
is working it. It works!
We busted flush. It's locked.
Bank robbery! Bank robbery!
Bank robbery!
President U.S. Grant's mother.
I'll get you out, Chadwell.
Goddamn it! Jesse!
We're flying! Come on!
They are trying to steal our money.
Come here, men, get these guns.
Here, load up.
Let's get 'em while we can.
(GUNS FIRING)
Damn it, you didn't have
to break my window!
I got one.
I think we're out of guns!
Come in here and rob our bank,
will you?
Lead in your belly, you...
Teach you to rob our banks!
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Bunker, get out of there.
Jesse James.
He's robbing the bank.
Get him out of there.
He's robbing the bank!
Get out of here!
Jesse James!
(GUNS FIRING)
They're coming back.
(BLARING CONTINUES)
(BLARING STOPS)
Bunker said something about it being Jesse James.
Can you believe that?
Oh, Jesse James and Cole Younger
don't ride this far north.
They're robbing the bank!
Look at that.
ALLEN: Oh, that poor old guy.
He was perfectly harmless.
How could they do
a thing like that?
I've got one of them
trapped in there.
They killed Heywood
in cold blood.
He died a hero.
We'll build a monument to him.
He saved our money.
Well, come on.
He saved all your money.
I told you it was
the safest place in town.
Can't you get that vault open,
Wilcox?
Well it has a time lock.
It'll open when it's ready.
It should be in a few minutes.
I hear ticking.
Now, you people get outside. Go on.
Go on. I'll handle this.
Damn it, Wilcox, you open that safe.
He is in there with our money.
I hear a click.
By God, we'll teach him
to come up here.
Shut up.
(SHUSHING)
(GUNS COCKING)
Jesse?
(GUNS FIRING)
WILCOX:
Now, get him out of there.
Quick.
Now, hurry up.
Let's get this vault closed before
anyone else tries to get our money.
ALLEN: Get horses. A posse.
Let's get them.
MANNING: Let's send a telegram.
Warn every town in Minnesota.
Here's another one.
Is he hurt or dead or what?
Get him up. He's got to notify every
town between Madelia and Mankato.
Should we tell them who it was?
I still can't hardly believe that myself.
Cole Younger.
Say cheese.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(SCREAMING)
Customers coming, girls.
(GUNS FIRING)
I want every man in that house
out here right now.
Let's hold 'em.
You. What are you doing here?
We're cattle buyers.
That story's getting old,
fella.
I got two of them,
trying to make a run for it.
Yeah. It looks like they're
running from something.
Got something to hide, huh?
He's one of them.
I'm almost sure of it.
Might as well get rid of all the
scum around here, while we're at it.
MAN: Right.
Move.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
(GUN FIRING)
Jesse, what've you done?
You can't leave horses to die like that.
I done them a kindness.
Your kindness could be
heard for miles, you damn fool.
Don't talk to me
about being heard.
That contraption you fixed
is what got us into this mess.
Yeah, Cole. That was the
dumbest thing I've ever seen.
(GUNS FIRING)
Hold your fire.
I think we got them.
They're coming out.
When you see Cole Younger,
shoot.
(MAN SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
What's he saying?
He says we wounded
two of them, but...
Well, he says they're the Shieldville
posse looking for Jesse James.
Damn it!
(EXHALES)
I thought it was them.
Yep.
Shieldville?
Well, they weren't much of
a match for us, were they?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Cobwebs, poultice of polecat
weed what we need now, Bob.
That'll stop the bleeding.
Now lie still.
Smarting's a sign of healing.
Cole?
Yeah, Bob?
Cole, there's a chilly wind.
Bob, you're looking better.
Time to be moving on.
Sure.
Let's get going.
Stay right there, Bob.
We're gonna lay low
until you're ready to go.
We ain't listening to you,
Cole.
This raid was your idea.
It was a damn fool scheme.
You got us into this mess
and I'm getting us out.
We stay here, and they're
gonna get us by the smoke.
He's right, Cole.
Besides, wood fries and sings like that,
it's a sure sign a bad rain's gonna fall.
Oh, that's just superstition.
That don't mean anything.
It's the truth. It don't
have to mean anything.
You're more in need of religion
and less in need of
superstitious babble.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
You gotta abide by the signs.
Shut up, Charley Pitts, I'll not be witness
to a man who brags when he gets lucky.
Boys, we're almost home.
Easy, Jesse.
Frank, I got me a vision.
Same scoundrels that took his doll,
Sammy, and broke open his head,
shot us all up
for no good reason.
Appears we can't get no
hospitality in this region.
Swarming with killers.
Well, they ain't coming in here. You
boys make yourselves comfortable.
After what you done for me.
This lady's like
a second mama to me.
He tells me there was a fight.
What was it about?
Oh, just a fight over
some money, ma'am.
Ain't that always the way?
Thank you, Mother.
Thank you, ma'am.
(LAUGHING)
Charley Pitts?
We sure showed them Yankees.
Right in broad daylight.
You see the looks on their faces when
they heard the name Jesse James?
Men fainted dead away
when they heard "Jesse James."
We lost Clell Miller
and Chadwell, Mr. James.
We got more than that
out of them, hoss.
Besides, you got to expect to lose
a few, you go on a guerrilla raid.
The purpose is to show them
Yankees the war's still going on.
This raid will be talked about
forever and ever.
By them or us?
Time to be moving.
This lady here's
got some horses and a wagon.
Ought to get us
over the state line.
Bob can't go, Jesse.
Bob can't go, then
we gotta leave him behind.
Mother here will take care of him.
This here's the safest place for him.
Safe for him, safe for us.
Cole, buddy, we run out on
Chadwell back there in the bank,
and we run out on Clell Miller
back there, too.
Now, Bob's your brother. My
brother, Frank, he'd understand.
Sometimes one's gotta be left behind
so the rest can move right along.
Let the dead bury the dead.
Why, Jesse's just saying
what the Lord said, Cole.
Bob ain't dead, Jesse ain't
the Lord and we ain't going.
Yet.
I been studying this here map.
According to the map, we're in
a place called Hanska Slough,
right near Winona
and Saint Peter Railroad.
Hole up until
Bob feels better,
put him on a train,
and go on home.
ALLEN: They must have got away.
I say we head for home.
MAN: Just a little longer.
Just got to look a little longer.
Just ain't got things
I need, Cole.
Fever root, rattle snake root.
I'm gonna get a doctor.
Charley Pitts?
He lives quite a ways,
but he come to my Harvey when we
was in need, and tended to him.
He's a good man.
I know we can trust him.
You watch the children.
She's going for a doctor.
Well, it's about time.
Bob needs something more
than that heathen medicine man.
Why don't you boys
come in and sit?
We're sitting just fine
right here.
You get some sleep.
We'll keep an eye out.
You know, Frank, it ain't right for a
lady to drive around these roads alone.
Specially with all these scoundrels
and night coming on and all.
The boys can watch out
for themselves.
We gotta look out
for little Mother, here.
You know, I sure wish
we'd got those boys.
Yeah. Tell you what, though,
sure gonna have some stories
to tell this winter.
Say, what's that?
What was that?
Just a doll.
Sounded like
the winter's wind to me.
WOMAN.:
Child's cry across the slough.
(GUN FIRES)
(GUNS FIRING)
(GROANING)
Better cover up
them bloodstains.
You know, Frank, we gotta get ourselves
a new gang when we get home.
We can get Jim Cummins,
some of them boys over at Fred Meffert's
Saloon over there in Liberty.
Yeah.
And what's that good-looking
young kid's name? Bob Ford?
Yeah. Bob Ford.
We can get him.
Yeah. I think
he'd fit in just right.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Now we're going to get
Cole Younger and Jesse James.
Remember, men, my reputation
is at stake. Now, get out there.
MAN: Henry Wheeler.
WOMAN: "Ja," you saved our money, Wilcox.
You saved it.
MAN: We showed you,
didn't we?
MAN 2: Rotten scum!
This sure will teach you
to come to Northfield!
(PEOPLE HECKLING)
Jesse's gone to get help,
ain't he, Charley Pitts?
Look at that one.
He's ugly.
MAN: Thieves! Thieves!
All of you, thieves.
Look at that man!
NARRATOR.: Northfield
was the boys' last ride.
Charley Pitts was dead.
Jesse and Frank got away.
And six years later Jesse James
was shot in the back
by a young man named Bob Ford.
Cole Younger had been shot
11 more times at Northfield.
That made 26 times in all.
WOMAN: He's getting up.
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
That's Cole Younger,
leader of the gang.
WOMAN: What is he doing?
I can't believe it.
Look at that.
MAN: Go on, you can do it.
MAN 2:
His name is Cole Younger.
Attaboy, Cole! He did it!
Look at that!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Ain't that a wonderment.
(CALLIOPE PLAYING)
NARRATOR.:
The people of Minnesota cheered him
all the way to the gates
of Stillwater Penitentiary,
where they locked him up
for 25 years.
And Cole Younger lived
right on up to 1916.
He saw a whole new era
come into being.
But at Northfield,
his outlaw days had ended.