353,015.
That's how many babies
will be born today.
It seems weird to me that
they weren't here yesterday...
That they didn't have
their parents
and their parents
didn't have them...
That this is
their first day ever.
353,015.
[ Babies crying ]
Nathan: Hey, buddy.
How you holding up?
Fine.
How's mom?
She's good.
She's being prepped, and
they're getting her her room,
and pretty soon,
you'll have a baby sister.
How long does that take,
dad?
That's hard to say.
But I'll be with her.
You're gonna hang out with Clay
and Aunt Quinn, okay?
Okay.
I want to stay, though.
I don't want to go home
until mom's okay,
and Lydia, too.
You sure?
Could be all night.
That's fine.
I feel pretty strongly
about it.
All right.
Well, then,
I have respect that.
You, my man,
are not a baby anymore.
Nope.
But they are.
[ Babies crying ]
♪ Looking for reasons,
find that I'm... ♪
Dad, do you remember
when I was born?
Yeah.
I sure do.
It's a boy.
You're a dad!
You did so good.
We have a son.
Here he is.
[ Crying ]
Welcome to the world,
James Lucas Scott.
Oh.
He's so beautiful.
♪ And I'll be waiting, waiting ♪
♪ waiting, waiting,
waiting up ♪
Hi.
We're having a baby.
Honey, you do understand
it takes about nine months.
Of course.
What we meant to say is --
we're adopting a baby,
and the girl who's having it
is having it.
Yeah.
Here.
Now.
Somewhere.
Okay. Well, first of all,
congratulations.
And give me a second, and I'll find
you that room for you, okay?
Thank you.
Hi.
There's my guy.
Ooh.
You ready to be
a Big Brother?
Yeah.
How come
you're not in a bed?
Well, this is the room
where they have me wait
till I'm a little closer
to having the baby.
So, is everything
all right?
You feeling okay?
Yeah. I feel great.
Thanks.
Oh, I can't believe you're gonna
have a little sister.
She's gonna need you
to watch out for her
and protect her.
Do you know that
by the time she's your age,
you're gonna be
in high school?
And when you and dad were
in high school, you had me.
That's right.
[ Chuckles ]
You're not allowed
to do that.
Oh, I remember the night
I told your dad
you were gonna be you.
He was gonna have a son.
Remember that, dad?
Yeah.
I had six turnovers
at the time.
You're not allowed
to do that either.
Haley: Six turnovers?
That is not the Nathan Scott
I know.
I got worried
when I didn't see you.
It's okay.
Everything's fine.
[ Sighs ]
♪ But after all the dust
has settled ♪
I need to ask you
a question.
Mm-hmm.
If I don't go to Duke...
If I don't play
college basketball...
I mean, if today is the best
it ever gets for me,
will that be enough?
Of course.
Nathan, as long
as you're a good husband
and a good father
to your son.
What?
It's a boy, Nathan.
[ Chuckles ]
You're gonna have a son.
[ Laughs ]
♪ Either way ♪
♪ either way ♪
Hi.
Chloe, hi.
I told you
it was coming sooner
than we thought.
Wow. I guess so.
How are you feeling?
What can we do?
Can we get you anything?
Call your parents --
No. No.
No, thanks.
I'll -- I'll be fine.
Okay.
Well, we just want you to know
we're here.
And we're gonna be here.
We're not going anywhere.
Okay.
Maybe you guys can come check up
on me a little later.
Yeah. Of course.
Whenever you need us.
You're gonna do great.
♪ Right away ♪
Okay.
All right.
See you.
♪ Running back to you ♪
Hey.
Yo.
Check it out, dude.
I got us
all kinds of stuff.
We have DVDs, snacks.
Comic books.
Graphic novels.
Oh, my gosh, UNO.
I'm the UNO king.
Okay,
that's a game of luck.
There is just zero skill to it
whatsoever.
Said not the king.
That sentence
had zero sense to it.
Anyway, what do you want
to do first, Jame?
I'm thinking I want to make
a book for Lydia...
With pictures and stories
and stuff.
Like a scrapbook?
Yeah, but more like a book
that she can read someday
and know all about stuff
that I didn't --
stuff about mom, you guys,
and all our friends.
Like, for example,
how Auntie Quinn
is the master
of a game of chance.
Or how Clay
is jealous about it.
I think
it's a great idea, Jamie.
Hey, you guys.
I was just about to call.
Hales just checked in.
Well, actually --
We heard.
It's so exciting.
Who needs snacks?
Clay: Mm.
I think we're good.
We have candy, gummy stuff,
candy cigars.
We've also apparently mastered
the game of UNO.
Really?
Letting it go.
What was that
all about?
I just don't want to steal
Haley's thunder today.
Especially for Jamie.
If we have news first,
then we can tell them, okay?
That's very sweet of you,
baby.
But are we
really getting snacks?
Because I was
kind of excited
about that part, too.
Yes,
we will get you snacks.
Are you nervous?
A little.
Are you?
No.
More like
completely panicked.
Oh.
[ Breathing deeply ]
Nathan:
How you doing, baby?
I'm a little panicked.
Can you tell me a story?
Uh, story.
Got it.
What kind of story?
Just a story.
Any story.
All right, all right.
Um...
I-I-I-I got nothing.
Oh!
In the history of the world,
any story that's ever been told.
Okay, I'm sorry. All I can
think of is the Three Little Pigs.
I don't know why the
Three Little Pigs. I have no idea.
But it's --
A memory, then.
Just something
to distract me, please.
Okay, okay. How about this?
How about this?
Did I ever tell you
about the high-school clown --
Don't say "clown."
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Jerk. The high-school jerk
who fell for the beautiful,
sarcastic girl who hated clowns?
I like that story.
Tell me that story.
Okay. Okay.
Um, she was tutoring him.
But they both knew
it was something more,
and so one day, when
he had screwed up yet again...
[ Pebble clatters ]
You trying to wake up
my parents?
That's their room.
Wait. Haley.
Look, I need to apologize,
okay?
You should buy them in bulk
if you're gonna hand apologies
out that often.
Look, will you just --
I don't know how to do this,
all right?
I'm --
I'm not like you.
What does that mean?
All right, I screw up a lot.
All right?
And being around you,
I just don't want to be
that guy anymore.
Who do you want to be,
Nathan?
I want to be somebody who's good
enough to be seen with you.
You should have thought of that
last night.
You know, I keep
putting myself out there.
And you keep blowing it.
And it's probably a good thing
because at this point
there's nothing that
you can say or do that's
gonna surprise me.
♪ Everybody's watching you now ♪
Except that.
♪ Everybody waits for you now ♪
You shouldn't have done that,
Nathan.
But I wanted to.
Yeah.
♪ I dare you to move ♪
And they fell in love.
And they had a son.
And soon...
They'll have
a daughter.
Mm-hmm.
And they'll all live
happily ever after.
I promise.
♪ Like today never happened ♪
♪ today never happened before ♪
[ "I don't want to be" plays ]
♪ I don't have to be anyone
other ♪
♪ than the birth of two souls
in one ♪
♪ part of where I'm going ♪
♪ is knowing
where I'm coming from ♪
♪ I don't want to be anything ♪
♪ other than what I've been
trying to be lately ♪
♪ all I have to do
is think of me ♪
♪ and I have peace of mind ♪
♪ I'm tired
of looking 'round rooms ♪
♪ wondering what I gotta do ♪
♪ or who I'm supposed to be ♪
♪ I don't want to be anything ♪
♪ other than me ♪
♪ One Tree Hill 8x18♪
Quiet Little Voices
Original Air Date on April 19, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
[ Crying ]
14,709.
That's how many babies
are born in an hour.
That's 245 new lives
every minute of every day.
By the way,
since I've been standing here,
another hundred babies
were born.
But none of them were my mom's.
Brooke: Hey, buddy.
What are you doing?
Making a learner's manual
for Lydia.
Clay says you can't tell
the players without a program.
That's cool.
Am I in it?
Yep.
I just need
a little information.
Okay.
Ask me anything.
When was the first time
you met my mom?
Isn't there anything else
you'd like to know?
It's kind of important.
Well...
It's kind of
a funny story.
[ Slurring ] So, we should
totally hang out more often.
What is your name,
anyway?
Haley.
Oh, no.
See, I don't like that name.
Let's call you Brooke.
I don't get it.
How come
you were acting so weird?
Were you sick?
Yes. Kind of sick.
Yes.
Look who it is --
Clay and Quinn.
What's up, guys?
Hey-o.
Did you guys know
that it's impossible
to eat six crackers
in a minute?
Random,
but perfectly timed.
That doesn't sound
impossible.
That's what I said,
but we're gonna do it.
You in?
Okay.
Aunt Brooke, can you time us?
Yeah.
All right, team.
Six crackers, one minute.
Ready? Set?
Go.
Oh, my gosh.
This is hard.
30 seconds.
[ Muffled ]
I can't breathe.
It's not so easy, is it?
My mouth is all pasty.
Come on. 20 seconds.
Keep going.
And...Time.
Mm.
I was so close.
I wasn't close at all.
[ Muffled ]
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Mm-hmm.
We should make Julian
try this.
Where is Julian?
Julian!
[ Babies crying ]
They're beautiful.
So are you.
♪ We've seen
what we never should ♪
How you doing?
Not so good.
Yeah, I know.
I don't think you do.
No, I suppose I don't.
But I want you
to know something.
I know that I've talked about
slowing down
and taking our time,
but I want you to know
that whenever
we do get pregnant,
that's gonna be
a great day.
And I'll be more than okay
with it.
♪ Planes crashing
and burn around us ♪
We're not gonna have
that day.
Baby, we will.
No, we won't.
♪ Three shouts,
and thank God I found you ♪
♪ with the crowd
and the fog around you ♪
They didn't
just tell me that...
That I wasn't pregnant.
They said
I'm never gonna be.
[ Voice breaking ] I can't.
You can't have children?
They told you that.
I'm sorry.
Brooke...
♪ But I hope
it will get better ♪
♪ these times
we're in together ♪
Shh.
Hey, shh, baby.
It's okay.
It's not.
It's going to be.
I love you so much.
But I want to have babies
with you.
I want to have a family.
Then we'll get
a second opinion.
And a third, okay?
We'll find the best doctors
out there.
But what if --
Hey, shh, shh.
I love you.
That's all that matters.
♪ ...With ourselves ♪
I love you, too.
♪ Oh, heaven, can you hear us? ♪
♪ right now we are not sure ♪
Hey.
♪ But I hope
it will get better ♪
I love you.
You know that?
And you're gonna be
an amazing mom...
Tonight.
I can barely breathe
when you say that.
It's okay, baby.
I'm here...
For all of it.
Mm.
I think it's cool how people
celebrate the day you're born.
Like, for the rest
of your life,
they have cake and presents,
and they celebrate
that you're here.
There's something really nice
about that...
Even when your Aunt Quinn
stuffs your face in the cake.
Aunt Quinn, you ate my cake
before I made a wish.
Quinn: Nah.
See...
I don't think
this is your real cake.
If you look really, really
close, you can tell,
because if it was,
I wouldn't be able to do this!
[ Gasps ]
Aah!
You're so dead.
[ Laughs ]
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
♪ I'll give you everything
I got inside ♪
Hey, remember
when you stuffed my face
in my birthday cake?
[ Laughs ]
And then you, me, and mom
had that cake fight?
That was awesome.
It was, huh?
Oh! [ Laughs ]
Yes, it was.
You know, pretty soon
you're gonna have
"remember whens"
with
your little sister.
Are you excited
to meet her?
Yeah.
But right now I'm kind of
half-excited, half-worried.
Well, there's no reason
to worry.
Your mom's gonna be home
in no time.
And, you know,
the best part
about having
a little sister
is if you do worry
and you do struggle,
she's always there
for you --
just like your mom's
always been there for me.
♪ I need a woman
who believes in me ♪
♪ I'll shine the way
through the darkest night ♪
Hey.
Wow.
Talk about a work of art.
You look great.
Thanks.
So, you excited
for tonight?
How do you feel?
You know,
if there's a feeling
of being
half totally excited
and half completely ready
to panic,
then that's how I feel.
Oh, don't worry.
It's gonna be good.
You're kind of great at the
picture-taking thing, you know.
Thanks.
Well, I'm glad
you think so.
I wanted you to give this
to you.
Oh. What is this?
My way
of saying "thank you"
for being there for me
this year.
I couldn't have made it through
without my little sis.
♪ ...Making all the right things
wrong ♪
♪ as the days go by ♪
I love it.
I really do.
I just want tonight to go well,
you know?
For mom.
Yeah. For mom.
♪ ...By ♪
[ Chuckles ]
Dan: Easy, son.
You're okay.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
You collapsed
during the game.
Doctor: Nathan?
How you feeling?
I have to piss.
You were
severely dehydrated.
We have you
in these ice packs
because your body temperature
was very high.
Now, I need to ask you
some questions
about the supplements
you're taking.
Benzedrine?
Methedrine?
Okay.
What about speed,
cocaine, ecstasy?
Hey, doc.
He's an athlete, not a junkie.
He's also a kid.
True.
But he's my kid.
So, how about you play
a little more doctor
and a little less
detective?
Mr. Scott,
could I speak with you?
♪ ...Storm slow us down ♪
Listen to me, son.
You're gonna be fine.
Okay?
You've been hitting it
a little hard lately.
We'll pull back a notch or two.
You'll be as good as new.
Hell, the scouts
won't even remember this
come the post-season.
Haley: Hey, it's me.
Uh...I guess
I'm just worried about you.
I really hate
the way we ended things.
So do I.
Nobody answered the door.
They're gone
for the weekend.
How are you?
[ Voice breaking ]
Not so good.
♪ ...Run us down ♪
Tonight...
I just need to...
Yeah.
I've made
a lot of mistakes, Haley.
♪ Run us down ♪
Sometimes
because of my dad.
Sometimes by choice.
♪ Run us down ♪
I just can't do it anymore.
It's okay.
No.
When I fell to the floor
tonight...
...I was so scared.
I was so terrified.
Then I saw you.
And I promised myself
that if I could just get up,
I would walk
straight over to you,
and I would tell you
how much I need you...
...How much I want you.
Nothing else matters.
♪ Please don't leave quite yet ♪
♪ don't leave ♪
Nathan: Haley...
♪ Please don't leave quite yet ♪
Brooke, I need to tell you
something.
I never told
my parents.
Really?
My ex-boyfriend's sister
drove me here.
How did you hide it
from them?
Well, I stayed in school
for the summer session,
and then I took a semester
overseas.
I just knew it was something
that my mom
would hold against me
for the rest of my life.
You know how moms are.
I know how my mom is.
♪ Licking sugar
from a razor blade ♪
♪ pull the needle
from a hand grenade ♪
You going somewhere?
Ah.
Back to New York.
The designs
are excellent.
The new line
should stabilize the company.
There's nothing left
for me to do here.
♪ ...I need ♪
There are a few things
that I need to leave you with.
We need to call
our publicist
and arrange
a series of interviews
announcing your return
to the company.
You need to speak
with the people at Red
and organize some sort of
charitable contribution,
and you need to fly
to Los Angeles
and tell that boy
that you love him.
What?
♪ There's no room to walk away ♪
When I was young,
there was a boy who loved me.
And I loved him back.
But he wasn't
from my circle of friends,
and he was different
than what my parents expected,
so I let him go.
And not a day has gone by
that I don't regret it.
Why haven't you ever
told me this?
Because I've been
a terrible mother.
I have a daughter
who is strong and bright,
kindhearted, so beautiful,
and I've nearly broken her
with my inability
to open my heart.
But I haven't broken her.
She's just as strong
and beautiful
and kindhearted as ever.
Because if this boy Julian
loves you
and you love him,
that's all that matters.
That is
the most important thing,
and the clothes can wait.
♪ Close enough to feel you ♪
This is for you.
♪ There's no room to walk away ♪
What is it?
It's the company.
It's all yours --
100%.
But why?
I'd rather have my daughter
than a company.
But you loved
this company.
Yeah.
And I was wrong.
I should have loved you more
and the company less.
♪ I'm on fire, love ♪
I just didn't know how.
I know my mom loves me.
But we were distant for
a long time when I was young,
and that was really hard.
I never felt like
I knew her.
I promise you,
I'm gonna know this child,
and they'll know me...
No matter what.
♪ I'm on fire, love ♪
There was a woman in Texas,
who gave birth to eight babies
all at once.
Well, actually,
she gave birth to two,
and then a couple weeks later,
she had six more.
I don't really know
how that works,
but it's not something you
forget once you hear about it.
I just want my mom
to have one...
And for both of them
to be okay.
♪ ...We've waged ♪
♪ take us down a little ways ♪
♪ got to let go ♪
Hey, dad.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
♪ Seize the day ♪
[ Sighs ]
You know, when your mom got hurt
before you were born,
I sat here.
I prayed
that she'd be okay.
And you, too.
Did you cry?
Yeah. I cried.
I know I did a horrible thing,
okay?
But I deserve to be punished
for that, not Haley.
She's a good person.
She'd be a great mother if...
[ Sighs, sniffles ]
Look, I know it must suck
how people are always asking
for things
and never giving anything back.
And I know that Keith saved me
at the bridge,
but Haley saved me
long before the accident.
There has to be
a miracle left for her.
Please.
Don't take her from me.
Don't take our child from her.
Haley: [ Weakly ] Hi.
[ Monitor beeping ]
Hi.
[ Sobs ]
[ Babies crying ]
Crazy, isn't it?
Having a kid.
Yeah.
I got to tell you, I'm
a little freaked out right now.
I don't think
I'm ready for all...This.
That's why they invented
mothers.
You think our parents
felt like this?
That they just wanted us
to have it better than them?
To be better than them?
Not to be them?
I think if they did,
then they were ready
to be parents.
And if you do,
then you are, too.
"Every child
comes with the message
that God is not yet
discouraged of us."
♪ You only know
what I want you to ♪
♪ I know everything
you don't want me to ♪
Hey, handsome.
My whole family was here.
It's usually best to be
in a coma for that,
so nice work.
I also need you
to tell you
that it's gonna take longer
to get into Nathan's
basketball games next year
because my right boob
is gonna set off
the metal detector.
Apparently I still have
the bullet in me,
so you can cross that off
your fantasy-girl wish list.
So just between us,
everybody's putting on
a really brave face,
but I think
they're all really scared...
Because they can't imagine
losing you.
But that's not gonna happen,
is it?
My man is too strong
for that.
So, why don't you
surprise us all
and open
those beautiful blue eyes
and take my breath away...
Like you know you do.
[ Voice breaking ]
Just open those eyes
that see me
like no eyes ever have.
♪ Your hands can bruise ♪
And I'll be
right here waiting.
♪ I don't have a choice,
but I still choose you ♪
♪ oh ♪
Hey.
Nate says
they're getting close.
You okay?
Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
I'm just feeling thankful.
For you and Haley
and my soon-to-be niece.
It's exciting.
Yeah.
You know, we'll have kids
of our own someday.
Well, they will have
your big, bushy eyebrows.
Oh. And your adept
card-game abilities.
[ Chuckles softly ]
You know,
you're not allowed
to say we'll have a family
someday unless you mean it.
Of course I mean it.
I love you, you goof.
Well, that's good...
Because I love you, too.
♪ But I always will ♪
♪ I don't love you ♪
♪ but I always will ♪
It's really good
that you have Julian.
You guys seem really happy
together.
We are.
He's amazing.
Yeah. I-it's be good
that there's two of you.
I just couldn't do it alone,
you know?
Raise a child.
I know.
Oh!
Contraction.
Okay.
Just breathe.
You're doing great, Chloe.
No, I need drugs.
You can do this.
Come on.
Just breathe.
Okay.
Okay. That's it.
You're doing great.
[ Breathes deeply ]
You're gonna be
a good mom, Brooke.
[ Breathing heavily ]
I just couldn't
do it alone.
♪ I always will ♪
I know.
It's okay.
I guess out of everyone
who's ever been born
probably the most famous birth
ever is Jesus.
But people make a big deal
out of Pandas, too.
[ Gasps ]
We need a name.
Our baby's gonna be born
without a name.
[ Chuckles ]
Oops.
[ Both laugh ]
Okay, calm down.
It's okay.
My dad once told me
about this baseball player
named U.L. Washington,
and the U.L.
stood for "un listed."
We are not naming our baby
"un listed."
Okay. I have a name.
Clear your head.
You ready?
Uh-huh.
If it's a girl, Brooke.
And if it's a boy...
Brooke.
If it's a boy, Julian.
And if it's a girl...
Julian.
No. You can't name
a girl "Julian."
Why not?
We can name our baby
whatever we want.
Mm.
Mom's middle name
is Bob?
Mm-hmm.
Wait.
Haley's middle name is Bob?
Yeah.
How does that happen?
You know my dad's name
was James James, right?
You make a good point.
But Bob?
Is that short for Robert?
No.
It's just Bob.
How come?
Well, before grandma and
grandpa ever had kids,
they had a tabby cat.
And they loved that cat
and took him everywhere.
And his name was...
Bob?
I was gonna guess Bob, too.
Ah. Then you're both right.
Bob the cat.
Oh.
He was their pride and joy.
But he was
stubborn and tough,
and he didn't really like
to be held.
Anyway,
when Haley was born,
she kept squirming
and squirming,
and the doctors handed her
to grandma.
And grandma was like,
"she keeps fighting me.
She's tough and stubborn,
just like Bob."
And so they named her
Haley Bob.
Mom was named
after a cat.
After a beautiful, tough,
old tabby cat.
That's awesome.
But mom's
not that tough.
Ooh. Gonna have to disagree
with you on that one, buddy.
Yeah.
Your mom's really tough.
Do you know her and Aunt Taylor
used to totally go at it?
Really? Like how?
It's not funny, Taylor.
Ow!
Let go!
Whoa.
Yeah.
That's not all.
Remember when Chuck
was bullying you?
Excuse me.
Can I talk to you for a second?
I'm Haley Scott.
I'm Jamie's mom.
Uh-huh.
Jamie came home from school
upset the other day.
I guess your son
was teasing him.
Jamie?
Is he the one with the cape?
[ Chuckles ]
Wow.
5 is a little old for a cape,
don't you think?
Maybe you should do him a favor,
take it away from him,
and then he won't get teased
anymore --
about the cape, anyway.
Listen, honey,
if your little brat
doesn't stop picking on
my son,
not only will I give Jamie
permission to kick his ass,
but I'll be kicking your ass
right alongside of him.
Got that, bitch?
I'd like to see you try, little girl.
Aah!
Man.
Mom's kind of crazy.
Yeah. I haven't even told you
about the slapping.
There's slapping?
Oh, there's slapping.
Hey, Brooke.
Name a few people
that Haley's slapped.
Jamie wants to warn
Lydia.
Oh.
Well, there's Rachel...
[ Crowd gasps ]
♪ I'm your kind of girl ♪
...Renee...
Ooh.
And Nanny Carrie.
You get the hell out of my house
right now!
Yeah. And in mom's defense,
nanny Carrie had that coming.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, yeah.
Now that I think about it,
you don't want to mess
with mom.
Hey, Clay,
did mom ever attack you?
Yeah.
But it was with her words.
You know full well this lying
whore didn't sleep with Nathan,
and you want to pay her
$200,000?
Whoa.
I don't want to.
I simply suggested
that it was an option.
It's not an option, Clay.
And while we're
suggesting things,
let me suggest
that you are a huge reason
why this is happening right now.
Okay.
You love it --
the parties, the women.
And you love having Nathan
alongside you
more than anything else.
That's not fair.
No?
The picture?
The one of that woman
draped all over my husband.
What party was that at,
Clay?
Who threw that party?
I'm not saying
you don't love him
because I know you do.
But you love having him at your
side more than anything else.
You could have protected him
from this.
How, Haley?
He's a grown man.
So are you.
Start acting like it.
Ooh.
Yeah, you may --
you ought to tell Lydia
just to never suggest
optional compromises.
You should write that down.
[ Monitor beeps ]
Doctor: That's it, Chloe.
You're doing great.
Now I need you to push, okay?
Here we go.
And push.
Push, Chloe.
Come on.
Push.
That's it.
You're doing great, Chloe.
Five counts.
Come on.
1...2...
3...4...5.
Good job, Chloe.
You're doing great,
and again.
Push, Chloe, push.
Come on.
Hey, it's you.
Oh. Hey.
Brooke, this is...
Eric. Hi.
Hi.
What are you
doing here?
I was about to ask you
the same thing.
That's
my girlfriend, Chloe.
I'm about to be
a father.
I think people love babies
because they see stuff
like hopes and dreams
in their eyes.
They see the future,
and they see goodness
and the chance they have
to be better than us.
So I think
babies are pretty cool.
Oh, and baby rabbits
are even cooler...
Although I'm kind of glad
Chester is a boy
and never had babies
'cause I'm not sure
I'd be able to give them up.
I'd be too worried
that they'd be okay
and that someone would love
them as much as I would.
♪ If ever I do hurt you ♪
♪ make your willows bend ♪
♪ if ever I deceive you ♪
♪ darling,
do not hang your head ♪
♪ if ever I betray you ♪
♪ cast shadows on your light ♪
♪ I pray
that you may pardon ♪
She just changed her mind,
Brooke.
She didn't want
to do it alone,
and then she wasn't alone.
She held her in her arms,
and she just couldn't
go through with it.
[ Crying ] It was a girl?
Yeah.
[ Sobs ]
It's a girl.
Yay!
Yes! [ Laughs ]
Whoo!
♪ We are but failed attempts ♪
[ Laughs ]
Oh. What do you say,
buddy?
Is mom all right?
And the baby?
Yeah, yeah.
Everyone's fine.
When can we see her?
Well...
Brooke.
You okay?
Yeah.
I'm just so happy
for you guys.
♪ ...Greatest triumphs ♪
♪ we cannot shake the fear ♪
♪ that the ones
that we most treasure ♪
Brooke: Hi.
Hi.
Lydia, I want you to meet
someone
you're gonna love
so much.
This is
your Aunt Brooke.
Brooke, this is
Lydia Bob Scott.
You want to hold her?
Yeah.
♪ ...Deserve you ♪
Oh.
♪ But if I ever dare forget ♪
Haley: 353,015.
That's how many babies
were born today.
And this one is mine.
Every child
comes with the message
that God is not yet discouraged
of us.
♪ Again ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==