['70s instrumentaI rock music]
Forman, man. It's a tiny, IittIe scratch.
And Red's never gonna see it.
No, Red sees everything.
He sees when I put cheap gas in the car.
I got it.
We'II put my ''gas, grass, or ass''
bumper sticker over it.
Listen, Forman, whatever happens,
we'II aII take the rap.
Yeah.
How'd you scratch the car, Eric?
FEZ: Have fun. Later.
HYDE: See you, Forman.
WeII?
WeII....
Sir, I was puIIing out of this parking space.
Creeping is more Iike it. I was creeping--
You were screwing around,
backed into a hydrant.
-I see the paint marks.
-No!
And by ''no,'' I mean ''exactIy.''
Yeah, but it wasn't my fauIt, sir.
KeIso was giving me a....
A what?
KeIso was giving me a purpIe nurpIe.
It's when you grab
somebody's nippIe through their shirt...
and twist it reaIIy hard...
untiI it becomes purpIe.
Give me the keys.
Dad, I....
Your driving priviIeges are suspended
untiI you Iearn some responsibiIity.
-Dad, I'm very responsibIe.
-No, you're not.
ResponsibIe peopIe don't go around
getting their nippIes twisted.
See, when you say it though,
it just sounds weird.
[Singing theme song] Hanging out
Down the street
The same old thing
We did last week
Not a thing to do
But talk to you
Whoa, yeah
Hello, Wisconsin!
Love!
Oh, my God.
''Hair Do's and Don'ts
of OIympic GoId MedaIists.''
Oh, my God, is that Dorothy HamiII?
She's a virgin.
Speaking of....
You know, those girIs at schooI
who do it, Iike, aII the time?
Yeah.
AII right, is it just me,
or do they seem more reIaxed?
BOTH: Hi.
ERIC: What are you guys doing?
They are taIking about sex.
Come on, Fez,
chicks don't taIk about sex, man.
It's dirty.
Yes, we do.
EspeciaIIy when it invoIves MichaeI KeIso,
my dreamboat.
Great. Now we have to taIk about
Jackie and KeIso's sex Iife.
This is my worst nightmare.
AII right, you know what?
Before you guys got here...
Jackie and I were actuaIIy
having a pretty good time.
I know. I was surprised, too.
-Donna, you wanna go to my house?
-You know what? Okay.
-So what do you guys wanna do?
-We couId waIk to The Hub.
Too far.
-We couId waIk to--
-Too far.
Man, this sucks.
I just can't beIieve
that Red took away my car...
because of one stupid IittIe scratch.
I know, man.
Who wouId think Red wouId overreact?
I did.
I have noticed Red is a reaI hard-ass.
One toe over the Iine,
sweet Jesus, you are cIobbered.
You know what I'm saying?
Hey, guys. Check it out.
Did you get a car?
Yeah. My cousin SuIIy
Ioaned me his wheeIs.
ERIC: Yes.
KELSO: So where to?
You just want to hang?
-Yeah.
-CooI.
[Fast-paced drumbeats]
Snookums?
Yes, Pookie?
Do you want turkey or tuna sandwiches
tonight for dinner?
Tonight? Tonight's meatIoaf night.
Right, but I have my cIass...
at the community coIIege
in Kenosha tonight.
-I toId you about it Iast week.
-You most certainIy did not.
Yes, I did, remember?
You were watching Baretta.
Midge, you can't teII me anything
whiIe I'm watching Baretta.
It's compIicated.
Bob, I've been teIIing you for months
how I've needed to expand my mind.
Is this about jeweIry?
'Cause I'II buy you jeweIry.
No, sweetie.
It's about me becoming a whoIe person.
Midgie, don't take this the wrong way,
but that's just stupid.
I don't think it's your decision.
I'm the man of the house...
and I say you're not going
to community coIIege.
You can't teII me what to do, you big ass!
['70s instrumentaI rock music]
What are we Iooking at?
That scratch.
What scratch?
The scratch that Eric put in the car.
I got most of it out
with rubbing compound...
but you shouId have seen it before.
It was a doozy.
That must have been quite an accident.
Was he kiIIed?
See, that's where
his smart mouth comes from.
Driver safety is serious business, Kitty.
You're right, Red.
We shouId teach him a Iesson.
So when he comes home,
I'II hoId him down...
and you burn him with a cigarette.
Just so you know, Donna,
when I finaIIy decide to do it with MichaeI...
I have the whoIe thing pIanned out.
First...
l'll be wearing a very sexy Renoir.
DONNA: Don't you mean peignoir?
JACKIE: Yeah, okay, whatever.
Stop ruining this, Donna.
DONNA: Okay.
JACKIE: And then
there'll be candles everywhere.
And also, there'll be a gigantic banner.
And then Michael will come in.
And the wind will be blowing...
and then we will have
the most magical night of our lives.
[Romantic instrumentaI music]
So, if you have it aII pIanned out...
why are you stiII waiting?
I want it to be reaIIy speciaI.
I mean,
how couId it not with a gigantic banner?
ExactIy.
Bob doesn't want me to take this cIass,
but it sounds so exciting.
It's aII about femaIe empowerment.
It's caIIed, ''The Woman Warrior:
''Fighting FemaIe Stereotypes.''
That's the professor. Isn't he cute?
DarIing.
So you want to come?
I can't say I'm not tempted.
Yes, I can. I'm not tempted.
Don't you want to become
an empowered woman?
You know, I just.... I don't have time
to be an empowered woman.
I'm too busy running this househoId.
You're so Iucky, Kitty. You have it aII.
A great famiIy and a great career.
How did you taIk Red into
Ietting you work?
Okay, weII, one day we sat down,
we did aII our biIIs...
and we reaIized we were
going to Iose the house.
This backseat sucks.
PIus it's too smaII.
Fez's Ieg is touching mine.
No. Your Ieg is touching mine.
I shouIdn't even be in the back seat.
You know, I shouId be driving my own car.
The reason you're not
driving your own car, Forman...
is because you're irresponsibIe,
and you scratched it.
Yeah. That's a good one.
[Screaming]
I'm trying to drive the car here, man!
[Soft music pIaying on stereo]
[ChanneIs changing]
No. Put it back, I Iike that song.
Pipe down, now, back seat CharIie.
[ ''Highwater Star''by Deep PurpIe]
AII right.
The back seat sucks.
WeIcome to my sad IittIe worId.
ANNOUNCER: When you
drive home tonight...
please remember to drive carefully.
Great, no pickIes. Now we gotta go back.
Shut up!
Why does SuIIy have a statue
of the Virgin Mary on his dashboard?
Maybe he's, Iike, reIigious or something.
Wasn't SuIIy in prison for arson?
Yeah.
PeopIe who burn stuff
beIieve in God, too, Hyde.
Why does his key chain say, ''I Iove Bingo''?
SuIIy must Iove Bingo.
AII right, I'm starting to think
that maybe this isn't SuIIy's car.
Then whose car is it?
[PoIice siren waiIing]
Yeah
This is great. I'm dead.
When we were in my car,
and I was running the show...
I don't remember
one singIe time we aII got arrested.
That's true.
Eric, wiII you just reIax?
We're aII in troubIe here.
No.
We're not aII in troubIe here.
Your parents have seven kids.
They won't even notice you're gone.
Your parents don't even
Iive in this country.
And your mom, probabIy one ceII over.
So, that just Ieaves me.
I'm the onIy one
who's reaIIy in troubIe here.
Look, Forman, I'II be
in as much troubIe as you as are...
as soon as Edna sobers up.
I wiII be deported.
They're gonna send me back
to my homeIand, the beautifuI isIand of--
Okay, who's the ringIeader here?
He is.
-You get one phone caII.
-To anywhere?
One IocaI phone caII.
[Door cIosing]
So who shouId we caII?
I'd caII Red, but I feeI safer in jaiI.
I don't know my phone number.
I can't caII Edna, man. It's poker night.
No offense, but isn't every night
poker night for Edna?
I know. I got it. I'II caII Jackie.
Her dad's a Iawyer,
and she's got a checkbook.
[Phone ringing]
HeIIo?
Jackie! Thank God you're home.
I was driving a stoIen car
and I got arrested.
MichaeI, this is
just Iike the book Prisoner of Love...
where CIiff, the rugged yet sweet
motorcycIe mechanic was thrown into jaiI.
And then his true love, Tasha,
was forced to be a slave girl...
for this really rich, mean guy.
Jackie, I'm not kidding around.
I'm reaIIy in jaiI.
My God. Are you okay?
Yeah, I guess. But I'm a IittIe coId.
It's IoneIy in the joint, Jackie.
My God. You're reaIIy in jaiI.
What if you never get out?
That wouId reaIIy suck.
Yes, it wouId, MichaeI. And I promise...
the minute you get out of prison,
I'm gonna prove my Iove to you.
CooI. Thanks.
MichaeI, do you even know
what I'm saying to you?
Yeah.
No.
We're gonna make Iove, you idiot.
AII right!
[Inmate whooping]
You two have a nice IittIe taIk?
Yeah.
-You know what's funny?
-What?
Nothing! Because you forgot
to ask her for heIp, you moron!
My God, you're right.
Give me another dime.
We onIy had one dime.
We onIy got one phone caII.
My God.
Somebody give me a spoon.
I'm gonna dig my way out of here.
[Rock instrumentaI music]
Look at this.
Here we are sitting down to dinner...
and Eric's not even home yet.
Honey, you took away his car.
He has to waIk everywhere.
WaIking is good for him.
Red, why do you have to be
so hard on him?
Same reason my oId man was hard on me.
To prepare me for the worId.
You know, Kitty, when I was his age...
I couId have parachuted
onto a deserted isIand...
with nothing but a Swiss army knife,
and I wouId've survived.
Okay, then we've Iearned something.
No skydiving for Eric.
I'II teII you, Kitty,
the worId is a tough pIace.
You drop your guard for one second...
and it'II kick you right in the ass.
WeII, you're right.
Red, the worId is hard.
So wouIdn't it be nice
if Eric came home to a pIace that wasn't?
AII right, Kitty, when you win the Iottery...
you can buy him DisneyIand.
I can't beIieve she went to that cIass.
Married women do not
abandon their famiIies.
Sure they do, Dad. It's the '70s.
I know what decade it is.
Doesn't change the fact I'm eating
a sandwich instead of a hot meaI.
You want me to microwave it for you?
I just don't understand why she needs this.
-I've given her a great Iife.
-Dad, that's not the issue.
The whoIe point of the
EquaI Rights Amendment...
is so that women
don't have to define themseIves by a man.
Donna, is this about cIothes?
'Cause I can buy you cIothes.
This is pointIess.
WhiIe you're up,
you wanna get daddy a beer?
Honey?
Eric, you've gotta do something, man.
Me? What about you, KeIso? Or Hyde?
I can't taIk to cops, man.
I go insane with rage.
And me, too. Nuts.
[ExcIaiming]
Eric, you gotta heIp us.
So now I'm back in charge?
This is so typicaI.
Okay, you know what? Fine.
Once again, I'II suck it up,
be the man and save aII your sorry asses.
Officer, I need to taIk to you, pIease.
You gotta Iet me go!
PIease, God. My dad's gonna kiII me.
You stoIe a car, kid.
What kind of cop wouId I be
if I just Iet you go?
My best friend the cop?
Look, it reaIIy wasn't my fauIt.
We borrowed it from a friend.
Yeah, haven't heard that one before.
Guess what?
They didn't reaIIy steaI the car.
They borrowed it from a friend.
ActuaIIy, they did. Turns out this guy SuIIy
borrowed it from his grandmother...
and she forgot and caIIed it in stoIen.
Nice oId Iady, though. She pIays Bingo.
-My God, this is great. So, we're free to go?
-Yeah. Which one are you?
ERIC: Eric Forman.
Forman? Is your dad Red Forman?
Yeah.
You poor bastard.
-WeII, thank you.
-Here.
-So?
-So caII a cab. We're sprung.
What? We're free?
AII charges dropped.
Wait, that is what you wanted, right?
[AII excIaiming]
HYDE: Let's get the heII out of here.
KELSO: Yeah.
[LiveIy instrumentaI rock music]
[ExcIaiming]
Hi, Bob.
Midge, I've been thinking.
If taking that cIass made you happy,
then I guess I'm happy.
Sweetie, it means so much to me.
And it's onIy twice a week, so it's not--
Whoa.
I thought this was a one-time deaI.
Bob, you can't Iearn totaI
femaIe empowerment in one night.
It takes 10 nights.
Wait. Midge, you are not going back.
Aphrodite, the Goddess of War
wouIdn't take this...
and neither wiII I!
['70s instrumentaI rock music]
ERIC: Hey, Dad.
RED: HoId it.
[CIearing throat]
About the car.
I know it was....
[CIears throat]
And I....
You see, when I was a kid....
Maybe I came down....
Here's the keys.
Thank you, sir.
-So where you been aII night?
-Prison.
Yeah, okay.
-Jackie.
-MichaeI, you've been sprung.
You don't know what it's Iike
on the inside, Jackie.
Did they beat you?
Yeah.
Damn those poIice.
No. It was Hyde. But he reaIIy frogged me.
Poor baby.
KELSO: Thanks, Jackie.
-Okay, so Iet's do this thing.
-This is so perfect.
I don't even miss the peignoir,
the pirate shirt, or the wind.
What about the banner?
It's okay.
The important thing is, I'm here with you.
And I'm prepared to give myseIf to you...
body, mind, and souI.
MichaeI, this is going to be
the most magicaI night of our Iives.
Yeah, and one more thing.
My parents are at the A&P,
so we onIy have, Iike, 15 minutes.
[Romantic music pIaying]
You guys enjoying your burgers?
Got enough pickIes on them?
That's how Fatso Burger does them.
Lots and Iots of pickIes. Yes, yes.
KELSO: Yeah. It's great.
ERIC: Got enough room back there?
KELSO: ActuaIIy, it's a IittIe bit crowded.
Good. That's the way it shouId be. Yes, yes.
I feeI Iike going to the movies.
Where do you guys wanna go?
-Let's go to the reservoir.
-Movies it is. Yes, yes.
I kind of feeI Iike going to the reservoir.
Reservoir it is. Yes, yes.