( Disco music playing )
== Sync by www.addic7ed.com ==
- ( Disco music continues, loud on jukebox)
- ( Chatter )
Hi.
I'm Bob.
Scott.
Okay, there you go.
Good boy.
Wait, no, don't lick it off.
Don't. That's good.
Okay.
I mean, look.
Look how Cannibal's
doing it, see?
See there?
That's it.
Good boy.
I need them
on set, Scott.
Right away.
Okay, you know your lines?
You know your lines?
Come on.
Man: Lou says we can't do the
growl and the attack in one shot.
We can do it,
but we need to do it
in two separate pieces.
We need to prep the dogs
separately for the attack.
I just don't understand
why we can't get it in one.
Because he's got the bite
suit on under his clothes,
so the dogs see him
as a big old chew toy.
I mean, it's fun for
them, they love it.
It's a safety issue.
Scene 37, take one.
Speed!
A and B camera,
common mark.
Brownie!
Cannibal!
Bullet!
- ( Dog barking )
- Right here, boys.
- We set?
- Set.
And action!
( Dogs barking )
( Yelling )
Woman: Scottie.
Your mother called.
Scott:
What did she want?
To see you.
- Do I have to?
- No.
Joe.
No, of course not,
but... she's your mother.
She says she's doing
much better.
- For how long this time?
- Joe, stop.
I'll think about it.
Joe:
Humph.
Oh, and a man named
Bob Black called.
Oh, okay.
Is that one of them
San Francisco fellas?
No. He's from here.
West Hollywood.
Oh.
- Bob: Hey, cheeks!
- Shh!
This is
where you live?
Yeah. Why?
You must have moved in after the
Clampetts left for Beverly Hills.
( Laughs )
Bye, Rose.
I'll see you tomorrow!
- Have a good time!
- Okay.
- ( Engine starts )
- This is Bob.
- Oh, hi, Bob.
- Hi, Rose.
( Music playing )
Announcer: And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
the star of the show...
the man who's famous
throughout the world...
for his candelabra...
and his piano...
Mr. Showmanship...
Liberace!
( Piano playing )
( Band playing )
- ( Music stops )
- Musicians: Hey!
( Music resumes )
Now, this next part of the
boogie woogie is so strange,
it really calls
for an explanation.
It's called
a boogie woogie break.
When I'm playing it
and I stop at a certain point...
you're going to think
I've forgotten the music.
But I didn't forget
the music.
There's just no music
written for that part.
That's why they call it
a break.
- ( Music stops )
- All: Hey!
- ( Music resumes )
- ( Audience laughs )
Oh, this is fun.
Let's try something.
Suppose only the ladies
in the audience
this time, okay?
All the girls together.
- ( Music stops )
- Women: Hey!
( Music resumes )
Oh, that was
terrific.
Okay, fellas.
It's your turn now.
- ( Music stops )
- Men: Hey!
( Music resumes )
I love it!
That was terrific!
You see, George?
I told you
men do come
to my concerts.
- ( Audience laughs )
- Well, I really appreciate it.
And I know somebody else
out in the audience
who appreciates it, too.
And that's my mom.
Mom, I tell you what.
Let them hear it from you...
and I'll play it just for you.
Okay, Mom?
- ( Music stops )
- Hey!
- ( Music resumes )
- ( Audience cheering )
Oh, Mom, you're in
the groove tonight.
I really
thank you all
for joining me
in this boogie woogie.
I'd like to try
a little experiment.
I've been playing
this boogie woogie
at eight beats
to the bar.
I'd like to try
playing it now
at 16 beats
to the bar.
Wow!
He's incredible!
- ( Music crescendos )
- ( Applause, cheering )
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
- Man: Bravo.
You know...
No, that's all right.
Stare as long as you want.
- ( Laughter )
- I mean, you paid for it.
( Laughs )
You know, I always get asked...
"How do you play the piano
with all those rings
on your fingers?"
And I always tell them,
"Very well indeed."
( Laughter, applause )
Thank you.
And now I'd like
to introduce
another pair
of piano-playing hands
to join me in a duet.
My protégé and friend,
Mr. Billy Leatherwood!
( Applause )
Bob:
Oh, look!
A matched pair of queens.
( Laughing )
Oh.
It's funny that this crowd
would like something this gay.
- Oh, they have no idea he's gay.
- ( Piano music playing )
There's Ray.
See him? In the black.
Come on, come on!
Ray! Ray.
Bobby!
- I'm so glad you made it!
- We loved it. Thank you so much.
This is my friend,
Scott Thorson.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
That was really something.
Thank you.
- Come on back and say hi to Lee.
- You sure?
Yes, he'd love
to see you!
Lee?
Look who's here!
- Hello, Bobby!
- Lee, you were fantastic!
This is my friend,
Scott Thorson.
His first time
in Las Vegas.
A lost babe
in the woods, huh?
It's like a Disney movie.
Little Bambi.
Very nice to meet you.
You were incredible
out there.
Oh, I'm just
a piano player.
But everybody did seem to enjoy
themselves, didn't they?
You were great,
too, Billy.
Ray, why don't we fix
everybody a drink?
- All right.
- Liberace: I'm not going to have one.
I still have
another show to do.
What... you're going to
do that all over again?
I don't know
how you do that.
Oh, aren't you sweet!
It's not bad
for an old bag, huh?
Bob:
Oh, you look fantastic!
And those bits
with the audience are gold!
Ray:
They work every time.
I stage this show
once a year.
It works the same way
every single night.
I'll tell you, when I was
working saloons in my youth--
back in Milwaukee,
they called them saloons.
That's how old I am.
I'm from Wisconsin, too.
No! You are?
Well, this
must be fate.
One night,
this audience asked me
to play this popular hit parade
song called "Three Little Fishes".
It barely had a melody,
it wasn't a challenge
at all...
but I played it, you know,
and they were happy.
And then, I don't know
where it came from...
but I got this inspiration
to play it
as if it was composed
by Strauss.
And they loved it!
They ate it up!
- You would have thought that I invented the piano.
- ( Laughter )
And I knew
right then
it was all about
giving them a good time.
And that's what
I'm all about.
I love to give people
a good time.
Ray: Bobby, you boys
staying in town tonight?
Bob: Oh, yes. It's too
late to drive back to L.A.
Ray: Lee, why don't we have the
boys over for brunch tomorrow?
Bob: No, that's
too much for you.
No, no.
That's a great idea!
Of course!
Let's do it.
But after 3:00,
okay?
'Cause I need
my beauty sleep.
( Dog barking )
Welcome, gypsies!
Is this a palace?
Lee thinks
he's King Ludwig II.
- Who's he?
- The Liberace of Bavaria.
Oh, is he
a piano player, too?
No.
Wow.
Almost time
for a dip.
( Dogs barking )
I'm sorry
I'm so informal.
- ( Barking )
- So happy you all could come.
Ray: Don't these things
belong in an oven?
He's so mean
to my babies.
I mean,
this is my family.
And this is Baby Boy.
Baby Boy,
( Kisses )
he's very old.
He's deaf, and he's blind.
I'm his
seeing eye person.
( Laughs )
I could get something to
help clear up his eyes.
- Bob: Scott works with animals.
- Oh.
I worked for a vet
you know, for a while,
and we had a lot of poodles
with eye problems.
Oh, that would be
fabulous!
No one's been able to help
my little Baby Boy.
I hate
to see him suffer.
- ( Barking )
- Liberace: I think my favorite review
is from San Francisco,
when they said:
"Liberace was no Rubinstein...
but then Rubinstein
is no Liberace."
- ( Men chuckling )
- Liberace: This is my houseboy, Carlucci.
He rules the roost
around here.
Thank you.
Pig.
- What?
- Pig in a blanket.
You want a pig
in a blanket?
No. Thanks.
After lunch, I'll give
you a guided tour.
- Great.
- ( Door opens )
( Door slams )
Liberace:
I do all my own decorating.
I just love it.
I call this
"palatial kitsch".
- Right.
- Don't you just love that?
I never saw
so many pianos.
Oh, I never touch them.
Mama made me play
every day in my childhood.
Didn't have
any friends.
So now I never play...
when I play.
( Laughs )
These are actual
Roman columns.
Ionic.
( Dog barking )
I personally
support
the entire Austrian
rhinestone business.
It's too bad
you're so big,
you could try
one of these on.
So, Scott, do you have
any family left?
Oh, no, not really.
My mom's been
in and out of places,
you know,
for my whole life.
Oh, really?
And I have two sisters...
and a brother,
and then four
half-brothers and sisters...
from two
different fathers.
Most of them live
with their fathers.
The rest of us,
like me and Wayne,
we were sent
to state-run homes...
and then Mom would come get us and
we'd live with her for a while,
then... she'd have her troubles again
and they'd have to put her away
so we'd get split up
and sent to foster homes.
But I was really lucky.
I ended up with Rose and Joe.
You know, a really nice
family, on a ranch..
You know,
with animals.
Sure, because
it was a ranch!
What a story!
You got everything but a
fire in the orphanage.
But the ranch is where you
got to like animals, and...
I guess.
And I am going to try and get
that medicine for Baby Boy.
You remembered
his name.
That would be
wonderful.
I'm going to give you
my private number.
It's unlisted.
Now, I'm counting
on you...
so don't you forget.
You'd better not walk
onto my stage
with a ketchup stain.
( Scoffs ) Like anyone
would give a shit.
( Phone ringing )
( Sighs )
He's so unprofessional.
- Hello?
- Hi. This is Scott... Thorson.
- I'm sorry, who?
- Scott. I'm Bob's friend.
I was at L-- his house.
I have medicine for his dog.
Hold on.
- A Scott somebody.
- Who?
- Friend of Bob's. who was at your house.
- Oh, Scott!
He has medicine?
Scott, is that you?
Hi.
Um... Yeah...
Mr.--
No, no. Please,
just call me Lee.
Lee. Okay.
I have
the medicine
for your poodle.
For his eyes?
Oh, my savior!
( Chuckles )
I was going to just
tuck it in the mail
tomorrow morning...
and it should be there,
you know, in a few days.
Oh, no, no. I don't want Baby
Boy to have to wait that long.
Why don't you just book a flight
and come up this evening?
At my expense.
( Laughs )
It's not that important.
Scott, why don't you let me
decide what's important.
You know, you'd be
doing me a great favor
if you'd fly up here
this evening.
And I promise you I'll fly
you right back to L.A.
after my first show.
- I promise.
- Okay.
Alone at last.
Thank you so much for
bringing my baby's medicine.
No problem.
He's going to be fine.
What would you like to do
with your life, Scott?
What's your dream?
I want to be
a veterinarian.
Oh, don't you
just love animals?
So do I.
You know, because they
love you, no matter what.
That's what makes them
dumb animals, I guess.
If they really knew
who we were,
they'd have nothing
to do with us.
Scott, I...
I feel like
I can trust you.
And I have to talk
to someone.
I've got myself
in a terrible mess.
What is it?
It's Billy.
My protégé.
I've created a monster.
A monster!
I gave him everything.
- I put his name in lights-- I made him famous.
- What did he do?
Well, he's out of control!
He's ruining me!
He's ruining my image!
I can't stand bad publicity!
My fans, you know?
Unfortunately,
they're not dumb animals.
He's just... he's done
terrible things!
He's breaking
my heart.
It's just he's drinking heavily,
he's getting into fights.
And I can't
get rid of him!
He's under contract
for six months!
I'm going to be ruined!
I just wish his wife
would come and take him away.
His wife?
Hand me a towel, please.
Thank you.
I never know whether
people like me for me,
or what they can get
out of me.
You know,
because I'm Liberace.
Walter Liberace,
for God's sakes!
I mean,
can you imagine?
I mean, Walter's fine
for Pidgeon,
but Liberace?
It was the only thing
my father gave me.
He was
a French horn player.
He left us
for an oboist.
So that's why
you're so musical?
No, that man had
nothing to do with it.
My talent
comes from God.
Everybody wants
a piece of me,
a piece
of the action.
My brother George, he
performs in some small club.
You know what
the marquee says?
"Liberace",
in big letters.
I built that name.
It's my name.
That's not his.
"Gimme, gimme, gimme."
No one I can trust,
no one I can talk to.
I hate my life sometimes.
I really do.
- No.
- No, it's true.
No matter how many people are
around, I'm all by myself.
Like, I'm with people--
they're not really
my family or my friends.
You know what
that feels like?
Yeah. I do.
Yes.
Yes, you do.
You've been good
for me, Scott.
When?
Now.
Just now.
- Oh, you mean talking and--
- Yes, you know.
And listening.
You're very good
at listening.
People... take...
You know what?
I have a great idea.
Why don't you come
work for me?
As what?
Well, you could be
my secretary.
I don't type.
Hell, Scott, I can
pay people to type.
I need a companion.
A bodyguard.
Someone to keep people
off my back.
Someone I can talk to
the way we talked tonight.
You'd be
my right-hand man.
You can take care
of the animals.
Please.
Say yes, Scott.
Liberace: Would you close the
drapes on the window, Scott?
Yeah.
It's really pretty
at night.
- ( Yelps )
- I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to
scare you like that.
Yeah, I just...
( Stuttering ) Things
are moving really fast.
Maybe I should just get
a room for tonight.
Oh, nonsense.
Look, I completely
understand
and I promise I'll stay
on my side of the bed.
I promise.
Good morning.
Well, look who's up!
( Sighs )
Joe: You're making a mistake here.
Listen to me.
- I worked for that old fag in his Hollywood house!
- Rose: Joe!
Oh, I'm not saying it
for that.
I'm saying it's not
a fit place for Scott!
You don't know him
like I know him.
Rose: Is this the kind of
life you want for yourself?
It's a job, Rose.
And it pays better
than getting two.
Yeah, and you know what
they call that kind of job.
( Sighs )
That's not what this is.
Look, he's old.
He doesn't like me
just for that.
Do you even like
this man?
Yeah. I really do.
He's lonely.
I can take care
of him.
And he can
take care of me.
My eyes
are open, Rose.
I promise.
Mr. Thorson!
Seymour Heller,
Lee's manager.
Lee's expecting you.
Is it any good?
It's amazing.
I love to cook.
We'll be a couple
of fat biddies in no time.
Great,
'cause I love to eat.
Come here, you.
She's going to see us.
People only see
what they want to see, Scott.
Liberace:
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, my God.
( Both panting )
We'll go shopping
tomorrow.
After cooking and sex,
I think shopping's the reason
to get up every day.
And it helps
so many people.
Do you mind if I ask you
something?
How do you stay hard
for so long? I mean...
that was the fourth time
since lunch.
You make me feel
so young.
And I've had implants.
I've had quite a drive,
you know, as well
and... you know,
I've had problems.
And it's a terrible thing
when you have such a desire
and the equipment
doesn't work.
It's like
wanting to sing
and being tone deaf.
And no one knows.
You're the only one
I told.
You see what
you mean to me?
Lee, I think--
just a minute.
I should
just tell you...
I'm bisexual.
I like women, too.
Well, good for you.
I love women!
I wish I could be
that flexible.
Make things
so much easier.
I am so sick
of getting fan mail
about my engagement
to Sonja Henie.
As if I would marry
an ice skater.
Please--
I mean, those thighs.
( Laughs )
No, I was a goner
from my first time.
He was
a Green Bay Packer.
He came to hear me play
at one of my saloons.
I couldn't miss him--
the guy was
the size of the door.
That's how I lost
my virginity.
- Isn't that romantic?
- ( Both chuckle )
You know, I tried
to make myself love women.
I'd stare at women's bosoms
and their backsides,
you know, trying
to feel something.
You see, I knew...
from being Catholic
what happened
to boys like me.
And I went
to confession.
Of course, I couldn't
confess everything.
The problem was,
according to Catholics...
not confessing a sin
is also considered a sin...
so, you know, I was damned
if I do, damned if I didn't.
I can't believe
you're still Catholic.
Devout.
The turning point
for me...
was Kennedy
getting assassinated.
I was working non-stop
and I was sick.
I felt terrible.
We found out later...
that when those heavy costumes
I wear get dry cleaned...
they use this
tetrachloride solution.
I would sweat...
and it'd get absorbed
into my bloodstream...
and shut down my kidneys.
Can you imagine?
But no one knew.
So I'm watching
the assassination on TV
and I think... at least
I'll have a few days off.
I mean, nobody's going to come
see me perform this weekend.
But, no.
No, Seymour made me work.
They thought
I was dying.
They couldn't figure out
what was wrong.
I mean,
everything's bloated.
I'm drowning
in my own fluids.
They put me on dialysis
and I'm thinking...
the only thing that's going to
get me through this is prayer.
Sometime within these
36 hours of treatment...
I wake up,
and there's this nun
in an all-white habit
sitting beside my bed.
I said
I wanted to pray,
and she told me
not to waste my strength.
And she assured me
I would live.
Next day, my kidneys
start to work.
The doctors were amazed!
They admitted to me
they had given up hope.
So I asked
to see the nun...
to thank her
for giving me strength,
and... they said,
"Oh, no,
there's no nun here
that fits that description."
"There are no nuns here
that wear all-white habits."
And I knew.
I knew my life
would not have been spared
if being gay was the sin
that the Church said it was.
I was saved... because
God looks upon me
with special favor.
That nun...
was a messenger.
Wow.
Isn't that something?
But, Scott-- men, women--
you know, who cares?
What's important
is to be yourself.
You just be who you
are, baby boy.
( Chuckles )
( Kissing )
Don't eat all of this.
You'll be angry that
your panties are tight.
Ah-ooh.
- You want some, Scott?
- Mm-mm.
Mm!
These are delicious.
Here.
Have one.
( Whispers ) Does he
do that every night?
Mm-hmm.
( Music playing )
( Over radio ) ? Have yourself
a merry little Christmas... ?
Liberace:
Be careful, Scott.
♪ Let your heart
be light... ♪
Perfect.
♪ From now on,
our troubles ♪
♪ Will be
out of sight... ♪
He made you
a pesto panini.
Oh.
Did you bring
my Fresca?
What?
( Sighs )
Here's what's going to happen.
You listening?
You think you're so hot
and sexy with your hard ass
and that bisexual
bullshit.
You know how many
there have been?
Bobby, Hans, Chase.
Oh, and some
country boy stripper
who was so dumb he wore
his G-string backwards.
He got rid
of all of them.
But I'm still here.
And one day,
Lee is going to call Seymour...
and he's going to tell him
to get rid of you.
Lee?
Oh, excuse me.
I was--
Lee?
Right here,
baby boy.
You've never seen me
without my hair, have you?
Terrible.
Terrible, isn't it?
But the pieces,
they're great.
You know what
I'm going to do?
I'm going to put you
in charge of my wigs.
I only do that
for people I trust.
- Would you like that?
- Lee, I'm sorry, but...
I think maybe
this was a mistake.
What's wrong?
What?
I can't do this.
I can't live like this,
in this house.
I mean, everybody
looks down on me.
Carlucci is always on
my ass about something.
He's treating me
like I'm the houseboy.
I just, I can't
live like this.
I'm sorry.
I don't want
to see you depressed.
When you have a sad face,
then I feel sad.
But it's not sad, it's...
This isn't working.
Well, then I've failed.
Because you have
made me so happy...
over these past
few months.
And if I haven't
made you happy...
Your happiness means
everything to me, Scott.
I just don't know
what to do.
( Piano music playing )
Liberace:
Why do I love you?
I love you
not only for what you are
But for what I am
when I'm with you
I love you not only for what
you have made of yourself
But for what
you are making of me.
I love you for ignoring
the possibilities...
of the fool in me
And for accepting
the possibilities
of the good in me.
Why do I love you?
I love you
for closing your eyes
to the discords in me.
And for adding
to the music in me
by worshipful listening
( Both panting )
No, I don't
like it.
- It makes it better.
- I don't want it.
( Sniffs )
Oh. Oh!
I've always
wanted children.
I regret that--
not having children.
I love Christmas.
I think I'd be a good daddy,
- don't you think?
- Oh, you're such a loving man.
Mmm.
Well, maybe
I'll adopt you.
I want you to take the money
that you're earning...
and buy a house
here in Las Vegas.
I'll co-sign.
But it'll be
in your name,
so... you'll have
some security.
Would you like that?
Lee...
are you serious?
I want to be everything
to you, Scott.
I want to be
father... brother...
lover... best friend.
Everything.
You know I love you.
Does that mean
anything to you?
Maybe all
those years...
all those
foster homes...
maybe I'm your
real family.
( Young girl singing ) ? I've
found a brand new idol ?
♪ He's charming
as can be ♪
♪ I really
can't describe ♪
♪ The strange effect
he has on me... ♪
( Piano picks up the tune )
♪ I start to shake,
I start to shiver... ♪
( Mutters )
♪ And every fiber in my being
seems to quiver... ♪
Want to smell that?
♪ It's a feeling
very close to ecstasy ♪
♪ That's what happens
when Liberace winks at me ♪
- Liberace: Isn't she sweet?
- Scott: Mmm.
She's got a little bit of a Judy
thing going on, don't you think?
Yeah.
You look hot.
I do, don't I?
The wink?
That was my idea.
- Scott: Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
I was the first person
in television
to look directly
into the camera.
I was the first
matinee idol
in television.
I was the one had the idea
of putting the candelabra
up on the piano,
you know?
I saw an old
Merle Oberon movie
when I got the idea.
From, uh... about Chopin.
What was the name of that...?
"A Song to Remember"!
Really? That's like
your trademark!
I know.
Who knew?
Wow.
Huh.
So, really, no matter
what you did,
you were just...
meant to be famous.
I guess so.
Hmm.
( Phone rings )
( Groans
Hello.
Oh, hi.
Yeah, hold on.
It's Seymour.
I told him not to call
this number.
I told you not to call
Hi, Lee.
I'm sorry,
I have to talk to you
about these dates.
We've got six months
of bookings.
I already told you
the dates I would do.
- ( Sighs )
- I'm not working after Thanksgiving
during the holidays.
Especially now.
But you can make double
on holiday shows.
Take a vacation later.
Seymour,
I do not want to be
the richest piano player
in the grave.
- Forget it.
- No, definitely not.
You're already
working too hard.
Lee, give the phone to Scott.
I have a question for him.
Hey, Seymour.
Hey, Scott.
Why don't you stay
out of my fucking business?
Now give me back
to Lee.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
No, you cannot come
for dinner tomorrow night.
- I'm making pork.
- ( Laughs )
Okay.
Bye-bye.
Ay-yi-yi!
Oy!
Doesn't he get insulted when you
don't invite him over for dinner?
He gets 10% of every
dollar I earn.
I don't have to
take him out for dinner.
And I don't want
any company.
I want my blond Adonis
all to myself.
Oh, shit!
Shit, shit, shit!
- Carson!
- Oh, hurry! Hurry!
Have we missed
my performance?
( Audience applauding )
Oh. Tsk.
Liberace: Oh, my Christ!
I look like my father!
I look like
my father in drag!
I look like my father in
"Hush, Hush, Sweet Charlotte"!
I would say
a full face lift...
with silicone implants
to prevent the return
of the lines
around the mouth.
My feeling?
Why go through all of the
work and the money...
just to have it all
fall down within a year?
You pay good money,
it should last.
Some of these doctors,
they keep you coming back
and paying,
time after time.
- I don't believe in it.
- No, you're right.
You know, I had
all this done a while ago,
but I don't think
he was as good as you are.
I'm going to recommend
a deep face peel
after the face lift.
You're going
to look fabulous!
You'll look as young
as Scott here.
Oh, thank you!
I feel so much better.
I mean, that Carson show
was like looking
at Dorian Gray
wither away in public.
But what about
the press?
How do we keep this
a secret?
We rent you a fully furnished
apartment under an alias
until the bandages
come off.
No one will know.
After that, you can
recuperate as you like.
Jack, I wish
I'd met you sooner.
I would still have
had a movie career!
That was my real dream--
to be a movie star.
Now, Jack, I want
to talk to you
about doing some surgery
on Scott here.
What?
Fine.
What would you like me
to do with Scott?
I want you to make Scott
look like this.
Can you do that?
Oh, I see.
Yes, I think
I can do what you want.
He's going to need
a nose job.
And I'm going to have to
restructure his cheekbones
and his chin
with silicone implants,
but it's not
impossible.
But first we have to
slim him down!
I have a terrific diet.
The California Diet.
Guaranteed loss of 15 pounds
in four weeks.
Bob:
Are you fucking kidding me?
The man wants to spend money to
make you thinner, prettier,
and younger and you are
thinking about not doing it.
But I am young.
Honey, in gay years,
you're Judy
during the Sid Luft
obese period.
Really?
They were talking about me
like I wasn't even there.
If Lee doesn't get what
he wants, you won't be.
( Sighs )
Well, I guess
I should be flattered,
him wanting me
to look like him.
Imitation's
the highest form.
That's what they tell
drag queens when they're born.
Oh, I don't know, man.
I mean, won't it be weird
looking in a mirror
and not recognizing
myself?
Should we take the Auburn
or the Camaro?
( Sighs )
I just don't understand
why I cannot keep my hair on
during the procedure.
If I die, I want you
to get in here--
I don't care if you have
to slap it on with Elmer's--
before anybody
sees me.
You're not
going to die.
( Music playing )
Oh, you are doing
so well, Lee!
Isn't he doing well?
I guess it's time to get
started on you, huh?
First, we're going to do
something about that weight.
The California Diet.
Those pounds
will just fall off!
You look, easily,
right now...
like a man
in his mid-40s.
Will I be able
to close my eyes?
Not entirely.
But this way, you'll always be
able to see people's expressions
when they see
how fabulous you look.
( Snoring )
Sweetie,
you're snoring.
- ( Snoring )
- Lee!
( Snoring )
- Sweetie, you're snoring.
- ( Snoring continues )
( Sighs )
Oh, look at you!
- My Adonis is coming back.
- Really?
Come here.
( Chaise squeaking )
What are these for?
Post surgery.
Okay, but I stay
on the California Diet?
Perfectly safe.
Just keep
taking those.
And one of these
is a prescription
for my own
special diet pill.
Uh, I want
a dimple on my chin.
Scott, Lee doesn't have
a dimple on his chin.
I know, but...
You know,
it's my face.
Not too deep,
just a little one.
Okay.
You think
Lee'll be mad?
Sleep tight,
my baby boy.
I'll see you
on the other side.
( Music playing )
( Music continues )
( Metal taps )
Rose over phone: Scott, it's
so good to hear your voice.
I'm sorry, Rose.
Just with Lee's schedule,
it's been so crazy.
I didn't say it
to make you feel bad.
So talk to me.
How are you?
You taking care
of yourself?
I'm great.
I've lost a whole lot
of weight, actually.
What for? You always
had such a nice build.
No, no,
it's a healthy thing.
It's the California Diet.
Lee and I
did it together.
He's really
into self-improvement.
Oh.
How is
Mr. Lee-berace?
He's great.
Actually,
we're going to see
some lawyers tomorrow...
because, um, he wants
to adopt me.
Adopt you?
I don't understand.
Why would a grown man want
to adopt another grown man?
So we can be family.
I don't understand.
In the state of Nevada,
if you're over 18,
you have the right
to be adopted...
whether your parents
are living or deceased.
So it won't be
an issue.
Well, then--
that's great.
Now, John, I want to make
this perfectly clear.
I don't want a word
of this out there
until the adoption is complete.
Not a word.
As your lawyer, I'm legally
bound not to discuss it.
I know, but, you know,
in casual conversation.
No one...
I mean, no one has ever
been closer to me
than this young man.
I want to make sure
he's taken care of forever...
no matter what
happens to me.
Scott:
The coat costs $300,000.
It is made entirely
of virgin white fox.
The train
is 16 feet long--
that is the longest
in the world.
It was designed exclusively
for him by Anna Nateece.
It has $100,000 worth of
Austrian crystals which line it.
And that is why it is the
only coat in the world
with its own
chauffeur and car.
- ( Women laughing )
- Woman: Oh, my God!
- Would you sign this?
- Sure, yes.
- Please. My name is Sue.
- Sue.
Woman #2:
But, dear, you can ask him.
Oh, I know.
There you are.
- $3.
- Thank you.
Woman: You're Liberace's
son, aren't you?
Liberace:
So, how you doing, Ma?
- You happy?
- ( Murmurs )
It is what it is.
Well, is the nurse
working out for you?
Yeah, I think so.
I mean,
they're fine.
So, is there
anything that you need?
No.
No, I'm just lonely,
that's all.
You can't do anything
for loneliness.
Well, you've got
George and Dora, right?
They're a few minutes away. Don't
they come down for a visit?
Same faces.
Every day,
same faces.
So, do you want me
to bring Angie from L.A.?
- Bring her down?
- Oh, no!
No, don't need that.
Please, I don't
need that. No.
No. All I need
is to be near you.
But you know out here,
all alone, I don't know...
it's every day the same.
You know,
but you, you have--
it's too much.
Oh, oh, oh!
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
But I know...
it's too much.
You always going
to give everything,
you're so busy--
it's too much!
I understand.
Give my son some more
iced tea, please.
This will be good
for you, not this.
Mm-mm.
( Applause, cheering )
Thank you.
Oh, thank you so much.
- Oh.
- ( Man whistles )
You're all
just so wonderful.
I feel so close
to you all.
I feel like I can
tell you something
that I haven't told
anyone at all.
But you have to promise
it stays in this room.
- ( Laughter )
- In my early days...
before sound
was invented...
( Laughter )
Well, I look pretty good
for 35, don't I?
( Crowd cheering )
Well, anyway,
back then,
classical piano players
always wore
black tuxedos.
Plain old
My mother, she wanted me
to be classical...
but I just couldn't stay
out of the saloons.
( Laughter )
But I did have a concert
at the Hollywood Bowl...
and I was excited.
If you've never
been there,
it's open air--
it's tremendous!
It's got 10,000 people!
I show up
for the rehearsal,
and I look at this vast...
this beautiful,
enormous
open-air theater.
And I look
at the black piano.
I think,
"Hmm."
"Black piano,
black tuxedo."
"Who is going to see me
in this giant clam shell?"
( Laughter, applause )
Well, I ask you...
can you see me now?
( Crowd cheering )
( Piano playing )
( Orchestra
picks up the melody )
- Scott: All I'm saying is..
- ( Dogs barking)
why can't we have fun?
- Kvetch, kvetch, kvetch!
- See people, you know?
Go to a party
every once in a while.
- All I do is give, give, give!
- Maybe see somebody.
And no matter how much I buy
you, it's never enough!
I'm not asking you
to buy me anything, Lee.
I'm just-- I'm crawling the
walls a little, that's all.
Why can't we
see people?
What are you
talking about?
I took you to the Jim Nabors-
Dom DeLuise concert.
That was...
that was one time.
Scott, I'm tired.
I work all night.
- This is not an inexpensive life.
- I know,
but you don't even
let me go out by myself!
- Why?
- I don't know!
Just to go out
and see people
and talk to them.
Just for a break!
A break from me?
Why do you need
a break from me?
I don't need
a break from--
I mean for you
to come with me!
I can't say
anything right.
Please don't
be unhappy.
I can't stand it when you
have a face like that.
Especially after
the money I paid for it.
Oh, you
want it back?
You want me to invite Charo
for brunch again?
- You liked her.
- Yeah, I like her fine, but--
But what?! What is it with you?
It's never enough!
- What more can I give?
- ( Dogs barking )
I'm not--
I'm happy, okay?
I am.
It's just... you have
to try to understand...
being somebody's
boyfriend?
This is not
exactly the life
that I had planned
for myself, you know?
I mean, I was going to be
a veterinarian.
You want to help
animals?
- Pick up the dog shit.
- ( Scoffs )
And you listen
to me.
You stop taking
those pills, okay?
Jack gives you
too much.
He's got some people
addicted, I hear.
You're getting too thin,
you're always in a mood.
- People are noticing.
- Oh, who? Seymour?
Seymour hates me.
- They all hate me.
- See, this is what I mean.
It's that shit
talking!
( Sighs )
( Dogs barking )
Hey, you know what a woman said
to me in the casino today?
She asked me
if I was Liberace's son.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
( Laughs )
Oh.
- Come here.
- No.
Come here.
You don't get anything.
You get nothing.
( Laughing )
I get it all.
- Yes, I do. Please.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Yes.
- Can we go out?
- Oh...
- ( Both laugh )
( Coin clinks, lever cranks )
Frances:
Walter was a twin.
Really?
He never told me.
Yeah, but the twin
was born dead.
But Walter...
Walter,
he weighed 13 pounds.
( Clicking, rattling )
Even in the womb, he wanted
more than anyone else!
( Chuckles )
What's a mother to do?
She loves
the child more.
Now the world must
give him what he needs.
Mm-hmm.
God. God gives us
the power.
It's not luck.
It's who you are.
- ( Bell ringing )
- ( Gasps )
- Oh!
- Whoa!
- ( Laughing ) I win, I win!
- ( Machine chiming )
I win, I win.
Look, look, look, I wi--
Scott:
Lee?
Lee.
- Lee.
- What? What is it?
She won, but there's
no money in the machine.
Oh, for chrissakes.
I don't have any change.
She won big.
Do you have
anything?
Gladys, do you have
any cash on you?
Liberace:
So, Ma, this is all we have.
But look
how much I won.
No, I know, but we don't
have any more cash.
But...
( Sighs )
Okay. Okay.
( Chuckles )
So I'll take
a check.
( Music playing on radio )
Are you
proposing to me?
I just don't have a lot of
ready cash available, so...
I can't go to Lee, 'cause he
doesn't want me taking it anymore.
Well, that's silly.
He wants you to stay
skinny, doesn't he?
Silly.
I mean, I'd like to
wean myself off it...
eventually,
but, uh...
I have it under
manageable control now.
I don't even think
I'm going to take them
on the European tour.
Totally up to you.
The body flushes it out.
There are no studies
that show it's addicting.
It's perfectly fine.
You look terrific,
by the way.
( Cheesy music from porno movie
playing on TV )
Liberace:
Oh, my God.
Man on video:
Oh, God.
Liberace: How does he get that
whole thing down his throat?
- It's bigger than his head!
- ( Men moaning )
Scott:
It's a freak show!
Liberace: I don't know how you
can be gay and be such a prude.
Scott:
I'm bisexual.
Well, which half
likes women?
I haven't met
that half yet.
You know, you're such
a booper.
Such a party
pooper-booper.
I don't even know
why you need that.
I don't need it.
I enjoy it.
It enhances it.
Sexuality is
something beautiful.
Right.
So how can you watch
those disgusting things
being done?
Disgusting is in the eyes
of the disgusting.
There's nothing wrong with
any part of the human body.
It's all
God's creation.
Well, God didn't make certain
parts for certain things.
It's variety, Scott.
It's what keeps
a relationship fresh.
You know, you are
such a prude!
I am not.
Then why won't you let
me fuck you sometime?
- Forget it.
- Why not?
- Because I don't like it.
- Why?
Because it's
kind of repugnant.
I'm repugnant?
No! Not you.
It.
That.
Doing that.
Only when
it's done to you.
Yes.
I can't help it.
- Well, you never tried it.
- Porno actor on TV: Oh, God!
Because I know
I wouldn't like it.
If you loved me,
you'd try it.
If you loved me, you wouldn't
ask me to do something I hate.
Oh, God!
All of a sudden
we're sounding like
a gay Lucy and Ricky.
"Oh, Ricky, you wouldn't
fuck me up the ass
if you really loved me."
Why am I the Lucy?
Because I'm
the bandleader
with the nightclub act.
( Phone ringing )
Hello.
Hold on.
It's your sister.
Angie, what?
When?
Okay.
Did you call...
what's his name?
Okay. Okay.
All right, let me
call Seymour on this.
It'll be first thing
in the morning.
Yeah.
Okay.
- Lee, what?
- ( Sighs )
Mama died.
Oh, no.
Oh, Lee,
I'm so sorry.
( Dogs barking )
You have been amazing
these past few days.
We haven't even had
a chance to talk.
How are you
feeling?
I'm free.
Liberace:
You're going to love this.
- Mm-mm.
- Come on. Just this one time.
No, I don't
want to.
Pooch, pooch, pooch, come on.
Ride my little scooter!
- ( Laughs )
- You can ride my little scooter!
- Don't tickle me.
- Let's see.
Oh, daddy!
( Bell jingles )
( Sniffing )
( Men moaning on movie
in another room )
( Music playing
from porn movie )
Lee?
( Music playing
from Lee? movie )
( Moaning continues
on porno movies)
( Slurred )
Lee?
( Knocking )
Man: Someone's in here!
What the fuck?!
( Retching )
( Laughing )
What are you doing?
( Groans )
Why was I on
the couch?
Because I couldn't
bear you last night.
And if you keep
taking that junk,
you'll be lucky to stay
on the couch.
Well, about last night--
I'm not ready for apologies yet, okay.
Apology?
Fuck you!
You are
a well-known star.
Are you out
of your mind?
Going to a place
like that?
What if somebody
recognized you...
and called the papers?
I mean, Jesus!
When the London papers
said I was gay,
I took them to court
and won the lawsuit.
They retracted the story
and they paid for it.
Only because
they didn't have
a witness of you
in a room of dildos...
with your dick hanging out
in a glory hole.
Are you out
of your fucking mind?!
Jesus, if Seymour
found out.
I mean,
the millions he spends...
keeping fans thinking you just
haven't met the right woman?
Oh, Scott,
you're right.
You're so right--
I got to stop.
Never again,
I promise, never again.
I swear to God.
You're so good for me.
I don't know
what it is.
I can't stop myself
sometimes.
It's like a drug...
you know?
Like when you need
a stronger fix each time?
You have to help me.
I'll do
whatever you want...
you crazy
old queen.
( Both chuckle )
You know that.
Just keep loving me.
But I want you to stop
seeing Dr. Startz.
I mean it.
( Crowd chattering )
( Door closes )
- The entrance? Showstopper.
- Thank you.
Hello!
Finally, you come
to one of my shows.
- No, I was here last year, remember?
- ( Laughing )
So, this is new,
right?
I have new costumes
every year--
it's in my contract.
You like it?
You did it again.
It just gets bigger
and bigger, right?
One day, Lee, I think you're going
to play the piano while you fly.
Ray's working
on that.
- Scott, why don't you get him a drink?
- You heard the maestro.
- Do your thing, Lee.
- Bonjour!
You guys, how did you
like the pool?
What would you like?
The money you owe me from last
time and a Jim Beam neat.
I don't have
any cash right now.
- Liberace: Did you wear your little Speedos?
- Man: I did.
I'll accept
whatever's handy, guy.
Liberace: Did you notice
the "L" on the front?
- It was missing an "A" on the back.
- ( Laughing )
You're cute.
- You are very cute.
- Stop.
Liberace:
I like that.
( Snorting )
( Water splashing )
Liberace: So, how is
the songwriting going?
Good.
I had some
positive feedback.
When are you going to let me
hear one of your songs?
- I don't know.
- Why?
'Cause I'm afraid
you wouldn't like it.
But I'm proud
of what you're doing!
I'm like a proud papa!
I think it's great!
Maybe when I'm done with
this one, you can hear it.
Whenever you want me
to hear.
Scott, we should talk.
I think
our relationship
is in a really
good place, don't you?
- Mm-hmm.
- I do.
So I think it'd be
a good thing for us...
if we were able to see
other people, too.
I don't mean
like you and me.
I mean, nothing
will ever be like us.
I just know there are things that
I like to do that you don't...
and things that you like
to do that I don't.
And I just think that
we're in such a good place
that we can allow each other...
you know, to do that
and still love each other
and stay together.
What do you think?
Okay. You know,
if that's what you want.
I think it'd be
good for us.
I really do.
Lee, he is
just a friend!
He is helping me
with my songs!
I told you I had
meetings with him!
You're just like
the rest of them.
All I do is give
and give and give.
All you want is what
you can get out of me.
I bet you can't
wait for me to die
so you can
get everything!
- Hey, the will was your idea!
- Jekyll and Hyde!
That's what you are!
I never know
who's going to show up!
God knows what you do
when I'm onstage.
- I don't do anything!
- How many others are there, huh?
- How many?!
- There aren't any others, Lee, I'm telling you!
Well, I'm telling you,
you can't have it all.
It's either me
or nothing.
Me or him.
Who?
He's a friend!
He's a fuck buddy!
If anybody's
fucking around, it's you.
I know you, Lee. You haven't
wanted it from me in weeks.
Don't tell me
you've been doing without,
you old queen.
Who the hell do you think
you're talking to?
Seymour: ...people out here, and
it seems a bit out of control.
- Where's Lee?
- ( Walkie talkie chatter )
Have a couple of guys
come help with security,
wait on the stairs at night,
just to stop the crowds.
- Otherwise...
- Hey, Jim, how's the house tonight?
( Music playing )
( Chorus singing ) ? Every
time I sing my song ?
♪ It takes me
right to you ♪
♪ I want to make you
smile each day ♪
♪ And see your dreams
come true ♪
♪ I want to hear you
laugh for joy ♪
♪ Oh, boy,
how much I do! ♪
♪ 'Cause every time
I sing my song ♪
♪ I belong with you ♪
( Young male singer solo ) ?
Every time I hum your tune ?
♪ It brings you
straight to me ♪
( Chorus continues ) ? I want
to fill your day with bells ?
♪ And play your melody ♪
♪ I love the music
that we share ♪
♪ I care,
oh, that I do! ♪
♪ And every time
I sing my song... ♪
Liberace: You know,
it's been my dream
to be on the Academy Awards,
and finally I am.
Isn't that fabulous?
I'm going to play a medley
of the nominated scores
and then present
the award for Best Score.
Just to be able to hold one
of those gold statues.
I know exactly
what I'm going to wear.
Cary, do me a favor.
Can you get me a towel?
Of course,
of course.
I want to hear about that
outfit when I come back.
( Dog barking )
( Murmuring )
Who are you
talking to, Mumbles?
Nobody.
What's the matter?
Why is he always
hanging around?
Who?
That boy that
you want to fuck
from Young Americans.
Oh, please.
Why is that little bitch
always in our dressing room?
Cary is my opening act,
Scott.
He can come and go
as he pleases.
Are you fucking him?
Are you stoned?
No, I'm upset!
Can't you tell
the difference?
No, I can't. But if
you're on that shit--
- I'm warning you...
- I'm not! I'm upset!
- I will not put up with this anymore.
- Don't change the subject!
- Stop that! Stop it!
- I know you, Lee!
I'm exhausted!
I work, you know?
And I have to meet Seymour
very early in the morning
about the Academy Awards
presentation.
( Dogs barking )
I see you
looking at him.
What?
That boy.
I watch you watch him.
I think he's
very talented.
I have an eye for new
and refreshing talent.
You have an eye for new
and refreshing dick.
You're disgusting.
If you're so interested
in talent...
have you listened
to my songs?
I haven't had a chance
to give it my full attention.
Are you
tired of me?
Am I too old
for you?
Well, this song
you're singing
is beginning to get
a little old.
I don't want him around
after the shows anymore.
What a little brat
you've become.
I thought you liked being
around people your own age.
You're always complaining we're
never with anyone else, you know?
You said we weren't doing the "seeing
other people" thing anymore!
- We're not!
- Then how come we haven't been together for so long?
Because you're always stoned
and you can't get it up!
I can get it up!
- Oh, Christ, I hit a nerve.
- I can get it up!!!
- All right, all right!
- I know you!
You can barely make it through a
performance without wanting to fuck!
- Where do you get it?
- It's terrible the way you talk to me!
You're getting it
on the outside!
- Where do you go?
- You're terrible!
- Do you go to the White House?
- Where my mother died?
- Are you insane?
- Oh, so you do go somewhere.
Where, huh?
Where, Lee?!
You're being
paranoid, Scott,
because of that shit.
Now, I am warning you...
this better stop.
So who's doing the
arrangements for the medley?
I'll find out. Probably
Bill or his assistant.
I bet that Vangelis kid
wins, you know?
I'm hearing him
all over the radio.
( Door bangs )
I'm going to L.A.
for the afternoon.
I'll be back in time
for the show.
( Huffs )
I just want to make sure I
have enough rehearsal time.
( Engine roars )
( Scott panting )
- And now he's going to use me,
- ( Snorts )
use me up
and toss me out,
I know he is,
I know he is.
Mr. Y:
This one's rigged.
- I love him, you know?
- That one's not rigged.
I love him.
I mean...
he's been my whole world.
He's my,
he's my best friend.
He's been better,
better than a father.
He was going to adopt me.
You know that?
Really? You can adopt
someone you're fucking?
That's a great law.
He said he always wanted
to make sure
- that I was taken care of.
- Right.
Look, you're practically
married, right?
Nobody ever took care of me
the way he did.
I have nothing
without him.
I don't even have
my own fucking face!
My fucking face
is fucking gone
for-fucking-ever, man!!
Hey, hey, hey.
Tranquilo, okay?
Calm down.
Look at me. You're
practically married, right?
So, he should
take care of you
in the style to which
you are accustomed.
That's a law, too.
I'm in the will,
but...
a lot of good
that does me now.
Being with him's like
a full-time job, correct?
- 25 hours a day.
- Yeah. So three words:
Sev-er-ance,
all right?
People who get fired
get compensated.
He's my whole world.
( Piano music playing )
( Music continues )
There you are,
you cocksucking
tenor fuck.
There's a call
for you.
Joe Carracappa.
- Joe!
- Hey, Scott.
Hey, I'm sorry,
I have to run.
I have to make
an entrance.
Rose... passed away
this morning, Scott.
What?
- She's been sick.
- For how long?
A while.
She never said
anything to me.
You know
how she is.
Was.
Can you come home, Scott?
It'd be good to see you.
We're having
services.
Yeah.
Yeah, of course.
Liberace:
I am so excited.
The Academy Awards
has been a dream of mine.
That and Radio City
Music Hall.
One down, one to go.
( Laughter )
My mom wants "On Golden
Pond" to win everything.
Yes, wouldn't
that be sweet
for the old folks
to win?
And I'm so glad that Jane Fonda
stopped all those causes of hers
and made a nice movie
with her father.
I just don't understand
people like her and Ed Asner,
shouting their opinions
all over the place.
Listen to me, because
you're all on your way.
When one reaches
star status,
it is not an invitation
to show everyone
how to change
the world.
It is not our business
to change the world.
We are here to
entertain the world...
- and to sell drinks and souvenirs.
- ( Laughter )
Ray: These kids better go
get ready for the next show
if they're going to
entertain anybody.
Cary: Will you watch us tonight?
We put a new song in
just for you.
Of course I will! Especially if
you put in a new song for me.
Go on now.
I'm going to get
my beauty nap.
- Lee.
- Please, do not start an argument.
I have to eat, and take
my nap before the next show.
I have no time.
I got a call today...
from Joe Carracappa.
The family that I lived
with when I met you.
And Rose...
my--
Joe's wife.
She died.
Oh, Scott,
I...
I'm so sorry,
Scott.
She was your favorite,
wasn't she?
There is a funeral
tomorrow... in Los Angeles.
I will be booking
a ticket in the morning.
- No, no, no, no.
- I don't know what time I'm going to get back.
I'll call Seymour
in the morning, okay?
And I'll hire a Learjet
and you can take that.
And this way
it'll be more private
and you won't have to worry
about reservations.
You come back any time
that you're ready tomorrow.
Come on, now.
( Sobbing )
It's just been so long since
we've been nice to each other...
and I was forgetting
what it felt like.
Well, let's just keep being
nice to each other, hmm?
How about that?
( Jet engine roaring )
( Jet engine whining )
( Vacuum humming )
Hi, Gladys.
- Hey.
- Bob: Hey, kid.
I didn't know
you were visiting.
Lee invited me for the day.
I heard about Rose.
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
Thanks.
- ( Vacuum stops )
- Where's Lee?
He has his final fitting
for the Oscars.
Come out by the pool
when you've settled in.
Hey, Bob?
- What's going on?
- What?
It just
feels weird.
Is there something
I don't know about?
Well...
yeah.
Yeah.
Last night... you know,
the kid that he... Right?
Cary, I think his...
( Piano music playing )
( Shatters )
( Clattering )
( Loud clattering )
We should move you to the Palm
Springs house this afternoon.
( Crashing )
Let's wait
in the den.
( Clattering )
( Panting )
( Snorting )
- I'm not calling him.
- So don't.
I mean,
he's in the wrong.
He should call me
and apologize to me.
He fooled around
on you.
I mean, who's the injured
party here, guy?
( Sniffs )
I'm not calling him.
So if his phone
doesn't ring,
it's probably you.
It's the only way
men learn.
Tell me.
- I am not calling him.
- So don't.
You scumbag,
piece of shit...
fairy, fucking queen
cocksucker!
- Mr. Y: That's what I'm talking about!
- How dare you!
- Mr. Y: Fucking A!
- How fucking dare you, Lee! I could kill you!
- I could fucking kill you!
- Mr. Y: Yeah, put that in your pipe and smoke it, baby.
( Phone plunger clicks )
( Sniffs )
He hung up.
Whoo!
( Sniffs )
Oh.
Mr. Schnelker.
This is Scott Thorson's
brother, Wayne.
Half-brother.
He's here
to help us.
Now as I said
on the phone,
Lee wants you to inform
Mr. Scott Thorson
his employment
has been terminated
and he must vacate
the apartment immediately.
Also, if possible,
we'd like you to convince
Scott to admit himself
to a hospital
for treatment,
at our expense.
Dorothy, June.
Dorothy: Mr. Heller.
He's on the couch.
Schnelker: Stay by the elevator.
Wayne?
Scott?
( Sniffing )
This is Tracy.
A private investigator.
He's come
to ask you to leave.
Get out of my house!
( Yelling )
- Wayne: I only came to help.
- I'm going to fucking get you out.
- He's going to get a gun!
- Has he got a gun?
- He has two.
- Don't let him get the guns.
Let's go, brother.
Stay back!
Stay back,
don't you come in here!
I'm calling the police!
- Back off!
- Schnelker: Fine.
I wish you would
call the police.
Scott, if you would take
advantage of our assistance,
I'd be happy to call a
doctor and we can help you.
Just fucking
shut up!
- Do you want me to help you?
- Shut up!
Back off!
I will fucking hit you!
Hello, hello?
Hello.
Yes,
I want the, uh...
- I want the...
- Schnelker: Scott.
- Who the fuck is this?
- Scott.
Fucking don't!
I will call the fucking Mafia,
and they will come here
and bring you to the desert
and fucking bury you!
( Panting )
Stay back!
( Lock clicks )
Wayne:
Scott!
I want to talk to Lee!
( Knocking )
Scott:
I want to talk to Lee.
That's not
going to happen, Scott.
You know what?
Fine.
If this is how he wants to
handle this kind of situation...
then I want to leave.
But I am taking all of my
personal belongings with me.
All of them, Seymour,
or I will fucking sue you!
Listen.
You have my word.
If you vacate
the apartment now,
you can come back
during the Academy Awards...
and I'll have all your belongings
ready for you to pick up.
Mr. Y:
Wow.
Stick it in
and break it off, huh?
( Drum roll plays )
Announcer: From the
Dorothy Chandler Pavilion
in Los Angeles,
California...
Wow.
The 54th annual
Academy Awards!
( Applause )
Wow.
( Piano music playing )
( Applause )
Actually, though, it's
kind of a cokey piano.
( "Love Is Blue" starts, plays
under the following scene )
Lawyer: Is it true
that you and Liberace
made an oral agreement when you
first went to work for him
- and moved from Los Angeles to Las Vegas?
- Scott: Yes.
You contend that
at some later date
after making
that oral agreement,
the oral agreement was put
into a written agreement
- prepared by attorney Joel Strote?
- Yes.
- Where he made certain promises to you.
- Did you ever sign that written agreement?
- Yes, I did.
- Did Liberace ever sign that written agreement?
- Yes.
Did you ever receive
a copy of it?
Joel Strote
has my copy.
Was there ever any other written
agreement between you and Liberace
other than this one
prepared by Joel Strote?
Yes. The will.
My will.
- Did you ever execute this will?
- Yes.
Did anyone witness
your executed will?
When you mean
"executed", uh...
I didn't
sign it yet.
- I mean--
- He doesn't understand "executed" to mean signing.
What did you mean
when you said "executed"?
Well, you mean,
did I ever sign it?
No, I never did.
No.
Why didn't you
ever sign it?
Because Liberace and I
were having problems.
What kind of problems?
I felt that he was
seeing other people.
Did you ever receive
a copy of this will?
Joel Strote
kept my copy for me.
Lawyer: Was it your expectation
that you would become
- the legally adopted son of Liberace?
- Yes.
And continue in a sexual
relationship with him
- after the adoption?
- No.
Is that when you thought
the sex would stop?
Our relationship
towards later on
went from a sexual
relationship to...
Lee always thought of me
as more of a son.
We had our
sexual relationship
in the beginning
of our relationship
and it was, more or less,
he thought of me as a--
He wanted me to think of him
as a, as a father type image.
He thought--
It's just so hard to explain.
Liberace:
His duties were expanded
to be a road manager,
acting as a buffer for me...
you know, for various employees
in various hotels...
the fans, media,
answering the phone...
answering knocks
on the door...
driving me from places
of engagement
where limousines
were not provided for me.
Lawyer #2: Did you make a
gift of three bedroom sets
- to Scott Thorson?
- No.
Did you make a gift of lamps
to Scott Thorson?
No.
Did you make a gift
of a water buffalo head,
- mounted, to Scott Thorson?
- No.
Did you make a gift
of any furniture
- to Scott Thorson?
- No.
What reason do you have
for believing that
the furniture and furnishings
you think of as gifts
were, in fact,
not gifts?
Well, this is what I do
with all my homes.
I furnish all my homes
for people to use.
But that does not mean
they can take the furniture
with them
when they leave.
It's my property.
Did you make a gift of any
furs to Scott Thorson?
- Yes.
- What furs?
Uh, a raccoon,
a black mink trenchcoat,
a leather
and black mink coat...
and um, that's it.
And what other gifts have
you made to Scott Thorson?
Jewelry.
What form of jewelry?
A ring with
his initial on it...
and two Krugerrands
made up the ring.
Gold chains.
Australian opal ring.
Bracelets,
things like that.
Lawyer #2: Okay, first off, you
have to understand something.
You're not getting
any of your property back.
You're not getting a dime...
unless you sign
this agreement.
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
- All right.
- ( Sniffs )
You're going to get
$75,000 in cash,
three of your cars,
three dogs
and all
your clothes.
$75,000?
That's it?
In return for the
money, the cars,
the dogs and the
personal property...
you're going to
sign over the title
of your Las Vegas home
on Laramore to Lee.
And that's estimated value
right now at $200,000.
You're going to give over
all the contents to Lee,
estimated at $50,000.
In addition,
you will be required
to sign over the titles
of your Chevrolet van,
the antique Cadillac
and your Auburn
to Mr. Liberace.
You will also give up
any other claims
against Mr. Liberace
of any kind in the future.
So assault, battery,
palimony-- out.
And you're going to sign
a clause prohibiting you
from revealing the true
nature of your relationship
to anybody,
public or private.
This is the best
we could do?
They're shortchanging
me $250,000.
Well, there's nothing in here
about the jewelry he gave you,
- so you get to keep that.
- I had to sell the jewelry!
- For what?
- For legal, uh, fees and other things.
I don't care...
what the judge says,
we were
fucking married!
Well, the law says
you weren't.
And a contract for sex
can't be enforced.
Scott, listen to me.
You're a drug addict.
This is all
you're getting.
Sign it.
You know, I called
Billy Leatherwood.
He got more.
Thank you.
Liberace: "At the tender
age of 16, I was seduced
by a blues singer
by the name of Bea Haven.
The thrill of making it
with an older woman diminished
as I grew older.
Younger girls started to
represent more of a challenge...
probably because
of their innocence.
And then I met the woman who was
to be the love of my life...
Sonja Henie."
♪ It's beginning to look
a lot like Christmas... ♪
- ( Phone ringing )
- ? Everywhere you go ?
♪ Take a look
in the Five and Ten ♪
♪ Glistening once again
with candy canes... ♪
- Hello?
- Liberace: Scott, is that you?
Lee?
( Slurring )
How have you been, Scott?
I'm... fine.
I'm fine.
And your health?
How are you feeling?
Good.
I'm doing good.
You sure everything
is all right?
Lee, what's wrong?
Well, you know, I guess
you heard the rumors.
I haven't been
feeling so well lately.
I'm not my usual
spring chicken anymore.
- Merry Christmas.
I know how
you love it.
You sure you're okay?
Yes, I'm...
It's all been checked.
I'm okay.
( Softly ) Would you
come and see me, Scott?
Come visit me.
Lee, I'm telling you,
I'm okay.
It's not that.
But would you just come
and visit me?
( Sighs )
Thanks.
I don't want you
to touch me.
I don't think
it matters, Lee.
Still.
You okay?
I'm so glad.
Seymour got
a story out...
that I just need
to rest.
He works so hard
for me.
( Sobbing )
I just don't want
to be remembered
as some old queen...
who died of AIDS.
( Sniffling )
Promise me...
that you won't tell
anybody how I looked...
( Sniffles )
when you came
to visit.
I asked you here...
because I want you
to know...
you made me
the happiest.
You did, Scott.
Did I make you
happy?
Yes.
Yeah.
The most happy.
Just a little
something...
( Sniffles )
to remember me by.
Man:
At 2:05 p.m. today...
Liberace died
of cardiac arrest...
caused by
cardiac failure.
His body will be
taken to Los Angeles,
where it will be
prepared for burial.
In an unusual
twist of events...
the Riverside County
Health Department
has rejected
the death certificate...
by Liberace's attending
doctor, Ronald Daniels,
and has ordered
an autopsy.
This request
is unseemly.
Mr. Liberace died
of heart failure...
due to an anemia caused
by a watermelon diet.
The body has already
been embalmed!
With respect to Liberace's
family during this time,
we have asked that the request
for autopsy be rejected.
Since Mr. Liberace
has already been embalmed,
it was necessary
to take tissue samples.
Along with the medical
records of blood tests
during his recent stay at the
Eisenhower Medical Center...
it is the conclusion of the Riverside
County Health Department...
that Mr. Liberace
died of complications
due to the AIDS virus.
Seymour: Thank you
all for coming.
I think that what should be
remembered today
is that Lee
was a great professional...
a great showman,
he loved his fans.
But we should also
look to the future.
As a result
of the scholarship program
which he's established
through his foundation...
many young people will have
a musical education
which they otherwise
could not afford.
Thank you.
Priest: My dear
people, let us begin
as we begin
all things holy.
In the name of the Father,
and of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
The grace of our Lord
Jesus Christ...
the love of God, and the
fellowship of the Holy Spirit
be with you always.
Congregation:
And with your spirit.
Priest:
In the waters of baptism,
Liberace
died with Christ
and rose within
to a new life.
May he now share
with Him
in eternal glory.
Let us pray.
( "To Dream The Impossible
Dream playing )
"To dream
the impossible dream
To be better far
than you are
To try when your arms
are too weary
To reach
that unreachable star
This is my quest
To follow that star
No matter
how hopeless
No matter how far
To be willing to give
When there's
no more to give
To be willing to die
So that honor and justice
may live
And I know
If I'll only be true
To this glorious quest
My heart
Shall lie peaceful
and calm
When I'm laid
to my rest."
Thank you.
You have made me
the happiest piano player
who has ever lived.
And no matter what,
I still believe
and always will...
too much
of a good thing
is wonderful!
== Sync by www.addic7ed.com ==
( Piano music playing )
Liberace:
Why do I love you?
I love you
not only for what you are,
But for what I am
when I'm with you.
I love you not only for What
you have made of yourself,
But for what
you are making of me.
I love you for ignoring
the possibilities
Of the fool in me
And for accepting
the possibilities
Of the good in me.
Why do I love you?
I love you
for closing your eyes
To the discords in me
And for adding
to the music in me...
by worshipful listening.
I love you
for helping me
to construct of my life...
not a tavern
but a temple.
I love you because
you have done so much...
to make me happy.
You have done it
without a word...
without a touch,
without a sign.
You have done it
by just being yourself.
Perhaps, after all...
that is what love means
And that is why...
I love you.
( Music playing )