[Bass Beat]
[Dog Barks In Distance]
[Knocking]
[Woman]
John?
[Continues]
John!
[Rap]
Johnny?
Johnny, I'm coming in.
- Ahh!
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Oh, shit!
- Ahh! Ahh! Ohh! Whoa! Whoa!
What? What?
What? What the fuck?
I didn't see nothing.
Jamie. Jamie, what-- Stop.
Jamie, what are you doing?
What's going on?
God, I'm sorry.
Oh, man.
I was--
I have jock itch, okay?
I was scratching my jock itch.
You scared
the hell out of me.
I didn't see anything, okay?
You can't just come in.
You have to call.
- I did call you! I called.
- What are you doing here?
I'm getting married.
Tim and I are getting married.
I'm engaged.
[Sighs]
I knew it.
I could tell from the sound
of your voice on the messages.
I knew it. Shit.
John, it's been seven years.
I don't know
what to tell you.
It still stings.
And it's still a surprise.
[Sighs]
Listen.
We're going to this party
tomorrow night.
Tim and I are going.
Just listen.
It's a great party.
Very cool people.
People who would
stimulate you intellectually,
and I, you know-- I hear really,
really kinda great chicks.
I'm not going to a party.
Yeah, you are.
You're coming.
You gotta get out of the house.
Just let me do my thing.
I'll find my own way.
I'll find someone
or I won't,
and I'll be a great uncle
to your kids.
Stop it.
You're going to
take a shower,
and you're going to
put some pants on
that are clean...
and those nice shoes.
And then you and Tim
will introduce me:
"Hey, this is the guy
that I dumped--
"who's my ex-husband--
but you'll love him!"
You know how pathetic
that sounds?
This is the perfect opportunity.
You're coming.
- I want you to come.
- I'm not going to a party.
[Stereo: R & B]
Hey.
Hey, John.
How's that going?
Good.
It's just, that, you know,
I could stare at a fire
for hours, you know?
It's like TV.
What?
This is--
I came. I got dressed up.
I know you did. I know.
John, drink that.
It's Red Bull and vodka.
[Chuckles]
Drink it. Get lit.
Ladies find you attractive.
Come on.
All right, all right.
I'm not messing around.
I'm serious.
You want me to get insane?
Yeah.
In the membrane.
[Laughs]
[Tim]
John, put it
inside your body.
Tip it. Tip it. Tip it.
[Jamie]
Let's go.
Ahh.
[Tim]
Giddyap. Come on, Big John.
[Jamie] Go, Johnny.
Come on.
Lot of pretty girls here.
Look at her. Oh, she's--
[Laughs]
No, you can't follow me too.
Just watch and learn.
They were $39,
and I'm like, "See those?"
And he's like,
"They're perfect."
Hey.
Hi.
Are you waiting
for the bathroom?
Uh, no. Go ahead.
No, no.
I was just asking.
I don't have to--
I don't have to go.
Oh, well, it's right there.
Anyway, um, so--
Where did you get those?
[Clatters On Floor]
Ooh, ooh.
Sorry.
[Grunts]
I think the screws
came out.
Anyway--
You're just gonna hold that?
Well, um, we're kind of, like,
having a conversation here, so--
Oh.
Oh. I'm--
I'm gonna have some
conversations too here,
eventually.
Hey, can I have
a vodka Red Bull?
[Chattering]
Hey.
- Do I know you?
- No, I was just being stupid.
You seemed friendly.
Hey--
Uh, red, please. Thanks.
Red Bull?
You having Red Bull?
Uh, wine.
Oh.
Thank you.
So-- Mmm, no.
No.
Thanks.
I'm not an architect.
I'm not a deejay.
I'm not a...
marketing executive.
Listen. Marketing--
You gotta be yourself
and be vulnerable
and be honest...
and just get out there
and talk to somebody
who's like--
Who should I talk to?
you know,
seems like a normal girl.
Name one person.
Look at the woman on the couch.
She's totally cool.
Okay, her? Done.
I'll go do it.
Okay.
Hi. Is anyone sitting here?
Uh, no, go ahead.
Ahh!
Hi. I'm John.
I'm Ashley.
Nice to meet you, Ashley.
Thank you.
Are you having a good time?
Not really.
[Chuckles]
Me, either. Uh...
Can-- Listen.
I know we just met.
Can I be honest with you?
I just want to level
with somebody, okay?
Sure.
I am in a tailspin.
And I'm lonely.
I'm depressed,
and I'm borderline desperate.
But... I don't know.
I just-- I know myself.
I know that
I'm a really fun person.
I'm not a lonely person
or a depressed person.
I have-- I don't know.
I just feel like if I could find
the right person to be with me--
I have
so much to give, you know.
I have all these gifts.
I'm like--
I'm a blast, you know?
I'm sorry.
I have to make a phone call.
Okay. That's--
Okay. Plan B.
You need to get more drunk.
[Chattering]
[Urinating]
- Nice penis.
- Ohh!
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
No.
- Go ahead, finish up.
- No, no, no.
Why does this
keep happening to me?
It's the second time this week.
Really?
Yeah.
The other one was my wife.
My ex-wife.
She's getting remarried,
but I'm fine with it, so--
Yeah, I overheard your--
your conversation
on the couch up there.
Ohh. Did you?
Yes.
- That was horrible.
- No, it wasn't.
I thought it was
really raw and honest.
You mean that?
Yeah.
- You really mean it?
- I did.
'Cause, um,
I've had a lot of
weird conversations tonight,
and if you really mean that,
I think I'm gonna start crying.
I mean it. I mean it.
I mean it.
Why am I even--
I can't talk to you.
What am I doing?
I'm just gonna mess this up.
'Cause you're a really
hot girl and I'm just--
I'm sorry.
You're not
messing it up.
- Are you flirting with me?
- [Both Laughing]
This is insane.
I'm like Shrek.
What-- What are you doing--
I-- I didn't say that.
What are you doing here
in the forest with Shrek?
I was gonna pee
in the bushes--
Really?
and you took my spot.
[Chuckles]
["Don't You Want Me"]
Oh! Do you hear that song?
What?
Wait. I'm sorry.
Wait right here.
It's the greatest song
ever recorded, and I'm
gonna go enjoy it,
and I'm gonna come back
and talk to you.
Don't worry.
[Footsteps Receding]
Dance song! Come on, move out!
Come on, it's good stuff.
Dance party!
[Continues
Dance party! Look out!
Clear the dance zone!
[Volume Increases]
Don't
Don't you want me
Come on!
You know I can't believe you
when I say that
I love Red Bull and vodka!
Don't, don't you want me
[Continues]
Don't believe it when you
say that you don't need me
[Singing Indistinct]
You think you've
changed your mind
You'd better change it back
or we will both be sorry
Don't you want me, baby
Come on!
Don't you want me, ohh
Don't you want me, baby
Come on, you guys!
It's a party!
[Continues]
I guess I'm the only one
who loves a good song.
I was working as a waitress
in a cocktail bar
Thank you!
That much is true
Yeah, baby.
But even then I knew I'd
find a much better place
Either with or without you
Thank you.
Get up, come on!
Don't you want me
Come on!
You know I can't believe it
when you say
[Continues]
What are you guys doing?
Come on!
[Singing Indistinct]
You think you've
changed your mind
You'd better change it back
or we will both be sorry
Don't you want me, baby
Yes! Yes! Keep going.
Don't you want me now
[Laughs]
[Sighs]
How did you do that?
That was crazy.
Ohh.
Do you do exercises
or something?
[Laughs]
You're amazing.
You're an angel.
You're a sex angel.
Oh, my God.
You want to sleep over?
Mm-hmm.
[Line Rings]
[Woman]
Hello?
Hi, Molly.
Hey, it's John.
Who?
John?
From last night?
[Chuckles]
Just kidding, John. Hi.
Oh, okay.
I'm glad you called.
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm glad I called too.
That was really fun
last night.
Mm-hmm.
And thanks
for the note and, um--
Hey, I was wondering if you
wanted to hang out tonight.
Sure.
Yeah?
Great. You want to come
over here then or--
Look, I have to run, but I'll
come over after work, okay?
Okay, sounds good.
Bye.
[Grunting]
Hey.
Hi.
How are you?
Good, good.
[John] There's a whole
custom-prepared plate.
[Molly] I want yours.
You're a very good cook.
[John]
I just decided
to give it my all.
Which is not
the cool-guy thing to do.
I'm not into that anyway.
[Molly] Okay?
[John] Okay.
I'll take your word for it.
[John] I know I'm not
supposed to say this,
but I really like you.
Is it crazy for me to say,
like, I want it to work out?
Is that too much?
Am I supposed to be
cooler than that?
Oh.
My life is really
complicated right now.
[Molly]
But I'm definitely interested.
Hey. Where you going?
[Whispering]
Hey, hey.
I-- I just have to--
I have to go.
Wait. Why do you have
to leave so late?
I just have to-- I have to--
Just call me tomorrow, okay?
Molly, wait.
Give me one second, please.
Are you married?
Is that where
you're going?
No, I'm not married.
What is it?
Are you a secret agent?
Just trust me.
What is going on?
Call me tomorrow, okay?
[Sighs]
Oh, my God.
[Door Opens]
[Door Alarm Dings]
[Door Closes]
- Hi.
- Oh, hi. Hey, hi.
[Clattering]
Sorry.
Uh, what am I doing?
It's okay.
Hi. Uh--
Can I help you?
Uh, I'm sorry. Is this--
I think I have the wrong
address actually.
What address
are you looking for?
Um...
Is this--
Does Molly live here?
Yeah. Can I ask who is asking?
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm John.
I'm a friend of hers.
I was in the neighborhood,
and I was, like,
"I think that's
Molly's house,"
but I didn't want to ring
the doorbell if it wasn't.
Um, no, it is. You can
definitely ring the doorbell.
That's more conventional.
But, uh--
Yeah, I know. I was just--
Whatever. I was shy. I was--
But I am a friend of hers,
and I'm sorry.
Oh. I'm Cyrus.
Cyrus. Yeah.
- Her son.
- Her son. Yeah, I know. Yeah.
[Sighs]
Um, yeah, anyway--
[Water Running]
So how long you known Molly?
Uh, actually,
just a couple days.
Wow. Just a couple days.
Yeah, we just met, so--
But you could feel it
already, huh?
Like there's something
really special happening?
[Chuckles]
Y-Yeah.
Can I--
How old are you?
I'm almost 22.
Oh, okay. All right.
I'm 21.
So you-- you guys have
always lived together?
You didn't--
You're not, like, in
from school or whatever?
No, I took my G.E.D.
when I was 16,
and then, um,
you know--
M-Molly and I are like
best friends so--
Oh, okay.
And my dad's not really
in the picture.
Uh-huh.
She kinda homeschooled me
and raised me by herself.
And since then,
I've sort of been focusing
on my music career.
Mm-hmm. Oh, that's--
So that's you? That's--
That's my studio.
That's my work space, yes.
Yeah, I saw that.
You got a couple synths there.
Oh, more than a couple.
I think I have something
around seven pieces.
Yeah. Vintage
and some new stuff.
Would you like to hear
some of my-- my work?
Yeah, why not? I mean, yeah.
Great. Great.
Okay, great. Great.
Um, it's-it's
untitled right now,
and it's an unfinished piece.
[Switch Clicks]
[Low Tone]
[Synthesizer: Slow
[Continues]
Sounds like Steve Miller.
You know that one
Steve Miller song?
No, it doesn't.
[Drumbeat
[Loud Pulsing Beat
[Continues]
[Door Opens]
Hi.
[Under Music]
Hey.
[Laughs]
It's good.
Ohh!
- Hi. Sorry.
- [Ends]
I was in the neighborhood,
and Cyrus came out
and let me in. I'm sorry.
- Hi.
Hi.
Hi. Hey.
Hey. Hey.
- Anyway--
- So, John, are you
gonna stay for dinner?
- [Clears Throat]
- Uh, uh--
Yes, dinner.
- [Cyrus] There's literally,
like, 15 peppers.
- [Molly] I know. Well--
I'm just not gonna be able to
eat it if they're on the side.
[Scoffs]
I know.
You asked for them
without peppers?
I did, but they never--
I'm not gonna use this place
anymore.
- There's a big red one
right there.
- That's okay.
So, John,
I have to apologize to you.
What?
You came in
and I-I sat you down,
and I just started blabbing
all about my life.
I get overly excited sometimes,
and I apologize.
I honestly am curious
to hear about you...
and, you know,
just want to-- want to
hear more about your life.
Well, uh, let's see.
I'm-I'm an editor.
I do freelance
editing work. Um--
I like to go to the movies.
I've got a pretty good
DVD collection.
- [Chuckles]
- I mean, what--
what else do you
want to know?
I don't want to know
what you do.
I want to know what you are.
Who you are.
That's more what I'm--
what I'm interested in.
Are we really gonna--
You want me to? Okay.
I'm, uh-- I'm--
I'm divorced.
I got divorced, like,
seven years ago.
And it wasn't my idea.
It was--
You know, I got left.
Uh, I was kind
of digging myself
into a hole with my life,
and my wife at the time
was not happy with it.
Told me so.
Said to work it out.
I didn't work it out.
I ran away from her
emotionally...
and made a huge mistake...
and have been in kind of a dark,
existential place,
to tell you the truth.
And then I met your mom
at a party,
and, I don't know.
Seems like things are
looking up for the first time
in a long time.
That's--
Wow.
You asked.
That's where I'm at.
[Molly] Wow. Wow.
I like your style, John.
To John-- Our new friend.
[Molly Chuckles]
[Cyrus]
You seem like a good man.
That was a lot
of information.
[Laughs]
So, uh, are you gonna
stay the night?
[Molly Laughs]
Maybe we should ask
your mom. I don't know.
Um, I think that's
between me and John.
[Cyrus]
Fair enough.
I was just messing around.
It's not, uh-- It's none
of my business.
It's valid. It's valid.
If I was in your position,
I'd probably be a little--
I mean-- Molly?
[Chuckles]
Seriously, don't fuck my mom.
I'm just kidding.
I'm just joking around.
Sorry. No.
Cy!
[Cyrus Laughs]
I know. I--
I'm sorry. Uh--
that's my attempt
at humor, John.
[Molly]
Okay.
That's, uh, just--
Enough said.
[Chuckles]
We did have sex.
I mean, if you want to be
adults about it, we did.
That's--
I'm sorry if that's
weird or whatever,
but I'm not gonna sit here
and pretend like we didn't.
We met at a party and--
That's not appropriate
to talk about here.
Okay. I mean, I don't want to
disrespect you by treating you
like a child or whatever.
You seem like you want to be
treated like an adult, and--
That's just it. That's--
That happened, so--
That's--
I accept that information.
[Water Running]
- Hey, John?
- Hey.
I just want to say I thought
it was really great...
what you did at dinner,
opening up to me like that.
And I know it was weird,
but I thought it was great.
Thanks.
And it's great to finally
have a new dad.
[Chuckles]
You got to get used
to my weird sense of humor.
But I really thought that was--
that was a great thing
that you did.
- Actually, your mom's
in the shower.
- [Water Continues]
[Cyrus]
The king
falls off the throne
[Cyrus, Molly]
The king falls off
of the throne
[Water Stops Running]
[Door Opens]
Hi.
- Night, John.
- Good night, Cyrus.
- Night, Molly.
Good shower?
Yeah.
Yeah?
You know, there's something
that I've been thinking about
in the shower. And I--
I really appreciated what you
were expressing in the kitchen
and throughout dinner.
And I've-- I--
I feel a little, um--
I guess a little embarrassed
and just a little, uh--
It's not even that.
I just want to say I appreciate
how open you were.
I love that about you,
and I'm sorry that I wasn't
as open about my boy.
No, that's fine.
It's your--
Yeah, I know.
your prerogative
not to say that stuff.
It's private, we just met,
and I was fine with it.
I mean--
He's a great kid too.
He is.
I'm glad you appreciate that.
I was going to leave,
and he was, like,
"No, come in, come in."
I'm happy to hear that.
I didn't--
And that's the thing.
He's so--
He's very mature,
as you can see,
in a lot of ways,
and he really pushes me.
But in other ways he's just--
he's not come into himself yet.
And-And it's coming,
and it's coming from
a very deep place.
This could be a--
This is a very sudden--
You are very sudden.
[Chuckles]
And I haven't had a man over--
to stay overnight--
since Cyrus, uh, was born.
So it's a new thing.
Well--
But to tell you the truth,
you didn't have me over.
I-- I stalked you over--
Yeah, you gave it a little--
I get seized sometimes,
so it's okay you're here.
Molly, everything is a gift,
at this point, to me.
Just getting to hang out.
Like every moment,
from moment to moment.
Thanks for talking to me
about my--
I just feel a little--
No, I know.
N-N-N--
No, we leave the door open.
Oh. I was just going to
take my pants off.
We just-- We--
We just always
leave the door open.
Um, okay.
Hey.
[Molly] Good morning.
You guys are early risers,
huh?
Yep. How'd you sleep?
Good.
How'd you sleep?
Very well.
Good.
Nice.
So what's-- What's, uh--
What's going on?
What's the plan?
What are you guys doing?
Um, we go to Elysian Park
every morning and eat
a little breakfast...
and take some photos
for a few hours.
Yeah. Cyrus composes
to images of nature.
Sounds cool.
I am supposed to work.
Should I blow it off?
I'll just get it over with.
I'll get in there. Get it done.
Then I have less to do
next week, so--
Anyway, all right.
Here you go, Mom.
Did you guys
see my shoes?
- [Cyrus, Molly] No.
- They were right here.
Weird.
[Molly]
Okay.
[Cyrus Grunts]
Yeah. I can't believe
how deep into it I am already.
That's amazing.
I'm so happy for you.
Thank you.
I really am.
It's amazing.
Is it that obvious?
Am I-- Am I glowing?
You actually are.
[Chuckles]
You look good.
Just, you know, slow down.
Let's just be here now.
Don't worry, I'm not--
I know. I just don't
want you, you know,
to obsess on this.
I was a little needy
out of the gate.
Yes.
I'll admit that.
But it's settling in nicely now.
And other than one little
weird blip this morning,
I am not concerned
about anything.
What? What is it?
Um, when I woke up this morning,
my shoes were missing
from their house.
Your white Adidas?
Yeah.
Your favorite shoes.
Oh, my God.
Well, then somebody
did you a favor.
Whatever.
It-It'll be fine.
- [Typing]
- [Cell Phone Rings]
- John?
- I definitely left my shoes
in their living room.
You know what I mean?
I wore shoes into the house.
Shoes-- John?
Can we not have
this conversation
at 1:30 in the morning?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I had no idea
what time it was.
But the more I think
about the shoes,
now it's like every look the kid
gave me seems really weird.
- Like he was
being friendly but--
- Yeah.
Will you please do me a favor
and meet them...
and tell me whether I'm the one
who's paranoid and crazy?
Sure.
Good night, John.
Fine. I will, okay?
It's got to be totally casual
and like it was an accident.
No.
Higher so that
it takes longer
and I can catch it.
Okay.
[Molly]
Yes.
Mmm. I love the ripples.
This looks incredible.
There they are.
Come on. Come on.
It ripples out almost
across the whole thing.
[John] Molly?
Hey.
[Cyrus]
Oh, my gosh, Cyrus.
How's it going?
John.
How you doing?
[Jamie]
Hi.
I'm Cyrus.
So nice to meet you.
[John] I was just saying,
"I wonder if they're
hanging out in the park."
- I'm Molly. We've met.
- This is Jamie.
- We go jogging here
all the time.
- You do?
Yeah.
That's so weird, because
we're here literally every day.
Yeah, you said that,
but I didn't make the--
I guess, I don't know.
I guess the jogging track--
We took a little bit of
a side diversion this time.
Yeah.
[Shutter Clicks]
What are you doing?
Your hair--
The light is hitting your hair
in this great way.
It's like a crippled tree
reaching for heaven.
John, would you do me
a huge favor?
Yeah, what?
Would you mind
getting into the tree?
Try one where
you get in the tree
just like a jaguar.
Like a jaguar?
Yeah, just climb up the tree
like a jaguar.
Oh, that's great.
That's great.
You're a natural.
[Clapping]
Now do one where you just
scream as loud as you can.
[Screams]
No, that's not screaming.
That's moaning.
[Chuckles]
You're bossy, Cyrus.
You look incredible right now.
I'm really trying to get
the most of this.
[John]
All right.
Now scream as loud as you can.
[Screams Louder]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Chuckles]
What did you think?
Did you like them?
Yes! I think
they're really sweet...
and, uh, kind--
And the wrestling
wasn't weird?
And quirky.
No, that was weird.
But, you know, in a good way.
I don't know.
I don't think it was,
like, "strange" weird.
I mean,
it wasn't "bad" weird.
You know?
They're really cool.
I like them.
They're cool, right?
They're fun.
They're great.
And I don't think
they stole your shoes.
[Chuckles]
Thank you for coming out here.
I appreciate it.
Don't worry.
All right, I'll see you
at the office in a second.
Relax, okay?
All right. Okay.
Okay.
You're the best, Jamie.
[Synthesizer]
Okay. That one.
That one's great.
No, let's skip that one.
[Cell Phone Rings]
Oh, that's perfect.
[Rings]
That's the perfect one.
Hello?
Hi.
No, no, no.
I don't need anything. Thanks.
I'll see you in a minute.
Okay.
Who's that?
John.
He's gonna come by.
Cool.
Yeah.
I was-- I--
I was going to tell you
and then--
- I don't know.
We never talked about it.
- Okay.
Anyway,
he's coming over.
That was a lot.
You could have just said
"John's coming over."
I know.
I guess I could have.
- I feel weird.
- You don't have to
explain yourself.
I think it's nice that
John's coming to see you.
I think it's lovely,
but I still feel--
I feel really--
I feel really weird.
You feel weird?
Mm-hmm.
Why do you feel weird?
Are you okay
with all of this?
Yes.
If I was 10,
maybe I'd feel weird,
but I am a grown-up,
and you deserve somebody
who can love you--
[Knocking]
in a way that
I can't love you, and--
Okay. Okay.
I think it's great.
Okay.
[Chuckles]
I'm the weirdo.
Hey. How you doing?
Hey, Cyrus.
Hey, John.
Hi.
Welcome.
Well, well, well.
You've closed the door.
[Cyrus Screaming]
Ohh!
What? What's going on?
No, no, no!
It's okay. Stay!
Stay in here. Stay here!
[Cyrus Screams]
[Screams]
Is everything okay?
Oh.
[Sighs]
[Cyrus]
Hi, John.
[Whispering]
Oh, hey.
I was just looking
for your mom.
I think she's asleep.
Oh, okay.
Come here.
You hungry?
I heard you scream,
and your mom didn't tell me
what was going on so--
Night terrors.
I used to get them a lot
when I was younger,
and I just recently
started getting them again.
I'm sorry.
I'll get through it.
Sounds terrible.
Um, I'm glad you're up,
because I've been wanting
to talk to you man-to-man.
No. I'm-- I'm all right.
I didn't want to say anything,
'cause Molly asked me not to,
but...
I think--
I think you might be
coming on a tad too strong.
Okay.
She said that?
She didn't say it
in those exact words but--
Wow. I mean--
I don't want to get into it, but
those were not the signals...
I was getting at all tonight.
In the past,
when she's losing interest,
she tends to
overcompensate sexually.
I just think that if you
pulled back 10% to 20%,
emotionally speaking,
you'd do a lot better
for yourself.
Wow.
Okay.
Okay, I'm gonna
go to sleep.
Night, John.
Good night.
[Molly]
Did you see John this morning?
He actually left
last night.
Last night?
Come take a seat, Mom.
You look so serious.
I talked to John last night.
Uh-huh.
[Sighs]
What?
He...
feels that things
are moving really fast,
and...
I think he wants to just
slow down a little bit.
He said that?
Read the note.
I mean,
it's just so not like him.
Are you saying
that I'm making this up?
No, I'm just--
I'm confused.
You're confused?
What do you mean
you're confused?
I'm just trying
to tell you the truth,
and you're, like, attacking me?
- I'm just trying to help!
- Wait!
Where are you going?
[Beeps]
[Microwave Whirring]
[Rings]
Hello?
[Molly]
Hey.
Can you come over?
Something's going on with Cyrus.
Is everything okay?
He's been gone all day.
He's missing.
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm on my way.
Thanks.
Okay, bye.
[Knocking]
Hey.
You okay?
Mmm.
Thanks so much for coming.
[TV: Indistinct]
Are you hungry?
You want something to eat?
Mm-mmm.
No?
I could order something
or pick something up or--
Mm-mmm.
You should
eat something.
Mmm, I'm not hungry.
Hey. Hi.
Hi.
Hello.
Hi. Come here.
What happened?
Molly, why don't you, uh--
why don't you sit down
for a sec, okay?
Sit down for a second.
Um--
You guys want to
talk alone or--
No, this concerns you.
You should stay, John.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Okay.
I don't want to
make this emotional.
I've decided to move out.
I'm an adult now, and I think
it's time for us to move on.
I-I--
It's pretty sudden though.
- I rented a room.
- You rented a room?
I found some musicians on
Craigslist, and I'm gonna rent
a room in their house.
And it's gonna be
better for both of us.
And besides,
you have John now,
and you guys need some space
for your relationship
to flourish.
It's for the best.
Yeah.
I think that maybe--
This is so sudden.
- Maybe you're feeling
some anger or--
- I'm not angry.
Maybe you should
just take it slowly,
step-by-step.
You guys are so serious.
It's not a big deal.
Well, I need to go,
'cause I'm gonna go
paint my room tonight.
Then I'm gonna come back
with a truck tomorrow
and get the rest of my things.
Will you pack them up
for me, Mom?
Uh--
Please. It'll be easier.
Just give me a hug.
I love you.
It's okay. We'll
take some time off and let
the dust settle a little bit,
and we'll all get together
for dinner or something, okay?
John, really nice
spending time with you.
Okay.
[Door Closes]
It's gonna be good.
I'm excited about
the new place.
Tilt it sideways a little bit.
Thanks, John.
Yeah.
Will you thank Molly
for packing up all this stuff
for me, please?
Actually, she had to work,
so I did most of it.
Oh.
Thanks.
No problem.
Okay.
[Engine Starts]
See you.
That's great.
There you are.
You are not
gonna believe this.
He did it.
He stole my shoes.
This means my whole friendship
with the guy is based on
bullshit.
All right, let me just finish--
The first night I was there,
he was messing with me.
That means there hasn't been
an honest moment yet.
Jamie!
I get it. I'm sorry.
I have to do this.
Then I have to go to
the flower shop for my wedding.
Can we just talk about this
later, please?
Yes.
I will wait.
It was the act
of taking the shoes
that was the big deal...
and the fact
that he's been lying
the whole time I've known him.
Bringing me in, acting like,
"Hey, yeah, come on in.
No problem.
Any friend of my mom's
a friend of mine."
The whole time just
to get me to trust him,
so he can turn around
and stab me in the back.
Oh, my God.
It's interesting.
Don't you guys see?
By saying
he's leaving because of me,
he makes me the bad guy.
Right?
It's like he lit the fuse
and ran away.
Will you go look
over at those flowers?
I'm sorry, you guys.
That's okay.
These are nice ranunculus.
Keep naming flowers, John.
Whatever you'd like.
It's just a wedding, honey.
Don't sweat it.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'll leave you guys alone.
I just have to--
I feel like--
It's all right.
She's sitting there, lonely,
in this house, miserable,
which is exactly
what he wants her to feel.
[Sighs]
Are you all right?
No.
Come here.
[Sniffles]
It's gonna be okay.
No, it's not.
I know it seems just weird
that it was so fast, but it
really is gonna be all right.
No, it's not okay!
Okay.
[Sniffles]
Let's just go to sleep.
Yeah.
Listen, I know you're tired
of me saying this.
So don't say it.
And it's upsetting
to hear.
It is.
But it's not
gonna be all right.
It's gonna be terrible.
[Laughs]
That's true.
Things are really
not gonna be okay.
That makes me feel better.
[Laughs]
Just be honest with me.
Yeah. Yeah.
[Laughs]
Thank you.
[Sniffles]
You're welcome.
[John]
I like you.
I want to be with you.
[Molly]
I love being with you.
[John]
I want to wake up
in the morning at your house...
instead of waking up
at my house going,
"I gotta get over to her house.
I miss her."
What do you think?
Did you just ask to move in?
Yes. I did.
So, hold on. Hold on. But...
I don't know which way the wind
is blowing with Cyrus.
And I don't know
how he's feeling.
Yeah, of course.
I don't think that he knows
how he's feeling and--
Let's take it day by day...
for as long as we can go.
[Molly]
Okay.
Yeah, let's do this.
Where are you going?
Where are you taking me?
Right there.
Hmm?
I'm taking you right there.
[Chuckles]
Oh, my goodness.
What are you doing?
I want to get fucked.
You're naughty.
Mm-hmm.
[Moans]
Hey, guys.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
[Screams]
What the--
Hey, man.
[Molly]
Cy--
Sorry for
interrupting you.
Good to see you.
Hi.
Yeah.
Uh, were you planning on
coming over?
We didn't get a message.
Just came home for a bit.
That was, uh, bad timing
there, huh?
Can I have a hug?
Yeah.
Come here.
I went through something
really tough tonight.
Oh, baby.
What happened?
[Clears Throat]
He wants to come back home.
Okay.
He's been having
panic attacks.
Oh, no.
Hmm.
The weird thing is,
it was his decision, you know?
He is an adult and--
I mean--
But these
are panic attacks,
and that doesn't
have anything to do
with being an adult or not.
Yeah.
An adult, that's--
No. I know, I know.
Yep.
Ohh.
Do you mind if
I go talk to him?
[Knocking]
Hey.
You can relax.
It's just me.
I'm sorry?
We should talk.
What the fuck are you doing
with all your shit in my room?
Oh, you're going to stop
bullshitting now? This is good.
[Shoes Drop On Floor]
You know,
I was gonna come back.
I was gonna apologize
to you both.
But after this shit
you just pulled? You just
fucked yourself, John.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna hide my belt now?
You gonna light
a bag of shit on fire
in front of my door?
You are out of your league.
I will do
whatever it takes.
Listen to yourself.
What do you think
your mom would say if she
could hear you right now?
Who's going to
tell her? You?
Who do you think
she's gonna believe?
Her son, who needs her now
more than ever after his battle
with panic and anxiety,
or this new guy who clearly
wants her kid out of the way?
You listen to me,
you little weirdo.
If you want to mess with me,
I'm gonna mess with you
right back.
Oh, buddy.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
I was feeling
a little panicky.
I was talking to John about
how happy I am to be around
you guys right now.
The thought of going back
to that house...
makes me all...
fluttery and nauseous.
You don't have to
go back there, sweetie.
You know, um,
I've never told anybody
this before, but, uh,
I used to get
anxiety attacks.
You did?
Yeah.
So I know how scary
they can be.
Wow.
Did you have a good family
to help you get through it?
You know, I didn't.
I couldn't imagine
going through this alone.
Yeah, but I did.
It was terrifying.
I didn't know what was going on.
They didn't even call them
anxiety attacks back then.
I just thought
I was going crazy.
I almost left college.
But I decided to tough it out.
And that decision
made me who I am.
This could be that
moment in your life.
Where you go from
being a boy to being a man,
and you say, "You know what?
You're not gonna beat me."
- Do you guys not want me
to come home?
- No.
'Cause if so, just say so,
and I'll totally find
another place.
I'll figure something out.
That's not what
he's saying, Cyrus.
No. Not at all.
I'm not saying that.
Look.
You know what
the right decision is.
You know in your heart
what the right thing to do is.
When I looked in my heart,
I decided that it--
I decided that
coming back here...
was not defeat,
but, in a way,
like a weird victory.
And if it's okay
with you, John,
I'd really like
to come back home.
[Mouths Words]
Okay.
Thank you, John.
You're an amazingly
selfless guy.
Thanks, buddy.
[Tim]
It's halftime.
Are you hungry, hon?
I am so fucked.
Honey?
I think it's time you
just had a conversation
with these people--
You know,
all three of you.
I can't.
I can't do that.
Why?
Because if I do,
it's just gonna be between me
and him, and she's gonna
pick him, and that's it.
I lose. I can't do that.
But you tell me
she's supersensitive,
and if you really love her,
then have the conversation
with her.
It doesn't, you know--
Just let the truth come out.
Good night.
Okay.
I love you.
[Cyrus]
Good night.
Oh, um,
I forgot to ask.
John, do you have
an extra tie I could borrow?
A what?
A tie.
I want to try and look nice
for the wedding tomorrow.
Uh, yeah. I think I do.
I've got a bunch of ties,
so I'll find one for you,
if you need it.
Thanks.
All right, good night.
Um, wow.
I didn't know that Cyrus
was coming with to the wedding.
Oh.
Yeah. Yeah. I-I--
I-I know it's a lot,
but he's going through
a lot, so--
Yeah.
Okay?
Okay.
Um,
I don't know
how to put this.
Uh,
do you ever feel like...
Cyrus is not being...
a hundred percent genuine?
How do you mean?
I don't know.
I know he's going
through a lot, and I'm not
trying to deny that.
Um,
I mean, like--
I'm sorry.
Spit it out.
No. Uh--
You're just--
He's behaving in a way
that I think...
is--
um--
All right,
I don't know how else to--
I wasn't gonna tell you
about this, but, whatever,
I'll show you.
My shoes were
in Cyrus's closet.
Hidden.
So, what--
what does that really mean?
I don't know.
You know,
sometimes I think--
and I want to put
this exactly right--
he might be...
acting...
out...
with this behavior.
How long have you
felt like this?
Do I feel that way?
I don't know.
I'm just unearthing things
in my own head right now.
I just--
You know what?
This is too important.
We should have Cyrus
come in here.
No.
Let's talk about this.
No, no, no.
Trust me.
It will really put him
on the spot.
He's having panic attacks.
We'll have a great time
at the wedding.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Yeah.
[Softly]
Cyrus.
[Gasps]
Shh, shh, shh.
It's okay.
Cyrus. Shh.
It's me.
Are you all right?
Am I all right?
Yeah.
What are you
doing in my room?
I want to talk to you.
Listen, I know why
you want to come to
the wedding tomorrow.
This wedding is really,
really important to me.
And my ex-wife's feelings
are really, really
important to me.
And I know we've been messing
around with each other,
and it would be a great time
for you to mess things up
for me and your mom.
I agree.
But here's the thing.
Do you know what it feels like
to be knocked unconscious?
Because if I sense for
one second that anything weird
is going on,
or you're even thinking
of pulling some shit,
I will knock you out.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Good.
Then let's have a great time
at the wedding tomorrow, okay?
How you doing, Roger?
Good. Good.
You look great.
Thank you.
Um,
you know this is a big day
for John, right?
Yes.
Okay.
I choose you to be mine.
To live with you
and laugh with you.
To stand by your side
and sleep in your arms.
To be joy to your heart
and food for your soul.
To bring out the best
in you always.
Jamie and Tim,
please join hands
and repeat after me.
[Woman]
I, Jamie, take you, Tim--
[Jamie] I, Jamie,
take you, Tim--
to be my lawfully
wedded husband--
to be
my lawfully wedded husband--
to have and to hold--
to have
and to hold--
to love and to cherish--
to love
and to cherish--
[Dance]
John. John.
Yeah.
[Dance]
[Plays Notes]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Door Opens]
Oh, I'm in here.
[Zipping]
What?
[Chuckles]
Cyrus, are you drunk?
What happened?
How did you get drunk so fast?
I saw the way you
looked at her, John.
You can't marry her.
You'll never,
ever marry her ever.
Listen to me.
Before you embarrass yourself,
let me call you a cab
and send you home,
'cause you're drunk.
Hey, hey, hey.
Stay away from my mother.
What'd I warn you
about last night?
Don't you do this to me!
She's all I have!
Don't marry her!
Knock it off!
You're not gonna
take her away from me!
Calm the fuck down!
You'll never fucking
punch me, John!
- Get your shit together!
- Just leave us the fuck alone!
Fuck you!
She's all I fucking have!
Go, John!
Go! Just go away!
- Just go away
and leave us the fuck alone!
- Put some water on your face!
Stop it!
Leave us alone!
You stop it!
Stop it!
What are you doing? Hey!
Hey! Hey!
I'm not doing anything!
What, are you
out of your mind?
You stop it!
[Cyrus]
He hit me.
- Did you hit him?
- He attacked me
in the bathroom!
Did you hit him?
[Cyrus]
He hit me.
[Jamie] John!
Open your eyes, Molly.
[John]
He went crazy in the bathroom.
Well, I didn't see
that part.
I didn't even know
that happened.
So, what did you think?
Did you think
that I suddenly--
I wasn't thinking.
tackled Cyrus
and was beating him up?
- How could you
think that about me?
- I just reacted.
I just saw my son
on the floor being hurt.
From the moment
that I met you,
as soon as your son
became aware of it, he made it
his mission to split us up.
Every step of the way,
every overture I made,
every time I tried to be
understanding and reach out
to him, he's shut me down.
He hates me, Molly.
- He hates me.
- He's having a really
tough time.
He's not having a tough time.
Your son hates me.
And I gotta say,
I fucking hate him too.
Nothing here
between us that's...
worth taking
another look at?
You and I--
We do have something.
And I know how rare it is,
because it's
been a long time...
since I had anyone
close to someone like you.
But I am not prepared...
to get deeper into it and
hoping it's gonna work out,
and then two years down the line
it's not gonna work out,
and you guys have each other,
and I'm alone again.
I just think
there's so much here
between us and--
He's gonna not--
He's gonna wreck it.
So that's it.
I'm sorry.
[Door Opens]
[Door Closes]
[Molly]
I've been thinking
about us, and...
I feel like
I've missed a few things
in our relationship.
And I feel that
I've done you a disservice...
with the way that I raised you,
in some aspects.
[Cyrus]
I'm so proud of...
who we are
and how close we are.
I don't think
there's any reason...
to feel negatively about that.
[Molly]
The fact that you and I
have a hard time...
letting another person...
hang out with us is...
unhealthy for us, I feel.
I don't want you
to think that...
I want you to be alone forever
or want you to be unhappy.
I want you to find somebody
and be with him.
But I know in my heart
that John is not that person.
[Molly] There are things
that are happening
from all sides of this.
I-I--
I know what happened
with the shoes.
Who cares? It's shoes.
It's so stupid.
It's shoes.
I don't care about shoes.
But I care if
you're lying to me.
[Cyrus] I used to feel like
you and I had a special
little thing, and now...
I'm feeling like you...
are letting me go away.
[Molly]
No one will ever...
ever take your place.
Ever.
[Cyrus]
Well, I'm happy he's gone.
[Molly]
I'm not happy right now.
[Knocking]
[Sighs]
What do you want?
I want you to come back
and live with us.
Are you
fucking kidding me?
Come on,
just go home, Cyrus.
It's not the same anymore!
Oh, it's not the same?
No. She's depressed!
That's 'cause you
fucked it up!
She misses you, John!
I know you love her!
Yeah, I know!
We had a great thing,
and you fucked it up!
Please, John. Just hear me out
and then you can make
the decision for yourself.
I'll move out.
I'll do whatever you want.
Don't punish her
'cause I'm a fucked-up person.
I-I-- It's--
It's not her fault.
No, it's not her fault!
It's not her fault!
It's your fault!
So you just live with that,
you asshole!
It's your fault that I'm back
in a shitty apartment all alone!
You're a little fucking liar
and an asshole!
So fuck you!
Go away!
Are you still out there?
Move over.
[Sniffles]
[Sighs]
Let me ask you something.
Were the panic attacks
real or fake?
They were real at first,
and then...
sometimes I would fake them
to get sympathy from Molly.
[Sniffles]
I brought you something.
It's mixed,
but it's not mastered.
So it's not final.
I think I might be
a really fucked-up and
dysfunctional person, John.
You did some
fucked-up stuff.
But it's my fault too.
How'd you get through
all these panic attacks?
[Chuckles]
I'm sorry.
I never had panic attacks.
I made that up
to try to get rid of you.
[Chuckles]
[Laughs]
It was war at that point.
I was desperate.
I had to come up
with something.
You were boxing me out.
You're good, John.
Well, you're good.
Would you mind--
Would you mind
giving me a ride home?
Okay. Is your mom home?
No.
All right. 'Cause--
I don't know. I'm just--
I'm really not ready
to talk to her yet.
[John]
I'm just gonna drop you off
right here, if that's okay.
[Cyrus]
Yeah.
Thanks for the ride.
No problem.
I have some of your stuff
in the garage that you left.
I'll go grab it.
Right now?
Yeah. I'll be right back.
[Sighs]
[Door Closes]
[Man]
My love
Please
Realize we're okay
I can't wait
to sleep tonight
Will you be there
My love
Please
[Ends]
[Guitar]
[Man]
I buried a bone
And, darling
you don't know him
Darling, you don't know him
Darling, you don't know
And just where you are
might be the right place
Might be that sweet space
But you don't know
Look me in the head
I got nothin' on my mind
I've been waitin' for you
all this time
And I seen a path
turn to an old road
But the secret's too slow
Or we're too fast
Look me in the mouth
I got nothin' in my smile
I've been waitin' for you
You're just my style
Look me in the gut
I got fear for my own name
I'd dig it up for you
If you'd do the same
I buried a bone
And, darling
you don't know him
Darling, you don't know him
Darling, you don't know
[Ends]
[Instrumental]