[Seagulls Crying]
Finn: There eitheris
oris not a waythings are.
The color ofthe day,
the wayit felt to be a child...
the feeling ofsaltwater
onyoursunburned legs.
Sometimes the water isyellow...
sometimes it's red...
but what color
it may be in memory...
depends on the day.
I'm not going to tell the story
the way that it happened.
I'm going to tell it
the way I remember it.
Aah!
Help! Help!
[Muffled Yells]
[Muffled Yelling]
What's your name?
Mmf!.
Whisper. What's your name?
Whisper!
Finn.
-Your last name?
- Bell.
Where doyou live?
Nearthe pier.
You have tools?
Help-- Mmf!.
Fuck. Doyou know
what bolt cutters are?
You knowwhatthey are or
you don't knowwhatthey are?
Mm-hmm.
Listen, I knowyour name,
I knowwhereyou live...
I can find you
and gutyou like a fish.
I'll pull out
yourfucking insides.
I'll makeyou eatthem,
you hear me?
I'll makeyou
fucking eatthem.
You be here
tomorrow morning at dawn...
with bolt cutters
and any kind offood...
or I'll kill you for sure,
you got me?
I'll fucking kill you
ifyou tell anyone-- anyone!
-Yourfolks--
-They're dead.
You tell anyone,
the last sound you hear...
will be your own scream.
All right. Go.
Whoa, Finn!Whoa!
Oh, it'syou,Joe.
Did I scareyou?
Soyou went outtoday?
Yeah. Got a nice tan.
No fish, of course.
Settin' traps
like everybody else.
Hey, where's the fire?
Nowhere.
Just got homework.
Hey, listen, Maggie's
on a kinda ranttoday...
soyou be careful, OK?
You coming home soon?
In about an hour.
You finish yourwork,
we'll go to Carvel's, OK?
You rest up.
Got a gardeningjob tomorrow.
Joe?
Yeah?
Nothin'.
Hey, Finn!
How doyou smoke
a swordfish?
Bill in your mouth
and lightthetail.
[Chuckles] All right.
I'll seeyou later.
Finn:I was raised
in whatlsuppose...
was certain amount offreedom
from mysisterMaggie.
Joe was her man.
They banned the big fishing rigs
in the gulfthatyear...
and we were poor.
We scraped by
on whatJoe could earn...
doing charters
and lawn work.
[Children Laughing]
[Game Show Plays On TV]
[Thunder]
Man: Hey.
Hey.
Come on. Come here.
Come on!
You alone?
You deaf?
Areyou alone?
No.
You're not alone,
oryou're not deaf?
Gimme that.
Come on!
Here. I broughtyou
something to drink.
Attaboy.
Ahh...
Ow!
Here. I tookthis foryou.
What's this?
Birth control pills?
Here. This, too.
Percodan.
Attaboy.
Nowyou're talking.
What else?
Come on, come on.
Jesus fucking Christ.
You biteyour nails?
That's a bad habit.
Peopletell you the eyes
arethewindowstothe soul.
Bullshit.
Hands...
that'sthe sign
of a gentleman.
Huh?
Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Finn:What??!.
Come on, come on.
Get in the boat.
If I don't get home,
my uncle--
Fuckyour uncle.
Get in the boat.
Pick up the anchor.
Let's go.
Where--
Shut up and
get in the boat.
Where are we going?
Mexico.
Man:What?
Police boat.
-What?
- Police boat.
Stop. Stop.
Officer: Ahoythere!
Son, areyou all right?
Uh-huh.
Whereyou headed?
Oh, nowhere.
An old lady over on Cat Cay
thought she saw a raft...
out hereyesterday
with a man on it.
He'd be wearing
an orange prison suit.
You see anything like that?
Mmm, nope.
Tie up our line
and we'll towyou in.
Finn:
Andthat wasthe endofit.
Perhapsyou've had
an experience like that...
in childhood
and told no one.
Perhapsyou've had that brush
with a world so large...
thatyou seldom or never
saw it again.
J oe: J esus.
It's the land time forgot.
It's Nora Driggers Dinsmoor.
You wait here.
I'm gonna go find out...
whattheywant us to do.
Is it all right
if I take a look around?
No. You stay put
till I come back.
I mean it.
God knowswhat's
in theseweeds.
Finn:
Nora Driggers Dinsmoor...
the richest ladyin the gulf...
who had lost her mind
30years ago...
when herfiancé left her
standing at the altar.
[Frogs Croaking]
Girl:
What's your name?
Finn.
[Whistles]
Hey, Finn?
Hey!
Come on.
Ha-ha-ha!
Hey, man,
we're out of here.
She slipped me $500
underthe door.
Gas money, she called it.
Weirdestthing.
What?
Nothin'.
Can I ridewith you?
Sure.Just don't
sittoo close.
You smell likefertilizer.
Really? I do?
Ha-ha-ha!
Joe: Mag?
Maybeyou've got
the wrong number.
You're not gonna believe
where we were--
Yes, well, he just--
Did he do something bad?
I'll be glad to.
That sounds really--
You got it.
OK. 3:00.
This Saturday?
And thankyou
so much, ma'am.
Babe,you are not gonna believe
where we were today.
Joe, thatwas
Nora Driggers Dinsmoor.
See, I knew itwas
too good to be true.
She want her money back?
She wants him. Finn.
The richest lady
in the whole goddamn state...
calls me on the phone
and wants my little brother...
to go playwith her niece.
Yeah? Why?
Why? She met him.
The old bat liked you.
He's a likable kid.
He's adorable.
Who knows? Who cares?
Joe, this is
a really good thing.
No, no, no. How--
Dinsmoor never even met Finn.
She wouldn't open the door.
She slipped this underneath.
What is it?
What is it,Joe? God!
[Joe Chuckles]
You like living here?
You like living here
with all the dead people?
What'swrongwith the people
down here all of a sudden?
I'm tired ofworking
so many extra shifts...
to put it back
intoyour boat.
Theytook awaythe nets.
I can't change that.
Fuckthe nets,Joe!
TV: Escapedconvict
ArthurLustig was recaptured...
earlierthis evening
bySarasota police.
This concludes a 4-day,
statewide manhunt for Lustig...
the convicted murderer
ofGene Valiente.
Valiente, reputed Mob boss
ofthe Castellano family...
was gunned down in
his Bradenton home last Christmas.
L ustig will be returned...
to Raiford Penitentiary's
death row...
where he is
scheduled to die...
by lethal injection
March 1 6th.
I'm Robin Wagner reporting from--
Holy shit.
Hey, you look sharp.
How do I smell?
[Sniffs]
You smell clean.
OK, tea time.
Now, be polite in there.
Sayyes, ma'am. No, ma'am.
I will.
You OKwith this?
He's great. Go ahead.
Say may I, please,
all that stuff.
[Gongs]
Oh. It's the gardener.
Girl:
The design ofthis floor...
wastaken from
the Alhambra in Spain.
The ceiling is gold leaf.
Real gold.
It's exactly like
thethousand wing ceiling...
from the Accademia
in Venice.
Finn: OldMs. Dinsmoor
hadn'tbeenseen inyears.
I'd heard
thatshe was crazy.
Go ahead.
Aren'tyou coming?
Quel sot.
Finn:
But nobodyknewhow crazy.
Her room smelled
ofdead flowers and catpiss.
[Music Playing]
[Bird Squawking]
Woman: Chicka-boom, chicka-boom,
chicka-boom-boom-boom.
Chicka-boom, chicka-boom,
chicka-boom.
[Record Plays]
Chicka-boom, chicka-boom,
chicka-boom.
Chicka-boom!
~ Bésame ~
~ Bésame mucho ~
~ Each time
I cling toyour kiss ~
~ I hear music divine ~
~ Bésame ~
~ Bésame mucho ~
~ Hold me, my darling ~
~ And saythat
you'll always be mine ~
~This joy
is something new ~
~ My arms enfoldingyou ~
~ Never knew
thisthrill before ~
~Whoeverthought I'd be ~
~ Holdingyou closeto me ~
~Whispering
it'syou I adore? ~
Who areyou?
Finn, ma'am.
What areyou doing
in my bedroom, Finn?
I don't know.
Give meyour hand.
What is this?
Your--Your boob.
My heart. It's my heart.
It's broken.
Can you tell?
I'm sorry.
Mmm.
[Record Ends]
It's all right. Come.
Shoo-shoo.
Tabby, scram.
Wow. That's a big cat.
That's the biggest cat
I've ever seen.
What doyou feed it?
Other cats.
Well, go ahead.
You can proceed.
Dance.
Huh?
I'd likeyou
to dance for me.
That's whyyou're here.
To entertain me.
So go ahead, dance.
Pony, fox trot, frug.
Philly dog, fandango.
Anything.
I can't.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
You can't?
" I'm sorry, ma'am"?
Oryou won't?
Dance! Dance! Dance!
Oh, get out of here.
Wait!
I can draw.
You can use my lipstick
and eyebrow pencil...
overthere
on the dressing table.
Estella?
Is tea ready?
I'd likeyou to sit
for a portrait.
A portrait?
Bywhom?
That boy.
The gardener?
I'll be in my room.
Come back and sit.
Please.
And you come sit
by me, hmm?
[Rreow]
Allez, allez.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Unejeune déesse,
n'est-ce pas?
Ne parle pas de moi
d'avant ce garçon.
What do you think of her?
Come on.
Whisper in my ear.
[Whispering]
I think she's a snob.
Anything else?
I think she's real pretty.
I think she
doesn't like me.
Butyou love her.
She'll only break
your heart. It's a fact.
It's tragic.
You're already in love with her.
And even though I warn you,
even though I guaranteeyou...
thatthe girl will only
hurtyou terribly...
you'll still pursue her.
Ain't love grand?
Woman:
~ Bésame mucho ~
~Que tengo miedoperderte~
~Perderte otra vez~
~ Quiero tenerte muy cerca~
~ Mirarme en tus ojos
vertejunto a mi~
~ Piensa que tal vez mañana ~
~ Yoya estare lejos
Muy lejos de ti~
~Which means... ~
I'd like to go now.
Oh, have you finished?
Before I'm a teenager, please.
Can I go now?
[Sighs]
Would you like
to come again?
to see Estella again?
Yes.
Poor boy. Poor boy.
Poor boy.
This isyours, dear.
Finn:
The ways ofthe rich...
andall mylonging...
which began that day.
To paint forthe rich,
to have theirfreedom...
to love Estella--
The things we cannot have.
Dinsmoor:
Give this to your guardian.
Would you see Finn out,
please?
Chicka-boom.
Want some?
It's not poisoned.
Mmm!
Finn:
You rememberit.
You rememberhowitfelt.
And then I went home
to drawit.
Joe:
You look in the drawer?
[Coughing]
I'm going to work.
What are you gonna do
beforeyou go to bed?
Brush myteeth.
That's really beautiful,
Finn.
Keep it up, OK?
Finn:
Maggie leftthatnight.
She never came back.
I'll seeyou
when you wake up.
Joe raised me.
We neversaida word.
We neversaid a word.
I still visited
Paradiso Perduto everySaturday.
Feel it. Feel it.
The money Dinsmoorpaid me...
kept me in paints
and brushes.
And there was Estella.
Chicka-boom.
Dinsmoor:
Smile.
All right, don't smile.
Ahh,yes, feel it!
Wonderful, wonderful.
Feel it in your bones.
[Singing]
[Music Ends]
[Clapping]
Where areyou going, dear?
I havethatcocktail thing
atthe Rewalds.
Lane Rewald?
Thatold gin blossom?
One more cocktail,
we'll be ableto eat him.
Karl Rewald.
Lane is hisfather.
Karl doesn't even drink.
Thewholefamily's pickled.
Who'syour escort?
Escort? Please.
This is the eighties.
I'll bringyou.
Certainly.
Finn will make a fine date.
Oh, God.
Then it's done.
OK, fine, butyou meet me there.
1 1 15 North Ocean.
All right. Sure.
And wearyour dinnerjacket.
Joe:
How much timeyou got?
None! I'm late!
I'm dead!Wow!
That'll pass
as a dinnerjacket, huh?
This is a girl's.
Just keep it buttoned,
and no one will notice.
Where'd you getthis?
It's Maggie's.
It's one of
the onlythings she left.
What a bitch.
What??!.
"What." Come here.
Jeez.
You all rightfor money?
Yeah, I'm good.
You a little nervous?
Yeah, a little.
Ahh--
You got it?
Thereyou go.
Wow.
You just beyourself, huh?
Go on. Have fun.
You're not on the list.
All right. Could you
checkthe name "Dinsmoor"?
Yes, I did, sir.
You're not on this list.
I'd appreciate
ifyou'd leave now.
Hi, Mrs. Lake.
Mr. Lake, right
in the usual spot, sir.
Mr. and Mrs. Catcher.
[Knock On Window]
Hi.
You wantto get me
out of here?
Yes.
Come on in.
Where doyou wantto go?
I don't know.
How aboutyour house?
All right.
Let's go.
The moths around
the light bulb here...
arefrom thethousand wing ceiling
in Venice, Italy.
Uh,Joe's not here.
He's, um--
He's, uh, I don't know,
playing dominoes.
Is thatyour room?
Yeah. Yeah.
I wasn't really
expecting company.
You know?
You still draw.
Yeah.
Gonna hang a couple ofthem up
atWashington Federal.
The bank?
Yeah.
You haveto goto NewYork.
NewYork?
It'sthe center
ofthe artworld.
Ifyou stay here,you'll end up
painting coconutsfortourists.
When did you dothis?
Awhile ago.
I don'twearmy hair
likethat anymore.
Butyou should.
I mean--
You like itthatway?
What else doyou like?
How come all thistime
we see each other everyweek...
you know, butwe
never did anything?
Did anything?
Went out, saw a movie,
whatever.
You never asked.
And if I had?
I'm here, aren't I?
Areyou with anyone?
Rightthis second?
No. I mean, like--
Like a steady boyfriend?
Yes.
No.
You could have anyone.
No rush.
What aboutyou?
Why not?
'Cause I...
I...
I just--
I know.
~Worried mornings
turn into days ~
~ And into worried nights ~
~ But it's all right~
~When you're all in pain ~
~ And you feel the rain
come down ~
~ Oh, it's all right~
~Though your garden's gray ~
~ I know all your graces ~
~Somedaywill flower ~
~Ohh ~
What'swrong?
Nothing. It's late.
Whattime is it?
It's, uh, it's 10:30.
Where areyou going?
I've gotto get home.
Why?
'Cause I have a million things
to do tonight.
Stay.
Je vaisaller
à France demain.
I don't speak French.
Quel dommage.
~When you're all in pain ~
~ And you feel the rain
come down ~
~ Oh, it's all right~
Estella?
Excuse me.
Haveyou seen Estella?
Finn:
Dinsmoorwas weirderthan usual.
But I had to see Estella.
I never come here.
Never.
You knowwhy?
26 years ago,
I trusted.
I saved myself.
I was a virgin.
It's funny, hmm?
Those were the times.
That's how I was raised.
[Laughs]
What kind of creature
takes such a thing?
Such a gift? Atrust?
Who does this?
Takes advantage
of a 42-year-old woman?
What kind of creature...
Ieaves this woman
waiting like a fool?
A man. A man does this.
So men must pay.
Am I right?
Estella will make men weep.
Doyou knowwhere she is?
Oh,yes.
She'll breakthem.
I taught herwell.
When she returns...
she'll cutthrough them
like a hot knifethrough butter.
Chicka-boom.
Returns?
Oh, my dear boy...
didn'tyou know?
Estella's left
for school abroad.
Switzerland for 2 years,
then Paris.
She's gone.
Didn't she say good-bye?
Oh, I'm sure she meantto.
Seeyou nextweek, dear.
~~ [Humming Bésame Mucho]
~You know
you're gonna lie toyou ~
Finn:
7yearspassed.
Istoppedgoing
to Paradiso Perduto.
I stoppedpainting.
I put aside fantasy
and the wealthy...
and the heavenly girl
who did not want me.
None of it would happen
to me again.
I'd seen through it.
I elected to grow up.
~ I know too well ~
~ Know the chill ~
~ Know she breaks ~
~ My siren ~
~ Know teenage flesh ~
~ Know the chill ~
~ Know she breaks ~
~ My siren ~
~ Know I know chill ~
~ Know I ~
~ Neverwas one
for a prissy girl ~
~ Coquette ~
~ Callingfor an ambulance ~
~ Reach high ~
~ Doesn'tmean she's holy ~
~Justmeans
she's gota cellular handy ~
~ Almost brave-- ~
Joe:
Finn!
This isJerry Ragno.
Jerry-- Mr. Ragno
is a lawyer in Miami.
And NewYork.
We have offices in Manhattan.
So, Finn,
I'm empowered by my client...
to makeyour dreams
come true.
Ha-ha-ha!
Really?
Any particular dream or...
just all ofthem?
Ragno: Haveyou
ever shown yourwork?
Joe:Well, they had
Finn's painting up...
atWashington Federal Bank.
Come on!
Thatwas 7-- 8years ago.
I told you
I gave all that up.
I-- I don't understand what
this is all about, Mr. Ragno.
Howwould you like a show?
A one-man show.
Thrall Gallery.
In NewYork.
Yeah. My client
Erica Thrall...
wants to bringyou
to NewYork.
Why?
For a show in her gallery.
This is bullshit.
Haveyou ever sent slides
ofyourwork...
totheThrall Gallery?
Probably. I sent
slides everywhere...
when I was in high school.
Obviouslytheymade
quite an impression.
A planeticket
to NewYork plus $ 1,000...
for incidentals.
Sorry. They're all in hundreds.
[Joe Laughing]
Whoo.
Mmm.
Well...
the hundreds
aren'tthe problem.
I just-- I don't
paint anymore.
Whoa.
~Bésame~
Finn:
Whose business was it?
Whose business was it
what I did with mylife?
Who'd gotten
mylife in order? Me.
I was in control.
And everything I wanted,
I had.
~ Bésame ~
Ms. Dinsmoor?
Cocktails ready, Thomas?
Uh, no. It's-- It's me.
It's Finn.
I came--
Looking for Estella.
I know.
That hook is in deep,
isn't it, dear?
Actually, I came
to askyou a question.
I see.
After nearly 10years...
without a word,
without a visit.
Come to interrogate me.
How interesting.
I'm sorry.
Things happened.
I knowwhat happened.
The love ofyour life
leftyou.
Hurts, doesn't it?
Come closer.
I've gone red.
Yeah, I noticed.
It's nice.
And look atyou.
All grown up. A man.
Ms. Dinsmoor, a lawyer
named Ragno came to see me.
Spider.
You know him?
Ragno means "spider"
in Italian.
You must learn
other languages, Finn.
This lawyer Ragno
says he represents...
an art gallery owner
in NewYork...
and theywant
to show mywork.
You can draw.
You can't dance
worth a shit...
butyou can draw.
I wanted to ask. Did you
know anything aboutthis?
Estella's in NewYork.
I doubt our pathswill cross.
Soyou're going?
You think I should?
I rememberwatchingyou
from thatverywindow overthere.
A scared little mouse
scurrying across my garden...
and through myfront door.
Now... another door opens.
Whatwill our mouse do?
I expect an invitation.
I'm sorry?
Toyour opening. Your show.
Ahh.
P.A.: This is
yourfinal boarding call.
What kind of equipment
you flying?
What?
They gotyou on
a widebody or767?
I have no idea. I just
hope it stays upthere.
[Chuckles]
Well,you better get on.
Yeah.
What happens if I get
up there and, uh...
I can't--
I can't do it?
Hey, Finn...
nothing harderthan
being given your chance.
At least
that's what I hear.
[Laughing]
Sir? Sir?
You can't proceed
without a ticket.
[Making Airplane Noises]
Taxi!
Man:
You fucked a dead man!
You know how I know?
'Cause I'm gonna kill
the motherfucker!
Hold on! Shit! Hold on!
Hey,you got change
for a dollar?
What?
Fuckyou! Fuckyou!
Wait-- Fuckyou, man!
Fuckyou!
Finn:
Well, then, there I was.
Ms. Dinsmoor
as mysecret benefactor...
sent me to New York to draw...
to have the girl...
to have it all...
and I looked out
on the great city...
as so many before
which held it all...
and it was that close...
and it was mine.
Liebchen, gut Morgen.
Are you still
holding the Picasso...
the red and green one?
Good, because I think
I have somebody interested.
No, I can't say right now.
Justthe Picasso.
Fabelhaft. Danke.
Yourwork, darling?
Here's whereyou
show meyourwork.
Right. I told you.
There isn't any.
Then you better get busy.
Belly out.
Why am I here?
You saw some slides?
I gave Keith Haring a show...
after he drew a sketch
in the palm ofmy hand.
Thatworked out.
Butwhich ones?
Which paintings did you like?
The point is I saw
the beginning of something.
And hereyou are.
Annette at Sotheby's.
Whatyou do here
is really uptoyou, isn't it?
Stay and paint, or enjoy
the sights and go home.
Your choice.
Eitherway, I always enjoy
meeting a young painter.
Look, I mean,
I'll do it.
I said that I'll do it.
I'll dothe paintings.
Wonderful. Call Marcy
when you have somethingfor us.
Finn:
Andl couldstill draw.
Nothinghadlessenedit
as much as I hadabusedit...
much as I hadabandoned it.
It was a gift,
and it was still mine.
And everything else
was less real.
What could it mean,
that picture ofthe world?
But when it's true...
we recognize it...
in ourselves, in others.
We recognize it,
like love--
completely undeserved.
You're drooling.
So...
Finn Bell...
in New York.
That's right.
You know,
I thought I sawyou...
Iastwinter around Christmas.
I was driving down Fifth.
Itwas mobbed.
No, itwasn't me.
I just got here.
Well, actually,
nowthat I seeyou...
this guywas...
bigger.
Bigger?
Fatter.
Mm-hmm.
And he had this long hair--
Yeah? You thought
thatwas me?
Well,you know, I hadn't
seen you in years.
It has been a while.
And here we are.
I have to run.
Well, wait, wait,
maybe we could--
Listen, why not
meet me tomorrow...
atthe Borough Club
around 6:00?
I'm meeting some friends
for drinks.
Ifyou're free, that is.
I'm free.
I'm glad you're here.
Man: A long time ago,
there lived 2 brilliant artists--
Geniuses--
Both true geniuses.
And one day, one ofthem
was painting out in the forest--
as artists do--
and he came upon
this little dog...
who was crying and whining
and obviously lost.
Man:
A puppy.
Please. Yes, sure,
a puppy. Fine.
So, um, he couldn't
concentrate anyway...
so he scooped
the puppy up-- puppy--
and he took him
back into town...
to find its rightful owner...
who turned outto be...
the prince
ofthe entire kingdom...
who was eternally grateful...
and verywealthy.
And that artist's name
was...
Michelangelo.
True story.
The other artist's name was--
Nobody knows, because he was
never heard from again.
Woman: Never heard from again.
Right, right.
No, that's so true,Walter.
Is it all right
if I smoke?
Man:We've all heard
your de Kooning stories.
You want one?
Woman:
Oh, really, come on.
It'syour last one.
Oh. Uh--
It's all right.
Uh, so, you're--
[Snaps Fingers]
Cigarette, please.
You're from Florida, too?
Yeah.
I'm surrounded.
Everybody's from Florida.
I'm notfrom Florida.
I hate Florida.
Too much sun.
- Man: Yeah.
- Really?
Actually,
Finn was my childhood--
Whatwereyou, exactly?
He was my, uh...
first love.
Man:
I thought I was.
Ifthat's whatyou say.
He painted a portrait ofme...
when I was 10years old
thatwas so beautiful.
Woman:
I satfor a portrait once.
Electric experience.
Man: Great. You slept
with de Kooning.
Can we get on
with our lives?
I did not.
I'd like to paintyou again.
Would you?
I wantto paint
your portrait.
What doyou think,
sweetheart?
Me?
Ha-ha.
Um--
Well, gee...
doyou charge bythe inch
or bythe hour?
[Laughter]
What?
How doyou priceyour art?
By, like, its size--
like, squarefootage--
or bythe time
ittakes to make...
[Others Laugh]
the art?
I--
I've actually never
sold a painting.
Sir! Excuse me, sir.
Please, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
That's a club jacket
you have on.
This isyourjacket.
Oh,yeah, right.
Let me helpyou.
Thankyou.
[Door Opens]
What areyou doing here?
Don'tyou wantto paintme?
Yeah.
Well,you've slept all day,
so it's time to work.
You wantto do it right now?
Mm-hmm.
OK.
How'd you get in here?
Theyjust letyou in, huh?
Not exactly
top-of-the-line security.
~ Everytime ~
~ I get no further ~