[♪♪♪]
PHIL:
Somebody asked me today,
"Phil, if you could be anywhere in the
world, where would you like to be?"
And I said to him,
"Probably right here,
Elko, Nevada."
Our nation's high at 79 today.
Out in California, they're gonna have
some warm weather tomorrow,
gang wars and some very
overpriced real estate.
Up in the Pacific
Northwest, as you can see,
they're gonna have some
very, very tall trees.
Clear across the Rockies
and the Great Plains, mostly.
But look out,
here comes trouble.
Oh, boy!
Front coming our way!
Look out!
What's that gonna mean to us in the Three
Rivers area? One of these big blue things!
This cold, frigid arctic air, this
big mass coming out of the north.
It's gonna meet up with all this
moisture coming up out of the Gulf.
Gonna mix together at high
altitudes and cause some snow.
Going out on a limb now:
Not gonna hit us here in Pittsburgh.
Gonna push off and hit Altoona.
Phew, close call, folks.
Let's take a look
at the five-day.
As you can see, nothing
to be too scared about.
Bundle up warm, of course, but I think
you can leave your galoshes at home.
I'm not gonna be
here for the 10:00.
Tomorrow is Groundhog Day, and
I'm going out to Punxsutawney
for our country's oldest
groundhog festival.
So as you know, according to
the legend, tomorrow, February 2nd,
if the groundhog wakes
and sees his shadow,
we've got six more weeks of winter to look
forward to. So keep your fingers crossed.
Sounds like a lot of fun.
You must really enjoy it.
This is your third year
in a row, isn't it, Phil?
Four, Nan. Four.
Thanks, Phil.
Up next, entertainment editor Diane Kingman
looks at sex and violence in the movies.
Stay with us.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN:
And we're clear.
Have fun in Punxsutawney, Phil.
For your information, Hairdo, there
is a major network interested in me.
Yeah, that would be the
Home Shopping Network.
Thanks, Larry.
Go wait in the van, will you?
That was nice, Phil.
"Big trees"!
Stop, Kenny. Look, can you
handle the 10 or not?
Yeah, yeah.
Listen, if for any reason you don't want
to rush back, I can do the 5 tomorrow.
Oh, come on. I wanna stay an extra
second in Punxsutawney? Please!
Well, Rita thinks it would be a great idea
to stay around for some of the other events.
You'll get some
incredible footage.
The people and the fun.
The excitement!
You haven't worked with her yet,
have you? She's really nice.
I think she's gonna be
a really good producer.
You guys are gonna have fun.
Mm-mm! She's fun. But not my kind of fun.
I will be here for the 5.
Rita.
[DELBERT McCLINTON'S
"WEATHERMAN" PLAYING]
Can you keep a secret, Larry?
I'm probably leaving PBH.
So this will be the last time
we do the Groundhog together.
I don't understand what's wrong
with the Groundhog Festival.
When I worked in San Diego,
I covered the swallows returning
to Capistrano six years in a row.
Someday, somebody's gonna see me interviewing
a groundhog, think I don't have a future.
I think it's a nice story.
He comes out.
He looks around.
He wrinkles up his little nose.
He sees his shadow, he doesn't see his
shadow. It's nice. People like it.
You are new, aren't you?
You know, people like blood sausage too.
People are morons.
Nice attitude.
I want you to look in the mirror and see what you
look like when you do that little groundhog thing.
Okay? For me? Once?
He comes out, and there he
looks at his little shadow.
Would you like some
blood sausage? I have some...
I like blood sausage.
[DELBERT McCLINTON'S
"WEATHERMAN" PLAYING]
Rita, I can't stay here.
LARRY:
Prima Donna.
What's the matter, Phil?
I hate this place.
I stayed here two years ago.
I was miserable. It's a fleabag.
I'm not staying here.
You're not staying here.
I'm not?
No.
Larry's just dropping me off.
I booked you in a very nice
bed-and-breakfast on Cherry Street.
Great.
You know, I think this is one of the
traits of a really good producer.
Keep the talent happy.
Anything I can do.
Would you help me
with my pelvic tilt?
[CHUCKLES]
Within reason. Would you like to
come to dinner with Larry and me?
No, thank you.
I've seen Larry eat.
[CHUCKLES]
You get your sleep.
I'll see you in the morning.
RITA:
Don't be late.
Did he actually call himself
"the talent"?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[SONNY & CHER'S "I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
DJ 1 [ON RADIO]:
Okay, campers, rise and shine!
And don't forget your booties,
because it's cold out there!
DJ 2: It's cold out there every day!
What is this, Miami Beach?
DJ 1: Not hardly!
And you know, you can expect hazardous
travel later today with that...
You know, that blizzard thing.
DJ 2: Oh, that blizzard thing.
That blizzard thing.
Oh, well, here's the report.
The National Weather Service
is calling for a big blizzard thing.
DJ 1: Yes, they are.
But you know, there's another reason
why today is especially exciting...
DJ 2: Especially cold.
DJ 1: Especially cold, okay.
But the big question
on everybody's lips...
DJ 2: Their chapped lips.
DJ 1: On their chapped lips, right.
Do you think Phil's gonna
come out and see his shadow?
DJ 2:
Punxsutawney Phil!
DJ 1:
That's right, woodchuck chuckers!
BOTH:
It's Groundhog Day!
DJ 1: Get up and check
that hog out there! Hyah!
DJ 2:
Sooey! Sooey! Come here, girl!
[BOTH OINKING]
Morning!
Morning.
You off to see the groundhog?
Yes, I am.
You think it's gonna be
an early spring?
I'm predicting March 21 st.
Good guess!
You know, I think that
actually is the first day of spring.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
I slept alone, Mrs. Lancaster.
Would you like some coffee?
I don't suppose there's any possibility of getting
an espresso or cappuccino this morning, is there?
Oh, I really don't know, um...
How to spell espresso or
cappuccino. This looks fine.
I hope you enjoy
the festivities.
Oh, yeah, I'm sure I'm going to.
There's talk of a blizzard.
Well, we may catch a break and that
blizzard's gonna blow right by us.
All of this moisture
coming up out of the south
by midday is probably gonna
push on to the east of us.
And at high altitudes it's gonna
crystallize and give us what we call snow.
Probably be some accumulation.
But here in Punxsutawney, our high's gonna
get up to about 30 today, teens tonight.
Chance of precipitation, about 20
percent today, 20 percent tomorrow.
Did you want to talk about the weather
or were you just making chitchat?
Chitchat.
Okay. See you later.
Bye.
Oh, um, will you be checking
out today, Mr. Connors?
Chance of departure today,
100 percent.
Phil? Hey, Phil?
Phil? Phil Connors! Phil
Connors, I thought that was you!
Hi, how you doing?
Thanks for watching.
Hey, hey.
Now, don't you tell me
you don't remember me,
because I sure as
heckfire remember you.
Not a chance.
Ned!
Ryerson!
Needlenose Ned.
Ned the Head.
Come on, buddy.
Case Western High!
Ned Ryerson, I did the whistling-bellybutton
trick at the high school talent show.
Bing! Ned Ryerson, got the shingles real
bad senior year. Almost didn't graduate.
Bing again!
Ned Ryerson, I dated your sister, Mary Pat, a
couple times till you told me not to anymore.
Well?
Ned Ryerson?
Bing!
Bing.
So did you turn pro with that
bellybutton thing, Ned, or what?
No, Phil.
I sell insurance.
What a shock.
Do you have life insurance?
Because if you do, you could
always use a little more.
Am I right or am I right or am
I right? Right? Right? Right?
Ned, I would love to stand here
and talk with you.
But I'm not going to.
See you.
Hey, that's all right!
I'll walk with you.
You know, whenever I see an opportunity
now, I charge it like a bull.
Ned the Bull, that's me now.
You know, I got friends of mine who
live and die by the actuarial tables.
And I say, hey, it's all
one big crapshoot anyhoo.
Tell me, have you ever heard
of single-premium life?
Because I think that really
could be the ticket for you.
Oh, God!
It is so good to see you!
What are you doing for dinner?
Something else.
It's been great seeing you,
Needlehead. Take care.
Whoa-ho-ho-ho!
[LAUGHING]
Watch out for that
first step. It's a doozy!
[FRANKIE YANKOVIC'S "PENNSYLVANIA
POLKA" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
RITA:
Hey, Phil! Phil, over here!
Where have you been?
It was horrible.
A giant leech got me.
You're missing all the fun.
These people are great!
Some of them have
been partying all night long.
They sing songs till they get too cold, and
then they go sit by the fire and they get warm.
And then they come back
and they sing some more.
Yeah. They're hicks, Rita.
So, did you sleep okay
without me?
You tossed and turned,
didn't you?
You're incredible.
Who told you?
[CROWD CHEERING]
Okay. It's groundhog time.
Okay. On me in three,
two, one.
Once a year, the eyes of the nation turn to
this tiny hamlet in Western Pennsylvania
to watch a master at work.
The master?
Punxsutawney Phil,
the world's most famous
weatherman. The groundhog.
Who, as legend has it, can predict
the coming of an early spring.
So I guess the question we have
to ask ourselves today is,
"Does Phil feel lucky?"
It's the same old
shtick every year.
The guy comes out with a big
stick and raps on the door.
They pull the little rat out,
they talk to him.
The rat talks back. And then they
tell us what's gonna happen.
[BAND PLAYING
"FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW"]
RITA:
Aw, isn't he cute?
Hey, do you like the guys
with the prominent upper teeth?
No.
[GIBBERING]
[GROUNDHOG CHITTERING]
This February 2nd,
at 7:20 and 30 seconds,
Punxsutawney Phil,
the seer of seers,
prognosticator
of prognosticators,
emerged reluctantly but alertly
in Punxsutawney, PA,
and stated in groundhog-ese,
"I definitely see a shadow."
[CROWD GROANING]
Sorry, folks.
Six more weeks of winter.
[CROWD SHOUTING AND BOOING]
On me in three, two, one.
This is one time where
television really fails
to capture the true excitement of a
large squirrel predicting the weather.
I, for one, am very grateful
to have been here.
From Punxsutawney,
this is Phil Connors. So long.
Okay, want to try it again
without the sarcasm?
We got it. I'm out of here.
Prima Donnas.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, boy.
Take a look at this.
What is going on?
I don't know, Phil. Perhaps it's that
giant blizzard we're not supposed to get.
This is impossible.
Hey, hey, hey.
No, no, no.
Nobody honks this horn
but me, okay, pal?
No, no!
[HORN HONKS]
You gotta take this thing
out of here.
Hey, commander, what's going on?
There's nothing going on.
We're closing the road.
Big blizzard moving in.
What blizzard? It's a couple of flakes.
Don't you listen to the weather?
We got a major storm here.
I make the weather.
All of this moisture coming up out of the Gulf
is gonna push off to the east and hit Altoona.
Pal, you got that moisture
on your head.
Now, you can go back
to Punxsutawney,
or you can go ahead and freeze to death.
It's your choice.
So, what's it gonna be?
[HORNS HONKING
AND SIRENS WAILING]
I'm thinking.
Come on, all the long-distance
lines are down?
What about the satellite?
Is it snowing in space?
Don't you have some kind of a line that you
keep open for emergencies or for celebrities?
I'm both.
I'm a celebrity in an emergency.
Can you patch me through
on that line, please?
Could I have one more of these
with some booze in it, please?
Ooh, I like it here.
Phil.
Going to the groundhog dinner?
No, I had groundhog for lunch.
Wasn't bad.
Tastes like chicken.
You two run along.
Wow, Larry.
Looking foxy tonight, man.
Hey, uh, is your troop gonna be
selling cookies again this year?
Oh, ha-ha-ha.
That's so funny, Phil.
So, what are you gonna do?
Uh, I think I'm gonna
go back to my room
and take a hot shower and maybe
read a little Hustler or something.
Suit yourself.
[PHIL GASPING]
[SCREAMING]
Yo, mom.
Isn't there any hot water?
Oh, no, there wouldn't be today.
Of course not. Silly me.
Sweet dreams.
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
DJ 1:
Okay, campers, rise and shine!
And don't forget your booties,
because it's cold out there!
DJ 2: It's cold out there every day!
What is this, Miami Beach?
DJ 1: Not hardly!
Nice going, boys.
You're playing yesterday's tape.
DJ 1:
You know, that blizzard thing.
DJ 2: Oh, that blizzard thing.
That blizzard thing.
Oh, well, here's the report.
The National Weather Service
is calling for a big blizzard thing.
DJ 1: Yes, they are.
But you know, there's another reason
why today is especially exciting...
DJ 2: Especially cold.
DJ 1: Especially cold, okay.
But the big question
on everybody's lips...
DJ 2: Their chapped lips.
Chapped lips.
DJ 1:
Their chapped lips, right.
Do you think Phil's gonna
come out and see his shadow?
DJ 2:
Punxsutawney Phil!
DJ 1:
That's right, woodchuck chuckers!
BOTH:
It's Groundhog Day!
DJ 1: Get up and check
that hog out there! Hyah!
DJ 2:
Sooey! Sooey! Come here, girl!
[BOTH OINKING]
What the hell?
[♪♪♪]
Morning! Off to see
the groundhog?
Yeah.
Think it'll be an early spring?
Didn't we do this yesterday?
I don't know what you mean.
Ah!
Don't mess with me, Pork Chop!
What day is this?
It's February 2nd.
Groundhog Day.
Yeah.
I'm sorry. You know,
I thought it was yesterday.
[LAUGHING]
[CHUCKLING]
[♪♪♪]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
Did I sleep well?
Would you like some coffee?
Yes, please.
I think I'll have a double.
I hope you enjoy
the festivities.
There's talk of a blizzard.
Do you ever have déjà vu,
Mrs. Lancaster?
I don't think so, but I could
check with the kitchen.
No, that's okay. Thank you.
Will you be checking out
today, Mr. Connors?
I'd say the chance
of departure is 80 percent.
Seventy-five, 80.
[♪♪♪]
PHIL:
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
Where's everybody going?
To Gobbler's Knob.
It's Groundhog Day.
It's still just once a year, isn't it?
Hey! Phil?
Phil? Hey!
Phil Connors!
I thought that was you!
My, oh, my, Phil Connors!
Now, don't you say you don't remember me,
because I sure as heckfire remember you.
Well?
Ned Ryerson?
Bing! Oh, first shot
right out of the box!
So how's it going, old buddy?
Well, to tell you the truth, Neddie, I'm not
feeling real well. Would you excuse me?
You know, it's funny you
should mention your health.
Because you will never
guess what I do now.
Do you sell insurance?
Ho-ho, Bing again!
You are sharp as a tack today!
Do you have
life insurance, Phil?
Because if you do, you could
always use a little more.
Right! I mean,
who couldn't?
But you wanna know something?
I gots a feeling...
[WHISTLES]
...you ain't got any.
Am I right or am I right
or am I right? Am I right?
I gotta go.
Phil...
Whoa-ho-ho-ho!
Watch out for that
first step. It's a doozy!
[LAUGHING]
["PENNSYLVANIA POLKA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
RITA:
Phil! Phil, over here!
Where have you been?
Rita. Do me a favor.
I need someone to give me a
good, hard slap in the face.
How's that?
Good.
If you need any help with the other
cheek, let me know, I'm right here.
Something's going on.
I don't know what to do.
Are you drunk or something?
Drunk's more fun.
Can I be serious with you
for a minute?
I don't know, can you?
Yes, I'm being serious!
I'm having a problem.
I may be having a problem.
Rita, Rita.
It's groundhog time.
See? I knew you
were gonna say that.
I really feel weird.
Let's just do this, Phil.
Then we'll talk.
All right, on me in three,
two, one.
Well, it's Groundhog Day, again,
and that must mean that we're
up here at Gobbler's Knob
waiting for the forecast from the world's
most famous groundhog weatherman,
Punxsutawney Phil,
who's just about to tell us how
much more winter we can expect.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Phil! Phil! Phil!
This is a riot!
[BAND PLAYING
"FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW"]
RITA:
Aw, isn't he cute?
[CROWD CHEERING]
BUSTER: This February 2nd,
at 7:20 and 30 seconds,
Punxsutawney Phil,
the seer of seers,
prognosticator
of prognosticators,
emerged reluctantly Phil!
But alertly in Punxsu...
PHIL:
Ha! Whoo! Oh, my gosh!
[PHIL GASPING]
Yeah, Sport,
I know there's a blizzard.
When are the long-distance
lines gonna be repaired?
Well, what if there is no tomorrow?
There wasn't one today.
Hello?
[DIAL TONE]
[♪♪♪]
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
[♪♪♪]
Morning!
Off to see the groundhog?
Oh, did you sleep well, Mr...?
Ah!
Hey! Phil?
Phil Connors! I thought...
Whoa! Hey, Phil!
Don't say you don't remember me, because
I sure as heckfire remember you!
It's me, Ned! Ryerson!
Needlenose Ned! Ned the Head!
Come on, buddy, Case Western...
Hey, look... Hey!
["PENNSYLVANIA POLKA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
RITA:
Phil! Phil, over here!
Where have you been?
Can I talk to you
about a matter that is
not work-related?
You never talk about work.
We really have to talk. Come on.
LARRY: Hey!
It's a creative meeting. Forget it.
Wait a second,
we've got work to do.
No, I don't.
I've already done it twice.
Now, when you get finished,
come and meet me in the diner.
Phil!
What's that all about?
I don't know.
Prima Donnas.
More coffee, hon?
No, thanks. Just the check, please.
These sticky buns are just heaven.
Aren't they?
[DISHES CLATTERING]
GUS: Oh, jeez, just put
that anywhere, pal! Yeah!
RALPH:
Good save!
[BOTH APPLAUDING
AND LAUGHING]
Okay, now tell me why you're too
sick to work, and it better be good.
Rita, I'm reliving
the same day over and over.
Groundhog Day. Today.
Okay. I'm waiting
for the punch line.
No. Really.
This is the third time.
It's like yesterday
never happened.
I am racking my brain, but I can't even begin to
imagine why you'd make up something like this.
I'm not making it up.
I am asking you for help!
Okay, what do you want me to do?
I don't know! You're a producer.
Come up with something.
You want my advice? I think you
should get your head examined
if you expect me to believe
a stupid story like that, Phil!
Phil? Like the groundhog Phil?
Yeah. Like the groundhog Phil.
Ha-ha-ha! Look out
for your shadow there, pal!
Morons, your bus is leaving.
You guys ready? We'd better get going if
we're gonna stay ahead of the weather.
Let's talk about it
back in Pittsburgh.
I'm not going
back to Pittsburgh.
RITA: Why not?
PHIL: Because of the blizzard!
I thought you said that
was gonna hit Altoona.
Yeah, I know that's what I said.
Phil, I think you need help.
That's what I've been
saying, Rita. I need help.
Well, no spots.
No clots, no tumors.
No lesions.
No aneurysms.
At least none that
I can see, Mr. Connors.
Of course, if you want
a CAT scan or an MRI,
you're gonna have to
go into Pittsburgh.
I can't go into Pittsburgh.
Why can't you go into Pittsburgh?
I told you, there's a blizzard.
Oh, right. The blizzard.
You know what you
may need, Mr. Connors?
A biopsy.
A psychiatrist.
That's an unusual problem,
Mr. Connors.
Most of my work is with couples,
families. I have an alcoholic now.
Well, you went to college, right?
I mean, it wasn't veterinary
psychology, was it?
Didn't you take some kind of course
that covered this stuff?
Yeah. Sort of, I guess.
Abnormal psychology.
So...
what do I do?
I think we should meet again.
How's tomorrow for you?
Is that not good?
[SUSIE STEVENS' "TAKE ME ROUND
AGAIN" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
I was in the Virgin Islands once.
I met a girl.
We ate lobster.
Drank piña coladas.
At sunset, we made love
like sea otters.
That was a pretty good day.
Why couldn't I get that day
over and over and over?
You know, some guys would look at
this glass and they would say,
"That glass is half empty."
Other guys would say,
"That glass is half full."
I peg you as a "glass is half empty"
kind of guy. Am I right?
What would you do if you were
stuck in one place,
and every day was exactly the same,
and nothing that you did mattered?
That about sums it up for me.
Good luck.
I'll drop you off.
This thing sticks a little bit.
You gotta jiggle it...
Come on up here, pal.
Come on, give me your keys, pal.
Give me the keys.
Friends don't let friends drive, right?
Come on, stand up here.
Take a deep breath.
You feel okay? Really?
Okay, you're all right.
Uh-oh. Whoa.
You wanna throw up here
or you wanna throw up in the car?
I think, both.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
Come on.
[TYRES SCREECHING]
I really don't think
I should be driving.
No, no. I don't either.
Watch your head.
Watch your knees.
Don't break anything.
All right. Hey, let's
not forget seat belts.
Hey, who else could go for
some flapjacks right now?
[♪♪♪]
Let me ask you guys a question.
GUS:
Shoot.
What if there were no tomorrow?
No tomorrow?
That would mean there would be no
consequences, there would be no hangovers.
We could do whatever we wanted!
That's true.
We could do whatever we want.
[BOTH SCREAMING]
Hey, Phil, if we wanted to hit
mailboxes, we can let Ralph drive!
Ha, yeah.
[SIREN WAILING]
Oh, hey. Hey, Phil.
I think they want you to stop.
Hang on!
[TYRES SCREECHING]
PHIL: It's the same
thing your whole life.
"Clean up your room! Stand up
straight! Pick up your feet!
Take it like a man!
Be nice to your sister!
Don't mix beer and wine, ever!
Oh, yeah.
Don't drive on
the railroad tracks!"
Well, Phil, that's one
I happen to agree with.
I don't know, Gus.
Sometimes I think
you just have to
take the big chances.
COP [OVER SPEAKER]: This is the police!
Pull over immediately!
Hey! We're talking in here!
[TRAIN HORN BLARING]
Uh, Phil.
Yeah, yeah. yeah.
I'm betting he's
gonna swerve first.
Phil.
Phil!
Aah!
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
I'm not gonna live by
their rules anymore!
I noticed that.
You make choices
and you live with them.
[SIRENS WAILING]
Ho-ho!
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Ow, my knee!
Let me handle this.
Yeah, three cheeseburgers,
two large fries,
two chocolate shakes
and one large Coke.
And some flapjacks!
Too early for flapjacks?
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Yes!
Oh! Rise and shine, campers!
Don't forget your booties,
because it's cold out there today!
It's cold out there every day.
What is this, Miami Beach?
Not hardly!
[CLASSICAL MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Slept like a baby, thank you.
Oh...
Would you...?
I'd love some of your coffee, please.
I hope...
Flurries moving in a little bit later,
but the blizzard's gonna hit
outside of town.
Uh, Mrs. Lancaster?
Was anybody looking for me
here this morning?
Perhaps a state official?
Maybe a blue hat, gun, nightstick?
Oh, no, no one like that!
Will there be?
Apparently not.
Will you hold my room for me, please?
I'm gonna stay an extra day.
Catch you tomorrow, pops.
Hey! Phil? Phil?
Hey! Phil Connors!
Ned?
I like to see a man of advancing
years throwing caution to the wind.
It's inspiring, in a way.
My years are not advancing
as fast as you might think.
More coffee, hon?
Yeah, just keep it coming, please.
Sure thing.
[DISHES CLATTERING]
GUS: Oh, jeez, real nice!
Just put that anywhere, pal!
RALPH:
Good save!
[BOTH APPLAUDING
AND LAUGHING]
Don't you worry about cholesterol,
lung cancer, love handles?
I don't worry about
anything anymore.
What makes you so special?
Everybody worries about something.
That's exactly what
makes me so special.
I don't even have to floss.
Ugh.
What?
The wretch, concentered all in self
Living, shall forfeit fair renown
And doubly dying, shall go down
To the vile dust
From whence he sprung
Unwept, unhonored and unsung
Sir Walter Scott.
[LAUGHING]
What, you don't like poetry?
I love poetry!
I just thought that was
Willard Scott. I was confused.
You think I'm acting like this
because I'm egocentric?
I know you're egocentric.
It's your defining characteristic.
Uh, are you guys ready?
We'd better get going if we're
gonna stay ahead of the weather.
Thanks, Larry.
Well, would you like
a doggy bag?
I'm gonna stay here and finish.
I thought you hated this town.
It's beginning to grow on me.
Larry, quit staring.
These are excellent.
Bon appétit.
Hey, did you see the
groundhog this morning?
Uh-huh. I never miss it.
What's your name?
Nancy Taylor. And you are?
What high school did you go to?
What?
High school.
Lincoln, in Pittsburgh.
Who are you?
Who was your
12th-grade English teacher?
Are you kidding?
No, no, no, in 12th grade,
your English teacher was...
Mrs. Walsh.
Mrs. Walsh, yeah.
Nancy. Lincoln. Walsh.
Okay. Thanks very much.
Hey. Hey.
["PENNSYLVANIA POLKA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Nancy?
Nancy Taylor!
Lincoln High School!
I sat next to you in
Mrs. Walsh's English class!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Phil Connors!
Wow! That's amazing!
You don't remember me, do you?
Um...
I even asked you to the prom.
Phil Connors?
I was short and I've sprouted.
Yeah.
Gosh! How are you?
Great.
You look terrific!
You look very, very terrific!
[LAUGHING]
Listen, I gotta go
do this report.
Are you a reporter?
I'm a weatherman with
Channel 9, Pittsburgh.
Wow. Gosh, I should
have known! That's great!
But maybe later we could...
Yeah, whatever!
Stay right here.
Promise me?
Yes.
Okay, I'll be right back.
Okay.
Wish me luck!
Good luck!
[♪♪♪]
[NANCY GIGGLING]
Oh, Phil.
Oh, Rita.
Who's Rita?
How should I know?
What is this, some kind
of one-night stand?
On the contrary, Nancy,
I love you.
I've always loved you.
This is gonna seem sudden but...
Nancy, will you be my wife?
Oh, Phil...
Rita.
Nancy.
Whatever.
A gust of wind.
[WIND WHOOSHES]
A dog barks.
[DOG BARKS]
Cue the truck.
[♪♪♪]
Exit Herman.
Walk on to the bank.
Exit Felix, and stand there with
a not-so-bright look on your face.
All right, Doris. Come on.
Hey, fix your bra, honey.
That's better.
Felix!
How you doing, Doris?
Can I have a roll of quarters?
Ten, nine, eight,
car, six, five,
quarters,
three,
two...
Felix?
Did I bring out two bags or one?
I don't know.
[♪♪♪]
I thought we were going
to a costume party.
[IMITATING CLINT EASTWOOD]
It's like I said, I love this film.
I've seen it over 100 times.
Phil!
Told you, call me "Bronco."
Sorry, Bronco.
Hi, Nancy.
My own fiancée
doesn't remember me.
Hi.
That'll be one adult and, uh...
Two adults.
Two adults, I guess.
...groundhog who, as legend has it, can
predict the coming of an early spring.
So I guess the question we have
to ask ourselves today is,
"Does Phil feel lucky?"
Rita, if you only
had one day to live,
what would you do with it?
I don't know, Phil.
What are you dying of?
No, I mean, the whole world
is about to explode.
What do you do?
I just want to know
where to put the camera.
What are you looking for, Phil?
A date for the weekend?
No, I'm just interested in you.
You know, what do you want?
What do you like?
What do you think about?
What kind of men
are you interested in?
What do you do for fun?
Is this for real, Phil, or are you just
trying to make me look like a fool?
I'm just trying to talk like normal
people talk. Isn't this how they talk?
Close.
Okay, so talk to me.
Let me buy you a cup of coffee.
And a doughnut.
All right.
PHIL: So, what do you
want out of life, anyway?
[CHUCKLES]
I guess I want what
everybody wants.
You know, career,
love, marriage, children.
Are you seeing anyone?
I think this is
getting too personal.
I don't think I'm ready
to share this with you.
How about you?
What do you want?
What I really want
is someone like you.
Oh, please.
Well, why not?
What are you looking for?
Who's your perfect guy?
Well, first of all, he's too
humble to know he's perfect.
That's me.
He's intelligent,
supportive, funny...
Intelligent, supportive, funny.
Me, me, me.
He's romantic and courageous.
Me also.
He's got a good body but he doesn't have
to look in the mirror every two minutes.
I have a great body, and sometimes
I go months without looking.
He's kind, sensitive and gentle.
He's not afraid to cry
in front of me.
This is a man we're
talking about, right?
He likes animals, children,
and he'll change poopy diapers.
Does he have to use
the word "poopy"?
Oh, and he plays an instrument,
and he loves his mother.
I am really close on this one.
Really, really close.
It's Phil Connors!
Hello.
Thanks for watching.
So, what are the chances
of getting out today?
Van still won't start.
Larry's working on it.
Wouldn't you know it?
Can I buy you a drink?
Okay.
Jim Beam, ice, water.
For you, miss?
Sweet vermouth on the rocks
with a twist, please.
What are the chances
of getting out of town today?
Van still won't start.
Larry's working on it.
Wouldn't you know it?
Can I buy you a drink?
Okay.
Sweet vermouth, rocks,
with a twist, please.
For you, miss?
The same.
That's my favorite drink.
Mine too.
It always makes me
think of Rome.
The way the sun hits
the buildings in the afternoon.
Ah.
Well, what should we drink to?
To the groundhog!
I always drink to world peace.
Can I buy you a drink?
Okay.
Sweet vermouth, rocks,
with a twist, please.
BARTENDER:
For you, miss?
The same.
That's my favorite drink.
Mine too.
It always makes me
think of Rome.
The way the sun hits
the buildings in the afternoon.
Well, what should we drink to?
I like to say a prayer
and drink to world peace.
To world peace.
World peace.
Amen.
Mmm, this is wonderful.
See? Didn't I tell you?
How do you know so much
about Punxsutawney?
I spend a lot of time here.
Small-town people are more real,
more down-to-earth.
That's how I feel.
Really?
Would you like to try
some white chocolate?
Yuck, don't make me sick.
No white chocolate.
There is something
so familiar about this.
Hm?
Do you ever have déjà vu?
Didn't you just ask me that?
[LAUGHING]
I think people place too much
emphasis on their careers.
I wish we could all live
in the mountains at high altitude.
That's where I see myself
in five years. How about you?
Oh, I agree. I just like
to go with the flow.
See where it leads me.
Well, it's led you here.
Mm-hm.
Of course, it's about a million miles
from where I started out in college.
You weren't in broadcasting
or journalism?
Mm-hm.
Believe it or not, I studied
19th-century French poetry.
[LAUGHS]
What a waste of time!
I mean, for someone else that would
be an incredible waste of time.
So bold of you to choose that.
It's incredible. You must be
a very, very strong person.
PHIL: I think people place too
much emphasis on their careers.
Gosh, I wish we could all live in
the mountains. At high altitudes.
That's where I see myself
in five years. How about you?
Oh, I agree. I just like
to go with the flow,
Yeah?
See what happens.
Well, it's gotten you here.
Uh-huh.
Of course, it's a million miles
from where I started out in college.
Oh, yeah, you weren't in broadcasting
or journalism or anything like that?
Uh-uh.
Hm.
Believe it or not, I studied
19th-century French poetry.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
You speak French.
Oui.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
I haven't done this
since I was a kid.
Me neither. It's fun!
It's good, clean fun.
I hope that one day I can do
this with my own children.
Where'd you get that?
Well, I went over
to the snowman shop.
Hey, an assassin!
I'll protect you, Your Majesty!
I shall die for you.
You shall not take her!
Find cover, my lady!
[LAUGHING]
I'm getting some good ones.
Ooh, hey, there's a boy.
That's a boy! Good try.
RITA:
Help me!
[LAUGHING]
[RAY CHARLES'
"YOU DON'T KNOW ME" PLAYING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOG]
[RITA LAUGHING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Ah.
What?
I'm just amazed,
and I'm not easily amazed.
About what?
How you can start a day
with one kind of expectation
and end up
so completely different.
Well, do you like the way
this day is turning out?
I like it very much.
It's a perfect day. You couldn't
have planned a day like this.
Well, you can.
It just takes
an awful lot of work.
Come on in. I want to
show you something.
I don't think I should, Phil.
I don't think you should either.
That's why I'm just gonna show you this
one thing, and kick you right out.
It'll just be one minute.
[♪♪♪]
It's just lovely.
Would you like to sit
and stare at the fake fire?
Okay.
It's a really wonderful room.
It is now.
I don't know, Phil.
I don't think we should do this.
I don't either.
You know what, on second
thought, I think we should.
It's the perfect end
to a perfect day.
Well, it's a little fast for me.
Me too.
Maybe I should go.
Where would you go?
Why?
We've got a perfect fire.
I've got some French
poetry here. Baudelaire...
Mmm.
C'est fantastique.
I will read to you.
I've got some ice cream over on
the windowsill. Hold on a minute.
Rocky road?
I love rocky road.
Yeah, I thought so.
You have to stay.
Oh, no, really, Phil, I'm tired.
We can see each other tomorrow.
No, tonight.
It's gotta be tonight.
No, Phil, really.
Come on, just stay for a while and if
you like it, stay for a while longer.
And if you like that,
stay for a while longer.
Let's not spoil it, okay?
We're not spoiling it.
I don't want to spoil it either.
You know I can't stay with you.
Why not? I love you.
You love me?
I love you.
You don't even know me.
Oh, I know you. I know you.
Oh, no. I can't believe
I fell for this!
This whole day has
just been one long setup.
No, it hasn't.
And I ate fudge. Yuck!
No white chocolate, no fudge.
What are you doing? Are you making
some kind of list or something?
No.
Did you call up my friends
and ask them what I like
and what I don't like?
No.
Is this what love is for you?
No, this is real.
This is love.
Stop saying that!
You must be crazy.
I could never love
someone like you, Phil,
because you'll never love
anyone but yourself.
That's not true. I don't even like myself.
Give me another chance.
That's for making me
care about you.
PHIL: I haven't done
this since I was a kid.
RITA:
Me neither. It's fun.
And good, clean fun too.
I think that's what's missing
in the world today, don't you?
Gosh, I can't wait to do this
with my own children.
Golly, I want kids,
lots of kids!
I want to adopt, I want to have my own
kids, I want to have foster kids.
I got this over at Snowman City.
Hey! Some kid just
threw a snowball at us.
Come here! Let's have some fun!
Come on, eh?
[LAUGHING]
Hey, kids, come on! I wish these were
my own kids hitting me like this.
Hey!
Hey! Ow, ow! Are any
of you up for adoption?
Hey, here's a humdinger
over here!
Wasn't that great?
[♪♪♪]
Stop it!
["PENNSYLVANIA POLKA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
RITA:
Phil! Over here!
Where have you been?
You're missing all the fun.
Phil, you look terrible.
What happened?
Rough night?
Yeah.
Okay, campers.
Rise and shine.
And don't forget your booties,
because it's cold out there today.
It's cold out there every day.
ALEX TREBEK [ON TV]: This
country's largest lake, Chapala,
is located near
the city of Guadalajara.
What is Mexico?
TREBEK: Leslie.
TREBEK: Correct.
Lakes and Rivers, 400.
TREBEK: Seneca is the largest of these
lakes in west-central New York.
What are the Finger Lakes?
TREBEK: Jim.
JIM: What are the Finger Lakes?
TREBEK: Correct.
Amazing.
TREBEK: This South American lake...
What is Titicaca?
TREBEK: Jim.
JIM: What is Titicaca?
TREBEK: Correct.
Lakes and Rivers for 1000.
TREBEK: Milky-colored...
What is the Rhone?
...when entering Lake Geneva,
this river is
clear blue upon exiting.
Jim?
What is the Rhone?
TREBEK:
The Rhone. Good for $1000.
You're $500 off the lead right now.
Very good. Very good.
This is pitiful.
A thousand people
freezing their butts off,
waiting to worship a rat.
What a hype. Groundhog Day used
to mean something in this town.
They used to pull the hog out,
and they used to eat it.
You're hypocrites! All of you!
You got a problem with
what I'm saying, Larry?
Untie your tongue and you
come out here and talk, huh?
Am I upsetting you, princess?
You know, you want
a prediction about the weather?
You're asking the wrong Phil.
I'll give you a winter prediction.
It's gonna be cold.
It's gonna be gray.
And it's gonna last you
for the rest of your life.
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Once again the eyes of
the nation have turned here
to this tiny village in Western
Pennsylvania. Blah-blah-blah-blah.
There is no way that this winter
is ever going to end
as long as this groundhog
keeps seeing his shadow.
I don't see any other way out.
He's gotta be stopped.
And I have to stop him.
Real good, Phil. Real good.
He's out of his gourd.
I'm worried. I think there's
something really wrong with Phil.
Yeah, there's a lot of things
really wrong with Phil.
Oh, hi, Phil.
I've come to the end of me, Rita.
There's no way out now.
I just want you to remember we had
a beautiful day together once.
All right, little fella.
Good job. He just smiled at me!
Did you see that?
I believe he did.
Okay, little fella.
There you go.
Hi, there, mister.
Something I can do you for?
Hey! What are you doing?
[♪♪♪]
Get the word out.
Somebody kidnapped Phil!
We're going after him!
[TYRES SCREECHING]
Why would anybody
steal a groundhog?
I could probably think of a
couple of reasons. Pervert.
[TYRES SCREECHING]
He must have just snapped!
This ought to be good.
[HORNS HONKING]
RITA:
What is he doing?
What can he be thinking?
That's not bad for a quadruped.
You gotta check your mirrors. Just the
side of your eye. Side of your eye.
[SIREN WAILING]
That's it. That's it.
Hey, they're chasing us!
Come on, make it fun.
Don't drive angry.
Hot dog! There's no way out
except the way we came in!
We got him now!
[ENGINE REVVING]
[♪♪♪]
What the hell is he doing?
I don't know.
If you gotta shoot, aim high.
I don't wanna hit the groundhog.
Well, we mustn't keep
our public waiting, huh?
[CHITTERING]
It's showtime, Phil.
All right, on me, Larry,
in three...
two...
one.
Phil!
He might be okay.
Well, no. Probably not now.
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Aw, nuts.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Did you sleep well,
Mr. Connors?
Would you like some, uh, toast?
[♪♪♪]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Oh, my God.
[HORN HONKING
AND TYRES SCREECHING]
That's him.
He was a really, really great guy.
I really, really liked him a lot.
I'm sorry?
What was that again?
I'm a god.
You're God?
I'm a god. I'm not the God,
I don't think.
Because you survived a car wreck?
You folks ready to order?
I didn't just survive a wreck.
I wasn't just blown up yesterday.
I have been stabbed,
shot, poisoned,
frozen, hung, electrocuted
and burned.
Oh, really?
Every morning I wake up without a scratch
on me, not a dent in the fender.
I am an immortal.
Special today is blueberry waffles.
Why are you telling me this?
Because I want you
to believe in me.
You're not a god.
You can take my word for it. This is
12 years of Catholic school talking.
I can come back
if you're not ready.
How do you know I'm not a god?
Ha! Oh, please.
How do you know?
Because it's not possible.
I'll come back.
Doris.
This is Doris. Her brother-in-law
Carl owns this diner.
She's worked here since she was 17.
More than anything else in her life,
she wants to see Paris
before she dies.
Oh, boy, would I!
What are you doing?
This is Debbie Kleiser
and her fiancé, Fred.
Do I know you?
They're supposed to be getting married this
afternoon, but Debbie is having second thoughts.
What?
Lovely ring.
This is Bill. He's been a
waiter for three years,
since he left Penn State
and had to get work.
He likes the town, he paints
toy soldiers and he's gay.
I am.
This is Gus. He hates his life here,
he wishes he'd stayed in the Navy.
Well, I could've retired
on half pay after 20 years.
Excuse me.
Is this some kind of trick?
Well, maybe the real God
uses tricks.
You know, maybe he's not omnipotent, he's
just been around so long he knows everything.
Oh, okay. Well, who's that?
This is Tom. He worked in the coal
mine till they closed it down.
And her?
That's Alice.
Came from Ireland when she was a baby.
She lived in Erie most of her life.
He's right.
And her?
Nancy.
She works in the dress shop, and makes noises
like a chipmunk when she gets real excited.
Hey!
It's true.
How do you know these people?
I told you, I know everything.
In about five seconds, a waiter's
gonna drop a tray of dishes.
Five, four, three, two, one.
This is nuts.
Okay?
Okay, that's enough.
What about me, Phil?
Do you know me too?
I know all about you.
You like producing, but you hope for
more than Channel 9 Pittsburgh.
Well, everyone knows that.
You like boats but not the ocean.
[♪♪♪]
You go to a lake in the summer
with your family up in the mountains.
There's a long wooden dock and a boathouse
with boards missing from the roof,
and a place you used to
crawl underneath to be alone.
You're a sucker for
French poetry and rhinestones.
You're very generous.
You're kind to strangers
and children.
And when you stand in the snow
you look like an angel.
How are you doing this?
I told you, I wake up
every day right here.
Right in Punxsutawney.
And it's always February 2nd.
And there's nothing
I can do about it.
If you still can't
believe me, listen:
In 10 seconds,
Larry is gonna come through that
door and take you away from me.
But you can't let him.
Larry?
Please believe me.
You've got to believe me.
You guys ready? We'd better get going if
we're gonna stay ahead of the weather.
What's that?
"... To stay ahead of the weather."
RITA:
Maybe it really is happening.
I mean, how else
could you know so much?
PHIL: Well, there is no way.
I'm not that smart.
Maybe I should spend
the rest of day with you
as an objective witness,
just to see what happens.
Gee, this sounds like
a science project.
PHIL:
Concentrate.
You gotta want it.
You've gotta want it, Rita.
Oh, come on. It's more in the wrist than
the fingers. You just gotta "pfft, pfft."
Pfft, pfft.
Be the hat. Come on, go.
Be the hat.
It would take me a year
to get good at this.
No, six months. Four to five hours
a day, and you'd be an expert.
Is this what you do with eternity?
Now you know.
That's not the worst part.
What's the worst part?
The worst part is that tomorrow you
will have forgotten all about this
and you'll treat me
like a jerk again.
No.
It's all right, I am a jerk.
No, you're not.
It doesn't make any difference.
I've killed myself so many times,
I don't even exist anymore.
Well, sometimes I wish I had
a thousand lifetimes.
I don't know, Phil.
Maybe it's not a curse.
It just depends
on how you look at it.
Gosh, you're an upbeat lady!
I want you to know it's been
a really nice day for me.
Me too.
And maybe, if it's not too boring,
we could do it again sometime.
I hope so.
You're still here.
Oh, I thought you were supposed
to disappear. Or I was or something.
Not until 6.
Oh! You rat!
I never said midnight.
You knew I was
waiting for midnight.
Does this mean
you're gonna leave?
No.
Good.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
RITA:
I'm sorry.
PHIL:
It's all right. You can fall asleep.
I promise I won't touch you.
Much.
It's all right. I'm not tired.
What were you saying?
I think the last thing
that you heard was,
"Only God could make a tree."
Really?
What I wanted to say was...
I think you're the kindest,
sweetest, prettiest person
I've ever met in my life.
I've never seen anyone
that's nicer to people
than you are.
Hm?
And the first time I saw you
something happened to me.
I never told you...
but I knew that
I wanted to hold you
as hard as I could.
[MOANS]
I don't deserve
someone like you.
But if I ever could...
I swear I would love you
for the rest of my life.
Did you say something?
Good night, Rita.
Good night, Phil.
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
DJ 1:
Okay, campers, rise and shine!
And don't forget your booties,
because it's cold out there!
DJ 2: It's cold out there every day.
What is this, Miami Beach?
DJ 1:
Not hardly!
["PENNSYLVANIA POLKA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Who wants coffee?
Get it while it's hot.
Oh. Thanks, Phil.
Larry?
Skim milk, two sugar.
Yeah. Thanks, Phil.
Pastry?
No. We're just setting up.
Pastry, Larry?
Take your pick.
Thanks, Phil. Raspberry. Great.
See, I was just talking with Buster
Green, he's the head groundhog honcho.
And he said if we set up over here
we might get a better shot.
What do you think?
Sounds good.
Larry, what do you think?
Yeah. Let's go for it.
Good work, Phil.
Maybe we'll get lucky. Let me give
you a hand with the heavy stuff.
No, no. You got your coffee.
I'll get it.
We never talk, Larry.
Do you have kids?
[MOZART'S "PIANO SONATA
NO. 16 IN C MAJOR" PLAYING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Yes?
Yes, I'd like a piano lesson, please.
Oh, okay. I'm with
a student now.
But if you want to come back
tomorrow, I could probably...
Well, I kind of want to get started.
I could give you $1000.
Come on in.
[SCALES PLAYING ON PIANO]
Morning!
Off to see the groundhog?
Buon giorno, signore!
Think it's gonna be
an early spring?
Winter, slumbering in the open air
Wears on his smiling face
A dream of spring
Ciao!
[PIANO PLAYING OFF-KEY]
Phil!
Rita, hi.
Hey, Lar, hi.
How does she look?
Great.
Thank you.
Did you know he could ice sculpt?
No.
[PLAYING RACHMANINOFF'S "18TH VARIATION
FROM RAPSODIE ON A THEME OF PAGANINI"]
Not bad, Mr. Connors.
You say this is your first lesson?
Yes, but my father
was a piano mover, so...
Phil? Phil Connors,
I thought it was you.
Ned Ryerson.
Yes.
I have missed you so much.
I don't know where you're headed,
but can you call in sick?
Uh...
[CHUCKLES]
I gotta get going.
It's good to see you, Phil.
[♪♪♪]
Hello, father.
Let's get you someplace warm.
Yeah. Yeah.
Remember me?
Sir? Are you the one who
brought the old man in?
Mm-hm. How is he?
Well, he just passed away.
[♪♪♪]
What did he die of?
He was just old.
It was just his time.
I want to see his chart. Excuse me.
Um, sir!
Sir, you can't come in here.
Sir, this is a restricted area.
Where's the chart?
Sometimes people just die.
Not today.
Gets hard down there
at the bottom.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Come on, dad.
Come on, pop. Come on, pop.
Come on. Come on, breathe.
Breathe, pop! Breathe, pop!
PHIL:
When Chekhov saw the long winter,
he saw a winter bleak
and dark and bereft of hope.
Yet we know that winter is just
another step in the cycle of life.
But standing here among
the people of Punxsutawney
and basking in the warmth
of their hearths and hearts,
I couldn't imagine a better fate
than a long and lustrous winter.
From Punxsutawney,
it's Phil Connors.
So long.
Nice speech, Phil.
Very nice.
Thank you.
Thanks. How was that for you two?
My man, you touched me.
Thanks, Larry.
Thank you.
I gotta go.
Phil.
Hm?
That was surprising. I didn't
know you were so versatile.
I surprise myself sometimes.
Where are you going? Would you
like to get a cup of coffee?
I'd love to. Can I have a rain check? I've
got some errands I've gotta run. Okay?
Phil? Errands? What errands?
I thought we were going back.
[♪♪♪]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMS]
What do you say? What do you say?
What do you say?
You little brat.
You have never thanked me!
I'll see you tomorrow.
Maybe.
You totaled it.
It's only a flat tire.
What are we going to do?
[ALL GASPING]
It's an earthquake!
Oh, it's not an earthquake.
WOMAN:
What is it?
Oh! Thank you, young man.
It's nothing, ma'am.
I had the tire and the jack.
Just be comfortable, all right?
It'll be a minute.
Who is that?
He must be from the motor club.
WOMAN: Oh, my God, he is having
a heart attack! Do something!
Call 411, an ambulance, a lawyer,
doctor, anything, oh, my God!
[BUSTER GASPING]
I think that did it.
If you're gonna eat steak,
get sharper teeth.
Enjoy your meal.
Thank you.
Who was that?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
WOMAN: Are you sure?
BUSTER:
Eat, eat!
LARRY:
Well, people just don't understand
what is involved in this.
This is an art form.
You know, I think that
most people just think
that I hold a camera
and point it at stuff.
There is a heck of a lot
more to it than just that.
Hey, would you be at all interested
in seeing the inside of a van?
Oh, you know, I really
have to get back to the party.
Great idea.
I think I'll go with you.
Let me just drop a tip here.
Okay.
Rita, hi. How are you?
Hi.
Rita, this is Nancy.
BOTH: Hi.
Nancy, Rita.
We were just gonna go
to the party. You gonna go?
Yeah, sounds like fun.
Maybe we should call Phil.
Phil Connors?
I think he's already in there.
Great.
[BAND PLAYING
ROCK 'N' ROLL MUSIC]
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
[PLAYING RACHMANINOFF'S "18TH VARIATION
FROM RAPSODIE ON A THEME OF PAGANINI"]
[BAND PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Isn't he good?
He's great!
He's my student.
I'm so proud.
Thank you.
Hello, welcome to our party.
Phil, I didn't know
you could play like that.
Oh, I'm versatile.
[BAND PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC]
It's that nice young man
from the motor club.
Thank you again.
It's nothing, ladies.
He's the fastest jack
in Jefferson County.
What was that all about?
I really don't know. They've been
hitting on me all night.
There you are!
I never thanked you properly
for what you did for Buster.
Well, he would've
choked for sure.
Well, he may have. He was
trying to swallow a whole cow.
I owe you one, buddy.
Hang on to him, dear.
He's a real find.
What did you do today?
Oh, same old, same old.
FRED:
Excuse me, Mr. Connors.
Hey, Fred, how was the wedding?
Well, I just wanted to thank you for making
Debbie go through with it and everything.
All I did was fan the flame
of her passion for you, Fred.
You are the best.
No, you're the best.
Rita, this is Debbie
and Fred Kleiser.
Hi.
Here you go, kids.
Congratulations.
What is this? Oh, no way.
No way!
WrestleMania!
No way! No way! Ha-ha!
How did you know?
We'll be in Pittsburgh anyway!
Thank you, Mr. Connors.
You're a real pal.
Oh, this is the best.
I don't understand.
Uh, yeah, I guess not.
How does everyone know you? I mean,
you only come here once a year,
and you seem like the most
popular person in town.
Excuse me, Dr. Connors?
Yes. Yes.
I want to thank you
for fixing Felix's back.
He can even help
around the house again.
Well, I'm sorry
to hear that, Felix.
Dr. Connors?
It's kind of an honorary title.
What is going on?
I really don't know.
No, there is something
going on with you.
Would you like the long version
or the short one?
Let's start with the short
and go from there.
[SONG ENDS]
Okay, folks, attention.
Time for the big bachelor auction.
Now, you all know the rules.
All the eligible bachelors
come down in front.
And you ladies,
you bid on them!
And you get to do whatever
you want with them,
no questions asked!
I don't want to know about it,
as long as it's legal.
Okay, so get out your pocketbooks,
and remember it's all for charity.
Phil!
What are you doing down here?
Go on, get up there.
I got 10 bucks
that says you're mine.
Hey, Buster,
I got your first victim.
Phil Connors, come on up here!
[BAND PLAYS FANFARE]
All right! Now, what am I bid
for this fine specimen?
Five dollars!
The bidding has begun at $5.
Ten dollars!
Fifteen!
Twenty!
Twenty-five!
Thirty!
DORIS: Thirty-five!
NANCY: Forty!
DORIS:
Forty-five!
NANCY:
Fifty!
Fifty-five!
Sixty!
I'm bid $60.
Do I hear more?
$339.88.
[CROWD GASPING]
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
I don't think we're gonna
accept any more bids.
I think that's sold
to the little lady for $339.88!
Congratulations!
[BAND PLAYING JAZZ MUSIC]
BUSTER:
Okay, bachelors, who's next?
[DRUMS PLAYING]
BUSTER: All right! Now,
what am I bid for this guy?
Do I hear a buck and a half?
Anybody?
Seventy-five cents?
I bid two bits!
Sold to the lady for 25 cents.
I got him!
Phil? Phil? Phil Connors,
I thought that was you.
Rita, this is Ned Ryerson,
he's my new insurance agent.
I'll say.
I have not seen this guy
for 20 years.
He comes up to me and
then he buys whole life,
term, fire, theft,
auto, dental, health,
with the optional death and
dismemberment plan. Water damage.
Phil, this is the
best day of my life.
Mine too.
Where are we going?
Oh, let's not spoil it.
[LAUGHING]
Let's not... I got that. Reow!
Why can't I look?
Because you bother me a lot.
I'm getting cold.
How much longer
do I have to sit here?
I'm just trying to give you your money's
worth. You paid top dollar for me.
Well, I think you were a bargain.
Sweet of you to say.
You're probably right.
[LAUGHING]
Is it finished yet?
Almost. I still have to put some cherry
syrup on the top and then we can eat it.
Come on, Phil.
I'm freezing!
One second, one second.
Let me turn it in the light.
[♪♪♪]
RITA:
It's amazing.
It's beautiful.
How did you do that?
I know your face so well, I could
have done it with my eyes closed.
It's lovely.
I don't know what to say.
I do.
No matter what happens tomorrow,
or for the rest of my life,
I'm happy now...
because I love you.
I think I'm happy too.
["I GOT YOU BABE"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
DJ 1:
Aw, please. Not again.
DJ 2: That is a great song.
DJ 1: No, it's not.
DJ 2:
Don't listen to this man...
[TURNS RADIO OFF]
It's too early.
Ow.
Something is different.
Good or bad?
Anything different is good.
But this could be real good.
Why are you here?
I bought you.
I own you.
But why are you still here?
You said, "Stay," so I stayed.
I said, "Stay," so you stayed.
Mm-hm.
I can't even make a collie stay.
I gotta check something.
Stay.
[♪♪♪]
They're gone!
They're all gone.
Do you know what today is?
No, what?
Today is tomorrow.
It happened.
You're here.
I'm here.
Oh, Phil. Why weren't you like this
last night? You just fell asleep.
[LAUGHING]
It was the end
of a very long day.
Is there anything I can do
for you today?
I'm sure I can
think of something.
PHIL:
It's so beautiful!
Let's live here.
[NAT KING COLE'S "ALMOST LIKE
BEING IN LOVE" PLAYING]
We'll rent to start.
[RITA LAUGHING]
[DELBERT McCLINTON'S
"WEATHERMAN" PLAYING]