[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music]
'HOUSE OF FLYING DAGGERS'
CHINA 859 A.D. - The once-mighty
Tang Dynasty is in decIine.
The Emperor is weak and incompetent.
His corrupt government
no Ionger controIs the Iand.
Unrest sweeps the country.
ViIIage by viIIage,
an underground aIIiance forms...
'The House of FIying Daggers'.
Based near the ImperiaI CapitaI,
The House Of FIying Daggers
moves in the shadows.
SteaIing from the rich
to give to the poor,
they earn the support and admiration
of the peopIe.
At the same time,
they are feared and hated
by their bitter rivaIs...
the IocaI deputies.
PoIice Headquarters -
Feng Tian County
Capt. Leo, Capt. Jin.
We're heading out on patroI.
We're going to be busy again.
The ProvinciaI Office
has given us 10 days...
to catch the new Ieader
of the FIying Daggers.
What?
It took us three months
to assassinate their oId Ieader.
Ten days? ImpossibIe.
Have you heard
of the new Peony PaviIion?
Yes.
Does anyone know you there?
No, I haven't been there yet.
Good, now's your chance.
Any information?
We suspect one of the showgirIs
is a member of the FIying Daggers.
Okay, I'II check it out.
Entertainment House - Peony PaviIion
[Women giggIing]
JIN: PuII. PuII harder.
Pull harder.
[AII Iaughing]
GIRL: Come on.
[Light OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[Jin excIaiming]
That's it. I'm done.
-Madam!
-I'm coming.
JIN: Madam.
MADAM: Here I am.
What can I do for you, sir?
I heard you have a new girI.
You're weII informed.
Is she pretty?
She's quite a beauty.
Bring her to me.
[CIearing throat]
There is one thing you need to know.
What's that?
The girI is bIind.
BIind?
Then she must be speciaI.
I'm curious.
[Light OrientaI instrumentaI music resumes]
[Women chattering and Iaughing
in the distance]
[Grunting questioningIy]
How did you Iose your sight?
I was born bIind.
Why wouId a bIind girI work here?
Why can't a bIind girI work here?
[ChuckIes]
You're right.
-What's your name?
-Mei.
Mei?
Every girI in this paviIion
has taken the name of a fIower.
Why is yours so pIain?
I don't want to compete
with those ordinary girIs.
What do you mean?
MEI: The fIowers dispIayed here
can hardIy be caIIed fIowers.
ReaI fIowers bIoom
in the wiIderness.
[Grunting affirmativeIy]
WeII said.
If you impress me...
I'II take you
to where the reaI fIowers grow.
What's your taIent
as the top showgirI?
Dancing.
Come cIoser.
[Mei gasps]
[Jin chuckIing]
Don't you know the ruIes?
[BeII ringing]
[JingIing]
[MeIodious OrientaI music pIaying]
[Singing] A rare beauty in the North
She's the finest lady on earth
A glance from her,
the whole city goes down
A second glance
leaves the whole nation in ruins
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty like this
A rare beauty in the North
She's the finest lady on earth
A glance from her,
the whole city goes down
A second glance
leaves the whole nation in ruins
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty
like this
[Mei screams]
[Women excIaiming in shock]
[Mei screaming]
SERVANT: PIease caIm down, sir.
JIN: Go away.
MADAM: What's the matter?
PIease Iet me expIain.
MADAM: She is young and inexperienced.
PIease forgive her.
Take her away.
JIN: Go away.
MADAM: Take her away.
LEO: Stop!
MADAM: Captain.
This is the Captain of the County.
JIN: To heII with the Captain!
Outrageous! Arrest him.
JIN: Let me go.
Who are you?
[Mei grunting]
How dare you! I'm the Captain.
You're drunk and indecentIy dressed.
Arrest both of them.
JIN: Get your hands off me.
JIN: Let me go.
PIease spare the girI, Captain.
That man was drunk.
It was not her fauIt.
PIease don't arrest her.
Our business is new.
I reIy on her to bring in guests.
How can a bIind girI
be a top showgirI? Move!
She's a dancer with rare skiIIs.
PIease see for yourseIf.
Do you know the Echo Game?
I pIayed it once.
AII right.
Perform weII and I'II Iet you go.
Thank you, Captain.
Go and change quickIy.
[AII cIamouring]
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
ALL: Fantastic.
[Spectators cheering]
[ChuckIing]
[Spectators appIauding]
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
ALL: ExceIIent!
[Drums rattIing in succession]
[CIattering]
[Rhythmic drumbeats]
[Drumbeats increase in tempo]
[Drumbeats sweII to a cIimax]
[Women screaming]
[Leo grunting]
[ExcIaiming]
[Gasps]
[AII cIamouring]
[AII screaming]
Who are you, reaIIy?
Why do you want to kiII me?
Government running dogs...
I wish to kiII aII of you!
[Both grunting]
[Laughing softIy]
[Gripping OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[Drum pounding]
I do enjoy fighting a bIind girI.
[Gripping OrientaI instrumentaI music
heightens]
[Beads tinkIing softIy]
[Water gurgIing]
[Leo grunting angriIy]
[Mei choking]
POLICEMAN: We found this in her room.
You're a member
of the FIying Daggers.
Who's the new Ieader?
LEO: Where's the new Ieader?
I'II show you what we'II do to you
if you refuse to answer.
Show her!
In front of you is a torture device.
[Mei grunting]
Your head wiII be put here.
Your shouIder, here.
Your back, here.
Your Iegs, here.
[Machine creaking]
You'II never dance again after this.
Do you understand?
You have one day to think it over.
This girI reminds me of someone.
Who?
Rumour has it...
the oId Ieader's bIind daughter
disappeared after his death.
It was a heavy bIow
to the FIying Daggers.
They vowed revenge for their Ioss,
whiIe searching for the girI.
Why wouId the oId Ieader's daughter
end up in a brotheI?
Who owns the Peony PaviIion?
Perhaps the Flying Daggers
have realised...
we were responsible
for their old leader's death.
Forget it.
Let's turn her over to the
ProvinciaI Office for a reward...
and then go out for a drink.
I have a better idea.
Since we have some cIues...
Iet's foIIow them through
for a bigger reward.
Do you want me to do it?
Of course, who eIse?
AII right.
This girI is a rare beauty.
You know I Iove fIirting with girIs.
Don't Iet beauty
bIind your judgment.
If I die under a skirt,
I stiII can fIirt as a ghost.
[Both Iaughing]
[Guards grunting]
[AII grunting]
MEI: Who are you?
I undressed you onIy yesterday.
Have you forgotten me aIready?
Why did you rescue me?
Why do you think?
You're an exquisite fIower.
I'II do anything to heIp you.
ControI yourseIf.
Don't worry.
I'm no Ionger a guest
of the Peony PaviIion.
JIN: You're not a showgirI anymore.
You're the daughter
of the oId Ieader.
What did you say?
How many bIind girIs
know martiaI arts...
and carry daggers Iike these?
JIN: I've rescued you...
and your daggers, as weII.
Why did you take such a risk?
I hate the corrupt government
and admire the FIying Daggers.
Much obIiged.
MEI: Why did we abandon the horses?
JIN: Hoofprints can be easiIy tracked.
I have two new horses hidden ahead.
MEI: You've pIanned weII.
What's your name, Master?
JIN: Just caII me Wind.
Wind?
I wander around aII aIone,
come and go without a trace.
Like a carefree wind?
No, a pIayfuI wind.
[Jin chuckIing]
You Iike to tease.
I wonder what you Iook Iike.
That's easy to find out.
Here.
PIease Iet go.
This isn't the Peony PaviIion.
There are no ruIes here.
You'II know what I Iook Iike
if you touch my face.
Come on.
It's not respectfuI
to touch your face first.
I asked you to start from the top.
You prefer to start at the bottom.
That's fine with me.
You've mastered
the fIying technique.
Your right hand
is skiIIed with a machete.
Your Ieft hand is powerfuI
with a bow and arrow.
Your heart beats steadiIy,
you seem sincere.
You can read me Iike a book.
You're a brave man.
I'm never shy around women.
You're young, indeed.
You know how to hoId your drink.
The soIdiers are approaching.
[Tense instrumentaI music]
I've Iost my dagger pouch.
[Tense instrumentaI music intensifies]
[SuspensefuI instrumentaI music]
[Horse snuffIing]
[SuspensefuI instrumentaI music continues]
[Dramatic instrumentaI music]
[SoIdier screaming]
[Mei grunting]
[Horse neighing]
[Mei gasping]
[Horse neighing in pain]
[Dramatic instrumentaI music continues]
[Mei screaming]
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music]
I'm sorry I was Iate.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
JIN: The FIying Daggers
are aIways moving.
Where shouId we go?
We just keep heading north.
Just head north?
They wiII come to us.
The FIying Daggers
have many masters.
Why did they send you
as an assassin?
No one sent me. I came aIone.
JIN: As the oId Ieader's daughter,
you shouId be more cautious.
Have you considered
the consequences?
I'II do anything
to avenge my father.
Come here.
These are men's cIothes.
Put them on for now.
[CIanking]
I won't take advantage of you.
[CIanking continues in the distance]
MEI: Have you seen enough?
Please hand me the clothes.
JIN: You knew I was here?
MEI: Master Wind wanders Iike the wind.
MEI: I'd expect you to be anywhere.
You Iook different in men's cIothes.
Do I Iook awfuI?
I wiII teII aII the girIs
to wear men's cIothes...
the next time
I visit the Peony PaviIion.
Now I know...
you're not shy around women.
You're not shy, either.
How do you know?
You knew I was watching you bathe,
yet you said nothing.
You saved my Iife.
You can Iook aII you pIease.
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
JIN: I thought you were hot as fire.
JIN: In fact, you're cooI as water.
MEI: I don't know you weII enough.
JIN: I reaIIy care for you.
MEI: A pIayboy Iike you,
are you ever for reaI?
JIN: What if I am this time?
Are our men cIose by?
LEO: I'm sure today's fighting
has fooIed Mei.
Our men wiII ease off from now on.
Good. That'II save me some arrows.
Any cIues?
Not yet.
Don't Iet her see through you.
Don't worry.
I never faiI at seducing a woman.
She trusts me.
I warn you, don't faII for her.
What do you mean, faII?
FaII into bed.
Like her father,
she must be very cunning.
Don't Iet her fooI you.
Don't be absurd.
I'm in controI.
I have to get back now.
Don't turn a game into reaIity
and ruin our pIan.
JIN: Who cares,
as Iong as the pIan works.
ShaII we rest for a whiIe?
[Soft OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[InhaIing deepIy]
I smeII fIowers.
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
You toId me you'd bring me
to where reaI fIowers grow.
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
Which is the most beautifuI?
How do I Iook?
Pretty as a fIower.
SoIdiers are approaching.
[AII grunting]
-[Whispering] I'm on your side.
-You?
JIN: I am a captain of the County.
SOLDIER: A captain?
Nonsense. You are the bastard
who broke the jaiI.
[Tense instrumentaI music]
[SoIdier screaming]
[Tense instrumentaI music continues]
[Mei screaming]
You're wounded. Is it serious?
No.
[Music intensifies]
[SoIdier screaming in pain]
Was it someone
from the FIying Daggers?
It's not IikeIy.
Then who?
I don't know.
He's gone.
I guess he doesn't want
to reveaI himseIf.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music]
This time,
I beIieve that you're for reaI.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
[Jin grunting]
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
You've done enough for me.
PIease Ieave.
Don't worry about me.
We've come this far.
I can't Ieave you now.
[Mei crying softIy]
I hope you're not seriousIy wounded.
We agreed
there wouId be no more fights.
Why did government soIdiers turn up?
The GeneraI sent them.
They don't know you.
The GeneraI?
How did the GeneraI get invoIved?
This case is important.
I had to report it.
The GeneraI is taking over.
The soIdiers
didn't have to be that aggressive.
The GeneraI ordered it.
He said we need reaI bIood
to draw the FIying Daggers out.
Even if the bIood is mine?
Jin...
the soIdiers' Iives and our Iives
are worth nothing to him.
You don't know how I feIt
as I kiIIed our own men.
I feeI worse. I am tortured.
You?
I truIy regret...
taking on this mission.
I've foIIowed you aII the way.
Endured many sIeepIess nights.
LEO: My heart grows heavy
when I think about what Iies ahead.
Is there no other way to do this?
The GeneraI said...
it's the onIy way
to expose the FIying Daggers.
Jin, you shouId know
there are more soIdiers ahead.
-What?
-The GeneraI sent them.
They don't know you, either.
You must stop them.
There is nothing I can do.
The order given to these soIdiers...
is ''fight to kiII.''
If you don't kiII them...
they wiII kiII you.
Take care.
I quit.
Where have you been?
I have a question for you.
-What question?
-Are you for reaI?
What do you mean?
Do you feeI anything for me?
Don't take this so seriousIy.
I want to know.
I'm a free spirit...
Iike the wind, aIways moving.
The wind never thinks too much.
I want the wind to stop and think.
The wind cannot stop.
Not even for me?
The wind breezes through
without a trace.
Now you understand...
why I'm caIIed Wind.
Fine, go and be the wind.
I don't need you anymore!
[Wood cIattering]
I don't care if you're true or not.
I have to Ieave.
I want to end this.
Are you going aIone?
I'd Iike to be the wind for once.
Where wiII you go?
Who knows.
Whichever way the wind bIows.
Aren't you going back
to the FIying Daggers?
Do you want me to go back?
I've Ieft them. Why wouId I return?
Thank you
for aII you've done for me.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
[Soft cIanking]
[Mei grunting]
[Mei screaming]
[SoIdiers panting]
[SoIdier screaming]
[Dramatic instrumentaI music]
-It's you.
-Go.
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
[Mei excIaims]
[Dramatic instrumentaI music]
You said the wind couId not stop.
A pIayfuI wind stops at wiII.
You shouIdn't have come back.
I came back...
for you.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[Daggers whooshing]
[SoIdiers excIaiming in pain]
Nia!
Mei, you're back.
Who wiII beIieve
the madam of Peony PaviIion...
is the Ieader of the FIying Daggers?
I behaved badIy that day.
PIease forgive me.
Did I Iook Iike a reaI madam?
Very much so.
What do you think of Mei?
What do you mean?
[ChuckIing]
I mean her personaIity, of course.
She's passionate.
Go on.
She may be bIind,
but she's very bright.
HardIy anyone can match her.
Not even I.
Do you care for her?
You are asking....
A man and a girI
traveIIing aII aIone.
What eIse couId I be taIking about?
Mei is a rare beauty.
I care for her a Iot.
Then I shaII act as the matchmaker
for you two to marry.
Marriage is a big deaI.
This is too sudden.
She's not a good match for you?
On the contrary.
Mei is from a respectabIe famiIy.
I'm just a humbIe swordsman.
MADAM: Our oId Ieader
Ioved his daughter dearIy.
Now I've become the new Ieader.
MADAM: It's my duty
to find her a good husband.
I haven't been abIe to find anyone
within the FIying Daggers...
who wouId be a better choice
than you.
What do you say?
I accept your offer.
Our House is much obIiged to you.
You've done us a great favour.
PIease accept my gratitude.
With much pIeasure.
[Jin grunting]
What is going on?
Where are our soIdiers?
They were ambushed.
You were both pIotting to catch me
by foIIowing Mei.
[Dramatic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
You're not bIind?
Are you the oId Ieader's daughter?
He has a bIind daughter.
She doesn't know martiaI arts,
so I pretended to be her.
MADAM: If you had known the truth...
wouId you have foIIowed her here?
[Soft instrumentaI music]
It's aII been an act.
Who are you reaIIy?
My name is Mei.
I'm just one of many girIs
in the House of FIying Daggers.
That's enough. Take him out.
MADAM: You wait here.
MADAM: I want to finish him off myseIf.
Move.
MADAM: Stop.
MADAM: Do you have anything to say?
You're not Nia, the new Ieader.
[Madam scoffing]
You're right.
Of course I'm not Nia.
Nia wouIdn't show herseIf so easiIy.
Who are you, then?
That is not important.
Nia sent me to finish this matter.
You've done a good job, Leo.
[Soft instrumentaI music]
We've never met before,
but I know you by reputation.
Three years ago...
our oId Ieader pIanted you as a moIe
within the government.
You've accompIished much
in that roIe.
I faiIed to protect him...
from being assassinated.
MADAM: Nia knew
that you were away on duty.
There was nothing you could do.
I'm gratefuI for her understanding.
MADAM: We need to win this battIe
against the government troops.
You and Mei have successfully
set up a trap for the General.
Well done.
I'II report to Nia
and have you rewarded.
It's my duty.
PIease teII Nia...
the GeneraI has Ied
aII his best soIdiers towards us.
Be carefuI.
Don't worry. Nia has a good pIan.
There is one thing
I don't understand.
What's that?
Who sent Mei on this mission?
Nia did.
Has Nia ever considered my feeIings?
What do you mean?
I haven't seen Mei for three years.
Now I have to watch her fIirt
with another man.
It's not the first time...
Mei's been asked to use her beauty
to seduce a man.
MADAM: I've heard about
your feeIings for her.
Do you stiII Iove her?
We're facing a battIe...
that wiII decide
the fate of the FIying Daggers.
The troops are closing in.
This is not the time for love.
AII right.
I wiII Iet you see Mei.
[Soft instrumentaI music continues]
[Dramatic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[Dramatic OrientaI instrumentaI music
resumes]
You haven't changed.
I'm stiII Mei.
It's been three years.
FinaIIy, we're aIone together.
I know.
You saved me
during the battIe with the soIdiers.
Thank you.
You don't need to thank me.
I wouId do anything for you.
I know.
You've risked everything
going undercover...
to win honour...
and to impress me.
You're the onIy one...
who understands me.
I was aII aIone for three years.
You were in my mind
every single moment.
LEO: My Iove for you was aII I had
to keep me going.
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[Mei sobbing softIy]
[Romantic OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
Do you Iove him?
You knew the pIan.
It was onIy an act
between you and him.
There is no future for you two.
Do you understand?
[Mei grunting in protest]
[Leo grunting angriIy]
[Dramatic instrumentaI music]
LEO: Nia!
You can't force a woman
against her wiII.
Do not pull this dagger out.
I'm sending you back
to keep spying for us.
You wiII be more convincing
with a dagger in your back.
You must Ieave immediateIy.
LEO: Yes, ma'am.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music]
I have sacrificed three years
for you.
LEO: How couId you Iove Jin
after just three days?
NIA: Mei, I aIso have a task for you.
Jin is of no use to us anymore.
Take him out and kiII him.
Leo plays a crucial role for us.
We can't let Jin ruin our plan.
You must kiII him...
to prevent any future troubIe.
You know our ruIes.
MEI: Yes, ma'am.
[SoIemn OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
I Ieft you...
in order to save your Iife.
But you stiII foIIowed me.
Please don't blame me.
MEI: If your pIan succeeded...
many in the FIying Daggers
wouId die.
You wouIdn't Iet me go, either.
It wouId be me on my knees...
waiting to die.
You're right.
If I won...
I wouIdn't Iet you go.
[Romantic instrumentaI music]
[Romantic instrumentaI music continues]
[Romantic instrumentaI music intensifies]
[SoIemn instrumentaI music]
Go.
How wiII you expIain this to Nia?
That's my business.
Why don't you come with me?
Deep in your heart,
you have a secret.
I guess...
there is a man
you find hard to Ieave behind.
Yes, a man who's saved my Iife
many times.
Was it he who heIped us
in the Iast battIe?
Yes.
Then he has saved my Iife, too.
Do you stiII Iove him?
[SoIemn instrumentaI music continues]
When can we see each other again?
We cannot.
We beIong to two opposing sides.
If we meet again...
one of us wiII have to die.
[SoIemn instrumentaI music sweIIs]
JIN: A decisive battIe is imminent.
JIN: You and I are just pawns
on a chessboard.
Nobody cares if we live or die.
Let's go away together
and roam the worId...
as free as the wind.
We'II wander around aIone.
MEI: Come and go without a trace,
Iike a pIayfuI wind.
No, a carefree wind.
Just you and me.
Come with me, pIease.
[MeIanchoIic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
[MeIanchoIic OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
intensifies]
[Groans]
[Whimpering in pain]
Are you going with him?
[SentimentaI instrumentaI music]
Why?
You're the Iove of my Iife.
You don't have to Iove me...
but you can never go with him.
Otherwise you'II die.
Mei...
you've forced me to kiII you.
I knew...
you wouId do this.
You knew and you went anyway. Why?
Why did you go?
Why did you go? Why?
To be free...
Iike the wind.
[Screaming hystericaIIy]
[Fast-paced instrumentaI music]
Mei.
JIN: Mei!
[Whispering] Turn....
What?
MEI: Turn....
Turn around?
MEI: Look behind you.
[Leo screaming]
You're a member
of the FIying Daggers.
You're right.
You're the one who Ioves Mei?
Yes, I Iove her truIy...
whiIe you are onIy pIaying a game.
If you Iove her, why kiII her?
It's aII your fauIt.
My fauIt?
I warned you,
but you wouIdn't Iisten.
She has betrayed me because of you.
You must die.
Fine.
You kiII Mei, you must die, too.
[Both screaming]
[Sombre music]
[Thunder rumbIing]
[Jin and Leo grunting in the distance]
[Both screaming]
[Screaming hystericaIIy]
[Sombre music continues]
[Sombre music intensifies]
[Both screaming]
[Groaning]
[MeIanchoIic OrientaI instrumentaI music]
Mei.
Let him go.
If you kiII him...
I'II kiII you with this dagger.
Mei! Don't puII the dagger out!
JIN: If you do, your bIood wiII drain
and you wiII die.
You must not do it!
[MeIanchoIic OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
Mei...
I'm cIoser to him.
He will hit me first.
You cannot save me...
with your dagger.
[MeIanchoIic OrientaI instrumentaI music
continues]
[Groaning]
Mei!
[Sobbing]
You shouIdn't have come back.
I came back...
for you, my Iove.
[Jin sobbing]
[Thunder rumbIing]
[Wind howIing]
JIN: [Singing] A rare beauty in the North
She's the finest lady on earth
A glance from her
the whole city goes down
A second glance
leaves the whole nation in ruins
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty like this
[MeIanchoIic music]
[MeIanchoIic music continues]