PAUL: Repeat after me, okay?
(PAUL SPEAKING FRENCH)
(JULIA REPEATING IN FRENCH)
Oh, Paul,
leave me alone.
Bon appetit.
- Bon appetit.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Butter.
Oh, my goodness.
You have to taste this.
Here.
Mmm.
I mean... It's...
I know.
- But I'm...
I know. I know. I know.
JULIA: Look at that!
Oh, Paul, it's so beautiful!
PAUL: Slow down.
(JULIA EXCLAIMS)
JULIA: Sorry.
PAUL: This is it.
Look, right... Just stop.
(JULIA LAUGHING)
I can't believe
we get to live here.
Paul!
(GREETING IN FRENCH)
Is this a mistake?
Should we have stayed in Brooklyn?
We're gonna love Queens.
Queens is beautiful.
Moving truck's here.
(CRASHING)
(JULIE EXCLAIMS)
You okay?
Everything
is falling down.
Hey.
What are we doing here?
Repeat after me.
Nine hundred square feet.
Plus, it's close
to your office.
to my office, but
we don't have to move.
We could renege
on the lease,
repack everything
and live in the Jeep.
You're right.
(CRASHING)
Eric, what is that noise?
What noise?
Is it going to be
like this every night?
Maybe.
Oh.
PAUL: Jule?
It's Versailles.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I'm so happy
you like it, darling.
(SIGHS)
(JULIA HUMMING)
(PHONE RINGING)
FEMALE OPERATOR:
Good morning, Lower Manhattan
Development Corporation,
MALE OPERATOR: LMDC.
Lower Manhattan
Development Corporation,
Julie Powell.
WOMAN 1: My son died
in the second tower.
I'm sorry.
(WOMAN CRYING)
I'm so sorry.
MAN 1: Are you the person
to speak to if I don't like
the plan for the memorial
that was in this
morning's Times?
You can speak to me.
Do you have any power?
No.
I wanna speak to
someone with power.
I don't like the plan.
I don't like the plan either.
(PHONE RINGS)
WOMAN 2: You people
are a bunch of heartless
bureaucratic goons.
I am not a heartless
bureaucratic goon.
I am just
a person in a cubicle,
and I am doing
the best I can, ma'am.
This is my sixth phone call
and the only thing
anyone ever tells me is
I have to fill out
a form to get in line
for an insurance payment.
And you do. But, I mean,
if you don't wanna
fill out a form,
I will fill one out for you,
but you're still going to
have to come in and sign it.
To your cubicle?
Yes.
I feel terrible about
what you're going through,
Mr. Diamond, but...
MAN 2: You have no idea what
I'm going through, Ms. Powell.
You have no idea.
- Please don't yell at me.
This whole thing is
completely inefficient.
Please stop yelling at me.
- It's ridiculous.
My 3-year-old is
more capable of helping.
I am your friend.
WOMAN 3: And now
the doctor says there's
fiberglass in his lungs.
He coughs.
He never stops coughing.
(SNIFFLING)
I don't know what to do.
His wife says there's
so much crap in his
lungs he can't breathe,
and now his insurance
is refusing to pay
for this drug that
might really work.
Tell her to call
the Health Department.
That's an answering machine.
Andrea Gomez
in the mayor's office.
Thank you. Thank you.
Chocolate cream pie.
You know what
I love about cooking?
ERIC: What's that?
I love that after a day
when nothing is sure,
and when I say
"nothing" I mean nothing,
you can come home
and absolutely know
that if you add
egg yolks to chocolate
and sugar and milk,
it will get thick.
It's such a comfort.
Bad day?
- Mmm.
Mmm.
When will this
pie be ready?
Soon, but I have to make
the whipped cream
first and let it set.
I'll be here.
It's a masterpiece.
Ritual Cobb salad
lunch tomorrow.
Dreading, dreading, dreading.
Subway.
Hi.
- Hi.
How are you?
What can I get
for you ladies?
I will have a Cobb salad,
no bleu cheese.
Cobb salad, no beets.
Cobb salad, no bacon.
Cobb salad, no eggs.
- Okay, tell them...
Are you listening
carefully, Tracy?
Tell them to take
the offer up to 185.
Repeat after me, Tracy.
Here she goes.
1-8-5.
- What's going on?
And call me
the second you hear back.
My assistant. It's almost
not worth having one.
REGINA: I know.
Yesterday I said to Allison,
"Go to the pharmacy,
get me a pair of
black pantyhose."
She came back and said,
"They didn't have any."
I said, "Did you
try another pharmacy?"
I mean, really.
Or Bloomingdale's.
What's wrong with
trying Bloomingdale's?
CASSIE: Yeah, I don't get it.
If only I could be
my own assistant.
You can be.
Fire your assistant
and don't hire a replacement.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
No, that's not
what I mean, Julie.
Excuse me. Oh...
Oh, those are cute.
- Oh, thanks. Thanks.
Okay, tell them 190,
1-9-0. Great.
"1-9-0." What?
What are you up to?
(WOMEN GASPING)
$190 million.
We're assembling
a parcel at Midtown.
Oh, wow. Oh, oh,
that is so great, Cassie.
A parcel of what?
Buildings.
We're gonna
tear them all down
and put up a high-rise.
REGINA: To your parcel.
- Thank you.
(TOASTING IN SPANISH)
And enough about you,
here's to me.
As of yesterday,
I am the senior
vice president
in charge
of corporate publicity.
CASSIE: No.
- Which means I get a raise
and I can borrow
half a million dollars
at 2% if I want to.
CASSIE: Great.
- If you want to?
(SIGHS)
So how's your job, Julie?
- Oh, it's...
I can only imagine. Heartbreaking.
- So sad.
Painful.
- Not in a bad way.
Excuse me.
Oh, God, I forgot.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Excuse me.
Hello?
- Hello?
Hi.
- Hi.
Hey, Jules?
I have got to interview you
for this piece
that I'm writing.
Sure, Annabelle, great.
I'd be honored.
Call Julie about interview.
Find out about dry cleaning.
Find out before dinner
on Thursday.
Saturday party.
No.
REGINA: I cannot
computer-coach you every day
while I'm with my girlfriends.
What is it about?
The article?
It's about our generation
turning 30.
People turning 30.
Oh, my life, I am so busy.
I don't know
when I can fit you in.
May I remind you,
I don't want to see you,
you want to see me?
Yeah. Would a breakfast work?
JULIE: I believed her.
What kind of idiot am I?
She said, "It's about
our generation turning 30."
What'd you expect?
Annabelle was always a liar.
"Julie Powell, once
the editor of the
Amherst literary magazine,
"the one we all knew
would be 'The One,'
"temped for eight years
before giving up on her novel,
"and now works in a cubicle
as a mid-level bureaucrat,
"attempting to deal with
the aftereffects of 9/11."
(EXCLAIMS ANGRILY)
Oh, God, you memorized it?
How pathetic.
She left so much out.
Anyway, the picture was good.
I looked fat.
Just your face.
JULIE: I forgot to tell you.
Do you know what
Annabelle's doing now?
Sarah told me. A blog.
Of what?
What do you mean "of what"?
A blog of Annabelle.
Of every thought that
passes through her brain.
Her stupid,
vapid, insipid...
I could write a blog.
I have thoughts.
And you're a writer,
which is more than
I can say for Annabelle.
If only that were true.
You wrote a novel.
Half a novel. And no one
wanted to publish it.
You're not a writer
unless someone
publishes you.
See, that's what's
so great about blogs.
You don't have
to be published.
You can just go online,
press enter and
there it is, out there.
What would I write
a blog about?
You're an editor, tell me.
Why don't you write about
how much you love Queens?
A short blog.
You could write
about your job.
If I wrote a blog
about my job
and anyone at work
ever read it...
I mean, hello.
This is good.
- Mmm-hmm.
This is really good.
On top of which,
the whole idea
of writing a blog
is to get away
from what I do all day.
The way that cooking
is a way that I get away
from what I do all day.
So write a blog
about cooking.
I'm not a real cook,
like Julia Child
or Mario Batali.
Julia Child wasn't
always Julia Child.
If I really wanted
to learn to cook,
I could just
cook my way through
Julia Child's cookbook.
I could blog about that.
I have a copy.
I stole it from my mother
last time I was in Texas.
When I was eight,
my father's boss
came to dinner and
it was a really big deal,
and my mother made
boeuf bourguignon.
But it wasn't just
It was Julia's
boeuf bourguignon.
And it was like
she was there,
like Julia was
there in the room,
on our side like some
great big good fairy.
And everything was
going to be all right.
I'm gonna try to flip
this thing over now,
which is a rather
daring thing to do.
She changed everything.
Before her,
it was frozen food
and can openers
and marshmallows.
Don't knock marshmallows.
When you flip anything,
you've just got
to have the courage
of your convictions.
Especially if it's
a loose sort of mass like...
Oh, that didn't go very well.
But, you see,
when I flipped it,
I didn't have
the courage I needed...
- She's so adorable.
...the way I should've.
But you can always
put it together.
And you're alone
in the kitchen.
Who's to see?
Pearls. The woman
is wearing pearls
in the kitchen.
...you've just got to
practice, like the piano.
I'm Julia Child.
Bon appetit.
MALE ANNOUNCER: Julia Child is
coauthor of the book
Mastering the Art
of French Cooking.
ERIC:  Bon appetit.
"For the servantless
American cook."
That's me, all right.
Okay, here's a problem.
I've never eaten an egg.
And I have a hyperacidic
stomach. We'll deal.
So I'll cook my way through
the Julia Child cookbook
and write a blog about it.
But I'll probably
need a deadline.
Why?
Because otherwise
it'll be like
everything else I do.
'Cause let's face it,
I never finish anything.
Hey.
- Well, it's true.
You know why I think it is?
ADD.
- You have ADD?
Yes. That's why
I'm so bad at housework.
Oh, is that it?
I'm just saying,
a deadline would be good.
So a deadline.
"I love deadlines.
"I love the sound
they make as they
go whooshing past."
Hitchhiker's Guide
to the Galaxy.
- I mean it.
Okay, so a year, or so.
- A year?
(CHUCKLING)
This thing weighs
like two pounds.
I have a full-time job.
Sometimes
I don't get home
until 8:00 or 9:00 and...
It's crazy. It's crazy.
Is it crazy?
Yes. Yes.
Okay, you want
to do Blog Z?
Yes.
Blog Z it is.
Nobody here
but us servantless
American cooks.
"Servantless
American cooks."
What do you think?
- Love it.
"Start blogging."
JULIE:
"The Julie/Julia Project."
The Book,
Mastering the Art
of French Cooking.
First edition, 1961
by Simone Beck,
Louisette Bertholle,
and, of course,
Julia Child, the woman
who taught America
to cook and to eat.
It's 40 years later
and no one can touch her.
The Challenge,
365 days, 524 recipes.
The Contender, Julie Powell.
Government employee by day,
renegade foodie by night.
Risking her marriage, her job,
and her cat's well-being,
she has signed on for
a deranged assignment.
How far it will go,
no one can say.
(CHATTERING IN FRENCH)
PAUL: Dear Charlie,
we're settled in finally,
and Julia loves it here.
She wants to stay forever.
You know how famously
grouchy the French can be,
dear brother.
Everyone here
is so delightful.
But Julia brings out
the best in a polecat.
So charming.
So she thinks they're
the most wonderful
people in the world.
I feel that I am French.
I just must be.
Well, you might be.
As for staying here forever,
I have to say,
I wouldn't mind it myself.
PAUL: I'm so glad
that you came,
I can't tell you.
WOMAN: It was a very nice show.
JULIA: Thanks for coming.
WOMAN: I enjoyed it.
Paul, congratulations. Excellent exhibit.
- Thanks so much, Jack.
Jack Donovan,
this is my wife, Julia.
It was such a wonderful
exhibition, Paul.
Thank you.
I am so proud of you.
Oh, good.
French people
eat French food!
Every single day!
I can't get over it.
They do.
(SIGHING)
You know I love you so much,
I'm gonna let you
take the first bite.
That's so good.
- Before I even had... It's good, is it?
(SIGHS)
What should I do,
do you think?
About what?
I don't really
want to go back
into government work.
Mmm-hmm.
You know, but I...
Shouldn't I find
something to do?
These wives don't
do anything here.
That's not me.
It's just not me.
I know.
I saw a notice
on the bulletin board
at the embassy
for hat-making lessons.
You like hats.
I do, I do.
I do.
What is it that you
really like to do?
Eat.
(BOTH LAUGH)
It's what I like to do.
- I know, I know. I know. I know.
And you are so good at it.
Look at you!
- I am good at it.
Now. How good you are.
- I'm growing in front of you.
I was thinking of
taking bridge lessons.
You like bridge.
I do. I like
the idea of bridge.
Four points for an ace,
three points for a king,
two points for a queen,
one point for a jack.
And breast your cards.
Do you have any
French cookbooks
in English?
I'm afraid not.
Oh, gosh.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
The salesperson. She...
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Had no idea...
Because, you see,
there is no French
cookbook in English.
And all I have is
this  Joy of Cooking
by Irma Rombauer,
which is an excellent,
excellent cookbook,
but it's not French.
So I did ask
my friend Avis De Voto
to look around
in the United States
to see if she could find...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Right. Right.
Gosh, I thought I was
speaking French to you!
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Oh, my goodness!
MAN: What do we have here?
It's a copy of...
- It's my memoirs.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, look.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Oh, it's fantastic!
But it's in French!
(ALL LAUGHING)
You'll get there.
- Thank you, darling.
I know. I'm learning.
I'm trying. I'm really...
Ooh. Happy birthday to me.
MAN: Happy birthday.
JULIA: What can this mean?
PAUL: What?
(READING FRENCH)
"Wash the thighs."
No, "bathe."
Bathe the thighs.
Look, but then...
- Where?
"In butter." I know that.
But what is the...
"Bathe the thighs
in butter and then
stuff the..."
What's that word?
The hen!
- Right. Hen.
"Until she just
can't take it anymore."
(LAUGHS)
It doesn't say that.
- It does.
I'll show you later
in the dictionary.
I'll go through
the whole recipe with you.
Why don't I go
to cooking school?
Why don't you?
I'm serious.
So am I.
Oh, my God.
What if you hadn't
fallen in love with me?
But I did.
- Mmm.
Oh, gosh.
(ALARM RINGING)
JULIE: Yesterday was Tuesday,
August 13th, 2002.
Day one. 364 days to go.
I cooked artichokes
with hollandaise sauce
which is melted butter
that's been whipped
into a frenzy with egg yolks
until it's died
and gone to heaven.
And let me say this.
Is there anything
better than butter?
Think it over.
Every time you
taste something
that's delicious
beyond imagining,
and you say,
"What is in this?"
The answer is always
going to be "butter."
It's incredible.
It's been whisked
into submission,
that's why.
The day there's
a meteorite heading
toward the earth
and we have 30 days to live,
I am going to
spend it eating butter.
Here's my final word
on the subject.
You can never
have too much butter.
August 24th, day 11.
Is this what you mean
when you say,
"Don't crowd the mushrooms"?
Is this a crowd?
353 days to go.
A horrible day at work.
An old grandma
who looked as if
she wouldn't harm a fly
called me a pencil-pushing
capitalist dupe.
But then I came home
and cooked chicken with cream,
mushrooms and port,
and it was total bliss.
Here's the big news.
I had been cooking mushrooms
the wrong way my entire life.
Don't crowd the mushrooms,
otherwise they won't brown.
Are you listening,
whoever you are?
You're gonna love that one.
Day 22.
This one's really good
with fig jam.
I got carried away
in Dean & DeLuca last night
and spent half
my take-home pay.
And the first thing I realized
when I got to the subway
with my groceries,
a bag of cat litter,
a bottle of olive oil
I absolutely
could not live without,
and a huge bunch of branches
was that the branches
were probably not a good idea.
Sorry.
They were slapping
folks in the face
right and left
and I was sweating like a pig.
Not surprising,
since I've been way too busy
cooking fattening food
to bother exercising.
And then I came home
and got a big vote of
confidence from my mother.
JULIE'S MOM: Remind me again
why you're doing this...
Blog.
Whatever it's called.
It's a regimen, Mom.
Like doing sit-ups.
Well, it's just
adding pressure.
What pressure?
You have a full-time job,
you have a husband,
and now you're gonna
get sick from blogging.
It's sort of like
being in AA.
What are you saying?
It gives you something
you have to do every day,
one day at a time.
How do you
know this lingo?
Honey, are you an alcoholic?
I'm saying
it's good for me
to have short-term goals.
Well, that is silly.
That is just plain silly.
Who's reading this blog?
People. People are
reading it, I'm sure.
Well, it's something
you decided to do,
and you can decide not to,
and not one single
person's gonna mind.
No. Don't you get it?
I just started.
I can't stop,
I have to finish.
It's all I've got.
(PHONE BEEPS)
Hello? Hello?
Stupid dead phone.
Hey, it's not all you got.
I know. I know.
I didn't mean that.
JULIE: Yesterday,
I poached an egg.
It seemed like
the perfect thing to do
on perhaps
the second worst workday
in recorded history.
Explain to me how
you've never eaten
an egg in your whole life.
I've had eggs in, like, cakes.
Never had an "egg" egg.
I was a very willful child.
It's simmering.
I had this notion,
God knows why,
that poaching eggs
would be simple.
But I was deeply wrong.
"Immediately and gently
push the white over the yolk
with a wooden spoon
"for two to three seconds."
Immediately.
BOTH: Ew!
Disgusting.
Oh, maybe
the eggs aren't fresh.
Julia says the eggs
have to be fresh.
They are fresh.
Okay. You don't have
to bite my head off.
I'm just quoting Julia.
JULIE: It took three of us,
crammed into the kitchen
over a pot of simmering water,
but, eventually, we nailed it.
Hello.
- Welcome.
How cute is that?
And I ate my very first egg
of my whole life,
ever, ever, ever.
I thought eggs
were going to be greasy
and slimy, but it tastes like
cheese sauce. Yum.
Julia Child,
you are so good.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
And, may I say, excellent wine?
- Mmm-hmm.
Do you think
Julia knows about you?
I wish.
I have this fantasy
that she comes for dinner
and I show her
my new lemon zester.
We become very close.
The truth is,
no one knows about me.
I feel like
I'm just sending things
into this giant void.
Which reminds me.
Annabelle's blog.
Have you read it lately?
Yes.
It's sort of funny.
Is it?
She's dating
this rich guy
who owns a plane.
His name's Lester.
And they do it
in the air.
People love it.
It's a huge hit.
What do you think
it means if you don't
like your friends?
It's completely normal.
Men like their friends.
We're not talking about men.
Who's talking about men?
JULIE: So it's
five weeks down, 47 to go,
and I feel fantastic.
Sometimes,
I can't help but wonder.
Is there anyone
out there reading me?
But I'm sure you are,
aren't you? Somebody?
(BLEEPS)
Anybody?
Ernestine, I have a comment.
My mother. Doesn't count.
Today we will begin
by learning to boil eggs.
First, you must make sure
that the egg is fresh.
I was so hoping that...
Well, for something
a little more advanced,
Madame Brassart.
But you are
not an advanced cook.
But I do know
how to boil an egg.
Do you know how
to bone a duck?
No, but that's exactly
the sort of thing
that I'm very interested
in learning how to do.
- Mmm.
There is one other class,
but you will not like it.
It's for  professionnel,
which you will
never be, I'm sure.
All men. All GIs.
And very expensive.
I cannot imagine
that you would ever
want to pay the tuition.
How much?
MAX: So the onion
is ready, but...
(GREETING IN FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You must hold the knife,
first of all, like this.
Wrist, easy.
Leave the thumb here.
The hand and the knife are one.
- Mmm.
And the hand,
the other hand,
you must protect it.
Here, you must cut
only the onion. Yes?
Not me.
Yes.
And then, you put
your thumb here and
the other fingers here.
Jule?
You're being a little
over-competitive,
don't you think?
Well, you should've
seen the way
those men looked at me.
As if I were some
frivolous housewife,
just looking
for a way to kill time.
Well...
Where are you going?
- Not here.
You hungry?
- No.
Good.
Ta-da!
Well done, Madame Child.
JULIA: Dear Avis,
I'm in my third week
at Le Cordon Bleu,
and I'm in utter bliss.
Every morning
the alarm goes off at 6:30,
and I leap out of bed.
I'm up!
By 7:30 I'm in class,
in my apron,
peeling potatoes.
Then we cook stock
and we bone fish.
We dress pigeons.
We make pastry
with so much butter,
it almost stops your heart
just to look at it.
My teacher moves so quickly
I'm sometimes lost.
But I'm way ahead
of the others in the class,
all of them men,
and all of them
very unfriendly,
until they discovered
I was fearless.
Something I realized
about the same time they did.
Morning class ends at 12:30,
then I go home and
make lunch for Paul.
Then Paul takes a nap.
And later in the afternoon,
he goes back to the embassy
and I go back to school.
You must have
a mortar and pestle.
Incidentally,
my father is horrified
I'm going to cooking school.
Offered to give me
extra money to hire a cook.
Go on. Fun! Joy!
This is what matters.
I'm probably the only
American I know in Paris
who thinks shopping
for food is as much fun
as buying a dress.
Course, you'd think so too,
if you lived in a country
where absolutely nothing
comes in my size.
By the way, did you know
that if you don't dry meat,
it won't brown properly?
Irma Rombauer doesn't
say a word about it
in the Joy of Cooking.
Avis, I am in heaven here.
I've been looking
for a career all my life...
Happy Valentine's Day.
- ...and I've found it.
(GASPS)
We met in Ceylon
when we were in the OSS.
But he never
noticed me at first.
Well, that's not true.
I noticed you.
I noticed your legs
straightaway.
Oh, you were such a roue.
All the women
were mad for him.
Can you blame them?
Anyway, we were
sent off to China.
Absolutely delicious,
if I do say so myself.
Julia.
When you finish
your term, you'll be
teaching at Cordon Bleu.
No, I don't think so.
The woman who runs it
absolutely hates me!
Come on.
Oh, no one could
possibly hate you.
That's true. But she does.
Were you spies?
No. Yes. No.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, so cagey, right?
You were in the Office
of Strategic Services
and you were not spies?
I was only a file clerk.
But Paul?
Paul designed all of
the secret war rooms
for General Mountbatten.
Well, just maps and
exhibits and things.
It wasn't...
He did!
He single-handedly
won the war for us.
Well, I had to. Someone did.
I mean, it was
dragging on, wasn't it?
Anyway,
so there we were in China,
just friends having dinner,
and it turned
out to be Julia.
It turned out to
be Julia all along.
(GLASSES CLINKING)
Julia, you are
the butter to my bread,
and the breath to my life.
I love you, darling girl.
Happy Valentine's Day.
PAUL: Dear Charlie,
Julia in front
of her stove has
the same fascination for me
as watching a kettle drummer
at the symphony.
The oven door opens
and shuts so fast,
you hardly notice
the deft thrust of a spoon
as she dips into a casserole,
and up to her mouth
for a taste check
like a perfectly-timed
double beat on the drums.
Then with her bare fingers,
she snatches
a set of cannelloni
out of the pot
of boiling water,
(EXCLAIMS)
and she cries,
"These damn things are
as hot as a stiff cock."
She said what?
JULIE: I know.
Julia Child said,
"Hot as a..."
I know, I'm shocked.
It's from a letter
that Paul Child
wrote to his twin
brother Charlie in 1949,
when Julia was just
starting classes
at Le Cordon Bleu.
So Julia and Paul,
beaucoup, beaucoup.
I know.
Just goes to show you.
What?
You can never tell about
a person's sex life
by looking at them.
They were so in love.
Hot sauce from a reader.
And today I had
12 comments from readers,
and I didn't know
any of them.
JULIE: Thanks to all
my faithful readers
for this loot.
I have now completed
65 recipes in 47 days.
(JULIE READING)
On track with 103 recipes
in just over two months.
Looks like a cupcake.
Lobster thermidor
is coming up,
and I am going
to have to murder
and dismember a crustacean.
How will I ever do this?
Last night our sleep machine,
the one we have by our bed
to drown out
the noise of freight trucks
rumbling past our apartment,
was speaking to me.
And it was saying,
"Lobster killer.
"Lobster killer,
lobster killer,
lobster killer."
One of my readers said
that if you put
lobsters in the freezer,
it sort of numbs them.
Then I got another
comment that said,
"Man up,
kill the damn lobster.
"Just take a knife
and do it."
(PSYCHO KILLER PLAYING)
# I can't seem to
face up to the facts
# I'm tense and nervous
and I can't relax
It's alive!
Eric.
# I can't sleep,
'cause my bed's on fire
# Don't touch me
I'm a real live wire
Oh, God.
"A note on dealing
with live lobsters.
"If you object to steaming
a live lobster," yes,
"plunge the point
of the knife
"into the head
between the eyes."
Oh, Julia,
you make it sound so simple.
ERIC: (IN SINGSONG TONE)
Lobster killer.
Eric.
(HUMMING)
Get out of here.
I don't need you at all.
You are completely useless.
I'm just gonna throw
them into the water
and put the lid on
and that will be that.
Fine.
Hello.
Goodbye.
I'm sorry.
(SINGING IN FRENCH)
# Psycho killer #
(SHRIEKS)
(JULIE CONTINUES SHRIEKING)
ERIC: You okay?
Okay.
Okay. All right.
All right, boys.
There's a new sheriff
in town.
(IN SINGSONG TONE)
Lobster killer.
Under control.
You are a saint.
Thank you. Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I can't. I can't.
You can.
No, I can't. I have a lot to do.
- You can.
Eric, I can't.
- I'm good.
Eric.
- Just give me one more,
give me one more.
Just one more.
- Fine. Go,
I have so much to do. Get!
Out!
Hey, thank you so much.
Hey, man. How you doing?
Happy birthday.
Yeah, terrific.
Good to see you.
Cake.
- Cake. Brother-in-law.
Love you so much.
GARTH: Hey, man.
SARAH: Hi, hi, hi, hi.
Bon appetit.
ALL:  Bon appetit.
SARAH: Happy birthday, Julie.
GARTH: Happy birthday.
- Hi! Thanks, sweetheart.
Oh, thanks for coming
all out here. Hey, you.
Here's an incredible thing.
When Julia and Paul met,
she was a virgin.
Really?
- Wow.
She was, like,
practically 40.
ANNETTE: You serious?
- How does anyone even know that?
There were all these
letters that Julia wrote
to her friend Avis De Voto.
And Paul wrote
to his brother,
and no one threw
anything out,
as far as I can tell.
When they got married,
she could barely boil an egg.
Isn't that amazing?
Really?
Braised cucumbers
are a revelation.
This is good.
I'm obsessed with her.
I'm totally obsessed.
She's totally obsessed.
Well, it's good that you are,
because this is amazing.
Seriously. So good.
Well, savor it,
because that's all there is.
I mean, lobster, major bucks.
Why don't you
put a PayPal thing
on the website?
People could send in money
if they felt like it.
GARTH: Oh, yeah. Absolutely.
You have fans,
your readers love you.
I do? I have fans?
Yeah, you do.
Well, I can't
ask them for money.
ANNETTE: Why not?
I think you should
do the PayPal thing.
That way we could
have more lobster.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
TIM: Harder. Get them.
Get them. Hey, hey, hey!
ERIC: Thirty. Thirty.
Thirty. Thirty. Thirty.
Happy birthday, sweetheart.
- Oh.
Thank you.
Just like Julia's.
Aww.
Only hers were
probably the real deal.
They're beautiful.
Help you put it on.
Let's give this a shot here.
How's that?
Yeah.
I'm 30.
I thought it was
gonna be terrible,
but thanks to you,
and thanks to Julia,
it feels like I'm
gonna get through.
Cake.
More cake.
How do you like that cake?
Hey, you.
I'm going to bed.
Ernie, 53 comments
on my lobster blog.
Shut up.
- Mmm-hmm.
(PHONE RINGING)
Julie Powell.
ERIC: (IN DISGUISE)
This the person I speak to
if I got a problem?
Yes, sir.
What is your problem?
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Too much food, not enough sex.
Eric, that's not funny.
I thought
it was pretty funny.
Okay, it was.
Hey, guess what?
- What?
You are the third
most popular blog
on salon.com.
I am?
- Yes, you are.
I am!
So I figure
for every one
who writes in,
there are, I don't know,
hundreds that don't.
Don't you think?
It's like there's this
whole group of people
who are sort of
connected to me.
They need me in some way.
Like, if I didn't write,
they would really be upset.
They'd probably take,
like, poison,
try to kill themselves.
Mmm-hmm.
(SNORING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Julia.
Are you still making hats?
Oh, no, I abandoned it.
But I am ready
to graduate from
the Cordon Bleu.
I can't get the damn woman
who runs the school
to schedule the test.
Madame Brassart?
Is that the woman
you are speaking of?
She is a bitch.
(LAUGHS)
She is, you're right.
I think she's almost
the only person
in the world
I honestly can't stand.
She is not the only
person I can't stand.
Do you two know each other?
You should. Julia Child,
Simone Beck.
Simca.
- Simca, how do you do?
And this is my friend
Louisette Bertholle.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I can't believe
you haven't met.
Simca and Louisette
are writing a cookbook.
For Americans.
Really?
Why do you need to
take a stupid test?
So I can get a diploma.
So I can teach.
You don't need
a diploma to teach.
You're probably right.
Avis says the same thing.
- Who is Avis?
My friend, Avis De Voto,
who lives in Cambridge,
Massachusetts.
She's very wise.
But I can't help it.
I want a diploma.
I am very conventional.
I don't know what to do.
Well, why don't you
write to the horrible
Madame Brassart
and threaten her?
Threaten her?
With what?
The United States of America.
Yes!
Tell her the
American ambassador
personally wants you
to take the examination.
JULIA: No, no,
no, no, no, no.
I couldn't do that.
Heavens, no!
The American ambassador.
Hardly even know the man.
Of course you can.
JULIA: Dear Madame Brassart,
everyone
at the American embassy,
including my dear friend
the ambassador,
will be very surprised
if I'm not allowed
to take my examination.
You will write the recipes
for  oeufs mollets.
- Cotelettes de
veau en surprise,
et creme renversee
au caramel.
Cotelettes de veau
en surprise.
I had no idea what
veal  en surprise was. None.
Cooked it in class.
It's a veal chop
with mushrooms in a bag.
(CHUCKLING) A paper bag.
That's the surprise.
You open the bag, surprise!
Veal and mushrooms,
it's just I've never flunked
a test in my entire life.
I am an A student.
You can ask
to take it again.
I can?
Of course.
Meanwhile, you can
come teach with us.
Oh.
Gosh!
Is it true
you plan to teach?
Yes, we're going
to teach Americans
in Paris how to cook.
Madame Child,
I must tell you,
you have no real
talent for cooking.
But the Americans
will never know
the difference.
(LAUGHING)
(SPUTTERS)
(ALARM RINGING)
JULIE: We are,
I am sorry to say,
entering aspics.
An aspic is sort
of a beef-flavored
Jell-O mold.
Doesn't that sound delicious?
I can't imagine why no one
makes them anymore.
You begin with a calf's foot,
which I am in possession of
thanks to my sainted husband,
and you boil it
until your kitchen
smells like a tannery.
And then it gels
in the refrigerator
and you flip it onto a plate.
Which, according
to Julia Child,
is supposed to be easy.
And all I can say about that,
no offense intended, Julia, is
the bitch lied.
Shit.
Shit!
- How many more aspics are there?
Seven.
No one will know
if you don't do them.
It's not like there's,
like, the Aspic Police
or something.
You could lie.
I can't. I just can't.
Julia will know.
It's like she's watching me.
I'm under her influence.
I'm becoming a much
better person because of her.
Yuck! The sink!
Look at this!
(EXCLAIMING DISGUSTEDLY)
I hate it here!
Did you put
something down the sink?
You hate it here?
How am I supposed
to cook anything
in this kitchen?
It's no wonder that
my mold fell apart.
I don't suppose
we have any Drano.
Not unless you bought it.
I do all of this
and I'm supposed
to buy Drano, too?
Right now,
you are so not under
the influence of Julia Child.
What if I don't
make my deadline, Eric?
I'll have wasted
a whole year of my life.
I used to be thin
and now I'm getting fat.
Fat?
- On top of which,
I have to bone a whole duck.
When?
- At some point.
Can you even conceive of boning a duck?
- No, I can't.
Of course you can't.
JULIE: I'm sure
you all remember, because
it was only a few days ago,
that I had a meltdown
over my aspic
and vowed to transform myself
into a better human being.
And then I was trussing
the poulet roti
a la normande,
which is roast chicken
stuffed with chicken livers
and cream cheese,
and it fell on the floor
and the stuffing fell out
into a big gooey mess.
(MUTTERING)
So, long story short,
another meltdown.
This is crazy.
Worse than the last.
(CRYING)
I can't even truss.
And I cried like a small,
emotionally disturbed child.
I'm a mess.
(PHONE RINGING)
I got it. I got it.
Hello?
Yeah, who's this?
Can you hold on
just one second?
I'm not sure if she's here.
She might've stepped out.
Hold on.
(SOBBING)
Hey, it's a reporter
from  The Christian
Science Monitor.
He wants to
write about you.
He does?
I should tell him
to call back, right?
No, no, I'll take it.
Hello?
Yes?
You want to bring
who to dinner?
No, of course,
I know who that is.
I know exactly who that is.
Who? Who, who, who, who?
That would be great,
that would be
completely amazing.
Goodbye.
Who?
- Guess who' coming to dinner?
Oh, my God.
To  Les Trois Gourmandes.
One for all and all for one.
Yes!
All right.
I had such a horrible time
converting these recipes
from the metric system.
Measurements do not matter.
Oh, but they do!
They absolutely do.
This is one of
the biggest arguments
Louisette and I had
when we worked
on our cookbook.
Which is finally finished.
Sent off to the publisher.
Soon Simca and I
will be famous.
We'll be the next
Mrs.  Joy of Cooking.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
Maybe. All right.
Well, let's try.
Let's just give it a...
Can I help?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Yeah. It is  mieux.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh!
So, yes. They're early.
Americans!
JULIA: Dear Dorothy,
your sister, Julia,
is now a cooking teacher.
We have three students
who pay $2 a class.
Barely enough to cover
the cost of the food,
but who cares?
Simca, Louisette, and I
are Les Trois Gourmandes.
Although
sometimes we are only
Les Deux Gourmandes
because Louisette turns out
to have headaches
and doctor's appointments
she schedules during class.
I have a little headache.
You'll meet them both
when you come here next month,
unless, of course, Louisette
is having a stomachache.
Perfection.
And even if it isn't,
never apologize.
No excuses!
No explanations.
JULIA: Louisette
abandoned us,
another stomachache.
And the day before that,
she left class
before we even finished
making the chocolate
Bavarian cream.
I can't believe
that's the only time
her dentist could see her.
Keep an eye out,
we don't want
to miss Dorothy.
It's impossible
to miss your sister.
I don't see her!
There she is.
Dorothy!
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
Hi, Julia!
I missed you!
So good to see...
Paul!
- Hi. Hi, sweetie.
I've had an adventure
on the ocean liner!
I didn't get sick once!
Good girl!
How about your legs?
People were dropping
like flies all around me!
Look.
Oh, my goodness.
Look at that.
All I think about
all day is food
and then I dream
about it all night.
It is true, she's obsessed.
If I didn't sit
in the kitchen,
I'd never see her.
Last week, I dreamed that
I made  cassoulet for Dad,
and he hated it, of course.
He doesn't
understand any of this.
I almost feel sorry for him.
He wanted so much
for us to stay in Pasadena,
marry Republicans,
and breed like rabbits.
Why didn't we?
Too tall.
Let's face it, it's true.
From the beginning,
you just don't fit in.
Literally.
So then you don't.
I know, it's true.
Do not bait Father
about politics when he comes.
No.
- Or he won't pick up the check.
He won't, will he?
- I can't make any promises.
He loves Senator McCarthy.
Oh, I know.
Pasadena.
- Pasadena.
Jinx.
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Dort, do you have...
You have the Brie.
Is this the Brie?
- Yes. Yes, that's the Brie.
Is that not
the most wonderful cheese
you ever had in your life?
Yes!
- Yes.
The answer's yes.
Mmm.
I got the chef
at Chez la Mere Michel
to give me the recipe
for  beurre blanc.
Beurre blanc.
What's  beurre blanc?
Butter in a white wine vinegar reduction.
- Oh, I love butter.
You whisk them together,
and the acid in the vinegar
works on the milk solids
in the butter
so that the butter,
instead of melting,
becomes this
creamy, light, frothy,
with kind of a fantastic
subtle kind of...
PAUL: Tangy.
It has a tanginess.
Tanginess?
Yes.
Well, that's...
That's who I married.
Anyway,
you serve it on fish
and it's splendid.
I'm going to make it for you.
That'll be divine.
- Yeah.
And, Dort, we're going
to throw you a party.