Robbed. Cleaned out.
$9,967, precisely as I told
you over the telephone.
And that girl did it,
Marion Holland.
That's the girl,
Marion Holland!
- Can you describe her, Mr. Strutt?
- Certainly I can describe her.
Five feet five, 110 pounds,
size eight dress,
blue eyes, black wavy hair,
even features, good teeth...
(CHUCKLING)
Well, what's so damn funny?
There's been a grand larceny
committed on these premises!
Yes, sir. You were saying,
black hair, wavy,
- even features, good teeth.
- Yeah. Yes.
- And she was in your employ four months?
- Mmm.
What were her references, sir?
Well, as a matter of fact...
Yes, she had references,
I'm sure.
Oh, Mr. Strutt,
don't you remember?
She didn't have any
references at all.
Well, she worked the copying
and adding machines.
No confidential duties.
Mr. Rutland. I didn't
know you were in town.
Just had a robbery.
Almost $10,000.
So I gathered. By a pretty
girl with no references.
You remember her.
I pointed her out
to you the last
time you were here.
You said something about how I was
improving the looks of the place.
Oh, that one.
The brunette with the legs.
Excuse me, men.
Mr. Rutland's a client.
I don't think you've got time to
discuss business today, Mr. Strutt.
- Not with your crime wave on your hands.
- Oh, no, no.
Always time for Rutland business.
You know that.
How are things
in Philadelphia?
The little witch! I'll have
her put away for 20 years!
I knew she was
too good to be true.
Always so eager to work
overtime, never made a mistake.
Always pulling her skirt down
over her knees
as though they were
a national treasure.
She seemed so nice,
so efficient, so...
Resourceful?
P.A. ANNOUNCER: Wilmington,
Baltimore, Washington.
Richmond,
Petersburg, Rocky Mount.
Wilson,
Fayetteville, Florence.
Charleston,
Savannah, Jacksonville,
Miami,
Tampa, Saint Petersburg.
Charleston, Pittsburgh, Camden
leaving on track number 12.
- Hello, Mrs. Maitland.
- Oh, so nice to have you back, Miss Edgar.
- We put you in your same room.
- Thank you, Mrs. Maitland.
Can someone drive me over
to Garrod's right away?
Of course.
Any time you're ready.
As soon as I change.
How do, Miss Edgar?
Good to have you back.
Hello, Mr. Garrod.
MARNIE: Oh,
there's my darling.
GARROD: That big old spoiled baby
of yours knew something was up.
Tried to bite me twice
already this morning.
Oh, Forio, if you want
to bite somebody, bite me.
Thanks.
GIRLS: (SINGING) Mother,
Mother, I am ill.
Send for the doctor
over the hill.
Call for the doctor.
Call for the nurse.
Call for the lady
with the alligator purse.
"Mumps," said the doctor.
"Measles," said the nurse.
"Nothing," said the lady
with the alligator purse.
- How many years will I live?
- Thank you.
GIRLS: One, two, three,
four, five, six,
- seven, eight, nine, 10, 11...
- Oh, it's you. Where's my mother?
She's making
a pecan pie for me!
That figures.
GIRLS: Mother,
Mother, I am ill.
Send for the doctor...
WOMAN: Who is it, Jessie?
MARNIE: Hello, Mama.
Well, I just swan. Marnie!
If you're not the very limit.
I can't take in the way
you jump around
all over the place
like you do.
MAMA: Boston, Massachusetts.
Elizabeth, New Jersey.
I brought you
some chrysanthemums.
MAMA: Those gladiolus
are brand fresh.
Miss Cotton brought them
to me only last night.
I never could stand gladiolus.
I'll get rid of these.
For land's sake... Marnie,
now watch the dripping.
Here, Jessica, why don't you
take these home to your mother?
She don't get home
from work till 6:00.
I'm supposed to
stay here till 6:00.
Well, take them out to the kitchen then.
Just get rid of them.
Take them on out to
the kitchen, Jessie, honey,
before they drip all over.
We could stand gladiolus!
I send you
plenty of money, Mama.
You don't have to
be a babysitter.
Well, whoever said I did
have to? It's my pleasure.
That smart little old Jessie.
Marnie, if you could just hear
some of the things that she says.
Oh, but I do.
Seems to me I get a report
in exhaustive detail
on all the bright sayings
of old Jessie Cotton.
What's more, every time I come
home, she's roosting here.
I see that you've lighted up
your hair, Marnie.
- A little. Why? Don't you like it?
- No.
MAMA: Too blonde hair always looks like
a woman's trying to attract the men.
Men and a good name
don't go together.
I brought you something, Mama.
Now what have you thrown
good money away on?
Oh, Marnie.
You shouldn't spend all your
money on me like you do.
But that's what
money's for, to spend.
Like the Bible says,
"Money answereth all things."
We don't talk smart about the
Bible in this house, missy!
Well, I just swan!
How do I wear it?
Like this.
Real high up under the chin.
MARNIE: Oh, it's smart.
It's very, very smart.
Going around buying fur pieces
like they's nothing.
Mr. Pemberton gave
me another raise.
I told Miss Cotton my daughter is
private secretary to a millionaire.
He's as generous with her as if
she was his very own daughter.
Miss Bernice, don't you want
to get my hair brushed up
before my mommy gets home?
Well, I sure do, honey.
You run up and get the brush.
Oh, that kid and her hair.
Puts me in mind of yours
when you was little.
The color.
This side of the street
don't get the afternoon sun.
My hip and my leg
ache me something awful.
(FOOTSTEPS)
I got the hairbrush!
Uh, Marnie, mind my leg.
MAMA: I never had time to
take care of Marnie's hair
when she was
a little kid like you.
- How come?
- Oh, child!
Well, after I had
my bad accident,
well, first I was sick so
long, and then I had to work.
JESSIE: Didn't you all
have a daddy either?
MAMA: No, we didn't.
We surely did not!
There. As pretty as
brushing can make you.
Oh, sugarpop, it's 6:05.
You better scat on home.
And you be sure to take
your mama those glads.
How about my pie?
How about my pecan pie?
I'll get it done tonight
and bring it over to you.
Now, Jessie, you mind
you go straight home.
Okay. Bye, Miss Bernice.
See you later, Miss Bernice.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Do you really like the scarf, Mama?
It's real mink.
Oh, there. You look just
like an old man's darling.
No man ever give
me anything so good.
We don't need men, Mama.
We can do very well for ourselves.
Just you and me.
A decent woman
don't have need for any man.
Look at you, Marnie. I told Miss
Cotton, look at my girl Marnie.
She's too smart to go getting
herself mixed up with men,
none of them.
Well, let's go on back to the kitchen.
I've got to see to that pie.
Uh, Marnie,
I've been thinking seriously
about asking Miss Cotton and
Jessie to move in here with me.
Miss Cotton is
a real nice woman.
She's decent. A hard-working woman
with a little girl to raise.
Come on, Mama, why don't you
just say what you mean?
What you want is for Jessie
to come live with you.
Marnie, you oughtn't let yourself act
jealous of a little old kid like that.
She don't bother me none. And we
could always use extra money.
The Cottons are
mighty decent people.
Why don't you love me, Mama?
I've always
wondered why you don't.
Oh, you never give me one part
of the love you give Jessie.
Mama.
Why do you always move away from me?
Why? What's wrong with me?
Nothing!
Nothing's wrong with you.
No. You don't think that.
You've always thought
there was something
wrong with me,
haven't you? Always!
I never.
My God! When I think of the things
I've done to try to make you love me.
The things I've done!
What are you thinking now, Mama?
About the things I've done?
What do you think they are? Things
that aren't decent, is that it?
Why, you think I'm
Mr. Pemberton's girl.
Is that why you don't
want me to touch you?
Is that how you think I get
the money to set you up?
I'm... I'm sorry, Mama.
I don't know what got
into me talking like that.
I know you've never really
thought anything bad about me.
No, I never.
Well, I'm sorry. I really am.
I'll pick up the pecans.
No, uh, you go upstairs and lay down.
You're all wore out.
I'll ask Jessie to come over
and pick up the nuts.
All right.
After all, it is Jessie's
pie, isn't it?
(TAPPING)
No, I don't want to. Mama, no!
Marnie, wake up. Marnie?
Don't make me move, Mama.
It's too cold.
Wake up, Marnie.
You're still dreaming.
- Get washed up. Supper's ready.
- Oh.
I was having that old dream again.
First the tapping and then...
I said, supper's ready.
It's always when
you come to the door.
That's when the cold starts.
- Miss Clabon.
- Good morning.
Is Mr. Ward in his office?
Yes, Mr. Rutland. He's interviewing
for the new office assistant.
Rutland & Company is an old
established publishing...
Oh, Mr. Rutland. This is
Miss Blakely, Mr. Rutland.
Well, you'll hear from us,
Miss Blakely, I'm sure.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you for your time, Mr. Ward.
- Good day, Mr. Rutland.
- Good day, Miss Blakely.
Well, I guess that does it. She seems
to have the exact qualifications...
Come in. Come in for
a moment, please.
- WARD: Now, sit down, Mrs. Taylor.
- Thank you.
WARD: I have here your
Pittsburgh references.
Reference, that is.
Kendall's, yes.
This the only reference
you have to show us?
MARNIE: Well, Mr. Ward,
I have good training,
but I've had very
little actual experience.
Kendall's was my
first real job.
After I finished school,
I was married.
My husband was a CPA and he helped
me keep up with my training.
I learnt a great
deal more from him,
accounting, cost-price, even
something about computers.
WARD: I see.
When my husband died
very suddenly last November,
well, he left me a little money,
but I felt I needed work.
Good, hard, demanding work.
I got the job at Kendall's,
but it was...
Well, it wasn't
a very exacting position,
and there didn't
seem much immediate
chance for anything
else at Kendall's.
Oh, I don't mean pay.
Salary isn't the most
important thing with me,
but more interesting work,
Mr. Ward.
Something that will
keep me busy, occupied.
Well, I don't care how much work
I'm given or what hours I work.
WARD: Uh, but, Mrs. Taylor,
why did you leave Pittsburgh?
Well, after my
husband died, I just...
Now, Mrs. Taylor, this is a
post of some confidence.
Oh, please, let me have a chance
to prove myself, Mr. Ward.
Uh, very well, Mrs. Taylor.
I suppose you might as well
report to work on Monday.
Our Miss Clabon in the outer
office will brief you.
I'll be out in just a moment.
Now, why are we taking on someone
without the proper references?
You're always
such a stickler...
Let's just say I'm an interested
spectator in the passing parade.
I don't get it.
You're not supposed
to get it.
- Hi, Miss Clabon.
- Fine, fortunately...
Hello, Mr. Sam.
How's the curmudgeon business?
WARD: Oh, Miss Mainwaring!
Is Mark in there?
I'm looking for a free lunch
and somebody to
cash a check for me.
I thought I'd stick Mark for the
lunch and you for the cash.
Go right on in.
WARD: You have your social
security card, Mrs. Taylor?
MARNIE: Yes, of course.
It's right here in my purse.
Who's the dish?
Miss Clabon will
show you around.
She's been with
us for seven years.
I believe she's found
the work exacting enough.
Good day, Mrs. Taylor. Miss
Clabon, will you call Personnel
and have them
send the forms up?
Certainly, Mr. Ward.
MISS CLABON: Hello.
This is Mr. Ward's office.
Would you please send up a W-4 and
the rest of the employment forms?
Yes, before lunch.
I'll wait. Thank you.
Maud, what about Saturday?
No, I only thought as you said
your mother wasn't coming with us,
I just wanted to make sure
about our reservations.
Well, why don't you
call me back?
All right. Any time.
Thanks, Mr. Sam. I'll try not to
do anything sensible with it.
- Bye, Miss Clabon.
- Bye.
That's Lil Mainwaring,
Mr. Rutland's sister-in-law.
- Her sister was Mr. Rutland's wife.
- Was?
Yes. She died about a year and a half ago.
Some kind of heart thing.
Imagine. Only 29.
Well, anyway,
she kind of brought Lil up.
Lil lived with them and old
Mr. Rutland down at Wykwyn.
I get the feeling little old Lil
plans to stay on permanently.
Anyway, like I was saying, old
Mr. Rutland, that's Mark's father,
they say he's never even been
inside this place.
And the company
was really headed
into the ground
when Mark took over.
They say the first week
he was here he retired...
(CHUCKLES)
Retired. Three board members,
the acting president,
the president's secretary,
and the secretary's secretary.
Coffee time, ladies.
Would you mind
bringing me a cup?
Just coffee? Doughnut,
Danish?
- Oh, lady, have I got for you a Danish!
- No, just coffee.
Oh, I'm out of red ink.
Oh, here, use mine.
- Oh, I'll get it.
- No, no, I will.
Thanks.
Mrs. Taylor, are you hurt?
Mrs. Taylor!
I think she's hurt. Find out.
Mary, are you all right?
What?
Of course, I'm all right. I just
spilled a little ink on my blouse.
The way you rushed
out of the office...
Mr. Rutland's
standing out there.
- He said he thought you were hurt.
- Well, I'm not.
All that happened was I spilled
a little ink on my blouse.
Good heavens. What a lot of
excitement over nothing.
(PHONE RINGING)
Why in the world does he keep
locking and unlocking that drawer?
He never can remember
the safe combination.
It's kept locked
up in that drawer.
Mr. Rutland and I have the keys
to it, too, for emergencies.
It's only five numbers,
for Pete's sake.
Mrs. Taylor? I've just had a call
from Mr. Rutland, Mrs. Taylor.
He remembered your saying you'd
be willing to work overtime.
He wondered if you'd be
prepared to work on Saturday?
- Saturday? Of course, Mr. Ward. What time?
- 2:30.
I'll advise Mr. Rutland
that you are available.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
MARK: Come in, Mrs. Taylor.
Good afternoon, Mr. Rutland.
Are you interested in
pre-Columbian art, Mrs. Taylor?
Those were collected
by my wife. She's dead.
The only things
of hers I've kept.
And that's Sophie.
She's a jaguarondi. South American.
I, uh, trained her.
Oh? What did you train
her to do?
To trust me.
Is that all?
Well, that's a great
deal for a jaguarondi.
Shall we get to work? You can
use the typewriter over there.
I want an original
and one copy of this.
If you can't decipher
any of it, speak up.
I typed it myself and I'm
a very creative typist.
"Arboreal Predators
of the Brazilian Rain Forest."
Before I was drafted
into Rutland's, Mrs. Taylor,
I had notions of
being a zoologist.
- I still try to keep up with my field.
- Zoos?
Instinctual behavior.
Oh.
Does zoology include people,
Mr. Rutland?
Well, in a way. It includes
all the animal ancestors
from whom man
derived his instincts.
Ladies' instincts, too?
Well, that paper deals with
the instincts of predators.
What you might call the criminal
class of the animal world.
Lady animals figure
very largely as predators.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
Put on the overhead light if you like.
The switch is by the door.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
Why don't you sit down,
Mrs. Taylor?
If the storm worries you that much,
I'll get you something to drink.
Mrs. Taylor?
The building is grounded,
Mrs. Taylor.
You're quite safe here,
from the lightning.
- The colors. Stop the colors.
- What colors?
It's over. All over.
You're all right.
Okay, now?
Would you like something to drink?
Some brandy?
No, thank you.
I'm awfully sorry. I...
Oh, don't be silly. What is it
about colors that bothers you?
- Colors? - Mmm. You seem
to be terrified of some colors.
No, no. What I'm terrified of
is thunder and lightning.
You know, I wouldn't have pegged you for
a woman who'd be terrified of anything.
Well, we've all
got to go some time.
Look, this place is wrecked and
you're in no state to work.
Suppose I drive you home. You can
do this job some other time.
- Oh, thank you. I...
- Go get your things.
It's cold and damp here. I must
get the maintenance people in.
I'm really sorry
about the cabinet.
Why should you be?
You said it was all you
had left of your wife.
I said it was all I had left
that had belonged to my wife.
Oh.
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO: Native Winkler
is second. Hopeless is third.
Oh, no, please.
I'd like to hear.
- You like racing? - I like horses.
I go to the races when I can.
- Was your husband a track fan?
- Yes.
- And you go alone now?
Atlantic City track's open
till the end of the month.
We could drive out
there next Saturday.
- All right. Are you fond of horses?
- No, not at all.
P.A. ANNOUNCER: Fast Return
moving up on the outside.
(ANNOUNCER CONTINUES)
Well, that's another one.
Oh, I like it here like this.
Well, you're the expert. What
do you like in the next race?
Lemon Pudding. He's finished
third his last three times out.
- He's got a good jockey up today.
- Lemon Pudding it is.
The morning line
says he's four to one.
I'll get on him.
Pardon me, but you're
Peggy Nicholson, aren't you?
Remember me?
I'm sorry.
What did you say?
I said,
aren't you Peggy Nicholson?
No, I'm not.
Yeah? I was pretty sure you were. You
know, when I first saw you down here...
No, I'm sorry, you've made a mistake.
I am not Miss Nichols.
- Nicholson.
Frank Abernathy introduced us
a couple years ago in Detroit.
Frank Abernathy.
You remember Frank.
No, I do not know anyone
named Frank Abernathy.
I have never known anyone
- Now, will you please go?
- Oh, come on now, honey,
you're trying to
pull my leg, aren't you?
Now, why should any young lady
want to pull your leg?
Oh, sorry. I thought
I recognized this lady.
- Did he recognize you?
- No.
You did not recognize her.
I said, I thought I recognized her.
I said I'm sorry.
Well, good for you. You've apologized
nicely. You may go now.
- You came back so quickly.
- Yes. Who's your fan?
You know, I just seem to
have one of those faces.
Well, what do you
like in the next race?
Can we go to the paddock?
I'd like to see Telepathy.
Been watching him ever since I saw
him work out once as a two-year-old.
Oh, I believe that's our
old friend Telepathy.
Yeah, number 8. Telepathy.
He's a lanky-looking piece of business
but I bow to your superior knowledge.
What is it?
What's the matter?
- Don't bet him.
- Why not?
He's walleyed.
Can we go now?
What a paragon you are. You
don't smoke, drink or gamble.
- Just this once, for luck.
- I don't believe in luck.
- What do you believe in?
- Nothing.
Oh, horses, maybe.
At least they're beautiful and
nothing in this world like people.
- Oh, yes, people. Thoroughly bad lot.
- Generally.
Did you have a tough
childhood, Mrs. Taylor?
Not particularly.
I think you did. I think you've
had a hard, tough climb.
But you're a smart girl,
aren't you?
The careful grammar,
the quiet good manners.
- Where did you learn them?
- From my betters.
What about your tough
childhood, Mr. Rutland?
The old, sad story.
Promising youth blighted.
Dragged down by money,
position, noblesse oblige.
By the time I came along, the
company was hanging on the ropes.
We had about a thousand employees who
were about to go down for the count.
What about the Rutlands? What
would've happened to your family?
Nothing ever happens to a family
that traditionally marries
at least one heiress
every other generation.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Well, you shouldn't
have chickened.
Your walleyed reject
just won by four lengths.
- I think I've had enough. Can we go?
- Well, if you like.
See here. The track's open
till the end of the month.
That gives us
two more Saturdays.
If your luck holds out, by this time
next month, I'll be a rich man.
- Oh, Miss Nicholson. - You really
are pressing your luck, old boy.
Where are we going this time?
I thought it was time I brought
you home to meet my old man.
- Oh, you should've told me.
- You're all right.
Dad goes by scent. If you smell
anything like a horse, you're in.
Here we are, old bean.
The homestead.
- Hello, Dad.
- Who's this?
This is Mary Taylor.
Mary, this is my father.
- How do you do, Mr. Rutland?
- A girl, is it?
Oh, it's all right, Dad. She's not
really a girl, she's a horse-fancier.
Now that the track's closed, I
thought if I brought her round
to see your horses, I'd hold
her attention a bit longer.
Splendid, splendid!
Come along, my dear. I was just
about to have a cup of tea.
Oh, Mary, this is my
sister-in-law, Lil Mainwaring.
- Mary Taylor.
- How do you do?
Hi. I've seen you at
Rutland's, haven't I?
RUTLAND: It bewilders me what any
of you can find to do at Rutland's.
Oh, dear! I think I rather
sprained my wrist this afternoon.
There's sure to be
droppage and spillage.
Would you mind awfully?
RUTLAND: Strong, please.
No milk, two lumps of sugar.
The meals in this
house are shocking bad,
but I do insist on good
Horn & Hardart cake at tea.
You take yours with lemon,
don't you, Lil?
Yes. Lemon for Lil, Mary.
- Strong with a dash of rum for me.
- RUTLAND: Spinster's tea.
Mucking up tea with strong drink.
Something sneaky about it, eh?
What's your opinion,
Miss Taylor?
Do you think old Mark
here is a sneaky one?
Possibly.
How do you take
your tea, Miss Taylor?
Usually with a cup
of hot water and a tea bag.
RUTLAND: Lazy habit, my dear.
I'll have quite a large slice
of that butter cake, please.
- Do you ride, Miss Taylor?
- A little.
RUTLAND: Best thing in the world
for the inside of a man or a woman
is the outside of a horse.
I shouldn't think you'd find
old Mark very interesting.
Doesn't hunt.
Doesn't even ride.
Please, Dad. I was hoping to
lead up gently to all that.
I'd even planned
to show her the horses first.
Swill that down or bring it
with you to the stables.
Mark's trying to behave as if he brought
Miss Taylor out to see the horses.
- He really brought her to see me.
- Really? Whatever for?
RUTLAND: Showing off. I'm quite a
presentable old party, you know.
Lil, I'm sure your sturdy young
wrist has recovered sufficiently
to pour Dad
another cup of tea.
- Yes, I will have another cup.
- I can't!
"When Duty whispers low,
Thou must.
"Then youth replies, I can."
Ratfink! And you misquoted!
Will you come out and spend
next weekend with us?
You can bring your tea bag,
have your pick of the horses.
Good night, Mary. I have to run.
See you on Monday.
Good night, Susan.
WOMAN: Good night!
See you Monday.
SECOND WOMAN:
Good night. See you on Monday.
I haven't got my powder puff.
Have you got one?
Yeah, here.
- WOMAN: Come on.
- SECOND WOMAN: Wait a minute.
- Come on.
- All right, I'm coming.
You mean you just have to hang
around and wait until he calls?
- Good night, girls.
- Good night. I'll see you.
- I think that's...
- Have a good weekend.
Yeah, I think that's...
- What are you gonna do?
- Well, I don't know. Let's get home.
- Because he may have already called you.
- Oh, well.
If I miss his call,
that's the way it goes.
Oh, this is
the best one you've had!
(DOOR CLOSING)
WOMAN: See you next week.
You're sure making time tonight, Rita.
What's the big rush?
I want to get to bed.
That's the big rush.
Please get down.
You'll walk back to
the stables. I'll ride.
Are you staying at an inn or have
you friends among the local gentry?
- You said you didn't trust horses.
- I don't, but they trust me.
Which brings us directly to
our relationship, Miss Edgar!
Is Edgar your real name?
And you're blonde.
You'll save
a good deal of time
and make for a better feeling all
round if you just tell me the truth.
Is Edgar your real name?
Now, don't crowd me, lady!
I'm fighting a powerful impulse
to beat the hell out of you.
At last we communicate.
Now, for the third and last
time, is Edgar your real name?
And don't bother to lie to me. I'll
check you out in every detail.
Yes, Edgar. Margaret Edgar!
Now, where are you from?
- California.
- Where in California?
Los Angeles.
Where's the money?
Here! Some of it.
- Where's the rest?
- Oh, don't worry. It's safe.
Safe? At some
pari-mutuel window?
Or has it gone for an operation
for your old sick mother?
Or perhaps you're putting your
kid brother through school?
I don't have a kid brother or a mother.
I don't have anybody.
Not even Mr. Taylor?
You know, I wouldn't be a bit surprised
to hear that the rest of the haul
is with your late husband,
Mr. Taylor.
Somewhere around these parts, I expect
to find him happily reincarnated,
and the pockets of his good blue burial
suit bulging with Rutland money.
The rest of the money is in a
registered package addressed to me
in a post office
box in New York.
You can pick it up there by tomorrow.
Here's the key.
Thank you, Miss Edgar. Now I'll
take the registration receipt.
This receipt and the unopened package
are as good as a signed confession.
You understand that?
All right. Now, where
does Mr. Taylor come in?
There's no such person.
I've never been married.
Mrs. Taylor was an old
friend of my mother's.
And when you
applied at Rutland's,
the name just
came to your mind.
I was trying to get away from someone.
I have a cousin Jessie. She's no good.
I was afraid if she found out
about the insurance money,
she'd try to get a part of it.
Make trouble for me.
What insurance money?
- Mrs. Taylor's. She died.
- Oh, Mrs. Taylor died. Pity.
Now you're working with
this naughty cousin Jessie.
Nobody's working with me!
You talk as if this was some
kind of regular thing I do, did.
All planned out
in cold blood.
- And it wasn't?
- No!
You're not from Los Angeles,
Miss Edgar.
Insurance is only pronounced
"insurance" in the South,
and that's where you're from.
Where? Around here?
You're a cold, practiced little
method actress of a liar.
- I can't help it.
- It would appear not.
I don't mean that.
I mean, I wasn't born in California.
I was born in Richmond, Virginia.
My father deserted
us when I was a baby.
My mother and I lived in
Richmond until I was seven.
And then we
moved to California,
where Mother could get work
in the airplane factories.
That's the truth. I swear it!
My mother died when I was 10, and
Mrs. Taylor took care of me out there.
Come on, get moving.
How did you find me?
You're here to answer
the questions, old girl.
Now how did you get the
combination to Ward's safe?
I took Susan's
key from her purse.
I see.
Now, suppose you just
begin at the beginning.
It's just like I told you. I was
born in Richmond. We were poor.
We were grindingly poor.
I was so horribly
alone after Mother died.
Well, go on.
You still have my attention.
I just went to school and took care
of Mrs. Taylor until she died.
She left me her house
and $5,000 in insurance.
I sold the house. It had a mortgage
so I only got $9,000 cash.
But there I was with $14,000. Me! I could
do exactly what I wanted to with it.
- There isn't much more. I bought Forio.
- Forio?
My horse at Garrod's.
I had two wonderful years.
Then last November it was all
gone so I had to get a job.
I went to Pittsburgh
and got the job at Kendall's
until I could look around
for something better.
All right, let's try again.
Let's back up and see if you can turn that
Mount Everest of manure into a few facts.
One, your dates
are all wrong.
Previously you were employed by
the firm of Strutt & Company.
I saw you there once.
Mr. Strutt is the tax consultant
for Rutland & Company.
He pointed you out to me
and you were a brunette then.
And then some months later
he pointed out your absence.
You mean, you knew all about
that when you hired me?
No. I wasn't positive.
But I thought it might be
interesting to keep you around.
And all this time you've been
trying to trip me up, trap me!
Um, I'm not sure anymore. I think
I was just curious at first.
And then things got out of
control and I liked you.
So I see!
Incidentally, I think
you took a bit of a chance,
knowing that Rutland's
was a client of Strutt's.
I didn't. My job at Strutt's
didn't give me access
to all the clients' names!
All right. Let's get on.
We've established that
you're a thief and a liar.
Now, what is the degree?
Are you a compulsive thief?
A pathological liar?
- Oh, what difference does it make?
- Some.
It makes some
difference to me.
Have you ever been in jail?
Certainly not.
I know you'll never believe
me now and it's my own fault.
It's true about Strutt.
I did it. I don't know why.
I just kind of went crazy, I guess,
but old Mr. Strutt was so...
Oh, I hated him!
Like you hate me?
Oh, no, not you.
Clean up your face.
Come on.
Good afternoon.
- What'll you folks have?
- A frank and a coffee, please.
- Same for me.
- Okey-doke.
Let's get on with
that little discussion.
The chronic use of an alias is
not consistent with your story
of sudden temptation
and unpremeditated impulse.
If you'd stolen almost $10,000,
wouldn't you change your name?
Oh, what's the use? Why should I
even try to make you understand?
I'm not only trying to understand
you, I'm even trying to believe you.
- Why?
- Because, damn it, I want to.
Can you understand that?
Here you are, folks.
Mark?
The reasons for what
I did at Rutland's,
they were so mixed up,
what I wanted to say before.
I needed to get away, can't you see?
Away from Rutland's.
Don't you understand?
Things were... We were...
So we were. Was that any
reason to run away?
Yes, I thought it was time
I got out before I got hurt.
I mean, why try
to kid myself?
- Are you called Margaret?
- Marnie.
Oh, God, Mark, if you let me go, I swear...
I can't let you go, Marnie.
Somebody's got to take care of you and
help you. I can't just turn you loose.
If I let you go, I'm criminally
and morally responsible.
Well, then, what...
Marnie. Yeah, that suits you.
All right, Marnie,
this is how it's gonna be.
I'm driving you
back to Philadelphia.
Tonight we'll go to the house.
Tomorrow you'll return to Rutland's.
You'll see that Susan's key finds
its way back into her purse.
How can I go
back to Rutland's?
You're covered.
I replaced the money.
When I called to pick you up yesterday
and found you'd pulled out,
I knew instantly
what had happened.
So I went to Rutland's
and checked Ward's safe.
Figured the loss
and replaced it.
Then I set out to find you.
Remember that
first day at the races
when you were so hot about
a horse called Telepathy?
I remember, you'd said you'd watched
him training as a two-year-old.
That's all I had to go on,
so I looked him up,
and found he'd been bred by a
Colonel Marston of Virginia.
I phoned Marston and asked him
if there was anywhere around there
that they had horses for hire.
He gave me the names of three.
Yesterday I drove up to the plains,
checked out the stables. No luck.
But at the last place, the man
said why didn't I try Garrod's,
over by Middleburg?
You folks be sure
and come back now.
Why are you taking
me back to Wykwyn?
Because I don't trust
you not to run away.
How can I run away?
You have the receipt,
the post office key, my name.
Margaret Edgar. You sure
that's all the name you have?
You sure you haven't misplaced
an old husband or two
- somewhere in your travels?
- I told you I've never been married.
- Near misses?
- No.
And no lovers, no steadies, no beaus,
no gentlemen callers, nothing!
Okay. Eat up.
- Mark, I'd like to go freshen up a little.
- Uh-uh.
You're fresh enough. Come on.
You know, I can't
believe you, Marnie.
There must've been a great
many men interested in you.
I didn't say men
weren't interested in me.
I said I wasn't
interested in them.
- Never?
- No.
That is, not until...
Why me?
Because you were
different, Mark.
It won't wash, Marnie.
But it's true.
I really liked you.
Yes, I think you did.
But don't try to make it sound
like any more than that.
When we get home, I'll explain
that we had a lover's quarrel.
That you ran away, that I went
after you and brought you back.
That'll please Dad.
He admires action.
Then I'll explain that we're gonna
be married before the week is out,
therefore you
should stay on at Wykwyn.
That I can't bear
to have you out of my sight.
He also admires
wholesome animal lust.
We'll be married just as
soon as the law allows.
We'll catch an outbound boat.
Where do you want to go? You
ever been to the South Seas?
What are you trying to pull?
I'm trying to pull a proposal.
Let's see, how shall I phrase it?
How about "will you be mine"?
You're crazy!
You're out of your mind!
That's a possibility.
The name Marnie. Yes, I'll
just go on calling you Marnie.
That's easily explained.
Pet name.
But the Taylor...
We'll just have to marry you off as
Mary Taylor. It's perfectly legal.
You can sign yourself Minnie Q
Mouse on a marriage license,
you're still legally married.
But you know what I am.
I'm Minnie Q Thief!
I'm a thief and a liar and...
Well, it seems to be my misfortune to have
fallen in love with a thief and a liar.
In love?
Oh, Mark, if you love me,
you'll let me go.
Just let me go, Mark, please.
Mark, you don't know me.
Oh, listen to me, Mark. I am not
like other people. I know what I am!
I doubt that you do, Marnie.
In any event, we'll just have to deal
with whatever it is that you are.
Whatever you are, I love you.
It's horrible, I know.
But I do love you.
You don't love me. I'm just
something you've caught.
You think I'm some kind
of animal you've trapped.
That's right, you are.
And I've caught something really
wild this time, haven't I?
I've tracked you and caught you,
and by God, I'm gonna keep you!
Oh, and, Marnie,
when we get home,
no cute ideas about absconding
with the Wykwyn silver.
Just get a grip on yourself
for one short week
and after that, well, you
can take legal possession.
Like you? Like you
take legal possession?
Yes, if you want
to put it that way.
Somebody's got to take on the
responsibility for you, Marnie.
And it narrows down to a choice
of me or the police, old girl.
RUTLAND: Indispensable.
(CHUCKLING)
Ah, Cousin Bob, I almost forgot.
Do you have the old necessary?
- Have fun, my dear.
- Traveler's checks in this.
- Letter of credit in this.
- Thanks, old man.
Will you see about having my
car picked up at the airport?
Bob is our banking cousin.
A very handy fellow.
Take care, Lil.
We'll send you a noble savage.
- Goodbye, Dad.
- Bye, Mark.
Thank you, Dr. Gillian. Without
you it wouldn't have been legal.
It's been a pleasure.
RUTLAND: Let's go back
and finish the champagne
and cake before they spirit it away.
Really splendid cake, you know?
I attended to that myself.
I've made the acquaintance of one of those
excellent Horn & Hardart executives.
That engagement ring must have
been at least five carats.
Six and a half. Blue-white.
Perfect stone.
His mother left
perfectly good jewelry.
It's just sitting there at
the bank in safety deposit.
He said he wanted her to have something
that had never belonged to anyone else.
But six and a half carats!
And cashing in a bond
to pay for a ring.
But he didn't pay for it. He charged it.
I helped him pick it out.
It cost $42,000, plus tax.
Did you say $42,000?
The man's deranged.
BOB: You know what he did
to me last Saturday?
He came out to the club
waving a check for $7,000
and insisted that I break up my
golf game, go in and open the bank
and hand over to him $7,000.
Then he drew out...
Well, let's just say enough to pay for
this trip plus the letter of credit.
He cashed that very nice bond
against my advice,
made me get him the money.
$10,000 in small bills.
And when I asked him why he wanted
$10,000 in small bills, he said,
"Well, old man, I'm being blackmailed
and they specified small bills."
I know that most people find
Mark's humor charming.
I do not. There is nothing
charming about running through,
including the unpaid
bill for a ring,
approximately
$70,000 in one week.
A $6,000 or $7,000 South Seas
honeymoon, conservatively speaking,
and a $42,000 ring.
All that money
spent to celebrate what?
This meager,
furtive little wedding?
He didn't even ask Mother.
"Pay off Strutt."
Strutt.
Booze?
Shall I fix you a drink?
Would you like some bourbon
to brush your teeth?
MARNIE: No, thank you.
Contrary to the movies
and the Ladies' Home Journal,
the battleground of marriage is
not, I repeat, not the bedroom.
The real field of
battle is the bath.
It is in the bath
and for the bath
that the lines are drawn
and no quarter given.
It seems to me, we are getting off to
a dangerously poor start, darling.
You've been in the bathroom
exactly 47 minutes.
- You can have the bath now.
- Thank you.
You're very sexy
with your face clean.
Marnie, come here.
Sit down.
I can't! I can't! I can't!
For God's sakes, Marnie!
I can't stand it. I'll die. If
you touch me again, I'll die!
I won't touch you.
I promise I won't touch you.
Just get out of that
damn corner, please.
Now, suppose you tell me
what this is all about.
Is it your own little way of saying you
don't find me particularly attractive?
I told you not to marry me.
I told you!
Oh, God, why couldn't you
have just let me go?
- Marnie.
- Don't. Please, don't!
- Let me fix you a drink.
- I don't want a drink.
- At least have a brandy.
- I don't want it. Just leave me alone.
Not till I find out what's the matter
with you and find some way to help you.
The only way you can help me
is to leave me alone!
Can't you understand?
Isn't it plain enough?
I cannot bear to be handled!
- By anybody? Or just me?
- You. Men.
Really?
You didn't seem to mind at my
office that day, or at the stables.
And all this last week I've handled
you, kissed you many times.
Why didn't you break out in a cold
sweat and back into a corner then?
I thought I could
stand it if I had to.
I see.
- Well, have you always felt like this?
- Always, yes.
Why? What happened to you?
Happened? Nothing.
Nothing happened to me.
I just never wanted
anybody to touch me.
You ever tried
to talk about it,
to a doctor or somebody
who could help you?
No, why should I?
I didn't want to get married.
It's degrading. It's animal. Anyway,
I was doing all right the way I was.
I wouldn't say that, Marnie.
If I hadn't caught you,
you'd have gone on stealing.
- No. No I wouldn't.
- Yes, you would, again and again.
Eventually, you would've
got caught by somebody.
Since you're such
a tempting little thing.
Some other sexual blackmailer
would've got his hands on you.
The chances of it being someone as
permissive as me are pretty remote.
Sooner or later
you'd have gone to jail.
Or been cornered in an office by
some angry old bull of a businessman
who was out to take what he
figured was coming to him.
You'd probably
have got him and jail.
So I wouldn't say you were
doing all right, Marnie.
I'd say you needed
all the help you could get.
Well, I don't need your help.
I don't think you're capable of judging
what you need or from whom you need it.
What you do need, I expect,
is a psychiatrist.
Oh, men! You say "no thanks"
to one of them,
and bingo, you're a candidate
for the funny farm.
It would be hilarious
if it weren't pathetic.
Let's try to get some rest, hmm?
We'll talk this out tomorrow.
There's nothing to talk out.
I've told you how I feel.
I'll feel the same way tomorrow, and
the day after, and the day after that.
All right, Marnie. We won't talk
about it until you want to.
But we're gonna be on this damn
boat for many days and nights.
So, let's just drop the
whole thing for the present
and try to get through
this bloody honeymoon cruise
with as much grace
as possible.
Let's try at least to
be kind to each other.
Oh. Kind!
All right, if that's
too much,
I'll be kind to you,
and you'll be polite to me.
You won't...
I won't.
I give you my word.
Now, let's try to get
some rest. How about it?
You in your little bed over there, and
me light years away in mine here.
Thank you.
I think I'd like to stay out
here for a while, but thank you.
You're gonna bring a little pizzazz
down to the old farm, my dear.
I noticed before we left, Dad was
pulling out his silk shirts.
What do you mean,
what will I do with myself?
I had of course assumed I would
become a society hostess.
In Africa, in Kenya, there's
quite a beautiful flower.
It's coral colored with
little green-tipped blossoms,
rather like a hyacinth.
If you reach out to touch it,
you'd discover that the flower
was not a flower at all,
but a design made up of hundreds of
tiny insects called fattid bugs.
They escape the eyes of hungry birds by
living and dying in the shape of a flower.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I'll close the door, if you don't mind.
The light bothers me.
Hmm, what's that, dear?
The light? Oh, yes, of course.
You've been an absolute darling about my
sitting up reading so late these nights.
I'm boning up on marine life
since entomology doesn't
seem to be your subject,
and I'm eager to find a
subject, Marnie, any subject.
All right.
Here's a subject. How long?
How long do we have to stay
on this boat, this trip?
How long before
we can go back?
Why, Mrs. Rutland.
Can you be suggesting that these
halcyon honeymoon days and nights,
just the two of us alone
together, should ever end?
If you don't mind,
I'd like to go to bed.
I've told you the light from
the sitting room bothers me.
Well, we certainly can't have
anything bothering you, can we?
If you don't want to go
to bed, please get out.
But I do want to go to bed, Marnie.
I very much want to go to bed.
(SCREAMING) No!
(GASPS)
I'm sorry, Marnie.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(MARNIE COUGHS)
Why the hell didn't
you jump over the side?
The idea was to kill myself,
not feed the damn fish.
Mark!
Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
Was Fiji grisly?
Well, we didn't get to Fiji. We jumped
ship in Honolulu and flew back.
And we had to take a cab from the airport.
We're both a bit tired and grimy.
Remember when you were six,
you wanted to go to New York?
I warned you then that traveling
was a nasty business.
You poor things.
You must be exhausted.
Yeah, I think what we'll do is go
straight up, have a fast drink,
and pop up to bed.
The travel lecture will have
to wait for morning, okay?
- Where's the rest of your luggage?
- At the airport.
Goodnight, Dad. I'll have breakfast
with you in the morning.
- We'll see you then, Lil.
- Goodnight, Mark.
Come on, Marnie.
It's not exactly a house
of correction, you know.
Look, Marnie, for the present,
all we've got is the facade,
and we've got to live it.
Dad has breakfast downstairs
at 8:30 every morning
and I always join him.
So, naturally,
as you want to be with me...
This is the drill, dear. Wife
follows husband to front door.
Gives and/or gets a kiss.
Stands pensively as he drives away. Oh,
a wistful little wave is optional.
Mark, are you going
to the office?
On the first day back after our honeymoon?
How indelicate.
No, I'm going down the road on
a little errand. I'll see you later.
Mark, I, um...
I don't have any money.
Oh, I'm sorry, Marnie.
I'll call Bob and have him
make out an account for you.
It won't be much for a while.
You understand, I've had
a lot of heavy expenses.
And you might as well know
I've paid off Strutt.
Anonymously, of course.
- MARNIE: But that's all over!
- So?
MARNIE: So, you've given away
$10,000, so you're a prize fool!
MARK: Possibly, but they don't put
you in jail for being a fool.
I'm not the one the cops are after.
Not yet. And I don't intend to be.
Not if there's anything
I could do to prevent it.
Perhaps you, madam,
but not me.
(PHONE DIALING)
Hello, Mama? No, I'm all right.
I'm perfectly all right now.
I had a bad case of the flu and
just didn't feel up to writing.
Oh, I couldn't.
I had laryngitis, too.
Oh, yes, I am still
a little hoarse.
Look, Mama, I can't talk long. I just
called to tell you that I'm all right
and that I'll send you
some money this week.
No, I can't. I don't know
when I'll get to Baltimore.
But not for a few weeks anyway.
But I'll talk to you soon.
If you need anything, just write to me at
the same post office box in Philadelphia.
I've got to go now, Mama.
Goodbye. Goodbye, Mama.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Oh, Forio! Oh, beauty!
Well, she said she
could ride a little.
- Mark?
- Hmm?
Mark, listen. I'm a good
fighter if you need me.
I mean, if you are in
some kind of trouble.
I have absolutely no scruples. I'd
lie to the police or anything.
What on Earth are
you talking about?
I heard you and Marnie
this morning right out here.
- Heard?
- Okay, I eavesdropped.
We should've made you go to
college or come out or something.
- I can see that now.
- Don't patronize me, Mark.
That Mary-Marnie brown-haired blonde
you married so fast and sneaky
and tried to hustle off to the
South Pacific, for Pete's sake.
I didn't have to overhear stuff about
your not intending to go to jail, too,
to know that you're
in some sort of fix.
- Please, Mark, will you let me help?
- All right, you can help.
You can help by being nice to Marnie.
She needs a friend.
I always thought that a girl's
best friend was her mother.
Poor old Mark.
Is her mother that ghastly?
I mean, when the in-laws are so grim, you
don't dare have them to the wedding.
The usual excuse is poor health or
the strain of the trip, you know?
But to claim they're dead,
now, come on!
All right, Lil, what is it
you're up to? Out with it.
Me? I'm just offering
you my services.
Guerrilla fighter, perjurer,
intelligence agent.
All right, intelligence agent.
Baltimore. There's a mother in Baltimore.
Marnie made a phone call this morning.
She said she hadn't been able to
write because she'd had the flu.
She didn't know when she'd
be able to get to Baltimore
but that she'd send
money this week.
She said to go on writing to her
at the same post office box.
I listened through
the library door.
She's having you on, Lil.
It's some sort of gag.
You've been ratty. She's set
out to teach you some manners.
- You're being had, Lil.
- You can say that again!
But I don't want to say it again. I
don't want to have to say it again.
All right, Mark.
You seem to be
growing up, Lil.
I expect what we should do
is find you some young man.
- What's your type?
- I was waiting for you.
I'm queer for liars.
Really? Well, what sort of liar do
you fancy? We could run an ad.
Would you prefer an indoor
liar or an outdoor liar?
Playboy or Field & Stream?
Anybody home?
Hi! Where's Marnie?
She and Dad are still out riding. He's
taking her over the hunt country.
Big deal. She's going
to ride with the hunt.
And Dad's throwing some kind
of bash to introduce her.
Oh. I was expecting a long-distance call.
Has it come in?
No. Not that I know of.
(PHONE RINGING)
I'll get it.
MARK: Hello? Yes. Now hold on, I
want to take it on another phone.
I'll take it upstairs.
Hang up as soon as I get it.
Uh, Lil, you will hang up,
won't you?
Okay, Lil.
Hello? Yes,
I'll talk to him now.
Hello, Mr. Boyle. You've found
anything interesting down there?
Hold on. Let me get a pencil.
Okay, ready.
Bernice Edgar.
116 Van Buren Street,
Baltimore.
Yeah, I got that. Go on.
Wait a minute.
You say she killed him?
Well, when was that?
That means the little girl must have
been about five, is that right?
Well, what happened to her?
No, not the woman. The child.
I want to know what happened to
the little girl, the daughter.
No, no. Stay on there.
Get me anything else you can.
Look, have photostats made
of all the court records.
Send them to me immediately.
Yes, to my office. Registered.
You're doing an excellent job, Mr. Boyle.
(DOOR CLOSING)
LIL: Marnie,
did you have a good ride?
Yeah. Mr. Boyle,
get the photostats to me. Yes.
And call me the minute you get
anything further on the child.
Thank you. I'll expect
to hear from you. Goodbye.
(KNOCKING)
Mama?
Oh, Mama, don't cry.
Please don't cry, Mama.
MARNIE: No! No!
Mama?
Mama, don't cry.
No!
Mama?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
- Mama?
- Wake up, Marnie.
- Marnie?
Mama?
Oh, don't hurt my mama.
- Marnie.
- Please don't hurt my mama!
Marnie.
No, don't, don't!
What's going on?
- She's having a nightmare.
- No.
- No, Mama.
- Come on, Marnie.
- Mama?
- Wake up. Wake up.
It's just a nightmare.
Come on.
- She's all right.
- I'm cold.
That's supposed to be your
department, isn't it, old boy?
Good night, all.
- Let me get you a brandy.
- Uh-uh.
Where did you
get these things?
I can get more any
time I want them.
Yeah, of course you can.
You can also find, at your convenience,
heights, ropes, ovens, even plastic bags.
The world's full
of alternatives.
I'd like to go
back to sleep now.
Why? Your sleep seems even less
agreeable than your waking hours.
That, uh, dream. You know,
you've had it before.
Is it about something
that really happened to you?
No, I don't know
what it means. Nothing.
Well, it's about your mother.
She wants you to get up.
Yes, but first there
are the three taps.
And then she says, "Get up, Marnie.
You have to get up now!"
But I don't want to. If I...
If I get up, I'll be
cold and they'll hurt her.
Who? Who'll hurt her?
The... The... Them!
I don't know. I don't know.
But I hear the noises. I'm
cold and I hear the noises!
What noises?
What are they like?
Who makes them?
You Freud, me Jane?
If you won't see an analyst, why
don't you try to help yourself?
But that's why I'm in this trap,
is from trying to help myself.
Just leave me alone,
Mark, please.
If I give you some books,
will you read them?
Your new homework?
Frigidity In Women?
The Psychopathic
Delinquent and Criminal?
- Have you read them?
- I don't need to read that muck
to know that women are stupid and
feeble and that men are filthy pigs.
In case you didn't recognize
it, that was a rejection.
I want you to read them. Start with
The Undiscovered Self.
Oh, for God's sake, Mark,
leave me alone! I'm tired!
Why can't you just
leave me alone?
Because I think
you're sick, old dear.
I'm sick?
Well, take a look
at yourself, old dear.
You're so hot to play mental
health week, what about you?
Talk about dream worlds. You've
got a pathological fix on a woman
who's not only an admitted criminal
but who screams if you come near her!
So, what about your dreams,
Daddy dear?
Well, I never said
I was perfect.
That was quite a speech.
It encourages me to believe
that you have leafed through
one or two books.
Which one did you find
the most interesting?
You're really dying
to play doctor, aren't you?
Okay, I'm a big movie fan.
I know the games.
Come on. Let's play.
Shall I start with dreams
or should we free-associate?
Oh, Doctor, I'll bet you're
just dying to free-associate.
All right now, you give me a word
and I'll give you an association.
You know, like, needles, pins, when
a man marries, trouble begins.
You ready?
Well, come on. I thought you wanted
to play doctor, so let's play.
Water.
Bath. Soap. Cleanse. Pure.
Made pure for me.
"And his tears shall wash away thy
sins and make thee over again."
Baptists. Mother used to take
me to church twice on Sundays.
There. I'm not
holding back at all, am I?
You're bringing me
out marvelously, Doctor.
You'll have me up on my poor
paralyzed little legs
by the very next scene. Go on.
Air.
Stare. And that's what you do.
You stare and blare and say you care,
but you're unfair, you want a pair.
Sex.
Masculine. Feminine.
Adam and Eve. Jack and Jill.
I'll slap your filthy face if
you come near me again, Jack!
Death.
Me. Oh, listen, Mark...
- Needles.
- Pins.
- Black.
- White.
- Red!
- White. White! White!
It's all right, Marnie.
Darling, come here.
I won't let anything bad happen to you.
You're all right.
(SOBBING)
- You're all right.
- Oh, help me!
Help me. Oh, God,
somebody help me.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
- BUTLER: What name, sir?
- Strutt.
BUTLER: Mr. and Mrs. Strutt.
- Mr. Strutt.
- Yes.
- Mrs. Strutt.
- How do you do?
I'm Lil Mainwaring,
Mark's sister-in-law.
- So good of you to come all this distance.
- So nice of you to ask us.
Wait till tomorrow, Charlie. Wait
till you see her on a horse, eh?
- I'm not a bit nervous, Mark.
- You have no reason to be.
You're unquestionably
the best-looking woman here.
The best-dressed, the most intelligent.
And you're with me.
- I think everyone's here. - Well, Lil's
scorekeeper. She has the list,
made the table arrangements
and everything.
I'm afraid I wasn't much help
but I'll do better next time.
You're doing well enough. I suppose
we should keep circulating.
Why?
- Why?
- I don't know. I swear I don't know.
He wasn't invited here.
He's never been invited here.
- It's Lil.
- Lil?
- She doesn't even know Strutt.
- It's Lil!
Get me out of here, please.
It's too late.
Here they come.
Look, call his bluff.
I'll back you up.
- Oh, hello, Strutt.
- Hello.
- Good to see you.
I don't know if we've met Mrs. Strutt.
I'm Mark Rutland.
- How do you do?
- And this is my wife.
How do you do?
Well, this is a surprise. I
hadn't heard about your marriage.
You know, we all think
a great deal of your husband.
We've been doing business
with the Rutlands
for a long time.
I believe we've met before.
I don't think so.
Think again, Mrs. Rutland.
Are you just recently married?
Oh, Marnie and I have been
married for two months.
But we've known each other quite
well for about four years.
Four years? Before Estelle...
Yes, didn't you know?
Darling, Betty seems rather
stranded over there.
You'll have to excuse us
for a few moments, Mrs. Strutt.
Oh, and Lil, would you see that
Mr. and Mrs. Strutt's glasses
are kept brimming?
That's a good girl.
- I'm going to be sick.
- You're not going to be sick.
You said we'd known each other four years.
Lil thought...
I don't give one infinitesimal
damn what Lil thought or thinks.
- Dinner is ready, sir.
- Good. Announce it.
Dinner is served.
Mr. Strutt, my wife's taken a fancy to you.
Will you see her into dinner?
Five minutes.
I'm five minutes behind you,
and in those five minutes you've
got yourself up like a cat burglar
and packed for a world cruise.
I've got to get out of here,
and you've got to let me go.
That man is going to send me to jail.
You know he is!
Oh, what are you using
for guts this season, Marnie?
Don't you understand?
He's coming back here tomorrow
and he's coming for my head!
Well, darling,
we just won't give it to him.
Strutt may be throbbing away out there
in the night with vengeful fantasies,
but the fact is
he's a businessman.
That means he's in the
business of doing business.
- So?
- So we try to do business.
The Rutland account is one
of the biggest he's got.
And if he insists on acting like
the little swine he is, then...
And he'll lose others,
too, I'll see to it.
But first I'll see to it that he
understands that I'll see to it.
Suppose you can keep him
from prosecuting,
you can't keep
him from talking.
I don't care if he outtalks every
Southern senator on Capitol Hill.
Well, I do. I care.
Darling, didn't your mother ever
tell you about sticks and stones?
Can't you understand, there
may be other things involved,
other people that I don't
want to hear about me?
Yes, I can understand,
but since you're the well-known,
friendless orphan child, who's to care?
The police, damn you.
Now what can the police do if we
can stop Strutt from prosecuting?
They can start investigating other jobs.
Other similar jobs.
- Well, that's something else again.
- Yes, it is.
How many? How many other jobs?
Well, tell me the truth, damn it. You've
nothing to gain by lying to me now.
- How many jobs have you pulled?
- Three.
Try again.
Four. Five counting Strutt.
Over how long a period?
Five years, and that's
the truth, I swear it!
All right. How much?
- How much all together?
- Under $50,000.
In what towns?
Buffalo, Detroit, Elizabeth,
New Jersey and New York.
Well, in New York
and Philadelphia,
I'll be poor old Mark Rutland who
lost his head over a pretty girl.
And in the others, I'm just
an accessory after the fact
- and equally liable under the law.
- Well, then let me go.
They can't blame you
because you didn't know.
After you found out,
I ran away. Just let me go!
If I let you run out now, nothing
could keep the lid on it.
They've got your real name. They'll
work up a complete dossier on you.
When they finally catch you, and
they will catch you, Marnie,
they'll throw the New York
City Library at you.
But suppose we
don't lose our heads?
All we've got to fight is Strutt's big
mouth. At least that gives us time.
Sit down. Listen.
Now, we can do one
of two things.
We can hire a lawyer
and a psychiatrist,
and make an immediate
voluntary confession
and an offer of restitution. That'll
make the whole thing public.
But the chances are very good that
you'll get a suspended sentence.
Now the alternative.
We can go together and make private
calls on all the places you've robbed.
You'll express deep sorrow and repentance,
sincere and vocal contrition.
And while you sob, I show a
check for the amount stolen
and press it into
their hot little hands
and ask as a special favor
to a distraught husband,
to withdraw the charge.
But if one of them says, "Thanks,
I'll take the money back
"but I won't drop the charge."
Then we've had it.
After that it's an open court case,
and a very probable sentence.
On the other hand, with a bit
of luck, we might pull it off.
Think it over.
It's late. You better get some sleep now.
You got to be up for the hunt.
You don't expect me
to ride in the hunt.
Certainly I expect
you to ride.
For one thing, I want you out of
the house when Strutt comes here.
And for another, I don't want
to give Lil the satisfaction
of seeing you chicken.
And, Marnie,
tonight the door stays open.
(DOGS BARKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(WHINNIES)
(SCREAMS)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Forio!
A gun! Give me a gun!
My horse is screaming!
- Get me a gun!
- You want to shoot your horse?
Hey, wait a minute!
I can't give you a gun,
my mister isn't home.
I don't know what he'd...
You must be crazy!
LIL: Mrs. Turpin!
Miss Mainwaring,
this woman comes tearing in here
demanding I give her a gun.
Tell this fool to give
me a gun. Forio's hurt!
- Marnie, wait. I'll call a vet.
- There's nothing a vet can do.
We don't have a phone anyway,
Miss Mainwaring.
If the horse is hurt bad, I
could give her Jack's pistol.
Hurry. Oh, hurry,
please. He's suffering.
Go get the gun!
I'll do it, Marnie.
You wait here.
Are you still in
the mood for killing?
Please, Marnie!
Stay out of my way!
Marnie, please!
If you don't want me to do it, then
let me go back for one of the men.
(HORSE WHINNIES)
There. There now.
So you can see, Mr. Strutt,
how very disadvantageous any action
on your part would be for everyone.
For me, certainly.
For a sick girl, and for you.
Yes, I'm sure that's the
fashionable attitude, Mr. Rutland.
But just wait until
you've been victimized.
MARK: Try to look at the situation
from a business point of view.
STRUTT: Yes.
MARK: We've been business friends
for a number of years now.
(CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
- MARK: I want you to apply them all
for my benefit. - STRUTT: Hmm.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh, sorry.
Hello?
Yes, Lil, what is it?
Yes, I understand.
I'm hanging up now.
You'll have to forgive me, Strutt,
I've had a bit of trouble at the hunt.
I'll talk to you again, possibly tomorrow.
I'm sorry to have to run out like this.
MARK: I'll take
you home, Marnie.
It's all right, darling.
You're just exhausted.
Now, don't panic.
I've spoken to Strutt. I think
I'll be able to talk him around.
I'll just put this away.
Go on. You want the money.
You wanted the money, or you wouldn't
have taken my keys, would you?
You took the keys,
now take the money!
I said take it!
What's mine belongs to you. It's yours.
You're not stealing.
You want the money,
take it. I said take it!
Marnie, now we're going to
Baltimore to see your mother.
- No!
- Yes.
Come on.
So, I knew you'd run away
and you'd want money.
It didn't take me a minute to find
out the office drawer key was gone.
If you tell my mother
about me, I'll kill you.
If you mean about the robberies, I've
no intention of telling her anything.
It's your mother who's going
to do the talking.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
Marnie, come on.
- No!
- Come on.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
- It's all right, Marnie. You're inside.
- MAMA: What in the wide world?
I'm sorry to crash in
on you like this, Mrs. Edgar.
I guess you know how
Marnie feels about storms.
- Marnie, stop acting like such a ninny.
- Pardon me.
Who are you, mister?
You're not Mr. Pendleton.
No, I'm not.
Who's Mr. Pendleton?
Then what have you got to do
with my Marnie?
Well, I'm Mark Rutland,
Marnie's husband, Mrs. Edgar.
Marnie hasn't been very well.
I don't believe she's been very
well since you had your accident.
My what?
I think you've always
called it "your accident."
What do you think
you're talking about?
Coming into my house like this,
talking about my accident!
You're not married to Marnie.
I don't believe you.
- MAMA: Marnie?
- Your daughter needs help, Mrs. Edgar.
You've got to
tell her the truth.
She has no memory of
what happened that night.
And she needs to remember everything.
You must help her.
Mister, you must be
plumb crazy.
If you won't tell her, I will.
I know everything that happened,
and I'll tell her the whole story.
Oh, no you won't, mister,
because you don't know the whole
story, and nobody does but me!
Oh. Well, since you're so very
knowledgeable, Mrs. Edgar,
do you also know that your daughter,
your beautiful, young daughter,
cannot stand to have a man
touch her? Any man?
She doesn't know why,
but you do.
Don't you think you owe it to
her to help her to understand
what happened to
make her like this?
What matters what made her?
She's lucky. She's lucky to feel like that.
Just plain lucky!
That's very interesting, Mrs. Edgar. But
I've had an investigator working here.
I've read the transcript. Hmm?
The records of
your trial for murder.
In the records it
states quite plainly
that you made your living
from the touch of men.
And it was one of your clients that you
killed that night. (THUNDER CRACKING)
Oh, God!
Was there also a storm
that night, Mrs. Edgar?
Is that why Marnie's
terrified of storms?
Was there thunder and
lightning that night?
Did the storms terrify
your little girl, hmm?
In addition to everything else
that happened?
Get out of my house.
You get out!
I don't need any filthy man
coming in my house no more!
Do you hear me? You get out!
(SCREAMING) You get out
of my house! You get out!
You let my mama go!
You hear? You let my mama go!
You're hurting my mama!
Who am I, Marnie?
- Why should I want to hurt your mama?
- You're one of them.
One of them in
the white suits.
- Shut up, Marnie!
- No!
Remember, Marnie.
Tell us how it all was.
The white suits, remember?
What does the tapping mean, Marnie?
Why does it make you cry?
It means they want in.
Them in their white suits.
Mama comes and
gets me out of bed.
I don't like to
get out of bed.
Come on, Marnie.
Get up. All right?
Good girl.
That's my baby.
There.
There. Mmm.
- You go on back to sleep, sugarpop.
- Bernice.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(SOBBING)
Now, you ain't afraid of a little
bit of lightning, are you? Huh?
What happens next, Marnie?
He came out to me.
Oh, I don't like him.
He smells funny.
Your old captain's gonna be
here all through the night now.
There's no reason to cry.
I want my mama!
I don't want you! Let me go!
Mama!
(SOBBING)
Get your damn
hands off my kid!
What are you trying to...
What are you...
Mama?
Make him go, Mama.
I don't like him to kiss me.
Make him go, Mama!
(MARNIE SCREAMS)
Get your hands...
- Get your hands...
- There's nothing the matter
- with my hands!
- ...off my Marnie!
MARK: What is it, Marnie?
What's the matter?
He hit my mama!
- No!
- What's the matter with you?
- You crazy or drunk?
Now, don't go hitting me. You're
gonna get hit yourself, girl.
(SCREAMING)
Oh, my leg!
- Mama?
- Is your mother hurt?
- How? How is she hurt?
- He fell on her.
Oh, she's so hurt. Oh, Mama.
Marnie. Marnie, help me!
I got to help my mama!
(SOBBING)
(MAN GRUNTING)
Marnie?
I hit him!
I hit him with a stick. I...
I hurt him!
(THUNDER CRACKING)
There. There now.
(CRYING)
(SCREAMING)
You're all right now, darling.
You're all right.
It's all over.
I thought when she lost
her memory of that night,
it was a sign of
God's forgiveness.
I thought I was being
given another chance
to change everything,
to make it all up to her.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Edgar.
Truly sorry.
Your mother told the police that she'd
killed the sailor in self-defense.
They could see how bad hurt I was.
They believed me.
And I never told
anyone the truth.
Never.
Not even when they tried to
take you away from me, Marnie.
MAMA: Not even then.
You must've loved me, Mama.
You must've loved me.
You're the only thing in
this world I ever did love.
It was just that I
was so young, Marnie.
I never had
anything of my own.
You know how I
got you, Marnie?
There was this boy, Billy.
And I wanted Billy's
basketball sweater.
I was 15.
And Billy said if I let him,
I could have the sweater.
So I let him.
And then later on when you
got started, he run away.
I still got that old sweater.
And I got you, Marnie.
And after the accident,
when I was in the hospital,
they tried to make
me let you be adopted.
But I wouldn't. I wanted you.
And I promised God right then,
if he'd let me keep you,
and you not remember,
I'd bring you up
different from me.
- Decent.
- Decent?
Oh, Mama!
Well, you surely
realized your ambition.
I certainly am decent.
Of course, I'm a cheat
and a liar and a thief,
but I am decent.
Marnie, it's time to have a
little compassion for yourself.
When a child, a child of any
age, Marnie, can't get love,
it takes what it can get,
any way it can get it.
It's not so
hard to understand.
Get up, Marnie,
you're aching my leg.
There. That's better.
Mark?
What am I going to do?
What's going to happen?
What do you want to happen?
I guess I...
I want it all cleared up.
Will I... Will I go to jail?
No. Not after what
I have to tell them.
We'll go now.
Mrs. Edgar, I'll bring Marnie back.
She's very tired now.
Goodbye, Mama.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, sugarpop.
Oh, Mark, I don't want
to go to jail.
- I'd rather stay with you.
- Had you, love?
GIRLS: (SINGING) Send for
the doctor over the hill.
Call for the doctor.
Call for the nurse.
Call for the lady
with the alligator purse.