A note from Tornberry:
The subtitles (both streams) were timed and made
for the ENGLISH audio track, NOT the Japanese audio track.
This is why they appear early, late, and when no one's talking.
My suggestion is to watch this movie dubbed. Great voice-actors!
Thank you, Disney!
[Male] If you're troubled
by something mysterious
or a problem that's hard to solve,
there's a place you can go
where you always find help.
You just need to look for it.
[Alarm bleeps]
[Murmurs]
[Gasps] Not again.
- Aren't you up yet?
- I'm up. I'm up.
Whatever.
Hey, Mom.
Really, why do you bother
setting an alarm clock?
Gotta go.
Too bad you don't have time to eat.
Mmm, mmm. It's delicious.
- That's just mean.
- [Mom] Have a nice day.
Oh!
[Shrieks]
Oh, my shoe.
Oh. Excuse me?
[Teacher] The kingdom is gone,
yet the mountains and rivers remain.
And the castle is draped
in the vivid green of spring.
Haru, we can see you sneaking in,
so just get to your seat, please.
Yes, sir.
Busted.
[Laughter]
[Groans]
[Girl] Sorry.
It's not fair.
First I have a bad morning,
then everyone laughs at me in class.
- Even Machida was laughing, wasn't he?
- Yeah, pretty hard.
Why me? Why are all these bad things
happening to me?
Hm, maybe it's some kind
of weird omen, Haru.
Like your life is
gonna get a whole lot worse real soon.
Thanks. That helps a lot.
That's odd. Never seen him.
- Why worry about what Machida thinks?
- I just think he's so cool.
- Tell him.
- What if he has a girlfriend?
He does. A freshman. Really cute.
Then why tell me to flirt with him?
I want a good laugh
when he blows you off.
- You are terrible.
- Machida's not that cool.
- My Tsuge is much cooler and...
- Careful.
- What was that?
- Cat burglar.
Where's he going?
Hey, dumb cat! You'll get killed!
- Oh well, it's just a cat.
- This doesn't look so good.
Ah! What is he doing?
Haru, don't!
I should be there in...
No way. What a catch!
Hey, you stupid jerk!
Oh, cat, that was close.
[Gasps]
That was quite a brave act
you performed. I am extremely grateful.
I hope you are not injured.
[Stammers]
I don't mean to be rude,
but I'm in a hurry.
- I'll return to thank you properly.
- Uh, that's okay.
Haru!
Well, so much for your stick,
but at least
you rescued that stupid cat.
- It talked.
- What?
That cat spoke to me.
Hey, did you hit your head?
Mom, I'm home.
Watch it! Quilt on the floor.
Oh my, this pattern's a disaster.
Could you make dinner tonight?
- Hey, Mom?
- Hm-mm.
Do you think cats can talk?
Sure. Why not?
[Haru groans]
What?
You've asked me that question before
when you were a little girl.
You said, "Mommy,
did you know I can talk to cats?"
- I said that?
- Yes. You don't remember?
Hmm?
Hey, what's wrong?
[Meows]
Oh, you're pretty hungry, huh?
Do you like fish?
They're really good. Here, try some.
You're really dirty, kitty.
Do you like the fish?
See. I told you.
- You want some more?
- [Meows]
Okay, you can have them all.
No, you don't need to
do anything for me.
- Haru.
- Mommy!
- What were you doing over there?
- I was talking with the kitten.
So I asked you
what the kitten said to you.
And do you know what you said?
You said the kitten told you
that life is tough.
I thought it was so adorable.
[Barking in distance]
[Sighs]
So it looks like that actually happened.
Let's forget about it, go to sleep,
and get up in time for breakfast.
[Bells tinkle]
[Meows]
- [Cats meow]
- Huh?
[Meowing and hissing]
[Meowing]
[Clears throat]
Uh...
Uh, come over here.
- Hm?
- Mm-mm. A bit closer.
Please allow me to present our wise
and incredibly magnificent ruler,
King of Cat Kingdom, the Cat King.
That's me, babe.
The cat whose life
you saved today was none other
than the king's only son Prince Lune.
Given the magnitude of the matter,
the king would like to express
his gratitude to you in his own words.
Oh.
[Murmurs]
Thanks a lot, babe.
- [Gasps]
- A list of what you shall receive.
Starting tomorrow,
that marvelous array of gifts
will be showered upon you.
- Thank you.
- Mmmm.
Ciao, babe.
[Alarm]
[Sneezes]
Just a dream.
[Telephone]
No way. You don't know
anything about this at all?
I have no idea. I just woke up.
Then where did these come from?
[Mom] Haru, get down here!
Look at this.
What has happened to our yard?
Those look like cat tails.
Okay. I must be working too hard.
I'm going back to bed.
[Both meow]
[Meowing]
Leave me alone!
Stupid cats!
Huh?
Hey, what do I do
with all the lacrosse sticks?
Hi, guys. Gotta run.
- What is that about?
- Does she have catnip on her?
- Catnip? What for?
- Beats me.
No pets on school property, young lady.
No! They're not mine!
What's going on?
Huh?
- [Squeaking]
- [Gasps]
[Shrieks]
So it wasn't a dream. Those cats
from last night must be behind this.
I'm starting to think
it was a big mistake to save that cat.
Huh?
Stick, cat tails, catnip, mice...
- Haru?
- [Shrieks] What?
Did you get the catnip off you?
Oh, yes. Someone stuck some
in my pockets but it's gone now.
Wow, that's weird.
Okay, I've got a big favor to ask you.
Can you do my cleanup duty today?
Tsuge's got a big game and if
I don't leave after class, I'll miss it.
Please, please, please.
Oh, Tsuge.
Yeah, sure, I'll do it.
Thanks, Haru. You're a lifesaver.
Come on, Tsuge. Go!
Yeah!
Yes! He's so cool!
Careful. Watch your step.
Thanks.
Ah... Hurt...
Oh, look at the mess I made.
Oh, I missed.
Who do I think I'm fooling anyway?
There she is. Miss Haru! Miss Haru!
Oh...
You cats just never let up!
Well, we're so glad that you're pleased.
No, I'm not.
How can that be? The whole kingdom
is working to make you happy.
And we all agreed
that the gifts were fabulous.
Don't you cats know anything?
I hate mice.
I'm allergic to cat tails
and catnip does nothing for me.
Oh, my my my my my.
I guess we made a little mistake.
Well, this is embarrassing.
The king will not be happy
when he hears about this.
I'm sorry. Did I hurt your feelings?
I overreacted, didn't I?
[Sighs] I've just been on edge recently.
Things have not been going well for me.
- What kind of things?
- I don't know. Everything, you name it.
I'm shocked to hear this.
But I suppose even pretty girls like you
have problems like everyone else.
- What? Stop. That's enough.
- It is nowhere near enough.
The Kingdom of Cats has vowed not to
rest until you are completely satisfied.
- There's more?
- Yes.
How would you like to have a private
tour of the spectacular Kingdom of Cats?
Are you serious?
I'm sure you'll love it there.
It's a marvelous place.
Great food, fabulous scenery
and the entire cat kingdom
is ready to welcome you.
And that's not all.
The king is so taken with you,
he has awarded you the most
valuable gift in the cat kingdom.
You will become his daughter-in-law
and marry Prince Lune.
Huh?
Don't think
about trying to pull that one on me.
There is no way I can marry a cat.
The royal family
thinks you're good enough
and the prince is so cool.
- He's cool?
- Hm-mm.
Hmm...
Who knows? Maybe I'd fit in better
with a bunch of cats.
You get to lie around all day,
don't you?
- But of course.
- Eat all the food you want,
take naps in the sun,
forget about all your problems.
But me getting married to a cat prince,
that's just ridiculous.
Right, cat?
Fantastic.
We'll collect you tonight, then.
No, I didn't agree to that.
Hey, wait!
[Haru] Ow!
Oh, I hurt.
Okay, think, Haru.
You gotta do something about this.
What can I do?
Those cats are relentless.
They'll find a way to kidnap me
and I'll have to marry a cat.
I now pronounce you cat and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
No, no, I don't want to marry a cat!
[Cries]
[Female voice] Haru. Haru.
What was that?
Haru, go to the Cat Bureau.
Find the Cat Bureau.
Hey, come on. Who's there?
Who's messing with me now?
They will help you there. Look for
a large, white cat at the crossroads.
He will show you the way.
A cat at a crossroad?
Find the white cat
and go to the Cat Bureau, Haru.
You'll need their help.
[Haru] Find the Cat Bureau.
Never heard of a Cat Bureau.
Look for a large, white cat...
At least it was a pleasant voice.
Maybe the white cat will be nice, too.
That was one long, weird day.
I definitely need a break.
- [Groans]
- [Screams]
What in the heck was that?
Hey, you big fatso.
You cats keep freaking me out.
Are you the big, white cat? Are you?
Listen, cat.
I need to know where the Cat Bureau is.
A voice told me to ask you.
Must have the wrong person.
I mean cat. I have the wrong cat.
Sorry I sat on you.
- Wait. I'll show you.
- It's him!
Wait a minute. Slow down.
Isn't there an easier way?
Hey. Hey, come on.
Guess I shouldn't have called him Fatso.
[Sighs]
Huh?
Oh...
Wow, this is one weird place.
Excuse me, where's the Cat Bureau?
Hello?
I need some help right now.
I'm gonna get dragged off
to the cat kingdom.
[Gasps]
Could this be it?
Enough, Baron. Turn it off.
No one's impressed
with your cheesy light show, okay?
Good evening. Welcome to the Bureau
Wow, you're cool.
Thank you. You're now in a world
quite different from your own.
This is a refuge for creations.
Whenever someone creates something
with all of their heart,
then that creation is given a soul.
Like me and Toto there.
That's... That's...
That is Toto.
A stone statue with a soul.
I see you have a visitor today, Baron.
How unusual.
Indeed. She's quite a fetching one, too.
Did he say Baron?
I am Baron Humbert von Gikkingen.
The artisan who created me
gave me that title.
I'll just call you Baron.
So, you say you're having trouble
with those cats from the cat kingdom.
Yes. Yesterday I saved their prince
from getting hit by a truck,
and now they won't stop
trying to repay me.
- I see.
- Huh!
Serves you right. Thought you'd help
the poor kitty, did you?
You should've minded your own business.
[Toto] Muta, what's your problem?
This girl saved one of your own kind.
You should be grateful.
Now she's in trouble for it, isn't she?
So she was stupid,
that's all I'm saying.
Where did you find her, Muta?
At the crossroads.
She knew about the Cat Bureau.
Hmm.
A voice told me about it. I don't know
whose voice it was, though.
- A voice?
- You're hearing voices?
Check into a loony bin.
Don't bother us with...
- Knock it off!
- You knock it off. Quit being so catty.
Don't try that again.
You guys, I'll just leave.
I don't want to cause any trouble.
I didn't get your name.
Haru. It's Haru.
Well, Miss Haru,
please step into the Bureau.
- Come along. Don't worry about them.
- Chicken wings!
Can't you tell the difference
between chickens and crows?
- Yes, I'm not the birdbrain here.
- I don't look like a giant marshmallow.
- At least I don't have a bird brain.
- You already said that.
- Go fry yourself, you big chicken.
- You already called me a chicken!
This looks close.
Wow, this place is beautiful.
- Make yourself at home.
- Thanks.
Milk with your tea, or lemon?
- Milk, please.
- Good choice.
You have great taste, Baron.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
How cute.
That's my own personal blend of tea.
It's a little different each time,
so I can't guarantee the taste.
Wow, that's the best tea
I've ever tasted.
Then you're lucky.
Just tastes like boiled grass to me.
Tea is too refined
for your crude taste buds.
At least I don't eat worms.
Muta, have a seat and tell us
what you know about the Kingdom of Cats.
It's a dangerous place.
You shouldn't go there
if you don't believe in yourself.
Good point.
They said not only will they kidnap me,
they're going to force me
to marry Prince Lune.
So, do it. You'll be set for life.
- Are you crazy?
- It might not be all that bad.
That's ridiculous.
- She won't know until she tries it.
- Now, then...
I've always entertained the idea of
paying a visit to the Kingdom of Cats.
- Now is the time.
- Have a nice trip.
- Hope you make it back some day.
- You're coming with me.
Nah, I'll pass.
But thanks for thinking of me.
Baron, you're not going to
take her there, are you?
We can't leave her unprotected.
But if Muta wants to stay here,
he can keep an eye on her.
No way. You can't leave her here.
I'm not baby-sitting.
- Why? Are you busy at the moment?
- Not really.
I'll just go home.
- Hmm?
- What?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to
cause you so much trouble.
Muta's right. It's my fault
for getting involved with those cats.
I'll figure something out.
Well, then, so sorry the Cat Bureau
couldn't be of any help to you.
Ah... All right, all right.
I'll watch the little baby.
Good kitty.
Then it's settled.
You can stay here with Muta.
You sure?
Don't worry about Muta. He complains
a lot but he has a heart of gold.
Hmph!
Hm... I see.
So he's just a big softie.
You could say that.
And this is the thanks I get.
Thank you for your help, Moo-ta.
[Gasps]
What? Moo?
Are you saying that I'm a fat cow?
- No, you're just fat.
- I like this girl better every minute.
I'm outta here.
That's too bad. I was just going to
get out some angel fruit cake.
- Where is it?
- It's in the upper-right shelf.
Why didn't you say so?
Our guest
deserves a proper afternoon tea.
This calls
for some of my special mulberries.
You're too much, Baron.
A tea party and everything?
- Anything I can do to help?
- Yes, there is something.
I need you to learn just one thing.
Always believe in yourself.
Do this, and no matter where you are,
you will have nothing to fear.
Baron, give me a hand
with this whipped cream.
- You're going all out.
- Better believe it.
Who knows?
Maybe this is the world I belong in.
[Knock at door]
Hey, is that Toto?
It's time to go to our kingdom,
Miss Haru.
You again!
No! Hey! Get away from me!
Skip the tea.
[Screams]
Don't let them take me away, please!
Baron,
a bunch of cats are headed this way.
- Oh no.
- A little late, birdbrain.
Toto, give me a lift.
Ouch!
We had a hard time finding you.
- Let me off.
- What?
- [Shrieks]
- Careful, Miss Haru.
Stop these cats.
I want off this thing now.
Don't worry. You're just having
pre-wedding jitters, that's all.
No, I'm not!
She could've waited
until after we had cake.
Ow! Quit that!
Let me go. Stop it. It hurts.
They're coming for me.
- I said let me go.
- Okay, Toto. Now!
Wait. I take it back!
Why did you let him fall?
You cats are terrible.
You're gonna regret that.
Muta!
We're over the weight limit.
- Toto.
- I see it.
[Haru screams]
Let me off this thing!
Outmaneuvered.
- Get above the trees.
- Right.
Now what?
They're riding the wind.
Follow the lights.
Got it.
[Haru groans]
Oh, that hurt.
Where am I anyway?
I can't see a thing.
[Gasps]
Muta. What happened? You're enormous.
No, kiddo. You got smaller.
Hm?
Why's that?
Because we're here, that's why.
That's the Kingdom of Cats?
That's it.
[Both meow]
Wow, there are cats all over the place.
What did you expect?
It is their kingdom.
Hey, you!
Ah, it's so relaxing here.
Hey, we have to find
a way out of there fast.
- Relax.
- Listen, kid...
I've never felt so at home in my life.
[Female] Hurry.
You've got to get out of here.
You must leave.
You don't belong here.
Wow! You're beautiful.
Everything's better here.
Even the cats.
Quickly. You don't have much time.
Please, Miss Haru, before it's too late.
Wait a minute.
How do you know my name?
Miss Haru! Miss Haru!
- Huh?
- Oh, not him again.
There you are.
I finally found you.
We seemed to have accidentally
dropped you upon entry.
Your fat servant
exceeded our weight limit.
Fat servant?
No, this is Muta. He's a friend.
That's nice. Come on. Everyone's
dying to meet their new princess.
Fat friend, you can come, too.
- I don't know about this.
- The king is waiting in your castle.
- My castle?
- The royal palace.
- Well, soon enough.
Hmm.
Hey, where do you think you're going?
The king's waiting for me.
It's rude not to say hi.
Have you completely lost your mind?
- This way.
- Wait a minute.
Can she come with us?
- Who are you?
- I'm Yuki. I serve at the royal table.
Oh, so you're employed by the king?
She works at the castle.
You'll see her there.
- Come.
- See you soon, Yuki.
Ow, ow, ow! Hey!
Poor Haru.
Ugh, look at that. Creepy.
Mmm, looks good.
My future daughter-in-law.
Hmm.
All right! Think I'll go
and have a look in person.
Hm. Why does that fatso
seem so familiar?
You'll need to change
before meeting the king.
I get new clothes?
- Please wait here, sir.
- I'm the baby-sitter.
- Back off.
- What's your problem?
Help yourself to refreshments
while you wait.
Yeah, okay, I'll wait.
Oh...
Hey, not bad.
Miss Haru, you're so lucky.
Every girl in the cat kingdom
has a crush on Prince Lune.
I'm sure you'll be very happy together.
You think?
No, wait. I don't think I wanna do this.
Wow, don't you look good.
Welcome to the royal family, babe.
Hmm.
Mmm.
[Grunts]
- Tell me, who is that cat?
- I believe his name is Muta.
Muta?
Never heard that name.
No match for my stomach.
Hmm...
King, I'm really flattered by all this
but I don't want to get married.
You what? I was told
you had already consented.
She has consented.
That's what I was told.
- What does the prince say?
- He is away on official business.
Look, first of all,
we don't really know each other
and second of all, he's a cat, right?
And I'm not.
So, clearly, I can't marry him.
- Huh?
[Both snigger]
That has already been taken care of.
You're half cat already.
Oh...
See, Miss Haru?
[Gasps]
Look at that. I'm a cat.
[Meows]
Muta!
[Screams]
Muta, what happened?
He had a weakness for catnip jelly.
He saw the bowl and dove right in.
Muta, you weren't supposed to die.
It's all my fault.
Don't leave me like this, Muta.
Time for the celebration.
No, I won't leave him!
Then we'll bring him with us.
[Haru cries]
- That's Prince Lune's bride.
- She has lovely fur.
And such delicate paws.
I hear you don't care for mice
but I bet you can't resist
my juicy, raw fish, huh?
I'm not sure she's enjoying herself.
- How about some entertainment?
- Excellent suggestion.
[Lively music]
[Laughter]
[Sobs]
- Not entertaining enough.
- Yes, sire.
[Shrieks]
[Giggles]
[Yells]
Next.
[Laughs]
[Yells]
Whoever's next better not stink. Got it?
[All gasp and whimper]
Your Majesty, I promise that I will
make the young lady smile.
- Shall we try him?
- Sure. Why not?
Huh?
Excuse me.
Would you care to dance?
Oh no, I'm a meow-sy dancer.
Now I'm starting to talk like a cat.
Just trust me.
[Accordion starts up]
Well, she seems to be entertained now.
[Thinks] What's happening to me?
I've never felt like this before.
Maybe life as a cat wouldn't be so bad.
Careful, Haru. Don't lose yourself.
Huh?
Believe in who you are.
[Slurps]
[Burps]
I said so before, didn't I?
Then you must be...
Stop right there, pal!
You're not from my kingdom, are you?
Exactly who are you?
How rude of me.
I should have introduced myself.
I am exactly who I appear to be.
I am Baron Humbert von Gikkingen
and I have come for Haru.
Baron!
- He's so cool.
- He is handsome.
He can't have her. Seize them!
[Groans]
I'm stuffed.
Muta? You're still alive!
- Oh no!
- Give me back my daughter-in-law.
Quickly,
get His Majesty to a safe place.
Emergency exit for all guests
right here, please. Enjoy your day.
Great technique, Muta.
I just lost my balance.
Over here.
Yuki, you're here.
I'm so thankful
you were able to help Miss Haru, Baron.
Do we know each other?
Many of us here
know of you and your bureau.
Yuki, I'm an idiot. I should've left
when you told me to. Now look at me.
If you leave here by dawn,
you can still turn back into a human.
I will?
This will get you outside the castle.
- Perfect.
- Wait. Where's Muta?
Hmm.
He'll be fine.
We just need to get you home.
[Shrieks]
The back of the castle.
The door to your world
is at the top of that tower.
[Haru] You've got to be kidding me?
And the only way to get to the tower
is through the king's maze.
Naturally.
Good luck.
And, Baron, take good care of Haru.
Hey, wait.
She's already gone.
I didn't have a chance to thank her.
Haru, does her voice
sound familiar to you?
Is it possible that she told you
to seek help at the Cat Bureau?
[Yuki] Haru, go to the Cat Bureau.
You must find the Cat Bureau.
You're right.
That was her voice.
But why help me?
[Yelling]
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Whose idea was it to leave without me?
I nearly got killed.
This is no time for finger pointing.
You're leaving me again?
- Are they going in?
- Yes, they've just begun.
Purr-fect.
No one's ever come out alive,
have they?
We can watch them go nuts
from over here.
- Hurry, we don't have much time.
- It's still noon.
- It's always noon here.
- What do you mean?
- At home, it's already after midnight.
- What? We've got to go faster.
Where do we go?
They're lost already?
They're doing worse
than most of our victims.
Pleased, Your Majesty?
Feeling good, babe.
- Where are the guards?
- Right there.
Hut, hut, hut, hut...
Let's start with this path. If we're
methodical, we'll find our way.
Keep your eye on the tower.
That will allow us to stay oriented.
Good idea.
Muta, you're cheating.
Gimme a break.
You think I'll get in trouble?
He's cheating.
She's gonna rub this in my face,
isn't she?
Let's get out of here
while Muta keeps them occupied.
Again, I'm tricked into being bait.
Stay behind me, Haru.
Wow!
Oh, how's your cane?
Bent, but it's about time
for a new one anyway.
I never knew they were so useful.
Nice shot, sire.
- Oh no, you hit one of ours.
- I did?
- Your Majesty, how could you?
- Let's keep that between us.
Excuse me,
but I think there's a bit of a problem.
- Our guards are scattered.
- Don't tell me they're lost, too?
[King] Where's my princess?
She's already halfway through.
- Hey!
- You found us.
- What's that way like?
- Just dead ends.
[Chuckles]
Now this is more like it, babe.
Hm, another dead end.
My, my, this is getting interesting.
Two rights and a left...
Wait a minute,
I know there wasn't a wall here.
- Your brain's overheating.
- We just walked through here, Muta.
What, walls have legs?
She's right, Muta.
This wall is fake.
[Meows]
[All meow]
- Told you.
- Good work, Haru.
All right, fine, good work.
How stupid do you have to be
to line up like dominoes?
[Meowing]
- Princess!
- Wait. It's not safe, Your Majesty.
Go ahead. I'll catch up to you.
Oh!
What a show-off.
- I can walk.
- Don't worry.
Hmm?
Your Majesty!
This is very dangerous.
I can't let them escape.
You'll never reach them in time.
Besides, we have guards in the tower.
Why didn't you say so?
[Chuckles] Toast.
Whoa!
- I'll have a word with the contractors.
- It's too late for that.
We'll have to use the detonator.
Not that, I beg of you, sire.
Think of what it will do
to your approval ratings.
- Button.
- I must have left it in the castle.
Look what I found.
No! Oh! No!
Hey, we made it to the top.
[Baron] Not much further now.
Bye-bye, tower.
- Baron!
- Brace yourselves.
[Chuckles]
Excellent explosion, Your Majesty.
Let's go.
You've got to be kidding.
We're back where we started.
Now what do we do?
Just stand here?
Nothing else we can do.
Hut, hut, hut, hut...
[King] Quick, quick! Get 'em! Get 'em!
Baron, nice to see you again.
Princess, would you please
accompany me back to the castle?
Being a cat's not so bad.
Do I have to learn to eat mice?
Perhaps you shouldn't give up
quite yet, Haru.
What in the world has Father done now?
Father!
Lune? You're back already?
The prince is here. Line up!
It's the prince?
Yuki sent a message
saying it was urgent I return.
Perhaps you'd like to tell me
what's going on?
Miss Haru!
- Yuki, you're here.
- I'm glad Lune made it in time.
I just wanted to repay
the girl who rescued you.
And I thought, just maybe,
you would be happy
to have a good-looking girl like Haru
for a bride.
I have already chosen my bride.
I have decided to marry Yuki.
That thing?
- Guess it was a surprise.
- I like this prince.
This is for you. I traveled
to your old home to get these.
I haven't had these in years.
Wow.
I used to love those when I was a kid.
I know. You fed me a whole box of these
when I was just a stray.
That filthy little kitten was you?
You're so beautiful now,
I never would have recognized you.
Yuki, will you accept these crackers
as a symbol of my love for you
for as long
as our nine lives shall last?
So these crackers mean that
you can marry the prince instead of me!
I'm so happy for you.
Thank you, Haru.
Thank you for feeding me
when I was a kitten.
Without you
I might not be alive today.
You're the girl with the fish crackers
Yuki told me about.
And you also rescued me
when I nearly got killed by a truck.
We both owe you our lives, Haru.
What can we do to repay you?
You don't have to repay me.
I'm just glad things turned out so well.
I guess I did the right thing after all.
[Sobbing]
This is all very moving.
I had no idea
you had a bride in mind already.
You should've told me.
Poor Haru.
You must feel like such a loser.
- Not really.
- I'm sure you do.
So, I have a great idea.
You should marry me instead.
I'll get you some fish, too, as a symbol
of my undying love and all that.
So?
That's very generous,
but I just want to be myself.
I'll change you back if you marry me.
Hm?
I've had just about enough of you.
Nobody who decided who I am but me,
and there's no way I'd ever marry you.
Was that a no?
[Laughs]
So you're not ready
to get hitched then, huh, kid?
[All grumble]
Not a chance.
I respect a woman
who stands up for herself.
Even if she does stick her nose
in other people's business.
So I, Renaldo Moon, will defend her.
- Renaldo?
- Renaldo Moon?
- The Renaldo Moon?
- So that's who he is.
- Who?
- How could you have forgotten?
He's such a notorious criminal,
his story is written on our walls.
Years back,
an enormous white cat appeared,
devoured all the fish in the lake
and then ran off.
He called himself Renaldo Moon.
Did you really do that, Muta?
That's disgusting.
And this time
I'll eat the entire castle.
Hurry! Get His Majesty to safety, now!
Protect Haru from the king.
Yes, sir.
Cat guard, advance.
Oh, you traitor.
Please, sire, it's not safe.
Take Miss Haru to the exit. I'll hold
back the king as long as I can.
The tower collapsed.
It's all right, the exit is still there.
- The sky.
- Oh no, the sun's rising.
I'll get her to the exit.
- Nice.
- Run, Haru. Hurry.
Good luck, and thank you.
Mm-hm.
[Thinks] Goodbye, Yuki.
I wasn't wrong to save a cat.
No matter what happens,
I believe in my decision.
I believe.
[Roars]
- I'll hold them off.
- Thanks, Muta.
- Where's the king?
- Up there.
Father, you'll hurt yourself.
Get down.
- Has he lost his mind?
- I'll find a way to get him down.
Fight like a cat, you chicken!
With pleasure.
- Need help?
- Take care of Haru.
You got it.
[Grunts]
[Glass shatters]
[Groans]
I win, King.
How embarrassing.
I heard rumors
about a nosy cat figurine
who likes to help others
with their problems.
I assumed you'd just be a kitschy
knick-knack that collected dust.
Had I known you were this good, I would
have asked you to come and work for me.
I prefer a life of sticking my nose
in other's problems.
[Haru screams]
Where am I?
What have you done?
I didn't do anything.
The tower
is hundreds of feet shorter now.
I wouldn't be surprised
if the exit had moved as well.
[Chuckles]
- Oh no, the exit moved!
- We should have foreseen this.
But, look, she's not a cat any more.
Help me!
I'm going to fall.
I'm going!
Haru!
Muta, I hope I'm not too heavy.
From now on,
you're not allowed to make...
...any more fat jokes.
[Haru screams]
[Muta groans]
I'm sorry, Muta.
Hold on!
I don't wanna die.
You're not dead yet. Open your eyes.
- Baron?
- Spread your arms and look down.
I can't. I'm scared.
Just trust me.
- Are you sure we're still alive?
- Yes. For now.
I think I could learn to like this.
[Muta]
What are all these chickens doing here?
- A flock of crows?
- [Baron] Perfect timing.
So, Muta, how does it feel to be saved
by a bunch of birdbrains?
Toto!
- It sure took you long enough.
- [Baron] Nice work, Toto.
I'm just glad I had enough friends
hanging out in the area.
Are you sure we're not too heavy?
- You're light as a feather, Haru.
- Thanks.
I beg to differ.
Haru, look.
That's my school.
I don't believe it.
I'm gonna make it home.
Thank you, everyone.
[Cheering]
Unbelievable.
We won't forget you, Miss Haru.
Your Majesty?
I've been thinking.
It may be time for me to retire.
I think I shall accompany you, sire.
Thanks, Toto.
Oh boy, my heart is still pounding.
- Scared, were you?
- Yes. But I had fun, too.
Really? I didn't.
Well then,
now that Haru's problem is solved,
we should let her go home
and get some rest.
Catnap.
I guess this is goodbye?
One last chore to do.
Baron, just for the record, I think
I may have a little crush on you.
Just for the record, I admire a young
woman who speaks from the heart.
If you ever need us, you will always
know how to find us again.
And the Bureau's doors will be open
to you, be it day or night.
Until then, trust yourself.
Goodbye.
I'll miss you!
Toto.
Baron.
And Fatso!
- Fatso? I heard that.
- She's only telling the truth.
Shut up, birdbrain.
Don't give me that again
or I might drop you.
Shut up, you birdbrain.
[Chuckles]
[Alarm]
[Yawns]
Oh! I've got to get up.
[Gasps]
Morning.
Haru? What are you doing up so early?
It's not even a school day.
I'm going out with Hiromi.
Don't want to waste the day.
Huh?
So...
I made some breakfast for both of us.
- What?
- I'm done so help yourself.
And I made some tea, too.
- Oh, by the way...
- [gasps]
...that's my own special blend of tea.
It's a bit different every time
so I can't guarantee the flavor.
Oh, okay.
What do you know? Smells good.
[Girl] That's a great outfit.
I got some big news
you'll be excited about.
Yeah? What is it?
Machida broke up with his girlfriend.
- Oh, that's too bad.
- What? Are you kidding?
- What do you mean?
- I thought you'd be ecstatic.
Not really. Doesn't matter any more.
- Hey, are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- Liar.
- I'm better than ever.
What's going on with you and Tsuge?
Nothing new.
- Come on.
- Nothing's happening.
[Muta yawns]
[Japanese background song]
>>