(MOTORCYCLE ENGINE ROARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
He's on the way, Mack.
I'm droppin' him right in your lap.
Copy that. We're all set up.
Now, listen, Alex,
everything by the book.
No stunts and no wrecks
today, all right?
(HORN HONKING)
Oh, shit.
It's the little things, you know,
that I'm still trying to get used to.
Like, if I drop my napkin... Ow.
...in a restaurant,
Alex gives me his.
Car door needs
opening, he opens it.
My neighbors, abusive?
He yells at them.
The other night, we were watching
a video, he let me pick it out.
Do you want to slowly merge into...
- Signal first!
- (HORNS HONKING)
Too late. Okay.
- Oh. That's good. Oh, boy.
- All right.
My last boyfriend, Jack, wasn't
exactly the romantic type.
Two years ago, for my birthday...
He gives me pepper Spray.
I think it's perfume.
I end up in the emergency room.
(LAUGHS)
- Uh-huh.
- I'm telling you,
relationships based on
extreme circumstances
- never work out.
- Right.
- Right?
- No!
- Watch the glass!
- (HORN HONKS)
Your boyfriend drive like this?
Oh, Alex? No. No, no, no.
Alex is so completely different.
He is. I mean,
he works beach patrol.
He spends all day on
a bicycle in Venice.
Shit.
I'm sure he's on the
beach right now.
That's how we met, by the way.
I was, uh, jaywalking.
- Jaywalking, huh?
- Yeah.
Well, you know,
jaywalking is a crime.
Yeah, but I needed to get across
and at the point where they...
Dip!
- ANNIE: Ow.
- Another dip!
Oh! Aah...
Two dips.
- It's our anniversary tonight.
- Yeah?
- (SIREN WAILING)
- Seven months.
Neither one of us has
ever dated longer.
That's why we're celebrating...
Look, why don't you slow down
and tell me your
problem, huh? Good.
Uh, make a left here.
I said... Oh! Easy!
Slow down!
Shit!
Miss, pull over to
the side, please.
the side, please!
Side.
I can't! There's a cliff!
MACK: On my command!
Shit!
Hold your fire,
gentlemen, he's too far!
All right, everybody
in the car! Let's go!
(GRUNTS)
(VAN SMASHES)
(MAN GROANING)
You're under arrest.
You have the right to
remain silent. Ow.
That hurt.
Pull over to the side, please.
Pull over here.
- I can't pull over.
- Stop right here.
This is absolutely not
my fault, Mr. Kenter.
Oh, I need my license back.
Oh, my God.
What? What?
Stop! Stop!
(DISTANT SIRENS)
(GROANS)
You'll never drive
in this town again.
ANNIE: Alex?
ALEX: Annie.
What... What happened? What...
How'd the driving test go?
Oh, it, uh...
Not good. Not good.
Um, why aren't you...
Why... Why aren't you at the beach?
You know, it's funny.
There's this...
Perfectly...
reasonable explanation...
You're a madman, Shaw!
Nice working with you, as always.
So far, they've recovered
some of the stolen computers
and apprehended one of the suspects
thanks mainly to SWAT
team member Alex Shaw
who was the officer injured
in today's high-speed chase.
You lied to me.
ALEX: Annie, I didn't lie about...
You never said that you were
on the suicide squad, ever.
You knew that I was a cop.
I said that I was...
Wait.
Oh, Come on. Ow.
Let me ask you.
When I had conversations with
you and I told you about Jack
and how he was always getting hurt
that I thought that he
was out of his mind
and that I would never date
anybody like that again,
a little bell didn't go off
in your head and say,
"Well, maybe I should tell her
now what I do for a living?"
Exactly. And blow it?
Well, when did you plan
on telling me this?
- Well, today.
- Oh, today?
Yeah, which is good you're here.
Today was the day...
Mr. Spontaneity.
You know what I pictured
you doing in Venice?
I pictured you...
I don't know, just busting
teenage pickpockets and stuff,
walking old women across the
street, drinking lemonade.
I do fill in for a friend down
at the beach occasionally.
And I often, often enjoy
a nice glass of lemonade.
You know what?
I don't even know you.
I feel I don't even know you.
I don't even know who
you are anymore.
I don't understand.
We got to spend some time together,
then we'll get to know each other.
Let's go away together.
Okay, where?
The Caribbean.
Oh, The Caribbean.
Do you have a concussion?
We work 6 days a week, Alex.
We've never even been
away for a weekend.
I was going to surprise
you tonight, but, uh...
It's a cruise.
This is so unfair, Alex.
You can't just pull out
tickets to some exotic island
and think that's going
to make everything okay.
I don't expect that
I can make it all right,
but, uh, you know, maybe
I thought we could.
No. Don't do that.
I want to be depressed right now.
I don't want you to, like, do that.
Don't.
All right, all right.
(SIGHS)
- Don't.
- I won't.
(HORN BLOWS)
Welcome to the Seabourn Legend.
Thank you. Welcome.
Oh, now, this is a cute couple.
How about a picture?
Don't move! Pictures don't move.
What are your names?
I'm Annie. This is Alex.
Adorable. My name's Dante.
How about a big smile
for the newlyweds?
Oh, actually, we're not newlyweds.
It's only 34.50 for a
double set of mugs
and if you don't like the pictures,
return them for photo
credit on a future cruise.
Welcome to paradise,
and the name's Dante!
This ship has 5 passenger
decks, A, B, C, D, E.
You'll be staying on deck C.
There's a swimming pool, a health
spa, a beauty salon, a casino...
Hey. Excuse me.
Sir?
I'm starting to get a little upset.
My golf clubs...
Have you found them?
Yes. There's absolutely
no reason to be upset.
They're downstairs in storage,
and I'll bring them up
just as soon as I get this
lovely couple to their cabin.
- We'll see you later.
- (CHATTERING OVER P.A.)
- Hi.
These are the coordinates
for the first leg, Captain.
Thank you.
Thruster is in.
All engines on standby.
Well, let's take her out, then.
(SHIP HORN BLOWS)
Welcome to your suite.
Believe me, in 7 days you'll
be sorry to leave room 6088,
your happy and humble home.
Now, if you two need anything
else, anything at all,
you just call Ashton.
And let me thank you both in
advance for the generous gratuity,
I know you'll be leaving me
at the end of this cruise.
- Just kidding.
- But not really.
Oh. And, you two
have a nice honeymoon.
Oh, we're... We're not...
Not married.
Nope.
Hyah!
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Big enough for you?
Well, size doesn't matter.
You know that.
Yes!
Why? I mean, all of the sudden,
I have Love Boat fever.
It feels really good.
I'm really, truly excited
about being on a cruise ship.
I don't know why.
Maybe they, like, pump drugs
through, like, the air conditioning
system or something like that.
What do you think?
Yeah, you know what I need?
I need lots of those
yummy little drinks
with those highly little
impractical umbrellas in them.
That is what I need.
Yeah, you're looking good.
So who's ready to party on
the big boat besides me?
What's the matter?
You look a little tense.
- Tense?
- Yes.
- No.
- No?
We're here to relax.
- Let's get a drink.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Let's go.
We're going to have
a really good time.
Yeah? You think so?
(GRUNTS)
(SINGING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE)
WOMAN: Yeah!
Yeah!
Love it!
Thank you.
See you later. Bye.
So, what do you want to do?
Do you want to shuffleboard
and then room or...
Or room, then shuffleboard?
(CLEARING THROAT)
Room, room.
Uh-huh. Okay.
I mean, of course,
if it's all right
with your new boyfriend
over there...
Romeo.
- Actually, his name's Geiger.
- Oh?
Yes. Yes, we talked.
Doesn't seem very
interested in golf
for someone who had a fit
about his clubs, though.
No? Really? Why do you say that?
Well...
The tournament's on
right behind him.
He hasn't even glanced at the TV.
You're absolutely right.
Honey, I think we need
to go arrest him.
- Excuse me! Excuse...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Aw, honey, you just wanted a hug.
I just want to give you a hug.
You're so sweet.
Baby, I got to ask you
to do me a favor,
something I've never really
asked you to do before.
What's that?
I need for you to boogie with me.
Oh, no, no, I don't, uh, boogie.
Oh, yes, yes. Just run in place.
Run in place.
Do you feel it? Do you feel it?
Yeah, I think so.
Come on, baby.
(BAND CONTINUES PLAYING)
(HORN BLOWS)
Wake up, boys.
(BEEPS)
See, the misconception
is that fat is bad...
in order to lose fat,
you shouldn't eat fat.
Well, guess what, guys.
False. Your body's
just a giant computer.
Mmm. See, if you don't eat fat,
your body's central
mainframe goes... Whoa!
Whoa!
WOMAN:
Better keep whatever fat I've got.
So you see, we at Fatbusters...
Well, we say fat is your friend.
MAN: Oh, yeah, a good friend, yeah.
I could use a good friend.
Yeah? Here, meet this guy.
Good.
There you go.
(SINGING) Take my whole life, too
I can't help
Falling in love
(APPLAUSE)
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have a question.
Who here would like a peek
at a multimillion-dollar
jewelry collection?
(APPLAUSE)
Okay. Well, on board
we have the Diamond Jewelers
of America with us tonight.
And they would like to
show you something.
Maybe we should get you
a little something.
I'll take a Camel unfiltered.
Honey, aren't you wearing
that nicotine patch?
The only way that patch is gonna
help me is if I roll it and smoke it.
WOMAN: Good evening.
(GASPS) Diamonds.
(PERFORMING TELL ME IS IT TRUE)
Don't bunny-hop.
(MOUTHING)
That's impressive.
I want to learn another language.
Her name is Drew.
She wants to know if
you're my sister.
Oh.
Let her down easy.
She says you're very
beautiful, and...
Our kids will be very beautiful.
Thank you.
Uh, can you picture me as a mom?
I think you're gonna
make a beautiful mother.
Just, uh, don't drive the carpool.
Jeez. Kids... I don't know.
What, kids aren't on the menu?
Kids are on the menu.
It just depends on who's ordering.
- I love it. It's beautiful.
- You're beautiful.
Oh, that'll make a
great picture. Hold on.
Let me get this one.
- Look.
So, can I order a la carte?
I don't know if you're sittin'
in my section or not.
I requested this table.
Are you a good tipper?
Hmm. Depends on the service.
Well, it's always service
with a smile for you.
How about at every meal?
Are you being serious right now?
Well...
- Yeah, I...
- Wow.
I mean...
Wow.
I just, you know, the other day...
I just found out that, you know,
I'm dating a daredevil,
so this is like, you know...
Oh, you're not serious.
You're not. (LAUGHING)
- Hello?
- Annie...
What?
- I'm, uh... I'm a little seasick.
- Huh?
Okay.
Let's go.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(MEN YELLING)
- MAN 1: I'll get the main valve!
- MAN 2: Aah!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome, sir.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
You can't be here right now.
- Huh?
- Sir...
I must be lost.
I saw the lights, thought
this was the casino.
Sir...
Please don't touch those!
Sure could use a drink.
Any of you gambling men?
- (GRUNTS)
- Sir!
Help the gentleman up, please.
Okay, sir, come on.
Let's get him up.
Sir, may we perhaps assist
you to help find your cabin?
Oh, no. I know where it is.
I... I know when I'm not wanted.
You guys just...
watch where you're going.
We'll do just that.
Good night, sir.
Listen, let's get you
back to your room.
Good night.
MAN: (ON RECEIVER)
Satellite looks good, sir.
We should have smooth sailing
for the rest of the night.
Okay, switch us back to autopilot.
MAN: Switching over now, sir.
That's right. Switch us over.
You never let me have any fun.
No fun? You have all
the fun in the world.
We have fun together, don't we?
Whenever you want something,
I buy it for you automatically.
I take you to concerts,
to museums, to movies.
I do all the housework.
Who does the tidying up? I do.
Who does the cooking? I do.
You and I, we have lots of fun.
Don't we, Lolita?
Come here.
(WOMAN SINGING OPERA)
Time for group therapy, boys.
I wouldn't trade you for all
the doctors in the world.
Mmm...
You take care of me,
I'll take care of the ship.
(GUN FIRES)
(GUN FIRING)
Mmm...
Alex?
Annie, Annie.
Hey, I've been looking all
over the ship for you.
Well, maybe you should have
looked in bed, where you left me.
Well, you looked so
beautiful, I didn't, uh...
Want to wake you up.
Yeah, beautiful woman
in bed, naked...
You had to leave. I get that.
So where were you?
- Skeet shooting.
- Skeet shooting?
You went skeet shooting,
but you couldn't...
Ah. Is that our song?
take one day not to go shooting...
- I wish they'd play that over and over again.
- One day?
I need a little fresh air.
After an evening which is tied
as one of the most
embarrassing of my adult life.
If you want me to be honest,
I kind of like the fact
that you got sick.
Well...
Don't quite know how
to respond to that.
Well, all I'm saying
is that I just like
taking care of you, that's all.
And what I said...
When you were joking
about that kid thing...
'Cause for a second, I had thought
you were completely serious.
I thought you were actually
gonna ask, you know...
And last night, when you
were basically blacked out,
I was like, he's a cop, and...
You don't even know his cop number.
My badge number?
Badge number, see? Badge number.
I don't even know what it's called.
Well, what does my badge number
have to do with anything?
Well, the point is is
that if you look at it...
I mean, we basically don't
even know each other.
And...
Um...
To get that serious and...
To make that kind of
commitment, I mean...
It's probably the last thing that
we both need right now, right?
Yeah.
WOMAN: (OVER P.A.) Attention.
If you would like to
reserve water skis,
paddle boats, jet skis,
or wave runners for use
while we're docked at one
of our upcoming ports...
Did you get the feeling that we were
really underdressed last night?
What's this?
Excuse me.
I do believe I had the "do not
disturb" sign on the door.
No, actually, it was
"Make up room, please."
Maybe you flipped the card.
Maybe I flipped the card.
Let's not split hairs.
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Captain on the bridge.
What's wrong, Merced?
I'm late for my guests.
Uh, yeah, I can't explain it, sir.
We're 4 degrees off course.
Well, switch us back
to manual, then.
We tried, sir. The
autopilot won't go down.
Well, try again.
I did. I sent an engineer
to check the mainframe.
It's all normal.
I did. I sent Eric to run
a mainframe diagnostic.
Everything seems normal.
Human error.
Must be human error.
Keep an eye on it.
Yes, sir.
(SINGING) Every move you make...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Every vow you break
Every step you take
I'll be watching you
They were out of size 10s.
You know, I told them size
didn't matter, but, uh...
They wouldn't give them to me.
One more thing.
What?
I'd like to boogie with you.
We're still 4 degrees off course.
Did you check the mainframe, Eric?
Captain Pollard, good evening.
How can you be running the ship
if you're not on the bridge?
Who is running the ship?
Oh, yeah. I am.
What is this? Who are you?
I spent a great many years developing
computer systems for these cruise lines,
including this baby.
And then I got pushed away!
What are you talking about?
That's what really infuriates me.
You don't even know
what I'm talking about.
How dare you!
(GRUNTING)
Traditionally speaking,
isn't it true that the captain
goes down with the ship?
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
I got one more.
Here, stand right here.
Oh, okay.
- This is good.
- Okay.
Captain, sweetheart,
would you mind taking a picture
with my sister and me?
No. Not at all.
Get in the middle.
Right here. Okay.
Say Dallas.
Dallas. Ooh!
Nice tropical shower.
Weather's gonna be
beautiful tonight, ladies.
Good evening.
No, I'm sorry.
Without a jacket, that
dress is not appropriate.
CELESTE: Daddy's right.
I like this dress and it's fine.
No, no, no.
You look like a clown.
No, I don't.
Well, she's fine.
Let her go.
She'll be back.
Ready...
Now.
(CONSOLE BEEPING)
(RUMBLING)
(ALARMS BUZZING)
What the hell is going on?
I don't know, sir.
Where's the chief engineer?
(SINGING) Let me take you, yeah
To that place
You never been before
Open the door to a dream
This almost seems too
perfect, doesn't it?
Want me to step on your feet?
- You already did.
- Oh.
- I meant again.
- (GIGGLES)
(LOUD RUMBLING AND HISSING)
Jesus Christ.
Make it
So beautiful
Hold me close
And don't let go
You know, I left you alone
this morning because
I needed to be alone to think.
Yeah.
See, the one thing that's got me
through everything in my life,
the one thing I could always
trust has been my instinct,
which has never been more
certain than it is right now.
Really?
Yeah.
What are you saying?
What I'm saying is, uh...
- I think that we should...
- (EXPLOSION)
(GASPING AND SCREAMING)
Oh, man, no. No, no, no, no.
Come on, keep dancing.
Keep dancing. Come on.
Hold up. Hold on.
Jesus Christ!
The main pumps are off!
- I'm trying to raise it!
- She ain't pumping out!
Shut down engines 3 and 4!
Get out of here!
Sir!
Look, I'm telling you,
they're not gonna hold.
Sir.
- Find the captain, will you?
- Yes, sir.
Harvey, it's an earthquake!
It can't be! We're at sea!
(SCREAMS)
I don't believe this.
Watch out!
- Watch it!
- Look out!
No!
This is my vacation! Damn it!
I had nothing to do with this.
Shut down engine 3A!
It's not working!
(SCREAMING)
(RUMBLING STOPS)
MAN:
It's all right, it's all right.
It's over. It's over.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm Liza, your cruise director.
Uh, this is only a minor incident.
Everything will be back to
normal in a few moments.
Why do I really not
believe her right now?
(BEEPING)
Turbine malfunction,
structural trauma...
Take a look at these monitors.
We're losing power
all over the ship.
I want all emergency
teams in position.
Get the coast guard on the line.
I don't care!
Where the hell is engine control?
It's dead.
- Try the low frequencies.
- The signal's gone.
We've got nothing.
(THUNDER AND RAIN)
Engine 3A is down, sir.
Can we do anything?
Yeah, look, try and run a
link to the engine room.
Joe, issue hand-held
radios to all the crew.
And please, somebody
find the captain!
- Keep trying.
- The system's not responding.
Yes?
GEIGER: Mr. Juliano.
It looks like the Seabourn
Legend isn't faring too well.
I advise you to start the
evacuation procedure.
Who is this?
Someone you should
start listening to.
I want you to sound the
alarm immediately.
Time is running out.
I can't authorize an evacuation.
The captain is the only
one who can do that.
The captain is dead, Mr. Juliano...
which means you are now responsible
for the people on this ship.
Don't waste time trying to radio the
coast guard or code in an S.O.S.
I've cut off all
outside communication.
You don't understand, maritime
regulations state that in the event...
Mr. Juliano, you are in
command of this vessel.
The authority is yours.
I'll make it easy on
you, Mr. Juliano.
I'd like you to look at the
emergency fire display.
Look at the port side,
"C" deck, section 686
on your display.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
(ALARM SOUNDING)
My God.
Oops.
See what you made me do?
Okay, just wait a minute.
Just wait one minute. Please.
And now the forward
section on the "A" deck
of both sides of the bow thrusters.
Also look at "D" deck
sections 187 and 188.
(BEEPS)
Sir?
All the fires are contained by
fire doors, which I control
and will open if necessary.
I've positioned charges
throughout the ship
and will set them off
without hesitation.
Sir, I think you should
push the button.
Look, how am I supposed to abandon
the ship while it's moving?
The ship will stop in
exactly 3 minutes.
I give you 15 minutes to evacuate.
Now sound the alarm...
Or I'll burn her down.
Sir, I really think you
should push the button.
(SHIP'S HORN AND ALARMS BLARING)
JULIANO: (OVER P.A.)
Attention. Attention, please.
This is the first officer.
All passengers and crew
proceed to the master deck.
The Seabourn Legend is to
be immediately evacuated.
This is not a drill.
I repeat, this is not a drill.
Abandon ship for this?
Does that make any sense?
That doesn't make any sense.
Let's go. Come on.
MAN:
Everybody through the rear door!
- We've got to find Drew.
- We'll find her, sweetheart.
- She can't hear this!
- I know. We'll find her.
No. No, Frank.
No, I have a feeling about this.
Come on.
STEWARD:
Outside to the master deck.
Let's go. Follow me.
Yes, please keep moving.
(SNIFFS)
- Sulfur.
- What?
You smell that? Sulfur.
What do you mean there's sulfur?
Sulfur out of that vent.
I swear I am never
leaving the house again.
JULIANO: Calmly go immediately
to the lifeboat stations.
All hands evacuate.
Engineers and electricians,
abandon your posts
and assist passengers at
your lifeboat assignment.
This way, ladies and gentlemen!
Please hurry! Please hurry!
Everybody, hang on!
Go!
Hey, no!
- No! The doors!
- Let me out!
- This door won't open!
- Let me in there!
(BELL RINGING)
Come on.
This way. Quickly.
Ask him, Rupert, ask him!
Look, I've got to speak
to someone in charge!
He's loading the lifeboats.
You're gonna miss them
if we don't hurry.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Mom!
Ugh! Oh!
Oh, God. (GRUNTS)
MAN: Push away from the ship!
You know what? I wanna
chase something down.
What are you doing?
- It seems odd.
- Yes, it is odd.
They're abandoning ship
in the middle of night.
I'll be right back. I promise you.
Go. Follow the crew.
No. Alex!
- Follow the crew. I'll be right back.
- No! (GROANS) Jeez.
Watch your step, ma'am.
Please, please stay seated.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Huh?
Christ. He's locked us out.
Sir, get yourself to a lifeboat!
Take it easy, man. I'm L.A.P.D.
What? You're what?
What is that?
Have any of these fires
at all been confirmed?
We're loading the lifeboats, sir.
Do you need more
confirmation than that?
Yeah.
(SAFE ALARM RINGING)
Last boat! Everybody
goes right now!
Everybody, into the boat!
That way, folks! Quickly!
- Come on, come on.
- Drew.
Help us, somebody!
Drew wasn't in the room.
Celeste, we have looked everywhere!
You guys, she's probably
on another lifeboat.
But we can't leave without her!
Come on.
I'm sure she's fine.
Come on, let's go! Let's go!
RUPERT: Celeste, there isn't time.
Drew's gotten on another boat.
Now, please...
Who's the officer?
I wanna see my sister!
Go, go, go, go!
Alex, come on! It's the last boat!
Come on, sir, we gotta move!
Move it! Quickly!
Did you find Drew?
She's not on the boat.
Did someone run a count?
She's probably on
another boat, sir.
Now, just get on, okay?
Look, about these fires.
Something's strange.
Your board's all lit up,
this is definitely a sulfur-based
smoke, which makes no sense.
Alex, come on.
I can only lower the boat
when the ship isn't moving.
Now, look, I've got no time left,
and I don't know what
this guy is capable of!
What guy?
We're on our way.
Oh, my God! The boat is moving!
(SCREAMING)
What is happening?
Annie, jump!
JULIANO:
We have to bring it back up!
Hold on to the rails!
Ensign, what's going on?
The winch must be jammed!
You gotta stop the ship!
I don't have any control!
Now get out of the way!
What... What...
What... What are you doing?
That cable will never hold,
and we've got to get them out.
What do you mean "we," Alex?
(YELLING AND SCREAMING)
ANNIE: You got it?
Be careful.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
(SCREAMING)
Oh...
What the hell is he doing?
He said he'd be right back!
We better get that end back up!
If it hits the water on
that angle, it'll collapse!
Don't move!
Please!
Please pull us up!
We're trying.
Just stay calm and keep
the weight balanced.
We'll bring you up one by one.
She's still there!
I know she's still on the ship!
Celeste, where are you going?
ALEX: No, no, no! Don't climb out!
Don't move!
It'll fall!
(SCREAMING)
Oh!
Throw me a rope!
I need to attach a line!
Sweetheart, it's not your fault.
ANNIE: Okay.
Here. Okay.
Watch out!
Now, get the rope! Grab the rope!
I'll get it!
Careful!
I got the rope!
Tie it up to the hull!
Pull the slack!
Be careful!
Okay!
(SCREAMING)
Hold on! Pull them up!
(SCREAMS)
Help!
Alex! Alex! Dante!
Help! Help!
(GRUNTS)
Come on.
- Pull me up, please! Pull!
- ANNIE: Alex!
God. Yes, you are nuts.
Come on. Pull me up.
- I got you.
- Please pull!
ALEX: Get another line!
Quickly! Get another line!
(GRUNTING)
There has to be something else!
The gangplank! Get the gangplank!
Alex. Alex.
Alex.
Hi, uh, get everybody
on here if you can.
Okay.
Okay. Thanks, man.
Thank you.
Okay, thanks.
ANNIE: Okay.
Thank you.
That's the last one, sir.
(CONSOLE BEEPING)
Sir, it's Merced.
(RADIO BEEPS)
Yes?
We have a situation on the bridge.
I bet we do!
Keep everybody together, Rudy.
I'll be on the bridge.
Stay with the passengers.
(ALARM RINGING)
It's the radar.
At first I thought this was a heavy
fog bank, but it's not moving.
(TYPING)
JULIANO: Saint Martin.
Well, there is a harbor
on Saint Martin.
He must be stopping
us on the island.
What's the heading?
It is full at southeast 165.
You think that's where
he's taking us?
You think that's the harbor?
He's taking us to the cliffs
right next to the harbor.
He's gonna slam us into a wall.
How long before we hit?
Sir, get back with the
other passengers.
How much time do we got?
I'm the first officer on this
ship, okay, and you're...
Now, look, you've lost
control of autopilot,
so there's got to be a hardwire
link to the engine control.
Yes, that's exactly right, sir.
But he's running the whole thing by
remote and there's nothing you can do.
There's gotta be a transmitter.
We gotta find the transmitter.
A transmitter? So how's he
transmitting the fires?
The fires don't exist.
They're not real.
Smoke canisters. Stun grenades.
Probably put them in the air ducts.
They're small.
They roll...
Like...
These.
Golf balls.
Golf balls, golf balls.
Geiger. Let's go get him right now.
Get his cabin number.
We'll get him. I'll get him.
We're locked out.
Where are the skeet guns?
Right here.
(THUMP)
(SCREAMS)
Why's everyone trying to kill me?
- What happened? Are you okay?
- Ow. Ow.
JULIANO:
Stay down, stay down. You're okay.
I can't override it. He's
changed all the access codes.
We have a very sick boy.
GEIGER: Exactly.
Do you think I'd be doing this
if I still had my health?
It ends now.
I know who you are.
I know you, too.
You look a little wet.
You see, Alex...
I designed this whole
autopilot system.
My company sold it off to almost
every shipping line in the world,
but when I got sick, they fired me.
I had no defense. They
just threw me away.
But now, I have a more
aggressive defense system.
- (BEEPS)
- Tell me, Alex,
did you ever have a false
sense of security?
(GRUNTING)
Everybody, to the deck!
Go! Go! Go!
(CHUCKLES)
Nothing's secure, Alex.
(MEN COUGHING)
That was odd.
What, you call that odd?
What kind of cop are you?
You're gonna get us all killed!
No, that's his plan.
Where's engine control?
What? Engine control?
We're gonna stop the ship,
then we're gonna get him.
I want you on the upper deck
with the other passengers!
Fine! I'll find it on my own!
Merced, go with him!
Sir, he's highly irrational.
You're an officer on this ship.
Now, make sure he
doesn't touch a thing!
Ashton, you okay? Come on, get up.
- MAN: Keep it moving.
- Annie.
- Yeah?
- They won't organize a search,
but I know Drew didn't get away.
- They'll find her.
- She's got to be here somewhere!
- Just keep it moving.
(HOLLOW METAL POUNDING)
This way!
Hello, miss. This way.
Dante, stop it. Do you hear that?
- Listen.
- Yeah,
I hear something coming
from down there.
Where? Show me. Come on.
Harder!
Can anybody hear? Hello!
Alejandro, I don't like this.
I really don't like this.
It's coming from
down here somewhere.
ALEJANDRO: Anyone!
Hello!
Is anybody in there?
Yes!
Yes, we're trapped!
Get us the hell out of here!
We're trying! Is there a
little girl in there? Drew?
No, there is no little girl inside!
Just big women!
Excuse me!
I mean, normal-sized women!
Come on, get us out of here, will ya?
(GRUNTS)
Oh, my God, there's smoke
coming out of the vent!
Everybody get back!
It's coming out everywhere!
Ow! We're trying.
Try to block the vent!
Don't worry. We'll get you out!
What the hell are you doing?
They told us to block the vents.
She's right.
I'll help you, lady.
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
This smoke's gonna kill us all.
Everybody just hang on!
We'll get you out in a second!
Help me, Harvey!
I'm trying to save your life!
Just hang on!
Okay. What is this?
Try that.
This won't work.
Just try it anyway.
I'll find something else.
I told you this won't work!
(COUGHING)
Oh, my God. It's coming out everywhere.
Harv, give me your pants!
My pants? No one else is
taking off their pants.
I took off mine.
I wanna know why she hasn't
taken anything off yet!
'Cause I'm not wearing
any underwear, Harvey.
Oh.
WOMAN: I can't breathe.
MAN: Come on, hurry up!
Come on!
What do we have?
Yeah, this'll do.
This will do.
Did you try to close the fuel
tanks manually, cut the power?
Yeah, but he's sealed off all
access to engine room 4.
Which of these controls
the autopilot?
MERCED: I don't know.
Look, I'm the navigator. I'm not
familiar with this equipment.
Oh, you're not familiar?
I see.
Are you...
Familiar with this?
Sir, this is Merced
in engine control!
He's smashing up all the equipment!
Do you copy?
Which of these is not
hooked up to the computer?
Look, there's plenty not
hooked up to the computer
but nothing that
overrides his program.
Then we have to fool his program.
We cannot stop the ship.
I wanna slow it down.
What you gonna do?
You gonna let the air
out of our tires?
What are these buttons?
What are these switches?
Don't you touch them!
They open the ballast doors!
You wanna flood the ship?
Sir, this is Merced!
Does anybody copy?
Hello? Somebody answer me!
We're gonna flood the
ship just like you said.
What are you talking about?
Might slow her down.
Right, now, you shut up!
You shut your mouth!
I never said that!
If we take on too much
water, we'll all go down.
Sir! Somebody answer me! Lis...
Flood it.
It's not working!
Will you hurry up?
Wait. Dante, I think
I've got something.
Whoa!
Everybody, back off!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
- Yeah, we found the key.
- (CHAIN SAW REVVING)
- What?
All right. Okay, okay.
Kick. Can you kick it?
Look out!
- (CHAIN SAW REVVING)
- (SCREAMS)
Can you get out?
Can you guys get out?
If you'll back off with the saw.
What?
If you'll back off with the
saw, we'll give it a try!
Oh, sorry!
Sorry. Sorry.
How much longer?
Look, I've never let a million
gallons of water into a ship before.
Give me a second.
I've got 3 watertight
doors to close,
and I've got to shut off
these sensors as well.
Where's this?
That's the ballast room.
That's right underneath us.
That's what we're flooding.
All right, watertight
doors are closed.
Ballast doors should
open any minute.
ALEX: Shit!
Close it! Close it! Close it!
You just told me to open them!
Follow me.
I can't close it just like that.
Don't let go of me!
(GASPS)
Hold on!
I'll hold on.
You okay?
You're gonna be fine.
Huh?
In case anything happens...
to us,
you want me to know that...
You... You...
Love me...
And that you're gonna
be 15 next month.
Relationships based on extreme
circumstances, they rarely work out.
LIZA: This way, everybody!
What's going on? Why has
the evacuation stopped?
SINGER: Stopped? When did it start?
Are we sinking?
Are we gonna die here?
The important thing is for
everybody just to stay calm.
You don't even work on this ship!
I've been in worse
situations than this,
and panicking does
not help. Trust me.
We have our life vests.
We can jump off the ship.
You'd get sucked into the propellers.
I wouldn't recommend it.
Oh, God, that would suck.
Alex.
LIZA: Oh, my God. Drew.
Where you been, huh?
Is she okay?
We'll find your mom.
- She all right?
- Yeah.
Come on, sweetheart.
- ALEX: You okay?
- ANNIE: Yeah, I'm fine.
What's happening?
Why did the ship start up again?
Why... Why... Why did
you leave me upstairs?
We have a situation.
I know we have a situation.
What? What?
Geiger's taken over the ship.
Geiger. I'm-not-looking-
at-my-golf-game Geiger?
No, Geiger... "I'm a
computer psycho..."
Geiger... "I designed
all the software..."
And Geiger... "I can
blow up everything."
Why would he do that? I don't know.
- Where is he?
- He's everywhere. Come up here.
(DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS)
That's him.
What?
Look, you go up to the
top deck with everyone.
You stay. You stay, and you wait.
Hey, you don't have
to save this ship.
Oh...
Freeze!
Drop the weapon.
Don't shoot.
It's not a gun,
it's just a computer.
Drop it, asshole.
Where's your friend Annie?
She's cute.
It would be a shame if
anything happened to her.
Hit the floor now!
I was just trying to
make conversation.
I'm putting it down now,
real slow.
(GUNSHOT)
(COCKS SHOTGUN)
GEIGER: (OVER P.A.)
The irony of my situation, Alex
is that dedication to job and
devotion to the company...
was repaid with a terminal illness.
(CHUCKLES)
You see, computers generate
electromagnetic fields, which over time
can cause severe copper poisoning.
I'm a smart guy, Alex and
even I didn't know that.
I would have really appreciated
some understanding
from upper management,
if you know what I mean.
Okay, is everybody okay?
We're fine.
But, no. They dropped me.
They treated me like
I never existed.
- Where are you going?
- I'll go find him.
Hang on. Wait!
Now, I'm just gonna
do whatever I can...
To get whatever I can get.
You're not gonna stop me.
This time it's good-bye
for good, Alex.
(DOOR SLIDING SHUT)
How you gonna stop
me now, my friend?
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING LOUDER)
Damn it.
Shit.
(STEREO TURNS ON)
(SINGING) I feel the earth move
(FIRE ALARM SOUNDING)
Oh, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
I've heard that music before.
Yeah, it's the music they
pipe in all over the ship.
No, no, no. I've heard
this music before.
Uh, ship-shopping music.
He's in the mall.
There's a fire in there.
Well, don't worry.
The flames won't get
past the fire doors.
Alex.
Alex, Alex.
- JULIANO: Don't touch that!
- Okay.
I need a... I need a...
I need my saw. I need my saw.
Shit! Alex!
Alex! Oh, God.
Don't touch anything.
Don't touch anything!
I know where to release
the fire doors.
Don't open the door.
Don't. It's a trap.
There's something in the door.
Baby, we can't get in to you.
Calm down. What does it look like?
Wait. What does it look like?
Okay, it's green...
Like a spray deodorant can.
I don't know. Can't think.
Okay. It's a grenade.
What?
There's a number on it. There
should be a number on it.
Uh, okay, yeah.
It's L-1619...
Magnum.
- Is the pin out?
- What?
- No, the pin's still in,
- but it's attached to a wire.
- Yeah.
You're gonna have to tie
the spoon to the grenade.
- Spoon? What?
- With a string.
Oh, baby, don't say grenade.
Okay. A string.
Your shoelace!
Come on.
I got it.
That's it.
Okay, all right.
Okay.
Okay, be real careful.
ANNIE:
All right. Here it goes. Uh...
You gotta hurry up.
Okay, Okay.
Got it. Got it.
Got it. What now?
Pull the pin out and
remove the grenade.
Uh... Uh...
You pull out the pin, and
I will pull out the grenade.
- Okay.
- On the count of three. One...
Two...
Three.
(GRUNTING)
Where is it? Where is it?
Where is it?
It's in your hand.
Where? Take it out. Take it out!
Take it out. Take it out.
Got it? Take it.
- I got it.
- Okay, got it?
- Yeah.
- Alex!
You can open the door now.
Okay.
(BEEPING)
No.
Here's some more dry towels.
Thank you.
I am so sorry I yelled at you.
That's Okay, Dad.
I'm okay.
Okay.
Where's Alex?
"Where's Alex?"
(COUGHING)
Come over here.
- Just sit down. Don't talk. Don't move.
- I'm okay.
You're not okay. Stop saying that.
All right?
Are you okay?
I don't think so.
What?
He's adjusting starboard.
ANNIE: What does that mean?
Does that mean right, left, around the
island, what? What does that mean?
No. Right into the island.
ANNIE: We're moving again.
JULIANO: He's turning us
1/2 a degree starboard.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on, guys.
We're getting closer.
Okay. I'm cutting the
serial port connection.
- Anything?
- Uh...
No, we're still locked out.
Come on.
MERCED: Hey, we're moving.
We have control again.
No, we're still dead here.
Are you sure, sir,
because we're turning.
It's him.
It's him, it's him, it's him.
He's on board.
Geiger's still on board.
Hey, guys. Guys, maybe
these people can help.
JULIANO: Hand me those.
Right there.
He's taking us right
into an oil tanker.
What?
You're right.
She's anchored 16 miles out,
and we are doing 17.8 knots.
Well, how long till they move?
From starting their
engines, 30 minutes.
There's no chance they're gonna
get out of our way in time.
So, what... What...
What does that mean?
Oh, man!
Uh, he's turning us another 1/4.
Ah! Damn it. (GROANS)
Can we turn the ship
without the rudder?
MERCED:
The bow thrusters would do it.
JULIANO: We can't get there now.
You guys flooded the access.
Yeah, well, we also messed
up his program, sir.
No, you almost sunk us.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Let's take a wrench and
dump it into the engine
and bust the transmission like
a car 'cause I've done that.
With all due respect,
this is not your car.
- This is a cruise liner.
- ALEX: She's right. It's a propeller.
We got to stop the propeller.
You could wedge something
into it underneath the ship,
(STAMMERING) like a steel cable.
This is not my
suggestion, obviously.
Great idea. I'll go under the ship.
No, you won't.
No, you won't. That's
not what I meant.
That's a stupid idea.
- No, it's a great idea.
- No.
It's suicide. These blades
are 12 feet across.
They'll suck you in and kill you.
Hey. Hey, Dino, I got one for you.
Okay, who played the German
captain in The Enemy Below?
Curt Jurgens.
Down the next stairwell
on the left,
straight to the bowels of the ship.
Bowels. That doesn't
sound very good.
How much time left?
Not very much. We better hurry.
Mayday, Mayday.
This is Seabourn Legend bearing
80 degrees east-northeast.
Engine and steering
control nonfunctional.
I repeat. Nonfunctional.
Where are we going?
Eindhoven Lion.
Eindhoven Lion, come in.
This is Seabourn Legend.
Eindhoven Lion, this
is Seabourn Legend.
Come in, Eindhoven Lion.
This is the only way out.
- This all the diving gear?
- Yeah.
Okay, here it goes.
- (BEEPING)
- Huh?
- You think that ship's gonna rescue us?
- What else could it be?
Alex, maybe this isn't
such a hot idea.
Maybe you should just leave
the propeller alone, huh?
We have to stop the ship.
There's not much time left.
Are you sure this is gonna hold?
Yeah. We use those lines
all over the ship.
ANNIE: Yeah? Well, guess what?
He's not going all over the ship.
- He's going under the ship, all right?
- Annie, Annie. It's okay. It'll hold.
Hold on. Let me lock it.
All right.
Hey.
(OXYGEN HISSES)
Annie.
What?
4296...
589J.
I don't know what that is.
What is that?
It's my badge number.
It's 4296589J.
Thank you.
I'll be right back.
Here's the guideline.
Feed it into the propeller, and
it will pull the heavy cable in.
- Not too much slack.
- Okay, okay, okay. I've got him.
ANNIE: He's getting too close.
Okay, Okay, he's close enough.
Stop it now.
Come on, baby. Let it go.
Let it go.
(GRUNTS)
It's taking the cable.
It's working. It's working!
ANNIE: Well, then let's
get him up then, huh?
- Come on.
- Pull him back up.
It's stuck. It's snagged.
The lines are crossed.
We have to bring him up.
Come on. Now. Do something!
(GRUNTING)
- it's sucking him in.
- We gotta get him out of there!
(SHIP CREAKING)
18.
Come on, baby.
17.5.
They're doing it.
They're slowing us down.
(BEEPING)
(CREAKING)
Oh, no, you don't.
(GRUNTING)
ANNIE: We gotta get him up.
JULIANO:
Come on, come on. Keep pulling.
Pull.
JULIANO: Pull him up.
Keep pulling.
What the hell's happening?
It's stuck again!
Get him up! Get him up!
It's not gonna hold.
(GRUNTS) Won't go any faster.
Won't go any faster!
JULIANO: Watch out!
Get back! (GRUNTS)
Think I broke my arm.
Alex! Alex!
Alex.
Come on. Hold on. Come on. Hold on.
JULIANO: We've got him now.
ANNIE: Are you all right?
What happened?
I don't know, something just...
Let him go.
You slowed her down, but
you're not gonna stop her.
Annie, I don't think your boyfriend
appreciates the logistics involved
in ramming the most
automated ship in the world
into a loaded fuel tanker
with no set anchor path.
Let her go.
Maybe you can spend the rest of your
days in some nice mental hospital
sticking leeches to your ass.
So you met my nurses.
They clean the copper
out of my blood.
Doctors gave me a couple
of years to live!
Those bloodsuckers might
give me a few more.
You walk away now, and there's
a chance I might not kill you.
Listen to you.
Let him go.
Now!
Go ahead.
Mr. Juliano, we'll be getting off.
I hope you don't mind but
I'll be taking Annie with me
as a little extra insurance.
You know the one-armed
freestyle, don't you?
(GRUNTS)
Hey! Come on, or you'll join them!
This way.
(GASPING)
Hold on, hold on.
(ALARM BUZZES)
I can't believe they can't see us.
How can they miss us?
I can't get her on the radio!
She's not responding.
She's closing in at 14
knots, bearing 166.4.
She's heading straight into us.
Get the anchors up now!
- MAN: Yes, sir!
- (ALARM SOUNDS)
Which way did they go?
The marina.
He's going to jump ship.
- You all right?
- I'm okay.
Hurry up!
(BELL RINGING)
Get moving!
Get off of me! Get off of me!
GEIGER: Very physical, aren't we?
Okay...
That way.
Down the stairs. Hold it!
We're going for a little ride.
Come on.
Can't let you go now.
You're my little hostage.
Come on!
Don't touch me!
Get down.
Get down!
All right.
That's it.
So...
How do you like your
vacation so far?
- Sit down!
- Ow.
You better hang on.
Annie!
Alex?
Alex!
Need a hand?
Hold on. I got you.
I don't think you want to
be on that ship now, Annie.
(YELLING)
- You know your way around the ship?
- Yeah.
You're okay?
What happened?
Alex, can you hear me?
I don't like this at all.
- Oh, my God.
- Jeez, we're coming in too fast!
How could this happen
on our honeymoon?
Wait a minute.
Oh, my God. Why don't we stop?
Why don't we stop?
Okay, everyone, move
away from the windows!
Away from the windows!
MAN: Brace yourself for the crash.
(ALARM SOUNDS)
How long before we have power?
Seven or eight minutes, sir.
In 8 minutes we'll be blown out
of the water! Now move it!
Speed the engines full power.
MAN: Prepare for hard forward turn.
Alex, if you can hear me,
use the ship's intercom.
Left, Alex, go to the left.
JULIANO: (OVER P.A.)
Alex, can you hear me?
If you can hear me,
use the ship's intercom.
I can hear you.
We're running out of time.
All right, look.
Which way to the bow thrusters?
You flooded it. There's
no way to get there.
I can get there.
Just talk me through it.
Okay. The bow thrusters
are 2 large wheels
connected by a small shaft.
Now, you can find them
at the end of the shaft
that runs below the
bilge pump room.
The bilge pump room.
Do you copy?
Yeah, copy that.
Look, stay with us.
You talk us through it,
following your voice.
Okay, you're in section BT-1.
Now, at the end of the
hallway, you'll find a hatch.
Now, that'll bring you
into the bilge pump room.
Hatch. Hatch.
Now, it's at the same
level as where you are,
so there must be some air.
Have you got it?
You're going to have
to lose the vest.
What do you mean, lose my vest?
We're going under.
Damn, man.
(HORN BLOWS)
Let's get the hell out of here!
Move away from the railing!
WOMAN: Harvey, wait for me!
Come on, over against the wall!
What's going on?
At the far side,
there's a short slide.
Now, that will lead right
into the bow thruster room.
Alex, can you hear me?
You're getting very close.
(HORN BLOWS)
The bow thrusters,
they're 2 large wheels
connected to a shaft that
will turn the propeller.
Now, when you find the wheel,
turn it as fast you can.
Hold on, hold on.
You only turn one wheel at a time.
If you turn them both,
you're canceling yourself out.
Make sure you turn the
starboard wheel only.
Okay, look.
We have to play tag.
I'll go down first.
You follow me in 15 seconds.
All right.
They're turning us. Sir,
they're turning us.
Yes. Yes, it's working.
(GASPS)
(HORN BLOWS)
No, no, no, no.
WOMAN: Make it stop.
(HORN BLOWS)
Oh, my God! Everybody down!
We're going to crash!
(SCREAMING)
Oh, God!
I think we did it!
We turned it!
Get down!
Whoo!
- I do believe we have a miss!
- (COMPUTER BEEPS)
Impossible!
No! No!
They did it.
We made it.
Oh, Jack.
Yes. Yes.
- I hope somebody got that on tape.
- Yeah.
(SQUEALING)
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
Aw, shit.
Mom.
Hey!
We got to get out of here.
DANTE: Yeah, no kidding. Come on.
Come on!
Come on, hurry up!
They're coming right at us!
Come on! Faster than that!
MAN:
Hey, we have the right of way here!
Sorry! Excuse us!
No way!
That was close!
To the bridge!
(ALARM BEEPING)
Where's anchor control?
We got to stop her.
What? Anchor control?
We can't drop it.
The ship's moving too fast.
- Did you see Annie?
- No.
MERCED: I got it! I got it.
JULIANO: No. No anchor
can stop a moving ship.
MERCED:
It's moving. It's going down.
I can feel it. We're slowing down.
JULIANO: No. Too fast...
It's not going to hold.
WOMAN: Harvey!
MAN: Get in the corner!
Brace yourselves!
Oh, my God! We're doomed!
We're not going to stop!
(ALARM BEEPING)
Drop the other one.
I'm telling you.
We're still too fast.
It's stuck.
God, no. No.
(BANGS)
Where's the horn? Where's the horn?
How can there not be a horn?
Wait a minute. There's got to be
a horn around here somewhere.
(YELLING)
Where's he going?
Oh, shit!
MERCED:
What are you doing with the wheel?
Huh?
It doesn't work!
What?
Jan, hold this for a sec.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, no. No, no, no.
(SCREAMING)
MERCED: I can't believe it.
This is slowing us down...
Nine knots.
Jeez!
Oh, man! Move us out!
Huh?
This isn't happening.
Oh, no. No more. Not again.
I found it! I found it! I found it!
(TONES SOUND)
Everybody get out of the way!
There's a big boat coming!
Please!
Now! Run!
Jump! Swim!
Come on, people,
move out of the way!
We don't have brakes!
This is not a dream! Jump!
Abandon your ship!
Oh, my God. We're mowing them down!
Stop!
MERCED: It... It's helping.
Seven knots.
Turn right! Turn right!
Look out!
Whoa!
Oh, shit!
(SCREAMING)
Ow. Ow. Ow. Ow.
MAN: Two bedrooms...
Dining room, kitchen, nook.
Mommy, there's a big boat.
I know. There are a lot
of big boats here, honey.
What a cute boy...
And very smart of you
to notice all the ships.
The walls are a soft
European eggshell...
JULIANO: My God, it'll
take forever to stop us.
Harvey?
(SCREAMING)
Quick!
We're not going to fit!
It's too tight!
(BARKING)
Get down!
(SCREAMING)
Six knots!
What? What? I can't hear you.
(GROANS)
It's coming.
Five knots!
(BARKING)
(SCREAMING)
(HONKS HORN)
Four...
Stop!
Here it comes now!
It's really big, Mom.
Oh, my God!
Get down!
(SCREAMS)
Two knots!
Almost stopped!
(BARKING)
Oh, no!
Get down!
(RINGS)
Zero.
(CAR ALARM)
My car!
(BARKING)
I got to find Annie.
JULIANO: Shit! She's going over!
DANTE:
We're tipping! We're tipping!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Ow.
We're docked.
We're docked!
I can't believe it!
We're safe.
Zero.
(SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE)
Say what?
Bad luck to run ship over town.
No shit, bad luck, man.
I just bought a condo here.
My God.
You all right?
Yeah. I think I broke my other arm.
The ship's parked in
the middle of town...
But, hey, it could've been worse.
I'm not sure how, exactly,
but it could've been worse.
I got to get my girl. Thank you.
(GROANS)
Sorry.
Be careful.
I'll go check on the others.
Looks like your vacation
is almost over.
Just stay away from me,
or you're going to get hurt.
I swear to God.
What are you going to do, Annie?
Splash water on me?
I'm driving now.
Hey, Annie! Hey!
Annie!
Come back! You stay with me!
You're my hostage!
I need a boat!
Can I help you?
I'm a cop.
I need to borrow your boat.
What?
You've got to be kidding me.
This is a joke, right?
You're messing with my head.
Come on, man, you've
got to be kidding me!
Can't you see I'm on a date?
My name is Alex Shaw, L.A.P.D.
This is a matter of life
and death. Start the boat.
L.A.P.D.? I'm in the
Caribbean, man.
What are you doing here?
WOMAN: Stop him, Maurice.
Do you know how many hours of therapy
I've had because of you guys?
And that shit's expensive!
You drive.
Hey, hey, where are you going?
No!
Hey! Annie!
Okay, Okay, take it easy, man!
- This boat cost me $150,000.
- Whoo!
That way.
MAURICE: Okay. That's it!
That's it! I want a
promissory note right now!
(WOMAN WHOOPING)
Give it!
Let go of me! Ow!
GEIGER: Do we have a fiery temper?
ANNIE: You have no idea!
GEIGER: There she is.
Look! Fireworks!
It's her.
- What?
- That way, fast.
Nah, I can't drive that fast!
There's shallow reefs
around here! Shit!
Get as close to that
plane as you can.
Give me one good reason.
If you don't, I'll throw you over.
Okay.
That's a good reason.
Almost at speed!
Don't! Don't you...
Ow! Let me go!
I think you better stay with me.
- Get closer!
- What?
Let me go!
You want to go? I'll let you go...
At about 10,000 feet!
Get me closer!
Huh?
He's going to shoot the plane!
Nice shot.
Let's see if he can hold on now!
- Follow me!
- MAURICE: Huh?
Let go!
He was supposed to let go.
No, no, he's reeling himself in!
Follow him! Follow him!
Oh, you little shit.
Here we go! (GRUNTING)
No!
No, don't!
Come here!
Oh, God.
Alex! Alex!
Annie!
- Hi.
Hi.
Come on.
Hold on!
Aah!
What's he riding that banana
peel for? What's he doing?
Aah!
(SCREAMING)
(SIREN WAILING)
MAN: (OVER P.A.) Abandon ship.
All the crew members,
abandon ship immediately.
MAURICE:
It's gonna blow, it's gonna blow!
Jump, fool! Get off that thing!
Jump!
I hope they can hold their
breath a long time.
Come on, don't run out of air.
Me not see 'em. Me think
they dead. They gone.
They're not gone.
WOMAN:
There they are! There they are!
MAURICE:
Hey, over here! Hey, this way!
(LAUGHING)
Here, come on. I got you. Come on.
Come on, hurry up.
Hurry up, come on. It's gonna blow.
Hurry up, hurry up.
Come on, it's gonna blow.
(CACKLING)
Untie 'em, untie 'em.
You're all right.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
You all right?
I was just so scared.
I was so scared.
I didn't think I was gonna
make it there for a second.
Thank you.
Look what I found in
international waters.
Whoo!
This really is paradise.
I got something for you.
Wow.
You want to wear this for a while?
How long were you thinking?
50 years.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Can I make all the travel
plans from now on?
Deal.
(YOU CAN GET IT IF YOU
REALLY WANT PLAYING)
Hello.
Mr. Kenter.
Oh, Annie.
- Oh, you're back again.
- Yeah.
Hope you don't mind.
I kind of requested you.
I wanted to make up for last week.
Why would I mind?
Gosh, uh, I'm sure it'll
go much better today.
Oh, yeah, it will.
Had some problems...
A little nervous,
yeah, a little bit.
Okay, Mr. Kenter, here we go.
(HORN HONKS)
Sorry, Mr. Kenter, but that
bus was going way too fast.
I noticed that.
Uh, make a left here.
Got it. Excuse me.
Thank you, thank you.
(HORN HONKS)
(CRASHING)
(LIVELY SONG PLAYING)
(NEVER GIVE UP PLAYING)