[ The outfield's "your love"
plays ]
¶ Josie's on a vacation
far away ¶
¶ come around
and talk it over ¶
¶ so many things
that I want to say ¶
Tammy: ¶ so many things
¶ you know I like my girls
a little bit older ¶
¶ I just wanna use your love
tonight ¶
hoo!
Uh, uh.
¶ I don't wanna lose your love
tonight ¶
uh.
¶ I ain't got many friends
left to talk to ¶
[ volume increases ]
¶ No one's around
when I'm in trouble ¶
¶ no one's around
¶ you know
I'd do anything for you ¶
¶ stay the night
but keep it undercover ¶
¶ I just wanna use your love
tonight ¶
¶ whoa ¶
oh, yeah.
¶ I don't wanna lose your love
tonight ¶
[ tires screech, crash ]
[ Music stops ]
[ Groans ]
Shit.
[ Sighs ]
What the hell?
Oh.
Aw, man.
Not another one.
[ Sighs ]
I shouldn't have been looking
for my chapstick, buddy.
[ Sighs, sniffles ]
You're just stunned, I think.
Yeah.
I mean, you got the wind
knocked out of you.
I did that on a jungle gym,
had the wind
knocked out of me, too.
You'll...
I'll give you a couple seconds.
You'll be fine.
Yeah.
Come on.
Maybe you just need a little...
a little mouth-to-mouth, man?
I'll give you...
maybe that'll help.
I just... I don't want you
to bite my mouth.
[ Blowing ]
There you go.
That's helpin'.
Okay, come on.
Let's walk it off, man.
Get up on all fours.
You can...
[ grunts ]
Ow! Aah!
[ Chuckles ]
Attaboy! Run!
Look at you go!
There you go!
Got a good gait.
Yes!
[ Music resumes ]
[ Car rattling ]
¶ Lo-o-o-o-se ¶
¶ your lo-o-o... ¶
[ engine shuts off,
music stops ]
Keith: Where are
my chicken sandwiches, Larry?
Come on. Let's go. Let's go.
Can I take your order?
Somebody get these.
Oh, my God.
Tammy, get over here.
You're late again.
Do own a watch much?
I know I'm late. A deer
jumped out of nowhere on 13.
You look like crud.
Oh, my God.
Get off the floor.
Tammy, my office... now!
I'm coming, Keith. God.
Tammy, do you know
how I got to where I am?
Sucking dick
and kissin' ass.
[ Knock on wall ]
'Scuse me, Keith.
We need some more ketchup.
Okay.
English, though, javier.
This is America.
It was English.
That wasn't English.
Is that blood?
Yeah.
A deer hit my car
on the way in.
You should maybe go
see a doctor.
Yeah. No kidding, right?
Okay, thanks, javier.
That's great advice.
See you later.
Tammy, I am terminating
your employment
at topperjack's.
You've gotta be
shitting me.
No. I'm terminating
your employment.
I need your badge.
What ba...
you mean my name tag?
Yes. Exactly.
I need your badge.
I need your badge back.
It's not a badge.
It's a shitty name tag,
and you made me buy it
with my own money.
That's company policy.
I need it back.
Well, I need you to stop
sweating through your shirts
and grossing everybody out.
[ Exhales sharply ]
It is hot.
And when it's hot,
people sweat.
That's how it is.
Not like that.
Yeah, well,
do you know what?
That shit's medical.
I've tried...
I've... listen.
Tammy, you have
already been fired.
I have already terminated
your employment.
You are at least
40 seconds fired,
so please exit
the topperjack's.
Fine. You know what?
I'm gonna give you this.
Tammy.
I got it here.
It's your middle finger.
No. Poom!
Read between the lines.
I knew that you were
gonna do it, Tammy,
so it's not as good.
I get it, Tammy.
Pa-poo! You get that?
What is that?
Little version of this.
Hey, don't let a deer hit you
on the way out.
You dick.
You know what?
Don't let
these ketchup packets
get stuck
in your gross armpits!
You'll have to buy new shirts,
you dick!
Those are
topperjack's supplies.
You are no longer
an employee of topperjack's.
Oh.
Yeah, that shit's
contaminated now.
For overtime due, Keith.
Overtime due.
Tammy, just get out.
Enjoy the special sauce.
Do not touch
the tower deluxe burgers.
Those buns
are all still good.
Just change the hats.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
I'm calling the police.
Uh, just thought you should know
that the meat here
is real shitty.
Oh, God.
Real, real, real shitty.
That's the truth.
That's not true.
That's not chicken.
I don't know what it is,
but it's not bird.
It's 110% chicken.
Bird doesn't come out
of squeezy tubes.
My gut fear...
it's mostly dick and beak.
[ Woman gasps ]
She's disgruntled.
You know what?
[ Gasps ]
Aah, my elbow!
Poom!
Later, loser.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Willie Nelson's
"bring me sunshine" plays ]
¶ Bring me sunshine
in your smile ¶
[ tires screech ]
Aw, are you...
[ Tires screech ]
¶ Bring me laughter
all the while ¶
shit!
You kidding me?
¶ In this world where we live ¶
¶ there should be
more happiness ¶
[ clank ]
¶ so much joy you can give ¶
¶ to each brand new
bright tomorrow ¶
aw, man.
¶ Make me happy
through the years ¶
ugh. Shit.
¶ Never bring me any tears ¶
little help?! Little help?!
¶ Let your arms be as warm ¶
little help?! Come on!
¶ As the sun from up above ¶
[ Scoffs ] Yeah, karma!
¶ Bring me fun,
bring me sunshine ¶
yeah, we'll see.
¶ Bring me love ¶
¶ bring me sunshine
in your smile ¶
¶ bring me laughter
all the while ¶
¶ in this world where we live ¶
¶ there should be
more happiness ¶
¶ so much joy you can give ¶
¶ to each brand new
bright tomorrow ¶
¶ make me happy
through the years ¶
¶ never bring me any tears ¶
oh, God.
Hey, Greg. I'm home.
I think your ringer's off.
I've been calling you.
That asshole Keith fired me.
Can you believe that shit?
Like I even want to work there.
[ Sighs ]
¶ Feel for you, baby ¶
what's going on here?
Hey, t-Tammy.
Wow.
You're home so early.
I'm sorry you got fired.
Shut up, missi.
Why are you in my house
making my husband dinner?
Uh, actually,
I made her dinner.
You're gonna get
your ass kicked.
Yeah, you hungry? You want
to eat my fist for di...
oh! Ow! Shit!
I am so sorry, Tammy.
You startled me.
Keep your dirty fingers
out of my mouth.
You scratched my tongue.
I'm leaving you, Greg.
I'm taking the household money
and gettin' out of here.
God! Nice, Greg.
You have to cheat
with the neighbor.
And you can forget about me
feeding your stupid cats, missi.
I'm divorcing you,
and I'm suing you, bitch.
For what?
You... for being an asshole.
That's what I'm suing you for.
Why is there only $63
in here, Greg?
Whatever.
I'm keeping all of it.
Ow, shit!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
[ Panting ]
I feel great, pervs.
Assholes.
You two deserve each other.
Shit.
God damn it.
Just don't touch anything.
And don't let her
touch my underwear.
[ Voice breaking ] You know,
you never made me dinner.
Not even once.
And it smells really good, too.
[ Door slams ]
Yeah, I'll see you in court.
I hope you both choke
on your shitty dinner.
Assholes.
Missi Jenkins is a whore!
And I kicked her ass!
Kicked her stupid ass.
Don't call me, Greg,
when she dumps you,
'cause I won't call you back.
No fucking way.
I'm gonna be too busy
fucking models and shit.
Mom. Mom!
[ Knocks on door ]
Mom, open the door.
Greg's cheating on me,
mom.
What?!
I know.
What a jerk, right?
What happened?
I went home
after a shitty day
and Greg and missi Jenkins
are having, like,
a really romantic dinner
at our dining room table
and Greg made it.
Okay, well, then
I'm... I'm sorry.
That's terrible. I...
yeah, I'm not exactly
thrilled about it myself.
I just need
to borrow your car.
Why? Where's yours?
Mine is smoking
on highway 13
'cause a deer jumped out
in front of me.
Okay? Can I just
have your car
so I can get out
of this shitty town?
I will drive you to work.
I'm not giving you my car.
I don't need you
to drive me to work, okay?
Keith fired me.
Little prick.
Are we really gonna
do this again, Tammy?
What?
Every time something
bad happens, you throw a fit,
you say you're leaving,
you never get more
than 10 Miles outside of town,
you start feeling sorry
for yourself,
and you come right back here
and throw another fit.
That's not true.
It's a pattern.
It's not a pattern.
It is.
That's not even
what a pattern is.
A pattern is a thing
that comes in pairs of two.
You just don't know science.
Oh, my God.
A pattern is a series
of things or events
that repeat themselves on and
on, sometimes into infinity.
That's what a galaxy is.
It's not a pattern.
Fine.
God.
If you don't want
to help me,
then just give me the keys
to dad's truck.
No. Absolutely not.
Fine. Then I'm gonna take
grandma's car.
No, you're not.
She is old and not well.
Well, then I guess
she doesn't need a car, right?
You answered that.
Don't go... Tammy.
Grandma,
I need your car keys.
Yep. I heard everything,
and I am ready to go.
I'm taking your car.
I'm not taking you.
You're not getting my car
unless you are taking me.
No.
Oh, yeah.
Mom.
What?
What? You... you
packed a bag?
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
No one is going anywhere.
I am. I'm just not taking
this asshole with me.
Hey, you're not exactly
my first choice
for a traveling companion,
either,
but at this exact moment,
you're the best bet I have
to get out
of this stupid house.
Mom!
I'm sorry, Deborah,
but it is a stupid house,
and I hate it.
I love you, but I am not
gonna die in this house alone.
Mom, you're not gonna die
here alone.
You're gonna die here
with me and don.
That's a shitty thing
to say.
It's a very shitty thing
I meant it in a good way.
What's a good way?
Oh, my God.
I just m... ugh, never mi...
shitty.
Very shitty.
Mom, your doctor says
you have to take it easy.
Dr. Lansing is an imbecile.
Do we have a deal?
No offense,
but no fucking way.
I have $6,700 in cash.
Bullshit. Prove it.
Yeah, that's gonna do it.
Mom! Tammy.
You snooze, you lose.
This is ridiculous.
Don't call me at 2:00 A.M.
lookin' for a ride.
Yeah, I won't.
Mom, please tell me
you have your pills.
Oh, Deborah, unclutch.
God damn it, mom.
I'm gonna call brookview.
I swear to God.
Well, you do
what you need to, baby.
Bye, mom.
[ Tires squeal ]
Not a good idea.
It's just a little swollen.
It's okay.
[ Horn honking ]
What's brookview?
It's an old folks' home,
like a prison for old people.
Horrible place.
I don't know
where I'm going.
I've always wanted to go
to niagara falls.
Okay.
[ Engine revs ]
That was a stop sign.
Yeah, I'm aware of that.
I know that.
All right, do you think
we could just try
to be pleasant?
What do you say?
How 'bout a beer?
No.
Um, whiskey?
Jesus, no.
Oh, my God.
You're pregnant.
I'm driving a car,
grandma.
Do you see what I'm doing?
Just 'cause you can't see
through your Magoo goggles
doesn't mean
I'm not doing what I'm doing.
All right, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
God.
You know what?
Screw it.
Give me a beer.
Oh, yes.
Okay. Here you go.
One little beer
can't hurt, right?
Ya-hoo-hoo-hoo-
hoo-hoo-hoo!
¶ I'm going up the country,
babe, don't you wanna go? ¶
whoo! Whoo-whoo!
Whoo!
¶ I'm going up the country,
babe, don't you wanna go? ¶
spin it.
Spin it. Spin it.
I got it.
¶ I'm going to some place
where I've never been before ¶
[ laughing ]
Hello, cows.
I'm sorry
you're so tasty, cows!
I'm gonna fuck you up
between two sexy meat buns.
[ Laughs ]
Whoa! That's a bump.
Whoa!
[ Laughs ]
I stuck the landing.
[ Sighs ]
You want to go
ride a cow?
Ugh.
Oh, shit.
Where the hell are we?
Shh, shh, shh. Come here.
When I was a young girl,
I used to feed deer
right out of my hand
at my grandparents' cabin,
and there was this one...
hee-yah! Hyah!
Get out of here!
You never did
appreciate nature.
Uh, not when
it totals my corolla.
No. Thank you.
I... [ Sighs ]
How the hell
did we even get in here?
Oh, my God.
You know what?
What?
I think this
is some "x-files" shit.
For sure.
I don't know.
You know what?
If we die out here,
we're just raccoon food.
[ Chuckles ]
It's not funny.
That's...
I saw that on a show.
Let's go. Get in the car.
We're going home.
Home?
Yeah, home.
What?
You're always talkin' about
how much you want to get
out of that stupid town
and we finally are out of it,
and then one little
thing happens
and you just want
to run on back?
[ Engine turns over ]
Come on. Let's go.
Fine.
I'm not surprised.
You always were a quitter.
I'm not a quitter.
Yes, you are.
Yeah? Really?
Does a quitter do this?
[ Engine revs, metal crunching ]
Ah! Oh, God.
I got it stuck.
It's all right.
Go ahead. Push.
That's it.
A little bit more.
My God. It's crushing it.
That's okay. Push it.
Got it.
I am not a quitter!
You're a doer!
I am a doer!
That's it!
[ Engine revs ]
[ Screams ]
You got it! You got it!
Do it! Do it!
Whoo! I am not a quitter!
Oh, shit!
Aah!
Who's a quitter no...?!
[ Tires screech ]
Aah!
Whoa!
Oh!
Girl: Oh, my God!
Sorry about that!
You should wear a helmet,
fyi!
Whoa.
[ Panting ]
Oh, God.
"Mark twan
national forest."
Where are we?
We're in Missouri.
We went
in the wrong direction.
And... You do know
who mark twain is, right?
I know who he is.
Good guy.
He's a good guy.
[ Sighs ] Okay, Tammy.
Tammy, listen up.
What?
Well, you're
at a crossroads, right?
You could change the trajectory
of your whole life.
You've got time.
I've got money.
You don't want to go back
to that town.
You deserve to have
a little fun, right?
[ Both chuckle ]
[ Lynyrd skynyrd's
"call me the breeze" plays ]
[ Children laughing ]
There's no alcohol
on the dock.
[ Sighs ]
It's my juice.
Whoo!
¶ Call me the breeze ¶
¶ I keep blowin' down the road ¶
whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, that...
that's not safe.
[ Chuckling ] No.
I am ripping shit up!
Slow down!
Whoo!
Look at that.
She is so brave.
Coming in hot!
I am comin' in smokin' hot!
Smokin' hot! Whoo!
Might be too hot!
Throttle's jammed!
Too hot!
[ Crash ]
Oh, my God!
Tammy?! Tammy?! Tammy?!
You scared the shit
out of me!
I can't believe this!
Aw, shit.
I lost my glasses.
Shit!
Are you kidding?!
$4,800?!
Is that your scam? Huh?
You like taking money
from little old ladies?
You break it, you buy it.
You're lucky
I don't call the police.
That machine
malfunctioned on me.
You're gonna be hearing
from my lawyer.
No.
Pearl: All right, all right.
Just stop it, Tammy.
Here you go. $4,800.
Don't give him cash.
You should put it on your card
and dispute it later.
I do it all the time.
I don't believe
in credit cards.
Cash is real.
You should be charging shit
like crazy,
'cause you're old,
and by the time they come
to get it, you may not...
all right, go to the car.
I'm just saying
you may not still be here.
I know what you're saying.
You could be dead.
Get in the car.
I'm trying to help you
with your business.
I don't... I...
get in the car.
Hey.
Dick.
She's an idiot.
Muscle shirts
are for muscles.
I said I'm sorry
about the four grand.
4,800 bucks.
Pay ya back.
So, why do you want to go
to niagara falls, anyway?
Well, I was supposed to go
with my daddy.
He was gonna take me when
I was about, um, 8 or 9,
but he got too busy workin'.
And then he got too busy
gettin' sick and dyin',
so I never did
get to see it.
Oh.
And now, uh,
some 60-odd-years later,
I'm gonna get to see
niagara falls with you,
with my granddaughter.
Don't you think
that's pretty special?
I think so.
Are you sittin' on a couch
or a toilet?
'Cause this is like
a therapy session.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey!
Come here!
Yeah?
Look at this thing!
My God.
It's amazing.
Yeah, it's, um... Yeah.
It's... it's cool.
It's okay.
I like it.
"Okay"?
It's majestic.
[ Chuckles ]
It's not "okay."
I mean, that is super-cool.
You're just jealous.
Oh, please.
What have you ever done
that's that cool?
Nothin'. Short list.
I watched Neil Armstrong
walk on the moon.
W... on his bike?
That's Lance.
It's... I don't care
which brother it is.
That's still lame
compared to this.
Boo.
I had
a six-month relationship
with one
of the allman brothers.
[ Chuckling ] Right.
Yeah. Me, too.
Bullshit.
Watch your language.
It happened.
Oh, my God.
Did you really have an affair
with gregg allman?
No. With Duane.
Who?
Duane allman.
The brother.
Did you at least
get to meet gregg?
Of course
I got to meet him a lot!
I was on the bus
for most of their first tour.
What?!
Yes!
I have to say, that's, like,
one of the coolest things
anyone in our family
has ever, ever, ever done,
like, going back to, like,
when we were cave people.
Probably is, actually.
[ Chuckles ]
I never thought of it way,
but...
[ Humming
"midnight rider" ]
¶ I got to run
to keep from hidin' ¶
remember that?
That's good.
¶ I'm bound
to keep on ridin' ¶
[ Chuckles ]
¶ And I've got one more
silver dollar ¶
¶ one more ¶
and, like, he goes low.
¶ Ain't gonna let 'em
catch me, no ¶
¶ ain't g... ¶
¶ ain't gonna let 'em... ¶
go low.
Both: ¶ midnight rider ¶
get your chin out.
You're doi...
¶ rider ¶
not like in a weird way.
¶ Rider ¶
¶ and I got one more
silver dollar ¶
little lower.
You're off.
¶ Not... ¶ listen.
¶ no, no, get you no ¶
¶ not gonna let 'em
catch the midnight rider ¶
that's it.
Better. Better.
[ Laughs ]
[ Both humming ]
You know, one time I got
fingered by boz scaggs.
Tammy.
No, it's okay.
It turns out it wasn't
actually boz scaggs.
It's a good bird.
Yeah, sweetie.
It's a great bird.
¶ I've got to run
to keep from hidin' ¶
¶ and I'm bound
to keep on ridin' ¶
¶ and I've got one more
silver dollar ¶
¶ but I'm not gonna let 'em
catch me, no ¶
¶ not gonna let 'em catch
the midnight rider ¶
pearl: Yes! We're here.
We found it.
Yep. We're here.
And you know what?
I can smell it
from the parking lot.
I think you're right.
She says this is the best bbq
in the city.
Then let's have dinner
and get off the phone.
Oh, no, sweetie.
We can't.
We... we already... thanks,
but we already
checked into a hotel.
Just give me my phone.
Bye.
But we'll probably
see you tomorrow.
Bye.
All right. Love you.
Don't hit me.
What are you doing?
Give me my phone.
We're not going
to see lenore.
Why?
'Cause hanging out
with an old lesbian
is not my idea
of a God time.
Oh, don't be silly.
She's an amazing woman.
She's remarkable.
She just lives life.
She just grabs it
by the horns.
I mean, you could learn
a lot from her
if you paid attention.
Are you...
what?
Don't do that. Ugh.
What?
[ Laughing ] What?
What are you,
gay for lenore?
You love her so much?
She is my cousin.
Oh, my God.
Would it be so terrible,
really, if I were gay?
No. I don't care
if you're gay.
Can we please just stop talking
about your twang?
I'm very proud
of my twang.
Ugh!
[ Big Al hall and possum creek's
"John Henry" playing ]
Mmm-mmm.
I am loving this brisket.
How's yours?
It's really good.
I-I love the bark.
And I would know
'cause I'm a bark shark.
Mm.
Hmm.
There are some juicy-looking
gentlemen in here tonight.
Uh-huh.
I think we might
just get lucky.
I might.
You might.
Don't know 'bout you.
That'd show Greg,
wouldn't it?
Yeah.
Nah. You know what?
It's too easy for me.
I mean, I can go out there
and just get... I can get
any guy in this room.
Really?
Yeah.
I don't know what it is,
but guys have always
been drawn to me.
Kind of like flies
on shit.
You might, in the future,
want to say "bees to honey."
Why?
All right,
what is this power?
I would like to see this power
in action right now.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah? You ready?
Yes.
All right.
You better get a notebook out
and a sharp pen.
Okay, I'm watching.
It's gonna be
a goddamn clinic.
I can't wait.
Yeah.
You show me, girl.
Pay attention.
Uh-huh.
Go ahead.
I got two. I got two.
[ Clears throat ]
Which one of you lucky fellas
wants to buy me some drinks
and cut a rug? Mm?
I'm sorry. What?
Wrong answer.
You. You just got lucky.
You want to buy me some drinks
and hit that dance floor?
Man: I'm gonna pass.
How 'bout fuck you
and fuck you, too?
[ Sighs ]
I think
they were together.
That must be why.
Oh. Now,
that makes sense.
Can't work your magic
on that, right?
It's... I'm mo... I mean,
a magic, but not... it's cool.
I didn't get... hey, I'm cool
with your lifestyle choice.
Yeah. Gay it up.
What?
I didn't know.
Here you go.
Thanks.
To your honey.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Both laugh ]
Now let's turn your honey
back to the music.
Turn my honey.
Mmm.
I just got that.
I just got
"bees to honey."
Does sound better
than "flies on shit."
Yeah.
Yeah, 'cause
the "flies on shit"...
Would mean you're...
yeah.
Yeah. All right.
I'm gonna keep that
catalogued in there
'cause I use that a lot.
[ Chuckling ] Okay.
Whoo!
Mmm-mmm-mmm!
Whoo-whoo-whoo!
Like your hat!
¶ John Henry
was a little baby boy ¶
¶ sittin' on his mama's knee ¶
¶ she picked up a hammer
in her little baby's hands ¶
3:00.
Got something
on the radar at 3:00.
That's 9:00.
Where are you putting
your 12:00?
Straight ahead.
Look at 3:00.
3:00, 3:00, 3:00.
Oh, boy.
Ooh, he's coming over.
He's coming over.
Oh, right.
Earl: Hi, there.
Little birdie told me
you might need some more beer.
Well, that's one smart
little birdie.
[ Chuckles ]
You two sisters?
No. She's like 100.
[ Thud ]
Ow. Don't.
Uh, I'm Earl, and,
uh, this is my boy.
Howdy.
I'm pearl,
and that's my... Tammy.
Hey.
Oh. Good grip.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
What's your name,
good grip?
I'm Bobby tillman.
Yeah, you are. Huh.
Yeah. I'm... I am.
Yeah, you are.
What do you do for a living,
Bobby tillman?
I run my dad's farm.
Cool.
Right.
Hey, Connie, can you bring
some shooters over here?
This lady would like
to get intoxicated.
That'll work, won't it?
Oh.
So, farm, huh?
Yeah.
Dancing juice.
That's what we need.
¶ Hey, man, here I am ¶
¶ I'm a man on the scene ¶
¶ I can give you
what you want ¶
¶ but you got to come home
with me ¶
¶ I have got
some good old lovin' ¶
¶ and I got some on the stove ¶
¶ whoo-hoo ¶
¶ when I get to throwin' it
on you ¶
¶ you got to come back
for more ¶
¶ toys and things
that come by the dozen ¶
¶ that ain't nothin'
but drug-store lovin' ¶
¶ hey, little thing,
let me light your candle ¶
¶ 'cause, mama, I'm sure hard
to handle, now, gets around ¶
¶ whoo, hoo ¶
[ cheers and applause ]
Whoo!
All right.
[ Laughs ]
All right, thank you very much.
We're gonna take a little break.
Tammy: One more time!
That was amazing! Whoo!
They got to take a break.
Whoo!
Oh, my God.
[ Blows ]
Oh!
You need a cool-off,
all right?
I'm so sweaty.
I was grippin' it up
out there.
Everybody was kind of really
just workin' as a unit.
I kept calling you in.
Did you see me?
You looked... you looked
great out there.
Ah, well, I can move.
[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
You're so bad!
Dad.
Mm. What? What?
Don't you think
it's time to go?
Well, look, Bobby,
let's not be rude, okay?
I haven't finished my drink yet.
[ Laughter ]
And now it's gonna take
a little bit of time.
I'm going to the bathroom.
When I come back,
we're leaving.
I don't care
if you finish your drink.
Ooh!
I'm gonna go pick up
that hint he just dropped.
Hey, is this
the bathroom line?
[ Door opens ]
[ Exhales sharply ]
Um, what are you doin'?
Just wonderin' where
your wife is tonight.
I'm not married.
Let's light this candle.
Whoa! Okay.
All right. Hold on.
I... I do not want your tongue
in my mouth.
Then where do you
want it, man?
[ Door opens ]
No. I'm gonna go...
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
You just...
you're welcome.
Okay.
Hm.
Yeah, not a chance.
Not a chance.
Good set, man.
Oh, no.
Thanks a lot...
Just ditchin' me in there.
Can't find my grandma anywhere.
Do you know where she is?
I... I do, unfortunately.
Oh! God!
[ Laughs ]
Hey!
[ Both moaning ]
Pearl:
Just go away. We're fine.
Get... God,
I think she took my keys.
Did you take my keys,
grandma?
Are you kidding me?
Come on!
Dad, cut it... aw, man.
Oh, my God.
I don't want to know
what that was.
Ugh.
That's a shitty way
to end the night.
You're tellin' me.
[ Sighs ]
Sorry I, you know,
made that...
Little pass at you
in there.
Little pass?
That was kind of aggressive.
Damn it,
I'm saying I'm sorry.
No, it's okay.
I was flattered.
It was just surprising,
you know.
Honestly, for the night
as a whole,
it wasn't the worst thing
that happened.
Do I say "thank you"
to that?
Yeah, there's a compliment
in there.
[ Chuckling ] I don't know.
In there somewhere?
[ Moaning ]
Oh, God.
Don't... don't look.
Don't look.
Oh! Oh, God!
I just told you not to look!
Why did you look?!
[ Groans ]
I tried
to save you from that.
Because by saying it,
it's like an invitation to look.
I mean,
it's like if somebody says,
"does this smell weird
to you?"
And they put it out,
you lean in and you smell it.
You don't smell it.
But you do.
You lean in
and you smell it.
All right, that's crazy.
I-I would not smell something
if somebody told me
not to smell it.
You would.
I can guarantee you.
I can guarantee you that.
Pearl: Don't worry. Don't worry.
Oh. Dad,
all right, enough!
We're only at first base.
Ooh-ooh-ooh,
here comes second.
Come on!
Dad, this is not fair
to mom!
Come on, man!
Mom?
It's complicated.
Yeah, you think?
I think so.
Hey, grandma!
Uh, uh...
that asshole is married.
Come on, dad.
He's married.
Earl: Sorry, darlin',
the inn is closed.
I'm sorry,
but he is an asshole.
I-I agree. He's a little bit
of an asshole.
I do... I can't...
oh, God.
[ Sighs ]
Look, will you do me a favor?
My mom is home alone
and she's sick and I need
to get back with her.
So do you have, like,
a pen or something
that I could borrow
real quick?
Yeah, I think so.
Yeah.
All right, look,
if they come out of there
at a certain point,
just give me a call and
I'll come pick him up, okay?
Here.
Thank you.
I knew you were into me.
I got your digits.
[ Laughs ]
Sorry. That was...
it was stupid.
It was dumb.
All right, Tammy.
Thanks for holdin' down
the fort. I appreciate it.
Yeah, I-I'll watch him.
Appreciate it.
Thanks.
Good luck.
Thanks. Bye, Bobby.
Bye.
Pearl: Oh! Yes, Earl!
You know who she fucked?
Duane allman.
Go away. Go away.
Yeah, she fucked
the wrong allman brother.
Enjoy that.
[ Scoffs ]
It's 119, grandma.
119! 119!
It's a rodeo.
Could you not do...
can I just
have my shit back?
No, no. Come on.
A gentleman always carries
a lady's things.
Oh, bingo!
Yeah!
119. You're right. 119.
Yeah. Yeah, great.
Yeah.
So, you want to come in
for, um, some colored TV
or sex?
Yeah.
No. No.
We had a deal.
[ Grunting ]
Yeah, bullshit.
Don't you dare!
You are too old
to be this strong!
Open this door, grandma!
God damn it!
Hey, Tammy! We need some ice,
baby! Okay?
Yeah, fuck you, Earl.
Fuck you.
Ow! Come on.
Don't... gah!
[ Sighs ]
Oh, shit.
I got to... [ Sighs ]
I got to pee.
All right, let's go for b2.
[ Vending machine whirs ]
You piece of shit.
[ Vending machine beeps ]
I paid for you.
Come on,
you tasty motherfucker.
Yeah, now who wins?
Me.
Tammy?
Hey, Tammy.
Tammy.
Tammy, what are you
doing out here?
Oh. They wouldn't let me
in the room.
You slept outside?
Oh, my God. Here.
Let me help you up.
Come here.
Thanks.
Yeah, of course.
Aw, you're all dirty.
She took my keys, and I just
didn't want them drivin' off
and, you know, doin'
something stupid, so...
That's why I gave you
my number.
You should've called me.
Oh, I didn't think
you meant that.
I said it. I meant it.
Okay?
[ Knocks on door ]
All right, dad. Come on.
We got to go.
I'm sorry about all this.
Well, I mean,
you didn't do it.
I know, but I'm the one
that's supposed to be keeping
him out of trouble, so...
[ Chuckling ] I don't think
you're very good at it.
[ Both laugh ]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm tired.
No, I think
you might be right.
Oh, God.
Tammy, what are you
doin' out here?
All right, let's go, boy.
[ Sighs ]
Dad, truck's this way.
Gotcha.
Well...
I guess
this is goodbye again.
Yep.
I'll take care of that one.
You take care of that one?
Okay.
See you, Bobby.
See you, Tammy.
Thanks again.
Yep.
[ Sighs ]
Get that out of your way.
I am so hungry.
Thank you.
Sure.
Mmm.
It's been such a long time
since I've had
a good servicing.
You know what I mean?
Ew.
Pass me the ketchup,
please.
You know, I didn't bring you
on this trip to babysit you.
You are on this trip
because of me,
because of my car and my
money... what's left of it.
So you just watch
your mouth.
Yeah, I'm too busy
watching you screw
crusty, old men
in dirty hotel rooms.
Oh, God. Here we go.
You gonna blame me for
everything, like always?
I do blame you.
I blame you for shoving me out
of a hotel room last night
and letting me sleep outside
like a dog.
I blame you
'cause you're already
on your second bloody Mary.
It's not even 10:00 A.M.
This is vegetables.
[ Voice breaking ] I blame you
for packin' up your shit
and makin' me come home
from school
when I was 10 years old
and finding
an empty fucking room.
That's what
I blame you for.
You know how shitty that was
for a little kid?
You left me all alone.
Well, you weren't alone.
Your parents were there.
It's not the same thing.
You were my best friend,
and you just left me.
I'm probably gonna need
a tetanus shot
'cause I got nipped
by a raccoon last night.
All right, Tammy, I know
I've done some wrong things
in my life,
but... I mean,
you don't know everything.
I know I don't need you
and I don't need your money.
But I'm gonna take
your car.
What?
Yeah, let's see how
you like gettin' left.
Don't you leave me here.
You cannot leave me here.
You come back here.
All right, now sit down.
Hey, anybody want
to screw my grandma?
Yeah,
just get her a drink.
[ Sly and the family stone's
"if you want me to stay" plays ]
¶ Yeah, oh, yeah ¶
¶ if you want me to stay ¶
¶ I'll be around today ¶
¶ to be available
for you to see ¶
¶ I'm about to go ¶
¶ and then you'll know ¶
[ cellphone rings ]
¶ for me to stay here,
I've got to be me ¶
¶ you'll never be in doubt ¶
hi, mom.
Deb: Tammy, put grandma on.
Uh, she's in the bathroom
right now.
Tammy, Tammy. She left
all of her pills here.
High blood pressure,
heart... everything.
You get that
she's diabetic, right?
She cannot go unmedicated.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
I get that.
Listen to me.
She thinks she can handle it,
but she can't.
Tammy.
Yeah, I know she can't.
Bye, mom.
I don't think you do,
because you...
Tammy.
Don.
¶ When you see me again ¶
¶ I hope that you have been ¶
¶ the kind of person
that you really are now ¶
¶ you got to get it straight ¶
¶ how could I ever be late ¶
¶ when you're my woman
takin' up my time ¶
¶ oh, oh,
how could you ever allow ¶
¶ I guess I wonder how ¶
¶ how you could get out
of pocket for fun ¶
[ sighs ]
You got to be kidding me.
One, two.
One...
...two.
I told you,
you can't drink in here.
One, two.
I'm calling the cops.
You don't have to call
the cops. I got her.
Oh. Well,
look who came back.
Yeah, I came back.
You did it, huh?
What?
Drunk by 11:00.
Mm. Ahh.
What do I win?
Car ride with me.
Come on.
Let me take... all right.
That's... pretty sure
you had enough.
You know,
this is real cherry.
And guess what
my secret ingredient is.
Try some.
Is it... is it whiskey?
No. It's whiskey.
[ Laughs ]
All right, all right.
Let me take...
no. This is mine.
Let's go.
Let's go, grandma.
Oh, I need my beer.
You got beer?
Yeah, I got beer.
No, they're still in the store
right now.
Bye.
Okay, we're leaving right now.
Just get the drunk
out of here.
You know what?
[ Security system beeps ]
All right, watch it.
Oh, hey! Hi.
Thanks for the beer.
What? Are you...
yeah, nice try.
I'm not buying you beer.
What are you? 14?
No, you don't have to.
I already bought it
for them, because these
are my new friends.
This is Jesse
and the girl,
and we have an arrangement
where I'm getting them the beer
and they're gonna give me
a ride out of here.
How would...
uh, on their bikes?
Yeah, the fucking old lady
promised us some beer.
Hey.
Give it to me.
Yeah, that's right.
Hey, don't swear in front of
my grandma, you piece of shit.
Hey, you're being
a real bitch, lady.
Don't say "lady."
I'm not that much older
than you.
What the fuck do you care
if we have the beer?
If you don't give us
the beer,
we're gonna turn
to street drugs.
Yeah, I hope you do drugs.
Yeah.
I want you to do bath salts
and then eat her face off.
Come on. Let's...
just give it.
No.
I'll take it.
Cool it, Jesse.
Don't shake the beer.
It's gonna explode.
I thought you were cool.
Stop that, Jesse.
I'm not afraid
to hit a girl.
Fuck her up!
Fuck this bitch up!
Neither am I.
[ Grunts ]
Ugh! Get off me!
Get off me,
you fucking rat!
Yeah, nice Jean shorts.
[ Siren wails ]
Oh, fuck! The cops!
Hey! Don't!
I'm taking this.
That's my grandma's beer!
[ Siren wails ]
Ooh. I'm sorry! I'm sorry.
That...
unh-unh.
Put your hands up.
All right, all right.
Get your hands up!
Two pens, one half-eaten rolos,
one lighter,
hair brush, one necklace,
two bags of trail mix,
$42 and 10, 20, 23 cents.
Sign here.
Yeah.
[ Snoring ]
[ Snoring stops ]
[ Gasps ]
What are you doing?
You were snoring
and then you stopped
and I just wanted to check
and see
if you were still breathing.
I'm sorry.
Well, keep your fingers
out of my nose.
No, I mean, I'm sorry
for landing us in here.
Well, it's not like you're
the worst person in the world.
I mean, you're close,
but...
I cheated on Greg.
With the ice-cream man.
You had intercourse
with Jerry Miller?
No! I didn't do it
with him.
I just let him
play with my boobs.
You didn't do it
for the free ice cream, did you?
Not at first.
[ Sighs ]
I don't know why I did it.
I think, at first,
I just wanted attention,
and then I kind of got
hooked on klondikes.
I don't know. I just...
Maybe I'm the worst person
in the world.
Oh, I don't think that.
What's worse
than Jerry Miller?
I tried to sleep
with your father.
What?
I tried to sleep
with your father.
Ew!
Nothing happened.
Aw.
Don was
a perfect gentleman,
and then he put me back to bed
before your mother got home.
It's... nothing happened.
Nothing.
Look, I just was not
in my right mind for many years
because of the drinking,
and when I realized
that I'd stepped over the line
where I was
actually thinking of
sleeping with my own
daughter's husband,
well, then I just didn't know
what could happen.
And... That's why I left.
Oh, my God.
No. Don't! Ow!
Grandm...
just... they're fine.
My God,
they look really bad.
They're fine.
Officer: Tammy banks.
Yeah?
Let's go.
Bail's been posted.
Okay.
Let's go.
Yeah, I bailed you out,
but I'm gonna stay
a little bit longer.
Just, there's a little...
Small glitch.
Officer: Let's go.
We're charging her
with possession of oxycodone.
Well, she's got prescriptions
for everything.
She's old.
She had 32 oxycodone pills,
and they were not prescribed
to her.
Judge set her bail
at $3,000.
We don't have
that kind of money.
I mean, Jesus, she's got
to get out of there now.
You know, she's got diabetes
and probably tons
of other shit.
I've got diabetes.
Glen's got diabetes.
Diabetes is a very
manageable condition.
I don't give a fuck
about Glen.
I'm sorry. I don't.
I don't know you.
My grandma needs to get out
of there now.
Then you better get
$3,000.
How am I
supposed to do that?!
It's not my problem, lady.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
You're welcome.
Yeah, I didn't mean
"thank you."
And I didn't mean
"you're welcome."
You're done here.
You better leave while you can.
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughing ] Yeah, she did.
She did?
[ Telephone rings ]
Yes.
[ Both laugh ]
[ Telephone beeps ]
Hello?
Hey, it's me.
Do we have, like,
a Christmas account
or a savings account with...
[ Missi laughs ]
Is she there?
Uh, yeah.
Okay, bye.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Deb: How much?
$1,600.
What?
No. I'm not gonna fund
your spring break.
And why hasn't your grandma
called me back yet?
Could you just trust me
for once, okay?
Can I just have the money?
What's wrong?
Is someth... is it grandma?
No.
No, I told you she was fine.
Oh, God.
I told you
this was a bad idea,
but you didn't want
to listen to me.
I hate to say it,
but I told you so.
I know you're right,
but I know how to fix this now.
How are you gonna fix it?
Hello? Tammy? Tammy?!
I got to go.
I know what I'm gonna do.
¶ What, what ¶
¶ what, what, what ¶
I can do this.
¶ What, what, what ¶
be a badass.
I am a badass. I'm a badass.
¶ Rollin' in, hella deep,
headin' to the mezzanine ¶
¶ dressed in all pink,
'cept my gator shoes ¶
¶ those are green ¶
¶ draped in a leopard mink ¶
¶ girls standin' next to me ¶
¶ probably shoulda washed this ¶
¶ smells like
r. Kelly's sheets ¶
¶ pisssssssss ¶
¶ but, shit, it was 99 cents ¶
¶ coppin' it, washin' it ¶
¶ 'bout to go and get
some compliments ¶
¶ passin' up
on those moccasins ¶
¶ someone else
has been walkin' in ¶
¶ hello, hello, my ace man,
my mello ¶
¶ John Wayne ain't got nothing
on my fringe game, hell no ¶
¶ I could take some pro wings,
make them cool, sell those ¶
¶ the sneaker heads would be
like, "aw, he got the velcros" ¶
¶ I'm gonna pop some tags ¶
¶ only got $20 in my pocket ¶
¶ I-I-I'm hunting,
looking for a come-up ¶
¶ this is fucking awesome ¶
ah! My finger!
[ Clears throat ]
Freeze. Nobody move.
[ Grunts ]
Shit!
Don't move!
Okay.
Don't move.
[ Grunting ]
Dang it.
Don't even think
about it.
I'm gonna need you to put
all the cash in a bag for me.
Okay.
[ Cash register beeping ]
And, you, get out here.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
Hey, just make it...
I only need $1,600, really.
You don't want all of it?
No. Just $1,600.
My grandma's still got
$1,400.
Just make it $1,650.
Round up.
Okay.
You, give me some pies.
Give me some of the good pies.
Hey!
What?
Jesus.
I said give me
some of those pies!
Take them from the back,
so they're fresh.
All right, you,
go to the other register.
Get the higher bills.
Go, go.
Okay, okay.
Reach to the back, man.
[ Cash register beeping ]
Don't give me shitty pies.
You'll regret it.
No screwing around.
I got you both covered,
all right?
But, excuse me,
that's... that's...
that's your finger, though.
Is it?
Is that just my finger?
Uh, I'm not sure.
Is it?
Shut up!
I would... for your own sake,
don't... don't get sassy.
Okay. Sorry.
Okay?
Yeah.
Just get pie.
You want some pies?
I like pie.
Well, get a pile for you.
Get a pile for...
if you change your attitude,
I'd like to give you some pies.
On me.
No, that's okay. Thanks.
I don't care for them.
God damn it.
What did we just talk about?
I have a gun on you.
You're right. Yep.
I offered you pie.
He likes pies.
He's got a gun to his face.
Anything I say, he's gonna like.
I ask you, "you want some pies?"
I like pies.
Come on.
That's what I'm talking about.
Feel like we're kind
of gettin' somewhere.
And, under
different circumstances,
this would probably work out.
We'd probably be, you know,
good pals.
Like, see movies
and... you know?
Yeah.
I'd like to find, like,
a hot tub or...
I-I actually have one
at my apartment complex.
Aw, man.
Okay, that would be...
fingers crossed
we... we meet up again.
Yeah.
All right,
put a stack of pies for her,
stack of pies for me.
And put...
I think this is all of it.
Give me.
Just get over there.
Go. God, don't walk
right towards a gun.
Sorry.
Put pies in there.
Put them in.
Don't cr... don't creep up
on me like that.
Larry, seriously.
You like apple?
I do like apple,
but don't make me...
I don't want to have
to choose between you.
Let...
choose Larry.
Larry, she's telling me
to take you out.
It's just, you're so
much older, you know?
Oh, my gosh.
I'm a veteran.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
Now I'm gonna have to put you
in the cooler.
Come on. Let's go.
Today.
Get your pies.
Let's go.
Larry, it's a real honor.
I want to thank you
for your service.
Here.
I don't know if it's a blanket
or a towel,
but it'll keep you warm.
I'll call the cops in 10 minutes
and let them know
you're in here.
Ow! Damn it.
Shit. Come on.
Aw!
Come on!
Oh, God! Oh, my God!
Oh... My God!
Ow!
[ Tires squeal ]
Where do I go
to bail somebody out?
Uh, name?
Pearl: Tammy?
[ Gasps ]
Where have you been?
Uh... Never mind.
Okay.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Well, slow down.
Slow down.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Okay, how did you
even get out?
Well, I called Earl,
and he very generously
had Bobby wire the bail money
to the station.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
What are you doing
with oxy?
Whose pills are those?
They're mine.
My foot was hurtin',
and, uh, you know, my pills
weren't working.
So I asked the Robinson boy
if he had any.
Eugene?
Yeah.
Eugene's a drug dealer.
Oh, no.
Yeah.
He stands out on the street
and sells drugs
in little sandwich bags.
Did you think
he was a pharmacist?
He's organized.
Yeah, so was Hitler.
Man on TV: Courthouse rounds
over the next two years
and upgrade those rounds...
Ah.
In other news,
there was a robbery
at the oaktree topperjack's.
Two employees were held
at gunpoint.
Michelle li joining us
live at the scene.
Oh, shit.
Li: Now, authorities
are describing this person
as a 5'2" white female.
The robber had a Navy t-shirt
featuring a bear with "mahalo"
written on it.
The robber was last seen
driving an older-model Cadillac
hauling a jet ski.
The suspect made off
with $1,600.
That's quite a coincidence.
Huh?
Yeah.
She was super bossy,
but, um, she did give us pie,
so that was cool.
All right, well, we're
certainly glad that you're sa...
[ TV turns off ]
What have you done?
Sit down.
Right now. Sit down.
Well?
Well, your feet were really
puffy, and they looked...
yeah.
They looked
really messed up.
And I j... I didn't know...
I didn't know how else
to get that kind of money.
[ Voice breaking ]
And I was afraid
if I didn't get you
out of there,
something bad
was gonna happen to you.
[ Sniffles ]
And I just always screw stuff
up, and I didn't want to s...
I didn't want
to screw that up.
Ah, sweetie.
My sweet, sweet,
sweet girl.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Look at me.
You have to take
that money back.
If you don't take it back,
I'm gonna turn you in myself.
Got to take the money back,
got to take the pies back,
all right?
I can't really take
all the pies back.
Why not?
Oh. Okay.
Kind of got into them.
Okay.
You're more badass
than I ever thought.
[ Sniffles ]
I think you take after
your grandma after all.
Hmm?
All right.
We'll fix it tomorrow.
Yeah.
We'll fix it.
I'm not.
Yes, you are.
I'm not wearing it.
I just made it for you.
Put it on.
It's full of grease.
Look at this.
Look, can you put it on
before someone sees us?
Can you see how much
grease is in this?
Put it on. Put it on.
You realize how much
it clogs your veins
when you're putting it...
all right.
Put it on.
You're killing me.
You argue about everything.
Oh, it's kind of calming,
actually.
Here. Just throw the money
through the window,
and we'll get out of here.
All right.
Fine.
Here we go.
Aah!
Oh, God.
She's returning the money.
No! I'm returning it.
She's returning it.
Calm down.
I'm returning the money
to you.
I'm calling the police.
Oh, no.
We're gonna need more pies!
I'm not robbing you.
I'm... I'm giving it back.
God, stop freaking out.
Stop crying.
I'm trying to...
I'm returning this to you.
Listen carefully.
Keep the car running.
No. Just relax.
It's okay.
Everything's normal.
It's cool.
My, um, bandit partner,
she just accidentally
robbed you last night.
She didn't really mean it.
And here's the money back.
No hard feelings.
Are you the grandma?
Look right here.
Okay.
None of this happened.
Just relax.
Oh! What are you doing?
You said, "come a-runnin'."
I said,
"keep the car running."
Well, you need to be
more articulate.
[ Sighs ]
I have a bag on my head.
And by the way, why does mine
have no expression
and yours
has a smiley face?
It's not smiling.
I'm showing tiger teeth.
Oh, I thought it was
a mustache and a smile.
Just go. Go! Go! Go!
Come on, Tammy.
Let's get out.
Don't be a hero!
Hey.
Where's Larry?
Oh, he has the day off.
He's pretty shaken up.
Oh.
Tell him hi.
Okay.
Watch the curb.
[ Kathleen crying ]
Oh, Jesus.
She's crying up a storm.
Somebody go hug her.
It's okay, Kathleen.
[ Both laughing ]
Oh, my God!
Niagara falls,
here we come!
Not in this car.
We're gonna go down straight
and then take a right.
What?
Yeah.
[ Engine shuts off ]
Oh, lenore. Hey!
Hey. It's been too long.
Too long, sweetie.
You look so great.
Ah, it's great to see you.
Come here.
All right.
Aww, is this little Tammy?
Look at you.
Oh, darlin',
last time I saw you,
you were knee high
to a grasshopper.
Yeah, I'm taller.
Yes, you are.
And you don't remember me,
do you?
No, I do.
You want to see some I.D.?
Family album?
She got a sense of humor?
Yeah, sometimes.
Okay.
Oh, darlin', how's your mom?
Good, I think.
You know, not real thrilled
with us at the moment.
But...
Yeah, pearly filled me in.
You knocked over
a topperjack's?
Grandma.
Lenore's cool.
Is that the vehicle you
perpetrated your crime with?
Yeah.
Okay, this is what
we're gonna do.
I want you to get in there,
and I want you
to take everything out.
Clean everything out of it...
all the evidence, okay?
You're on my land, and
you're a fugitive from justice.
Think about it that way,
all right?
Jesus.
I'm gonna pull that trailer off,
and I'll pop those plates, okay?
Okay.
Okay, what
do you want me to do?
Oh, honey, why don't you
hunker on back down there
in that rv, put your feet up?
I got this covered.
Okay.
All righty.
All right. Ow.
$4 a gallon.
Thanks, obamacare. Ugh.
I don't think
this is such a good idea.
Lenore: I do.
You want to go to prison
for robbing a store?
Well,
I returned the money.
Well, I'm no lawyer,
but I don't think
you want the police
gettin' ahold of this car.
Ah!
Shit!
I wouldn't stand there
if I was you.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, my God.
[ Engine turns over ]
Buckle up.
Oh, my God.
Ah, holy shit!
¶ Ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
¶ ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ¶
oh, I am so happy
every time I come here.
Susanne. Hi.
Hi, pearly. Hi.
Oh, it's so good
to see you.
Oh, so good to see you.
Yes, I do.
I do remember you.
Hey, Tammy.
Oh, I haven't seen you in ages.
Welcome. Welcome.
Thanks.
Holy shit.
You guys are loaded.
Tammy, that is so rude.
Uh, what?
This is like... this is like
"falcon crest" shit and stuff.
I thought you owned
a pet-food store.
Yeah, well,
I own 22 of them.
No. Oh, my.
Yeah.
Wasn't it, like, Martha's
or mabel's?
Merlin's.
Why Merlin's?
'Cause I dig wizards, man.
Oh, my God. I do, too.
I love wizards.
Get out of town.
She does.
I like them 'cause they can blow
shit up with their fingers.
Susanne:
Tammy, have you ever been
to a lesbian
fourth of July party?
Not that I know of.
Well, th-they are fun.
Come on, penny.
So, let's hear this again.
I-I-I'm fascinated.
I just m... I meant it.
Mm.
I meant it as a compliment.
I said you were super hot.
You know what I mean.
When I think of what
a lesbian looks like,
I think of somebody
who looks more like...
like me?
[ Chuckles ]
Personally, I prefer
the term "labisian."
[ Laughter ]
We should talk
about that shirt.
Yeah. Okay.
I love this shirt.
I know, but it's time
to give it a little break.
What are we gonna do
for the party?
Please don't wear that shirt
to the party.
Tammy: Uh-oh.
You're gonna doll me up,
and then I'm gonna have to be
beatin' the ladies off with a...
with a lesbian stick.
[ Laughter ]
[ Capital cities'
"center stage" plays ]
¶ There's a good time
to do it on your own ¶
¶ there's a good time,
now it's time to go ¶
pearl: Mm!
There you are.
Look at you.
Oh, my gosh. Wow.
You look so...
Softened.
I don't know.
Susanne made me put on
lenore's shirt.
It actually looks better
on you than her.
Look at you.
Oh, my gosh.
So nice.
Well, thanks.
Hey, I don't want
to be a bummer,
but I just want to say something
in a super loving way,
but could you not
get shithoused tonight?
Oh. Sure.
Easy-peasy.
I mean it.
Okay.
So, you want to dance?
No. They'll probably think
we're a couple.
Oh, it's too late
for that.
[ Both chuckle ]
Come on.
Look at you. I love it.
Oh, really?
¶¶
¶ check it ¶
¶ I can't do nothin', girl,
without somebody buggin' ¶
¶ I used to think that it was
me, but now I see it wasn't ¶
¶ they told me to change,
they called me names ¶
pearly! Pearly! Pearly!
¶ and so I popped one ¶
oh, I need your help
with something.
Is s-s-something hurtin'?
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on.
Oh, my gosh.
You're a little sweaty.
I know.
You're dancin' hard.
Well, I-I'm... I'm killing it
on the dance floor.
I'm sweatin'.
Let's just try
to glow less.
Cool off.
Oh, my goodness.
Look who it is.
Hey, Tammy.
What are you guys
doing here?
Pearl invited us.
Earl: Pearly, where's
the dance floor and the bar?
Not in that order.
This way, baby.
Grandma. Gr...
sweetie, have fun. Bye.
See you later, son.
Well, that was fast.
Got to say, you... [ Sighs ]
Your mom and dad have got
to have a real weird setup,
'cause I don't get it.
They've actually been separated
for a long time
and she's been sick
for quite a while
and he still
takes care of her.
So...
It's kind of complicated.
Yeah. Complicated.
Anyway.
Kind of all spiffed up,
aren't you?
I just put on, like,
a shirt and pants.
I'm not...
Maybe a little aftershave.
Is that what
I'm kind of smellin'?
I put on some cologne.
Did you put on man perfume
to come and see me?
N... I didn't put on m...
hmm? [ Chuckles ]
I think you did.
Come o... come on.
Let me get you a drink.
Come on. Come on.
It's kind of a vanilla.
Like a little...
it's not vanilla.
It's regular.
It's just normal.
I don't know.
Ooh, I know.
I know what it is.
You smell like a cookie.
Shut up.
I don't smell like a cookie.
[ Laughs ]
I think you do.
Come on. Come on.
¶ Your business ¶
¶ now you shouldn't
even get into ¶
yeah. Yeah.
¶ Who I'm givin' skins to ¶
oh! Oh!
¶ It's none of your business ¶
oh. Oh.
¶ So don't try
to change my mind ¶
¶ I'll tell you one more time ¶
yeah.
¶ It's none of your business ¶
[ Bobby laughs ]
¶¶
Does that smell weird?
No, it's fine.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, you...
I t... I told you.
You made me smell it.
Oh.
Why did I do that?
I told you.
Because I told you,
if somebody says,
"does this smell weird..."
Hmm?
I don't want to hit anybody.
What was that?
It's a... it's a...
it's a dog cookie.
[ Chuckling ]
You ate a dog biscuit.
You tricked me, Tammy.
'Cause I'm tricky.
I actually don't think
you're tricky.
I think you're kind of
a straightforward person.
That's one of the things I like
about you a lot.
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
Thanks for bailing
my grandma out.
It was really nice.
Of course.
But, I mean,
anybody would've done it.
No, not really.
They wouldn't have.
So it was... Thanks.
So...
Well, I'm glad
I could help.
I like your hair like this,
by the way.
Oh.
It's nice.
I don't know.
Susanne did this weird
clampy thing.
No, it's pretty.
You look really pretty.
Thanks.
I know this is stupid,
but I'm still married.
And it's a...
It's a shitty marriage,
and it's over,
but it wasn't all Greg's fault,
and I was kind of
an awful wife.
I just didn't... you know,
I just don't want to...
It's okay.
...Add to the...
it's...
you know, I'm sorry. I...
no. Do... no.
You're right.
I didn't mean to, you know...
Anyway.
You know, I get it.
You know, you get a little...
a little taste of Tammy
and you kind of come
clamoring back for more.
You get it? R-really?
[ Chuckles ]
I'm kind of...
I'm like a cheeto.
You can't eat just one.
[ Both chuckle ]
Tammy, that's lay's
potato chips.
That's not cheetos.
No, not for me.
I-I love a cheeto.
Tammy, Bobby,
come on, you two.
You're g... you're gonna want
to see this.
Come on.
Oh, all right.
All right.
Come on!
Chop, chop!
Okay, okay.
We're coming.
Get your asses down here.
Hey, what are you doing
with the jet ski?
Viking burial.
It's trashed.
Viking burial!
All: Viking burial!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Okay. Would you like
to do the honors?
It's your craft.
Yeah, but you love
blowing shit up so...
Yeah, I do.
God, help me.
I do so love it.
Go, baby.
Bobby: Get on, lenore.
The tribe has spoken.
Although we did not
have the opportunity
to feel your mighty engines
thrum between our thighs,
we salute your watery prowess
and we commend your spirit
to Valhalla.
Valhalla!
All: Valhalla!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Go, baby! Go, baby!
[ All cheering ]
Whoo!
Yeah! Oh!
Holy!
Viking burial!
[ Laughs ]
[ Tapping on microphone ]
Pearl: [ Slurring ] All
lesbians, attention, everybody.
Shit, grandma. Excuse me.
Hi. My name is pearl balzen,
and I want to take
this opportunity
to thank my cousin lenore
and the beautiful susanne
for this kick-ass party!
Yeah! Yeah!
[ Cheers and applause ]
Mm-mm-mm-mm.
And I just want to say,
happy fourth of July!
Yeah!
Amen, pearly! Amen!
All right, enough of that.
Seriously, folks, I want
to give a little birthday gift
to America.
I don't know how old
America is right now,
but I just wanted to say,
Happy Birthday, America.
Beep!
Shit.
Yes!
Those are beauties.
All right, let's go.
Really beauties.
You're done. You're done.
Hey! Hey!
You're done.
What the fuck did you do?
All right, go get me
another drink right now.
Damn it, you said
you weren't gonna drink.
Oh, I said
I wasn't gonna drink.
Now you get me a drink.
Come on.
Oh, uh, may I introduce
my granddaughter,
a hamburger...
what are you doing?
Cheeseburger, sorry.
She's actually cheeseburger.
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
What? What?
Don't tell me what to do.
Just get off it.
Get off this.
I don't want some fat loser
telling me what to do.
You're just being
an asshole
because you're drunk
and it's not okay.
Hey, w-we're all drunk,
Tammy.
She didn't mean anything
by it.
Lenore: Pearl...
pearl: No, I absolutely
do mean it.
I-I totally understand.
I don't blame Greg.
I w...
I would leave her, too.
I mean, I wouldn't want to have
anything to do with her.
Look at her.
Come on, everybody, people.
[ Chuckles ]
Look at that.
Oh. What?
What?
At least I didn't try to fuck
my daughter's husband.
How'd you know
about that?
Fuck you.
What?
Always something,
right? With her.
Fucking drunk.
What's going on?
Lenore:
Okay, we're havin fun.
All right,
let's get the party going.
Earl: All right, pearly.
Why's everybody being so quiet?
Here we go. Here we go.
What? What? All right.
What did I say?
Thank you, 'sanne, everybody.
Whoa!
Whoa.
Lenore: There you are.
I've been looking
all over creation for you.
Quite a show
you two put on.
I didn't start anything.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, you sure finished it,
though, didn't you?
What was I supposed to do?
Just stand there while
she said shitty things to me?
It's not fair.
What the hell does fair
have to do with it?
I got a big news flash
for you, Tammy.
Life isn't fair.
You're gonna have to scrape
and claw
for everything you want,
just like the rest of us.
You know, for years,
you've been bellyachin'
and complainin'
about how your life sucks,
but you haven't done one
single thing to make it better.
It isn't magic, you know?
You can't just bitch and moan
and expect shit to change.
You think this house
just fell on my head one day?
I had to work hard.
You know, gay hasn't always
been in fashion, my friend.
Susanne and I...
If you had any idea how hard
we had to work...
We didn't have anything
handed to us.
You need to grow up,
honey.
You don't know
anything about me.
You're not that mysterious.
Dogs are mysterious.
Cats, birds, fish.
Fish are
the most mysterious.
And I've made a mint.
Thank you, Jesus.
But we're not mysterious.
[ Sighs ]
Look, you know,
she shouldn't have said
all those ugly things.
I agree with you,
but [Chuckles] she's drunk.
She won't remember it
tomorrow.
Yeah,
she's always drunk.
She's an alcoholic, Tammy.
She's sick.
You need to focus on getting
your shit together.
Why don't you figure out
what it is that you really want
and just go after it?
Maybe you can help her out.
I'm gonna go blow up
some fireworks.
¶ Suzanne takes you down
to that place by the river ¶
Bobby: Hey.
[ Gasps ] Oh, God.
[ Chuckles ] Oh, sorry.
Tammy: Why are you c-coming
at me, like, out of the dark?
Bobby: I was... I'm sorry.
I was just checking on you.
It looked like you were havin'
a hard time out there.
Mm. She kind of told me
I was an asshole
and to get
my shit together.
Jesus.
That's a little harsh.
I'm not so sure
that she wasn't right.
I can't exactly keep
complaining about my life
and not doing
anything about it.
Yeah,
but you had a hard night
with your grandma
and everything, so...
yeah, that was great.
[ Chuckling ] Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm the one who let her walk off
to the bar with Earl.
I don't know.
I shouldn't have brought
Earl here.
I knew it, but I...
I wanted to see you.
[ Scoffs ]
Yeah, 'cause
I'm such a great catch.
No, it's not that
you're a catch.
I mean, I'm not saying
you're not a catch.
I'm just... you know,
my life's boring,
and you're a... a very
not-boring person,
and, you know, I... it's...
wow.
You're... you're kind of
super bad at compliments.
[ Both chuckle ]
Like, it's...
it's kind of amazing, really.
I'm doing my best,
but I think...
I think you know
what I meant.
I knew what you meant.
I don't know. I...
I don't really think that now
is kind of a great moment
for either one of...
you know?
You've got a dad
you're chasin' after,
and I don't...
I don't even have a car
or, you know, a job or...
You know, I just...
I don't think that putting
two messes together
is gonna somehow make
an unmess, you know?
I guess I just think
you're wrong.
[ Sighs ]
Probably.
I usually am.
Well...
I should probably
get out of here,
because my dad is now
starting to flash his breasts
to the lesbians.
[ Chuckles ] Oh, God.
So...
Yeah, that's probably
your... Your cue.
Yeah.
I guess
we're goodbying again.
Yeah.
[ Chuckles ]
Just wanted to mix things up
a little.
Mm.
[ Fireworks exploding ]
I still think you're wrong,
I got to say.
I can't hear you.
Lenore's blowing shit up.
Oh!
Morning.
Quite a party, huh?
'Twas, indeed.
Oh. I'll get in on that.
Thanks for the ass-kicking
last night.
No problemo.
Where's grandma?
Outside.
Maybe I'll...
maybe I'll bring her a cup.
Can we call a truce, or do
we have to actually fistfight?
[ Chuckles ]
Grandma, I brought you
some coffee.
Hey.
Hello.
Grandma, I brought you
some coffee.
Grandma.
Grandma?
Grandma? Grandma?!
Grandma?! Grandma?!
Come on. Shit.
Come on! Wake up!
[ Voice breaking ]
Grandma, wake up.
[ Sniffles ] Wake up!
[ Crying ]
I'm sorry.
[ Sniffles ]
I'm so sorry.
Shit.
[ Crying ]
Hey!
She's not breathing.
Susanne: What?
She's dead.
Oh, my God! What?
Oh, Robin, call 911.
She's dead.
She's not breathing at all.
You can't be serious.
W-w-w-what happened?
She's not breathing, and
I just let her drink all night.
Oh, no, no.
It's not your fault.
Oh, honey,
it's not your fault.
It is my fault.
Tammy,
it's not your fault.
Oh, my God.
Aah! Aah!
Pearl! Oh, my God!
[ Crying loudly ]
Pearl!
Oh, my God! Pearl!
What the fuck?!
What is this?!
Go get her!
Oh, my God.
Susanne: She's not dead!
What? What?
Okay, okay.
I think she passed out.
What were you thinking?
What?
You w-weren't breathing.
We all thought
you were dead.
Y-you are gonna clean
your shit up.
You're gonna stop
all this drinking.
Do you hear me?
You look terrible.
Well, my feet...
I don't feel so good.
God damn it, pearly.
Nobody should die
in a lawn chair.
All right, all right.
Don't shake her.
Don't bounce her so much.
Remember, she's not taking
all of her pills
she's supposed to be taking.
Man:
Okay. Thank you, ma'am.
Did I... Flash my boobs
last night?
Yeah, you did.
Yeah.
You were throwin' them around
last night.
Beep-boop.
All the way, yeah.
Earl has them
all over Facebook.
Yeah.
They look good.
I mean...
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I was mean.
Oh, I was mean to you.
I called you cheeseburger.
Oh, my God.
It's okay.
Pearly, we'll be
right behind, okay?
It's okay. It's okay.
Oh, no. Oh, my God.
We'll follow, okay?
Yeah.
[ Sighs ] Oh, shit.
Hey, officers.
Ambulance got here first,
but she's gonna be okay.
So don't worry about it.
Thank you, though.
Ma'am, we got reports
that someone
was burning a jet ski
on the lake last night.
You see anything?
Oh, it's,
uh, super uncool.
I would never burn
a watercraft.
No.
No?
We've also been tracking
a 2004 Cadillac de ville
towing a jet ski that
was involved in a robbery.
Anything on that?
Mnh-mnh.
Uh, you know,
uh... Pooh. Wow.
That's a Hawaiian bear shirt.
You don't see a lot of those
around here.
You probably see
quite a few.
You're gonna have to
come with us.
Let's go.
Oh, come on, man.
Let's go, ma'am.
Stand back, ladies.
Right this way.
Ugh.
You know,
I... I'm going with you.
I'm be... I bet you see
a lot of bear shirts.
No. No, ma'am.
Const... are you...
yes, ma... ma'am! Get...
are you... are you serious?
Ow.
There was a bee.
There's no bees here, ma'am.
You can't run from the law.
[ Man speaking indistinctly
over p.A. System ]
Guard: Tammy banks.
[ Gate buzzes ]
Guard #2: Open the gate.
See you later.
I hope not.
Hey, dad.
Tammy.
You rehabilitated?
I guess.
Then let's go home.
Wherever that is.
Yeah. I'm not too happy
with Greg.
Yeah. Me, either.
Look, um, you want me
to take care
of that wiggly little
motherfucker for you?
What?
I'll go over there and kill him
for you right now.
I'm old.
I don't care if I go to jail.
They got magazines in there,
don't they?
Oh.
I thought you were serious
for a minute.
[ Chuckles ]
You're kidding, right?
Jesus, dad.
You know we're
at a prison. Okay?
I do not... I do not want you
to hurt Greg in any way.
God.
You know, grandma told me
that she made a pass at you.
[ Scoffs ]
Oh, yeah, well, she used to hit
on everybody all the time.
You know the ice-cream guy,
Jerry Miller?
He was the only one
who went for it.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, God.
Let's roll.
Mom's waitin'.
Tammy: Oh, God!
You don't have to go in there
right now.
Now's a good a time
as any.
Hey, Tammy.
Hi, Greg.
Uh, come on in.
Really?
Yeah.
Whoa.
See you kind of made
yourself at home, huh?
Bold.
Uh, just wanted to, you know,
let you guys know
that I'm... I'm okay.
You know? With me.
Not so much
what you guys did.
That's... I mean, you know,
that's really between you and...
and that guy upstairs.
But I think he frowns
on adultery.
I'd say that.
So I think you burn,
actually.
So I'm just gonna
get my stuff.
Missi: I, uh...
I folded your clothes.
I'm so glad you're home.
Thanks for
letting me stay here.
Oh, yeah.
Mm.
You look good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Prison agree with me?
[ Both chuckle ]
Think it kind of did.
I got your room
all set up, so...
yeah?
Yeah.
God. I'm not bunkin'
with grandma, am I?
No.
[ Both chuckle ]
She's at brookview.
What?
Did you lock her up?!
That is bullshit!
Tammy, I...
give me your car keys, dad.
Tammy, wait. I did not...
I'm gonna remember that
when you get old.
Tammy!
[ Tires screech ]
Hey!
Hey, super old guy!
Where's pearl balzen?
What?!
Oh, God!
Huh?
Oh, come on, man.
Grandma.
[ Gasps ] Tammy!
I didn't know you were comin'.
Come here.
Give me a hug.
Oh, God. Look at you.
It's worse than I thought.
What's happening?
Okay, let's go.
Move, move, move, move, move.
Bye, everybody. I'll be back.
I'm gettin' you
out of here.
Okay. Hey! Wait!
What are you... stay!
I got the car. Let's go!
God damn it.
I'll get the door.
You could've killed me.
What are you thinking?
Just stop.
Do you hear me?
Oh, my God.
You can still walk.
Of course I can walk.
I was teaching
an exercise class.
Well, why were you sitting
in a wheelchair?
Because most of them are
in wheelchairs.
Well, why didn't you tell me
you were in here?
I didn't want
to make you jealous.
I mean, you were in jail,
and I'm at this cool place.
My aa meetings are here,
I made friends,
and I'm seeing this...
this 84-year-old from Philly.
I mean, he was a hockey player,
so he seems younger,
but... We've been
goin' kind of slow,
and this might be
the weekend.
[ Sighs ]
You look good.
Thanks. You look great.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I was afraid to eat the meat
in jail, so...
That's a good call.
Yeah.
God, I am so sorry.
So sorry about everything.
Mm.
I'm sorry.
I was a total jerk to you,
and I should've taken
better care of you.
No. It wasn't your job
to take care of me.
Little bit it was.
Well, I love you so much.
I really do.
Well, I'm pretty great.
You are really great.
I love you, too.
Want to go see some water?
[ Tires screech ]
Let's light this candle.
[ Laughs ]
Let's go, woman!
I got it.
You're strong.
Ooh.
"Dukes of hazard" -style.
Lenore stocked up the rv,
so we're all good to go.
[ Tires screech ]
[ "Do your ears hang low"
plays ]
Oh, God.
It's Jerry Miller.
Ladies.
Who wants a bone cone?
Go. Go. Just go.
Oh.
So, what do you think,
grandma?
Is it a good day to go
to niagara falls?
I'm ready.
You know, my daddy always said
that niagara falls
is the closest thing
to heaven on earth.
[ Cheering ]
So, how'd you know to come here
to niagara, anyway?
A little birdie told me.
Is the bird named pearl?
Yes.
[ Both chuckle ]
So, what's... what's going on
with you, Tammy?
What's... what's next?
Thinkin' about gettin'
my own place in louisville.
Really?
Yeah.
Interesting.
Yeah, it is, isn't it?
Get myself
a sweet little place
and, you know, maybe you can
come over and watch a movie.
Do you guys feel how the falls
are charging the ions?
It's incredible, right?
Yes.
Romantic.
Yeah, it is.
[ Clears throat ]
Oh.
Well, my daddy was right.
It's beautiful here.
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
You think I should try
to rent a barrel
and try
to shoot the falls?
I think we should
just look at them, maybe.
Mm, really?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I got a good feeling.
I feel like... I've been
thinking about a course,
and if I just shoot out into
the middle soft spot there,
it'll probably
just pillow-carry me
right over that Canadian lagoon
over in there.
I think if anyone could do it,
it would be you.
Oh!
Oh, I thought
I saw the cheetos.
It's not them.
You guys want to get cheetos?
¶ Josie's on a vacation
far away ¶
I can't believe you're
leaving me for that dick!
Well, that dick
is gonna have
his own franchise
in three goddamn years.
What are you gonna do?
Come on. Shake a tit.
Happy hour's over
in 20 minutes.
Ah!
That's how it's done.
Greg: This is b.S.
This is a huge mistake.
¶ I just wanna use your love
tonight ¶
you were right.
This hot tub is awesome.
Right? Yeah.
So, how you likin'
louisville?
I love it.
I love where I live,
where I work,
I love the man I lay with.
It's a-okay with me.
Great.
Hey, Larry!
This sangria is awesome.
Thank you.
The secret's
in the maraschino cherries.
Oh, I see you got a couple
of maraschino cherries
yourself.
Whoa!
[ Laughter ]
¶ I just wanna use your love
tonight, whoa ¶
¶ I don't wanna lose your love
tonight ¶
¶ try to stop my hands
from shakin' ¶
¶ somethin' in my mind's
not makin' sense ¶
¶ it's been awhile
since we were all alone ¶
¶ I can't hide the way
I'm feelin' ¶
¶ as you leave me, please,
would you close the door? ¶
poo! Poo! Poo! Poo! Poo!
Poo! Poo! Poo! Poo!
Hey, don't let a deer hit you
on the way out.
You dick.
You know what?
You are no longer an employee
of topperjack's.
[ Laughter ]
My secrets! My secrets!
[ Big Al hall and possum creek's
"love somebody" plays ]
[ Man vocalizing ]
¶ I was sittin' in the grass
on a summer's day ¶
¶ watchin' the clouds go by ¶
¶ there's one that looked
like a turtle ¶
¶ holding hands
with an apple pie ¶
¶ there were cowgirls
riding fishes ¶
¶ and many barnyard friends ¶
¶ and they all looked down
and they opened their mouth ¶
¶ this is what they said ¶
¶ love somebody ¶
¶ love someone ¶
¶ love somebody, son ¶
¶ take a hand and run ¶
¶ you got to love somebody,
son ¶
¶ I was drivin' in the country,
singin' in the breeze ¶
¶ there was water in the glass,
but it was hard to estimate ¶
¶ I was in the vines
and cypress ¶
¶ more trees than ever tread ¶
¶ and they leaned up
to my window ¶
¶ and this is what they said ¶
¶ love somebody ¶
¶ love someone ¶
¶ love somebody, son ¶
¶ take a hand and run ¶
¶ you got to love somebody,
son ¶
¶ I was sittin'
in a restaurant ¶
¶ pokin' at my plate ¶
¶ there was water in the glass,
but it was hard to estimate ¶
¶ when a Chevrolet descended on
the far side of the room ¶
¶ and my heart jumped up
inside me ¶
¶ sang a little tune ¶
¶ love somebody ¶
¶ love someone ¶
¶ love somebody, son ¶
¶ take a hand and run ¶
¶ you got to love somebody,
son ¶
¶ love somebody ¶
¶ love someone ¶
¶ love somebody, son ¶
¶ take a hand and run ¶
¶ you got to love somebody,
son ¶