[Drumbeats, Thunderclaps]
[Drumbeats Continue]
[ Gasps ]
[Man´s Voice]Put your faith
in what you most believe in
Two worlds
One family
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
To guide these lives we see
A paradise
untouched by man
Within this world
blessed with love
A simple life
They live inpeace
Softly tread the sand
below your feet now
Two worlds
One family
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
Toguide these lives wesee
Beneath the shelter
of the trees
Only love can enter here
A simple life
They live inpeace
Raise your head up
Lift high the load
Take strength
from those that need you
Build high the walls
Build strong the beams
A new life is waiting
But danger's no stranger here
[ Croaking ]
[ Growling ]
[ Chittering ]
[ Growls ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Growls ]
[ Screeching ]
- [ Screeching ]
- [ Growls ]
[Loud Screeching]
No words describe
a mother´s tears
No words can heal
a broken heart
- [Baby Crying]
- A dream isgone
But where there´shope
Somewhere something
is calling for you
Two worlds
One family
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
To guide these lives we see
[Baby Crying]
[Gorilla Sniffing]
[Wind Howling]
[ Gasping ]
[Baby Crying]
[ Crying ]
[Crying Continues]
- Huh ?
- Eh ?
[ Sniffing ]
Achoo !
[Coughing]
[ Cooing ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Sniffing ]
Agh !
[ Grunts ]
[ Cooing ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Snarls, Growls ]
[ Snarling, Growling ]
- [ Cooing ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Snarls ]
- [ Cooing ]
- [ Snarling ]
- [ Laughs ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Snarls ]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Gasps ]
Anh-anh-anh-anh.
[ Baby Laughing ]
[Growling]
[ Growls ]
Everymoment now
the bond grows stronger
- Two worlds, one family
- [ Snarls ]
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
Toguide these lives wesee
Mommy, look !
Look over there !
[Ape]
Kala, she´sback!
[ Sighs ]
Are you all right,
dear ?
I'm fine.
No, really, honestly.
It'sjust that I got
a little bit... sidetracked.
[ All Gasping ]
Well, isn't that, uh--
Well, so--
Well,
it'sjust so, so--
That's freaky-lookin', okay ?
That's what it is.
- Terkina !
- Well, it is !
- I mean, what the heck is it anyway ?
- He's a baby.
Ow ! I can't--
- [ Cooing, Laughing ]
- So, where's his mama ?
Well, I'm going to be
his mother now.
[Baby Cooing]
You know, he´snotso bad
onceyouget usedto him.
Kala's gonna be its mother now.
[ Grunts, Sniffing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Kerchak, I saved him from Sabor.
Kala, it won't replace
the one we lost.
I know that.
But... he needs me.
But, it-it-it--
Kala, look at it.
It´snot ourkind.
[ Sighs ]
No. You have to take it back.
Take him back ?
But he'll die !
- Ifthejungle wants him--
- I want him.
Kala, I cannot let you put
our family in danger.
- Does he look dangerous to you ?
- [ Roaring ]
[Baby Crying]
Hmm. Was it alone ?
Yes.
Sabor killed his family.
- Are you sure ?
- Yes. There are no others.
[ Sighs ]
Then you may keep him.
- Kerchak, I know he'll be a good son.
- Isaidhe couldstay.
That doesn't make him
my son.
We will nest here
for the night.
So, um,
whatcha gonna call it ?
I'm gonna call him...
Tarzan.
Tarzan ? Okay.
He's your baby.
All right, little lady, come on.
It's way past your nest time.
- Oh, Mom, five more minutes ?
- No !
- Two more minutes ?
One more "minutes" ?
[ Gasps ]
Oh, no, no, no.
- Shh, shh, shh. Don't cry. I'm here.
- [ Crying ]
Come on, come on.
Come, stop your crying
It'll be all right
Just take my hand
Hold it tight
I will protect you
from all around you
I will be here
Don't you cry
[Man´s Voice]Foroneso small
Youseem so strong
My arms will hold you
Keep you safe and warm
This bond between us
can´t be broken
l will be here
Don´t you cry
´Cause you´ll be in my heart
Yes, you´ll be in my heart
From this day on
Now and forever more
You´ll be in myheart
No matter what they say
You´ll be here in my heart
Always
Always.
Mmm.
[ Gasps ]
Tarzan ?
- Tarzan ?
- [ Trumpets Like An Elephant ]
- I sure scared you, Mom. Whoa.
- You sure did !
Can't you imitate
any quieter animals ?
Oh, Mom, they're no fun.
Wanna see me be a leopard ?
[ Snarling ]
- Why don't you just come up
with your own sound ?
- [ Screeching ]
Mmm.
[ Yelling Sounds ]
- [ Imitating Yelling Sounds ]
- [ Mothers ] Kala !
[ Yelling ]
- Oops.
- [ Quiet Growls ]
Hee-hee.
Tarzan, thank goodness
you're all right !
Kala and I have been
so worried !
Thankyou. Thankyou so much
for finding him, Kerchak.
You aresuch a wise
andcaring leader.
Run.
Ooh !
Um--
Hello !
Are you thick in the head ?
- What ?
- How many times do I have to tell ya ?
Ifyou want Kerchak to like you,
stay away from him !
- Come on, Terk ! Step on it !
- Last one there's a dung beetle !
- Yeah ! And the first one's
gotta eat it !
- Terk, can I come ?
Well, yeah, you could ifyou could keep
up, but... you can't really keep up.
Wait up, guys.
Wait up ! Right behind ya.
[ Elephants Trumpeting ]
Ah, yeah, take that.
Stop hitting yourself.
- Stop hitting yourself !
Stop hitting yourself !
- Ow ! Ow !
The fun has arrived
Thankyou very much.
What tookyou
so long ?
I had a little pest control problem,
but it's all taken care of.
Hi, guys.
Terk, what is this ?
Some kind of joke ?
[Mungo] Tell me l´m not
lookin´ at the hairless wonder.
Terk said I could come along
if I could keep up.
- Ah, no, Terk, come on !
- Terk !
I'll handle this, guys.
Okay ?
Listen, buddy, come here. We got a tiny,
little, itsy-bitsy problem here.
Personally, I'd love to hang out
with you. You know I would.
But the guys, they need
a little convincing, you know.
Okay.
What do I gotta do ?
Do ? What do you gotta do ?
It's so stupid !
- What ?
- Well, you gotta--
You gotta go get a hair.
A hair ?
- Yeah, a hair. Uh-huh.
- [Elephant Trumpeting]
An elephant hair.
[ Trumpeting ]
An elephant hair ?
Like I said,
it's stupid, right ?
Listen, take it from me.
Go home, okay ?
Who needs this aggravation ? You know ?
I'm probably gonna leave soon myself.
You go, I'll catch up.
All right ?
You see ? Leave it to me.
I told ya-- Tarzan !
- [ Tarzan Yelling ]
- Tarzan, no !
[ Yelling ]
- [ All Groaning ]
- That one hurt him.
Look !
- [Terk]
Oh, oh, there he is!He´salive !
- Hey, guys !
[ All ]
Hi !
[Terk]
Oh, no. No, no, no !
Come back !
This guy's great ! lf he lives,
you should bring him around more often.
- Come on, let's go get a better seat.
- Ohh.
- You never get enough sleep.
- I get enough sleep.
Mom, are you sure
this water's sanitary ?
It looks questionable to me.
It's fine, honey.
Yech !
But what about bacteria ?
Tantor, can't you see
Mommy's talking ?
[ Gasps ]
Watch out ! There's something
swimming ! It's coming right at you !
Honey, Mommy's losing
her patience.
- But this time I really see something !
- Oh, boy.
[Gasping]
Piranha !lt´sapiranha !
Sweetheart, there are
no piranhas in Africa.
Don't tell the kid that. Ofcourse
there are piranhas in Africa.
No, she's right.
They're native to South America.
Get outta here.
No way !
Come on. Do you think I'd be
standing here ifthere were ?
Aah ! It's right behind you !
[ Trumpets ] Run !
- For the last time, honey,
there are no piranhas in--
- My butt !
- Itoldyou!
- There's something on my butt.
- What is it ?
- Are there any more ofthem ?
Ahh !
- What is it ?
- It's a piranha !
[ Together ]
Huh ?
- [ Gasps ]
- Piranha !
- Whoa ! Whoa !
- Tantor, where are--
- Aah ! Aah !
- [ Gasps ]
[ Trumpeting ]
- He's dead !
- [ Trumpeting ]
We're dead !
Whoa ! Oof !
We didn't do it !
They're the ones !
[ Trumpeting ]
Oh, thankyou, Kerchak.
Tarzan, buddy ! Buddy, come on.
Tarzan, don't die on me.
Don't die on me.
You weren't supposed to do it !
Get away from there !
Don't you know a piranha
can strip your flesh in seconds ?
What ? He's not a piranha !
He's--
- [ Coughing ]
- He's alive !
- He's alive ! He's alive !
He's alive--
You idiot !
- You nearly gave me a heart attack.
Ya happy ?
- Uh-huh.
You-- I don't believe it.
You got the hair ?
Is that what this is all about ?
I got a whole tail ofthem.
- [Kala] Tarzan !
- Terkina !
[Terk, Tarzan]
Oh, no !
- Who's that ?
- [ Terk, Tarzan ] My mom.
- Tarzan !
- Hi, Aunt Kala.
- Hi.
- Oh, you scared me ! What happened ?
- Well, l--
It's sort ofa long--
It's involved because what happened--
- [Terk]lt wasa weird--
- What happened ?
- It was my fault, Kerchak.
- Tarzan !
We were playing and well--
I'm-- I'm sorry, Kerchak.
You almost killed someone !
- But it was an accident.
- He's only a child.
That's no excuse, Kala !
You can't keep defending him !
- But he'll learn !
- He will never learn !
- You can't learn to be one of us.
- Because you never give him a chance !
Give him a chance ?Kala, lookat him.
He willneverbe one ofus.
[ Kala ]
Kerchak !
Tarzan !
[ Sighs ]
[ Heavy Breathing,
Grunts ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunts ]
Tarzan,
what are you doing ?
Why am I so different ?
Because you're covered
with mud. That's why.
- No ! Kerchak said
I didn't belong in the--
- Close your mouth.
Kerchak said I don't belong
in the family.
Never mind what Kerchak said.
Now, hold still !
But, look at me !
I am, Tarzan.
And do you know what I see ?
I see two eyes,
like mine.
And a nose...
somewhere.
Ahh... here !
- Two ears ! [ Chuckles ]
- [ Giggles ]
- And, let's see. What else ?
- Two hands ?
That's right.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
Close your eyes.
Now forget what you see.
What do you feel ?
My heart.
Come here.
- Your heart.
- See ?
We're exactly the same.
Oh !
Kerchakjust can't see that.
I'll make him see it !
I'll be the best ape ever !
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, I bet you will.
Oh, the power to be strong
And the wisdom
to be wise
All these things
will come to you in time
On this journey
that you´re making
There´ll be answers
that you´ll seek
And it´s you who´ll climb
the mountain
lt´s you who´ll reach
the peak
Son of man
look to the sky
Lift your spirit
Set it free
Some day you´ll walk tall
with pride
Son of man
A man in time you´ll be
Though there´s no one there
to guide you
No one to take your hand
But with faith
and understanding
You will journey
from boy to man
Son of man
look to the sky
Lift your spirit
Set it free
Some day you´ll walk tall
with pride
Son of man
A man in time you´ll be
In learning
you will teach
And in teaching
you will learn
You´ll find your place
beside the ones you love
All and all
the things you´ve dreamed of
The visions that you saw
Well, the time
is drawing near now
lt´s yours to claim it all
Son of man
look to the sky
Lift your spirit
Set it free
Some day you´ll walk tall
with pride
Son of man
A man in time you´llbe
Son of man´s a man for all to see
Don't even think
about it.
- How'd you know it was me ?
- I'm your mother. I know everything.
- Where have you been ?
- I thought you knew everything.
Hey, Auntie "K."
You're looking remarkably groomed today.
Hello, Terk.
[ Terk ]
Not the neck. Not the neck there, "T."
[ Grunting And Groaning ]
Whoa ! Okay. It's all fun and games
till someone loses an eye.
Pleasestop.
Somebody´sgonnaget hurt.
- And it's always me. Please.
- [ Terk ] Cramp in the calf !
Okay, you win ! Ow, ow !
Okay ! You win. Hello ?
Yo, yo, let go !
- Oh, sorry, Terk.
- What kind ofanimal are you ?
I've been thinking lately
that maybe Tarzan could be
some subspecies ofelephant.
[Terk]
What, areyou crazy ?An elephant ?
[Tantor] Listen to me.
Thinkabout it. He enjoysapeanut.
- I enjoy a peanut.
- He looks nothing like you !
- [ Growling ]
- [ Shrieking ]
[ Roars ]
[ Snarling ]
[ Roaring ]
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Growling ]
[ Quiet Growling ]
[ Kerchak Sighs ]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Tarzan Yells ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Growling ]
[ Growls ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[Rustling]
[Apes Chittering
Nervously]
[ Tarzan Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Tarzan's Yell ]
[ Trumpets ]
Okay, everybody, move aside.
Outta my way !
Best friend comin' through.
That would be me.
And you, don't make
a habit ofthat, okay ?
There are other ways
of gettin' attention. You know ?
- I'll try to remember that.
- All right.
[Terk]
I wasright behindya ifyou neededme.
[Rifle Shot]
[ Birds Squawking ]
What was that ?
Ayah, it wasn't me.
I swear !
- [Tantor] Okay, maybe it was.
- [Kerchak] Everyone!
Let's move.
[Rifle Shot]
[ Sniffing ]
Hmph.
[ Coughing ]
[Rifle Shot]
[Man] This reminds me
of the safari I led up the Zambezi.
[Chattering Continues]
Back, back,
back, back, back.
Ooh, was it scary there.
Two men with only three rifles.
We blasted away.
[Man] That´s when I knew
I wasborn for Africa !
And Africa
was created for--
[Rifle Shot]
[ Grunts ]
[Man #2]
Clayton !
Oh, there you are.
What is it ? What is it, Clayton ?
Are we in danger?
I thought I saw something.
Is it a Hippopotamus Amphibious,
or a Rhinoceros Bihornus ?
- Professor, don´t move !
- Ah, right.
Daddy ?
[Grunting]
Daddy, what's all
the hullabaloo about ? Aah !
What is it, Daddy ?
Mr Clayton asked me not to move.
He saw something.
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts, Bushes Rustle ]
Oh, I moved.
Ah, Mr Clayton, sorry.
Excuse me, uh--
But my father and I came on
this expedition to study gorillas.
Ibelieveyourshooting
might bescaring them off.
You hired me to protect you,
Miss Porter, and protect you I shall.
And you're doing
a marvellous job of it.
- We only have a short time
before the ship returns--
- [Porter Gasping]
Jane ! Jane, do you realize
what you're standing in ?
- A gorilla's nest !
- Oh, Daddy !
At last,
our first sign in days !
- Do you think the beasts
could be nearby ?
- Could be.
[Porter] There´s the evidence.
Not veryfar, anyway.
Daddy, look !
Over there and there !
[Porter] Where ? Oh, yes,
more nests!lsee them !
-Just as you predicted.
- Whole family groups !
Jane, I love you !
[Clayton Laughing]
Family groups ? Excuse me,
but these are wild beasts...
that would sooner tear your head off
than look at you.
On the contrary. Daddy's theory
is that these are social creatures--
[ Rifle Shots ]
[ Birds Squawking ]
Mr Clayton, please !
What if it's a gorilla ?
It's no gorilla.
Hmm.
- But perhaps we should press on.
- Yes, indeed.
We should keep heading west
following the Ganoderma Ablonatum.
Excellent, Professor! I could´ve used
your expertise on my last safari.
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh !
[ Chuckles ]
Are you what all the fuss
was about ?
Daddy !
Daddy, quick !
No, wait, wait.
Hold still.
Oh, my.
Oh, my good--
You may not be agorilla,
but you are one sweet little--
[ Gasps ]
Huh. There you go.
What do you think ?
[ Cooing ]
What ? Oh !
Why, you little--
Well, this is
absolutely peachy !
Come to study gorillas, and get
my sketchbook pinched by a baboon !
[ Laughing ]
Ohh. Ah-ha-ha.
Give me that !
[ Grunts, Cooing ]
Come on now, enough of this.
I want this paper on the count of three.
One, two--
Oh, look, bananas !
[ Laughing ]
I can't believe you fell for that one !
- [ Crying ]
- No, no, don't give me
those crocodile tears.
- What would your parents have to say ?
[ Gasps ]
- [Growling]
Oh ! See, I told you
they'd be cross.
Go easy on him.
Children will be children. [ Gasps ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Panting ]
Oh ! l´m flying !
What on earth am l-- [Gasps]
[ Screaming ]
Get off ! Get off !
[ Screams ]
[Jane Screaming ]
Oh ! Put me down !
Put me down !
No !Pickme up, pickme up !
[Screams]
Aah ! Oh, no !
[ Chuckling ]
Unhand me !
[ Grunts ]
[ Screaming ]
Uh-oh.
[ Screams ]
- [ Groans ]
- Ah, over there !
[Jane Screaming ]
[ Screams ]
[ Chittering ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Gasping ]
I'm in a tree with a man
who talks to monkeys.
Ooh, I can't do this !
I can't-- Oh !
This is good.
This is... very good.
[ Gasps ]
Wait. One, two--
Ohh !
- It can't get any worse, can it ?
- [Thunderclaps]
Obviously, it can.
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Screams ] Ah... no ! Oh !
[ Grunts ]
Stay back. No, don't.
Don't come any closer. Please, don't.
What are-- What are you doing ?
[ Laughing ]
Please don't.
That tickles.
No, get off, get off--
Get off !
Itservesyou right.
Stay away from me like
a very good wild man. You, stay.
I'm warning you.
My father won't take kindly to you--
No. That's--
Now, that's close enough.
How dare you ?
[ Gasps ] Wha--
Ohh !
[ Gasps ] Um--
- [ Heartbeats ]
- Oh, oh.
Oh, dear.
Oh, dear, oh, dear. Oh, dear !
Yes, thankyou. It's a lovely heartbeat.
It's very nice.
Oh, thankyou. I can't do a thing
with it in this humidity though. It's--
You--
You do speak.
And all this time I thought
you werejust a big, wild,
quiet, silent person-thing.
Why didn't you tell me ?
I must say I'm rather curious
as to who you are. I'd love--
[ Grunts ]
Tarzan.
[ Grunting ]
Oh, I see !
Tarzan.
Oh, I see.
No, no, no.
No.
[ Clears Throat ]
I'mJane.
No, no, no. No.
[ Clears Throat ] I'mJane.
No, no.
Jane. Tarzan.
Jane.
-Jane.
- Exactly.
- [Rifle Shot]
- Clayton !
Extraordinary !
Um, please,
can you take me to my camp ?
[ Makes Rifle Shot Sound ]
Yes ! Clayton !
Wonderful !
Um, could we--
Um, can't we walk ?
[ Tarzan ]
Can't we walk ?
- Tarzan !
- Tarzan, where are ya ?
[ Mungo ] Let's hope
we find him before Kerchak does.
- [ Flynt ] Maybe he's lost.
- [ Mungo ]
Or found something more interesting.
What, are you nuts ? What could be
more interesting than us ?
[ All Gasping ]
What's everybody lookin' at ?
[ Gasps ]
[TantorGasps]
Ohh !
[TantorShrieking]
The horror !
It's gruesome ! Hide me !
- Pull yourselftogether.
You're embarrassing me.
- Huh ?
- These things aren't alive.
- I knew that.
- Tarzan !
- Tarzan ?
Hello ?
What kind of primitive beasts
are responsible for this mess ?
Whoa !
Wow ! Come here, you guys ! Come here,
come here, come here. Look at this !
- What is that ? Funny. Wow, it's--
- What is that thing ?
- [ Bell Rings ]
- [ Together ] Oooh !
- [China Shattering]
Hey, do it again.
Do it again.
- [ Bell Rings ]
- Like this ? [ China Shattering ]
- [ Paper Rips ]
- Yeah !
- [ Bell Rings ]
- [ China Shattering ]
Yeah, rip it !
- [ Laughing ] I love that part !
- [ Bell Rings ]
- [ Silverware Clatters ]
- [ China Shatters ]
- Let me hear it, big fella.
- [ Paper Rips ]
- Now, hit it !
- [ Laughing ]
- Yeah !
- [ Clattering ]
- [ Ringing ]
- Nice !
What the heck ?
Bye-bye.
- Terk !
-  [ Horn Blares ]
- Yeah, Tant ?
- Hmm ?
Now ! Hit it !
Come on, Tantor !
-  [ Horn Blares ]
- Oh, llove it !
Stay with me, fellas.
I feel somethin' happenin' here.
[ Horn Blaring ]
[ Scatting ]
[ Scatting Continues ]
[ Horn Blaring Continues ]
Yeah !
[ Scatting ]
[Terk]
Ahh ! Yeah !
[ Scatting Continues ]
[ Horn Blaring Continues ]
[ Scatting ]
[Continues]
Whoa
Ahh, gorillas !
[ Grunting ]
[ Both Grunting ]
He's one ofthem !
Ooo.
Oh, my--
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screams ]
Ohh !
- [Jane Whimpering]
- [ Sniffs ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Sniffing ]
[ Roars ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Snorts ]
- [Porter]Jane!Jane!
- [Clayton]Jane!
[Porter]
Jane, where areyou ?
Jane ! Oh,Jane !
Oh, thank goodness.
Good heavens,
what happened ?
Are you all right ? We've been
everywhere looking foryou. I--
- Oh, my goodness ! Daddy !
I was out walking. I was--
- Yes, yes.
- Little baby monkey. I drew a picture.
- Yes, go on.
- Suddenly the monkey starts crying.
- Oh, poor thing.
- I turned 'round and there's
a whole fleet ofthem !
- Ofwhat ?
- There's an army of monkeys.
A huge tree full ofthem.
- Monkeys ? Monkeys !
Screaming at me !
Ooo-ooo-ooo !
- That's Theripithicusbaboonus.
She's very good at this.
- Oh, really ?
- Terrified I was. And suddenly,
I was swinging in the vines.
- With the monkeys, yes ?
- Swinging, flying. I was in the air.
- In the air, yes, I know.
- And I'm all surrounded.
- What did you do ?
- Daddy, they took my boot.
- They took--
Those are the ones I bought you.
And I was saved ! I was saved
by a flying wild man in a loincloth.
- Loincloth ? Good Lord.
- What is she talking about ?
I haven't the foggiest idea.
Takes after her mother, you know.
She'd come up with stories like that.
Not about men in loincloths, ofcourse.
- And there were gorillas.
- [ Together ] Gorillas ?
- They were doing--
- You saw the gorillas ?
Where, Jane, where ?
He left with them.
Who, dear, who ?
Tarzan.
- Tarzan ?
- The ape man.
Hmm.
Everyone, we will avoid
the strangers.
- Do not let them see you,
and do not seek them out.
- They mean us no harm, Kerchak.
- Tarzan, I don't know that.
- But I do. I've spent time with them.
You may be willing to risk
our safety, but I'm not.
Why are you threatened
by anyone different from you ?
[ Snarls ]
Protect this family,
and stay away from them.
[ Grunts ]
Tarzan, for once
listen to Kerchak.
Why didn't you tell me there were
creatures that looked like me ?
[Jane ] Well, he didn't stand upright,
he sort ofcrouched, like that.
- Really ?
- Supported his weight on his knuckles.
- On the knuckles !
- See ?
- Exactly like a gorilla !
- Extraordinary !
Ah, it was amazing !
Andhe bendshis elbows out like this,
andthen he walks like this.
Oh, I see !
Like Aunt lsabel !
- [ Porter ]  Bup-bup-bup, oh-oh
This is capital !
- Mmm.
Oh,Janey,Jane !
What a discovery !
A man with no language,
no human behaviour.
And no respect
for personal boundaries.
- How do you mean ?
- He was this close, Daddy !
Staring at me.
He seemed confused
at first,
as if he's never seen
another human before.
His eyes were intense,
and focused and--
I've never seen such eyes.
Oh, shall l,
ahem,
Ieave you and the blackboard
alone for a moment ?
Daddy, stop it. The point is,
think ofwhat we could learn from him.
- We must findhim.
- Ooh !
Professor, you are here
to find gorillas,
not indulge
some girlish fantasy.
Fantasy ? I didn't imagine him !
Tarzan is...
- [ Gasps ]
- real.
Ah ! It's him !
It's, it's, it's him. Tarzan !
- Professor ! Jane ! Stand back !
- Wait !
- No !
- [ Rifle Shot ]
[Tarzan]
Clayton.
Huh ?
- Clayton.
- Ahh ! [ Chuckles ]
Have we... met ?
How does he
know my name ?
He thinks it means
thesoundofagunshot.
-Jane.
- Yes, hello, mmm, Tarzan.
I see what you mean
about those personal boundaries.
- What's he doing ?
- [ Grunting ]
- [Porter]Lookat him,Jane.
- [ Laughing ]
Moves like an ape
but looks like a man.
He could be
the missing link !
Or our link
to the gorillas.
Ahh, yes, yes.
[ Clears Throat ]
Where are the gorillas ?
Go-ril-las !
Shouting won't help, Mr Clayton.
He doesn't understand English.
Then I'll make him
understand.
If I can teach a parrot
to sing "God Save the Queen,"
I can certainly teach this savage
a thing or two.
Go-rilla.
- Go-rilla.
- Oh-ho ! He's got it !
Gorilla.
Gorilla !
- Perhaps not.
- No, no, no, no !
- No, no, no, no, no !
- No, no, no. Gimme that.
No, no.
Leave that. No.
Mr Clayton,
I think I'll take it from here.
What ever you do
l´ll do it too
Show me everything
Tell me how
lt all means something
And yet nothing to me
I can see
there´s so much to learn
lt´s all so close
and yet so far
I see my self
as people see me
Oh, I just know there´s
something bigger out there
l wanna know
Can you showme
l wanna know about
these strangers like me
Tell me more
Please show me
Something´s familiar about
these strangers like me
Every gesture
Every move that she makes
makes me feel like never before
Why do lhave
This growing need
to be beside her
Ooo, these emotions
I never knew
Ofsome other world
far beyond this place
Beyond the trees
above the clouds
I see before me
a new horizon
I wanna know
Can you showme
I wanna know about
thesestrangers like me
Tell me more
Please show me
Something´s familiarabout
thesestrangers like me
Come with me now
to see my world
Where there´s beauty
beyond your dreams
Can you feel the things
I feel
Right now with you
Take my hand
There´s a world
I need to know
[Clayton] We´ve wasted
all this time on what he wants.
The boat could arrive any day.
Now ask him straight out.
Tarzan ?
Will you take us
to the gorillas ?
Do you understand?
I understand.
- Ooh ! Good work, Jane.
- Well ?
I can't.
- What ?
- Why not, Tarzan ?
Kerchak.
Wh-wh--
[ Sighs ]
l wanna know
Canyoushowme
l wanna know about
these strangers like me
Tell me more
Please show me
Something´s familiar about
these strangers like me
l wanna know
Oh, Terk, I've never
seen him so happy.
Eh, I give it a week.
[Thug#1]
Aye, cut her loose!
- [Thug #2] Arg, c´mon.
- Allright, move it, you fieldrats.
[ Horn Blows ]
Put your back into it.
Wait, please. Don't--
I've waited 30 years for this,
and I won't leave
until I see a gorilla.
Oh, isn't this dreadful,
Tarzan ?
Whoa !
No, no. Wait.
[Clayton]
You´re the captain.
Just tell them you've had engine
trouble, and give us two more days.
And be late at every port
from here to London ?
We'll have come all this way
for nothing.
I'm sorry, Miss Porter,
but I simply can't do it.
Agh !
This is your fault.
I should've followed my instincts,
and set traps for the beasts.
Don't you think I'm disappointed
about the gorillas ?
- You are absolutely impos-- [ Gasps ]
- Oh !
Tarzan ! I was so afraid
you wouldn't come in time.
The boat's arrived.
The boat that's come...
to take ushome
to England.
And Daddy and I were wond--
Well, I was wondering--
Well, we really hope that you'll
come with us. Won't you ?
Go see England today,
come home tomorrow.
Oh, no.
Well, you see, it would be
very difficult to come back... ever.
Not come back ?
Oh, no, no. I know it sounds awful,
but you belong with us.
- With people.
-Jane must stay with Tarzan.
Wh-- Stay here ?
Oh, no, no. My laundry.
No, I can't stay.
Look, I've got--
I've got my father
and--
Jane, stay.
- But--
- Please.
[ Sighs ]
But... I can't.
[ Crying ]
[Clayton Chuckles]
Women !
How typical !
Thankyou,Jones.
Even ifyou hadn't grown up a savage,
you'd be lost.
There are no trails
through a woman's heart.
Jane is going.
Yes. Ifonly she could've spent
more time with the gorillas.
She's so disappointed.
Crushed, really.
Sorry, old boy.
Oh, well. I'd best
getJane's things to the ship.
Clayton !
IfJane sees gorillas,
shestays ?
Say, that's why she came,
isn't it ?
I'll do it.
- Good man ! Snipes ?
- Sir ?
Get the boys together.
There's gonna be a change in plans.
Terk, all you have to do
is get Kerchak out ofthe way.
- What ?
- I'd be happy to get Kerchak--
Shut your trunk
and get me outta here.
Can you believe that guy ?
Drops us like a newborn giraffe--
kerplop !
Now waltzes in here
and expects us tojust--
Terk, I'm asking you
as a friend.
Aah ! Aah !
With the face
and the eyes, and the--
Aah ! All right !
But don't make me do
anything embarrassing.
I'm gonna kill him !
A-Actually, I thought that dress
was rather slimming on you.
Oh, really ? I thought it was
a little revealing and kind of--
- [ Roaring ]
- Aah !
- How does she move in this thing ?
- [ Yells ]
[KerchakRoaring]
[ Terk ]
Look out !
- Oh, look, Daddy.
- Where ? Wh-- Wh--
Jane !
[Clayton]
Be careful, Professor.
She's beautiful.
She's my mother.
Th--
This is your...
mother.
[ Chittering ]
Wh-What's happening ?
Idon´t know,
Daddy.
- Oh, it's getting away !
- No ! You'll only frighten her more.
[ Chittering ]
Oh, yes. Absolutely, my dear.
Good idea.
What are you doing ?
Do you want to frighten them off ?
Get up !
Get--
Don't get up.
Ah.
[ Stammering ]
Ohh.
[Chittering]
Hello.
[ Grunting ]
[ Chuckling ]
Ooh.
It's very nice
to meet you too.
[ Laughing ]
Oh, Your Majesty, you're such a tease.
[ Groaning ]
Hello. Hello. Uh,
Archimedes Q. Porter at your service.
Aah !
Quite a grip you've got.
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, thankyou.
- Is that one of mine ?
- [ Chittering ]
Oh, this is wonderful,
Mr Clayton !
Look ! Look !
Social grooming.
Congratulations,
Professor.
Our dream has come true.
- [Chittering]
- Give me that !
Hey, what're you doing ?
Stop that ! Stop !
Hold on, now ! Leave that !
That is not
to be played with !
[ Giggling ]
- [ Excited Chittering ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Can you teach me ?
- Speak gorilla ?
Mmm, yes.
- Oo-oo-ee.
- Eh-ooo.
- Ooo. Ooo.
Ooo.
[ Laughing ]
- [ Grunts ]
- Ooo-ooh-ee-ah-ooo.
[ Excited Chittering ]
Good heavens !
What did I say ?
ThatJane stays
with Tarzan.
Stay ?
But I thought we'd already--
- But, Tarzan, l, l--
- [Terk] Whoa !
[ Yelling ]
Whoa ! Look out !
Whoa ! Ow !
- Is that my dress ?
- Oh, no.
[ Roaring ]
- Oh, Daddy.
- Ooo-ooo.
[Grunting]
Give it to me!
- [ Roars ]
- Huh ?
No !
- [ Yells ]
- [ Roaring ]
Go !
- Wait ! Wait ! Tarzan !
- Go now !
Jane, quickly !
Hurry ! Come along.
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
Kerchak, I didn't--
- I´m sorry, l--
- I asked you to protect our family,
[ Sighs ]
and you betrayed us all.
I'm so confused.
[ Sighs ]
Come with me.
There's something I should've
shown you long ago.
[Glass Shattering]
Is this me ?
And this is my father,
and,
and my--
Now you know.
Tarzan, I just want you
to be happy,
whateveryou decide.
[Footsteps]
[ Sniffles ]
No matter where I go,
you will always be my mother.
[ Sighs, Crying ]
And you will always
be in my heart.
Oh, goodbye, Tarzan.
[Jane ] Tarzan !
I'm so glad you found us in time.
Let's get in the boat, shall we ?
Mustn't keep the captain waiting.
Tarzan !
We're too late !
I can't believe it !
Ifyou'd have pulled over
and asked for directions--
We didn't get
to say goodbye.
Yeah, well, good riddance !
All right ? Who needs ya ? Huh ?
Go on, get out of here, bald boy !
You ingrate ! You bald ingrate !
Go on and rot,
for all I care !
Go !
- What are you lookin' at ?
- I'm gonna miss him too.
[ Groans ]
[ Sighs ]
[Jane ] Tarzan, you can't imagine
what's in store foryou.
You're going to see the world.
Everyone's going to want to meet you.
Kings, scientists
and famous writers.
Yes, Darwin and Kipling.
Queen Victoria.
I haven't met her,
but I heard she's awfully nice.
- And I'll be withJane ?
- Mmm. Mmm.
Yes, withJane.
[ Laughs ]
Ooh ! Slippery.
- [ Men Cackling ]
- [Jane ] Tarzan !
- Ow !
- Tarzan !
Get him !
- [Jane] Tarzan !
-Jane !
[ Groaning ]
[ Yells ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [Rifle Shot]
- What's going on here ?
- Clayton. Clayton, help.
- [Tarzan Grunting]
- Have we met ?
Ah, yes.
The ape man.
Clayton, you--
You--
[ Groans ]
So sorry about
the rude welcome, old boy.
But I couldn't have you
making a scene...
when we put your furry friends
in their cages.
- Why ?
For 300 pounds sterling
a head.
Actually, I have you
to thank, my boy.
Couldn ´t have done it
withoutyou.
Lock him up
with the others.
[ Yells ]
Uh, that sounded
like Tarzan.
He sounded like,
like he was in trouble.
Yeah, well, why doesn't he get his new
friends to help him ? I don't care.
That's it !
I've had it with you
and your emotional constipation !
Tarzan needs us,
and we're gonna help him !
You got that ?
Now, pipe down and hang on tight.
We've got a boat to catch.
[ Trumpeting
"Charge" Song ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Coughing ]
I've never felt so alive !
Good !
'Cause I'm gonna kill ya !
No time for that now,
missy.
[SonarBeeping]
[ Grunting ]
Tarzan, it's no use.
Don't !
[ Panting ]
[ Snarls ]
- Clayton.
- Yes, Clayton.
Clayton betrayed us all.
- I'm so sorry, Tarzan.
- No.
I did this.
I betrayed my family.
Kerchak was right.
Oh, those magnificent creatures,
shivering in cages !
What is this world
coming to ?
[ Yelling ]
Oh.
Oh, byJove,
don't know my own strength.
[ Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
What was that ?
- You are an animal !
- [ Trumpets ]
- [Crashing]
- That sounded just like an elephant.
- Tantor !
- [ Trumpets ]
- Thanks, guys.
- I thought I would never
see you again, and here you are !
- Aah !
- Sometimes you embarrass me.
- Hmm.
- [Explosion]
[ Nervous Chittering ]
- [ Yelling ]
- [ Roars ]
[ Frightened Chittering ]
Aah !
[ Grunting ]
[ Roaring, Groaning ]
Ah, I remember you.
I think this one
will be better off stuffed.
[ Snarling ]
[Tarzan Yelling]
- [ Tarzan's Yell ]
- [Tantor Trumpeting]
[ Porter ]
Charge !
Aaarrgh !
- You came back.
- I came home.
[ Gasps, Roars ]
[ Yelling ]
Errr !
Mm-hmm-hmm.
Aah !
Heh-heh-heh !
Fire !
You there ! Take what you can
back to the boat !
I've got some hunting
to do.
Hey !
[ Grunting ]
Heh-heh.
[ Gasps ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Coos ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Aah !
- [ Frightened Chittering ]
- Don't worry.
I'm going to have you
out ofthis in a second.
[ Grunting ]
Right.
This should do the trick.
- [Rifle Shot]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Roaring ]
Ah.
Aaah !
[Rifle Shots]
Hiding, are we ?
- Go on !
- Clayton, you--
I could use a challenge
because after I get rid ofyou,
rounding upyourlittle ape family
willbe alltoo easy!
[Thunderclaps]
[ Groans ]
Go ahead, shoot me.
[Laughing]
Be a man.
[ Laughing ]
[MakesRifle ShotSound]
- Oh.
- Not a man like you !
Aaah !
Clayton !
Clayton, don't !
[ Yelling ]
Agh !
Oh, no.
[ Laboured Breathing ]
Tarzan.
Kerchak...
forgive me.
No. Forgive me
for not understanding...
that you have always been
one of us.
Ourfamily
wiIllook toyou now.
No, Kerchak.
Take care ofthem,
my son.
Take care ofthem.
[ Grunts ]
London will seem so small
compared to all this.
I will miss you,
Jane.
- [Captain] MissPorter!
- I, I know. I'm coming.
[ Sighs ]
Well, I suppose we should say goodbye.
Goodbye.
[ Sighs, Crying ]
Goodbye, Tarzan !
Goodbye.
Oh, I'm going to miss
that boy.
Jane, dear, I can't help feeling
that you should stay.
Daddy, please don't. We've been through
all ofthis. I couldn't possibly st--
I, I belong in England with you,
with people, and-- Aah !
But you love him.
Go on.
[ Chuckles ]
- Oh.
- Oh !
[ Laughing ]
[ Chuckles ]
Uh--
Thankyou.
Thanks for getting my glove.
[ Clears Throat ]
- Well--
- [ Laughing ]
But, what--
What am I doing ? Captain ?
Tell them that
you never found us. Eh ?
After all, people get lost
in thejungle every day. Right ?
Tootle-pip !
[ Clears Throat ]
Ooo-ooo-ee-ah-ooo.
[ Cheering ]
Put your faith
in what you most believe in
Two worlds
One family
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
To guide these lives
To guide these lives we see
Put your faith
in what you most believe in
Two worlds
One family
[ Tarzan's Yell ]
Come, stop your crying
and we´ll be allright
Just take my hand
Hold it tight
I will protect you
from all around you
l will be here
Don´t you cry
For one so small
you seem so strong
My arms will hold you
Keep you safe and warm
This bond between us
can´t be broken
l will be here
Don´t you cry
´Cause you´ll be
in my heart
Yes, you´ll be
From this day on
now and forever more
You´ll be in my heart
No matter what they say
You´ll be here
in my heart
Always
Why can´t they understand
the way we feel
They just don´t trust
what they can´t explain
Well, I know we´re different
but deep inside us
We´re not that different
at all
And you´ll be
in my heart
Yes, you´ll be
From this day on
now and forever more
Don´t listen to them
´cause what do they know
We need each other
to have, to hold
They´ll see in time
I know
When destiny calls you
you must be strong
I may not be with you
but you´ve got to hold on
They´ll see in time
I know
We´ll show them together
´Cause you´ll be
in my heart
Believe me
you´ll be in my heart
l´ll be there
from this day on
Now and forever more
-  Oh, you´ll be in my heart
-  You´ll be here in my heart
No matter what they say
l´ll be with you
You´ll be here
in my heart
l´ll be there always
Always
l´ll be withyou
Well, l´ll be there
for you always
Always and always
Just look over your shoulder
l´ll be there always
Put your faith
in what you most believe in
Two worlds
One family
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
Toguide these lives we see
A paradise
un touched by man
Within this world
blessed with love
A simple life
They live in peace
Raise your head up
Lift high the load
Take strength
from those that need you
Build high the walls
Build strong the beams
A new life is waiting
But danger´s
no stranger here
No words describe
a mother´s tears
No words can heal
a broken heart
A dream isgone
But where there´s hope
Some where something
is calling for you
Two worlds
One family
Trust your heart
Let fate decide
Toguide these lives we see