[Traffic noises]
[Horn honks]
[Clears throat]
See you monday.
- Where are you going now?
- I'm going home.
No.
Yeah.
[Man Vocalizing]
What did it smell like?
Animal. Meat.
My boss, he call over here.
Nothing.
Neighbor said,
"I can hear the sound-- this animal."
Handcuff.
Like, in jail?
They shackled him
to the radiator?
Look.
[Purrs]
It's just a baby, too.
Not full-grown.
Trying to get out.
It's not our fault, the tiger.
You write that, right?
[Inhales]
Uh--
[Panting]
Sorry. I just--
I need some air.
This is no kind of thing.
I don't want to hide.
They're little.
They're buried stories, I guess,
but... They're yours,
so you get attached.
It's not offbeat.
It's news,
and if you put it in offbeat,
it makes it-- it makes it sound like a joke.
This is a really
good story, raj.
Look, relax, leigh.
Hey! Thank you.
We're very happy.
She was very happy.
Well, about time I manned up, right? [Chuckles]
To the tiger.
May the road rise.
May the tiger-- don't say anything about the tiger.
May the tiger run free
in tiger heaven...
Where the steaks
are plentiful...
And there's a lot of tree stumps for scratching.
[Woman]  Come Back Meet me at the lakefront
He Says, "Hey,
We're all waiting there"
Tiff Is Coming Too
But That Bith
Is always late
Donny
And his slutty girlfrien
Heidi And Her Sister, Yeah
Says We'll Smoken
An apple
I Say I'm Not A Girl Scout
Do You Know How
How To Get Me There?
Make Me Forget
Fall is in the air
Come On, Last Forever
We Won't Last Forever
Mom Is Calling Us,
But we're still high
Still High For Now
Uh-oh, Uh-oh, Oh
He Says,
"Don't you ever stop
I Say, "We're Raindrs
In the sun"
Still High For Now
Uh-oh, Uh-oh, Oh
Uh-oh, Uh-oh
Still High For Now
Still High
For now
Uh-oh, Uh-oh, Oh
[Sighs]
Well, I--
here you go, moose.
Go on, bud.
[Chuckles]
Are you sure about the--
why did you bring your cat?
Because
I couldn't leave him?
Well, couldn't you have
a friend look in on him or--
look in on him?
Uh-huh.
Mom. I'm calling peta.
Well, we don't have
a litter box, so--
mom?
Yeah?
What? No, no, no!
Don't move anything!
There's an order
to all of this.
Okay.
[Jangling]
Are you stripping?
No.
Are you sure?
It's belly dancing.
I started a new class.
I-- I have four students.
And is this the name that you chose?
"Dance mamas"?
- Really?
- Yeah. Ha, ha, ha.
I happen to like the name.
Please, just don't mess anything up.
- I'm trying to start a business.
- Oh. Can I keep this?
- Hi! Hi!
- There she is. Hi, baby.
Oh, give me a hug!
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
[Leigh] I wanna move back in with you guys.
Honey, you're 30 years old.
I'm 29. I'm 29.
And 10 months.
I've never, you know,
asked for--
I just need some time out
of my life.
Well, we all do.
Are you all right,
leigh?
Yeah.
I just don't want
to turn 30...
And still be
in that life anymore.
Well, what's wrong with the life you have in the city?
It's not--
it's not good.
I mean, I'm not--
I'm not happy.
You're depressed?
Is that it?
Are you depressed?
No. Not c-- clinically.
My life hasn't turned out
like I pictured.
[Grunts] [Chuckles] Well--
well. It's just nice
to have you here.
Okay?
If you're gonna
stay here,
you have to contribute.
To what?
Okay.
Of course.
[Bells chiming]
[No audible dialogue]
I would-- I would say you both have a very keen eye...
Because this painting
represents...
A very small percentage
of what he produced.
And this is a happier piece--
um, this is one
of the happier pieces.
Um, but there's a--
[Man] if I'm gone for 30 minutes,
nobody notices. Nobody even cares.
This is your ideal job.
How long are you here for?
I think a while.
Like... A while.
Why?
I'm getting back to basics.
What about your job?
Yeah.
No.
What about your boss?
He--
um, that guy's engaged.
Leigh-leigh.
Why are you just
standing here?
I need you to cancel your plans with anyone else ever.
Okay.
Have you seen mel?
No. Why?
You should probably see mel.
[Chattering]
I'm home!
[Laughing]
No. You guys can talk.
Sorry. I'm gonna-- I'm here,
but I'm-- I'll close--
[Woman]
Get Back To The Island
Get Back To The Rain
Get Back To The Start
So We Can Do It Again
Snuffed By The Sunshine
Covered In Gray
Get Back To The Sun
So we can feel it again
[Chattering]
I saw todd.
I know. I can't--
thirty,
still in the closet.
Seriously?
It's like--
hey, do you still smoke?
I'm not supposed to.
What, are they bad for you?
Um-- well--
[Engine starts]
[Seat belt alarm beeping]
No, we're trying
to get pregnant.
Like, with a human baby?
Mm-hmm.
But it's been about six months,
and there's just...
Nothing happening.
It'll happen.
So you don't-- no.
[Lighter clicks]
Yes. Yes.
I will.
All right.
Don't tell john.
Okay. Oh, shit.
Can anyone see me, do you think?
Mmm. Maybe.
Well, then we should go.
Wow.
Teen mom.
Place Me
In the shadow of your love
Like An Alley Cat Aroused
[No audible dialogue]
I Believe We've Had Enough
Hey, Hey, Hey
Place Me
In the shadow of your love
[Fades]
I have a plan.
- You have a plan?
- A good plan.
I'm gonna lifeguard.
[Chuckles]
What?
- She was a lifeguard in high school.
- And college.
- Where?
- Fox crest condo complex. It's really good money.
[Laughing]
It's good money?
How much? Wait.
Can I-- hold on.
I'm sorry. Can I just say,
what the hell are you talking about?
It's like
nine-something an hour.
You realize that minimum wage is 8.25 now,
so that's-- that's not exactly--
you sure?
[Todd] You cannot be a lifeguard.
You're not going to have your high school job.
You have a college degree, and you're 30.
I'm 29.
Todd, I'm 29. That's a fact.
Hey, hey, hey.
Todd, can I have--
thank you.
Can you please not do that?
Come on.
It's one drag, john.
Fine. Okay?
I got a question
for you, leigh.
You think these guys
are gigantic losers...
Because they've never
left ridgefield?
I mean, I don't think that.
I'm just asking, you know--
that's a really judgmental question.
[Mel] yeah.
Well, leigh's cosmopolitan now,
and she understands this kind of thing.
- What do you think?
- Definitely. Absolutely.
- See?
- Honestly, I do.
It's a sweet job.
You do nothing.
But in my field
of expertise.
Do you remember that red one-piece
bathing suit she used to wear?
- She looked like a swiss army knife.
- You guys could come visit!
Are you having a nervous breakdown, leigh?
[Mel] john.
- [Laughs] what?
- What? I'm kidding. Jesus.
[Chattering]
Is this parking lot passed down in the DN.A. Of skaters?
Like a geese
migratory path?
- [Todd] look at us.
- That's true. John.
Yes?
You don't know this, but...
This parking lot,
this very place--
it was like the beating heart of our
high school social life. This was it.
We used to come here
every night.
Then we'd try and think of what
we were gonna do that night.
But really we would just end up
standing around the parking lot.
Oh, yeah?
Like making out and stuff?
- [Todd] more than that.
- [John] I'm sure.
I'm pretty sure I opened the back hatch of someone's--
- [John] No, no, no, no, no.
- Of someone's--
[Mel]
We're not talking about that.
[Todd] I'm sorry that I brought it up.
Who was it in the back?
[John] Come on, please.
[Mel] stop it.
Can you not--
stop it.
Well, despite
our elderliness,
some things remain
from our youth.
[Alarm chirps]
No.
I get up so early.
It's torture. Me too.
I have to go.
I'm asleep right now.
Good night.
Just--
no, don't go.
Shit.
I'm coming.
It's probably the same shit
as before.
I wasn't here in 2000,
so I don't know.
You've gotta log the pressure in these tanks every day.
They drop below 10 or above 30,
you gotta let me know.
I remember.
The ritual.
I usually cut the grass about once a week,
every 10 days.
When it gets really high,
I try to keep it out of the pool.
You got the hook
over there.
Got new chairs.
All right then.
Here are the keys.
I'm usually around unless I'm not.
Don't skimp
on the cleaning.
I will not.
Okay.
Hello.
Hi.
Hey.
I'm little jason.
My dad's big jason,
head of maintenance.
Leigh.
New lifeguard.
Yep.
I-- I live right there.
Apartment in the garage.
Oh.
Oh. Yeah.
See ya.
[Fence rattling]
[Rock, Muffled]
Hey.
Hi.
[Grunts]
[Water splashing]
[Whistle blows]
No running.
Hey!
[Whistle blows]
No running!
What are you doing
in here?
[Gasps] Stop!
Oh, my god! Stop it!
Fuck you,
you fucking bitch!
Suck my dick.
Excuse me?
You need to leave the pool, now.
Get out.
- No, bitch. Suck it.
- Get out! Out! Out!
Right now! Get out!
No running!
Fuck you!
You're fucking ugly!
Get out, now!
Leigh.
Small jason.
How you doin'?
Fine.
Can I have a cigarette?
Do you know the kids
who live here?
Some of 'em.
Do you know one
who's about 10...
But he looks like
a 1930s italian gangster...
Except shrunk
into a miniature,
and he's really obnoxious
like he has no mother?
Aaron.
He has a mom.
She's fat-- to, like,
the point of not moving.
Why? He can't come to the pool anymore.
He's banned.
Why?
Because he wouldn't listen,
and he and his friends
swore at me,
and they wouldn't listen.
And I'm not--
I'm not invisible.
I'm the fuckin' lifeguard,
motherfucker.
And some cunt just sat
over there in her chair,
flipping through her magazine
like I didn't even need her help.
Oh, shit.
Whoa.
Well, she was.
I'm not a babysitter.
I'm not here
to be screamed at.
You gonna quit?
I don't want to.
I really don't, but--
thought you were supposed
to be healthy, lifeguard.
I'm just supposed to
make sure you don't die.
You're talking about
middle schoolers?
There were four of them.
Leigh, were they standing on each other's shoulders,
or how did this--
I told mel
we'd pick her up later.
Do we have reservations?
For what?
Let's just, you know,
do whatever.
You don't even have to come.
Really. It might not even
be fun for you.
If you don't want me to come,
just say so, okay?
Maybe stay home?
Is that okay?
I just want to get it out of her-- you know,
what she's doing.
And then I'll come home
and tell you everything.
Yeah.
I really don't care.
You don't... Care?
You can't drink though.
One glass of red wine
is... Fine.
Honestly. How else would
french women get pregnant?
Oh, okay. Yeah.
Whatever, mel.
[Whispers]
Asshole.
[Exhales]
Hey.
Mmm. Jesus.
Hi. So--
lifeguard.
Yeah?
Can you buy us beer?
Please? Yeah.
Lumpy's brother was supposed to,
but circumstances
intervened.
No.
Why?
I mean, because
we have lives...
That don't need to be interrupted
by the long arm of the law.
What would we
get out of it?
I don't know.
I think you do.
What is valuable to someone
looking to broaden his mind?
Something you could perhaps purchase.
It grows in nature.
Oh.
A moment, please,
while we conference.
What about mel?
I don't know, lifeguard.
No. No, no, no.
Excuse me.
You didn't say anything about getting
weed from my 16-year-old students.
They look older.
Yeah. No.
We should go then.
Hey. No. No.
If you're so worried,
then don't do it.
Oh, that's so much fun.
I'm so glad that I left my car at home.
Then do it.
They'll think you're awesome.
Keep your voice down. No.
This is not-- I could get fired.
'Sup?
Vice principal smith-lentz.
[Sighs]
Hi, boys.
Um-- all right.
Let's talk about this,
because this is potentially...
Very confusing, I think,
for everyone.
I came here with these people not
knowing what they were intending to do...
Or with whom...
Or... What.
I don't care if you smoke weed with us...
Because
I'm droppin' out.
Yeah, me too.
Yeah, I don't give a shit.
Are you insane?
Do-- do you actually want to face this cold,
harsh world...
Without
a high school diploma?
Why don't you just blind yourself while you're at it?
No.
I hate it here.
We're moving
to Vermont.
- [Mel] Vermont?
- Yeah.
I definitely am.
My sister's up there.
Yeah, my mom's there with my stepdad,
like an hour away.
It's way better
than here.
You heard
what they said.
They're not
your students, so--
shall we?
Todd?
Great.
No. This is wrong.
To you, it is, mel.
Not to the rest of us.
Oh, wow.
This is-- now you see what I have to put up with.
Mm-hmm. But--
I-- hey. Hey.
No, I do not approve
of this!
You went to RH.S. Too?
Yeah.
Um, leigh was actually
valedictorian.
What were you?
Um, I--
well--
leonard, it actually took me
until after high school...
To really focus.
Really?
Oh, yeah.
[Todd] Do not share this
location with anyone unworthy.
Does the old lady have, like,
a fuckin' shotgun for trespassers?
She doesn't have
a shotgun.
But if I find out any
of your friends came here...
And desecrated
a tiger lily...
Or littered,
I will have a shotgun.
[Chuckling]
That's cool.
What?
Don't be an idiot.
Just--
I wish I could
impress that upon you.
Okay.
I know you think
this town is bad...
And, you know,
you need to leave,
but I don't think you realize how
privileged this experience is.
How's it privileged?
Nature, for one.
Excellent public school
education,
for two.
It's safe.
You're sheltered-- which you never will be again.
Well, me and him
get arrested one more time,
we're tried as adults.
My classes suck, so--
well, stop doing
dumb shit, "a."
And "b,"
Your classes don't suck.
I'm in special ed.
I have AD.D., so--
what?
Having AD.D. Does not mean
you should be in special ed.
Thanks.
I know.
Orion's belt.
Big dipper.
Mmm... Seven sisters.
You're 16.
You have your whole life ahead of you.
You have no idea
how lucky you are right now.
[Engine off]
Thank you for driving.
That was...
Probably unfortunate.
Fuck you guys.
- What?
- I really needed to have fun tonight.
And you didn't even care.
And you don't even--
you never ask
how I am or--
mel, what's-- what's wrong?
It's just really hard,
trying to get pregnant.
I-- I think
that's normal, right?
Isn't your life perfect?
No!
Oh!
Hey. Hey.
I read somewhere they did a
study of children in jamaica...
Whose mothers smoked weed
during utero,
and they were actually happier and
more creative than other children.
I believe that.
Absolutely.
Mm-hmm.
"Remember to not be too nostalgic for this time.
[Laughing] Our lives are what lay ahead--
[Coughing, laughing] In this
uncharted territory of our dreams.
Aw.
Be brave and bold--
[Mel giggles]
And do not look back,
classmates,
for the future
is meant to be seized...
With both hands."
Both hands.
Oh. So embarrassing.
[Laughing]
Both hands.
Really?
It's that funny? Yeah.
Leigh london,
valedictorian...
And virgin?
Yes. See? What did I know?
[Phone ringing, muffled]
Absolutely nothing.
Mm-hmm.
[Ringing continues]
[Laughing]
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Hi.
[John speaking, faint]
Right.
I don't want to drive.
[Whispering] tell him you're too tired.
I'm very tired.
I'm tired!
Because I've had
a long week.
No. John, I'm just tired.
Okay.
All right.
See you tomorrow.
Hey. I love you.
I'm sleeping over.
Yes!
I will prepare us
cereal.
[Sighs]
[Exhales]
I'm so jealous of you.
Me? Why?
Because you
get to be lost.
It's okay.
Hey.
I thought you lived
in fox crest.
Yeah.
And you were too fucked up to walk
the 20 yards back to your bed?
My mom kicked me out.
Because you were
fucked up.
[Sighs]
I'm gonna go puke.
Here.
Better be careful, man. You pass out like
that in Vermont, you froze in the snow.
Ah, the myth of Vermont.
Myth?
Shee-at.
It's on the map.
Next week.
Well, that's just not gonna happen, man.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know. I know.
But that's why I'm trying to have a
conversation with you about cap rates. Right.
Exactly. Yes.
Well, that's why I hired you.
Don't be an asshole about it.
No, we don't trust bankers.
We do not trust bankers.
Okay?
[Dog barking in distance]
We got this guy. When he starts to push back,
that's what you do.
It's sort of like--
right. Yeah.
This is a, uh-- this is a chuck e.
Cheese we're talking about.
Obviously,
don't use that language--
but you know
what I mean.
[Continues, faint]
[Man]  Let Me Take You To the outside place
[Continues]
[Screaming, laughing]
Whoo!
[Continues]
Whoo! Whoo!
Let Me Take You
To the outside place
Oww!
-  Oh, Do You Wanna Go
- again! Again! Again!
To The Place
Where you belong?
-  Oh, Do You Wanna G
- oww!
To The Place
Where you belong?
Do You Wanna Go?
Most people get better with age with driving.
He's actually gotten worse.
I don't think that's--
no, because you started out
as a fairly good driver.
It was intentional bad driving.
Was it? It was intentional?
Yes.
Leigh?
Give me a m--
number one,
you got a nice community here.
Number two,
you have no respect for--
hey.
Leigh london.
How you doin'?
Hi, rick. How are ya?
Listen, I know these guys.
Can I help at all in this situation?
No.
This is police business.
- They're skating.
- And someone complained?
Or-- is there an ordinance against it?
I didn't think there was.
Ma'am, I'm gonna have to
ask you to go away now.
Unless you have a valid reason to
be cornering these underage youths,
what you're doing right now
is called harassment.
Maybe I should take you downtown
for impeding an arrest.
Am I impeding
an arrest?
If you have a reason to arrest
them and you can prove it,
then, I mean,
by all means take me down,
'cause I--
I will understand.
No more skating.
But why, rick?
[Chuckles] You're a real piece of work.
You're kind of a bitch,
actually.
I'm sorry.
What was that, Officer?
You know I'm a reporter
for the associated press, right?
[Officer chuckling] Fuckin' nuts.
[Car engine starts]
[John] so you're just gonna take
some time off and then, uh--
I mean, what,
are you thinking of a career change, or, uh--
[Leigh]
Uh, I don't know.
Okay, well,
are you gonna look for something else around here?
Or were you gonna go back to
the city once the pool closes?
- I have no idea.
- Okay.
That's... Good.
Good.
Ah, no. No, thanks.
I will pass on that.
Uh, leigh, evidently,
will not.
Can you just keep...
Drinking your beer? Yeah.
Let's try and have fun.
I know that it's weird, whatever.
But... Let's just try
and have a good time.
[Laughs]
Okay.
[John] I can't believe it's not developed yet.
It's a park, john.
Nature.
It's "pra-served."
We used to come
when we were little.
Remember leigh had all these plans
about getting married under the arbor?
I'm thinking
it's water table issues.
Otherwise the city would've developed
the shit out of this place by now.
[Stammers] What does this remind me of, mel?
It's like, uh,
great expectations. Right?
Remember that?
It's all overgrown and old and everything.
[Todd]
No way.
This is a piece of chandelier.
This is a crystal.
It's original.
I just found it. Bullshit.
That's probably a hypodermic needle.
Let me see it. No!
[Leigh] 'Cause better classes now at,
you know, a better college.
I don't wanna go
to college.
Okay.
What do you want?
I don't know.
Something cool.
Something...
Outside.
Wh-what does that mea--
[Clears throat]
You have to be specific.
You can't just drift.
What?
You seem really sad.
Well, it's just leigh never seemed like
the kind of person that would be lost.
You know?
Me, on the other hand--
yeah, well, you know,
real life can be disappointing...
When your expectations
are so high.
[Spits]
I have high expectations.
You know what
I'm talking about.
Everybody does.
Well, whatever.
Excuse me.
I'm not gonna hang out
with those kids anymore. Okay?
Why not?
We didn't smoke weed.
[Chuckles]
Seriously, mel?
I mean--
[Scoffs]
Leigh is being a fucking idiot.
Okay?
I mean, todd wants to,
like, rape those kids.
Hey. Hey.
You can't say that.
Look, I just wanna hang out with adults.
Okay?
Is that too much
to ask?
Great.
"Great"?
[Chuckles]
Fine!
Fine. It's fine.
What are you
doing?
Slap my face...
With your dick.
Wh--
what's wrong with you?
Hey. Hey.
Hey, hey, hey, baby.
Hey.
I love you.
Okay?
Hey.
It's okay.
[John sighs]
[Tv clicks on,
indistinct]
I did a story about a guy who
kept a tiger in his apartment...
In the city.
The tiger got sick and died.
[Chuckles]
Well, that'd be cool. Right?
To have a tiger
as a pet.
And fuckin' invite everybody you hate to the house.
What?
It's not cool.
It's sad.
It's incredibly sad.
This creature was kept...
Against its will...
In a totally unnatural
environment for it.
And it was kept
in, like, a cell...
In someone's apartment...
For their amusement.
But it was cruel,
and it killed it.
Someone took
this amazing thing that--
that should have been
running free...
And kept it prisoner.
And it died.
And it was just--
it wasn't even full grown.
Well, maybe,
'cause you wrote
the article,
you know--
um, I-if somebody
had an animal...
And they weren't
treating it right,
they would read your article
and-- and... Change their minds.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Oh.
Ohh!
[Chuckles]
Lifeguard?
Please don't ban me
from the pool.
You didn't listen.
You were behaving in a way that
was dangerous to everyone.
Please!
I'm sorry!
You disobey
lifeguard's orders again,
and that's it--
you're out for good.
But you can come back.
[Whispers]
Yes.
Well, um, lifeguard?
Can you tell little jason and
those guys to leave me alone?
'Cause I said sorry
to you now.
Okay.
[Door opens]
What the fuck!
[Door closes]
You fucking scared me.
It's raining.
[Scoffs]
So?
[Clears throat]
I recognized your car.
I should
lock my doors.
[Chuckles]
No.
Where are
your no-good friends?
I don't know.
Where are your
no-good friends?
I don't know.
I'm... Gonna--
what?
Um--
[Door closes]
[Thunder rumbling]
You didn't bring an umbrella?
I didn't know this would happen!
Hey.
Forgot your keys.
Thanks.
What's up?
What's goin' on, man?
There we go.
[Pop]
[Chattering, muffled]
[Man]
I Was Cut Open
On The Way Down
Reelin'
From The Blow
And You Were There
On The Other Land
In Between
The Tears
And the light show
[Continues, Faint]
What's gonna happen?
You're asking me?
Um--
everything's gonna be fine.
Life has great things in st--
But All This Talkin'
It's Drivin' Me Insane
And I Was Told
If I Was To Sing Along
Forget About Myself
We're All The Same
[Murmuring]
Yes. Take it down.
Well, Maybe I Should Chae
My point of view
[Both moaning,
grunting]
Dizzy In The Morning
And I'm Shakin'
In the afternoon
There's Never No Warning
When It's Gonna Hit
And I'm Lie
An earthquak
When I Get To Thinki'
Too much
Everything's Fallin'
And shakin' and fallin
Through My Hands
Well, Maybe I Should Chae
My point of view
Leigh,
what is wrong with you?
What?
Nothing.
Just because
you're staying here...
Doesn't mean you can take advantage of
your father and I and pretend this is a hotel.
You came in
at 3:00 in the morning.
I was worried.
I didn't know where you were.
Sorry.
I lost track of time.
Just do a couple of dishes once in a while.
Pick up after yourself.
Huh?
Your father's out.
I need to get out of here too.
You need a ride to work,
you got to get going now.
I don't-- I don't need a ride.
I'm not working till the afternoon.
[Hans]
Good morning.
Hans, what are
you doing here?
Leigh's got the morning off,
so I thought we'd make granola bars like the old days.
Yes!
Please tell me this isn't happening.
You're supposed
to be in hartford.
What?
Picking up my banners
for the trade show.
You told me
that you would do it...
Because today I have to do
the yoga workshop, hans.
I'm so sorry, justine.
I forgot. Shoot.
I saw leigh's schedule
on the fridge,
so I thought this would be a
good morning for us to do this.
Oh, and you didn't happen
to see the directions...
That are right there to the printer?
No.
What kind of a trade show is it?
It's a health
and fitness trade show...
To get out the word
on dance mamas.
Uh--
[Snickers]
I'm sorry. It's just the name, mom.
It's-- it's just the name.
Justine, I'm sorry.
I forgot, okay?
Sweetie? Justine.
[Door slams]
- shoot.
- Yikes.
We got all morning.
[Chattering, laughing]
[Babbling]
Sorry. I--
I'm s-- sorry.
In the summers,
when I was really little,
we'd go up to my mom's friend's,
up in Vermont.
He had, like,
a... Cabin.
So small,
on a lake.
You'd have to shower
in the lake.
We'd catch sunfish.
And, you know,
they were just--
people usually
throw 'em back.
But we'd cook 'em
on the fire.
They were the best.
You can bite.
Be careful.
We don't want you getting hurt.
[Man]  I Was Out Paying close attention
Or Was I Lost
Inside my thoughts
These Days
It's hard to tel
What's Outside
From what's in my mind
Oh, God, It's Beautiful
Insatiable
The Way
Our chemicals collid
Slower.
I Was Out
Catching up to tomorrow
Or Was I Caught Up
In the past?
These Days
It's hard to tell
What's Out In Front
From what's behind
Oh, God,
It's Unforgettable
Unpredictable
The Way
Our chemicals collide
[Moaning]
[Fades]
Think we're
gonna move soon.
School's gonna start.
Gotta get a move on.
Soon when?
Few days.
Do you actually
have money saved?
I have, like,
400 from helping my dad around here.
Jay, you need
at least a thousand.
At least.
You don't know how long it's gonna
take you to get work up there.
Why don't you just take
a few more weeks...
And work hard with your dad...
And...
Just hang out?
[Resumes]
I Was Sleeping
In the lilies
Or Was I Up All Night?
These Days
It's hard to tell
What's Half Asleep
From fully alive
We Were Loving
Like a landslide
Or Were We In A Fight?
These Days
It's hard to tell
What's Right From Wrg
And wrong from right
Please, please,
don't be doing something...
That I can't know about.
What?
I would have to tell.
You're stoned.
I am?
I am.
I am merely
spending time.
I am merely sucking up his youth like a vampire.
[Todd] When are you leaving?
Okay.
[Matt]
A week.
[Todd] Excuse me.
[Leigh coughs]
They're leaving
in a week?
What?
It's time.
If you want
a change,
then, uh, try
picking up a hobby.
Yeah. Guys, I-- I really--
I wanna talk about this.
I think we can even bring guidance in to-- no.
No. No.
I'm not staying in this fucking
town with these asshole people.
Okay?
There's, like,
a world out there outside of this town.
[Leigh] The world is full of assholes.
At least we're the assholes that you know.
You need a drink?
Let's get you a drink.
I'll come.
[Todd] Oh.
Do you have a lighter?
Thanks.
Are you okay?
No. I hate it here.
I hate my life.
I did too.
But, like,
why don't you leave, man?
I mean, like, you actually could, like,
go to New York city.
'Cause I can't.
And my parents are here,
you know.
Family, friends.
People know me.
Once I leave,
everything...
Would be
very, very different.
You know
how my brother died?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we were seniors.
I remember really well.
Like--
he was a fuckup.
I mean, he was
such a fuckup.
But--
I don't know.
And, like,
he died,
and my mom can't even stand the sight of me.
Like, for real.
I see it on her face
every time I walk in the room.
So--
I'm sorry.
That's terrible.
What the fuck, dude?
I'm not gay.
No, but you're very cute.
What is wrong with you?
I was trying
to fucking talk to you.
Look, I was-- I was-- we were talking.
I'm sorry.
I was
talking to you.
Sorry.
What the fuck, matt?
Let's go tomorrow.
Why? I thought we said,
like, in a week or whatever.
I need to get out of here.
I need to get the fuck
out of this town.
Are you coming or not?
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
But not, like, tomorrow.
I mean, dude,
I need some time to get some money.
I don't wanna just go
up there with nothing.
How much time do you need?
I don't know.
But not now.
Okay.
[Chattering]
[Man]  I Have Seen You In various stages of undress
I Have Seen You Through
Various states of madnes
I Have Seen
Your refractions
And I Did Not
Recognize you
I Have Seen You
In various states of madness
How High
Your Highest Of Heights?
How Low Are Your Lows?
How High
Your Highest Of Heights?
How Low Are Your Lows?
Um, 2003,
I think--
I wanna say.
So yeah,
like nine years.
Shit, my dad could do this
in, like, two months.
They want
to do it themselves.
It's like a...
Midlife thing,
like a... "Do something
with my hands" thing.
Yeah?
Well, they didn't.
[Laughs] I know.
I know.
[Groans]
It's so embarrassing.
It's like--
how hard is it...
To just move forward and--
leigh.
Just wanted to make sure
you weren't the raccoons.
[Both laugh]
[Crickets chirping]
Oh, no. Are you still up
because of me?
[Justine] We started that addition
when you went off to college.
You know, I made
your dad do it.
I made him go
to home depot.
I made him do
the plans with me...
So we would have...
Something together.
You know how that worked out.
But it's not funny, leigh.
And it's not yours--
it's not yours
to be embarrassed about.
I--
I need you to move out. Now.
Are you serious?
Mom, I'm sorry that I was snarky about the addition--
has it ever
occurred to you...
That I might be working
on my life?
Hmm?
We both can't be doing that
at the same time?
Oh, is that
what you're doing?
Yes.
You know, I'm al--
I'm allowed
to, um, be confused...
And stumble
once in a while.
Okay? I've never done that up until this point.
Okay? Never.
Let me tell you something.
I've always been 100 %--
your father
would be so happy...
To keep you
as a baby forever.
But it's different
for the mother.
Now, I know you don't know
what that means yet, but--
you know that you were
the solar eclipse of my life?
That's what I wanted.
I hung on
your every breath...
Until--
well, until recently,
and I-- I just can't--
I'm not--
I can't go back
in time with you.
I'm not asking you to.
You have to go.
[Exhales]
[Sobbing]
[Sniffles]
No, no, no. No.
Sweetheart, I'll talk to mom,
and we'll smooth this out. Okay?
You can't, dad.
[Suitcase zips]
Leigh?
I'm leaving now.
Moose! Moose!
Hi.
Can we come in?
[Mews]
Hey.
So, matt went to Vermont.
Already?
I think so.
His car's gone.
His mom said he left yesterday at breakfast time...
And hasn't been back.
Why did he go without you?
At the fields,
I told him I wanted more time.
You know, so--
I don't know.
Maybe he's
feeling it out up there.
You know?
Getting the jobs lined up.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
Jay.
Hmm?
[Throat
clearing]
Oh, my god.
Sorry.
[Clears throat]
Hello.
[Sighs]
News FLASH: Time moves
in one direction.
Okay?
[Sighs] John--
you're-you're not
a kid anymore, mel, okay?
You are 30 years old.
And we have a plan. Okay?
So you need to stop dicking around.
I'm not dicking around.
Oh, yeah, right.
I'm just being free. I'm--
what, um-- what?
You're-you're being what?
You're being free?
I'm sor-- I'm being... Carefree.
[Chuckles] Oh, yeah.
And it's normal.
It's normal, john--
people this age.
You feel--
yeah.
Nostalgic, I guess,
and you have a hard time making--
come on. That's
fucking bullshit, okay?
I don't. I'm not. Right?
You know what this fucking is?
This is leigh. Okay?
She is scared to death of her life,
so she comes running home,
and you guys all start acting like fucking teenagers.
This has nothing to do with leigh.
Yes, it does, damn it!
Do you love me?
Yes, of course I love you.
Okay, and do you wanna
make a family with me?
Yes.
Theoretically, I do.
Okay.
All right.
Then let's do it.
Right here,
right now.
[Shoe hits floor]
No.
Yes.
I'm mad at you! No!
Listen to me, okay?
I need you to promise me
you're gonna do this, okay?
That the two of us
are gonna do this together,
and-and-and-and you're not gonna be,
you know, drinking...
And-and-and-and smoking.
No more doing drugs.
We are gonna move forward...
Like two people,
like two adult people do, okay?
Right now, right here.
[Pats table]
I just need
a little bit more time.
No, baby.
I--
please.
I'm sorry.
[Exhales]
Okay.
[Cell phone chimes]
Mm-mmm.
Oh, shit.
What?
Leigh's cat...
Ran away
from little jay's.
Well, obviously,
you can't bring a cat to a stranger's house.
They're gonna freak out.
Well, she's there with him.
What do you mean,
she was there with it?
She wasn't there when it happened.
She was probably at the pool.
She's not-- she's not staying at little jason's.
Todd?
Todd, don't look at me.
Oh, my god.
You let this happen?
What is wrong with you?
I wish everyone
would stop saying that.
Oh, my god.
You've any idea how much
you just hurt me, mel?
[Sarcastic chuckle] I-- I-- I can't even--
this has nothing to do with me.
[Chattering]
What's wrong?
What the fuck?
What is wrong with you?
Hey, no shoving
on the pool deck.
Jason, where's your dad?
I need to speak to him.
Wait. Wait.
Mel, what-- what is going on? No, leigh.
Okay-- okay, wait.
Just--
mm-mmm.
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait!
No! You lied to me.
Stop, mel.
- I didn't. No, I didn't. I--
- where's your dad?
Mel, stop. No.
Fuck you for putting me in this position.
- Please.
- Leigh, he's a kid!
Why did you have
to come home?
Just come home
and fuck everything up.
I didn't. Everything
was already fucked up.
And-and-and things
aren't fucked up.
I'll tell him you've been hanging
out with us and drinking and stuff.
Oh, my god.
[Sighs]
Mel--
no.
You know what?
I think that you couldn't let me have my shit together.
'Cause that was always your thing,
and I was the fuckup, so--
- what? That's not true. That's not true.
- Congratulations.
- That's not--
- I'm so sorry, jason.
Jason, really,
I am truly sorry.
Why? I'm-i'm fine.
I mean, it's not like
she rapes me or anything.
Oh, my god.
[Exhales]
[Mel] I'm gonna lose my job.
I'm gonna have to resign.
No.
Yes, 'cause it's
the right thing.
You're my friend,
and I let you suck me down this rabbit hole.
Please, mel. Mel, please.
Please, you cannot--
you can--
please, you can't tell.
I can't--
please.
Tell, leigh?
Leigh, you're an adult.
Grow up.
I'm gonna
take care of this.
And fuck you both.
Mel!
[Softly]
Fuck.
[Exhales]
[Man]  There's A Painting Of a face
Underneath
The hancock train
Christmas Lights Hang Don
From the sky
Going out.
Paper Dolls Say Pray
To A Watercolor Stain
Moose?
To Keep Us Se
From August
Moose.
To July
Moosey!
[Kissing sounds]
[Sighs]
Moosey!
Moose!
Moose.
[Kissing sounds]
Moose?
[Singsongy]
Moose!
Moose.
No, no, no, no.
Don't look. Don't look.
[Gasps]
No, no. No, no. No, no.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
[Whimpering]
Don't, don't, don't, don't.
We got to get him down.
Okay.
Okay. Don't look.
Don't look. Don't look.
[Sobs]
Wait. No, he-- no, he--
don't, don't, don't.
We have to get him down.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
[Hyperventilating]
Get him down.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
[Sobbing]
Okay. Shh.
I'm gonna take you--
so we're gonna go tell your dad.
He's in Vermont though.
Yeah, we're gonna go tell your dad, okay?
And you lean on me,
'cause I'm gonna take you.
I'm taking you, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Come on.
[Jason crying]
Who's gonna tell his mom?
It's the second time...
That some cop has to come
and tell her that her kid is dead.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'll do it.
Uh, I'll tell her.
All right.
[Leigh]
I'll do it.
[Crying]
Mrs. Graff?
Yeah?
My name is leigh.
I'm the lifeguard, and--
I need to speak with you.
[No audible dialogue]
[Woman]
I
Must
Follow
These Movements
Wherever They Go
I
Must
Follow
These Movements
Wherever They Go
I'm Caught
In Your Undertow
Caught In Your Undertow
[No audible dialogue]
I've
Been
Trying
So Hard
I've Been Up Here So Long
I've
Been
Trying
So Hard
I've Been Swimming So Long
I'm Caught
In Your Undertow
Take Me
Out To Sea
I'm sorry.
Away
From
You And Me
Let
Me
Float
Lead Me
Out To Sea
Um, Mr. Paciorek?
Sorry.
Just wait a minute.
I didn't get a chance
to personally apologize.
Not necessary.
Well, I just wished that I'd acted on my suspicions...
And protected
your son better.
From what? Getting laid?
And that's not me saying that's
what actually happened officially.
Right. No.
I know you don't-- you don't wanna say that.
Um--
but the school would like
to help jason process, and--
anything that we can do--
you know he wants to drop out.
Look, jason's been through enough in his life already.
Real problems.
You get me?
This thing with the lifeguard--
things happen.
Keep moving or die.
You understand?
I got to go.
All right.
Okay.
[Door closes]
[Engine starts]
[Scoffs]
[Door chimes]
[Laughs]
What are you doing here?
I just wanna talk.
So, um--
what happened?
Is, uh,
leigh going, uh,
down the river?
[Chuckles]
Or up the river,
whatever they say. [Chuckles]
It's not funny, john.
I know.
No, she's not.
Jason and his father,
they refused to name names,
and... Principal holley just won't accept my resignation.
Uh, good.
That's good.
Is it?
Yeah.
Do you really think
that I could be a mother?
'Cause I don't know.
You are a little...
Out of control.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm. And you're
a pervert, right?
I mean, not like leigh,
but you know what I mean. Right?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, mel, I do.
Obviously.
[Laughing] John-- come on.
[Laughing continues]
Just come on.
All your dance clothes and
workout gear are in the closet.
This computer
actually works.
And I hooked up the printer,
got you an e-mail--
dancemamas@gmail.
The password is "outofmyhouse"-- one word.
I love you so much.
I love you too, mom.
[Man] yea,
though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil,
for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
Thou preparest
a table before me--
whose outfit
is that?
My mom's.
I'm sorry.
I know.
[Sighs]
[Meows]
You're leaving.
I'm gonna go back to the city.
Todd's gonna stay with me
until he finds a place.
I'm gonna look for another job.
New York times.
Education beat.
[Moose mewing]
You remember
the tiger in the apartment?
I won a journalism prize
for my story.
Um, it's a thousand dollars.
Wha-- no, I can't--
I can't take this.
You have to. Please?
Please.
So you can leave...
And go to Vermont.
Why would you
do this for me?
'Cause you know
who you are...
And what you need.
You really do.
And you're gonna be just fine.
You are, believe me.
Believe me.
I have to go.
[Man]
We Salute At The Threshold
Of The North Sea
In My Mind
And A Nod To The Boredm
That drove me here
To Face The Tide And Swim
[Chorus Vocalizing]
I Swim
Oh, Swim
[No audible dialogue]
Dip A Toe In The Ocean
Oh, How It Hardens
And it numbs
The Rest Of Me
Is a version of man
Built To Collapse
In crumbs
And If I Hadn't Come Dn
To the coast to disappea
I May Have Died
In a landslide
Of Rocks
And hopes and fears
So Swim
Until you can't see land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Can't
See land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Can't
See land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
[Chorus Vocalizing]
Up To My Knees Now
Do I Wait?
Do I dive?
The Sea Has Seen
My like before
Though It's My Firt
And perhaps last tim
Let's Call Me A Baptist
Call This A Drownig
Of the past
She's There On The Shorelie
Throwing stones at my back
So Swim
Until you can't see land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Cant
See land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Cant
See land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
And The Water's
Taller than me
And The Land
Is a marker line
All I Am Is A Body
Adrift In Water,
Salt and sky
So Swim
Until you can't see land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Cant
See land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Cant
See land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Swim Until You Cant
See land
Swim Until You
Can't see land
Are You A Man?
Are you a bag of sand?
[Rock Intro]
[Woman]  Come Back Meet me at the lakefront
He Says, "Hey,
We're all waiting there"
Tiff Is Coming Too
But That Bitch
Is always late
Donny And
His slut girlfriend
Heidi And Her Sister, Yeah
Says We'll Smoke In
An apple
I Say I'm Not A Girl Scout
Do You Know How
How To Get Me There?
Make Me Forget
Fall is in the air
Come On, Last Forever
We Won't Last Forever
Mom Is Calling Us,
But we're still high
Still High For Now
Uh-oh, Uh-oh, Oh
He Says,
"Don't you ever stop
I Say,
"We're raindrops in the sun"
Still High For Now
Uh-oh, Uh-oh, Oh
Uh-oh, Uh-oh
Still High For Now
Still High
For now
Uh-oh, Uh-oh, Oh