(THE CLIENTELE'S " [I CAN'T SEEM TO]
MAKE YOU MINE" PLAYING)
♪ In the silence
Of the garden ♪
♪ Moss arising on the wind
♪ And the beast is pondering
Love, love, love ♪
♪ Till the rusty nail
Grow dim ♪
♪ I can't seem
To make you mine ♪
♪ Through the long
And lonely night ♪
♪ And I try so hard, darling
♪ But the crowd
Pulled you away ♪
♪ Through the rhythm
And the rain ♪
♪ And the ivy coiled around
My hand ♪
(WHIMPERS)
You coming or not?
♪ I can't seem
To make you mine ♪
♪ Through the long
And lonely night ♪
♪ And I try so hard, darling
♪ But the crowd
Pulled you away ♪
♪ Through the rhythm
And the rain ♪
♪ And the ivy coiled around
My hand ♪
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
MAN: All right, I'll
get her in right away.
MAN 2:
Appreciate it.
Hi.
WOMAN (OVER PA): Dr. Klyczynski to ER,
stat. Dr. Klyczynski to ER, stat.
Hi, excuse me.
Yeah, just a minute, okay?
Fill this out for me
and wait over there.
No, I'm... I'm Dr. Forster.
I was told to report here.
You'll be covering 22 patients
on rounds today,
this floor and the next.
Twenty-two?
Quiet morning.
If you get into trouble,
beep me,
but don't make it a habit.
The med students
will help you out with scutwork.
What's he doing here?
I ordered an MRI, stat.
Transport said
about four hours.
He could be dead in four hours.
Never mind. Dr. Forster, MRI.
That's a right, two
lefts, elevator to two.
Okay.
Follow the signs.
Hustle back here for rounds.
Um, Dr. Kly...
Are you taking me somewhere?
I certainly hope so, sir.
How are you feeling today?
Am...? Am I gonna make it?
Uh, yes.
Absolutely.
(SAW BLADE WHIRRING)
(MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
Alex!
I made my famous spinach pie.
The trailer's nice and toasty.
I can't.
Look, it's really cold
out here.
Don't get sick on me
or anything.
I never get sick.
So I heard you bought a house,
and apparently
I'm the last one to know.
I thought I mentioned that.
Wait.
Where?
Outside of town.
Up the shore a little bit.
Up the shore?
There's no houses...
Oh, God.
You don't mean that thing
with the stilts and the...?
(WOMAN YELPS)
You all right?
Yeah.
Are you crazy?
Why would you take that house,
Alex?
It's made of glass.
There's no privacy.
Mona?
Huh?
Get yourself some boots.
ALEX:
Hey, Gonzalez!
(MUMBLING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHISPERS)
Four-thirty.
You lost?
Yeah.
Takes a while
to get your bearings.
I'm Madhvi.
Kate Forster. Hi.
Oh, wrong floor.
Where'd you do your residency?
Just a little community hospital
up on the North Shore.
(♪)
KATE: Dear new tenant,
welcome to your new home.
As the previous tenant,
let me say
I hope you'll like living here
as much as I did.
I filed the change of address
with the post office,
but you know what a crapshoot
that can be.
So if anything slips through,
would you do me a favor
and forward my mail?
I'd appreciate it.
My new address is below.
Thanks in advance.
P.S.
"Sorry about the paw prints
by the front door.
"They were there
when I moved in.
Same with the box in the attic."
Paw prints?
What the hell
is she talking about?
(DOOR SHUTS)
Hey, baby girl. Hi. Hi. Hey.
(FLICKS SWITCH)
(KEYS JINGLING)
Fix the light.
Get dog food, huh?
(DOG BARKS)
Get human food.
(♪)
Hey. Hey.
(DOG BARKING)
Hey, come here.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
KATE:
Sixty degrees on Valentine's Day.
This can't be Chicago.
KATE'S MOTHER:
The TV says it's global warming.
The icebergs start melting,
water covers the earth.
Thank God we won't
live to see it.
KATE:
What's this?
Hm? Oh.
That's nothing.
It's one of your father's.
Dostoyevsky?
Oh, yeah.
It's about a guy
who breaks the neck
of a poor woman with an axe
and, so far, keeps wandering
around regretting it.
Mm.
This is good.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. It's really good.
Mmm.
MAN:
I'll meet you there.
What are you thinking?
WOMAN:
My folks are coming into town.
Nothing.
When your father passed away,
it was hard.
It still is hard.
Holding his books,
I feel like he's
with me somehow.
Knowing that he was once
on the same pages,
reading the same words.
(VEHICLE HONKING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
KATE:
Dear God.
WOMAN 2: Oh, my God!
Somebody call an ambulance!
(PANICKED SHOUTING)
We need an ambulance
at Daley Plaza.
A man has been struck by a bus.
Get an EMT crew here. Sir...
COP: Get out the street.
Get on the sidewalk.
On the sidewalk. Off the street.
Sir? Sir?
Get on the sidewalk!
ALEX: I'd like to get the foundation
on number 17 dug today.
MULHERN: Look, I know you're
kind of new around here, kid.
What?
I can't get to 17 until
at least next week.
Come on, Mulhern.
That's bullshit and you know it.
Take Clemens and Rodriguez
off of roofing.
Jorge can run the backhoe
they're not using on 14,
and grab four or five
of those other guys
who are sitting around
doing nothin' on seven and 10.
Paulie, Carlos, Frank, Danny,
and what's-his-name,
the tall guy.
Rafael.
Let's go.
Okay.
MAN 1: Ready?
MAN 2: Yeah.
MAN 3: All I need's a 10 and 11.
(WHISTLES SHARPLY)
Hey!
WOMAN (OVER PA): Housekeeping ER
to the Suture Room, please.
Housekeeping ER
to the Suture Room.
Hey.
Hi.
I heard about Daley Plaza.
Mm-hm.
EMT said you fought hard
for the guy.
Mm-hm. Yep.
Really knocked myself out.
KLYCZYNSKI: Kate, I'm going to tell
you what I tell every young doctor.
Hopefully,
you'll be the first to listen.
On your day off,
get as far away
from this place as you can.
Go someplace where you feel...
most like yourself.
(♪)
(DOG PANTING)
(DOG WHIMPERS)
ALEX:
Dear Ms. Forster:
I got your note,
and I'm afraid there must be
some kind of misunderstanding.
As far as I know,
the lake house has been empty
for several years.
Maybe your note was intended
for the Sandburg house
down the shore...
"... since no one has lived
in this house for years.
But I'm curious
about the paw prints."
KATE:
Dear Mr. Wyler,
I'm very familiar
with the Sandburg cottage,
and I can guarantee
I never lived there.
I'm old-fashioned,
but I don't think a cottage
should be over
6000 square feet.
So let me try again.
I used to live
at the lake house.
Then I moved.
Now I live at 1620 North Racine
in Chicago.
I'd appreciate it if you would
forward my mail if you get any.
Oh, by the way, it's 2006.
Has been all year.
Ask anyone.
2006?
What does she mean, 2006?
God.
Oh, God.
MAN: Good morning, Mr. Wyler.
WOMAN: Morning, Mr. Wyler.
ALL: Morning, sir.
Morning, morning.
Hello, Mr. Wyler.
Mr. Wyler.
Sir.
Well, uh...
obviously I derive
my inspiration
for the metaphor
of the fugue, the loop...
Yeah.
(HUMMING)
HENRY: Two hours of that shit.
You kidding me?
WOMAN: What are you talking about?
He didn't say a word.
Sadistic, bitter,
bitter old man.
I think you're being
a little overdramatic.
Where are you going?
MAN:
Oh, I love that place.
I can't believe that thing's
still running.
Yep.
You look like shit.
I missed you too.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, forget about him.
ALEX:
Condos.
Riviera Estates.
You're joking.
I don't believe this.
I come back after four years,
and I get this in front of me.
What?
My little brother thinking
he's Frank Lloyd Whatever.
Oh, come on.
Dad keeps you hostage
in that little mythmaking
factory of his,
while you haven't built
so much as a phone booth
or a hamster cage.
That's funny you say that,
actually.
I have a hamster cage in mind.
A development of them, actually.
Ah.
Prefab, no foundations.
What do you think about that?
See, that's what
I'm talking about.
You have vision.
Ah.
Speaking of which,
I'd like you to know...
I bought a house.
Where?
On the lake.
You bought a lake house.
So you are making some money.
Well, it's a dump.
Been abandoned for years, but...
Oh, so you got an abandoned,
haunted lake hou...
I guess... Yeah,
that's as good a reason as any
for selling out and joining
the flabby-developers' guild.
How about this?
I even got a dog.
You got a dog?
He just showed up at the house,
from out of nowhere.
(CARLA BRUNI'S "LA NOYÉE"
PLAYING)
♪ Ou bien
Frôlant quelques ronces ♪
♪ Tu hésites
Et tu m'attends... ♪
HENRY:
What are we doing here?
ALEX:
I have to deliver a letter.
It should be here.
1620 North Racine.
HENRY:
But...
there's nothin' here.
Are we meeting someone?
Does somebody live here? What?
Yeah.
I thought so.
HENRY:
Should we ring the bell?
(MAKES BUZZER SOUND)
ALEX:
Dear Ms. Forster:
I went to 1620 North Racine,
and it's not there.
It's just a construction site.
From the pictures
it looks nice,
but not for another 18 months.
What am I missing here?
Maybe you got
the address wrong,
because I noticed
you got the date wrong too.
You really
wanna play this game.
If you are truly
in the year 2004,
then...
be forewarned.
Remember that day?
You were not happy.
Remember that?
(SIGHS)
I know.
KATE: Okay, my mystery
correspondent, I get it.
Just in case you really are
where and when
you think you are,
you'll need this.
There was a freak late snow
that spring
and everyone got sick.
So plenty of rest,
lots of fluids.
Doctor's orders.
(SCOFFS)
Snow. Right.
Yeah, come to papa.
(WIND WHISTLING)
(SNEEZES)
(♪)
KATE:
Jackie.
Jack.
(JACK BARKING)
Jack, come on. Come on, girl.
Come on, come on. Jack.
(BARKING)
"Impossible, I know.
Not possible...
but it's happening."
Okay.
(SIGHS)
Where am I?
(SNIFFS)
(SIGHS)
Very clever.
"The lake house."
The lake house.
Yes, well, as you can see,
I, too, am at the lake house,
but I'm getting
tired of these games
so I'm leaving, okay? Bye.
Thank you. Bye.
Maybe we should
introduce ourselves properly.
KATE: I'm a doctor, dedicated
to curing the sick.
(SPRAYS)
At least, trying to.
ALEX: I'm an architect.
I like to build.
And while I wouldn't say
my current project is ideal,
it allows me to be here,
in this place,
and that's enough for now.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
But tell me something.
If you're working
in a hospital in Chicago now,
where were you before,
in my time?
KATE:
Two years ago, in your time,
I was working in internal
medicine in Madison.
(ALARM BEEPING)
ALEX:
Tell me about the future.
What's it like
in the year 2006?
KATE: Hm. I'm afraid the
world's pretty much the same.
Of course, we all dress
in shiny metal jump suits
and drive flying cars,
and no one talks anymore
because we can
read each other's minds.
(CHUCKLES)
But the truth is,
man from the past,
not much
has really changed in 2006.
(JACK BARKING)
KATE:
Speaking of the past, though,
I've been thinking about
the paw prints.
How is that possible?
Well, I think
we have the same dog.
KATE: Oh, yeah?
What's yours like?
According to the vet, mine
is 8 years old, in my time.
Uh, 6 in yours.
She's skinny, has sad eyes,
snores...
and sleeps like a person.
I don't know why,
but I call her Jack.
Hello, Jack.
ALICIA (OVER TV):
It's nice out here.
Let's not go out for dinner.
Let's stay here.
Hey.
DEVLIN (OVER TV):
We have to eat.
What are you doing?
You're supposed to be asleep.
I'll cook.
I thought
you didn't like to cook.
No, I don't like to cook.
GIRL:
Is she gonna marry him?
What do you think?
I don't know.
He's kind of old.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay, he's not that old.
My mom's
last boyfriend was bald.
He was nice,
but my mom didn't marry him.
No?
"There's always somethin' better
comin' around the corner."
That's what she says.
Maybe that's
what that lady should do.
Wait for something better
to come around the corner.
Maybe.
But if she's not careful,
she could spend
her whole life waiting.
Do you want me to bring
anything back with me?
Yes. What about
a nice bottle of wine
to celebrate?
What time shall I come back?
Seven o'clock.
KATE: Sorry I haven't made
it to the mailbox lately.
It's been a long week.
All night shifts.
ALEX: Good to hear from you.
I thought you left me.
You should know that
you're my only connection
to the future.
How come we never talk
about the things we like?
KATE: Hm. Well, let's see.
Reading the classics to Jack.
ALEX:
Who's his favorite?
KATE:
Dostoyevsky.
ALEX:
For me, this city,
on a day when
the light is so clear
that I can touch every detail,
every brick and window
in the buildings I love.
Come on, take a walk with me,
this Saturday. Let me show you.
KATE:
You're crazy.
Why are you going through
all this trouble for me?
ALEX: No trouble.
Summer's here.
(EELS' "ANT FARM" PLAYING)
♪ Walk down the street
I'm thinking ♪
♪ Everybody move along
♪ I've got a sad-hearted
Needing to belong ♪
ALEX: Okay, your turn.
Favorite things.
KATE:
Where to start? Okay.
When I smell the flowers
before I see them.
When it starts to rain
just as the picnic is ending.
And I love the smell
of Jack's paws.
ALEX: You didn't forget to
mention your husband, did you?
KATE: Oh. Well, of course
I love my husband,
who is also a doctor.
Plastic surgeon
for small farm animals.
ALEX:
Good. I'm married too.
I've got eight children,
and none of them look like me.
I'm worried, Kate.
KATE: I would be too.
(ALEX CHUCKLES)
ALEX:
I'm single.
KATE:
Me too.
Oh. Wow.
Number 27.
ALEX: She's a beauty.
My father used to tell me
she was the grandma
for all the houses in the city.
He used to take me on walks
like I'm taking you now.
KATE:
Alex?
ALEX:
Kate?
KATE: I wish we could have
done this walk together.
So, what do you think?
He sounds like a nice boy.
Sounds like a nice boy.
Anything else?
He has wonderful penmanship.
Mother,
look at the date on the letter.
The date.
Oh, you mean the time thing?
Yes.
That's just a detail.
Just a detail?
(SIGHS)
(GERRY MULLIGAN'S "ALMOST LIKE
BEING IN LOVE" PLAYING)
SIMON: About the, uh...
The other day, uh,
it was not a good moment.
I was in a hell of a hurry.
ALEX:
Of course.
You've got some
nice pieces here.
Oh, yeah.
Music's fine, music helps.
(CHUCKLES)
It's like Nietzsche says:
"Life would be senseless..."
"Without music."
I guess I told you that, huh?
Pour yourself a drink.
Can you appreciate
a good wine by now?
You bet.
You know, you'll have to forgive
your father for being curious,
but where have you been
all these years?
I thought your Kerouac days
were behind you.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry, what?
What?
Oh, you can come up
if you like.
What are you working on?
Oh, I'm just...
I'm just remembering things.
It's not such an easy job,
let me tell you.
Nor is it particularly innocent,
in my case.
Your father
is writing his memoirs.
Are we in it?
What do you think?
Do you wanna be?
Do you?
Of course. You were all
a part of your father's life.
Why are you talking to me
in the third person?
Well, I... I don't...
Because I'm writing
about myself, I suppose.
Why, doesn't it suit you?
I thought you might like these.
What are these? Something
you've been working on?
No, they're...
They're yours.
From a house I just bought
on the lake.
Oh, yes, I heard.
They said some sleazy
little condo developer
had snapped it up.
Oh, come on.
Indulge your father.
Can't you take a little joke,
for God's sake?
Come on.
Tell me.
Where have you been?
I really want to know.
I was trying to forget you.
Or forgive you.
Did you succeed?
No.
Let me know if you need
any help remembering.
Oh, yeah, I will.
KATE: Charging 360.
Get 1 milligram of epi.
Have 300 amio ready
in case we need it.
All clear?
NURSE: Clear.
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
Hold compression,
start bagging.
He's got a rhythm. Slow.
Do we have a pulse with that?
We got a pulse, thready.
It's getting stronger.
KATE:
Long days, these days.
I just worked
30 hours straight.
Every time
I stop to take a breath,
I realize how isolated
I've let myself become.
Believe me,
you can get a bit desperate.
That one?
Okay. There you go.
Nice move.
Very nice. Nice.
It's not that I'm complaining.
I love my work.
And our tour through Chicago
opened my eyes to its beauty.
But my heart still misses
the lake house...
and its trees.
I miss those trees so much.
(BRAD MEHLDAU'S
"WHEN IT RAINS" PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
ALEX: Don't worry, Kate.
We'll be together in time.
Even if we're far apart,
I'll find a way
to be close to you
and take care of you.
Oh, lu, lu, lu, lu.
Katerina.
Take this.
You should eat more.
You too skinny.
I'm not too skinny.
Remember how you used to eat
when you were little?
Chuga, chuga, chug, chug.
With your hands.
Yes, I remember.
Now, did you or did you not
write to each other?
To your father?
No, to Clark Gable.
Yes, to Dad.
I, uh...
What, Mom?
Before your father...
Yeah?
There was this boy.
Did you love him?
Yeah.
Well...
Why...? Why didn't you
marry him?
So that you could ask me
this question someday.
(♪)
Looks smaller.
Uh, when did he complete it?
You weren't born yet,
and I was 8.
God.
Corbusier meets
Frank Lloyd Wright.
You know, Dad played cards
with both of 'em.
Sharing a joint.
Yeah, well...
(CHUCKLES)
ALEX:
Can't swim.
There should be a stairway
down to the water,
a porch, a deck.
Here, you're in a...
In a box.
A glass box with a view
to everything that's around you,
but you can't touch it.
No interconnection between
you and what you're looking at.
HENRY:
I don't know, you know.
He's got this big maple growing
right in the middle
of the house.
Containment.
Containment and control.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
This house is about ownership,
not connection.
I mean, it's beautiful.
Seductive, even.
But it's incomplete.
It was all about him.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Dad knew how to build
a house, not a home.
But you know,
I think he wants us to do
what he couldn't.
But admitting that...
would mean admitting that
he came up short in some way,
that he could do more.
And that tortures him.
Do you remember
being here with Mom?
I remember she tried
to make it work here...
with us...
with him.
Hey, what about
Visionary Vanguard?
What about it?
Come on.
You can't convince me
you're gonna be happy
building these saltboxes
for tourists.
Nobody's gonna admire you
for that.
Admire me for that?
Yeah, Visionary Vanguard.
(LAUGHS)
That's your idea.
I can't.
But you can keep the name.
No, come on.
It's gotta be you and me.
Henry, I'm sorry,
I can't. I...
I just, uh...
What?
I've got other plans.
You have a girlfriend?
Nah... Mm, no.
What is that?
You hesitated.
No, I didn't hesitate.
Come on, man. I don't have...
I don't have any time for that.
What does time
have to do with it?
Oh, you're gonna think
I'm crazy.
KATE:
My dearest Mr. Wyler:
Are you willing to play
a game with me?
Two years ago today,
I was taking the 145 train
to Madison
from the Riverside station,
and I forgot something there.
It was a gift from my father.
If you find it,
can you please put it
in the mailbox?
It would mean a lot.
Yours, Kate.
Final call for
the 5:46 to Madison.
Do you really wanna know?
Come on.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
All aboard.
MAN: Okay.
I'll call you.
(♪)
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
ALEX: Kate, I found it.
I have it with me.
One day I'll get it to you.
Trust me.
I know how important
it is to you.
You might not remember,
but we saw each other.
At least, I saw you.
You never told me
how beautiful you are.
KATE: Well, maybe you
saw somebody else.
That was a bad hair year
for me.
ALEX: Long brown hair.
Gentle, unguarded eyes.
KATE:
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
You saw me.
But I still don't know
what you look like.
ALEX: Well, why don't we just
get together in the future,
and you can let me know
what you think.
It's a date.
Okay.
Why don't you call me
July 10th, 2006, at...
9:05 p.m.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
MAN:
Kate?
Yes.
It's Morgan.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Morgan.
Yeah, I'm here, in Chicago.
I came down for a meeting,
but it was canceled,
so I thought
I'd give you a call.
MORGAN:
Hey, uh, have you eaten?
No, but I'm not...
Neither have I.
I just realized
I'm totally starving.
We could grab a quick bite.
Okay.
Yeah?
All right.
MAN:
Hey, wait up.
WOMAN:
Watch out, man.
MAN:
All right.
Looks pretty good.
Oh.
Perfect.
No, Morgan, it's...
It's not.
No, no, trust me.
It's... Okay.
Hi there.
One sec.
Could you hold on
for a moment, please?
We'd love a table for two.
The name?
Oh, um... we don't...
We don't have a reservation.
I'm sorry, sir, we're booked...
until October.
October?
Well...
I'll get back to you.
That went well.
(LAUGHING)
It's no big deal.
(SIGHS)
Oh, come on, stop it.
It's the best restaurant
in town.
Nobody gets a table here.
No, it's not that.
Well, what is it?
I didn't do this right.
There wasn't a meeting,
was there?
You'd see me
if there was no big deal.
If it was just...
Mm-hm, ambush.
You know, coffee,
and coffee can turn into dinner,
and dinner can turn into...
Turn into what?
I'll admit, I do sometimes get
a few steps ahead of myself.
Morgan, a few steps?
You're always leaping...
10 steps ahead.
We were dating, what, a week?
And you had our entire future
mapped out for us?
Still in my residency,
you were picking out
real estate.
I would go to your house
for the weekend,
you'd have the entire town
in your house to meet me.
You know, I do seem
to remember that
you made pretty fast friends
with one of them.
What are you talking about?
Oh, you know
what I'm talking about.
That guy.
What guy?
The guy I caught you
making out with.
I wasn't making out with him.
What, are we in...
junior high school right now?
What do you call it, then?
A kiss.
It was just one kiss
with some random guy that just...
Years... You know what?
Gentlemen...
unit 381 on Riviera Estates
is complete.
(ALL CHEERING)
Congratulations.
You did a good job.
Ah.
One down...
Forty-four to go.
We're not terrifyingly
behind schedule,
just alarmingly.
(SIGHS)
It's gonna be okay.
The guys are getting
to know their job,
but we could use
another backhoe.
And the water on 14
needs to be resealed.
Shut up.
What?
I'm kind of disappointed
in you.
Why?
Because you're supposed to be
on top of things around here.
I thought I was.
Well, you never noticed these.
Don't you remember?
You told me to get 'em.
Right, right.
Wow. Not exactly
what I had in mind, but...
You like 'em?
I like them.
I think we should go out.
Tonight.
(JACK BARKING)
If you're not doing any...
Jack? Jack.
Hey, Jack.
Jack!
Come on, Jack!
Alex, wait for me!
ALEX:
Jack!
(JACK BARKING)
Yours, I take it?
Yeah. Yeah,
sorry. Thanks.
Come here, Jack.
What were you thinking,
huh, girl?
What were you thinking?
She's never run off
like that before.
You gotta keep an eye on them.
What's his name?
Her. Jack.
Jack. It's a good name
for a girl.
I should get one like you
for my girlfriend.
She loves dogs.
Hey, have we met before?
No, don't think so.
Morgan Price.
Alex Wyler.
Hey, man, you need
a hand with this?
MORGAN: Yeah.
ALEX: Okay.
MORGAN:
Lived here long?
ALEX: Just a few months.
I've got a place on the lake.
The lake, really?
I've been thinking...
Alex. Oh, good.
(PANTING)
Thank God you found him.
Yeah.
Mona, Morgan.
Morgan, Mona.
Well, hello.
Hi.
It's good to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Nice boots there.
Listen, just so you don't think
I'm gonna drink
all this by myself,
I'm having a bunch of friends
over tonight for a party.
You two are welcome to come.
Oh, hey, Alex.
Take my card.
I might be looking
to rent a place
on the lake myself.
Okay.
It's Kate, my girlfriend,
she's never really liked
this place,
and I promised her we'd look
for something new
once she finishes
her residency in Madison.
So if you hear of anything...
Sure. She's a doctor?
Yeah.
Alex.
Great to meet you, Morgan.
Great to meet you.
All right.
(CAROLE KING'S
"IT'S TOO LATE" PLAYING)
Hey, Morgan,
what time's that party at?
Eight o'clock.
It's Kate's birthday.
♪ Stayed in bed all morning
Just to pass the time ♪
It's Kate birthday.
Come on, Jack.
♪ There's something wrong here
There can be no denyin' ♪
♪ One of us is changin' ♪
♪ Or maybe we've just
Stopped tryin' ♪
♪ And it's too late, baby
Now it's too late ♪
♪ Though we really did try
To make it ♪
♪ Something inside has died
And I can't hide... ♪
Hi.
What can I get you?
Glass of white wine, please.
♪ It used to be so easy
Thank you.
You're welcome.
♪ Living here with you
♪ You were light and breezy
And I knew just what to do ♪
♪ Now you look so unhappy
And I feel like a fool ♪
♪ And it's too late, baby
Now it's too late ♪
According to most
accepted social norms,
a person should not drink
alone after 10 p.m.,
unless they have a good excuse.
Mm.
What's yours?
Gosh, don't have one.
(GIGGLES)
I do.
My youngest left for college
this morning.
Marie.
One day she's splashing around
a wading pool in diapers.
Then she's packing up a Volvo
and driving to California.
I just hope she knows
what she's getting into.
Don't tell me.
Premed?
Bingo.
Hey, how are you?
Good to see you.
I'm well, thanks.
I want you to meet
some friends of mine.
Alex, Mona, this is the Wootch.
Susan, Johnny.
Hi.
Let's get you something
to drink.
Come on. Back here.
Bar's back here.
Come on.
Hey, this is Marjorie.
Why didn't you mention
it was today?
We would have had a cake
for you or something.
Oh, it's just time passing.
I hate making
a big deal out of it.
You keep a lot to yourself.
Nothing wrong with it.
But I've sometimes wondered
what else you have
in your life besides work.
Family? Boyfriend?
Well, I did. Once.
His name was Morgan.
Morgan?
Mm-hm.
Morgan.
That's a sexy name.
(GIGGLES)
ALL:
Surprise!
(LAUGHING AND CHATTERING)
Happy birthday, Katie.
WOMAN 1:
Happy birthday.
MAN:
WOMAN 2:
We got you.
This is Kate, obviously.
Hi, Kate.
This is Alex and Mona.
Hi.
This guy's gonna help us
find our lake house.
Oh.
Right?
You haven't had cake.
KATE:
Anyway, well, I ended it.
And I'm happy now,
and it was
the right thing to do.
So who is it you write to?
I couldn't help...
Every time you get
a break at the hospital,
you're writing something.
There is someone.
It's kind of
a long-distance relationship.
How did you meet?
(LAUGHING)
We haven't.
What?
No.
The story of my life.
You're kidding.
Keep everything at a distance.
Everyone.
The man who was standing
right in front of me,
the one that wanted to marry me,
him, I push away.
I run from him.
In the meantime, the...
The one man I can never meet,
him, I would like to give
my whole heart to.
He must write one hell
of a letter.
Mm-hm.
It's nice.
It's safe.
Christ, he's in prison, isn't he?
No.
You're one of those women,
aren't you?
No. No, he's just a guy
who lives on a lake.
He's an architect.
(♪)
(WHISPERS)
Oh, my God.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SIGHS)
ALEX:
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
I hope it's a great year
for you.
Thank you.
I'm Alex.
The lake-house guy.
Oh, yeah.
How you doin'?
May I?
So you're gonna...
You're gonna find us a place
on the lake, huh?
I hope so.
Yeah.
If I can.
You're a real-estate
agent?
No, I...
I just, uh, have a lake house.
Oh. Is it nice?
Yeah, you'll love it.
You're gonna rent it
after I move out.
Oh, really?
Kate, have you...
read Persuasion?
What?
By Jane Austen.
I know who it's by.
Yeah, it's, um...
It's my favorite book.
Why...? Why did you bring
something like that up?
What made you bring that up?
I just... A friend of mine
gave it to me recently,
and I was wondering...
what it's about.
It's... It's wonderful.
Yeah.
It's about, um...
About waiting.
(CHUCKLES)
These two people, they...
They, uh... They meet.
They almost fall in love,
but the timing isn't right.
They... They have to part.
And then,
years later, they...
They meet again.
They get another chance.
You know, but they don't know
if too much time has passed.
If they waited too long,
if it's,
you know,
too late to make it work.
Why do you like that?
(LAUGHING)
I don't know.
No. Don't get me wrong.
It's beautiful in a kind of...
No, it's terrible.
It's terrible.
Terrible.
That's terrible.
It's terrible.
That's...
Yeah, it's...
That's terrible.
It's a personal question,
but have you ever been
through anything like that?
Me? No. No, no.
No.
(SIGHS)
When I was, uh...
When I was 16...
I was completely in love
with this guy.
He played guitar, and, um,
I ran away from home
and, uh, went to San Francisco
so I could go live with him.
Yeah, he convinced me
I had a beautiful voice,
and I, uh... I dreamed
of becoming a singer.
I love San Francisco.
Yeah, he was...
He was my first love.
Probably the only one.
He must have been a great guy.
I don't...
I don't know, I...
He may have been. It didn't last
long enough for me to find out.
Yeah. Truth is, I...
I can't even remember
what he looked like.
Really?
Yeah.
That's too bad.
My dad...
My dad showed up, actually.
You were in trouble.
Yeah, he came in.
Yeah, I was in trouble.
He yanked me back to Chicago.
Yeah.
And he was sick, and he, uh...
He had these...
These dreams of me becoming
a doctor, you know?
You know, and eventually,
they became my dreams too.
He was right.
You know, I...
I feel good helping people.
Then he died.
Kate.
What?
(SIGHS)
I, uh...
You...?
(PAUL McCARTNEY'S "THIS NEVER HAPPENED
BEFORE" PLAYING OVER STEREO)
I just, uh...
What?
♪ I'm very sure ♪
Do you know this song?
Mm-hm.
♪ This never happened
Yeah.
♪ To me before
♪ I met you...
Do you sing?
(KATE CHUCKLES)
No.
Nobody wants to hear me sing.
You don't wanna hear me sing.
I... I didn't mean,
you know...
(CHUCKLES)
But, yeah.
♪ This is the way
It's supposed to be ♪
But I can dance.
♪ I met you, and now I see
♪ This is the way
It should be ♪
It should be for lovers ♪
♪ They shouldn't go it alone ♪
♪ It's not so good
When you're on your own ♪
♪ So come to me
♪ Now we can be
What we wanna be ♪
♪ I love you
And now I see ♪
♪ This is the way
It should be ♪
It should be for lovers ♪
♪ They shouldn't go it alone ♪
♪ It's not so good
When you're on your own ♪
♪ I'm very sure ♪
♪ This never happened
To me before ♪
♪ I met you, and now I'm sure ♪
♪ This never happened before
♪ This never happened
MORGAN:
Kate.
Hey, um... Alex was, uh...
Alex was just telling me
about the, um... The lake house.
Yeah, it sounds...
Sounds really great.
Great.
Alex, it's late.
Yeah.
Yeah. Um...
Good night.
KATE:
It was you.
WOMAN:
Do you work tomorrow night?
Why didn't you say anything?
ALEX: You would've thought
I was crazy or drunk. Or both.
Yeah, but...
I liked you.
You should have said something.
How? You were
with your boyfriend.
You know what?
Excuses, excuses.
You are a coward.
I'm not a coward.
Oh, really? Well,
what about your girlfriend?
What? I told you already,
she's not my girlfriend.
He's not my boyfriend either.
Oh, really?
Well, what is he, then?
Your brother?
Ah. We have a comedian.
What'd you have, a clown
for breakfast this morning?
Wonderful. Our first fight.
You could write a song about it
and go sing it in San Francisco.
(PHONE RINGING)
What?
Hello.
Hey, Henry.
What?
MAN:
You'll let me know, right?
WOMAN:
Yes, I will.
Hi.
Good afternoon.
I'm looking for my father.
I don't know
which room he's in.
Simon Wyler?
Mr. Wyler, the architect?
Yes.
I'm Anna Klyczynski.
I'm the Attending
for your father.
Hey. What happened?
How is he?
He's okay. He's had
a heart attack.
Fortunately, relatively minor.
His vitals are fine,
and he's stable,
but it will require
an intervention.
He's agreed to schedule it
for tomorrow.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Good to see
you're taking it easy.
Well, you...
You didn't need to come.
I'm perfectly well.
Perfectly all right.
Well, you had
a heart attack, Dad.
I had an episode,
for chrissake.
Nothing more.
Appreciate it if you kept
everything in its perspective.
Well, then, I just wanna
let you know
I'm here if you need anything.
Coffee.
What?
You heard me.
Coffee.
ALEX: There's something
I never told you, Kate.
You see, it was my father
who built the lake house.
I mean, with his own hands.
And it was a long time ago,
before he was famous,
when he still had a family
and worshipped my mother.
Her name was Mary,
and the house was a gift
for her.
She was smart and funny.
She could've done anything,
but chose to take care
of my brother and I
and help him build his career.
You see, the more successful
he became,
the more impossible he was
to live with.
Finally, she just couldn't take
living with him anymore.
She left him.
Within a year, she got sick.
Unfortunately, she never
learned how to stop loving him.
He wasn't at the funeral.
When I asked him why...
Go on, Alex.
What did he say?
He said, "She was dead to me
the moment she stepped
out of the house."
And then he gave me
one of his
architect-of-the-year grins.
I hope you appreciate this.
I had to sneak past
three nurses and your Attending.
Oh, jeez, it's hot.
It's not decaf, is it?
It should be, but it isn't.
Ah... Mm.
That's not bad.
Thank you...
son.
You're welcome.
Where's your brother?
I sent him away.
He wasn't feeling well.
You know how he is.
He worries.
Yeah, I know.
He gets that from your mother,
I'm afraid.
She always worried too much.
What are you looking at?
Hm?
Oh, yeah, here, take a gander.
It's a proposal for a museum.
Who is it?
Oh, someone new.
Oh, I like the walkways,
where the light falls.
What are the materials?
Granite. Aluminum.
White panels
are straight out of Meier,
but the interior color coming
through the front windows,
that's different.
It's not new,
but it's clean, uncluttered.
I like it.
When was the last time
you were in Barcelona?
Years ago, with you,
Mom and Henry.
Do you remember visiting
Casa de la Caritat?
The almshouse.
Mm-hm.
That's right.
You mentioned Meier.
His Barcelona museum
stands in the same area
as Casa de la Caritat.
It drinks the same light.
Meier designed
a series of louvered skylights
to capture that light
and cast it inward
to illuminate the art within,
but indirectly.
And that was important,
because although light
enhances art,
it can also degrade it.
But you know all that already,
you son of a...
(CHUCKLES)
Now, this...
(COUGHS)
where do you suppose
this is to be built?
I have no idea.
Oh, but you said you liked it.
Conceptually.
Now, come on.
You know as well as I do
that the light in Barcelona
is quite different
from the light in Tokyo.
And the light in Tokyo is
different from that in Prague.
A truly great structure,
one that is meant
to stand the tests of time,
never disregards
its environment.
A serious architect
takes that into account.
He knows
that if he wants presence,
he must consult with nature.
He must be captivated
by the light.
Always the light.
Always.
(♪)
Hey. I have an emergency.
Take my shift. Please.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
KLYCZYNSKI:
Mr. Wyler?
Yes.
This is Dr. Klyczynski
at Chicago City Hospital.
I'm afraid I have some
difficult news for you.
KATE:
I'm so sorry, Alex.
I wish somehow
I could be there with you,
that we could sit together
and look out over the water
and the light
in this house
your father built.
I could be a shoulder for you
like you've been for me.
And tell you that
everything is gonna be okay.
If I could do one thing
for you today,
from here,
one small, simple thing
from the future,
I hope this is it.
It won't be published
for a couple of years,
but I don't think you should
have to wait that long.
I hope it helps you know
how much you were loved.
(SIGHS)
Aw.
(SNIFFLES)
(SIGHS)
(SOBBING)
(NICK DRAKE'S "PINK MOON"
PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
♪ I saw it written
And I saw it say ♪
♪ Pink moon is on its way
♪ And none of you
Stand so tall ♪
Pick a place.
I'll be there, I promise.
Tomorrow, what do you say?
But, Alex,
it won't be tomorrow for you.
You're gonna have
to wait two years.
I know, I don't care.
I'll wait.
Are you sure?
I don't know.
I do. I've never been so sure
of anything in my life.
Okay. I'll see you
in two years, then.
See you tomorrow, then.
Kate,
where would you like to go?
Il Mare.
HOSTESS: When were you
hoping to dine with us?
Two years from tomorrow.
Two years from tomorrow?
Yeah.
Two years?
From tomorrow.
Uh-huh.
Hi.
Hello. Name?
Uh, Forster.
Can I have your name?
Wyler.
Or, uh, Wyler, I'm...
I'm really not sure.
I think we should be
able to accommodate you.
Great.
Wyler?
Mm-hm.
(CHUCKLES)
Wyler.
Your waiter
will be right with you.
(ROSEMARY CLOONEY'S "THERE WILL
NEVER BE ANOTHER YOU" PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
♪ And I'll be
Standing here... ♪
Good evening, miss.
Complimentary.
♪ There will be
♪ Other songs to sing
♪ Another fall
Another spring... ♪
♪ But there will never be
Thank you.
(WHISPERS) Good luck.
♪ Another you
♪ There will be other lips
♪ That I may kiss
♪ But they won't thrill me ♪
♪ Like yours used to do...
Another glass for the lady?
(ROSEMARY CLOONEY'S
"I WISH YOU LOVE" PLAYING)
♪ And more than wealth
♪ I wish you love
♪ I wish you shelter
♪ From the storm
♪ A cozy fire
♪ To keep you warm
♪ But most of all
♪ When snowflakes fall
♪ I wish you love
(♪)
KATE:
You weren't there.
You didn't come.
I don't understand.
ALEX: Something must have happened.
I'm sorry.
I've got two years, Kate.
We can try again.
KATE:
No, Alex,
it's too late.
It already happened.
It didn't work.
ALEX:
Don't give up on me, Kate.
What about Persuasion?
You told me. They wait.
They meet again.
They have another chance.
KATE:
Life is not a book, Alex.
And it can be over in a second.
I was having lunch
with my mother at Daley Plaza,
and a man was killed
right in front of me.
He died in my arms.
And I thought:
"It can't end just like that
on Valentine's Day."
And I thought about
all the people
who love him, waiting at home,
who will never see him again.
And then I thought:
"What if there is no one?"
What if you live
your whole life
and no one is waiting?
So I drove to the lake house
looking for any kind of answer.
And I found you.
And I let myself get lost.
Lost in this beautiful fantasy
where time stood still.
But it's not real, Alex.
I have to learn
to live the life
that I have got.
Please don't write anymore.
Don't try to find me.
Let me let you go.
(♪)
(PAOLO CONTE'S
"CHIAMAMI ADESSON" PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
What? I'm sorry, hold on.
I can't hear you.
I'll be right back, sorry.
Hello. Hold on.
Hold on.
Hello.
Hi.
How long are you here?
I'm at a bar with some friends.
Come on.
Well, don't get too excited.
I find that hard to believe.
Mm. It is good.
And it was really good
to hear your voice.
I was surprised how good
it was to hear your voice.
So how was your meeting?
It was good.
Yeah?
Yeah, I, uh...
I got the job.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, congratulations.
Imagine that.
Yeah. A telecom company.
I'll be in-house counsel.
Pays well.
And it's here,
in Chicago.
Well,
it's great news.
Hey.
(♪)
What?
(WHIMPERS)
Jack.
(BARKING)
Hey, Jack.
Jack.
(♪)
MORGAN: Are you gonna
come down this weekend?
Hm?
(CHUCKLES)
Don't you miss me a little bit?
Oh, just a little bit.
Not a lot, huh?
Okay. No, I heard you.
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
Um, Kate, I'm gonna
have to call you back, okay?
Still wanna rent a lake house?
It's what Kate wants.
How the hell do you know
what Kate wants?
Trust me.
(♪)
(BARKING)
Hey, you.
I know you.
MAN:
Whatever you want out back.
ALEX:
What do you think?
You're fixating. You know?
Why do you keep
tweaking the lake house?
Why don't you do your own work.
Because it's hers.
You're, uh, talking about
the girl from the future.
Kate.
And you're still writing
with Kate?
No.
Why not?
She asked me not to.
Why?
Time.
Hey, come on.
This is a good thing.
You know, you need a real woman.
(LAUGHING) A woman...
Henry, listen.
Listen to me.
While it lasted,
she was more real to me
than any of that stuff.
She was more real to me
than anything I've ever known.
(♪)
I saw her.
I kissed her.
I love her.
And now she's gone.
She's gone.
(SIGHS)
and Duckett squirts through.
First thing...
(UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN 1: How could the Ab Scissor
four-minute ab machine...?
MAN 2: ... and your potatoes
cooking on the top.
ALICIA:
It's nice out here.
Let's stay here.
DEVLIN:
We have to eat.
We can eat here.
I'll cook.
I thought you
didn't like to cook.
No, I don't like to cook.
But I have a chicken
in the icebox,
and you're eating it.
What about all
the washing-up afterward?
We'll eat with our fingers.
Could you turn that down
a little, babe?
Don't we need any plates?
Yes. One for you,
and one for...
(♪)
(SIGHS)
"There could have been
no two hearts so open,
"no tastes so similar,
no feelings so in unison."
(SIGHS)
ALL:
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one.
Happy New Year!
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come in.
(HAMMERING)
Hi.
What do you think?
This is what I gave up
lunch for?
I know it needs work.
Work? How about
a wrecking ball?
(CHUCKLES)
I found an architect
who specializes in renovations.
I made an appointment
for tomorrow.
Oh.
(NICK DRAKE'S
"TIME HAS TOLD ME" PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
Ambush.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on.
We can't stay in my apartment.
We've been there over a year.
I wanna keep moving forward.
♪ What I really don't
Want to love ♪
♪ Time has told me...
KATE:
It's a new firm.
MORGAN:
"New" as in inexperienced?
KATE:
No. "New" as in cheap.
MORGAN:
Ah.
♪ A soul with no footprint...
Hi.
Hi, Dr. Forster.
We'll be with you in a moment.
Great, thank you.
♪ Your tears, they tell me
♪ There's really no way ♪
Oh, by the way...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Happy Valentine's Day.
Oh, God, Katie,
I didn't get you anything.
I'm sorry. I've just been
so swamped and...
Doesn't matter.
♪ And time will tell you
♪ To stay by my side
♪ To keep on trying
Whoa.
What is this?
It's global warming.
Dr. Forster?
Hi, I'm sorry
to have kept you waiting.
♪ So leave the ways
That are making you be ♪
♪ What you really
Don't want to be ♪
♪ Leave the ways
That are making you love... ♪
KATE: Good to see you again.
Dr. Forster.
You, too, welcome.
Hi, I'm Morgan.
Hey, Morgan.
Vanessa Vanderbeck.
Wow.
So obviously,
the first thing you see
is what we had talked about.
The atrium.
Wow. That's stunning.
So we were able to do it
with all the... All the...
The glass panels in...
In the metal structure?
Yeah.
Can I...?
Hey, you wanna
get a beer after work?
I'm sorry, I can't.
I'm taking Vanessa out
for Valentine's Day.
(CHUCKLES)
♪ For a troubled mind
Wait.
Say that again.
It's Valentine's Day today.
I'm taking out Vanessa,
my girlfriend.
Cold champagne, some oysters,
maybe a little chocolate.
What's the date?
It's February 14th.
February 14th, 2006.
Yeah.
Stunning.
Thank you so much.
Our pleasure.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Henry will make sure
you have everything.
Great. They were
absolutely beautiful, I...
Thank you.
What?
Katie,
I gotta get back to work.
Who did this drawing?
HENRY:
Uh, my brother did, actually.
Who's your brother?
Alex Wyler.
Did you know him?
Yeah.
Yeah, I know him.
Um, do you know how, uh,
I can get in touch with him?
Uh, is... Is he...?
Is he anywhere that I can...?
Um...
I'm sorry, um...
He...
died.
Uh, two years ago today,
actually.
Uh, there was
an accident, and...
Where?
(♪)
MORGAN:
Kate!
Wait, just stop.
Just stop.
Goddamn it, answer me.
What is the matter?
Kate.
Kate!
(SOBBING)
(♪)
KATE:
Sixty degrees on Valentine's Day.
This cannot be Chicago.
The TV says
it's global warming.
Nothing wrong with that.
It's a dangerous thing.
KATE:
Alex.
I know why you didn't show up
that night.
It was you at Daley Plaza
that day.
It was you.
Please, don't go.
Just wait. Please.
Don't look for me.
Don't try to find me.
I love you.
And it's taken me all this time
to say it, but I love you.
(CRYING)
And if you still care for me,
wait for me.
Wait with me.
Just wait. Wait.
(DINGS)
Wait two years, Alex.
Come to the lake house.
I'm here.
(♪)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
You waited.
(♪)
(PAUL McCARTNEY'S "THIS NEVER
HAPPENED BEFORE" PLAYING)
♪ I'm very sure ♪
♪ This never happened
To me before ♪
♪ I met you, and now I'm sure ♪
♪ This never happened before
♪ Now I see
♪ This is the way
It's supposed to be ♪
♪ I met you, and now I see
♪ This is the way
It should be ♪
It should be for lovers ♪
♪ They shouldn't go it alone ♪
♪ It's not so good
When you're on your own ♪
♪ So come to me
♪ Now we can be
What we wanna be ♪
♪ I love you, and now I see
♪ This is the way
It should be ♪
It should be for lovers ♪
♪ They shouldn't go it alone ♪
♪ It's not so good
When you're on your own ♪
♪ I'm very sure ♪
♪ This never happened
To me before ♪
♪ I met you, and now I'm sure ♪
♪ This never happened before
♪ This never happened
♪ This never
Happened before ♪