"When a man loves a woman"
"Can't keep his mind
on nothin'else"
"He'll trade the world for
the good thing he's found"
"If she is bad,
he can't see it"
"She can do no wrong"
"Turn his back
on his best friend"
"If he put her down"
"When a man loves a woman"
"Spend his very last dime"
"Tryin'to hold on
to what he needs"
"He'll give up
all his comforts"
"And sleep out in the rain"
-"If she said that's the way
it ought to be"
- Hey, that looks good.
That sandwich. Looks good.
You on your lunch hour?
[ Sighs ] Any news?
ln the paper?
Would you like to read
a section of this?
No, thanks. l, uh, actually
read for a living,
so that's the last thing I want to be
doing with my lunch hour.
- Oh, excuse me. Sorry, excuse me.
- Hey !
Miss--
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- [ Sighs ]
- What?
Where are you going
after this?
Why would you be
asking that?
Ah. I am a pilot.
And I'm gonna barely make
my flight to Seattle-Tacoma,
and I haven't had a chance
to pick up my laundry.
- And?
- I thought you could pick it up for me.
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Laughs ]
I'd give you the money
and everything.
Here's the receipt... and $30.
That should cover it.
What do you propose that I do
with your laundry after I pick it up?
Good question. Ahh.
Here's the keys to my place.
The address is on the, uh,
little thing,
and I will be there at about
1 2:30, and...
you can bring it by then.
- After midnight?
- Uh, excuse me, actually--
Now hold on.
One second, one second.
lf I could impose
one further question.
-Okay.
-Why wouldn't I drop off your laundry...
at my convenience,
since I have your key?
Because then I wouldn't
be able to thank you properly.
Oh, I see.
And how would you do that?
I would give you something...
that you can take away with you.
And what might that be?
- Oh, you want to know up front?
- Oh, yeah. [ Laughs ]
Excuse me.
I bake.
You bake?
[ Laughing ]
You like... chocolate.
I'm allergic...
to chocolate.
Do you like... carrot cake?
Very much.
[ Man ] Well, then?
Cream cheese frosting?
My specialty.
[ Other Patrons ] Check it out. Look !
[ Other Patrons Laughing ]
Mmm.
[ Patrons ] Jesus ! Whoa !
- Cable guy come this morning?
- [ Laughing ] Mm-mm-mm.
[ Man ] No? That's three weeks
those kids are without adult movies.
What a fuckin' world.
Hey, that looks good.
ls that Chablis?
Does anyone have, like,
a towel or something?
Now, this is you.
lnside.
Not inside the dress.
Inside the body.
- How did I get in there?
- That's a whole other set of videos.
And they won't
let you watch those.
- Give me an Eskimo.
-[ Younger Girl ] There you are.
Why wasn't
your real daddy there?
- You say the dumbest things.
- I'm four years old.
[ Woman ] Guys?
-[ Older Girl ] Mom, can you tell her?
-Ohh !
I married your daddy...
because he made me a cake
with cream cheese frosting.
That's how much he wanted me.
- How come Daddy wanted you?
- [ Gasps ]
God, woman,
just look at her.
Ooh, late !
Second team, take over.
-[ Alarm Wailing ]
- Porsche.
Jesus, one more time.
Amy?
Jess has to do her homework tonight
so she doesn't leave it for the weekend.
-[ Alarm Continues ]
- Let's go. Amy, did you get that?
Which part were you afraid
I missed?
Amy?
Sorry.
Happy anniversary.
[ Alarm, Barking Dogs, Sirens Continue ]
[ With A Southern Accent ]
lt's a press-on tattoo ! [ Laughs ]
Itsays, ''lf found naked,
please return to Alice Green.''
lt's to wear on trips, so that
the stewardesses know you're spoken for.
- Flight attendants.
- Flight attendants, whatever.
- Very thoughtful.
- Mmm.
I went over
the twenty bucks.
Oh, hey, I didn't go over
- Really?
- Yeah.
You rat.
That's incredible.
Now I'm gonna have to
do that thing to you tonight.
'' [ '' My Funny Valentine'' ]
[ Alice ] I think she wants you, baby.
- [ Laughs Loudly ]
- Hello, how you doin'?
[ Woman ] Fine.
[ Laughs ] Ooh, good dancer.
- Thank you.
- Ooh ! [ Laughs ] Thanks.
-[ Man ] How was he?
-[ Woman ] Great.
[ Laughing ]
Happy anniversary.
- Ohh !
- [ Groaning ]
-[ Car Alarm Wailing ]
- [ Alice Laughing ]
- Oh.
- Ohh ! Porsche again.
Oh, honey.
C'mere.
- Mm-mm.
- No, no, no. Alice?
- Honey?
- Goddammit.
[ Groans ]
Hey!
It's 1.:00 in the morning.
People are trying to have sex
up here !
Alice, there's nobody down there.
You're talking to a car.
Goddammit !
- Alice.
-[ Alarm, Siren Continues ]
-[ Moans ]
- Alice !
- Alice.
- Damn it ! Shut up !
-Alice!
-[ Dogs Barking ]
- Alice, I'm not gonna like this.
- Here.
- Agh !
- Ooh !
- Agh ! Agh ! Shut up !
- Ooh. Ah.
Ohh !
Shit !
[ Alice Muttering ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
Okay, batter up.
Right here !
[ Alarm Wailing, Alice Shouting ]
Right here.
C'mon, let's go.
Yeow !
[ Shrieking ]
- Ohh.
- [ Laughing Hysterically ]
Mmmm.
I'll start your shower.
You're not suggesting
I go to work.
Yes.
Can you promise no one
will be loud?
Six hundred kids?
Sure.
[ Sighs ]
Go on.
Get dressed, sugar.
We're runnin' late.
See, I'm not sure that
Matthew Wasserman's glance...
at your breasts rises to
the level of sexual harassment.
Well, what if he said,
''You know you want it''?
- Did he?
- No. But what if he did?
Well, that would be closer.
I think if we can get him to lift up
your dress, we can put him away.
So, uh--
[ Clears Throat ]
What is the deal with
cutting language lab? Shit !
[ Sighs ]
Another self-mutilation day.
[ Sighs ] I'm checking on availability
for end-of-the-day wind-down.
Oh, come on. My problems gotta be
more sordid than Shannon's.
Okay, a quick one.
Michael's got a trip.
Yes.
- Hi. Where's Alice?
- Hey.
- That's right, where's Alice? Bye.
- Amy ! Amy !
Amy, Amy, Amy, Amy.
[ Sighs ]
Listen, l, uh, got a trip.
I'm late, and Wayne's supposed to
meet me. I've got no way to call him.
He's waiting at my Lamaze class.
I just can't not show up.
Amy-- Amy, this is important.
I got a trip.
You're not saying...
my life is less important?
Of course not.
I didn't think so. Bye.
She didn't come home.
I did notice that.
I have a trip.
What if she
doesn't get back?
I'll just go down to the corner
and offer the first person l
see five bucks to stay with you.
- Michael.
- Okay, ten bucks.
[ Sighs ]
You're so pretty.
Twenty minutes, lights out.
- Okay?
- Okay.
[ Michael ] You're okay.
I've called
everyone we know.
Hospitals. School.
- [ Laughs ]
- Huh?
- You're up.
- I'm supposed to be up.
I'm just supposed to be
doing it in Chicago.
Ohh.
Hey.
Stop that.
You got a trip.
[ Sighs ]
Really. I better
get a move on.
I forgot that.
I'm sorry... about your trip.
- What happened?
- [ Sighs ]
- We went for a drink.
- Pam.
Yeah, Pam. My friend. She needed me.
She needed to talk.
-She needed me 'causeJoe is an asshole.
-[ Ball Slamming ]
I'm glad she needed you,
'cause she's the one that got you.
- Nobody else got a fucking phone call.
- We were just talking.
She was crying, and, uh--
Ah, when I looked at the time,
I just figured you were asleep, so, uh--
I-I-I don't know how
I forgot the trip.
I don't know either.
Christ, Michael.
You don't know what I go through.
You don't have a fucking clue.
- What do you go through?
- My job, for one,
the girls, and--
and running this place.
And I know a lot of women
go through the same thing,
but their husbands
aren't gone half the time.
[ Sniffling ]
I miss you...
when you go.
[ Sniffles, Sighs ]
You got pressures,
you come to me.
Why do that to you? What're you
supposed to do with all that?
Let me worry
about that.
I'm gonna trade Ed Buckley
for a trip to Mexico for a week,
and we're gonna disappear.
Would you like that?
Would you like to disappear?
- Go get some candy from Grandpa
and Mama Andretti.
- [ Chuckles ]
Hello, Casey, Casey !
How are ya?
Ha-ha !
Look what I got for you. See?
I'm not staying
with her.
Hey, it's gonna
be okay, honey.
Yeah, but she doesn't
care about us.
Listen, she's crazy about you,
and she's gonna spoil you rotten.
- Hi, Mom. How are you?
Thanks for coming.
- Hello, Michael, dear.
She still puts you down,
and I don't like it.
Hey, you're gonna have to cut
Grandma a little bit of slack.
She hasn't had the easiest life.
Jessica.
How's my sweet angel?
Oh,just fine, Mom.
How are you?
- Have you lost weight?
- No.
I guess you're
just tired.
Wish I had time
to be tired.
- Give me a smile. C'mon,
give me a big smile !
- Walter.
- Don't let Michael carry
all those bags in by himself!
- Sorry.
It's all right, Ma.
It's only two bags.
Well, give him the small one.
He likes to feel useful.
I got it. I got it.
I got it.
Mom, can I get you anything
before we...
fly off and leave you
with the kids?
The best thing you can do for me is just
have the grandest time in the world...
and come home rested,
please?
- Hello.
- Hey, Dad.
When Mama comes home we're gonna
have a big surprise for her.
We're gonna
have the whole house clean.
- Won't that be nice?
-[ Casey ] Mm-hmm.
- Thanks. I gotta go. Bye.
Bye, girl. Thanks. Bye.
- Have fun.
[ Michael ] Thanks.
[ Grandpa ] Safe trip.
-[Jess ] Bye, Mom. I love you.
- Love you. Bye.
- [ Grandma ] Okay, let's go.
-[ Michael ] Don't clean too hard.
[ Car Starting ]
- [ With A Southern Accent ]
lt's a press-on tattoo.
- [ Giggles ]
Just in case. You never know what
might happen in Mexico.
Found a guy at the beach
who'll watch us have sex.
Oooh.
- A local?
- Mm-hmm.
- C'mon, honey.
- Ooh.
Okay. C'mon.
""[ Spanish ]
Ah.
Baby. Gotta tell you somethin'.
Listen. [ Clears Throat ]
I think we should
do this more often.
[ Clears Throat ]
I do.
Because...
they paid you to fly here.
I got a pass.
The hotel is
a remarkable discount.
There are meals,
as you've said before. [ Giggles ]
You gotta eat anyway.
- So we can afford this.
- Not unless they comp the drinks.
Ohh. What's that
supposed to mean? Hmm?
- Hey !
- You lookin' for a fight, buster?
- No. Sit down, Alice.
- Buster, buster.
- Wait, I got a few moves here.
- Alice, Alice ! Please.
- [ Shouting ] Hey ! Alice !
- lf you want a fight, I can give you...
- all the trouble you can handle.
- Sit down. Okay, I know you can.
Alice, sit down.
[ Shouts ] Sit !
- Sit.
- Woof.
Alice ! Alice !
[ Michael Gasping, Coughing ]
I'm waiting
for my spanking.
I know we have pressures,
and we need to have fun.
But wringing you out at the end of an
evening is less fun than it used to be.
And thinking back, it's been going on
for quite a while, Alice.
What's wrong, babe?
Can you talk about it?
You scared me last night.
Didn't you scare you?
Huh?
What's gonna happen?
I'm gonna stop
drinking so much.
Last night was the best thing
that could've happened.
Straightened my ass out.
I promise you.
I promise me.
-[ Michael ] Hey!
-[ Alice ] Jessie! Ow!
-[ Michael ] Pinatas!
- They're here !
-[ Grandma ] Oh, honey,
don't get dirty!
-[ Michael ] Casey!
- Hey !
- Someone's getting married.
Hi, pretty girl !
- Hi, Casey.
- You look wonderful.
- Hey.
-[ Grandma ] Hi. Oh, my God, I hope
those pinatas aren't full of candy!
- You'll ruin their teeth.
- Hi, Daddy.
- [ Grandpa ] Good to see ya.
- Hey, Pops, how are you?
[ Alice ] Oh, man.
-[ Alice ] Hi, Mom.
-[ Grandma ] Hi, honey.
[ Michael ] I smell Murphy's Oil.
[ Grandma ] Yes. I used it--
[ Grunting ]
[ Sighs ]
Sh-h-hit.
[ Doorbell Ringing ]
Well, everything's
fine on the curb.
Garbage compulsion.
I feel much better now.
Come on, baby,
it's late!
[ Michael ] Casey?
You're not going to Dana's.
Case? I think we're gonna
have to fill out one of those
homicide reports for Felicia.
She's soaking off
her makeup.
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
- Did I miss something?
- She didn't do her book report,
so she can't go to Dana's.
- lt's not due 'til Monday.
- I told you last night not to
save it for the weekend, to--
[ Michael ] Good morning.
Good morning.
Good morning. Good morning,
first words out of our mouth.
I think we have all we can
handle right now with our
coffee and our little spoon.
[ Cartoon Voice On Television ]
Ready! Take her away.
-[ Cartoon Voice ] Steady now!
-So,you go to Dana's,
and the report gets done
first thing Saturday...
and not last thing Sunday.
Okay?
- What's the difference?
- The difference between me
helping you do it,
- and me pulling your lungs out
through your belly button.
- [ Girls Giggle ]
- Sorry I'm late.
- That's okay.
Um... Casey's
taking a nap, and...
Jess is teaching
Samantha how to use the computer.
Hmph. Hmm.
You all right?
Ah, ohh. Whoa.
I had lunch at
this Thai place, and, uh,
something in the oil
maybe, but...
I'll be fine.
See ya tomorrow.
Uh, Alice, um...
I can call my mom.
I'm sure I can stay
and make some supper.
I said, see ya tomorrow !
- Alice, I think you should maybe--
- Ah, ah, Amy.
Go home.
Okay?
Please !
Go home.
You get some rest.
And I'll call you
a little later.
Mom. Look.
Samantha drew a Buick
on the computer. lt's green.
Do your homework.
Mom?
- Mom, are you sick?
- [ Screaming ] I said...
do your homework !
Mom... are you sick?
Mm ! Ohh.
[ Crying ] I did my homework !
That's all I wanted to tell you !
[ Door Slams ]
[ Sobs ]
[ Retching ]
Good girl.
Jess ! [ Gasps ]
[ Retching ]
[ Glass Breaking ]
Mom?
[ Sobbing ]
[ Man ] Is there
a Michael Green?
Michael Green?
Switchboard tracking
you down, I guess.
Hello?
-Jess? What's the matter, honey?
- Mommy died.
- What?
- She just fell through
the shower door...
and all the glass is all
shattered on the floor,
and she's laying
in the middle of it.
Jess, listen to me. I'm
gonna have somebody over there
right away. You understand?
- Okay.
- Okay, and I'm gonna call you
right back.
Okay.
I need an outside line.
[ Phone Clicking ]
[ Shouting ]
I need an outside line !
[ Sighs ]
[ lnhales Deeply ]
Hi.
You're all right.
The doctor says.
How's Jess?
She's really happy
you're okay.
I hit her hard, Michael.
[ Sniffles ]
I hit her so hard.
lt's all right.
She's fine.
We're gonna get you better so it
doesn't happen again. All right?
God,just don't hate me.
- Mmmm.
- Because I'll die if you do.
That thought would
never enter my mind.
I start at 4:00 in the morning,
and it goes all day.
I drink in the john,
I drink in the closet,
and I drink in the kids' room
when they're not there.
[ Sniffles ] You know how when we...
go out to the car,
and I have to go back
inside for a second?
Mm-hmm.
I have to be high
to do anything.
I'm scared all the time.
I drank for Casey's
goddamn birthday party.
So did l.
[ Sniffles ]
I drink a quart a day.
[ Sniffles ] lt's vodka, so you
couldn't smell it.
How come I didn't see this?
Because I hid it.
[ Sniffling ]
You were scared.
- What am I gonna do?
- We'll figure it out.
And I don't want you
to worry about it.
I'm gonna find you the best treatment.
Best in the fuckin' world.
You're not alone, honey.
Never.
- Okay, girls, I'll see you later.
-[Jess ] Bye.
- Amy.
- I'll just wait in the kitchen.
Okay.
So.
We'll talk on the phone,
and you'll come see me.
- And then I'll be home.
- And we'll go to the beach?
Are you gonna
take care of your sister?
I'm gonna take care of Daddy.
Sorry, baby.
Itwill never happen
again.
Mommy loves you.
That's us.
Hi. Uh, we're,
uh, Alice Green.
Hi. Welcome.
Alice, before we check you in,
I need to look through your bag.
Is that all right with you?
It's strictly routine.
We've got all your paperwork,
so...
everything's ready.
Um, sorry.
So, come on, Alice,
and we'll get you checked in.
Just Alice.
- Gimme a minute.
- Mmm.
- I'll call you tonight.
- I'm sorry, there's no phone calls.
Excuse me. She's my wife. She can
call me whenever she needs to call me.
She'll be in detox
until Tuesday,
and she'll be busy
getting well.
She'll call you
as soon as she can after that.
I love you.
"I can hear her heartbeat"
"From a thousand miles"
"And the heavens open"
"Every time she smiles"
"And when I come to her"
"That's where I belong"
"And I'm runnin'to her"
"Like a love song"
"She gimme love
love, love, love"
"Crazy love"
"She gimme love, love
love, love"
"Crazy love"
-[ Sighs ]
-"She gimme love, love love, love"
"Crazy love"
Jess.
lt's 6:00
in the morning.
Kids are unbelievable.
First she wants French toast,
then she wants tuna,
and then
she wants a cucumber sandwich.
Case.
Wanna know what
she finally eats?
- She ate fruit.
- Right.
-[ Casey Moaning ]
My hair hurts.
[ Michael ] Casey, is that you?
Ohh. God !
- I did her hair.
- Oh, I like it.
Let's see that hairdo.
- Ooh. That's a little tight there.
Let me see that.
- Ow !
- Oh, sorry ! [ Chuckles ]
- Mommy does it better.
Oh, Mommy does
everything better.
She cooks better, she looks better, she
kisses better. Mommy's a better person.
You know, I bet you
have a lot of questions.
Things you're
feeling about Mommy.
We could talk about that.
Like if you're sad or scared
or angry or something...
-you could just--
- What's a alcoholic?
Someone with a bad habit.
You know, like if you drank stuff
that made you sick,
but you really liked it,
so you kept drinking it,
and it kept making you sick.
Wouldn't you want to
learn how to stop?
What's a alcoholic?
lt's why
she does all that stuff.
When she does all that stuff,
like when she talks like she's sleepy,
forgets stuff,
and when she's sad.
When she cries?
She cries in the bathroom.
She... she
did that a lot,
I bet, huh?
Your hair is so pretty.
You know, Mommy can't wait
to get back just to brush it?
[ Shivering, Gasping ]
I got her. Alice?
I'm Dr. Mendez.
I'm a counselor.
You know you're supposed to be
in community now.
Your nurse said
you've got a problem?
[ lnhales Deeply ] No problem.
I don't have any problems.
You think I have a problem?
- Yeah, at least.
- I just want to make a phone call.
I just want to make
a phone call to my husband.
lf you wanted to make
a phone call to your husband,
would you call that a problem?
No, but I'm not in detox
dealing with an addiction.
- Look, we'll let you make
a phone call as soon--
- Now !
Now is when I wanna call him !
- Now! Can you understand that?
- Alice. Alice. Look--
Can you understand
fucking anything?
Yeah. I can.
Two more days, hon.
You can do this.
- Hang in.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Come on.
- Ohh ! [ Gasping ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Hello?
- [ Alice ] Michael.
- Alice?
- [ Laughs ] Yeah.
You can call?
Yeah, what d'ya know?
They let me use the phone.
How was detox?
Itwas nifty, you know.
I threw up
like a good girl.
Right.
Hard part's over, baby.
Yeah, the hard part's over.
Party time.
Well, so, uh...
basically I just, uh...
sit around... and...
think of you naked.
Because, you know,
you have this...
amazing body.
You still do, don't you?
State of the art.
So you'd be, what,
sixty-five pounds now?
[ Sighs ]
- Honey.
- [ Sighs ]
Alice.
Honey, you there?
- Alice.
- [ Crying ]
- Yeah.
- Everyone here is pulling for you.
[ Sobs ]
Alice, they say
they tear you down...
the first two weeks,
so they can build you back up.
[ Sobbing ]
- Alice.
- God, I'm sorry, baby.
lt's just so hard.
- Honey, are you there?
- Yeah.
I'm here, babe.
I love you.
I miss you.
Listen, I'll see you, um--
I'll see you on Sunday. Okay?
- The kids are so excited to see you.
- I can't talk for too long,
because there's, um, one phone
and a whole line of people, so--
[ Sniffles ]
Can you bring my
gray sweat suit?
Yes.
I'm just running down my list
of dumb things to say right now.
Good for you.
[ Dial Tone ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sniffles ]
[ Liquid Sloshing ]
You're supposed to
wrap it.
What?
ln newspaper...
or a paper bag.
So nobody sees it,
or something.
Mommy tell you that?
[ Sighs ]
Hey.
You wanna do one?
C'mon.
Take your pick.
Vodka, huh?
[ Crash ]
[ Yawns ]
Oh.
All right.
Okay, let me see,
here.
Now, if Mommy cries
when she sees you,
it's because
you're beautiful.
Okay?
Piggyback?
Oh, the purse.
- Ready? [ Snorts ]
- [ Giggling ]
- [ Whinnies ]
- [ Squeals ]
Where is she?
I don't know. We'll see.
She said she'd be out here.
There she is.
You see her in the hat?
Mommy !
Aah !
[ Both Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Chuckles ]
Hi, baby.
Hey.
Say hi to Mommy.
Mmm. Hi, beautiful girl.
- Hi.
You wanna take 'em for a walk,
and I'll catch up later?
Hmm? Bye-bye.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
- Come on, you guys, let's go.
- [ Laughing ]
[ TVAnnouncer]
Martin Long left alone.
[ TV Crowd Cheers ]
-[ Man ] Nice shot.
- Can you get coffee in here?
What do I look like,
a fuckin' waitress?
- Aw !
- Hey!
I saw you with Alice.
You're her significant other.
Good to meet you.
Your wife's amazing. Malcolm.
- Oh, uh, Michael.
- Yeah, Michael.
- Come on in.
- No, I got the kids outside.
- Naw, that's okay. This is Earl.
- Hey, I'm Earl.
- Hi, Earl. Michael. I got the kids--
- Watch the game.
- Have a seat.
- Okay.
[ Color Commentator ] There's that
middleman. Blaylock is still on him.
- How ya doin'?
- Good. How are you?
[ Commentator ] ...moved up the lane,
opened up that soft spot.
- On the other side there--
-[ TVCrowd Roaring ]
[ Michael Clears Throat ]
Been a while since you watched
a game without a beer?
- Me?
- You.
Actually, I-I don't,
I don't, uh, drink much.
[ Laughing ]
-[ Man Chuckling ]
- Can you believe that, man?
- I been there, man. Denial.
-Jesus.
- Ain't just a river in Egypt.
-Shut up!
-[ Shouting ]
- Cork it, Danny.
Are you guys sayin'
that this dude don't drink?
- I'm saying shut the fuck up, man !
- Fellas, my fault.
Hey! It's a cunning,
baffling disease, man.
The man doesn't have a problem,
pecker-face,:you do!
Cunning, baffling disease !
- Save it for group, man !
Save it for group !
- [ All Shouting ]
Save it for group, all right?
Yo, Earl, man.
I like your new friends.
Oh, did you
meet Malcolm?
- Big black guy.
- Cokehead.
We hit it off.
The girls are with him.
Right now?
Oh, come on, Michael.
He's not a child molester.
He's an armed robber.
[ Sighs ]
What?
Well.
[ Clears Throat ]
Whatever you think
of these people, Michael,
think that of me,
because it fits.
I thought you'd quit.
I did.
Malcolm and l, um...
really talk.
You know, we talk
about everything.
Everything.
[ Exhales ]
We have a lot in common,
and the truth is that right now
I really need these people.
I'm glad you have 'em.
And when you come home,
you'll have me.
What's wrong, Alice?
Hmm?
You were fine when
the kids were around. What's wrong?
Long day.
-[ Alice ] Hey.
- Hi.
Gary, this is Michael.
Hi.
- I feel like I know you.
- Oh, yeah?
Yeah. Your wife's
a very comforting person.
Yes.
Very-- Do you mind
if I talk to her for a second?
- No.
- l-- Just for a second.
I'll just be
one second.
- What's the matter?
- Uh--
[ Whispering ]
I'm sorry.
[ Yelling ]
[ Malcolm ] Yea!
- [ lmitating Airplane Sounds ]
- [ Laughing ]
Bob! Bobby!
No, that's not what I said.
I have never turned
the company down in an emergency.
- Bob ! Bob !
-[ Girls Screaming ]
I am not gonna leave my kids
for four days with Alice gone !
I'm certainly not gonna bring Alice's
mother into the picture at this point.
- They have enough grief already. Amy !
-[Jess Screaming ] Gimme it!
- What?
- Come on ! Gimme it !
Rollbacks?
Will you settle down? Amy !
[ Screaming ]
Amy! Amy! Hello?
- What do rollbacks
have to do with this, Bob?
-[ Screaming ]
Oh, Bobby, why don't you save
the little subtle threats.
lt's making me embarrassed
for you. Amy !
Can you hold on
a second? Hold on !
[ Girls Crying ]
[ Michael ] Hey, hey!
What is this, huh?
Get up !
Get up right now !
- She bit me hard !
- Did you bite her?
- Yeah.
- Well, that's no excuse !
This is your baby sister.
You could hurt her !
You're much bigger than her !
You should be loving each other !
- Now, who spilled this Coke?
- [ Together] She did it !
- Who?
Right.
ln bed, right now !
[ Girls Crying ]
Ah, don't you hear
those kids fighting?
I haven't eaten all day.
lt's 1 0:00.
- Why don't you put 'em to bed?
- I did. They just keep
poppin' back out.
They miss their mother.
They're out of control.
They spilled
some Coke, Amy.
- I'll get it in a minute.
- ln a minute? Itis
soaking into the rug !
Don't yell at me.
I am working overtime to help you out.
Okay.
[ Breathes Deeply ]
Where are the paper towels?
There are
no paper towels !
Jesus Christ, I am
in a crisis, here !
I need some help! I need someone
that can look around the house...
and when there are no paper
towels, they go to a store
and buy some paper towels !
I mean, how many
goddamn stores do you pass...
on the way home from school
that are filled with paper towels?
I need someone to use
a little common sense around here !
Why don't you get
somebody else?
Amy. Amy !
Amy. Amy.
I w-- Amy, I didn't--
I was kidding.
Amy, I might have--
Oh, no.
Oh, no. No.
Bob.
[ Woman ] ...make a call, please
hang up and try again.
[Jess ] I'm not gonna do it.
I don't have
another choice,Jess.
This isn't fair.
Well, you know,
sometimes life isn't fair.
I told you. They're tryin' to
get rid of the experienced pilots.
They want
to bring in kids.
- Kids can't fly planes.
- Not kid kids, men kids.
I'm not living with her,
and you can't make me.
lt's four days,Jess.
Four days.
Well, why can't we live with Amy?
She loves us.
- I tried that. She won't talk to me.
- Well, whose fault is that?
Look, now. This is not a vote.
I am your father.
No, you're not !
Oh, yes, I am. I am the only father
you've got, little girl.
I know things
are tough,Jess,
but Mommy's sick,
and I'm all alone,
and we need to pitch in.
lt's time
you understand that.
I'm gonna go to my dad.
Your dad calls you
from Oregon maybe twice a year.
Plenty of time, all the time,
and you don't know !
I'm sorry, babe.
I didn't mean that.
I'm gonna go to my mom !
[ Whispering ]
Shit !
Jess ! Jess !
- I want my mom ! I want her !
-Jess !
- I want my mom !
- I know. I know.
Let go of me !
Stop it ! Stop it !
-I know. lt's okay. We'll work it out.
-I want my mom !
Okay, we'll work it out.
We'll work it out.
- [ Crying ] I want my mom.
- I want your mom too.
What's wrong?
lt's no fun to eat shit.
So don't.
Then you'd be
stuck with Grandma.
Let's go in.
Come on.
Wait for me here.
[ Speaking Chinese ]
You.
Me?
What did you say
about me?
That you were the one...
with the paper towels.
Guilty.
I'm very sorry I did that.
Can I talk to you a second
in the kitchen or someplace?
Don't bother. Nobody speaks English,
'cept my cousin Vu.
And I'd love
to hear this.
Uh... okay.
I got a... trip.
If I don't go,
I get fired.
I don't want to leaveJess
with her grandma.
Why is this my problem?
Actually, it's not.
So you're
basically begging?
Well...
it worked.
You gonna leave without
saying goodbye?
It's okay.
You don't have
to tell me nothing.
Ready to go, huh?
I don't know.
I don't know how I'm gonna do
anything anymore.
[ Laughing ] You're supposed
to give me an answer here.
You're supposed to say something
very encouraging.
- This is why you get those big bucks.
- No, no.
They tried to tell me
that shit when I first went home,
and it never did me
a damn bit of good.
- When you first went home.
- Yeah, that's right.
Two-time loser.
I know you're scared shitless,
'cause I sure as hell was.
There's no easy way
through it.
You just gotta
do the work.
I'm gonna disappoint him.
This is not the person
that he married.
I don't know who this is
supposed to be now.
Well, who was
the other person?
Well, every now and then,
let's face it, she was a blast.
A-And I'm not gonna
be fun.
Mm-hmm. That's exactly
what happened to me...
when I first went home.
Exactly.
So everything turned out
okay in the end, right?
- No. We got divorced.
- [ Laughs ]
[ Laughing ]
"Oh, sacred place
It's with my soul and body"
"There's a rainbow above me"
"That the storm clouds hide"
"It will never die"
"But the magic, it comes"
"Springs from above"
"Love"
"We laugh sometimes but it's
a little word like love"
"Makes our earthly home
heaven above"
"And there is no sorrow
heaven cannot heal"
"A fire within,
no cross, no crown"
"Runnin'from mercy,
heaving and cold"
"Swim in our sleep
down in oceans ofjoy"
"Died in the arms
of a natural life"
"Wakin'our happiness,
drowning in life"
"Oooo"
"Oo-oo-oo oooo"
Wake 'em up.
Come on, wake 'em up.
You're dyin' to wake 'em up.
I promised them.
Aah-choo !
Mommy.
- Hi.
- Michael,you said you'd wake me up.
Mommy.
- Casey.
-Jessie, shh.
[Jess Whispering ] Casey, it's Mom.
[Jess ] Casey.
Mommy.
[ Girls Screaming ] Mommy ! Gimme it !
- Mommy !
- Gimme it !
- Stop it !
- Hold it! Both of you!
- She said I could use it !
- She's breaking it !
- Mine's already broken !
- Gimme it !
- Aah ! Now it's mine.
Hey, hey, hey !
Ho, ho, ho, what's the baby problems?
-[ Shouting ]
-First guy to say one word loses, okay?
Whatever this is, you don't need to
bother Mommy about it.
- Michael, we'll be okay,
- All short guys upstairs.
- because we were just sorting it out.
- I'll be up in two minutes.
- We were just--
- Upstairs.
Did you hear me?
Go. Yes.
Go.
[ Quacking ]
We were j-- We were
just workin' it out.
Sounded like it.
Finish your work.
I'll settle their hash.
We've been doing
Walkman wars all month.
See, Michael, I would rather handle
their fights lately.
- That's all you need, babe.
- Oh, what does that mean?
I'm not up to it?
Oh, no, Mr. District Attorney,
my wife is perfect.
She's really perfect.
You hear me?
Thank you for
the vote of confidence.
What?
I'm being overly--
Attentive.
A little bit, yeah.
Like I'm pregnant
or psychotic...
or like I'm made of glass.
You're handling play dates,
polishing toilets, shopping up a storm.
A storm.
Yeah, have you looked
in the freezer lately?
There's 83 cans of frozen
orange juice in there,
if you can see past
all the frozen waffles.
The kids like 'em now.
Ah. Oh. '' Now.''
The post-shameful-
incarceration era.
That's what
we like to call it.
Sorry.
So...
I was thinking...
about this weekend.
- I call Ed and trade him
for the Mexico route.
- [ Chuckling ]
[ Sighs ]
- I spoke to Amy.
- Amy, yeah.
Michael, don't you think this is
all just a little bit inappropriate?
What?
I mean maybe I should learn
to live in reality...
before I start trying
to escape from it again.
I mean, Rachel was in my group.
She's 46.
She taught Russian history
at Berkeley.
She has two kids,
her family has money,
and she was living under a bench
in Golden Gate Park for three years...
before her sister
found her there.
You think
that can't happen to me?
Ask me how much
I want a drink right now.
How come we haven't
talked about this?
How come we haven't talked
about a lot of things?
I think-- I think maybe
we should see someone.
A-At the place, they said
that sometimes it's good...
for a couple to see someone
who knows about this stuff.
You mean, like
a licensed contractor?
You would do that?
Only if you were
incredibly grateful.
Now, this is ever since
you've been back?
Mm-hmm.
Th-- I'm, uh,
just agitated
and pissed off,
and it seems unreasonable
to me, and l-- And it's--
I feel like
I'm being unfair, and, uh,
especially to Michael,
because he's been trying to be sweet,
and he's really--
You know, he just
wants to be there for me.
So you're saying that there's
a problem in your marriage,
- and that it's your fault.
- No, I don't think that's
what she said at all.
I'm sorry, Alice. ls that
what you meant to say?
- What I heard was--
- No, I didn't mean to say that,
and, Michael,
I can talk for myself.
So how do you feel
right now?
I'm irritated.
Because he does this.
Sometimes he just does this.
He just-- Like, he-- I was trying to
settle a fight between the two girls,
and he kind of came in,
he took over,
and it pissed me off.
You know, it just
pissed me off.
- And this is since you've been back.
- Yeah. Well--
No, he's always
done that.
- Like?
- Like the time that...
Jess wouldn't do her homework,
so I said she couldn't go
to her girlfriend's house.
And he came into the kitchen,
and he took over again...
and erased
everything I did.
Belittled me
in front of them.
When was this?
When you told me I had all
I could handle with my coffee
and my little spoon.
What was that
about, Michael?
Itwas a joke,
to begin with.
And...
she was very hung over,
and I was trying to help.
So, Michael,
how do you feel?
Manipulated.
lrritated.
- Why?
- Because we're here to be
closer to one another.
And talking over your problems
isn't getting closer?
Michael, have you ever thought about
going to an Al-Anon meeting,
a meeting for families
of alcoholics?
Why that face, Michael?
lt's the only face
I have,Janet.
A little slutty.
- Slutty?
- Yeah.
Amish.
Not Amish enough.
lt's her first
boy-girl dance, Michael.
We should let her
go as a girl.
[ Laughing ] lt's just like...
yee-haw !
- Did you put that together?
- No.
That's a sad
little ensemble.
Oh, well, I forgot how good
you were at this, Michael.
lt's just that I know eight-year-old
boys have one thing on their minds.
One thing:
fourteen-year-old girls.
I feel like an
eight-year-old right now.
You look
like a 1 4-year-old.
That's sweet, right?
Yeah.
[ Man Laughing ]
- Gary, there's so much
truth coming out of you.
- It is. This is the depth.
[ Laughing ] I think I'm gonna
share this tonight.
You gonna go
to the meeting tonight?
[ Alice ] Hey.
Honey, you remember
Gary, right?
Sure. How's it goin'?
Good. lt's really good.
How you doin'?
You got a great house.
You really do.
lt's her. Yeah.
Excuse me.
- I'm sorry. I'm gonna go.
- I'm sorry.
[ Chuckling ]
No, I'm sorry.
Tell him I'm, uh, sorry if l
inconvenienced anything, you know?
Hey, it's not
about you, okay?
- I know. All right.
- I'm sorry.
- You take care.
-Slow down.
- I love you.
- Thank you so much. Okay.
- I'll talk to you later.
- About 3:00, I'm free.
- Okay.
- Okay. Good night.
[ Sighs ]
Why would you suppose
he dashed off like that?
I don't know, Michael.
Could it have been your face?
You looked like we were
naked or something.
Do you wanna
ask me something?
- No.
- You think this thing
with Gary is romantic?
I don't know what
to think about anything.
Well, I'm glad
to hear you say that.
We haven't sat close
like that since I can remember, Alice.
Not since I'm back.
And if you think about it,
not since a while before that.
Gary needs me,
and that feels good.
And when I'm scared,
he can't help,
and he doesn't
pretend that he can.
And it's not
just Gary, Michael.
The people that I really lean on
are the ones at my meetings,
and you never even
ask me about them.
Don't you wonder who they are
or what we talk about?
Well, I do now.
So why don't you
ask me?
Come on, Michael.
Let's talk about it.
Okay? I'll tell ya
anything you wanna know.
Do they know
how this got started?
How I became
an alcoholic?
No.
They don't know that.
Nobody seems
to know that.
[ Exhales ] My dad's drinking
didn't help.
The way my mother made me
feel like nothing.
Or maybe it's genetic,
or l--
Nobody knows.
Did you think
this was about you?
Why would you say that?
I don't know.
You seem a little defensive.
Wh-Why would I be defensive?
ls somebody attacking me?
No.
Nobody's attacking you.
Michael, I am just
hanging on here.
The girls need me
really badly.
I am trying to reestablish
a little credibility at school.
I'm trying
to make my meetings.
So that kinda tells me my place
in the batting order...
of what you need.
I'm so tired
of all this shit.
[ Sniffs ] I don't wanna
be angry anymore.
I don't wanna--
I don't wanna
feel... guilty...
or...
sad or depressed
or frustrated...
or confused or--
Just once, for five minutes,
I wanna feel good.
- My name is Joanna.
- [ All ] Hi,Joanna.
I am so grateful for Maria's topic,
emotional abuse.
Until I came to Al-Anon,
I was not even aware
of how cruelly I was abused...
by my alcoholic
husband,
because I did not
own my own feelings.
Every waking hour was about
my husband's feelings.
When he was down,
I was lower.
When he was happy,
I thought I was too.
Every day I walked in that door
waiting to see what shape he was in,
so I could find out
how I was gonna feel.
Now, thanks
to this program,
I not only
have my own feelings,
but I have feelings
about my feelings.
And I am so grateful.
Anyway, thanks.
[ Man ] Thank you,Joanna.
[ Clears Throat ] As you know,
we have no dues or fees,
so we're gonna continue sharing
as Bob passes the basket around.
[ Door Unlocks, Opens ]
- Hi.
- You okay?
- Never better.
What happened?
Somethin' at A.A.?
Uh... I'll be okay.
lt's just a really bad day.
You wanna tell me what's wrong?
Somethin' I can do?
- Thank you, but--
- Can't fix it unless
we know it's broke.
[ Exhales ]
How was your meeting?
First time.
I'll get used to it.
There was a lot of people
there feeling sorry for themselves.
Itwas like an alcoholic
has ruined their lives,
and they'd rather be a victim
than try and fix it.
Fix it, huh?
What'd I do now,
Alice?
Nothing, Michael.
Nothing.
I'm talking about some losers at my
meeting. You're taking it personally.
The trouble with all these losers
at your meeting...
is that they're not perfect
like some people.
They're married to alcoholics who are
bouncing off the walls,
and they don't know
what the fuck to do.
So you might have to
be a little tolerant,
give them the benefit of your
expertise in problem solving.
Good meeting, huh?
You guys drop acid or something?
Like I said,
I'm having
a really bad day,
and I don't mean
to take it out on you.
What is it?
You want a drink real bad?
That wouldn't distinguish it
from any other day, Michael.
One of your friends
fall off the wagon?
Nothing happened,
Michael.
Nothing has to happen
for me to have a bad day.
That's the thrilling
part of all this.
Itjust comes and hits and runs me over
like a goddamned freight train.
Okay. When's the next
freight train comin' through?
You got a printed schedule?
'Cause I could plan around
these things,you know, and...
give you the space
so you can,you know,
smoke.
Maybe you shouldn't
have to, Michael.
One of the women at my meetings
is going to a halfway house,
- because she's not making it
in her home environment, and l--
- What?
You're actually
thinking about this.
Oh, now, wait.
Don't start jumping to conclusions.
What?
Excuse me for taking my life
personally, Alice !
What is wrong
with our home?
- Nothing.
You said it was something.
What is it, huh?
ls it the couch?
ls it an area rug?
Or is it possibly, Alice--
Alicia-- me? ls it me?
- lt's not your problem.
- No, it's not my problem !
lt's just my fucking fault !
Everything is my fault !
My sick wife is not making it in her
home environment ! Why, exactly?
I mean, I am not
your problem.
I am not your problem
to solve !
Itwas so much more fun in the old days,
wasn't it, Michael?
I'd get drunk, pass out,
and you'd put me back together.
That was
the best, huh?
That made you
feel good.
And that's what hurts.
Oh.
Oh, fuck that !
Fuck making it better, Michael !
It's not
getting better!
I don't know how
to make it better,
and I swear to God
you don't either !
Baby--
Every time
you say that,
every time you look
at me like that, Michael,
I wanna come
right out of my skin.
You make me feel like
a stupid, worthless, weak animal.
I don't know
how to try anymore.
Not giving up.
Sticking together. lsn't that what
we're supposed to be trying for?
No, Michael.
We're supposed to try to be real.
And when you feel alone,
you are not together, and that is real.
And when you don't know,
you just don't know.
[ Sighs ]
I think I could love you again...
if you could just for once
say, ''I don't know.''
I don't know.
Didn't work, did it?
I'll go pack some stuff.
Michael, I didn't
ask you to do that.
- No, Alice?
- No.
- No?
Come on, let's be real.
You're clean.
You stay hopeless
and confused.
Keep polishing those skills,
and I'll take the heat,
'cause I got
some needs of my own.
When I touch someone, I like it better
when their skin doesn't crawl.
- That's not what I meant.
- My wife hurts.
I need to say,
''What's wrong, honey?
Somethin' I can do?''
And, ''I love you.''
So fuck me.
[ Walking Upstairs ]
Hey.
What's the matter, baby?
You guys
were really loud.
Oh.
Where's Michael?
He's out.
So, are you getting all excited
about Ashley's sleep-over?
I'm not going.
You're not going?
Why?
What changed your mind?
I didn't
get to be invited.
Everybody hates me.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, sweetheart,
that's not possible.
ls this
Ashley Barrows?
- Ashley Canter? Ashley Goodwin?
- No.
- Ashley Whipsnade?
- There is no Ashley Whipsnade.
There is too.
I can prove it.
[ Sighs ]
Michael moved out.
For a while.
But I'm here,
and we're gonna be fine.
He left us?
- Don't blame him.
- But how could he leave us?
You blame me.
I messed up, baby.
But I'm fighting
my way back,
so you help me.
And don't you
blame him.
Not ever.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Hey, double trouble.
[ Laughing ]
Where have you been?
I've been on a trip.
Are you ready for the beach?
-Where you been?
-I told 'em you were staying with Peter.
lt's only until
Mommy feels better.
Mommy feels better already.
See how well
it's working?
Are you guys
getting a divorce?
[ Alice ] Hey,
don't be silly, baby.
You guys go
have a great time.
Let's go. Up you go.
[ Grunts ]
- Bye.
"When your day is long"
"And the night"
"The night is yours alone"
"And you're sure
you've had enough"
"Of this life"
"Hang on"
"Don't let yourself go"
"'Cause everybody cries"
"Everybody hurts"
"Sometimes"
"Sometimes
everything is wrong"
"Now it's time
to sing along"
-" When your day is night alone"
-"Hold on"
"Hold on"
-"If you feel like lettin'go"
-"Hold on"
"If you think
you've had too much"
"Of this life"
"Well, hang on"
"'Cause everybody hurts"
[ Laughing ]
"Take comfort
in your friends"
"'Cause everybody hurts"
"Take comfort
in your friends"
- [ Clears Throat ] Hi, I'm Michael.
- [ All ] Hi, Michael.
I have been
coming here for...
four months.
This is the first time
I've talked.
[ Sighs ]
My wife is an alcoholic,
and we're separated.
And she's doing great.
She has her life, uh, back.
She seems
to have her life back.
l, on the other hand, am not doin'
so good, which is funny, I guess.
I miss my wife.
And I miss my daughters.
And things at work--
Basically everywhere--
I can't get
a handle on things.
Everything's loose and...
fuzzy.
I look at her now when I drop off
the kids at the house,
and I see what a wonderful job
she's doin' with the kids,
and I wonder why.
That maybe she never
really needed me...
as much as I thought
she needed me.
She thinks the girls
need more watching after.
Especially Casey.
She's our youngest.
You think they're
growin' up fine...
on automatic pilot.
But, uh, you really
have to watch 'em closely,
because, you know,
they just--
They're always hiding stuff,
even from themselves.
[ Coughs ]
Anyway...
I like coming here.
[ Man ] Thank you, Michael.
Well, it's, um--
Yeah, I guess it's a speech.
At my meetings,
when you have six months,
you stand up
and tell your story.
That's all.
And it's
a week from Saturday.
And I'd really
like you to come.
What? I'm not gonna say
bad stuff about you.
- Oh, you're gonna lie, huh?
- [ Laughing ]
I'm gonna accept
responsibility.
That's what it's for.
No wonder I'm confused.
I'd really
like you to come.
- Well, I'll sleep on you-- it.
- [ Laughing ]
You wanna go home
with me, huh?
- Never entered my mind.
- Enters mine.
- Really?
- Yeah, all the time.
I just don't know
what it would be like.
- Because I'm really afraid
of that roller coaster thing...
- I hate that.
- when people break up
and make up and break up.
- People can be immature.
And the very thing that attracts them is
the reason they shouldn't be together.
And I can't do that, Michael.
I can't do that anymore.
I'm moving to Denver.
They're talking about rollbacks
in this domicile,
and if I take
the transfer,
I have a better
chance to keep flying.
[ Sighs ]
lt's either that
or change airlines,
and I'd have to start
from the bottom scale.
I told them that I'd have
to talk to you first...
before I could commit.
Well, you've worked a lot of years
to just start at the bottom.
I can bid for
the San Francisco route.
And with passes
and everything, I can s--
This accepting responsibility
stuff is really fun.
I better go home.
- Don't go yet. Don't go.
- I gotta go.
[ Engine Starts, Car Door Closes ]
Hey, partner.
Can I see that?
I thought Mom was gonna pick me up
after movement class.
She is.
I'm just here for a visit.
lt's a bug box.
Thank you.
I just want to see it.
Ooh.
I like a name
that tells you what it is.
How come you're here?
Come here.
I came to say I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for the fight we had the other
day at the park. That was my fault.
And I'm sorry for not making it better
when Mommy was away.
Wasn't so bad.
I'm really sorry for almost leaving you
with Grandma.
But mostly I'm sorry for the kind of
daddy I was or wasn't...
all the time
since I've known you.
Why are you
saying this?
I'm leaving
for Denver tonight.
I'm moving there.
You and Mommy
are getting divorced.
No. No one's even
talked about that.
And if that were
to ever happen,
I'd get lots
of free passes,
and I'd call you
all the time,
and I'd come to visit
all the time.
'Cause Casey will still
be your daughter?
No. 'Cause you're
my daughter.
And I will always
come back to see you.
I will always come back.
[ Sniffles ]
Not like my dad?
[ Sniffles ] I love you so much.
Just like your real daddy.
But I'm really scared.
I'm really scared.
I'm scared that you don't know
how much I love you,
and so I'll always have to be
doing stuff so you'll know.
[ Sobs ]
I'll try
to do stuff too.
You have
to go there, huh?
[ Sniffles ]
Yeah.
Oh.
[ Sobs ]
I'm gonna
miss you so much.
I'm sorry, baby.
You can do it.
Hey, there, buster.
Ya goin'on a trip?
Boo!
Bad decision.
Cat got your tongue?
lt's a long trip
this time.
Like Mommy's trip?
Maybe longer.
But I'm gonna call ya
every day.
Every day.
And I'll be back
every chance I get.
And when I can't,
you'll come visit me.
Like Mommy?
Yeah.
[ Kisses ]
Will there be swans?
Swans?
Swans are possible.
- Bye, baby.
[ Kisses ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Applause ]
[ Aircraft Radio Chattering ]
Thank you for the fan
appreciation, folks.
Itwas a lot less dramatic
than it looked.
For those of you
connecting out of Denver,
please check your monitors
for any delays.
For the rest of you,
welcome home.
Hi, l-I'm Alice,
um, alcoholic.
[ All ] Hi, Alice.
I've been sober
for 1 84 days.
[ Applause ]
I-I drank my first beer
when I was nine years old.
My dad's an alcoholic, so, uh, my mother
liked to blame my lapse on his example.
That way she could
hurt both of us at once.
Anyway,
I liked my beer...
and the ones that followed.
And about a year ago,
I-I got drunk.
I couldn't stop
getting drunk.
Ithad never really happened quite
like that, and I still don't know why.
I've lied to everyone
that I know,
everyone I love,
and, um...
I was ashamed
and terrified...
and humiliated every day.
Um, one day l...
got out of the shower,
grabbed a towel...
and decided
to go get the paper.
And nobody saw me go out
the front door or at the curb,
which was
a very good thing,
because I was holding the towel
just folded in my hand.
-[ Laughter ]
- [ Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
I know how lucky
I've been,
'cause there were times when I drove
my little girls around...
just ripped out of my mind.
One Saturday I took
my baby girl on errands,
and when I got home,
I realized
she wasn't with me.
I had left her someplace.
And since I couldn't
remember where I'd been,
I had no idea where, so--
[ Sighs ]
I spent the next few hours calling
every shop I'd ever been to...
until finally the tile guy
rang my front doorbell.
They had found
my address on a check.
I rewarded him, of course, you know,
by never going back to his store.
My bottom
was 1 84 days ago...
when my, uh,
my little girl
watched me...
wash down aspirin
with vodka.
And then I hit her.
And when I passed out,
she was alone with me,
and she thought
I was dead.
And all of my life, I will never know
what that did to her.
I know I have to
forgive myself for that.
And I have to forgive myself
for what I've done to my husband.
It's horrifying how much you can
hate yourself for being low and weak.
And he couldn't save me from that,
so I turned it on him.
I tried to empty it onto him,
but there was always more, ya know?
When he tried to help,
I told him that he made me
feel small and worthless.
But nobody makes us
feel that, man.
We do that for ourselves.
I shut him out because...
I knew if he ever
really saw...
who I was inside,
that he wouldn't love me.
And we're separated now.
He's moved away.
And it was so hard
not to beg him to stay.
And I don't know if I'm
gonna get a second chance,
but I have to believe
that I deserve one.
Because we all do.
[ Applause ]
Thank you, Alice. Everyone, let's
take a 1 5-minute coffee break.
Thanks.
That was
so beautiful.
I just hope
I can do it too.
How do you feel?
Like a cigarette?
- Yes. Thank you, sponsor.
- You're welcome.
- Thanks for letting me talk.
- Alice, you really made me cry.
Me, too.
My wife is an alcoholic.
Best person I ever met.
She has 600 different
kinds of smiles.
They can light up
your life.
They can make you
laugh out loud,
just like that.
They can even make you cry,
And that's
just with her smiles.
You'd have to see her
with her kids.
You'd have to see
how they look at her...
when she's not lookin'.
To think of all the things
she lived through,
and I couldn't help her.
Maybe helping
wasn't your job.
The hell it wasn't.
See, I love her.
And I tried everything...
except really listening.
Really listening.
Subtitles by Ayaz [ ayazonline@gmail.com ]
And that's
how I left her alone.
I was so ashamed of that.
And I couldn't even
tell her.
Maybe if I tell her,
she'd love me anyway.
No, more.
She would've loved you
even more.
I think you should
tell all this stuff to your wife.
"Hold me, love"
"I can't sleep again"
"Ooh, I have
to kiss your lips"
"I wanna lay here
next to you"
"Oh"
"I remember"
"Walkin'in the rain"
"Rain was falling
on my head"
"I don't wanna live
through that again"
"No"
"Outside"
"It oughta get dark now"
"Love is walkin'
in the park now"
"Children singin'songs"
"One day we'll make
all our dreams come true"
"I will love you"
"It only takes love"
"Love is a healin'thing"
"When you give everything"
"You're lovin'the world"
"The world gives you love
to hold on to"
"Remember"
"When sorrow is over"
-"Somewhere"
-"Just give me many chances"
-" Oh, no"
-"I'll sing of you my love"
-" The memories"
-"Just give me time to learn, to grow"
"Just give me
many chances"
"I'll see you soon,
my love"
"Just give me time
to learn, to grow"
"Just give me many chances"
"I'll see you soon,
my love"
"Just give me time
to learn, to grow"
"In September"
"When the rain comes"
"And the wind blows"
"I will see you walking
in your coat"
"Oh"
"Just give me
many chances"
"I'll see you soon,
my love"
"Just give me time
to learn, to grow"
"Time to learn, to grow"