[sighs]
Man on radio:
foxtrot 31 delta...
Tango one romeo headed
for your 20, over.
Second man on radio:
zero alpha, copy,
bring it on, out.
Dr. lightman?
This way, doc.
"doc." i like that.
i do, you know? i do.
Right this way.
Watch your head here.
Festive.
Yeah, the more i make,
the better they get.
Welcome to the north pole,
dr. lightman.
John parks, team commander.
How do you do?
Look, straightaway,
i see you're wondering
what idiot came up
With the plan
to send me over here.
So, we have something
in common.
Charlie team
at altitude,
Waiting for your
go-order, boss.
Right now, all you
and i care about are my
12 soldiers in the air,
Ready to halo into
the taliban compound
our new friend here says
Are holding
those two marines.
Wait. i mean,
you already sent
the mission over
Before i even had
a chance to talk
to you?
I moved my team
within striking distance.
I do my job,
you do yours.
Final decision's mine,
period.
No disrespect,
but we don't have
a lot of time
To screw around
before these animals
start cutting heads off.
All right, well,
do me a favor, will you?
Just hold on
the go-order, you know,
till i've had a chance
To talk to your
new friend here.
Yeah, i'll do my best not
to screw around, all right?
We gave him a shave,
cleaned him up.
Sat-link eyes
to your people.
Do you believe
in santa claus?
Up.
Cheers.
Say hello to
the folks back home.
I'm serious.
Say hello to the folks
back home.
Hello.
Whoa. he felt that.
Deep sadness at
the mention of home.
Loker: what are they?
paper snowflakes?
Torres: when lightman asked him
if he believed in santa claus,
i saw a flash of hope.
Where's home for you,
franko?
What?
Where's home for you,
franko?
1276 bayview,
baltimore, maryland.
Torres: blurts out
a street address, like he
memorized it by heart.
I--i lived
with my aunt.
Aunt wendy.
[chuckles]
i'm sorry?
Franko:
wendy perriman.
my aunt.
Is that supposed to mean
something to me or--
My aunt.
Bayview what?
Bayview avenue?
Bayview...terrace?
boulevard?
Street? what is it?
[whispers]
avenue.
Lightman: 'cause you seemed,
you know, pretty sure
about every other detail,
Except for that
one small thing.
Bayview road, baltimore.
And the natives
pronounce it "ballmer."
You know, i'm not
buying much, if any,
Of the whole aid worker,
Aunt wendy story.
I mean, why lie about
your aunt wendy
Unless she's part
of some cover-up,
Some--what is it?
Cia?
Oh, that struck a nerve.
All right. moving on.
How do you know where
the taliban are holding
these two marines?
Why give up
that information?
Because
i'm an american,
not like you.
Ex-cia,
Rogue lunatic--
i mean, whatever it is,
any idiot can see
That you've--you've
grown some deep...
Hatred of all things
uncle sam.
You know what i think?
i think you're just...
A traitor...
Trying to save
his own skin.
What's your
taliban name, franko?
This close to the border
with pakistan,
The taliban never moves
more than ten miles
With prisoners
in the first 48 hours,
And only at night.
The place i told
these soldiers about
Is the safest place
to hide
That close to where
the marines were
captured.
He said the first
half of that with
extreme confidence
Because it's
probably true.
But he used
the word "safest,"
Inferring that the
taliban have more
Than one place
they hide out.
Where else might
the taliban be hiding?
Nowhere.
Oh, well, your shoulder
begs to differ.
Man: all call signs,
stand by for go.
He's lying.
Yeah, he's sending you
to the wrong location.
He's...lying.
Man on radio: charlie one,
over target area now.
You're sure he's lying?
yeah.
No. well, 70%.
Yeah, at best,
he's sending you to
an empty compound;
At worst, it's
an ambush, right?
sit down.
70%?
it's not an exact science.
If it was, you'd have
bin laden by now,
wouldn't you, huh?
Abort.
Do it, mo. now.
Abort. say again,
abort the mission.
You better be right,
dr. lightman.
Yeah.
Parks: forget it.
no way in hell.
Look, i get that
you're a scientist,
But this is no place
for experiments.
Look, this guy,
he's definitely
hiding something.
Whatever it is,
it's buried it deep.
And there's a connection
to your government
somewhere.
I'm telling you,
you gotta let me
Dig it out of him.
You mean to tell me
this maggot's some
sort of spy for us?
Yeah. cia, or related.
And either
he's protecting
Some long-term
deep cover operation,
Or he's just been
out here too long
And he's flipped
to the other side.
Those are just
theories, doc.
Look, you already
proved smarter
than that
When you axed plan "a."
Don't give up
on me now, pal,
Or i'm on
the first donkey
out of here, all right?
Whatever he is,
whoever he is,
I don't care.
I need accurate intel
from him,
And i need it yesterday.
Yeah, yeah.
no, you're right.
Sod the science.
give me a weapon.
Well, at least
i'll get home in time
For my daughter's
christmas party.
I'm serious.
weapon please.
Mr. komisky?
Please. ed.
State department?
pentagon?
Defense.
Special deputy
operations and plans.
I'll be observing
dr. lightman's progress
with the prisoner.
Top secret news sure does
spread fast in this town.
Ha ha!
welcome.
Cute.
this way.
Rah!
All right.
Well, he's ready
for battle,
And he's smart enough
to know when to live
to fight another day.
So he's a warrior.
he's not a martyr.
These are 3 of the boys
you tried to lead
To the wrong
taliban compound.
What was it? eh?
Was it an ambush?
Was it
an empty compound?
Oh, empty compound.
Well, that's something,
i suppose. eh, lads?
Hey!
We keep hearing
this story
About you being a cia
agent who got boned.
That you got sent
out here years ago,
Left for dead.
is that right?
If i don't get home
to texas, boy,
My wife is gonna take
my daughter
And move back
to michigan.
Look, this is
my last tour.
After this, i'm done.
Is it true you got
boned by the cia?
Still don't understand
what you did.
What'd i do?
You went over to the enemy,
you punk.
Attempt at anger.
No, wait, wait.
Now, i get it.
i see your shame.
I see it.
All right, it was
either join them or die.
I mean, these 3,
they might not do
what you did,
But i might.
I mean, i'm
a natural born
coward, me.
My blood runs as yellow
as the next man's.
Lightman just called him
a coward.
How is this helping
get our marines back
exactly?
Well, lightman just
called him a coward
Because he's about to
present him
With an opportunity
for redemption.
Watch.
But what you've
got in common
with these guys
Is that it's
all about living
to fight tomorrow,
Right, in the hope
that someday soon
You get to go home.
If that's not
on the cards,
Then all that remains
is the last fight
you fight.
And then the question
becomes...
Which side of the fight
are you on?
He's thinking about it.
Oh, god. i'm--crap.
i'm so sorry.
Uh, here, let's--
quick, before it stains.
There is another hideout
in the area.
But first, i have...
First you have what?
A condition.
It's a very common
power play
For someone who feels
backed into a corner
With nothing
to lose or gain.
You have a what?
what do you got?
Every time you ask me
a question,
I get to ask you
a question.
The truth buys you
the truth.
You lie, i lie.
All right.
But first, you
show me on the map
Where the taliban
are holding these
two marines.
All right?
Ok, here.
there's two caves
With a tunnel
that connects them.
It's been there
for over 200 years.
Why didn't you
tell us about this
place to start with?
No. he's been with
the taliban too long.
You're still
the bloody enemy.
Me, on the other hand--
I'm all that's
between you two.
I'm really sorry
about this.
I needed an excuse
to talk to you
Away from komisky.
We need to figure out
some signals
Or this is gonna get
expensive.
Komisky's no stranger
to franko.
Yeah. you saw that, too?
Another thing i saw--
He's careful to keep himself
off the sat-link cameras,
Hidden from lightman
and franko.
Have you heard from my dad
in the last 24 hours?
Yeah. yeah. why?
Well, he always calls
to check in when he's
out of town,
And he hasn't this time.
His phone goes straight
to voicemail.
Sweetheart, he's really
swamped right now,
And he'll call
as soon as he can.
Hey guys, we're minutes away
from...
Hi, em,
how's the party coming?
Well, what are they
minutes away from?
Minutes away from what?
He will be back
before you know it, ok?
I gotta go, em, all right?
we'll talk later.
Yeah, yeah. that's it.
That's the cave.
Bloody better be.
Tell me.
Am i ever gonna get home?
We don't have time
for this game.
It's not a game.
it's a test of trust.
Right?
Well, if you ever
do get home,
You're pretty much
screwed.
It's the right cave.
i'm 100% certain.
Charlie one,
target confirmed.
move, move.
Man, over radio:
charlie one, copy, out.
Stand by...
Contact!
contact!
[gunfire]
Man, over radio:
man down!
Casualty--charlie three.
You and your science
just let this bastard
lead us into an ambush.
Man, over radio:
man down! man down!
[indistinct]
Hey! no! back off!
All right. hey.
What did he just say
to you? what did he
say to you?
He said, "kill me now,
it would be an honor."
You meant it,
didn't you?
Who are you now?
huh? who are you?
My taliban name
is khaled.
yeah?
My name is mo--short
for mohammed.
Man, over radio:
zero, charlie one,
charlie three's hit bad.
Wait. out.
Oh!
Did you or did you not
send my men into an ambush?
I did not!
I told you it was
a taliban hideout.
Did you expect it
to be guarded?
Maybe you underestimate
your enemy.
No, wait!
no, wait!
Hey, he's telling
the truth.
No, he was as
shocked as you are
by what happened.
And you're not going
to kill an unarmed man
in cold blood
Just out
of sheer frustration,
so knock it off.
All right?
You know that man?
You know
that man?
I've never
seen him before.
Do you know that man?
I've never seen him
before.
Foster? foster,
who you got in there?
Ed komisky,
defense department.
Hi, ed. i see you've met
my friend franko,
Oh, a little bit ago.
There you go.
[indistinct]
Is he one of the ones
who sent you here?
Hey?
Is he the one
that sent you here?
What did he tell you?
what did he tell you?
Did he tell you
you were gonna be a hero?
Did he tell you you were
gonna be a patriot?
Is that...
what then, eh?
then what?
Oh, that's between
you and him?
Well, i'll be very happy to set
up that face-to-face meeting,
But right now, we've got
some mess to clear up,
All right? move. move.
Kill the feed.
Kill the feed!
Komisky: what,
he's shutting us out?
Get him on
the sat-phone.
Order him to
give us eyes back.
Yeah, if you think
cal lightman is gonna jump
Just because you bark,
you don't know the man.
Trust me.
Call me
if he comes back online.
You know franko,
don't you?
The only reason i'm here
Is because i want
to see those two marines
Returned home alive.
Us, too.
Look at you, huh?
look at you.
A minute ago, you said
you were willing to die
At this man's hand,
it would be an honor.
Now look at you.
You'd anything you can
to get home
Just because of what you saw
on that sat-link.
Man, over radio:
zero, charlie one, over.
Casualty, charlie three.
Chest wound.
Stand by air support
and casevac.
Stand by for coordinates.
If he calls in
an air strike, right,
In a matter of minutes,
a lot of people are gonna die.
Doesn't matter
what side you're on.
When i got here,
You thought i was here
to help you, didn't you?
Didn't you?
There's another way in.
Where?
When did you get hooked,
dr. lightman?
Let's go! let's go!
hurry the hell up.
What? what?
On war. on this.
You get high on being
in the middle of it all.
Don't you?
Don't you? i can
see it in your face.
Why are you--
why are you doing this?
Ok, you know what?
There is no
other way in.
they're dead.
Look, i told you,
you lie, i lie.
All right, bosnia, 1994.
I didn't see direct action,
But i was
this close to it.
You get lucky just one time.
you survive, right?
It's the rush.
there's no--
There's nothing like it.
It's delusions
of immortality.
Right? right?
You're enjoying this.
No, no. no, no.
now. now it's your turn.
You owe me the other
tunnel to that cave.
Tell them to go left--
No. you tell 'em.
you tell 'em.
You tell him!
you tell him!
Tell them to go left
about a hundred yards.
There's a rock
with an arch in it.
This doesn't work,
he's done.
Yeah, well,
so am i.
Man:
charlie call signs...
This isn't just
a test of trust,
is it?
Right.
You're playing this game
Because you think
that if this mission
goes south,
Then you're not
the only one to blame.
But if it succeeds,
I'm gonna become your
brother in arms, right?
I'm gonna be more
likely to help you
Somewhere down the road,
right?
Don't hold your breath.
Ms. lenox, what do you
know about ed komisky?
Mr. komisky
is a hangover
From previous
administrations.
Man's more like
a pentagon ghost.
We're beginning to think
that he was involved
In some sort of operation
Which abandoned this man
franko in afghanistan.
Are you aware of
any such operations?
No.
You don't want
to think about it?
I know of no operations
involving franko.
No records exist of cia
Or any other
agency's involvement.
But he could be
an agency asset
That you have never
heard about?
No. i understand
what you're asking.
But i'm not sure
i can get
Any answers quicker than
you can.
Franko's aunt.
I need her here as soon
as possible.
Can you do that?
Hey, lightman's
back on line.
He needs our eyes and
ears for this next part.
We never had--
Never had this
conversation.
i got it.
If i help get
these marines out,
I want my story told.
That's above my pay grade,
pal. dream on.
It's right at
my pay grade,
If your story's true.
Well, that's
the back entrance
into the cave.
They're gonna hit a tunnel.
And they can go
one of two directions.
Left?
left is bad.
Charlie one, move right,
over.
No, no, no!
wait, wait, wait!
Wait a second!
If this is a back way
into the cave,
It's also a back way out.
We mount a frontal assault.
That way they'll try and
haul ass out the back way
With the prisoners.
That's what i'd do.
How about you, eh?
[gunfire]
Hold, positions, charlie one,
Hold positions.
set evac charges.
Stand by for enemy, over.
That's not florida.
Emily...
how did you get in here?
You lied to me.
He lied to me.
Charlie one,
hold positions.
Set evac charge.
Stand by for enemy.
over.
Em!
Dad?
Emily.
[gunfire]
Dad!
did he just get...
No, no, no,
he didn't.
Man, over radio: charlie one,
move to alternate cave entrance.
Complete.
Charlie three, charlie three,
zero alpha, over!
How'd the taliban
find us?
They got his radio
when he was hit.
They used it for directions
to find us here.
Fire support,
confirm position.
Moving through tunnel now.
Going firm
at tunnel intersection.
[gunfire]
Contact! contact!
Marine prisoners and taliban!
3 taliban dead.
Zero, this is
alpha whiskey.
Evac complete.
We have the two marines
and rescue team complete.
Setting evac charges now.
over.
Copy that.
Alpha whiskey one standing by
waiting for your signal. over.
[explosion]
Need medic on board
with all his toys. over.
[explosion]
It's a direct hit.
The radios are dead
for good.
They're out there
on their own now.
Wait. what about us?
You got any contingencies?
In the event
of loss of comms
During contact
with the enemy,
We have 20 minutes to
haul ass out of here.
What happens
in 20 minutes?
Smart bombs turn
this place into
a parking lot.
And everything in it.
So the only way that you
can get out of here
Is if you lure the enemy
into the kill zone,
Which happens to be...
right?
Copy that.
Oh, thank you
very much.
All right,
you wait here.
If i'm not back
in 18 minutes,
You leave by that door.
You know how to use that?
[explosion]
Not bad
for a scientist.
I've had my moments.
Terrific.
We've got 17 minutes.
You want to tell me
about your moments?
That game's over now.
yeah, i mean...
Besides, you're
the one who wants
his story told, so...
How badly you want
to hear it?
[explosion]
All right, well,
The answer's probably
gonna stay in this
room anyway. go on.
Ask your question.
What did you do
in bosnia?
Intelligence.
You seem like you don't want
to really talk about it.
Why is that?
Well, the past
is the past, right?
I can relate to that.
I know that
you're trying to get
some common ground
Between us, all right,
khaled,
But i didn't betray
my country.
You betrayed something.
Yeah, i betrayed myself.
how about you?
[explosion]
Mr. komisky,
a moment of your time?
You too, torres.
My real name is
specialist glen welsh.
What branch
of the military
were you in?
Uh, back to bosnia,
your betrayal.
All right.
Sarajevo. '94.
Right, we were
interrogating
a serb officer
About his
sniper positions.
We?
Yeah. mi6,
british intelligence.
And i didn't
believe him,
So we changed
his clothes
And chocked him out
into sniper alley.
He lasted 4 seconds,
Got about 18 feet-ish.
His information
was accurate.
But he was the enemy,
right?
[gunfire]
I'm a scientist. i'm
not an executioner.
War got the better
of you, too.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
now your turn.
I was aiming
for special ops.
Before i got there,
'99,
I got in a bar fight.
They threw me in the brig
for three years.
Manslaughter.
I could tell you
my drinks were spiked,
But what would you care,
right?
Right.
Two years later,
and this is right after 9/11,
I got jumped in the brig
and was thrown in the hospital.
Somebody had knifed me
in my back.
That's when they
offered me a way out.
That man you saw
on the sat-link.
Yeah?
[explosion
and gunfire]
Ms. perriman.
Franko's aunt wendy?
Franko?
is he alive?
Where is he?
And they moved you straight
from the brig hospital
To a training facility,
right?
Uh-huh.
where?
Somewhere out west.
i don't know exactly.
They didn't tell me--
you know,
It looked a lot like this
hell hole.
All right,
and they trained you
to do what?
[explosion]
They taught me pashto.
They--they put me through
Their own brand
of special ops training.
And then they dropped
me in the middle of
taliban territory,
Posing as an aid worker
with shia sympathies.
You know, they said
they were gonna be watching me,
That they'd have my back
And that they'd pull me out
when the time was right.
All right,
but they didn't.
They never came back
for you, right?
Yeah.
They betrayed you,
right, so you went over
to the other side.
Is that it?
Did you ever kill any
american troops?
No.
That's a bloody lie.
No. no. look.
Look, look, you try
to shoot over their heads,
But those bastards,
they just keep
shooting back.
What? what?
what are you doing?
Ah! aah!
Hold still!
hold still!
[gunfire]
How did the people
that put you here,
How did they know
how to find you?
How were they
tracking you? eh?
I think i know.
i think i know.
Hold still!
if i'm right,
This is gonna prove
your story's real.
What the hell
are you doing,
lightman?
All of you, you have to help me
hold him still!
Hold him still!
Hey, we gotta go!
we gotta go right now!
Not until
i've done this!
You listen to orders!
I often have orders
from the president.
Did i forget
to mention that?
Now hold him still.
Aah!
All right, give me
the pliers.
The pliers!
[gunfire]
Aah!
My sister, peg, died
giving birth to franko.
And i raised him
just like he was my own.
Have you two
met before?
No.
What elementary school
did franko go to?
Who was his first
girlfriend?
Ms. perriman...
I believe you really did have a
sister who died in childbirth,
Which is what makes
your story believable...
To the layman.
It's not a story.
Do you carry a picture
of your nephew?
I just--i imagine
over the years
Of not knowing
where he is
Or if he's even alive,
It might be a great
comfort to you,
You know, a symbol of hope
top have some--
Komisky:
that's enough.
You don't have
to answer that.
They came to me
after 9/11.
My sister's death didn't have
to be for nothing, they said.
She's definitely
telling the truth.
Now, i can tell you want
to get this out,
So please keep going,
ms. perriman.
Someone from the cia
did come to me.
I guess it was
like an acting role...
For my country.
You gotta understand,
i wanted
To do something.
We all wanted
to do something.
Including you, sir.
I believe that.
But you sent a man
into afghanistan
To infiltrate
the taliban.
Then what? you just
forget about him?
Or you just leave
him there to rot?
Or worse.
We lost him.
The battery in his
tracking device died.
The battery?
it happens.
Know how hard it is to find
anyone out there?
I've heard.
We kept waiting
for him to show up,
And when he didn't,
we assumed he was dead.
So please, take your
sanctimonious judgment
And park it
somewhere else.
Aah!
Snow.
If we don't
get out of here,
It'll be the last white
christmas we ever see.
Not until i finish.
not until i finish.
hold on.
Aah!
Hey, hey, hey,
hold still!
Aah!
There.
It's a tracking device.
Two-year battery life.
He is one of ours.
Why didn't you tell us
Who you were
in the beginning?
Orders.
I disobey, i'm dead.
The only person
i reveal my
identity to
Is the man
with the code.
nobody else!
[explosion]
The code is aunt wendy.
Well, that's a reason.
But it's not
a real reason, is it?
Come on, you can do
better than that.
And these bastards caught
me, and they beat me.
Yeah. i was taliban.
Well, that's better.
So, who are you now, eh?
You're the expert.
you tell me.
[explosion]
You tell your mom?
No.
Why not?
Same reason you
didn't tell me.
Don't you think
you should tell her?
He can tell her
when he gets back.
Move out!
let's go, go!
Let's go! move, move!
Move, go!
Lightman,
you're out of here!
Lightman:
no. no, no, no.
We saw it on your face
earlier, right?
You've got orders never to let
this man leave this room alive,
Don't you? eh?
Am i right?
These men remind you
of what you wanted to be,
All right?
And so now it's about
a last fight you fight
And which side of the fight
you're on,
All right, and if you
finally get to do
What you came here
in the first place to do.
Ok?
I need 45 seconds
of fight out of him
To clear the tunnel.
Here.
Where's home?
1245 glenview park,
iowa city.
Say it again!
say it again!
12245 glenview park,
iowa city.
[gunfire]
Nice job, doc!
Not really!
[explosions]
That's him.
Heard you helped
get us out.
Thank you.
No. thank you.
Dr. lightman.
Oh. the real
aunt wendy.
Please don't do this.
This is a matter
of national security.
What story
did you people tell
specialist welsh,
Franko's, family?
Killed in action?
Died in the brig?
Oh, died
in the brig.
nice one.
I was serving
my country.
Oh, yeah?
our country, you mean.
It's our country.
It's about time
you let that one
go, mate.
You go public with this,
you'll be breaking the law.
I'm not going public
with it.
I'm gonna tell
a man's family
The truth about
their son.
You know what i mean.
You know...
sooner or later
You got to stand up
and be counted for
our mistakes, right?
Your man, franko,
he went over...
To the taliban.
That's a big mistake.
But in the end...
You know what i mean?
Mr. welsh?
Yeah, but what's
going on out here?
Who are you?
Who is it, hon?
Do you mind
if if come in
for a minute?
There's a few things
i'd like to tell you
About your son,
glen.
Glen?
Do you mind?
[wipes feet]
Happy holidays.
Dr. lightman...
Would you let me
do the talking?
Just so long as
it's the truth.
* santa baby *
He's late.
Yeah.
midwest is snowed under.
Delays everywhere.
Yeah. my mom's stuck
in st. louis.
What are you
gonna you do?
* santa baby *
* a '54 convertible please,
light blue *
* i'll wait up for you, dear *
* santa baby *
* so hurry down the chimney
to me *
Hi.
Hello, darling.
I know.
You shouldn't have had
to see that, em.
I was scared, dad.
I was really scared.
I know. yeah.
Yeah, me, too.
me, too.
So is it naive
to ask you,
beg you really,
Never to do anything
like that again?
No.
Well, yeah.
it's a little bit.
Oy.
Well, let's share
some of that.
All right.
Aw...
it's beautiful.
Well, darling...
Are you ok?
I'm not sure.
Good.
you're not meant to be.
Ria.
Hey.
You look nice...
Thank you.
Ish.
Lokar.
I got you
a secret santa.
I'm watching you.
Oh, man.
Yeah. don't
mention it.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com