- (KIDS TALK INDISTINCTLY)
- (DOG BARKS)
MAN: Great work!
(PEOPLE CHEER)
(SIREN WAILS)
WOMAN: Michael is having
a heart attack. (LAUGHS)
- MAN: That's my girl!
- ANDREW O'KEEFE: So...
MAN: Take it. Take it.
Shell. $15,000, Shell.
I知 thinking fishing boat.
WOMAN: Oh, you might be
thinking fishing boat.
- I知 thinking a gown.
- O'KEEFE: Ah!
- WOMAN: Nice.
- MAN: Yes.
O'KEEFE: Well, if you went one more
and you didn稚 knock out the 75,
your offer would be about 37,000,
so there's a wedding plus a gown.
There's no denying, Michael,
that is exceptionally good cash.
There's no denying that the risk...
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
- You called the ambos up?
- Yeah.
- What has she taken?
- Heroin.
O'KEEFE: (ON TV) But there is
also no doubting
that if you avoid it, your next offer
will be something like 25.
MAN: No guts, no glory, I suppose.
(WOMAN ON TV SIGHS)
MAN: it's all up to you, darl.
Think clearly, though.
WOMAN: Um...
- No deal!
- O'KEEFE: Awwww!
(O'KEEFE LAUGHS)
Wow! Wow!
Look at your husband.
So...
WOMAN: I知 sorry, I don't remember
if I have actually asked number 14
what she thought she may have.
- PARAMEDIC 1: Narcan's in?
- PARAMEDIC 2: Yes.
WOMAN: (ON TV) Oh, yes,
you did too, didn稚 you?
- Oh, lordy, lordy!
- O'KEEFE: Lots of lordy!
WOMAN: (ON PHONE) Hello.
Grandma, it's J.
- Who?
- Josh.
Oh, Josh!
How are you, darlin'? (LAUGHS)
Yeah, good.
Um, Mum's gone and OD'd
and she's died and so...
(GASPS) Are you OK?
Yeah, I知 OK. Sorry.
I probably should have
said it a bit slower
and not just go and blurt it out
like that.
I don't really know
what I知 supposed to do now.
- Where is she?
- They took her away.
The ambulance came.
What about the cops, honey?
They showed up and they took
a statement and that,
but I said that I was 18
and now I don't really know
what I知 supposed to do.
Right, right.
They didn't say anything, you know.
Like, am I supposed to organise
the funeral and that?
Like, I don't know
what I知 supposed to do
with all the paperwork
and the arrangements
and that, you know?
Yeah.
And I remember
when Grandpa Donny died
that you were on top of everything,
so, you know, I called.
Listen, baby, hang on.
I知 coming to get you, OK?
Yep. Um...
Do you...do you remember
where we live?
(LAUGHS) Of course I do, sweetheart.
You sit tight. I値l be right there.
Yep. OK.
'Bye.
(PHONE BEEPS OFF)
Oh! (PANTS) Puffed.
You got your bags packed?
Come here, sweetie.
Get your bags, honey.
(TITLE MUSIC)
(TITLE MUSIC CONTINUES)
J: Mum kept me away from her family
because she was scared.
l didn稚 realise it at the time,
but they were all scared,
even if they didn稚 show it.
l think even Barry Brown was scared,
even though he never showed it.
Everyone felt safe around Baz.
He'd punch your head off
if you got in the way,
If he was in the middle
of an armed rob and...
BAZ: 9,400.
...you got between him and the door,
he'd put you on the ground
and not think twice about it.
Morning, baby.
But he was good to me.
And to everyone else.
You want juice? Smurf's juicing.
J: Hi, Uncle Darren.
Seriously, you've got to stop calling
me 'uncle'. It gives me the creeps.
Darren was only a couple of years
older than me.
When we were little Kids,
he was like my best friend.
We used to throw rocks
at cars and that.
He had a way better BMX than me.
CRAIG: Daisy, come here!
My bike was shit.
Come here. Good girl. Come on.
- Come on, come on.
- What you doing, hon?
What's it look like? Get out!
- Stay there.
- (JUICER WHIRRS)
(SHOUTS) Stay there!
- (JUICER WHINES)
- Oh, Mum. Fuck. Seriously!
What the fuck is going on?
Who said you could bring
that noise thing in my house?
- It's yours.
- It is not. Bullshit.
Yes, it is. I found it
under the sink.
- Do you want a juice?
- No.
J: My uncle Craig moved
really fast like...
...he was trying to stay
in front of something.
- Craig.
- What?
- Come here.
- I知 busy.
And Grandma Smurf...
- Doing what?
- I知 just busy.
Come here and give me a kiss.
...she just seemed to want to be
wherever the boys were.
And she just wanted to be around
whatever the boys were doing.
But they were all scared,
even if they didn稚 show it.
Even if they didn稚 know it exactly.
Even if they were having to do
what crooks do all the time,
which is block out
the thing they must know-
they must know it...
(WOMAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY
ON PHONE)
... which is that crooks
always come undone.
Always.
One way or another.
In Melbourne at this time -
this was a while ago now -
the Armed Robbery Squad
was out of control.
They were shooting guys willy-nilly
and getting away with it.
And they'd been after Baz
and my family for months.
But the guy they really wanted,
the guy they really hated,
was my other uncle - uncle Andrew.
But everyone just called him Pope.
He was hiding in
a motel room somewhere
'cause he heard he was next.
These are for you.
Thanks, mate.
He's not here.
You guys are wasting your time.
Who's not here?
You know who I mean.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
J: Craig was selling drugs.
He was selling lots of them.
Has your brother heard the noises Armed
Robbery Squad have been making?
Yeah.
He said they're out to get him
so he's fucked off somewhere.
He had a detective in the drug squad
helping him do it.
A guy called Randall Roache.
Is this the Anderis gear?
No, that's half. The other half's
still in lockup.
We'll talk about it later, mate.
My kid's in the car.
I've got to go to soccer practice.
They'd meet in a fish shop
In Footscray
'cause Craig loved fish.
CRAIG: What have they got
against him, anyway?
ROACHE: Well, they want him
gone, mate.
They don't think anything
they've done's gonna stand in court
so they want to put him
off themselves.
CRAIG: And why are they going on
about Pope?
- What about Baz and Darren?
- ROACHE: Fuck, I don't know.
You know what these guys are like.
They're cowboys.
- They do whatever they want.
- What's he supposed to do?
Just tell him to pull
his fucking head in, mate.
The whole thing's
falling apart over there.
Armed Robbery's about to be disbanded
and everything will just go away.
Just tell him to pull
his fucking head in.
His head's in. Your head doesn't
get any more in than Pope's head.
Mate, even if I gave a shit,
you'd be telling the wrong bloke.
Fuck!
J: And I don't know, like,
all this seems strange to me
but not strange either.
You know what I mean?
Kids just are wherever they are
and they just do whatever
they're doing, you know?
This is where I was
and this is what I was doing.
After my mum died, this was just
the world I got thrown into.
Hey, buddy. Hey!
Light's green, you idiot.
You got a staring problem, mate?
What the fuck you looking at?
- (ENGINE REVS)
- Yeah, fuckin' get me.
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
- CRAIG: Go get him.
- MAN: Oi!
And do what?
Let him know who's king.
Come on, come outside.
I値l deck ya, mate. Come outside.
Come on, idiot. Come outside.
Wha-hey-hey!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, brother.
Just relax, man. I was just gonna
have a chat to him, alright?
(LAUGHS)
Just chill, bro.
Fuck this, man.
(CRAIG GIGGLES)
MAN: Fuck out of here, man!
(CRAIG LAUGHS)
How did that feel? Huh?
Did you get a little stiffy? Yeah?
('BERSERK WARRIORS'
BY MENTAL AS ANYTHING PLAYS)
Bit of fun, huh?
I値l give you 100 bucks.
Come on!
- I値l give you 100 bucks.
- Honey, people are watching.
200 bucks.
Would you fuckin' motivate
your girlfriend?
- Mate, just let her alone.
- Yeah?
OK, open up. 200 bucks.
Alright. That's the way.
- (LAUGHS)
- Awesome!
- NICKY: Fuckin' rich!
- (LAUGHS)
Hey, so Nicole's a sweetie.
Where'd you find her?
Found her at school.
- Where are you going?
- What?
Did you wash your hands?
No.
You had your hands on your cock.
Your hands go anywhere near
your arse or your cock,
you wash them after.
Jeez. Come on.
Bit of soap.
(WATER RUNS)
Yeah. Get a lather going.
Rinse.
Alright, that's enough.
Now stick them under there.
I知 invisible.
These things never see me.
No-one's invisible, mate.
You've got to get right up in there.
(DRYER BLOWS)
There you go.
Excuse me.
The bill.
Roache said just pull your head in.
Right? You all got to
pull your heads in.
Sir, there's no smoking in here.
Sorry. Just doing it a little bit.
They're not watching you.
CRAIG: Can't you cut 'em in?
Just give 'em a drink.
It's the Armed Robbery Squad, mate.
They don't do business.
Mmm.
Roache just says pull your heads in
and it'll all go away.
- (GROANS)
- Right?
- Sir, you cannot smoke in here.
- Oh, for fuck's sake.
Alright. That's alright.
We're done here. It's good.
('SITTING IN LIMBO' BY JIMMY CLIFF
PLAYS)
Mum! I知 going home.
Oh, darling, are you alright to
drive? You're not drunk, are you?
No, I知 OK. I知 fine.
Come and give us a kiss.
BAZ: Do you ever stop, mate?
Seriously, every time I see you
you're chopping in.
Why don't you try going to sleep
for once in your life?
Bazza, I sleep like a baby.
Want some?
Oh, no, she's alright.
Says you.
Yeah. Don't trample
her freedom, mate.
Sweetheart, would you like some?
We're here having a nice night
and you have to do your own thing.
Well, fuckin' avert your eyes.
J, can you go and get some drinks?
Can you get Bazza a really big one?
Loosen him up just a little bit.
BAZ: Well...
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTTLE SHATTERS)
CRAIG: Oi!
SMURF: Are you alright, love?
SMURF: J?
- (WHISPERS) OK, tell 'em, tell 'em.
- I知 alright.
Are you sure?
Guess - who am I?
Uncle Pope.
- Do you know me?
- Yeah, you're Julia's kid.
CRAIG: Better be cleaning that up
in there.
Ruined my surprise.
They're not actually gonna shoot ya.
You know that, don't you?
Bet that's what they said to Mickey
and Petey...Petey Speed as well.
Mate, if they had anything on us,
they would be using it.
But they don't,
so then all they can do
is sit in a car
outside my fucking house.
Yeah...
BAZ: They've got bigger fish to fry.
The Armed Rob's getting shut down.
Half those guys will get shuffled
over to Major Crime Squad.
Rest will go, you know, wherever.
And their whole club
will fall to bits.
All they can try and do now
is get something over on us.
They got something over on you.
Yeah, they made you run.
You're a fuck.
You don't have them out there
telling people
they want to knock ya.
- Baz, we should go.
- Yeah, in a minute, babe.
It's late. We should go.
Charlie's babysitting.
Yeah, well, I知 just talking.
Call Charlie.
I値l pay her 1,000 bucks
if she stays over the night.
Yeah, nine grand a pop's
as good as it gets now.
I don't know that you've got
1,000 bucks to give the babysitter.
Yeah. True. That's not untrue.
(ALL LAUGH)
Hey, hey. Can you hear that?
- Shh.
- What?
Fuckin' listen.
SMURF: What is it, hon?
- Pull my finger.
- Oh!
(LAUGHS) Pull my finger!
- Argh!
- Ow!
Mongrel!
SMURF: Kids, cut it out.
Get off him, hon.
CRAIG: Andrew's got my arm! Argh!
(TURNS VACUUM OFF)
- Where are you going?
- Supermarket.
What to get?
Not much.
What?
(TURNS VACUUM ON)
I知 gonna meet Pope.
How long's that car gonna stay
parked outside our house?
(TURNS VACUUM ON) This is what
I知 gonna go meet him about.
- It's been there for a week.
- Mmm.
Yeah, well, this is what I知 gonna
go and meet him about, aren't I?
Can you not pinch my arse
every five seconds?
Oh, but I can't help it.
I just... I love it!
(BOTH LAUGH)
See ya.
- Get milk.
- Nuh!
Here, mate.
Take that. That's my number.
That'll be my number
for the next week or so
and then I値l change it every week.
BAZ: Right. That's your split.
It's bullshit.
- Sorry, love.
- Excuse me.
Mate, I don't know what you're
thinking about your future and that
but I知 about done with this shit.
I need some sort of change.
The stock market's working.
You know that 20 grand
I put in there is 60 now?
See, you get a foot in that door,
there's serious money
to be made, you know?
I don't know anything
about the stock market, mate.
So what? Neither did I.
Doesn't matter.
You get the paper, you learn it.
It doesn't matter.
Our game, it's over, mate.
It's getting too hard.
It's a fucking joke.
You know, Craig's making a fucking
fortune with the drug thing.
You saw the house he's bought.
I don't know I got that in me.
- It's grubby.
- Mmm.
You know? Grubby business.
The stock market, mate.
There's a resources boom.
I値l get you started. I値l set you
an account up and you're away.
Yeah, I...mate, I知...
I don't have a computer.
Don't need a computer.
Well, I don't know
what I知 gonna do. What...
Well...
..either do I, is what I知 saying.
But every day's a new day
is what I知 also saying.
What the fuck
is that supposed to mean?
BAZ: Aw, fuck.
Here we go.
Oh, shit, guys, you just missed him.
That's alright. I like you better.
- DETECTIVE: He's got a gun!
- (GUNSHOT)
- You spoken to Cath?
- I gotta go, hon.
Huh?
It's OK to cry, honey.
Honey, come here.
Dogs!
Fuck.
- FUCK!
- Hey, come on, baby.
Calm down. Come here. Come on.
Shh.
(CRAIG SOBS)
- (WHIMPERS)
- Shh. Shh.
ALICIA: it can't happen, Nick.
You're at school. You're in Year 12:
He really needs somewhere, Mum.
There's things going on.
- What things?
- Things.
I don't know.
It'd just be for a while.
You're still at school, Nick.
You're probably gonna make
a mess of it as it is.
And you shouldn't be asking me this
right in front of J.
Why? 'Cause you don't want him
to see what a bitch you are?
Hey, hey, hey, come on.
Look, one of J's friends
got shot by the cops today,
and he's dead, OK?
And I don't think it would be
that big a deal to let him stay here.
I didn't know him too well.
GUS: Where was this?
Um...Prahran, I think.
That was on the news.
I didn't know him too well. It was...
it was just a shock and everything.
Well, uh, I mean, can we do anything?
I mean, do you want a drink or...?
No, thanks.
So maybe you can think about that.
(DOOR SHUTS)
# I知 lying alone
with my head on the phone
# Thinking of you till it hurts
# I know you hurt too
but what else can we do
# Tormented and torn apart
# I wish I could carry
your smile in my heart
# For times when my life
seems so low
# It would make me believe
what tomorrow could bring
# When today doesn't really know
# Doesn't really know
# I知 all out of love
I知 so lost without you
# I know you were right
Believing for so long
# I知 all out of love
What am I without you?
# I can't be too late
# To say that I was so wrong
# I want you to come back
and carry me home
#Away from these long, lonely nights
# I知 reaching for you
Are you feeling it too?
# Does the feeling seem oh, so right?
#And what would you say
If I called on you now?
#And said that I can't hold on... #
(NICKY EXHALES)
She's beautiful, mate.
SMURF: You know why your mum and I
didn't talk for so long?
No.
We had a fight...about...
You know the card game 500?
She reckoned you can play the joker
whenever you want
in a no-trumps hand.
She was drunk.
I was drunk too, but I was right.
So look what happens.
Years go by and then she's gone.
And I lose my only daughter...
...'cause you can't play the joker
whenever you want
in a no-trumps hand.
And I don't get to see you for years.
That made me real sad.
But I知 getting to see you now.
All the time.
OK. Stand up.
Let's have a look at you.
Sweet!
- How do I look?
- You look good.
Correct. (LAUGHS)
Beautiful boy.
(LOW, DISCORDANT SOUNDSCAPE)
(DISCORDANT HUM INTENSIFIES)
Where'd you get that suit?
What's that suit?
DARREN: It's a suit.
What, do you think
it looks good on you?
What?
Looks gay. Are you gay?
Fuck off, will you?
It's a serious question.
I don't care if you're gay
or if you're not gay, you know?
It's alright if you are, mate.
I just want you to tell me
about it, you know?
I don't care whether
you're gay or you're not gay.
I just want you to talk to me
about it, you know?
Making yourself a drink?
- Yep.
- What is it?
It's a bourbon and coke.
Bourbon and coke's
not a very gay drink, mate.
I think...look, if you're a gay man,
if you are,
and you want to make yourself
a gay drink,
just go ahead
and make yourself a gay drink.
You know what I mean?
That's what I知 talking about, mate.
I just want you to tell me things.
You know, it just kills me
to see you living a lie.
Look, will you fuck off? Seriously.
What do you think we should do?
I think we should be there
for Cath and the family and that.
What are you gonna do, Darren?
It's wrong and all that
but, you know...
You know, if Baz
was still here right now
and we'd just been to your funeral,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
'Cause he'd have already
done something about it.
If you don't want to do anything
because you're scared...
Is it because you're scared?
It's alright if you are.
I just want you to tell me about it.
Just talk to me.
(CICADAS HUM)
(SHOWER RUNS)
- Where's Craig?
- I don't know.
I need a favour, alright?
You're good with cars, yeah?
- Yeah.
- OK.
You go get me a Commodore
or something like that
and bring it to Darren's place.
Alright?
At, uh, 2am.
How come?
'Cause I told you to.
(CAR REVS IN DISTANCE)
(ENGINE SPUTTERS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Where is it?
It's parked around back.
It's a white Commodore.
What are you doing that for?
What are you doing that now for?
What makes you think that's
a good idea to do that now?
The bag. Get the bag.
Oh, and hey,
anyone calls while we're out,
you tell them Darren's in the shower.
(LOW, TENSE MUSIC)
I知 so sorry I知 late.
See you out there, mate.
(INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO
COMMUNICATION, MEN CHAT)
(GUN CLICKS REPEATEDLY)
Great. Thanks, Sergeant.
MAN: (ON RADIO) Richmond 49,
do you copy?
49 Richmond, we copy.
MAN: (ON RADIO) 49,
what's your current position?
49: We're heading west on Bridge Road
towards Church.
MAN: (ON RADIO) 49, Boroondara's
units are all tied up at present.
Can you head over to 36 Darcy Street
In Hawthorn?
A Mrs Birnie of that address
has reported
a white Commodore sedan
in the middle of the road.
Says it looks stolen.
Windows are smashed.
49: Roger. We'll give it a look.
(STRAINED MUSIC)
- Oh, this looks like it.
- Yep.
(CAR DOORS SHUT,
INDISTINCT RADIO COMMUNICATION)
(GUNSHOT)
Turn around, pig cunt.
(TWO GUNSHOTS)
(DOG HOWLS)
(INDISTINCT RADIO
COMMUNICATION)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DARK ELECTRONIC MUSIC)
(WATER RUNS)
Darren?
- Darren, what happened?
- Go to sleep.
Should I go home?
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
(CALLER HANGS UP)
CRICKET COMMENTATOR: (ON TV)
Oh, he's stretched out that one.
And he's asking the question.
A little shrug
of the shoulders, uh...
(DOOR OPENS)
He obviously doesn't know.
- And I think that's out!
- (DOOR SHUTS)
Yes, he lifts his foot to get it back
and I think the ball is off...
Hey! Hey.
This Sri Lankan guy here,
what's his name?
It's... Muralitharan?
- What?
- Muralitharan.
Yeah. He's funny.
(CHUCKLES)
Where's Craig?
Oh, I don't know.
Hey, who cuts your hair?
Nicky.
Yeah?
Do you think maybe she'd cut my hair
if I asked her?
Maybe.
- Where are you going?
- Just gonna go to my room.
Listen, you know if you ever want
to talk about anything or anything,
I知 there, right?
I mean, if you need help
with anything or whatever,
I'd like to do that for you.
Yeah. Right, OK.
(ETHEREAL MUSIC)
G'day, Josh.
I知 Detective
Senior Sergeant Leckie.
This is Detective Norris.
Mr Harrop here's from
the Department of Human Services.
It's a requirement under the law
when questioning anybody
under the age of 18
that they be accompanied by
a guardian or legal representative.
In the absence of such a person,
a department officer
such as John here must be present.
I must also advise you
you're under no obligation
to say anything at this point in time
but anything you do say
can be used as evidence
in any later court appearances.
- Do you understand?
- Yeah.
OK. This shouldn't take too long.
I've already been here for hours.
Yeah, I知 sorry about that.
It's been a big day,
as I知 sure you can understand.
Please state your full name.
Joshua Daniel Cody.
And do you know why
you're here, Josh?
I wouldn't have a clue.
Right, well, last night,
two police officers were shot dead
investigating a stolen car
in Hawthorn.
Can you tell me where
you were last night?
- I was at home.
- What's the address there?
1 7 Harding Street, Ivanhoe.
OK. What were you doing
at home last night, Josh?
J: Just watching TV:
Were your uncles at that address
with you all night last night?
They were home,
but I fell asleep pretty early
so I wouldn't have a clue, really,
what they were up to.
Think they might've just been
watching TV, sort of thing.
They were watching TV with you?
They came in at some point
but by that point
I was already half asleep, so...
What were you watching?
I think it was that
'Funniest Home Videos'.
I was pretty much just
having a nap on the couch.
And so, at some point, all three
of your uncles came into the room?
Is that right, or...or just
one of them, or...or maybe two?
Can you tell me exactly
who was there?
I can't really tell you. I was...
I was that tired that I only remember
there were people around
but, you know, I can't
say who exactly is...
Basically I had my eyes shut,
sort of thing.
You don't remember who you heard?
The reason...the reason
I was so sleepy
is 'cause I壇 smoked some marijuana
and...you know, I was knocked out...
..sort of thing.
I didn't want to
have to tell you guys that.
Do you remember where you were
when you heard the news
of Barry Brown's death?
I was home.
And how did the family
take that news?
I... I imagine Craig was pretty upset.
Yeah, he was sad.
Sad in what way?
He was crying.
You actually physically saw
him crying? What did you see?
His face was red, he had...
...water coming out of his eyes
and he was rubbing them.
How was he rubbing his eyes?
Um, just...
And, uh, what's taken place
after that?
Has he said anything or made
any comments that you can recall?
Oh, look, I致e been smoking
a fair bit lately
so my memory's pretty fucked.
But...
..don't know, I don't think so.
Is there anything else
you'd like to add
in regard to these matters
we've discussed here today?
No.
OK, we'll suspend the interview
right there.
Uh, Detective Norris and I
will be back in a tick.
You want a drink or anything?
No.
- Orange juice or something?
- No, thanks.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Have you forgotten about Baz,
have you?
Who's been looking after you?
Who's been giving you money?
Huh? Me and Baz have. That's who.
And what does Craig give you?
He's making a fortune.
How much does he give you?
Craig bought me my flat.
Nuh.
Nuh. You don't own it.
He just lets you live there.
What is it you think
you've done for Baz?
You think Baz gives two hoots
for what you've gone and done?
Thanks, love.
- Can we have the bill, please?
- Sure.
He's dead.
I know you care, honey.
But don't you go thinking you care in
a special way like nobody else does.
- (MOBILE PHONE BUZZES)
- DARREN: Craig's here.
Hey.
Maybe you should start
taking your pills again.
Hmm?
(SIGHS)
What the fuck? Hey?
What were they doing there so quick?
They know who Baz's friends are.
- Fuck!
- Keep your voice down.
Mate, if they knew something,
we'd still be in there.
They want to talk to you too, hon.
You should call Ezra
and take yourself in tomorrow.
I知 not going in there.
Are you fucking nuts?
If you don't, they'll think
you've got something to hide.
I fucking do! I知 not going in there.
They'll come looking for you
if you don't, sweetheart.
Calm down.
CRAIG: (SIGHS) Fuck.
Where's J?
CRAIG: Where is J?
- Is he still in there?
- I don't know.
What's he saying?
I don't know, OK? Calm down, Craig.
If he's not talking,
what are they still talking about?
- Where is he?
- How the fuck should I know?
Like I知 supposed
to know where he is.
CRAIG: Oh, fuck.
Um, could I help?
Yeah, you could get
the, um, knives and forks.
(TV PLAYS IN BACKGROUND)
So how was your day today?
It was OK.
How was yours?
It was good.
Dinner's ready.
You can take those.
(TV SOUND IS MUTED)
How was your friend's...funeral?
It was OK, you know.
Sad and everything.
Yeah. We saw it on the news.
Hey, buddy. Mwah!
Where have you been, Nicole?
Detention. I told you.
- No, you didn't.
- Yeah, I did.
- You had to sign that form.
- I signed the form.
Oh, yeah.
Well, then, get angry at him
for not telling you.
I can't be having to tell you
everything all the time...
(SOLEMN MUSIC)
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
- ALICIA: J. Are you in there?
Yep.
Your uncle's at the door.
I知 coming.
What'd you let me fall asleep for?
Mmm, I fell asleep.
Yeah.
Hey, um, we gotta go.
Alright.
It was nice to meet you.
- See you.
- Hey, Daz.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I do a lot for you, Nick.
You're still at school
and you're allowed to have
your boyfriend sleep over.
That's a...big thing for me.
Where are we going?
DARREN: To see our lawyer.
(STARTS ENGINE)
This is really fucking important, mate.
I need to know word for word.
You know?
They just kept asking me
a couple of questions.
I said, 的 don't know,
and then they let me go.
DARREN: Well, what were you
doing in there so long?
Nothing. They just sat me in there
with no-one coming in or anything.
EZRA: That's good. That's OK.
Now, I want you to listen
very carefully.
From now on, mate,
you don't say anything,
and that means nothing at all.
You don't say, 的 don't know.
You don't say, 的 was sleeping.
You just refuse to answer
any of their questions, OK?
By law, these cunts
can't make you say anything.
You don't even
have to give your name, OK?
Now, this is very important.
Don't let them push you around.
You just sit there in silence,
at least, you know, till I get there.
This goes for you with your
girlfriend too. What's her name?
- (MUMBLES) Nicole.
- Cole?
- Nicole.
This goes for you with Nicole too.
Now, there's certain things
you just don't...you don't
talk to girls about, you know?
It doesn't matter
how special they are
or what you have and haven't done.
Girls, they get frightened.
They...they natter.
They can't help it.
It's just the way the world is.
There's not really much
to understand about this
except...
..you shut up.
Are you clear with all that, honey?
Yep.
There's nothing to worry about.
Hey, do you want a cold drink?
I've got lots of different
kinds of drinks.
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
(POLICEMEN CHAT INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, mate. Um, just that petrol.
Number two, mate? $44:50:
Ta.
(CASH REGISTER WHIRRS
AND DINGS)
(COINS JINGLE)
- Thanks, mate.
- Thanks.
(DOGS BARK)
(GUNSHOT)
- (GUNSHOT)
- CRAIG: Whoo!
Fuckin' monster!
- It's a nice gun, Rich.
- Yeah.
- Can we go hunting?
- Yeah, maybe, mate.
I've got a few things I gotta do.
Look, can you just not blow holes
in me silo?
CRAIG: It's fucked. It's written off.
(GUNSHOT)
RICH: So how long were you
wanting to stay?
And where's Kelly?
We split up, mate. Ages ago.
Don't worry.
You know, it's mutual
and everything, so...
It's for the best.
(SCANNER STATIC)
Fuckin' piece of shit!
You OK, mate?
What's with the scanner?
I値l fight through, mate. You know?
I値l fight through.
Look, um, I知 just thinking
it's only fair
if you're gonna be hanging
here for a while,
it's only fair you tell us
what this is about.
Is that fair?
I don't know what's going on, Rich.
I don't know what's going on, mate.
(DOGS BARK OUTSIDE)
- Can you hear that?
- Hear what?
(DOGS BARK ON SCANNER)
I can hear your fuckin' dogs.
(QUIET, SOLEMN MUSIC)
What's going on?
I don't know. I don't know.
WOMAN: Tell him he can't stay here.
I can't tell him nothin', love. Just...
Cunt motherfuckers!
What's that, Rich? What's that?
- I don't know. What is it, mate?
- It's a bug!
There's a fucking bug on your house.
I don't know about it.
How can there be a bug on your house
24 hours after I told you
I知 coming, huh?
They're probably bugging
your phone, mate.
I don't know. I知 not lying to you.
Fuck.
What am I gonna do now, mate?
I don't know, mate.
Maybe it's just best you leave, eh?
Yeah. OK. Alright.
Yeah, I gotta go, OK?
I値l go.
I値l go, yeah?
- You'll be alright, mate.
- Yeah.
Did I bring anything else?
(MUSIC BUILDS)
Shit.
(WHIMPERS)
(COCKATOOS SCREECH)
(EMOTIVE MUSIC BUILDS)
(GRUNTS)
- (GUNSHOT)
- Agh!
(GUNSHOT)
(SOMBRE MUSIC)
LECKIE: What did you tell her?
SARAH: I said you might be there
or you might not.
That's the way. Spin it round.
Wha-hey! Wha-hey.
Well, I reckon there's more chance
of me not being there at the moment.
SARAH: Oh, well, she'll get over it.
(PHONE RINGS)
- Is it up there somewhere?
- Yeah.
G'day, mate.
NORRIS: (ON PHONE)
Craig Cody's gone, mate.
Oh, what do you mean?
We've had to drop him.
He found the listening device
In Bendigo.
He sounded unhinged
so they went in to apprehend him.
He lost the plot. Had to drop him.
Why didn't anyone call me?
I would've got the soggies up there.
There was no time for that, mate.
He just lost the plot.
Alright, give me a sec to think.
SMURF: (TEARFULLY) I知 having
trouble trying to find my positive spin.
I知 usually very good at it.
Usually it's right there
and I can just have it.
But I知 having trouble finding it now.
(SOBS)
POPE: I don't know why.
People just don't listen, do they?
You know, if you hadn't
have got in his ear, Mum,
about turning himself in,
there'd be none of this shit,
none of this carry-on.
Did you think about that? Did you?
Fuckin' gone and spooked him.
Now look what's fuckin' happened.
(SMURF GRUNTS)
Stop hitting me! I didn't kill him.
I thought that's what we did.
We take it out on whoever turns up.
Don't, alright?
- J: Leave her alone.
- I知 alright, J.
Just...just relax.
- Come here, mate.
- Don't you touch him.
- Come here.
- J: Relax.
- Come here, you little...
- SMURF: Don't you touch him!
G'day, Josh. I've got
some bad news, mate.
Yeah, he knows the bad news.
LECKIE: Is everything OK here?
Yeah. Everything's great.
You alright, mate?
He's fine, Mr Leckie.
Josh, I'd like you to come down to
St Kilda Road with me, if that's OK.
Hey, what's he done? Tell me.
I値l make sure he gets disciplined.
Will you come with me, Josh?
What do you want to talk to him about?
Talk to me about it.
We'll speak to you again
at a later time when we're ready.
I might, um...might have
some information for you
about those two murdered police.
I've been asking around a bit
and there's a few theories
floating around
but I don't know
if any of them are true or not
but might be able to help you
with your investigations.
Oh, thanks for that.
Will you come with me, Josh?
You go, love.
I値l call Ezra.
Go put your shoes on.
I知 not currently in a position
to discuss what happened today
but I can arrange for
counselling services to visit,
should you require any.
Hope you find the killers.
Yeah, so do I.
You know you're not alone, right?
We'll get you through this, mate.
OK?
LECKIE: This is a record
of interview between
Detective Senior Sergeant Nathan
Leckie and Joshua Daniel Cody.
Present is solicitor Ezra White.
Now, I値l remind you again, Josh.
You're under no obligation
to say anything at this point in time
but anything you do say
can be used as evidence
in any future court appearances.
- You understand that?
- Yes, he understands that.
OK.
OK, now, picking up where we left off
when we last spoke,
you were telling us
how upset your uncles were
over the death of Barry Brown.
Can you remember what was said
or any...any comments that were made
at that time exactly?
Josh, has Mr White
provided you with advice
in respect to how you should conduct
yourself in this interview today?
Yes, he'll be remaining mute.
OK, I can appreciate you've been
advised not to say anything to me,
but the sooner you help us
with our inquiries,
the sooner we can scratch you off
the list and move onto a different line.
You do understand that, don't you?
Nothing else you want to say
at this point?
There wasn't a good
feeling in the room.
Leckie was running the whole
添esterday you were
very helpful routine.
That was probably for my benefit.
But I don't know.
Look, he's just a kid.
Kids are stupid, they're weak.
He may think he's doing
the right thing
but really, you know,
his foot's covered in dog shit
and he's got it stuck
right in his mouth.
I知 pretty surprised you let him get
anywhere near to you, to be honest.
- I told you to go get that car.
- No, you didn't.
- I told you to go get the car.
- No, you didn't!
You never fuckin' mentioned it
to me once, Pope!
EZRA: I don't want to hear this.
You've just gotta be worried
about what he's doing.
DARREN: He's a big kid.
He can look after himself.
EZRA: Can he, now?
Can he handle police?
It's a totally different
kettle of fish.
What should we do?
I'd start by keeping an eagle eye
on him, that's for sure.
Where is he now?
He's in his room with his girlfriend.
Is he? What's she doing here?
- Really?
- (GIRL TALKS INDISTINCTLY)
Yeah, well, we'll do it anyway.
Yeah, cool.
OK. Well, call me back.
EZRA: Is he talking to her?
DARREN: How should I know?
EZRA: Mate, I can't help you
with the how part.
You've just gotta be looking out
for this shit, you know?
What? So he's my responsibility now?
I値l call you tomorrow.
(DOOR OPENS)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- This is bullshit.
Well, you know I知 not
fucking telling them anything.
Mate, the cops are serious
about this thing, J.
And they're onto you like a rash.
So if you just stick close by,
everyone will keep calm.
- What am I supposed to do?
- How the fuck should I know?
Go in your room
and do some colouring in.
NICKY: I致e gotta go get him. Yeah.
- Hey, J, Danielle wants to...
- Can you give us a minute here?
- Why? What's going on?
- Don't be a stickybeak. Just...
Danielle just wants to talk to you
for a sec.
I値l talk to her in a minute.
Look, mate, I don't know if you
want to hear this or not but...
.. I would think pretty hard
about giving her the flick.
- I don't know what you have or...
- Haven't been telling her anything.
Life will be easier
if you just cut her loose, J.
Believe me.
She shouldn't be hanging
around here right now.
This has got nothing to do with me.
Mate, everything has
got to do with everyone.
Don't you fucking understand that?
Do you understand that, J?
- J, do...
- Yes!
Thank you.
Maybe it's just for a little while.
I just need some space and that.
For what?
Just some things I gotta do.
(BOWLING PINS CLATTER)
Do you love me?
Yeah.
Why?
'Cause you're nice.
Please don't get upset, Nicky.
(NICKY SNIFFLES)
G'day, Josh.
Oh, what the fuck...
We need to talk, mate.
No, we don't.
- Are you alright?
- She's fine.
Am i, fuckwit?
Oh, come on,
where are you going, Nicky?
Can you just go away?
We can either talk in here
or outside.
- There's nothing to talk about.
- I will arrest you if I have to.
- What for?
- Under-age drinking.
Oh, give me a fuckin' break.
You want me to make a scene?
(STARTS ENGINE)
(VIDEO GAME PLAYS)
- Hey.
- is J here?
No, J, he's...he's gone
down to the shops.
But, um, come in. Come and wait
for him if you want. He won't be long.
(TURNS OFF VIDEO GAME)
POPE: Have a seat.
Did he say how long he'd be?
Uh...no, he won't be long.
Where you been tonight?
Just down at the Zanoni.
Zanoni, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Anyone there you know?
Talk to anyone you know?
There was nobody there that I know.
Oh, well, I was about to
have a shot but, uh...
You want some?
What is it?
Oh, it's fun.
DARREN: No, she's just going home.
It's fun.
Have some.
POPE: Go ahead. Come on.
Put your arm out.
Come on.
There you go. That's it.
(SOFTLY) Now, there we go.
There we go.
You been talking to the cops?
What?
About what?
About anything.
Nuh. It's none of my business.
Yeah, yeah, it's your business,
isn't it?
When you're in love with someone
and you're whispering
sweet nothings in their ears.
Hey? Look at me. Look at me.
I got a call from someone
who told me that you've been
talking to the cops.
NICKY: What cops?
Oh, down at Zanoni's.
You can tell me.
You been talking to the cops?
Come here.
Come here, baby.
- DARREN: Fuck. Pope.
- (NICKY WHIMPERS)
Pope, what the fuck you doing?
What the fuck you doing, Pope?
Pope, what are you doing?
- (NICKY WHIMPERS)
- Pope!
Pope!
Pope, what are you doing?
DARREN: Please, Pope,
stop it, please.
Andrew, please.
Shhh. Shh.
Oh, fuck, Pope, what are you doing?
Shit, man.
What the fuck?
You've gone and done it again,
haven't you, Darren?
You've smoked yourself silly.
You think something's going on.
(CHILLING ELECTRONIC
SOUNDSCAPE)
(SOLEMN MUSIC)
Why'd you bring me here?
For your safety.
You want a sip of my drink?
What's the matter?
Are you scared?
Scared of me?
That can't feel too fuckin' good.
(DOOR OPENS)
Bananas.
Let's go sit outside for a bit, eh?
Just you and me.
You know what the bush is about?
It's about massive trees
that've been standing there
for thousands of years
and bugs that'll be dead
before the minute's out.
It's big trees and pissy little bugs.
And everything knows its place
in the scheme of things.
Everything...everything sits
in the order somewhere.
Things survive because they're strong
and...everything reaches
an understanding.
But not everything survives
because it's strong.
Some creatures are weak,
but they survive because they've
been protected by the strong,
for one reason or another.
You may think that because of the
circles that you move in or whatever
that you're one of
the strong creatures.
But you're not.
You're one of the weak ones.
That's nothing against you. You're
just weak because you're young.
But you've survived because you've
been protected by the strong.
But they're not strong anymore.
And they're certainly not
able to protect you.
We're here because we know who
you are and we know what you've done.
Now, I know you feel like
you're in a tough situation.
But you have an out.
There's nothing your uncles can do
to squirm out of this one.
Craig's learnt that the hard way.
But you're not like that.
We can see that.
And you know that.
Now, I know they're saying to you
that talking to me
is betraying the family.
But they've betrayed you.
The fact that you're talking to me,
the fact that you've been
left to deal with us...
...is all the proof that you need.
And you're in danger.
Don't be confused about that.
I think you know.
And I think you know
that I can help you.
But I can't keep offering.
You've got to decide.
You've got to work out where you fit.
I don't know why
you're telling me all of this.
Yes, you do.
OK, we're going home.
(MOODY ELECTRONIC MUSIC)
Justin, we're leaving, mate.
(DARK, PENSIVE MUSIC)
SMURF: You know, you can say
what you like about Craig,
but at least he was clean.
Hi, sweetie. Where you been?
J: Uh, just at Nicky's house.
Oh, yeah?
How is she?
Yeah, she's OK.
POPE: (ON PHONE) Hey. Yeah, it's me.
He's here. He's just walked in.
Fuck. Calm down, Darren.
(NICKY'S PHONE RINGS NEARBY)
(CHILLING MUSIC)
(EDGY MUSIC)
(DOOR OPENS)
SMURF: What's wrong, hon?
My fuckin' car keys.
Where the FUCK are my car keys?
(KEYS JINGLE)
Give us yours, mate.
I知 going to take your car.
What's that girl痴... Where...
That girl...
You know the girl -
what's her address?
- The fuck...
- SMURF: What's wrong?
Just tell me what's
her fuckin' address?
You went there the other day, mate.
Yeah, and I fuckin' forgot, didn't I?
Just tell me,
what's her fuckin' address?
(VIDEO GAME PLAYS)
Sorry.
Nicky's not here, J.
Is everything alright?
Yeah.
Was she with you last night?
Yeah, I think she went to stay
at Danielle's place.
I知 just gonna use the toilet,
if that's OK.
Yeah, sure. Fine.
(PHONE RINGS)
- Darren?
- J, you've got to get out.
Pope just left here in a bad way
and he's heading over there.
Well, how does he know where I am?
I don't know. Just get out, alright,
man? You've gotta get out, alright?
Just go, OK?
OK?
OK.
Hey, Gus, um, would you be able to
give me a lift somewhere, please?
Mate, I致e got a shitload of work
to do here. I知 sorry, mate.
It's just that I知 a bit late and
it's down near the shops and that.
Alright, just give us a moment.
You're gonna have to turn that off,
buddy.
Yep, we're gonna go for a ride.
Here, whack that on.
(TALKBACK RADIO PLAYS)
OK, this is the stuff.
This Vietnamese place
in Russell Street makes this.
Real chilli sauce. Smell that.
- Don't suck it in.
- (COUGHS)
Right, half a teaspoon of that, OK?
Keep the noodles on the stock
for another minute or so
and then pull them off.
Or just taste them.
You'll know when they're ready.
Then chuck the rest of the stuff in.
You should be right.
Yep. Do I keep stirring?
Yeah. Why not?
- See you later.
- Yep. See ya.
(SMURF SIGHS)
Ezra says don't get your hopes up
about the committal.
But he said he...
..there were strings he could pull.
They're all pulled.
How you keeping, hon?
Well, hold on, what did he say about
getting a bail application in?
Is he on this thing or what?
Darren, honey.
Say something.
POPE: Speak to her.
What's going on in here?
Will you speak to Mum,
you fuckin' sook?
What'd Ez say about whomping
the bail application in?
What do you think he said?
It's been whomped.
You're not getting bail.
What on earth made you think
you were gonna get bail?
What do you think you're in here for?
- Don't fuckin' start up again, Mum.
- Hey!
If you let anything
happen to him in here...
What?
What are you gonna do?
Huh?
What are you gonna do, Mum?
Darren?
Baby.
Better do something.
- Hi.
- Hello.
We gotta do something about J.
What do you mean?
He's got to go.
He's in witness protection, Janine.
You know what
witness protection means.
Here's the address
of where he's staying.
Get in the car.
You really want to go down this path?
We're still working on this.
Where did you get this?
I've been around a long time,
sweetie.
J's turned and he's not coming back.
Even if the boys get off,
I won't be seeing J again.
And I don't want Darren
to rot in that jail.
If my boys go down, that's it.
I got no-one left.
J's gone,
whatever happens.
We got to set up a meeting.
Is your office safe?
Look, I know you got a problem,
Janine.
But I don't see how
this mess your boys are in
has got anything to do with me.
So if you've called me in here to see
if there's some strings I can pull,
then you're way off course.
Is that what this is about?
Hey, Randall, before you go on,
this boy who's currently
being looked after -
tell me if you agree with this -
this boy who's being looked after,
he knows who you are.
And you know how these things go.
They're gonna ask him
all sorts of questions
about everything
he's ever seen or done.
Everyone he's ever met.
The whole shemozzle.
And you've done some bad things,
sweetie.
Haven't you?
I want this part to be clear.
This is not about you
doing me a favour
or...me blackmailing you,
anything like that.
It's just a bad situation
for everyone.
Ezra's got the address.
It shouldn't be too hard to set up
a raid on the house.
There'd be reasonable grounds,
what with all the strange activity,
the comings and goings day and night.
One of the neighbours might've seen
a gun or something.
This is your area of expertise.
I知 not trying to tell you
how to suck eggs.
What do you think?
I really don't see how
anything can be done, Janine.
Randall...
...I feel sick about this.
I知 not happy at all,
not one little bit.
But we do what we have to do.
We do what we must.
Just because we don't
want to do something
doesn't mean it can't be done.
(TV PLAYS)
Hey!
They're cops.
Jesus Christ, what the fuck
are cops doing here?
Who says they're cops?
'Cause they're wearing fucking
flak jackets, it makes them cops?
- Who else would it be?
- I don't fuckin' know.
They're wearing flak jackets with
fuckin' 'Police' written on them.
- So what do we do?
- We surrender. There's six of them.
- I知 not taking them head-on, mate.
- They're fuckin' cops!
I don't care who they are, mate.
I知 not fighting a war.
I知 not fighting a war
over some fuckwit kid!
Fuck that! I値l shoot him myself.
What are we gonna do?
I don't fuckin' know what we're
gonna do. What are you gonna do?
That's it. I知 done.
What?
Oh... Fuck!
- (HAMMERING ON DOOR)
- Police! Open up!
Open the fucking door! Open the door
or we'll bust it down.
- MAN: We're witness protection.
- ROACHE: Fuck.
POLICEMAN: Don't fuck around.
Open it now!
- MAN: Alright. OK. OK.
- ROACHE: Oh, fuck.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Shit.
You'd think the executives
at that station,
they need a new host for their show,
they could find someone
with straighter teeth.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
I don't mind his personality
but his mouth's so off-putting.
Oh, my goodness.
I need to talk to you.
- What you doing here?
- Is there anyone inside?
Just my neighbour Helen, love.
I wanna get Pope out of jail.
I can't live like this.
Of course, dear.
I want to set up a meeting with Ezra
and that barrister
from the committal.
OK. Of course.
I don't trust Ezra
so I知 not going to anyone's house.
It has to be somewhere public.
But it also has to be somewhere
no-one we know would go.
OK, honey. OK.
Mate, if you really
want to help the boys,
coming home is the thing to do.
I知 not coming home.
I知 not safe there.
Yes, you are, dear.
No, I知 not.
I知 not safe in witness protection
either,
but I壇 rather take my chances there.
You'll be safe at home, honey.
You can't promise me that.
I can. I can.
I知 not coming home.
I知 going back there.
I知 just letting you all know
that I知 here to help.
I think J's made his position clear.
Where that leaves us now
is to decide how best to proceed,
given the brave offer
of assistance he's made.
You know, this thing's going to trial
with or without J, that's a given.
What we want is to win it.
You know what I liked
about the committal hearing?
Despite the fact that we've been
ordered to stand trial, of course.
But what I liked about the committal
was that for the most part,
their case looked
pretty flimsy to me.
Largely dependent
on witness testimony
that shouldn't be too hard to
discredit, I wouldn't have thought.
And if the committal痴 any indicator,
then J here's their star witness.
Without him, they'll need
to strengthen their brief,
which they will do
with something else.
Personally, I壇 rather tackle
the evidence I saw at the committal
than any rejigged brief
they come up with
should J suddenly decide to leave.
You know what I mean?
So I think we should
just get into it.
There's a bunch of things
we'll need to go through...
Come with me.
- Where have you been?
- Hiding.
You shouldn't have left the house.
Where did you go?
I was hiding.
It was the Drug Squad
who raided the house today.
OK? They'd been told
something funny was going on here.
It was just a fuckin' mix-up.
Now, you're not in any danger,
alright?
I need you to understand that.
- OK?
- OK.
Did anybody see you out there today?
No.
OK.
You alright?
I知 fine.
I think courtrooms make everyone
feel a little bit nervous.
You ready?
(SOLEMN MUSIC)
- (MAN SPEAKS ON POLICE RADIO)
- Coming down.
Your girlfriend, Nicole,
died from a heroin overdose.
- Is this true?
- Yes.
And is it true you believe your
uncles were responsible for this?
- Yes.
- How?
They injected her.
Maybe don't rush your answers.
The more hesitant you are,
the more uncertain you'll appear, OK?
How's he gonna remember all this?
He doesn't need to.
It's better if he doesn't.
We don't want him reciting lines.
He just needs to get into
the swing of it,
wrap his head around
the flavour of it.
Do you understand that, J?
So you're saying
they forcibly injected her
with what's known as a 'hot shot'.
Yes.
- Did you see them do it?
- No.
Was she known to you
to be a user of heroin?
Sometimes, yeah.
Was she? This is me talking now.
No.
Then say no. You don't need to lie.
Was there any reason why
on this particular night
she might have wanted to use heroin?
Maybe.
Why maybe?
I broke up with her.
- That night?
- Yeah.
So to some extent you feel
responsible for Nicole's death.
I don't know, maybe to an extent.
But you want your uncles
put away for it,
even though you didn't see them do it
and she was justifiably upset
on this night
because you had ended
the relationship.
You're looking for someone to blame
for something
you feel responsible for.
Would you agree with that?
Blah, blah, blah.
It's good.
- You feel OK?
- You OK, sweetheart?
Yeah, I知 fine. Can you go grab us
a drink or something?
Of course.
There must be a drink machine
around here somewhere.
(GUN CLICKS)
Have you worked out where you fit?
SMURF: That's all due to this trauma.
Now, my family痴 been dragged
through the mud over this.
And that kind of action
plays heavy on your mind.
You know, the police go off
on a tangent, fly off the handle,
and...wee young kid like J
gets the idea
you can't even trust
the law to work properly.
The justice system, yeah?
REPORTER: Um, OK.
Alright. Maybe that's enough of that.
Uh, Andrew, I was hoping
to get some shots of you and Darren
reacting to the news
of your acquittal on the TV.
What?
So we'd shoot you guys
watching the TV
Like you're watching a news report
of yourselves, celebrating.
No, I知 not doing that.
I知 not a fuckin' monkey.
(PHONE CLATTERS)
(DIAL TONE BEEPS)
DARREN: Can I dial out from here?
No, these might be different.
They're OK? Alright.
Don't know that we need that, do we?
Hi.
I just want you to know I don't
bear you any ill will, Mr Leckie.
I really don't.
You were just doing your job.
I hope you catch the people
who did that terrible thing.
If you're as smart
as I think you are,
you'd know to walk right on by me
Like we've never seen each other
before in our lives,
and you'd know to feel lucky.
You'll come unstuck.
I've got a feeling about it.
I think you do too.
I reckon you probably carry
that feeling around with you
every second of the day.
But I don't, Nathan.
(BIRDS CALL)
('APRIL SUN IN CUBA' BY DRAGON
PLAYS)
J: Hey, Grandma.
(GASPS)
I was wondering
when I壇 see you again.
Been missing ya.
You OK?
Yeah, I知 OK.
Um, is it OK if I move back here?
I don't really know where else to go.
Course.
You want food? You look Biafran.
No, thanks.
I think I want to go lie down
for a bit.
You don't want to eat?
Pope's cookin'.
No, thanks.
OK, sweetie.
Your room's still there.
I've missed you.
Say hi to the guys.
POPE: You know what I mean?
It doesn't do anything.
Doesn't cook anything, you know.
Hey.
Hey, mate.
('APRIL SUN IN CUBA'
CONTINUES PLAYING)
You hungry?
No. I just came out to say hi.
I知 gonna go lie down for a bit.
Alright, mate.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hmm.
It's a crazy fuckin' world.
(GUNSHOT)
(SLOW, POIGNANT MUSIC)
(END CREDIT MUSIC)