[HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING]
In accordance with the regulations
of the state of Mississippi,
we gather today
to lay to rest
the remains of inmates
R. Gibson, number 4316,
and C. Banks,
number 4317.
Ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
May God have
mercy on their souls.
Amen.
You can go
ahead, fellas.
Look like you
finally free now, boys.
Finally free.
Friends of yours, old-timer?
Well, let's just say
we spent some time together.
Now, why do I
get the feeling
when you say "some time,"
you mean "some time"?
I'd been here a good
while when they come.
They come here,
must've been 1932.
Ah, man!
Shit, that's like...
Wait a minute.
That's 65 years, son.
Shit.
Didn't they burn up
in that fire yesterday?
Listen, man,
I seen them niggers
before they
put them in the box.
And when I tell you, them
niggers, they was bacon burnt,
shit, it was like some shit
from the X Files, man.
What you got in that bottle
anyway there, old-timer?
This is
Rayford's special recipe.
See, he had
what we call
"exacting standards"
when it come to the hooch.
So, what were they,
bootleggers?
Something like that.
[BAND PLAYING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Hank, my man,
how you doing?
Oh, no.
Not tonight, Ray.
Spanky's not
happy with you.
Is Span Ky here?
Do yourself a favor
and find another place
where they let you
in the front door.
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
What about that time I bought your
girl them alligator shoes, man?
What's the problem? Did
I come through for you?
Yeah, yeah.
Bitch was wearing
pigskin when I met her.
I got her out of the swine.
She's wearing alligator.
Let me in.
Help a nigger out.
There you go. That's how it goes, brother.
That's how it goes.
Thank you, man. I appreciate it.
Appreciate it, man.
How does this tie look? Looking sharp.
Looking sharp.
Yeah, I feel lucky
tonight, too.
Yeah!
Here's to your new job
down at the bank.
Thank you.
I always knew you'd make
something of yourself.
You know what I'm gonna buy
with my first paycheck?
What, baby?
Season tickets to the Yankees, right
there, on the first base line.
What's wrong, baby?
I was hoping you were gonna say
an engagement ring, Claude.
Engagement ring?
That's what
respectable folks do.
Get a job, get married,
start having babies.
That's what you want,
isn't it?
Baby, I just don't
see no reason
to rush into things,
that's all.
Look, I got to clean this. I'll
be right back, baby. All right?
[PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
Good evening, sir.
Hello. Can I have
a towel, please?
Of course.
Oh. Look at this.
Hey, now, there ain't no reason to get violent.
Look, I tried to call.
Sit your ass down.
Congratulations, Claude.
We understand you finally
got yourself a job.
Yeah. Now you can pay Mr. Riley
that 50 bucks
you owe him.
Look, fellas, I got
a bill to pay out there.
Lookie here, $22.
Not bad for a start.
Not bad.
That's two weeks' pay, man.
I'm here with my girl.
You gotta
leave me something.
How about your legs?
My legs?
Oh, those are good.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, yeah, that's good.
I'll keep the legs,
you know.
Oh, excuse me. Sorry.
How'd he get in here?
Evening.
ATTENDANT: Evening.
CLAUDE:
Always messing with me.
Um, you got any of
that French shit?
Yeah, bro. Here.
Yeah, that's the one.
That's the one there.
Yeah. Thanks, man.
All right.
I smell French?
Yeah, that's it.
Yeah. Here, you keep the change.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hey, don't I know you?
I don't think so.
Yes, I do. I know you.
What is your name?
Claude Banks.
Claude Banks!
Claude Banks, hey,
it's me, Ray Gibson.
We went to high school together.
How you doing, man?
You went to Monroe?
Monroe.
Yes, definitely.
How you doing, man?
Look at you,
looking all sharp.
Make me feel good to see colored
folks doing good for themselves.
Yeah, well,
I went to Jefferson,
so you must have a different
Claude Banks in mind.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, man.
My mistake.
Yeah.
[MUSIC CONTINUES]
Hey, you wearing
that dress!
Whoo!
Hey, Isaac,
what's going on, man?
This is about my tab, huh? Don't
worry about it, I got it covered.
Man, it's hot in here tonight.
Hot.
This ain't
about your tab, Ray.
You got bigger
problems than that.
Hold up one second.
I had...
You should've never ran numbers
on Spanky's side of Broadway.
Let's go.
But I really think we
gotta get out of here.
Excuse me,
sir, your bill.
The bill? Oh, yeah,
yeah, of course, the bill.
How can I forget the bill?
Such an incredibly large bill.
[MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
Just tell me where
you want me to go.
Get over here.
Get over there.
RAYFORD: You done
took my ankle.
All right,
that's not nice.
Yeah, right.
What do you think
they're gonna do to us?
I don't know. What'd you
do, dine and ditch?
Over 10 bucks?
Yeah.
Probably just looking at
a thumb or something.
Who is he, Ray?
Friend of yours?
I never met this man
before tonight.
Okay? He's a lowlife that
hangs around in bathrooms
pickpocketing people.
Me? I'm a professional man.
Now, I got a job
that starts on Monday.
I'll pay you back with my first
paycheck, with interest.
I don't wanna tell you
how to run your business here,
but if you cut off my fingers,
you won't get nothing.
Working on adding machines, I
got to be whole. Ching-ching.
You know, you can understand that.
I need these for praying.
Drop him.
Wait, what does
"drop him" mean?
MAN: Time for a little dip.
What do you mean, "Drop him"?
Now this ain't the way
you treat somebody.
Hey, Spanky, you know, you ain't
got to do that to that guy.
You don't have to drown him.
He's a square.
He didn't know who
he was fucking with.
Oh, no! Man, it's
filthy down there.
Oh! Damn, there's a rat.
Man, I hate rats.
But you do. What does
that say about you, Ray?
What does that
say about me, Ray?
Spank, look,
I'm just trying to get by.
Man, you remember
what it was like
when you first
started out, Spank.
Come on now.
Nigger, please.
Hey, Spank, wait a second. Hold on.
Hold on. Wait a second.
Look. Look. I want you to see this.
Look at this. Check this out.
I got access to that.
What is that, Ray?
Some more of
your bathtub brew?
Hell, no, Spanks, this come
up from the Mississippi, man.
I can get a lot
more of that, too.
I was thinking about going
into business for myself.
Under present circumstances, I
think I may take on a partner.
What you say?
I was supposed to
wear this suit on Monday!
RAYFORD: Spank?
Oh!
If you give me the front
money and a truck...
Listen to me now. I think I can get
down there in two or three days,
as long as I have somebody
to help me do the driving.
[CLAUDE SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
CLAUDE: Come on, now! All right,
now I'm really getting angry.
Come on, Spank.
I'm gonna tell
you something, Ray.
You fuck me on this, I'll
spare no expense on your ass.
I understand. I understand.
Do you hear me?
I hear you, Spank.
You got a deal.
All right, okay.
Pick a man and get
the fuck out of here.
RAYFORD: Spank, with all due
respect to you gentlemen,
I think I'm gonna just take the
choirboy down there, Spank.
You got to be crazy.
If I'm gonna pick somebody, at
least I'm gonna pick somebody
who gonna be able to watch
my back in a tight squeeze.
I just wanna be with somebody that
ain't gonna put a bullet in my head
once the truck is full.
Lift him.
But not that you would do
something like that...
Lift him!
You know what
I mean, Spank.
Okay.
There you go.
Sure he
ain't dead, Spank?
Sure hope you can drive.
RAYFORD: I'll tell you what though,
this little rum run we're doing
is gonna really improve my relationship
with Spanky, I'll tell you that.
He's a good man to
have on your side.
He got
the capital connections.
That's what you got to have in this
business, capital connections.
I'm gonna get me
the connections.
I ain't got no capital yet,
but I'm gonna get some.
I'm gonna get the connections,
then I'm gonna have my own place.
Don't get me wrong,
I like Spanky's,
but I'm gonna
have my own place.
Yeah. Get this.
I'm gonna call my place,
check this out,
Ray's Boom-Boom Room.
Don't that sound
like something?
Don't that sound like
a place where it's fun?
Sounds exciting.
Ray's Boom-Boom Room.
Yeah, I like that.
Hey, man, if you heard there was a
place called the Boom-Boom Room,
wouldn't you
wanna check it out?
Hell, yeah! Hell, yeah, you'd want to.
Shit, yeah, you'd want to.
Whoo!
The Boom-Boom Room.
[CHUCKLES]
What you think?
Hey, you ain't said
nothing since we left.
I think the least you can do is give me
a little friendly conversation, boy.
I don't want
a friendly conversation.
I don't want to
be your friend.
I just want to do this thing and get back
to New York in time to start my job.
And what the hell
kind of job you got?
Well, if you must know, bank teller
at First Federal of Manhattan.
[CHUCKLES]
What's so funny?
Oh, I was laughing at myself, man.
Excuse me.
No, you found something very amusing.
What's so funny?
I don't know,
it's just, bank teller
just sound like
ladies' work to me.
It's something I always
pictured a woman doing.
Maybe I should dig around in other
people's pockets for money.
It's obviously been
highly successful for you.
Hey, you'd be surprised what you
find in other people's pockets.
Besides, I ain't never
heard of no man
setting out to
be no bank teller.
That's for damn shame.
This time next year,
I'll be a loan officer.
If I want to get
some frog skins
and come down to
the bank to get a loan,
I gotta come down and deal with a
tight-ass son of a bitch like you?
That's right.
Well, how do I
get a loan?
You? Yes, me. What's, "You?"
What is that shit? Why can't it be?
I can't get no money?
You need collateral.
What, you think I
ain't got collateral?
I have... Look at this. What about this here?
Look at that. Huh?
That thing?
Who'd you steal it from?
I ain't steal that. My daddy give
me that watch. Look at that.
[MUSIC PLAYS ON WATCH] Yeah,
well, who'd he steal it from?
Hey, you watch your mouth what you
say about my daddy. My daddy's dead.
You say whatever you
want to say about me,
but you can't drag
my daddy into it.
This watch is
sterling silver.
It's top-shelf,
top of the line,
and it's very near and
dear to my heart,
so no wisecracks about it,
or I'll whup your ass.
Looks like a fake to me.
Loan denied.
Hey, you know something, Claude?
Fuck you.
I'm gonna take
my business elsewhere.
And for future references, you will not
be welcome at Ray's Boom-Boom Room.
There's no
Boom-Boom Room.
When there is one.
When there is
a Boom-Boom Room,
don't come down to the motherfucker,
'cause you ain't getting in.
[SNIFFING]
Smell that?
Yeah, I smell something.
Smells good, right?
Yeah, you know, I think maybe
we should go to another place.
The ambiance ain't
really very welcoming.
Are you kidding?
Tell me you don't want
one of these pies
right here, Ray.
Right over here.
Them pies look good, Claude, but
I kind of lost my appetite.
When I came in here,
my appetite just left me.
Good afternoon, Billy.
Uh, we'd like some coffee
and a couple slices of pie.
How do you know
my name is Billy?
Well, it says it
right there on your shirt.
If you boys can
read so good,
how come you missed that
sign on the door over there?
Oh, that sign on
the door that we just...
How come we
didn't see that sign
that say "No Coloreds
Allowed," Claude?
We just rushed in. We was really
hungry, so we kind of missed that.
But we see it now, so bye.
Come on, man.
Look, ma'am, we've been
traveling all day.
Yeah, let's go.
All we want is some coffee and a couple
slices of pie. Is that all right?
No. These are
whites-only pies.
Well, do you have
any Negro pies?
Hey, Claude,
come on, now.
This woman ain't got the
recipe to no Negro pie.
Where would she
get that recipe?
At another establishment
we can get us some pies.
How far to the next town?
Thirty-five miles.
Hey, come on,
let's get out of here.
I'm not driving
no 35 miles
to get no pie.
Lady! Ma'am!
Okay? Now we want some pie, okay?
We are hungry. Okay?
Billy, we want some pie.
Let me
take care of this.
Why does somebody
got to die
'cause we want some pie?
Let me take care of them.
Look here.
Look, we're from New York.
My name Ray Gibson, okay?
Let's talk turkey.
How much it gonna cost
to turn one of them white-only
pies into nigger pie?
How about I turn
y'all into nigger pie?
So you said about 35...
Thirty-five miles.
Maybe we find another
establishment down the road,
where we
won't have a problem.
Yeah, I didn't know white folks
so serious about pie down here.
Hey, we're looking for Slim.
You found him.
That's it, fellas. 36 cases
of Mississippi's finest.
Five bucks a case.
That's $180.
All right.
What do we got?
Come on. Pay the man.
Man, that music's hot. What
goes on down there, Slim?
That there's
Natchez-Under-The-Hill.
Really? Colored folks
welcome down there?
Green's the only color
that matters under the hill.
That right?
SLIM:
They got gambling, girls.
You boys ought
to check it out.
Maybe we will.
Nice doing
business with you, Slim.
Let's go down there, have
ourselves a little reward,
see what's shaking.
Reward?
Yes, a reward.
There's people down there
having a good time, man.
I wanna be one of them. Hey, man,
I want you to be one of them.
Let me tell you something. Listen to me.
Listen, listen.
Monday, you can go
be a bank teller.
But tonight you
are a bootlegger
with a truckload of
Mississippi's finest
and a fistful of cash.
That's gas money, Ray.
Come on. Think.
Man, you are incredible. Tell you what.
Here's two dollars.
You stay here and
watch the truck.
I'm gonna go have
myself a good time.
And I got the keys with me, in
case you want to leave a nigger
down here in the woods.
I know how you think,
you motherfucker you.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING]
All right. Yeah. This look like something here.
I can work it here.
Hey, Ray. Keep an eye on you. Make
sure you don't do nothing stupid.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
All right. Well, put a little
something on your step.
I don't want these farmers
to think I'm from around here.
They know the way I walk,
I ain't from around here.
Yeah, 'cause I'm
from New York City.
CLAUDE: How y'all doing?
What's up, country boy?
Cock-a-doodle-doo, nigger!
Tens over nines.
Oh!
I ain't never seen
you in here before.
That's 'cause I ain't never
been in here before.
My name's Sylvia.
What's your name?
Can't you remember
your own name?
I know it begins with a
Well, Mr. C.
How about buying a gal a drink?
Two bourbons.
I really shouldn't. I gotta keep
an eye on my friend over there.
He look like he can
take care of hisself.
[EXHALES]
[WHIMPERS]
Claude.
[LAUGHS]
That's my name, Claude.
You know that's never
happened to me before.
You're cute.
[CHUCKLING]
Thank you.
You got
any money, Claude?
Yeah, two dollars,
but I need that to get home.
What's wrong?
What you wanna
go home for?
It's so early.
I'll take one.
One for New York.
Thank you.
Me's want one.
Can I get that for you, sir?
Thank you, baby.
RAYFORD:
Give me a deuce.
Here you go, honey.
Thank you.
All right.
You all want to pick
up this country pace?
Bet's to you, sir.
Bet a dollar.
MAN 1: I sees that.
You "sees" that?
Well, I sees that dollar,
and I raise you two dollars.
Is "sees" a word?
All right now.
I'm out.
What? You going back to the farm now?
Pick your tomatoes?
I'll see the two.
And I raise you $10.
Damn. Out.
Well, Mr. Hancock, I don't
think I have any more money.
Big city boy.
[LAUGHS]
Well, that's too bad.
Now, hold on, now.
Just give me
two seconds.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
[SIGHS]
Top-shelf.
It look good to me. I think
that'll cover it. Call.
[SIGHS]
I got a full boat with
the ladies doing the paddling.
MAN 1: Mmm-mmm!
MAN 2: Whoo!
I don't think they come in
much stronger than that, sir.
Four threes.
What the fuck?
Goddamn.
MAN 1: Broke again.
New York, New York.
Don't take it too hard, New York.
Here, have a round on me.
Can I get you
something, sir?
No, I'm all right.
Hey. Hey!
What the fuck is this?
You're hurting my arm.
Where you going?
Come here.
Okay. No, no, no. Hell, no.
Hell, no! Hey, Hancock!
Hey. hey!
Oh, shit.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON WATCH]
[CHUCKLES]
My goodness.
If it isn't my old friend,
Winston Hancock.
I thought we agreed that
you was gonna leave town.
Well,
I was gonna leave,
Sheriff Pike,
but your wife,
she begged me to stay.
[LAUGHING]
[LAUGHS]
You just
committed suicide, boy.
Hey, Ray,
I've been looking for you.
Guess we better
get going, huh?
Yeah. You still
got that two dollars?
Uh.
Not exactly.
You see, I met this girl.
Real nice girl, Ray.
A God-fearing girl.
The same girl I seen
you over here with?
Yeah, she looked religious.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, well...
Yeah. So you gave
her the two dollars?
Yeah, well she was
in a tight spot.
Her mama needs
this operation.
She ain't have the money
for it, and so, hey,
she tell me the church
took up a collection,
but they still
were short, so I...
Two dollars short?
Yeah.
Yeah, so I gave it to her. You
know, when the spirit moves me...
I guess we both got fucked. While
you was upstairs doing God's work,
I was over there
getting jack-legged
by one of these
fucking farmers
and one of these
goddamn waitresses.
I know the bitch is
in here somewhere.
They beat me down
to my goddamn socks.
You lost all our money
in a card game, Ray?
Fuck the money. It's not
even about the money.
Fuck the money.
I lost my daddy's watch.
Man, fuck that
cheap-ass watch, man.
Oh, I apologize.
It gotta stop some...
You right.
One more again,
one more again, see that I take
all your fronts out, I swear.
See how you go
back to New York.
[WHISTLES] That's how you gonna be back
in the car, all the way back there.
I'm sorry.
Fuck that.
Say something about the watch, Claude.
Bring up the watch.
In fact, just bring up watch.
Ray...
Look like you was fixing to make
your mouth up to say "watch."
If I see you... I'm gonna whup your ass.
Ray, Ray...
In fact, don't even
say "watch" no more.
You can't say
"watch" around me.
Say "little clock"
or some shit.
You say watch,
I'm gonna just dive on you.
How are we supposed to get
home without any money?
We got 36 cases of booze.
That's better than money.
Oh, okay. So we gonna
drive home drunk.
Is that it? Come on! Let me
pay and get out of here.
Hey, where's that girl
that was working over here?
What girl?
"What girl?"
Next time I come
back in here,
whichever bitch I start
choking, that's what girl.
Come on, man.
Big-time hustler, came and got
girked by a couple of farmers.
I'm gonna tell you something, Claude.
Can that twitter.
I'm all shot, and I just
wanna get back to New York.
What makes you think...
Ray, Ray.
Oh, shit.
I think he's hurt
pretty bad, man.
Hey, man, this guy's dead.
I ain't never seen no
dead body before, Ray.
What are you doing?
The man's been dead two seconds,
and you're in his pocket?
Don't you have any respect?
It ain't here.
What ain't there?
My daddy's watch.
This is the guy that
took my watch from me.
You motherfucker,
you fucked around with
the wrong person, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Now look at your ass out here bleeding.
BILLY: Hey!
What you boys
doing out here?
Hey, how y'all doing?
Hi.
We're just taking care
of our friend here.
What's wrong
with this one?
Drink...
Yeah, he's just
a little drunk.
Nothing at all.
He's just a little drunk.
Nobody drink
like old...
Winston.
Winston, Winston, yeah.
Yeah, he's always drinking. Old
drunk-ass Winston always drinking.
This fella look
like he's dead.
Oh, no. No, no, not...
He's not dead. He's drunk.
He is too drunk.
CLAUDE: He likes to drink
until he pass out.
You know what'd
serve him right?
Just let him lay here
and sleep the shit off.
We gonna go. I'm gonna tell
his wife that we left him.
Let's go back to the car.
We gonna go...
I think you boys
better come with us.
MAN: That's right.
I think that... We're gonna
go to your car then.
Yeah, let's go.
Excuse me, Winston.
We're gonna go with
this gentleman here.
You know what, Ray?
You're responsible for this
whole situation. Yeah, yeah.
I blame you for everything, Ray.
Okay?
If it wasn't for you, man, I'd be home
right now about to have a hot meal.
If it wasn't for me,
your black ass would be
floating up on
a beach at Coney Island,
right now.
You forgot all that shit?
"I need all my finger and thumbs for
adding and..." You remember that shit?
I saved your life, nigger. They
think we killed somebody, Ray.
This is blood, okay?
Just shut up.
Listen.
Just sit your ass down. Let me
work some shit out with this...
I got a job
that starts Monday.
You're gonna
be late Monday,
'cause I got to work this
out, this whole thing.
Evening, boys.
Evening there, Sheriff.
Well, well, now.
What do we have here?
Billy Bob and the boys found them down
under the hill with Winston Hancock.
That's right.
He was dead.
Looks like murder.
Yeah.
Yep, it does.
Is that right?
Looks like they was running hooch.
Got 36 cases of evidence.
How about a little reward,
Billy Bob?
Well, thank you, sir.
Why bother with bootlegging when we
got us a clear-cut case of murder?
Hey, Sheriff Pike, like I told
your associate over there,
we didn't kill nobody.
The man was like
that when we found him.
He was out there dead.
He was already dead.
Now as far as
bootlegging goes,
well, I happen to work for a
very important man back east.
Yeah, yeah, does the name Spanky
Johnson mean anything to you?
Spanky Johnson?
No, I'm afraid not.
Hey, hey, Sheriff Pike.
Sheriff Pike, listen.
Listen.
This guy, Spanky Johnson,
is very well-connected.
Ooh!
Very well-connected. And if
you were to give us a break,
I can guarantee you, he would do
something to show his appreciation.
Now I'm sure.
[CHUCKLES] Mr. Pike.
I don't doubt that
you can buy your way
out of trouble
up in New York City,
but down here, we take
murder very seriously.
We didn't kill nobody.
I keep telling you, the man
was dead when we found him.
He was already dead.
CLAUDE: He's telling
the honest truth.
Now the liquor was ours.
That's our liquor.
There was no breath in him.
We're being truthful.
But that man's
being honest.
That was our liquor.
But the man was dead.
If that's the truth,
you boys don't have
anything to worry
about then, do you?
I guarantee it. I'll see
y'all in the morning.
You believe us, right? What time
you gonna be here in the morning?
Boys, don't drink all that
stuff tonight, you hear?
All right, Sheriff.
PIKE: See you in the morning.
Wait a minute.
He sounded like he
believed us, right, man?
The man's got a point.
We didn't kill nobody, Ray.
Hey, Claude, what about the
truckload of booze, man?
Man, that's Spanky's booze!
You know what?
Tomorrow,
I'm gonna tell that judge,
"Judge, we didn't
murder nobody.
"That was Spanky's booze."
What's the worst that can
happen to us, Ray? Huh?
Life!
What do you mean, "life"? Hell,
no, I ain't doing no life.
This is a mistrial!
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
I didn't even kill nobody. The
man was dead when I got there.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING]
DILLARD:
Welcome to Mississippi.
Here, you will be provided
with ample opportunity
to repay your debt to society
through the rigors of hard labor.
We got fields need clearing,
roads need building,
and ditches need digging.
You will eat only
what you can grow.
Your crop don't come in,
you go hungry.
This here is Camp 8.
Camp 8 is for incorrigibles.
But whatever you done
to get here,
believe me,
I'm not impressed.
I've seen it all before.
We ain't got no fences
here at Camp 8.
We don't need no fences.
We got us the gun line.
Tell them about
the gun line, boss.
This is the gun line.
It runs from shack to shack
clear around the yard.
You are now
inside the gun line.
You step outside the gun line without
my permission, you will be shot.
You trip and fall over the
gun line, you will be shot.
You spit, you pee,
you so much as stick your
Johnson out over the gun line,
you will be shot.
And you, Slick, don't try to
run, don't try to escape.
One of my trustees will put
a bullet in your head.
You prisoners are now the property
of the state of Mississippi,
which is to say
I own your ass.
[CHUCKLES]
And in case you haven't met
this handsome young fella,
this is Hoppin' Bob.
You run afoul of Bob,
you run afoul of me.
Everybody, shut up!
Right now.
I don't wanna hear a sound.
Got some fresh meat for you.
Right down there.
Take yourself right down
there, find your ass a bunk.
Move it.
Acting all scared.
We ain't got no wallflowers
here in Camp 8.
Don't y'all worry none.
Ain't nobody gonna
mess with you tonight.
That'd take all the fun
out of the courtship.
You hear me, boy?
WILLIE: I didn't see nothing special
the first time Ray and Claude
walked into the cage.
To me, they were just a couple
of fools whose luck had run out.
Course,
I was wrong about that.
I don't believe
this "before Abe" shit.
I didn't go to night
school to dig no ditch.
What the hell you doing? Don't do that.
I wouldn't do that shit.
Oh, man, shut up.
What do you know anyway?
Okay?
It's too damn hot.
Why ain't that
boy's pick swinging?
pick swinging?
Why ain't that
pick swinging, nigger?
It's too hot.
I'm tired, boss.
He said he's too hot, boss.
He's tired.
Too hot?
He's tired?
Uh-huh.
You tell that lazy jigaboo
the state of Mississippi
ain't interested in his
meteorological assessments!
Listen up, jigaboo!
The state of Mississippi
ain't interested in your...
Your, uh, "metacalogical"
assessments!
You tell him the state of
Mississippi is only interested
in getting this here ditch
cleared by sundown.
State of Mississippi wants this
here ditch cleared by sundown.
You got that, boy?
Got it, boss.
He don't sound like
he from around here.
He from New York City, boss.
That one there, too.
They'll find we do things
different down here.
Yeah, we noticed.
[GRUNTS]
Don't smart me, boy.
You just shut your mouth and do your work.
You got that?
[LAUGHS]
Looks like we got
a couple of live ones.
How long these boys in for?
The judge gave them
the long ride, boss.
Life, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, they step
out of line again,
we'll shorten up
that sentence real fast.
Get them picks a-swinging!
You heard me, New York Cities.
You don't want me
to come down there.
I ain't nice like Boss. I'll
slap the black off your ass.
Get to work!
Either one of you new
fellas know how to read?
I know how to read.
Why?
I've been carrying this
letter for four months now.
You mean to tell me,
none of y'all can read?
Last fella what could read made
parole, what, around Christmas.
I don't even know
who this come from.
Give me that.
You can't read?
Almost 60 years old,
motherfucker can't read.
Here. Look, it's from your
mama's neighbor, Mrs. Tadwell.
You know who
that is, Mrs. Tadwell?
She thought you ought to know
that your second cousin Bo died.
Bo died. And your other cousin,
Sally, on your daddy's side,
she died.
And apparently
your sister died, too.
Jenny?
No, it say Marleen here.
Marleen died.
Oh, no, no, no.
Marleen...
Jenny died, too.
Jenny and Marleen both dead.
Then it goes on
for a while about how
the crop didn't come in
on the account of the frost.
She finished up with...
There's been a big tornado,
in which your mama and your
daddy were both killed.
Well, don't worry, 'cause she
gonna take care of the dog.
That is, if he gets over the worms.
Dog had worms.
Appreciate it.
Yeah, you know,
anytime I can help out.
Anybody else got
something they want read?
No.
Can't blame y'all.
Hey, hey. hey,
how you doing?
I'm fine, thanks.
Good. First time in?
Nah, not at all.
I've been in and out
of prison, mostly in.
So you won't have
no problem adjusting?
Shouldn't have
a problem, no.
If you need anything of any
kind, give me a holler.
My name's Jangle Leg,
Jangle Leg.
I appreciate it.
Jangle Leg, you said?
Jangle Leg, Jangle Leg.
I'm Claude.
Claude.
Yeah, Claude.
Your hand nice and supple,
like a lady.
Jangle Leg!
What the hell I tell you about
pitching woo on the job, boy?
Sorry, Captain.
Story time is over.
All you sissies
get back to work right now.
Let's move it!
Now!
What the fuck?
Y'all heard the man,
get on line!
MAN: Let's go, boys!
He made a pass at me.
Yeah, I see.
Why do you think they
call him Jangle Leg?
You're gonna
find out before me.
Eyes front, mister.
Ain't nobody
doing nothing.
I'm hungry. What...
[SCRAPING BREAD]
See how you get that off?
Fuck that. You better eat,
and stop aggravating people.
I ain't
aggravating nobody.
You got nerve,
scraping toast and shit,
making excess noise.
Come on, Ray.
You're making a lot
of noise down there.
Look at this spoon,
man, it's filthy.
Filthy, ain't it? Fuck
that spoon, and just eat.
Be cool.
My name's Ray Gibson,
and this is Claude Banks.
Willie Long.
RAYFORD: Willie, huh?
Mmm.
Pretty sensible man.
What you up in here for?
It's a long story.
He killed son of a bitch with a claw
hammer when he was 13-year-old.
So they say. A lot of
people say it, though.
Wait a second. You been in
here since you were 13?
That's right.
How about you, boy?
How long you been in here?
What'd you do?
Son of a bitch chopped his
sister in the head with an ax.
She was my half-sister,
so I cuts her ass in half.
At least I ain't the one
who poisoned my own ma and pa.
Now tell that.
Tell that.
They deserved it, Radio.
What you talking about,
Biscuit?
You're the one that skinned
your landlady alive
and made a jacket
out of her.
Well, at least he
didn't kill Santa Claus.
Santa Claus? Which one of you
niggers killed Santa Claus?
It wasn't the Santa Claus.
He was just wearing the suit
and ringing a bell.
Damn, that's true.
RAYFORD: He had presents.
I ain't get nothing.
You killed one of
them Salvation men,
them dudes be out there
on the street with a bell?
Something like that.
That's what he did.
Anybody try to
escape from here?
They run,
but they never get too far.
Cookie there made it clear to
Greenville a couple of years back.
Take a mighty cagey
country boy to navigate
his way through
them wood and bayous.
Gotta know what you're doing.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, what y'all did?
Oh.
Uh...
What the fuck
y'all do?
Uh...
Well, we went on a...
Yeah, a violent killing spree.
The most violent, you know.
All around the country, we've been
killing people. All this month.
All month, man. If y'all was out
and was reading the papers...
You ain't heard about it?
Claude and Ray?
Fuck it. You know,
sometimes you got
to do certain shit.
It's just enough
that people know that
I go where I need
to go to get it done.
If you push my button, there's
no telling what I may do.
Stab you, choke you, bite you.
Yeah, don't give a fuck.
I mean, whatever it take to make
a motherfucker stop existing.
I will do that.
I wish this spoon was sharp,
I'd stab a nigger right now.
I bit one motherfucker to death.
You don't wanna fuck with us.
No, you don't really
wanna fuck with us.
Press the wrong button,
nigger pop.
Hey, girl. You gonna
eat your corn bread?
Oh, trouble.
JANGLE LEG:
Don't say nothing to him.
You talking to me?
Yeah, I think he's
talking to you.
Uh. No, not at all.
I want you to have it.
Willie, you mind
passing this down to...
Hey, no. Don't pass
your corn bread to him.
That's your corn bread.
Ray, I'm a grown man.
Okay?
I'm not gonna eat
this corn bread.
If he wants the corn bread,
damn it, have the corn bread.
If he wants some corn bread,
let him up to the front
and get his own
portion of corn bread.
That's your corn bread.
Fuck him.
Hey, man, he gonna eat his corn
bread, all right? Fuck you.
Ray, look, I don't need
you to take up for me.
I'm all right. I'm a grown man.
I can handle that.
If you let him
have your corn bread,
you're gonna be ironing his drawers
and clipping his toenails.
CLAUDE:
I ain't gonna be ironing.
Maybe I ought to
eat your corn bread.
Motherfucker, you can't have my
corn bread, that's for damn sure.
'Cause if you try to take my corn
bread, part two of my killing spree
gonna begin up in here
on your ass right now.
If you're thinking
about my corn bread,
better get the taste
out of your mouth.
That's for damn sure.
No, fuck him, fuck that.
'Cause I'm from New
York City, God damn it.
Nobody take
no corn bread from me.
That go for you and any other
of you motherfucking farmers
wanna try some shit.
You fuck around with me,
there's gonna be consequences
and repercussions.
ALL: Oh!
Get up!
Come on, New York!
Show that big son of a bitch how
y'all does it up in Harlem now, boy.
Come on!
[GRUNTING]
Come on, New York.
I appreciate you going through all
the trouble over my corn bread.
You don't get a lot of
compliments around here.
[GROWLS]
Get up! Get up!
Ray, I think you made your
point, whatever that is.
Now's a good time to throw in the
towel, you know what I'm saying?
Not over no
corn bread, man.
Goldmouth, I know a bitch named
Della hit harder than you.
That's it. The man's taken
enough of a beating.
Goldmouth, pick him up
and carry him on inside.
[WHISPERS] He ain't getting
my corn bread, Claude.
[GRUNTS]
You were scared, huh? Don't be scared.
Uh-uh. Don't be scared.
[SIGHS]
[SINGING]
Papa!
That's my boy.
Request permission to
go to the tonk, boss.
Conjugal visits are
for married prisoners only,
and I don't see
no wedding ring.
Can't you make an exception,
just this once?
I could issue a temporary marriage
license, for a nominal fee.
CLAUDE: Here you go.
Sure is pretty.
I now pronounce
you man and wife.
You go have a good time.
[CHUCKLES]
Claude Banks
going to the tonk!
heading for the tonk!
Mmm, mmm, mmm!
Lordy, Lordy, Lordy.
Come on, now.
Five cents.
MAN 1: That's right. That's a nickel apiece.
MAN 2: Want my money back...
Hey, New York. You ever been
to that there Cotton Club?
The Cotton Club in Manhattan?
Many times.
Man, I damn near
lived in the Cotton Club.
I tell you,
Cotton Club is all right,
but they ain't got nothing
on the Boom-Boom Room.
You ever go to New York,
go to Ray's Boom-Boom Room.
Hey, there, Ray, what is that you
talking about the Boom-Boom Room?
That's my spot.
Ray's Boom-Boom Room.
Most happening space
in all of Manhattan.
So you got
your own nightclub?
Right now it's kind of
in the development stages,
but I'm working on it.
I'm gonna get it.
So it don't exist?
It exists in my mind, Goldmouth.
That's where it start.
It start your brain first. You know,
it got to exist up here first.
As a man thinketh,
so shall he get.
Some shit like that. You
know, you read the Bible.
Did you go see
my cousin Melvin
like I asked you
to in my letter?
Of course I did. He said he'd
file an appeal right away.
Listen, Claude,
Melvin wanted to know
if he should file an appeal
on behalf of your friend, too.
Ray Gibson? No.
No. No. No.
No, Daisy.
He's the reason
I'm in here.
For all I know, he's got
a record a mile long.
I got a better shot of getting
out of here on my own.
You tell Melvin to think
about me, all right?
Just concentrate on me.
Claude.
Cookie made me
a map to Greenville.
So?
So, nigger,
you know what I'm saying.
Yeah, I know what you're saying.
And guess what
I'm saying.
If you made it that far,
they'd be checking
every train that
pulls out of that station.
We ain't taking the train.
There's a farm on the map.
Cookie told me
there's a boat on the farm.
What do you know about boats? You
probably don't even know how to swim.
I know a boat can help
sail our ass away from here.
Come on, nigger, we can do this shit.
Stop bullshitting.
Why are you always talking about "we"?
Say what?
There's no "we," Ray, okay?
There's a me, there's a you.
Why are you
talking so loud?
There ain't no "we"
between us.
Hey, Ray! Ray!
Yeah?
What's the name of that there
nightclub of yours again?
You talking about
the Boom-Boom Room?
Yeah, the Boom-Boom Room.
That's it. Boy, I'd sure
like to see that place
when you get it all up and
running and pretty-looking.
Yeah, me, too, Ray.
Me, too. I'd like to
see that room, too.
Yeah, I'll tell you what,
though, Radio.
You should've been
by there last night.
You'd have had
yourself some big fun.
What you talking about,
"There last night"?
Just like I said,
last night.
Satchmo was up in there and nearly
blew the roof off the place.
Ray, who that?
Satchmo.
You mean Louis...
Louis Armstrong?
Yeah, Satchmo, that's what I call him.
I know him personally.
Whenever he come by my spot,
I call him Satchmo,
and he come by
whenever he in town.
Hey, ain't nobody trying
to hear that bullshit, man.
Shut the fuck up, man!
Just shut up.
You always trying to say
something at the wrong time.
Let him finish, and do
whatever you got to do.
Go to sleep.
Let us have our fun.
Go ahead there, Ray. Finish
telling us about that Satchmo.
Go on. Tell me some more.
Go ahead, Ray.
Continue, Ray.
Damn!
As I was saying, last night
y'all should've come by, man.
Big fun. But y'all will never
guess who gonna be there tonight.
Who gonna be there, Ray?
Who that there?
Who?
Who that, Ray?
Just guess.
[SINGING]
You go, Biscuit.
Sing, girl.
That's right, fellas.
Catch any cab heading uptown
because all the drivers know
about Ray's Boom-Boom Room.
Hey, Ray!
Where am I?
Oh, come on, Goldmouth,
somebody's gotta watch the door.
Hey, Ray! Now I could get
used to this. Ladies.
Mmm!
Ray, this steak
tastes like butter.
Made it just
for you, Cookie.
You got some steak sauce?
Boy, get us some
Worcestershire sauce.
And clean off that damn table,
or I'll whup your ass.
Is something wrong with your ears?
Move it!
Hey, Ray! I know
your club got gambling.
Poker. Wouldn't be
a club without some dice.
Lucky seven! My man!
Let it ride!
All right,
Poker, letting it ride.
Yes!
Raid! Don't move!
Oh, shit!
Party's over.
Son of a bitch!
Goddamn! Party over.
Get the back door! Put all
the women in my car! Gibson!
You about ready to spend
the night in the hole, boy.
Now shut up and go to sleep.
You got that, boy?
Huh?
That goes for
the rest of you girls, too.
Now I don't wanna
hear another peep
about no fucking
Boom-Boom Room.
[FARTING]
Sorry, Captain.
Shut your mouth and
your fat ass, boy.
Don't be playing with yourselves.
You gotta work in the morning.
Come on, come on.
DILLARD:
Mail call!
MAN 1: That's mine.
MAN 2: You know, I
hate this part.
I'm gonna get back to that
game in a little while.
Craddock.
All right.
DILLARD: Williams!
BOB: Williams!
MAN: Williams!
Banks.
Right here.
"Melvin Banks,
Esquire, Attorney at Law"?
What's going on?
This don't concern you.
Excuse me.
DILLARD: M. Bay.
Oh, yeah,
obviously not.
CLAUDE: Yeah.
BOB: M. Bay.
Slow up, slow up.
You see me counting.
Go on. Come on.
This here is Biscuit.
This is New York City One.
DILLARD: All right, let's get a move on!
New York City Two.
Only 15 hours
of daylight left.
BOB: Got all my
rocks here, boss.
Phew! Sure is hot. Think
it's gonna rain later?
Now what you want?
What I want? What makes you
think I want something?
My daddy told me
when motherfuckers
start talking
about the weather,
keep your hand
on your wallet.
Now what you want?
Your daddy must
have been a wise man.
A hell of a man.
Cut the shit
and tell me what
you want, Claude.
You still got that map?
Yeah, I still got it. Why?
Well, if you thinking about
booking it, I want in.
I think we can make it.
We? Ain't you the one
told me wasn't no we?
Now you wanna be we again?
What happened?
We get some bad news in that
letter back there, nigger?
Look, my cousin Melvin
is a lawyer
and he filed an appeal
on my behalf.
On your behalf? What happened to "we," Claude?
What happened to "we."
Ray, the appeal
was denied.
Well, I'm glad.
Then Daisy went
and fell for Melvin.
Now they're
engaged to be married.
Can you believe that?
That's hard to believe.
He a big, successful
New York lawyer,
and you down here with a bright
future in the cotton industry.
Let me figure it out for you.
Eenie, meenie, miney, Melvin!
Come on, Ray.
Look, I'm serious.
Don't shut me out. You, me,
the map, we can go places.
You know something, Claude? The
whole time we been down here,
you don't do nothing but
blame this whole shit on me.
That's all you did. And you don't do
nothing but think about yourself.
Your little scheme that you had.
Was I part of that?
No. All right. You're
gonna be honest now
'cause you wanna
be my friend.
Wanna be my friend
now, huh?
Let me tell you something Claude "Mr.
My Shit Don't Stink" Banks,
you got to learn a whole
lot more about friendship.
A lot more.
Lot more!
Hey, boss,
he ain't working!
Does this mean I'm in?
Nah, you'd probably
just slow me down.
You're gonna be out
there worrying about
your silverware being
clean and all that shit.
You one of them
soft motherfuckers.
What you say?
I said you soft.
So what?
What you gonna do?
Don't no man call me soft.
I hate that,
all right?
Let me slow you down
'cause I'm a man,
and I called you soft,
first of all.
And I don't like
you swelling all up
and all. What's all
this swell-up shit?
What's that about? What you taking
in all this air for, Claude?
What you feeling, huh?
What's on your mind, huh?
What, you gonna put your chin up, huh?
That mean something to me?
'Cause I said "soft"?
So what?
I say it, I spell it.
S-O-F-capital-T! Soft!
Huh? How you like that? What you gonna do, Claude?
What you gonna do, huh?
Hell, no. You must be crazy, nigger.
I'll kill you.
Oh, this is good.
Break it up!
[FIRES GUN]
God damn it!
Shit! I'm getting ready to shoot
somebody here, God damn it!
I'm gonna shoot a motherfucker today.
Okay, okay.
Ain't gonna forget this shit,
you New York Cities.
He started it.
Don't go to sleep, nigger.
I don't mess with
nobody around here!
Knocking me down.
You knew that...
BOB: Fucking knock me
down in the dirt for.
You know what "back to work" means, boy?
It means back to work!
This ain't over, nigger. I
don't give a fuck what he say.
I'm gonna shoot your ass.
That's right.
Don't go to sleep!
Don't you go to sleep.
We'll see who
go to sleep.
Come on, come on!
Two running!
CLAUDE: I know these
trees all look alike,
but this one is
awful familiar.
Let me see that map.
[PANTING]
You call this a map?
What was Cookie smoking
when he drew this?
Cookie didn't draw it.
I drew it up.
You drew this?
Ray, we out here in
the middle of nowhere.
Don't tell me you don't know
where we're going.
I drew it up 'cause I knew your ass
wouldn't come unless I had a map.
Now come on.
Come on, Claude!
Wait up. Wait up!
[DOGS BARKING]
Come on!
Take the dogs
around the house!
BOB: Y'all bring the dogs with me!
Come on! Keep moving!
Come on.
Come on!
[EXCLAIMS IN PAIN]
Come on! Come on!
Here they are,
Superintendent.
Tracked them all the way
to the Tallahatchie.
Well, that's quite a ways,
isn't it?
Well, I'm glad you New York
boys got to see some of
our beautiful countryside
while we got you down here.
Mae Rose!
Honey, what you think
we ought to do
with these two to
teach them a lesson, huh?
MAE ROSE: Um...
A night in the hole?
Better make it a week.
RAYFORD: I told you, I don't
move so fast in this shit.
Fuck y'all!
Hey, Claude!
What?
You got a toilet
in yours?
WILLIE: That was the first
time that Ray and Claude ran,
but it sure
wasn't the last.
NEWSREADER: Japan suffers its
most crushing defeat of the war.
General Douglas MacArthur. ..
WILLIE: Years passed,
and the world went to
war for a second time.
While they was fighting
for freedom on the outside,
why, we were dreaming
about it on the inside.
DILLARD: Camp 8 is
for incorrigibles.
So whatever you
done to get here,
believe me, I'm not impressed.
I've seen it all before.
You probably noticed that we ain't
got no fences here at Camp 8.
We don't need no fences 'cause
we got this here gun line.
It runs from...
What the hell you doing, boy?
What is your problem?
Excuse me, boss, but the boy can't talk.
Something wrong with his head.
Just can't get right, boss.
"Can't get right."
All right. We'll see
how long he lasts.
Now, where was I?
We don't need no fences
at Camp 8, boss.
Oh, no. What?
We don't need no fences
here at Camp 8, boss.
The gun line, boss.
Yes. Yes.
You prisoners are now
inside the gun line...
WILLIE: When Dillard found out
that Claude was a baseball man,
he put him in charge
of the team.
That way, when we lost, he could
blame it on somebody else.
[PRISONERS EXCLAIMING]
No, no, that's not it.
[SIGHS]
You know, try to teach them
the finer points of the game,
share my wisdom,
but do they listen?
They damn sure
don't learn.
I tell you what. What you're dealing
with is a total lack of talent.
Ain't nobody
got no talent.
Come on, here.
Every year Camp 12
wins the championship.
Every year they get to roast a victory pig.
This year, I want that pig.
Jangle Leg,
put it right to him, man.
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Radio, yes!
Who wants to hit next?
Find the card.
Don't nobody wanna hit?
What, do you wanna hit?
Hey, man, let Can't Get
Right have a swing.
Him?
Come on, now.
He can't be no worse
than the rest of them boys.
Ray, I...
Come on.
Let the boy have a swing.
Go on.
Take a swing at that.
CLAUDE:
All right. Come on.
Go on there.
Have a swing at the ball.
Let's see
what you can do.
All right,
put that bat in your hand,
hold it real tight,
and take a nice swing.
You gonna be all right.
Jangle Leg,
a little easy on him.
He's new,
so we don't wanna...
RAYFORD: Yeah, don't try to
hurt the man, you know.
Take it easy on him.
Even swing,
there, Can't Get Right.
Swing it now. Don't be
scared of the ball.
Whoo!
Shit.
CLAUDE: That wasn't bad.
Put that on it.
That... Yeah.
That might have been one of them,
you know, retard mistakes.
Ha! Let's try it.
Put it right here.
RAYFORD: Yeah, give him
that tricky one.
Yeah, Can't Get Right. That
motherfucker can hit, yeah.
Damn.
ABERNATHY: Hey, boy.
Daddy!
That's just like fresh water.
Hey, my little girl.
Look like little Mae
Rose done growed up.
And out.
That girl got gams.
ABERNATHY:
How was the honeymoon?
Tom, now, you are gonna stay
for supper, aren't you?
Afraid not, I'm
shipping out this afternoon.
Hey, boy, you looking
just a little bit too hard.
My ass. You
better just, you know,
take some of that glare
off your stare.
Turn around to the left.
We have a little problem.
It all right to
glance occasionally,
but you staring like you want to go
up and jam your... Start fucking.
Turn around.
I'm keeping you out of some trouble.
Paint the fence.
Banks! Get over here.
I'll be right back.
All right.
Yeah?
This is Stan Blocker, a scout
for the nigger leagues.
Negro leagues, actually.
Right.
Pittsburgh Crawfords.
Ever hear of us?
We get the games on
the radio sometimes.
We played down
in Jackson yesterday,
heard a rumor you got a boy up
here who can hit the ball a ton.
You must mean
Can't Get Right.
That's him,
right over there.
Get your ass
back here, boy.
"Can't Get Right"?
That's the kid's name?
Yep.
Well, can I
talk to him?
Well, you could try, but you won't get too far.
Why you interested?
Crawfords are always
looking for new talent.
Maybe you haven't noticed, Mr. Blocker,
but this here is a prison.
There are ways around that.
Right, Sergeant?
Oh. One never know.
[SCOFFS] Nice-looking squad.
Look at the way she glows.
Oh, she is pretty,
isn't she?
Thanks, Mom.
And we're gonna have a baby.
Oh, my goodness.
Can't Get Right, no, you can't do that.
No, don't... No!
Can't Get Right,
no, you can't do that. No!
Let's keep what mind you got
focused on the game.
If you hit that ball
like I know you can hit it,
you just might be our
ticket off this farm.
Come on.
Think victory.
The ball! Keep your... The ball!
Eye on the ball. Down there.
The ball.
Get up underneath that
motherfucker and do your thing!
Put some of that
dumb-dumb strength on it!
Come on do that thing now!
Come on, boy.
I'm right here
with you.
We gonna knock that shit
right over the trees!
Let's go!
That's right. Yeah, that's
what I'm talking about!
Oh, shit!
[WHOOPING]
Don't stand there! Run!
Run!Go!
Just haul ass!
Run, nigger, run!
CLAUDE:
Oh, that's our ticket, baby.
That's our ticket
off this farm.
BLOCKER:
You mark my words.
In five years,
there's gonna be
a colored man
playing in the majors.
You think?
I don't think the world
will change that much.
Maybe not yet,
but it will.
I'll be out of a job.
Damn, that's some
tasty hooch.
It's amazing
what Ray here can do
with a couple of pounds of
potato skins and some molasses.
Tell me, Mr. Blocker, what
you think about our boy?
You think
he got something?
I think that boy could
be the next Josh Gibson.
Is that right?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, it's
getting late, boys.
We got a game
in Memphis tomorrow.
What about us? Don't
forget to mention us.
Yeah, you know, 'cause we
kind of like his handlers.
We take care of
everything for him.
Yeah, I'll put in
a good word for you boys.
All right. He can't
function without us.
Okay.
You've done a good job with that boy.
Thanks a lot.
We hands-on with him,
you know.
Okay. All right.
Take care. Okay.
Have a nice day. Yeah.
Walked off smooth
with my drink, didn't he?
He sure did.
I ain't gonna say nothing.
Have a good day!
Take care now.
RAYFORD: Enjoy, man!
All right.
COOKIE:
Y'all come on over here!
Y'all got something
to drink over there?
WILLIE: Look what we got!
Some of your stuff, Ray!
Can't Get Right,
this one's for you, baby!
What in the world?
What?
Is Mae Rose all right?
She's doing just fine.
What about the baby?
He's a big'un.
"He"? It's a boy?
Honey, it's a boy!
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, buddy!
Let me see that boy!
Where is that boy?
Show me that grand-boy!
Sergeant Dillard,
I want every man
in this camp on
the line right now!
Right now!
I mean right now!
Bring them out here!
Let me see them!
Ugh! Hope not.
It was somebody
in this camp.
I can feel it in my bones.
Daddy, give me my baby back.
What you laughing at, boy?
You laughing at me?
You know who the daddy
of that chocolated baby is?
Huh? You do?
Well, who is it?
Speak up!
It's my baby, boss.
He's lying. I'm the father
of that baby, boss.
Boss, I'm that
baby's daddy.
Any fool can see
that baby belongs to me.
I wanna differ. That little
rascal belong to me.
Proud to say, boss,
I'm that baby's daddy.
I be the pa, boss.
I'm the pa of that
there young 'un, boss.
I the pappy-
[INMATES LAUGHING]
WILLIE: That was the
last we ever saw
of Superintendent Abernathy
and little Mae Rose.
To celebrate his departure, Camp 8
threw ourselves a little party.
Ray provided the moonshine,
and Claude managed to
scare up some girls.
It wasn't quite the Boom-Boom
Room, but it was close enough.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Come on, now.
Forget that, man. She don't
mean nothing to him.
Don't pay that no mind.
BISCUIT: To hell with him.
It ain't that.
What's your problem, sitting
around looking all sad and shit?
It's almost all right
in here today. Almost.
What's this?
This is a release form. Man,
you getting out this month.
What you sitting around
looking all sad for?
What am I gonna
do out there, Ray?
I can't go home
to my mama like this.
Man, that shit you
talking is crazy.
Your mama gonna be happy to
see you when you get home.
But not like this, Ray.
Hey, look. The world done changed a lot.
It's 1945, boy.
Not for me,
it ain't.
Look.
[SIGHS]
You can't stay here.
That's for damn sure.
I tell you what else, anybody
else in the whole place
would give his right arm
to be in your shoes right now.
I know I would.
Shit. Fucking release papers,
sitting over here looking sad.
I ain't gonna sit here
with your ass looking all sad.
You got the best news of the day,
you sitting here looking sad.
I'm gonna go over here
and slow grind with the sheep.
You cheer up. You're
going home, all right?
Hey, man, that's good news. Now, come on, now.
You're going home.
You gonna
smile or something?
There you go. All right, nigger.
I'll see you in a minute.
Where you going, Biscuit?
Oh!
Where you going, boy?
RAYFORD: Don't do that!
Don't do it!
Hold it right there!
Hold it!
Biscuit!
Man over the line!
RAYFORD: Hey! Hey!
Hey, come on, now! Shit!
[FIRES GUN]
Come on, J.
Come on, now.
[STRUMMING LUTE]
[WILLIE HUMMING]
I got Chicago!
Goldmouth,
Yeah?
Come on, fellas.
Where you going?
Why you all dressed up?
What's this?
What the fuck is going on?
Blocker!
What's going on here?
The kid's getting out.
I got him a pardon.
What about me and Ray? I didn't
see our names on that pardon.
You said you'd put
in a good word for us.
I did.
I mentioned you.
I mentioned both of you.
But the fact is,
pardons don't come cheap.
That kid can hit.
What can you guys do?
We're the ones who worked with
him night and day on that game.
Forget it, man.
Let it go.
I'm not gonna let it go, Ray.
No, I'm not, okay?
The man said he was gonna
put in a good word.
Explain yourself.
At least the kid's getting out.
That's what you wanted, right?
Yeah. Of course.
Okay.
You show them Crawfords
how to play ball.
Make them
throw you strikes.
Go. You're a free man.
DILLARD:
It's all right.
Come on, son.
MAN 1:
We love you, boy.
[PRISONERS TALK INDISTINCTLY]
MAN 2:
Hit that ball, boy.
MAN 3: You hit one out
the park for me.
MAN 4: Gonna miss you,
Can't Get Right.
MAN 5:
Play hard, Can't Get Right!
MAN 4:
We'll catch you on the radio!
All right.
So that's that.
Look, one of the new boys
told me
they're farming that land
up there by the swamp.
He said he seen
a crop duster...
I'm not in the mood
right now, Ray.
They keep the crop duster
behind the barn.
It can't be that hard
to fly a plane.
Lots of people
do it, Claude.
They're called pilots, Ray.
I'm serious,
I'm not in the mood
for one of your
fucked-up plans right now.
I don't hear you coming up
with no plan, nigger!
My plan is on his way
to Pittsburgh right now, Ray.
Can't Get Right just
got himself a pardon
signed by the governor,
thanks to us.
But we can't seem to do
nothing for ourselves.
Don't you feel a little
frustrated right now, Ray?
Crop duster.
I'm not getting in
no airplane with you.
You know, I'm finally wrapping my
mind around this whole concept.
Oh, really?
What concept is that?
They threw us in this
shithole for life, Ray.
Don't you get it?
We gonna die here.
We might as well
head up to the cemetery,
pick a plot,
and start digging.
Now let me tell you something, my
daddy died in a place like this
because of that
shit you're talking.
He gave up hope
and hung hisself.
I ain't going out
like that, Claude.
Maybe you're
fooling yourself, Ray.
Maybe you just
a chip off the old block.
Now, you're gonna take that back,
or we ain't friends no more.
News flash, Ray. We ain't
never been friends.
We just been stuck
together for 12 years.
It's been
nothing but pure hell
since the moment I
ran into you, Ray.
Every time I look at you,
I get sick to my stomach
thinking what
my life could've been
if I never, ever bumped
into Ray Gibson.
All right,
you better slow down,
'cause you fixing to say
something you gonna regret.
You better
quiet down, nigger.
Only thing I regret is
the day I met you, Ray.
That's the way it is, huh?
Yeah, that's
the way it is.
I ain't got nothing else
to say to your ass then.
Thank you!
WILLIE: Now if you ask me, when
Can't Get Right left Camp 8,
a piece of Claude
left with him.
And with Ray and Claude
not talking,
the place felt a little
harder, a little colder.
[NEWSREADER OVER RADIO]
I have a dream.
...be the greatest!
I'm the king of the world.
And it is time for you and me
to fight for ourselves.
I'll see y'all
in New York City!
Oh, shit!
WILLIE:
Round about 1972,
I got transferred
to the infirmary,
and those two fools
were still at it.
But no matter
how tough a man is,
he spends enough
time on this farm,
he'll find
his breaking point.
It could be triggered
by any little thing.
A face. A voice.
Even a smell.
White-only pies.
Man over the line!
[EXCLAIMS]
That boy went crazy.
You comfortable?
As a pair of
fur-lined bedroom slippers.
That's very amusing. We'll
see how them slippers feel
after, let's say,
about 24 hours.
I need a volunteer!
Gibson, stand up.
I'll make you
trustee right now.
If that pie-eating son of a
bitch step off them bottles,
if so much as
one toe hit that dirt,
I want you to shoot him
right in his ass.
I want you to kill him.
I want you to shoot him dead.
You do that, I swear to
God, you're a free man.
Hell, I'll walk you
out the gate myself.
What do you say?
I got to be
honest with you, boss.
You don't wanna
give me that gun,
'cause I'd probably
shoot you with it.
That was
the wrong answer, boy.
CLAUDE: You a fool.
I'd have taken that deal.
I beg your pardon?
You say something to me?
I'd have knocked you off the
bottles, put a bullet in your ass,
and be halfway to
New York right now.
Well, my goodness. After all
these years of blissful silence,
I forgot how annoying
the sound of your voice is.
Ray, I hope you don't think
I owe you anything,
'cause I don't owe you
a damn thing.
I ain't do nothing for
you to owe me nothing.
What you got I ain't got?
I did it for me.
I'm a man, God damn it. I ain't no
motherfucking, bootlicking trustee.
You gonna make me fall off this
shit, talking to your ass.
It's about being poised, Ray.
Just poise yourself.
Poise, my ass.
Look here, Ray,
I'm sorry to hear
about your mama passing.
Yeah, that was
about five years ago.
Thank you.
I know, but since we're talking,
I thought I'd mention it.
We not talking, you talking. And
doing a little bit too much of it.
Every time you start talking,
I almost fall...
Would you stop...
Don't say nothing
else to me!
You about to
make me fall, Ray.
Hold still and
don't say nothing.
Oh!
Damn, one of my toes
in the bottle.
Damn it, Ray, shit.
[LAUGHING]
What you laughing about, Ray?
What's so funny?
Thinking about you
running with them bullets
flying all over
the top of your head.
That's something
to see there.
That was
a sight to see, nigger.
Bullets weren't
the problem, Ray.
That pie was too hot.
Burned my damn tongue.
It sure is good
talking to you again.
Good talking
to you, too.
Come on! Let's move!
We got 14 acres of land to clear today!
Let's go!
Gibson, Banks, get your
sorry asses over here.
Every morning I
wake up praying
that Ray Gibson and Claude Banks
have died in their sleep.
And every morning
you disappoint me.
Sorry, boss.
You two got 15 minutes
to clear out your lockers.
The both of you
have been transferred
to the superintendent's
mansion.
And I, for one,
won't miss you.
Here's your medicine,
Mr. Wilkins.
My pills.
Thank you, Claude.
Oh, you're welcome.
Oh, yard boy.
This myrtle could
use some attention.
Perhaps some fertilizer
would restore its exuberance.
Get your ass to work.
Claude.
Tell me what you
think of this place.
It's one of these new
retirement communities
they built
down on the Gulf.
I figure I ought to try to enjoy
myself what few years I got left.
[CHUCKLES]
Let's take a look at this.
Eyesight ain't what it once was.
Oh, this is nice here.
"Ocean views, palm trees.
"Two heated swimming pools."
Sounds a damn sight better than
that infirmary across the way
where I'm gonna end up,
I'll tell you that.
Claude.
I must apologize, Claude.
That was rude of me.
That's all right, boss.
Takes more than some colorful
brochure to hurt my feelings.
You've been on the farm for
quite a spell, haven't you?
Over 40 years now. Me and
Ray Gibson out there.
Forty years.
That's a long time for
any crime, even murder.
It's a hell of a lot longer
when you're innocent.
Half the men in this prison
swear they're innocent, Claude.
Don't you think
that's kind of funny?
You have to forgive
me if I don't laugh.
Excuse me.
What you looking at, Ray?
Just what the fuck
you looking at, Ray?
I noticed that...
I noticed you and Mr. Wilkins
been mighty friendly lately.
Y'all wanna be a new
couple or something?
Kiss my ass, Ray. Okay?
Mr. Wilkins just an old
man that like to talk.
That's all that is, Ray.
That's all that is.
Y'all like to talk. I'm lonely,
and I like to talk, too.
What you wanna talk about, Ray? Huh?
What you wanna talk about?
Nigger, I wanna talk about the
plan you've been working on.
I ain't working
on no plan, Ray!
I know you.
And I know when you got
something brewing. I know it!
What I got brewing, Ray?
You tell me!
You done lost
your damn mind, Ray.
I don't care
what you believe.
I don't care what
you believe
'cause I know you got
something up your sleeve.
Think I'm gonna stay up
arguing with you all night?
You cutting into my sleeping time, okay?
Kiss my ass and good night.
Go to sleep, nigger.
I hope it's the long one.
Why you talking instead of sleeping?
Good night.
I'm going to sleep.
Why don't you go to sleep?
Why can't I just sit here
and look at your ass?
And wonder what you
got up your sleeve.
I got something brewing.
I got an ass-whupping
brewing for you, Ray,
if you don't stop
fucking with me.
Is that right?
That's right, Ray.
All right.
Sleep tight, nigger.
Fuck you.
Yeah, fuck you, too.
I hope your ass piss the bed with
that weak-ass bladder of yours.
If I do, then I'll put the sheets on you.
How you like that?
[SINGING]
Now just where the hell
you think you going?
Mr. Wilkins' driver
got the flu,
and he asked me
to fill in for him.
How the hell you gonna fill in for somebody?
You can't drive.
You ain't got no driver license,
you ain't drove in 40 years.
He know he's taking his life in
his own hands, letting you drive?
Shut up, Ray.
I'm not gonna shut up.
Where the hell you
supposed to be going?
If you must know...
Then I must know.
I got to know, nigger.
What's up?
Greenville. Pick up the new
superintendent at the bus station.
What's with
the old pretty suit?
Who you supposed to be,
Harry Belafonte?
I look very dapper,
very debonair, don't I?
Now don't touch this car.
I piss on the motherfucker. Ain't
gonna touch it, I'll piss on it.
Why you got to
say nasty shit, Ray?
'Cause I'm
a nasty motherfucker.
You know I
trust you, Claude.
I hope so.
Be right back.
[KIDS LAUGHING]
[RADIO PLAYING]
[MOUTHING]
What the fuck?
Naturally, I had to get set down next
to your proverbial hypochondriac,
middle-aged fat lady with a
goddamn wart on her nose,
hair growing out of it,
for Christ's sakes.
[YOUNG PIKE'S VOICE]
I tell you, I got to know
her goddamn gallbladder
like the back of
my goddamn hand.
Claude?
Mr. Pike, Claude.
There you go, boy.
Come on, Claude.
It's time to go.
Let me get that door for you.
You just stretch out.
Now you're sure
it was him.
Some faces you
just don't forget.
Warren Pike is
one of them.
All right.
[BOTH EXCLAIMING]
Got a bird!
That's quite a haul,
huh, Claude?
What do you say, Mr. Pike? You
about ready to call it a day?
[MUSIC PLAYING ON WATCH]
PIKE:
Yeah, it's getting late,
and I sure as hell could
use a nice, hot bath.
That's a mighty fine timepiece
you got there, Mr. Pike.
Even play
a fancy tune, huh?
Yeah, it's special.
They don't make
them like that anymore.
I'll bet they don't.
You wouldn't mind if I asked you
where you got that from, would you?
My wife gave it to me on our
anniversary some years back.
Uh-huh.
About 40 years back?
Forty years.
Yeah, something like that.
She give you that
scar on your face, too?
I ought to kill you
for that remark, boy.
What's going on here?
I think I might just have
to teach this uppity nigger
a lesson in manners.
Ray, be cool. You gonna get
us in a lot of trouble now.
He's right, Gibson.
You put that gun down, or I'm
gonna have to shoot you.
Then we about to be
some shot-up motherfuckers.
Now, wait a minute.
Don't nobody shoot nobody.
Ray, I wanna see this son of
a bitch dead just like you.
I don't wanna see
you go down with him.
Ray, give me the gun. Come on, now.
Give me the gun.
Claude, he got my daddy's watch!
He killed Winston Hancock!
Don't listen to him, Wilkins.
He's crazy.
Gibson,
I want you to stop now.
Think about
what you're saying.
I know just
what I'm saying!
That's the only thing my daddy
ever give me, and he's got it.
Tell them what you did.
Is there any truth in
what this man is saying?
What the hell
difference does it make?
At least the state
of Mississippi got
40 years of cheap labor
out of the deal.
Motherfucker, you done took
our lives away from us.
Give me the gun, Ray.
I'm gonna kill this
motherfucker myself.
No!
WILKINS:
Put it down, Pike!
I believe
this belongs to me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
My daddy's watch.
We were walking back. A bird
came out low on our left.
I swung on it.
Mr. Pike walked directly
in my line of fire.
Where were the two convicts
when the shot was fired?
They were loading up
the truck, I believe.
They'd gone on ahead.
Why don't he just
tell him the truth?
He know nobody
wanna hear the truth.
He gonna tell them
what they wanna hear.
I don't know, Ray.
We'll talk, okay?
Thank you.
Here he comes.
I think they bought it.
One of the deputies
is a member of my church.
Gibson, I don't think
there's any way that
I could...
Claude...
There's no way to
make up for 40 years.
I'll get Charlie
to draw up your pardon papers
in the morning.
Would you mind
helping me upstairs?
Sure, boss.
I'm not your boss.
Not anymore.
JAKE: So Ray and Claude
get their pardons, right?
No, ain't get
their pardons, man.
If they got their
pardons way back then,
we wouldn't be burying
them here today, would we?
That's right.
Damn.
What happened is
Old Man Wilkins
never come out
of the bathroom.
Sat right there and
died on the shitter.
[CHUCKLES]
That must've been pretty
messed up for them, man.
What happened to them
after that, old-timer?
Let's see.
What happened after that?
Oh, yeah!
They got old.
[CHUCKLES]
Shit. We all got old.
And getting out took on
a whole new meaning.
Looks like Jonesy
got his walking papers.
RAYFORD:
Yeah, there he go.
Over to the morgue,
up the hill to the cemetery.
Phew! I'll tell you what, Claude, you
were right when you said what you said.
You said we wasn't never
gonna get out of this place.
And you were right.
You said the only way
we gonna get outta here
is through
the morgue and the cemetery.
And you're right,
'cause we right here.
Right here, right now.
Yeah, I remember
saying that.
We next.
Let's be real.
We next. You like baseball?
We on deck.
On deck for what?
For what?
That upper room, nigger.
[SINGING] The upper room
When Jesus...
Know where that is,
the upper room
the motherfuckers
be singing about?
The upper room
Yeah, I'll tell you what.
You die first, I'm gonna
sing at your funeral.
I'm gonna just bust up
in the motherfucker and go...
[SINGING] The upper room
Let them shoot me.
I don't give a fuck
if they take me out
singing that motherfucker.
[CHUCKLES]
You crazy, Ray.
Hell, yeah.
Friend.
Yeah. We next.
[SIGHS]
I wanna be at the game.
I'm on a roll.
[SINGING] Mama and my
daddy don't know how
Two Percodan, baby. There you go.
Give me what you got.
I'll raise you.
[LAUGHS]
Yo, what the fuck are those?
It helps keep
the cholesterol down.
Old man, do I look
like I give a damn
about my cholesterol
right now?
Come on, now.
You want a bump, G?
No, I don't want
none of that shit.
That's right.
I wouldn't put that
in my nose if I were you.
You know how they get
it in here, don't you?
Tell him how
they get in here.
People smuggle it in,
in their ass.
Say What?
I know the motherfucker
that bring it in here.
That come out of somebody's
asshole, so go on, enjoy.
Whatever.
I know if I got to
get high,
I got to smell some shit,
I ain't gonna have none.
That ain't high.
That's low.
[PRISONERS LAUGHING]
That cocaine, heroin, marijuana, all
that shit, bring it all in here,
in their ass.
That's right.
Look like it's up
to you, ass-sniffer.
Okay, boys, come and get it!
Jell-O!
Jell-O pudding!
Play one more hand.
I'm gonna get my Jell-O.
Come on.
Y'all gonna take all my
money and go run off
'cause nurse said, "Jell-O."
Ray. I don't want no
Jell-O, God damn it.
No, I ain't said
nothing about the Jell-O.
I was thinking about what we
talked about this afternoon.
I think I got a plan.
You got a plan?
Yeah.
I'm a visionary
on this one.
You got it all
worked out, huh?
I think I really do.
Listen here.
Any plan you got
I don't even wanna hear
'cause I know it's fucked up.
All fucked up.
If you don't wanna believe me, you
don't wanna believe me then, Ray.
I'm too old. I ain't got time for no plan.
I'm 90 years old, Claude.
I never thought
I'd see the day
that old Ray Gibson
give up hope.
Never thought...
Say what now?
I said I never thought
I'd hear the day
that old Ray Gibson
give up hope.
Nigger, I ain't given up
no motherfucking hope.
I'm keeping it real, like them
niggers in here keep it real.
Ain't nobody
give up nothing.
But you know what?
You'd probably
slow me down anyway.
Said which?
You'd only
slow me down.
You must be high if you think I'm
gonna slow your slow ass down.
I got a plan.
I tell you what.
Fuck your plan.
Come on, Lou. Cover that up. Don't
nobody wanna see that shit.
Put your drawers
on or something.
Lou, cover it up.
Don't touch it.
Put your hand away.
That turn my stomach. I don't want no
Jell-O after I seen them old-ass balls.
Who gonna enjoy Jell-O
after I seen what I've seen?
I don't even want Jell-O.
Lou ruin my stomach.
MAN:
Anybody seen Claude?
I been sitting here the whole time.
He ain't come out.
Claude ain't out!
Claude has died, God!
No, Ray, don't go!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
Claude!
Ray, you can't
go in there!
Ray, come back!
Claude!
[SCREAMING]
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
MAN 1:
How did it start?
MAN 2:
Probably old wires.
Place was a tinderbox
just waiting to go.
I guess we should've torn this old
building down a long time ago.
Gibson made it this far before he
was probably overcome by smoke.
From the looks of things, Banks
didn't even make it out of bed.
You really
bummed me out.
That's a terrible story.
Nigger. you crying?
No, I got allergies.
I'm cool.
Oh, my God, man.
Ain't nothing wrong with a man
crying every now and again.
Listen, man. What was
Claude's plan, anyway?
Claude figured
he could steal a couple of
bodies from the morgue, right?
That way, when he set
the infirmary on fire,
in all the commotion,
him and Ray could just
slip right onto
them fire engines, see?
Hide out,
wait until the morning,
and roll right on
out with them, you see?
That way, when they find the two
bodies, they think it was them.
What makes you
think that ain't work?
Mmm.
I never said
it didn't work.
Wait. You mean to
tell me that this is
not Ray and Claude
in these two boxes?
[CHUCKLES]
Is it, old man?
[CHUCKLING]
Hey, old-timer, is it?
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
[SPECTATORS CHEERING]
I like that.
See?
You feel part of this
baseball game, don't you?
They only get one
out of me today.
Now, we were arguing
about something, okay?
I didn't appreciate when you
said something about...
You had just said
I was...
You said that...
You know what?
Hell with it.
It's a hell of a day
for a ball game.
Yankees on fire.
Motherfuckers kicking ass.
Which ones the Yankees?
Well, the ones up
at the mound.
Go, go, you! Run!
That's the Yankees
right there.
Which ones there?
That's the Yankees
right there.
It's a perfect plan.
We're out.
What's so perfect? Took 65
years to come up with it.
Why can't you
just say thank you?
You want me to say thank you?
You can kiss my ass, too.
[BOTH ARGUING INDISTINCTLY]
I'm ready to go
back right now.
Then let's go, Ray.
Hold my frank.
Come on.
Help a nigger out, man.
Don't make me
stand out in this cold.
Your bitch would be
standing... I'm sorry.
You fuck around with me, it's gonna
be consequences and repercussions.
What's repercussions?
Uh-oh.
[LAUGHING]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Let me get that.
Yeah, I know it's 1932.
I'm the first one
to have this.
Hey, mud head. Hey, watch... Shit.
I almost got stung by a bee.
You were scared, huh?
Don't be scared.
Uh-uh. Don't be scared, and don't laugh either.
'Cause it ain't funny.
That boy got
God-given talent.
God made his...
[LAUGHS]
What's wrong?
The mustache too big?
[ALL LAUGHING]
He give up hope
and hung himself
because of the airplane
that's coming over.
Make me have to loop all this shit.
I ain't looping shit!
We either get it now,
or not at all!
My name Jangle Leg,
Jangle Leg.
[LAUGHING]
You think that's funny?
That's probably the last time.
Sorry.
My bad.
This ain't my daddy's watch.