(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(PANTING)
I'll take that now, sir. Thank you.
- There you are, sir.
- Thank you.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(ENGINE KNOCKING)
(ENGINE STRUGGLING)
- It's the heater switch.
- You told me that last week.
- You didn't leave it long enough.
- Work on it now.
- You got an appointment?
- What are you, a doctor?
MAN: (ON RADIO)
The bakery workers' strike continues
with no bread for a week.
Unseasonable temperatures
for New York...
Gotta change... Come on, start.
- ...with a humidity of 79%.
- Damn.
I've gotta make an appointment?
(HONKING)
- Get away from there!
- Get out of here!
What are you going to do?
(ENGINE STRUGGLING)
(HONKING)
Move that crate!
Will you move that heap?
- I'm talking to you, mister! Move!
- All right.
You're a menace!
Do you know that,
you senile, old cocker?
Don't you tell me to langsamer,
you Kraut meathead!
- Langsamer!
- Go on!
You Limburger-loving schmuck!
Jude! You are a Jude!
You Nazi bastard!
Go on! Get going,
you Mercedes bastard!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
Get going! How do you like that?
(LAUGHING)
Come on!
Damn it!
(LAUGHING)
Come on!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(HONKING)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
How do you like that?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(HONKING)
Hey! You maniac, you!
Go on, you son of a bitch!
Come on! Come on back!
You anti-Semitic bastard, you!
Come on back!
(BOTH SHOUTING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Behind schedule?
(DOG BARKING)
(GROWLING)
Put a leash on that dog!
(PANTING)
Here comes the Creep. Yo, Melendez.
Hey, Creepy! Hey, twinkle toes!
Creepy!
Gonna time yourself in the shower?
What was it yesterday? 16:02.
I was faster. Shit!
...has shattered the peace
of this East Side neighbourhood
on this traditional Jewish holiday
of Yom Kippur.
Two men have been killed
in this accident.
An explosion and fire,
which you see behind me.
I'm going to talk to some people
to find out what happened.
- What were you doing here?
- I was taking pictures.
- Can you tell me what happened?
- "Boom", that's what.
REPORTER: One of the men killed here
was Klaus Szell,
the brother of the infamous Nazi,
Christian Szell,
thought to have perished
fleeing Berlin at the end of World War ll.
Tom Ellis,
reporting direct from the scene.
(CLAMOURING)
(BELLS RINGING)
(HONKING)
What's this?
DRIVER: They are
protesting against pollution.
They are a pain in the ass.
(ALL HONKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Janey!
London was hectic, but I'm fair.
Get a cab and get over here.
I've got plenty of room.
Oh, screw appearances. I miss you.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Just a second.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Excuse me, that's not my suit.
(APOLOGISES IN FRENCH)
I don't know what it was about.
The valet came into the wrong room.
I'm not jittery.
Who else knows I'm here?
Are you sure?
Why don't you finish what you're doing
and get your ass over here?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- MAN: ...in francs is a lot of money.
- WOMAN: Is it really?
The price is too high.
You do speak English?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'd like to offer you half.
- Bon appÈtit, bon appÈtit.
- I guess I didn't do it right.
We haven't done anything right
on the whole voyage.
I'm far too sensitive
for this kind of work.
Something for your crash diet, LeClerc.
The least I could do.
Merci, Scylla.
My diet is going badly.
I'm beginning to think I lack willpower.
Why were you surprised to see me?
I wasn't.
You were when I came in.
Did you think I was dead?
(SCOFFS) That's ridiculous.
I expected you three days ago, that's all.
London got busy.
I'm over here to do a lot of things.
You're only one of them.
Mmm.
I haven't got anything for you here.
- Why not?
- Well...
I couldn't keep it in the shop.
Look. I'll have it for you tonight.
You'll have to come to the opera.
The opera!
It's worse than that.
It's a very long French opera.
You'll have it tonight, won't you?
Leave the ticket at the box office.
I'll be there before it's over.
(TICKING)
Plaza AthÈnÈe.
Mike, who you have for English lit?
Bayley? He sucks.
- Which room is Biesenthal's?
- 107.
You were picked for his seminar?
You weren't?
Ah, Levy. Good of you to come.
Won't you join us?
Tell us the subject
of your dissertation, please?
Tyranny, sir.
The use of tyranny
in American political life.
Such as?
Maybe...
Coolidge breaking up
the Boston police strike,
Roosevelt putting Japanese-Americans
into concentration camps...
You might consider
the McCarthy business?
- Sir?
- McCarthy.
Senator from Wisconsin?
Ran a series of purges in the '50s?
Yes, I'm aware of that, sir.
I was planning a chapter on him.
A chapter, I see. Yes, interesting.
Well, you four have the dubious honour
of having been picked from
over 200 applicants for this seminar.
There's a shortage of natural resources,
breathable air and adequate claret,
but there's no shortage of historians.
We grind you out like link sausages.
It's called progress.
Manufactured doctorates
is called progress.
I say, "Let us hush this cry of progress
till 10,000 years have passed."
That's a quote. Who said that?
Come on. Who said that?
Well, somebody must know the answer!
Tennyson, Alfred Lord Tennyson.
You can't compete on a doctoral level
and not know Locksley Hall.
I hope you all flunk! Dismissed.
- Levy?
- Yeah.
Come.
Oh. Sit.
I knew your father.
Rather well, in point of fact.
He was my mentor.
I know.
- There was another of you.
- I have an older brother.
A rich, successful businessman.
My father would have disowned him.
Why are you at Columbia
for your doctorate?
It's not just the way things worked out.
Your father got his at Columbia.
You can't fill his footsteps,
I'm sorry to say.
You might end up leaving
larger tracks than that,
but they'll be your tracks,
they won't be his.
Why didn't you answer
that Tennyson question?
It was obvious you knew.
I don't know.
How am I to fathom your mind
if you continue to hide it from me?
If you persist,
I'll conclude you're a drone.
The McCarthy section
is central to your dissertation, yes?
Yes.
Very worrisome.
You wish to write about a period in
our history that destroyed your father.
But we're talking about
an objective doctoral thesis.
It mustn't become a hysterical crusade.
That's not the way to clear him.
All right, you may go.
I don't have to worry about clearing him,
because he was innocent.
(GUN FIRES)
Don't you think he was innocent, sir?
No, I think he was guilty.
He was guilty of being arrogant
and brilliant and of being naÔve.
Of not being able to cope with
the humiliation of being dismissed.
But of the charges,
I know he was innocent.
And if it matters, Levy,
I wept the day he died.
It was a bad day for all of us, sir.
Under no circumstances do anything,
but call as soon as you...
Yes, I have the number.
Bye.
Bonjour. Commander.
We're meeting tonight, right?
- At the hotel?
- No, make it the Palais-Royal.
- Same time, then.
- I don't know. I'm going to the opera.
- NICOLE: You go to the opera? Bye.
- DOC: Goodbye.
There's something going on here
that we don't know about.
- Can't you be more specific?
- Yes.
I almost got my ass blown off
at the flea market.
I'd like to find out by whom and why.
Also, LeClerc was not expecting me.
You sure you're not
overusing your limited imagination?
The bomb was not imaginary.
Three bombs a day have gone off
since the strikes began.
- I know that.
- Everyone with a grievance is busy.
- Am I crazy?
- Yeah, you're crazy.
- But you'll check it out?
- Of course.
Why do you need to be reassured?
We use you because you're the best.
(MAN SINGING OPERA)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CHATTERING)
I'm sorry I'm so late. I was down...
(SHUSHES)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
LeClerc, want to hear
something really silly?
(SLAMMING)
Nicole?
Nicole.
Keep going, keep going.
LeClerc's dead.
It's not safe.
(THUDDING)
Nicole?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CLAMOURING)
(BELLS RINGING)
(GROANS)
(SNAPPING)
(DIALING)
- MAN: Division.
- Scylla.
- Yes, Scylla?
- Removals.
- My hotel.
- MAN: Room 72?
- DOC: And alert the clinic.
- Okay, Scylla.
(BUZZING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Sorry.
What was all that about?
I was just telling him
how you fucked up my tennis game.
What did he say?
Well...
We won't be playing doubles for a while.
Can you move it?
That's it?
That's it.
That's not bad.
Szell's brother's been killed in
Manhattan, an accident with an oil truck.
Oh, boy.
Any changes?
Only everything.
They're getting all the couriers.
Please could you tell me,
Boss Tweed, around 1875...
Boss, is that his name? Boss?
No, that's his nickname.
William Marcy Tweed.
- Marthy...
- I'll write it down for you.
They called him Boss,
because he was a corrupt politician.
He had a bunch of political hacks
called "the Tweed ring".
This I know. Thank you.
- Could I have the pencil, please?
- It's mine.
(HONKING)
Miss Opel!
Miss Opel. Hi. Sorry.
You forgot your book.
I thought it might be important.
- Thank you. Bye.
- Bye.
Your name and address
were on the inside of it,
in case you were wondering
how I knew where you live.
I wasn't.
- Thank you again. Bye.
- Bye.
Goodbye.
Bye.
You say "good night", but you don't go.
I twisted my ankle on the way.
I was hoping to rest it.
- But you're not limping.
- I'm a marathon runner.
When you race 26 miles,
you don't give in to pain.
- It hurts, but I don't pay any attention.
- You won at this?
I haven't run a whole marathon yet,
but I hope to.
I wish you good luck. Bye.
- I'm sorry I stole your book.
- What?
I took your book.
I didn't know how to talk to you.
I was embarrassed, so I took your book.
- Aren't you embarrassed now?
- Yeah, I'm humiliated.
Why do you pursue people
who sit at your library table?
I don't. It's just that you're pretty.
I can't talk about how smart you are.
I don't know you. I'm done lying.
Are you always
so incompetent with women?
- Today is above average for me.
- Congratulations. Good night.
That's too bad.
I could make you so happy.
I'm smart as a whip.
You won't meet
another thief like me in a library.
Why don't you say you'll see me? Huh?
- All right. I'll see you again.
- (PHONE RINGING)
But it won't come to anything.
You can't tell.
Yes, I can.
(TOLLING LOUDLY)
(CHATTERING)
(OPERA PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- How do you say "seals" in French?
- Phoques.
So you look at the phoque?
How do you spell that?
- You don't believe it.
- How do you spell it?
- F-O-C.
- No "K"?
(CLANGING LOUDLY)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(TUNE PLAYING)
I like you.
I like you, too.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Merde.
- I know.
- What's the time?
- 11:47. You're faster.
- It's 'cause of you.
- Come on. Lunch!
- One more!
- Oh, no!
(PANTING)
No, Babe. Not again.
Come on.
I can't!
Neither can I.
Thank God!
Come on.
BABE: What?
ELSA: Babe! Babe.
Babe!
(GRUNTING)
BABE: "Dear, Doc,
I don't feel much like writing,
"too torn apart, I guess,
"but maybe I ought to tell you
something about Elsa Opel.
"I met her recently.
"She's a history student.
I think she's Swiss.
"In a sense, I guess
we are what you might call smitten.
"Maybe I should tell you what happened.
"We were in Central Park one night.
We stayed too late.
"You were right about this town,
'cause we finally got mugged.
"It's a funny thing.
"You always talk about
how I don't confront things.
"But I feel like if
I could find those guys,
"for the first time I feel like I could,
maybe I could kill them.
"It's funny, 'cause I never knew
I could feel like that inside.
"So what else is there to say?
There's nothing else new here.
"Reach me if you can. Babe."
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH OVER PA)
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have news, unfortunately,
that there's been no solution
to the strike at Kennedy Airport.
We trust this won't cause you
too great an inconvenience
and that you will once again fly with us.
Muchas gracias.
WOMAN: (OVER PA) Will passengers
who have identified their baggage
please go to customs?
(MAN LAUGHING)
(INAUDIBLE)
The land of plenty.
They were always so confident
God was on their side.
- Now, I think they are not so sure.
- (LAUGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(THUDDING)
Who's there?
Who is it?
I got a gun.
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
- Articulate as always.
- Prick. You scared the shit out of me.
(CHUCKLES)
- What time is it?
- Don't know. Must be about midnight.
- Why didn't you say you were coming?
- I wanted to test your reflexes.
- Still challenging me?
- As always.
Don't worry about me.
Worry about yourself.
Waking me up
in the middle of the night.
- Ouch!
- What's the matter?
Doesn't matter.
I could take you with one hand.
- How are you?
- Fine. How are you?
- You look terrific.
- What happened?
- A lousy bottle of Mouton broke on me.
Hey, get some glasses.
Do I have to hear a lecture
on the glories of a Burgundy again?
This is a Beaujolais, schmuck.
Moulin-‡-Vent, '71.
(SIGHS)
Don't you ever
clean this armpit of a place?
How can you live like this?
I'm down in Washington.
- Here we go.
- I can put you up. Go to Georgetown.
No, thank you, but I prefer my hovel.
- I'll do it.
- Thanks.
You did it, huh?
- You really are uncouth.
- You wanted glasses.
You didn't say they needed
to be clean, asshole.
So, how's business?
- The oil business is always good.
- Just a bunch of polluters and thieves.
It's a crazy world.
Any way you can skin it
is your business.
- Cheers.
- Up yours.
- (GARGLES)
- (SCOFFS)
- Irmgard must love your style.
- We don't drink this shit.
- What happened in the park?
- Exactly what I wrote you.
- How many?
- Two.
- Kids?
- They were more like businessmen.
They looked like you. They had suits on.
What's this?
More bullshit for your thesis?
Some interviews about Dad. Read them.
Not interested.
I just want you to read it.
Face it. The old man is dead.
He was a drunk. He killed himself.
He didn't start to drink
till after the hearings.
I got it from his friends.
- Where were those people then?
- They were afraid.
- You're throwing your life away.
- I don't think so.
Nothing you write will change that!
- Give me the courtesy to read it!
- It's over! Forget it!
Maybe for you.
Do you want me to become
a corporate hustler like you?
- My life's thrown away, anyway.
- What do you mean?
I'm supposed to be
the best in my business.
I'm the best because
people think I am the best.
I'm past it. I know it.
Soon it'll become common knowledge.
Boy, something has gotten you.
Babe...
I bet you still have that goddamn gun.
Why do you keep it?
I don't know.
For a liberal pacifist,
you've got some sense of vengeance.
Is Helga as morbid as you?
I know you're trying to bait me.
You know her name isn't Helga.
Or Ursula or Irmgard.
- You know what her name is!
- All right, all right.
Can I take you and Elsa
to lunch tomorrow?
- But don't eat with your fingers.
- I promise.
It's a deal.
- Okay, I get the bed.
- Same as always.
You have any clean sheets?
I think I may have one left.
I really wanted to say that...
What?
I'm glad to see you.
Doc?
I'm glad you came down.
- When did you last take a subway?
- About 1962.
Excuse me, sir.
Would you mind putting on this tie?
Why?
It's a rule of the house.
You have to wear a tie here.
- I don't have a button.
- Put it here.
- Would you like me to help?
- BABE: No, I can do it.
- Fine. Thank you very much.
- What a klutz.
- How could you forget a tie?
- Who wears a tie for lunch?
At least his fly is buttoned.
The truffles en croute here
are marvellous.
And if you get hungry,
I'll send the waiter to McDonald's.
- Does it look all right?
- Perfect.
- Number 36, Chablis Grand Cru.
- Yes, sir.
The great Chablis of the world
are almost always green-eyed.
In fact, they're the ones
that most resemble diamonds.
Please, start.
Sir.
- You approve?
- Too much.
- It's delicious.
- It should be.
I could pay my tuition
for what this meal costs.
See the watch he gave me
the last time he was here?
Nice.
Do you miss home? I bet you do.
What do you miss most of all?
The people? The country? Skiing?
ELSA: I suppose all.
DOC: I'm not that familiar
with Switzerland.
What part are you from?
A tiny place. Verbier.
Verbier?
- I don't believe it!
- What?
A guy in my office, a ski bum,
a pain in the ass about skiing.
Excuse me.
He's always going on about Verbier.
Right at the foot of Mount Rosa?
- It's the best skiing in the world. True?
- Of course.
- DOC: Was he 100% right?
- ELSA: Sure.
You must know Claude LeSeur.
- Have you skied with him?
- Yeah!
Where is it?
- Verbier.
I've made all this up.
There's no Mount Rosa in Verbier
or Claude LeSeur.
You're not Swiss. What are you?
What are you?
- Can't you guess?
- Sure. German.
- ELSA: Anything else?
- How long are your papers good for?
Wait. If this is a joke, it's not funny.
I don't need work papers.
I'm a student here.
Many foreigners marry Americans
to make things legal.
- Then the marriages don't work out.
- Is that what you think of me?
Stop it.
- Ask me if I care for him.
- Why? You haven't told the truth so far.
Why don't you ask me if I love him?
Why don't you...
BABE: Wait a minute. Elsa! Wait!
Let her go. She's a phoney.
She's after something. Can't you see it?
Stay out of it!
- You ordered Scylla to be prompt?
- Ja.
SZELL: You keep me waiting.
Why? To upset me?
DOC: Good evening.
SZELL: I'm not one
to be mocked. Behave...
DOC: Don't give me shit
about my behaviour.
Not after what you've been pulling.
- I've done nothing.
- So Chen acted on his own?
I don't mind you hiring him,
but getting my brother involved?
- It was nothing.
- It was a violation.
We do not involve family, ever.
Think of it as a warning. Nothing more.
(GRUNTS)
Think of that as a warning
and nothing more.
SZELL: You'd like to fight, wouldn't you?
It will not happen.
I'm much too old
and far too smart for that.
But we must talk. Truthfully.
- Are you to be trusted?
- No.
Is that the truth,
or are you trying again to upset me?
- You'll go to the bank sooner or later.
- Perhaps I've already been.
If so, you wouldn't be here with me.
- What else do you know?
- I know you're panicking.
- You think you'll get robbed.
- Who would do that?
- Obviously, you think I would.
- Well?
- Can I trust you?
- You never could. You only had to.
We're talking of my safety.
- May I be candid?
- Yes.
I couldn't give a fuck about you...
(GASPS)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello? Hi, Elsa.
Are you all right? Did you get my note?
I've been trying you for two hours.
Finally, I just went running.
I'm sorry about your brother.
- It doesn't matter.
- It does!
I don't care. Forget it. It didn't happen.
I wanted to explain.
I lied about the Swiss, because...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Take it easy, will you?
I can't understand.
Let me come over.
Okay? I'll take a shower, I'll be there?
Thanks. Okay, bye.
(EXHALES)
(YELLS)
Doc!
- What? What?
- Babe...
I can't hear.
You look at me
like I'm doing something wrong,
like I did something wrong,
I don't understand it.
I don't know anything.
- DETECTIVE 1: Your name?
- BABE: I told you my name!
- DETECTIVE 1: Take it easy.
- Thomas Babington Levy.
DETECTIVE 1: You're a student.
I come from a family of historians.
My card is proof.
Please put the papers down.
Tell them. Put the papers down!
DETECTIVE 1: Take it easy.
What's in the papers?
It's a paper I'm writing.
DETECTIVE 2: Would you
tell me who this is?
It's my father.
DETECTIVE 1:
Where can we contact him?
He's not alive any more.
- DETECTIVE 2: Is this yours?
- Yes. The license is in the drawer.
I don't know anything.
Why ask about this?
It has nothing to do with it.
DETECTIVE 1: Okay, enough.
- Here.
- Thanks.
DETECTIVE 1: I know this wasn't easy
and this is a bad time for you,
but it's gotta be done,
you can understand that, right?
Good evening, sir.
- Whoever did it must have set him up.
- Get them all out of here.
I'll get the ambulance guys.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I'm sorry to intrude.
I was a friend of your brother's.
My name is Peter Janeway.
Call me Janey. All my friends do.
I'm not your friend.
Listen.
- I'm anxious as you to find who did this.
- I'm a little more anxious.
- I think it may have been political.
- Political? Why?
Considering what your brother did.
And your father, of course.
- What about my father?
- He was H.V. Levy, for Christ sakes.
He's been dead for 20 years,
and he was innocent.
What are you saying?
Get off my back!
They've been after me for two hours!
I didn't mean to imply...
They told me they were done!
What are you saying?
I'm sorry.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Come in.
Listen...
Why don't we begin
with what happened tonight, hmm?
Perhaps you could
give me some of the details.
I was here. Doc died. You came.
That's it?
I'm a demon for details.
- You want me to explain, then?
- That's right.
- Where did your brother live?
- In Washington.
- What did he do?
- Oil business.
Wrong.
I know exactly how Doc made his living.
The closest he got to the oil business
was when he filled up with gas.
- Tell me what you're talking about.
- All right. Follow me.
Doc lived in Washington,
which is the centre of...
- Government.
- Correct.
All the branches are competitive.
Truth is they're all paranoid schmucks.
When the gap gets too large between
what the FBI can handle effectively
and what the CIA
doesn't wanna deal with, we step in.
- Who's we?
- The Division.
- And my brother worked with you?
- Yes.
You're full of shit.
- What do you do exactly?
- We provide.
- Provide what?
- Anything.
And you two work together?
Why didn't Doc tell me?
Why did he lie to me?
He was afraid you'd be
disappointed in him, I expect.
We were very close for many years.
Believe me.
I know whereof I speak.
Doc was desperate to get here.
Remember anything he said?
He said my name a couple of times.
Okay, I'm just guessing now,
but whoever killed him
will probably want to speak to you.
- I don't know anything.
- They won't know till they talk with you.
I'm staying across the park,
at The Carlyle,
and if you don't mind,
I'd like to use you as bait.
- Bait.
- Yes.
- Will they come tonight?
- No.
I know it's risky, and I don't wanna
force you to do it. It's up to you.
(SIGHS)
(CREAKING)
MAN 1: Tub.
MAN 2: All right.
(CREAKING)
MAN: (WHISPERING)
All right, I got it. Here it is.
Turn it off. All right.
Shit. Jesus!
Shit.
(WOOD CRACKING)
BABE: Help!
Help! Help! Please!
Somebody help me!
Help!
Help! Help!
(GASPING)
Is it safe?
Are you talking to me?
- Is it safe?
- Is what safe?
- I don't know what you mean.
I can't tell you
if something is safe or not
unless I know specifically
what you're talking about.
Is it safe?
Tell me what the "it" refers to.
Yes, it's safe. It's very safe.
So safe you wouldn't believe it.
Is it safe?
No, it's not safe.
It's very dangerous. Be careful.
Relax, relax.
Come on. Open. Open. It's okay.
- That hurt? I should think it would.
- Uh-huh.
You should take better care
of your teeth.
You have quite a cavity here.
- Is it safe?
- I told you I can't tell you... (SCREAMS)
- Think he knows?
- Of course. He's being very stubborn.
No, please. Please don't. No.
SZELL: It's okay.
Is it not remarkable?
Simple oil of cloves
and how amazing the results.
Life can be that simple.
Relief, discomfort.
Now, which of these I next apply,
that decision is in your hands,
so take your time and tell me.
- Is it safe?
- Please...
Please stop.
- MAN 1: Take him.
- MAN 2: I got him.
More.
Thank you.
(GROANS)
(YELLING)
Thank you. Thank you.
Things are coming together.
Down, or your head gets blown off.
Those two guys I wasted
work for Christian Szell.
- Know that name?
- No.
He did experiments at Auschwitz.
He was called The White Angel,
Der Weiﬂe Engel, due to his white hair.
The wealthiest and most wanted Nazi
left alive.
He's hiding out in Uruguay.
In '45, Szell told Jews in Auschwitz
he'd help them escape for a price.
He started out with gold, naturally,
but went on to diamonds.
Heard this?
Szell saw the end early.
His brother took
the diamonds to America
to a safe deposit box in New York.
Szell's brother had the key.
The only other key
Szell kept in Uruguay.
If he comes out to use it,
he'll expose himself to great risk.
Everything went fine till his brother
got killed by an oil truck.
Why was it natural to start with gold?
He took it from the Jews' teeth
before he burned them.
Szell was a dentist.
He's not coming to America,
Mr Janeway. He's here.
No. We'd have known it.
The dentist almost killed me.
He kept saying, "Is it safe?"
White hair? Keep your head down!
Did he have white hair?
He was bald.
He's shaved his head!
He's here, and he's panicked.
- Why is he after me?
- Your brother was a diamond courier.
Szell thinks Doc said something to you
before he died.
- Did he?
- You say my brother worked for Szell?
No! He worked for us.
Everything we do cuts both ways.
Szell ratted on all his buddies.
He kept track on all the Nazis.
When we wanted to bring one in,
we went to Szell.
Babe, you gotta do one thing for me,
just one thing.
- Quit protecting Doc!
- I'm not.
- He kept alive to say something.
- He didn't.
- He must have. Tell me!
- Nothing!
Shit!
I thought you killed them.
You killed them!
You fucking killed them!
You killed my brother!
I don't think he knows anything.
I think he knows too much.
You can afford to think what you wish.
I can't.
The gun had blanks,
the knife a retractable blade.
Hardly original, but effective enough.
I think you'll agree.
(WATER RUNNING)
I'm told you are a graduate student.
Brilliant, yeah?
You're an historian,
and I am part of history.
I should have thought
you would have found me interesting.
Frankly, I am disappointed
in your silence.
Why do you have so little accent?
I had alexia as a child.
Alexia is a disease...
I know, it's where
you can't understand written speech.
Highest marks.
At any event, my writing is childish still,
but I'm a fanatic about spoken language.
I envy you your school days. Enjoy them.
It's the last time in your life
no one expects anything of you.
I know I behaved terribly,
but I had to be sure what you knew.
You see...
I'm positive
your brother meant to rob me
when I left the bank with my diamonds.
I don't know anything.
- Did Scylla plan the robbery alone?
- Robbery?
- You know the value of diamonds?
- No, I don't.
Neither do I. Not in today's market.
Tomorrow, I must go and find out
before I go to the bank.
You see...
Your brother was incredibly strong.
Strength is often inherited.
He died in your arms.
He travelled far
and in great pain to do that.
(WHIRRING)
There has to be a reason.
I don't know anything.
Karl!
(YELLS)
Please don't worry.
I'm not going into that cavity.
That nerve's already dying.
A live, freshly-cut nerve
is infinitely more sensitive,
(WHIRRING)
so I'll just drill into a healthy tooth
until I reach the pulp.
Unless, of course,
you can tell me that it's safe.
(WHIRRING LOUDLY)
(SCREAMING)
SZELL: Erhard!
He knew nothing.
If he'd known, he would have told.
Get rid of him.
JANEWAY: I don't think
you've heard the news.
- What is that?
- Your flight is at 1:00 tomorrow.
- You are a very confident young man.
- It's all a front.
Just think of me
as any young executive on the come.
You're uncontrollable.
What you offer us is valuable, but it's
not worth the chaos you're causing.
And if I'm unable to conclude
my business by 1:00?
You'll just have to manage that,
won't you?
As far as we're concerned,
Mr Szell, you're a relic.
And you're on your way.
I find you rather detestable.
May I say that
without hurting your feelings?
Praise from Caesar.
I'm just doing my job.
I believe in my country.
So did we all.
Jesus!
Come on, unlock it.
(GRUNTS)
JANEWAY: Get up.
Get him!
(SIREN WAILING)
Hey!
Stop!
(GUN FIRING)
- He went around the corner.
- Get the fucking car!
(PANTING)
(FIRING)
He's on the north ramp.
Come on, for Christ sakes!
(HONKING)
JANEWAY: Run him down!
Run him down!
What the fuck...
(HORN BLARING)
Why are you walking away?
You guys are crazy!
BABE: No, don't slow down. Keep going.
You can drop me at the corner.
- Do you have a dime for the phone?
- DRIVER: What, a dime?
Here.
Take this and just give me a dime.
Wait. Let me see what you got.
It's a Rolex. My brother's watch.
Hey, come on.
Please.
Here is a dime, man.
Here's some more change.
- Hello?
- Elsa.
Babe? What's the time?
I don't know. About 5:00.
I want you to do something for me,
to meet me.
- Where?
- 51 st and Broadway.
- I can't.
- There's an all-night drugstore.
Why? Tell me what...
Just get hold of a car.
Please. In an hour.
- But why?
- I'll tell you later.
- 51 st and Broadway.
- 51st and Broadway.
Bye.
(BUZZING)
(WOMAN PROTESTING)
Mrs Melendez,
I have to see your son, it's important.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BUZZING)
MAN: I'll cut your finger off
if you don't let go of that buzzer!
Melendez, it's me.
I want you to do a job for me.
One more time and I'm coming down
with the butcher knife!
Please. I'm from across the street.
I want you to do something for me.
- Who is this?
- It's Tom Levy from across the street.
- Who the fuck is this?
- Tom... Creepy. It's the Creep.
- Creepy?
- Open up.
(DOOR BUZZES)
What happened to you?
Come here.
Listen, man, it's past my bedtime.
I want you to rob my apartment.
Why?
Some guys are after me.
I got a gun in my desk.
And get me some clothes.
What's in it for me?
I got a TV set. I got a hi-fi.
You can take it all. Do it.
What's the catch?
The catch is it's dangerous.
Please do it.
That ain't the catch, it's the fun.
Come on.
(DOG BARKING)
(RATTLING)
All right, guys.
Let's go, move out of there.
Blow it out your ass, motherfucker.
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR SLAMS)
- Hi.
- Hi, Elsa.
- How... Babe, what's happened?
- God, I'm glad you're here.
- What's happened to you?
- I'll tell you later. Let's go.
(WINDCHIME TINKLING)
You like it?
I must get the key.
- How did you find this place?
- I hope the key is here.
How did you find it?
A girlfriend in my building.
It belongs to her family. Ah.
Is it Szell's?
Szell's?
You're very tired.
Where is Janeway?
Huh?
- What do you do for Szell?
- Babe...
- What?
- I'm sorry...
Tell me when they're coming.
What did you do for him?
- Let me explain.
- Explain it.
- Explain my brother! Say it!
- Please. Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Tell me when they're coming.
I don't know, Babe. I...
Soon.
Good.
Thanks.
- When did you know?
- I didn't.
Till now.
Whose house is this?
ELSA: Szell's brother's.
(BANGING)
No, Babe.
There's nobody here. Let's go.
(SHUSHES)
Please, Babe. Let's go.
We still have time.
I can get you out of here.
BABE: So that was Szell.
- What's keeping them?
- ELSA: I don't know.
What were you?
Were you Szell's mistress?
- Tell me.
- No. I was a courier. Nothing more.
I took money from Paris into Uruguay,
that's all.
I never even met him.
God, you are pretty.
BABE: Where is he?
Where is Szell?
- Where is Szell?
- It's a lovely morning.
BABE: Hold it!
We're awaiting further instructions.
Do we take three giant steps or what?
Cops will be here soon.
I don't think the police are coming.
Neither do I, but I could be wrong.
We can work out what you wanna
work out, but shouldn't we do it inside?
Okay. One at a time.
No! Over here. Over here.
Sit. Sit!
You should realise we're only
authorised to go to certain limits.
Cut the bullshit. Tell me where Szell is.
Why did you let us get so close?
You're all in my killing range now.
Taken target practice, have you?
A wizard at hitting paper?
It's not the same with flesh.
Smashing bone is different...
I wanna know where...
Hey.
...Szell is.
If the police were coming,
you wouldn't be so panicky.
- BABE: They're coming.
- Somehow I don't believe that.
Turn it on.
Easy. Easy.
We're all gonna take it easy.
Isn't that right, Erhard?
We're all just gonna sit here
and wait for the police, right, Karl?
Where is he?
Elsa, why don't you move away,
give the boy some room to breathe?
No!
- Drop it! Get it down!
- All right, it's down!
I didn't want this to happen,
but I couldn't trust them.
I'll give you Szell for your brother.
He's at a bank at 58th and Madison.
Go.
Go!
Babe! (GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
- What are you looking for, sir?
- Anything we can show you today?
Morning, sir.
Anything I could interest you in today?
We heard that you were not there,
but I wouldn't say it was relevant.
I can't give you that much.
That much I don't make.
DEALER: Okay.
Maybe we can make a trade.
No trade, I want cash for the ring.
If you want cash, I'll give you cash.
Let me take a look at it.
I'd like to see a three-carat diamond.
Why?
If you just wanna see, go window-shop.
- I was interested in...
- First there's gotta be trust.
So I'll get this three-carat stone.
We'll take it to this
independent appraiser I know.
If he doesn't swear
I'm practically giving this stone away,
I just have to get myself
a new brother-in-law.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm gonna do you a big favour.
- Can't you just tell me what it's worth?
- I'm no high-pressure artist. I sell value.
You never answer me!
SZELL: I'm only interested
in gem quality.
Around the size of my little fingernail.
DEALER: You're talking six carat, sir.
More probably.
- Would that be prohibitive?
- Fifteen thousand.
Fifteen...
Per carat, naturally.
Naturally.
MAN: I know you.
Perhaps you do.
I'm pretty good at faces myself.
- I know this man.
- Christopher Hesse. How do you do?
Christopher Hesse. How do you do?
Wait, let me think.
I think...
Surely, you came
to our antique shop in London?
No, that wasn't it.
- No? But you've been to London?
- But I don't think...
Hesse of Golders Green, since '33,
when we got out of Germany.
Our shop is quite fashionable now.
I always wanted to visit London.
I suggest you hurry while it's still there.
I thank you for your time.
I'm sorry, 90,000 is far too high for me.
Our little shop isn't that fashionable.
Thank you.
I know that man.
It can't be... Szell?
Szell.
Szell!
Szell! Szell!
My God! Stop him!
Szell! Stop Szell!
It's Szell. Der Weiﬂe Engel!
Der Weiﬂe Engel is here.
Oh, my God. Stop him.
Stop him! Der Weiﬂe Engel!
Der Weiﬂe Engel.
He has to be stopped.
My God! He gets away.
Der Weiﬂe Engel is here!
Szell. Stop him! Oh, please help me.
He's a beast.
He's a murderer. You must stop him.
Oh, my God, there he goes!
He's getting away!
MAN: She's crazy.
Der Weiﬂe Engel is here!
Stop him! Stop him!
I will stop him! I will stop him!
- The beast! The beast!
- (TYRES SREECHING)
(HONKING)
(PEOPLE CLAMOURING)
Szell!
I know who you are, you murderer.
I know who you are!
Help! Help!
The man needs help here!
Help! Quick! A doctor! Quick!
58th Street and Madison.
(DOOR BUZZING)
- Morning, sir. Thank you.
- Thank you.
GUARD: Two-five-nine-six-six.
All finished, Henry. Thank you.
- Everything all right, Mrs Rosenheim?
- Yes. See you next week.
There you are, sir.
Close the door for the light, sir.
No one can enter.
Ha!
Everything all right, sir?
Yeah!
Yes!
BABE: It isn't safe.
Move.
They're all dead. Move.
SZELL: You'd be foolish
to do anything hasty.
BABE: Move.
SZELL: I have things in my possession...
BABE: Just keep moving.
DISPATCHER: Name is Arnie, walks
with a limp, green jacket, brown pants.
Ten-four.
- What are you guys doing in here?
- BABE: We'll just be a little while.
- There's nobody allowed in here.
- Well, get out!
Get out!
Hurry up!
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Okay, let's see what you got.
If you will just give me a chance
to get this open.
That's okay. Take your time.
All this happened because you were
afraid you were gonna be robbed?
Yes.
But you weren't sure.
No.
Jesus Christ.
I was in a state of hysteria, you know.
Don't you want to
take a closer look than that?
- No.
- You see...
In a sense, one becomes
more emotional with age.
First after a lifetime of being taken
by friends and enemies alike,
and then, just when you think
you have your possession sure,
your health begins to go.
- That is, of course, the ultimate theft.
- That's close enough.
- In the circumstances, one's paranoia...
- Close enough!
- ...gets out of hand.
- Stop!
Well?
What are you going to do now,
shoot me?
No, I don't think so.
Then you'll take these from me.
If I could say a word about that?
No, you can keep them.
You can keep
as many as you can swallow.
Pardon me,
I'm not quite sure what you said.
Swallow?
Yeah, swallow.
Eat.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
- You're joking.
- No, I don't think so.
I'm not joking.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(YELLS)
No, wait!
That man who was here
has seen your gun!
He'll bring others!
Swallow!
This is madness!
Swallow.
Again.
No.
I won't.
You'll have to shoot me.
Come on.
Shoot.
You won't.
You can't.
You're too weak.
Your father was weak in his way,
your brother in his, now you in yours.
You are all so predictable.
(YELLING)
Go get them!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)