Wilee.
(AUDIO REWINDING)
Shit.
(LAUGHS)
WILEE: I can't
work in an office.
I don't like wearing suits.
I like to ride.
Fixed gear,
steel frame, no brakes.
The bike cannot coast.
The pedals never stop turning.
Can't stop.
Don't want to either.
(CAR HORN HONKS
AND TIRES SCREECH)
There are 1.500
bike messengers
on the street
in New York City.
You can e-mail it,
FedEx it, fax it, scan it,
but when none of
that shit works
and this thing has to be
at that place by this time,
you need us.
Some of us
get killed out here.
Pedestrians are a menace.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(WOMAN YELLS)
Cabs are killers.
One time or another
we all get hit.
Sometimes we gotta hit back.
If you're not gonna use it,
I guess you don't need it.
My mirror!
(GROANING)
WILEE: And we stick together,
'cause most people
just wish
we'd get off the street.
"Go get a haircut.
Take a shower.
Get out of the way."
Stop!
(CAR HORN HONKS
AND TIRES SCREECH)
Pay heed!
WILEE: They have no idea
why anyone
would risk their lives
in a death maze
for 80 bucks on a good day.
But if you're out here
thinking about the money,
you're not gonna
be around to spend it.
(GRUNTS)
(CAR HORN HONKS)
Hey!
(LAUGHS)
(PHONE BEEPS)
(OVER PHONE)
Hey, it's Vanessa.
Leave me a message
and I'll call you back.
(BEEP)
'Kay, I'm actually
leaving a voice mail now.
This is demeaning.
Why won't you call me?
Hey.
Samantha Harris, TVM?
Yep.
And sign here, please.
You need a number, too?
You got a pickup for me?
You already got it.
Positive I did not.
No, someone from
your company.
What'd he look like?
He was prettier than me.
Whoo!
Hey, watch your back.
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE BEEPS)
Manny's office,
this is Manny.
Dude, you jumped my route?
I had a drop-off.
It was sitting
right there, man.
Dude, but that's my tag.
Then how come it's in my bag?
I'm coming to get it.
Wasting your time, man.
I'm almost there already.
Well, I'm right behind you.
Yo, it isn't yours,
it's mine now.
Like your girlfriend.
Oh, I'm getting
worried, dude.
Real concerned.
It's been a couple of days.
Manny's a gentleman,
but Manny's got appetites.
Click!
Asshole.
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
No, no, no, sweetheart.
Think Gandhi,
not Sitting Bull. Boom!
Yes, I'm already on it.
Sweetheart, I gotta go.
(PHONE RINGING)
Security Courier.
Uh-huh.
Get line two a 20 on Squid.
Got it.
I'm right here.
Goddamn radio got run over.
Raj. What the hell, man.
Manny jumped my route?
Is it so?
Yes, it's so.
You shouldn't try
to be Zen, dude.
You're wearing a gold chain.
Ah, Tito, my midtown monster,
slow and steady comes in last.
You get passed
by a hot dog cart today?
The pedals turn, Raj.
Not just the left one,
but the right one, too.
I have no idea
what he's talking about.
The words he says,
they don't go together
to create meaning
in a traditional sense,
but I believe
it is profound.
Hey, I'm light.
You got anything else today?
I need another job.
Ah, the pedals turn,
my friend, the pedals turn.
That doesn't mean anything.
Ah, well,
Tito said it, not me.
No hello?
RAJ: Hey, Vanessa,
I hope you're gonna fix
that wheel and
get back out there.
Yep.
Why didn't
you call me back?
I don't have
anything else to say.
Okay, I know you're not
about to kiss me right now.
Why? You don't want me to?
My hand to God, I don't.
Then why did
your back just arch?
It did not.
Yes, it did.
Nope.
Like it always does.
See, you did it again.
Stop!
Really? Come on.
No.
Okay. Ride safe.
(PHONE RINGING)
Security Courier.
Yo, Nima, what's up?
Yeah, he's here.
Where we going?
Okay.
Okay. All right.
Great. Got it.
Wilee, you're in luck.
Your alma mater summons.
116th Street entrance,
law school main office,
drop is in Chinatown.
I need you south of
Pell in 90 minutes.
Let's go.
You're getting 50
for that run at least.
Give me 40.
Forget it. Tito.
Never mind.
Marco. Polo.
I got a nice long
run for you guys.
Can't do it.
Why not?
Gotta get hammered.
Fair enough.
Come on, man.
I'm tired, I'm hungry,
my day is taking a turn
for the shitty,
give me the 40.
I'll give you 30.
Don't screw it up.
It's premium rush.
Hey, Wilee.
You and me, man!
Central Park. Just one lap.
Straight up bicycle race.
No whale riding,
no bumper surfing,
none-a your alleycat bullshit.
I'll kick your ass, man.
Have you seen my thighs?
(PHONE RINGING)
What do you want?
So you into Spandex now?
On your right!
God, can you
forget about Manny?
He's just helping me move.
Move?
What, you guys are moving?
No, I'm moving,
she's staying.
Why?
I don't wanna talk about it.
She wants me out
by the end of the day.
What, did you get
into a fight with her, too?
I'll call you back.
Shit.
Hey, walk that thing!
Wilee? Oh, it is you.
Hey, man.
Hey, what you
been up to, man?
You know,
running reds,
killing peds.
I heard you
never took the bar.
It's on my list.
Don't stress about it.
Hey, they say if you
snort some Ritalin,
it's a cakewalk.
Sage advice, Mr. Hand.
Oh.
Hey, Nima. They didn't
tell me it was you
who called. That it?
It must be there by 7:00.
Deliver only to Sister Chen.
Where am I going?
Chinatown. 147, Doyers.
Is that going
to be difficult?
Would be for some.
It's a tiny street,
very hard to see...
I'll find it.
Time is now, uh, 5:33.
Sign here
and print your name
under it, please.
You okay?
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
I heard you got,
uh, roommate troubles.
I feel bad,
I kinda hooked you guys up.
Deliver only to Sister Chen.
It must be there by 7:00.
It's extremely important.
Always is.
Gonna need the envelope.
Thanks. Have a nice day.
MAN: Hey!
Oh, hey, there you are.
♪ Drugs, give me drugs,
give me drugs
♪ I don't need it,
but I'll sell what you got
♪ Take the cash
and I'll keep it
♪ Eight legs to the wall,
hit the gas, kill them all
♪ And we crawl, and we crawl,
and we crawl
♪ You be my detonator ♪
Hey!
Hey, excuse me,
messenger guy.
That envelope you picked up,
I gotta ask for it back.
Who are you?
Forrest J. Ackerman.
Head of campus security.
The woman who gave
you the envelope,
she's not authorized
to use the school account.
It's an internal matter
I've been investigating.
Not your problem.
Can I have
the envelope, please?
Yeah, the thing is,
once it goes in the bag,
it's gotta stay in the bag
unless I hear
from a dispatcher.
Fine. Call him.
I'll talk to him. I got
the receipt right here.
Nima gave that to you?
Who?
Nima.
You don't know the name
of the woman
you're, um, investigating?
Oh, yeah.
Nima, right. I'm sorry,
I couldn't hear you.
Your mouth was full.
Thing is, man,
company I work for,
it's called
"Security Courier."
The "Security" part
means that once people
give us their shit,
we don't just hand it out
to random strangers
on the street, so...
Listen, I just spent $7
on this delicious
urban food log,
so if you'd step aside
and let me eat,
that'd be great.
What's your name?
Wilee.
Wile E? Like the coyote?
Mmm-hmm.
That's cute.
Thanks.
You got a real name?
A girlfriend?
Family?
People who give a shit
if they see you again?
Who are you, man?
(CHUCKLING)
I'm the guy
you don't fuck with.
Hold my log.
Hey!
Have a nice day, douche bag!
Okay.
(PHONE RINGING)
I just wanted
to say I was sorry.
That thing
was important to me.
Maybe that doesn't
mean shit to you...
No, it means something to me.
I just forgot, that's all.
Okay, I get it.
Look, this is
three sorrys now.
It's actually only two.
Well,
you hung up on one of 'em,
so that's on you.
I don't get it.
Honestly? Watch it!
MAN: Whoa!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
VANESSA: Excuse me.
I just don't get it.
I mean, you have opportunity
and all that brain
and you throw it away.
Look, why are we
having this conversation?
You get it.
You ride like I do.
No, I ride,
but not like you, Wilee.
I put a brake
on my bike and I use it.
Yeah, and that brake's
gonna get you killed.
You should get rid of that.
The worst shit that
ever happened to me
happened when I had a brake.
Brakes are death.
You know what?
That thing you say,
it's not as cute anymore.
You could have
any job you want.
When I see a guy
in a gray business suit,
my age,
makes my balls
shrivel up into my abdomen.
Whatever.
Hi, Alonzo.
We get paid to ride.
What could be
better than that?
Do you know why I ride?
Because I hate
waiting tables. Thank you.
Look, I'm sorry
that I didn't come
to your school thing.
But what do you want me
to do about it right now?
My "school thing"?
It was graduation
and you blew it off
for a race.
Look, I know it took me
eight years to get my degree,
but I'm gonna get
a decent job and sit behind
a desk all day.
I don't need anyone
in my life telling me
that it's meaningless
'cause it means
something to me.
And I need to know
that I can count on you.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Hello?
I gotta go.
Of course you do.
I'm gonna call you back.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN HONKING)
Hey, what?
Douche bag?
What the hell's
the matter with you?
Come on, son, this is silly.
You're gonna skin your knee.
Oh, I think
I'll be all right.
Thank you, though.
Just pull over,
right up here.
Come on.
You're a very
uncooperative guy,
you know that?
Come on, give it to me!
No!
You take care now!
Oh, shit!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
(CAR HORN BLARING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Whoa! Ah!
Shit.
I'm chasing a bicycle.
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
Jesus.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(HORNS HONKING)
Ah, tricky.
You moron!
You're right!
You maniac!
Sorry! My fault!
Hey! Give me the envelope!
What?
You can hear me,
you little shit.
Sorry, I can't hear you!
Ah, what's it to you?
Come on!
(HORN HONKING)
Give me the goddamn envelope!
Oh, that? No.
No, no, no.
(HORN HONKING)
I just wish
they wouldn't ride on
the sidewalk, you know?
I mean, look,
I understand you've got
a job to do.
MAN: Whoa! Oh!
Excuse me!
Ah!
Whoa!
Hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey! Slow down!
(GRUNTS)
Now, see?
I told you this
wouldn't end well for you.
Huh?
Where'd you go?
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Hey!
Come here!
Yo! Hey!
Whoa.
Yo, you crazy?
NYPD! I wanna talk
to you for a minute!
Great.
Hey! Pull over!
BOY: Hey!
Ah!
Delinquent scum!
Red shirt on the bicycle!
NYPD!
You just caused
an accident back there!
Pull over!
(HONKS HORN)
Come on.
Oh, shit!
(GROANING)
My baby!
(GRUNTS AND SCREAMS)
(HORNS HONKING)
(SCREAMS)
Shit.
You little shit.
VANESSA: Thanks for
helping me with this.
MANNY: You know
I'm always there for you.
Well, I couldn't
have done it on my own,
so thanks.
Look, it's none
of my business,
but, um, you know
you saved yourself
a lot of heartache
breaking up
with the Coyote Man.
I mean, seriously,
you know, he's crazy.
And it's not like
he's some great cyclist
or something.
I mean, he's just got
a death wish, that's all.
That's no skill.
Only reason
he beats me in alleycats
is 'cause the man
got a mental instability.
I mean,
all that fixie bullshit.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
You know,
the no brakes, no gears.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah, I hear ya.
Look, think about it, okay?
He's broke his
left collarbone twice.
Got a couple concussions,
a pin in his wrist.
That's when he was
doing all that trick stuff.
He's not into that anymore.
Okay, sure,
but the way he rides, hmm?
What does that tell you?
How much
he loves it, I guess.
Then he's got him
some confused
priorities, babe.
Whoa.
Yeah. No, Manny.
(LAUGHS)
Hey, uh, my roommate's
in some kind of trouble
and she won't text me back.
Can you just drop me
off over on Broadway?
Please? I gotta go find her.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Thanks.
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
Jesus.
Shit.
This douche bag tried to...
I can hear you.
Sorry. Uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Guy tried to rob me
and run me over with his car.
Are you injured?
No.
You wanna file a complaint?
No, I want him arrested.
It's like attempted
vehicular manslaughter,
or whatever.
Is it, Your Honor?
Have a seat,
someone will be right out to
take your statement.
I also have a picture
of his license plate number.
That's fantastic.
Have a seat, someone
will be right with you.
Thank you for your concern.
(SIGHS)
(WHIRRING)
Holy moly.
Hey. What do ya know?
Detective Monday graces us
with his presence.
Yeah. I'm sorry I'm late.
Your wife had a lot
of unusual requests.
Yeah? She still
got that rash?
Mmm. Yeah.
I worked around it.
(LAUGHING)
What's the matter
with your face, Monday?
Goddamn tooth
went abscess on me,
vicious little bastard.
I go to the dentist,
son of a bitch got
me in the waiting room
an hour and a half.
Finally,
he sits me in the chair,
takes one look at it...
Yanks it right out of my head.
Can you believe it?
Yeah, that's why I'm late.
(RATTLING)
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
Oh, yeah.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah. Got you now, sucker.
Monster hand, monster hand.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
MONDAY:
Jesus, you're kidding me!
Goddamn shit! No!
Next time better luck,
Bobby, huh?
Not bad hand, not bad hand.
Almost, Bobby.
Everything okay, Bobby?
Oh, it's great. I just
gotta get to work is all.
Same old, same old.
Mr. Monday, Mr. Sunday.
(GRUNTS)
Rebuy.
(SPEAKS CANTONESE)
Hello? Rebuy.
Let me get you a Coke, Bobby.
No, thank you.
I need five grand.
What's the problem?
It's up to 17.
Which happens
to be my lucky number.
This isn't your game, man.
Anglos don't have
the math for Pai Gow.
Mr. Lin thinks...
What does Mr. Lin think?
Huh? He can't get shut down
'cause a cop owes him
a few dollars?
Come on, you don't
wanna talk like that.
MONDAY: 72nd Street.
Brooklyn Players.
They all went
down eventually.
They all go down,
Charlie Chan.
Maybe you need to go
get some fresh air.
You take a walk in the park!
I want a rebuy!
MONDAY: Sorry, sorry,
sorry, sorry, sorry. Sorry.
Sorry.
Look, if you really
need cash...
I shouldn't be
telling you this.
What?
You know
that bitch snakehead
my sister works for?
Yeah.
She said they got
a serious ticket
coming down from a hawaladar
in Morningside, tonight.
Mmm. How much is it worth?
Fifty grand.
And that ticket
is as good as cash.
If you get
a hold of that thing
and bring it here,
your money problems
with us are over.
Maybe I take
a little finder's fee,
let's just say a third.
Mr. Lin gets the rest,
and you're even.
What do I look like,
a change-snatcher to you?
I'm a cop.
I look like a purse-pincher,
a goddamn mugger?
I'm just trying
to help you out.
You don't wanna do that,
then be a big boy,
go to the Shy,
borrow what you gotta borrow.
Mr. Lin gets his 17,
you're right back in.
Yeah.
What's the vig?
Twenty points.
That's ridiculous.
Don't take it.
From our friends
in Ozone Park?
You wish.
Brighton Beach.
Ah, shit.
Seriously, don't take it.
Give it to me.
(GRUNTS)
Hey, where you going?
He took it
across the street.
I have now seen it all.
Look at that sick bastard.
(WOMAN SPEAKING CANTONESE)
MONDAY: Come on.
Yeah, come on, come on.
MAN: Are you sure you want
to put that all in one hand?
MONDAY: Yeah, I'm sure.
Come on.
This is the one.
Let's see,
what do we got here?
What do we got?
Ah, nah, nah, nah.
Keep your eyes to yourself,
all right, buddy?
I'm not done.
Six plus seven is shit!
Six plus five is shit.
Eight plus five is six...
Is seven... Is shit.
It's all shit,
no matter how you add it up.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
Yeah.
Whatever, whatever.
Thanks a lot.
(GRUNTING)
That a Chinese phone book?
Yeah.
Don't stop yet.
Why, you getting tired?
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Tired, my ass.
(MONDAY GROANING)
What... That...
That's my tooth!
You piece of shit!
I said nothing permanent!
Hey, I'm talking to you!
Get over here!
There are goddamn rules
about this shit!
Okay? You think
it doesn't apply?
I'll take a lump
or two if I cross the line,
but you think
I'm gonna grow new teeth
at my age?
Mr. Lin...
Mr. Lin!
Hey!
(GROANS)
What? Is Mr. Lin in charge?
Is Mr. Lin President
of the United States?
Let me tell ya
something, boys.
I am a cop!
You do not do this!
(PASSING TRAIN
CLANKING ON TRACK)
Hey. Come on,
it wasn't that bad.
(GROANING)
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
He'll be all right.
Come on. Come on, papi.
(GRUNTS AND COUGHS)
Yeah, there you go. See?
Get your buddy to Bellevue.
Fourteen minutes.
I timed it.
That's how long it took you
to soak yourself in gasoline
and set it on fire.
That ticket
you were talking about?
I think I'm gonna
need the address.
Yeah, the goddamn dentist.
Is that a good enough
reason for you?
Two hours in the chair.
Can you believe it?
Well, a man's gotta do
what a man's gotta do.
I'm gonna go get my morphine.
I'll be right back.
(LOCKS DOOR)
(SIGHS)
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
MAN: You know, I've been
thinking about firemen.
MAN 2: What about 'em?
They hang out together,
you know, they work out.
They cook pasta.
Pose for calendars.
What are you talking about?
We should do that.
I'm not posing
for any calendar.
No towels?
Depressing.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
MAN 1: Hey, look who's here,
Lance Armstrong.
MAN 2: Hey, what's up?
Hey, guys.
Whoa, hold up a minute.
What's up?
What happened to you?
I just got my ass kicked
by a kid on a bicycle.
Jesus, you okay?
I'm all right.
Monday, come on,
we gotta see that guy.
Yeah, all right.
(SIGHS)
DETECTIVE 1:
Monday, seriously,
we gotta go. Let's go.
You talk to him this time.
He responds to you better.
DETECTIVE 2:
Really? I don't know why.
I can't stand the guy.
DETECTIVE 1: Yeah, but he
doesn't know that.
Monday, are you coming?
Uh, yeah, I, uh...
I forgot my bullets.
I'll meet you guys
there, okay?
DETECTIVE 2:
Who forgets their bullets?
DETECTIVE 1: Monday.
Shit.
Hey, red shirt! NYPD!
Come on, dude.
(MUTTERING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, really?
I'm working on it.
MAN: The guy's dead.
What?
The guy you beat up, Bobby.
He didn't even make
the ride to the hospital.
You got a real knack
for making it worse,
you know that?
Mmm.
God damn it.
Uh, I'll make amends.
Start with the money.
Get that ticket.
Bring it to Mr. Lin's
shop on 28th.
You got one hour.
(HORN HONKING)
Heads up. Look out,
look out. Outta the way.
(HORNS HONKING)
(DRIVER SHOUTING)
Police! On your left, lady,
look out!
(HORNS HONKING)
Jesus Christ.
What do you want me to do?
Hello, everybody!
Stand still!
Lady, stand still!
You're good. There you go.
Police!
Coming through.
Lady, please.
Whoa!
Heads up, man.
(GRUNTING)
(HORNS HONKING)
Whoa, buddy!
Oh, my God! Stop already!
You're making it
worse for yourself,
I swear to God!
Keep the kids back!
Keep 'em back! NYPD!
Oh, no!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
God damn it!
(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
(KIDS CHATTERING PLAYFULLY)
Mister!
That way!
(KIDS CLAMORING)
Get your arms inside the bus!
(LINE RINGING)
RAJ OVER PHONE: Dispatch.
What did you do to me, man?
What the hell am I carrying?
Wilee? Where are you?
I do not carry drug shit,
or whatever the hell this is!
It's not drugs.
It can't be drugs.
It's from a highly respected
East Coast college.
It's probably drugs.
Yep.
Listen to me.
I almost got my ass killed
three times in
the last 20 minutes!
And it wasn't my fault!
Is somebody
messing with you?
You need backup?
No. I just wanna
get rid of the thing.
Well, I got nobody else.
The only person here is Tito,
and I can't send him
that far north.
The guy's like 98 years old.
No offense.
(GRUNTS)
Dude, just call the college
and tell them
I'm bringing the package
back, okay? I'm done with it.
No, no, don't take it back!
Come on! Wilee...
Manny.
Just the person
I need to see.
What's up?
Yeah, hello.
Uh, I'm calling about
an order you just picked up.
Order number?
Um... Yep, yep,
got it right here. 2231970.
Yeah, that's it.
Uh, I'm gonna need to change
the delivery address
on that envelope.
Yeah.
Me, I'm Forrest J. Ackerman,
Dean of Students.
I've got
that appointment now.
I'll see you in a bit.
Okay.
Hi.
Hey.
I'm almost done.
My friend borrowed
a truck to help me move,
so I'll be outta here
by 6:00.
Thank you.
I'm sorry it is so sudden.
You will be all right?
Yeah. I'm staying
with my aunt
until I find a place.
Okay, good.
I still don't get
what happened.
Did I do something
to piss you off or something?
No, I told you,
it's a private matter.
Okay.
Excuse me,
I have some things
to take care of.
Whoa.
Where'd you get all that?
This is my business.
Better for you
to stay out of it.
Are you going out with that?
'Cause this is New York City,
you can't walk around
with all that money.
Where are you going?
Down the street.
Where?
The nail salon.
The nail salon?
This is
something I have to do.
I don't have a choice.
Okay. I'm coming with you.
No, thank you.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(INAUDIBLE)
Mr. Leung?
(KNOCKING)
NYPD.
Yeah?
You got a minute?
Count it.
A lot of money
for a young lady.
Took me two years.
I work three jobs.
American dream, huh?
Is to work three jobs?
These days, yes.
(BOTH SPEAKING MANDARIN)
You speak Mandarin?
Yes.
If you lose the ticket
I cannot give you back
the money.
You understand?
This ticket now
is money.
For whoever holds it.
If you have problems
you don't call the police
you call this number.
The Hawala system
settles its own problems.
This money is
for a snakehead?
Yes.
Which one?
Sister Chen.
She won't take cash.
She sent me to you.
Did you tell anyone
you were coming here?
Only my friend.
This city
is not your village.
Many people would rob you
if they know what you have.
My friend
wouldn't tell anyone.
If she did they may be
watching for you.
Can someone else
deliver the ticket for you?
Someone they
won't recognize?
I don't know.
Think about it.
May the Buddha
watch over you.
MAN: Hey!
(PHONE RINGING)
Security Courier.
Yo, Nima. What's up?
I have a pickup
from our office.
It will be ready
in about 10 minutes.
Is Wilee available?
Yeah, he's here.
Where we going?
Okay.
Okay, all right.
Great. Got it.
Wilee, you're in luck.
Your alma mater summons.
Come on!
(CAR HORN HONKS)
Good to see you, too.
Excuse me.
Damn.
Damn it.
Oh, hey. Excuse me.
Yeah.
Uh, NYPD.
I'm looking for
a young Asian woman,
about 22, 23,
blue shirt, black pants.
She just walked by
a minute ago.
Know where I can find her?
Let me think. Yeah, I do.
Hey, walk that thing!
Yeah, I believe so.
Thanks. Have a nice day.
MONDAY: Hey!
Oh, hey, there you are.
Hey, there.
Forrest J. Ackerman,
Internal Revenue Service,
Wire Fraud
Investigation Unit.
Yes?
Now, young lady,
you realize this system
of money transfer
you're participating in
circumvents about 18
different United States
banking regulations?
I'm not sure I understand.
Oh, relax.
It's not you
that's facing jail time.
At least I don't think so.
These hawaladars
are known to prey on
unsuspecting
illegal immigrants.
I'm not illegal.
We don't have
to get into that.
I have a student visa.
With you?
At home.
Oh, see, it's supposed
to be with you at all times.
Yeah, you leave it at home,
that's a good way to
get yourself deported.
But we don't have
to go down to Immigration
and talk about that now.
That's totally unnecessary.
We need to
settle it right here.
I just need
to see the envelope
the hawaladar gave you.
Please.
I don't understand.
What don't you understand?
Why someone who says
he's an IRS agent
has a New York City
police detective's badge.
Come over here.
Okay.
What are you doing?
Let me go!
Okay, smarty-pants.
(GASPS)
You know what
the HR shrink said I have?
(SCREAMS)
Impulse control issues.
(WHIMPERS)
Like you need
a college degree
to figure that out.
I'm telling
you this so you know
that it's in your
best interest
not to lie to me
or waste my time,
but give me
the goddamn envelope.
Please. Before I lose my shit
and rip your throat out.
Clear enough?
What's that?
What did you do?
(GRUNTS)
Damn it. Damn it.
Oh! Hey!
Excuse me!
Messenger guy!
That envelope
you just picked up?
I'm gonna have
to ask for that back.
What are you doing here?
What is up with you?
Nothing.
Well, that doesn't
look like nothing.
It's my problem.
It's personal.
Did that cop find you?
You saw him?
What did you tell him?
He said there were
some people planning to
rob you and he was
trying to stop it.
He wanted to help you.
Oh, yes,
he helped me very much.
What's going on?
You're no friend.
We are not friends.
Yes, we are.
I told you one thing,
and you almost ruined it all.
I'll take care of myself.
Nima. You gotta
start trusting somebody.
Please, tell me.
What's going on?
Wilee?
What are you doing here?
Oh, Nima.
You can't have
delivered already,
it's not possible.
You know what?
It's really uncool to
let a messenger service
deliver your
illegal bullshit.
Where is my envelope?
It's hard enough out there.
Where is it?
I gave it back
to the front desk.
Did a messenger just come by
and drop off an envelope?
Yeah, and another one
just came and picked it up.
Who told them
to change the address?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Hey.
You get your envelope back?
Someone else
come and pick it up?
But it's going to
the wrong place.
What?
Why?
What do you care?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(SOBBING)
So, what was that thing
I was carrying?
It's like a receipt
for a great deal of money.
What's the money for?
A she-tou. A snakehead.
What's that?
It's a kind of importer.
Right. So you're, uh,
involved in some kind
of drug thing?
No.
What are you "importing"?
My son.
I came to this country
on a student visa.
He was to come
right after me.
It is not illegal.
He can travel on my visa.
But then an article
I wrote about Tibet
a long time ago
was posted on the Internet.
For the past years
they have not let him
leave China.
So I have to get
him out another way.
Because I will have my son.
Why'd you have
to go and ask for me?
Huh?
Vanessa always said
you was the best
at what you do.
She says maybe
she can never count on you,
but at work,
there's no one better.
She said that?
Is it true?
Can I count on you?
Let me see
the name on the sheet.
How come you don't
answer my calls?
Because I got
a business to run.
What do you want?
You picked up
an envelope from Nima
at the college office
at 5:30. Where is it?
Jesus, what is it
with this envelope?
People love it, they
hate it, they gotta have it,
they gotta get rid of it.
It's like cigarettes
or Democrats.
Where is the, uh, opener?
Who's got it, Raj?
Your boy Wilee
pussied out.
He said he was
taking it back.
So it's back at the school?
Negativo. Somebody called to
change the drop-off address.
Why are there
a million tools in here
and nothing to open a beer?
A man or a woman?
That would be a dude.
So who's gonna pick it up?
I gave it to Manny.
Shit.
(BEEPING AND TRILLING)
Which way are you going,
you roided-out freak?
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
(SCOFFS)
(HORNS HONKING)
Really?
(LAUGHS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hey, where are you?
Corner of
Broadway and Kiss My Ass.
What do you want?
Need that envelope
you just got.
Oh, do you really?
Yeah, seriously.
You don't know what it is.
I know exactly what it is,
50 bucks if I get
it there by 7:00.
What, you're getting 50?
Raj is only giving me 30!
Yeah, speed costs
money, pussy!
Pull over
and give it to me, man!
I'll explain later.
Okay, pussy,
I'll wait right here.
There, I just stopped
at 112th.
Bullshit, dude,
I can hear the wind.
You're still moving.
Yeah, Manny rides fast!
You should try it,
it feels good!
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Hello? Asshole!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
VANESSA: Wilee?
Oh, now you want to talk?
This whole thing is my fault.
You're hard to keep track of.
I accept your apology.
Can I call you back?
That envelope Nima
gave you is for her kid.
She has a kid.
I know. I just talked to her.
Well, do you still have it?
I'm chasing it down
Broadway right now.
I really gotta call you back.
Manny is taking it
to the wrong people.
I tried to call him,
but he won't pick up.
I'm on it. I'll get him.
No, it's my fault.
You don't need
to get involved.
Well, it's on my way
home anyway.
Just tell me where you are.
Baby, this situation sucks.
I don't want you
anywhere near it.
Hey, Jersey,
you wanna move
your fat-ass SUV!
You know how sexy you are
when you talk like that?
Wilee.
I'll call you when I deliver.
Wait!
Count on it.
Shit.
(GRUNTS)
(HORN HONKING)
(GROANS)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, Wilee, I got an idea.
Why don't you race me for it?
You get to 28th Street
before I do, I'll give you
the envelope.
We'll go through the park.
Enter on 106.
I don't have time
for this bullshit, man.
You don't got
the legs for it, man.
And that steel pig
you're riding
ain't gonna help you neither.
Be like me, baby.
Parlee, custom-cut
carbon fiber!
I am begging you.
My bike fits me
like a Naturalamb, son.
Just listen for one second.
See you in the park.
Manny!
Peace!
God damn it.
(HORNS HONKING)
Okay. You wanna race,
let's race.
(HORNS HONKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Dispatch.
Raj, I need that address
you sent Manny to right now.
Manny? Come on.
Don't the three of you
ever get tired
of this Real World shit
you keep playing?
Raj!
Manny, Wilee, Wilee, Manny.
When does Raj get to climb
Mount Vanessa, hmm?
The address, God damn it!
Hold on, let me look for it.
Piece of shit.
Fellas.
Manny!
I'll give you the 50 bucks!
Manny can't hear you,
Manny's moving too fast.
Come on, man,
you don't wanna drag your
hefty ass up this hill.
Not a problem for me, baby.
I'll just drop
into my little ring.
Hey, Fixie, I bet you
wish you had gears now,
don't you?
Gravity, you is my friend
again, baby.
Whoo! Yeah!
Hey, Wilee,
I got something for ya!
You like that, huh?
Yeah, I know you do,
you little bitch.
(BOTH GRUNT)
I got you, Spandex!
I'm on your wheel!
I'm in your draft, dude!
It's like you're on my team!
Slow down! Hey.
Guys, get off of the path!
21 dispatch.
21 dispatch, come in.
2-1, bike post 3,
you on the air?
Yeah, this is Roselli.
Go ahead.
Your bike freak.
Beat-up white bike,
red shirt?
Yeah?
He's at it again. Park Drive,
headed south towards 7th.
I'm on it.
Careful on the path, ma'am.
Dude,
when's the race starting?
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
(HORNS HONKING)
VANESSA: People, please!
Stay awake! Stay alive!
Look out! Look out!
(HORN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(BARKING)
Whoa!
God!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
That one hurt.
(HORN HONKING)
You're too slow!
Give it up!
NYPD!
Stop the bikes!
Both of you!
(TRUCK BEEPING)
MAN: Back it up!
You're such an asshole!
Screw you, Wilee!
(HORNS HONKING)
Billy, pull forward!
Pull forward!
Hey!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHS)
(BOTH GROANING)
Who the hell are you guys?
Damn!
Oh, is that it?
No! Gimme that! Gimme! No!
Look at you.
(VANESSA CHUCKLES)
You have got
to be kidding me!
Come here! Come here!
Whoo!
(BOTH LAUGH)
(GROANS)
Hey, what happened
to you here?
(SIGHS)
You use that
goddamn brake again?
Yeah, I took that shit off.
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
Hey!
Them! Them!
This way, this way.
(SIREN WHOOPS)
Shit!
What are you doing?
Looking for the thing.
Here it is.
Roll this up.
Really tight, really tight.
Okay. Shit.
I mean, holy shit, right?
I know.
Is it good?
Yeah.
Come on, guys.
Come on!
Hey!
No, you don't.
Oh, shit.
Wilee!
Huh?
(HORNS HONKING)
(HORN HONKS)
Shit.
(HORN BLARING)
VANESSA: Wilee?
Aren't you afraid
you're gonna get killed?
You believe in luck.
When your number's up,
your number's up.
(VOICE OVERLAPPING)
Aren't you afraid
you're gonna get killed?
I mean, the way you ride.
Wilee! Wilee!
Aren't you afraid
you're gonna get killed?
Yeah, but if it comes,
that's just gonna
come outta nowhere.
Am I afraid?
Sure, but that's part of it,
you know?
There's no feeling like that.
When your number's up,
your number's up.
You could say that.
So you're a Buddhist, then.
(CROWD CHEERING)
DREAD: Yo, give it up
for Sleigh Bells!
That's what's up,
that's what's up!
Sleigh Bells, yo!
You believe in luck.
You know it's the Taoists
that believed in luck.
The Buddha rejected all that.
He insisted on
cause and effect.
What kind of
bike messenger are you?
(BOTH LAUGH)
The kind with a Masters
in Bullshit and Obfuscation.
(LAUGHS)
You still haven't answered
my original question.
Aren't you afraid of dying?
I mean, the way you ride.
You wanna know
what scares me
is what happened
to my friends who just
got out of law school.
That is collective insanity.
Compared to that,
going down Broadway
at 50 with no brakes is fine.
Sounds good.
It also sounds like bullshit.
The bike wants to go fast.
It's steadier that way.
I've never been hurt
going all-out.
It's just the hesitation
that'll kill you.
So you're one of those guys.
No brakes.
No, I hate brakes.
Brakes are death.
DREAD: Now it's time
to announce the winner
of the Fifth Annual New York
Bike Messenger
Association Alleycat Race.
Grand prize is $100
and Felipe's bike.
(CROWD CHEERING)
You like that?
To the winner for
the third consecutive year,
the original bumper surfer,
the Coyote Man, Wilee!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Wilee!
That's my boy, right there!
All right, baby!
DREAD: Well, come on.
Come and get it.
Get up here.
Give it up, give it up!
Whoo! Yeah!
You back?
Where's my bike?
Yeah, you're back.
Where's my bike, seriously?
Relax. Relax.
I can't leave
without the bike.
I'm going with him.
No.
What the hell are you doing?
You stay here.
Hey,
I need some help over here.
This woman is unruly.
What?
Calm down.
I didn't even do anything.
You got to relax.
Fine. Okay.
Is this my bag?
Thank you, I appreciate that.
Hopefully there's
nothing missing.
This crazy man...
I don't care what happened!
Because you tackled me!
I didn't mean to tackle you.
Just FYI,
there's a lawsuit happening.
I'm not saying
I'm gonna do it or whatnot,
but there is one coming.
Thank you.
All right, come on.
Get your stuff.
Hey, chief,
I need to talk to you.
Hey, what's up?
Uh, did he come to?
Yeah. He's awake.
A little messed up.
He's got a couple
of bruised ribs,
but he'll be all right.
Listen,
I gotta ask you a favor.
Yeah, shoot.
I have got to talk to
this guy right away.
V?
The bike.
MONDAY: His partner got away.
I gotta find him
before he gets too far.
Is there any way
I could ride and ask him
a couple of questions?
What, right now?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If I could just sit with him
on the way to the hospital?
That's very unusual.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Well, NYPD needs a favor.
Okay?
Okay, chum?
All right,
come and ride with us.
All right. Thanks.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Drive.
Hey, buddy?
Hey, buddy? Hey...
Ah, they're not your buddies.
You're one of
these bike assholes.
You know how
much time they waste
scraping you shitheads
off the street?
This whole city hates you.
Hey, man.
You headed to the impound?
Yeah. Why?
Good. Take this thing.
I'll meet you there.
When this asshole
comes for his bike,
he's mine.
Time to quit
dicking around, son.
You got involved
with some people
with real problems.
Real deadlines.
Life and death shit.
What is this to you?
What, the slope that
gave you the ticket,
she gave you some sad story?
Eighteen cousins in Fujian
that wanna come to Chinatown,
dish out Mongolian beef
with snow peas?
Well, life's hard.
Turns out they can't come.
It's for her kid, man.
Do I bother her
with my problems?
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
Where's the ticket?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I hear you
got some cracked ribs,
that's gotta sting.
We better be careful.
Don't want you bouncing
around too much in here.
Might poke a lung.
(SCREAMS)
Oh, I'm sorry.
Is that uncomfortable?
Douche bag.
I don't really care much
for that term "douche bag."
People throw it around
like crazy these days,
like it's suddenly okay.
You know what else
people say now? "Suck it."
I was watching TV
the other night, 8:30,
middle of prime time.
Kids could be watching.
Guy says, "Suck it."
Everybody's laughing.
Ha, ha, ha!
How is that appropriate?
I'm gonna ask you
some questions.
And you're gonna give me
one-word answers,
yes or no.
Even a bagboy should
be able to handle that.
First question.
Do you know where
the ticket is?
Hello!
(SCREAMS)
(HORNS HONKING)
(COUGHING)
You better give me an answer
or I'm gonna snap your ribs
like toothpicks.
(PANTING)
Do you know
where the ticket is?
Will you give it to me?
Good boy.
Just get me my bike.
Are you negotiating?
Yeah. Yeah,
and you're outta time.
You might have these
assholes in the bag,
but you can't lean on me
like this when we get
to the hospital.
That's my offer!
Get me my bike!
I'll get you the ticket.
How do we make that happen?
Manny. Bring me Manny.
(RINGING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(CONTINUES
SPEAKING MANDARIN)
MAN: How ya doing, George?
MAN 1: Charlie,
pull up to the side!
MAN 2: Put it back there?
MAN 1: Yeah,
I'm pushing it through.
Shit.
MONDAY: Get out. Come on.
Here they come.
I'm gonna kick your ass
till Thursday
if he doesn't have it.
It's in his bag.
Why do you think
I was chasing him?
Mmm-hmm.
Can I get
my bike now, please?
Hey. Hey, fellas.
What's up?
Take this kid inside
to get his bike.
All right.
But bring him back.
Will do.
Hello, sir! Rough day, huh?
(LAUGHS)
Yeah. Yeah.
Have to ask your permission
to search your bag.
You're not
in any trouble at all.
I have reason
to believe somebody
may have
put something in there
without your knowledge.
Uh...
Okay.
Hey, did you just
bring a bike in?
End of the row.
Okay.
Hey, you see somebody
hanging on the back
of my truck?
No, I just got here.
Like who?
Like some batshit
crazy messenger chick.
I think she was
holding on the whole time
I was on
the West Side Highway.
Damn.
Something I've been
looking for all damn day.
I've had a bit of
a rough day myself.
What are you doing?
VANESSA: (WHISPERS) Psst.
Got it.
Nice!
Are there
any more compartments?
MANNY: For what?
(GROANS)
Over here.
I love you for more
than one reason.
God damn it!
Have a nice day.
Yeah, just leave it
right there!
MANNY: I'll take care of it,
not a problem!
Shit.
I'm gonna shred
the living shit
outta that thing.
Wait.
I'll see you outside.
Hey! Where is
the little shit?
Left him back
there behind the bikes.
End of the row.
You left him?
What, you wanted me to
watch him the whole time?
No, I wanted you
to give him the keys
to your car, jackass.
Where'd he go?
God damn it.
Bastard!
MONDAY: Can I get
some help here?
♪ I seem to think, I think
I got a little situation
♪ So listen to me, sister,
listen, maybe you can help
Go round the other side!
Outta my way!
♪ But not for me
they always seem to be
for someone else
♪ While all people always
seem to just be on vacation
♪ What do I get from it?
I don't get anything at all
♪ I'm like a trash can
holding all the information
♪ And every single time
I'm in the field
to be taught ♪
Hey! Come here!
Cut him off!
Jesus Christ!
Hey! Close the doors!
Okey-doke.
MONDAY: Come on.
Hey, somebody stop her!
The girl on the bike!
MONDAY: Come on!
(GRUNTS)
Close the doors!
MAN: Angus, grab her!
Come on! Come on!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
MONDAY: Come on!
Hey!
You know what? I'm done.
(HORNS HONKING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Hey, you out?
Holy shit!
That was the most fun I ever
had with my clothes on!
You know what to tell him?
I'm on it.
(TIRES SCREECH)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(SHOUTS)
(BOTH TALKING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(PANTING)
I need a flash mob,
like, five minutes ago.
(PHONE RINGING)
24/7 Delivery.
Moosey, it's Raj.
Hey, what's up, Raj?
I need the cavalry, bro.
No shit. Where we going?
(PHONE RINGING)
Roadrunner.
Thought I told you
not to call me, Raj.
Oh, really?
Hey, it's Phoebe.
Who's at the bridge?
(PHONE RINGING)
Cyclehawk.
This is Johnny.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah. I got it. I got it.
Well, tell him I got it.
He can send whoever he wants,
the Red Army, General Chow,
I don't give a hoot.
Yeah, I have the money.
147, Doyers Street.
Cross is Pell.
Five minutes.
Check this out.
Whoa, man!
That was a faux back.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
Oh, shit. Come on,
I gotta go. I gotta go.
(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
(CELL PHONES CHIMING)
Time to ride!
Pay heed, people!
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
Here we go!
(WHOOPING CONTINUES)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
You know how they say,
"There's enough
to go around for everybody"?
There isn't.
Give me the ticket.
Yeah, you know
the thing about these folks?
They never testify.
Who's to say
you didn't lunge at me?
Give me the ticket.
Oh, what, is that
your backup?
Yup.
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
Them, too.
Suck it, douche bag.
(GRUNTS) Get off me!
(CLAMORING)
Stay the hell off me.
I said stay away!
(GRUNTS)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
Sister Chen?
Delivery.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, what? What, huh?
I'm a cop, you zipperheads.
What are you going to do?
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
What?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait a second.
Wait a second. I need a...
(GRUNTS)
Okay.
Okay, just gimme a break.
I need to think for a second.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(BOTH SPEAKING IN MANDARIN)
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Thank God.
Are you okay?
WILEE: I'll still
take 6th Avenue at rush hour
over an office with a view.
Might have to put
on the suit someday,
but not yet.
Fixed gear,
steel frame, no brakes.
(HORN BLARING)
Can't stop.
Don't want to, either.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
DAVID KOEPP: Let's get this.
This is Joe's bike.
And that's where he ended up.
That's rough.
This is cool.
I mean,
kids, don't try this at home
or nothing, but, like...
KOEPP: Seriously, let's,
um, get you to the hospital.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC FADES)
(ENGLISH US - PSDH)