[♪♪♪]
[JAY-Z'S "99 PROBLEMS" PLAYS]
And so?
And so,
I'm sitting there
staring at him, right?
He tells me to get my fucking
crunchy fucking fucknuts
the fuck out of there.
You believe that shit?
You know what I said, right?
No, what did you say?
Shit. "Okay."
You fucking said, "Okay."
I'm sure you did.
Ha, ha, ha.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Control Center,
this is Stillwell 1 21 5.
Go ahead, Stillwell 1 21 5.
I'm about four cars
out of 57th Street station
being delayed
by a red signal light.
Should be green,
Stillwell 121 5.
Yeah, tell me something
I don't already know.
All right, roll through it slow,
extreme caution,
per the rulebook.
Yeah, cracked rail.
Nine-hundred feet from the
east end of the platform.
It's the goddamn cold.
Metal contracts,
you know that.
I got it, I got it.
How long it take to fix it?
Gotta put a plate on it.
Two hours.
Thank you. Make it
an hour and a half,
I'll buy you a beer.
[TRAIN HORN HONKlNG]
DELGADO:
Shit, G.B.
I hate to see
you down here
on the floor, man.
Temporary, baby.
I'll be up there behind the glass
before you know it.
Okay, l'm gonna need
the R train
to switch over
to the express tracks
at 34th.
Which express tracks?
The one that Q uses.
Once they exit the 57th Street,
they can switch over to the F Line.
Boom, straight shot
into Queens.
Once they get to Queens,
they switch back at 36th Street
to the R Line.
All you gotta do is suspend the W,
N and R will pick up the slack,
all right?
[♪♪♪]
Excuse me,
I can't see
where I gotta look.
Unlock the door.
Do it now or
I'll fucking kill you. Do it.
All right, all right.
Shut up and walk.
First car, go.
See?
I told you I could do this.
Big fucking deal,
you did what you said
you'd do.
All right.
Five minutes of peace.
DELGADO: Yeah!
MAN: Nice!
[LAUGHING]
Nice.
All right.
There you go.
I'm on the train
and l still got you.
[OVER COMPUTER]
You still got me?
I got you.
What are you doing?
GIRL:
You still got me?
Oh, my God.
Baby? Baby?
Give me the cutting key.
Cutting key.
Control Center calling
Pelham 123. Come in,
Pelham 123.
Why did you stop?
You're all green ahead.
[OVER RADlO]
Control Center calling Pelham 1 23.
yhy did you stop, 1 23?
You got green ahead.
It's okay.
Life is simple now.
You just gotta do what I say.
Not now, okay?
Where are you from?
Brooklyn.
You lrish?
Yeah.
I thought so.
Who's driving Pelham 123?
Maybe something fell on the tracks.
Wait. Are we going backwards?
[PEOPLE MURMURING]
42nd Street tower,
I got a train wrong-railing
on the southbound
Lexington Avenue Line
just north of you.
[OVER PA]
Listen up,
we need to stop and stay in-station.
All southbound locals
just north of the 51 st Street station.
The operator on 123
is Jerry Pollard.
Jerry Pollard. l know Jerry Pollard.
I went to motorman school
with Jerry Pollard.
Pelham 123,
come in to me, Pelham 1 23.
Pelham 123, Jerry Pollard,
what's going on down there?
[OVER RADlO]
This is Control Center.
yhat's going on, 1 23?
Let's get an express train to
go up, pull alongside them,
see what we see in the cab.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Yeah, this is South Ferry 1 05.
I can't get my windshield wiper
to turn on.
South Ferry 1 05,
there's a circuit breaker
right behind you for that.
What's going on?
Maestro, what's going on?
Cop.
COP: Excuse me.
Fuck.
Watch your backs.
When I say stop, stop it hard.
Transit Police.
Stop.
[BRAKES SQUEALING
AND PEOPLE SHOUT]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[GUNSHOTS THEN
WOMAN SCREAMS]
Everybody sit the fuck down!
[YELLS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Down!
Aah!
Sit the fuck down!
MAN [ON RADlO]:
Jesus! We're getting reports
of gunshots down the tunnel.
GARBER:
Sergeant Moran.
Delgado, let's call off that express.
Got it.
[YELLING lN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
I'm gonna die.
I'm gonna fucking die, man.
Come on! Hey.
Everybody up!
By the window!
Come on, up, up, up!
Stand up! Stand up! Come on!
Move it!
Against the window!
What the fuck is going on?
RAMOS [OVER RADlO]:
There was a cop.
Bashkin shot him.
I think-- I think he's dead.
Put Bashkin on and
find your fucking guts!
Do it!
Fuck.
RYDER: What happened?
A cop. He's dead.
Put the conductor on.
yhat's your name, conductor?
Regina.
Regina, baby, listen,
you got a job to do, honey.
A job?
Yeah, God put you on
this Earth for one thing
and one thing only.
You're gonna conduct
those people off the train
and up to the platform station.
You got that? Let me hear it.
Let me hear you do that.
Listen up,
everybody.
We're gonna go back
to the platform.
I need everybody to--
RYDER:
Regina. Let's do it again.
Conduct those people.
Listen up, everybody.
Now, we're gonna head back
towards the platform.
I want everybody
to slowly get up.
I'm gonna get you off this train.
Good.
Now, we're gonna be on the tracks,
so if you don't need it, leave it.
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
WOMAN [OVER RADlO]:
Have been put on alert regarding--
OFFlCER:
Right here, right here.
Cross right here, right here.
MAN 1 :
Go.
OFFlCER:
Cross over right here,
right here.
MAN 2:
Let's go.
Up the stairs, up the stairs.
OFFlCER: Here you go.
Every cop in the city is on the way.
Maybe it wasn't even gunshots.
I mean, a train could be
blowing the breakers, right?
Or the motor blew?
No, this is on purpose.
Fuck you.
Yeah, l'm coming.
Get the fuck off the walls.
Shut the fuck up and come on.
Shit. Come on.
Ramos.
Turn the power off
from there down.
What?
Turn the power off
from there down!
Okay, l got it!
BASHKlN:
My fucking lucky day.
Shit.
What the fuck is
wrong with you, man?
RYDER [OVER RADIO]:
Pelham 1 23 to Rail Control Center.
Do you read me?
Yes, l read you, Pelham 123.
This is Control Center.
Who is this?
Heh, heh, heh.
It's me, man.
I didn't wanna call
till everything was ready.
WHlSPERlNG] lt's not Jerry.
I don't know who it is.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I understand, I understand,
Pelham 123.
Who the hell is this?
This is the man
who's gonna rock this city.
who's gonna give the city
a run for the money.
Look up.
Look up at your screen and
you tell me what you see.
You see what l've done?
I see it.
RYDER:
One car is much more manageable
than 1 0 with the manpower I got.
Mr. Motorman's
gonna tell you all about it.
Tell him what we got here.
They got hostages,
lots of them.
And, uh, they got machine guns.
WHlSPERlNG] That's Jerry.
WHlSPERlNG] Yeah. That's Jerry.
RYDER: Yeah, that's right.
You check me,
do you understand that?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I check, I understand.
Didn't l tell you
to knock first?
RYDER [OVER SPEAKER]:
Good, because this is what
we call a cash transaction.
Now, you understand
commodities, don't you?
You know, pork bellies?
Gold? Light crude?
Listen.
Listen, no disrespect,
but maybe--
Maybe I'm not the guy
you should be talking to.
Oh, no,
you are exactly the guy
I wanna talk to.
Now, I want you
to look at the ticker
and you tell me
what is the going rate
for a New York City hostage
today?
You think a milIion dollars
is too much? I do.
I think it's corny.
Now get your calculator out.
You got one?
Uh...
RYDRT: Do you haνe a calculator?
Yeah, we got one. I got one.
Okay, good. Add this up.
You got $526,31 5 and 79 cents.
That's 526,31 5.79.
Now, times that by 1 9.
What do you got?
What is he,
a goddamn accountant?
That's 1 0 million?
What do you got?
That comes out to 1 0 million
plus one cent.
Oh. That is a deal.
You call the mayor
and you tell him the price.
And then you tell him
l want it in 1 00,000 $1 00 bills,
you got that?
I got it.
What about the one cent?
Oh, you keep that one cent,
that's your broker fee.
Now, I want the rest
in plain suitcases
the kind with the wheels
and the portable handle,
okay?
Now, this is not
a futures contract.
This is a spot trade.
That means there's a time limit on it.
Okay, you got that?
Now, what do you think
is a fair time limit?
You know, I don't know.
I'm really just a guy--
Come on,
give me a time limit.
Give me a
fair time limit.
Thursday.
I was thinking more like an hour.
Now, what's your watch say?
Two-thirteen.
Oh,
that's exactly what
my watch says.
So at 3:1 3,
I want that money here,
motherfucker.
And after that, there is a late fee.
What do you think
that late fee is gonna be?
Come on, tell me what it'll be.
You're gonna kill
the passengers?
Oh, commodities
is what I start to kill.
One for every minute
past the deadline
I am forced to wait.
Now, they become more valuable
this way
and still at the same price.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
He's underground in the tunnel.
He's never gonna pull this off.
Don't tell me, tell him.
Who the hell is this guy?
I don't know who it is!
MORAN:
Garber, Garber,
just stay with it.
RYDER:
Now, what's your name?
I didn't get your name.
What's your name, my man?
My name?
What's your name?
Tell him?
Garber.
Garber, okay.
Now, seriously, man,
in 59 minutes,
I'm gonna start
killing passengers.
So my advice to you
is to get on the phone,
get the mayor notified now.
Listen, l mean...
I'm just a civil-service employee.
I can't get ahold of the mayor.
Well, that's your problem,
man, that's not mine.
It's like, who's responsible
for who lives and who dies
in New York?
That's New York City's problem.
Get the fuck off the radio
and notify the mayor,
motherfucker!
Okay.
Nine months of this,
and l'm free.
Next mayor gets inaugurated,
I'm gonna be sitting
in Saint-Tropez on the
beach with a piña colada.
I will never have to ride
the subway ever again.
Never say never, sir.
Never.
All right,
what's next for
the afternoon?
East Harlem Elementary
at 2:30.
You're supposed to read
The Cat ln The Hat
to the third grade.
Every time I go to
the schools, l get sick.
They all have runny noses.
Call Dr. Katz, tell him
I want him waiting at the
school, with a fu shot.
Mayor's office.
He's in Car 3.
MAN: Yeah.
What happened?
Somebody just hijacked
a 6 train.
It's stopped in the tunnel
between 51 st and 42nd.
Another idiot with a gun.
What do we know?
It's unclear, but l have a car
waiting for us downstairs.
Subway will get us there faster.
All right. Let the doors close.
Tell them we'll meet them
at 59th Street.
Tell the conductor
this is now an express.
We're skipping the next five stops.
What?
MAN: l gotta get to work.
Hold on, hold on.
Everybody will get
where they need to go,
we'll make all the stops.
Maybe he's not such
a douche bag after all,
huh?
Funny.
Figures you'd be the one
to get a call like this.
Hostage negotiation team
is here in five minutes, and
the mayor's been notified.
You gonna tell him?
Get the fuck out of here.
My shift's over in 1 0 minutes.
What are you staring at?
Your face.
I'm trying to remember
for when it's not here
anymore.
You gonna start in
on me now?
Damn right,
I'm gonna start in on you.
Don't fuck this up, Garber.
You wanna do it?
It's your station, it's your call.
Oh, it's my call now?
JOHNSON: That's right. Your call.
Come on.
GARBER [OVER RADlO]:
Pelham 1 23, come in, this is
Rail Control Center. Are you there?
Gerber Baby boy.
What's up?
Garber.
Just wanted to let you know
the mayor's been notified.
Are they gonna pay?
I don't know. l'm just the,
uh, what'd you call me?
The, uh, broker.
No, no. No, you represent
the city of New York right now,
buddy.
Well, l can tell you you're dealing
with one of the all-time
bureaucracies, I know that.
I mean, it takes time.
You'd better fix the bureaucracy,
because when the time comes,
these motherfuckers,
these hostages
are gonna go real quick.
You got it, you got it.
Any other demands?
Yeah, well,
no fucking pizza for them,
either, man.
No, I mean, are you guys, like,
you know, are you terrorists?
Do I sound like a terrorist?
Do I terrorize you?
Actually, you don't, but I mean,
not that I ever talked to one.
So--
So, what,
this is just about money?
Oh, is there anything else?
There's not dying.
Yeah, well, you know, you live,
you die. You either go with
the current or you fight it,
you all end up
in the same place.
Where's that, Jersey?
Yeah, you watch it.
I was born there, man.
I'm just saying,
you're up in the
motorman's cab.
That means you're on the radio,
which means that you're an
easy target.
You gotta know the drill.
I know that soon
I won't be alone,
and if I'm the first to get shot,
I'm the first of many to get shot.
That's correct,
but then you'd still be dead.
Dead is an improvement
on a lot of things
I can think of, buddy boy.
Sounds like he slept
with my ex.
You know,
we all owe God a death.
And l'm a man
who pays his debts.
Are you a man who pays his debts?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
TV, cable, and my mortgage.
That's a little like dying
once a month.
Oh, you're married,
you're a married man.
Maybe.
No, no, no. You're married, man.
Married men have mortgages.
What about you?
You got a mortgage?
Well, l don't know, Garber.
Why don't you tell me,
then we'll both know?
I don't know. l mean, you...
I'm sure someone out there
loves you dearly and, uh,
you know,
would be worried about you.
Like I said,
you're in the motorman's cab,
you got no cover,
sniper on the way.
Well, you know,
circumstances are
my protection
because right now, you know,
hostages are good insurance.
By the way I see it,
I'm pretty well-protected.
You know, this reminds me
of being in a confessional.
GARBER:
Are you Catholic?
I'm married, you're Catholic.
Maybe. I don't know.
No, you're Catholic.
And a Catholic--
A good Catholic
would know that he's
got a trainload of
innocent people.
I mean, you don't wanna
kill innocent people, do you?
A good Catholic knows
that nobody is innocent.
And l'm not gonna kill
all these hostages.
I'd give up my leverage.
Well, l hope you know
what you're doing.
Yeah, well, it's running
like a fucking Swiss watch
down here,
so don't worry
about it.
So, what do l call you anyway?
Call me Ryder.
As in "train rider"?
Call me Ryder,
with a Y.
Ryder.
I like you, Garber.
Ha, ha. I do like you, man.
You may be
the last friend
I ever make.
Well, l hope you're wrong,
Mr. Ryder.
But, you know, I'm just a guy.
I'm just a guy
on the other end of the mic.
Oh, you don't think
this was meant to be?
You don't think this was fate,
you and me?
I don't know. You know,
things happen that lead
to other things.
And maybe this was one of them,
but that's it.
I never get excited
about coincidence.
Well, you got
50 fucking minutes,
so check me.
All right. 50 minutes, check.
And don't call me
unless you got news.
You got it.
Motherfucker.
DELGADO:
G.B.
You're fucking good, man.
Okay. Move it the other way.
All right, come on,
move it.
The other way.
Okay, now move it back
a little less.
Bingo. Got it.
RAMOS:
All right, we got it.
[PHONE RINGING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Who's talked to these jokers?
That would be me.
Yeah,
under my supervision.
Who are you?
Vincent Camonetti,
N.Y.P.D. Hostage
Negotiation Team.
JOHNSON:
John Johnson,
Chief Transportation Officer.
Walter Garber.
I'm Console Dispatch,
right now.
What can you tell me, Walter?
Uh, his name is Ryder, with a Y.
And he's asking
for $1 0 million by 3:1 3.
CAMONETTl:
Good. He's looking toward the future.
He say what he'd do if
he doesn't get the money?
Yeah.
He said he'd kill a passenger
every minute we go over.
Starting at 3:1 3 p.m.?
3-1-3, yes, sir.
Anything else?
He's smart.
JOHNSON:
If he's so smart, why is he doing
something so fucking stupid?
Is he on the train radio?
GARBER:
Yeah, yeah, we can
get him right here.
Any chance that
we can get a signal
down there?
We'd like to get him
on one of our cell phones.
No,
there's no chance,
not where he is. Uh-uh.
What's this?
"Leverage, spot trade"?
Yeah, it's weird.
He's like a money guy,
like a Wall Street.
He talked about
the passengers like
they were commodities.
"Catholic"?
Yeah, l think he's Catholic.
For chrissakes, Garber,
you gonna tell us what
his zodiac sign is now?
No, I'm just saying,
in my opinion,
I think he's Catholic.
Man asked me
about "Catholic."
I wrote it down.
I'm giving him my opinion.
Unlike other people,
around here, I actually
have an opinion.
Fellas, can we settle
this domestic dispute
later?
Absolutely.
CAMONETTl:
Why do you think he's Catholic?
Well, l think he's Catholic
because he talked about
original sin and confessions.
I don't know,
I wrote it down.
I didn't know what else to do.
Did he ask for a priest?
GARBER: No.
Good. Anything else?
Uh, yeah, he sounded like,
you know,
the way he was talking,
he sounded
like he's not afraid to die.
Yeah, well, it's early yet.
Hm.
The calls are coming through...?
Yes, sir. Right here.
You hit the blue button here,
you can reach him.
And then he'll come back to you.
You mind if I take your seat?
No, no, go right ahead.
CAMONETTl: Thank you, Walter.
GARBER:
You're welcome.
And then this one here,
this is the six wire.
You don't have to touch that one.
All right. Okay.
That goes around the whole room.
Six wire.
Listen, why don't you, uh--
Just hit the talk here,
and then that mutes it.
Take the rest of the day off.
Get out of here.
I thought I'd stick around,
just make sure that...
Well, that wasn't a suggestion.
So why don't you go home?
All right.
This is it.
You got all the information
over here about the 31 3.
Wait for his call.
MAN:
You want me to work it up right now?
CAMONETTl:
You call headquarters,
let them know that l'm here,
and l'm on the job. Okay.
[♪♪♪]
I gotta take a piss.
So who's stopping you?
All right. We wouldn't
wanna end up on any
Amnesty lnternational lists,
so step up to the door,
face out.
Open the middle door.
Do what you gotta do.
Can I jump down there?
[ZlPPER UNZIPS]
You gotta go or don't you?
I do, l gotta go.
Step up, my man.
Let's go, let's go.
That kid's going places.
All right, close the doors.
CAMONETTl [OVER RADIO]:
Pelham 1 23, come in.
Pelham 1 23, please come in.
All right, everybody, sit down!
Who is this?
This is Lieutenant Camonetti.
I'm with the N.Y.P.D.
Hostage Negotiation Team.
I'd like to talk to you
about the situation
that we're in.
Where the fuck is Garber?
Mr. Garber is a train dispatcher.
This is now a police matter.
Yeah, well, l wanna talk to Garber.
I'm sorry, Mr. Ryder,
but Mr. Garber is
no longer involved.
Motorman, up!
Put Garber on the line.
To be honest,
Mr. Garber has gone home.
Put Garber on
the fucking line or
I kill the motorman.
I guarantee you, Mr. Ryder,
that I am the best person
for you to be talking to right now.
Just give me a moment
and l'll explain why.
You were always gonna
be the first one to go.
MAN:
Oh, Jesus!
WOMAN:
Jesus.
Mr. Camonetti,
you got 60 fucking seconds
before I kill another.
Okay? Fifty-nine, 58, 57...
CAMONETTl:
Get him.
Just get Garber, huh?
Fifty-six, 55, 54...
We're trying to locate Mr. Garber
ASAP, Mr. Ryder.
Why did you do that?
Mr. Camonetti or whatever
fucking greaseball name
you got,
the city of fucking New York
killed Jerry, okay?
Fifty-three, 52, 51 ...
[♪♪♪]
Garber. Garber!
Garber,
he killed Jerry Pollard,
man.
Come on, he wants to
talk to you right now.
He's here. He's on the way.
Eleven, 1 0, nine, eight, seven...
CAMONETTl:
He's approaching the desk.
Six, five, four, three, two, one...
Hey, it's me, it's Garber.
Garber!
You didn't say goodbye.
You killed Jerry?
No, the city of fucking New York
killed Jerry, okay?
The biggest rat hole
in the world fucking killed Jerry.
Okay? Now you can
chalk another victim up
to NYC.
Now, can everybody hear me?
Yeah, we hear you,
loud and clear.
Well, good, because now
you don't have to
tell the cops
that they don't tell me
how to do it or
how it's gonna be.
I fucking tell them.
Don't you ever, ever
leave me again.
Or I'll just have to
hunt you down
and l'll kill you.
Now, you got 39--
Thirty-nine minutes.
Check me.
Thirty-nine, check.
This is Staley to ESU 2.
What's your position?
OFFlCER 1 :
ESU 2 approaching hostage car
from south tunnel.
OFFlCER 2:
Go, go, go.
Ten-million dollars.
I'll just write him a check
and get it over with.
He wants it in cash.
I was joking, LaSalle.
But we've been given one hour
to get the money together.
Ten-million dollars.
Where do they get
these numbers?
Oh, actually, 1 0 is the limit, sir.
MAYOR:
Why is that?
You just sign a request
to the City Controller,
he forwards it
to one of our lenders,
cash gets released to
the Federal Reserve.
Limit at any one time is 1 0 million.
Well, some idiot with a gun
wouldn't know that.
I didn't know that.
Well, you're very busy, sir.
How do you know that?
Here he is.
MAYOR:
Henry, what's the situation?
They just killed a hostage.
Bitch of a way to find out,
but these guys
may be the real deal.
Guys?
I thought there was one idiot
with a gun. Who are they?
Multiple gunmen.
We don't know.
They're not sure.
They've got 1 8 hostages,
they say.
They'll kill more in an hour.
That's the time limit.
They want you to know.
Well, what do we know about them?
They're not amateurs.
They cut out a car,
stopped on a rise
in the tunnel.
They can see us coming
1 00 yards either way.
All right.
How long to get
the money together?
I don't know.
Find out.
You're not thinking of
paying these pricks,
are you?
I'm thinking of buying time
and being ready.
Call the Controller.
Tell them we'll pay.
What's with you
and Garber, huh?
Tell me about him.
Was he scheduled
to work today?
Yeah, absolutely. But, uh...
But what?
Well, he's only had
this particular job
for a couple weeks now.
Well, why is that?
Well, he's under investigation.
What?
JOHNSON:
We were gonna suspend him,
with pay--
CAMONETTl:
What's he being investigated for?
[INAUDIBLE DlALOGUE]
He went to Japan.
He had to take a look
at some new trains,
[CELL PHONE RINGlNG]
and the allegation
is that he took a bribe.
Took a bribe?
Does he have
a previous record?
No. Not that l know.
You sure of that?
Yeah, yeah.
I don't think so.
I gotta take this.
MAN [OVER COMPUTER]:
The identity of the hijackers
is stilI unclear.
The Hostage Negotiation Team has
just arriνed at MTA headquarters
to determine
if this is a terrorist enterprise.
Is that what we are?
An enterprise?
[LAUGHING]
We're an enterprise.
Well, pilot reports
that the aircraft has
begun its descent.
This is Staley to ESU 4.
What's your ETA?
OFFlCER:
Approximately two minutes
south of target.
Why is the train called
Pelham 123?
Comes out of Pelham Bay
at 1 :23 in the afternoon.
How did you end up with this call?
Uh, it's a Lexington Avenue train.
I got the Lexington Avenue desk.
Came through my desk.
Can you think of any reason
why you'd be targeted?
Someone wanna hurt you?
Something against you
or something?
No.
You recognize his voice?
Uh, no. No, as I said,
it was a coincidence
it came through my desk.
Did you pick this desk?
Or was it assigned to you?
Did I...?
I said, did you pick this desk
or was it assigned to you?
Can I take my coat off?
Doesn't make any sense.
What doesn't?
The guy you're talking to.
He ain't a train dispatcher.
Walter Garber.
He's a big shot.
Big shot at what?
Rail Control.
I mean, he runs
things up there.
At least he did before l went up.
His name is Walter?
RAMOS:
Yeah.
Dude like that
shouldn't be
answering the phone.
Mr. Ryder wants to talk to you.
GARBER: Right.
Are you sure you don't have
some sort of relationship
with him?
I assure you, whatever
relationship l have with him
is better than yours.
Jerry, my friend,
was killed while
you were talking to Ryder.
So maybe that's a question
you should ask yourself
instead of asking me.
I mean,
I didn't have anything
to do with this.
I didn't say that.
Well, l'm sure.
But what I have in you,
Mr. Garber,
is an unknown variable.
GARBER: An unknown variable?
That's right.
And people's lives
are at stake.
I understand that.
So please excuse me
if l try to get
more comfortable
with you, okay?
It ain't working, but okay.
All right.
Now, with that in mind,
would you agree to
a consensual search
of your house?
Take me 40, 45 minutes
to get a warrant.
What...
Yes, okay.
Got him.
Walter Garber, right there.
RYDER: Whoa.
No shit, look at this.
Guy took a bribe, man.
Yeah.
Woo-hoo, baby!
ESU 2, this is Staley.
What's your overall status?
OFFlCER:
All positions secured.
STALEY [OVER RADIO]:
All right,
hold your fire until instructed.
Pelham 123,
can you hear me?
Yeah, loud and clear,
back at you.
All right, uh,
the mayor has agreed to pay,
and, uh,
they're getting the money
together right now.
RYDER [OVER RADIO]:
Good.
Well, you know,
you got 28 minutes,
so l advise him to make haste.
I'm sure he will.
So is your first name
Walter?
Excuse me?
Your name, is it Walter?
Yes, it is.
RYDER: Good.
What are you doing
dispatching trains?
I thought you were some
sort of MTA big shot.
I work for the MTA.
Today they put me at dispatch,
and my bad luck.
Oh. l thought you didn't
believe in bad luck.
I said I didn't believe in fate.
Do you believe in
rigged contracts
for new trains?
Look, l--
What are we
talking about this for?
Look, l need to know
who I'm dealing with.
You need to know who--?
Yeah, l want to know
who I'm dealing with. I mean,
are you a bad penny?
Let me explain something to you.
Being accused of something
is one thing.
Being guilty of it
is something entirely different.
Well, agreed.
But you gotta take me
through this, my man.
You got to tell me from the top.
This whole train thing. Come on.
GARBER:
All right,
I started out in maintenance.
Platform maintenance,
track maintenance,
flagman,
conductor.
RYDER: Conductor, really?
Yeah. And then motorman.
A motorman.
How long did you
do that for?
I drove them
over six years.
I went to tower operations,
assistant dispatcher,
dispatcher.
I finally ended up--
Yeah, you're assistant
chief transportation officer
or something.
Right?
That's right.
And part of my job is to go
out to the manufacturers,
you know,
the people who buiId the trains
and bid on contracts for the trains.
Is that where you took the bribe?
The Japanese train
over the Canadian train?
I did not take a bribe, all right?
I was accused of taking a bribe.
I have not been proven guilty yet.
Well, they haven't said yet.
I mean, they haven't decided.
Well, they got no proof.
I don't care what they decide.
It-- What--
They don't need--
It doesn't matter--
And then is this when
they demoted you?
That's correct.
They demoted me,
pending the outcome.
And now they're trying
to humiliate you,
is that right?
Motherfuckers.
Look, I know
how these things work,
man, okay?
Everything doesn't seem
to appear like what it is.
But you've gotta be
completely honest
with me, man.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
How did you do it?
I didn't. I'm innocent.
Oh, you're innocent.
No, you're talking
to a Catholic, man.
We've been over
innocent before.
Okay?
Look, man,
I've been through all this,
man.
So just tell me,
how did you do it?
I didn't do it.
Okay, that's it!
That's fucking it!
Damn it.
Kid. You.
Me?
No, no, you. Up.
Get the fuck over there.
I don't know what you did
to piss him off but you did.
Garber.
You know what I'm looking at?
Do you know what I'm looking at?
No, I do not.
First there's my gun,
and at the end of my gun--
What's your name, man?
George. Everyone calls me Geo.
George. His friends call him Geo.
Got this '80s skateboard thing
going.
He makes it work,
but it's not gonna
look too good in his casket.
Listen, Ryder, just slow down.
We haven't reached the deadline.
No, there's no fucking deadline,
man.
You just gotta tell me
the truth.
About what?
RYDER: The bribe!
Did you take it?
GARBER: l didn't take a bribe.
Okay, you got five seconds
to save this kid's life.
GARBER:
I didn't do anything.
Five...
Just wait a second.
Four, three...
Wait a second!
RYDER:
Two...
Fucking tell him
how you did it.
All-- All right, okay.
RYDER: Say it.
I took the bribe.
How much?
Thirty-- Uh...
How fucking much?
Thirty-five thousand dollars.
How did you do it?
I went to Japan
to look at these trains.
It's part of my job.
I...
I don't get to vote, okay?
I just recommend.
I-- l chose what I thought
was the best train,
and the Japanese had the best train,
and l made my recommendation.
That's before you took
the bribe.
Yes.
That was the train
you were gonna pick
anyway, huh?
Yes.
And now you're fighting for your job
and they're trying to humiliate you
aren't they?
No, no, no.
I did what I did.
And, um...
And it's not, you know,
it's not the MTA's fault.
What did you spend it on?
Look, what does this
got to do with anything,
huh?
What did you
fucking spend it on?
I used the money for my kids,
all right?
To pay my children's tuition.
I have a 1 7-year-old.
I have a 1 9-year-old daughter.
[♪♪♪]
And l used the money to pay
for their college tuition, all right?
RYDER:
You know what, Garber?
You're my goddamn hero,
you know that?
You got a kid here,
you don't even know him,
you saved his life.
That's brave, man.
That's fucking heroic.
Tell Garber thank you.
Thank you, Garber.
"Thank you, Garber,
for saving my life."
Thank you, Garber,
for saving my life.
You're welcome.
Sit down.
You're just like me,
Garber.
I fueled this city.
I fed it breakfast every morning,
and now we're the bad guys.
I don't think so.
I don't fucking think so!
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
Hello, Therese.
THERESE [OVER PHONE]:
Honey, look.
There are police here, Walt.
They wanna search the house.
They said you said
it was okay.
Uh, yeah. Yeah, it's okay.
It's-- Just let them in.
We got nothing to hide.
Is this about the investigation?
No, no. You watching TV?
This hostage thing.
Yeah, yeah, I'm watching it.
Well, it's just that, um...
Well, l'll tell you about it
when l get home,
but I'm in the middle of it
here right now and they just
wanna do background checks
on everybody that's involved here
from the MTA.
That's why they're at the house.
All right, okay. But you're okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Just let them in.
I'll see you when l get home.
All right. Okay, bye.
I'm sorry, Walter.
I am.
Listen, don't let this guy
bring you into his reality,
all right?
That's what he wants to do.
He hurts you,
you gonna get angry.
He's got the advantage.
Understand?
Yeah.
Just deflect, if you can.
Okay? All right.
All right.
[♪♪♪]
[ENGINES REVVlNG]
I hope they don't get
fucking lost.
Fuck me!
Ten-million bucks.
The joke is,
say we dipped in,
took some?
Bad guys would count it,
come up short, probably kill us.
No shit.
Geo,
what the fuck's happening?
GIRL [OVER COMPUTER]:
Geo. Geo, what's going on?
Geo.
I'm a fucking hostage.
Listen to me.
Stream it on our site.
Call the news.
Shit.
WHlSPERlNG]
Hey.
We've gotta do something.
They're gonna kill us.
You got a plan?
I thought you'd have one.
Because I'm some
tough-looking black guy?
I saw that ring
on your finger.
That was a long time ago.
Okay?
My husband had one just like it.
WOMAN [ON COMPUTER]:
A severe selI-off underway,
the Dow is down 450 points
in very heavy trading
as yall Street reacts
to the terrorist attack
of the New York City
subway system.
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
MAYOR:
How's my hair look?
It looks fine.
You ready to make
a statement?
I'll make a statement when
I have something to tell them.
It's a leadership moment, sir.
I'm not running
for re-election,
I'm not running for
fucking president.
I left my Rudy Giuliani suit
at home.
You're being selfish.
It'll take 30 seconds
to reassure them.
WOMAN 1 : Over there!
MAN 1 : Mr. Mayor!
WOMAN 2:
Mr. Mayor! Mr. Mayor!
MAN 2:
Will you be making a statement?
We're doing everything
the situation demands.
I'm not gonna speculate
right now. All right?
MAN 3: Mayor, is it terrorism?
MAYOR: No.
WOMAN 3:
Hey.
MAN 4:
Mayor! Are they terrorists?
All right, all right, all right!
Listen,
nobody said anything
about terrorism,
or a bomb, anything like that.
Let's stop that right now, all right?
How about your divorce?
Care to speculate about
how that's going?
Your divorce, sir.
Been a lot of talk
in the news lately
that you have
extramarital problems.
Your divorce, sir!
[REPORTERS SHOUTING]
Put it on
channel 1 5.
We got a girl in Brooklyn
watching it on her
boyfriend's computer.
It's on the damn Internet.
What?
Hold on.
Son of a bitch.
That's Ramos, isn't it?
That's motherfucking
Phil Ramos.
Yes, it is.
Who's Phil Ramos?
He was a motorman. He
killed a couple of passengers,
what, 1 0 years ago?
Right. He was high on cough syrup,
ran into the platform,
went to jail for manslaughter.
Phil Ramos,
five minutes,
I want everything.
Prison time,
known associates, the works.
Looks like it's from the floor.
Should the Internet
be working down there?
No. No way.
Maybe that's how
he knows about you.
Maybe he Googled you.
Or maybe Ramos told him,
who knows?
CAMONETTl:
Goddamn, it's the mayor.
Hello, Your Honor.
Do me a favor,
forget about
those guys.
GARBER:
Easy for you to say.
Would you rather be
one of those hostages?
No.
Listen up,
I'll give you a crash course
on hostage negotiating.
We're like rodeo clowns.
We keep the bull
from focusing on
what he'd like to do.
Which is what?
Kill a cowboy.
Exactly.
Now, he's got his deadline.
You slow things down.
Preservation of life.
That's our mission.
Guy's already proven
he's serious.
Next deadline's gonna
give him a chance
to prove it again.
How do we deal with that?
Hopefully,
get the money there
on time.
And if we don't,
we pretend the deadline
doesn't exist,
we talk through it,
we buy time, we
get a little movement.
Movement?
That's right.
Contradicts himself,
inconsistency in his demand,
you got some movement.
Right.
All right, let's go out there.
MAN [ON COMPUTER]:
This was the scene
moments ago
outside the Rail Control Center
in Midtown.
MAYOR:
I'm not gonna speculate right now.
That is a beautiful suit
he's got there.
Can't get it out of my head.
I'm gonna die today.
Visualization's
a very powerful thing.
You keep thinking it,
you never know.
Please let it be me
who drops this motherfucker.
RYDER:
Hey, Garber.
You there, buddy?
Yeah, l'm here.
RYDER [OVER RADIO]:
A little birdie told me
the mayor just walked in.
Can I talk to him?
Can he hear me?
How does he know l'm here?
Does he have a camera in here?
Can he hear me?
Uh, we can, we can, we can--
We can all hear you here. Yes.
Okay, good. So tell him--
Tell him I wanna
make him a deal.
Tell him I'lI make him a deal
right now.
Okay, all right.
Well, come on, speak up,
Mr. Mayor.
You're talking to
your constituents.
We got a train full
of registered voters.
Don't you care?
Don't you care about your voters?
This is not a good idea.
Your Honor, don't talk.
Don't engage with him.
I know what I'm doing,
I've been doing this
for a long time now.
RYDER:
Come on, buddy, speak up.
You gotta hit
the blue button there,
Your Honor.
Yes, this is the mayor.
Heh, heh, hey.
Good to meet you, man.
Hey, listen,
tell me this,
is this true?
I read that you make,
like,
one dollar a year to be a mayor
of New York, is that true?
Yes, but at least
it's honest work.
After taxes that's, like,
87 cents, isn't it?
Uh, yes.
Don't bullshit me, man.
It would take, like, 3000 years
to pay off that suit that
you're wearing.
What do you got, 20, 30 million
dollars or something like that?
You don't get that
without screwing someone,
screwing everyone.
I'm sure your wife knows
something about that, huh?
You said you had a deal
for me.
Yeah, l do have a deal.
I wanna make you a deal.
I wanna tell you
you could come down here,
and l will trade you
for all these passengers
in the train, how's that?
Okay, you could save the lives
of 1 7 New Yorkers.
Now, that's a good deal.
yhat do you think?
Give us a moment.
RYDER:
Okay.
I'll give you a moment.
You turn this into a circus,
you're gonna get someone
else killed, all right?
Now,
you entered his world,
exit it.
Okay, time's up.
What's the deal?
It's a very nice offer,
but I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to decline.
Oh, good.
Because if you begged me,
I wouldn't give you that deal, man.
You think anyone cares
about a philandering asshole
like you?
The city of New York
would love me to pull the
fucking trigger on you, brother.
Hey, Garber. This is the dude.
This is the guy that's
trying to get rid of you, my man.
Keep talking.
RYDRT: Do you believe this shit?
GARBER: You gotta calm--
RYDRT: You don't think he
broke the same rules
that we broke?
He knows it, l know it.
Calm him down.
All right, hey--
RYDRT: He can eat shit.
CAMONETTl: Calm him down.
You're-- Speak--
You're breaking up.
Tell him he can fucking kiss my ass!
I like the deal.
I think it's a good deal, but--
RYDER:
Fuck you, Mr. Mayor!
Now, I want my fucking money now!
You understand me? Now!
Just tell him the
money's on the way.
The money's on the way.
Yeah, yeah. Because he's,
like, a used-car salesman,
this asshole.
He can lick my bunghole,
motherfucker!
One mistake and everyone
has something to say.
Was she worth it?
Yes.
You have nine minutes.
How are you gonna get
the money here?
They're shutting down
every intersection from
here to Brooklyn.
[♪♪♪]
Phil Ramos, male,
Hispanic, 39.
Sentenced two to four years
for manslaughter,
paroled last month
from Clinton Correctional.
Now, his PO, Justafarro,
says he's living in a
halfway house in Queens.
He's not an absconder,
he made his all his appearances,
his piss has been clean.
But he was a no-show
at work today.
He didn't call in, nothing.
He knows the system.
The perfect place
in the subway
to stop the train.
He's only been out a month.
This wasn't planned
in the last three weeks.
Find out who
Ramos's cellmates were, who
worked in the laundry with him.
Call lists, visitors lists, ASAP.
[♪♪♪]
WOMAN [OVER RADlO]:
1 05 North Avenue.
Oh, shit! Look out!
Shit!
WOMAN [ON TV]:
The market has tumbled
nearly 7 percent
as investors continue
to react to events...
They just came off
the bridge.
Why didn't we send
a helicopter for the money?
Walter, now remember
what I said about talking
through deadlines, right?
We better have a plan B
in case the money
isn't there on the dot.
Put him back on his heels.
He knows things.
We know things too, right?
Right.
Ask him about Phil Ramos.
All right? Just get him talking.
DELGADO:
You can do it.
Hey, Ryder.
RYDER: The money here yet?
GARBER [OVER RADlO]:
On the way.
Then what the fuck
are you calling me for?
GARBER:
Actually, I just called to talk.
RYDER [OVER SPEAKER]:
Oh, yeah?
yhat do you wanna talk about?
You said that being
in the motorman's cab,
that was a little like being
in a confessional, right?
Yeah?
I was thinking maybe it's like
being in a prison cell too.
What are you trying to say?
That if l get caught,
I'd better get used to it?
No, I'm just wondering.
Maybe you're already used to it.
I'm wondering maybe that's how
you meet a guy like Phil Ramos?
How the fuck
he know that?
Well, why don't you tell me,
Garber?
Then we'll both know.
I mean,
after today's confession,
you're gonna find your ass
in prison too.
Which is my point.
I want you to hook me up
on the inside.
I know you know everybody.
This way, when I come up
with my own heist plan,
you know, I'll cut you in.
I can see I've inspired you.
Okay, l got a story for you.
It might help you in prison.
You wanna hear it?
We got a minute.
Yeah, l'd like to hear a little story.
RYDER:
AlI righty. So back in the day,
when I was a high roller...
GARBER:
When were you ever a high roller?
RYDRT: Well, you know,
I told you I fed this city
breakfast every morning.
Grits and eggs?
Oh, something like that.
Anyway, back in the day,
I took this chick to Iceland.
Iceland? Is that where
all the high rollers go?
Iceland?
Six hours from Kennedy and
the nightclub scene is, uh,
you know, is intense.
I thought I'd take this chick
to Iceland.
What's her name?
Ludvika.
She was Lithuanian.
She was an ass model.
She asked you what?
You heard of hand models,
right?
Advertisement?
Right, she was an ass model.
She did jeans and, you know,
magazines and shit.
Anyway,
it was Fashion Week
in New York,
and l took her to Iceland.
Ludvika, Lithuanian,
ass model, lceland,
you took her to the ice.
So what?
RYDER: Well, for 500 bucks,
they'll take you on a dogsled ride
on a glacier.
GARBER: Dogsled?
RYDER: Yeah.
And you know the old saying:
If you're not the lead dog,
the view never changes?
Right.
Otherwise, you're always
looking at the asshole of
the dog in front of you.
RYDER:
That'Il be funny in a minute
when I get to that part.
It's funny now.
[♪♪♪]
And it's 8 in the morning,
we haven't been to bed yet,
and we're tooling across
this glacier,
and l got this hangover that's
creeping up the back of my neck,
and guess
what I'm looking at?
Obviously you're staring
at the ass of the dog
in front of you.
RYDER:
You got it.
So this dog,
out of nowhere, just
lifts its hind legs up,
and puts them in
the harness there
and just takes a shit
while he's running
on his front paws.
So he's dumping
and running
all at the same time.
Now, that's
multi-fucking-tasking
if you ask me.
Get out of here.
Did it hit you?
Shit always hits you, man.
[♪♪♪]
I didn't know it at the time,
but it was profound.
GARBER: Profound? You lost me.
RYDER: Yeah.
Well, you know,
when l went to prison
later on, which you called,
uh, I had trouble
going to the toilet.
You know, a privacy thing.
And l couldn't take a shit.
I was scared shitless, literally.
So you know
what I thought of?
You thought of the dog.
RYDER: That's right.
I thought if that dog could
do what it needed to do,
so could l.
Saved my fucking life.
Wow, that is profound.
WHlSPERlNG]
Keep going.
And, you know, it's--
It's-- It's--
People adapt.
It's like you and l,
like today.
We didn't know how
the day was gonna start.
RYDER: Wrong.
GARBER: Wrong what?
I knew exactly
how it was gonna start.
Yeah, but do you know
how it's gonna end?
I'm tired of talking to you, Garber.
Now, wait a minute.
Call me when the money comes in.
You got four minutes.
I don't know
what he looks like,
but he sounds good.
Fucking talk shit,
what are you fucking doing?
He's got a sexy voice
though, man.
He'd be my bitch in prison.
Where are we?
Less than 1 0 blocks away.
We'll make it.
[♪♪♪]
Fuck, look out!
[HORNS HONKING]
MAN 1 :
Jesus.
Shit. The goddamn
money car crashed
on 1 st Avenue.
Get a radio car, put it
on the motorcycles,
get it there.
[GROANING]
MAN 2:
Watch it. Easy.
MAN 3:
Here, lean up here.
MAN 4:
Hey, get that last bag.
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
You got 22 seconds, Garber.
GARBER: All right, we just had
a little problem over here, that's all.
I don't care.
Two minutes.
HENRY: Just tell him it's here.
How the hell's he gonna know?
I don't think we should lie.
CAMONETTl: Tell him the truth.
HENRY: No, tell him it's there. Do it.
GARBER:
Tell him the truth?
He's gonna make me do it.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six...
Tell him the truth or lie?
Tell him the truth.
No. Tell him it's there.
Four, three...
HENRY: Tell him it's here.
It's here.
Two, one.
The money's there,
it's at 42nd and Vanderbilt.
Liar!
Motherfucking liar!
Seven.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
GARBER: Ryder. All right, listen.
Lucky lady, up. Come on, up.
GARBER: We made a mistake.
Shit. I think that's him. That's Ryder.
RYDER [ON VlDEO]: Lucky lady, up.
GARBER:
Ryder, listen to me.
Listen, listen. lt was an accident.
Keep talking.
Ryder, we made a mistake. l'm--
It's my fault. The car crashed.
MAYOR: Tell him something!
GARBER:
That's why the money's not there.
Up!
Wait.
Fuck, no.
RYDER: Get up!
No. Get back in line!
Ryder,
like one minute
it's gonna take.
Ryder, don't do this,
for God's sake.
It was an accident.
Come on.
Wait.
It's the only plan I got.
Ryder, listen,
it was an accident.
It was an accident, Ryder.
We made a mistake.
It was an accident, Ryder!
It was an accident!
Come on, motherfucker!
Oh, shit.
WOMAN [ON SCREEN]: Aah!
God!
Oh, my God.
ESU Team 1 to Sniper 1 ,
do you have a shot?
That's your fault.
SNlPER:
I got an easy shot.
Please advise.
OFFlCER: Stand by.
Roger that.
[♪♪♪]
SNlPER:
Aah!
Shit!
[SCREAMlNG]
[HOSTAGES SCREAMING
AND GUNSHOTS ON TV]
What the fuck happened?
Accidental discharge.
I just got bit by a fucking rat.
It's accidental discharge.
Who? Who got shot?
Was it Ryder?
No, it was Ramos.
Sergeant? The money there yet?
What? Yes, yes.
GARBER [OVER RADlO]:
Ryder, are you there? Ryder?
RYDER:
Get in here.
Shoot any motherfucker that moves.
That's an order!
Shit on your orders.
GARBER:
Can you hear me, Ryder?
Okay,
now somebody else
has to die.
Two people,
maybe all of us.
Did you hear me?
GARBER: l heard you,
but you gotta understand,
the circumstances,
they're different now for you.
You gotta rethink this.
No.
You got to adapt.
No, I gave you instructions,
and you know the consequences!
I mean, don't you have a plan B?
No, plan B is enforcing plan A!
And the minute
you stop believing me,
motherfucker, that's it!
I believe you,
but you gotta believe and
understand that those cops
are gonna be down
that tunnel and
next to you any second--
Bring it, man!
Let them unload their guns,
I don't care!
And what's the point of that?
Huh? What's the point?
I told you we all
owe God a death.
And now it's two minutes
past the deadline,
two minutes.
Which means two people,
almost three, have to go.
They have to die.
The money's there, Ryder.
Nobody else has to die.
The money's there.
I don't know what you owe God,
but I can tell you,
you can't pay him in cash.
You never see a U-Haul
behind a hearse, Ryder.
The Egyptians tried it.
It doesn't work.
You can't take the money with you.
Ryder?
All this talk of God,
I think I need to pray.
Give me a minute.
I can do that.
You did good, Walter.
HENRY:
What's the reality of getting
in there and ending this?
We'd have to be willing
to accept heavy casualties
on all sides.
It's a hard choice,
but I say make it.
New York City does not have
an acceptable casualty rate.
Now, this is your area
of expertise,
what do you suggest?
I say we should buy time.
So far this son of a bitch
hasn't allowed us to do that.
But this might be
the first time
we got through to him.
Trust your man here?
He confessed to a
felony 20 minutes ago.
In my opinion, there are
people down there who
are alive because of him.
Until we change the rules
or hope runs out,
we should stick
with the situation
we have now.
Do what you need to do.
Hey, Garber, you there?
Yeah, l'm here.
RYDER [OVER RADIO]: Speak up.
GARBER:
I'm here.
I talked to God.
That's good. yhat did he say?
He said l should trust in him.
All others, pay cash.
How soon can you get it down here?
Uh, from that station,
it would take them about
five minutes to walk it down.
RYDER: No can do.
About 1 0 minutes to walk it down.
No, no, no,
I mean you, man.
How long would it take you
to come down here?
I don't understand.
What do you mean me?
I mean you.
I wanna meet you, Garber.
And if you bring it,
I know the cops
aren't bringing it.
Well, you know,
I don't know how
I'm gonna carry that money.
I mean, it must weigh...
Two-hundred and twenty pounds.
Stick it in a wheelbarrow
or something.
Why are we discussing weight?
Shouldn't you be thinking:
"Get the fuck out of there"?
Okay, get the fuck out of there.
Good, that's progress.
Now, look, plan B. Your idea.
And part of plan B is you,
Garber, deliver that money,
or l kill another hostage,
you got that?
You got seven minutes,
buddy boy.
You got six minutes
and 55 seconds,
check me.
Do it!
I check.
And tell that sleazebag
negotiator to call me
when you've got the money.
You don't have to do this.
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
Finally somebody
got their head
out of their ass, huh?
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
GARBER:
Hey, how you doing, baby?
What are you doing?
What do you mean,
what am l doing?
I'm watching the thing,
the hostages.
They mentioned you, I think.
They said a dispatcher
was talking to the terrorists.
Yeah, yeah,
they're not terrorists.
They are if they're down
there waving guns at people.
Right, right.
Listen, Therese,
are you listening?
I'm listening.
Look, l'm the one that--
You're right.
I was the one that's
been talking to them.
I knew it.
I am so proud of you.
After everything, all this,
them trying to fire you.
[OVER PHONE]
Them sticking you
in a dispatch job and you--
Where are you?
I'm at a heliport.
I'm getting ready
to get on a helicopter
because they want me
to take the money
down to the tunnel.
What? Are they crazy?
It's real simple. There's nothing to it.
CAMONETTl: Over there.
What it is, is he knows
I'm not a cop, so he
wants me to come down--
Is it all right if l wait here?
Can I wait here?
They need me to take
the money down there
because they know l'm not a cop,
and, uh, you know,
they're saying that
he might kill somebody, honey.
Well, then somebody has to die,
because you can't.
He's talking to his wife.
I understand, baby.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
Just tell Angela at the meet--
CAMONETTl: Let's go!
When she runs over the hurdles
tomorrow.
Tell her to run straight through
the hurdles tomorrow.
Just like, you know,
I always tell her, okay?
Come on,
we gotta go.
You tell her yourself.
Now, you listen to me.
Yeah, l'm listening.
Now, you do what you have to do,
but we need milk.
So on your way home,
I want you to bring a gallon.
Of milk? Okay.
You promise.
Why do we--? Why a gallon?
Why not a half a gallon?
Just bring a gallon. A gallon.
Okay. Okay.
I can get a half a gallon,
I'll get a half a gallon.
I gotta go.
All right, thanks, guys.
Put your-- Put your headset on.
You ever do anything
like this before?
You know, go in unarmed?
Yeah. Two years ago, Brooklyn.
Flatbush Avenue.
I got the hostages out.
Oh.
And the guy with the gun?
The guy with the gun,
didn't end well for him.
For the guy with the gun?
Yeah.
It's nice seeing it
from this perspective,
huh?
You can see what you're fighting for.
[♪♪♪]
GIRL [OVER COMPUTER]:
I love you so much.
Did you hear me?
Yeah.
yell, do you love me back?
GEO [OVER COMPUTER]:
Can't really talk right now.
All you have to say is "Yes."
That's a lot less words than saying,
"I can't taIk."
GEO:
I'm having a really weird
fucking day.
Oh, God.
If we'd anticipated this,
we could have made
a lot of money.
What kind of guy
would you expect
to take a model to Iceland
for the weekend?
An ass model.
A Wall Street guy.
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
WOMAN 1 :
He's here!
WOMAN 2 [ON TV]:
The one-hour time limit
reported earlier has expired.
We're not sure who this is entering.
It could be hostage negotiators
or police detectives.
Once we have any updates,
we'll be back to you live.
Camonetti.
How are you? Hey.
Mr. Garber.
Lieutenant Staley.
Pleasure.
You got a radio set up to the train?
Set up right back there, okay?
You can talk directly
to the train or
to Rail Control.
Okay. Just do what he says,
and remember everything you see.
Let's go.
So who the hell did you fuck
to get this job?
Myself.
It was easier
than it looked.
Yeah, fucking yourself
always is.
CAMONETTl [OVER RADIO]:
Pelham 1 23, come in.
Who am I talking to?
This is Lieutenant Camonetti.
We spoke earlier.
Yeah, you're the greaseball.
What'd you do, go out for a pizza?
yhat's my money doing, man?
Where is it?
CAMONETTl:
Mr. Garber is in the tunnel.
The money is two minutes away.
Oh, Garber, man.
That is a dependable man.
He's a good man too.
CAMONETTl:
Absolutely.
How about you, Ryder?
Everybody's got some good in them,
don't you think?
Oh, is this the part where
you try to get through to me?
I don't think so, motherfucker.
Now I got three instructions for you.
Number one, when
this conversation is over,
I want you to restore the power
to the whole sector.
Number two,
I want you to clear the local tracks
from 68th Street
down to Coney Island.
And when l say, "Clear,"
I don't wanna see no cops.
I want all the lights green.
And don't trip me up with a red one,
got that?
Absolutely.
And number three,
don't play games with me,
or l'll track you down and I'll
fuck you in your greaseball ass,
motherfucker!
Over and out.
Let's go.
All right.
Know how to use one of these?
No.
It's really simple.
Okay?
Safety's on, safety's off.
On, off.
Just aim at anything you don't like,
and you pull the trigger,
you got that?
What if they frisk me?
We got that covered.
That's it?
That's it.
It's got a false bottom.
It's gonna be this one.
You got that?
I got it.
Good.
Don't worry about it.
Just don't fuck it up.
HILL:
Okay.
We got an ID on Ryder.
Dennis Ford. He was released
from Clinton Correctional
two weeks ago.
Did a nine-year stretch.
The last four on the same
cell block as Phil Ramos.
His name shows up on an
Icelandic Air passenger list
in September of 1 998,
right after Fashion Week.
Dennis Ford. You remember?
We used his case
when he was running
as an example of--
The kind of nonsense
that we would clean up if
I got elected mayor, yeah.
He ran a private equity firm.
His biggest client was
the city pension fund.
He siphoned off...
Try twenty-million dollars.
He did a plea bargain for three.
The judge gave him 1 0.
Maybe that's why
he's so pissed off.
Judge gave him 1 0 years
because we didn't recover
all of the city's money.
There was a couple of million
unaccounted for.
It was seed money.
JOHNSON:
Seed money? For what?
For today.
You play the terrorist card,
you panic the market into a drop.
And if you know it's coming,
you make a great deal
of money with $2 million.
What about the hostage money?
Are you kidding?
That's nothing compared
to the money you could
make in the market.
Let's get downtown,
get to the SEC.
Check the trades,
especially the put options.
[POWER WHlRRING]
MAN 1 : Good luck, Garber.
MAN 2: See you when you get back.
[♪♪♪]
We got company.
Garber.
When you put your
socks on this morning,
did you ever think...?
Turn around,
let him frisk you.
I was worried about you.
I thought maybe you'd get lost,
but then I remembered
you were a motorman, so...
These tunnels don't change much,
do they?
Just the people in them.
Are we good?
It's here. We're good.
All right, come on up.
Let's go.
Damn.
You're taller than
I thought you'd be.
You're good-looking too.
Come on, sit down.
It's nice to meet you.
What do you weigh,
about, what, 220?
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah,
220 on a good day.
Oh, that's Ramos.
He's what you would have called
the brains in the operation.
Heh, heh. Pow.
Dumb fuck.
So how long has it been
since you've driven one of these?
Uh...
That's why you brought me
down here?
Well, you're a motorman, right?
Once a motorman,
always a motorman.
You play your cards right,
you might get a part of the cut.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
[EMRl SPEAKING
IN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
[BASHKlN & EMRI CHUCKLING]
GARBER:
Well, this is, uh--
It's a new train.
I'm not certified
on the new trains.
Well, l got faith in you, man.
But I'm going to ask you
one question.
You know, that thing
when you told your wife
about the 35 K,
how did she react?
Look, we gotta talk about--?
Don't be sensitive.
I'm not being--
Did she freak out or what?
She wasn't happy,
but she understood.
Well, that's love, right?
No, that's marriage.
That's another thing.
[CHUCKLES]
All right, so what's the deal?
You think they're gonna
move that train?
Seems like a possibility.
How are we covered with
street-level exits, emergency exits?
STALEY:
I got a blanket on the fuckers.
I got radio cars and
a man at every exit from
42nd to South Ferry.
RYDER:
We gotta go.
Hey, Camonetti.
Fucking greaseball, man.
Hey, greaseball,
speak up.
I see red. l don't see green.
What's taking so fucking long?
Blanket is not tucked in yet.
You have to stall him.
I need two minutes,
buy me two minutes.
Still haven't
cleared the tracks yet.
Mr. Ryder, we'll be up and ready
in less than two minutes.
Okay, let me tell you.
We're gonna move forward here,
okay?
We're gonna move forward,
and if we get onto a red signal,
and the brakes trip up
your friend Walter Garber's
getting it in the head.
You got it?
Yes, sir. I got it.
Let's roll, let's roll.
Hope you were bluffing.
Yeah, l'm bluffing, man.
You gotta say what you gotta say.
You thought by coming down here,
you'd be redeemed, didn't you?
God bless you, Garber.
You're more fucked up
than I am.
Heh, heh, heh.
At least the same
fucked up. Ha, ha.
Come on, let's go,
let's go, let's go.
Let's go.
[♪♪♪]
She's on the move.
Put some speed on it.
He's by me, headed south.
Male, black, at the controls.
Motherfuckers.
You're playing with fire, my man.
I wanna see them green.
Turn to green or l'll put a hole
in Garber's head right now.
Do it!
CAMONETTl: We believe you.
We're moving as fast as we can.
What happens if they run a red light?
It'll trip the brakes.
Coming up on the first one.
[BELL RINGS]
There, that's what I'm looking for.
That's what l'm looking for.
Here he comes, right now.
Whoa.
That man Garber's
driving the train.
Sniper confirmed it.
Yeah, so what are you saying,
that he's in on it?
There ain't no fucking way.
Sniper killed Ramos,
he was their driver,
they probably need Garber
to drive.
[CHATTERING]
When they get to Coney Island,
they're gonna hit the trippers
and the brakes will come on.
Is that 33rd?
Yes, sir.
How far to the signal?
About a tenth of a mile.
All right.
You stop when we get there.
We're moving out. You got that?
I'm slowing down now.
Are they slowing down?
They have to.
They're coming up
to a signal point.
GARBER:
What is that?
You're the old motorman,
you tell me.
[BRAKES HlSS]
She stopped just below 33rd Street.
What the hell are they doing?
Oh, jeez.
Why that little stop?
Train has to stop
at signal points.
Some kind of an override?
RYDER:
Yep, some kind of an override,
that's right.
There we go.
Okay, let's move out.
Let's go, let's go.
Roosevelt tunnel,
which way?
Which way?
She's moving again.
Next stop, 28th Street.
CAMONETTl:
Why that little stop, huh?
I told you, the signal points.
Yeah. How do you know
they didn't set the throttle
and jump out?
Doesn't matter.
We got every exit covered.
There's nowhere to go.
Listen, the throttle can't be set.
It has to be held.
[OVER HEADPHONES]
lt's the failsafe,
it's a dead-man's switch.
If it doesn't have a man's hand
pressing down on it,
the train stops cold.
Believe me,
they're still aboard.
[♪♪♪]
[SCREAMlNG]
It's going faster.
Emri, off the track.
Come on.
Let's go!
Garber, come on.
Come on!
It's gonna derail
before it gets to Coney lsland.
That's it.
That's it right there.
Roosevelt tunnel.
RYDER:
It's a fucking train crossover.
Come on. Cross over now!
What?
Come on, move!
Hey!
RYDER: Fuck it, let's go!
BASHKlN: We gotta find him!
RYDER:
We don't have time!
Let's go!
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
I love you. l fucking love you.
[OVER COMPUTER]
Geo, I fucking love you too.
WHlSPERlNG]
Hello? Hello?
[PHONE BEEPING]
HILL:
We're getting calls.
Cops on the platform
are seeing passengers
on the train,
nobody in the motorman's booth.
Believe me, they're still aboard.
It's okay, it's all right!
As soon as we hit a red light
the brakes will stop it
automatically.
Yeah, but they're all green!
[♪♪♪]
[ALARM BEEPlNG]
[SCREAMlNG]
Four stops away.
Two stops.
Oh, Jesus.
The train just stopped.
[LAUGHING]
Oh.
I really gotta take that piss.
[LAUGHING]
There's no hijackers
onboard,
just passengers.
Where was that stop,
that first stop
that they made?
Near 34th.
That's by the Roosevelt spur.
CAMONETTl: The what?
JOHNSON:
A derelict tunnel
built under the Waldorf Hotel.
Converge everything on that area.
Throw a goddamn dragnet over it!
[♪♪♪]
GARBER:
Hey!
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
OFFlCER 1 :
Freeze!
[SPEAKS IN FORElGN LANGUAGE]
OFFlCER 2:
Put your hands in the air!
[♪♪♪]
Hey!
Hey. Get out,
get out, get out.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHING]
[HORN HONKlNG]
Out of the-- Get out of the way!
[♪♪♪]
Just go, go, go.
WOMAN [OVER PHONE]:
91 1 operator.
Hello? Hello?
This is Walter Garber, MTA.
WOMAN:
How do you spell that?
Gar--
Don't worry about how to spell it.
Just tell Lieutenant Camonetti
that Ryder is headed
to the Manhattan Bridge!
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
[HORN HONKS AND
BRAKES SQUEAL]
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Cars everywhere. Nobody's
going anywhere for a Iong time.
Hey. Hey!
Is he in there?
No, no, no.
No.
Where did he go?
Brooklyn.
He said he couldn't wait,
he started walking.
This fucking city!
Come on, you guys. Move out!
GARBER:
Ryder!
Don't move.
So is this how you thought
the day was going to end, huh?
When you put your
socks on this morning?
Huh?
This make you feel better,
Garber?
That make everything okay now?
No! But it's a start.
[TRAIN HORN BLOWS]
Don't move.
Don't move!
Hey!
Garber Baby boy,
I ain't going back to prison.
I don't-- I don't think you got any--
Any options now or leverage.
Hey!
We all owe God a death,
I told you that.
You're wrong, Ryder.
We owe God life.
Life. And that's the life
I gave you back today.
And now you have to
give me something back.
What are you talking about?
You got a gun in your hand,
I want you to use it. Shoot me.
No, shoot me before
they shoot me,
or l'm gonna kill you.
I will shoot you.
I don't want to, but I will.
Hey!
I thought you cared.
No!
You said:
"Ryder. Ryder,
don't you have anyone
who cares?"
I thought that was you.
Come on, man, pay it back.
GARBER: l'm not gonna shoot you.
All right,
I'm gonna give you 1 0,
then the deal's off.
I got a gun, I'm gonna use it.
I'm gonna take your life back.
Hey!
RYDER: Come on, man!
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six, five--
You gonna take this
down to zero?
Come on, motherfucker,
shoot me!
I am not going to shoot you!
Five, four. Come on.
GARBER: Hey!
RYDER: Three.
Police, drop your weapon!
I'm disappointed in you.
Two.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTS]
You're my goddamn hero.
OFFlCER:
Drop your weapon!
MAYOR:
Mr. Garber.
Interesting day, huh?
Yes, sir.
You know,
just about every day
I make a speech,
and it starts with:
"I'd like to thank you on behalf
of the city of New York,"
blah, blah, blah.
And l never know
who I'm thanking or why.
But you
did a hell of a thing today.
You went to bat
for the city of New York.
And on behalf of me,
I'd like to thank you.
Well, you're welcome.
I mean, it's been an amazing day.
Everybody's thanking me all day,
but I appreciate it. You're welcome.
And l want you to know
that tomorrow, the city
of New York is going to
go to bat for you.
In a big way.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
And this city has
a very good batting average.
I appreciate it.
All right.
I'm gonna get home.
Oh, take my car.
No, no, I'll take--
Put the siren on and everything.
There's a siren on there?
Yes.
No, I'll take the subway.
But I appreciate it.
Really?
Yeah. Yeah.
You know, me, subway
all my life. I get home
faster than you anyway.
I mean, not you, but,
you know, everybody else.
But thank you, sir.
You a Yankee fan?
No. Well, uh, yes.
Yes, of course.
Ha. Yeah, right.
[♪♪♪]
MAN [OVER PA]:
Stand clear of the closing doors.