[THE CRYSTAL METHOD'S
"KEEP HOPE ALIVE" PLAYING]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[MUSIC ENDS]
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
♪♪♪
COP 1: Delta Team, Delta Team,
he's about 50 meters away.
Can you see him?
Delta, copy that.
He's headed your way.
He's on the move
so let's be on standby. Roger.
[MAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
All right, let's roll.
[MACHINE WHIRS]
[GUNS COCKING]
♪♪♪
[SCREAMS]
[SHOUTING]
MAN:
Hold your fire!
[GUNFIRE]
[GRUNTING]
Everybody hold back out there.
Hold back.
Let him run.
He ain't going anywhere.
[SIREN BLARES]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[GRUNTS]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[GRUNTING]
[HELICOPTER APPROACHING]
[PANTING]
Back away! Back away!
Get it out of here!
Go on, get it out! Go!
They're gone. Nobody's gonna
hurt you. Put that gun down.
Put it down.
Don't make me.
[SCREAMS]
♪♪♪
It could be considered
inappropriate
for a murderer to appear
at his victim's burial, detective.
Just here to pay my respects.
Respect?
For the blood of my child?
My orphaned grandson?
Your son made his choice.
And you made your choice,
detective.
The day you chose to pursue
a vendetta against me.
Against my family.
Detective, your position offers you
far more opportunity
for arrogance than safety.
[SIRENS BLARING]
[FIRECRACKERS EXPLODING]
[CROWD CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
[TALVIN SINGH'S
"JAAN" PLAYING]
[SQUEALS]
[IN CHINESE] Don't open it. Mr. Wei
needs to see you personally.
My son is dead.
My condolences.
[SIGHS]
A child is irreplaceable.
Which brings us to your task.
It involves a cop.
That's why we want
an outsider.
After that,
your obligation to me ends.
♪♪♪
[CHILD LAUGHS IN DISTANCE]
CHILD:
Dad, come on.
♪♪♪
[IN CHINESE]
I went against Mr. Wei today.
There will be consequences.
[IN CHINESE]
What do you want me to do?
I'm worried about
my mother and sister.
I want you to take them from
Shanghai to someplace safe.
Here is some money.
Help me send it to them.
[IN ENGLISH John, we are
talking about Terence Wei.
Safe has a very
limited meaning.
There's been a problem.
MAN:
Hey.
Why ain't this car done, huh?
I gotta get this thing
on the boat tomorrow.
Nobody leaves until
this car is done,
you hear me? All right.
And get rid of
the VIN numbers.
I don't wanna get caught
for that shit again.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
All right. All right, you guys,
get back to work. It's for me.
And how the hell do
you guys get phones?
I don't pay you enough
for that shit.
Yeah. What do you want?
Eddie, it's John.
Hey, what happened? The piece wasn't where I left it?
I put it there myself.
It was there.
I need a passport,
can you help me?
Yeah, I'll just call Bob Bruin.
No problem.
No, he works for Mr. Wei.
Everybody works for Wei.
What do you want?
JOHN [OVER PHONE]:
I want someone who doesn't.
[GROANS]
I know this broad.
I try not to use her too much because she's
a pain in the ass, you know what I mean.
Her name's Meg Coburn.
Meg Coburn?
EDDIE [OVER PHONE]: Yeah. She's in
the Olive Building, you know? Uh...
I'll hook you up in the morning.
Where you gonna be?
Better if you don't know.
All right, Johnny boy.
Watch your back, huh?
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[TRICKY'S "MAKES ME
WANNA DIE" PLAYING]
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
MEG:
Yeah?
Meg Coburn?
Never heard of her.
Eddie.
Eddie sent me.
Great.
All right, well,
just hang on a second.
All right, come on in.
[BUZZES]
Can I help you?
I need a package.
A package?
What's a package?
Papers, you know?
No. I don't know.
I'm kind of slow that way.
So I think you're gonna have
to be very specific.
I want forged documents
to China.
Okay. You said "forged."
We'll do it.
Now have a seat.
Or not.
I don't have much time.
As you will.
China? Mainland?
All right. You're gonna need a visa,
a birth certificate, a driver's license,
and a passport.
Now, to make coming
and going easier,
we make you an
American citizen.
So, what you need
is gonna cost you.
No problem.
The only way money isn't
a problem is if I see it upfront.
Because you know,
I don't like hassling with assholes,
you know what I'm saying?
How soon did you say
you needed this?
From here I go to the airport.
One hour.
That soon'?
All right, back up.
You have to back up because I'm taking
your picture. It won't come out.
Smile and say,
"Flight from prosecution."
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
Okay. What's your name?
John.
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
And?
John Lee.
Thank you.
You sure you want John Lee?
Because aren't there like a billion
John Lees in China'?
Yeah, all right. John Lee it is.
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
I can fix that.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
Yeah?
Meg Coburn?
Never heard of her.
[GUNS COCKING]
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
[GUN COCKS]
[GUNSHOT]
MEG:
This way!
[GLASS BREAKS]
[THUG GAGGING]
[SIREN WAILING]
[NECK SNAPS]
COP:
All right, hold it right there!
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[HANDCUFFS CLICK]
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
[MACHINE BEEPS]
He's still out there.
He won't get to China.
We shouldn't be chasing
our problems, Mr. Kogan.
We should be solving them.
How would you like this handled?
Bring in professionals.
Men of John's talent.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[PHONE RINGING]
[KEYBOARD CLACKING]
Coffee, no sugar okay?
Nope, no sugar.
And a ham sandwich
would be better.
I mean, I've been sitting here
for 12 fucking hours.
All right. Let's see
what Meg Coburn's
all about, shall we?
Ah, swindle, bad checks,
mail fraud. No heavy felonies here.
But still what you lack in weight,
you make up for in volume:
12 arrests before your sweet 16.
It's a little unusual for a girl at that age
to be in that much trouble, don't you think?
Well, I've always considered
myself a feminist pioneer.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, you've been clean here
for about four and a half years.
That's a good thing.
You either got smart
or you've been very, very lucky.
COP:
ls there a third choice?
ZEEDO:
It doesn't matter.
Your good luck ran out today.
So now let's talk about your office
and four dead bodies.
I'll bite.
Where did they come from?
You didn't kill them, did you?
Detective, you really think a lightweight
like me did all that damage?
Who's that?
It looks like a ghost.
Oh, come on, Meg, you can
do better than that.
[CHUCKLES]
COP:
It was in your computer.
[SIGHS]
You're a bright girl in a bad place.
I can help you.
Yeah.
Well, you see, detective,
I can't seem to remember
one single bad place
a cop ever helped me out of.
Is that so? Well...
somebody had to help
your ass out
when you were 14.
Custodial placement.
But you don't remember that,
do you?
Fuck you.
You don't know
a goddamn thing about me.
I know everything about you.
It's all right here in black and white.
Go on. Read it.
It's your life, nobody
screwed it up but yourself.
Hey. You're looking
at two years, babe.
Minimum.
ZEEDO: Oh, you're not as smart
as you think you are, are you?
Because if you were, you wouldn't be
messing around with Terence Wei.
Terence Wei?
ZEEDO:
That's right, Terence Wei.
Where the hell do you think
all those dead bodies
in your office came from?
I have never dealt with
Terence Wei in my life.
COP:
Well, you have now, okay?
Okay, this is the part where I get to
talk to the court-appointed attorney.
You're not under arrest, Meg.
Which means
you have no right to an attorney.
It also means
I can walk out the fucking door.
Sure, you go right ahead,
but I tell you what,
there's somebody on the other side
that wants you dead.
I'm real scared.
Do you see me shaking?
I sure as hell do.
[CHUCKLES]
I've got a deal
for you.
Hm?
You tell me everything
you know about that guy,
and I can make
this all go away.
Put you under
police protection.
You know what,
I honestly don't know anything.
But even if I did,
I wouldn't give it to you.
Suit yourself.
Last chance to arrest me,
Detective Zedkov.
I didn't think so.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, by the way, tell whoever
you're gonna put on my tail
that I'm gonna lose them
on 6th Street.
Put Morris and Duke
on her ass.
Why don't we just
charge her, man?
She's red meat.
I'll put her on a hook
and see what the dogs do.
[WHISPERS]
Shit.
♪♪♪
[CLATTERING]
[WOOD CREAKING]
Aw, Jesus Christ!
What the hell are you doing here?
I still need papers.
Yeah, great.
How do you expect me
to cook a passport?
With crayons
and construction paper?
I mean, take a look
around you.
Anything that didn't get shot
full of holes, the cops confiscated.
My $3000 computer
is now a paperweight.
And, you know, four years
of work are down the drain
because you picked my door
to walk through.
We go to Eddie.
What for?
For help.
You must be kidding. I'm not
going anywhere with you.
You're like a walking
goddamn bull's-eye.
So are you. You're safer with me.
Is it my perfume or something?
You're the second guy today to assume that
I need, want or will accept help. I won't.
It's not an option.
And what happens when
I tell you to go fuck yourself?
Okay-
If that's the way you wanna play it.
But when the gun is in my hand,
we're gonna have
this conversation again.
[BEEPING]
Okay, come on, Nick,
what do you got for me, huh?
How about it?
My kid works faster than this, huh?
I'm trying, there's just
not much there.
Okay, I think I got it.
There's your ghost.
Good stuff, Nick.
Come on.
♪♪♪
Hey!
Next time kidnap someone
with a Bentley.
So how'd you piss off
Terence Wei?
Cops told me.
What did you say?
I didn't say nothing.
What, you think I'm an idiot?
I know you got me mixed up in
some Chinatown gangster bullshit.
Less I know, better.
Buckle up.
[SIGHS]
♪♪♪
Eddie?
Let's go.
Oh, shit.
JOHN:
Eddie.
[GUN COCKS]
You two make a cute couple.
You're welcome to try.
Take his gun.
Check them.
I beat my head against the wall
trying to anticipate your next move.
Actually, I beat Eddie's head
against the wall, ha-ha-ha,
trying to anticipate
your next move.
Mr. Wei will be pleased
we found you.
Okay-
Obviously, this situation
has nothing to do with me.
So I'm just gonna walk out that door
and pretend I never saw anything.
I'm sorry, Meg, but
you're in a little too deep.
You picked
the wrong partner.
Partner?
No, no, no, wait.
I'm his hostage.
I just met this guy
yesterday.
And he told me his name
was John Lee.
His name is John Lee.
And you know what
happens to hostages.
They tend to get killed.
Cuff him.
Cuff them both.
[GRUNTS]
Shit!
Ugh!
[GRUNTS]
How's that leg?
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
How's yours?
[THUG GRUNTS]
♪♪♪
[GUN CLATTERS]
Bring the car around.
Flush him out!
[MACHINES HUMMING]
[GRUNTING]
[GUNSHOT]
[WHEELS ROLLING]
[GRUNTING]
Oh, fuck!
Oh, Jesus. I wondered if you
were coming back.
Get down!
Oh, shit!
[GUNSHOTS]
JOHN:
Go, go, go! Get in!
MEG:
Keys! Take the keys!
Give me a gun!
Get this car moving!
Come on!
MEG:
Move the car! Go!
[TIRES SQUEALING]
Hey, let's go! Let's go!
Put the gun down!
Oh, shit!
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[GUNSHOT]
Another problem, Mr. Kogan.
John was lucky.
It won't last.
Don't confuse luck with skill.
I served with John's
father in China.
He was an honorable man.
But he could be ruthless.
John is like him.
Where are John's
replacements?
Arriving as we speak.
♪♪♪
[MEG GROANING]
It's gonna hurt.
Just do it.
[BOTH GRUNT]
[GUN COCKS]
I told you we would have
this conversation again.
You son of a bitch.
Now, what the fuck did you
get me into with Terence Wei?
He's my patron.
Patron?
He made it possible
for me to come here.
What, does he sponsor you
to play the violin?
In exchange for...
services.
What a nice way of saying
you kill people.
Did you think you could
fuck Terence Wei?
fuck Terence Wei?!
And now his foot soldiers are
all over the streets looking for you.
And for me.
Put your gun down.
Now would you let me walk
out of that door?
I didn't think so.
You're not leaving me with a whole
hell of a lot of options now, are you?
Do it.
Shoot me! Do it! Do it!
Do it right now!
I'll do it for you.
Ahh!
[BREATH ES HEAVILY]
Mm.
[MEG GRUNTS]
[INHALES SHARPLY]
I'm sorry.
Ahh!
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Then tell me what the fuck
is going on!
[SIGHS]
Our situation in China
is difficult.
I was born a soldier.
I've seen people die.
All I ever wanted
was for my family to be safe.
I would do anything
to protect them.
Anything-
Mr. Wei used my mother
and sister
to persuade me
to do three jobs.
The first two were criminals.
It wasn't difficult.
And the third?
I couldn't do it.
[CLICKS]
If I don't get back to China...
my family will die.
You picked a very bad day to grow
such a selective conscience.
[GUN CLICKS]
The day chose me.
[PHONE RINGING]
MAN:
Hello?
Alan.
[IN CHINESE]
It's me. How is my family?
ALAN [IN CHINESE]:
I'm having trouble finding them.
And Wei's people
are searching too.
I need a passport.
You can use mine.
Thank you.
MEG:
What was that all about?
[IN ENGLISH]
I have a passport.
Fix it for me.
Then you can go.
My family is running
out of time.
I'll need a picture.
This time it's two jobs.
But it's the two of you.
John is more trouble
than we thought.
MAN:
So, what's the time frame?
Immediate.
So I'm just curious,
what made you assume
I could jack a car?
Lucky guess.
Your mother or your father?
Mechanics Illustrated.
My father taught me
how to shoot.
Playing catch is so impersonal.
He was a general.
A very important man.
Was?
What happened?
He was re-educated
in the Cultural Revolution.
What does that mean?
Anyone who disagreed with
Chairman Mao was made loyal.
Families were punished.
Many were beaten,
tortured, shamed.
And how did a general
get re-educated?
By his son.
When I got older,
I promised
I would get my mother
and sister out of China.
[BRAD'S "BOOM BOOM CAW"
PLAYING]
[PINBALL MACHINE BEEPING]
What do you mean,
that's all you got, fool?
Give me the money.
Get the fuck out of here!
What's up, Meg?
Damn, you look good!
Not today, Loco.
Hey, what's with
the attitude, girl?
See, you need to spend time
with me. Get some of this love.
Meet my new friend.
What's up, "friend"?
Ain't no harm.
No harm, right?
Old boyfriend?
I try to stick
to my own species.
All right. Here we are.
Fastest passport photos in town.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
Now, give me 3 bucks.
Hostage etiquette.
Kidnappers pay for incidentals.
Thank you very much.
You gave me 4.
I'll take it as a tip.
Sit still and stare
straight ahead.
You know you could have saved
yourself a lot of trouble
just by doing that third job.
It was wrong.
Mr. Wei was taking revenge.
A man named Zedkov
killed his son.
MEG:
Zedkov?
Jesus Christ,
you're getting yourself killed
for a cop?
Not a cop.
JOHN:
His son.
What?
A 7-year-old boy.
Why?
That is how Mr. Wei deals
with his enemies.
Through the families.
All right, John. You're done.
Get out of there.
[CROWD CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
MEG:
Picture's not done yet.
We're gonna have to
wait a few minutes.
[WHISPERING]
Don't turn around.
Cops?
No.
JOHN [WHISPERS]:
Assassins.
♪♪♪
[CROWD SCREAMING]
Stay close to me, okay?
Now!
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[SCREAMS]
[GUN COCKS]
MEG:
Let's go!
[SIREN WAILING]
MEG:
John!
[GUN COCKS]
[SIREN STOPS]
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Hey, champ.
How you doing?
Dad!
Uh, what are you up to there?
STEVIE [OVER PHONE]:
Making a shake.
Listen to this.
ZEEDO [OVER PHONE]:
Let me talk to your--
[BLENDER WHIRRING]
Z, this just came in, man. Two officers
down in a shootout. Gotta move now.
Oh, hey, uh-- Hey, uh, Stevie!
Stevie! Stop it, would you?
I gotta go.
Daddy's gotta go work now, okay?
Hey, are you canceling tonight?
[ZEEDO SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKER]
ZEEDO:
I wouldn't cancel.
STEVIE: Because you promised
we'd go to the movies.
ZEEDO:
We are.
I'm gonna take you to see
the cartoon...
[BLENDER WHIRRING]
Shit. That kid turns that
blender on one more time,
I'm gonna shoot him myself.
Then I would have to kill you.
Wei specifically wants
the kid's brains
dumped in Daddy's lap,
my friend.
♪♪♪
Alan.
Alan!
[WHISPERING IN CHINESE]
I moved your family to Canton.
But I told Wei's men
they'll be in Shanghai.
[IN CHINESE]
How long do I have?
Wei will find them
by tomorrow night.
Get to them first.
Alan.
Alan!
I'm sorry, Alan.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[SHOUTING IN CHINESE]
[IN ENGLISH]
Why not me?
Why?
MEG: How do you figure
getting to the airport
in one piece with those
two professional killers after you?
They won't be.
They're here to finish my job.
Zedkov's boy must die
in his arms.
Then he will share Mr. Wei's pain.
MEG:
Zeedo's son for your family. Wow.
It's a hell of a choice.
People die.
Children die.
MEG:
People die.
Children die.
MEG: The same thing happens to your
family if you don't get there first.
When I was a kid, my mom
was kind of a weak woman.
She could never make her own money,
so we always had a lot of boyfriends
in and out of the house.
The one that stuck was Lester.
He used to beat on her.
And when I would
stand up for her,
he would belt me
in the mouth.
So...
I learned to shut up.
Then I hit 14,
and I was passing for 21
in all the local bars.
And, uh, old Lester started
getting real friendly with me.
So that was it.
I was out of there, clean.
Only I, uh,
left a 10-year-old brother behind.
Named Joseph.
I-- I-- I thought he
would be okay, you know,
because he was a boy,
and, uh, I didn't think Lester
would touch him.
And, uh...
One night Lester just
[CRYING] put Joey's head
through the kitchen wall.
[MEG SNIFFLES]
MEG [CRYING]:
People die.
Children die.
[SIGHS]
I've spent whole days
thinking about that one thing.
That one good deed that's gonna
wipe out all the shit that I've done.
You ever feel like that?
So you didn't wanna shoot a kid.
Welcome to the human race.
Standing aside is no different
from pulling the trigger, John.
[WHISPERS]
Here.
Now, that's some
of my best work.
Have a nice trip.
I'll need guns.
MAN 1:
Yeah!
[MEN CHATTERING]
[ITHAKA'S "ESCAPE FROM THE
CITY OF ANGELS" PLAYING]
[MEN CHATTERING]
What the fuck?!
[GUNS COCK]
MAN 2:
Aw, shit. That fool getting jacked.
You picked the wrong place
for that shit.
Oh, yeah?
Why don't we take it to the jury,
see if they'll stand up for a rat?
What's the story, Loco? Tell me something.
Should I dump on him?
No, no, no.
No, don't trip.
I got it all under control.
That's good.
Now get up. Get up!
MAN 3:
Like that, dog? Damn.
LOCO:
Keep my dice warm.
[MEN CHATTERING]
[DOG SNARLING]
[DOG BARKING]
Righteous,
these are my people.
Now I know what you're thinking.
And it ain't even like that.
Y'all's two is marked with
every drug dealer in town.
Now, if I'd been seen with you all
and I didn't make that call.
Shit. I'd be causing myself
unnecessary drama.
We wouldn't want that,
now, would we?
All right.
Break out the munitions.
That .45 is all I got.
You sure about that?
I forgot about that one.
You know what.
You can have that.
That's on me.
Give us your keys.
Say what? No, no, no.
Now you're tripping.
You stand by your product, Loo'?
[SCOFFS]
You're gonna bust me a cap
right here?
[GUN COCKS]
Oh, damn. Can you make
that a little louder, Loo?
I told there ain't nothing in there.
You got both my straps.
Thanks for the ride, Loo.
How am I supposed
to get home?
You've seen our car.
Just twist the red wire
and the yellow wire together.
Oh, man.
[IN CHINESE]
The time and the place.
[GUN COCKS]
The boy is at the
beginning of his life.
♪♪♪
[CAR HORN HONKS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[GUN COCKS]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[HORNS HONKING]
[WHISTLES]
[LAUGHS]
Mister Magoo! Reporting
to Fairfield Avenue! On duty!
[HORNS HONKING]
Follow me!
Ha-ha!
[GUN COCKS]
[CROWD CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
MAGOO".
Under cover, everyone!
Sir, may I?
All leaves canceled, lieutenant,
until I contact headquarters.
[MAGOO BLOWING WHISTLE]
Hello? Hello?
Do you read me?
This is recon calling
Blue Devil. Over.
[MAGOO SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY]
[EXPLOSION ON FILM]
Whoa! Great Scott!
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
[EXPLOSION]
[SCREAMS]
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
[EXPLOSIONS]
Zedkov, get your kid down!
[GRUNTS]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[CRYING]
Go!
Hold on! Hold on, Stevie!
We're gonna be okay,
all right!
[CLICKS]
[CRYING]
Zeedo, get your boy out
of here! I'll cover you.
Okay, okay!
Go!
Run! Run! Run!
[GUNSHOTS]
It's my boy.
They went after my kid.
Listen to me. We're gonna
lock down this goddamn city.
It's not them.
Coburn and her pal
saved my ass in there tonight.
What?
They saved my son.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
Come here, boy.
How you doing?
You still scared?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
Come on.
You sit here in the car.
Come here.
Guess what.
What?
I love you.
I love you too.
Hey!
You got the keys?
[KEYS JANGLE]
Have them take Stevie home
to his mother's.
Put them both under guard.
Pick somebody good. I wanna make
sure they're safe till this is over.
You want us to tell her
what's going on?
Tell her whatever
you want to tell her.
What are you doing, Z?
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
♪♪♪
Oh.
MEG:
John?
Call Zedkov.
He knows now.
You'll be safe.
Safe?
What about you?
My family is not protected.
So, what are you
gonna do?
Kill all of Chinatown
just to get to Wei?
I cannot run from battle.
From what I am.
There's a difference between
battle and suicide.
It would be
the last death I cause.
Fair enough.
Okay, John. Let's go.
You saved the boy.
This is not your fight.
I know.
Just somewhere along the way
I've developed a problem
with watching you die.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
I have the same problem
with you.
I believe
he'll come here next.
So Will Zedkov.
I don't think we should wait
for either one of them.
Of course not.
Call the airport,
then our men in Shanghai.
You'll handle his mother
and sister personally
before John gets to them.
And me?
Stay here.
Earn what you were paid for.
[GUNSHOTS]
[GRUNTS]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[SCREAMING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[YELLING]
Hey, hey, hey!
[PANTING]
Meg.
Meg, I'm gonna find you.
[CLATTERING]
But you could save me time,
and put a bullet in your head.
If the position were reversed,
I'd do the same for you.
[METAL CLATTERING]
[WHIMPERING IN CHINESE]
MEG:
Are you?
[CHUCKLES]
Excuse me?
Gonna put a bullet in your head
now that our positions are reversed?
Meg, it doesn't--
I didn't think so.
[GUN COCKS]
Checkmate.
[GRUNTS]
[GUNS CLICK]
[GUN COCKS]
The boy will die, John,
as well as your family.
Not in your lifetime.
♪♪♪
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[PANTING]
[GUN COCKS]
[GUN CLICKS]
John?
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[SIREN APPROACHING]
COP:
Zeedo!Zeedo!
What's going on, man?
They're gone.
[CHUCKLES]
[PLANE DRONING]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Attention, please.
Flight number 623 now arriving...
[WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA]
MEG:
Hey.
Hi.
I brought you a
going-away present.
[MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA]
♪♪♪
For your family.
Thank you.
You know, I've never made
a passport before
for someone
I didn't want to see leave.
[CHUCKLES]
This was a lot easier when
they were shooting at us, huh?
I will miss you.
[CHUCKLES]
[PLANE DRONING]
[TRICKY'S "MAKES ME
WANNA DIE" PLAYING]