Steve: This thing's moving too fast,
and it's heading for New York.
Carter: [British accent]
Give me your coordinates.
I'll find you a safe landing site.
There's not gonna be a safe landing,
but I can try and force it down.
I-I-I'll get Howard on the line.
He'll know what to do.
I got to put her in the water.
Please, don't do this.
We... we have time. We can work it out.
Peggy.
This is my choice.
[Wind whistling]
[Teakettle whistling]
["That Man" plays]
♪ I'm in a little bit of trouble ♪
♪ And I'm in real deep ♪
♪ From the beginning to the end ♪
♪ He was no more than a friend to me ♪
I thought we could stop off in Lucerne
for a late-night fondue.
Stark is the best civilian
pilot I've ever seen.
We're lucky to have him.
♪ 'Cause like the sweet serenade ♪
♪ Bet he know he's got it made with me ♪
♪ Ooh, that man is like a flame ♪
♪ And, ooh, that man
plays me like a game ♪
♪ My only sin is I can't win ♪
♪ Ooh, I wanna love that man ♪
♪ Ooh, that man is on my list ♪
♪ And, ooh, that man, I wanna kiss ♪
♪ My only sin is I can't win ♪
♪ Ooh, I wanna love that man ♪
[Sighs]
- Don't bother.
- Colleen.
I can't feel my feet.
They let 10 girls go yesterday.
[Sneezes]
Did they say why?
Because 10 more G.I.s got discharged.
I had to show a guy from
Canarsie how to use a rivet gun.
Ohh. I think I have tuberculosis.
Thanks, by the way.
You loaned this to me last
night while you were at work.
[Scoffs] It looks better on you.
Kind of thing might really
catch a man's eye...
Say, on a... date?
Well, don't hold your breath...
Especially with tuberculosis.
You know, there's a difference between
being an independent woman and a spinster.
Is it the shoes?
[Chuckles]
Clock out, pull the curtains,
and sleep. Peggy's orders.
[Sighs] 'Kay.
If I don't see you, remember,
we're going to the movies on Saturday.
I have the night off.
I'll try.
You know how busy the office keeps me.
Peg, you work at the phone company.
It ain't life and death.
Darling, you have no idea.
Synced by emmasan
www.addic7ed.com
[Horns honking]
[Jackhammer pounding]
[Indistinct conversations]
[Elevator bell dings]
[Telephones ringing]
Good morning, Rose.
Lot of hubbub today, peg. D.C. line's hot.
Love the hat.
[Gears grinding]
[Elevator bell dings]
Who was the asset on that?
The asset was...
[Telephone rings]
[Alarm buzzing]
Agent Carter, we just
caught a redball out of D.C.
All hands on deck.
Meaning cover the phones.
Rose, forward all calls
to the briefing room.
Covered. Shall we?
[Fanfare plays, projector running]
Announcer: Americans have long followed
the career of inventor Howard Stark,
from boy genius to weapons developer
to multimillionaire.
Even more have followed his private life.
But his most recent exploits
threaten to send this
flyboy into a nosedive.
Accused of selling weapons to the enemy,
the founder of Stark Industries
was recently called to Capitol Hill.
May I ask a question?
Webster: Not until you answer the question
already before this committee.
It's been so long, I don't
even remember what it was.
Did you knowingly sell
military-grade technology
to enemies of the United States?
Not knowingly.
Did you do it unknowingly?
Now, by definition, that
would be impossible to answer.
[Laughter]
[Projector stops]
So far, six pieces of Stark's technology
have turned up either on the black market
or in the arsenals of enemy states.
He's been waffling on the Hill,
treating the whole thing like a joke.
Yesterday was the final day of hearings.
Stark didn't show.
They checked his half a dozen houses
and his half a dozen offices... Nothing.
So, as of this moment,
Howard Stark is not only
in contempt of Congress,
he's a fugitive from justice.
Find him.
Squeeze him till he loses
his sense of humor.
Thompson.
You're lead.
I'll ground his planes,
freeze his bank accounts.
There's a girl at First Federal
who wants to owe me a favor.
Sir, I really must object.
Why am I not surprised?
I knew Howard Stark during the war.
His help was invaluable.
He may be a great many
things, but he's not a traitor.
We're all aware of your record, agent.
I'm sure being Captain
America's... liaison...
brought you into contact with
all sorts of interesting people.
But the war's over.
Let the professionals decide
who's worth going after.
Sounds like Carter knew a
lot of guys during the war.
What'd you say, Krzeminski?
I wasn't talking to you.
You owe the lady an apology.
Oh. You standing up for her now, Sousa?
Better hurry. I don't have all day.
Huh? No?
Okay.
[Both laugh]
Agent Sousa, about what you just did...
Ah, don't worry about it...
I wish you hadn't.
You're an agent. They
treat you like a secretary.
- I just wanted...
- And I'm grateful.
I'm also more than capable of handling
whatever these adolescents throw at me.
Yes, ma'am.
Doesn't mean I have to like it.
Well, that's another
thing we have in common.
Carter?
Gonna be a little busy
with your friend Stark.
If you don't mind,
these surveillance reports
need to be filed, and...
You're really so much better
at that kind of thing.
What kind of thing is that,
Agent Thompson? The alphabet?
I can teach you.
Let's start with words beginning with "A."
[Chuckles]
Thanks, kid.
Adios. Auf wiedersehen.
Aloha.
Poor guy.
Heard he got his personality
shot off in Iwo Jima.
[Big-band music plays]
♪ Sugar ♪
I saw him once at a U.S.O. show in Passaic.
You can eat him with a spoon.
Yes, I understand he was quite something.
[Bell dings] Cook: Order up!
Everything all right, English?
Fine, Angie, if you don't count work.
Boys at the phone company
giving you a hard time?
No more than usual. It's just...
During the war, I had a sense
of purpose, responsibility.
But now I... connect the calls,
but I never get a chance to make them.
Do you know what I mean?
I had an audition today, uptown.
Took three trains,
got two bars into "Is You
Is Or Is You Ain't"...
They gave me the hook.
I guess I ain't.
We all got to pay our dues,
even if it takes a while.
You got talent.
It's just a matter of time
before Broadway calls.
I'm afraid I can't carry a tune.
Doesn't matter when you got legs like yours.
Man: This is supposed to be a BLT?
Where's the girl?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Do you not work here anymore?
Looks like I got to go.
Is he a regular?
Yeah, but a regular what,
I'm not allowed to say that on the clock.
See ya later.
♪ Though it may be rainin'
I still ain't complainin' ♪
♪ 'Cause you are my
shelter from the storm ♪
♪ When the wind is howlin', I won't... ♪
[Indistinct conversations]
[British accent] Miss Carter?
Do I know you?
Oh, we haven't had the pleasure.
But we may yet.
You're coming with me.
[Engine turns over]
[Tires squealing]
[Tires screech]
I know.
I should've called first.
Did you miss me?
They're calling you a traitor.
I'm calling it a setup.
I have a vault.
"Had," I should say.
Sub-basement of my office...
Triple-thick, lead-lined.
It was where I kept my bad babies.
Bad babies?
Inventions too dangerous for anyone...
Even my friends.
Which begs the question,
why invent them at all?
I can't help what I think of,
but I can damn well control what I sell.
At least, I could until last month.
What happened last month?
I was in Monaco... with
a lovely tax advisor.
When I got back, I found
a hole under my vault,
all the way to the sewer.
Somebody cleaned me out.
A couple of weeks later, my bad babies...
They start turning up on the black market.
But why run?
Why not tell the Senate the
truth, ask for their help?
Apparently, it's not too big a jump
to see me cutting a hole in my own vault
and making some money on the sly.
Really?
I'm just considering all the angles.
Seems you have a lot of them.
Now, that's the Peggy Carter I need.
- For what?
- To clear my name.
You can't be serious.
I try not to be,
but sometimes it just slips out anyway.
Oh, come on, Peg.
You know darn well I didn't do this,
which means the SSR is
looking for the wrong guy.
I want to find the right guy.
But I'm gonna need someone on the inside,
someone I can trust.
And, Peg, there's no one
I trust more than you.
Howard, you're asking me to become a traitor
in order to prove you are not one.
You do see the irony?
Come on, Peg.
I know they're not using
you right over there.
You want a mission that matters?
This is it.
My technology in the hands of some nut
that wants to be the next red skull...
You have no idea how bad that could be.
Right now, you're the only
one that can stop that.
Here's good.
Kill the lights.
[Engine shuts off]
[Buoy bell rings]
Where are you headed?
Some of my babies have
already sold overseas.
I'm gonna pay them a visit.
The rest of them are here somewhere,
which is where you come in.
Word is, one of the nasty ones
is hitting the market
in the next day or two.
What is it?
Just a piece of paper...
My formula for molecular nitramene.
Technically, we're not even sure it works,
but, well, let's face it...
I invented it, so it works.
If that stuff were ever fabricated...
Boom?
This much would level a city block.
And I'm not talking the
short ones... avenues.
I'm going to regret this, aren't I?
Absolutely.
But when you're not humiliating him,
that fellow up there is
my butler... Edwin Jarvis.
He'll help you in any way he can.
I owe you one, pal.
[Buoy bell rings]
There are only a dozen fences
that can handle something this hot.
[Boat engine turns over]
You just got to learn which one.
And I figured you'd never
have any trouble finding a man.
The trick is finding the right one.
Nice to see you, too, Howard.
[Buoy bell rings]
The next time you approach
a woman in a dark alley,
you might introduce yourself.
Well, I shall endeavor to remember that,
provided my concussion isn't too severe.
Should you need me.
Call any time before 9:00.
What happens at 9:00?
My wife and I go to bed.
7:00, Sherry. 8:00, Benny Goodman.
9:00, bed.
You're new to espionage, aren't you?
Far from it.
Last summer, I caught the cook
pocketing the good spoons.
What now, miss Carter?
Now I go to work.
[Indistinct conversations]
[Horns honk]
[Telephone rings]
Man: Oh, good, good. Good.
No, I've been waiting for your call.
Yeah, you know, it was
about two weeks ago...
You know, you are expected
to go home at night.
Most fugitive cases are
solved in the first 72 hours.
If Stark's sailing into the sunset,
maybe this is where he starts.
He must have really liked that girl.
Hmm?
Because there's no other
reason why he'd get in a boat.
I'm sorry, Daniel, but Stark hates water.
He can't even swim.
Really? How do you...
He tried to kiss me on V-E day.
I knocked him into the Thames.
We had to get frogmen to fish him out.
Classified information...
Something's up.
Thompson's working on his next medal.
Got word of a fence
trying to sell one of Stark's inventions...
Club owner named Spider Raymond.
Where's it happening?
Need-to-know only.
Kind of gives you a warm
feeling, doesn't it?
Get you a refill?
Actually, I'm still...
Drinking that.
Post eyes at the exits and at
the newsstand across the street.
Dress sharp... Handkerchiefs, spit shine.
It'll be a rich crowd.
Do your best.
I'll call o'Dwyer, get
you some uniformed backup.
Too showy. Raymond's paranoid.
Only things he lets slide
are blondes and money.
If we want to grab Raymond and his buyer
with whatever it is that Stark is selling,
then I go in light and fast.
We want everyone feeling real comfortable.
Two men, sidearms only.
That how you did it in Okinawa?
Sometimes. Other times, we brought a tank.
Figured we'd save that for later.
[Chuckles]
Okay, Thompson, this is your play.
Grinding beans over there, Carter?
This is field agents only.
It's okay, chief. Let her stay.
Maybe she'll learn something.
Thank you, agent. I already have.
What do you really want?
I wonder if I might request a sick day.
What's the matter? Got a headache?
Amongst other things.
Ladies' things.
Oh, geez.
[Clears throat]
Yeah, sure, take the day.
Go shopping, whatever makes you feel better.
Thank you for your understanding.
Enjoy your coffee.
You got any issues need taken care of?
[Big-band music plays]
Raymond: If this stuff does what
you say it can, Brannis,
you're gonna be very rich.
And I'm guessing a fair amount of people
are gonna be very dead.
You know, we could, uh,
do some serious business
if you'd just tell me what else you got
out of Howard Stark's basement.
What've you got?
A-bombs? Ray guns?
Jane Russell's number?
[Chuckles]
Well, whatever it is,
if you need to liquidate, my door's open.
[Door opens]
Nice talking to you.
[Music continues]
You look like a lady looking to dance.
[American accent] I'm afraid
I'd only step on your toes.
Another time, perhaps.
Oh, no, we're supposed to be upstairs.
[Camera shutter clicks]
I'm looking for Mr. Raymond.
I have something I'd like to sell.
First door on the right.
Thanks, sugar.
[Knock on door]
Mr. Raymond, is this a bad time?
We'll only know after it's over.
Bring the rest of you in here.
I hope you don't find me forward.
Well, I'm not the judgmental type.
Um... [Chuckles nervously]
[Clears throat]
I know you are in, um...
possession of a certain chemical formula.
I got a lot of club to run,
miss, so if you'd just...
It's okay. Let's make this a game.
You seem like you might like games.
You don't have to tell me anything.
You just have to, um...
look right here.
Now, I don't care where you got it,
but cards on the table...
You are the proud owner of
a certain chemical formula.
Just a little piece of paper, right?
I have some friends who
would be very interested
in buying that formula.
Now, I know... I said, "Spider Raymond,
"he doesn't hold on to anything for long.
He must already have a buyer."
But, you see, the thing is, I think I can...
Offer you more.
Is it here?
Do you want me to search you?
Sweetheart, I don't have it on me.
[Chuckles]
[Grunting]
Hey, boss, there's a guy downstairs that...
I guess I'll just have him wait.
[Sighs]
[Normal voice] Well,
that was a bit premature.
[Dial clicking]
[Lock clicks]
Crikey O'Reilly.
[Telephone rings]
♪ I dreamed a dream of you last night ♪
Jarvis residence.
- They've weaponized it.
- Miss Carter?
Do you know anyone else handling
high explosives at this time of night?
As a matter of fact, no.
It's just that I promised
my wife a soufflé,
and if I don't get it in the oven by...
Mr. Jarvis, what was once
a theory is now a bomb,
so apologies to your wife,
but dinner will have to wait.
No, you're quite right.
Mr. Stark left a note. Hold the line.
♪ The sweetest dream ♪
♪ I ever knew ♪
♪ Where I awake ♪
Is the nitramene, by any chance, glowing?
Yes.
Oh, that's not ideal.
"An orange glow would indicate
"the nitramene has reached peak volatility
"and should be handled with caution.
"Cracking its shell would
result in an implosion
with a blast radius of..."
Oh. 500 yards.
Delightful.
"Render it inert with a solution
of sodium hydrogen carbonate and acetate."
Where you're going to find that at
this time of night, I have no idea.
Leave that to me.
There's one last note here.
"Avoid touching the core
to the containment ring.
Touching the core will result in..."
Death?
I was going to say "core overload,"
but yes.
[Door opens]
Anna: Edwin, I'm home!
Uh, I won't be a moment, Anna!
If that will be all?
Mr. Jarvis, you do realize
that this job will have certain
after-hours requirements?
So does my wife, Miss Carter.
Good night.
[Click, dial tone]
[Jazz music plays]
You boys got a warrant,
or are you just here to socialize?
Both.
You don't mind if we take
a look around, do you?
[Indistinct conversations]
[Laughter]
[Gasps]
What?
You don't say.
[American accent] Fancy a dance?
Uh, so glad you changed your mind.
What can I say? It's every woman's right.
Oh, no.
No, no, no!
Hey, now.
Listen, friend, I know we had a deal,
but the blonde must've taken it.
I can fix this.
[Silenced gunshot]
Dip me. What?
Thanks, doll. We should
try it again sometime.
Maybe we shouldn't have spent all that time
changing our clothes.
Seal the damn exits.
[Switch clicks]
Peg? Is that you?
[Sighs] Oh, hey.
They sent me home... Fever.
I didn't know what time you'd be back.
I can take the chair.
[Normal voice] No, don't
even think about it.
[Sniffles]
I'll make you some tea.
Wow.
Peg, you look like a million bucks.
Wait. Were you out out?
In a manner of speaking.
[Chuckles]
Oh, Peg, I'm... I'm really proud of you.
I knew you were too great a catch
to be alone for too long.
I want you to tell me all about it...
In the morning.
[Fizzing]
[Energy crackles]
[Breathing heavily]
[Sighs]
[Clattering] Colleen?
Is everything all right?
[Bottle clanks]
Colleen?
[Breathing shakily]
[Floorboards creak]
[Grunts]
[Gas hissing]
Aah!
[Thud]
[Dog barking in distance]
[Crying]
Jarvis: I'm sorry to appear callous,
but is there any way it can
be traced back to you?
My name wasn't on the lease.
No one knew me except...
Did she have any family?
She lost a brother at guadalcanal.
I'd only known her a few months.
I needed a place to stay.
I didn't know anyone in...
I seem to have a habit of
losing people closest to me.
Perhaps "losing" is too nice a word.
I get them killed.
Miss Carter.
When Howard came to me,
I was damn happy to see him.
I'd been wallowing in it since the war,
wondering why no one would
give Agent Peggy Carter a shot.
So I grabbed the chance.
But I mucked it up.
And now Colleen is dead...
because of me.
Miss Carter, I've read your war record.
You are a credit to your profession.
If the men in your office can't see that,
then they're fools.
You were trying to do something good,
and I believe you accomplished it.
But was it worth it?
I don't think we'll know that
until the job is truly done.
[Sighs]
Where does your wife
think you are right now?
One of Mr. Stark's more... amorous admirers
has refused to vacate his penthouse.
I am presently supervising her extraction.
I imagine that's quite believable.
[Coughs]
You have no idea.
We need to know where this came from.
But I can't exactly walk it
into the ssr headquarters.
I may know a gentleman.
Jarvis: Dr. Vanko, what do we have here?
Dr. Vanko: [Russian accent]
A lanthanum carbon alloy.
Rather clever. I might add, rather unstable.
So it couldn't have come from very far away.
Well, before the war,
there were only three refineries
capable of something like this.
The Navy tore down Franklin Chemical,
and Eaglestar converted to Diesel,
so that only leaves...
Roxxon. Right.
This has to be 200 acres.
It would take weeks to search.
Dr. Vanko, please tell me
that isn't still, um...
volatile.
Oh, volatile... No, no.
Active?
[Chuckles] Oh, yes.
The nitramene still emits
low levels of vita-radiation.
Vita-rays?
Yeah, we occasionally use
them in our experiments
to stabilize the...
I know what they do.
[Horn honks]
I'm gonna need a rain check on that dance.
A week next Saturday, at the Stork Club.
You got it.
8:00 on the dot.
Don't you dare be late.
Just be there.
We'll have the band play something slow.
I'd hate to step on your...
[Static]
Steve?
Steve...
[Crutch clicks]
Sorry.
I still haven't quite got the hang of...
It's fine.
I can assure you, I don't do this often.
You know, after I got hit...
At the field hospital, the chaplain asked me
was there anybody I wanted
to send my effects to,
should, you know, the worst happen.
I told him I didn't think
my dad had much use
for two pairs of green socks
and an old paperback.
Let him remember my life, you know?
'Course, I didn't die,
which was inconvenient,
because the chaplain had
already trashed my footlocker.
Still missing half my stuff.
Can't find my leg anywhere.
[Chuckles]
Daniel.
You're one of the lucky ones.
[Sign buzzing]
[Static]
[Typewriter keys clacking]
[Static crackling]
[Typewriter bell dings]
[Bell dings]
[Static crackling]
♪
Well-armed for a mothball facility,
wouldn't you say?
Keep your eyes open.
But I'm coming with you.
Mr. Jarvis, that cook with the spoons...
Was she a large woman? Violent?
Well, no, she was quite
diminutive, actually,
but she had a vicious tongue
and extremely long...
fingernails.
[Device humming]
Oh.
Oh!
[Canister hisses]
Takes a minute to cool.
I'm taking a pretty big risk doing this.
Least you could do is smile.
[Gasps]
Jarvis: Miss Carter, it seems that...
[Click]
[Beep]
[Device squeals]
Aah!
[Panting]
That's far enough!
I wouldn't.
[Synthesized] You don't want to fire again.
Who are you?
I'm an independent businessman
just trying to make his mark.
By murdering people?
I don't murder people.
I just sell to people who do.
And what about your friend?
Green suit?
Scar on his throat like yours?
He's not my friend.
Tell me his name,
or so help me God, I'll
blow us both to hell.
He doesn't have a name anymore.
And you can go ahead and pull that trigger,
'cause if he's here, we're both dead anyway.
Leviathan is coming.
Who?
They'll tell you themselves soon enough.
You're not gonna like the future...
Such as it is.
30 seconds, agent.
[Tires squeal]
Mr. Jarvis, do you think you
could bring the car around?
Of course. When would you like it?
Oh, in about 20 seconds.
[Tires squeal]
Man: Stop him! [Machine-gun fire]
Meet me on the access road!
You know I'm being shot at?!
Now!
I'm terribly sorry, Mr. Stark!
Where are you?!
Just keep driving!
Could you be slightly more specific?
No!
Miss Carter?!
Go! Go!
Don't you want to get in?!
Drive faster!
We've only got 10 seconds!
What happened back there?
If we live, I'll tell you all about it.
Faster! I am going faster!
[Tires screeching]
It would seem it works.
Sousa: Flight manifests turned up nothing.
We got a call in to London.
I know a guy there. He's...
We were in the middle
of something here, Jack.
That bouncer from the
broom closet finally came to.
Says he caught a blonde with
Raymond's body around 9:30.
Why didn't he stop her?
'Cause they're still pulling
staples out of his face.
[Telephone rings]
Get that.
Chief Dooley's office.
So we're looking for an angry blonde.
Have you called my house?
And that is where my
promotion comes in, chief.
I talked to the club photographer.
He thinks he got a shot of her.
I'm thinking real hard about
kissing you right now, son.
Yeah, I'll tell him.
Double-time this over to
the lab, see if we can...
Port Authority says Roxxon
Refinery just blew up.
The whole thing?
Any casualties?
Hard to say. They can't find the building.
Let's go. You two, you're with me.
[Jazz music plays]
Carter: Perhaps some warm milk.
Jarvis: Something a little
stronger might be in order.
You did very well, Mr. Jarvis.
Your wife would be very proud.
She must never, ever know.
You'll get used to that.
What word did he use?
"Leviathan."
I'll check Mr. Stark's files.
Provided the SSR hasn't taken them all.
Get some rest.
To be perfectly honest...
I'm not sure I'll sleep for days.
[Bell dings] Cook: Order up!
Hey, honey, you back there,
or are you still getting your beauty sleep?
Yes, sir. You're in early this morning.
How can I help?
You do know the difference
between real eggs and powdered ones, right?
Believe it or not.
I did three weeks in a P.O.W. camp.
The Nazis fed us better than this.
Next time, don't get
smart with me, sweetheart.
Your brains aren't your best feature.
[Smack]
[Chuckles]
[Door opens, closes]
I understand you're not
happy with your meal.
- You work here?
- Unfortunately, no.
Ohh! Just so we're clear,
this is pressed into your brachial artery.
It may be dull, but I'm determined.
Keep smiling.
Once you start to bleed,
you'll lose consciousness in 15 seconds.
You'll die in 90 unless
someone comes to your aid.
Now, given your recent behavior,
how likely do you think that is to happen?
[Groans]
To prevent this not entirely
unfortunate event from occurring,
I'd suggest you find a new place to eat.
Do we understand each other?
[Strained] Yeah. Good.
Oh, one more thing... Tip generously.
[Exhales deeply]
[Indistinct conversations]
Jarvis: [Sighs]
Swish the glass with the vermouth,
tip it out, then add the gin.
Well, I'm sorry, Mr. Stark,
but I'm afraid I can't
be everywhere at once.
Well, you're quite right.
Miss Carter's an excellent choice.
I don't think she'll have
any suspicions at all.