Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
Only the Avatar
can master all four elements
and bring balance to the world.
[Dramatic music]
The equalists
are on the attack.
The Lieutenant
and his chi-blockers
invaded air temple island
and forced Tenzin
and his family to flee.
In the daring escape
lin beifong sacrificed herself
and saved the airbenders.
But she was captured
and Amon took her bending away.
Now team Avatar is in hiding
as they await help
from General Iroh
and the united forces.
It is a glorious day
my equalist brothers
and sisters.
Amon has torn down
the tyrannical
bending government!
He has declared
bending illegal.
And he has the Avatar
on the run.
Our great leader has a vision
for the future.
One day soon
bending will no longer exist
and we will live in a world
where everyone is finally equal!
The united forces
are on their way right now
to try and stop that dream
but we will prevail!
[Cheers and applause]
Can you believe Hiroshi?
"The Avatar's on the run."
I'm not running from anyone.
Let's go back up there
and knock some heads.
They'll never know
what hit them.
Relax.
General Iroh's coming
with an entire fleet
of battleships.
Then Amon will be
the one who's running.
I hate this
"being patient" stuff.
[Squeaking]
You two were gone a while.
We were doing
reconnaissance.
Whatever.
Welcome back!
Hope you worked up an appetite
'cause dinner is served.
Thanks so much for
letting us hide out with you
the past few days.
Honored to oblige.
My associates and I
heartily oppose Amon's so-called
"equalist" policies.
We got benders and non-benders
living together down here
but do you see us fighting?
No, siree.
We figured out how
to harmoniously co-exist.
You are a wise
and noble hobo.
Mmm.
This is the best-tasting
street gruel I've ever had.
Seriously.
I culled it
from the finest dumpsters
the city has to offer.
[Chokes] Blagh!
[Coughing] [Squeaking]
Can't sleep either?
No, I have this
awful pit in my stomach.
Me too.
It's so crazy.
A few months ago
I was in the South pole
practicing for
my firebending test
and now I'm in the middle
of an all-out war.
I know.
We didn't even
know each other then.
And now, I can't imagine
my life without you in it.
You're the most loyal
brave, and selfless person
I've ever known.
I think you're
pretty incredible too
but you already knew that.
I should probably
try to get some sleep.
Me too.
Good night.
[Grunts]
You will now be cleansed
of your impurity.
[Groans]  Next.
[Whimpers]  Coast is clear.
Once the united forces
arrive
we need to be ready to help
in any way we can.
They're here.
[Gasps]
Whoops.
Hmm.
Amon had to know
we were coming.
So why aren't
we meeting any resistance?
Wait a second.
Where are
the equalist airships?
I don't see any
mecha-tanks either.
Something's not right.
[Rumbling explosions]
It's a trick!
Water and earthbenders
detonate those mines!
[Muffled explosions]
What is that sound?
[Low buzzing]
[Buzzing intensifies]
What now?
[Engines rumbling]
Where does Hiroshi
find the time
to keep inventing
new evil machines?
[Whistling]
Incoming!
[Screaming]
[Gasps] [Grunts]
[Screams]
[Deep breath] [Screams]
Aaaah!
[Gasps]
[Water bubbling]
[Gasps, coughs]
It's all right.
I've got you.
[Coughing] Avatar Korra...
You saved my life.
Thank you.
I was prepared to deal with
sato's mecha-tanks
but not these new
high-speed aircraft.
I know.
Every time we think
we have an advantage
Amon outsmarts us.
No matter what our plan is
he always has a better one.
Amon is winning so far
but we're not
out of the fight yet.
I like this man's
confidence.
So how are we not
out of the fight?
A second wave
of reinforcements
is on the way.
But I need to warn them.
Do you still have a way
to get a message out?
I know just the man
for the job.
[Click]
And who is the recipient
of this top-secret message?
Commander Bumi.
Second division
of the united forces.
[Knuckles cracking]
Tenzin's brother?
Yes.
A bit of a wild man
but the bravest Commander
you'll ever meet.
Ready, sir!
Fleet ambushed and destroyed
by equalist aircraft.
Retreat to red sand island
until my signal.
Do not approach city
until you receive the all-clear.
[Beeping]
Now comes the hard part.
We need to ground
those aircraft
otherwise Bumi's fleet
will never be able
to retake the city.
They flew in
from this direction.
The airfield must be somewhere
over this Mountain range.
Everyone get ready.
We leave at dawn.
It's time
to take down my father.
Wait.
I'm sorry, but I'm not
going with you tomorrow.
What?
Why not?
I'm sick and tired
of hiding from Amon.
It's time I face him.
That's not a good plan.
We need to stick together.
I'm not waiting for him
to hunt me down.
My gut's telling me
it's time to end this.
On my terms.
Korra, this is not a mission
you should be handling alone.
She won't be.
I'm going with you.
You don't
have to do that.
Yes, I do.
[Sighs]  My grandfather would
respect the Avatar's instinct.
So will I.
Love you, little bro.
Love you back, big bro.
[Sniffling]
Korra, Amon is a nasty dude.
Be careful.
I will.
Good luck.
If you're going
into the mountains
you should bring naga.
[Grunts]
Take good care of bolin
for me.
Asami.
I'm sorry things got
so messed up between us
but whatever happens today
I want you to know
how much I care about you.
I care about you too.
Good fortune and success
to you, Valiant heroes!
There's Amon!
We need to get
into the temple.
Then, when he returns...
We ambush him.
What are you two
doing here?
Uh
we were just transferred.
Well, you're getting
transferred again.
Amon wants extra security
at the arena today.
The arena? For what?
The rally.
You should have
been briefed about this.
We'll be there, sir!
I know another way in.
Let's hide in the attic.
Uh, we're not alone up here.
Tarrlok?
I don't suppose
you're here to rescue me?
We had no idea
you were here.
Are there other prisoners
on the island?
No, I'm the only one.
And what makes you
so special?
I'm Amon's brother.
Both: [Gasp]
Amon is from
the northern water tribe.
He is a waterbender
and a bloodbender
just like I was.
What?!
Did you know
this all along?
No, not until
after he captured me.
How did your brother
end up becoming Amon?
It all began
with my father, Yakone...
With the help
of his former gang
he escaped prison
and underwent surgery
to change his appearance.
He assumed a new identity
and settled down
in the northern water tribe.
That's where he met my mother
a warm, caring woman.
Before long, they started
a family together.
[Laughs]
Amon was the firstborn
under the name Noatak.
I was born three years later.
Noatak was a good-natured kid
always looking out for me.
Those were the good years
before my brother and I
discovered
we were waterbenders.
At first, we were excited
by our new abilities
but our training brought out
a different side of my father.
Tarrlok!
You better shape up
or you'll be out here
in the cold all night
until you get it right.
I'm trying, but...
try harder!
Your brother
was never this sloppy.
Dad, he'll get it.
He just needs time.
Don't talk back to me, son.
Ever!
Even back then
my brother wanted everyone
to be treated
fairly and equally.
When I was seven
my father took me and Noatak
on a hunting trip
far away from our home.
He told us his true identity
was Yakone Republic city's
most notorious crime boss
and that he was once
a bloodbender of rare skill.
What's bloodbending?
The most powerful and feared
form of bending in the world.
It was declared illegal
thanks to that coward, katara.
Our family has the strongest
line of bloodbenders in history.
You boys have this power
inside of you
and I will teach you
to master it.
What happened
to your bending, dad?
The Avatar stole it from me.
That's why I brought you
out here... to learn your destiny.
You two will become bloodbenders
of the highest order.
When the time is right
you will claim Republic city...
and you will
destroy the Avatar.
You must avenge me.
That is your purpose in life.
The good days
were behind us.
Every full moon
our father took us on
another supposed "hunting" trip
where he secretly trained us
in bloodbending.
We kept the truth
from our mother.
[Animal groans]
[Groaning]
Stop! You're hurting it!
Toughen up, Tarrlok.
You'll need
a thicker skin for this.
[Animal groans]
Very good, son.
Very good.
A few years later
my father taught us
to bloodbend anytime
without the need
of the full moon.
We practiced constantly
and I hated every minute of it.
[Growling, barking] [Whining]
I had no stomach for
manipulating helpless animals.
My brother, however
seemed to revel
in his newfound power.
[lnhales]
[Whining]  He was a prodigy
mastering my father's
psychic bloodbending technique
by the time he was 14.
[Whining]
[Gasps]
That's the way it's done.
That's what you need
to strive for.
Even though Noatak
was my father's favorite
it wasn't any easier for him.
He carried the burden
of all Yakone's
expectations and demands.
Something changed
in Noatak over the years.
The loving brother I once knew
became cold and detached.
[Thunder rumbling]
Our father pushed us
to extremes
and one day he made us
bloodbend each other.
Noatak, go.
[Inhales] [Groans]
[Screams]  Excellent.
Uhh!
[Panting]
Tarrlok!
Your turn.
No, I won't do it.
Bloodbend your brother
Tarrlok!
That felt awful!
I don't want to
do that to anyone!
I never want to
bloodbend again!
You're a disgrace
a weakling.
I'll teach you a lesson
you insubordinate...
unh!
Stay away from him.
How dare you bloodbend me!
What are you going
to do about it?
You're the weak one.
Unh! Aah!
You always say bloodbending
is the most powerful thing
in the world
but it isn't...
the Avatar is.
He took your bending away.
What could be
more powerful than that?
I made you what you are!
You're mine!
We're your sons
not your tools of revenge!
Let's go.
We can run away
from him, forever.
Run away?
But what about mom?
We can't just leave her.
He was right about you.
You are a weakling.
Hunh!
[Groans]  Noatak!
Don't leave, please!
Noatak!
My father and I searched
for days
but we never found
a sign of Noatak.
We thought he perished
in that storm.
My mother was never the same
after the loss of my brother.
My father stopped training me.
With Noatak gone
his hopes for revenge withered
and he passed away
a few years later.
That's one of the saddest
stories I've ever heard.
Avatar Korra
I am truly sorry for all that
I did to you.
I thought I was better
than my father but his ghost
still shaped me.
I became a soldier
of revenge
just like he wanted me
to be and so did my brother.
The revolution
may be built on a lie
but I think Amon truly believes
bending is the source
of all evil in the world.
How did you figure out
Amon is your brother?
When he took my bending
the sensation
was somehow familiar.
I later recognized it as
my brother's bloodbending grip.
So he somehow
uses bloodbending
to take people's bending?
I don't know how
he does it, but then again
I've never encountered a bender
as strong as Noatak.
How in the world
do we beat him?
We can't.
Any attack we throw at him
he'll redirect with his mind.
That's how he's been able
to challenge any bender.
So much for our ambush.
If we stay here, we're toast.
But there's another way
to beat him.
How?
This whole time
Amon has been
one step ahead of us.
But finally we have
the advantage...
we know the truth about him.
If we expose him
as a bender in front of all
his supporters...
At the rally...
We could take away
his true power.
And undermine
this whole revolution!
Thank you for your help.
We can't just
leave him here.
Go. Amon can't know
anyone spoke with me.
Defeat him.
Put an end
to this sad story. V
I think we found
our secret airfield.
Bolin, once we get down there
I need you to tear up
those runways.
We can't let those aircraft
take off.
Aye-aye, captain...
ooh, general. General.
[Naga whimpers]
All right, you guys wait here
until we get back, okay?
Uh-uh.
Stay.
[Naga whimpers]
Why would there be fence
posts
but no fence?
[All screaming]
[Mechanical whirring]
[Cheers and applause]
Thank you all for joining me on this historic occasion.
[Cheering]
When I was a boy
a firebender struck down
my entire family
and left me scarred.
That tragic event
began my quest
to equalize the world.
That's a lie, Amon.
Or should I call you "Noatak"?
You want her taken out?
No.
Everyone, calm down.
We have nothing to fear
from the Avatar.
Let's hear
what she has to say.
Amon has been lying
to you.
The spirits
didn't give him the power
to take people's bending away.
He uses bloodbending to do it.
Amon is a waterbender.
[Crowd murmuring]
What is this nonsense?
You're desperate, Avatar.
Making up stories about me
is a pathetic last resort.
Your family wasn't killed
by a firebender.
His father was Yakone
and his brother
is councilman Tarrlok.
[Crowd murmuring]
[Chuckles] An amusing tale.
But I will show you the truth.
[Crowd gasps]
This is what a firebender
did to me.
What?
The Avatar is lying!
I'm telling you
he's a waterbender.
They don't believe me.
It didn't work.
We said what we had to.
Let's get out of here.
I wouldn't leave yet
Avatar.
You'll miss the main event.
[Whirring] [Grunting]
No.
They got away.
We saw them get away.
[Footsteps approaching]
Asami.
Asami, I know I have hurt you
and I am sorry.
But I believe that one day
you will come to your senses
and we can be a family again.
Are you insane?
How can we be a family
after everything you've done?
Mom would hate you
for what you've become.
How dare you!
I am avenging her death!
The airplanes are ready
for takeoff, sir.
Good.
Annihilate the fleet.
Both: [Gasp]
That's right, general.
I intercepted your message
to Commander Bumi.
I know exactly
where they're hiding.
How are we gonna
get out of here?
I don't suppose
you know how to metalbend?
That is a negative, sir.
Naga, over here.
[Naga roars]
Who needs a metalbender?
We got naga! Yeah!
I'm going after
those airplanes.
Whoa! No, naga!
[Gas hissing]
Huh, what do you know.
Just like
a future industries forklift.
[Screams]
[Gear clicks propeller whirs]
Aah!
Tonight, I rid the world
of airbending...
Forever.
[Crowd cheering]
Amon, let them go.
You're welcome
to come down here
and try to stop me.
He's trying to bait you.
I don't care.
We have to save them.
The Avatar
needs to be reminded
of the power I possess.
[Crowd screaming]
[Grunting]
Where are Pema and the baby?
In prison.
Beifong?
I don't know.
[Grunting]
Aah!
Follow me, kids.
Get them out of here.
We'll create a diversion.
Let's go get your mother
and the baby.
Prison break!
[Exhales]
[Exhales] [Screams]
[Grunting]  Let her go!
[Grunting] [Groans]
[Grunting]  No!
Korra!
[Gasps]
I told you
I would destroy you.
[Suspenseful music]  Aah!
[Screams] [Whistling]
Thanks for
looking out for me, aang.
[Grunting]  Whoa!
Whoa!
Thanks, naga.
Asami!
What do you think
you're doing?
You are aiding the very people
who took your mother away!
You don't feel love
for mom anymore.
You're too full of hatred.
You ungrateful
insolent child.
[Grunts] Aah!
I now see there is no chance
to save you!
Aah!
[Grunts]
Mr. sato, you are
a horrible father!
Aah!
You really are
a horrible father.
Aah!
[Groans]
[Naga whimpers]  Finally
you are powerless.
[Grunting]
[Struggling]  Amon!
Everything the Avatar said
is true, isn't it?
I just saw you bloodbend her.
You traitor.
I dedicated my life to you.
[Grunting]
You served me well
Lieutenant.
[Screaming]  Mako...
My bending...
Everything
will be all right.
We just need
to get out of here.
[Grunting]
I'm impressed.
No one has ever gotten
the better of me like that.
[Grunting]
It is almost a shame
to take the bending
of someone so talented.
Almost.
[Gasps] No!
[Grunts]  Impossible...
I-I can airbend?
I can airbend!
Hunh! Ha!
Ha! Hunh!
Aah!
[Grunting]
No... You...
Don't!
Aah!
[Crowd gasps]
Did you see what happened?
Who was that?
[Crowd murmuring]
Can you see him?
[Crowd gasps]
Could that be...?
You bending tyrant!
Evil Avatar!
What did you do to our
leader?
[Gasps]  He's waterbending.
What?
He is a bender!
The scar is fake!
The Avatar
was telling the truth!
[Suspenseful music]
Noatak.
It's over, brother.
I'm sorry for what
I had to do to you.
[Sighs]  Our father
set us on this path.
Fate caused us to collide.
I should have left with you
when we were boys.
[Lock rattles]
Leave with me now.
We have a second chance.
We can start over together.
Please, you're all I have left
in the world.
I can't believe
Amon got you too.
Hey, at least you unlocked
your airbending.
Bro, not the time.
Right, right.
I'll just stand over here.
Quietly.
In silence.
You saved Republic city.
But Amon got away.
Yay!
Uncle Bumi's here!
Wa-hoo!
[Claps]  Great.
Now I have
to entertain my brother.
The two of us
together again.
There's nothing we can't do.
Yes, Noatak.
Noatak...
[Chuckles]
I'd almost forgotten
the sound of my own name.
[Melancholy music]
It will be just like
the good old days.
[Oogi snoring]
[Door sliding open]
I've tried everything
in my power
but I cannot
restore Korra's bending.
But you're the best healer
in the world.
You have to keep trying!
I'm sorry.
There's nothing else I can do.
Korra can still airbend
but her connection
to the other elements
has been severed.
It's going to be all right, Korra.
No, it's not.
[Somber music]  Korra, wait.
Go away.
I will
but I just want you to know
I'm here for you.
No, I mean go away
back to Republic city.
Get on with your life.
What are you
talking about?
I'm not
the Avatar anymore.
You don't need to do me
any favors.
I don't care if you're
the Avatar or not.
Listen...
When Tarrlok took you
I was losing my mind
at the thought
of never seeing you again.
I realized...
I love you, Korra.
I...
I can't.
Korra!
We need to be patient
with her.
It will take time for her
to accept what has happened.
[Naga panting]
[Sobbing]  Not now, Tenzin.
I just want to be left alone.
But you called me here.
Aang.
You have finally connected
with your spiritual self.
How?
When he hit
our lowest point we are open
to the greatest change.
[Exciting music]
I love you too.
Thank you.
I am so proud of you
Avatar Korra.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.Com