[Computer beeping]
LEADER:
Bio-readouts are in the green.
Looks like she's alive.
There goes our salvage, guys.
MED-TECH: How are we today?
RIPLEY: Oh. Terrible.
MED-TECH:
Better than yesterday, at least.
Where am I?
MED-TECH: You're safe.
You're at Gateway Station.
Been here a couple of days.
You were pretty groggy at first,
but now you're OK.
Looks like you've got a visitor.
Jonesy! Come here!
Hey, come here.
How are you, you stupid cat?
How are you?
Where have you been?
BURKE:
Guess you two have met, huh?
I'm Carter Burke.
I work for the Company.
Don't let that fool you.
I'm really an OK guy.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
They tell me the weakness and
disorientation should pass soon.
That's just
natural side effects...
of such an unusually long
hypersleep.
What do you mean?
How long was I out there?
Has no one discussed this
with you?
No.
But, I mean,
I don't recognize this place.
No, I know. Uh... OK.
This might be a shock.
It's long...
How long?
Please.
Fifty-seven years.
What?
BURKE: You were out there
for fifty-seven years.
You drifted
right through the core systems.
It's really just blind luck...
that a deep-salvage team
found you.
It's one in a thousand, really.
You're damn lucky
to be alive, kiddo.
You could be floating
out there forever.
You OK?
[Hiss]
Oh.
[Heartbeat]
- [Hiss]
- Oh!
BURKE: You OK?
[Hiss]
Oh!
God!
BURKE: Nurse! Please!
Someone get in here now!
RIPLEY: No!
BURKE: Now!
- Hold...
- Please.
DOCTOR: Hold her.
Kill me!
No!
MED-TECH: Bad dreams again?
You want something
to help you sleep?
No.
I've slept enough.
Jonesy.
Come here.
[Meow]
Shh.
It's all right.
It's all right now.
It's over.
[Birds chirping]
[Chirping stops]
BURKE: Hi. Sorry I'm late.
Been running behind all morning.
RIPLEY: ls there
any word about my daughter?
Uh... I think we should
worry about the hearing now.
We don't have a lot of time.
I read your deposition,
and it's great.
If you stick to that,
we'll be fine.
The thing is, there are gonna be
a lot of heavyweights in there.
Feds, Interstellar
Commerce Commission...
Colonial Administration,
insurance company guys.
Do you have any news
about my daughter?
We did come up
with some information.
Why don't we sit down?
I was hoping to wait
until after the inquest.
Uh...
"Amanda Ripley McClaren..."
married name, I guess...
"age sixty-six."
That was at the time
of her death...
which was two years ago.
I'm real sorry.
Amy.
BURKE:
She was cremated and interred...
at Westlake Repository,
Little Chute, Wisconsin.
No children. I checked.
I promised her...
that I would be home
for her birthday.
Her eleventh birthday.
Ohh...
INVESTIGATOR: I'd like to
go back to this point...
about the override
destruct elements.
I don't understand this.
We have been here
three and a half hours.
How many different ways
do you want the same story?
VAN LEUWEN: Look at it
from our perspective, please.
Please?
You freely admit to
detonating the engines of...
and thereby destroying
an M-Class star freighter...
a rather expensive piece
of hardware.
INVESTIGATOR: Forty-two million
in adjusted dollars.
That's minus payload, of course.
VAN LEUWEN: The lifeboat's
flight recorder...
corroborates some elements
of your account...
in that, for reasons unknown...
the Nostromo
set down on LV-426...
an unsurveyed planet
at that time...
that it resumed its course...
and was subsequently set
for self-destruct by you...
for reasons unknown.
Not for reasons unknown.
I told you.
We set down on Company orders
to get this thing...
which destroyed my crew
and your expensive ship.
The analysis team...
which went over the lifeboat
centimeter by centimeter...
found no physical evidence
of the creature you describe.
Good! That's because I blew it
out of the goddamn air lock.
Like I said.
INVESTIGATOR:
Are there any species...
like this hostile organism
on LV-426?
ECA REP: No. It's a rock.
No indigenous life.
Did IQs just drop sharply
while I was away?
Ma'am, I already said
it was not indigenous.
It was a derelict spacecraft.
It was an alien ship.
It was not from there.
Do you get it?
We homed in on its beacon.
And found something
never recorded once...
in over three hundred
surveyed worlds.
"A creature that gestates
inside a living human host."
These are your words.
"And has concentrated acid
for blood."
RIPLEY: That's right.
Look.
I can see where this is going...
but I'm telling you
that those things exist.
Thank you, Officer Ripley.
That will be all.
Please! You're not listening.
Kane... the crew member...
Kane, who went into that ship,
said he saw thousands of eggs.
Thank you. That will be all.
God damn it, that's not all!
If one of those things gets
down here, that will be all!
And all this bullshit
you think is important...
you can kiss all that good-bye!
It is the finding
of this court of inquiry...
that Warrant Officer
E. Ripley...
N-O-C-one-four-four-seven-two...
has acted
with questionable judgment...
and is unfit
to hold an ICC license...
as a commercial flight officer.
Said license is hereby
suspended indefinitely.
No criminal charges...
will be filed against you
at this time...
and you are released
on your own recognizance...
for a six-month period
of psychometric probation...
to include monthly review by
an ICC psychiatric technician.
These proceedings are closed.
BURKE:
That could have been better.
Look, I think... Ripley.
RIPLEY: Van Leuwen.
Why don't you just
check out LV-426?
VAN LEUWEN:
Because I don't have to.
People have been there
for over twenty years...
and they never complained
about any hostile organism.
RIPLEY: What people?
VAN LEUWEN: Terraformers.
Planet engineers.
They go in,
set up atmosphere processors...
to make the air breathable.
It takes decades.
It's what we call
a shake 'n' bake colony.
How many are there?
How many colonists?
I don't know.
Sixty, maybe seventy families.
Do you mind?
Families.
Jesus.
[Honk honk]
AL: l'll be down in maintenance.
- AI?
- What?
- Hey, Al.
LYDECKER: Remember you sent
some wildcatters...
out in the middle of nowhere
last week...
out past the llium Range?
One's on the horn,
a mom-and-pop survey team.
He's onto something,
wants his claim honored.
AL:
Why wouldn't it be honored?
LYDECKER: Because you sent them
on Company orders maybe?
AL: Christ. Some haunch in
a cushy office on Earth says...
"Go look at a grid reference."
We look. They don't say why,
and I don't ask...
because it takes two weeks
to get an answer out here.
The answer is always,
"Don't ask."
LYDECKER:
What do I tell this guy?
AL: As far as I'm concerned,
if he finds something, it's his.
- Lydecker?
- What?
LYDECKER: You kids know
you're not supposed to be here!
Get out!
TIMMY:
You go in places we can't fit.
NEWT:
So? That's why I'm the best!
MOTHER: Knock it off.
If I catch you playing in the
air ducts, l'll tan your hides.
NEWT: Mom, all the kids play...
FATHER: Wait.
Have a look at this.
Folks,
we have scored big this time.
What is it, Dad?
I'm not sure.
Let's see if we can't get
a closer look at this thing...
maybe through that crack
on the side.
MOTHER: Shouldn't we call in?
Let's wait till we know
what to call it in as.
That's about as close
as we can get.
Should we look inside?
MOTHER: You kids stay inside.
I mean it.
We'll be right back.
- TIMMY: OK.
- NEWT: Bye.
TIMMY: Huh?
NEWT: Timmy,
they've been gone a long time.
TIMMY: lt'll be OK.
Dad knows what he's doing.
MOTHER: Mayday! Mayday!
This is Alpha Kilo Two-four-
niner calling Control!
This is
Alpha Kilo Two-four-niner!
NEWT: Aah!
Aah!
[Meow meow]
[Doorbell beeps]
BURKE: Hiya, Ripley.
This is Lieutenant Gorman
of the Colonial Marine Corps...
Ripley, we have to talk.
We've lost contact
with the colony on LV-426.
I don't believe this.
You guys throw me
to the wolves...
and now you want me
to go back there?
Forget it.
It's not my problem.
- Can I finish?
- No.
There's no way.
GORMAN: You wouldn't be
going in with the troops.
I can guarantee your safety.
BURKE: These Colonial Marines
are very tough hombres.
They're packing
state-of-the-art firepower.
There's nothing
they can't handle.
Lieutenant, am I right?
We've been trained to deal
with situations like this.
Then you don't need me.
I'm not a soldier.
BURKE: But we don't know
exactly what's going on.
It may be a downed transmitter.
But if it's not...
I'd like you there
as an advisor, and that's all.
What's your interest
in all this? Why are you going?
The Corporation co-financed
that colony...
along with
Colonial Administration.
We're getting into a lot
of terraforming now...
and building better worlds...
RIPLEY:
Yeah. I saw the commercial.
I don't have time for this.
I've got to get to work.
Right. I heard you're
working the cargo docks.
That's right.
Running loaders and forklifts.
Yeah. So?
Nothing. I think it's great
that you're keeping busy.
I know it's the only thing
you could get.
There's nothing wrong with it.
What would you say
if I told you...
I could get you reinstated
as a flight officer?
The Company's already agreed
to pick up your contract.
If I go.
Yeah, if you go.
Come on.
That's a second chance, kiddo.
I think personally for you...
it would be the best thing
to go and face this thing.
Get back on the horse.
Spare me.
I've had my psych evaluation.
I know. I've read it.
You wake up every night,
soaked in sweat...
I said no, and I mean it!
Now please leave.
I am not going back...
and I would not be
any good to you if I did.
OK.
Shh.
Would you do me a favor?
Just think about it.
GORMAN: Thanks for the coffee.
[Meow]
Aah!
Oh.
[Beeping]
Hello.
Ripley.
You OK?
RIPLEY:
Just tell me one thing, Burke.
You're going out there
to destroy them, right?
Not to study.
Not to bring back.
But to wipe them out.
That's the plan.
You have my word on it.
All right, I'm in.
I think that...
And you, you little shithead...
you're staying here.
[Hinges squeak]
[Chain jingling]
[Beeping]
[Coughing]
DRAKE: They ain't payin' us
enough for this, man.
DIETRICH: Not enough to have to
wake up to your face, Drake.
What? Ls that a joke?
DIETRICH: I wish it were.
DRAKE: Hey, Hicks.
Man, you look just like I feel.
APONE: All right, sweethearts...
what are you waiting for,
breakfast in bed?
Another glorious day
in the Corps.
A day in the Marine Corps
is like a day on the farm.
Every meal's a banquet,
every paycheck a fortune...
every formation a parade.
I love the Corps!
HUDSON:
Man, this floor is freezing!
APONE:
Want me to fetch your slippers?
Gee, would you, sir?
I'd like that.
Look into my eye.
Fall in, people!
Come on, let's go.
FROST: I hate this job.
APONE: Crowe, Wierzbowski,
on your feet.
FROST: I'm talking about
breathing, not this frozen shit.
DIETRICH:
Yeah, Top, how about it?
APONE: First assembly's
in fifteen, people. Shag it.
VASQUEZ: Hey, mira.
Who's Snow White?
FERRO: She's supposed to be
some kind of consultant.
Apparently,
she saw an alien once.
HUDSON: Whoopee-fucking-do!
Hey, I'm impressed.
VASQUEZ: Qué bonita.
HUDSON: Hey, Vasquez.
Have you ever been
mistaken for a man?
No. Have you?
DRAKE: Ha ha! Oh, Vasquez.
You're just too bad.
HUDSON: Hey, Top, what's the op?
APONE: A rescue mission.
You'll love it.
There's some juicy
colonists' daughters...
we have to rescue
from their virginity.
SPUNKMEYER: Dumbass colonists.
SPUNKMEYER:
What's this crap supposed to be?
FROST: Cornbread, I think.
HICKS:
lt's good for you, boy. Eat it.
FROST: I wouldn't mind getting
more of that Arcturian poontang.
Remember that time?
SPUNKMEYER: Yeah, but the one
you had was a male.
FROST: lt doesn't matter
when it's Arcturian.
HUDSON: Hey, Bishop,
do the thing with the knife.
BISHOP: Oh, please.
HUDSON: Come on. All right!
APONE: I don't want to see that.
HUDSON: All right!
What are you doing, man?
Quit messing around, Drake.
Bishop. Hey, man.
- Do it.
- Hey, not me, man!
DRAKE: Yeah, you. Don't move.
Trust me.
Aah!
APONE: All right, knock it off.
Thank you.
[Laughter]
DRAKE: Enjoy your meal.
That wasn't funny, man.
BISHOP:
Lieutenant Gorman? Mr. Burke?
BURKE: Yeah, thanks.
Looks like the new lieutenant's
too good to eat with us grunts.
FROST: Boy's definitely
got a corncob up his ass.
BURKE: I thought you
never missed, Bishop.
You never said anything about
an android being on board.
It never occurred to me.
It's common practice
to have a synthetic on board.
I prefer the term
"artificial person."
Right.
Is there a problem?
BURKE: I'm sorry. I don't know
why I didn't even...
Ripley's last trip, the syn...
the artificial person
malfunctioned.
Malfunctioned?
There were problems,
and a few deaths were involved.
I'm shocked.
Was it an older model?
Yeah.
The Hyperdyne Systems 120-A-2.
That explains it. The A-2s
always were a bit twitchy.
That could never happen now
with our behavioral inhibitors.
It is impossible for me
to harm...
or allow to be harmed
a human being.
Sure you don't want some?
[Crash]
Just stay away from me.
You got that straight?
FROST: Guess she don't like
the cornbread, either.
APONE: Squad, ten-hut!
Officer on deck!
GORMAN: As you were.
APONE: Quickly, quickly.
Settle down.
All right, listen up!
GORMAN: Good morning, Marines.
I'm sorry we didn't have time
to brief you before we left...
HUDSON: Sir!
What is it, Hicks?
HUDSON: Hudson, sir.
He's Hicks.
What's the question?
Is this gonna be a stand-up
fight or another bug-hunt?
All we know is there's still
no contact with the colony...
and a xenomorph may be involved.
APONE: Excuse me, sir. A what?
GORMAN: A xenomorph.
HICKS: lt's a bug-hunt.
What exactly
are we dealing with?
GORMAN: Ripley.
RIPLEY:
l'll tell you what I know.
We set down on LV-426.
A crew member
was brought back on board...
with something attached
to his face...
some kind of parasite.
We tried to get it off.
It wouldn't come off.
Later, it seemed to come off
by itself and die.
Kane seemed fine.
We were all having dinner.
It must have laid
something inside his throat...
some sort of embryo.
He started... Um, he...
VASQUEZ: Look, man,
I only need to know one thing...
where they are.
DRAKE: Vasquez, kick ass.
VASQUEZ: Anytime, anywhere.
HUDSON:
Right. Somebody said "alien..."
she thought they said
"illegal alien" and signed up.
- Fuck you, man.
- Anytime, anywhere.
RIPLEY: Are you finished?
I hope you're right.
I really do.
GORMAN: Yeah, OK. Right.
Thank you, Ripley.
We have Ripley's report on disk.
I suggest you study it.
RIPLEY: Because just one
of those things...
wiped out my crew
in less than twenty-four hours.
If the colonists
have found that ship...
there's no telling how many
have been exposed.
Do you understand?
GORMAN: Anyway, we have it
on disk, so look at it.
Any questions?
What is it, Private?
How do I get out
of this chickenshit outfit?
You secure that shit, Hudson.
All right.
Now listen up.
I want this thing to go smooth
and by the numbers.
I want DCS and tactical database
assimilation by 0830.
Ordnance loading,
weapons strip...
and drop-ship prep details
will have seven hours.
Now move it, people!
You heard the man,
and you know the drill.
Assholes and elbows!
Hudson, come here.
Come here!
APONE: I don't care if you are
short, Hudson. Get it done.
HUDSON: You'll get lip cancer
smoking those.
APONE: I want this loading lock
sealed. Now!
- How many more, Spunkmeyer?
- Last one.
Good. Take it away.
SPUNKMEYER: Clear behind.
APONE:
Did you check number three?
Hi. I feel like a fifth wheel.
Is there anything I can do?
I don't know.
Is there anything you can do?
Well, I can drive that loader.
I have a Class Two rating.
Be my guest.
Where you want it?
Bay twelve, please.
APONE: We're a team, and there's
nothing to worry about.
We come here,
and we gonna conquer...
and we gonna take some.
Is that understood?
That's what we gonna do.
We are going to get some.
All right, people,
on the ready-line!
- Are you lean?
- Yeah!
- Are you mean?
- What are you?!
- Lean, mean Marines!
APONE: Get on the ready-line!
Get some today!
Get on the ready-line!
Move it out!
Move it out, God damn it!
Get hot! One, two, three!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Move it out! Move it out!
Move it out!
One, two, three, four!
One, two, three!
[Grunts]
Absolutely badasses!
Let's pack 'em in!
Get in there!
Move it!
HICKS: Let's go, let's go.
APONE: One, two, three,
four, five, six!
I want combat seating.
You know your places.
Get those weapons stowed.
Let's go.
Come on. Settle down, people.
Lock them in, Hudson.
HUDSON: Ready to get it on?
You know it!
GORMAN: OK, Bishop, let's go.
Roger.
HUDSON: I'm ready, man.
Ready to get it on! Go!
FERRO: Stand by.
Cross-locking now.
Pre-launch auto-cycle engage.
Primary couplers released.
Hit the internals.
HUDSON: Oh, shit, man.
FERRO: Confirm cross-lock
and drop stations secured.
GORMAN: Affirmative.
All drop stations secured.
Stand by. Ten seconds.
Stand by to initiate
release sequencer...
on my mark.
HUDSON: We're on
an express elevator to hell.
Going down!
Two, one, mark.
Whoo-hoo!
FERRO: Switch to DCS ranging.
SPUNKMEYER: Two-four-oh,
nominal to profile.
FERRO:
We're in the pipe, five by five.
SPUNKMEYER: We're picking up
some hull ionization.
FERRO: Got it. Rough air ahead.
We're in for some chop.
RIPLEY: How many drops
is this for you, Lieutenant?
Thirty-eight.
Simulated.
How many combat drops?
Uh, two...
including this one.
DRAKE: Shit.
HUDSON: Oh, man.
Range zero-one-four.
Turning on final.
FROST: I got a bad feeling
about this drop.
CROWE: You always say, "I got
a bad feeling about this drop."
FROST: When we get back without
you, l'll call your folks.
GORMAN: All right.
Let's see what we can see.
Everybody on-line.
Looking good.
Drake, check your camera.
There seems to be a malfunction.
That's better.
Pan it around a bit. Good.
HUDSON: I'm ready. Check it out.
I am the ultimate badass.
HUDSON: State of the badass art.
You do not wanna fuck with me.
Check it out.
Hey, Ripley, don't worry.
Me and my squad of ultimate
badasses will protect you.
HUDSON: Check it out.
Independently targeting
particle-beam phalanx.
Whap!
Fry half a city with this puppy.
We got tactical
smart missiles...
phase-plasma pulse-rifles,
RPGs.
We got sonic,
electronic ballbreakers!
We got nukes.
We got knives, sharp sticks...
APONE: Knock it off, Hudson!
All right, gear up.
Two minutes, people. Get hot.
Somebody wake up Hicks.
FERRO: Coming around
for a seven-zero-niner.
SPUNKMEYER:
Terminal guidance locked in.
FERRO: Where's the damn beacon?
Oh, I see it.
RIPLEY:
That's the atmosphere processor?
BURKE: Yep, that's it.
Remarkable piece of machinery.
Completely automated.
We manufacture those,
by the way.
GORMAN: OK, Ferro.
Take us in low
over the main colony complex.
Storm shutters are sealed.
There's no visible activity.
All right. Hold at forty.
FERRO: Roger.
GORMAN: Give me a slow circle
of the complex.
Structure seems intact.
They still have power.
GORMAN: OK, Ferro.
Set down on the landing grid.
Immediate dust-off on my clear,
then stay on station.
FERRO: Down and clear.
APONE:
Ten seconds, people. Look sharp!
I want a nice, clean dispersal
this time.
Let's go! Move it out!
Head 'em out!
GORMAN: First squad up, on-line.
Hicks, get yours in a cordon,
and watch the rear.
APONE: Vasquez, take point.
Let's move!
Move up.
Hudson, run a bypass.
Second squad, move up.
Flanking positions.
Second squad, on-line.
APONE: You set?
Second team, move inside.
Hicks, take the upper level.
APONE: Sir, you copying this?
Looks like hits
from small-arms fire.
We got some explosives damages,
probably seismic survey charges.
Are you reading this?
Keep it tight, people.
GORMAN: Hicks, Hudson,
use your motion trackers.
HICKS: Nothing.
Not a goddamn thing.
GORMAN:
Quarter and search by twos.
HICKS:
OK, Dietrich, Frost, you're up.
[Beeping]
[Motion tracker beeping]
[Beeping louder]
HUDSON: lt's right in here.
- Now!
HUDSON: Hyah!
VASQUEZ: Good one, Hudson.
HUDSON: Uh, sir, we have
a negative situation here.
Uh, moving on, sir.
RIPLEY: Wait.
Wait, tell him to...
Hicks, back up.
Pan right.
There.
HICKS:
You seeing this all right?
Looks melted.
Somebody must have bagged
one of Ripley's bad guys here.
BURKE: Acid for blood.
If you like that,
you're gonna love this.
HUDSON: Quit screwing around.
APONE: Second squad,
what's your status?
HICKS:
We just finished our sweep.
Nobody's home.
APONE: Roger.
Sir, this place is dead.
Whatever happened here,
we missed it.
The area's secured.
Let's go check their computer.
- It's not secure.
- The area's secured.
GORMAN:
First team, head for Operations.
Hudson, get their CPU on-line.
HUDSON: Affirmative.
Hicks,
meet me at the south lock.
We're coming in.
HUDSON: He's coming in.
I feel safer already.
VASQUEZ: Pendejo jerkoff.
HUDSON: Sir, we got
the CPU on-line. No problem.
GORMAN:
Good. Stand by in Operations.
OK, let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
DRAKE: Sir...
they sealed off this wing at
both ends, welded the doors...
and blocked off the stairs
with heavy equipment.
But it looks like
the barricade didn't hold.
- Any bodies?
- No, sir.
FROST: Last stand.
DRAKE: Must have been
a hell of a fight.
HICKS: Looks that way.
GORMAN:
All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able to cut through
the med lab to Operations.
HICKS: Lieutenant.
Gorman.
Are those the same ones?
Careful, Burke.
HICKS: Looks like
love at first sight to me.
Oh, he likes you, Burke.
BISHOP: Two are alive.
The rest are dead.
"Surgically removed
before embryo implantation.
"Subject Marachuk, John J.,
died during the procedure."
They killed him taking it off.
[Beeping]
FROST: Yo, Hicks.
I think we got something here.
HICKS: Behind us.
RIPLEY: One of us?
GORMAN:
Apone, where are your people?
Anybody in D-Block?
APONE: Negative.
We're all in Operations.
DRAKE: Talk to me, Frosty.
FROST: Let's keep moving, baby.
[Crash]
HICKS: lt's moving.
DRAKE: Which way?
FROST:
lt's coming straight for us.
Straight up.
[Beeping louder]
DRAKE: Fuck!
HICKS: Hold up.
Ripley.
RIPLEY:
Hey, shh, it's all right.
It's all right.
GORMAN: Grab her, Corporal.
RIPLEY: Don't be afraid.
Come on. We won't hurt you.
Shh. It's all right. It's OK.
Come on out. Come on. Easy.
HICKS: I got her. Ow! Damn!
RIPLEY: Don't let her go.
HICKS:
She's under the grill!
GORMAN:
Frost, get your light up here.
RIPLEY: Where'd she go?
FROST: She's on the other side.
RIPLEY: Shine the light!
BISHOP: Here. Here.
RIPLEY:
Keep back. Don't scare her.
HICKS:
Grab her. We're gonna lose her.
RIPLEY: Damn it!
RIPLEY: Wait.
It's OK. It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
See?
Wait. No, you don't.
It's OK.
You're gonna be all right now.
Shh.
Easy. Easy.
It's gonna be OK.
It's all right.
You're gonna be OK.
Shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
GORMAN: What's her name again?
DIETRICH: Rebecca.
GORMAN: Now think, Rebecca.
Concentrate.
Just start at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
Look, Rebecca, you have to try...
Gorman, give it a rest,
why don't you?
GORMAN: Total brainlock.
DIETRICH: Physically, she's OK.
Borderline malnutrition,
but no permanent damage.
GORMAN:
Come on. We're wasting time.
RIPLEY: Try this.
It's a little hot chocolate.
There you go.
Whoop.
That good, huh?
Uh-oh.
I made a clean spot here.
Now I've done it.
Guess l'll have to do
the whole thing.
Hard to believe there's
a little girl under all this.
And a pretty one, too.
You don't talk much, do you?
HUDSON: Smoking or non-smoking?
GORMAN: Tell me what
you're scanning for.
BURKE: PDTs.
Personal data transmitters.
Every colonist had one
surgically implanted.
If they're within twenty klicks,
we'll read it out here.
So far, zippo.
I don't know how you
stayed alive...
but you're one brave kid,
Rebecca.
Newt.
What'd you say?
My name's Newt.
Nobody calls me Rebecca
except my brother.
Newt.
I like that.
I'm Ripley.
It's nice to meet you.
And who is this, hmm?
Casey.
Hello, Casey.
What about your brother?
What's his name?
Timmy.
RIPLEY:
ls Timmy around here, too?
Maybe hiding like you were?
Any sisters?
Mom and Dad?
Newt, look at me.
Where are they?
They're dead, all right?
Can I go now?
I'm sorry, Newt.
Don't you think you'd be safer
here with us?
These people are here
to protect you.
They're soldiers.
It won't make any difference.
SPUNKMEYER:
Need anything else?
Hello, Bishop.
Do you need anything else?
No.
Nice pet you got there.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yo! Stop your grinnin'
and drop your linen!
Found them.
GORMAN: They alive?
HUDSON: Unknown, but it looks
like all of them...
over at
the processing station...
sub-level three...
under the main cooling towers.
HICKS: lt looks like
a goddamn town meeting.
Let's saddle up, Apone.
APONE: Aye, sir.
Let's go. They ain't payin' us
by the hour. Head 'em out.
OK, Frost, you're driving.
It's OK. Don't worry.
It'll be OK.
GORMAN: I want
a straight "V" deployment...
second team on left flank.
Advance on axial six-six-four.
Tracker on-line. Set the V-gain
to filter R-F ambient.
APONE: Hudson, tracker on-line.
Left and right, little buddy.
GORMAN: Forty meters in,
bearing two-two-one...
there should be a stairwell.
APONE: Check. Got it.
GORMAN:
You want sub-level three.
APONE: Let's go, people.
Hudson, you got the point.
Hicks, watch our tails.
Nice and easy.
Check those corners.
GORMAN: Watch your spacing.
APONE: You heard the man.
Don't bunch up. Stay loose.
GORMAN: Your transmission's
showing a lot of break-up.
HUDSON: Probably getting some
interference from the structure.
APONE: Use those lights.
GORMAN: Next one down,
and proceed on a two-one-six.
APONE: Roger.
That's a two-one-six.
GORMAN: I'm not
making that out too well.
What is it, Hudson?
HUDSON:
You tell me. I only work here.
What is that?
I don't know.
Proceed inside.
APONE: Watch your fire
and check your targets.
Remember, we're looking
for civvies in here.
APONE: Easy.
HICKS: Tighten it up, Frost.
We're getting a little thin.
APONE: Nice and easy.
DIETRICH: Looks like
some sort of secreted resin.
HICKS:
Yeah, but secreted from what?
APONE: Nobody touch nothing.
BURKE:
Busy little creatures, huh?
FROST: Hot as hell in here.
HUDSON: But it's a dry heat.
APONE: Knock it off, Hudson.
Lieutenant,
what do those pulse-rifles fire?
GORMAN: Ten millimeter
explosive-tip caseless.
Standard light
armor-piercing round. Why?
RIPLEY: Look where your team is.
They're right under
the primary heat exchangers.
So?
So if they fire their weapons
in there...
won't they rupture
the cooling system?
BURKE: Oh, ho ho. Yeah.
She's absolutely right.
So what?
This whole station is basically
a big fusion reactor.
Right?
So she's talking about
a thermonuclear explosion...
and, "Adiós, muchachos."
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit!
Look.
Uh... Apone.
We can't have any firing
in there.
I want you to collect
magazines from everybody.
HUDSON: ls he fuckin' crazy?
FROST:
What do we use, harsh language?
GORMAN: Flame units only.
I want rifles slung.
APONE: Sir, I...
GORMAN: Just do it, Sergeant.
And no grenades.
APONE: You heard the man.
Pull 'em out. Let's have 'em.
Come on, Vasquez.
Clear and lock.
Damn!
You, too. Give it up, Ski.
Crowe, I want it now.
Give it up.
DRAKE: Right on, Vas.
APONE: Let's go. Give it up.
Frost, you got the duty.
Open that bag.
FROST: Thanks a lot, Sarge.
APONE: Hicks, cover our ass.
Head 'em out, people.
HICKS: I like to keep this handy
for close encounters.
FROST: I heard that.
GORMAN: Any movement?
HUDSON: Nothing.
Zip.
APONE: Holy shit.
RIPLEY: Newt, go sit up front.
Go on!
Now!
APONE: Steady, people.
Let's finish our sweep.
We're still Marines,
and we got a job to do.
Keep it moving.
Easy.
- Top!
- What?
DIETRICH: We got a live one!
You're gonna be all right.
Please... kill me.
DIETRICH:
Stay calm. We'll get you out.
It's gonna be all right.
We've got to get her
out of here.
APONE: What is it, Dietrich?
What's going on?
Convulsion!
RIPLEY: Ohh!
APONE: Dietrich, get back!
Aah! Aah!
No!
APONE: Frost, flamethrower!
Get back! Flamethrower! Move!
[Screeching]
- [Beeping]
- Movement!
What's the position?
I can't lock in!
Talk to me, Hudson!
Multiple signals.
They're closing.
APONE: Go to infrared, people.
Look sharp!
GORMAN: What's happening, Apone?
We can't see anything in here.
RIPLEY:
Pull your team out, Gorman.
HUDSON: I got readings
in front and behind.
FROST: Where, man?
I don't see shit.
HICKS: He's right.
Nothing's back here.
HUDSON: Something's moving,
and it ain't us!
FROST: Oh, shit.
HUDSON:
Tracker's off-scale, man.
They're all around us, man!
Jesus!
DIETRICH: Maybe they don't
show up on infrared at all.
Aah!
FROST: Aah!
APONE: Frost!
DIETRICH: Aah!
Come on!
CROWE: Aah!
GORMAN: Jesus Christ, Apone!
What is going on?
HICKS: Wierzbowski
and Crowe are down!
APONE:
Dietrich, Crowe! Sound off!
Frost! Frost!
WIERZBOWSKl: Aah!
Wierzbowski!
VASQUEZ: Let's rock!
DRAKE: Yeah!
Yeah!
Who's firing? God damn it!
VASQUEZ: Yeah!
I ordered a hold fire.
HUDSON: They're coming out of
the goddamn walls! Let's book!
Uh, Apone...
I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with...
APONE: Vasquez, Drake,
hold your fire, God damn it!
GORMAN: Are you copying me?
Lay down a suppressing fire
with the incinerators...
and fall back by squads...
APONE: Say again?
All after "incinerator."
Lay down a suppressing fire
with the incinerators...
and fall back...
[Loud gunfire]
APONE: Aah!
HUDSON: Sarge!
Apone, talk to me.
Apone? Talk to me!
RIPLEY: He's gone!
[Shouting and gunfire]
Get them out of there!
GORMAN: Shut up!
Hicks, whoever's left,
get the hell...
- Shut up!
- God damn it!
HICKS: Where's Apone?!
Where's Apone?!
The Sarge is gone!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
HICKS: Let's go, Marines!
Hudson?
Vasquez?
HICKS: Hudson, look out!
HUDSON: Get it!
HICKS: Hudson!
GORMAN: Hicks! Hicks!
HICKS: lt's too much!
Fall back!
GORMAN:
I told them to fall back.
RIPLEY: They're cut off!
Do something!
Fuck!
HICKS: Keep movin'!
RIPLEY: Hold on, Newt.
Ripley,
what the hell are you doing?
GORMAN: Turn around!
That's an order!
RIPLEY: Get off me, damn it!
GORMAN:
God damn it, that's an order!
BURKE:
You had your chance, Gorman.
HICKS: Come on!
VASQUEZ: Come on, Drake!
DRAKE: Yeah!
HICKS: Let's move it!
VASQUEZ:
Come on. Let's go! Let's go!
HUDSON: lt's blocked, man.
We got to go around!
RIPLEY: Open the door! Hicks!
HICKS: Drake, we are leaving!
DRAKE: Run for it!
Shit!
[Grunting]
BURKE: Let's go!
VASQUEZ: Drake, come on, man!
Drake, come on!
Aah!
No!
HUDSON: Fire in the hold!
HICKS: He's gone!
VASQUEZ: No! Drake's out there!
HUDSON: Put it out!
VASQUEZ: Drake's coming!
HICKS: He's gone!
VASQUEZ: No, he's not!
HICKS: Forget him! He's gone!
Get on the goddamn door!
HICKS: Eat this!
HUDSON: Aah!
HICKS: Ripley! Go, go, go!
HICKS: Whoa!
GORMAN: Oh.
[Screeches]
HICKS:
lt's all right! We're clear!
Ripley,
you've blown the transaxle!
You're just grinding metal!
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
RIPLEY: You OK?
HUDSON: I'm all right.
Get away from me, man!
HICKS: Lieutenant.
RIPLEY: What happened to Gorman?
HICKS: I don't know...
maybe a concussion,
but he's alive.
VASQUEZ: No, man, he's dead!
Wake up, pendejo!
I'm going to kill you!
HICKS: Back off.
Right now.
Somebody get me a first aid kit.
HUDSON: Hey. Hey, look.
The Sarge and Dietrich
aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low,
but they ain't dead.
Then we get them.
- We don't leave people behind!
- I ain't going back!
You can't help them!
You can't.
Right now they're being cocooned
just like the others.
HUDSON: Oh, dear Lord Jesus,
this ain't happenin', man.
HICKS: God damn it.
HUDSON:
This can't be happenin', man.
This isn't happenin'!
We've got
seven canisters of CN-20.
I say we roll them in there
and nerve gas the whole nest.
HICKS: lt's worth a try, but we
don't know if it'll affect them.
HUDSON: Let's bug out and call
it even. Why even talk about it?
RIPLEY: I say we take off and
nuke the entire site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
HUDSON: Fuckin' "A"!
BURKE: Hold on one second.
This installation
has a substantial dollar value.
They can bill me.
OK, look.
This is an emotional moment
for all of us, OK?
I know that.
But let's not make
snap judgments, please.
This is clearly an important
species we're dealing with...
and I don't think you or I
or anybody has the right...
to arbitrarily exterminate them.
Wrong.
VASQUEZ: Yeah. Watch us.
HUDSON: Maybe you haven't been
keeping up on current events...
but we just got
our asses kicked, pal!
I'm not blind
to what's going on...
but I cannot authorize that kind
of action. I'm sorry.
Well, I believe Corporal Hicks
has authority here.
Corporal Hicks is...
RIPLEY: This operation
is under military jurisdiction.
Hicks is next in chain
of command, right, Corporal?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
BURKE: Yeah. Look, Ripley...
this is a multimillion dollar
installation, OK?
He can't make that decision.
He's just a grunt.
Uh, no offense.
HICKS: None taken.
Ferro, do you copy?
FERRO: Standing by.
HICKS: Prep for dust-off.
We need immediate evac.
FERRO: Roger. On our way.
HICKS: I say we take off,
nuke the site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Let's do it.
HICKS: Let's go.
Pick it up, Hudson.
Pick it up, baby.
All right. Set him down here.
Move it, Spunkmeyer.
We're rolling.
Hold on a second.
There's something...
FERRO: Just get up here.
I'm in. Ramp closing.
Spunkmeyer.
God damn it.
[Door slides open]
Well, where the fuck...
Run!
Well, that's great.
That's just fuckin' great, man.
Now what the fuck
are we supposed to do?
We're in some real
pretty shit now, man!
HICKS: Are you finished?
HICKS: You all right?
NEWT: I guess we're not
gonna be leaving now, right?
RIPLEY: I'm sorry, Newt.
You don't have to be sorry.
It wasn't your fault.
HUDSON: That's it, man.
Game over, man! Game over!
What the fuck
are we gonna do now?
What are we gonna do?
BURKE: Maybe we could build
a fire, sing a couple of songs.
Why don't we try that?
NEWT: We'd better get back
'cause it'll be dark soon...
and they mostly come at night.
Mostly.
HICKS: That's everything, right?
This is absolutely everything
we could salvage...
out of the APC wreckage.
We got four pulse-rifles
with about fifty rounds each.
That ain't so good.
We got fifteen
of these M-40 grenades.
Don't touch that.
Dangerous, honey.
RIPLEY:
ls that the only flamethrower?
HICKS: Yeah. It's only
half-full, but it's functional.
And another one's damaged.
I don't know about that one.
But the good news...
we got four of these
robot sentries...
with display
and scanners intact.
They really kick ass.
They'll come in handy.
How long after we're declared
overdue can we expect a rescue?
Seventeen days.
Seventeen days?
Hey, man, I don't wanna
rain on your parade...
but we're not gonna last
seventeen hours.
Those things are gonna come here
like they did before, and...
Hudson! Hudson!
This little girl
survived longer than that...
with no weapons and no training.
Right?
Why don't you put her in charge?
You better just start
dealing with it, Hudson.
Deal with it,
because we need you...
and I'm sick of your bullshit.
Now get on a terminal
and call up a floor plan file.
Construction blueprints.
I don't care.
Anything that shows the layout.
- Are you listening?
- Yeah.
RIPLEY: I need to see air ducts,
electrical access tunnels...
sub-basements...
every possible way
into this complex.
We don't have much time.
OK.
OK, I'm on it.
RIPLEY: Hudson!
Just relax.
l'll be in med lab.
l'll check on Gorman,
continue my analysis.
Fine.
You do that.
RIPLEY: This service tunnel...
must be how
they're moving back and forth.
HUDSON: That's right.
It moves from
the processing station...
right into the sub-level.
Come down on that.
OK, come over.
Hold it. Go back.
Punch that in there.
HICKS: No. It's back here.
RIPLEY: OK.
There's a pressure door
at this end.
Couldn't we put a remote
sentry unit in the tunnel...
then seal that door?
HICKS: That'll work...
but we gotta figure on them
getting into the complex.
RIPLEY: That's right, so...
we repair the barricades
at these two intersections...
HICKS: Right.
...and weld plate steel over
these ducts here and here...
and here.
Then they can only come at us
from these two corridors.
HICKS: Right. Then we put
the other sentry units here...
and here, right?
- Right.
- Outstanding.
Now all we need
is a deck of cards.
Let's move
like we've got a purpose.
HUDSON: Affirmative.
NEWT: Affirmative.
HUDSON: Do your thing, baby.
Come on, Vasquez,
let's get out of here.
"A" and "B" sentries
are in place and keyed.
HICKS: Roger.
Stand by. Arming now.
Test it, Hudson.
- Do it.
- Fire in the hole!
HUDSON: Great.
Let's get the hell out of here.
We're sealing the tunnel.
Come on, baby.
HICKS: For what it's worth.
I want you to put this on.
RIPLEY: What's it for?
It's a locator.
Then I can find you anywhere
in the complex on this.
It's just a precaution.
Thanks.
Doesn't mean we're engaged
or anything.
All right, what's next?
RIPLEY: Last stop.
Get in.
Scoot down.
That's good.
Now lie here and have a nap.
You're very tired.
I don't want to.
I have scary dreams.
Well, I bet Casey
doesn't have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
Nope. Nothing bad in there.
See?
Maybe you could just
try to be like her.
Ripley, she doesn't
have bad dreams...
because she's just
a piece of plastic.
Right.
I'm sorry, Newt.
RIPLEY: There.
My mommy always said
there were no monsters...
no real ones, but there are.
Yes, there are, aren't there?
Why do they tell
little kids that?
Most of the time it's true.
Did one of those things
grow inside her?
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
Isn't that how babies come...
I mean, people babies?
They grow inside you.
No. That's very different.
NEWT: Did you ever have a baby?
Yes, I did.
I had a little girl.
Where is she?
She's gone.
You mean dead.
Here.
Take this.
For luck.
How's that?
Don't go, please.
Newt, I'm gonna be
right in the next room.
And you see that camera?
I can see you
through that camera...
to see if you're safe.
I'm not gonna leave you, Newt.
I mean that.
That's a promise.
You promise?
I cross my heart.
And hope to die?
And hope to die.
Now go to sleep...
and don't dream.
Sneak.
BISHOP:
The molecular acid oxidizes...
after the creature's death,
completely neutralizing it.
Bishop, that's interesting,
but it gets us nowhere.
I'm trying to figure out
what we're dealing with.
Let's go through it again.
They grab the colonists,
they move them over there...
and they immobilize them
to be hosts for more of these.
Which means there would have
to be a lot of these parasites.
One for each colonist.
That's over a hundred, at least.
Yes. That follows.
Each one of these things
comes from an egg, right?
So who's laying these eggs?
I'm not sure.
It must be something
we haven't seen yet.
Hey, maybe
it's like an ant hive.
- Bees have hives.
- You know what I mean.
There's, like, one female
that runs the whole show.
BISHOP: Yes. The queen.
HUDSON: Yeah. The mama.
And she's badass, man.
I mean big.
- These things ain't ants.
- I know that.
Bishop, I want
these specimens destroyed...
as soon as
you're finished with them.
Mr. Burke gave instructions...
they were to be kept alive
for return to the Company labs.
He was very specific about it.
Those two specimens
are worth millions...
to the bio-weapons division.
If you're smart, we can both
come out of this heroes...
and we will be set up for life.
You're crazy, Burke.
Do you know that?
Do you think you can get
a dangerous organism...
past ICC quarantine?
How can they impound it
if they don't know about it?
But they will know
about it, Burke. From me.
Just like they'll know
you were responsible...
for the deaths of one hundred
fifty-seven colonists.
BURKE: Wait a second!
- You sent them to that ship.
- You're wrong.
I just checked
the colony log...
directive dated 6-12-79,
signed Burke, Carter J.
You sent them out there
and didn't even warn them.
Why didn't you warn them, Burke?
What if that ship
didn't even exist?
Did you think about that?
I didn't know.
So if I made a major
security situation out of it...
everybody steps in...
and there's no
exclusive rights for anybody.
Nobody wins. I made a decision,
and it was wrong.
It was a bad call, Ripley.
RIPLEY: Bad call?
These people are dead, Burke!
Haven't you any idea
what you've done?
I'm gonna make sure
they nail you right to the wall.
You're not gonna sleaze your way
out of this one.
Right to the wall.
Ripley.
You know,
I expected more from you.
I thought
you'd be smarter than this.
I'm happy to disappoint you.
[Alarm from robot sentries]
HUDSON: What's going on?
HICKS: They're coming.
- Where?
- In the tunnel.
Here we go.
"A" and "B" gun
tracking and firing.
Multiple targets.
[Aliens screeching
over sentry transmitter]
Look at those ammo counters go.
"B" gun's down 50 percent.
Man, it's a shooting gallery
down there.
HICKS: Sixty rounds left on "B."
Forty... twenty... ten.
"B" gun's dry. Twenty on "A."
Ten... five...
That's it.
HUDSON: Jesus.
They're wall-to-wall in there.
[Loud thumping noises]
They're at the pressure door.
Man, listen to that.
BISHOP: Bishop here.
I'm afraid I have some bad news.
Well, that's a switch.
RIPLEY: lt's very pretty,
but what are we looking for?
BISHOP: That's it.
Emergency venting.
HUDSON: That's beautiful, man.
That beats it all.
HICKS: How long till it blows?
BISHOP: Four hours...
with a blast radius
of thirty kilometers...
equal to about forty megatons.
HICKS: We got problems.
HUDSON: I don't fucking
believe this!
HICKS: Vasquez,
close the shutters.
RIPLEY: Why can't we
shut it down from here?
BISHOP: The crash
caused too much damage.
An overload was inevitable
at this point.
HUDSON:
Oh, man, I was getting short.
Four more weeks and out.
Now I'm going to buy it
on this rock.
VASQUEZ: Give us a break!
HUDSON: Four more weeks.
Oh, man.
RIPLEY: We need the other
drop-ship from the Sulaco.
Can't we bring it down
on remote?
The transmitter was on the APC.
It's wasted.
I don't care how.
We better think of a way.
HUDSON: Think of what?
We're fucked! We're doomed!
Shut up! What about
the colony transmitters?
The uplink tower
at the other end?
The hard-wiring between here
and there was damaged.
We can't align the dish.
Somebody's gonna
have to go out there...
take a portable terminal
and patch in manually.
Yeah, sure. With those things
running around?
You can count me out.
HICKS: We can count you
out of everything.
BISHOP: l'll go.
HUDSON: You go, man.
RIPLEY: What?
l'll go.
I'm the only one qualified
to remote-pilot the ship.
HUDSON: Yeah, right, man.
Bishop should go.
Good idea.
BISHOP: Believe me,
I'd prefer not to.
I may be synthetic,
but I'm not stupid.
RIPLEY: How long?
BISHOP: This conduit runs
almost to the uplink assembly...
one hundred eighty meters.
Say forty minutes
crawling there...
an hour to patch in
and align the antenna...
thirty minutes
to prep the ship...
and about fifty minutes
flight time.
RIPLEY: lt's gonna be close.
RIPLEY: Good luck.
BISHOP: See you soon.
Watch your fingers.
Oh.
VASQUEZ: Vaya con Dios, man.
HICKS: This is unbelievable.
Twenty meters and closing.
Fifteen.
RIPLEY: How many?
HICKS: Can't tell. Lots.
"D" gun's down 50 percent.
"C" gun's right behind it.
HUDSON: lt ain't stopping 'em.
Jesus, it ain't stopping 'em.
HICKS: A hundred and fifty
rounds on "D."
HUDSON: Come on, baby. Come on.
HICKS: One hundred rounds.
HUDSON: Come on, come on.
[Beeping]
"D" gun's down to twenty.
Ten.
Damn it!
Wait! They're retreating.
RIPLEY: The guns stopped them.
You're right.
HICKS: Next time
they walk right up and knock.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
They're probably looking
for other ways to get in.
That'll take 'em a while.
- Maybe we got 'em demoralized.
- Shut up.
I want you two
walking perimeter.
Move!
HICKS: Hey, listen.
We're all in strung-out shape...
but stay frosty and alert.
We can't afford to let
one of those bastards in here.
All right. Vámonos.
How long's it been
since you got any sleep?
Twenty-four hours?
Hicks, I'm not gonna end up
like those others.
You'll take care of it,
won't you?
If it comes to that,
l'll do us both.
Let's just make sure it doesn't
come to that, all right?
All right.
Hey, I want to introduce you
to a personal friend of mine.
This is an M-41A pulse-rifle,
ten millimeter...
with an over-and-under
30 millimeter grenade launcher.
Feel the weight.
OK, what do I do?
HICKS: Pull it in tight here.
- Right.
- Lean into it.
HICKS:
All right, it will kick some.
When the counter
reads zero here, you...
- I press this up?
- That's right.
Get another one in quick.
Slap it in hard.
Now you're ready
to rock 'n' roll.
- What's this?
- The grenade launcher.
I don't think you want
to mess with that.
You started this.
Show me everything.
I can handle myself.
Yeah, I noticed.
RIPLEY: How do you feel?
GORMAN: All right, I guess.
One hell of a hangover.
Look, Ripley, I just want...
RIPLEY: Forget it. Excuse me.
[Newt moaning]
RIPLEY: Shh, shh, shh.
It's OK. It's OK.
[Whispering]
Newt. Wake up.
- What?
- Be quiet.
We're in trouble.
- No!
- Aah!
Move, Newt!
RIPLEY: Hey!
[No sound]
NEWT: Help!
Help!
RIPLEY: Hicks!
HICKS: Say again, Bishop?
You've got it
into auto-refuel mode...
and it's sequencing right?
BISHOP: That's right.
HICKS: Good. Stay on it.
Get back to me when you've
activated the launch cycle.
He's at the uplink tower.
BURKE: Terrific.
- Hicks! Hicks!
- Help! Help!
Hicks! Help us!
Break the glass!
Break it, break it.
RIPLEY: l'll try.
Ripley, I'm scared.
Me, too.
Stay here.
[Alarm sounds]
HICKS: lt's the med lab.
Hudson!
Vasquez! Meet me in med lab.
We got a fire.
HUDSON: We're on our way.
They're coming, Newt.
Oh, please.
Aah!
Uh!
Shoot it out!
- Hudson!
- Jesus!
Oh!
Christ, kid, look out!
Fucking die!
- Over there!
- Yeah!
- Ready?
HICKS: Hudson!
HUDSON: Yeah, all clear.
Nailed the other one.
It's history, man.
HICKS: Jesus.
RIPLEY: Burke. It was Burke.
I say we grease this rat-fuck
son of a bitch right now.
HICKS: lt just doesn't make
any goddamn sense.
RIPLEY: He figured
that he could get an alien...
back through quarantine
if one of us was impregnated...
whatever you call it...
and then frozen
for the trip home.
Nobody would know about
the embryos we were carrying...
me and Newt.
Wait, now. We'd all know.
Yes. He could only do it by
sabotaging certain freezers...
on the way home, namely yours.
He could jettison the bodies
and make up any story he liked.
HUDSON: Fuck! He's dead.
You're dog meat, pal.
This is so nuts.
Listen to what you're saying.
It's paranoid delusion.
It's really sad.
It's pathetic.
Burke, I don't know
which species is worse.
They don't fuck each other over
for a goddamn percentage.
HICKS: All right, we waste him.
No offense.
RIPLEY:
No, he's got to go back...
They cut the power.
HUDSON: What do you mean "they"
cut the power? They're animals.
I want you two with trackers
checking the corridors! Move!
- Gorman, watch Burke.
- I got him.
Newt, stay close.
- L'll go this side.
- You do that, man.
Anything?
HUDSON: There's something.
- [Beeping]
- It's inside the complex.
You're just reading me.
- [Beeping]
- No, it ain't you.
They're inside the perimeter.
They're in here.
RIPLEY: Hudson, stay cool.
Vasquez?
[Beeps louder]
Hudson may be right.
RIPLEY: Get back.
HUDSON: The signal's weird.
Must be some interference
or something.
There's movement
all over the place.
Get back to Operations.
It's game time.
Newt.
RIPLEY: Seal the door. Hurry!
HICKS: Come on.
Come on, get back.
Work fast.
Cover your eyes, Newt.
Don't look at the light.
Movement. Signal's clean.
Range, twenty meters.
RIPLEY: They found a way in,
something we missed.
HICKS: We didn't miss anything.
HUDSON: Eighteen.
Seventeen meters.
RIPLEY: Something under
the floor, not in the plans.
- Fifteen meters.
- Ripley!
Definitely
inside the barricades.
Let's go.
RIPLEY: That's right outside
the door. Get back!
HUDSON:
This is a big fucking signal.
- How you doing, Vasquez?
- Almost there.
That's it.
HUDSON: Twelve meters.
Eleven. Ten.
- They're right on us.
- Nine meters.
Remember...
short, controlled bursts.
Eight meters.
Seven.
Six.
- That's inside the room.
- It's reading right!
You're not reading it right.
HUDSON: Five meters, man.
Four. What the hell?
HUDSON: Oh, my God.
HICKS: Give me the light.
Aah!
There they go! Get them!
- Come on!
- Get them!
BURKE: Do something, Gorman!
HUDSON: Look out! Look out!
Look out!
There's more of them!
Medical! Get to medical!
Do it! Now!
HICKS: Hudson, look out!
Aah!
Now!
Burke!
Open this door!
Burke! Open it!
Aah!
Come on! Let's go!
Fall back!
HICKS: Go!
HUDSON: Die, you bastards!
Die, motherfucker!
GORMAN: Burke!
HICKS: Hudson!
Hudson!
HUDSON: Motherfucker!
Come on! Come on!
Come and get it, baby!
I don't got all day!
Come on, you bastard!
Come on! You, too!
You want some of this? Fuck you!
Aah! Fuck you!
- Hicks!
- Hudson!
[Hudson screaming]
VASQUEZ: Come on, Hicks, go!
RIPLEY: lt's locked!
HICKS: Got it! Let's go!
GORMAN: Go! Go!
- Move, Gorman!
- Seal it!
RIPLEY: Burke! God damn you!
Open this door!
BURKE: Aah!
HICKS: Get back.
VASQUEZ: Hurry up.
HICKS:
Gorman, get out of the way!
NEWT: Ripley, this way.
RIPLEY: Wait. Get behind me.
Whatever you do, do it fast.
- Hicks!
- Come on, let's go.
GORMAN: Move!
- Which way to the landing field?
- This way.
NEWT: Go right.
NEWT: This way.
- Which way?
- Straight ahead and left.
Bishop, do you read me?
Come in. Over.
BISHOP: The ship is on its way.
ETA, sixteen minutes.
Stand by there.
We're on our way.
- Which way now?
- That way.
- No, wait. This way.
- You sure?
GORMAN: Vasquez, move!
- Right up here.
- Hicks!
- We're almost there.
- Newt, wait!
Newt!
Yaaa!
Aah!
HICKS: Vasquez!
GORMAN: Go!
Ohh! Oh, no!
RIPLEY: Newt.
NEWT: Up there, there's
a shortcut across the roof.
Hicks.
[Click click]
You always were
an asshole, Gorman.
RIPLEY: Aah! Newt!
- Ripley!
- Newt!
Hicks, get her! Hurry!
Oh! Hold on, Newt!
- I'm slipping!
- Don't let go!
- Ripley!
- Hold on.
- Help!
- Got you.
I got you.
Aah!
Newt! No!
HICKS: Come on.
We can find her with this.
Stay where you are, Newt.
- Ripley!
- We're coming.
Ripley!
[Beeping]
This way.
- She's close.
- Newt!
Ripley!
RIPLEY: Where are you?
Can you hear me?
- Newt!
- Here! I'm here!
RIPLEY: Where?
Newt, are you OK?
HICKS: Gonna have to cut it.
RIPLEY: Climb down, honey.
We've got to cut through.
Newt? Now, don't move.
Stay very still.
NEWT: OK.
We're almost there.
Hang in there, OK?
[Beeping]
Hicks. Hurry.
- I know.
- I mean it!
Newt, just stay still.
Aah!
HICKS: Almost there.
RIPLEY: No!
Newt!
No! No!
- Let's go.
- No! They don't kill you!
They don't kill you!
She's alive! She's alive!
HICKS: All right, I believe you.
She's alive.
We've got to go. Now!
- Hicks.
- Get it off!
Aah! Get it off! Aah!
RIPLEY: Here.
[Hicks groaning]
RIPLEY: Go.
Come on, you can make it!
RIPLEY: Bishop, how much time?
BISHOP:
Plenty. Twenty-six minutes.
- We're not leaving.
- We're not?
[Locator beeping]
BISHOP: Ripley...
RIPLEY: I don't want
to hear about it. She's alive.
BISHOP: In 19 minutes, this area
is gonna be a cloud of vapor...
the size of Nebraska.
- Don't let him leave.
- We ain't going anywhere.
- See you, Hicks.
- Dwayne.
It's Dwayne.
Ellen.
Don't be gone long, Ellen.
[Alarm sounds]
COMPUTER VOICE:
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have fifteen minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
COMPUTER VOICE:
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have fourteen minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
[Locator beeping]
[Locator beeps faster]
[Very fast beeping]
[Sobs]
[Screaming]
Aah!
NEWT: Ripley! Ripley!
RIPLEY: Grab on to me!
Hold on!
[Hissing]
[Screeching]
NEWT: Let's go!
Behind us!
[Alarm sounds]
COMPUTER VOICE:
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have four minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
[Queen screeches]
Come on, God damn it!
Hold on to me!
COMPUTER VOICE:
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have two minutes
to reach minimum safe distance.
No.
Bishop, God damn you!
Close your eyes, baby.
NEWT: Look!
NEWT: Come on! Come on!
Punch it, Bishop!
BISHOP: lt's OK. We're OK.
RIPLEY: Hey.
We made it.
NEWT: I knew you'd come.
BISHOP: He's gonna be all right.
He's just out. I had to give him
another shot for the pain.
We need a stretcher
to carry him up to medical.
RIPLEY: OK.
BISHOP:
I'm sorry if I scared you.
That platform
was becoming too unstable.
I had to circle and hope
things didn't get too rough...
to take you off.
RIPLEY: Bishop... you did OK.
I did?
Oh, yeah.
Go! Move!
No! Here! Here!
Run!
Here!
Aah!
Get away from her, you bitch!
Come on! Come on!
Aah!
Ripley!
[Alarm sounds]
Aah!
Oh!
[Screeching]
Aah!
Bishop!
- Mommy.
- Oh, God!
Not bad for a human.
Are we gonna sleep
all the way home?
All the way home.
Can I dream?
Yes, honey.
I think we both can.
- Sleep tight.
- Affirmative.
Ripping & Subtitles
4EverPsycho
lovespiral@mail.ru